NARRATOR:
Previously on Justified...
Hey, Uncle Jack?
It's Kendal.
You cared so much about Kendal,
he'd be back in Miami with you right now.
Just like how you're down in Florida
with your little girl right now, you mean?
Help me get Darryl.
You really think I'd betray my family?
Sorry you wasted your time
coming all the way up from
Harlan just to give me shit.
Oh, I didn't come up here
to talk to you, Alison.
I... I came to
talk to your boss.
RAYLAN: Two weeks, huh?
- Yeah.
- I could use two weeks off.
I got some vacation time.
I'm gonna go down to Florida, see my kid.
Going on your own dime this time?
No, Chief.
I won it on a radio contest.
That's why you ought to rely
on the heavenly mother.
I'm not interested in religion, Penny.
You interested in staying alive?
You saying you can get heroin?
That's what I'm saying.
The hardest part ain't getting the drugs.
It's getting them inside.
What do you want to do? I'm
gonna book a one-way ticket
to Mexico and bring back
my 25 kilos of heroin.
Don't do it!
What the hell are you doing?
He pulled on me!
(LAUGHS)
Good luck getting that shit out of Mexico.
Tell Mr. Yoon we have
a problem.
(CONVERSING IN SPANISH)
(FLIES BUZZING)
I hope they're talking about breakfast.
I'm starving.
He's bitching about having to bury us.
Alberto...
While your demeanor
is cause for some relief,
I take it there's more to the story.
You keep your lives.
ALBERTO: You forfeit the
shipment and the cash.
The business relationship is over.
Hey, come on, man.
That is some bullshit.
You agreed not to spill blood,
yet there are four bodies.
Well, I don't see any bodies.
I don't see any bodies 'cause
my boys picked them up
and hauled them back
across the border, Alberto.
There will be no headlines
in your local paper.
Now, I know I'm not
in a position to negotiate,
but when I make a new friend,
I generally like to keep them.
So, will you please call
Mr. Yoon one more time?
(DIALING)
That's gonna look awful bad,
we get pulled over
with a load of dead dudes in the truck.
You ain't got to worry, cousin Dewey.
We'll hide them underneath
all that heroin.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Okay.
The bodies disappear, all is well.
Muchas gracias, mi amigo.
Boys, you heard him. Let's go!
So, we get 'em in the truck,
but without hot rod's connection,
how in the goddamn hell we supposed
to get four bodies across the fence?
Jimmy, do I have to
have an answer for everything?
DANNY: Well, it ain't like
we ain't smuggled shit before.
DARRYL: But through Texas?
Who? Flores?
He hates my ass.
DANNY: He's over that shit.
DARRYL: He ain't over it.
Over what? What, you kill
his dog or something?
DANNY: Oh, his sister's
definitely a dog.
We didn't kill her.
Except make her a little
bowlegged for a day or two.
It ain't happening, man.
We ain't calling him.
She took a lot of dick for a little lady.
The answer's no.
Only thing that Flores loves
more than his ugly sister,
is green gringo cash.
He got that shrimp boat down in Matamoros.
DANNY: (SIGHING)
Come on.
(STUTTERING) what else are we gonna do?
Think about it.
Could be worth a shot.
Well, then I suggest you take it
'cause I don't care if it's up
your ass or on your back...
You're responsible for getting
my dope across that border.
Now, you shot 'em, so you put
'em in the back of the truck.
Okay.
Let's go, y'all.
Hey, little boy.
Want a lollipop?
I don't like candy.
Aw, what kid don't like candy?
You know, I lost a puppy near here.
Real cute, just like you.
Want to help me find him?
Don't like dogs.
Get in.
KENDAL: You're such an asshole, Uncle Jack.
You got big.
You've gotten old.
What do you say, grab your sister?
Get some breakfast?
Hmm?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
You'd be surprised.
All that's sprung up
in the north country...
Every one of them,
bona fide American boomtown.
JACK: You mark my words.
Five... Ten years tops, fracking is
gonna wean us off the Iraqi oil tit,
keep the jobs and the money right
here in the good old U.S. Of A.
Wait. So you're sayin' you're in the
shale oil hydraulic fracturing business?
No. Well, see, what I do,
I was moving around a bit,
put down in Williston, set up
a regular game of hold 'em.
You know how it is with those roughnecks.
They get their 1st and 15th.
Starts burning a hole in their pocket.
It's been good for me.
That's why I'm down here. I
wanted to take a few days off.
Can I get another cocoa?
It costs for refills.
Shit. Are you serious? What is it, a buck?
Go on, man. It's on me.
So, how is it that you
actually got prettier?
Oh, please, Jack.
What?
You are just gonna blow his
hopes all out of whack,
and I'm gonna have to
stop it... Again.
You just always do this. You
make me out to be the villain.
No, I don't.
That's not true, is it?
Why are you really here?
You need money?
No, I don't need...
I'm not here for money.
The boy called me.
A few times.
Well, he probably just thought it was best
you visit while his brothers are gone.
How is Danny?
He still wants to cut off your dick.
So, is that really
what this is... A visit?
Is that so inconceivable?
Huh?
Hey, you know what I was thinking?
Come this weekend, how about I
take you both to cedar point?
Where's that?
Ohio.
They got rolly-coasters there.
One's called the millennium force.
Dude, it's a face-melter.
Let's do it.
Actually, you know what?
I have a better idea.
We'll go on your holiday
break, take a whole week.
Do a whole rolly-coaster tour.
Yeah. Okay.
Look, let's finish up and get you back
to school before you miss an entire day.
Excuse me.
(SIGHS)
(INHALES DEEPLY)
So, you like it here?
I hate it here.
(SIGHS)
Shit!
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
- Finally!
- God almighty. Stop freaking out.
I'm not freaking out.
You've left me like 800 messages.
Would you put your uncle
Jack on the phone right now?
Okay.
Yello?
WENDY: You listen to me. You
need to turn that car around.
Wen, babe, we'll call you from Ohio.
You asshole. Turn around and
get back here right now.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Who were you talking to?
I'm sorry. What?
On the phone, all agitated.
Who with?
I don't work here.
I'm more of a silent partner.
If you're looking for some action,
the girls don't get in till later.
It's early still.
Who was on the phone?
You keep asking me that like
it's somehow your business.
I apologize.
That was rude of me.
My name's Michael.
I'm looking for a man named Jack Anderson.
Heard he might be found here.
Oh.
I mean, Tina's got a regular by
the name of Jack Macy, I think,
but I don't know any Jack Anderson.
He a local?
He's from North Dakota.
Why?
Well, the guys around here don't
always volunteer their name,
but sometimes where they're from.
I don't really remember anybody
from North Dakota, though.
Anyway...
Can I get you a drink?
I'm not here to drink.
You a cop?
Do I look like a cop?
I'd have believed you
if you said you were.
What you got back there?
Oh. (CHUCKLES)
Somebody asleep on the job.
Yeah. Well,
good help's hard to find.
Think I changed my mind.
I'll have that drink.
Rum and coke.
You got it. I'll get it
for you when I come back.
(GLASSES CLINKING)
(GUN CLICKING)
(THEME SONG PLAYING)
♪ On this lonely road
♪ Trying to make it home
♪ Doing it by my lonesome,
pissed off, who wants some?
♪ I'm fighting for my soul
♪ God get at your boy
♪ You try to bogard fall back, I go hard
♪ On this lonely road
♪ Trying to make it home
♪ Doing it by my lonesome,
pissed off, who wants some?
♪ I see them long, hard times to come ♪
Said I'd pay you back for
those drinks the other night,
so I bought you something.
Oh.
Lingerie? Really?
A bathing suit.
A nice one...
Least, I think.
Well, you know I don't have
a pool or a lake house
or a membership
at the "Y."
Funny story.
I recently won some money
in a radio contest.
What?
Caller Number 7
(LAUGHING) That's the craziest thing.
And plus, I've been thinking
about what you asked me.
I kind of forget. Short-term
memory is a casualty of my habit.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
RAYLAN: On vacation.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
I was thinking, uh, take my
winnings and go down to Florida
and... See my baby girl,
check in with the ex.
Oh. That. yeah.
And I bought you that bikini thinking
you might want to come with.
You want me to parade around
in front of your ex-wife?
What, show off my body, make her jealous?
No. I didn't suppose
you two would even meet.
But I thought, hell, you're suspended.
Flights are cheap.
We could blow the two grand
on a nice motel.
Really?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yeah.
You could hang out at the spa while
I spend a little quality time...
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
...and then we can meet up
later and have a meal or two.
Still, taking a girl with you to
visit your semi-estranged family...
It's a weird scenario.
I didn't say it wasn't.
But I'm trying.
So, what do you say? Will you
come with me to Florida?
(BREATHES DEEPLY) Hmm.
All right.
Cool.
Well, pack a bag.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
You should grab that.
It's obviously something.
(SIGHS)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Givens.
Hi. It's Wendy Crowe.
I need your help.
That's putting the shoe on the other foot.
Kendal's been abducted.
Well, then, you do need help, but not mine.
Call the police.
Okay, not abducted
abducted, but he's gone...
With his Uncle Jack.
I thought our relationship
was adversarial.
Now you're reaching out?
I'm on vacation.
There's someone after Jack, and
I fear for Kendal's safety.
Dial 911.
You wanted something on my brothers.
I'm gonna give you something, okay?
They're in Mexico.
- And?
- And you'll get the rest later.
You know that t-shirt... "I think
you've mistaken me for someone who..."
I'll call your girlfriend's boss,
get her off her suspension.
Eh, she's on paid leave.
She's fine with it.
Who is it?
Wendy Crowe. Kendal's
run off with an uncle.
She wants him back, and she's worried
there's this bad man
that's after the uncle.
Where are you?
DARRYL:
I know what you thinking.
Well, I'll wager you a crisp
ben franklin you do not.
You wondering, "Can I trust
these dusty-ass Crowe boys?"
I owe you $100.
You keep that money, Boyd.
Time we get to Harlan with all them drugs,
you'll realize you can make
so much more with us...
Than without.
Well, Darryl Jr., needing
you and trusting you
are two altogether different things.
I hope one day you stop
thinking of us as partners,
but family.
You sure about that?
Yeah, man. I don't want all this
mistrust to go and poison the well.
Well, I'll bear that in mind.
And you bear in mind that I just executed
the last blood relative that I had.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Hey!
(THUDDING) Hey!
Shit.
BOYD: Hey!
Hey!
What is y'all doing?
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Hey!
Get out! Get out!
Do you know we got 25 kilos of
heroin in the back of this truck?
It's hot, man.
It's goddamn hot.
I can't take much more riding
back there with them corpses.
The dude I was on, I could
feel his insides letting go.
Couple more hours like that,
it's gonna be seven bodies.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
You better sleep with your eyes open!
What's wrong with you, man?
We gonna have to get another car.
Well, can I request we get one with A/C?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(SIGHS)
Hello?
Yeah.
Well, can't be.
I know for a fact that card expires 2015.
JACK: Well, it's not my fault
it didn't clear.
Wait. Ho...
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What did you just say?
Well, what did he look like?
Is that Wendy?
No.
I was at a motel last couple nights.
Manager just called and says
I charged a bunch of stuff,
but I didn't charge...
That stuff.
So I didn't pay for it.
But... I was in there.
I was thinking...
I've rode all that shit at cedar point.
What we should do
is go hit six flags Texas.
You know, I'm not a kid anymore, okay?
Tell me the truth.
Are you in trouble?
All right.
I was at a bar back in Williston
with a buddy of mine and his sister.
She heads into the can.
And a few minutes later, we
start hearing this screaming.
So I charge in there.
And I see her about to get raped.
I had this pool cue in my hand,
and I... I just went off.
I put the dude in the hospital.
And I just got out of dodge.
That was my buddy calling,
saying the dude's out of his coma.
He's gunning for me.
That's the truth.
Think maybe you should go home.
I bet you can handle him.
Either way, I think you should go.
Where?
Hold on tight.
(MUMBLES)
Ready?
Mmm-hmm.
One, two, three.
PENNY: Ah!
(AVA GROANS)
Ahhh!
Help! Guard!
PENNY: We need medical help!
She's hurt.
AVA: Oh!
Any news?
They were here.
Now they're gone.
Got a general heading based on
Kendal's cell pinging the towers,
but not much more since we spoke.
What about this Michael person?
I can't pin him down based on your story.
Could be an old friend, could
be Jack's banging his wife.
I don't know.
He seemed to mean business.
You shot his car full of buckshot.
You think I provoked him?
Well, I don't know, do I?
Oh, see, this is that attitude
you have had
right from the very beginning,
this antagonism.
I approached you, attempted to bargain.
After considerable unpleasantness.
Anyway, I'm here now...
- To help.
- You've got your reasons.
You are obsessed
with my family, after all.
Oh, no.
I think of them like cancer,
and I'm just a doctor working on a cure.
I am deeply offended by that.
You ain't offended.
You're conflicted about helping me.
All I want is to
get Kendal back home safely.
And yet, you were the one who took him
out of a good, Christian foster home,
threw him back to those wolves.
Time is wasting.
Can we go?
All right, come here.
Can you squeeze
your fingers down in there?
These things are a jiff to get started.
We're stealing a car now?
That wasn't clear?
How much trouble are you in?
Well, he's a very angry man,
and he knows my car.
You're lying.
No. I'm not.
Yes, you are. You lie about
everything, and you always have.
Name one lie.
You're my dad and Wendy's my mom.
How long have you known?
A long time.
- Wendy told you.
- No, I figured it out, okay?
Now cut the shit.
What did you really do?
'Cause I don't think you're
some hero that stopped a rape.
(SIGHS)
I followed the workers, the money...
North Dakota, Montana.
I was running poker games.
And I had an idea that I was gonna
buy in to this fracking operation.
MAN: Coming through.
(SIGHS)
Shit.
Come on.
I was gonna buy into this
fracking operation in Mexico.
So I started skimming
from my regular game...
Heavy-duty
player in particular.
It was a good hustle...
Till the guy found out.
It's mostly his money in the bag.
How much?
About $35,000.
Whoa.
Trouble is,
he wants it back... Bad.
So, you were trucking down to Mexico...
...gonna lay low
and start your own thing.
KENDAL: And you got my call,
and you came back for me?
That's exactly right.
Why didn't you
tell me that from the start?
Wh...
(SIGHS)
What a pussy.
(BUZZER)
Crowder, Ava?
Says the shoulder's dislocated?
Yes.
Have a seat.
Happened before.
The coach just...
(GROANS)
...yanked it out
and pushed it back in.
Hurt like hell.
Unless this was back before the
civil war, your coach was a fool.
Lay down.
(GROANS)
There you go.
(SIGHS)
Wasn't quite that far back.
Going on 20 years now.
(AVA GASPS)
All right.
Ahhh!
Now it should feel better.
(GROANS) All right, sit up.
It does. It feels better.
(SIGHS)
It'll be sore again later.
I can give you some Aspirin.
I was told that you might have a way
to bring in some
more powerful pain-killers.
Don't lay on that side.
And don't lift anything
more than five pounds.
I said, I was told...
You can't get more powerful
pain meds, all right?
If you dislocated your own
shoulder just for that,
you're an idiot.
Get your Aspirin from the dispensary.
(SCOFFS)
This mess.
You don't see how trouble
follows your family?
The men, mostly.
What are they up to in Mexico?
Kendal's not my brother.
See? Now, that doesn't get me anywhere.
He's my son.
Jack is his father.
Just thought you should understand.
Good lord. Why?
I don't know.
I was 22 when I met him.
I was studying for my LSATs.
He was a real hustler
and an asshole piece of shit,
but I found him intoxicating,
for some unknown reason.
So I got pregnant, and, of course,
the thought of being
a dad scared him shitless.
So...
As much as it might benefit
you to unburden yourself,
I'd like to get back to Darryl
and what criminal activity
he might be engaged in.
Not until you get Kendal back.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
It's Jack.
Where are you?
W... Can we put aside
the bad blood?
Can we do that?
All right.
'Cause I need your help.
All right. I'm listening.
We got to be smart about this.
We got to scare up one of your brothers.
Darryl, Dilly, Danny...
Whoever.
I messed up... Bad.
Really, really bad.
He's got Kendal.
Sometimes shooting out
a man's tires ain't enough.
Maybe he had a second car
stashed somewhere
or a second driver keeping
tabs on the situation.
Or maybe he's just a bad dude who's
good at hunting people down.
I just don't get it.
He found them before you did.
But isn't that what marshals
are supposed to do?
Again, Wendy, I don't know how
the man beat me to the punch,
and I don't give a shit.
The important thing is not how we
arrived at this sad state of affairs.
It's how we get Kendal back safe
so you can live up to
your side of the deal.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
It's coming.
Not here about that.
You go to church as a girl?
I did.
But it didn't take, huh?
Not for me, neither.
But what me and my girls got going on here
ain't about no good book
or the holy ghost feeling.
It's about prayer.
Pretty much every girl in here
is in here because of a man.
You any different?
Hmm.
Pretty girl like you,
growing up in Harlan.
You're in good shape still.
Probably a cheerleader back in school.
Probably went out with the
quarterback, got married,
had it good for a minute. Things
got ugly, and you got divorced.
How am I doing?
Well, he wasn't a quarterback.
He was a running back.
We didn't get divorced.
I shot him.
Good for you, sister.
Who do you pray to?
God.
As I see her.
For guidance.
Strength.
No man to come save us,
not even our release.
Not even to find a way to get drugs in.
Ain't none of that our
mother god's responsibility.
That shit's on you.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Tell me Kendal's all right.
Come to the far end of the lot,
and I'll give you the dough.
JACK: I don't feel comfortable
being the goddamn bait.
RAYLAN: You're only the bait
if we're looking to catch
what's-his-name,
which I'm not.
What? Why are you even here?
What the hell?
This is the bad guy in all this.
That's how you see it, huh?
I'm telling you...
He's a heavy dude.
He's definitely wanted for something.
Why you took the money and ran.
You're such an unbelievable chicken shit.
Even I stood up to him.
With a pump gun.
All I had was this...
Which, incidentally, is
just gonna piss him off.
Because now what?
'Cause he's expecting $35,000.
All I have is $20,000 in here.
I bought that Chevelle,
which I hated to leave.
Yeah, but leaving your son...
That, you were fine with.
I get it.
I panicked and ran.
Don't you think I feel shitty about it?
Jesus, Wendy.
Let's not get bogged down in the past.
Focus on the plan.
I feel shitty about it all.
I should have never come got him. I
should have just blasted down south.
- Don't you dare blame Kendal for this, Jack.
- What'd I just say?
WENDY: This whole thing
is your own goddamn...
But I'm not the one that makes him want
to leave his own family and escape.
They're a bunch of psychos.
When you knocked me up, you ran then,
too, didn't you? Story of your life.
I do not want to hear
another word of this story.
What's gonna happen is, when he comes,
you tell him all you got is the $20,000.
He'll take it, even if
I have to persuade him.
We'll take Kendal.
And that's it?
He just goes?
Yeah, Jack.
You too.
I want you to find a hole somewhere,
crawl in it, and stay there forever.
(STAMMERS) Hey, how about a little respect?
You know what your deal is?
You're born to lose.
Lose well for once.
You might earn some respect.
So, uh, do we need to call for a backup?
I can handle one guy.
Yeah, but what about Kendal?
He'll be fine.
Yeah.
And if not, what do you care?
You're clearly not legit. What
kind of trouble can you get in?
I care... To a point.
You balling Wendy?
You owe her a favor?
Your ex-wife and I
have an agreement.
What she's gonna tell me when this
is over, that's what I care about.
Yeah. He's got a problem
with Darryl and Danny, too.
Oh.
So, he's not a total asshole?
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
(SIREN WAILING)
Oh, shit.
(GUN CLICKS)
Not unless you have to.
But if you have to,
you make every shot count.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Boys.
Well, I'm sorry, but that's
all the Spanish I know.
Jimmy?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Better I speak English, no?
Well, it would help.
What are you carrying?
Uh... Bibles.
We're missionaries, here to spread
the word to the far-flung citizenry.
Have you accepted Jesus Christ as
your lord and personal savior?
(SCOFFS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(SIGHS)
You do realize that this country
is 80% catholic, right, gringo?
Well, we're here for the other 20%.
You think that people look at you
and you move them into conversion?
Well, I... I do admit we are a
little rough around the edges.
We have all done some time, but...
Have been saved by his personal light.
For all have sinned and fall
short of the glory of god.
That's romans.
It's in the Bible.
Preach.
You know, it's a dangerous
road to be traveling at night.
You know what happens
around here, missionaries?
Uh, we're just trying to make Reynosa,
hop across the border by sunrise.
Ah, yes, yes.
But, uh, who will protect you
lambs in your journey, huh?
Who but us?
And, unfortunately, uh, protection
does not come free, my friend.
I'm sorry.
Are you attempting to extort
servants of the lord?
(CHUCKLES)
Let me tell you something, gringo.
White people come to this
country for two reasons.
One is for margaritas.
The other one is for drogas.
How much?
Ah. Now, that's better, ah? Now
it's all out in the open, right?
Ah, let's call it, uh...
1,000.
Pesos?
No problemo, mi amigo.
2,000 dollars, pendejo.
Oh, hell no!
Darryl.
No problem, amigo.
(SIGHS)
Gracias.
And, uh, we will also take the truck.
Man, we ain't giving up the...
Hey!
(ALL SHOUTING SPANISH)
DARRYL: How we gonna
give up the truck?
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
The truck ain't for sale.
Let me tell you something, my friend.
In Mexico, everything's for sale...
Everything.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
God. Goodness. This is some bullshit, man.
You gentlemen have a
pleasant night, safe trip.
Enjoy Mexico.
MICHAEL:
Can't clean up your own mess?
Got to bring your girlfriend
and his big brother?
Let's not escalate the situation.
Well, I think that ship sailed when
ginger over here shot my car to shit.
Mistakes were made.
My experience... Best
to accept and move on.
- I'm prepared to act in kind.
- That right?
You'll never hear
the word "kidnapping" from me.
I just want the boy home safe.
Kendal, get out of the car.
Take the money, Michael.
MICHAEL: You think that's what I want?
A couple of thousand dollars?
I want to break this asshole in two.
Not gonna happen.
Punishment ought to fit the crime.
Shit, Jack.
What'd you do?
He put my son in a coma.
The rapist?
What?
Well, he said he put a rapist in a
coma, but I didn't believe him.
He was ripping off my son,
his partner in staking
a weekly craps game.
Shut up. Come on, man.
My son found out
he was skimming every week.
Instead of sitting down,
owning up, face-to-face,
he hit him in the head with a
brick and ran like a pussy.
New deal...
You're both under arrest,
since you're a fugitive...
You're a dick.
Let KSP send you back
to North Dakota, work it out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
RAYLAN: Get off!
(GRUNTS)
Stay down.
You too.
Man, Jack. Jesus.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
MAN:
All right, I'll let him know.
(SIGHS) Hey.
So, I've been thinking,
you know, this whole ordeal...
Well, you and I have always had
a really shitty relationship.
I've been a bad person.
A bad mother.
Yeah. There... I said it.
I know you probably already suspected it,
but I thought it was probably
time you heard it from me.
So...
There you go.
(CHUCKLES)
Pretty messed up, huh?
Compared to what?
Good point.
Anyway...
On the bright side...
You only got half a dose
of the Crowe-family DNA.
Yeah, 'cause dad's such a prize.
I actually thought
he was, once upon a time.
Crazy, right?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(SIGHS)
Anyway...
How you want it to go now?
I don't care...
Sis.
(WATER RUNNING)
(WATER STOPS)
(SHOUTING IN DISTANCE)
This the one you talking about?
Mmm-hmm.
Just need to check on your
shoulder, see how it's doing.
You a fool coming to me like that.
You don't speak about this shit in the
infirmary with other people around.
You got it?
I will help you.
Two conditions.
You don't let Judith know
I'm the way in on this shit.
And your man outside...
You got a man outside?
Yes.
He gonna have to do something for me.
What's that?
Not saying.
Can you count on him?
Okay, then.
That's what it's gonna take.
You in or you out?
I'm in.
Shoulder looks good.
WOMAN: Stay out of trouble.
(SIREN WAILS)
How you doing?
KENDAL: Who gives a shit?
Think you'll survive three more years?
No.
I bet you will.
You know, turn 18, can get
the hell out of this mess.
Join the navy, make a life for yourself.
Shit, strap on a backpack
and bum around France.
It's not very likely.
It gets better, Kendal.
Man, I ain't gay.
Same principle applies.
Keep your head down,
think about the road ahead.
You'll make it through okay.
What the hell you know about it?
More than you'd guess.
I mean, I didn't grow up with a
whole family full of trouble...
Just one.
But he was the asshole king of them all.
Kept my head down, boy.
And you grew up and become a cop.
Big victory there.
A lot of my friends grew up with
the same insanity in the home.
Got caught up in it.
Said, "Hell with tomorrow,"
and that was that.
Very few of them living today.
Trying to scare me straight?
Just like a cop.
Here.
What the hell?
It's some money I won in a contest.
It's not like it's mine, even, really.
(RAYLAN SIGHS)
Man, you some kind of
pervert or something?
I don't want nothing from you, Kendal.
Save it.
For the future.
Rather buy an ATV or a gun.
So, uh, I guess this is where
I'm supposed to be grateful.
Or, if that's uncomfortable for you,
you can just tell me about
your brothers' activities.
I don't... Really know what my
brothers are up to in Mexico.
You got to be kidding me.
Mexico was kind of all I had.
I... I needed to
keep stringing you along.
You... This...
Lady, you are something.
Can't you even tell me
where they are in Mexico?
No.
But isn't that what you marshals do...
Find people?
I'd be in Florida about now.
WENDY: What?
Nothing.
Never mind.
I got the kid.
That's the important thing.
Hey.
Thanks again, marshal.
That was your first
"thank you."
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
It's coming.
How?
Not saying.
You gave me your story,
but I still don't know you.
Who's to say I tell you how, you
don't just go and cut me out?
You don't trust me.
I don't understand you, either.
Your whole god story...
It don't add up.
I'll admit...
I'm disappointed.
(LAUGHING)
Where'd you learn all that Spanish?
DARRYL: Cramming all the dope
in this shit heap,
leaving them bodies
in the back of the truck?
That's a two-bird/one-stone
stroke of goddamn genius.
I'd love to see their face
when they open the truck.
Smell probably killed them.
I'll bet they're scouring the
countryside for the likes of us,
make us into heroes
of legend and lore, like...
Butch and Sundance.
And their four redneck friends.
Hey, man.
To success, all right?
DARRYL: Mmm-hmm.
Well, we ain't succeeded yet.
Come on, Boyd. The way we played
them greedy-ass federales?
You and me is working together,
ain't no mountain high enough.
Easy, Tammi Terrell.
- Your man was supposed to be here by now.
- He's coming, man.
Everything last-minute like
this takes a little time, man.
Come on, man.
Let's go.
Got to trust me, man.
There it is.
Look at that.
Mmm!
And there he is.
Hey!
Shit.
Hey, y'all wait right here.
Where you go, I go.
Amigo.
Darryl.
Who are your friends?
Question is, where's your boat?
No. The question is, where's my money?
I got 50 bricks in the trunk of the car.
You take one for your troubles.
That'll more than cover it.
- Okay. We take the car, too.
- All right.
Take the truck.
Drive into Matamoros,
cross the bridge into Brownsville.
I'll see you in Galveston.
That's awfully forgiving of you.
Yeah, how's that?
Well, I heard the story.
Hey, Boyd, man.
Now, these two boys
double-teamed my sister,
BOYD: I don't think I could let
the water go under that bridge.
(SCOFFS)
Why you got to bring that story up?
I mean, look.
I... I told him the story
of your sister, man.
(STUTTERING) I wasn't saying
it in a bragging way.
It just came out, man.
It's a long time ago.
We good, though, right?
We good?
If I went after every
white boy got with my sister,
I'd have blisters on my gun hand.
There it is.
We good, man.
Yeah, we good.
I'll see you in Galveston.
Yo! Let's go, man!
Let's go home!
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
(CONVERSING IN SPANISH)
Hey, Boyd. You got any money? I was
gonna get a bottle for the road.
Hey, ponytail just said
something to the other one
about Darryl calling his boss on Martes.
You don't even have to
tell me what that means.
Darryl had this planned the whole time.
Yes, Sir.
Y'all want to go home?
What do you want to do?
You heard the man.
Let's go home!
BOYD: Shotgun!
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
You find Kendal?
I did.
Safe and sound.
That's a relief.
You gonna invite me in or keep
me out in the hallway all night?
Sure. Come on.
Something the matter?
No.
Want me to open a bottle of wine for you?
Mmm... Nah.
Well, I'm gonna get a beer.
All right.
I'm sorry about all this, by the way.
You understand why I
hesitated to get involved.
Oh, don't...
Don't apologize, please.
Miss Crowe's gonna keep her
word, nullify your suspension.
You may have your boss watching
your every move for a while,
but you'll be back at work.
Good, 'cause I cannot waste
another day stuck in this place.
About Florida...
Yeah.
I'm good. I'm ready.
- Uh-huh.
- We might want to scale back the extravagance a bit.
I, uh, gave away the contest
money to charity... Well,
Kendal, on a whim.
Really?
That's unexpected.
You're telling me.
Huh.
Us going wasn't tied
to that money, though.
I mean, we can go tomorrow morning.
But now I'm due back at work.
Right.
Well, I can always enter another
contest, if you don't mind waiting.
That way, we can plan it out,
do it up right.
Go, say, end of next month.
We're not going to Florida, Raylan.
You seem very sure about that.
Yeah, unfortunately.
So...
Yeah.
I'm breaking it off.
How about that.