We can still make this work.
- You don't know what I've done.
- Ian!
I don't want to hurt you.
That's not what I'm here for.
All I want is to trust him.
- Ian Reed's here. He's got a gun!
- No, no, no!
(ZOE SCREAMS)
- Zo?
- No!
Zo?
- Ahhh!
- (POLICE SIREN BLARING)
What have you done, Ian?
AUTOMATED VOICE:
You have one new message.
JOHN: Rose, Rose,
it's me, it's me, Luther!
It's Ian, I think he's hurt her.
Send a medic. Please.
Just send a medic over there now!
You were right.
Poor bastard.
Poor bastard, my arse. Poor Zoe!
Argh!
Ripped By mstoll
(GASPING)
What's happening here?
- And you are, sir?
- Mark North. Where's Zoe?
Ah, Jesus God.
No, no, no...
(YELLING)
(THEME SONG PLAYING)
♪ Love is like a sin
♪ My love
♪ For the ones that feel it the most
♪ Look at her with her eyes like a flame
♪ She will love you like a fly
♪ Will never love you again ♪
(TALKING IN DISTINCTLY)
What's going on?
About an hour ago
we received a 999 call.
Gunshots heard, 23 Parthenial Street.
First responders found a woman dead.
- Single gunshot wound.
- Zoe Luther.
- No...
- Don't speak up for him, Justin.
Not yet.
He argued with her.
That doesn't mean he did it.
He was there.
His fingerprints are all over the place,
in his wife's blood.
She's murdered, he's in the wind.
What does that tell you?
He wouldn't do it. He wouldn't do it.
Painful as it may be, I'm afraid the
evidence currently tell us otherwise.
You ready?
Ready.
First thing to know,
we're in damage control.
We keep an airtight lid on this
until it's resolved.
That means no press,
no briefings and no leaks.
Well, the press will
get there soon enough.
Which is why we need Luther
in custody without delay.
I don't want any
"Killer policeman at large" headlines.
Are we clear?
Teller is in charge
of the investigation, but, uh,
Martin will be assisting heavily.
You'll give him
your absolute cooperation.
But you need one of us
there on the ground to advise.
- Someone who knows him.
- Yeah? And should that be you?
Absolutely, it should be me, yeah.
Right, so do you believe
John Luther shot his wife tonight?
I can't be sure. Not yet.
- It's just too early...
- Exactly!
The last thing I need
is for this operation to be hindered
by your celebrated loyalty.
DS Ripley, you'll assist
Detective Chief Superintendent...
Oh, well, with respect,
sorry, Justin, but Ripley...
Yeah, he may not know Luther
quite as well as you,
but he's a damn sight
better-placed to be non-partisan.
You, you remain here,
you can advise as necessary.
Sorry, I think that's a mistake.
I'm not interested
in saving John Luther.
I want the full force of the law
stamping down on his face
before sunrise,
and I want your help to do it.
Are we clear on that?
Good. Now let's bring him in.
(PANTING)
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
(MESSAGE TONE BEEP)
I know what you did, Ian.
You tried to make it
look like I killed her because you think
if they're coming for me, I can't
come for you. Well, you're wrong.
I am coming for you.
All I have to do is
stay free long enough to see you dead.
And I'll do that, Ian.
I'll see you dead.
Justin. Justin.
Hey.
- What do you think?
- I don't know what to think.
Yeah, me neither.
Thing is, though, if he didn't do it,
where the hell is he?
Perhaps he knows who did it,
and he's gone after them.
Whatever happens, all right,
if you hear from him,
you contact me, okay?
Not Teller, not Schenk, me.
He needs his friends.
Yeah. Of course.
Okay.
(PHONE BEEPING)
I'm sorry for your loss.
I didn't lose her.
She was taken from me.
You know why?
The truth of it is, we're not here to
talk "why". That comes later.
Right now, it's all about "who".
Meaning John Luther.
That is a possibility.
Yes, it's something we're looking into.
Oh, I can't tell you the times,
since I met Zoe,
I've had to talk
about this guy, John, John.
John, poor John.
Needy John. Broken John.
Now, I need to know anything that
might have happened between
John Luther and Zoe
over the last few days...
- They were seeing each other.
- Seeing?
Yep, sleeping together.
When did you find out?
Look, I stayed with friends tonight.
You've only got to ask them.
We know where you were. When did you
find out about John and Zoe?
Uh...
About a day and a half ago.
I said to her, "Choose.
Choose between us,
"but stick with your choice."
And she chose me.
She chose me.
And she paid for it.
If that does turn out to be the case,
what you must never ever do
is blame yourself.
If you pull the trigger
on another human being,
the responsibility for that
is yours and yours alone.
If John killed Zoe,
I will not rest
until I see him punished for it.
(EXHALES)
If you'll excuse me,
I'll have another officer
come and take an official statement.
(DOOR OPENS)
Sorry, I, um...
No, no, it's me.
Sorry, I'm miles away.
Is this actually happening?
No. In a few minutes, I'm gonna wake up
and my alarm's going to go off.
By the time I get to work,
I'll have forgotten I ever dreamt it.
(ROSE SCOFFS)
Um, he... He just called me.
Who?
- Who do you think?
- When?
- Just now.
- What did he say? Where is he?
He just said that I did it. Again.
Oh, Ian.
JOHN ON RECORDER:
I know what you dial Ian.
You tried to make it look like
I killed her because you think
if they're coming for me, I can't
come for you. Well, you're wrong.
I just don't understand it.
Why would he project it onto me?
I don't know what to do.
I'm telling you this, it feels like
I'm betraying him, you know?
Well, it doesn't matter now,
you've told me.
See if you can
track the phone he's using.
Get a lead on where he might be.
- Yeah, okay.
- If we can pin
this mess on mental illness,
then I can't be held accountable
and the unit might survive.
Okay, all right.
Wow, I hadn't really thought of that.
Yeah, well, you don't
have to think like that. I do.
(SIGHS)
I should never have taken him back.
Oh, I knew the risk!
God knows they warned me,
"He's nitro glycerine."
And I didn't listen,
because I was so bent on making it work.
I just so wanted to make it work!
Boss.
It's not your fault.
(SOBBING)
(DOOR OPENING)
If you wanted a key,
all you had to do was ask.
I didn't think you slept.
Oh, only lightly and not for very long.
Why are you here?
I just needed a place to think.
About what?
Zoe's dead.
Are we speaking figuratively?
No.
Did you kill her?
- Would it matter?
- To me?
(LAUGHS)
Well, it's nice to see you
retain your sense of humour.
I mean it.
Well, I liked her.
But if you killed her,
I'm sure you had a reason.
Well, I didn't.
Fine.
Who did?
(OFFICERS TALKING IN DISTINCTLY)
He only smashed symbols
of her relationship with this new chap,
which makes for a very intimate scene.
And we know that
he smashes things when he's angry.
All of which tends
to align us in Luther's direction.
Unless this was staged for our benefit.
By Whom?
Mr North?
It's worth considering, surely.
Well, even if he didn't have an alibi,
when a man stages a murder scene,
he tends to make it look like
how he thinks it should.
It's always wrong.
But this scene is
consistent with the thesis.
And to stage such a scene correctly
would require a very chilly heart.
Which doesn't seem
compatible with a crime of rage.
But it's not right.
Tell me how.
This kind of killing, jealous husband,
sex, rage and all the rest of it.
You'd expect a knife, a bludgeon
of some kind. A fist. Not a gun.
You don't like the choice of weapon,
so that makes Luther innocent?
I want him to be innocent.
But if he's not, then I'll do my job
properly and without hesitation.
That's a very brave answer.
It's not supposed to be.
It's just the way it is.
So are you going to kill him?
I've thought about it.
That's all I've thought about.
Then why are you here?
I just need a safe place to think.
(SIGHS)
You know, in 1988,
two psychologists published an article
arguing that
positive self-deception is a normal
and advantageous part
of most people's lives.
It turns out, people lie to
themselves about three things.
They view themselves
in implausibly positive ways,
they think they have
far more control over their lives
than they actually do,
and they believe the future will be
better than the evidence
of the present can possibly justify.
But you're way beyond that now.
You're on the other side
of that particular mirror.
Lying to yourself
isn't going to help any more.
So, please,
tell me again.
Why are you here?
Alice, I need you to help me.
You're asking me to be your accomplice?
Yes.
Excellent.
Where do we start?
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
JOHN: Justin. Can you talk?
Uh, absolutely, yeah, I can talk.
- You at the house?
- Uh, yeah.
It wasn't me.
Yeah, I know, I think.
If Luther was going to do
something like this,
he'd make it look
like Mark North did it.
He might be insane, but he's not stupid.
You're a good man, Justin.
So where are you right now?
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
I don't doubt it. Any info at your end?
No, I'm not going to compromise
you more than I have to, okay?
But don't trust Ian Reed.
Sorry, it's a bit clattery over here.
Can you repeat that?
Don't trust Ian Reed.
Um, can you run the details by me?
Not now.
- Who is that?
- Um, one moment.
Telephone intelligence.
Trace on Luther's phone. No news.
Um, okay, I'm going to
need a brief precis of what you've got.
Soon as you like.
Well, as soon as there's time,
I will explain.
We may have found the gun.
- Did you get that?
- I got that.
Got it.
MAN: It's a nine millimetre Beretta.
Pass it to me, I'll clear the chamber.
- Chamber cleared.
- MAN 2: Bag it.
Sir.
Forensics in the house
are circumstantial.
This gun is hard evidence.
And I don't want it contaminated
or going missing
as a consequence of
some police officer's
- misguided sense of loyalty.
- Seriously?
Oh, they're good men,
but sometimes goodness
attracts its own temptations.
JUSTIN: So what do we do?
MARTIN: Well, first rule of evidence,
limit the amount of transfers.
Take it to the lab ourselves.
(EXHALES)
They found it.
Found what?
The gun.
Well, you didn't pull the trigger,
doesn't matter.
It's got no value as evidence.
No, but if Ian Reed left a gun,
he left it for a reason.
Meaning?
There was a gun.
There was a gun,
I touched it, I gave it to him.
It's got my fingerprints all over it.
If that's the gun he used on Zoe,
my fingerprints are all he needs.
And so?
So it's on its way to ballistic testing,
fingerprint analysis, DNA analysis.
Well, if that happens,
it's over for you.
If that happens.
But it's not going to happen.
Right. They're leaving from there,
taking the evidence to there.
We're here.
We can get there before them,
as long as Schenk
doesn't use the blues and twos.
What do you know about stealing cars?
- Nothing.
- Doesn't matter.
'Cause I know everything
about stealing cars.
- Hmm.
- Do you got anything for my...
Mmm-hmm, thank you.
They'll know it's you.
You're not an easy man to disguise.
- That's not the point.
- Well, what is?
Deniability.
- Look, if we get caught...
- I say you forced me to help.
You threatened my life.
- You're not even joking, are you?
- Absolutely not.
(SIGHS)
What's wrong?
Well, do you ever step outside
yourself, wonder what you're doing
and think you've gone mad?
No.
Look, you and I
are who we are.
So I need to tell you this, John,
of all the people in the world,
I would never betray you.
We're on Iron Road.
Should be about 20 minutes. Over.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
- Are you armed?
- No. You?
No. Urgent assistance required.
Repeat, urgent assistance required.
(GRUNTING)
- Where is it?
- In the glove box.
- Glove box?
- Yeah.
- Wait, hit me.
- What?
You've got to hit me,
you've got to make it look right.
Go on.
(GROANS)
(COUGHING)
This will achieve nothing.
You're not acting in a reasonable way.
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
Justin. What's happening?
He took the gun.
What do you mean? Wh...
What do you mean, he took the gun?
We were taking it to the lab.
He intercepted us, DCI Schenk and me.
Shit.
All right.
Okay, you listen to me.
You need to come in.
All right?
We need to start facing facts.
What do you mean?
I mean, he's not behaving
like an innocent man, is he?
Why'd you do it?
Hmm. Do what?
Your parents.
Because I wanted to.
How could you want that?
Well, let's put Ian Reed
in a room with you,
and then let's talk about
who wants what.
Are you sure
you don't want to keep this?
No.
No guns.
(SIGHS) Suit yourself.
(IN DISTINCT CHATTER OUTSIDE)
Maintenance!
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
It's him.
What do you want, Ian?
I just want to talk.
You sound scared.
Are you scared?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm scared.
Yeah, you should be.
You should be scared.
I can't handle this.
I can't deal with this, John.
It's in my brain. It's like...
It's like my head's full of spiders.
I can't stand it. I think I'm going mad.
Honestly, mate, I can't stand it.
That's not going to stop me
coming for you.
Look, I can't undo it.
All right? I wish I could.
Hand to God,
if I could go back,
I'd rather it was me that was dead.
I'd rather be dead than go through this.
That can be arranged, Ian.
(SNIFFLING)
Listen, just meet me, okay?
Please.
Just, uh, just hear
what I've got to say.
And then, after that,
whatever happens is in your hands.
All right then.
9:00. Faraday Memorial.
ALICE: You're not going
to do what he wants?
Yes, I am.
(INHALES)
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Shouldn't you be at home?
It's just a cracked rib. I'll be fine.
Okay.
Do we have any idea
of the accomplice's ID? The woman?
Um... I don't know.
Young. White. Slim build.
Also wore a stocking.
- She didn't speak?
- No.
- But it was Luther?
- It was Luther.
You're 100% positive?
Well, he wore a cursory disguise,
a stocking mask,
but given that, I'd say (CLICKS TONGUE)
95%.
Do you know what a decent defence
called 95%? Reasonable doubt.
Was it him?
- On balance, I'd guess so. Yes.
- You'd guess?
I couldn't swear to it.
He killed his wife! Zoe!
He's stolen the only hard evidence
we have to convict him!
He busted your ribs! Wake up!
Stop protecting him!
I'm not.
John just called.
He wants to set up a meeting.
Rose, Rose, I can't use this.
If we put you unprotected
in John's path, he's going to kill you.
It's not going to come to that.
He's convinced you killed his wife.
He's delusional.
So, actually, it may come to that.
Listen, I trust him. It'll be all right.
- I can bring him in.
- I'm not sending you in naked.
No more than I like doing it.
But this is John we're talking about.
Look, you owe him nothing.
All right? He owes you. He owes us both.
You're not going in there unprotected.
Final word.
All right, but I'm not using this.
So what kind of thing you talking about?
Tactical weapons support.
If it looks for one moment...
For one moment...
- Oh, no, no.
- ...your life's in danger,
I give the order.
- Rose...
- All right, we do it like this
or we don't do it at all.
Your call.
All right, okay, fine.
Fine.
Bring in the shooters.
(SIGHS)
Don't speak. Drive.
You and I
have been through something today.
And that makes us comrades-in-arms.
Yeah, I suppose.
And so, as a comrade, I'm asking you
what's troubling you?
In what way?
People like you and me,
we know how people look
when they're hiding something.
- Is this an accusation?
- Of what?
An atypical reaction to betrayal?
- What do you want?
- To know what you think.
- About what?
- (SIGHS) Luther's psychotic.
He claims to believe Detective Chief
Inspector Reed killed his wife.
If that's so, why did he go to
the trouble of stealing back that gun?
It doesn't fit the delusional framework.
No, I suppose not.
So what's going on in Luther's head?
Who can say?
Well... Who indeed?
(GRUNTING) No!
- (GRUNTING)
- Mark!
Hey! Mark, listen to me.
Listen to me!
(PANTING)
I didn't do it.
It wasn't me.
Luther set the meet, here.
For what? A chat?
- Apparently.
- No, he's lying.
Of course he's lying, but why?
All you need to do is
be there at 9:00 a.m.
They'll be leaving, they'll ask you to
wait until they return.
- You'll be alone.
- So I do what you say and then what?
And then you say you want to leave.
They can't stop you.
Then you come back to me.
You're putting Reed
at very considerable risk.
I'm mindful of that, sir.
But he's right.
This is the best way
to bring Luther in without bloodshed.
And Reed?
Reed will be elsewhere.
CO-19?
Kitted and ready to go.
And if circumstances warrant,
you won't hesitate
to give the kill order?
Absolutely not.
(EXHALES)
Okay, okay.
You're not coming?
This doesn't fall within my compass,
for which I'm grateful.
I've no desire to see what happens next.
You know, you don't have to be there.
I do.
We ready?
I need to speak to you.
Okay, of course. It's just that
we have a live situation right now.
That's all right. I can wait.
- You sure?
- Absolutely.
I'll look after Mr North.
There's really no need. I can wait.
Nonsense. I'll keep you company
until the others return.
Mr North, if I may?
This isn't going to work
if you can't control your temper.
It's a weakness. He'll use it.
- I can control it.
- Well, you'd better.
'Cause if I understand correctly, police
marksmen don't shoot to wound.
No. They shoot to stop.
Go for the centre of mass.
Here. The heart.
How apropos.
(INDISTINCT SPEECH ON POLICE RADIO)
There he is, by the stairs.
- Sergeant?
- We've got a clear shot and good to go.
On my order. Not before.
Received and understood.
What do you want me to do?
Kill you?
Forgive you?
I don't understand
how you could believe I did this.
(SCOFFS)
You've changed your tune
since the last time we spoke, Ian.
No, John.
I believe you did it, Ian,
because you did it!
If you really believe that, deep down,
then why did you steal the gun?
JOHN: The gun.
Yeah, you did a decent job with that.
But it's gone now.
And so is the only piece of hard
evidence they've got against me.
So whatever you're trying to do...
Whatever you're trying to do
to save yourself, it's over.
It's done.
You're not answering my question.
I think I am!
IAN: But if you didn't do it,
how could there be
any hard evidence against you?
- How's that possible?
- What are you trying to say?
I've spoken to the doctors, John.
And what's happening to you
is called a dissociative state.
It's the mind distancing itself
from things that are
too much for it to process.
You're blaming me because you can't
bear to confront what you've done.
You're in pain, you're distressed.
You need help. So come home. All right?
Let us help you.
(LAUGHS)
Thing is, Ian,
you didn't come alone, did you?
Wouldn't have the balls.
No, you came with CO-19, who, right now,
have their assault rifles
trained on my centre of mass.
And we do not shoot to stop.
Not in our game, no. We shoot to kill!
Ain't that right, fellas?
- Sergeant?
- Still clear and good to go.
Ain't that right, boss?
You got the centre of mass, right here.
'Cause that's what
we're here for, isn't it?
You prod me, you wind me up,
I lose it, I threaten your life.
And then you have
a legal reason to shoot me.
Bang, bang, bang. There goes your
problems, all out of the window.
Oh, Luther, couldn't contain his temper.
John, John, listen to me. You're ill.
(LAUGHS) And you're sick!
I wonder,
are you even interested
in why I've come here
if I knew what you was up to?
I don't know. Maybe you wanted to
get something off your chest.
About something you did
to Henry Madsen, maybe?
JOHN: Oh, nice try, no, no.
I've got nothing to confess.
Henry Madsen fell. And you know
how hard I tried to save him.
I know how hard you tried.
No, I...
I came out here...
Still clear, still clear.
(WHISPERS) ...to get you away from
the locker rooms.
What's he saying?
...where you're keeping the diamonds.
Or where you were,
up until about five minutes ago.
Oh, dear. Oh, dear, oh, dear.
Tick, tick, tick.
I wonder where they could have gone.
(LAUGHING)
I didn't hurt Zoe, John.
- Ian, you do me a favour.
- What?
Don't say her name.
Not any more.
No more. All right? It's over.
What can I do to prove it? just tell me.
Tell me, tell me what I can do.
I actually thought
I could listen to this.
I thought I could stand here
and listen to you lie!
To my face! Even now!
How can you stand there
and lie like it's nothing?
IAN: Because I didn't do it!
He goes for a weapon, you take the shot.
IAN: I didn't do it.
I loved Zoe, John.
She was like family to me.
Wait to see a weapon,
wait to see a weapon.
So please, for her. For Zoe.
Please just come home.
- Don't!
- I love you too, man.
Don't say that! You piece of shit.
All I want to do is hear you say it.
Just say it one time.
Just say what you did.
Say it to me.
Ian, mate, say it to me now!
- I can't!
- Say it!
No, because I didn't do it, John!
You did.
OFFICER: He's got a knife.
IAN: You killed her.
It's your fault!
- Do it. Take the shot.
- John! Run!
Run!
Got a shot, ma'am.
Hold your fire! Hold your fire.
Don't shoot him in the back.
All units, be alert.
Suspect John Luther leaving the area
on foot, heading south-east, fast.
- Shit!
- Head him off! Stop him.
Do you know what you've done?
- Yes, I do, ma'am.
- Don't "ma'am" me.
Badge!
Arrest this man.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
- Come on!
- Ah!
(GRUNTING)
Come on!
- Ah!
- How'd it go?
I got what I wanted.
And how close did you come
to getting shot for it?
I didn't get shot.
Fine. Your funeral.
That dick!
- Let it go.
- Would you?
"Run, John". What was he thinking?
He thought he was being John's friend
and it's already cost him everything.
So let it go.
What, you suspended him?
And charged him as an accessory.
Ripley's finished.
Yeah, that's what being John's
friend does for you in the end.
We all paid a price for it.
Come on, let's get back.
Just, um.
Once more, if I may.
Um, Luther came to see you,
- uh, he was distressed...
- He was greatly distressed, yeah.
It feels unseemly to keep probing this,
such a raw wound, so soon.
I must ask what he said.
He said he didn't do it.
Well, I suppose all things are possible,
although not equally.
Is this going to take much longer?
No, I, uh,
think I've got everything
I want from you.
If I could just ask you
to wait a little bit longer.
The insight you've given
into his mental state,
- it may be of value...
- Can I please use the bathroom?
Of course.
(INDISTINCT)
All right. Get on with it.
Ian?
Thank you.
I'm sorry the... Um, um, bathroom?
- I was...
- Oh. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, it's out there, on the right.
The, um, flush is broken
on the cubicle nearest the wall.
You might want to watch that.
I will, thank you.
Listen, uh,
I'm sorry
for your loss. She was very special.
That's very kind. She was.
OFFICER: Excuse me.
I, uh, I need to be away from here.
Oh, yes, possibly that's the best thing.
We could arrange an escort,
a protective detail.
I don't think Luther will be back.
Even so, I, uh,
I hope you're not on your own.
It isn't healthy.
Yeah, I, uh, I have somewhere to go.
As you wish.
Come on. Come on.
It's Mark. I'm on my way.
All right.
Hi, this is DCI Reed.
Can you do me a favour?
Uh, can you run me a trace and track?
Okay, it's Mark North.
(BEEPING)
Tick, tick, tick.
I wonder where they could have gone.
JUSTIN: John! Run! Run!
John! Run! Run!
How long did you want to
become a police officer, Justin?
Since I can remember.
And why?
Why a police officer?
What does it matter?
Big family?
- Yeah, pretty big.
- They're proud of you?
Yes.
Family's important to you, isn't it?
Family,
loyalty, trust.
And rules are important, too.
- Aren't they?
- Yes.
Yes!
So why throw it all away for nothing?
You're not a fool.
What have you got to lose?
Your pride, your self-respect?
Your job?
Well, they're all gone!
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Something's happening
that no one else can quite see.
Well, I want to see it!
What's happening?
- ROSE: Excuse me.
- What is it, Martin?
We need to find
Detective Chief Inspector Reed.
Most urgently.
(BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(GRUNTING)
(REED GRUNTING)
Shh.
So you've got North
doing your dirty work for you.
Your dead wife's boyfriend,
stealing evidence.
What is it about you, John?
You corrupt everything around you.
You turn everything to shit.
(PANTING)
All this.
All this, what you did...
For what? For greed?
Because you were scared?
Well, now, look.
What do you want me to say, John?
Huh?
(QUIVERING)
What, I wish I hadn't killed Zoe?
I do.
I wish I hadn't.
I didn't go there meaning to.
But I did.
And so, now we're here,
just do what you got to do.
All right, just commit.
She begged you.
Come on! just get it over with.
It'll be a relief. I'm sick of this.
I know.
I didn't come to kill you, Ian.
What, I wish I hadn't killed Zoe?
I do. I wish I hadn't...
What, so all this,
bringing me here,
sending her boyfriend to the station,
stealing the diamonds,
that was all a play?
(LAUGHS)
You set me up for a confession?
Pretty much.
If I was you, I'd have killed me.
There's nothing I'd like to do more.
Do it, come on.
I've come so far, I don't even care.
You know this is the end for me.
No.
- Why not?
- Because I choose not to.
Did she ever tell you
about her and me? Zoe?
Oh, no, she didn't.
Of course she didn't. I knew that.
What do you mean?
It started one night...
You'd stayed away working
once too often.
That's not going to work, Ian.
She cried afterwards.
Yeah, washed the sheets.
That's one of the memories
I've got of her, crying,
naked, stuffing the sheets
into a machine.
Calling me an arsehole, a bastard.
Still made me do it again before I left.
It's not going to work.
She told me I taught her
how to really come.
You know, Ian, you can't play me.
You can't make me shoot you.
You can't choose...
No, no, no, no, no, no,
I can't play you!
You're John Luther!
Who sees all, knows all!
Come on, John,
after a marriage that long,
that unhappy, with a woman that needy?
Oh, there must have been quite a few.
Maybe you knew
about some of them deep down.
But you know what?
- I think I was her favourite.
- No more, Ian!
Because I was her revenge.
Every orgasm she took from me
was to pay you back.
Enough!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CHOKING)
How does it feel, eh? You murderer.
Come on, how does it feel, tell me?
- (GASPS)
- No.
(COUGHS)
No.
(IAN GASPING)
Ian Reed,
I'm arresting you
for the murder of Zoe Luther...
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(IAN GASPS)
You should have done it, John!
Now, look what you're
making me do. Look!
Don't...
Now, look what you're making me do!
Ian...
You should have stopped me, John!
ALICE: Ian!
(GASPING)
Are you?
Yeah.
He swore he wasn't going to kill you.
He thought the humiliation
of prison would be worse.
The beatings, the rapes,
the incessant fear for your life,
but I told him,
"No, John, you're wrong.
"Dying would be worse."
Because, well,
honestly, it is, isn't it?
Dying's just worse.
So...
Do I pull the trigger or not?
No! Alice!
Well, I'm in favour.
Which leaves us 50-50,
with one vote left to cast.
Mark?
What do you think?
You're a liar.
- He is a liar.
- Deciding vote, Mark.
Alice. Alice, don't.
Wasn't it enough to take her life?
Where is your respect?
Where is your shame?
She didn't look like a whore,
though, did she?
JOHN: Don't listen to him.
Don't listen to him.
I mean, not dressed, anyway.
But strip her down,
roll her around a bit.
- Oh!
- Stop, stop, stop!
Okay, listen!
Ian, stop! Mark, I know
how much you want
to see him die, but don't do it.
I mean, she had
a few good rides left in her.
Do it! Do it! Do it!
No, no, no!
(DON'T LET ME BE MISUNDERSTOOD PLAYING)
Oh, no!
(SIRENS WAILING)
Now what?
(DON'T LET ME BE MISUNDERSTOOD
CONTINUES PLAYING)
Ripped By mstoll