Anybody in plumbing,
please go to aisle 4.
God... damn.
I see you got the Dewalt cordless.
Nailgun, Dewalt 410.
Yeah. The trouble is,
you leave it in a truck for a while,
need to step up and use the bitch,
the battery don't hold up, you know?
Yeah, cordless'll do that.
You might want to consider
the powder-actuated tool.
The Hilti DX 460 MX
or the Simpson PTP...
These two are my Cadillacs.
Everything else on this board
is second best, sorry to say.
Are you contracting, or just doing
some work around the house?
No, we work all over.
Full time?
No, we had about 5 jobs last month.
With that rate, the cost of the
powder-actuated guns justifies itself.
- You say "power"?
- Powder.
- Like gunpowder?
- Yeah.
The DX 460 is fully automatic,
with a .27 caliber charge.
Wood, concrete, steel to steel...
She'll throw a fastener
into anything,
and for my money, she handles recoil
better than the Simpson or the P3500.
Now, you understand
what I mean by recoil?
- Yeah, the kickback. I'm with you.
- That's right.
.27 caliber?
Yeah, not large ballistically,
but for driving nails, it's enough.
Any more than that,
you'd add to the recoil.
Man, shit.
I seen a tiny-ass .22 round-nose
strap a nigger plenty of days, man.
Motherfuckers get up in you
like a pinball,
rip your ass up.
Big joints, though...
Big joints, man,
just break your bones,
you say, "fuck it."
I'm gonna go with this
right here, man.
How much do I owe you?
669 plus tax.
No, no, you just pay
at the register.
Nah, man, you go ahead
and handle that for me, man.
And keep the rest for your time.
This is $800.
So what, man?
You earned that buck
like a motherfucker, man.
Keep that shit.
- We good?
- Yeah, man.
The man said if you
want to shoot nails,
this here is the Cadillac, man.
He mean Lexus,
but he ain't know it.
- Hold the charge better?
- Man, fuck the charge.
This here is gunpowder-activated,
.27 caliber,
full auto, no kickback,
nail-throwing mayhem, man.
Shit right here is tight.
Fuck just nailing up boards.
We could kill a couple motherfuckers
with this right here.
You laughing.
I've been schooled, dog.
I'm trying to tell you.
- All right, all right.
- For real.
Season 4 - Episode 1
"Boys of Summer"
7 and counting.
All of them caught on the wire.
We're not above the corners yet,
but we soon will be.
- They're not dumping phones?
- Every month or so.
Sloppy enough that we may
be able to track a phone or two
up to Marlo or the people
he keeps close.
Truth is, if they're still using
cellphones in this day and age,
they're mine.
And if Marlo Stanfield is on a cell,
he'll be mine, too.
Cool Lester smooth.
That's not trash talk,
darling, that's simple fact.
Marlo Stanfield may have a lot
of heart and a lot of corners,
but he's a babe in the woods
when it comes to this right here.
I was proud to be chasing
those Barksdales,
- but this Stanfield kid...
- Not as fierce as we thought.
For months now, there hasn't been
a body we can put to him.
You two sound disappointed.
This unit needs good, hard targets,
or it'll go soft.
Be that as it may, I'll assume
you want another 30 days on your taps.
At least.
And we got subpoenas
to go out this week as well.
- Subpoenas?
- Asset investigations.
- On Marlo Stanfield?
- Come here.
All this is from the Barksdale
money trail.
We've been running down all the paper
we pulled out of Stringer's apartment
and the B&B office downtown.
I miss Prez, man.
- I do.
- I hear you.
The truth is, those guys
had money going everywhere...
Investments, political donations,
consulting fees...
- You want to do this now?
- I wanted to do this a year ago,
but fresh cases got in the way.
And your lieutenant's gonna OK
this kind of paper?
Our lieutenant has a fearless heart.
This will get you started.
Wait, wait, wait.
Wait right there.
My coupons.
You were gonna
give this lady my coupons.
Been clipping them for two days,
and you damn near
sent them out with your mess.
- Well, why are they in my pile?
- Why is your pile in my workspace?
Because I'm doing real work!
Working my nerves
is what you been doing.
4 weeks before
the Baltimore City primary,
you hand me a stack
of drug money subpoenas
that hit a dozen
key political figures.
There's an election?
Who's running?
And I think I can.
Shit, I don't think we can take
4 more years of this guy.
This city's in the toilet.
That's what they said
during my term, too.
Yeah, well, you got dealt a bad hand,
I mean, with the riots and all.
- Yeah, sure.
- Anyway, I think I squeeze in
if Tony Gray draws off
25%, 26% of the vote,
because most of that's
out of Royce's base.
25% is a big number for Gray,
don't you think?
I don't know.
Royce's negatives are up...
Even among black voters.
Yeah. In a minute, Norman.
You know what I think, Tommy?
No matter what,
you got your name out there,
and it'll help you down the road
if you ever want to step up
to the legislature.
But as one paisan to another,
the day of the white mayor
is over in this town.
Excuse me, your eminence.
You're due at the Baylor-Edison
senior center,
and I don't want to be lying
to a roomful of wrinkle-assed voters
because you wanted to talk shop
all the damn morning.
Seniors?
They vote, Tommy.
Got to run. Sorry.
The candidate's on your clock.
Don't ever let him forget it.
No, indeed.
Need your sig on vehicle logs
and a corrected court report
and office memo subpoena requests
and a requisition to city
purchasing for a large fan.
A fan?
Caroline says it stays
hot in the wire room
with the door closed.
It's beautiful, lieutenant.
I never seen a beach house so fine.
You think so?
Shit. Makes me think about retirement,
and I only got 9 years on.
- When do you break ground?
- Next march, if I have my permits...
Which reminds me,
on Tuesday,
I have to get over to Delaware
and see my contractor.
Oh, no problem.
Me and Lester,
we'll cover for you on that.
No problem at all.
Cake.
You know what I'm saying, yo?
That's my baby's mother
we talking about, yo.
But y'all been broke up, right?
Man, I ain't living with her
or nothing,
but I still be giving her
a couple dollars here and there,
you know, stop and pass.
Pandemic! Pandemic!
Look at this.
Hey, Nay.
Namond!
What the fuck am I
paying you for, nigger?
Oh, my fault, B.
Damn.
Yo, man, and do something
with that ponytail.
Cops can make his ass
from a mile away.
Braid it or something!
Yeah, you know, me and Patrice
been together for a long time.
Yeah, but you say she running
with the boy Fruit now, right?
If he don't back the fuck off,
I'm gonna fill his ass
with some hot ones, yo.
Shit. You don't think I will?
I got that Pandemic.
Man...
do what you gonna do.
- Bodie.
- What's up, big man?
You ain't real with us
all week, man.
You stepping on that package
or what?
Yo, man, everything's slow.
It been slow since we moved
down here from Fayette Street.
Yeah, well, Marlo wanted Fayette.
Man, I do not like backing down
from niggers, man.
I feel like a punk.
I feel like doing shit.
Ain't like the old days, dog.
Mayor Barksdale left.
You out here on your own, dog.
Give it up.
B., let's roll.
Hey, Lex, man,
I'm gonna give you the truth
because you need the truth.
That boy Marlo
got the world by the ass,
and Fruit, he work for Marlo.
So I'm saying, fuck that bitch.
And move on.
That's just the way it is.
That's just the way it is, man.
Pandemic!
Thank you, sir.
Just one moment, ma'am.
- You seen Hoskins?
- Lieutenant went upstairs already.
Step through, please.
Madam President.
Council President's hot as balls.
I'd fuck you to fuck her, man.
Yeah?
You'd fuck a guy for a chance
to fuck a hot broad?
You don't think that makes you
a faggot or nothing?
It's just an expression, man.
Been on this detail how long?
- 8 months.
- 8 months with Clarence Royce.
So let me ask,
are you ready to take a bullet
for the mayor of Baltimore?
Lieutenant, sir.
Is the truck OK,
or do we want to call one?
Nah, the truck works.
He said he needed just 10 minutes.
No, not now.
Maybe tomorrow?
Is that Krawczyk again?
Every time
he writes another check,
he turns around
and calls for something
just to see that he can.
Getting calls from
Carcetti's people, too.
They want one debate
for crime and safety,
the other on economic stuff
and schools.
Tony Gray crying the same blues.
Like they're gonna
get the whole night
to smack me with the crime rate.
I told the "Sun" paper
we're open to any format,
which we'll be for another
couple days or so,
in which time we'll say,
"Fuck you. One debate."
Two debates. Shit!
That lost-ball-in-high-grass
motherfucker Carcetti.
He needs to get used to life
in the wilderness.
And not just the downtown areas,
but your communities
here on the east side.
We stand or we fall together,
and I'm here today to ask for
the chance to stand with you.
Thank you for your time.
Questions?
Yes, ma'am?
Is it the Salisbury steak
for lunch today,
or is they doing tacos?
Because it's developments
like this one,
planned residential towers,
with waterside retail space
and restaurants,
that grow Baltimore's tax base
and help rebuild our city.
I want to thank Ed Bowers
for his vision,
but more important,
for his commitment.
For his commitment
to the city of Baltimore.
Ed.
Mr. Mayor,
I want to thank you
and your administration
For making this next stage of
redevelopment for Baltimore's harbor
a reality.
You talk about vision
and commitment...
Mayor Clarence Royce.
Pandemic! Pandemic!
What up, Nay?
Yo, what up?
What you got?
Nothing. It's just a story about
A.J. from North and Woods.
Yo, you know they gave him
700 years?
Read this shit, son.
This corner is dead, man.
You still working?
Yeah, because we was gonna
gonna go under the road
and catch some fresh birds.
I don't know.
Let me see if I can bounce.
Hold up.
- Hey, B.
- What's up?
I wanted to know
if I could leave early
because me and the fellas
want to go down to [?]
for some back-to-school stuff.
What you need
back-to-school stuff for?
- Your ass stay suspended.
- Come on, stop playing, B.
Hey, if it wasn't
for social promotion,
your ass would still be
in pre-k, motherfucker.
Probably day care up this bitch.
Pandemic right here!
Fuck it. Hey, yo, man.
Pay this late-to-work,
early-to-play nigger out
for 5 hours, yo.
Yo, you owe me extra time
tomorrow, though.
Lex! Did you hear me?
Damn, y'all!
Young'uns don't got a scrap
of work ethic nowadays, man.
If it wasn't for his pops,
I wouldn't even bother.
Yo!
Make sure you come early tomorrow
because it ain't always
gonna be this slow.
Pandemic!
At least I hope it ain't.
Mr. Mayor.
Mr. Mayor, excuse me.
I just want to make sure
we're still OK
for that median cut
on Boston Street.
I really need that access
to make the site viable.
Right. I'll get my people on it.
Thank you, sir.
Something going on
with his median?
Not once he ponies up.
I think he can do a lot better
than the 4,000.
Don't you?
I don't even want to know.
No, Chris, please, man.
[?]
Doesn't matter.
We got vacants on both sides.
He'll stink is all.
Chris, please.
Don't fret, boss.
I got you covered.
Quick and clean, I promise.
Man, shit like that don't even
work in them cartoons.
The roadrunner just snatched
the birdseed and booked.
We ain't in no cartoon.
- Yeah, you is.
- Be still.
Yeah, you scaring away the birds.
I'm talking to both y'all.
Took me off the clock
for this craziness?
What the fuck is you thinking?
We're serious, Nay.
This bird could be worth,
like, 300 or 400.
Nigger, please.
Yo, you know the boy Nemo
who worked Marlo's pigeon coop?
Said he got 400
for a white homing bird.
- And that's a homer?
- I mean, it's white.
- So that makes it a homer, right?
- Might could be.
Damn! Son, you need to put some
hamburger meat in that trap.
That shit would've been got.
Shut your mouth,
it'd have been got.
The fuck is wrong with you,
throwing bottles and shit?
You just cost us cash money.
You know that?
- Yo, I ain't done nothing.
- You're a seriously backwards dude,
you know that, right?
Playing with bugs
like he's still in pampers.
- That wasn't even necessary.
- Nah, you don't want any pampers.
Put them over that mouth you got.
Catch all that shit you be flushing.
Y'all be stinking like rat fart.
There you go!
All right, all right.
Come on, come on, come on. Come on.
Y'all acting like little bitches.
Yo, you seen my man Duke?
Clocked him, got him
upside his head.
Only because I didn't want
to get too close
and touch the dirty motherfucker.
Could have come up with aids
or some shit like that.
Dukie fight like a bitch, yo.
Duke, man, you scared away the birds.
I blew me up a bug bomb.
You want to come and see the pieces?
Nah, I'm good. I got to go.
All right.
Hey, hey, Randy.
That pigeon wasn't a homer.
You know, homers got the metal
things around their leg.
That way, you can tell them
from the other birds.
How you know that?
You know Nemo let me
clean out his coop sometimes.
So... he was schooling me.
Which leaves us a total of 54.
No surprises on who's coming back...
all the regulars.
We lost Mr. Parker
and Ms. Bowles.
- Griffey's leaving?
- Hired by the county.
And Bowles, I knew she wasn't
coming back,
the way they tore up
her classroom.
So we're short two in math
and 4 in science.
Man at the door.
No system I.D.,
but says he's new here.
Well, buzz him in before
something changes his mind.
All the way on the left.
Pull it hard.
Hard!
- It's locked.
- All right. I'll be right down.
Not a goddamn thing up in here
works like it should.
Well, you turn to
the cafeteria assignments,
and you see that's gonna leave
Ernest alone for second period,
and he can't handle it alone.
You tell them,
because I ain't even gonna try
to pronounce it.
Roland Pryzbylewski.
Everyone just calls me "Prez."
Woodrow Willis.
I'm principal here.
New in math.
I won't have my certificate
until next year,
but with the resident
teachers program,
they said I'd be getting classes?
Because of staff shortages?
Jesus. Lambs to the slaughter here.
What did you do before you decided
to teach, Mr. Pryzbylewski?
I was a police... in the city.
Marcia Donnelly,
assistant principal.
Welcome to
Edward Tilghman Middle.
That leaves Tullman
as [?] for the 12th.
You think he can handle
the whole shift?
Now, which one's Tullman, again?
Goofy redhead, kind of looks
like Opie from Mayberry,
but less fierce.
Jimmy, major wants to see you.
Jimmy, come on in.
I know I offered
when I first came over here,
and I know your answer then,
but I'm still asking.
Can I get you out of a radio car?
- No thank you, Major.
McNulty, I'm short two men in ops,
and my follow-up squad couldn't
make a case to save its life.
You're too damn good
to be humping calls.
Thanks for the offer, though.
You don't think I asked him 10 times
when I was acting commander?
He's in the wrong fucking place.
For us, yeah.
For him...
Yo, po-po, man.
Po-po. Shut it down.
Where is the love, Bodie?
Where is the motherfucking love?
I go back so far with this kid,
I was chasing him through juvie.
But does any of that matter
when we roll up here?
I get so much as a wave,
a nod, a smile?
Nothing?
How about just "hello"?
- Hello.
- See?
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Lex, my man,
how's your day going?
Not to criticize or anything,
but I think you missed
a spot there.
Little Kevin, how's it hanging?
Reesey, you look like someone
just shot your dog.
You all right, man? You OK?
Reesey still messing up the count?
You hear what he said?
Yo, dog, you send him up
to Lamelle next month,
I'll make sure Ms. Davis
puts him in remedial math,
and we'll have done
some good here today.
Fucking cop, man.
- Everything good?
- Yeah. Just words.
Mr. Entrapment. How you doing?
Don't look like that.
I'm still dining out on that story.
You know how he beat
the wiretap a year ago?
Claimed entrapment when he was
clocking in Bunny Colvin's Hamsterdam.
Shit you not.
Smart kiddo. I loved it.
When I roll back in an hour,
this corner's bone-dry.
Your people are done for the day.
OK. So let's try this again.
I say, "have a good evening,
Mr. Broadus."
And a good evening to you,
Sergeant Carver.
See? We're right here.
And a very good evening
to you, Officer Colicchio.
Fuck yourself with a 40, shitbreath.
What the fuck was all that about?
You can't bust every head, Tony.
I can't?
Bust every head, who are you
gonna talk to when the shit happens?
Hi, Rachel.
Tim, thanks
for doing that yesterday.
Yeah, no problem.
You ran late all morning.
Late for the seniors,
late for the stonewall meeting
with Della.
Late for the gay-lesbian alliance.
Them seniors, they talk slow.
Bullshit. It was breakfast
with Young Tony
when they sat there swapping stories
over cold coffee.
- Young Tony?
- I was getting sage advice.
From a one-term mayor?
Wasn't his fault
he takes over in '67,
Sees the city burn.
That was an opportunity.
Spiro Agnew made his whole
career on the '68 riots.
- Agnew?
- One man's shithead's
- another man's vice president.
- True today as it ever was.
- Hey, is that polling data?
- Raw numbers. It's incomplete.
Right now, you need to be
in the call room,
- dialing for dollars.
- Fuck!
I can't do it anymore!
I hate it.
I hate it more than anything.
I fucking hate it!
You don't do this, you don't have
the money to pay for the damn TV spots
in the last two weeks.
Mothersucking cockfuckers.
Oh, Jesus. I fucking hate this.
Hey there, Jim.
Tom Carcetti here.
Remember me?
We met at your sister's house...
You know, the one that's married
to that republican cunt.
I know you don't remember me.
I know you don't have any use
for fucking politicians,
And frankly, I don't give a flying
fuck about what you think
or what your concerns are.
But I do care about what
your cute little blonde wife,
thinks about so many things.
But, Jim, the reason
I'm calling is because
I want you to write me out
a check for $4,000.
The maximum allowed by law.
Now, because we don't trust you
to actually mail that check,
We're gonna send over a couple
of furloughed DPW workers
to beat the check out of you.
All finished?
You need $30,000...
in the next 3 hours.
No bullshit, Tommy.
You hit your number
or die in this room.
Yeah, whatever.
So what are you watching, then?
Anything on the tube?
No fucking way.
They got enough power
in the middle of the lineup.
What they need is pitching.
What you looking at?
Fucking crazy.
Oh, like I'm really gonna give
them motherfucker a ride to Woodlawn.
Shit.
Help! Somebody help!
What's up, Patrice?
You're letting it ring, right?
You're not hanging up
after a ring or two?
I'm making the calls, Terri.
I don't know what to say.
Nobody's home.
30,000, Tommy.
You mean Lex, the boy
who used to go with Patrice?
He her baby's daddy.
He ain't the first one
to get his spurt.
You ain't got to talk like that.
Nigger just walked up to him
outside of the Paragon
and served him up.
One to the face.
Shoot. He was real cute.
Lex and his 9 took all the cute
out of that lazy-eye motherfucker.
Anything off his phone?
Nothing. I've gone for two hours.
- Sure.
- It's no problem, though.
Sure.
I really need your help.
Put me down for 4.
Well, how about your wife?
Think she can come up with 4?
I don't think we can do 8.
- The kids?
- They're in strollers.
I know they're in strollers.
I was kidding.
That's funny.
Yeah, never mind.
4,000 is good. Thanks.
No problem.
One to the left temple.
Close range in a lot
full of club trash,
but of course,
nobody sees a thing.
We hear your shooter goes by "Lex."
We were up on your victim's
cellphone, too.
We'll go back through the calls,
send you whatever's there.
Got this from his pocket.
You can pull numbers from that
as a consolation prize.
This fucks you guys up, don't it?
Losing a guy you had wired?
Nah. We're up on several
phones on the street level.
With or without Mr. Fruit,
we're on our way.
You know, it's strange.
We're not seeing bodies.
This is the first drug hit
in months,
and it's Marlo's boy who falls.
- I thought Marlo was the new power.
- He is.
Shit, he's got everything
from MLK to Fulton now.
How do you hold
that much real estate
without making bodies?
You hear anything more about
this murder on your wire, Lester,
The Bunk expects a call.
Yeah, I know he does.
The hell with Norris.
You're my real partner, Lester.
My life partner.
Don't tease, bitch.
Look at that bowlegged
motherfucker.
I made him walk like that.
So who the fuck is Lex?
- Dontrelle's cousin.
Used to be with Cantel's people.
He working some corner
over the Hilltop now.
He ain't more connected than that?
And he coming near one of mine?
- Wasn't about no business.
- Pussy, man.
Yo, Fruit was into something
that Lex thought was his own.
You say the word,
we take off that whole
motherfucking corner.
Every last one of them bitches.
What corner are we
talking about, again?
Ragtag shit up on Pacer.
Man, they get their shit from Joe,
but they're mostly independent.
They gone, Marlo.
Just say so.
That what you think?
Just do them all?
And take their fucking corner, too.
What do I want with some
off-brand Hilltop corner?
And why I need to
be stacking bodies
when there ain't no one
trying to war with us?
Just Lex.
He did one of us,
and he got to fall.
Get out, Tommy. You're done.
Get up, Tommy!
Come on, pretty boy. Come on.
You don't have to go home,
but you can't stay here.
Come on. Let's go.
Yeah. That's it.
There we go, little trooper.
6:30 tomorrow morning.
Don't make me drag you out of
bed like you did yesterday.
Damn, boy,
what happened to you?
Terrace boys banged me,
coming across the tracks
over there by Ramsey Street.
Teron, Manny, Herbie.
Man, all them Terrace niggers.
They can't whup on Dukie like that.
Yeah, I know.
Only we can whip on Dukie like that.
- We got to step it up, even this up.
- Nah. Fuck even.
We gonna hurt them twice as bad.
Give them a whup-ass
they ain't gonna never forget.
If we straight-up fight them,
It's as many of them
as it is us... more, even.
- So what you saying? You scared?
- Nah, I'm just saying.
If we're gonna hurt them,
we need to think on it.
Do something go past
beating on each other.
You talking guns and shit.
Nah, I ain't talking guns.
What?
Shit. Randy got an idea.
Hey, Norman.
You know what I had for dinner
last night?
Tuna sub. I ate in the car.
When I'm finished
writing my memoirs,
that shit'll be in there,
no doubt.
You see what I just ate?
In the car?
A fucking tuna sub.
In order to prevent distemper,
Norman,
you must vary the candidate's menu.
If you're done chewing,
let's give these new radio spots
a listen.
We've seen what Tommy Carcetti
can do at City Hall as a councilman.
While the current administration
bent to special interests,
- Tommy Carcetti...
- What?
that is protecting jobs
at the fort
by preventing the overdevelopment
of our waterfront.
300,000. Great.
Thanks for sharing.
prevented budget cuts
to vital city services...
3 and 5 zeroes...
Mayor's latest TV buy,
and it's 4 weeks out.
- Turn that shit off!
- You don't like the spots?
I read the copy
before the studio mix.
- I think they're strong.
- They're bullshit! Weak bullshit!
I wouldn't vote for me.
Fuck!
Fuck Royce! Fuck Tony Gray!
Fuck me!
Where am I going again?
One of those neighborhoods
between Oliver and Middle East.
Middle East.
Now, that's a good name
for a fucking Fallujah.
Command performance.
Ms. Victorina Simmons.
she holds sway over
two big vote precincts,
no matter who the EDC
is lying down with...
Fucking Royce!
300,000, like it's fucking water.
And then there's also
the Reverend Garnett.
What are they complaining
about today?
Fucking shithole of a city.
Whining bastards,
bitching about the trash
or the crime.
Or this or that.
It's my fucking fault
it went to shit.
These motherfuckers.
- Boss.
- They can bite my bloody ass.
Ms. Simmons.
Reverend Garnett.
Good to see you again.
I had a meeting going on,
but I'm here now, and I know
there's things to see.
We called and called downtown,
and ain't nothing gets done.
OK. Show me.
Right this way, Councilman.
The first thing I want you
to take a look at...
See, you got to drink a lot.
Think about the water running.
And that way, you know...
How the fuck you know what
water running be like, dude?
Water been off in your house
since last year.
- Man, that's cold.
- Yeah, that's cold, Nay.
Oh, shit. I'm ready.
Can't go when niggers watching, yo.
When we call,
he'll send somebody,
most of the time,
and they write it all down
just like he doing now.
But nothing ever gets done.
Come here, Councilman.
I want you to see this.
Now, see them drug boys?
They block the aisles like this
so the police
won't chase them down there.
All this trash.
Rats everywhere. Houses vacant.
We keep trying to get them
down here and clean this up.
I guess that's too much like right.
Well...
truth is, Royce won't let
the city agencies
take any of my constituent calls.
But let me see what I can do.
Come on, let me show you
this down here. Come on.
Yo, y'all Terrace niggers
know that boy
who go by the name "Dese"?
- Dese?
- Yeah, Dese Nuts.
Yo, yo, come on.
Come on. Come on.
Damn! I knew those bitches
was gonna set us up.
Yeah, fucking say it, bitches.
Don't ever disrespect Terrace.
Damn!
- I fucking pissed myself.
- Fuck!
Over here!
Randy!
Hey, yo, he run in there!
Remember that phrasing
is a cornerstone
in communicating
with your students.
This applies not only
to the questions you ask
or their comprehension
of the lesson,
but how they perceive you
as an educator.
and where does that begin?
Out loud and enthusiastically.
I.A.L.A.C.
Let's go. Once again.
And what are we telling ourselves?
I am lovable and capable.
Now I see those smiling faces.
...where the listing
on the lower half of the page
indicates some typical
soft target locations.
An officer alert to the terrorist
threat must ask himself
"Do I know the location
of my soft targets,
those where large numbers
of civilians congregate?"
Train terminals,
office buildings, stadiums.
Another hot zone in the classroom
is the pencil sharpener,
where children tend to
congregate and...
I had a pencil sharpener
in my class once.
Antoine Granderson ripped it
from the wall and threw it at me.
I'd like to know
what your lesson plan suggests
when Harold Hounchell
sends a full set of textbooks
through a closed window.
Thank you.
Settle down, everybody.
And for emergency procedures,
In the event of biochemical agents,
you can refer to appendix "b."
No disrespect to your appendix,
but if them terrorists
do fuck up the Western,
could anybody even tell?
Some Al-Qaedas were up
on Baltimore Street
planning on blowing up
the chicken joint.
But Apex's crew jacked them up,
took their camels and robes,
Buried their asses,
[?]
At least that's what I heard.
Y'all want some real terrorists?
You go up on Pencey and Gold.
You're doing one heck of a job.
Not another fucking word.
Thank you.
So...
You beast.
I can't help it.
You stirred my manhood.
Little boy blue.
What the fuck
are you doing here?
I caught one. Got a street dealer,
by the name of Lex.
Lester heard it on the wire.
Lester's up on the wire?
Shit, boy, you are out of the loop.
You know this mutt?
Goes by Lex?
He is familiar.
You know who you should ask?
Carver.
He'd love the job, man.
All right. Carver it is.
I still feel the need
to pull your coat.
- For what?
- The taste, Jimmy. The taste.
How about you and me
hit a few of our favorite spots?
You know, me on the Glenlivet,
you on the Jamey?
Go see if that train
is still on the track.
Why don't you come round
some night for dinner?
Say hey to Beadie
and the ankle-biters.
Dinner?
located in high-rise structures,
as well as residences,
are detailed alongside...
Hey, Santy.
This horseshit? You serious?
Back to school for the kids.
Hey. Yo, Namond, I'll pay you back.
Nigger, you ain't never
gonna have no money.
- Yo, Michael, they got you.
- Ain't nothing but a scuffle, man.
Everybody made it back,
though, right?
Nah. Keith had to go []
to close up stitches.
He got hit with a brick.
I see you changed clothes already.
He had to. Yo, he was stinking.
Yo, Randy, man, that was
the stupidest thing
you ever thought of.
But it was kind of funny
when it happened, though.
You know what I'm saying?
Yo, you want something
before we bounce, I'm buying.
One for every solider
that stood tall.
- I was down there.
- Yeah, fuck you, Duke.
So you get out all right?
Yeah. Hurt my ankle
going around the corner, but...
But you got away, then?
The Lieutenant Governor
is up in arms
because two democratic
national committees...
- I know we're way late...
- Ain't no thing. You did good here.
Turn that bullshit off.
You really think they're gonna
vote for the white guy?
Black folk been voting white
for a long time.
You come correct, we listen.
It's y'all that'll never vote black.
Shit, you got my vote, anyway.
I don't have your vote, Norman?
You're my deputy campaign manager,
and I don't have your vote?
Last white man I could
vote for was Bobby Kennedy,
And you ain't no Bobby K.
I thought you just said...
I was speaking in general about
the kindly nature of black folks.
In particular,
I ain't all that kindly.
So you're gonna take
my fucking check
and run with my fucking campaign...
Well, I do know who pays me.
Yessir! Oh, yessir, boss!
Who are you gonna vote for?
Royce? Tony gray?
One of them brothers.
Don't make me tell you again.
It's 9:00 sharp, boy.
And I'm smelling
what has to be urine.
What you been at, boy?
Well, we were playing
with Dukie today.
You know how he be
with his clothes and all.
Well, it's good that child
has friends, I suppose.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Get in there.
- Come on, now, give me a break...
- Come on, Dougie. I know it's late,
but I got to come backdoor like this,
or the agencies won't do shit.
You know that as well as I do.
- Come on, Tommy...
- Come on, Tommy. Hustle.
This is ridiculous.
- Come on, give me a break...
- Look, Dougie. Yeah.
I'm sorry to bug you at home,
but this asshole Royce
won't handle a thing
out of my office,
and I need
a couple of alleys cleaned.
1200 block of Federal Street,
both sides,
and then Chester and Collington,
run in either direction off that.
Jesus, Tommy.
I know you're gonna be out there
again in a couple of days
and can you call Frankie
in Special Services
And have him send a cold patch truck?
Federal Street's a fucking tank trap.
Great. Thanks. Love to Denise.
Hustle up, Tom.
How you doing? Good evening.
Hi.
You're over two hours late, Tommy.
You ain't gonna win
disrespecting your base.
Hold up, Tony.
Look, man. We got to talk.
I feel bad about the way
things have turned out,
but right or wrong,
if you're elected,
then I'm gonna do whatever
I can to help you,
and if I get in,
I'm gonna need your help.
I mean, it's not personal, Tony.
Fuck you, Tommy.
So this is me?
This is you.
Pandemic!
Pandemic! Got that pandemic
right here!
- What's up?
- What's up, man?
I got all this from the Koreans
today at a discount.
When school start,
I'll be selling it for 3 times that.
Tell you what...
let me get them skittles.
Nah. Do me a favor for the rest.
Go up the block and tell Lex
There's a girl that want to see him
at the playground behind Fort.
Girl?
Tell him Patrice say he should come
to the playground after 8:00.
- Why don't you tell him yourself?
- Look, dog,
I don't want to be taking none
of Bodie's shit today
about cutting work.
All right?
Just do me that favor.
Pandemic!
Pandemic right here!
For a skinny motherfucker,
he sure do sweat some.
We got to keep
an extra change in the car
So we don't have to come home
in the middle of the day.
Well, we're way past late now,
so...
- Damn it!
- Here, let me.
Hey Norman.
Maybe I'll go to clip-on
for a while.
Hey, Terri got in new polling data.
Did you get a bump?
Well, she won't show me anything
till it's all broke down,
But, yeah, I deserve a bump,
don't I?
4 more weeks, Jen.
Quality time with the wife and kids.
That's what, 4 minutes?
More like 6.
6. Shit, I could have got laid.
- Yo. Yo, Chris, I... I didn't...
- Yeah. It's good.
Pandemic!
Pandemic right here!
No Lex. Where's that skinny mope?
He was here earlier.
Well, fuck it. We'll come back,
jack him tomorrow, no problem.
All right.
Yeah. If Mr. Money's playing,
let me heat these bad boys up.
Share the sodas, too.
- What's up? What's up?
- Hey.
What's up?
Let me holla at you real quick.
What up?
You did like I said?
Yeah, you must have,
because the nigger
went up the block.
He ain't never coming back down.
Chris and Snoop...
- What?
- Look.
Just be cool, all right?
- Our heroes back from the wars.
- Those poll numbers tallied up yet?
- Not too bad, either.
Royce: 35, you: 26, Gray: 20.
19% undecided.
We're fucked if we haven't
moved any more than that.
I need to be at 30, and I need
Tony taking 25 of his points.
Royce's negatives are way up.
Like, what, 34% unfavorable
to 43% favorable?
- He's vulnerable.
- Geri, understand this.
In order to win, I need Tony Gray
to take a huge bite
out of Royce's lead... huge.
Tony's moved, what?
Two points in the last month?
That poll says 1 in 5 voters
hasn't decided anything yet.
Yeah. The first batch of radio spots
worked magic, didn't they?
How much money
we piss away on those?
Look at these first district figures.
I mean, that's my base,
and I'm polling 37%
with 24% undecided?
Fuck me! I'm done!
Tommy, nobody's focused
on this race yet.
We're gonna own the first.
Christ, look at what Royce
is polling in the fourth.
No doubt, Tony's got to get
some traction in West Baltimore.
Yeah, he needs to be rounding 25%
and headed for 30.
And, by the way,
who can tell me when the fuck
did the sixth district
become 64% black?
About 5 years ago
in the last redistricting.
Mostly as I recall, to give your ass
more white votes
over there in the first.
What the fuck was I thinking?
A hell of a lot can happen
between now and election day.
I've been ahead further
than Royce is and lost.
I can't win this.
Tommy. Where the fuck you going?
I'm your ride home, man.
The man can read a poll.
You been drinking?
I'm fine.
Well, you need to be fine
somewhere else.
Park curfew is midnight.
City's averaging a murder a day,
and here you are with...
rec and park rules?
- What are you, a smart ass?
- Sorry.
I didn't mean nothing.
Don't I know you?
I'm running for mayor.
Tommy Carcetti, first district.
I'll be coming back through
in about 20, Councilman.
Do me a favor
and take it down the road.
- Randy?
- Yes, ma'am.
Transcript par Raceman
Sous-titres par la Wired Team
www.thewire-france.com
www.forom.com