- daddy, wake up!
Wake up, daddy, wake up!
Wake up.
- oh, hey.
What's going on, sweetie?
- it's time to put my patch on.
Hurry up daddy.
- trinity has got to quit
smoking.
I can't have her smoking
anymore, it's ridiculous.
- she was on cigarettes
last year,
And they put her on the little,
little patch she used to wear
And I thought she was off
the cigarettes.
Now apparently she's back
on the cigarettes,
And she's on them hard too.
- she had the idea
we quit together,
A good father/daughter thing.
So we're gonna quit,
go on the patch.
- I only got one patch left,
so I to give you half.
- you took the last patch?!
- well, I just needed it
last night. Here.
I'll give you half of it.
- I want a cigarette.
- I want one too, but we can't.
We promised we're gonna quit
smoking together. Remember?
We can do this, can't we?
- we can do it.
- let's go to the store
and get some more patches.
You want to start the car up?
- yeah.
It's the gas injectors, daddy.
- no, it's probably
out of gas, honey.
I have to steal gas
cause I'm broke.
Gas is a fortune now
with all this government
bullshit taxes and stuff.
It pisses me off,
cause provinces like texas
and calgary, it's not so bad.
It should be the same
everywhere.
But the government is friggin
screwed up that way.
Drives me nuts.
- ricky, what are you doing?
Do you want to go back to jail?
- borrowing a little bit of gas.
You can't go back to jail
for that.
- is that true, julian?
- yeah, you can't go back
to jail for stealing gas.
- supreme. Can't believe
lahey burns supreme.
- jail is fun, and the food
and stuff is really good there,
But you know, I guess
it's more fun outside of jail
When you can still do crazy
things and get better dope
And get drunk
and stuff like that,
So it's not
that we don't like jail,
But we just don't really want
to go back to jail anytime soon
So we decided talking to people
in jail that the best thing
we can do
Is still break the law but do it
on a lower-type-scale
kind of thing.
You guys are probably wondering
why we called this meeting.
We want you to shut the fuck up
and listen to julian.
- alright, guys, I'm never, ever
going back to jail again, okay.
I've got a plan
to make money.
I think it's perfect.
We're gonna do low-risk crimes
And open up some small
semi-legit businesses.
- you gotta do two things.
Instead of breaking the law
big time for a big payday,
You gotta break the law a lot
but little tiny crimes
And then you still make
as much money and the cops
won't mess with you.
And you need to set goals
is the second thing,
Where you want
everybody to want do something.
So what we're thinking,
Or what julian is thinking,
I don't mean
to take credit for it,
He wants us to go on a cruise.
Break the law,
work towards that.
So you don't get people
ratting you out
And got something
to look forward to.
When you're breaking the law,
you know it's for something.
- if you guys work for me,
you'll get employee benefits.
You'll get paid
like any other job,
Except there's gonna be
a higher vacation-pay deduction.
- he's taking off
60% of everything,
it goes into this fund,
And we get on a big boat
and go party.
It's gonna be wicked.
- you mean one of those big
cocksuckers out on the ocean?
- yeah.
Awesome food, there's booze,
There's ladies,
I'm talking dope.
- ladies. Video games.
- all inclusive.
- probably got video games,
yeah, everything.
- oh boys, I hope you're not
teasing me right now.
That would be cruel. Cause
I wanted to go on a trip
Since I don't know when.
I couldn't ever afford it.
- guys, if we all
work together on this,
we can make this happen.
- what's the first thing we need
to do, julian? Sign me up.
- we're gonna open up
a little gas station
here in the trailer park.
- ha! Let's do it.
- I'd do anything
to go on a cruise, julian.
- there's no way
this can get fucked up.
- it's gonna be just like
a real gas station
we're running at ricky's.
Julian's making me
the gas-distribution manager,
Which is the most important job
there is.
I can't let the boys down,
I gotta work my ass off
so that we can do the, uh,
go on the cruise.
I've never been
on a fucking cruise before.
- you gas this up yesterday?
- yeah,
I put fifty bucks in her.
- the gas gauge reads empty.
Siphoning.
What kind of idiots
would steal gas
from the trailer-park supervisor
And think they could get away
with it, randy?
- unleaded, blue container.
Supreme, red container.
Diesel in the green. Okay,
are we clear here, guys?
- yeah, but how can you tell
which is the supreme?
- what are you stupid?
You fucking taste it.
Unleaded tastes a little tangy,
Supreme is kind of sour
and diesel tastes pretty good.
- will you please...
For godsake's, stop it.
Man, can you do something
about your daughter?
- just let her hit you, corey.
Stand down and listen to me.
- stop it! Stop it!
- hey, hey. Corey.
You gonna fight my daughter
who's nine years old?
You're probably
going to get hurt, okay.
Stand down and listen to me.
Boys, don't fuck this up.
I am your boss.
You do what I say when I say it,
Or I'll report you to julian
And you won't be going
on this cruise, okay?
- come on,
that's ridiculous, dude.
- corey, shut up and leave
my daughter alone, and listen.
Go to the store,
get julian some rum
and go siphon some gas.
I gotta take trinity
to get patches.
- sure, man.
- can we take bubbles?
- you bet we can.
- we'll take the money
from the gas station
and launder it here,
So you don't have any onsite.
- cool. That's a great idea.
- yeah, I know.
- we'll have coupons
from the salon
so that you know who's cool.
Different-coloured coupons
for a different amount.
If somebody
gets a perm coupon,
It's like twenty or forty bucks'
worth of gas.
- great idea, lucy.
And we'll take twenty percent.
- twenty percent.
Come on, girls. Fifteen percent.
I'm not gonna go any higher.
- no, julian. I said twenty.
- alright, if we're gonna do
this coupon thing,
twenty percent. That's fine.
- okay. Lucy and I will sell
coupons all over the park.
- hi, mr. Lahey.
- we're about to sail
into a shit typhoon, randy,
So we better haul in the jib
before it gets covered
with shit.
- what are you doing here,
mr. Lahey?
- video evidence, randy. Because
video evidence doesn't lie.
In a court of law,
Video evidence
is tantramar to the truth.
- hi jacob.
- oh hey, trin.
- how's it going?  I need
a box of nicotine patches.
- whoa! What are you doing?
Don't shoot me.
- I went in to buy some patches
and all of a sudden,
My gun was out,
which is no big deal,
And he freaks out, thought
we were robbing the place.
- oh no, no, it's alright.
We're not robbing you
Or anything like that.
Oh, trinity!
(gunfire)
(screaming)
- everything is cool. Get
the fuck back up here, jacob.
Everything is fucking cool here.
- trinity, how many times
does daddy have to tell you,
You can't play
with his handguns.
- you shouldn't leave it
laying around.
- it's okay, sweetie.
- we're on video camera.
- so since it was
on video camera,
I decided,
we take a bit of shit.
- for the legal record,
we were not robbing the store.
- it looks like
we robbed the place.
Go grab some groceries, bubbles.
- we're not taking anything,
ricky.
- it's not robbing.
Instead of suing,
we're gonna take a bit of shit.
I want a copy
of the videotapes.
If the cops saw this shit,
I'd go to jail for ten years.
- if you're gonna go to jail for
robbing the place you may as--
(dog barking)
will you shut the fuck up, dog?
If it looks you robbed a place,
you take some shit.
I'm not gonna jail
for robbing a place.
So we took a bit of stuff.
- are you alright, ricky?
- yup.
- you said you're not supposed
to smoke with the patch on.
- daddy's bigger than you
so he can.
I'm having a couple
cause they were free.
- ricky! Where
did you get this stuff?
Don't tell me you stole it.
- I didn't steal it.
- they did steal it.
- oh no, julian, uh, going
into a store, firing a gun off,
And leaving without paying for
everything, that's not stealing.
- yes, it is stealing.
- trinity accidentally
fired my gun off,
It looked we robbed the place,
so we took a bit of stuff.
- of course,
it's not a big deal.
- ricky
got the surveillance tape.
He's got everything
under control.
- exactly.
- nothing to worry about.
- you've got to stop fucking
around, okay, please!
You keep pulling stunts
like this,
We're gonna be back in jail
so fast ricky.
- we're not going back to jail.
- julian!
We got our first customer, boys.
- how's it going?
We got a perm coat coupon,
that's 20 regular.
And a cut and blow.
We're gonna need
a safety inspection, bubbles.
- safety inspection!
- get the fuck out of my way!
- sorry about this.
- julian, he's got
a cigarette lit and I'm covered
in flammable liquids.
- put that out!
Put it out, ricky!
Put it out!
- oh my god.
- daddy, I want a smoke!
- you can't smoke
with the patch on.
Give me that cigarette.
- you have a patch on
and you're smoking it.
- I'm way bigger than you.
Trinity,
don't lit that cigarette.
- why not?
- julian, hold this for a
second. Give me that cigarette.
- how come ricky's
in charge of the gas?
- I'm serious,
I need that cigarette.
Mummy's gonna be mad.
You know what mummy will say.
- well, mummy will say,
mummy will get mad at you
Because you're smoking
with the patch on.
- trinity, give daddy
the cigarette, please.
- drop your cigarette.
Step on it.
- give me the cigarette.
- no.
- it's diesel, man.
- man, I'm feeling sick, dude.
- maybe we should stop
doing this.
- yeah man, but the cruise.
We gotta do the cruise.
- yeah,
I guess it's not that bad.
- oh, shit, security dude.
- oh, fuck man.
What the fuck are you doing?
- oh! Oh!
- fuck you.
(horns honking)
- we're drawing
too much attention.
We gotta shut it down
for a while.
- it's ricky's fault.
- listen, man, we're drawing
too much attention.
Lahey could come around.
J rock, tyrone,
We're shutting down for a while.
Move these cars out.
- people are yelling at me...
Change tires and--
- I paid for it!
- that's a fucking good muffler.
I'm keeping that fucking thing.
- get the fuck going, come on.
- I bet you this coupon
doesn't get you a perm.
- it says perm
right on it there, mr. Lahey.
- randy,
there's a distinct possibility
That ricky and julian are
operating a prostitution ring.
Is this rolling?
- rolling.
- see the camera?
- can't see a thing.
- let's move.
- I was thinking
of more height in here.
What the hell
do you want, lahey?
- well, we'll have whatever
these coupons will get us.
- alright, have a seat.
- thank you.
- have you ever had one
of these before?
- never.
- hey, what are you doing?
- undoing my pants,
they're a little tight.
- you can do them back up.
- jesus, randy.
- look, there's a lot of traffic
in ricky's lot.
Ergo, they're doing
something illegal.
We're gonna get them
on videotape,
And when we have
enough evidence,
We're gonna call in 9-1-1,
Law enforcement,
the cops, the boys in blue.
We'll have it all
on tape, randy.
- right, come ahead.
Alright, j rock,
I'm opening up again, okay.
I want to keep
everything low-key,
I don't want to see
a traffic jam here, alright?
- let's get this pump going.
Got your coupon?
- yup, right here.
- twenty bucks, perfect.
- what are you doing?
- pumping your fucking gas,
what does it look like?
- with a cigarette
in your mouth?
You're gonna kill somebody, man.
- give me a level, randy.
- check one,
Check two, test one, test two.
- that'll do.
We've got them on multiple
angles, so they're fucked.
Rundown, randy, let's go.
- pull into the zone,
contact the target.
Procure stolen merchandise.
Ensure we capture
the exchange on tape,
Then fall back
to the designated safety area.
- I'll be in the woods.
The sale goes down,
I'll call in the heavies.
Are we clear?
- clear, mr. Lahey!
- hey julian, we just saw lahey
and randy snooping around.
- they've got a video camera
hooked up to their car.
- holy shit.
- what are you doing with this?
- you have her working here?
- she's not working here.
- you've got my daughter working
at an illegal gas station.
- she's my daughter too
and she's not working.
- let's get her out of here.
You better not fuck this up.
- that's my squeegee.
Julian, do you think
that's true?
Lahey's gonna have us on
videotape selling illegal gas.
- ricky, ricky, get over here.
Get over here. Alright, boys.
Everybody stay calm.
There's no money onsite here,
okay?
We can shut this business down
at any time.
Lahey doesn't have shit on us.
- well apparently lahey's
got all these cameras.
He's got some in his car
and he's got handheld video.
He's gonna catch us on tape.
So, julian's got
this great idea, we throw it
right back in his face.
- boys! Where in the hell
were you guys?
- we're sick, julian. We've been
drinking fucking gas.
We've just gotta sit down
for a minute.
- what the fuck took so long?
- come on, dude.
Here's your shit, man.
(smashing sound)
- oh, fucking nice one, corey.
You smashed the rum.
- I'm sorry, dude.
- you're gonna have to
get him more.
- I'm all fucked up, man.
Drinking this shit.
I think I'm dying.
- you've got a customer, julian.
- j rock, take care
of this customer.
- you guys
just got gas sickness.
Drink some water
and dilute it, man.
You'll be fine
in six to eight days.
- ricky, you can't smoke
with the patch on.
You're gonna get dizzy.
- I'm fine. Oh fuck,
here comes fucking randy
and his stupid fucking cameras.
- boys.
- what are we gonna do?
- stay calm and do what
we rehearsed, alright?
- hey boys. What's going on?
- hey randy.
- everything's cool.
I know what's going on here.
I just want some cheap stuff,
just like everybody else.
- randy, you better go on
with your perm coupon,
Gut cassidy and
the sundance cheeseburger.
- what?
- what are you looking
at my eyes for?
I got no candy for you.
- just a second, randy. Boys.
- holy fuck, I'm dizzy.
- don't look now.
- it's the patch.
- don't look now,
but lahey is in the woods
with a video camera. Don't look.
- fuck, julian,
what are we gonna do?
- just stay calm
and stick to the plan.
- he's gonna get us.
- corey, trevor.
Deal with randy.
Let's go, trevor.
Get up. Take care of randy.
- okay, boys.
Here's twenty dollars cash.
Fill it up for me, please.
- ricky?
- we don't want your money,
corey and trevor.
- what's wrong
with you guys anyway?
- we're sick
from all the fucking gas
we've been stealing.
We should be better
in six to eight days though.
- why corey and trevor,
that's highly illegal.
You shouldn't be stealing gas,
corey and trevor.
- it's fucked up
to be stealing gas
like corey and trevor did.
And I don't want anything to do
with corey and trevor's
gas stealing.
- is this the gas
you were stealing right here?
- what the fuck
was that all about?
- is this the gas you stole?
- is that the gas you stole?
- it's what you told us to do.
- good job, guys.
- I just gotta chill out
For a second, guys.
I'm fucking dizzy here.
(explosion)
- holy fuck, boys!
- holy fuck, ricky!
What are you doing, mo-fucker?
(sirens)
- it wasn't me!
I didn't do shit!
(yelling and swearing)
- thank you, mr. Lahey,
For your expert testimony
And for providing
this very illuminating tape.
Your honour,
I think the video evidence
Clearly speaks for itself
And that any sane
and rational person
Would have no choice
but to convict
These individuals
of these ridiculous crimes.
- blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, fuck.
- oh, objection.
That's the seventeenth time
that he has sworn so far.
- richard, please?
- alright. I'm fuck... I'm sorry
about all the bullsh...
About all the stuff.
But the prosecutor
is a f... He's a f...
He's an f-ing bad guy
and he's pissing me off.
- he can't even speak
without swearing.
Your honour, this is ludicrous.
It's a disgrace
to these proceedings.
- richard, since you chose
to defend yourself
And fire the public defender,
I guess it's your turn
to question the witness.
- thank you, your majesty.
- and richard, before you begin,
I'd like to say
that I think this is a bad idea.
However, you do have
a right to defend yourself,
So proceed, but please remember
to watch your language.
- look, I can't speak
without swearing
and I've only got my grade 10.
I haven't had a cigarette
since I've been arrested
And I'm ready to snap,
so I'd like to make a request
Under the people's freedom
of choices and voices act
That I be able to smoke
and swear in your courtroom.
Cause if I can't smoke
and swear, I'm fucked
And so are all these guys.
I won't be able to properly
express myself
At a court level
and that's bullshit.
It's not fair,
and if you ask me,
I think it's a fucking mistrial.
- this man
can't represent anyone.
Your honour,
he's a complete and total idiot.
- well, although I am opposed
to that kind of language
in my courtroom,
I'm gonna allow it,
as unfortunately,
It is part of your right
to a fair trial.
So you may proceed,
but please,
I want to remind you
that this is not a carnival.
Richard, you have permission
to smoke and swear.
- thank you. I've just gotta get
some cigarettes actually.
Let's go, smokes.
- but I only got two left.
- I don't care.
You've been a dick.
It's the least you can do.
- oh, for the love of god.
- just the defendant please.
- my first order of business
is to tell the prosecutor
To shut up and wipe
that stupid grin off his face,
Cause it's distractulating
my case.
Next I'd like to announce
that randy and lahey
Have been drinking
all fucking day,
They're wasted out of their
minds and they're both assholes.
And the testimony they just gave
was total fucking bullshit.
I can prove it
and I'm gonna show
you what happened here.
- okay, boys,
here's twenty dollars cash.
Fill it up for me please.
- don't know what that's for.
Probably prostitution.
We don't want your money.
Watch him put right, right
in his pocket, right there.
- oh, man, we're sick
from stealing so much gas.
But we should be better
in like six to eight days.
- stealing gas!
Why, corey and trevor,
that's highly illegal.
You shouldn't be stealing gas,
corey and trevor.
- that's right, it's fucked up
to be stealing gas
like corey and trevor did,
And I don't want anything to do
with corey and trevor's
gas stealing.
We wanted nothing to do with it.
- me neither,
you know what I'm saying?
Only whack suckers
like corey and trevor
steal gas, and deal dope.
- now, I don't want
to say anything about the dope,
Cause you know,
I don't know
anything about that.
But clearly they accepted money
on film and they admitted
They stole gas.
And they're sick,
I mean look at them.
That's gas sickness.
Fucking idiots.
I've got nothing else to say,
Except that the crown and lahey
can go fuck themselves.
- you're not buying
any of this bullshit, are you?
- sit down, sir, or
you'll be in contempt of court.
And watch your language.
- yeah lahey, sit the fuck down.
Truth fucking hurts, doesn't it,
you son of a bitch.
Whatever. Defence rests,
everybody else can fuck off.
Except you. I didn't mean you.
- thank you, richard.
You may be seated.
- can you guys get the fuck out
of the way, please?
- okay, well I think
I've heard enough,
And I'll be back shortly
with my verdict.
- well you know, just because
these young men
Have little education
and live in squalor,
It doesn't entitle them
to commit antisocial behaviour
and get away with it.
- there's two things mo-fuckers
gotta know about j to the r o c.
First of all, I spin more rhymes
than a lazy susan
And I'm innocent
until my guilt is proven.
Peace. Representing sunnyvale,
straight the fuck up.
- be seated please.
Well, I've reached a verdict
in this ridiculous case,
And I do mean ridiculous.
Given richard's deconstruction
of the video evidence,
Clearly trevor and corey
are the only ones
With any hard evidence
against them here.
- but we were framed.
- quiet please.
- you fucked up.
- therefore, I find richard,
julian, jamie and bubbles
Not guilty on all counts.
(cheering)
- order please. Order please.
Trevor and corey, please stand.
I find you guilty
and sentence you
to 450 hours' community service.
Case closed.
- trevor and corey
got a bit of community service,
which sort of sucks,
But it's good experience
they should be doing
That sort of stuff,
going to jail once in a while.
We do it.
Why they shouldn't be doing it?
I don't really
feel bad about that.
It's their fault.
- what's going on guys?
We haven't seen you in so long.
What's up?
- julian,
tell them why we're here.
- we just wanted to say thanks
for not ratting us out,
And to not forget we're going
on a cruise. Remember that.
- we'd never rat you out julian.
- yeah, man.
- ricky, give them the stuff.
Come on.
- brought you guys some smokes
and a couple of joints, alright.
- oh man, thanks, dude.
That's dope.
- thanks a lot.
- so we're cool?
- yeah, man.
(tires squealing)