ADAM'S APPLES
Adam?
Sorry I'm late.
Ivan Fjeldsted.
Call me Ivan.
I'm a bit flustered but I've
been looking forward to meeting you.
Let's get going.
Let me take your bag.
That was...
Come on.
People who have been in prison are
often a bit protective of their stuff.
Have you lived
in the country before?
This is our small church.
Just take a look at this.
This is our apple tree.
We're very proud of it.
There are lots of apples this year.
Lots and lots.
It's probably because of
the warm summer.
They're not ripe just yet.
Don't eat that. Come with me.
- Good morning.
Adam will stay with us.
This is Khalid and Gunnar.
I won't talk to the egghead.
Don't worry,
there will be lots of time for talk.
Come on, Adam.
What does the O stand for?
In Adam O. Pedersen?
What's the story about the O?
Your parents must have told you.
- I forgot to ask.
- That's a good answer.
It says here
that you're a neo-Nazi.
Are you really?
It's not the first thing that springs
to mind by looking at you.
Here it says you're EVIL. What a
rude thing to write on a person's CV.
Are you really evil?
I didn't think so. I'll tell you what,
let's just forget about this.
There are no evil people.
We don't believe in that.
If you only search for evil
then the whole world appears evil.
But you can try to focus on
the silver lining, as we do here.
That makes everything easier.
In recent years, the Devil
has sent his minions to test us -
but we have conquered them all.
All of us here have
found God in some way.
You just met Khalid and Gunnar.
I saw that you did.
Gunnar was paroled
four years ago.
He was only required to stay for three months,
but he chose to remain.
Gunnar was
what you would call an alcoholic.
He was a thief and a rapist
but now he's cleaned himself up
and is studying theology. He's not
the only one. There's also Khalid.
He used to rob gas stations.
Do you remember the young man who got
shot when he went to buy condoms?
- No.
- Khalid is still not allowed in any Statoil stations.
Yes, there were a few hostage mishaps,
but now he's learning Danish and doing much better.
Tell me what I have to do.
I can't do that. You have
to discover that for yourself.
All I want is for you
to set yourself a goal.
Are you listening to me?
Yes, I believe I am.
In any other situation
I would say that you are rude -
- but let's not talk about that now.
What do you want your goal to be?
I would like to bake a pie.
Bake a pie?
Oh, an apple pie?
Yes, an apple pie.
- My goal is to bake a big apple pie.
- With the apples from our garden?
- Yes, the apples from the garden.
- That's a good idea.
I think we found your goal.
You're going to bake a pie.
You'll look after the tree
until the first of August.
Then you'll use the apples
to bake an apple pie.
I just wanted to give you this. It has
both the old and the new testament.
It's a good thing to have.
Sleep tight.
Evil has many faces -
- and it can be difficult to tell
them apart and choose sides.
Especially these days where so many
things are said in this and that town.
Everything has so many nuances.
We are all human.
If the game of chess had undergone
the same development as humans -
- the queen would be in front,
the rooks would be crooked -
- and the pawn
would be the main piece.
We no longer know
who we are and this rootlessness--
Are we boring you, Poul?
Is the word of God boring to you?
- Are we boring you?
- I need to go to the loo.
- Can't it wait?
- Not really.
We finish in 20 minutes.
- I think that Poul can wait that long.
- Let him go for fuck's sake.
- We can sing now.
- Okay, democracy has spoken.
Go, Poul.
Go take a crap.
- But you can't come back in.
- That's okay.
You have to use the hospital loo
because you can't use ours.
- Why not?
- It's locked during the service.
- Why?
- For security reasons.
Let's continue
if it's okay with Poul.
We'll sing 634
"You know my heart".
There's fried pork.
It was a good sermon today.
At least it was shorter than usual.
Too bad for old Poul Nordkap.
Ivan is always on his case.
He leaves during the sermons.
It's not nice of him.
He always does that.
It's because he was in
a concentration camp during the war.
He's become restless in his old age.
He's 86.
It won't be any fun
when I get that old.
Don't worry about Ivan.
He's okay. Just don't venture
into an argument with him.
- What the hell are you doing?
- Me?
- My phone!
- I thought you were sleeping.
And my wallet! Are you stealing
my stuff? Have you gone insane?
- I'm sorry.
- Piss off, fatso!
- Sleep tight.
- Piss off!
BOOK OF JOB
- They're not moving.
- Fucking cheeky bastards.
Fly home, for fuck's sake!
What are we going to do?
There won't be
any apples left for your pie.
Let the Paki monkey climb up
and shoo them away.
- I'm not talking to you.
- I don't know anything about birds.
What do we do
in a case like this?
You leave them alone, I think.
- Can't we let them eat the apples?
- They're Adam's apples for the pie.
- For fuck's sake, he can't bake.
- You don't know that.
If Adam wants to bake us a pie
it's our job to support him.
- He can't bake shit.
- Shut up!
- I can tell.
- What the fuck do you know, Paki?
That's the right attitude. That kind
of attitude will get us some pie.
- There's more of them coming.
- That's just plain rude.
That's good.
Very authentic.
- No bird will come back now.
- Reverend Fjeldsted?
Yes?
Call me Ivan.
- I'm Sarah Svendsen.
- Hi. This is my assistant Adam.
I'm not from around here. I wanted
to come to the service but I couldn't.
Don't apologize.
You only belittle yourself.
What's this?
You don't look so good.
Let's go inside and talk.
- I met this guy.
- The milk has gone bad.
- Fine.
- I was thinking about her.
- Me too.
- No, you weren't.
Are you saying I wasn't?
Are you?
Let's have this discussion right now.
This may be the right time and place.
John says: "He came to Canaan
after having turned water into wine. "
"A boy was sick. Jesus said: Do unto
others as you would have them do unto you. "
Don't call me inconsiderate.
It's okay.
- I don't like milk.
- Maybe we have some cookies.
Adam, could you go see if there's
a few cookies for Sarah and me?
Maybe I shouldn't have come.
No, no, no.
- So you met a guy?
- Yeah.
I have been in Indonesia working for
the World Wildlife Federation.
I made love to a man
and got pregnant.
I used to drink a lot before.
Now I'm in AA
and I've been sober for 341 days.
Now they're saying that
the baby may be handicapped.
- I don't know where the dad is...
- Just a second, Sarah.
Why do I get three cookies and Sarah
only two? Don't you find that odd?
There were five left.
Hers looked bigger.
I don't think so.
Why?
Did you measure the cookies?
What?
Right. Who measures cookies?
Alright, let's stop this discussion.
- You would like to get rid of the baby?
- Yes... No!
There's a 60% chance
that the baby will be handicapped.
I have to decide within a week
whether or not to keep it.
I can't handle
a handicapped child.
60 percent is high, right?
It's just statistics.
Let me tell you something.
When we were expecting our son we
were told that he could be disabled.
We could have been intimidated
by the statistics
- but we chose to look
on the bright side, and now...
When I see him run around in the
garden or doing his math homework -
- we're happy that
we chose to have him.
You won't find anyone
to say otherwise.
The Devil is testing us all the time.
We have to make the right choices.
If we all listened to reason, the
world would be a gloomy place to live.
You need to follow your heart
and have the baby.
- Fuck!
- Good morning.
Fuck, that hurt!
Why the hell didn't you
turn off the stove!?
This looks bad.
What did reverend Fjeldsted say?
He's a frigging idiot.
He may be weird,
but he's a good lad.
His life sure as shit hasn't been easy.
Everything went wrong from the start.
His mother died
giving birth to him.
He lived with his father and sister.
Until they took him away.
Ivan? They took Ivan away?
No, nobody took Ivan away.
The father was taken away.
Henning.
Why?
He beat those kids black
and blue. They could hardly walk.
- Shut up and fix this.
- Pardon me for being blunt.
I've learned
it's best to tell it like it is.
We're all best served
by being told the truth.
Adam?
What's this I hear?
Burned by the stove?
- Gunnar forgot to turn it of.
- Take a seat. I'd like to talk to you.
Do you know why
all this is happening?
Why are all these birds in the tree?
And the stove. Why did you
burn yourself all of the sudden?
I think someone is trying to tell you
that you shouldn't go near the stove.
You can't bake
a pie without a stove.
I think Satan is testing us.
By not letting me bake the pie?
He's trying to fight us. He's testing
your strength to withstand him.
He's always doing it to me.
Look at your hand.
You're a complete moron.
Nobody is doing anything.
- Gunnar just forgot to turn it off.
- He always makes sure to turn it off.
- That fat pig is always hammered!
- Fat and drunk!
So many accusations,
but there may be an explanation.
You should know that in his youth,
he was the top-ranked Danish tennis player.
He won all his matches but then,
one match, a ball was mistakenly called out.
Gunnar lost
and everything went downhill.
What about Khalid?
This was in his coat pocket.
- What are you saying?
- Those two haven't changed.
- You're a joke.
- Should we forbid people to wear hats?
It's a balaclava, and this is summer.
Khalid is from a hot climate.
- Here's fucking 17,000 in cash.
You're reaching, Adam.
Khalid is saving to buy new clothes.
You didn't know.
Give me my phone and my wallet
or I'll smash your face in.
That's not fucking mine!
Stay away from my stuff.
Do you understand?
You're lucky that I'm going back in
because I would beat you every day.
- I'm going to the emergency room,
- Will you pass the market?
- I might.
- Could you get me some cough syrup?
- Sure, what brand?
- Von Osten.
Right. Think about what we can
do concerning the birds, if you have time.
Here you go. It can't be traced
but throw it away anyway.
Can you shoot with that hand?
Are you going to whack the priest?
He's fucked up.
He got it in the ass as a kid.
- Now he's all "turn the other cheek."
- You're getting out in 11 weeks.
We're all waiting for you.
Espen can't control the guys.
- I'm not going to shoot the priest.
- I just want to understand him.
I need to break him.
All that goodness shit.
Does it involve the pear pie?
Espen says you talk about a pie.
It's an apple pie, okay?
It doesn't matter.
I said that I would bake a pie
and the idiot won't let up.
He says that the Devil is testing us
because birds are eating the apples.
Do you need help?
Who the fuck do you
think you're talking to?
See you.
Go on.
Get them!
Don't be afraid.
Go on. Get them.
He's making them nervous.
- They don't fucking care about the fucking cat.
- They're looking right at him.
- Yes. Lambert is not working.
My granddad
had a cherry tree.
It was attacked by birds, so he shot
a few in the morning and evening.
Shot them?
With a gun?
No, a waffle iron.
Of course it was a gun.
What gun?
One like this.
You know what?
I think that we should try it.
Can you take them from there?
We can use guns?
For fuck's sake, why didn't you say so?
- Well...
- Lambert?
Lambert, are you okay?
What just happened?
He's dead.
- It was a shitty cat anyhow.
- He shot my cat.
Let's stop with the accusations.
It was an old cat.
He just happened to fall down
while we were shooting.
If you want
to discuss it now we can.
Okay.
We talked about your grandfather.
Do you know what I think?
I think
it's going to be a good day.
It's too bad that Khalid won't come in
when we're making his favorite food.
- He's embarrassed about Lambert.
- Where did he get the gun?
- Is he a terrorist?
- He wants to return to Saudi Arabia.
You should see his dream house.
It's really nice.
With a little more money from
a few more Statoil stations, he can finally go home.
- Why not just rob a bank?
- Khalid is very committed to politics.
He only robs multinational companies.
That's why he robs Statoil stations.
Statoil stole his father's land for the
oil. Khalid is taking back his property.
- Statoil is Norwegian.
- No, I don't think so.
- Statoil is Norwegian!
- Remember to tell Khalid that.
- So Ivan knows what he's doing?
- Yes. Ivan just wants him to be calm.
Ivan is not exactly normal.
The anniversary
of his wife's death is coming up.
- He had a wife?
- Yes, Linda.
She took some pills and killed herself
because they had a handicapped son.
He's got cerebral palsy. He can't
move at all. She couldn't take that.
Can I come in?
Adam, there sure is no shortage of
recipes for apple pie in this world.
It looks like we've
won round one.
What a handsome man. Your father?
That's Hitler.
No.
Hitler had a beard.
Ah, you're right. I'm thinking of that
Russian guy. Very well..
Hitler's enemies didn't
take him seriously either.
Don't you think that I do?
That's just plain rude.
Old Paul Nordkap--in the
hospital with no will to live -
- he was a bigger Nazi than anyone.
Why do you think
they ask me to cheer him up?
Wasn't he in a camp?
Sure. He was working there.
He met Goblins and all those folks.
- Goebbels?
- He was probably there as well.
Come with me to visit. Then we
can see who takes who seriously.
Deal?
BOOK OF JOB
Hello!
I'm glad that you could make it.
He's dying. He won't last through
the night. I broke it to him gently.
Well,
let's give him a good sendoff.
- How's the hand?
- Okay.
What about the honker, Ivan?
It took quite a beating.
You don't have to waste
money on perfume anymore, Ivan.
You won't smell anything again.
Yes.
Come on, Adam.
What's up with you, Poul?
Have you lost your appetite?
I've brought a guest for you.
- Hello. Adam Pedersen.
- Are you feeling a bit low?
- I'm scared.
Relax.
What have you been up to?
- Have the nurses been nicer to you?
- Don't make them. I don't deserve it.
They have been nagging Poul because
of this past but we put a stop to that.
Didn't we, Poul?
Has Miriam been nicer to you?
Yes, she made me hot chocolate
yesterday and tucked me in.
- They are all so nice to me.
- That's good. Don't be upset.
- I don't deserve it. Let me be.
- Everybody deserves to be tucked in.
- Did she fluff your duvet and pillow?
- Yes.
There, there.
I apologize for
trying to skip your sermons.
I just don't like
being inside the church.
- That's all forgotten now.
- I know that's what you always say.
I'm scared, Ivan.
I dare not sleep. I'm so afraid.
Bah!
You have nothing to worry about.
Let's focus on the people who care
for you and all your lovely memories.
Oh God!
Poul, don't cry anymore.
Don't be so hard on yourself.
All has been forgiven.
If you only knew what we did...
All those poor people.
- It can't be forgiven.
- Stop it. Nobody remembers anymore.
Oh God!
Stop your whining.
It's not all that bad!
We all make mistakes
but we don't let them bring us down.
You're...crazy...
Why do you say that? Why spoil
the mood by being rude?
I'd be happy to discuss it,
but this is not the place.
Let's focus on the word of God.
God forgives all, Poul.
God forgives all.
It's always difficult.
Even though I've seen it before
it's still difficult every time.
- Did you discuss your wife's death?
- Yes, I talked to a lot of people.
- A wife's suicide must be painful.
- Yes, it can't be nice.
- Linda didn't take her own life.
- But she took pills?
Yes, but it was an accident.
Accident how?
Christoffer had been playing with her
pills and had put them in a candy dish.
Linda always had a sweet tooth and
she thought they were yellow M&Ms.
Your son Christoffer?
- So he's actually able to move?
- Why wouldn't he be?
- I thought he was paralyzed.
- No, I wish.
There's no slowing him down. Just
yesterday he was playing rounders.
I don't believe you, Ivan.
- I just don't.
- I've never heard anything that crazy.
Has Gunnar tbeen telling tall stories and
playing fast and loose with the truth?
If he has
that's just plain rude.
Why don't you bring your son tomorrow?
He's already coming. He's been
pestering me all week to come.
Good.
Then you can see for yourself.
- Good morning.
Christoffer, this is Adam.
Adam, Christoffer.
Maybe you could go say hello.
Yum, eggs.
Small mouthfuls.
He's paralyzed.
What did you say?
- I have to go in tower.
- You two stay here.
- I need to shoot more crows.
- Sit down.
He's paralyzed.
Christoffer,
go into daddy's office. Now!
This will not be pleasant to watch.
What did you say?
He's paralyzed.
Isn't he paralyzed, Ivan?
Is he really, Adam?
Yes, he has cerebral palsy.
That is just crazy.
Khalid, what do you have to say?
Khalid?
He does.
Ivan, he's paralyzed.
Your son's a retard.
Your wife killed herself.
Your mother died giving birth to you.
Your dad raped you.
Look at me, Ivan.
Look at me.
You're bleeding from the ear. You're
bleeding from the ear, for fuck's sake!
The other one!
- Ivan was bleeding from an ear.
- That happened to me once.
Just drink milk.
Plenty of milk.
Just give up, Ivan.
Adam.
There's something
you should know.
Christoffer is recovering from
a very nasty bout of the flu.
I'm the first to admit that
he's been a bit sluggish lately.
- Shut the fuck up!
- If one hurts you, turn the other cheek.
God is on my side.
What is his problem?
He needs to be locked up!
I'm not one to gossip -
- but he's always been
considered a phenomenon.
- I don't know if you don't.
- How the hell should I know?
- He's sick. Very sick.
- I bloody well know that.
No, not like that.
Well, he is that, too -
but...
he's terminally ill.
- What's wrong with him?
- Cancer.
He has a brain tumor
the size of a volleyball.
I've never seen anyone
with such a large brain tumor.
I'll bash your face in
if you call him a walking miracle.
Have you heard about
the Ravashi syndrome?
Ravashi was
an Indian footballer -
- who lost both his feet
in a go-kart accident in 1957.
In a state of shock over the accident
he ran home on the stumps of his legs.
His brain blocked the fact
that he had no feet.
For two months
he came to practice.
- He kept his midfield position.
- Without feet?
They were a bad team.
They were maybe in the fifth league.
Ivan has experienced
so much hardship -
- that he needs to find an
explanation in order to live with it.
That's why he thinks that
the Devil has it in for him.
Ivan would say that
everything is a test.
You're a test, his cancer is a test,
his son's handicap is a test.
In Ivan's mind he's locked in
fierce battle with the Devil himself.
Ivan has no mind to lose and he
blocks out everything like Ravashi.
He's in denial about all the bad stuff.
Death, mutilation, hardship, evil.
That simply
doesn't exist in Ivan's world.
Why does he bleed from his ears?
We have asked ourselves that. I think
it's when something comes too close.
Someone once got through to him.
He bled from his ears once before.
That was three years ago.
- What happened?
- You don't know his sister Katinka.
An utter whore.
She fucked everybody.
I even fucked her when she was
here to have her tonsils removed.
When she died
Ivan almost fell to pieces.
He bled from his ears
and got sick.
- What happened then?
- You know Ivan.
A few days later
he was jolly as ever.
You could simply kill him by
making him understand the truth?
Yes, in theory.
Give up, Adam.
God is on my side.
Never forget that.
Hi.
The stove is broken.
- I wanted to make Christoffer a pizza.
- Let's fix it.
- I don't know how.
- We'll get by.
- Where did Christoffer go?
- He's in your office with a woman.
She's quite upset. Her name is Sarah
and she's a real hottie.
When she saw Christoffer she started
screaming. She didn't want coffee.
Well, we'd better...
So nice of you to visit again.
- Has he been good?
- Tell me he isn't yours.
I can't because this is Christoffer.
Have you two been introduced?
How can you say the things you did?
What kind of things?
You said that nothing was wrong
with him. That he could do math.
Yes, he can.
Even the complicated kind.
Adam, maybe you should go get
some of the cookies that Sarah likes.
I'll come too.
Is anyone hungry?
You can hook up the new stove now.
We'll see if this one lasts a bit longer than the last.
- What are you doing?
- Playing a drinking game with coins.
- Gunnar is good.
- But you're pregnant.
- It's a bit late for that.
- We're rewriting an article.
- About what?
- The tigers in the Orient.
Here it says that
there's only 400 left.
It won't be long before they're extinct.
- Like the last round at the pub.
- What do you do then, Gunnar?
- You buy a pint and a chaser.
- The fuck you do!
Gunnar is right.
We have to do something.
- Shut up, man!
- Stay out of it.
Yes, Adam, stop disturbing us.
We're busy.
- Five tigers die every day.
- Six! Six tigers a day, Adam.
They can really
jump high, those tigers.
I'll come right out and say it.
You better come with me.
What now?
There's a new apple problem.
Meet me in five minutes by the tree?
I don't understand.
I see nothing but worms.
Yeah, I found them,
but I don't deserve any credit.
For fuck's sake,
they're in all the fruit.
That's just plain rude.
Yes, Adam,
it never stops.
Let's do something about it. Take
down the sick fruit and spray the rest.
Gunnar, come with me. We have
to arrange Poul's return to God.
BOOK OF JOB
Poul Baegel Hermann, known to
friend and foe as Poul Nordkap -
- lived a long and full life.
In his life Poul learned that to know
God you must dance with the Devil.
If anything, Poul Nordkap surely did that.
Poul learned that it's futile
to fight Good because -
- despite all the pain and suffering
he caused in his youth -
- he realized in the end that
this was just a mere moment.
The ocean heaved
but it was a wasted effort.
The world continued
and Good prevailed as always.
That's why Poul can return
to God with peace of mind.
Adam and I were by his side
when he passed quietly away.
His last words were:
"I'm not afraid. I'm ready. "
But this is not all about Poul -
- because today Christoffer turns nine.
Before we gorge ourselves on cake -
- let's honor Poul
with a hymn.
Kaj Munk's number 634.
"You Know My Heart."
There you are.
I thought you had gone to bed.
- I'd like to talk to you.
- Can't it wait?
It has been a long day for
Christoffer with all this attention.
I'd like to talk to you now.
Okay.
Okay, then.
Go into dad's office
and cuddle up under a blanket.
What's up with you?
Is the business with the birthday cake?
- What if the Devil isn't testing you?
- What do you mean?
What if it isn't him
who's been dogging you?
I see.
You're reaching again.
If not the Devil then who?
A little elf?
Maybe all the birds, the stove and
the worms are just a coincidence?
Is that what you're telling people, Adam?
God.
- Pardon?
- God.
- I don't understand.
- What if God is on your case?
Why would he do that?
Because he hates you.
I've read this book. Book of Job.
- Yes.
- You've read it, right?
No. It's about a crocodile.
That's what I've heard.
Yes, it's about a crocodile,
but it's also about much more.
Remember God killed Job's cattle?
His seven camels and his ten kids?
He takes everything away from him
and makes him a leper.
Does that
remind you of anything?
I never had a camel.
Look at me.
Look at me, Ivan!
You know that God
is behind this, right?
God is not on your side, Ivan.
Yes, he is.
I don't believe any of this shit.
I just want you to know that it's God.
The Devil hasn't
wasted any time on you.
God wants to kill you.
You're just so dense
that you don't get it.
Why are you doing this to me?
Because I'm evil.
You can't change that.
There's fire in the sky.
- Is Ivan gone?
- Yeah.
He forgot his retarded kid.
For fuck's sake,
it was new!
Now go to bed hungry
every night.
He's done for. You could use him
for a paperweight. Have you had coffee?
- No. Is he going to...
- Die? You bet your ass he is.
Why do you think that the bloke began
bleeding from all orifices in his skull?
I give him four weeks, five tops.
From a medical point of view it doesn't
matter. He's come to his senses.
Somehow you've managed
to take away his faith.
- That's why I want to buy you coffee.
- It doesn't matter.
Well excuse me.
Are you ready?
Get up, Ivan,
we need the room.
Go with Adam.
Are you coming?
Call me
when he gets too weak.
We'll give him a room
and a shot of morphine.
God hates us, Christoffer.
He's always hated us.
He doesn't look too good.
Gather the others.
Well, the fact is...
Adam already knows but...
I'm dying.
- Die? What?
- Sleep with the worms.
- You can't stay?
- No, that would be difficult.
What are we to do?
Well, I hope that you...
I don't know.
I don't know what you should do.
I don't know anything anymore.
If I said anything that you
can use then do that or don't.
I don't care.
That's all.
- Where you're going?
- I feel like a drink. I've earned that.
- Gunnar...
- Leave me alone.
- You idiot!
- Gunnar, that's stupid.
There was a hair.
Here's one more.
We have three.
Ivan deserves a good pie.
What the fuck are you doing?
- I'm picking apples.
- With a Paki?
- What happened?
- Lightning.
What's wrong with you?
Are you fucking kidding us?
What did you say?
- You're climbing trees with a Nigger.
- Wait...
- Esben, just go home.
- He said go and take that fat friend with you.
Jaegen, let's teach our little
black friend some manners.
What the fuck are you doing?
I feel stressed.
He came with that psycho knee.
- He shot me.
- He's my witness. You were already shot.
- He shot me!
- I said sorry, fatso!
- Take him with you.
- You'll regret this.
And you, Nigger, you're dead.
- Are you stupid? I have a gun.
- You can't just shoot people.
He came with that shoulder.
Psycho shoulder. Oh, and there's his back.
Stop it!
I'm a bit off balance.
I don' like seeing Ivan like he is.
It's been a shitty day.
I want to leave this faggot country.
Khalid...
You have to talk to him.
He has problems.
Gunnar is also behaving strangely.
- Well, you know... They need you.
- Leave me alone.
Yes, but just have a talk with them.
They'll listen to you.
I'll put the apples in the fridge.
Do as you please.
Gunnar, what are you doing?
- Nothing.
- Where's Sarah?
- She's gone home.
- What's with all those things?
- It's just an eggplant...
- And the racket?
It's okay.
Everyone said that it was okay.
- Go on in.
- Not while you are here.
Can I see your room?
No.
- She got very drunk.
- What have you done?
Nothing yet.
She just got drunk.
- She wanted it.
- Put that stuff down.
It's her fault for getting that drunk.
Let's go to bed.
You come with me.
Go on.
- Wow, so many guns.
- Khalid, where are you going?
Statoil must burn.
- Wouldn't you rather stay here?
- No.
- You won't shoot anyone, right?
- Drop it. I don' want to shoot you.
You meddle
and I shoot you in the face.
- Can we go with you?
- You want to rob a station with me?
- Yes.
- Nice. But no smoking in the car.
Of course.
Get in.
I'll go in first.
I have to use the loo.
Okay, but no shooting anyone
before I come in.
Hat on, Gunnar.
Is there a back door?
Run! Get out of here!
Get out!
Run!
- Where are the clerks?
- They ran.
For fuck's sake!
- Are you done?
- Don't you want some cigarettes?
Stop it!
Let's go!
Are you hurt?
That went well.
You have to talk to Ivan.
You need help, both of you.
He also needs help.
Come on.
- Take off that hat.
- Yes.
- Hi. Where did you go last night?
- We were at the gas station.
- Was I very drunk?
- No, you were nice.
What are you doing?
Where are the other apples?
- We ate them.
- You ate seven apples?
- He was hungry. You only had beer.
- For fuck's sake!
You look good in that outfit.
Did we fool around yesterday?
The girlie boys are here again.
There are more this time.
- Go into the church.
- I won't hide from that bunch of faggots.
Look how many there are.
Go into the church.
You can go fuck yourself.
- We just want the Paki.
- Will you stop that with that noise!?
I really shouldn't have to come out here
and ask for some peace and quiet.
I have six,
maybe seven, days left to live.
I deserve a little nap time.
You people are so rude.
Please leave.
We just want the Paki and him.
Do what you want. You can take
them to the woods. I just want peace.
- Fuck you!
- How rude...
We'll do this another way.
Give me all your noisemakers.
What the fuck was he doing?
Asshole!
- I wasn't my fault.
- Let's get out of here.
In medical terms
this is called a Half-Kennedy.
He won't get over that.
I can assure you.
Well, you just say your goodbyes
and I'll stick the kettle on.
It's not nice to take the church car.
It's for the dead.
Shut up, Gunnar.
Goodbye to you all.
- You could stay. Ivan may return.
- Ivan is done.
I have to go home.
What about you, Adam?
I don't know.
You decide.
I'm going. I'm sorry about Ivan.
I'm sorry that you can't make a pie.
See you, Adam and Sarah.
Fuck you, Gunnar.
Well, okay.
- Go to your room.
- Don't get angry, but...
- Where is that from?
- Don't hurt me.
I took it by mistake. I'm sorry.
I'll never do it again.
- Enter.
- His bed is empty.
- Yes.
- Where is he?
It doesn't make sense. I'm a man
of science. I believe in figures.
He should have been
going to the afterlife,
and not to the garden to have a
cheeseburger after being shot.
- Is he in the garden?
- Yes.
He just got up
and went for a walk.
The bullet simply
shot the tumor away.
Now they're telling me that the bloke
is well again. I've bloody well had it.
Hi, Adam.
- I baked an apple pie.
- Yes.
Shall we try it?
- What's the name of the child?
- Ivan Lambert Andersen.
Ivan Lambert Andersen...
I baptize you in the name of the
Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Will you come back.
- There's no time.
- We're going to Indonesia.
- Interesting. Because of the tigers?
No, I plan to play tennis again.
They have the best courts.
It's because of junior.
With his Down's syndrome
he'll look just like the natives.
Yes, tigers are really fascinating.
You're always welcome.
- We have to go.
- Don't you have to change?
I'll do it in the car.
Come on, Gunnar.
Arne and Noller.
Ivan Fjeldsted. Call me Ivan.
Okay then. This is my assistant,
Adam Ole Pedersen.
We've been looking forward
to meeting you.
Well, let's go.
I'll take the bags.
What the fuck
is wrong with your eye?
- What do you mean?
- You look like a retard.
Really?
I think that's an awfully
rude way to break the ice.
We can go through town
and ask what they think of me.
This is not the place for that
discussion because you'll lose.
The eye is fine.
We'll discuss it in the car.
Good idea there.
Come on.
Subtitles by Korimokosan