[♪]
MAN:
Still the questions remain:
Was it economic,
was it social, or was it cultural?
Or was it simply human nature?
Why did some people do something
and others nothing at all?
Good job, Mr. Bowden.
It's nice to see a few more A's.
Including Mr. Bowden's, of course.
This concludes
our week on the Holocaust.
If you want to know more, you may
find the Santo Donate Library
to be an excellent resource.
[♪]
[AIR BRAKES HISSING]
[Bus DOOR CLOSES]
[BELL RINGING]
JOEY: Guess who likes you?
TODD: Who?
JOEY: Becky Trask.
You gonna ask her out?
You know who I'm talking about?
I know who she is.
I'll think about it.
No, you don't think. You just do it.
All right?
And could you give me your
trig notes from last year?
I knew this was leading to something.
I've got Fiscarelli.
I'll bring them in tomorrow.
All right? Cool. Ask Becky out.
I still gotta think about it.
What are you doing after school?
I'm busy.
[♪]
[RINGING DOORBELL]
[KNOCKING]
All right, I'm coming.
For God's sake.
Yes?
What do you want?
[SCOFFS]
If you're selling something
I'm not interested.
I have your newspaper.
I'm not selling anything.
Then what do you want?
If you could let me in for a minute,
I just want to talk.
Talk?
I don't have anything to say to you.
Good day.
Bergen-Belsen,
January '43-June '43.
Auschwitz, June '43-June '44.
Then you went to Patin.
[♪]
After that, you disappeared.
But then in 1965
you were spotted in West Berlin.
Listen, boy,
I don't have time for this game.
Now get out of here
before I call the police.
Call them if you want.
I'm sure they'd love to meet you.
Who are you?
My name is Todd Bowden.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I just really want to talk to you.
If you could let me in for a minute?
Please, Mr. Dussander.
All of this because you saw an old
man with a raincoat and an umbrella?
It wasn't that easy.
These pictures are 40 years old
at least.
But when I held them up next to
the ones I took, I knew I was close.
You took photographs of me?
Yeah, but even then I wasn't sure.
I needed real proof.
So I dusted your mail box
for fingerprints.
You know, that's a lot harder
than people think.
You need a lot of stuff.
Then I waited until
you were at the movies.
You put dust on my mail box
for fingerprints?
You took photographs of me.
What else did you do?
I already had a copy of your fingerprints
from your Israeli wanted sheet.
It's all on database
at UC Irvine.
[COUGHING]
Are you okay?
Would you care for a drink, boy?
How about milk?
Milk?
Have you told your parents all this?
JOEY:
Do you think I'm crazy?
It takes eight good matches
for a print to get accepted in court.
They're called "compares"
One or two is not so hard to find, but
eight good ones, that's really tough.
It all sounds very exciting, boy,
but I'm afraid
all your work has been for nothing.
I found 14 compares.
Boy, what you have done,
I have to explain this to you because
clearly you don't understand.
What you have done is a violation.
Like those experiments
with the decompression chamber?
Now that's a violation.
To hell with this and to hell with you.
I'm calling the police.
Your father's going to beat
your behind when he picks you up.
He doesn't believe in violence.
They should start. I'm calling.
My name is Denker.
Hmm. Arthur Denker.
[SIGHS]
I'm an American.
I became a citizen in 1955.
I vote.
You've no right to come here
and say these lies about me.
[♪]
I have your fingerprints.
I have your photographs.
One way or another,
I'll get them to the right people.
[SIGHS]
This is unbelievable.
What do you want? Tell me.
I want to hear about it.
Hear about what?
The stories. Everything.
What everything?
Everything they're afraid
to show us in school.
You were there.
You did those things.
No one can tell it better than you.
That's all I want.
Then I'll leave you alone.
And just so you know...
Everything I have on you,
the compares, the want sheet,
all the photographs
are all in a very safe place.
If anything happens to me,
someone will find it, believe me.
Tell me, boy,
why should I consider doing this?
Because you hung up the phone,
that's why.
[CHUCKLES]
Judging by the results
of your first exam,
for most of you, we moved
too fast through chapter one.
By a show of hands, how many of you
think you know what sociology is?
[CLASS CHUCKLING]
As I thought. All right, class,
let's turn to chapter two.
[CARLOS KLEIBER & BAYREUTH FESTIVAL
ORCHESTRA'S "TRISTAN UND ISOLDE" PLAYING]
TODD: Once they were in the
chamber, how long did it take?
A minute? Five?
No, the Prussic acid
took about 15 minutes.
But the monoxide could take an hour,
sometimes more.
What happened to them?
I mean, exactly?
It was a mess.
They would lose control
of their bodies.
They vomited, urinated
and defecated themselves.
Even though the gas
came through vents in the ceiling,
they climbed up on each other,
desperately reaching for fresh air
that wasn't there.
There died in a mountain
of themselves.
What about the children?
On the bottom.
Did anyone ever survive it?
One time,
the gas didn't work.
There was a leak in the pipes,
so oxygen mixed with the monoxide.
It was horrible.
But after an hour,
they were still moving.
Stumbling around the room
like drunks, their eyes glassy.
[♪]
What did you do?
I ordered more gas,
but we didn't know about the leak.
Soon they began to twitch all over,
like they were dancing.
Some even fell to their knees,
laughing this terrible
high-pitched scream.
Even the guards were frightened.
It didn't kill them.
After two hours,
I sent five men in with rifles.
It's getting dark.
Your mother will be worried.
Shit! I've got to go.
I can be here tomorrow by 3:15.
I wanna hear the end of this.
The end?
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
The end.
[♪]
[Does BARKING]
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[INDISTINCT WHISPERING]
[SCREAMS]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Todd, are you up?
Honey, let's go. Joey's outside.
TODD:
Tell him I'm coming, will you?
I thought you said
you were up half an hour ago.
Todd?
Yeah. I must have fallen back asleep.
Listen, honey, I'm gonna see
a client tonight at 7:00.
But I've got some cold chicken
in the fridge.
It's okay. I'm gonna eat
over at Mr. Denker's house.
And do what, watch TV?
I told you. He doesn't watch TV.
I read books to him. Don't worry about it.
Listen to me now. Invite him over here.
Daddy and I still want to meet him.
Okay?
DENKER: The policeman said: "Mr.
Denker, if you can't see the road,
you shouldn't be driving.
How many fingers am I holding up?
I said,
"Well now, officer, let me guess.
One?"
[ALL LAUGHING]
That was the end of my driving
in America. I take the bus.
Of course, I'm not driving much
either with this wheelchair,
but my sight
is not what it used to be.
Oh. That's a white-tailed buck.
Hmm. it's a remnant from our life
in Carolina.
Dick brought that down
in Yadkin River seven years ago.
Seven.
Your grandson never told me
he came from a family of hunters.
Todd never took a shine to guns.
No, he's good at other things.
Baseball is Todd's game.
Arthur, you sure I can't interest you
in a cigar?
No, thank you. If you don't mind,
I'll have one of my cigarettes.
Where are they?
Let me help you with that, Arthur.
My dear,
your generosity humbles me.
Thank you for the most
enchanting evening.
[MONICA CHUCKLES]
Arthur, I wonder if you'd mind
if I ask you a personal question.
Not at all.
What did you do during the war?
I was in the reserves,
as were most young men, Victor.
But my poor eyesight
kept me out of combat, thank God.
I spent most of the war
in the military hospital
washing bed linens
and nurses' uniforms.
Hmm.
You're been pretty quiet tonight, pal.
I'm sorry, it's just that I've heard
all these stories before.
Todd!
DUSSANDER:
Oh, that's quite all right, my dear.
The boy's just being honest.
It's a privilege of boys.
A privilege that men
must sometimes give up.
[CHUCKLES]
That reminds me...
[COUGHS]
It must have been my first year
at the university,
there was a group of about
three or four of us, and...
DUSSANDER: At first my men took turns
shooting them, but there were so many.
Two or three bodies
could be packed into each oven.
They were ground into fine ash.
A whole town was wiped
off the face of the earth.
[♪]
And still
it wasn't enough for Himmler.
It was a dark year.
He ordered every Jew in Kiev
to come to the Babi Jar ravine.
Remember, the 20's
were a desperate time in Germany.
The Treaty of Versailles
had left us crippled.
They would hide.
We always found them. If the dogs
didn't, smoke and fire would.
We would round them up
and march them out to a large pit.
At the time, the shooting was no longer killing.
Nothing would stop us.
Killing was no longer death.
I will never forget
the sound that night.
So many of them
on top of each other like that.
After a few hours,
they began to settle.
A head would fall.
An arm would drop.
It was a bit like the sound
of blowing leaves.
What did it feel like?
It's just something
that had to be done.
A door had been opened
and couldn't be shut. It was the end...
You don't understand.
MAN: You've done it a million times.
Let's go! Let's go!
[PLAYERS YELLING]
MAN:
All right, that's it. Hit the shower.
Where have you been?
What do you mean?
Well, if you're return
your phone calls,
you'd know that Damon's
having a party on Saturday night.
I've been busy.
Too busy for your best friend?
Look, I've been studying a lot, okay?
I'm sorry.
Are you going to go?
I don't even know
if I can get the car or not.
I know someone
who'll give you a ride.
Who? Oh.
BOY 1: I don't get it.
BOY 2: Well, did you talk to her?
BOY 1:
Yeah.
My dad wants me to get a tutor.
BOY 2:
Forget about her. I'll help you out.
BOY 1: I have to pass.
I can't goof around anymore.
BOY 2:
He's always so worried.
[BOYS TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
[♪]
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[INDISTINCT YELLING]
MAGOO [OVER TV]:
I've been accepted!
[♪]
The Ritzy Vista Country Club.
My life's ambition.
Officer, can you tell me
where to get to the bus
to the Ritzy Vista Country Club?
Ritzy Vista Country Club.
Here it is.
MAN: Where you going?
This is the bus to the country club,
isn't it?
Very humorous.
What do you want?
[TV CONTINUES PLAYING]
Hello?
MAGOO: Judge Stevens put me in.
TODD: Hello?
MAN: Okay. Sit down.
MAGOO:
Thank you.
[ENGINE STARTS OVER TV]
MAN:
This way, buddy.
MAGOO: My, what an impressive entrance.
Look at those big iron gates.
Wake up.
I'll kill you!
Oh.
I thought you were dead.
You look terrible.
It is Saturday.
Since when do you
come here on Saturdays?
I brought you something.
[WHIRRING OVER TV]
Aren't you going to open it?
Wait. Let me pull the shades down.
What for?
To be safe.
The hell with this. You open it.
Relax. Open it.
You wrapped it yourself, I see.
Merry Christmas.
Mary mother of God!
Where did you get this?
it's pretty real.
"E.F. Montgomery Costumes,
Tappan Zee, New Jersey."
Well, try it on.
Have you completely lost your mind?
What on earth makes you think
I would put that on?
I thought you would like it.
Like it?
You're a bigger fool than I thought.
Maybe I'll put it on and do a little
shopping. Is that what you thought?
The indignities I've suffered with you,
I should smash you.
What you've suffered
with me is nothing
compared to what the Israelis
would do to you.
You forget that.
And I'll admit that's my fault.
But don't ever forget the file
I have on you.
I tried to do things the nice way,
but you don't want to.
So we'll do it the hard way.
You'll put this on because
I want to see you in it. Now move!
I see I've been promoted.
Yeah, I know. it's all they had.
But that's a perfect fit.
Checked on one of your suit coats.
It itches like hell.
Quiet.
Put the hat on.
Please!
Please, put the hat on.
Attention.
[STOMPS]
What's so funny?
March.
Do it.
I'm serious.
Stop fucking around. March!
That's it. March.
Face right.
Face right!
March.
Face right.
Face right. March!
March!
[♪]
Okay, that's enough.
Stop.
Stop it!
Oh.
[PANTING]
Boy, be careful.
You play with fire.
[UPBEAT POP MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
Okay, I can tell you're not into this.
No, I am. Really.
It just takes me a while.
Right.
You know why I like you, Todd?
Because you're the only guy
that never tried to impress me.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
Do you ever wonder
why people do the things they do?
Think about it.
Okay. Heh.
Seriously.
Uh-uh. It's better not to think.
It's better to just do it.
Ah.
Who are you, kitty?
[CAT PURRS]
Oh.
It's getting cold out here, kitty.
Hmm?
Kitty.
TODD: I'm sorry.
We can try again later.
I don't know. That's never
really happened to me before.
It's all right.
Could you blow that
the other way, please.
Maybe you just don't like me.
No, it's not that at all.
I really do.
Maybe you just don't like girls.
[LAUGHS-ls]
[CAT MEOWING]
[GRUNTS]
Huh?
Kitty, kitty. Kitty, Kitty.
Goodbye.
[♪]
[CAT SCREECHING]
You motherfucker!
[MOANS]
[LAUGHS-ls]
[THUD]
[♪]
WOMAN:
Class, you have five more minutes.
[TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
JOEY:
"Dear Mr. and Mrs. Bowden.
I suggest we have a conference
about Todd's first-semester grades.
In light of his
previous outstanding work,
the deterioration of his grades
suggests a specific problem,
which should be addressed
before his academics is jeopardized.
I'm ready to work out a time for us
to meet. Earlier is usually better.
Sincerely yours, Edward French."
JOEY:
Jesus, man. What are you gonna do?
Fuck if I know.
What?
I said, "Fuck if I know."
[BALL SLAMS]
Hey, man, you're throwing it up hard.
Let it roll off your fingers more.
I don't need a lesson, okay?
All right.
Man, with your dad too.
I'm a fuck-up. My dad expects this
kind of crap from me, but you?
Ooh.
[MUTTERING]
You're talking to yourself, Bowden.
What's going on with you?
Nothing. I fucked up. I'll fix it.
Whatever you say.
What's happening
with you and Becky?
Who?
Heh. Becky Trask, idiot.
What did you call me?
You're being a real dick, man.
I've got to get to practice.
[BALL DRIBBLING]
"Talking to yourself'?"
"You're being a dick."
[Coos]
[WINGS FLUTTERING]
[♪]
[THUD]
DUSSANDER: "--time for us to meet.
In such a case as this,
earlier is usually better.
Sincerely yours, Edward French."
Who is this Edward French?
Headmaster?
No, he's a guidance counselor.
What is that?
He guides and he counsels.
You read the letter.
What stinks in here?
I bet it's my TV dinner, I'm afraid.
TODD: We've got a real
problem here, you know that?
We? I'm not the one in trouble.
We'll see about that.
Don't turn this on me. It's not
my fault your grades have fallen.
That's where you're wrong.
The shit you're telling me keeps me up all night.
I fall asleep during class.
I need a fucking pencil.
Do you have one?
What will your parents do?
They're never gonna see it.
That's the whole point of this.
This isn't just a little slip-up here.
My parents will freak.
They'll wanna know what happened.
And what happened is you.
Do you get what I'm telling you?
I think so.
You'd better be sure.
It's your sorry ass that winds up
in jail, not mine. I need a pencil.
A sharp one, please.
Thank you.
Tell me, does this Edward French
know your parents in a social way?
No, my parents wouldn't mix
with a geek like him.
How about professionally?
Has he ever spoken to them?
No, I've never needed it till now.
You're messing things up
with that carbon paper.
What do you know about it?
Here, out of the way.
I was forging documents
before your parents were born.
[PAPER CRINKLING]
[BELL TOLLING]
Hey.
Hi.
Todd, Mr. French will see you now.
Do you know what this is about?
I'm sorry, I don't.
See you later.
MAN: That's my son, he's
always chewing gum.
He means the world to me.
Hey, Todd, have a seat.
Hello there.
It's okay, sit down.
We're just talking
about what's been going on.
Do you want to talk about it?
Not really.
This is nothing
to be embarrassed about.
It's not your fault. We both want
to help you get back on track.
Both of you?
I must admit that the situation
in Richard's home is appalling.
I was raised to believe that the man
should take responsibility for his family.
But when you came to me in tears
and asked me to intervene
then I realized this was not
a matter to be trifled with.
That's why I arranged this meeting.
We all appreciate your concern.
Todd, I've been looking
at your record,
and according to your progress
report, every grade is way down.
Even your strongest subject, history,
went from a solid A to C-.
Trigonometry down to a D.
Todd, did you know you were on your
way to finishing first in your class?
Yes.
Your grandfather and I have
been talking and we both agree,
that what's going on,
with your father's work problems
and your mom with the drinking,
that maybe home
isn't the best place to be studying.
So he's offered to let you study over
at his place every day after school.
I think it's a good idea.
You do?
Yeah.
In fact,
I offered to go a step further.
But it means
we have to make a deal.
What kind of deal?
Finals for this quarter
are in three and a half weeks.
If you can give me all A's,
then I'll talk to your teachers,
and see if we can't discount
your midterms,
and let this quarter's grades
rest with your final exams.
If you come back with B's or C's,
I can't help you.
But all A's, that shows everybody
that you're serious.
You can do that?
Yeah.
But first you've got to start
being honest with me.
No more forging
your father's signature.
No more hiding my letters.
For now, we can deal
with just the three of us,
if it makes things easier at home.
But you try and pull one over on me,
next time I show up at your door.
Is that clear?
He's offering to help.
I know.
But that's a whole lot to do
in three weeks.
What if I can't do it?
Mr. Bowden, I can't thank you
enough for coming down here today.
But if it's all right with you, I'd like to
talk to Todd alone for a few minutes.
It's quite all right.
If you didn't excuse me, I'm afraid
that my desire for a cigarette would.
[WHEEZING]
You can take my word.
When the time is right,
I'll tell Richard about all this.
He and Monica need to know
what's happening to their son.
I'll expect you after school.
Mm-hm.
He's a very persuasive man.
Tell me about it.
Listen, Todd, I understand what
you're going through. I really do.
My wife and I just went through
the nastiest divorce since Henry VIII.
And I know it's not easy
being a senior and only 16.
And now we're asking a lot of you.
But your grandfather thinks you can do this.
Todd, I know you can.
So from now on, I don't want you
to feel like you have no one to talk to.
Okay? Your parents,
or girl problems...
Anything at all,
here's my home phone.
Anything at all, anything,
you call me, Todd.
Call me.
Deal?
I'm telling you, buddy, you get past
this little hurdle,
I promise you, the world's going to
open up for you like you won't believe.
Okay.
Bye.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[DOOR OPENS]
Have you lost your mind? What the
hell were you thinking, Grandpa?
What are you so excited about?
You've got some fucking balls!
I could've screwed you up.
Anything could have happened!
You played it beautifully.
I knew you would.
Are you fucking drunk?
I could've busted you right there.
Yes, you could have, but you did not.
Now why was that?
Your Edward French is not
going to give you any more trouble.
So now you are upset because the
only way you can make things right
is to work.
I'm upset because you had him thinking
I can do something that can't be done.
But it can and it will. You simply
have to work. No more stories.
No more screwing around.
I don't take orders from you.
You do now.
Oh, you think so?
Don't forget. I can walk in there
and pick up the phone.
And do what?
Did you really think
that I would stand aside
and let you turn me in without
dragging you with me? Do you?
Your American self-confidence is so
bloated you've lost touch with reality.
90,000 died in Patin.
To the whole world I am a monster.
And you have known about me
all this time.
If I am caught, when the reporters
stick their microphones in my face,
it will be your name that I will repeat
over and over again. Todd Bowden.
Todd Bowden.
Yes, that was his name.
For how long?
For months, almost a year.
He wanted to know everything.
That was how he put it.
Yes. Everything.
You're crazy.
They'll never believe you.
It doesn't matter.
You're going to be infamous, boy.
Take my word for it.
Do you know what such a scandal
can do? It never goes away.
Not for you. Not for your parents.
And besides, lying to judges and
reporters isn't as easy as you think.
You'd have to be brilliant.
Can you do that? I know I can.
There's no way in hell I can pull out
of a half year slide in a few weeks.
That shit just doesn't happen.
Boy, the time for discussion is over.
You are going to work.
You're going to spend the rest of this
quarter and all your vacation studying.
[♪]
[RATTLING]
[DOGS BARKING IN DISTANCE]
[BOTTLES CLINKING]
[CLATTERING]
[TV PLAYING]
[CHUCKLING]
[MEOWS]
[LAUGHING]
[TV SHOW PLAYING
AND LAUGHTER CONTINUE]
[♪]
WOMAN 1: Hawthorne was one of the most
interesting writers of his time ,
[MAN 1 SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
WOMAN 2:
--longitude and latitude.
MAN 2:
--by K leaving you with--
MAN 3: In this study, how 22 of
them influenced behavioral--
[VOICES OVERLAPPING]
MAN 4: Why did some people do
something and others nothing at all?
This concludes our week
on the Holocaust.
If you want to know more, you may
find the Santo Donate Library...
DUSSANDER:
You are a monster.
Ls this clear enough for you?
What you have done is a violation.
TODD:
I wanted to know more.
[VOICES OVERLAPPING]
DUSSANDER:
A door had been opened...
[VOICE OVERLAPPING]
TODD:
I fucked up.
DUSSANDER:
You'd have to be brilliant.
Lying isn't as easy as you think.
[VOICES OVERLAPPING]
DUSSANDER:
Boy, be careful. You play with fire.
[GIRL SCREAMS]
[THUD]
[♪]
DUSSANDER:
it never goes away.
Not for you.
[DUSSANDER LAUGHING]
Mm-mm.
[LAUGHS-ls]
Ha-ha!
[COUGHING]
How about some melba toast?
Sure.
Good.
[HUMMING]
I would have expected you to be
doing backflips down the hallway
after such good news.
[CHUCKLES]
But you're so quiet.
Today I think I will give you
the day off from studying.
How's that?
[LAUGHS-ls]
How about
one of my stories instead?
I still have a few good ones left.
I don't care.
Let's see. I could tell you
about the special soap we made.
There's always the story
of how I escaped from Berlin
after I was so foolish
as to go back.
That was a close one.
I can tell you...
No, none of these. I think
you don't seem to be in the mood.
I think today,
I will tell you the story
of an old man who was afraid.
He was afraid
of a certain young boy
who was, in a queer way,
his friend.
The boy proved
to be a very good student.
But not perhaps in quite the way
his mother and his teachers
had envisioned.
[CHUCKLES]
At first, the old man
disliked the boy intensely.
But then he began to enjoy
the boy's company.
Of course, there is still a great deal
of distrust between them.
Each knew something
the other wanted to keep secret.
Over time, the old man felt
his hold on the boy slipping away.
He thought the day might come
when the boy no longer needed him.
So one sleepless night,
the old man got out of bed,
and wrote down the story
of his involvement with the boy.
Everything he could remember.
From the first day forward.
He wrote how the boy forced his way
into the old man's house.
And blackmailed the old man
to serve his own morbid fascinations.
When the boy's grades
began to fall,
he blamed the old man and ordered
him to impersonate his grandfather.
At the end, his hands
were stinging with arthritis,
but he felt happy
for the first time in weeks.
He felt safe.
The following morning,
the old man put on his best suit.
And went down
to one of the local banks
and rented a safe-deposit box.
[♪]
The bank officer explained
to the old man
that only the old man
could use the old man's key,
with one exception:
The exception was in the event
of the box-holder's death.
Then what?
The box would be open
in the presence of a bank official
and a representative
of the Internal Revenue Service.
And the contents of the box
would be inventoried.
But in this case, they would
only find a 12-page document.
Non-taxable, but highly interesting.
You didn't do this.
I don't believe you.
My boy, it is already done.
Look at you!
You could go at any time.
Don't be so theatrical.
A man five years older than me
worries more about his failing heart
than being sent off to Israel.
And the day will come,
if I live long enough,
when I decide that what you know
no longer matters.
Then and only then,
I will destroy the document.
So many things can happen.
Accidents, sickness.
You could slip in the shower!
♪ Que sera sera ♪
J' Whatever will be will be J'
I The future 's not ours to see I
♪ Que sera sera ♪♪
I can see you're thinking it now.
Even now.
It's in your eyes. Killing me.
[♪]
All it would take
is the flick of a knife. Tsk.
Push me down the steps.
Make it look like an accident.
I'm old. You are strong and angry.
Good assets for killing,
but there is something missing.
To have someone in your control.
To have them know
that they are alive
all because you have not decided
to the contrary.
Do you have that power?
Ask yourself.
It's not an easy question.
I think you know that.
You know this means we're through,
don't you?
You won't be seeing me
around here anymore.
I suppose I won't.
What are you doing?
This is the end.
Here.
Drink. To our lives together.
The beginning and the end.
[GLASSES CLINK]
I think you should fuck yourself.
Oh, my dear boy,
don't you see?
We are fucking each other.
MAN:
A strike!
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
Two outs.
[CROWD CHATTERING
AND CHEERING]
[LIANE & THE BOHEME BAR TRIO'S
"DAS IST BERLIN" PLAYING]
[CHEERS AND APPLAUSE]
MAN: What are you guys waiting for?
Let's go!
Come on, rebound the ball.
Move it!
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[AUDIENCE LAUGHING]
[MOVIE PLAYING]
[MAN LAUGHING]
Watch your step.
Sir?
Excuse me.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
I could help you carry those.
You don't gotta be afraid.
I could help you.
I don't need your help.
I'm not a bad guy.
You don't have to worry.
Please, I just want--
Whet? Why do you bother me?
We're practically neighbors.
I stay right over there most nights.
I see you walk down the street.
I just want to help.
It's called being neighborly.
Piss off.
You don't-- You don't--
There's no reason to be rude.
I know something about you.
I know you're a nice guy.
I'm nice too. Just like the boy.
I see.
I'm not ashamed to say that I
could use a drink about now. Oh.
But I don't take no charity.
If you were to invite me in
like a friend, we could have a drink.
A drink?
That's what I'm saying.
You smell like a toilet.
Maybe you'll let me
use your shower.
But first a drink.
Then I will do anything you say.
[♪]
[MUNCH & BOSTON SYMPHONY ORCHESTRA'S
"LIEBESTOD FROM TRISTAN UND ISOLDE" PLAYING]
I had him hooked up, rolling,
four and a half, three minutes.
That was my best time.
I didn't see that dog
in the back seat.
Hmm?
Didn't see it.
What dog?
That dog. I heard it barking.
I hear dogs barking all the time,
even when they ain't there.
So I didn't pay no mind.
So the DOT didn't want to hire me
because of that thing with the--
Anyway...
Who wants to talk about that?
So I was an independent.
It meant that I could go all over.
The whole city.
I believe
we need another bottle.
Oh.
If you're offering
I will accept.
It's no trouble at all.
Why don't you take mine?
Thank you.
[DOOR OPENS]
So like I was saying,
I worked as an independent.
The DOT, they wouldn't hire me.
So I was able
to go all over the whole city.
Midtown, downtown--
Where is my bottle opener?
Ah, there it is.
You stay right there.
So then I moved on.
Washington Heights was always good.
[ARCHIE TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
The Dominicans there, they like to...
Then they dropped that cinder block
on that cop and it got all crazy.
But you've got to be moving
because they come back,
they catch you hooking their ride.
[GROANS]
Do you mind?
No, not at all.
You know,
maybe in the morning,
after everything goes okay,
you could let me have $10.
Yeah, perhaps.
Maybe even 20.
Perhaps, we shall see.
You can relax. I've done this before.
That's all right.
So have I.
Let me go pee first.
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMING]
[CLATTERING]
[GROANING]
Did you look at this
before you signed it?
That bill was written in Japanese.
Numbers are numbers
in any language.
Well, that man did not speak
one word of English.
[PHONE RINGING]
The point is,
you look before paying a bill.
I didn't understand what he said.
That's exactly the point.
Hello? Yes.
Maybe it was in yen.
MONICA: Sure.
Maybe it is.
Todd, it's Mr. Denker.
He sounds very anxious.
MONICA:
Why would he be calling now?
Hello.
DUSSANDER [OVER PHONE]:
Come over right away, boy.
I'm having a heart attack. A bad one.
[♪]
That sounds exciting, Mr. Denker,
but I have to study my trig.
I understand you cannot talk
but you can listen.
I cannot call an ambulance.
I need help.
And that means you need help.
If you put it that way.
Tell your parents I have a letter.
And I need you to read it to me.
Sure, I'll be right over.
[LINE CLICKS]
Now we'll see what you're made of.
[DUSSANDER GROANING]
What happened?
Ah, boy.
Where are you bleeding?
It's not my blood.
It was self-defense.
Boy, now listen.
What are you talking about?
Shut up!
Nobody comes here until you
have done what needs to be done.
Go down the steps.
[MOANS]
What did you do?
Go down the steps.
That's right.
[LOCK CLICKING]
Hey!
Let me the fuck out of here.
If you won't help me,
I have to make you.
That's enough! That's enough!
That's enough!
[BOTH YELLING]
Fuck you!
If you're going to behave
like a fucking schoolgirl...
[GROANING]
I'm going to break
your goddamn door down!
Fuck!
Don't be afraid, boy.
Now what are you doing?
I'll break the goddamn door down.
What are you doing?
[CLATTERING]
There is no point.
[GRUNTS]
[GASPS]
[GROANING]
[CLATTERING]
[SCREAMS]
[GROANING]
ARCHIE:
Why are you doing this?
OW! Ah!
[GRUNTING]
[MOANING]
[EXHALES]
[THUD]
[♪]
[RAIN PATTERING]
[DUSSANDER MOANS]
DUSSANDER:
Call an ambulance.
The key.
The key of the safe-deposit box,
where is it?
Boy, I need a doctor.
Now.
Give me the key.
I'm dying.
I know.
Oh, no. Not like this. Please.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
DICK:
You did good, son.
You did real good.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
[SIGHS]
It's a good thing you called
us when you did. You saved his life.
Dad, come on, let's go make sure
he gets checked-in all right.
[♪]
[MONITOR BEEPING]
You shouldn't have.
It's from my mother.
They say the operation
was a success.
They say I have another 20 years.
A new lease on life.
I took care of everything.
Except for the key. Where is it?
There's no safe-deposit box.
There never was.
I lied.
I had to protect myself from you.
You understand?
I suspect that we will never
see each other again.
No.
Wait.
I want to ask you something.
What?
What did it feel like?
[♪]
I better go.
Wait.
Perhaps I could
persuade you to stay.
Just until I fall asleep.
My medicine makes me drowsy.
Please?
[THUMP]
Excuse me, young man.
You are a very good boy
to visit your grandfather like that.
Thank you, but he's just a friend.
Then you are a very good friend.
Tell me.
Is he very bad off?
He doesn't talk much.
The doctors say he'll be out soon.
That's good news.
From his accent,
I would guess he was German.
From the south, I think.
I don't know.
I wonder if he was in the war?
I don't think so.
He's never mentioned it anyway.
It doesn't matter, I suppose.
It was a long time ago, the war.
Soon, in this country,
we will have a President
born after the war was over.
How about that?
I'm sure you're right.
He's so very lucky to have you.
A great man once said:
"No man is an island,
entire of itself."
John Donne.
Ha-ha-ha.
Have a nice evening, sir.
Goodbye.
I don't have to listen to that talk.
How about this kind of talk?
[LAUGHTER OVER TV]
That's just a warning.
MAN 1 [OVER TV]: if you crave for
Florence 's food, that's a weird craving.
MAN 2:
Jenny's the one who's pregnant.
They said they had something
to tell us.
We 're going to be
grandparents again.
I just can't wait to tell everybody.
[♪]
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHTER
OVER TV]
[MONITOR BEEPING]
[♪]
What's wrong? What's wrong?
[SOBBING]
What's wrong?
[MAN SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
[DUSSANDER
SPEAKING IN GERMAN]
Yes.
I'm speaking to you.
Mr. Kramer
is recuperating elsewhere.
Are you awake now, Dussander?
Yes, of course.
But you seem to have confused me
with someone else.
My name is Denker.
Perhaps you have the wrong room.
My name is Weiskopf,
and you are Kurt Dussander.
No, I know no one by that name.
Should I call the nurse?
The man in the next bed
was Benjamin Kramer.
He was imprisoned
for 10 months at Patin.
You were responsible for the death
of his wife and two daughters.
My name is Arthur Denker.
I am an American.
Don't bother. Your papers won't
stand up to serious examination.
RICHLER:
We have all we need here.
Who is this man?
I'm Dan Richler, FBI.
This is Detective Getty, LAPD.
You know who I work for.
When you're strong enough you will be moved.
Until then, this entire ward
will be under guard.
You can expect to be in Jerusalem
by the end of the summer.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[BELL TOLLING]
Where do you want us to sit?
Anywhere but the front row.
DICK: There's Carla.
MONICA: Carla! How are you?
Hi, Chelsea.
Hi. Congratulations.
It's a big day for everybody.
[CHATTERING]
Hey, Todd.
Mr. French.
You did it, buddy. I knew you could.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
Oh, hi. These must be your parents.
Ed French.
Dick Bowden.
Nice to meet you.
Your son really pulled one off.
You must be very proud.
MONICA: Yes, we are.
This is my wife, Monica.
Are you a teacher of Todd's?
Actually, I'm his guidance counselor.
Oh.
MONICA: Nice to meet you.
I was looking forward to seeing
your grandfather. Where is he?
It's a long trip from Charlotte.
He's been in a wheelchair for years.
They don't get out here much.
Usually Thanksgiving.
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
[BELL RINGING]
Oh.
That's your cue.
That's my cue.
Okay. Good luck up there.
Nice to meet you.
MONICA: Nice to meet you.
DICK:
Take care, Ed.
I don't feel so well. Maybe after the
ceremony we could go straight home?
DICK:
Are you okay? What's the matter?
MONICA:
You know what? it's probably nerves.
Just take a deep breath.
TODD: Let's see how it goes.
TODD: All great achievements
arose from dissatisfaction.
[♪]
It is the desire to do better,
to dig deeper,
that propels a civilization
to greatness.
All of us
have heard the story of Icarus.
The young boy who took the wings
his father built for him.
Wings that were meant to carry him
over the ocean to freedom.
And used them instead
for a joyride.
For a brief moment Icarus felt
what it was like to live as a god.
To touch the sun.
To soar above the common man.
And for doing so
he paid the ultimate price.
You boys better come down to the
cellar. You're not gonna believe this.
Like Icarus,
we too have been given gifts:
Knowledge, education, experience.
And with these gifts
comes the responsibility of choice.
We alone decide how our talents
are bestowed upon the world.
This is our destiny, and we hold it
in the palm of our hands.
[APPLAUSE]
[CROWD CHEERING]
MAN [OVER TV]: --an investigation by local
police, the sheriff's department, FBI,
and the Department of Justice.
Police have confirmed that a body
has been found
in the basement of Arthur Denker.
The Santo Donate resident
believed to be a Nazi war criminal.
The cause of death
has not been revealed.
Authorities are withholding
identification of the body
until more information
is available.
The apprehension of Dussander
brings to a close a manhunt
that's been underway
for 40 years in three continents.
[ALL YELLING]
I'll be taking care of you from now on.
Just try to relax.
Todd, I'm Dan Richler of the FBI,
and this is Dr. Weiskopf.
I'd like to hear about
your involvement with Dussander.
Actually, you knew him
as Arthur Denker.
Yes.
How did you know him?
Do you feel up to this?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
[♪]
RICHLER: Let me tell you what
we're interested in here.
You said Denker had a heart attack
while you were reading him a letter.
Yes.
Was it in English or German?
German.
[SIGHS]
You speak German?
No.
So you had no idea
what you were reading?
No, but he seemed to understand
every word I was saying.
[♪]
What we can't seem to figure out
is the letter, Todd.
Do you have any idea
what happened to it?
I guess it's still on the table.
I couldn't swear to it though.
Then it should still be there.
It isn't.
RICHLER: No. When you arrived, Mr.
Bowden, did you see it?
Uh-- No, but I wasn't looking for a letter.
I was concerned about Todd.
Maybe someone broke in
and took it.
Why would somebody break
into a house to steal a letter?
Unless, of course,
they wanted to protect him.
A close friend. Another fugitive.
I know all this sounds
like Robert Ludlum kind of stuff,
but while Dussander
was in the hospital,
our Mr. X scooted over to the house
and swiped the letter.
That doesn't make sense.
Why not?
If he had an old Nazi buddy in town,
why didn't he read the letter?
Maybe he's in a wheelchair
or maybe he's blind.
Guys that are blind don't normally
go scooting out to steal letters.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Did he ever talk about his past?
No.
Excuse me, Dr. Weiskopf, I'm just
curious, what kind of doctor are you?
I'm a school teacher.
RICHLER: Dr. Weiskopf is a professor
at the Judaic Institute in Munich.
He assists the Israeli Government
in certain matters.
[MONITOR BEEPING STEADILY]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[KNOCK ON DOOR]
Hey, buddy, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
I just can't believe it.
Even after what those guys told me.
It's mind boggling.
Your mother and I feel terrible
about this. Like we let you down.
It's not your fault.
We're going to talk to a lawyer.
He's very good.
It's nothing to worry about.
I just don't trust these cops.
Okay.
I think that's a good idea.
Your old man's on top of this.
All right? I'll take care of this.
I know.
Dad.
Yeah?
I really never knew
anything about this.
I never thought you did.
I know.
See you later.
Are you going to talk
to the boy again?
I don't think so.
Somehow he didn't even... Oh.
When you were a boy,
what did you do for fun?
I went to the movies.
Why? What did you do?
I used to chase girls.
[BOTH CHUCKLING]
And now I chase old men.
[♪]
[CROWD YELLING]
Special Agent Richler,
Dr. Weiskopf,
this is the hospital administrator
and his chief of staff.
How do you do?
So do we have a plan?
They've arranged an exit for us.
[♪]
Mr. French.
Hello, Todd.
What are you doing here?
I came by to see your parents.
Are they home?
No. What about?
That's between me and them.
Why isn't it between you and me?
Wanna tell me what happened?
[♪]
[ALL YELLING]
[CROWD CHANTING]
[GAGS]
[GASPING]
[FLATLINING]
[STAFF CHATTERING]
[WOMAN ANNOUNCING OVER PA]
He needs to be turned
on his left side.
Get him over. Get him over.
I wouldn't know where to begin.
You're gonna have to tell me
something, Todd.
I can tell you that it'd be better
if we both just forgot about that.
I'm sorry, I can't do that.
[♪]
[STAFF TALKING INDISTINCTLY]
Can you hear me, sir?
Get the crash cart right now!
Tell your parents
I'll be back to see them later.
Mr. French.
What?
I thought we had a deal here.
"Pull up your grades and the world
will open up for you."
You want me to forget about this?
I just wanna go to college
and get on with my life.
Todd, okay, we're not gonna talk
about this right now.
It was a mistake to come here.
I'll do this over the phone.
Clear the way. Move it!
Can I ask you something, Ed? You
don't mind if I call you Ed, do you?
Now that I'm out
of your fucking school?
[♪]
Does it ever work?
What?
I really wanna know.
Or am I the first one?
If I'm the first, I'm flattered,
but somehow I can't believe that.
Not after you fixing my grades.
Giving me your home phone number.
Coming out here
when my parents aren't home.
What are you talking about?
You've got some balls!
Is this why your wife left you?
[MONITOR BEEPING
ERRATICALLY]
[STAFF SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
You must really have wanted
to shake my hand or something else.
Now wait a minute. Are you going
to tell people I did something to you?
I don't wanna drag you down with me.
But I will.
I'm better at this than you are.
Better at what?
I'm trying to help you.
Can't you see that?
You've helped enough.
I won't just do nothing.
You're going to fucking have to!
WOMAN: Still flatline.
MAN: Clear!
The things I'm going to say,
they'll never go away.
Not for you.
Think of your job.
[♪]
Ha. Think of your son.
MAN:
And clear.
So what's the story here, Ed?
[BALL DRIBBLING]
Do we have a deal?
You can't do this, Todd.
You have no idea what I can do.
[CONTINUOUS TONE]
[♪]
[STARTS ENGINE]
[DRIBBLING]
[LIANE & THE BOHEME BAR TRIO'S
"DAS IST BERLIN" PLAYING]
[♪]