(Man ) Did you hear that?
(2nd man ) Come on.
(Loudspeaker) Freeze! This is
the police! Drop your weapons!
(Gunshots )
(Moans )
(TV) 'And in local news,
'six gang members were killed in
a shoot-out last night with police.
'Police Commissioner Davidson
called a news conference this morning
'to comment on the shootings.'
(Davidson ) 'I have called
this emergency news conference
'because the juvenile gang problem
is out of control.
'The missing automatic weapons
have not been recovered.
'A lead shows that some weapons
have fallen into the wrong hands.
'Law enforcement is being driven
to horrible extremes,
'but those guns are out there,
'and believe me, if the people
who have them get organised
'no one will stand a chance.'
(Reporter) 'Commissioner Davidson...'
(TV clicks off)
Para los seis.
Cholo.
For the six.
This is Lieutenant Bishop in unmarked
vehicle requesting assignment.
Is Staff Seven there?
(Radio ) 'Stand by.'
(Radio ) 'One-W-20,
if I look around real hard
'maybe I can find something
for you to do.'
Hey, Captain Collins, hello there.
I'm surprised
to hear your voice, sir.
'W-20, so how's it going so far,
Lieutenant?
One-W-90, OK,
being as I've been on the job
exactly...four minutes.
'W-20, I've got a temporary
reassignment for you tonight,
'a supervisory job for the police.
'Proceed to Precinct Nine,
division 13
'and take over from Captain Gordon.'
Isn't that the Anderson precinct?
'Affirmative.'
But they're closing it down.
Nothing for me to do there
except stare at the packing crates.
'Wanna be a hero
on your first night?'
Yes, sir!
'There are no heroes any more,
Bishop, only men who follow orders.'
W-90, yes, sir. Proceeding
to Precinct Nine, division 13.
'KMA-492.'
Starker?
This way.
They sure gave you some sweet job.
Better than some.
Carrying a busload of hate is not
my idea of better than anything.
(Coughs )
This is Wells and Cornell.
- Is he all right?
- He's just got a little cold.
- Where's Wilson?
- We got him in a special room.
This is Napoleon Wilson.
Got a smoke?
Close the door.
I want you to know something, Wilson.
I don't enjoy
driving anybody to Death Row,
but try anything - anything -
I've got two guards with shotguns
that'll blow you apart.
Sure could use a smoke.
You understand me, Wilson?
You mumble a little bit...
I get the general idea.
Let's go.
Slipped right out of the chair.
Yeah, I don't sit in chairs
as well as I used to.
Get him up.
All right, let's go.
I'm all jealous of you, Wilson.
You get this VIP treatment.
They let me walk around almost free.
- Hey.
- What?
- You got a smoke?
- Yeah, but I'm not giving it to you.
- Why not?
- Smoking can kill you.
You don't like competition, huh?
You think you're real fancy,
don't you?
I have moments.
Knock off the talking. Let's move.
(Coughing)
OK if I...stretch a minute?
You're gonna chain me to a seat
and drive for hours,
then you're gonna chain me in a cell,
maybe for 90 years.
Chains is all I got
to look forward to.
Go ahead.
You know, Wilson, I'm gonna miss you.
That's not the truth, Warden.
Now, you should always
tell the truth.
Even a little white lie
can sometimes trip a man up.
Oh!
He don't stand up
as good as he used to.
(Radio ) 'But sunspotting
caused an...'
'..the shooting of six youths
'now known to be members of a Los
Angeles gang known as Street Thunder.
'Davidson also commented
'on the unusual interracial mixture
of the gang victims and...'
(Turns radio off)
Let's go over this again,
what are you gonna tell Margaret?
I forget.
You say, "Margaret, I want you
to live with us now Fred is gone."
I want you to come
and live with us now Fred is dead.
- Gone.
"We have a big spare room
all ready for you."
We have a big spare room
all ready for you.
"And I told my daddy
if you don't come and live with us
"I'm going to run away from home."
She'll never buy that.
- OK, drop that one.
- Daddy?
- Yeah?
- I'm hungry.
You'd rather eat than get your nanny
out of this...horrible neighbourhood?
I'd know what to say even better
if I had something to eat.
Where is that street?
I can never seem to find that street.
(Girl) Why don't we ask them?
Uh...Bonair Place, I think
it's just a couple of blocks more.
Mr Seward
says policemen answer questions
and help when you're in trouble.
Obviously, Mr Seward has never taken
any steps outside of the sixth grade.
Huh?
We're not in any trouble, honey.
(Revs engine )
Yeah?
Uh, I'm Lieutenant Bishop.
Yes, sir. One moment,
I'll tell the captain you're here.
(Knocks )
Hello, Lieutenant.
Hi.
- I'm Leigh.
- Ethan Bishop.
(Leigh) This is Julie.
- Hello, Julie.
- Hello.
- Things are quiet.
- For a change.
You took over at the right time.
Apparently.
When are you moving?
They shut off the phones and
electricity at 10am tomorrow.
Sounds pretty final.
- Would you like some coffee?
- Thank you.
- I'll get you one.
- Thanks.
(Julie ) Hello, 7814?
No, the precinct has been relocated.
Let me give you the new number.
Seven-three-four-three-six-one-two.
You're welcome.
Phone company should be doing this.
They were due at five.
(Julie ) Hello, may I speak
to supervisor 12, please?
Black?
For over 30 years.
I'm sorry.
Two sugars.
I grew up...four blocks from here.
When I was four my father
sent me in here with a note.
Detective read it and said, "We lock
up little boys who can't behave."
When he called my father I carved
something on his desk with a knife.
For months I was afraid
he might come after me.
Why did your father send you in here?
For using foul language
in the presence of my mother.
What did you carve on the desk?
Advanced for a little kid.
Your father obviously got you
out of Anderson early enough.
The captain would like to see you.
Be right there.
By the way,
no one took me
out of Anderson when I was a baby.
I walked out myself when I was 20.
- Enjoy your new police station.
- I will.
Thanks for the coffee.
(Man ) Then get 'em out!
Double your patrols.
Send 'em up there.
Don't call here
every time a division stubs its toe!
What a night!
We've had a 3-12 every 15 minutes.
12 stolen cars, three burglaries,
eight aggravated assaults,
and it's not even eight o'clock.
Could be the sun spots.
Pressure on the atmosphere.
I heard it on the radio.
It's seven o'clock,
I'm going to the new station.
You take over here
till Weaver comes in at four.
All you do is answer the telephone
and send over any strays.
Maybe some still think
this is a police station.
Are there any facilities left here?
Couple of cells and a bathroom.
Why is this place still open?
Well, it is and it isn't, Lieutenant.
The result of transition.
I think someone in central office
wanted to give you something special
for your first night out.
That sure got around fast.
(Sighs )
(Ice cream van chimes )
(Chiming continues )
(Tyres screech)
(Coughing)
I'm going to talk to Wilson.
Watch me.
Don't mind if I sit down,
do you, Wilson?
- Got a smoke?
- You asked me before.
I never got a definite answer.
I don't smoke.
That's a definite answer.
Another one gone.
When you're in my position
days are like women.
Each one is so goddam precious...
and they always end up leaving you.
What do you want?
- Do I have to want something?
- You're a cop.
You're either curious about me
or you want to give me some shit.
I don't understand you, Wilson.
Curious.
You're not a psychopath,
you're not stupid...
I am an asshole.
Can't take everything away from me.
Why did you kill those men?
Everybody asks me the same question.
I always tell 'em the same thing.
First time
I ever saw a preacher he said,
"Son, there's something
strange about you.
"You got something to do with death."
Being real young, I believed him.
Turned out he was right.
That's no answer.
I thought it was pretty good.
Where'd you get a name like Napoleon?
- I'll tell you some time.
- When?
The moment of dying.
I'll do my best to be there
when your time comes.
(Coughing violently)
Hey!
He's really sick.
The warden said it was only a cold.
The man is sick.
- How long till we get to Senora?
- Another six hours.
We gotta stop.
What's the closest precinct?
Anderson.
(Ice cream van chimes )
Desconco to Pinehurst...
Daddy!
- Glenoaks?
- Daddy!
Daddy, the ice cream man.
Wait a second, Margaret.
(Chimes continue )
Here you go.
OK...uh, Fabio Place?
Carunso...I mean
Desconco to Glenoaks, right?
Right. Then I...
Can I get an ice cream?
It's late, sweetheart. I'm closed.
Your music's still playing.
(Chimes stop )
Please, can't I get an ice cream?
- What flavour?
- Vanilla twist.
Jesus! Come on!
I'll give you my money,
just don't hurt me - please!
Hey, this is regular vanilla.
I wanted vanilla twist.
(Silenced gunshots )
OK, Margaret,
I'll see you in a few minutes. Bye.
(Sobs )
(Car engine starts )
Gun...in the truck under the dash...
- Hello.
- Special Officer Starker.
Ethan Bishop.
I'm on my way to Senora
with three prisoners.
One's sick and I think it's serious.
What is it?
I'd like to put him in here
until I can call a doctor.
I guess you missed the sign.
The station isn't here.
It's being relocated.
But you're here.
Waiting for the electricity
to go off.
So I can't put him
in your holding tanks?
If you get back on the main boulevard
and go about 10 blocks...
I don't have time to discuss it.
If what that man has is infectious,
then all of us'll have it.
The sooner we put him in the
holding tanks and I call a doctor...
- OK. Bring him in.
- Thanks.
Isn't that...overdoing it a little?
Napoleon Wilson.
No kidding?
Got a smoke?
No. Sorry.
Well...if you see one floating
around...snag it for me, will you?
- There may be a sick man here.
- Just passing through.
I have to admit it, Wilson,
you do have some fancy moves.
For a man in leg-irons.
(Car engine purrs )
(Tyres screech)
(Silenced gunshots )
Come on, pull yourself together!
Speak up!
Lieutenant!
- (Whispers )
- Who?
- What...?
- Lot of action for a closed station.
Ease up, Chaney. He can't talk.
He said somebody's following him.
All right, who?
Come on... Operator,
I have been waiting 10 minutes.
(Starker talking in background)
Yes, I'll con...
Continue holding. Police doctors(!)
Just a minute, calm down...
There's nobody out there.
Chaney, help me take him
to the captain's office.
Hello?!
I just got cut off.
- Do we have a blanket somewhere?
- Yeah.
Keep him warm. I'll call the doctor.
Good luck. I got cut off and now
I can't even get a dial tone.
- They didn't cut you off.
- What?
It's dead.
(Bishop ) Maybe they
shut it off early.
That's it, I'm leaving.
You run this station
like chicken night in Turkey.
Thanks a lot!
He was mumbling
about his daughter being shot.
- Where?
- I don't know.
What about the phone?
- Now what?
- Power failure?
The streetlights are still on.
I'll call Ellendale
on the two-way in my car.
(Silenced shots )
(Laughs ) Chaney just fell down.
(Gunshots )
He didn't fall.
He was shot.
(Julie ) What?!
Couldn't tell if he's alive.
- There wasn't any sound...
- They're using silencers.
(Bishop ) They're in those trees.
Why would anybody
shoot at a police station?
Starker! Lock the doors!
Stay away from the windows!
(Starker) No lights... With
the Highway Patrol running things,
it's amateur night!
(Silenced gunshots )
(Wilson ) Open this door! Let me in!
Come on!
(Wells) You're gonna
leave us here?!
At least take these cuffs off!
Hey, pig!
(Sustained silenced gunfire )
(Gunfire slows )
(Gunfire stops )
Leigh...
I want you to stay at the window.
I'll be right back.
You both all right?
Fabulous, as usual.
What's happening out there?
Hey, come on! We got a right
to know what's happening!
Hey!
Left out again.
Life just seems to pass us by,
doesn't it?
I think they're gone,
I can't see anyone.
- Is there a back way out?
- Past the holding tanks at the rear.
We're blocked off back there.
How come?
There's a big wall
with barbed wire around it.
The only way out
is to come around the front.
Come with me.
What about the houses
behind the wall?.
All the houses
are condemned and boarded up.
No one lives nearby?
There are two houses
at the end of the block.
How far away are they?
Five, six hundred yards.
- So no one nearby heard anything.
- That's impossible!
They're using silencers -
no gunshots.
The only sounds are
the windows breaking.
Somebody could have heard that!
I really think they're gone,
I mean...
Take a look.
I found a box of magnesium flares.
No flare gun.
Figures.
Try to get that open.
Nothing. Not a goddam thing moving.
See?! Just look outside.
They're gone.
Look, I can't get this open.
Damn thing's solid.
We should be
figuring a way to get out!
You got any suggestions?! Huh?
We're gonna stay here and hold
until somebody comes, OK?
We're in the middle of a city,
inside a police station.
Someone's bound to
drive by eventually.
It may take 15-20 minutes,
but they'll come.
It doesn't look like
they've cut our phone lines.
They're still connected to the pole.
I bet they took out
a whole pole down the block.
What does that mean?
If the phone lines are down in
the area no one nearby can call in.
(Julie ) Doesn't the phone company
know where there's a line down?
(Bishop ) Wait a minute.
There they are.
(Bishop ) They've set up a roadblock.
(Julie ) Someone's coming!
What does that mean?
It means we've just been marked
for something.
Let me guess what it is.
This is a siege.
It's a goddam siege!
He's the one they want.
Why don't we give him to them?
Don't give me that civilised look!
This is my station tonight
and he came in here for help.
He's gonna get
all the help we can give him.
Very nice, Lieutenant.
Thank you.
No!
(Silenced gunshots )
Get them out of the cells.
(Wells) Come on, baby! Hurry it up!
(Leigh) OK. Get out front.
- OK.
- Quick!
Move!
(Banging at door)
(Door crashes open )
(Crack)
Hah!
Give me a gun!
They're coming down the hall!
I can't hold it!
Shit!
(Gunshots )
The window!
Watch the front!
Julie?
Wilson!
We'd better barricade that door,
give me a hand.
Wells, watch the front
and the two offices.
You saved my life. Twice.
- Twice?
- First time outside by the bus.
Figure that was a mistake
on your part. I let it go.
Then you did it again when you
pulled us out of the cells.
You must be serious
about keeping me alive.
I want all of us alive.
This time I know somebody heard us.
There'll be squad cars here
in five minutes.
Acetylene.
If a stray bullet had hit this...
(Wells) Look at this!
How is it?
I can't move it and it hurts
like a son of a bitch.
It was close timing.
You were good.
If I'd been any good in here
maybe she'd still be alive.
They moved the car.
I can't believe it. They parked
them where they were before.
Why'd they do that?
From a distance the street
looks normal - like nothing happened.
Like nothing happened?!
They shot five police officers,
a secretary, one prisoner!
And we killed a dozen of them!
Where are the bodies?
They took them away.
- How'd they do it so fast?
- Got the Good Fairy to help them?
You really are a smart-ass!
Prison bus is gone,
so are the bodies.
They dragged old Starker away.
(Cocks pistol)
Too bad. I promised
to tell him something.
What's going on?
What are they doing out there?
They're hiding every sign
that they attacked this building.
What I wanna know is...
what started all this?
Came running in here...
Jesus Christ, 30 minutes ago!
All of this for one man?
Don't forget the cholo.
They delivered it to us.
Cholo?
You look like
somebody spit in your socks.
No one said anything about the cholo.
All right, what does it mean?
It means they don't care.
(Sighs )
They're not afraid to die -
any of 'em.
They want to rip us apart,
no matter what it costs.
It means...
to the death.
How do you know?
I spent some time in a cell
with some crazy young bastards once.
This can't happen.
Not in...in the middle of a city!
Not today.
Pinch me to wake me up.
There was gunfire
for a minute and a half...
Two minutes!
I can't believe no one heard us.
Maybe they heard it.
What do they see?
An empty street,
empty police station.
Maybe somebody
from the new precinct will come by.
In the meantime, I've got this plan,
it's called "Save Ass".
It works like this, I slip out
a window and run like a bastard.
(Bishop ) Wells...
You know I can't let you do that.
I'm not asking you to let me.
They'll cut you down within 10 feet.
- You're on his side?
- No sides to it.
We're all together.
I've been shot once tonight.
I don't feel like a second time.
I want to say one thing
before you jump out that window.
When they drag you off I'll lean out
and ask them to say a prayer
as they dump you in some vacant lot
next to the
five other police officers
and your sick handcuffed friend.
I go through all that
and his gun isn't even loaded.
(Wells laughs )
(Gun clicks empty )
That damn silencer!
I've been clicking off empty shots
all night and I didn't even know it.
(Wilson ) VERY close timing.
You are good.
Sometimes.
Problem is, he's not alone.
Goddam thing's got three shots left.
Wilson?
- Three rounds.
- Leigh?
Two shots.
If there's any spare ammunition
I don't know where it is.
Anybody got a smoke?
Got a light?
(Radio ) 'One-X-five,
'we have reports of firecrackers
and/or gunfire between Ninth and One.
'Telephones are out in the fourth
quadrant from Warren to Vermont,
'telephone repair vehicle
does not respond to radio.'
Jesus, we got a war going on
and we can't find the damn thing!
This is unit seven, we're making
a rapid circuit of quadrant four.
Everything looks normal, nothing
unusual to report at this time.
We'll make another circuit. Suggest
back-up and helicopter surveillance.
(Radio ) 'As soon
as units are available,
'they will be sent into your area.
'All helicopters
are in use at this time.'
We can't find anything
without back-up.
Damned Saturday night overload.
This is unit seven, 10-4.
Don't you wanna check that street?
- That's Gramsci, wasn't it?
- Yeah.
- Just the old station there.
- We should cruise it.
What for?
(Bishop ) It'll work.
You're crazy!
- Sure about the basement?
- Yes.
- What if you're wrong?
- I said...
- But if you're wrong!
- I know this place.
Looks pretty good to me.
Looks like hell,
but it's all we've got.
Who goes?
I gotta tell you,
I don't know how to hot-wire a car.
I'm a cop.
Between me and Snow White.
Shit!
Shit, shit!
- We haven't flipped a coin yet.
- I'm gonna lose.
You got a bad attitude, Wells.
I always lose.
How do you think I ended up in here?
Maybe it'll change.
It might...if we don't flip a coin.
- Let's do something else.
- What?
'Taters.
OK.
(Both) One potato, two potato,
three potato, four.
Five potato, six potato,
seven potato, more.
Eight potato, nine potato,
ten potato, eleven.
Kiss my ass and go to heaven.
Y-O-U spells you!
I said I'd lose. Do it again.
Hey, there isn't time.
- How come she's out?
- Can I do it with one arm?
Still no sign of them.
Let's get moving.
- Want me to show you where it is?
- I'll take him down. You stay here.
It's next to the furnace.
Nobody gonna wish me luck?
(Both) Good luck.
Look at that,
two cops wishing me luck.
I'm doomed.
Five feet down.
- To the sewer?
- 20 yards straight ahead.
- The manhole.
- Right.
I wanna know,
what's the difference between this
and what I was gonna do
10 minutes ago?
- No difference.
- But you stopped me then.
Why not now?
One thing - when you get out
make sure you call the cops
before you head for the border.
What makes you think I'd do that?
I'll see you, Wilson.
That basement's not a bad place to be
if they come at us again.
The only way in is that long hallway.
We might be able to hold 'em...
a couple of minutes.
We'd be trapped.
We won't last up here
with only eight shots.
The upstairs is out.
It's wide open up there.
(Bishop sighs ) Someone will come.
A man with faith. A rare quality.
What about you?
I've never had much faith
in anyone coming to my rescue.
(Wilson ) You associated
with the wrong people.
I've been with policemen
for five years.
Enough to grow hair on a rock.
- And you?
- I believe in one man.
Hey, he's there!
Stay clear. Move!
What's he waiting for?
He's clear in front.
Move, damn it!
He's out.
Go, you son of a bitch.
They've seen him.
Save it for us.
He made it! He's made it!
(Starts engine )
- Go! Go!
- Hit it! Hit it!
He's gonna make it.
(Tyres screech)
(Silenced gunshot)
Maybe it was just a window breaking.
(Bishop ) Wretched...
Too bad, Wells.
You never got to see the border.
We'd better get down
in that basement.
We're out of time,
out of ammunition...
Just like Wells, we're out of luck.
Take a look.
Let's go.
(Wilson ) We can make one last stand.
Take that sign, put it down the
hallway, it'll help stand 'em off.
What do we use
to hold them back with?
Anything we can find.
- Still have a gun?
- Two shots. Do I save it for us two?
Save 'em for the first two
through that vent.
They're bound to have seen Wells
come through the manhole.
What do I use on the rest of them?
Then you'll have to wing it.
None of us know who he is, what
happened to him or what he's done.
(Leigh) He could be anybody
or anything.
I'm curious about one thing.
Just one?
There are other things, but at the
moment this interests me the most.
What's that?
Why didn't you climb down that vent
and take off?
There are two things
a man should never run from,
even if they cost him his life.
One is a man who's helpless
and can't run.
What's the other?
(Bishop ) Come here a minute, Wilson.
The least of our problems
is we're out of time.
It's an old story with me.
I was born out of time.
Acetylene tank, magnesium flares.
We strap the flares onto the tank,
tie them on that plank,
I stand in the doorway with my rifle,
I shoot the flares,
they ignite the tank.
We blow the hell
out of everybody in this hallway!
What stops it
blowing the hell out of us?
You hold up that sign
in front of the door for cover.
- Can you hit it from there?
- I got three shots, that's enough.
Can't argue with a confident man.
Let's go.
This is unit seven, we've checked
between Gramsci and Imperial.
Dark, quiet and deserted.
Request instructions, over.
What are those cars doing there?
There's a few people on duty
moving things out of there.
They're probably between here
and the new station.
We're wasting time here.
- I don't know.
- Huh?
There's something funny back there.
(Radio ) 'We have
continued reports of gunfire.'
We don't hear a thing!
'Most reports are unable to pinpoint
the location of the gunfire.'
'The telephone repair vehicle
is officially reported lost.
'We are sending four back-up units
in to assist you.'
This is unit seven.
Still nothing unusual to report.
We cannot locate the gunfire.
Repeat request for immediate
helicopter surveillance.
'One-X-five, when helicopter
is available we will send it in.'
Unit seven, 10-4.
There's something wrong here.
Listen to that, it's starting
to rain. Just what we need(!)
There's something funny
about that station.
Wait, that's not rain...
What the hell is that?
Jesus Christ...
This is unit seven, emergency
to all precincts and vehicles.
Emergency! Emergency!
(Explosions upstairs )
Molotov cocktails.
They'll set the goddam place on fire.
This is it.
(Bishop ) Let's go.
(Explosion upstairs )
(Glass smashes upstairs )
(Glass smashes )
(Bishop whistles )
Sorry.
Kinda pretty.
Can I ask you a question?
Being a cop I figured
you'd get around to it eventually.
How did you come to be named
"Napoleon" Wilson?
I'll tell you sometime.
(Shouting and banging from upstairs )
- When will you tell me?
- Maybe in a minute.
(Crashing)
(Gunshots )
(Frenzied shouting)
(Silenced gunshots )
(Gunshot)
Can't argue with a confident man!
(Police sirens )
(Sirens in distance )
Anybody got a smoke?
(Handcuffs click)
(Man ) We have a stretcher
for you, miss.
Miss?!
Get away from him!
It would be a privilege
if you'd walk outside with me.
I know it would.
You're pretty fancy, Wilson.
I have moments.
DVD Subtitles by
European Captioning Institute