Hold it right there.
Hold it again.
Hold it.
Oh, come on, Paul.
One more.
You're not going to show those
to anyone, are you?
Sure. Why not?
You've got
a prime figure.
You really have,
you know.
That's a euphemism
for fat.
You want to go back
to the hotel?
What's the matter
with right here?
We're
too civilized.
I remember
when we weren't.
But we'll go back
to the hotel.
Paul, I don't want
to go back home.
[Hawaiian Music Playing]
Announcer: Trans World Airlines
passengers on TW76
from Honolulu to New York
should proceed
from the check-in counter
to the friendship lounge
for boarding.
[Honk Honk]
[Honk]
You want to know
what was happening
while you and Joanna
were living it up
in Maui or Kauai or Yowey...
whatever it is?
What?
There were 15
murders the first week
and 21 last week
in this goddamn city.
That's a lot.
You know, decent people
are going to have
to work here
and live somewhere else.
By "decent people",
you mean people
who can afford to
live somewhere else.
Oh, Christ!
You are such a
bleeding-heart liberal, Paul.
My heart bleeds a little
for the underprivileged, yeah.
The underprivileged are beating
our goddamn brains out.
You know what I say?
Stick them
in concentration camps.
That's what I say.
Henry.
Hello.
I've been running
a cost-and-profit
on the Jainchill development
in Tucson, Arizona.
Well,
based on these figures,
I don't see how Blue Ridge
can underwrite 50% of it.
Well, Jainchill's been
very successful...
in a small way.
Well, then I suggest
you send a man down
from our San Francisco office
to step it out...
redesign it,
if necessary,
because that's a high risk
for the acreage involved.
I'll talk to
Inge about it.
Thanks, Paul.
Oh, uh, Paul,
how does it feel
to be back
in the war zone after Hawaii?
I was feeling pretty good
until I ran into Sam
and he delivered
the crime rate statistics.
What this city needs
is more cops than people.
You'll have to find
other options, Samuel.
No one could pay
the taxes.
Ha ha ha!
Whoo hoo hoo!
[Indistinct Shouting]
Whoo!
$2.17.
Would you have these
delivered, please, Mary?
Good-bye.
[No Audible Dialogue]
Hey, I'm going
to do a thing.
Shit, man.
Got business.
Let's go, man.
I'll get it.
Who is it?
Groceries, ma'am.
Aah!
Nobody gets hurt,
Mother.
Just hold still.
Don't move.
What do you want?
Don't jive, Mother.
You know what we want.
He's not going
to hurt us?
Not if you
got money.
Nobody, nobody.
Hey, Mother.
Look at the artiste
doing his art.
Think they're
beautiful, Mother?
My purse
is in the kitchen.
Just
stand still.
We'll do as
they say, Carol.
Where is your purse?
Shit, you only
got 4 bucks.
I got 3,
and 2 bits.
You're going to get the shit
kicked out of you, Mother.
It's all we have.
Rich people
like you? Shit!
We want money,
Mother. Now get it!
It's true.
That's all we have.
Aah!
How'd you like
to get fucked?
No!
I'm going to stick
you in the ass.
Aah!
Leave her alone!
Goddamn rich cunt!
I kill rich cunts.
Your mother's getting the shit
kicked out of her.
Aah!
Hey, let's screw
this one, man.
No, man.
Let's travel.
No, man. Let me
paint her ass.
[Clothes Ripping]
Hey, man. You think
you're the artiste?
I'll show you
how to paint, man.
I'm going to paint
her goddamn mouth!
Man: He's gonna
paint your mouth.
You're gonna
like that.
You got any ideas
about biting my paintbrush,
you're going to get
what Mother got.
You're going to swallow
all that paint, honey.
Open that
goddamn throat!
[Indistinct Shouting]
[Daughter Screaming]
Mother's going
for the phone!
Shit!
Let's split!
Thelma, will you get my wife
on the phone, please?
[Telephone Rings]
Mr. Kersey's office.
[Intercom Buzzes]
Is it my wife?
No, sir.
It's your son-in-law.
Hello, Jack.
Dad.
Dad,
we got trouble.
Trouble?
You and Carol?
Don't tell me
about it.
No, no.
Dad,
it's Mom and Carol.
They're taking them to the emergency
receiving at Canal Hospital.
What the hell for?
Look,
I don't know.
The police
just called me.
What's happening,
Jack?
I don't know
any more than that.
I'm at my office.
I'm going to the hospital.
Just meet me
there, OK?
P.A.: Dr. Fanning,
go to the emergency room, stat.
Dr. Fanning,
go to the emergency room.
Dr. Diaz...
How are they?
Are they all right?
I don't know.
I just got here a few minutes ago.
Do you know
anything?
Were they cut,
stabbed, what?
I...
No, sir.
Just beat up.
This is
Officer Joe Charles.
He came in the ambulance
with Mom and Carol.
Are they going
to be all right?
I've told Mr. Toby
all I know.
If there's anything I can do,
ask for me at the 21st Precinct.
Good luck to you.
Come on, Dad.
We might as well go sit down.
What did
he tell you?
Not much.
Yeah, but what?
They beat
them both up.
Who did? Why?
Take it easy, Dad.
I'm just as rattled
as you are.
The officer said that Carol
wasn't making much sense.
2, maybe 3 men,
they...
She opened the door
to let them in
because she thought it was
the delivery boy from the supermarket.
Jesus God.
When are we going
to know something?
Do they know we're here?
The nurses know.
I spoke to one of them.
Somebody
ought to come.
There's a man over there.
He's bleeding,
and nobody comes.
Nurse, we're
waiting to find out
what happened
to my wife and daughter.
A doctor will see you
after he's made his examination.
But we've been
waiting a long time.
It hasn't been
that long, Dad.
Just 2 or 3 minutes.
Mr. Toby?
Yes.
Your wife is all right.
We've sedated her
and put her to bed.
My name is Paul Kersey.
How's my wife?
I'm sorry.
She died a few minutes
ago, Mr. Kersey.
Man: Almighty God,
we commend to You
our neighbor Joanna,
trusting Your love
and mercy
and believing in the promise
of a resurrection to eternal life
through our Lord
Jesus Christ. Amen.
Almighty God, father of the whole
family in heaven and on earth,
stand by those who sorrow,
that as they lean
on Your strength
they may be upheld
and believe the good news
of life beyond life
through Jesus Christ
our Lord. Amen.
I'm going back
with Sam and Adele.
They go right
by my place.
Don't you want to come
to our apartment?
It's time
I went to my own.
I have to sometime.
Baby?
I'm going back
with Sam.
You get plenty
of rest.
She'll be all right, Dad.
[Honking]
Radio: Residents
of northern suburbs
will need quite some time to dig
themselves out of a snowstorm
that's taking
much of Connecticut
and Rockland and Westchester
counties by surprise.
In New York City,
light snow flurries
lingering till about midnight.
No accumulation,
but afternoon...
Turn that thing off.
I'm listening to
the weather report.
Why haven't
you found my dog?
He's vital to my income.
He paints such marvelous
pictures with his paws.
Man: Yes. Help you?
Kersey: Can you tell me where I
can find Officer Joe Charles?
What's your business?
My name
is Paul Kersey.
A couple days ago, my wife
and daughter were attacked,
and he was one of the policemen
on the scene.
I want
to talk to him.
Hattie,
is Joe Charles
still back there
or has he gone
on duty yet?
Yeah. There's someone out here
that wants to talk to him.
Have a seat.
He'll be right out.
Woman: I told you
that somebody snatched my purse.
The man came up
from behind me.
My credit cards is in there,
my rent money.
I don't have no key.
Do I have
a description?
The man came
from behind me!
Man: You didn't
see who it was?
Hello,
Mr. Kersey.
Officer Charles.
I dropped by to see
if you had any information
on the people who
attacked my family.
I'll take you to the detective
in charge of the case.
Lieutenant?
This is Mr. Paul Kersey,
case number 884.
His wife and daughter
were assaulted.
Glad to know you,
Mr. Kersey.
I'm going on duty now, Mr. Kersey,
so I'll leave you.
Right this way,
Mr. Kersey.
Will you have
a seat, Mr. Kersey?
Have you found out
anything yet?
Well, the supermarket
security officer
and one of the checkers remembers
these 3 characters leaving
right after Mrs. Kersey
and your daughter.
They think they could have gotten
the apartment number
off the address
on the grocery bags,
but they haven't been able to
pick the faces out of the mug book.
How is your daughter,
Mr. Kersey?
She's under
doctor's sedation right now.
But today
I had the funeral
for my wife
up in Connecticut,
and she was able
to make that.
Your daughter didn't give us
much information, Mr. Kersey.
We wish we could persuade her
to take a look at the mug books.
Did she refuse?
Her husband asked us
to wait for a few days.
In fact, the sooner she looks
at the mug books,
the better chance she has
of recalling one or 2 of the faces.
Well, I'll talk
to my son-in-law
and see what
can be done.
I'd appreciate that,
Mr. Kersey.
Is there any chance
of catching these men?
There's a chance.
Sure.
Just a chance?
I'd be less than honest if I gave you
more hope, Mr. Kersey.
In the city,
that's the way it is.
I thought
you were asleep.
Aahhh!
TV: Are you getting
the most out of life?
Are you satisfied,
fulfilled, happy?
Our bank has helped many
to a better future.
[Object Falls On Pavement]
Good morning,
Mr. Kersey.
Good morning.
Would you give me
$20 in quarters, please?
[Door Opens]
Good morning,
Paul.
Morning.
Paul, you're tough.
You know,
you really are.
I told Ives
you'd come in this morning.
I said Paul is not
the kind of man
to leave the pieces of his
life lying around.
He'll just start
picking them up.
Just a matter
of keeping busy, Sam.
Paul,
welcome back.
Good morning,
Henry.
See you
for lunch, Paul?
Yeah. Sure.
Paul, I'm going to
give you a vacation.
From New York,
that is.
The Jainchill development
of Tucson, Arizona:
I want you
to take it over...
redesign it,
if necessary.
Whatever
you have to do.
All right?
That's all right,
but can I give you
an answer in about a week?
I don't want to leave New York
just now because of Carol.
Fine.
When you're ready,
let me know.
Beautiful place,
Tucson.
They can breathe
out there.
She's sleeping
too much.
It's not normal.
I've got a couple
of TV dinners in the oven.
Come on.
It will just be
a couple of minutes.
Jack, this drink's
enough for me.
I've never seen you drink
without eating.
I'm not hungry.
I think maybe you ought to take
Carol to see another doctor.
I did. Today.
A psychiatrist.
He seems to feel
it might help her
if I took her away
to another environment...
out of New York,
on the shore someplace.
Sounds like
a good idea.
I'll go along
with you.
Uh, no, Dad.
He seemed to feel
that it might be better
if she didn't have
any association with anyone
that might remind
her of that day.
How the hell do I
remind her of that day?
Well, you know
how it is, Dad.
It happened
in your apartment.
And you're
living there.
You remind her
of Mom.
Dad, don't make it
tough for me.
OK, I'll make it
easy for you.
Ives asked me to go
to Tucson, Arizona, on a job.
How long
will you be gone?
I don't know...
until I look the job over.
But you call me
every other day.
Let me know
how Carol is.
Sure I will, Dad.
You know, that will
be good for you.
I hear Tucson's
a really beautiful place.
Yeah, yeah.
That's what everybody says.
How are you
today, sir?
Son of a bitch.
Turn around,
son of a bitch.
Motherfucker!
I said
turn around.
Now hand me
the money.
Aah!
Paul Kersey.
Yeah.
Aimes Jainchill.
How do you do,
Mr. Jainchill?
Aimes.
I'll call you Paul.
Come on.
Let's get your bags.
How did you know
who I was?
Well, you look like
a New Yorker.
[Cattle Mooing]
Ho!
Howdy, Jud.
I wanted you
to see this country
before you looked at the
drawings back at the office.
Give you
a better idea.
I don't want to
change these hills.
Don't want to
bulldoze them flat.
You'll waste a lot
of building space.
Ha ha!
Wasting space.
Now, those are some words
that you big developers
have got to change
for something else.
Such as?
Well,
space for life.
Like old Jud
up there.
Space for people,
horses, cows.
I got funny ideas
about building things.
Man: Howdy, folks.
Welcome to Old Tucson,
the famous movie location
and studio.
In just a few moments...
Come on.
Let's wet our whistle
before I trot you
back to the motel.
Glass of beer,
maybe.
Announcer: ...take their positions
on the porches and boardwalks
of the Red Dog Cafe,
the territorial gunsmith shop...
What's happening here?
Oh, it's a phony
western town.
They shoot movies
here sometimes,
but the rest of the time
it's for the tourists.
Announcer: this is where the
actual performance will take place.
These fellas
are pretty good.
You want
to watch this?
Announcer:
the Wild West lives again.
Man: Where's the Marshal?
Second Man:
He's in the bank.
I spotted him through
the window as I came by.
What have you
got in mind to do, then?
Well, why don't you
steal my horse?
All right.
That's a good trick. We'll use it.
You spot yourself
on the porch
while I draw the marshal
out into the open.
Marshal!
Hey, Marshal!
Marshal:
What's the matter, fella?
Somebody
stole my horse.
Marshal: I told you
to get out of town by sunset.
Man: You missing a bay mare
that was tied to the hitching rail?
Saw a feller come and
take her just a spell ago.
Marshal: well,
what did he look like?
Well, he was
about this tall, and he had this...
Get him, Frank!
Let's put him
inside here
and get to the bank
and make that withdrawal.
Marshal: All right,
boys. The fun's over.
Throw out your guns,
and step out with your hands up.
You'd better listen,
Marshal.
I've got 3 sticks
of dynamite here.
Don't be a fool.
Announcer: The outlaw life
seemed a shortcut to easy money,
which could buy
liquor, women,
and a turn
at the gambling table,
but there were
honest men with dreams
who would fight
to protect their...
Let's get that beer.
Announcer: ...and who were to plant
the roots that would grow into a nation.
Blue Ridge won't buy it.
I don't build a thing that's going
to be a slum in 20 years,
and I won't
doze those hills.
What I build
conforms to the land.
And you can't hear
the toilets flush next door.
You want our help,
you'll have to
let me work with it.
Well, up to a point,
I want your help.
Up to a point,
I'll give it to you.
When do I get
a look-see?
In a couple days.
Guard says you were here
till after midnight last night.
Yeah. That's
the way I work.
Somebody once said... I forget who...
that he never looked back
because something might
be gaining on him.
What's gaining
on you, Paul?
$20 million investment.
What else?
Well, I was
going to ask you
to have dinner
with me at the club,
but I don't think
you'd be very good company.
No, I don't think
I would.
It might amuse you,
though.
Being from New York,
maybe you never seen a club like this.
It's a gun club.
We shoot guns.
So goddamn much hoopla
from the gun control people.
Half the nation's scared
to even hold a gun!
You know,
like it was a snake,
it was going to bite
you or something.
Hell, a gun
is just a tool...
Like a hammer
or an ax.
Wasn't long ago,
used to put food on the table,
keep foxes out
of the chicken coop,
rustlers off the range,
bandits out of the bank.
Paul, how long since you held
a pistol in your hand?
A long time.
Which war was yours...
Korea?
Yeah.
See much action?
A little.
In the infantry?
I was a C.O.
in a medical unit.
Oh, commanding
officer, huh?
Conscientious objector.
Oh, Christ.
What a guest to bring
to a gun club!
You're probably one
of them knee-jerk liberals
thinks us gun boys
shoot our guns
because it's an extension
of our penises.
I never thought
about it that way,
but it could be true.
Well, maybe it is,
but this is gun country.
Can't even own a handgun
in New York City.
Out here, I hardly know a man
that doesn't own one,
and I'll tell you
something...
Unlike your city,
we can walk our streets
and through our parks at night
and feel safe.
Muggers operating
out here,
they just plain get
their asses blown off.
Here. Slip these on.
All righty. This is
a percussion pistol.
1842.
You ever handled
one of those before?
You know
how to fire it?
Watch the kick.
Boy, you're
going to think
that your arm's
going to hit the ceiling.
Goddamn!
Paul, you hit
dead center!
Mind if I try
this hogleg Colt?
No.
Well, you a peculiar
conscientious objector.
These notches
for real?
Yeah. Belonged to a gunfighter
named Candy Dan, 1890.
Hmm.
I do know something
about guns, Aimes.
I grew up with them...
all kinds of guns.
You see, my father
was a hunter.
I guess out here
you'd call him a gunman.
My mother was
the other side of the coin.
When my father was killed
in a hunting accident...
some fool mistook him
for a deer, you see...
my mother
won the toss.
I never touched
a gun since.
I loved my father.
[Telephone Rings]
There are your hills.
Every house has a part
of one for a backyard,
for kids, dogs, horses.
400 houses, 100 more
than you allowed for,
and you still have 12 hills.
I'm catching the 10:40
back to New York.
What do I tell them?
You tell them
I'll buy it if they will.
You're checking this bag
through, aren't you?
Yeah.
Good.
Let me slip a little going-away
present in there for you.
Thank you.
P.A.: Trans World Airlines
flight 63
from Tucson to New York
is now boarding...
Good morning, sir.
How are you today?
Checking one bag?
Paul, I can't
thank you enough
for what
you did for me.
I want you to know if you ever
get tired of living in that toilet,
you're welcome here.
P.A.: Trans World Airlines
flight 7
to London and Frankfurt
is now boarding.
Passengers should proceed
to gate 11...
Welcome home, Dad.
Hi, Jack.
I halfway expected to see Carol.
Come on.
Let's go get your bags.
What is it?
She's in the hospital.
When I last spoke
to you on the phone,
you said she
was feeling better
after coming back
from the shore.
Well, I didn't see any need
to get you all disturbed
on a long-distance call.
P.A.: Will Mr. Cory, a passenger
on Trans World Airlines flight 100
from Vancouver,
please report to...
Oh, come on, Dad,
don't do a number...
Don't do
a number on me.
Look, there was nothing
you could do.
They haven't even
let me see her for 2 days.
They tried insulin
shock yesterday.
She's not
responding.
You want the
technical jargon?
I can reel off
yards of it:
catatonia,
dementia praecox,
passive
schizoid paranoia.
It all boils down
to the fact
that she's had an experience
that she can't face,
and she's running away
from it inside herself.
P.A.: Will Mrs. Lager, a passenger on
Trans World Airlines flight 45 to Paris,
please contact
the information desk...
You didn't handle her
right, Jack.
Aw, Christ, Dad!
I'll get other doctors.
Who are these goddamn
doctors you have?
They're good doctors!
Dad, she's almost
a goddamn vegetable!
If you don't sign
the papers, what happens?
I guess they keep her in the hospital
until the insurance runs out.
That won't be too long.
If you sign the papers
and she's committed, what then?
Well, I've got
an insurance policy
that covers it up to
about 600 a month.
They've recommended
a sanatorium out in Long Island.
Jack...
this commitment...
is it a one-way thing?
Nobody can
answer that, Dad.
You want to know
what they are?
They're statistics
on a police blotter...
Mom and Carol along with
thousands of other people.
And there is nothing
that we can do to stop it.
Nothing but cut and run.
[Laughing]
Boy: Oh,
what a bummer, man.
That was the worst fucking movie
I've ever seen.
[Faint Siren]
You got money, man?
Shit, I'll kill you!
Give me your money,
or I'll bust you up!
[Retching]
Oh, Jesus.
Jesus Christ.
Ohh...
Oh, Jesus.
Ahh...
[Groaning]
[Vomiting]
[Indistinct Police Radio]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Sneezes]
Good morning, Inspector.
Good morning.
What have we got?
We got a corpse
down here,
one bullet hole
in his chest.
Fellow over there
was jogging
through the park
at daybreak,
found him
on the path here.
You got a make
on the dead man?
Yeah. His name is
Thomas Leroy Marston.
He had a parole card.
We got a radio check
on that.
He served 42 months of a
5-year hitch for grand larceny.
He's a drug addict.
He's probably popping smack again.
There's punctures,
both arms.
We found this
on the grass next to him.
Thing hasn't been fired.
Deceased had a gun
clip on his belt.
Think it must be his.
What would you say if I
suggested that he tried a heist,
he got shot
for his trouble?
Man: Maybe 2 guys trying
to heist each other.
Inspector: No, no.
This man wasn't robbed.
Still has money in his wallet.
[Knock On Door]
Good morning, Paul.
Good morning.
- Sam: Hi, Paul.
- Morning.
Morning, Sam.
Well, we've marked it out
as you've indicated.
It's beautiful.
What's our profit?
Uh... not quite 3 million,
but I believe that
our investment
can be amortized
in 2 years,
and it is a showplace
operation.
Look at all that
wasted space.
Jainchill loves those hills.
Besides, it's a take-it-or-leave-it
proposition.
Well, it's too pretty
to leave.
OK. I'll run it
for the board.
May need
your help, Paul.
OK.
Oh, Tucson agreed with you.
You look well.
Paul: I feel, uh...
good.
[Scuffling]
[Muffled Shout]
[Siren]
[People Shouting Questions]
Man: Was he a white man
or a black man?
Second Man:
I just don't know!
Come on. They were
under that streetlight.
I wasn't seeing too good.
I had blood in my eyes.
Was he tall? Short?
Thin? Fat?
Hank, forget it, huh?
Ride the ambulance
to the morgue.
When they get the slugs
out of those bodies,
run them over
to the lab for ballistics.
[Siren]
You saw him pretty good,
didn't you?
You're full of shit.
Thank you.
Ahh...
You know, if we had the brains
to live here in the country,
we wouldn't be here
for the reason we are today.
We'd be going into
the city to work.
Mom and Carol would
be safe at home,
waiting for us
to come back.
Nothing to do
but cut and run, huh?
What else?
What about the old American
social custom of self-defense?
If the police
don't defend us,
maybe we ought to
do it ourselves.
We're not pioneers
anymore, Dad.
What are we, Jack?
What do you mean?
I mean, if we're not pioneers,
what have we become?
What do you call people...
who, when they're faced
with a condition of fear,
do nothing about it,
they just run and hide?
Civilized?
No.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have to start this
investigation somewhere,
so let's start here.
[Siren Outside]
[Coughs]
Motive...
revenge.
I want the records checked.
Go back, say, uh...
3 months.
Limit it to homicide.
We could be looking
for a man
who's had a member or members
of his family killed by muggers.
Now, he shoots
that pistol pretty good.
Right?
OK.
Combat veteran.
So put Vietnam vets
at the top of the list,
because they're youngest
and toughest.
Then you can
work your way
through Korea
and World War II.
Oh, my God!
Who said that?
Hmm?
Well, whoever said it,
you're right on the button.
By God and Jesus Christ,
it's impossible,
but until we find
a shortcut,
we'll at least keep busy.
So when the media demands to know what
we are doing to apprehend the vigilante,
we'll tell them
we have definite clues.
OK?
We won't tell them we have
about a thousand definite clues.
[Woman Screams]
Man: There's a body in there...
2 of them!
Where'd he go?
Did anybody see
what he looked like?
We are here in Police
Commissioner Dryer's office,
waiting for a press conference
scheduled by Commissioner Dryer.
Last night, there was
another double killing
which appears
to be the work
of the person New York news media
have dubbed "the vigilante".
[Speaking Italian]
[Speaking German]
[Speaking French]
American Announcer: This will be
the first official statement
from Commissioner Dryer
on the vigilante killings.
I can see the commissioner now
as he walks past...
Commissioner: Good morning,
ladies and gentlemen.
With me
is inspector Frank Ochoa,
who has been placed in command
of a police detail
assigned to what we've all
been calling the vigilante murders.
Now, it has been confirmed
by our ballistics laboratory
that the same gun,
a .32 pistol which was used
in the previous 3 homicides,
was used last night
in a shooting aboard a subway train.
Now, I know
that this person
has captured the imagination
of many people in our city,
and I want to say
to our citizens,
murder is no answer
to crime in this city.
Crime is a police responsibility,
and if this person
is listening to my voice,
I urge him
in the name of law and order
to desist
from this one-man crusade
and turn himself in
to the police.
He'll be given fair treatment.
How do you like it?
That's our police
commissioner, you know,
that's Dryer...
the king of cliches.
Reporter: Vigilante's identification?
No comment at this time.
Second Reporter:
Do you think this man's crazy?
Well, he's got
a wire down, all right,
but I don't believe we're dealing
with a raving maniac.
Third Reporter:
Commissioner,
it's rumored that the rate
of street muggings
has dropped since the vigilante
became headline news.
Is that true?
Not true.
If it were true,
would you announce it, sir,
or are you afraid
that would stimulate
imitators of the vigilante?
I don't want to get into
these hypothetical questions.
I bet muggings are down.
They're afraid to tell us.
There's only one way
to find out...
take a walk
on Columbus Avenue tonight.
Thanks a lot, Paul.
I think I'll wait
for the official report.
Commissioner On TV:
Successful, regardless of the...
[Ring]
Yes?
Ah.
You want to confess
to the vigilante killings?
All right.
I'll put you through
to Rosenberg.
He's in charge
of confessions today.
That's the 23rd.
Put him through.
We couldn't get any prints
off the vigilante's groceries.
Wasn't there a sales slip?
Yeah. Here.
D'Agostino's.
Mm-hmm.
Some of this code must
identify the particular store.
Find out where it is.
When we get the records,
check on families that have had
somebody killed by muggers.
Let's put them
through the computer
and see if any of them
live near this store.
People are inclined to buy groceries
in their own neighborhoods.
Hi, Jack.
Come on in.
Dad.
Make yourself a drink.
[Music Playing Loudly]
Hey, what do you think?
The new paint?
Well, it's a little hard
on the eyes, but...
Hard on the eyes?
It's cheerful.
[Turns Music Down]
Hey, Jack,
turn it back up.
I can't hear.
[Turns Music Up]
We got liver and spaghetti
for dinner.
How do you like
your liver done?
Uh...
Hey, no drink?
Let me make you one.
No. Dad, listen,
that's all right.
I'll get it myself.
I, uh...
I saw Carol today.
Aren't you going to ask
how she's doing?
I know how she's doing.
I went up to see her
yesterday.
Then what the hell
are you so high about?
What the hell
you want me to do...
moan and groan
for the rest of my life?
How do you want
your liver... medium?
Medium.
I'll make it medium.
[Van Honking]
Hey, there goes
the pussy posse.
[Women Laughing]
Hey, mister,
got a match?
Yeah.
What else you got?
Let's see the money, man.
You'll have to take it.
Shit.
[Women Shouting Incoherently]
He went that way.
Who rode the ambulance
with him?
I did.
Well?
Was he talking?
He said he cut
whoever it was that shot him.
Exact words:
"I cut that motherfucker.
I hit him."
Can't save him.
Too much internal bleeding.
One slug chewed up
the liver.
Here.
.32s.
TV: ...city tonight, the mysterious
vigilante is in the news again.
A little more
than 2 hours ago,
in an 8th Avenue
subway underpass,
2 men were shot.
One died on the spot.
The other managed to reach
the street before he collapsed.
He died shortly afterward
in the hospital.
The 2 men
have been identified
as Joseph Roscoe Adams
and George Reech.
Both had
long criminal records.
The vigilante himself
may have been wounded.
The actions of the vigilante,
as lawless as they may be,
seem to be giving others
new attitudes
toward crime
in the streets.
Instead of helplessly allowing themselves
to be mugged and robbed,
a few are fighting back.
I have with me
Mrs. Alma Lee Brown,
who today
successfully defended herself
against 2 muggers
with an unusual weapon.
Mrs. Brown,
would you tell us
how you drove off
your attackers today?
Mrs. Brown:
With a hatpin.
You ever seen a hatpin?
Reporter: I can't
say that I have.
Well, that's what
we used to use
to hold our hats
on with,
and I ain't got no gun
like this vigilante fellow,
but I went to my closet,
and everybody better look out
for me from now on,
'cause I been robbed too many times,
and I've got enough!
Second reporter: Some of the men
building this skyscraper here
made what you might call
a citizens' arrest today.
I'll ask Andrew McCabe,
one of the foremen, to tell you about it.
Me and my crew
was working down in the hole.
One of the boys
up on the steel yelled down,
"There's a mugging
going on!"
So we come out of the hole
and through the gate,
and we caught
this guy running.
We roughed him up a little bit
before the police came.
Reporter: The hospital report
says the man had 2 broken arms,
a broken jaw,
and cracked ribs.
No kidding? Jeez.
Poor guy must have
fell down.
Woman: Walking distances
from D'Agostino's:
2 blocks crosstown,
6 short blocks uptown and downtown.
I mean, that's how far
I'd be willing to walk to a market.
Good. Very good,
Miss Gemetti.
Gemetti: We have 12 families
living within this area
who have suffered a death
in the family in the past 3 months
from mugging, stabbing,
shooting, assault.
2 of these families
have no male members.
One family has only
an 80-year-old grandfather.
That leaves 9 families.
Total number of male persons
in these families
who are old enough to have served
in the Vietnam war, Korea, or World War II
comes to 14.
Wild.
It's a real wild shot,
but the fact is
that the vigilante
plugged his first victim
in Riverside Park,
exactly 2 1/2 blocks
from that D'Agostino Market.
Even if all these guys
are clean,
we still can't ignore
that coincidence.
No, sir. Our friend lives
in that neighborhood.
But, Frank,
he was on a subway
with groceries
5 miles uptown.
There's no better come-on
for a mugging
than a guy
with a bagful of groceries.
Means he's got some money
in his pocket
and his hands
are occupied.
He might have been carrying
those groceries for hours.
I want a preliminary line
on these names:
where they work,
service record,
reputation,
police record, if any,
and I want it fast.
You know,
like today, huh?
Woman: It's probably having as much
effect on the total crime picture
as putting a band-aid
on a leper.
Sam: I don't know
about that.
A mugger's going to think twice
about who he hits.
Man: Sure.
They're hitting more old ladies.
Paul, how you doing?
Let me get you a drink.
Man: I'll tell you one thing...
the guy's a racist.
You notice he kills
more blacks than whites.
More blacks are
muggers than whites.
What do you
want us to do...
increase the proportion
of white muggers
so we'll have racial equality
among muggers?
Racial equality among muggers?
I love it!
He hasn't been the same
since that terrible incident.
Who we got here?
A guy named Paul...
Kersey.
His wife was murdered
in their apartment.
Interesting detail:
the attackers, 3 of them,
gained entrance
to the apartment
by posing
as delivery boys
from our
D'Agostino's Market,
where the vigilante
buys his groceries.
What else about him?
He lives alone now.
Development engineer
for the Blue Ridge Corporation.
Served in Korea...
medical corps.
Conscientious objector.
No police record.
Credits, reputation excellent.
Conscientious objectors
are unlikely vigilantes.
We got a finger?
Yeah. Over there.
Patrolman Joe Charles.
Good.
Good morning, Mr. Kersey.
Joe Charles, Mr. Kersey.
Paul:
Oh, yes, of course.
How do you do?
Good to see you again.
How's your daughter?
The same.
Take care.
Follow him.
Yes, I'll see to that,
Mrs. Cohen.
[Footsteps]
Just a moment.
You're not residents here.
Who do you wish to see?
I'll call up for you.
Ochoa: No, you won't.
[Knocks]
[Coughs]
Man: The district attorney
will see you now.
[Ochoa Coughing]
Ochoa: Commissioner.
Commissioner:
Frank, you know the district attorney.
Ochoa: Mr. Peters.
Inspector.
The commissioner says
you have a pretty good suspect.
Well, he, uh...
fits the bill in some respects.
We, uh, got a blood sample
from the knife
used on him
in the subway
and checked it
against the sample
I found
in his apartment.
It narrows it down.
But in the balance,
he could be the man?
Yeah.
Yeah, he could be.
Commissioner:
Frank,
suppose this Paul Kersey
is the vigilante.
All right.
Let's say that.
We don't want him.
OK.
Inspector, on my desk
I have a statistic
red-hot
out of the computer.
Ochoa: Mm-hmm. Mugging has
gone down by how much, sir?
From 950 a week
to 470 reported last week.
You understand
not too many people know that.
And you want to keep it
that way, huh?
We have to keep it
that way, Inspector.
This whole city
would explode.
We'd have vigilantes
out in the street
killing anybody
who even looked greasy.
You can see that.
We want this man
to quit, desist, go away...
to stop.
So the mugging rate
can go up?
If I arrest him,
wouldn't that get him off the streets?
My God, man. I don't want
a martyr on my hands.
All right.
I just want to
hear you say it.
I'll try to scare him off,
but that's as far as I'll go.
That's right, Frank.
Scare him off.
Scare him off?
[Intercom Buzzes]
Yes?
Woman: A call for you from a man
who says he's an old friend
and wonders if you'll
recognize his voice.
Do you want the call that way,
or shall I insist upon his name?
Ok, I'll take it.
I'm putting you through.
Paul: Hello?
Is this Paul Kersey?
Yes. Who's this?
Mr. Kersey, you're under
police surveillance.
You're being watched.
[Dial Tone]
Scare him off. Ha!
Man: Papers! Papers!
Read all about the vigilante!
Get your papers here!
How are you this evening, sir?
Papers! Papers!
Read all about the vigilante!
Police Officer:
All right, you. Get your hands up.
Come on.
Hands on the car. Come on.
Spread your legs.
OK. Turn around.
Let's see some identification.
[Indistinct Police Radio]
Where do you live?
33 Riverside.
OK, Mr. Kersey.
Sorry to have roughed you up so much.
We're looking for a guy
pretty close
to your description.
He's supposed to be armed,
and we couldn't take
any chances.
I hope you understand.
Look, if you want to
make a complaint,
I'll give you my number.
It's all right.
Nobody was hurt.
Police Officer:
OK. Thanks.
Good night,
Mr. Kersey.
OK?
Yeah.
OK.
Went in the building
about 10 minutes ago.
Went to D'Agostino's Market first.
[Indistinct Police Radio]
Let's check him, huh?
Go to that phone booth
on the corner, call his number.
He's up there.
Check him anyway.
[Mutters Indistinctly]
[Indistinct Police Radio]
Officer: Police!
I need the phone.
Come on!
Who is this guy?
Girl:
He must be crazy.
He said "police".
I didn't see a badge.
[Telephone Ringing]
I'll call as soon
as he gets off the phone.
Thanks, pal.
Yeah? Up yours!
No answer. He could be
in the shower or something.
Stay here.
[Indistinct Police Radio]
Good night, Mr. Kersey.
Good night.
I'm supposed to meet Paul Kersey.
Has he gone up yet?
Yes, sir. He went up
and came down.
Just walked out.
[Tires Squeal]
Where did you go?
He didn't show here, did he?
Can I ask a simple question?
Is this Paul Kersey the bird?
I ain't gonna ask
any more questions.
Go home, will you?
I don't need you.
Weird!
[Boat Horn Blows]
Come on down,
motherfucker.
We going to take you.
That's right, motherfucker,
and you can't
go back up, either.
[Muggers Laughing]
Come on down and bring us
the money, honey.
Second Mugger:
How much money you got, honey?
Ha ha ha ha!
What the fuck?
Fuck!
Ah!
[Siren]
Police Radio:
Units in the 2-6 precinct.
A 10-34, 1-2-5 Street
and the West Side Highway.
[Siren]
Paul: Hey!
Fill your hand.
Huh?
Draw.
[Siren]
[Crowd Yelling]
[Car Horn Honking]
[Siren]
[Indistinct Police Radio]
Where is he,
this patrolman?
You're Reilly?
Yes, sir.
I'm Ochoa.
You were the first man
on the scene?
Yes, sir.
[Sneezes]
God bless you, sir.
Never mind that.
They told me on the radio
you had to see me?
Paul Kersey.
You spoke to him before
the ambulance got here?
No, sir.
What did you get?
His address, sir.
Is that all?
Well?
You enter this
on your report?
Not yet, sir.
Why not?
I was, uh...
waiting for
instructions, sir.
You never saw it.
Yes, sir.
Oh, uh...
what's your full name?
Jackson Reilly, sir.
21st Precinct.
OK. I'll remember it.
Reporter: Inspector, is it true
that you have the vigilante in there?
Ochoa: No.
Well, who have you
got there?
You in charge?
How is he?
Wounds are clean.
Nothing vital.
We have a transfusion
going on now.
Soon as we get some blood in him,
we'll sew him up.
Is he in there?
Yeah.
All right if I go in?
He won't be able
to talk much.
Can he hear me?
He is conscious.
[Indistinct P.A. Announcement]
Police. I'd like to
have him alone.
Good evening,
Mr. Kersey.
This is your gun,
We tried to give you
a chance to get rid of it.
You wouldn't take it.
Do you hear me OK?
We, uh...
have here a
peculiar situation, Mr. Kersey.
We find it necessary
to make you a proposition,
since you are not
going to favor us by dying.
You, uh, work for a company
with lots of offices.
Get a transfer
to another city,
and I'll drop this gun
in the river.
Are we connecting,
Mr. Kersey?
We want you to get
out of New York...
permanently.
Inspector.
By sundown?
[Sneezes]
Reporters:
There he is. Here he comes.
Do you have the vigilante,
Inspector?
Can't you give us
some information, Inspector?
No!
Isn't the wounded man
the vigilante, Inspector?
No. He's just
a mugging victim.
How do you explain the first reports
that he is the vigilante?
False reports.
It happens all the time.
Then the vigilante's
still out there?
That's right. He's still
out there on the streets.
Let me through.
Was he shot
by the vigilante, then?
P.A.: The Amtrak train
from New York to Chicago
has arrived on track 8.
Man: Mr. Kersey.
Paul Kersey.
Fred Brown.
Welcome to Chicago, sir.
Did you have a nice trip?
Yeah, it was OK.
Good. I found a nice
apartment for you.
I hope you like it.
It's on Lake Shore Drive.
You have a view
of Lake Michigan, morning sun.
We've got your office
ready, too.
There's a very good
golf club, if you play.
Listen, I think
you'll enjoy it here.
Excuse me.