Come on.
Come on, mutt.
Look at that ball. All right.
- Come on. Get that ball. Baah!
- [Barking]
There's no problem
with that.
Oh, goddamn it.
If it happens,
let me know.
What the hell are you doing here?
This is not the office!
- This is my private time.
- Five minutes.
No! I said no Tuesday,
I said no last week,
and I'm gonna keep sayin' no
till you hear me.
Five minutes,
Mr. Chairman.
- It's all I ask. Five minutes.
- [Dog Barking]
- You want some coffee?
- No, I don't want any coffee. I want to play with my dog.
Look, I'm not asking you
to vote for it.
I know you can't.
Just release your people.
Let them go
the way they want.
Telecommunications
Security and Privacy Act!
Invasion of privacy
is more like it.
You read the Post?
"This bill is not the first step
towards the surveillance society.
It is the surveillance
society. "
- Liberal hysteria.
- Listen, I'm not gonna sit in Congress...
and pass a law that lets the government
point a camera and a microphone...
at anything
they damn well please.
- Phil.
- [Grunts]
Look, I don't care
who bangs who,
what cabinet officers
get stoned.
But this is the richest, most powerful
nation on earth, and therefore the most hated.
And you and I know what
the average citizen does not:
That we are at war
24 hours of every day.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Do I have to itemize the number
of American lives we've saved...
in the past 12 months alone with
judicious use of surveillance intelligence?
Thomas, cut the crap.
I've got three major employers
in the Syracuse area alone...
who are gonna get
just killed by this bill.
I promise to get you funds
equal to...
or greater than whatever those
companies gave your last campaign.
I'm not talking about
campaign contributions, damn it.
I'm talking about my constituents
being out of work.
Jesus, man!
Wake up!
National security isn't the only thing
going on in this country.
God.
This conversation
is over.
I beg of you, Phil.
Please don't.
I've been there for you in the past,
haven't I? There have been times,
personal situations, when you needed
my assistance and my confidence.
Are you blackmailing me,
you ambitious shit?
I'm sorry we can't find a common ground
on this one, Congressman.
You're a good man.
People of your district are lucky...
to have you
representing them.
Come on.
[Grumbles]
[Hamersly]
Come on. [Grunts]
[Screaming]
[Dog Barking]
[Barking Continues]
[Whimpering]
[Computer Blipping, Beeping]
- [Siren Wailing]
- [Helicopter Blades Whirring]
[Motor Whirring]
[Dog Barking]
[Tires Screeching]
[Rapid Beeping]
[Sirens Wailing]
Let me fight management.
Okay, I can accept that.
But this is our own
goddamned union leadership...
tryin' to railroad us into signing
some sweetheart contract.
Look, everybody knows...
that the mob has been controlling these
guys since as long as I can remember.
And now, uh...
now we got Pintero's goons...
down there
tuning up my people.
Well, first off, that's a Hobbs Act
violation, probably a RICO.
- Hey, thanks. Great.
- How you doing, Eddie? How's it goin'?
- Robert Dean.
- Tony O'Neill. Nice to meet you.
A Hobbs and a RICO.
Ooh, baby, don't stop.
Sounds like you guys need
a labor lawyer. What happened?
We were in Louie's
two nights ago,
I go to use the bathroom,
and these two fuckin' guidos jump me.
Uh, I prefer we use the term
"Italian-Americans. "
Eh, whatever, but they were really goin'
to work on me. It could've gotten serious.
- But then Larry Cash came in and he went after 'em.
- Larry Cash is in the hospital,
with a broken jaw
and a ruptured kidney.
Is this becoming a criminal
investigation, Robert?
- Um, no, it would take years to see that thing through.
- [Intercom Beeps]
Besides, these people have families
that are living through this every day.
Hey, Julie, can we send a case
of Chianti over to Larry Cash?
- Larry Cash?
- Yes, he's at St. Luke's.
And send some flowers to his wife,
Brenda. They're both in the Rolodex.
Yes, Mr. Dean.
Well, why don't you guys
just head on home?
I'm your lawyer. I'm in the process of
dealing with these guido motherfuckers.
Pintero doesn't stand
a chance.
So, how's the trout?
- Tastes like fish.
- It is fish.
No, I mean it tastes like
every other fish I've ever had.
Okay.
[Clears Throat]
Brill's note said that...
this is the videotape you need
to convince Pintero with.
And watch out for the F.B.I. Brill says
the place is under surveillance.
- So when do I get to meet him?
- Pintero?
Brill.
Never.
Okay. Um...
Wow. That's not exactly
the answer I was hoping for.
And what was the answer
you were hoping for?
Oh, I don't know. Soon.
Uh, definitely sooner than never.
Bobby, why do we have to
go through this every time?
Brill talks to me,
I talk to you.
That's the way
it works.
Well, pardon me for being
a little uncomfortable...
with hiring someone that
I don't know and I've never even met.
Then don't hire him.
[Exhales Sharply]
$10,000.
And I'm also uncomfortable havin'
to carry that kind of cash around.
Well, this should lighten
your load.
I don't know if it's Brill's price
that's goin' up or your commission.
I take 15%,
as always.
Brill's fee varies
with risk.
Maybe you'd be more comfortable
using someone else.
- What, other than Brill?
- Other than me.
- What's wrong with you?
- Oh, there's nothing wrong with me.
Just, you know,
someone with whom...
you don't have quite
so complicated a history.
I like our history,
and I like you.
Tsk.
I like you too.
Look, I-I just want to make sure that
I'm not breaking the law in any way.
- You're not.
- And how can I be so sure?
Because
I wouldn't let you.
[Dean]
So, Mr. Pintero, the guy on the left...
is Carl Matthews,
president of Local 6650.
And this is Dave Early,
secretary-treasurer of the National.
Oh, right there,
you see... you see the guy there?
That's Hugh Simic.
He administers the pension fund.
Hey, you're going to recognize
this fellow right here.
- [Beeps]
- That's you.
- Am I correct, Mr. Pintero?
- That ain't me.
- [Chuckling]
- Let's watch a little more.
- Take a picture of this.
- Everybody say "money. "
Here comes a great shot
right here.
Everybody say "not guilty. "
- [Dean] Right here; here it comes.
- [Remote Control Clicks]
- That's not you?
- That ain't me.
[Chuckling] Well, you know, that's
actually really great news for me.
It lifts a huge weight
off of my shoulders.
Because the conditions of your parole
specifically forbid you from having any contact...
- of any kind with any union officials.
- I know that.
Well, I'm saying,
so hypothetically, had that been you,
I mean, you'd be headed
back to prison for...
fifteen... I don't know...
maybe twenty years... even more.
But, I don't know, that ain't you,
as you so eloquently put it.
Are you fuckin' with me?
Eloquently? That's not me.
Oh, that's not you. Well, I'm sorry
I've wasted your time, gentlemen,
you know, since
that's not you, um...
Oh, you know what? I'm thinkin'.
Maybe I'll just, you know,
run this tape past
the federal prosecutor.
You know, they have
really great VCRs down there.
A lot of times, they can see
things that we can't see.
You ain't runnin' this
by nobody.
- What do you want?
- My clients want to vote their contract up or down...
as they see fit, without,
shall we say, any outside influences.
Okay.
Sit down.
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
- No, you are not fine.
Now sit your ass...
down.
I would like my clients to be able
to exercise their constitutional rights.
And if that happens, that tape will
disappear forever into my private collection,
along with the Zapruder film
and the porno from Hitler's bunker.
You got any copies
of this thing?
- Absolutely.
- Who made it? You make it?
I'm an attorney.
I don't make videotapes.
Now you listen to me,
you fuckin' eggplant.
This fuckin' videotape
may save your clients' asses,
but you can be goddamned sure
it ain't gonna save yours.
Now, who made
the fuckin' videotape?
- I don't know.
- How'd you get it?
- Through an acquaintance.
- [Wheezing Chuckle]
Mr. Dean, he's got acquaintances.
Me, I got friends. I don't know.
Vic, get outside. See if they're
any acquaintances out there...
that are of
the black persuasion.
Carlos, why don't you
get out of that chair?
Talk to Mr. Dean.
Who's your fucking
acquaintance?
Listen to me. I wanna know
who made that videotape,
but I wanna know
in a week.
Or I'll kill ya.
Hey, smile.
- What?
- Smile for the F.B.I.
[Chuckling]
- [Woman] Who's the brother?
- [Man] I don't know, but he doesn't look Italian to me.
Table Harvest to 101.
We got a blue overcoat heading east.
- [Sighs]
- [Engine Starts]
Give me a loose one.
See if we can get his plates.
- [Siren Wailing]
- [People Chattering]
[Woman] I'm standing by live at
the Lockraven Reservoir right now...
where police and fire officials
are in the process of removing...
a classic Mercedes owned by
Republican congressman...
Phillip Hamersly
of Syracuse, New York.
[Woman #2] This accident comes
at a very untimely juncture,
since the congressman was working on a
controversial piece of legislation, Dale,
opposing the Telecommunications
Security and Privacy Act.
Fire officials do tell me
that it appears the congressman...
was by himself
in the car.
We have confirmed that.
However, strangely enough,
his favorite dog, Bob,
is currently with police.
[Woman #1] I understand there
was a history of heart problems.
[Woman #2] There was, in fact,
a history of heart problems.
In fact, the congressman endured open-heart
surgery just a couple of years ago.
Homicide investigators have told me they
did find a bottle of pills in his lap.
That might mean that the congressman...
and I speculate here...
may have suffered a heart attack before
going into the Lockraven Reservoir.
He leaves behind
a family of four.
[Woman #1] We'll have
more details as the story develops.
[Siren Wailing]
[Man Talking
On Police Radio, Indistinct]
[Reporters Talking,
Indistinct]
[Beeping]
I need a 10-27 on a...
brown and tan
'75 GMC Jimmy.
D.C. Tags.
Eight, kilo,
six, three, nine, four.
And a 10-28
on the registered owner.
[Man Talking
On P.A., Indistinct]
[Beeps, Whirrs]
[Man] Do not give me
optimistic numbers. I hate optimism.
- Sir?
- I want to know how many votes we have in the bank...
aren't gonna change their mind
every time the wind blows.
- Thank you.
- [Remote Control Beeping]
We may have a problem
out at the lake.
This is Daniel Zavitz. He's a nature
photographer with some government grants.
One of them is for monitoring
migratory patterns of Canadian geese.
Or lack thereof.
The box is called a hide.
It contains a motion-activated...
digital video camera
with a compound lens.
It was aimed directly
at the boat ramp across the lake.
We need two techs with full electronic
capabilities... two humpty-dumpties.
Get Fiedler to organize it,
and call Kramer...
to get us some
ex-military cutouts.
How do I describe
the project?
Call it a training op
hosted here.
Set up a link
with the N.R.O.
- That's good.
- Falsify F.B.I. Approval.
And none of this goes beyond our team.
And get that videotape.
- Of course.
- Get a wire on our bird-watcher.
You got it.
Fiedler, it's Hicks. I need
an intercept on a Daniel Leon Zavitz.
202-555-0108.
And, uh, what's
our authorization?
We're calling it a P-1 training op.
F.B.I. Approval.
[Man]
Kruger and Jones, sir.
We were with the 22nd Marine
expeditionary unit. Kramer sent us.
- Nice haircut.
- [Hicks] Thirty months in a federal penitentiary...
at Marion, Illinois, for a G.V.H. -1... on
your gunnery sergeant... what's that about?
The guy was an asshole, sir,
and he deserved it, if you'll excuse me.
[Horns Honking]
[Man On TV]
All new, designed for today.
[Woman On TV]
The electric car is here.
[Man]
A sedan for you.
[Woman Reporter] I'm standing by
live at the Lockraven Reservoir...
right now, where police and fire
officials are in the process of removing...
a classic Mercedes owned by Republican
congressman Phillip Hamersly.
You may be able to see it here,
being removed in the background.
Now, fire and police officials
aren't saying much at this point.
Here's what I do know.
I have been told that the congressman...
was alone in the vehicle when this
accident happened just under an hour ago.
You may know that the congressman
suffers from a heart condition.
Homicide investigators have told me that
they did find a bottle of pills in his lap.
That might mean that the congressman...
and I speculate here...
may have suffered a heart attack before
going into the Lockraven Reservoir.
- [Computer Beeping]
- I am also told that there was no one in the car...
Fuck a duck.
Holy shit!
...on the ground,
and is currently with police.
He's from Syracuse, New York.
The congressman was an opponent of the
Telecommunications Security and Privacy Act.
- [Phone Ringing]
- News desk.
Lenny, you are not going to believe
what I have in my possession.
- Zavitz. Long time.
- Lenny, I've got...
the Phil Hamersly murder
on videotape.
Phil Hamersly died
of a heart attack.
Negative. Hamersly was professionally
wasted under the direction...
of some anal-retentive with what looks
like a serious vitamin D deficiency.
- How did you get this tape?
- My conservation study at the lake photographed the murder.
- You're kidding me!
- The camera was aimed straight across at the pier,
right where Phil Hamersly
was killed.
- How fast can you get that tape over here?
- I'm making a copy right now.
- [Cell Phone Ringing]
- Uh, Mark, I have to take this.
Good. Thank you.
Call if you need
anything.
[Phone Chimes, Beeps]
Fiedler,
is this line secure?
- Yes, it is, sir.
- Go ahead.
Zavitz is speaking
to a Lenny Bloom,
a former anti-war activist.
He publishes a variety of left-wing
newsletters on various political subjects.
- He's taking the tape now to Bloom's offices. Over.
- Put a tap on Bloom.
- And give us a dedicated satellite for this operation.
- It's already done.
Yeah, so, Julie,
I'm gonna take the rest of the day.
Finish up my Christmas shopping.
Take my mind off things.
Hey, do chicks dig
lingerie?
All right. I'll see you
in the morning.
¤¤ [Pop]
- Hi.
How you doin'?
Why, hello.
- Hi. Can I help you?
- Hey, hi.
- Uh, yes.
- Do you see something you like?
- Uh, I'm married.
- That's allowed.
Uh, um, I just...
I need... I need some,
uh, a...
a Christmas present.
- For your wife? - Yes, of-of
s-several years. We're ver... Uh, yes.
- You want some lingerie for your wife?
- Yes-Yes, I would.
Do you like
Christian Dior?
You know, I have to be really honest
with you. Um, I'm not really...
- experienced in this.
- Get out of town!
I- I mean, don't get me wrong. I mean,
I'm-I'm experienced, you know, from...
- Yeah. Right.
- From a certain perspective, I-I just...
I don't want to come in here and,
you know, look stupid. [Chuckles]
- [Forced Chuckling]
- Too late.
- Yeah. What size?
- I'm sorry?
- Oh, my wife. Oh, uh, she's, um...
- Yeah.
- She's about... She's...
- Size six.
Yeah, right, she's, uh...
She's ab... She's, uh... she's a six.
Right. And what
about cup size?
Um...
Oh! Oh, she's
way bigger than that.
I mean, not...
I mean, not noticeably.
- Oops.
- Should have gotten her a watch.
- [Knock At Door]
- [Woman] Hello?
- It's me, Ruthie.
- Shit.
They disconnected
my phone again.
Uh, mine's not working either.
I think it's a problem with the line.
Um...
Let me borrow some change
for the pay phone, man.
Come on.
I gotta call Dr. Mike.
Danny!
Danny, I always pay you back.
Come on!
Danny!
- [Ruthie] Open the door! -
[Phone Beeping] - [Phone Beeping]
Shit. Fuck.
- [Ruthie] Come on, man!
- Uh, one minute.
- I'm goin'.
- Come on, Danny!
Come on. Come on.
- Oh, shit.
- [Computer Beeps]
Shit.
It's not working.
I got him! I got him!
He's rabbiting!
- [Grunting]
- He's out the back.
Give me real-time imagery
coverage at LAT 38, 55, LONG 77, 00.
[Man] Got it.
Base, this is local control.
Requesting immediate
keyhole visual tasking.
Maximum resolution,
LAT 38, 55, LONG 77, 00. Over.
Roger that. I'll need a minute
on satellite visual. Over.
Run, run, Danny! They got guns!
[Screams]
- Where is he?
- He's on the roof. Right there.
[Beeping]
[Man]
Okay, satellite imagery coming through.
Roger that.
Patch visual, my location.
Confirm visual.
Thank you much.
All units:
Target heading north on rooftop.
Columbia and 18th.
Request immediate visual support. Over.
[Man]
Roger that. We have visual.
Everybody move. He just jumped
to the adjacent building.
- All units, he is entering rear entrance of Capt. Ike's.
- [Man] Roger.
- [Shouting]
- [Meows]
- Get out of the way!
- [Pistol Cocks]
- [People Screaming]
- [Man] Hey!
Air One, be advised, suspect
heading towards front entrance.
- Detail front of building on Columbia.
- [Man] Copy that.
I got him!
- [Horn Blares]
- All units, target entering the barbershop.
- Hah! Bullshit! We lost him; we lost him.
- We lost him!
Units in pursuit, target seen exiting
rear of barbershop in alley. Follow.
[Barking]
- I'm blank. I can't see anything.
- We lost the visual.
- I'm blank. What do you got?
- Who's got him?
Oh!
Zavitz!
Dan Zavitz!
It's me, Bobby Dean. We were at
Georgetown together. You okay?
- Help me.
- Are you hurt?
What do you think of this one, sir?
Yeah, this is Becky.
- Becky, say hi.
- I'm s... Can I have second, please?
- He's right on top of Pratt. Running down Connecticut.
- Right.
- He's on your 6:00. Turn around.
- Got him!
- Move, move, move. Get out of the way!
- [Woman Screams]
Hey, hey!
Come back, man! Come back!
- Hey, I got him!
- [Tires Screeching]
Target northbound...
northbound on Connecticut.
[Man]
Okay, got him.
- Go, go, go, go!
- [Horns Blaring]
Switching targets. Heading southbound
towards DuPont circle.
Stop!
[Siren Wailing]
[Horn Blaring]
Target down on Connecticut Avenue.
Air One confirm.
[Man] Target is down.
Target is down permanently.
- [Chattering]
- [Whistle Blowing]
- What happened?
- A guy on a bike got creamed.
[Sighs]
Oh, Jesus.
[Turns Ignition Off]
[Sighs]
- I'm beatin' you.
- Yeah, right.
Oh, you are.
Hey, hey!
- I'm beatin' you.
- No, I'm beatin' you.
- Hello.
- Hi, Mr. Dean.
Am I in the wrong house?
I'm looking for and eight-year-old boy,
about yea high.
Kinda good-looking.
Allegedly my son.
- [Both] No.
- Hmm. Maybe he's behind the TV.
- Eric?
- [Boys Protesting]
- Eric? - [Protesting
Continues] - What? What?
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Are those my Christmas presents?
- Yep, some of them.
- Can I open them?
- Yeah, sure, here you go.
- Seriously?
- In your dreams, buddy. Beat it.
- Dad!
- Are you staying for dinner tonight, Dylan?
- If it's okay with you.
- Got any money?
- He's kidding.
- I'm going to sleep over at Dylan's, okay?
- Did you ask your mother?
I was going to,
but she's too busy yelling at the TV.
Oh, well there goes the Fourth
Amendment... what's left of it.
- Hey, Maria.
- Hello, Mr. Bobby.
- [TV Blaring]
- [Smooches]
- [Growls, Barks] - Hey, you're about
a bark-and- a- half from being homeless.
Baby, listen to
this fascist gas bag.
- Uh-oh. ... and freedom
have always existed in a... -
in a very precarious balance,
and when buildings start blowing up,
- people's priorities change.
- He's got a point there, sweetie.
- Bobby!
- I mean, who is this idiot?
He is talking about ending
personal privacy.
- You want your phone tapped?
- I'm not plannin' on blowing up the country.
Well, how do we know until we've heard
all your dirty little secrets?
- You're just gonna have to trust me.
- Hmm.
Oh, I know.
We'll just tap the criminals.
We won't suspend the civil rights
of the good people.
- Right.
- Then who decides which is which?
- I think you should.
- Bobby, I think you should take this more seriously.
Honey, I think you're taking it
seriously enough for both of us,
and half the people
on the block.
Tens of millions of foreign nationals
living within our borders,
and many of these people consider
the United States their enemy.
- They see acts of terrorism...
- Do you remember Daniel Zavitz?
- We were at Georgetown together?
- Vaguely.
- I saw him today.
- How's he doing?
- He's dead.
- What?
- He got hit by a fire engine pretty much in front of my eyes.
- My God!
I ran into him in a store,
and he was upset about something.
- About what?
- I don't know.
Before we had a chance to talk about it,
he ran out of the store,
and next time I saw him,
he was dead.
Baby!
Come here.
Ohh, I love you
so much!
I love you, too,
sweetie.
That's not even to mention the gangster
that threatened to kill me today.
- Hah! Very funny!
- Oh, you think?
- Hilarious.
- Mmm. What'd you get me?
A bowling ball.
No more of that MSNBC terrorist talk.
You're scaring the kids.
We'll be back with your phone calls for
Congressman Sam Albert right after this.
- Tell me.
- Zavitz is dead. So is Lenny, the guy from the paper.
- What about the tape?
- We found the original in Zavitz's apartment.
- The original?
- There was a copy.
- There was a copy?
- I think so, sir.
- Any more good news?
- They never made it to the paper, but there was a private contact.
- Who was that?
- Several indiscriminants and one primary.
- Who?
- Robert Dean, a D.C. Labor lawyer.
Lives in Georgetown with his wife,
Carla Dean. She's also an attorney.
She's with the A.C.L.U.,
as it happens.
I suppose he could've given it
directly to Bob Woodward.
Maybe we dodged a bullet.
Find out what Dean knows.
Make contact.
- Yes, sir.
- I hate doing this at Christmas.
[Hicks] Fiedler,
we need a complete FinCEN, EPIC...
and a DRD work-up
on a Robert Clayton Dean.
His social's 986-26-0901.
Pull up keyhole data files, okay?
Let's go!
Let's get this show on the road!
Eric, just call me in the morning
when you want me to come pick you up.
You know, if you decide
you want to stay at Dylan's...
till the end of the weekend or the end of
the century, your mom and I have discussed it.
It'll be difficult initially,
but we think we can live with it.
Dad's kidding.
He's gonna miss you, just like me.
[Panting]
Honey, hurry back.
- You know what that means. - Mmm-hmm.
That you're gonna be asleep when I get back.
That only happened
one time, sweetie.
[Fiedler] We're running
a comprehensive database search.
Brian did a preliminary
analysis and comparison,
and he came up with
some pretty interesting stuff.
Thanks, Brian.
Thank you.
Prioritize his phone bill.
Who's he been calling?
- Oh, man. Check this one.
- Who?
Rachel F-for-you-know-what Banks. God,
would I love to have her ruin my life.
Do a cross.
They were at Georgetown
together, sophomore year.
They have the same address,
same phone number.
They remain close. Many calls,
regardless of marriage.
- [Fiedler] Oh, here we go.
- [Hicks] What?
Dean, over the past
18 months,
has four, five, seven cash
withdrawals of 4,000, 5,000,
and up, and up,
and each time,
the delectable Miss Banks makes large cash
deposits of her own within a day or two.
- Blackmail?
- Well, her deposits aren't the same,
but let me figure this out.
- [Beeping]
- Oh, yes, they're exactly...
exactly 15% of the amount
Dean withdrew.
Brian, can we get some more?
[Whistles]
I mean, you know, we got the blimp cam,
we got the police officer cam,
we've got two A.T.M. Cameras,
but this is the one showing promise.
This is the security camera
at the underwear store. Freeze there.
- [Computer Beeps]
- Rotate us 75 degrees around the vertical, please.
Freeze there.
Times ten.
- [Tapping At Keyboard]
- [Beeping]
Focus on the drop.
Enhance, then forward
frame-by-frame.
All right. Now, just before the view's
blocked, there's a shape change in Dean's bag.
See the shadow variance?
See?
The shadow's wrong. Zavitz changed
the configuration of Dean's packages.
- Is it a tape?
- It's hard to say for sure. These things are...
- Can the computer take us around to the other side?
- It can hypothesize. Chris?
- Yeah?
- Can you rotate us...
75 degrees around
the vertical, please?
[Beeps]
- What do you think it is?
- It looks a lot bigger than a tape.
Zavitz had digital compression
equipment in his apartment.
He could've downloaded it
to anything.
Or maybe the bag twisted
in Dean's hand.
Or something moved in front of the light
and altered the shadow. Maybe it's nothing.
Maybe it's everything.
Let's get it and find out.
- Beat it. I got work to do.
- [Barking]
Go. Porsche!
Ohh!
- [Doorbell Chimes]
- Go away!
- [Porsche Barking]
- Damn it, Porsche!
- Hello, Mr. Dean?
- Uh, yes. Can I help you?
This is Detective Benning.
I'm Pratt. We're with D.C. Metro.
- Shh.
- Uh, sorry to bother you at home, sir.
We were hoping to ask you
a few questions about Daniel Zavitz.
- Wh... I'm s... Can I see your badges, please?
- Certainly, sir.
[Benning]
Sure.
All right. Come on.
Back up, Porsche.
- All right. Nice and smooth. Come on.
- Okay.
I didn't really see the accident.
I don't know whose fault it was.
- We're not here to talk about the accident, Mr. Dean.
- I'm sorry, I thought you said...
[Pratt] We should apologize
for the confusion, sir.
It's just that we're handling
a different aspect of the inquiry.
It turns out Mr. Zavitz was
involved in an extortion scheme.
- What kind of watch is that?
- It's an Omega.
- So you're not constrained by
attorney-client privilege? - [Barking]
- Shh-shh. Yeah, that's correct.
- You see, Mr. Dean,
we have reason to believe that Mr. Zavitz
may have passed sensitive materials to you.
- [Growls]
- What kind of materials?
[Pratt, Over Speaker] Well, sensitive,
so we were hoping you could tell us that.
[Dean Sighs]
No, he didn't pass me anything.
These voice stress points indicate
a really high degree of anxiety.
Anxiety about what?
That's the nature of physics. If he'd
given me something, I would've known.
- Oh, he's lying!
- What about your packages, sir?
Could something have slipped in amongst
the purchases without your knowledge?
Excuse me. Daniel Zavitz
did not give me anything.
- That's a Parker pen.
- It's a Mont Blanc.
He didn't secrete it
into any of my bodily orifices.
- Whatever it is, I don't have it.
- Could we look at them?
I don't think so.
Not without a warrant.
- Oh, Christ.
- This guy's good.
- How did you happen to be at Ruby's today?
- I was shopping for lingerie.
- That's still legal, isn't it?
- You buying that for your wife?
No, I was, uh,
picking something up for myself.
I do a little cross-dressing on the
weekends. You know, you'd be surprised...
how a nice pair of edible panties
can make a guy feel sexy.
We thought it might be
for Rachel Banks.
Good night, gentlemen.
- Good night, sir.
- Good night, Mr. Dean.
[Porsche Growls, Barks]
What are they talking about, Porsche?
There's nothing here.
Honey, I'm home.
- [Door Shuts]
- Uh, yeah, just a second, sweetie.
Well, either he's getting ready to do
something with it, or he doesn't know he has it.
Or he doesn't have it.
You know what I've seen?
I've seen killers walk free...
because the eyewitness
was an alcoholic.
I've seen sex offenders that couldn't be
touched because the victim was a call girl.
Credibility... It's the only currency that
means anything on this kind of playing field.
Dean's got the tape,
and he's gonna come out with it.
And when he does,
I want his credibility.
I want people to know he's lying
before they hear what he says.
We could take his wife and kid.
He'd give it up for them.
We'd have the police and the F.B.I.
All over this in 24 hours.
Put taps on his 20 most frequently called
numbers, and let's get into his life.
The union situation has-has mob
written all over it.
And he's definitely vulnerable
on Rachel Banks.
I want to know about his wife,
I want to know about his parents,
I want to know about his gambling problems,
his urine samples, his porno rentals.
I want to use every means possible
to get what we need.
Because this little son of a bitch is not
going to be the final chapter of my life.
- [Carla] Tell me something.
- [Dean] Uh-oh.
How did you find out Pintero
was associated with union officials?
I'm just that good.
I hired an investigator.
- Hey.
- Shut up the dog!
My mom used to have
one of these. Come on.
Ow!
The dog bit me!
- Who was the investigator?
- Wh-What do you mean? His name?
Come on, Bobby. You know what I'm
asking. Is it the guy who Rachel knows?
Why do... Why do we have to go
through this every time?
- Baby, I'm just asking, okay?
- Carla,
Rachel Banks is not
an issue anymore.
You are the only woman
in the world for me.
You and Janet Jackson.
- [Scoffs] - I have to be honest.
If-If Janet Jackson called me,
I w... I might have to change
my last name to Jackson.
- Yeah, right. I'd have to break that woman's legs too.
- [Dean Snickering]
[Camera Shutter Clicking]
- Lower, like kids would do it.
- You sound like a fuckin' old lady. Shut up.
Ooh, sensitive.
Jones has some issues
we need to resolve.
- Oh. Control, they are home.
- Uh-oh.
Move, guys.
Oh, nice blender.
Oh, my God.
- [Barking]
- [Carla] Oh, Porsche.
Shh.
Oh, damn.
The dog is green.
[Chuckles]
Jones painted the... the dog!
This is Robert Dean, 2811 Sutton.
I'd like to report a break-in.
I don't know. It's been vandalized.
From the looks of it, i-it's kids,
but I need
a squad car here immediately.
[Siren Wailing]
Here we go.
We'll be checking out the rest
of the house, sir, ma'am.
At least
they left me one.
How do you know
it wasn't Pintero?
I don't. It was just
kind of frivolous.
I guess I'm just hopin'
it was kids.
John.
What have we here?
I think we have
a winner.
Phone for phone.
[Man]
Take any of your clothes?
No, they threw all my shoes
and suits in the tub,
and spray painted
my damn dog.
- Black.
Perfect.
How does that look?
Paging Mr. Dean.
We have you bugged,
Mr. Dean.
They thrashed my computers, my
big-screen TV... They took my blender.
- What about jewelry?
- Nope.
- What about silverware?
- Nope. Just my blender.
- Blender, huh?
- Loved that blender.
You know, I did stuff
when I was a kid.
I mean, not breaking-and-entering,
but, you know, stuff.
Yeah, we all did stuff. I just wish
they hadn't stolen my damn blender.
You seem a little attached
to this blender, Robert.
Yeah, well, some people meditate,
some people get massages.
- I blend.
- You're really weird, you know that?
Yeah, then on top of it, the only suit
they leave me is three years old.
Hasn't gotten any better
with age.
[Dean] Blow over? I'm not gonna sit
around and wait for this to blow over!
Jerry, I-I'm suing their right-wing
asses right into Chapter 11!
This is flagrant! They never even called
to see what my side of the story was!
- [Knock At Door]
- They have no Sullivan protection with this!
- Mr. Dean, Rachel Banks is on line one.
- Yes.
And Silverberg and Blake would like
to see you in the conference room.
Uh, Jerry,
I got to take this call. All right.
Hey, what's up?
My firm called me this morning
telling me not to come in.
- What? Why not?
- I don't know.
Reporters are calling, asking me
about my relationship with you...
and how long
I've worked for the mob.
- The mob, Bobby.
- Jesus.
- Do you know how hard I worked to get this job?
- Yeah, I know. I know.
Mr. Dean, Silverberg and Blake are still
waiting to see you in the conference room.
- I heard you the first time. Thank you.
- You got your own problems.
- Uh, no, Rachel. It's fine.
- [Phone Hangs Up]
Oh, damn it!
I just got off the phone
with a source that I trust.
A grand jury is being convened
to look into your labor practice...
as far back as the
electrical workers' strike.
And why is that?
They claim you helped create a shell
company for Sam Villotti in Zurich.
And through your continuing relationship,
the Peitso family has been able...
to exert influence and provide
false witness to discredit our case.
- Oh, well, that's true.
- You're admitting it?
Sure. Everything except
setting up a company in Zurich.
Or even knowing anyone
named Sam Villotti.
Or having any relationship whatsoever
to the Peitso family!
This is ridiculous!
- Robert...
- Mark, I'm telling you.
This is Pintero.
He's coming back after me.
You give me one week... one week
and four guys from litigation,
and I guarantee you,
we'll have this guy begging us...
Tell us
about Rachel Banks.
Tell you what? Uh, she was my
girlfriend the second year of law school.
We keep in touch. We-We toss one another
some work every once in awhile. That's it.
Did you have an affair
with her four years ago?
You ever beat off
in the shower, Brian?
Hmm? You ever have
any homosexual thoughts?
- Bobby, that is...
- None of my fucking business! You're damn right it's not!
I love my wife,
and I love my son...
absolutely, with no equivocations, and
that's none of your fuckin' business either.
Uh, we think that you
should take a leave of absence...
until we're able
to, uh, sort all this out.
- Are you firing me?
- I think you just fired yourself.
Carla!
Where is she, Jen?
Don't go in there.
She doesn't want to talk to you.
- Why not?
- Because she's reading the paper.
Asshole.
Carla...
How could you let me
find out like this?
I'm findin' out like this. This is
all lies. None of this stuff is true.
So you're saying
you weren't there with her?
Yes, I had lunch with her.
We have lunch once a month.
She's the contact for the investigator,
Brill. You were right about that.
Someone must have taken this picture off
the security camera outside the restaurant.
- You said she wasn't an issue.
- She's not!
I have to see her for business.
And I knew if I told you that...
Bobby, you had an affair
with this woman! An affair.
We went to a counselor
for a year!
And now you're standin' there
lyin' about even seein' her?
You make me sick!
Carla, I am smeared all over the newspapers for money
- laundering schemes, mob ties...
I lost my job.
I am asking you.
I am asking you to please just trust me
on this Rachel Banks thing right now.
How in God's name
can I trust you?
Bobby, I want you
to leave.
Carla, I'm telling you
that this is all bullshit!
I don't want
to hear anything else.
I cannot think with you in my face.
I want you to leave.
What do you need to think about?
I'm telling you it's bullshit!
Just leave, so I can think!
For me, okay? Just leave.
Just go, Bobby.
Go.
Go!
- You want a blend?
- Yeah.
Thanks.
- Hi.
- Hi. I'd like to have a room for the evening, please.
Okay.
Thank you.
- [Computer Beeps]
- [Woman] I'm sorry, sir. This card was declined.
Declined? This is a brand-new card.
Try it again, please.
Yes, sir.
- [Computer Beeps]
- You know, maybe it's not activated yet.
Thank you.
Run this one, please.
- Thank you.
- Yes, sir.
No, it didn't
go through.
- But I'll try it again.
- No, thank you.
- My briefcase is gone.
- Excuse me, sir?
- My briefcase was right here.
- Are you sure you brought it in?
Yes, I'm sure
I brought it in!
[On Cell Phone] Hi. This is Rachel.
Leave a message after the beep.
- Hey, Rachel, it's Bobby. I need to talk to you,
- [Beeping]
And I need to talk to you
face-to-face.
Meet me tomorrow, 11:00 a. m.,
Mount Vernon Square. I'll see you then.
Yes.
All right, we're moving into
phase two of the training op.
Selby's gonna brief you on it,
so listen up, okay?
We're gonna be following the subjects
through the square.
We're gonna have three listening stations
and two video surveillance units...
with unidirectional mikes.
Pratt, you're three.
Jones, Fiedler, Krug,
you guys are at ground level.
You'll be following the targets.
You move when I say,
you go when I say.
All handoffs go
on my command.
Now, for the uninitiated,
if we don't have line-of-sight,
we can't hear
what they say, right?
- Right?
- Yeah. Got it.
- All right. You guys clear?
- Yeah.
Jones, Krug, what, are you guys
from communications?
- No, we're ops.
- You can tell by their haircuts.
[Chattering, Indistinct]
I would like to sit down
with Mr. Pintero in private...
so he and I can discuss
what's happening to me.
I called; they said
he was here.
Mr. Pintero would like
to help you.
[Chuckles]
But he won't.
- And why not?
- Well, first, you haven't told him...
who made the tape,
and second,
we've spent hundreds
of thousands of dollars...
on shyster lawyers
just like you...
because of shyster lawyers
just like you.
Actually, I believe the slur "shyster"
is generally reserved...
for Jewish attorneys.
I believe the proper slur
for someone like myself...
would be, uh,
"eggplant. "
Boom. This kid gets brighter
every time I see him.
[Siren Wailing]
[Rachel]
You said 11:00 sharp.
I know. Uh,
Christmas traffic is horrible.
You know, it's not so smart, us being
seen together in public like this.
- Do we have anything to hide?
- Heavy background on one. Can we do better on two?
- [Rachel] Unfortunately not.
- Two is better.
[Rachel]
The I.R.S. Contacted me this morning.
- Two, you're good. Hold position.
- They say my lifestyle...
- exceeds my income.
- Ohh. You're being audited?
For the last four years.
What's going on, Bobby?
Uh, look, don't worry about that. My
firm will represent you free of charge.
- [Seth] Eighty percent.
- You don't work there anymore, remember?
It's a temporary
situation.
- Your 80's becoming a 20. Move to audio three.
- On three. Much better.
- [Rachel] We're screwed.
- Wake up, one.
[Rachel]
We are out.
Rachel,
I'm going to fix this.
- How?
- Tell me about Brill.
- Did he say "Bill"? - No, "Brill,"
with an "R." - I can't do that.
- Cross-reference Rachel's file.
See if "Brill" comes up. - Got it.
Rachel, don't you see that he
is the key to this whole mess?
From the second you gave me that tape,
my life has been falling apart.
You assured me
that this-this guy was legit.
- You needed information; I got it for you.
- Two, you're good.
- Three is good.
- This conversation is over.
- [Dean Stammering]
- Okay, here we go.
- [Dean Continues, Indistinct]
- Two, you gotta do better.
- Shit.
- You want your life back?
I don't have
a life.
I'm in love
with a married man.
Okay, I have 'em
on the bench.
Rachel,
I'm sorry, but there's nothing
I can do about that.
What makes you think
it's you?
It's not me?
I j... I just as-assumed
from...
- You're a moron, you know that?
- Yes. I know.
Rachel, you're gonna have
to tell me about Brill.
Let's get out of here.
All right.
They're on the move.
- Comin' to three. - Stay
with 'em. - I got 40, 20...
- [Garbled Audio]
- You're following through trees. Two, can you track them?
I have lost line-of-sight.
Repeat, I have lost line-of-sight.
- Three, you've got nothing.
- I've lost line-of-sight. I'm out.
We've lost audio; it's gone. But we still
have his tracers. We can still follow 'em.
When I need
to reach Brill,
I chalk the mailbox
outside my house.
When he crosses the mark,
I make the drop.
The location's always the same...
same time, same place.
3:00 p. m. Ferry
to Gibson Island.
- [Dean] You ever see him in person?
- He's the cautious type.
He's not gonna like you
trackin' him down.
The drop is
behind seat 32.
I leave something;
he picks it up later.
[Horn Blaring]
I'm sorry it took so long. I had to
make sure you weren't being followed.
- Brill.
- Brill's dead.
Died of smallpox when he was two.
Buried in a field in Kansas.
- What is that? - It's a
bug-sweeper. - [Beeping]
- Take off your left shoe.
- What does it mean when...
Take off your shoe. I don't have time to
explain. Take off your shoe right now.
Come on.
It's a beacon transmitter.
Thousand-yard range.
They're close.
Let's go.
Who is "they"?
And why are they puttin' things
in my shoes?
No, get in the back,
like you're a customer.
Everything's gone... the wife,
job, bank accounts, everything.
You said Zavitz was behind
an extortion scheme?
- No, they said it.
- You were the last one that talked to him?
- Yeah.
- What did he say?
- He said, "Help me, Bobby. "
- Help me with what?
I don't know.
We never got around to that.
- What did he give you?
- Nothing. He didn't give me anything.
[Tires Screeching,
Horn Honking]
Listen, you gotta come clean.
If you bullshit me, I can't help you.
- He didn't give me anything.
- A name? A phone number?
Nothing!
He didn't give me anything!
- Who the hell is that?
- Just somebody trying to get our attention.
Well, he's doing
a good job.
Two-zero-nine to anybody.
I need help.
- Who you calling? I thought you worked alone.
- Shut up a second.
[Tires Screeching]
[Horn Honking,]
Tires Screeching]
Stay exactly
where you are.
Look what you did
to my car!
- [Beeping]
- Shit!
¤¤ ["Twelve Days
Of Christmas"]
Okay, gentlemen, we have a subject
entering the structure...
on the northeast corner
of Chambers and Light.
- That's 105 Chambers Avenue.
- Run a check on all six tracers.
[Van]
All six tracers are operative.
- Call up geo-position.
- Yeah, I got it.
- Task keyhole coordinates.
- LAT, 39 degrees, 14 minutes. LONG, 74 degrees, 39 minutes.
[Beeping]
[Ringing]
- Hello.
- Carla, don't hang up on me.
- Robert, do you know what I'm looking at right now?
- Carla, listen.
Photographs of you and Rachel
taken today. Is this true?
Carla... Carla, how did
you get the pictures?
By messenger, Robert!
By messenger.
- What does it matter?
- [Sighs] Look, all right, um...
Something's going on.
I don't know who it is.
Robert,
I went to the store today,
and my A.T.M.
And my credit cards didn't work.
- I know. Mine either.
- I couldn't buy food.
- I gotta go.
- What do you mean you gotta go?
Carla... Carla,
I gotta... I gotta go.
Wait a minute...
Get on the fucking elevator.
- [Man Chattering]
- Oh, really?
[Elevator Dings]
Got vertical movement here.
Elevator.
He's in an elevator.
- We're losing our tracking. - Anybody
got a visual? - We need a better signal.
- Are you guys there yet?
- Negative.
[Elevator Dings]
What the fuck
is going on?
- [Grunts]
- Shh.
Wait. They stopped.
Hold it.
- I don't know what your problem...
- Shh.
I'm getting high-frequency clutter.
We lost tracers one, two and six.
- Their signals are dead. Something is wrong.
- [Switch Clicks]
Get up.
- Tracers three, four and five are on their way up.
- He's getting help, boys.
We had an arrangement.
No contact. You broke the rules.
Air One, we need
to establish visual on the rooftop,
northeast corner,
Chambers and Light.
Copy that. Rooftop,
northeast corner, Chambers and Light.
Do you know how many federal agents
you had following you on that ferry?
- I don't...
- Who are you working for?
- I'm not working...
- Is that about me? Am I a target here?
- Do they know me?
- Who is "they"?
- I don't know what you're talking about!
- [Elevator Dings]
- You're either very smart or incredibly stupid.
Get off. Come on.
- I got separating signals.
- Tracer three is on its way down.
Where did he go?
How did you find out about the ferry?
- Who set that up for you?
- Rachel did. Who was that other guy?
- What did he say, exactly?
- He said he was Brill.
Did he say it or did you, and he
picked up on it? Come on. Think.
- Shit, I said it.
- Goddamn it. That's why I have rules.
- Is all this about Pintero?
- You think the mob uses devices like this?
- Excuse me, sir. Where are your elevators?
- Right over there.
In your phone was a G.P.S. Sat-tracker.
Pulse is at 24 gigahertz.
- I don't know what that means.
- It's like a Lo Jack.
- Only two generations better than what the police have.
- What does that mean?
- You speak English?
- Obviously not that well.
You're kind of a jerk,
aren't you?
- The N.S.A. Can read the time off your fucking wristwatch.
- Enough of this bullshit.
Either shoot me or tell me
what the fuck is going on!
Jones, take the stairs. Krug,
hold the perimeter. Come on my signal.
The National Security Agency
conducts worldwide surveillance.
Fax, phones,
satellite communication.
They're the only ones in the country who
could possibly have anything like this.
- Why are they after me?
- I don't know, and I don't wanna know.
Here they come. I thought these sat
dishes would scramble their signals.
Control, this is Air One.
Repeat coordinates.
105 Chambers Avenue.
You're transmitting.
They still have a signal on you.
Your collar, belt, zipper.
- Get rid of your clothes.
- Then what am I supposed to do?
Nothing. You live another day,
I'll be very impressed.
Two targets, rooftop,
north side.
Two targets, rooftop.
Maintain visual, please.
- You have something they want.
- I don't have anything!
Maybe you do and you don't know it.
Stay away from Rachel and me.
Come near either one of us, I'm gonna
kill you. Get rid of your watch.
- My wife gave me this for our anniversary.
- Then keep it.
Stay off the phone.
- Either he just committed suicide here...
- Or he learned to fly.
- Air One, stay with him.
- Target's on the move.
Satellite imagery
coming through.
One meter res layering wireframe
coming your way. Over.
Okay, gentlemen,
we're back on-line.
Wireframe download complete.
We have a tracer in the stairwell
on 20 traveling down.
Nineteen. Eighteen.
- Seventeen.
- Moving up!
He's out of the stairwell
on 17. Go to 17.
[Elevator Dings]
Oh, shit.
[Knocking]
- [Beeping]
- Shit.
[Knocking]
Mr. Wu.
- Target is holding on 17. Zoom three Mag.
- Zooming.
[Knocking]
Mr. Wu.
- [Beeping]
- [Door Opens]
- Thank you very much.
- You're welcome.
Hi. I'm from
hotel hospitality and evaluation.
No, no. No tip. I'm fine.
Thank you. No tip.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I wanna make sure you folks have everything
you need to be completely comfortable.
- [Beeping]
- I got something here.
- We got him.
Krug, Jones, get your asses up here
to the 17th floor.
That's really important
to us here.
[Pratt Knocking]
Mr. Dean?
- I'd like to talk to you.
- Aw, shit.
- My clothes.
- [Speaking Chinese]
- Shit!
- Yeah.
- [Speaking Chinese]
- [Knocking] Mr. Dean?
- Whoo! [Speaking Chinese]
- [Pratt] Mr. Dean?
Come to the door,
and we can work this out.
I got rabies or something.
I can't do it.
It'a a go.
[Screaming]
- That's our last tracer.
- Mr. Dean!
Let's not let this get out of hand.
Let's not involve the hotel guests.
Down, ma'am, sir.
Sit down. Thank you.
- Door!
- Everything's gonna be all right, folks.
Krug, balcony!
Air One, we got him.
He's dropped to the 16th floor.
Air One, visual support. Check
perimeter, south side of the building.
Ten-four, Control.
We have visual.
- He jumped to 15. Go to 15.
- Go!
[ Jones]
Grab his clothes.
- Let's go, gentlemen. Weapons away.
- [Speaking Chinese]
- Go!
- [Grunts]
Move!
Dean, open this door,
goddamn it!
[Men Shouting]
Dean, come on now!
We just wanna talk! Open the door!
[Fire Alarm Ringing]
- [Ringing Continues]
- Open that door.
[Yelling]
D.C. Metro.
Our partner's trapped inside.
We gotta evacuate
this building.
[Sirens Blaring,
Horns Honking]
Control, we have
approaching emergency vehicles.
The show's going public,
and they're coming in the front door.
- Stand down. Maintain visual perimeter.
- We're outta here.
[Firemen Shouting]
Chavez on the 15th floor. We got
one man trapped and possibly down.
There's a guy
trapped in there.
You're going
to be okay, guy.
[Siren Blaring]
- Okay, we are traveling. Known destination?
- St. Elizabeth's.
- We need sat backup now.
- It's already done.
Take it easy, guy.
You're going to be all right.
Calm down. It's okay.
- Easy, fella.
- I gotta go. Stop the ambulance.
- Tell him to stop it now! - Pull
over, George. - Take it easy, fella.
- [Horn Honking] - He's
getting out! - Son of a bitch!
He's escaped the ambulance and he's
on foot. But our guys are in pursuit.
- Task keyhole that coordinate.
- LAT, 39 degrees, 27 minutes.
LONG, 74 degrees,
42 minutes.
- Move, guys.
- Go, go, go! Damn it! Go around!
- You're on. Go.
- Tunnel Control, This is D.C. Metro.
In pursuit armed felon in tunnel.
Requesting video help.
Metro, this is Tunnel Control. We got a 20
on your suspect heading south in tunnel six.
Copy that.
We got him. He's right
in front of us. Tunnel six.
He's heading south down tunnel six.
He's got nowhere to go.
He's crossed over.
He's on the wrong side.
Stop! Stop!
We lost him. We lost him.
Son of a bitch! Pull over.
- He's currently entering vertical stairwell five.
- Where does that lead?
Five leads to main access
to sub-ventilation tunnel.
- Closest vehicular access?
- Adjacent utility entrance, south side.
He's in the ventilation tunnel. Proceed to the
adjacent utility entrance on the south side.
- There is no visual coverage.
- He's in a ventilation tunnel.
To the service entrance at
the south end! Come on! Let's go!
Come on! Go!
[Yells]
[Cars Approaching]
[Grunting]
[Horn Honking]
[Singing Reggae]
Normally,
I wouldn't do this.
Do you guys have him?
Talk to me, people.
[Horns Honking]
[Horns Honking,
Tires Screeching]
- Shit!
I don't understand
why this is so difficult.
He shed the sensors.
He's clever. And he's had help.
- Maybe it's the real Brill.
- There's 23 Brills in the Baltimore/D.C. Area.
None of them check out.
We're running it through EPIC now.
- Do you think we're being set up?
- Somebody in the agency?
I don't know.
It just tastes
a little off, doesn't it?
- I know what you mean.
- Let's raise the stakes.
Make things a bit more serious for Mr.
Dean. We'll both think about how, okay?
Okay. Good.
- Anything wrong?
- No.
You should have made deputy director
two years ago, maybe three.
But it'll happen now. Once this bill
passes, that'll be it for you.
Thanks, Marie.
[Barking]
Porsche, what are you
barking at, boy?
[Growling]
[Barking]
Porsche?
- It's me.
- I know it's you. You scared the shit out of me.
The house is bugged. Everything
you say, they can hear and maybe see.
Listen to me.
Listen, listen.
I never... I swear to God.
I never... This is the truth.
I never, ever since the problem,
touched Rachel like that.
I never even looked at her
like that, honey. I love you.
I love you, and that is it.
That is it. Only you.
What about Eric?
And Eric.
And I love your family.
Except for your dad.
I need you. I need you real bad.
I need you, okay?
Okay.
I told you, Bobby.
I told you they had
this type of capability.
And that goddamn privacy bill is just
another way for them to expand the power.
- Shh.
- Don't you "shh" me.
You were right. I was wrong. But this is
not the time for the "I told you so" speech.
That day when Daniel Zavitz got hit
by the fire truck, he was running.
The people that were chasing him,
that's the people that are chasing me.
- Bobby, are you serious?
- Go to Philadelphia, stay with your family.
- Just give me time to work this out.
- I don't think so.
They're not chasing me
out of my house.
- I picked those drapes.
- Shh, shh, shh. Nobody cares about the drapes.
Just one time can I make
some decisions around here?
Just go to Philadelphia.
I need you to do that for me, okay?
- Okay.
- I miss you.
Oh, God.
- You can't wear that. That's a Christmas present.
- I know. I'm sorry.
But, baby, I missed you.
I was lonely.
How you just gonna go
through my stuff like that?
Until I actually give it to you,
that's still mine.
Yeah, but it looks better on me,
don't you think?
Baby, you're
as bad as Eric.
I missed you so much.
- What?
- That was the night.
That was the night that
I came home with the presents.
- Where is Eric?
- He's at Dylan's house.
He's probably on the way to school.
What's going on?
[Gasps]
What are you doing with that?
- Shh, baby. Shh, shh.
- What do you want me to do with this?
Get me some money. I need some clothes.
Tell Maria we need her car.
Chances are they wouldn't have
bugged it. Oh, shit. Eric.
The nanny is leaving.
- Please advise.
- Stay put.
We have satellite tracking
and Bingham at the school.
Aw, man, let me follow
the nanny.
She doesn't shave
her legs. Jesus!
Women like that
are so hot.
- [Dean] Is there anybody following us?
- No. No, Mr. Bobby.
Drive a little faster. I wanna catch 'em
before they get to school.
[Children Shouting]
- There they are.
- Pull up and tell them to get into the car.
Okay.
Eric, Dylan,
get in the car, please.
- No, we're okay.
- Get in the car right now.
- But school's right down the block.
- You heard me. Now, get.
- What's up, fellas?
- Dad?
No. Turn around.
Sit down. Face forward.
- But, Dad...
- What did I say, Eric?
We're gonna play a game.
Pick a spot and look right at it.
You can't let anyone know
I'm back here, okay?
How you been, E.?
I missed you, man.
I missed you, too, Dad.
Where did you go?
Oh, they've been keeping me
really busy on this case.
They're trying
to work me to death.
- Are you and Mom getting a divorce?
- Face forward.
What are you talking about?
No, we're not getting a divorce.
We had a little fight.
Sometimes married couples have fights.
- That's nothing for you to worry about.
- Who won the fight?
This is your dad, Eric.
When I put my foot down, that's it.
- My mom won.
- I have a question I need to ask you.
It is absolutely imperative
that you tell me the truth.
Now, no matter what you say,
you are not going to get in trouble.
- All right? You ready?
- Yeah.
You remember that night I came home
with those Christmas presents...
I just looked in the bag, Dad. I wouldn't
have taken it, except it was already open.
All right, so we're clear. But I need
it. I promise I'll get you another one.
- Dad. It's broken.
- What's the matter?
It's not Eric's fault, Mr. Dean.
It was always broken.
The screen just scrambles
when you turn it on.
- But I need it. Do you have it here?
- Yeah, we have it.
Eric, just pass it
around the side to me.
[Dean] Yes. Hello. Hi.
My name is Leon Newman.
I'm sorry.
What's your name, ma'am?
Sergeant Miller. Yes,
we live at 454 Beaumont Terrace.
Actually, my mother lives there.
I'm calling for her.
There's been a van
sitting outside all day.
I'm not trying
to get anyone in trouble,
but I think they might be doing drugs
or something in there.
I was hoping you
could send a car by.
- [Beeping] - Thirty-one
Allison, all available units.
Check out a white van at 454 Beaumont
for a possible 1031 narcotics violation.
Oh, eat me. That's us.
[Knocking]
Rachel.
Oh, shit.
- [Door Handle Squeaking]
- Open the door. Open the door!
I thought I told you
to stay the fuck away from me.
Please, not now. Just drive.
- All right, what happened?
- Rachel's dead.
I told you not
to contact her. I told you.
Get out of the car.
- I think I found what they're looking for. My son had it.
- Get out of the fucking car.
Give me the toy.
You know
why they killed her?
Trying to make it
look like it was me.
They had my stuff planted
all over her house.
First, if you're a murder suspect,
you're gonna be easier to find,
and second, to discredit you,
in case you ever go public against them.
The N.S.A. Set you up.
It had nothing to do with Rachel.
Absolutely nothing.
- What have we got?
- We got nothing.
Pull up everything
we have on tape so far.
The square,
the house surveillance.
Van, give me the sat imagery
of the hotel roof.
Okay, here. These are the parametrics for
the space vehicle during data acquisition.
Can we take a look at this guy
who's helping him?
Can you get
a feature extraction?
Mm-mmm.
He never looks up.
- He's smart.
- Why does he have to look up?
The satellite's about 155 miles above
the earth. It can only look straight down.
- That's kind of limited.
- Maybe you can design a new one.
Maybe I will, idiot.
Stay put.
I need some food. I need to eat.
¤ Rockin' around
the Christmas tree ¤
¤ Let the Christmas
spirit ring ¤
¤ Later we'll have
some pumpkin pie ¤
¤ And we'll do
some caroling ¤
¤ You will get
a sentiment... ¤¤
[Ringing]
- Hello.
- Yeah, it's me.
- Oh, it's you, asshole. What are you calling me for?
- Shut up and listen.
Go to the house. Go.
Do not call Carla.
Rachel Banks is dead. The papers
will make it sound like I killed her.
Tell her
that I didn't do it.
Make sure she goes. Get her
out of there. Tell 'em I love 'em.
The call is coming from 840 McClean,
Baltimore, between Hood and St. Anne's.
Copy that. Yes!
What's up, man?
We're gonna have to look at your
surveillance tapes for the last 20 minutes.
- Hey, Larry!
- The surveillance footage is coming in now from Pratt.
Freeze it and process it
for face recognition.
Pratt, do we see
which way the car went?
No, sir. This kid here at the register
thinks that it might have went south.
Unfortunately,
the shot's too tight.
I got make, model and color,
but the plates are phony.
- Order satellite coverage on this sector.
- It's already done.
- You planning a quick getaway?
- Yeah, ever since I met you.
[Cat Purrs]
I hate to see the chicken
that lives in this coop.
This is where I work.
This has been my office for 15 years.
It's completely secure. Copper wire
mesh keeps the radio signals out.
[Fiedler] This is the satellite
imagery of the convenience store.
- They're in El Camino.
- [ John] Eighty-six.
[ John's Voice,
Indistinct]
- There it is.
- John, give us LAT 30, 64 minutes, LONG 72, 29 minutes.
- [ John] That's affirmative.
- [Reynolds] There they are.
Coming in from top left.
[ John's Voice,
Indistinct]
[Reynolds]
Let's get them.
[Brill]
I call it the jar.
No phone or utility lines
coming in.
Self-contained.
Unplugged from the world.
Nothing for a wire bug
to piggyback in on.
That leaves transmitters. It's easy
enough to signal-sweep for those.
Signal-sweeping for transmitters.
You're just a party animal.
The government's
been in bed...
with the entire telecommunications
industry since the '40s.
They've infected everything.
They can get into your bank statements,
your computer files, e-mail,
listen
to your phone calls.
- My wife's been saying that for years.
- Every wire, every airwave.
The more technology you use, the easier
it is for them to keep tabs on you.
It's a brave new world out there.
At least it better be.
There it goes.
It's some kind of simple encryption.
Oh, conspiracy theorists
of the world, unite.
It's more than a theory with me.
I'm a former conspirer.
I used to work for the N.S.A.
I was a communication analyst.
Listen to international calls,
calls from foreign nationalists.
That G.P.S. Tracking device we found
in your cellular telephone?
I designed one of the first models
in that series.
Fort Meade has 18 acres
of mainframe computers underground.
You're talking on the phone and you use
the word, "bomb," "president," "Allah,"
any of a hundred key words,
the computer recognizes it,
automatically records it, red flags it
for analysis; that was 20 years ago.
You know the Hubble Telescope
that looks up to the stars?
They've got over a hundred spy satellites
looking down at us. That's classified.
In the old days, we actually had
to tap a wire into your phone line.
Now calls bouncin' around on satellite,
they snatch right out of the air.
What's this?
- [Dean] That's Phil Hamersly.
- Jesus Christ.
[Sighs]
Who's this guy? I'm gonna check
the executive N.S.A. Files.
Let's run
the photo I.D. On him.
Reynolds, Thomas Brian.
Born 9-11-40.
Attended Episcopal School, D.C.
B.A., Harvard, PhD, Princeton.
On loan from the State Department
since '95.
This guy's not a professional.
He's a politician.
[Beeping]
Aw, shit! Take that.
- When was the last time you contacted somebody?
- When we stopped for food.
- Didn't I tell you not to use the telephone?
- I called from a pay phone.
- What did I tell you?
- You told me no calls.
I told you no calls.
- Get the cat. Get the cat.
- Hey, man...
- What's the cat's name?
- Babe.
Come here, baby. Come here, baby.
Baby, come, come. Come here!
- [Snarling]
- Shit!
Goddamn it.
All right, baby,
what do we got?
What the...
[Purrs]
[Beeping]
- Subjects exiting.
- Williams, get the hell out of there.
This bitch is gonna blow!
Go, go, go!
[Purrs]
Come on! Go!
Move! Move! Move!
[Shouting,
Indistinct]
Move! Move!
- What is happening?
- I blew up the building.
- Why?
- Because you made a phone call!
[Train Horn Blows]
- Tell him to pull over!
- Pull the vehicle over now!
Pull over now!
Pump action!
Gosh damn!
Fuel line
must be broken.
- Get it out! Goddamn!
- Stop the car!
[Yelling]
[Yelling Continues]
- Where's the disk?
- Shit!
No! Shit! Look,
is there any way to save it?
- Ah, that's ruined.
- What do we do?
- I'm leaving.
- Subjects heading west across the coal fields.
- You're leaving?
- The disk is gone.
We've got nothing.
It's over.
We have control.
Put down your weapons.
You think I wanted that idiot
to put that goddamn disk...
Who gives a fuck
what you wanted?
Since you've shown up, Rachel's dead
and the N.S.A.'s onto me.
Onto you? What do you mean
onto you? Onto you about what?
You're not the target.
I am.
We got him.
He's right in front of us.
Come on, come on.
We got him.
He's got nowhere to go.
Air One to ground, they're
somewhere between the trains.
Get the fuck
away from me.
Damn it!
We're coming back around.
- You're blowing my whole life.
- What life? You live in a fucking jar...
so the world
can't touch you.
And you didn't give
a shit about Rachel!
Just some package
under seat number 32.
- Come on! - Do you have
a problem? - Go on! Do it!
I'm all you've got!
And you're all I've got.
Heading west
towards the freeway.
[Horn Honks]
- Get out of the fucking car!
- All right.
- Come on. Get out.
- Don't do this to me.
- Tell your story walking.
Hey, wait a minute.
Don't... Oh, for God sakes.
- Thanks for your help back at the train.
- Wait a minute.
Oh, for Jesus...
Air One to ground, I think we lost them.
They're somewhere beneath the overpass.
[Purrs]
Well, you certainly carjacked
a really nice car.
This is a piece of shit.
What are you talking about?
[Sighs] I need sugar, you know.
I'm getting cranky.
Getting?
I'm hypoglycemic. My body
can't metabolize the sugar, so...
So you're a pain in the ass
when you don't eat.
Basically.
Yeah. Right.
- We should eat then.
- Let's do that.
[Hicks]
His real name is Edward Lyle.
Graduated from Drexel University.
Enlisted in the army, 1953.
Rapid promotion, excelled
at intelligence and communications.
- Join N.S.A. In '65.
- Of course.
He was in the agency till 1980 when
he vanished and went underground.
- Hasn't been seen since.
- That's a long time.
Lots of black bags,
lots of deleteds.
He's familiar
with explosives, obviously.
His last assignment, he went into Iran,
late '78, after the Shah.
- This is our problem.
- This man.
So, we were helping
the secret police supply weapons...
to the Afghani rebels
fighting the Soviets.
My partner and I were on the eastern border
monitoring Soviet military transmissions.
It was kind of fun actually.
I liked the Iranians.
Back in Tehran, the hard-liners
seized the embassy,
and overnight,
the whole country changed.
People we'd been working with,
they turned on us. I got out.
My partner didn't.
By the time I got home,
the whole mission had become
a press disaster waiting to happen.
Aiding and abetting
the new enemy.
The agency conveniently
forgot I existed.
I don't blame them.
It's what they had to do.
I loved the agency.
I loved the work.
I loved the people.
It was my whole life.
Your partner
was Rachel's father.
Yeah. The idea was...
The idea always was that if one of us got
out, he'd take care of the other's family.
Rachel was all he had.
So she became
my promise to him.
- [Woman] Here you go, hon.
- Thank you.
Maybe we can still keep
that promise in a way.
You're a threat now,
just like I was.
Threat to whom? To them?
To your family, friends,
everyone you know, everyone you meet.
That's why I went away and didn't
come back. You gotta go away, Robert.
No, I don't think so.
This is my life.
I worked hard for it,
and I want it back.
I grew up without a father.
I know what that is.
And I will not allow
my family to go through that.
[Kid]
Mommy,
I don't wanna go home.
Wanna take
a poke at me?
- Come on.
- I don't hit senior citizens.
- Oh, come here, Babe.
- [Purrs]
Come up here. Come on.
In guerilla warfare, you try
to use your weaknesses as strengths.
- Such as?
- Well,
if they're big and you're small,
then you're mobile and they're slow.
You're hidden
and they're exposed.
Only fight battles you know you can win.
That's the way the Vietcong did it.
You capture their weapons and you
use them against them the next time.
That way they're supplying you.
You grow stronger as they grow weaker.
- Hey, try these.
- Can I have something else, please?
- Yeah. Here.
- Never mind.
- That's my best aloha shirt.
- Well, say "aloha" to it.
- Steve, how you doing? Need some gear.
- Howdy. Help yourself.
- Hi, Bill. - Say hi to
Bill. - How you doing, Bill?
Steve, where's the two gigahertz
video transmitters?
Right behind you,
second shelf.
Steve? I thought you said
his name was Bill.
No. You're Bill.
- If I'm Bill, let me know I'm Bill.
- I just did.
The president has not
committed himself,
but he does recognize that we
do need something in this area.
And I think he will come to see
that this bill will, in the end,
provide the kind
of security that this...
- What security?
- The kind of security he's gonna need.
[Brill]
Ah, here we go.
Modified cell phone
interfaced with laptop computer.
- Creates an enormously powerful tool.
- What is that?
This is Congressman Albert's
home address and his cellular E.S.N.
Now, we reprogram
our phone...
with Congressman Albert's E.S.N.,
and you know what we got?
[Albert] Hi, sweetie.
We just landed. So, how are the kids?
- [Woman] Melissa has a fever.
- She okay?
She's fine. When will you have
some time to talk?
About 30, 40 minutes.
I'll be in suite 59, Lincoln Hotel.
You're a dangerous man.
[Chuckling]
Oh, shit.
Aw, shit.
[Click, Beep]
- Say something.
- Excuse me?
- Louder.
- What are you talking about?
That's good.
- Won't they look in there?
- That's the idea.
Great plan.
I've been a law-abiding
citizen my whole life.
One day with you, I'm shooting and...
breaking... I have to go to the bathroom.
- [Man] Rest well.
- [Albert] Thanks. Bye.
Good work, guys.
[Knocking]
Hmm.
- We got him.
- [Woman Sighs]
Yeah, go for it,
Mr. Congressman.
- You're too young to watch this part here.
- Yeah, so is she.
[Sighs]
[TV On]
Yeah, could you send somebody
up to my room, please?
Yes, this is Christa,
the congressman's aide.
- [Men Chattering]
- How the hell am I supposed to know what it is?
I'm just a congressman,
for Christ's sake.
Security expert tells me...
it's like a PX-73 burst transmitter,
whatever the hell that is.
Except it's
much more sophisticated.
Of course I'm going to send it down.
That's not the...
Because I want to know
who in the hell put it there, Jim.
[Knocking At Door]
- Hi there.
- Hola. Si?
La electricidad? Oh, si.
- [Baby Crying]
- [Man On TV] The category, Barbara.
This is very irritating.
Get one channel and stay with it.
[Channel Changes]
- Stop jumping...
- We're on TV!
- Stop jumping around.
Okay, these are the ones
they wanted us to find.
They're all ours.
We made 'em.
Thomas, could
I see you a second?
Look, there's $140,000 here.
I have no idea where it came from.
- What are you talking about? An extra 140?
- Yeah.
Look, it's right here.
Two separate $70,000 deposits
on the same day.
Yes, I see the deposits,
thank you.
- I have no idea where they came from.
- Tom.
I'm sorry.
That was Shaffer.
He wants to see
all department heads at 0800.
You're going in
on Sunday.
- That's just great.
- Emily.
This is
your separate account.
- I have no idea...
- By the way, who is Christa?
"Eternally yours"?
[Shaffer] I want
the entire history of this device,
from birth to abortion,
on my desk in two hours.
From birth to abortion,
I want the name
of the tech who made it.
I want to know
who authorized its use,
who checked it out
from inventory,
and for what purpose.
Most important,
how on God's green earth...
it got into Congressman
Albert's hotel room.
Listen, people, everyone here
knows where this is going.
Now, if this
was a legit op...
If this was a legit op,
and I can't possibly see
how it could be, then so be it.
But if this was somebody's
unilateral wet dream,
then that somebody
is going to prison.
It's him.
- Yes?
- [Lyle] Thomas Reynolds?
Who is this?
I have that environmental study
you've been looking for.
Can we discuss this
in person?
Be at the corner
of Iowa and Third at 3:00.
- I'll be there at 4:00.
- [Phone Hangs Up, Dial Tone]
We have to get a confession out of
this guy, on tape and fast, okay?
Oh, you shouldn't have. This thing
must've cost 12, 13 bucks easy.
Now, they expect me
to be wired, all right?
So what they'll do
is they'll sweep me.
But once they're done,
I'm gonna give you the signal,
- and you turn the mike on.
- What's the signal?
Putting gum in my mouth.
So after the signal,
you turn the mike on. Turn it on now.
- Let's try it. - [High-Pitched
Squeal] - Okay, off.
- [Clicks Off]
- Good.
To be safe, they'll try to scan
all the frequencies...
to try to track you down.
If these guys are good, and they're
probably very good, in a location like this,
they'll have you
in five, six minutes.
So in four minutes time, after you turn
that tape on, regardless of what's happening,
you get out that door.
You got that?
- No.
- [Sighs]
[Siren Wails]
Record. On-off.
All right,
let the games begin.
Hey there.
Edward Lyle. Policeman.
- Very clever.
- Why don't you call your friends over.
Pratt.
Step towards the fence for me.
This won't take a second.
[Electronic Humming]
He's clear, sir.
[Reynolds]
So, do you have the tape?
- Yes, I have.
- Here?
- No.
- Then what is there to talk about?
- Money.
- Money?
I was wondering why I hadn't seen it
on CNN. Have you looked at the tape?
- What's on it?
- Your ugly-ass face is on it.
It shows the death
of Congressman Hamersly.
The needle
behind the ear.
- Three faces, readily identifiable.
- How much you want for it?
- 1.8 million dollars.
- What?
And my file cleared.
I want my life back.
My 1980 salary with cost of living
increases for the past 18 years.
- Plus interest.
- Oh, shit.
Plus the retirement package for
executive level, E-16. Comes to 1.85.
- I rounded it down.
- And for this, I get the tape and Mr. Dean.
- Actually, it's Dean that has the tape.
- Aw, shit.
- What does he want?
- He wants to know why you killed the girl.
- What girl you talking about?
- I tried to explain it to him, but I couldn't figure it out.
You're getting self-righteous on me?
Because I've seen your file.
- Not exactly a beacon of light.
- Yeah, I agree.
It's just that...
You kill Hamersly, okay.
I wouldn't have,
but I understand the argument.
But why the girl?
Just to get to some schmuck
that barely knows you're after him?
- Schmuck?
- We never dealt with domestic. With us, it was always war.
You won the war. Now we're fighting
the peace. It's a lot more volatile.
- Does he take this long doing everything?
- [Purrs]
Now we've got ten million crackpots out
there with sniper scopes, sarin gas and C-4.
Ten-year-olds go on the Net, downloading
encryption we can barely break,
not to mention instructions on how
to make a low-yield nuclear device.
Privacy's been dead for 30 years
because we can't risk it.
The only privacy that's left is the
inside of your head. Maybe that's enough.
- Get him to say something.
- We've located subject. Keep him talking.
You think we're the enemy of democracy,
you and I? We're democracy's last hope.
There's always
going to be power.
You shouldn't be there, Robert.
But if you are, get out.
Get out
and follow procedure.
Get out now, Robert.
Get out!
[Horn Honks]
- You gonna shoot a policeman? You wouldn't get a block.
- Get in.
[Phone Ringing]
- Yeah?
- [Woman] Tom?
- Emily, what is it?
- Tom, our Visa card's been canceled...
- Did you try the American Express?
- Yeah, I tried that too.
- I can't deal with this now. I'll call you back.
- Listen, I... No, Tom...
Credit cards not working? That can be
a real pain in the ass, can't it?
Come in.
- Asshole.
- Great plan.
- Tell him to give me the tape.
- [Laughing]
- What guarantees do we have if...
- None.
[Lyle]
None?
Does everybody here know that you
killed Phil Hamersly and Rachel Banks?
This guy is going down, and he's
going to take all of you with him.
Trust me on this. Aah! Goddamn!
Oh, you son of a bitch!
Rachel Banks is not the issue.
Hamersly is.
He was killed for a purpose.
Where's the tape?
[Groaning]
Oh, shit.
Where's the tape?
- Tom! - [Cocking Gun]
- [Dean] All right.
- I'll give it to you.
- Thank you.
What are you doing, you moron?
That's our only leverage!
- For Christ's sake.
- I'm the moron? Me? No, you're the moron!
- Where is it? - Washington and
Fourth. - Washington and Fourth.
[Horn Honking]
- That's my blender.
- So?
Fourth and Washington.
- Where is it?
- The restaurant.
11169 Fourth Street.
Stand by to enter.
Wait a second.
- See if you can get the plate
on that van. - T-S-1-8-7-8-5.
- You go in with Pratt and bring it out.
- I don't think so.
- Oh, you don't think so?
- If I go in there and I bring that tape out, I'm a dead man.
We go together,
you and me.
You view the tape,
you sign off on it.
They let Brill go, you take the tape
home, everyone has a Merry Christmas.
What assurances do I have
that you haven't copied that tape?
You think
I want copies?
That tape has been
the bane of my existence.
I wish the one that we have
was at the bottom of the Chesapeake.
I wanna go home.
- Give me a piece.
- Yes, sir.
All right, you and me.
And Pratt and Bingham.
Fiedler, get one of those
little cameras on Bingham.
Guess what. It's
a government vehicle. Shit!
I'm going in cold.
If I need you, Hicks will call it.
You guys got some food
or something in here?
Oh, behind you.
You're either incredibly smart
or incredibly stupid.
We'll see in a minute.
Watch out for the F.B.I.
- I'll be back to get my blender.
- I'll have it gift wrapped.
It's your show.
- Isn't that the guy that was here last time?
- You're right.
No, no. Thank you.
- You guys like the food?
- Yeah. - It's good food.
- It's good food, huh? I made it.
- Yeah, yeah, sure you made it.
- [Pintero] Come on. Eat your food.
- I am.
- Boss, black guy's back with a couple creeps.
- Yeah, show him in.
[Pintero]
Hey, how you doing?
What's this, the F.B.I.?
No, sir, Mr. Pintero. This is
the gentleman you wanted to meet.
- Oh, that's him?
- Yep, that's him.
- So you made the tape?
- What?
Did you make the videotape?
Look, he wants it back.
Really? I don't give
a shit what he wants.
Could we have
some privacy, please?
Yeah, maybe we should.
- Get the kids out of here.
- Come on, boys.
Get 'em out of here.
Go on.
Come on! Uncle Paulie
will take you to the zoo later.
[Coughing]
- Ooh, ooh, Hicks.
- What the hell's the matter with him?
- [Retching]
- No, not on the equipment. We gotta get him... Okay.
[Vomiting]
Check this out. Come here.
Tony, they just pulled
a guy out of the van.
He's puking and bleeding
all over himself.
- Shit. It's a city cop.
- [Door Opens]
Hey, Babe.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
- He's your friend. Persuade him to give us the tape.
- Hey, look.
Number one:
He's not my friend.
- And number two: It's not his tape.
- Whose is it?
It's mine, okay?
It's mine. I bought it.
You sold it to him?
Now, you listen to me.
Who are you? What the fuck
you trying to do to me?
- Oh, this looks bad.
- I'm with the federal government.
The federal government
made a videotape?
- You guys oughta get in there.
- Wait a minute. Listen.
Now, we can go get a warrant and come back
with the F.B.I., take anything we want,
arrest anybody that we want...
just give the man the videotape.
Only one gonna
get arrested here is you...
for felonious cocksucking with
an attempt to swallow the evidence.
And you, get the fuck
out of here.
Go get your warrant.
Until then, get out of my joint.
You gotta get in there! They're gonna
be dead bodies all over the place!
- Shut up!
- Get in there!
- Okay, let's go.
- This is it. This is it.
Krug, take the rear. Jones,
you're in the side entrance.
What are we waiting for?
Come on; let's go!
Tony says we wait
until they show up.
- Put the guns away.
- You put your guns away.
Put it away.
[Door Opens]
All right,
I'm putting it away.
- Now, what will it take for us to get that videotape?
- The end of the world.
Let's go.
We're leaving.
- Put the guns down now.
- Drop your weapons! - No!
[Sirens Blaring]
Go! Go! Go!
- Get your hands up.
- You get your hands up! Drop the gun!
- On your knees.
- Easy with this guy. He's not one of them.
Easy, easy. Get up.
Come on.
- Let's get this place cleaned up.
- Not too stupid after all.
Let's go.
Let's move it. Come on.
Right there.
Somebody get the paramedics.
We need some paramedics in here.
We have 13 bodies in here.
[People Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
[Sirens Blaring]
All right, listen up. Get some I.D. S on
these guys. Get these guns out of here.
[Lyle, On Tape] This guy is going down.
He's going to take all of you with him.
- [Gunshot] - [Lyle] Goddamn!
- Rachel Banks is not the issue.
Hamersly is the issue. He was killed
for a purpose. Now, where's the tape?
Why did you record it?
Okay, uh, first of all,
we were there for technical support.
- And, uh, we had no idea...
- Do they know that Reynolds is dead?
- Yeah. - They know
all that? - Right.
But they're
still stalling.
- A tape.
- A tape of it.
- What did you think was going on?
- I thought it was an S.T.O.
- S.T.O.?
- Standard Training Op.
Congressman! Does this mean
the privacy bill is dead, Congressman?
In its current form, yes, but the issue
is still very much alive, I can assure you,
unless, of course, no one worries
about national security anymore.
We knew that we had
to monitor our enemies.
We've also come
to realize...
that we need to monitor
the people who are monitoring them.
Well, who's going to monitor
the monitors of the monitors?
I wouldn't mind doing
a little, uh, monitoring myself.
Yeah, and you got lots
and lots of monitoring to do.
Are you guys talking
about sex?
- Boy!
- Oh, no. It's time for dinner.
Get in there and eat your dinner.
No more hanging with Dylan.
- [Channels Changing]
- [TV Blaring]
[Purrs]
Brill,
you are one sick man.
Yeah, me too.
Ooh, you're gonna need
to get a tan on those things.
Congressman Albert,
how do we draw the line...
between protection
of national security,
obviously the government's need
to obtain intelligence data,
and the protection of civil liberties,
particularly the sanctity of my home?
You've got no right
to come into my home.