WOMAN: The NTSB guys are here
about that bulkhead problem.
Okay, thanks.
It's there.
MAN:
I should run the algorithms, though?
TED:
Nope.
MAN: You wanna wait for those
spectrometer results?
TED:
No.
-Hi.
-Hey.
What about dinner tonight?
We go out to dinner,
we might never come back.
Okay.
I wanna wake up with you...
...Mrs. Smith.
I want to at least see where you live.
I live here...
...Mr. Smith.
OPERATOR: Metro Division.
-Uh, Lieutenant Nunally, please.
Lieutenant Nunally comes on
at 6:00 tonight.
-Can someone else help you?
-That's okay, l'll see him later. Thank you.
[WHOOPS]
[BEEPS]
Hey.
JENNlFER: Afternoon, Ciro.
CIRO: Hello, señora.
TED:
Hello there.
You're home early.
Yeah.
I just felt...
...a sudden urge.
Are you okay?
Yeah. l could use a hug.
You know, I've been
watching you sleep...
...at night.
-That's creepy.
-Yeah.
Sometimes at work,
I'll start thinking about you...
...and l'll just get....
-Just overwhelmed.
-Ted.
It's a dense, crushing...
...geophysical force,
like l'm pinned at the core.
While things change, you know?
Do you ever get
that way about me, Jen?
I don't think l can
do one of these tonight.
I'm just trying
to describe my feelings.
Those don't sound like feelings.
Oh.
What's the sound of a feeling?
You think you're so much
smarter than me.
It must make you feel very powerful.
Helpless, actually.
-Okay, maybe it's time to really talk.
-No.
-No?
Fine, whatever.
I'll go change. l'll make some dinner.
I love you.
I know.
Does he...
...Mrs. Smith?
-l'm sorry.
-Don't be.
Knowledge is pain. l'm used to that.
Not that l don't get
some little pleasures...
...in return for the pain, mind you.
Mr. and Mrs. Crawford?
You all right?
[DOOR KNOCKS]
Is everybody okay in there?
[GUNSHOT]
COP: Notice anything out of the ordinary?
CIRO: l didn't see anything unusual.
-Just Mr. and Mrs. Crawford.
-Nobody else?
CIRO:
No. No.
NUNALLY:
Flores, how you been?
FLORES:
Good, good. You know, same.
We got one witness, maybe.
The gardener.
His name's Ciro.
Hey, guys, this is Lieutenant Nunally.
-Good to meet you.
CIRO: Hello, sir.
So, what do we know?
[PHONE RlNGING]
NUNALLY:
Mr. Crawford?
-Who is this?
-My name is Lieutenant Robert Nunally.
I'm a hostage negotiator
with the L.A.P.D.
Mr. Crawford?
Okay.
You two, let's go.
Just you, please.
Mr. Crawford?
I'm just gonna slide the door open
just a bit, all right?
-Hi.
Do I call you Rob?
Sure, yeah. lf you want to.
Lots of vampires out there.
Mr. Crawford, what do you say
you give me the gun?
That way I can pay more attention
to what you're saying. All right?
Is that your best shot, Rob?
So to speak.
Tell you what. I will if you will.
We both put down our guns.
We set them down and we step away.
Then you can pay attention
to what I'm saying.
All right, l'm gonna have to ask you
to put yours down first, then.
Then you have my word.
Everybody gives a little...
...we'll see what we can do
about getting you what you want.
Happy ending, then.
Mr. Crawford,
your gardener tells it...
-...that your wife--
-lt's Ted.
-l'm sorry?
-You can call me Ted.
Ted. Great. Ted.
Your wife, is she here?
Is she all right?
I don't think she is. l shot her.
You shot your wife?
It's just like l suddenly snapped...
...and l got the gun
and l shot her in the head.
I know it was wrong.
Are you listening to me, Rob?
NUNALLY:
Oh, Jesus Christ.
I read somewhere that the best place
to find a pulse is in the femoral artery.
It's on the inner surface
of the upper thigh.
So if you just
put your fingers up her skirt...
...you'll find it.
[GRUNTlNG]
MAN 1 : Break it up!
MAN 2: We got a victim down!
All right.
PARAMEDIC:
She's got a pulse.
FLORES:
Rob. Good job.
You all right?
I wanna be in the room.
FLORES:
Well, we got it covered.
Yeah, l know.
I just wanna be there.
And l want this thing locked...
...before we pass it to the DA.
WlLLY:
Stop yelling, Phil.
I called you as a courtesy
and now you're trying to take advantage.
I'm not. l'm not knocking it down
to a class C.
My backlog of open cases
doesn't mitigate the fact...
...that your client tried
to kill his brother-in-law.
A golfing accident. Phil...
...your client owns one golf club,
no golf balls...
...and the accident happened
in a stairwell...
...of an after-hours,
illegal gambling hall.
I'll see you in court.
[CELL PHONE VIBRATlNG]
Well, l won't,
but someone from this office will.
You can take it up with them.
WOMAN:
Los Angeles district attorney's office.
-Beachum.
WOMAN: Yes, it is.
Hello.
No, I didn't.
-Yeah.
-Wooton Sims?
Shh.
-[WHlSPERS] Wooton Sims?
-[WHlSPERS] Shut up.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Short notice is fine.
It's fine. Uh-huh.
Black tie? Fine.
What time? That'll be fine.
Thank her for me. All right.
-How many times did I just say "fine"?
-[IN NORMAL VOlCE] You asshole.
How the hell did you get
a job at Wooton Sims?
I can't even get an interview.
I've been here five years, Willy.
I'm your supervisor.
I graduated USC, summa.
-l need a tuxedo.
-A tux?
-You are full of shit.
-l need it for tonight. ls that possible?
-Of course.
WlLLY: They do that?
-Same day sort of thing?
MONA: Uh-huh. Sure.
-Can l give you that?
MONA: Yeah.
-Okay.
-Well, that's maxed out...
...so l'm gonna give you this.
So, what's this all about?
You know, Burt Wooton's
having a charity-opera thing and....
-Burt?
-Well, that's what he told me to call him.
You're gonna need
to pick out a style, Willy.
WlLLY: Like what?
-Willy Beachum's office.
-l'm thinking maybe classic.
WlLLY: Classic.
MONA: Yeah, no problem.
-Classic.
Just makes sure it comes with
cuff links and kneepads.
MONA: Willy.
-Oh. That's not classic.
-That's what I'm saying.
-Before, after.
NORMAN: That's the way l go.
-God wants to see you.
-Our God?
-Who art on the fourth floor.
Mr. Lobruto? Mr. Beachum.
-Have a seat.
-Thank you.
William "No Middle Initial" Beachum.
Wow, a 97 percent conviction rate.
-That's impressive.
-Thank you, sir.
Of course, you traded all
your losing cases to other DDAs.
Well...
...l took on two or three cases
for every one I gave away.
They just couldn't
handle their caseloads...
...and l don't like to lose.
You won't always win
working at Wooton Sims.
Working at Wooton Sims
sort of is winning.
Isn't it?
Well, you'll need a middle initial.
-Sir?
-Well, those guys all play squash...
...and have middle names.
They go in for their mother's
maiden name a lot.
Well, my mother
doesn't have a maiden name.
I think you belong here, William.
With all due respect, sir...
...l just didn't work this hard
to stay where l belong.
Yeah, well, l didn't think so.
Well, you have your
litigation experience...
...your chops...
...and your juicy private-sector job.
Pretty soon you'll be courtside
at Laker games.
Anything else the city
of Los Angeles can do for you?
No, sir. l think that'll be all.
MONA:
It's a cummerbund, Willy.
That's gonna go
around your waist, okay?
-Okay. Are we good?
-Uh-huh.
-Good. Good.
-All right.
NORMAN [OVER PHONE]:
Willy?
Willy, come on. Pick up the phone.
What, Norman?
Got an attempted homicide.
Guy shot his wife, she's in a coma.
Arraignment's at 3:00
with Judge Moran.
Three o'clock is in 1 5 minutes.
You do still actually work here--
Would you just find
somebody else to do it?
Everybody's booked.
It's not going to trial.
There's a weapon with prints...
...and a signed confession.
Just take the arraignment,
wait for the plea.
It's a real confession?
Spontaneous and signed.
Come on, Willy.
All right...
...but here's the problem.
MORAN:
That'll do! l've given my ruling.
If they wanna squabble,
they can take it outside.
MAN: l apologize, Your Honor.
Your Honor, please. Your Honor.
[CHATTERlNG]
Mr. Beachum.
Nice to see a man
who dresses for court.
I'm very sorry, Your Honor.
I'm very sorry.
It's a long story.
BAlLIFF: The people of the State
of California v. Theodore Crawford.
PUBLIC DEFENDER: The public defender
is representing Mr. Crawford...
...for his arraignment, with the
understanding that he will secure...
...private counsel
for further proceedings.
MORAN: Mr. Crawford,
you have been charged...
...with Section 664 slash 1 87...
...of the California penal code,
attempted murder.
Do you waive further
reading of the complaint...
-...and complete statement of rights?
PUBLIC DEFENDER: You do.
I do. But l--
And do you wish to enter
a plea at this time?
Yes, not guilty. But I also want to waive
my right to counsel and represent myself.
Surely you won't have trouble
finding an attorney, Mr. Crawford?
-No, but I want to do it.
-lf I can have a moment with my client....
I'm not your client.
Try and keep up, will you?
MORAN:
Mr. Crawford...
...you're facing some
very serious charges here.
I strongly urge you to retain counsel.
That's very kind,
but I believe l'm within my rights.
Be aware that lack of counsel
will not be grounds for an appeal.
Oh, l understand. l understand.
MORAN: The People have an objection,
Mr. Beachum?
Well, Your Honor, we have...
...a verbal and signed confession.
So l would strongly advise
Mr. Crawford to....
To get a competent attorney
to try and negotiate a plea.
That's pretty damning evidence.
You wanna reconsider?
Absolutely not.
It's gonna turn into a circus.
I appreciate your concern
for the dignity of the court, 007.
Unfortunately, the man
is a tax-paying citizen...
...and entitled by our Constitution
to try and manipulate the system...
-...like everybody else.
-lf Mr. Crawford wants to go pro per...
...that's gonna take a while,
and sadly...
...l won't be here for it.
But the People have no objection.
Your Honor, l'd like to...
...waive my right
to preliminary hearing...
...and go direct to trial
as soon as possible.
Does that help you, Mr. Beachum?
MORAN: You don't have to worry
about Mr. Beachum.
The district attorney's office
will assign another prosecutor.
No, I like Mr. Beachum.
Mr. Beachum...
...he likes you.
Yes. That's terrific.
It appears Crawford has an understanding
of his rights and responsibilities...
...so it's your call, Mr. Beachum.
Why not?
All right, then. Case will move to trial
at the first available date.
NUNALLY:
Beachum.
[KEYS DROP]
You're supposed to be good.
Is that right?
Who the hell are you?
I'm Lieutenant Nunally.
I took Crawford's confession.
Oh.
[SIGHS]
Okay. So, what can I do for you?
Are you gonna be on this, or what?
Because it looks to me like you got
one foot out the door already.
Oh.
You should be taking this seriously.
You know, be careful with this guy, he's--
There's something not right about him.
You took the confession, right?
-You took the gun out of his hand.
-Yeah.
Good. So it's done.
Don't worry about it.
-Can l have a bourbon?
-Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Are you a shark?
-Excuse me?
-You've been circling this lobby...
...for half an hour now.
Like if you stopped, you'd die.
Yeah, l'm a shark.
What about you? Are you a shark too?
Did you say hi to Burt?
Oh.
Burt's talking to the mayor.
Do I know you?
Nikki Gardner.
Your new boss.
Oh.
You're the one who sent
the invitation?
Well, l thought l ought to
get to know the mystery man...
...that Burt plucked out of nowhere.
Well, l don't really know Burt.
So every partner has a team
of senior associates.
Every senior associate
has a team ofjunior associates.
And you're on my team, which means...
...l'll supervise your casework and I'll
steer you through the office politics.
-Kind of like a mentor.
-Kind of like a probation officer.
Oh, you're trying to scare me.
Let me ask you a question.
Okay. Shoot.
We have a senior associate
at the firm named Calvin Tyler.
Kind of a rising star.
He goes into court against you,
some client's kid is DUl...
...and the next thing we know,
Calvin is fired.
And Burt Wooton, who has never even
interviewed a junior associate before...
...let alone hired one,
says you're starting in two weeks.
Calvin came to me for a deal.
So l told him if he can get me
a meeting with Mr. Wooton...
...that l'd throw the case.
He set it up, but he came
to court unprepared...
...and l mopped the floor with him.
Your client got the maximum,
and then, next day...
...l was meeting with Mr. Wooton.
Burt.
That's--
You didn't actually do
anything all that wrong.
I wasn't exactly honest with Calvin.
[CELL PHONE RlNGlNG]
Are you gonna get that?
Everybody l wanna talk to is right here.
Welcome to Wooton Sims.
Get your phone.
-Yeah.
FLORES: Hey, it's Flores. l got bad news.
The gun. lt's no good.
What do you mean, the gun's no good?
Well, it's a fine gun.
It's just no good as evidence.
-lt's never been fired.
-Never been fired?
Well, it's the gun
from the house, isn't it?
Yeah. lt's...
...the property of the defendant.
Bought about one month ago.
Well, the guy never left the house.
He was locked inside
from the time of the crime...
...to the time of the arrest.
[WHlSPERS]
So the gun is in there.
So don't tell me
that the gun isn't in there.
Go find it. Get a team out there
tomorrow and find it.
[SINGlNG OPERA MUSlC]
No, I haven't. l have not.
Well, everything's been so expedited, you
know. And I guess I just thought that....
I don't know. l thought
however it was decorated...
...was how it was decorated.
Huh?
WOMAN: Right away, sir.
-Well...
...what do most of the other
junior associates have?
Oh.
Well, what--
What is the difference between...
...ltalian and English?
I know that they're
two different countries.
I was talking about in terms
of interior design.
Can you hold on one second?
[WHlSPERS] What kind of style
would you say that this is?
Homicidal modern?
I don't know. l guess l'll just
know it when l see it.
Uh-huh.
Ooh. Two o'clock? l don't--
Yeah, all right. I can do it.
Bye-bye, now.
All right, good to see you.
-What the hell is this?
-lt's a...
...thing. lt does stuff.
-What, did he make it or something?
-The guy? Yeah.
Here, take a look at this.
It's for the Glock 45...
...found at the scene.
Now, we got no other
sign of a gun so far.
No weapon. No powder on his hand...
...no blood on his clothes.
We found four shell casings.
Forty-five's wiped clean. No prints.
That's four shots fired.
Four bullets missing from the case.
Four shell casings on the floor
with no prints on them.
And a gun that's never been fired.
The guy's screwing with us.
He's stacking the deck.
She's pretty.
Look, the gun is in this house.
Maybe he was wearing gloves.
Maybe he had time to change.
But it's in the house,
and l'll tell you why.
Because people
were watching the house...
...and he never came out.
I could be wrong,
but I don't think that the gun...
...grew little gun legs
and ran out of the house.
So if you need more guys...
...l'm all for it.
KARLA: That's disability insurance.
-Uh-huh.
Most of our employees get that.
It's only an additional $6.84 a month.
-All right.
-Just be sure...
...you sign the one with the devil
in blood. lt's not binding otherwise.
I'm going to a meeting.
Wanted to stop by...
...and make sure you're getting
everything you need.
I'm getting more than l need.
I'm running a little late.
Will you walk with me?
-Yeah.
NIKKl: I'll send him right back.
KARLA: No problem. We were
just finishing paperwork and ordering.
-Gonna give him swatches and chips.
WlLLY: Which I thought was to eat...
-...didn't l?
-Yeah, you did.
WlLLY:
All right.
KARLA: I like that.
-Oh, I like that one too.
-No purple.
-Let me handle it.
NIKKl:
"More than l need," huh?
Oh, l was just talking
about the furniture.
Don't get too attached.
You won't be here much.
Two weeks from Tuesday, whole team's
getting on a plane to Chicago.
-Why, what's going on in Chicago?
-Warfield.
Warfield? Ain't that
the biotech guy who stole...
...like, 300 million
from his own company?
That biotech guy who had no idea
whatsoever what his CFO was doing.
WlLLY:
Oh, right.
This is a test, Willy.
Burt told me to give you a trial by fire.
I'm good at trials by fire.
He wants you up to speed on eight
months of depositions in two weeks.
-No problem.
-What about closing out your old job?
Don't worry about it.
Willy?
WlLLY: Yeah?
-Beachum.
No, Danny, no.
No, no, no. I-- No.
The idea is to get things out of here.
Oh, is that the idea?
I'm really sorry.
-Enjoy a jellybean.
-Thanks.
-What color did you get?
-Yellow.
Oh, that's popcorn. That's gross.
-Well, thanks.
-Told you.
Danny, this isn't ev--
[DOOR BUZZES]
WlLLY:
All right.
[CELL PHONE RlNGS]
Sorry.
How's my wife?
WlLLY:
Uh, I don't know.
I'm sure she's been better, though.
I heard somewhere, l think on NPR, that
you're supposed to talk to people in a coma.
Play their favorite music. It may
help them or get through to them.
-Uh-huh.
-But you're probably too busy...
...getting up to speed
on the Warfield case, I suppose.
-Excuse me?
-Hm?
Oh, no, l'm not--
I'm not judging you, Willy. No.
Anyone coming
from what you came from...
...then paying your way through
East Okie Cowshit College...
...by writing papers
for Princeton kids on the lnternet--
My God, $60,000 in debt...
...and a 97 percent conviction rate, wow.
You deserve it, kiddo.
What have you been doing?
I'm permitted the use
of a private investigator.
-Not to investigate me.
-Why not? You're investigating me.
-Because you shot your wife.
-Allegedly.
That's how it works, right?
If l can't introduce something in court
as evidence, it doesn't exist legally.
I'm not gonna play games with you.
I'm afraid you have to, old sport.
What is this? What is it,
some kind of form of communication?
Uh-huh. You sent me a box of papers.
It's called disc--
It's called discovery, all right?
That's where the state
is legally obligated...
...to provide all the evidence
to the defendant...
-...so you can prepare your defense.
-There's nothing in it, Willy.
You haven't actually discovered anything.
That's one point of view.
Another might be that
I've hit the mother lode.
Oh, have they found the gun?
I don't need the gun to convict you.
Ah.
Tell me something.
Does it bother you that l call you Willy?
No.
Willy.
Willy, l'd like you to consider
becoming my lawyer.
I'll pay you lots of money.
I'm prosecuting you.
Yes, but l'm giving you a chance
to get on the other side...
...of this unholy mess
while you still can.
Right.
Are you out of your mind?
I think, on advice of counsel,
I'll decline to answer that one.
All right. Well, look, l'm gonna--
Thank you for your offer.
I'm gonna stay right where I am.
At least for one more week.
Look, just keep this. Don't send it back.
You need that. You also need to
come up with a witness list.
No, I'll leave all
that witness crap to you.
Right. Because you're not gonna
call any witnesses.
No, I'm innocent, remember,
until proven guilty.
Whatever. You heard the judge.
You know that's not grounds for an appeal.
What the heck? Jury of my peers,
and so on and so forth.
WlLLY:
Right.
[WlLLY KNOCKS ON DOOR]
TED: You know, my grandfather
was an egg farmer.
This isn't gonna be about
your rough childhood, is it?
No, I used to candle eggs at his farm.
Know what that is?
You hold an egg up to
the light of a candle...
...and you look for imperfections.
First time l did it...
...he told me to put
the cracked or flawed eggs...
...into a bucket for the bakery.
And he came back an hour later...
...and there were 300 eggs
in the bakery bucket.
He asked me what l was doing.
I found a flaw
in every single one of them.
You know, thin places in the shell...
...and fine hairline cracks.
You look closely enough,
you'll find everything has a weak spot...
...where it can break, sooner or later.
You looking for mine?
I've already found yours.
What is it?
You're a winner, Willy.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah. Well, I guess the joke's on me,
then, isn't it?
You bet your ass, old sport.
[DOOR BUZZES]
WlLLY: What time was that?
CIRO: About 5:00.
Then she went into the house.
WILLY: Prior to that, had you seen
Mr. Crawford arrive?
-Yes.
-When was that?
Earlier than usual.
Maybe 4:00.
Did Mr. Crawford park in the carport?
No, he always parks in the garage.
He's very careful with his car.
WlLLY: Would you say that Mr. Crawford
was a very careful man?
CIRO:
Oh, yes.
Always.
Thank you.
No further questions, Your Honor.
Mr. Crawford.
Yes, Your Honor?
Uh.... Hello, Ciro.
No, Mr. Crawford.
It's your turn
to cross-examine this witness.
Oh, no. No questions.
[GALLERY MURMURlNG]
WlLLY: What time?
COP: Five-twelve exactly.
We called in SWAT as soon as we knew
there was a possible hostage situation.
Then l tried to establish contact
through the front gate intercom.
Any answer?
COP: None.
WlLLY: What then?
COP:
Two other uniformed squads arrived.
We established a perimeter
outside the walls as quickly as possible...
...to keep the house under observation.
Oh, l'm sorry. Sorry, Mr. Beachum.
Your Honor.
WlLLY: So the house was
completely surrounded...
-...within minutes of your arrival.
-All four sides.
And neither you nor any other officer...
...saw anyone go into
or come out of that house?
-No.
WlLLY: And what happened next?
KANG: The bullet pierced through the
frontal cortex and the temporal lobe...
...coming to rest on the upper right side
of her brain, against the skull.
-And degree of injury?
-lt inflicted grievous and irreparable injury.
WlLLY:
Dr. Kang, is it safe to say...
...that someone who inflicted
this kind of wound intended to kill?
Oh, a moment.
-Mr. Crawford?
-Yes, Your Honor?
ROBlNSON:
You might want to object.
The witness can't know
your state of mind.
No, thank you, Your Honor.
Proceed.
Sorry.
WlLLY:
And after you put down your gun...
...what did Mr. Crawford do?
He confessed to shooting his wife.
He confessed.
Now, did Mr. Crawford
appear confused...
...intoxicated or impaired in any way?
NUNALLY: No. No, not at all.
He knew exactly what was going on.
WlLLY:
Detective Nunally...
...what did Mr. Crawford say?
He said, "lt was like
I just suddenly snapped.
I got the gun and l shot my wife.
-l shot her in the head."
-Objection.
I'm sorry, Mr. Crawford,
did you say something?
TED:
Yes, l wish to object.
ROBlNSON: On what grounds?
-l don't know.
-Your Honor--
TED: Um....
I don't know what you'd call it, but--
It wasn't the first
time it happened either...
...but l....
I don't know the legal terminology.
Well, why don't you try
and explain it in layman's terms?
Um....
Fucking the victim.
[GALLERY MURMURlNG]
You said layman's terms.
-Your Honor--
TED: l'm sorry...
...but what would you call it, legally,
when the officer who arrested you...
...was having sexual intercourse with
your wife? I think it's objectionable.
It's rather disgusting is what I think.
But l don't know, maybe I'm wrong.
Tsk.
Rob?
Oh, shit.
Can l talk to you for a second?
[GALLERY SHOUTING]
WOMAN:
No!
Order. Order. Just-- Bailiffs. Order!
Order! Bailiffs! Please.
-You lying son of a bitch.
ROBlNSON: Please. We're in recess.
He had my witness list
and he should've filed to suppress.
-My mistake, I'm sorry.
-Mr. Crawford, you were warned.
-You don't get to use that as an excuse.
-What about the fact that it's true?
I mean, isn't that the point here,
to get to the truth?
Mr. Beachum, is it true?
I have no idea, Your Honor.
I just heard about it five minutes ago.
Put him back on the witness stand,
if you don't believe me.
This is getting out of hand.
Now, he just provoked my witness
with an outrageous allegation.
My dick has evidence.
-Excuse me?
-My dick, my private investigator.
I call him dick. Perhaps I should call him
as a rebuttal witness.
Because since the tragedy, he's dug up
hotel records and witnesses...
...that confirm that my wife
and Mr. Nunally were having an affair.
-My dick is good.
-Your Honor, so, what if he was?
ROBlNSON: Mr. Beachum.
-Even if he was--
Your witness was intimate
with the victim...
...and assaulted the defendant
during the arrest.
Actually, while trying to obtain
my so-called confession.
-Yes.
-Oh, come on.
Is that a legal argument,
"Oh, come on"?
Don't make me come across this table
because l will--
He dictated
and signed his confession...
...at the station
long after the incident, all right?
In fear for my life,
since my wife's lover...
...who had just beaten me,
was in the room with his friends...
...and the other officers.
Was Detective Nunally present
during Mr. Crawford's interrogation?
He may have been, I don't know.
Because if that is indeed the case,
the confessions, both of them, are out.
If Nunally was there,
Mr. Crawford was under duress.
Confessions and evidence gathered
with Nunally present...
...will have to be excluded
as fruit of the poisonous tree.
-This is insane.
-That's the Bible, isn't it?
"The fruit of the tree" and all that?
It's Matthew. Or is it Mark?
He set all this up.
-This is a setup.
-l'm sorry, Mr. Beachum...
...but l am not going to allow
coerced confessions in my courtroom.
Do you think I could go home...
-...with Thanksgiving around the corner?
-Unbelievable.
Don't push it, Mr. Crawford.
What l'll do is I'm going to give
Mr. Beachum a few days...
...to come up with some new evidence.
If he can't, then maybe you can go home.
So we will reconvene
on Monday morning.
-l think that's all.
-Thank you, Your Honor.
Farewell.
LOBRUTO: Didn't even have the guts
to come talk to me.
I was going to...
...after l figured out...
...how l was gonna handle it.
What makes you think
that's your decision?
-You taking me off this case?
-Your bags are already packed.
Just go.
Even if l find new evidence?
From where? The evidence store?
What, are they open early
the day after Thanksgiving?
My witness lied to me.
Yes, because he could.
Because you weren't looking.
And l know why.
Your head was in the fast lane
on your big salary.
You picked that and what we do
is not important anymore.
So that's what this is about, isn't it?
-l'm not gonna be like you in 20 years.
-Hey, you be very careful.
You wanna judge me, be my guest...
...but this thing was a setup.
The confession, everything.
Maybe.
But it didn't have to turn into
a public humiliation for this office.
You walked in there unprepared.
You were arrogant and sloppy,
and you did damage.
How much, we don't even know yet.
And l noticed
you didn't even care to ask.
But don't worry yourself, Willy.
We'll clean up after you.
[MUSlC PLAYlNG
& PEOPLE CHATTERING]
MAN:
Coming around....
BARTENDER:
Yeah.
-Hey, what can I get you?
WlLLY: Bourbon.
All right.
So...
...you got killed today.
You gotta admire the cleverness of it.
WlLLY:
Oh, yeah?
Sure, give the devil his due.
So, what did Lobruto say?
He took me off the case.
Good.
-ls it?
-Yeah.
Damage control.
Look, you don't know this guy.
I had to fight with Burt today...
...to stop him from firing you.
You want this, right?
Yeah.
Good.
I have to hang out here another hour...
...so...
...l think you should go home.
And l'd like you to call me later.
Call me later.
You....
You don't have to go, William.
Yeah, l do.
NIKKl:
No big family Thanksgiving?
WlLLY:
No.
Well, l have to...
...put in some face time
with mine, if you want.
All right.
Thanks.
Don't thank me yet.
Mr. Beachum, can l help you?
Look, please, Mr. Beachum.
I want it back.
I take complete responsibility
for what happened.
Although I do feel like
it would have happened to anyone.
But if I'd been paying attention,
it wouldn't have happened to me.
I'm not giving you back this case
so you can repair your ego.
Well, it's not just about my ego.
It's also about the fact that this guy...
...he's just enjoying all of this.
Enjoying this? That's not evidence.
Right...
...but someone's gotta put him away.
If you just give me a chance...
...and if there is a way, l'll find it.
And if you can't?
Listen, you leave now, l replace you.
I'm covered, I took some action.
But if you go on with this
and you lose...
...l guarantee you your shiny new job
will not be waiting for you...
...and l can't keep you on here.
This is a public office. Heads gotta roll.
Still want it back?
Thank you.
[CELL PHONE RlNGS]
Yeah.
-The gun's in the house.
-Yeah, except it's also just not.
Then what'd he do?
He tie it to a goddamn helium balloon?
Maybe.
Maybe he dissolved it in acid.
MAN:
You got a DOB on that?
-You know, detective...
WOMAN: Here it is.
MAN:
And that's the last known address?
...your inability to do your job effectively
is making it very difficult for me to do mine.
All right?
I'm back in trial on Monday.
Okay, fine. I'll get a team together.
I'll go over it one more time...
...and that's it.
My wife took the kids to her mom's.
And l got the media
all over my front lawn.
What were you thinking, huh?
You get called to your
girlfriend's house.
I didn't know it was her house.
Well, it's her last name.
I didn't know her last name.
Not her real one, anyway.
We just--
We met at the Miramar.
Same time, twice a week and--
There were no questions asked, no phone
calls and that's just-- Those were the rules.
Those were her rules.
All right. Did you get the feeling
that she had all these rules...
...because she'd been doing it before
with other guys?
Be honest.
No.
I don't know if you can understand
this because you're a fucking lawyer...
...but this thing that we had,
it was real.
It wasn't just an affair.
This girl, she made me feel like....
What was I supposed to do?
Tell me.
I tried to warn you, didn't l?
No, you warned me
that he was smart.
You didn't warn me...
...that you were stupid.
Fuck you, you little punk. Fuck you!
Fuck me? Well, you already did that.
I didn't think that he knew, okay?
There was no way for me
to know that he knew.
I just thought the guy
was fucking nuts, you know?
WILLY: Y'all got security cameras, right?
SECRETARY: Yes, we do.
Can l get a copy of those tapes
from November 1 0th?
As soon as I can.
I'm just-- l'm under the gun here.
That's exactly the way he left them?
-Yes.
-Mm-hm.
What, were they planning
a trip next week?
[PHONE RlNGS]
Excuse me.
Crawford Aeronautics.
Yes, he is.
It's for you.
Just pick up Line 1 .
-Hello?
-Hey, Willy, old sport. How is it going?
Uh....
Well, l'm...
...still out here
and you're still in there, so....
Yeah, you're right there.
So the world still makes sense,
does it?
Have you got everything
you need, Willy?
Would you like some coffee?
No, thank you.
Okay.
You got some new evidence, have you?
What's the matter, Willy,
aren't we friends anymore?
I'm trying to help you. You're in a bad
place and you've nowhere else to turn.
-Okay, I'm gonna hang up.
-Do me a favor, will you, pal?
Ask Tina to cancel my wife's tickets.
Yeah, we had
plans to travel, you see.
Get away, so to speak.
Next week, actually. Sort of a,
you know, second honeymoon.
Painfully ironic, that part, l must say.
But l don't think Jennifer's
gonna make it, Willy. Do you?
Well...
...tore the whole thing apart.
No gun.
I'm sorry, Willy.
Good night.
WlLLY:
"Do you dare stay out?
Do you dare go in?
How much can you lose?
How much can you win?
And if you go in,
should you turn left or right?
Or right and three-quarters?
Or maybe not quite?
You can get so confused
that you'll start in to race...
...down long wiggled roads
at a breaknecking pace...
...and grind on for miles
across weirdish wild space...
...headed, l fear, towards
a most useless place.
The waiting place.
For people just waiting.
[EKG BEEPING]
Waiting for a train to go.
Or for a bus to come.
Or a plane to go.
Or the mail to come.
Or the rain to go.
Or the phone to ring.
Or the snow to snow.
Or waiting around for a yes or a no.
Or a string of pearls
or a pair of pants.
Or a wig with curls.
Or another chance."
What are you doing?
Uh....
I heard that it might help.
Who told you that?
The guy who shot her.
WOMAN:
Are you a member of the family?
WlLLY:
I'm from the district attorney's office.
And we...
...ran out of witnesses.
You know, she moved earlier.
She moved her eyelids
like she was trying to open her eyes.
Yeah, well sometimes
we have to tape their eyes shut.
They all move, they--
They twitch, they make sounds.
You think they're dreaming,
but they're not. lt's just--
It's just what's left of the system.
Normal reflex is downward.
Up indicates brain trauma.
If she comes back,
she may not remember how to speak...
...let alone who shot her.
[WHlSPERS]
What if she can hear you?
She can't.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] It happens, right?
People wake up. lt's not impossible.
[IN NORMAL VOICE] You gonna ask
the same question different ways...
...till you get the answer you want?
I guess. That's what I do.
I knew l should have gone
to law school.
GARDNER: I thought it was so funny
when he did that dance at the end.
[CHATTERlNG AND LAUGHlNG]
GARDNER:
Would you like some more wine?
-Are you not gonna eat your turkey?
-l'm a vegetarian.
-White or dark meat this time?
WlLLY: Oh, it doesn't matter...
-...Your Honor. Thank you.
-l think Willy's already chosen...
...the dark side.
Mr. Sierra Club and Ms. ACLU here...
...give me a hard time
at the holidays...
-...because l can buy and sell them.
-We're not actually for sale, Nik.
GARDNER: Well, since you have
the advantage on all of us...
...surely it won't bother you
if we just mention...
...to Willy that he could put
his talents to more noble use.
NIKKl: You don't have to do this.
WlLLY: Oh, it's all right.
I get this from time to time...
...and it's most always
from people with money.
Oop. You win.
I usually do.
Except in trial this week.
-Nice, Lee.
-lt's not over till it's over.
That looked pretty over.
Anyway, Willy's off the case, so....
Well, it may not seem like it now, Willy,
but it's really a blessing in disguise.
Well, l'm actually not.
-What?
-Off the case. l'm back on it.
But that doesn't make any sense. Lobruto
has to do some kind of damage control.
Yeah, well...
...l asked him to let me finish it.
You didn't think
I might wanna know that?
Did you hear me when l said l had
to convince Burt not to fire you?
Could we not do this here?
NIKKl:
Fine.
Actually, I need to talk with you.
You lied to me.
It doesn't work with me.
I didn't lie.
I told you l could be ready...
...and l still can be ready in time.
I got one thing,
one thing l gotta do first.
You're not in yet, Willy.
You pulled a stunt.
-You got your foot in the door.
-l could still win this case.
I don't care.
That's not what this is about.
-What is it about?
-lt's about whether...
...you can do what you're told.
You wanted corporate, right?
That was the point.
Did I misunderstand that?
If you do this, if you win,
I'm still screwed.
It says l don't know what
my subordinates are doing...
...my judgment is bad,
and l'm not in charge of my team.
I went out on a limb.
I told Burt this was over.
I didn't ask you to do that, Nik.
Know what nobody understands
about certain kinds...
...of low-paid public service work?
Every now and then
you get to put a fucking stake...
...in a bad guy's heart.
Now, we're not supposed
to talk about that...
...when we visit a 3rd grade
classroom for Career Day.
And it doesn't get you very far
into a country club locker room...
...but it's hard to beat
when you actually get to do it.
I have some work to do.
Thank your family very much
for a lovely evening.
Thank you, Judge Gardner.
Officer.
We gotta find the gun.
-l had three teams out there--
-He did this.
We know he did it, right? So...
...let's find it.
We can't.
You wanna move on?
I know a guy in the evidence room
and he owes me a favor.
He can swap these
for the shells in evidence...
...give us a ballistic match,
and we'll have our gun.
Go home.
What else you got, man?
What else you got, Willy?
[PHONE RlNGS]
WlLLY [ON MACHlNE]: This is Willy
Beachum. You tell me what I need to know.
Hey, it's me.
Things sort of got
out of hand today and l guess....
I guess this is something neither of us
was expecting in our lives right now.
And l think we have to....
I think we have to figure out
what to do about that.
This is where to find me.
Call me.
WOMAN [ON MACHINE]:
You have one unheard message.
Sent today at 4:1 0 p.m.
STEPHANlE: Hi, Mr. Beachum.
This is Stephanie from Miramar Hotel.
The security tapes you
were asking for are ready.
You can pick them up any time
at the reception desk. Thanks.
FLORES:
You know it's him, all right?
There's no doubt that that guy is him.
WlLLY:
Well, there's no face.
So? We enhance it.
-Enhance a hat?
-You know that is him...
...and he's there on the day
he shot her.
-And why is he there the day of?
-What?
-Why is he there the day of?
-What are you talking about?
This is a guy who plans everything
down to the hat, okay?
What's he doing there the day of?
What part of the plan is that?
What the f--
Okay. He's there because
he's gotta see it for himself.
-They're at the pool.
-Yeah, at the pool.
-He's jealous, his wife's having an affair.
-No, no, man.
He's there, getting worked up.
He's about to shoot her, trying on
the dress, sniffing her panties.
This guy, this guy here?
He's a psycho. And the point is
that you're missing...
...he's a psycho
we just caught on tape.
-You got motive.
-l do not have motive.
I don't have motive unless I have him...
...and l don't have face,
so l don't have him.
-That is such lawyer shit.
-lt is lawyer shit.
Why do you think
I'm getting out of criminal law?
Huh? And I'll tell you, l'm not
gonna end my career on a case...
...where all l have is an enhanced hat
when what l should've had...
-...was a murder weapon!
-That is new evidence.
What l should've had
was a signed confession!
-l told you he was playing games.
-You and your men should have got that.
-That is a cop-out.
-Don't tell me that.
You couldn't find my gun and you let Nunally
take the confession of a guy he beat up.
Nunally? Nunally lied to me,
that's what happened.
-l gotta go make a case out of nothing.
-Just being an asshole.
[PHONE RlNGING]
-Beachum.
NUNALLY: It's done.
In the toolshed,
taped to the lawn mower blade.
MAN: Two-ten, eastbound. They were going
about 85 miles an hour....
WOMAN:
District attorney's office.
WlLLY:
Can l talk to you?
-Have a seat.
-Okay.
-l'm not mad at you or anything.
-Oh, okay.
Are you all right?
[SIGHS]
Can l ask you to do something
for me this morning?
Yeah.
-You got your cell phone on you?
-Yeah.
Could you sit outside the courtroom?
Because I might call you.
And if l do...
...just hang up.
And come inside and whisper
something in my ear about...
...finding the murder weapon.
You found it.
I haven't decided that yet.
Okay.
REPORTER 1 :
Mr. Beachum. Mr. Beachum.
REPORTER 2: Sir?
REPORTER 3: Mr. Beachum.
Mr. Beachum. Mr. Beachum,
do you have any new evidence?
Mr. Beachum.
Your Honor...
...l would like to submit
a motion at this time.
What type of motion, Mr. Crawford?
I move for a judgment of acquittal.
-Objection.
ROBlNSON: On what grounds?
The prosecutor doesn't
have any actual evidence...
...proving that l did anything.
I'm about to present my evidence,
Your Honor.
But all of his witnesses
will testify to the same facts.
That my wife was shot
and that l was...
...tragically in the house at the time,
and in a way, a victim myself.
I'll stipulate to the testimony of
Mr. Beachum's entire witness list.
Accordingly l move for a judgment--
I'm sorry. Under the California...
...penal code, section 1 1-1 8.1 ,
for a judgment of acquittal...
...on the ground that the evidence is
insufficient to sustain a conviction.
Thank you.
Your legal skills
seem to have improved...
...over the long weekend,
Mr. Crawford.
Mr. Beachum,
have you any new evidence?
WlLLY:
Your Honor.
May I have a moment, Your Honor?
TED: Your Honor.
-Mr. Beachum.
Mr. Beachum.
I have no further evidence
at this time, Your Honor.
Motion for a judgment
of acquittal is granted.
The jury is released with our apologies
and the defendant is free to go.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Well, even a broken clock
gets to be right twice a day.
Hey, Rob, take it easy, huh?
[CELL PHONE VIBRATES]
NIKKl:
Willy?
Hey, I just heard. l'm sorry.
What'd you think,
I wasn't keeping tabs?
I don't know what l thought.
Listen, what do you say...
...l take you out tonight
and get you completely trashed?
Tomorrow's just a travel day.
[GUNSHOT]
What was that? Willy?
Are you there?
MAN:
Over here.
WOMAN: lnitial there and there,
sign and date at the bottom.
Mr. Beachum.
What a surprise.
Now don't tell me, let me guess.
You've got religion or something, haven't
you? You've found God, all that stuff.
Because it's not just the winning
or the losing anymore.
It's the injustice of it.
This is priceless.
Oh, come on, Willy. You gotta let me
enjoy this just a little bit, old sport.
You really need to be nice
to me now, Willy.
Why?
Because...
...what's left of a life...
...depends on a machine
powered by a cord...
...that leads to a plug
in an electrical outlet...
...and l decide when it gets pulled.
That's why.
[CHATTERlNG]
WlLLY: Excuse me. l'm looking for--
-l'll call you.
WlLLY: Oh, never mind. Thank you.
-l called you all night.
Listen, l need your help.
I don't know anything
about civil court.
I gotta get a restraining order...
-...or this guy's gonna pull the plug.
-What are you doing?
-What?
-You shouldn't be here.
I gotta tie him up.
I gotta challenge his health-care proxy.
I gotta find somebody.
I don't know who.
Like a family member to stop him.
-l really tried, Willy.
-Hey, hey, hey.
Don't.
This man is gonna kill his wife.
And what does that have
to do with Wooton Sims?
Hey. Excuse me. Hey. Sorry.
-Do you know any civil-court judges?
-Walk with me.
Do you know any civil-court judges?
-l just need a number.
-Have you been at home at all today?
No, I've been trying to find somebody
who can put me in touch with a judge.
There's a restraining order
out against you.
I've got a restraining order against me?
You were at the hospital, right?
Overnight.
-And he got one against me?
-Yeah. He has a lawyer now.
-They went to Judge Gorman this morning.
-Who's his lawyer? Goldstein?
Listen to yourself.
He can have you arrested.
Your one shot, you had it, okay?
I know l had one shot
and l blew it, all right?
Yeah. And he walked,
and there is nothing we can do.
He's a private citizen now.
We have no standing.
When you're done, you are done.
Those are the rules.
What about her?
You have to worry about yourself now.
No, I've, you know, done that.
I've done a lot of that.
[EKG BEEPING]
Your Honor?
I got nowhere else to go.
-Hi, Ted.
-Hi.
GARDNER:
It probably won't hold up on appeal.
I just need the time.
Here we go.
WOMAN:
Reflexes, no change.
Turn off the ventilator.
WlLLY:
Hey.
-What's going on?
-Step outside.
-l got a court order.
-l'm sorry. Just step outside.
I got a-- l got a court order.
-l got a c--
[EKG FLATLlNES]
You're not answering your phone.
That's kind of an answer
in itself, isn't it?
LOBRUTO:
Need a hand with this?
Can l get you a beer or something?
Thank you.
So, what now?
Something else.
You belong in a prosecutor's office.
Well, what happened to
"heads must roll"?
Yeah, well, it's my office.
At least until the next election.
Thank you, but no thank you.
We all lose, Willy.
I let a man get away with murder.
How am l supposed to live with that?
Well, you learn to.
Well, l hope not.
All right.
You know,
if it makes you feel any better...
...technically you let a man
get away with attempted murder.
For what it's worth.
[PHONE RlNGS]
Yeah? All right. l got it all right here.
I finished the r--
[CELL PHONE VIBRATlNG]
It's in the box right now,
it's coming. lt's-- Just a sec.
Hey, honey. I'm just on a call.
Yeah. Okay, just a sec.
No. I will not do that.
It's not-- And thank you. Good--
Right. Well, I've--
Like l said, the reports are done.
They're on their way.
Hey, hon. No, did you get the suit?
-Yeah, I got the cut.
-Can l read that?
Okay, hon.
I'll pick up the kids,
see you at the school.
I'll bring the suit.
No, I'll be there. l'm leaving right now.
I am not going to be late, okay?
Hey. Why don't you go home?
Get a life.
[CELL PHONE VIBRATES]
Alrighty.
Turn off the lights when you're done.
Yeah, hon?
It's yours.
-Yeah.
-Hello, old sport.
Willy, can you hear me?
I called to say goodbye.
I'm leaving tonight on that second
honeymoon we talked about.
Won't be quite the same
without our Jennifer, though, will it?
Anyway, I have
a little something for you.
It's a present, a little gift...
...and I was gonna send it
to Wooton Sims but...
...l guess that's not
working out anymore.
And the DA's office didn't
have a forwarding address.
Um, do you have any suggestions?
[DOORBELL RlNGS]
Just let yourself in. l'll be right out.
[BEEPS AND DOOR BUZZES OPEN]
Good evening, Willy.
So, what do you think?
Oh, yeah, that's...
...really...
...really, really nice of you.
A simple "no, thank you"...
...is the preferred etiquette
when declining a gift.
It takes a very special sort of person...
...to look into someone's eyes
and shoot them, Willy.
A certain kind of strength...
...if you know what l mean.
Well, l guess you'd know that,
wouldn't you?
Oh, yes, I would.
Anyway...
...l've got another bag to pick up.
Don't you start shooting
without me now, will you?
I noticed something.
It's a little late.
Oh, hell, it's a lot late.
But l noticed...
...that...
...you and Nunally
have the exact same gun.
So?
That's why you went to the hotel
that afternoon, isn't it?
You took his,
you put yours in his place.
I gave it back.
Right, you gave it back.
And all he could see was her.
And then you knew
that he would just...
...walk the murder weapon
right out of the house, didn't you?
That's very clever.
It wasn't just clever.
Admit it, Willy. lt was beautiful.
He sat through the entire trial...
...wearing the only piece
of evidence on his hip.
Yeah.
Then he used it on himself.
Sometimes life gives us
these little gifts...
...if you know what l mean.
I do know what you mean.
I know exactly
what you mean because...
...l got the bullet.
The one in your wife's head.
That one we couldn't take out
as long as she was alive.
I'm pretty sure it's gonna match Nunally's
and that gives me the murder weapon.
Nicely done, Willy.
Truly.
A regular chain of evidence.
Great stuff.
Vivid.
Heartbreaking.
The victim cries out
from beyond the grave.
Yeah. Jurors love all that sort of crap,
don't they?
I bet you don't even need
a confession anymore...
...do you, Willy?
I tell you what, though, old sport.
Let's make you a new one just in case.
The real deal, all the juicy details.
You can get your rocks off on that,
then, can't you? Huh?
Yeah.
I shot my wife in the face, right there.
She didn't look so pretty after that.
And l stood there
looking down at her...
...and l watched her eyes go all empty.
I could smell the blood and the shit.
Smelled like metal.
And the look on his face.
He was trying to get her back to life
and l was pissing myself laughing...
...because I took both the bastards out
with one fucking bullet.
Yeah.
And now you've got your
little bullet, haven't you?
Got what you want.
So bring it all on, kiddo.
Bring it all into court.
Except you can't.
Can you?
Let's see, now, first year law,
double jeopardy.
I went to trial, you lost.
Oh, pity about that.
It doesn't matter what you do now.
It doesn't matter what you know.
I mean, she could come back
from the dead, you see...
...and testify, spill the beans,
and it would mean...
...nothing.
So you can't touch me...
...ever.
She was alive.
When you first went to trial
for attempted murder...
...your wife was still alive.
But you just had to pull that plug,
didn't you?
Well, now she's dead,
and that's murder.
That's homicide, first degree,
and that's new charges.
That's new evidence.
That's a new trial.
Get the fuck out of my house.
All right.
I just don't know
why you didn't let it go.
The doctor said...
...she probably would have
outlived us all.
BAlLIFF:
All rise.
The Superior Court of Los Angeles...
...People of the State of California
v. Theodore Crawford.
The Honorable
Judge Joseph Pincus presiding.
Looking good.
Are the People ready, Mr. Beachum?
Very well.
We will now proceed
with opening statements.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury....
[ENGLISH SDH]