§§[Rhythmic clapping]
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§ OldMiss Lucy's
deadandgone§
§Leftmehere
to weep andmoan§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§ OldMiss Lucy's
deadandgone§
§Leftmehere
to weep andmoan§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let'donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§Bring Sally up
andbring Sally down§
§Let's donestart
Gotta till theground§
§ OldMiss Lucy's
deadandgone§
§Leftmehere
to weep andmoan§§
§§[Radio:IndistinctRap]
cornerofWiltern
and Wetherly.
Tumbler messed up.
He said the Porsche should be...
at the corner
ofWiltern and Wetherly.
- It's right there.
- You're bullshittin'me, right ?
- 9024 Wiltern ?
- What ? That ?
I gotta get my tool.
Kip ! He ain't
bullshittin'.
Kip ! That's nota tool.
That's a damnbrick !
Kip, man, we gonna use a brick,
man, we might as well call
a prison and make reservations.
Ah, come on.
[Alarm Blaring]
Get the number.
42850.
Hurry up, man.
Man, let's go!
Let's get the hell
outta here.
Okay, Billy Badass,
you got us in here.
Now tell me how the hell
we gonna get out.
Oh, no. I knowyou ain't gonna do
what I thinkyou're gonna do.
- Oh, man !
- Come on !
- This ain't The Dukes of Hazzard.
- [Screaming]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Whimpers ]
- [ Horns Honking ]
Yo, so check out my new move.
I call it ''The Stranger.''
What I do is, I sit on my hand
for like 1 5, 20 minutes...
untilitgoes numb,
no feeling atall.
And then... I rub one out.
The Stranger, huh ?
It's like a little boys' nursery
school I've come upon here.
Where are they ?
[ Engine Revving ]
- You wantit ?Allright.
- Hey.
- Leave thosepeople alone.
- Oh, my God.
Sweetie, you're so talented.
- Wha-- Hey, hey.
Stolen car. Stolen car.
- I know. I know.
Hey, I loveyou.
[ Engines Revving,
Tires Screeching ]
Man, we goin' tojail, man !
Come on !
Keepyour hands behind your back.
You have the right to remain silent.
Hey, watch it !
We have a silver Porsche.
Estimated speed: 80 miles per hour.
- [ Laughing ]
- Heading west on Wilshire Boulevard.
This isAir One. We have a visual
ofthesuspectsouthbound...
on Vincent Thomas Bridge.
- Something wrong, Tumbler ?
- Yeah, I'm missingJerrySpringer.
[Horn Honking]
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah !
That's right, that's right,
that's right, that's right !
[ Laughs ]
What's up, old man ?
She'll go zero to 60
in 5.2 seconds.
Believe me,
Ican vouch forthat.
Groundunits beadvised, suspects last
seen enteringsouth side ofwarehouse.
- [ Muttering ]
- Thirteen down, thirty-seven to go.
- What the hell is that ?
- What is that, man ?
- Nowyou've gone and done it, Raines.
- Tumbler !
- Get the board and get the lights !
- Igotit, Igotit!
This is bullshit.
It's not comin' off !
- Keys ! Get thekeys !
- I got 'em. I got 'em !
come on, everybody!
Let's go! Hurry up !
- I got it !
- Let's go! Toby, getit!
- Let's go, boys !
- Come on, come on ! I got the light !
Go, go, go !
Let's go !
Shit !
[ Sirens Wailing ]
§Iguess Ididn'tknow§
§Iguess Ididn't
Iguess Ididn'tknow§§
[Police Radio, Indistinct]
[Offiicer]
Get the VINnumberon that ?
- Igotit.
- We've gotalamp shade bya truck.
-[Offiicers chattering]
- What do we got ?
All gone. We didn't get
a single one of'em.
And we are talking
about professionals.
No visible damage to locking mechanisms,
steering columns or ignitions.
And, as you can see,
these are not Honda Civics.
This is one ofthree
brand-new Mercedes,
a car they say
is unstealable.
Yeah, unless you get
the laser-cut transponder key...
sent directly to the U.S.
dealer from Hamburg.
They got somebody
working on the inside.
- Find out which dealership sold
them, serviced them, etc., etc.
- Yeah, I'll get on it.
- Mr. Drycoff ?
- Yeah ?
Let's impound these cars for
one month. I don't give a damn
ifthey belong to Tom Cruise.
control, vision, determination.
These are the three
fundamental components...
ofthe new generation
race car driver.
Speed is a byproduct.
Going fast.
But remember: The car is you,
you are the car.
Okay ? Let's ride !
[ Kids Cheering, Shouting ]
Billy, youjust shaved
one second offyour lap time !
[ Cheering ]
Tommy, I don't know what
that was, but it wasn't driving.
Go get 'em !
Well, well, well. What doyou pay
your pit crews with ?
Oreos and Gummy Bears ?
I folded, Atley. You know that.
What areyou doing here ?
- Is there someplace we can talk ?
- About what ?
Aboutyour brother
and the deep shit he's in.
Frank, can you watch
the kids for a minute ?
Tell me about Kip.
He took ajob,
and he fumbled it.
Now he'sjammed up.
He'sjammed up bad.
- What kind ofjob ?
- A boost. A big boost.
A boost ?
What's Kip doing on a boost ?
Oh, you're shittin' me, man.
Kip's become quite
the little crew runner sinceyou left.
You don't talk toyour ma ?
She neglected to mention it.
[ Sighs ]
Listen, I need something.
I-I need something
cold to drink.
I thought we were goin'
someplace to talk.
- Who was thejob for ?
- A new guy named Raymond Calitri.
They call him
''The Carpenter.''
He's runnin' all the dark
ponies down there now.
It's a full-on '' Devil came
down to Long Beach'' trip.
He's bad.
He's real bad.
And this Calitri is the one
who's after my brother ?
Like stains on a mattress.
And you should know...
I work for him.
There weren't a lot ofopportunities
for retired car thieves on the gimp.
He put me to work.
I-I gotta tell you, Memphis, this guy,
he scares the shit out ofeven me.
[ Grunting ]
What areyou doin', man ?
Stop ! Stop !
[cell Phone Ringing]
AtleyJackson.
Gotit. Theyhave Kip.
Take me there.
Raymond Calitri,
Memphis Raines.
-[TVSportscaster, Indistinct]
- I try...
to learn yourways,
understand your obsessions.
But this baseball--
it's sobleeding boring, isn'tit ?
Where's my brother ?
Memphis Raines,
your legend precedes you.
Atley tells me
you're the best.
Afteryouleft, auto theftin the
South Bayarea wentdown 47percent.
Where's my brother ?
I'm proudofthese. Straddle chair
from theArts andcraftsperiod.
Mahogany table
with cloud-lift pattern.
Blackwalnut wine table.
Metal's cold, ugly.
Wood's warm, clean,
providedbynature.
See a piece offurniture take shape,
it's like watching a child grow.
I asked you a question.
They threw us out of England,
threw us out of France,
but here we are,
flourishing really,
except for the minor inconvenience of
despising everything aboutyour country.
On this listyou'll fi nd
50 cars-- five-zero.
I need all 50 delivered
to Long Beach Harbor, pier 1 4
by 8:00 a.m. four days from now.
I'm paying $200,000.
I'm not interested.
I'm just here for my brother.
Young Kip came to me.
He had street cred.
The brother ofthe notorious
Memphis Raines.
So two weeks ago I hired him
and advanced him $1 0,000.
Atley told me. Ifit's about the
advance, I can understand your anger.
The debt has to be settled.
Ten grand, from me toyou.
- I wish it was that easy.
- I don't see the complication.
I have four days to deliver 50 cars,
and I have no cars.
- Well, that's another problem.
- It is another problem, isn't it ?
It's about me delivering 50 top-end cars
because I said I would.
Because ifI don't, my South American
friend goes somewhere else from now on.
And that's not good.
It's a humiliation.
Because I'm the asshole
who said I could deliver.
Am I an asshole ?
Do I look like an asshole ?
Yeah.
- I need that paper satisfied.
- I'm retired.
And where the hell
is my brother ?
I made this as well.
My fi rst one.
It takes 80,000 pounds
ofpressure to crush a car.
- Kip ?
- Who's that ?
- Memphis.
- Oh, shit.
You okay ?
[ Grunting ]
Shut it off !
-[Kip] Turn itoff!
- You've got 30 seconds
to consideryour options.
- Shut it off !
- One: You kill me; they kill you.
- Your brother dies anyway.
- [Screaming continues]
Two: You lie, you accept thejob,
you takeyour brother, you run.
I huntyou down, I kill you, I kill
your brother, and I kill your mother...
for the aggravation
you've caused me.
Three: Youaccept the deal,
youstealsome cars,
you make some money
and you be a big brother.
-[Kip] Memphis !
- 8:00 a.m. Friday morning.
The cars are on the boat,
oryour brother's in the coffi n.
Getme outta here !
Somebodygetme outta here.
Listen, youreally don't
have tomakemeanything.
Oh, hey, you come down here.
You saved my ass.
It's the least I can do.
Hey, I heard you were, uh, pumping gas
someplace up North or something, right ?
- Yeah, working with kids.
- Oh, really ?
'' First place.''
I remember this.
Oh, yeah, that was--
that was a long time ago.
What'd you put in it ?
[ Chuckling ]
I don't know.
[ Coughing ]
It's good.
Ow. Ow. Oh, God.
Does Mom know
about any ofthis ?
No, no, no, she doesn't,
and I don't think she should.
You know, she-- she works
really hard, and this-- this--
She doesn't need to know
about any ofthis stuff.
Look, you know,
I got everything under control.
Kitchen's on fi re.
Uh, man.
Hey, Memphis.
It's good to seeyou.
[Man]
Haul the cartons overthere !
- Hey, Fuzzy.
- Aw, shit. What areyou doin' here ?
- I told you I don't know anything.
- Yeah, butyou're a liar.
- You're gonna get me fi red, man.
- Fired ? That's not good.
You're on parole, right ?
Fuzzy, hey, nobody
wants to getyou fi red.
Wejust need this
information is all.
Two weeks ago, a call came in
for a lot oftop-end cars.
- And who made that call ?
- I don't have a clue.
- Okay. We should go talk toyour boss.
- Oh, shhh.
The delivery date.
I know the delivery date.
- And when is that ?
- Thursday, Friday, end ofthe week.
Well, you get me a name
within 48 hours, orwe'll be back.
Good to seeyou, buddy.
Thankyou.
§§[country OnJukebox]
I'm looking
for Helen Raines.
Helen, someguy's
here foryou.
What guy ?
What's he look like ?
Like a fi recracker.
Likeyour son.
You look so good.
Thankyou, Momma. Here.
Spring-- Spring bouquet.
What areyou doing here ?
Well, uh, AtleyJackson
came to see me.
Told me something about Kip.
Can I helpyou
with one ofthese ?
Okay, that'syours.
Tell Castlebeck he's not gonna believe
whojust walked into the Quality Cafe.
I can't say I'm surprised.
All his life he looked up toyou,
tried to beyou.
I guess now he is.
So why is this happening ?
I send you guys money.
He-- He met some people,
and he changed.
He lost that--
that sweetness, you know ?
Okay... tell me.
How deep in is he ?
Deep.
Can you get him out ?
It means doin' things,
things I told you
I'd never do again.
Do what it takes, Randall.
[Drycoff]
When didyougetinto town, Raines ?
- Last night.
- Last night ? What for ?
I thought I'd catch a Lakers game.
Heard we got Shaquille.
- [ Laughing ]
- Guys wanna go ?
- Guess not.
- Randall, Randall, Randall, come here.
I get this call from this
uniform, you know ?
Axton. Very nice man.
Remembers everything.
This man calls me up, says, ''Guess
who's back in town ?'' I say, ''Who ?''
He says, ''Randall Raines. ''
Isay, ''Randall Raines the carthief?''
He says, ''Yeah.'' I say, ''Impossible.''
He says, '' No, he's back.''
I say, '' No, he's not.''
He says, ''Yes, I will betyou $200
I just saw Randall Raines.''
- You guys said a lot. Look, Detective--
- No, whoa, whoa.
What's really, really
ironic about this--
Two nights ago we snare these
1 3 fresh stolens waiting for export.
At the time I'm thinking,
''This feels like Randall Raines.''
Now, it didn't haveyour
panache, your, uh, flash,
but itjust felt
like Randall Raines.
Andnowhereyouare.
Look, I don't know
whatyou boys are looking for,
but I just got back, okay ?
It was a family emergency.
Now, that's the truth.
Family emergency. Yeah, I got
a family emergency too, Randall.
I gotta go tell mywoman
that I just lost $200 on a stupid deal.
- Mmm, she's mean.
- What ?
She can be mean.
[ Mutters ]
Come here.
Come here, Randall.
Take those glasses off, Randall.
Please, do me a favor.
[ Sighs ] Sixyears agoyou make
a real smart move, you know ?
You retire from a life that's gonna get
you busted or killed or maybe even both.
And I'm thinkin' that not putting
you awaywhen I had a chance...
is like this big bug up the ass ofthis
real impressive career that I've had.
Oh, yeah.
Well, without disappointment,
you can't appreciate victory.
Eleanor tell you that ?
Now, that's hittin'
below the belt.
Yeah, all right, let me tell you
about below the belt, Randall.
From here on out, ifyou walk across
the street outside ofa crosswalk,
ifyou roll
through a stop sign,
ifyou use an aerosol can in
a manner other than directed--
I mean, I don't care,
you make one slip,
and I will putyou away
for good.
- Okay.
- By the timeyougetout, asshole,
there won't even be cars.
We'll all be cruising around
in your little, vroom, spaceships.
[ Laughs ]
That's gonna suck.
Who's Eleanor ?
It's a damn car.
And don't ever
talk about mywife.
Excuse me.
You know where Otto is ?
- He's in the back, in the paint shop.
-[Workers chattering]
[ Snarling ]
Is thatyou ? About time
you came to see me.
- I missed you.
- Good to seeyou !
[ Laughing ]
You look great.
- It's good to seeyou.
- You too. Oh, remember myJunie ?
Hey,Junie.
How areyou ?
- We're doin' good, thankyou.
- Good, good.
You look happy.
Well, I am happy.
I really am.
So what happened here ?
- What doyou mean ?
- Well, it's nice.
But the chop shop,
the stripped cars, my education.
What happened ? Hey.
[ Mutters ]
Old age happened.
That's what happened.
Got tired ofkilling 'em.
You know, I woke up
one morning and thought,
''I'm no longer a destroyer.
I'm a means ofresurrection.''
Now we restore,
we revive.
comehere.
Remember we usedto do this ?
- What ?
- You know. Come here. Okay.
-[Engine Revving On Tape]
- It's a Ferrari 365 GTB-4 Daytona.
Le Mans, 1 971 .
- Five cam--
- That's a V-1 2.
V-1 2, right, right,
right, right !
Here it peaks
at 5,500 r.p.m. !
- What doyou know
about Raymond Calitri ?
- Who ?
Raymond Calitri.
Uh, excuse us, sweetness.
I'll be right back.
- We can talk here.
- No, no, no, no, no. It's all right.
Raymond Calitri.
He's ajackal tearing at the
soft belly ofour-- ofour fair town.
And he's an asshole to boot,
so be careful.
I heard about Kip.
Areyou considering a comeback tour ?
- Doyou think it can be done ?
- Don't do this to me, okay ?
Please, please not now.
Oh, man.
- How many cars ?
- Fifty.
- How many days ?
- Three.
How many in your crew ?
One, but I came here
hoping to negotiate for a second.
No way.
It can't be done.
I mean, you need time to prep,
time to shop. You know that.
It has to be.
They're gonna kill him.
Oh, man.
It was a mistake
to come here.
You have a great life now.
I don't want to upset that.
Uh, waitaminute.
Uh, holdon.
Look around you.
These days...
I'm all about second chances.
So, uh, let's make a few phone calls,
and we'll go from there, okay ?
Okay.
- [ Horns Honking ]
- Don't look at me !
Look at the people next toyou !
- [ Woman Screaming ]
- That's-- Turn the wheel !
- Pull over ! Pull her the hell over !
-[Horns Honking]
[ Man Shouts ]
Asshole !
Learn how to drive !
[ Sighs ]
Don't touch nothing. Just--
No !
You can't negotiate turns.
You can't signal properly.
You can't maintain speed.
You can't parallel park.
Hell, you can't drive, honey.
Shit, I can't swim.
I know I can't.
Soyou know what I do ?
I stay my black ass outta the pool.
- [ Crying ]
- All right now,just--
[ Cell Phone Ringing ]
Can you-- Oh !
Hello ?
- [ Crying Continues ]
- Memphis ! Hey, how areyou ?
Sure, sure.
When ? Okay.
- 3296981 1 .
- All right. Thanks a lot.
Donny.
Just take it around the block
a couple oftimes, okay ?
Allright.
[ Tires Squealing ]
Hello. I'm calling
for Frankie Fish.
Frank's dead, man.
Yeah, he got scragged.
- I'm sorry.
- Uh, yeah, I'm looking
for Henry Santoro.
He went down to Florida
with that asshole Frankie Fish.
- Tellhim I wantmymoney.
- I didn't mess with your money.
Yes, ma'am. I'm looking
for Dan and Mikey.
Both of'em up to Chino.
Doin' a nickel apiece.
Now I'm not so sure
I want to tell you who this is.
- Yeah, try it, asshole.
- You sound very busy right now.
- [Woman Moaning]
- You sound very, very busy.
- [ Barks ]
- [Moaning continues]
Whew. There's
only two names left.
Yeah ? Let me see.
[ Muttering ]
Those two ? No way.
There's no one else.
[ Chuckles ]
Areyou sure ?
- You tell him.
- Listen, why should I--
- Come on !
- You were the one
who answered the phone.
- Fine ! Fine !
- But how's a guywho can't speak
gonna take a phone call ?
You've gota call!
Sphinx, is thatyou ?
Press a button ifit's you.
Sway, you set up
this brakejob ?
[Woman]
Yeah. He warpedall fourrotors.
Must've beenridin'those
brakes likean oldlady.
- That's nice.
- Sounds like the left
bank's running lean.
[Engine Revving]
The service department's
over there.
- Can I talk toyou ?
- Talk to me ? Yeah, sure, talk.
- The thing ofit is,
I came back because--
- Doyou know what time it is ?
It's 5:30.
I came back because--
I gotta go.
I'm late forwork.
- [ Muttering ]
- [ Sighs ]
You're at work.
I got twojobs.
I have discovered thatyou have
to work twice as hard when it's honest.
[ Chattering, Laughter]
- Hey, Sway, can I get another shot ?
- Yep.
Still lookin' amazing.
Whileyou look
like a Bible salesman.
You're healed.
can we improvise
alittle bit ?
Sure. What doyou have in mind ?
Wanna get a little crazy ?
There's a Cutlass 442 in the back
we can strip down and shine the hood.
- What doyou say ?
- Uh, that's not what I had in mind.
No ?
It's about my brother.
- Kip's in trouble.
- In trouble ?
- Took a boost, and he blew it.
- Shit.
[ Sighs ]
And you got some Italians ?
- Five or six.
- Right.
It's 50 ladies in 24 hours,
$200,000.
Well, I've cleaned up.
I understand. I hate
to even come here and ask--
Sway, can I get
that drink now, please ?
I had to ask a few ofthe others too,
and I feel bad about it, but--
- Butyou had no choice.
You had to come here--
- Pretty much.
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
I'd love to help Kip,
but I-I'm not into the life anymore.
Well, that's a good thing.
- Yeah.
- I'm glad to seeyou're doing well.
Sorry, I can't helpyou.
- I'd like to pay foryour drink.
- That's fi ne.
How about that drink ?
Yeah, how about that drink ?
Raines !
Memphis Raines, huh ?
- Do I knowyou ?
- Well, youshouldknowme...
considering all the business you done
screwed up for me in the past, baby.
-Johnny B.
- That's me.
What can I do foryou ?
Well, I'm gonna tell you
whatyou can do for me, baby.
Get out of Long Beach, tonight.
I'll be gone in three days.
I'm just here on some family business.
Word on the street says Raymond Calitri
hired you and your brother...
for a top order, a order
that should've went to me.
That's not the way
it went down,Johnny.
[ Grunting ]
Hey ! Get away
from my car, asshole !
Gotsomethin'tosay
before Ikillyou, fool?
[ Grunting ]
[ Bones Crunching,
Screaming ]
[ Gasps, Whimpers ]
Sphinx. Otto send you ?
[Man On Radio]
§I'm gonna call the doctor§
§I'm gonnagetbetter§
§I'm gonnarun
forthepriest§§
- Oh, Dad.
-§§[continues, Indistinct]
We'd probably both be working
at the dealership ifhe hadn't died,
Just like normal people.
Shit.
[ Sighs ]
What's the matterwith you ?
Eh, sixyears does
a lot ofdifferent things to people.
Youknow, Idon'tknow
whereyou went, but...
you know, you're in there,
you're talking about being normal--
Imean, you were always the one
who was goin'afterthe easymoney.
I didn't do it
for the money.
I did it for the cars.
Gleaming in marina blue,
sunfi reyellow,
Marlboro red.
Begging tobeplucked.
And I'd do it.
I'd boost her...
andjust blast
to Palm Springs,
instantly feeling better
about being me.
Andthen thenextday,
itseemslike,
I'm gettingshotat,
my friends are dying,
people are going tojail.
I didn't like
what I'd become.
Yeah, and then you left,
and then I didn't
have a brother anymore,
andnowyou want
togive meadvice...
andIdon'tevenknowyou.
And, youknow, Igotmy own familynow,
Igotmy own friends.
And you can saywhatyou want
about them, but they're loyal.
Well, when you hit the wall,
the same thing's gonna happen.
You and your family...
are either
gonnagetshot...
or get a five-year
Jolt at Corcoran.
[Horn Honking]
Those Mercedes we impounded?
Needthosenewfangledlaser-cutkeys.
Each one's from Dressner Foreign Motors
downtown Newport...
where all the employees
are clean, except for him.
James Lakewood. Served a nickel
at Folsom for auto insurance fraud.
My gosh, I bet hejust neglected
to mention that to the people at
Dressner Foreign Motors, huh ?
It gets better. YoungJames there
places orders for lost keys...
to the Mercedes
home office in Germany.
- The list.
- [ Groans ]
The list. I guess we gotta
start beating the bushes and try
to fi nd out where they--
- Whoa ! 1 967 Shelby GT-500.
- Iknow. Iknow.
-You got Eleanor here ?
-Otto, there's somebody here to seeyou.
Oh, thepuppy's
abig dog now!
- Howareyoudoin'?
- Hey there, Kip, what is this--
What's that up under there ?
[ Laughs ]
Hey, Otto, howyou doin' ?
It's a long time.
Good to seeyou.
What areyou
doin' here, Kip ?
- Well, we actually came
to talk about some things.
- About what ?
Well, you know, it seems like
you guys need a little help,
andwe thought
that we shouldparticipate.
But I just promised Mom
I was getting you out ofthis.
No, no, we're talking
about a lot ofmoney here.
- And ifyou guys thinkyou're
gonna get into our Kool-Aid---
- What ? Money ?
Is that whyyou think I'm doing this,
you inconsiderate little punk !
Ifyou wanna participate, well, then
you call Mom and you explain to her--
canyouexplain howyouare gonna
steal50 cars in two days ?
Hey. Hey.
This is why I do not
do business with family.
I thinkyou should
consider this.
Oh, come on, Otto, please. No, his
criminal career has come to an end.
Well, his life will come to an end
unless we pull this off.
How can we do it without them ?
It can't be done, and you know it.
You guys have
any skills at all ?
- Please !
- Yeah, we have skills.
We-- Mirror Man here,
he's an electronics expert.
You know, he's got some gadgets
that-- thatyou old farts
probably never heard of.
You know, uh, Tumbler over here,
he can pretty much drive
anything with wheels...
and, youknow,
some things without wheels.
And, uh, and Toby,
he's a computer genius.
He's-- He does fascinating
things with computers.
What exactly can you do
with a computer, Toby ?
I can hack
into the D.M.V. mainframe.
Ican change VINnumbers.
Ican changeaddresses, registrations.
I can do a lot
ofreally tricky stuff. I can.
All right, all right.
We do this, we do it myway.
I run the show.
You takeyour orders from me.
Ifyou have any problems
with that, you can leave now.
No, that's fi ne.
That's fi ne.
- Well, who is Gilligan here,
and what does he do ?
- Gilliganis actually Freb.
- Freb can order pizzas
like nobody's business.
- What ?
- It's true.
- Hey, people gotta eat, right ?
This is outrageous.
I want my lawyer.
I'm not saying a word
till I get a lawyer.
All right,James,
that's an option.
And frankly,
a reasonable one.
Soyou call
your lawyer,James.
You tell him you've been arrested
on suspicion ofgrand theft auto.
- We indictyou.
- He'll bail you out.
- And we move on to trial.
- Okay, okay.
A kid came to me,
said he'd pay $500 a key.
So I put the order forms through, and
he picked 'em up a couple days later.
- What's the kid's name ?
- We kept it anonymous.
He was a well-built kid.
Uh, looks like a boxer.
- What doyou want me to do ?
- When he comes back, you call us.
- What says he comes back ?
- A hunch.
To make the Friday 8:00 a.m. deadline,
you're gonna have to go old school.
A one-night boost.
Put all your nuts in one basket, okay ?
- One night ? What, areyou crazy ?
- Yes. No, I'm notcrazy.
- What, doyou have like
a better plan or something' ?
- Yeah, you spread it out.
- You play shadow games and shit.
- We're on a truncated timetable.
Otto, I'm sorry. Can youjust listen
to me for one second, all right ?
We heardyou, Kip. Shadowgames.
But whatyouhave to understand...
is that ifyou play shadow games, by
the second night, the heat is ontoyou.
With a one-night boost, by the time
the fi rst car's reported stolen,
your ship's set sail;
it's a surprise attack.
This is a complicated list,
fellas, it really is, okay ?
There are 25
thataren'taproblem,
but these exotics
are tough to fi nd.
And the new Mercedes,
they require laser-cut keys, okay ?
- Yeah, I got that covered.
- You have that covered ?
- What'd I just say ?
Yeah, I got it covered.
- Yeah.
All right, all right.
Well, then let's get to work.
[Memphis] Toby, hack into
theinsurance database...
andfindas many cars
asyoucan.
[Toby] Yes ! Igotaddresses
on Hillary, Natalie and Tracy.
[Memphis]
Donny, check the D.M. V. for
theremaining cars on thelist.
[D.M. V. clerk]
I'm sorry, miss, butyou've
missedfiive questions.
- That's a failing.
- No ! [ Whining ]
- Next.
- No ! Why ?
You're supposed to go faster
when somebody tailgates you.
- Ah. Hello again.
- Mm-hmm. Here'syourlist...
ofthe 20 car owners' names and
addresses thatyou requested.
- Thankyou.
- That's $1 00, please.
- A hundred dollars ?
- Well, five dollars a car.
Twenty cars.
Would you like a calculator ?
It used to be two dollars a car.
Thanks a lot.
My name's Roger, sir.
May I be ofsome help ?
That's funny, my name's Roger.
Two Rogers don't make a right.
- [ Laughs ] Roger, I have a problem.
- Yes ?
I've been in L.A. for three months now.
I have money, I have taste.
But I'm not
on anybody's ''A'' list,
and Saturday night is the
loneliest night ofthe week for me.
- Oh. A Ferrari would
certainly change that.
- Perhaps. Mmm.
But, you know, this is the one.
Yes, yes, yes.
I saw three ofthese parked outside
the local Starbucks this morning,
which tells me
only one thing.
There's too many self-indulgent
wieners in this city
with too much bloody money !
Now, ifI was driving...
a 1 967 275 GTB four-cam--
You would not be
a self-indulgent weiner, sir.
- You'd be a connoisseur.
- Precisely.
Champagne would fall
from the heavens.
Doors would open.
Velvet ropes would part.
I don't have one here,
however I do have one
in the warehouse.
Superb.
What else doyou have
in the warehouse ?
Mm-hmm. Allright.
Uh-huh.
That was Mr. Lakewood
from the dealership.
He says thatboxer-lookingpunk
is gonnapick up thekeys...
to three new Mercedes today.
Same make and models
as the ones we already got impounded.
- Now we're talkin'.
- [ Ship's Horn Blaring ]
The ElSpirito
de Graciela...
sails Friday,
8:00 a.m. sharp.
We'll target all the cars
within 45 minutes ofhere.
By the time theiralarm
trackingsystemsare activated,
the cars willalreadybe
in these containers.
[Motorcycle Engine Revving]
Fellas, this is Sway.
No questions.
I'm here for Kip.
- All right.
-Allright.
[ Engine Revs ]
- [ Phone Auto-Dialing ]
- [ Cell Phone Rings ]
- It's me. He's here.
- The red Chevy Nova ?
- That's affi rmative, sir.
- [ Indistinct ]
As soon as he leaves, you call me
with the owners' addresses, all right ?
I'll get those forms
right over, sir.
Damn boss.
Always on my case.
- I got three here ?
- Mm-hmm.
Thankyou.
[castlebeck] Huh, Randall Raines,
DonnyAstricky, Otto Halliwell.
Should I set up
some tails ?
Uh-uh. They're
too smart for that.
They'll just
dump the cars.
No, we'll get them
with the Mercedes.
Let's set up, uh, three surveillance
teams at those addresses.
You go ahead and you
makeyour move, man.
And I will
be waiting foryou.
Why doyou call 'em
girls' names ?
That's a good question.
Why do you call 'em girls' names ?
It's code. YousayJane,
yousayShirley, Lucy, Edna,
and nobody listening
on the waves is the wiser.
Got 'em.
Okay.
All right, we've got the addresses
on all 50 ladies. Let's scout 'em.
- There she is.
- Nice.
Damn, it's cold up here !
They keep these Ferraris refrigerated ?
And you know black people
don't like cold weather !
We're tropical people, man.
When this is over,
I'm gonna smoke ajoint,
watch two hours of Roots,
and I'm gonna kickyour ass.
Hello, and welcome
to TVcar Trivia.
First question: Who was
the driver ofa '73 Firebird ?
- Uh, Otto ?
- Uh,Jim Rockford, RockfordFiles.
Give me columbo.
- A Peugeot convertible.
- What color ?
- Grey.
- How'd you know that ?
[ Kip On Walkie-Talkie ]
'Cause I love that show.
I got three words
for all ofy'all. Get a life !
- [ Kip Laughs ]
- Ah, this is some kiddie shit, Sphinx.
What's on Magnum P.I.'s
license plate ?
[Tumbler]
''Robin 1. ''
[Kip] Wait. Wasn'tRobin that
faggotyguy whohung with him ?
No, that was Higgins.
That was Higgins.
Hey, hey, ten points
for our fearless leader.
Sway, how 'boutgiving us thehonor
ofthe Bill Bixby trifecta ?
[ Beeping ]
-[Sway]
He drove a corvettein The Magician,
-[carAlarm chirps ]
a Fordpickup truck
in The Incredible Hulk,
andin The Courtship
of Eddie's Father, he walked.
[ScannerBeeping]
- Bingo.
- My man.
§§[WomanSinging,
Indistinct]
[EngineStarting]
-[castlebeck On Radio]
Al, tellmesomething.
-[Horn Honks]
Nothin' doing here, sir.
Nobody's showing.
Copy.
Minivan approaching.
Itseemsalittle late
forsoccerpractice.
Heads up. I thinkwe got
some activity right here.
[castlebeck] Oh, thatis--
Looks likeit's Kip Raines,
andwe gota Randall Raines.
Ifthey take this,
we will take them down.
He'spullingsomething
outofhispocket. Yousee that ?
It's a camera. Looks like
he'sjustdoingsomehomework.
Allright,
let's leave him be.
I don't wanna burn this.
Theywill be back.
Huh.
You know what ? Let's go over
to Otto's in the morning.
Kick over some rocks,
see what's underneath there.
[ Memphis ]
We saved the best for last.
The '67 Shelby Mustang GT-500.
- The GT-500 ?
- Yeah, yeah.
There she is.
Yep, there's Eleanor.
Eleanor is Memphis's unicorn.
- What's a unicorn ?
- Fabled creature.
You know, the horse with the horn,
impossible to capture.
It's the one car, nomatter
howmany timesyou try toboost,
something always happens.
We're gonna get through this this time,
right ? It's gonna be smooth...
- What's he doing ?
-andeasy.
He's talkin' to her, man.
Tryin' to get reacquainted.
Donehadarough history. Shealmost
gothim killeda couple oftimes.
- I don't want any talking back.
- He flippedone on the Harborfreeway.
He went off
the Long Beach pier once.
A smooth, easy ride.
We'rejust gonna glide.
Big night tomorrow, guys.
Let's go home.
- Did you-- Did you get the picture ?
- Yeah.
Seeyou tomorrow night,
Eleanor, with your fi ne ass.
Man, we're almost home.
You wanna get something to eat ?
I'dlike toget
a chocolatemalt.
[ Tires Screeching ]
- Hey !
- Get out ofthe car !
Go, go, go, go, go !
[ Kip ]
Why are people shooting at us ?
[ Randall ]
'Cause I blew up their car !
[ Grunting ]
Over here !
- '' Beast.''
- [ PuppyWhimpering ]
Okay, okay.
[Dog Snarling, Barking]
Oh, shit ! Oh, shit !
- [ Barking Continues ]
- Hey !
[ Chickens Clucking ]
- Oh !
- [Barking continues]
[ Grunts ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
Oh, you--
you thinkit's agame ?
Johnny B.
Cops, man.
[Johnny B. ]
Iain'tgotnothin'but time, baby.
[ Chattering ]
Oh, man, we're gonna
be here all night, man.
Look ! Cop car ! Uh-huh.
Long as I'm in here, you'rejust gonna
sit out there, aren'tya ? Aye ?
Hey, listen,
this is the plan.
This is what we're gonna do.
There's a big rig over there.
[ Scoffs ]
Uh, mister, is thatyour truck
out there, the Big Rig Wrecker ?
- Big Rig Wrecker's mine.
- That's cool.
What do I gotta do ?
How do I learn ? Where do I go ?
- Well, you gotta go
to truck drivin' school.
- Truck dri--
I know, man. I know.
But I mean like, um---
- You boys ready to play
a little pin the tail on the donkey ?
- [ Snickering ]
- Can I getyou ajelly donut
or something, man ?
- No, I'm just gonna go.
- 'Cause I'm gonna have a waffle.
- Maybe next time, though.
- I'm gonna smokeyou !
- [Truck EngineStarts]
[ Yelling, Shouting ]
What the hell's going on ?
- Want some ofthis ?
-[Shouting continues]
Yeah.
- You guys got permits
for these weapons ?
- Oh, man !
[ Horn Honks ]
Soyou think I can only
get pizzas, huh ? Boosted it myself.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
How'd you get it ?
- Actually, the keys were in it.
- Oh, well, thatkindofdefiies
thepoint then, don'tit ?
You stole a car
that wasn't on the list.
that wasn't on the list !
Why didn'tyoujust go to the
police station in a red clown suit...
and let everybody know
what we're doin' here ?
- What have we got ?
- I don't know.
Shit ! Fellas.
- What ?
- Gimme that.
- check this out.
- Check this out !
- Let me see that.
This looks like heroin.
- Yeah.
- What !
- Exactly.
- Where did you get this car ?
- In front ofsome poker parlor
in Chinatown.
Did you ever considerwhy a car
in a neighborhood like that...
- wouldhave its keys leftin it ?
- No.
Maybe because nobody in that
neighborhood would be stupid
enough to rip this car off.
- All right. Get this shit
outta here. Take it back.
- No, no. We can't take it back.
- Get it outta here !
- Will everybody relax for a second ?
- [ All Shouting, Arguing ]
- Take it back !
I'm comin' after that shit.
Gimme that.
- No !
- [ Arguing Continues ]
- Man, I will knock the shit out ofyou.
- [KnockAtDoor]
- Wait, wait, wait.
- Who is it ?
- Detective Castlebeck.
- Oh. Christ.
Goddamn it.
- Hey, hello, Otto.
- Detective. Good to seeyou.
- Long time.
- Yeah. You're lookin'good.
Thankyou.
So Randall,
what do we got here ?
We got a multigenerational
gathering ofplayers ?
- Is that what we gothere ?
- Right.
Here's Donny.
- Howyou been, D ?
- I'm just happy to seeyou, brother.
Yeah. I gotta tell you, Randall.
Seeing you here, Otto, Donny,
makes me feel
almost nostalgic.
Kind oflike
a big reunion.
You should stick around,
'cause a little laterwe're gonna...
make s'mores
and sing '' Kumbayah.''
- What is this ?
- What ? They call this a Cadillac.
- [Laughs]
- Yeah.
- What's wrong with it, Otto ?
- Rest--
- Needs restoration.
- What ?
- Brightening.
- Otto.
- You got a '39 Ford right there.
- That's a pretty car.
- Isn't that a nice car ?
- Yeah. Right hereyou got
a '53 Fiat Vignale.
Now, theseare beautiful cars, Otto.
Andhere we gota '83 cadillacEldorado.
- Yeah.
- I mean, who the hell pays...
to brighten up
a Cadillac Eldorado ?
I think it holds a certain
sentimental value, you know.
Nothing more.
Run me down a tag.
License 3-2-9-H-R-O.
That is Harold, Randall, Otto,
burgundy Cadillac.
No faith in our newfound
goodness, Detective ? Huh ?
Task force runs on statistics
and numbers, Otto. You know that.
- Randall, this Kip ?
- That's my brother.
He's all grown up.
[Woman On Radio]
One-Baker-eleven, PacifiicDivision...
three-two-niner,
Harold, Randall, Otto.
No wants, no warrants at this time.
D.M. V. noton file.
Copy that.
Thankyou.
See, I know whatyou're doin'.
I know.
You're thinkin' there's no want,
but that I stripped its guts...
and crated her up, right ?
Is that whatyou did,
Randall ?
No. I didn't do it. You know, you're
trying to hurt my feelings ? Fine.
You know what ? Go ahead.
Do it. Let her rip.
- Go ahead, rev it up.
- All right, goddamn it. I will.
- Sell it toyou cheap.
- [ Laughs ]
Yeah. '83. Firstyear they
put the auto-ride control on these boys.
Oh, I don't know. You probably know
more about cars at this point than I do.
- You slippin' on me, Randall ?
- No, it'sjust
your knowledge overwhelms me.
- It's got a real nice-sounding engine.
Right, Otto ?
- Four point one liter.
- Digital fuel injection ?
- You got it. You're the man.
Give it some more.
- Yeah, that's it !
- Go, go !
- [ Whooping ]
-[Engine Revving]
Baby, don't be so mean !
Yeah, that's it !
[ All Whooping ]
- Oh, that was good.
- Yeah, you break it,
you buy it, my friend.
- [All Laughing]
- Yeah, shegotsomepowergoin'on.
[ Sighs ]
All right.
I'll catch you later.
- It's on for tonight.
- How doyou know ?
They got the call signs
on all the units working tonight.
- Wh-What wereyou gonna do with this ?
- I was gonna bonk him.
Bonk ?
For the next 24 hours,
all your decision-making
privileges have been removed !
- Yougotit ?
- Got it.
- Yeah, that's cool.
Obviously they're onto us.
He's sniffi n' real close.
Ifanything tonight
appears out ofplace,
I wantyou to cut bait,
get out ofthere and walk away.
And get rid ofthis
goddamn car !
- What's up, Kip ?
- Bobby, what areyou doin' ?
You thinkyou're comin'
with us, butyou're not.
What areyou talkin' about, man ?
I'm part ofthe team. I get to go.
No, no, wake up. Gonna end up
in thejail or the morgue
or some shit. Don't be stupid.
What am I supposed to do ?
Did you see a box
ofrubber gloves here, man ?
Gloves ? Man, you don't need gloves.
This is the new age. Check this out.
- What is this ?
- Let mejust see that big claw
you call a hand.
That's not doughnutjelly,
so don't eat it.
Your new fi ngerprints.
Elvis is back.
- Hmm.
- [ Laughs ]
- Boy got skills, right ?
- Yeah, you do.
Look like a little
ghetto Smurf.
I am a bad man.
Thanks.
Thanks for doin' this.
Keep it real.
Think slow.
We should get through it
Just fi ne.
'' Low Rider,'' Donny. Donny ?
'' Low Rider.''
§§[Music clicks On]
§Allmy friends
knowthelowrider§
§ Thelowrider
is alittle higher§§
Okay, let's ride.
§§[continues]
- [ Shattering ]
- Oh ! Shit.
Gimme that torch. Aha !
I tell you, I'm the man.
Now, where does this go ?
Find a way to get in here.
Get this--
I tell you, I'm runnin' this shit !
You do that again, I will kick--
Cool, man. You don't have
to take it so damn personal.
Ah. Everything is perfect.
Hello, ladies. Always was
a sucker for a redhead.
Let's go. Come on, move, move !
Go, go !
Workyour magic, baby. I know
you know Ferraris. Workyour magic.
- Girlgotskill.
- [ Engine Starts ]
[ Whoops ]
[carAlarm Starts,
EndsAbruptly]
[EngineStarts]
-[EngineStarts]
- You all right ?
- You thinkwe're gonna make it ?
- I don't know. It's too early to tell.
[Engines Starting]
[Randall On Radio] Diana, Tricia,
NadineandRoseare on their way.
Good goin', guys.
Al, tell me something.
Unit two. Sorry, sir.
Nothing yet.
Son ofa bitch.
I knowyou're not parking
right in front ofme.
Oh, no. I can't see
a damn thing.
All right.
We gotta move.
Youeverfeelbad
aboutany ofthis ?
Hell, no. I'm Robin Hood, man. I rob
from the rich and give to the needy.
- [ CarAlarm Wailing ]
- Damn. Donny !
I gotyou.
- You mean the poor.
- Cutters.
Cutters.
-[Alarm Stops]
- No, like I said, the needy.
'Cause, brother,
we need this car.
[EngineStarts]
- What's up, Doc ?
- You're new, aren'tya ?
- Yeah. How can you tell ?
- Now, listen, son.
You take real good care ofthis car,
and I'll take care ofyou.
Tell you what. Save it. You get
another one ofthese suits, all right ?
- God bless you, son.
- You need a fashion counselor.
All right, babe. I ain't here
for the door. I here for the car.
Getyour big ass out.
- Hmm ?
- Out ! What areyou lookin' at ?
- Hey, man, that was as easy as pie.
- I'm a veteran, son.
Get outta the car, bitch,
or I'll blowyour brains out !
- You gotta be shittin' me.
- I will shootyou, damn it !
Damn !
You lazy, half-ass bully !
Any asshole can pull a gun on somebody !
You don't know the fi rst thing
about stealin' a car ! Boy, I--
- You need a role model !
- [ Moaning ]
Stacy.
§Down anddirty, baby§
- Shannon.
-§ can'tstop therock§
§ can'tstop therock
Youcan'tstop therock§§
§§[continues]
Laura.
Lindsay.
Rachel.
Hey. check this out.
J.J ., he's back. But he's smart.
He watches his ass.
Justholdourpositions.
Ifherolls,
-youfollowhim out.
- Copy that.
What's he doin'?
What-- Whatareyoudoing ?
We mightas wellroll down
our windows andwave.
-J.J ., you tail him. All right ?
-[AJ. On Radio] copy that.
Let's go.
- Good luck.
- Piece ofcake.
Unit one, this is unit two.
Astricky has landed.
[castlebeck On Radio]
Iftheyroll, we take them down.
Last night that van was parked
four houses down. Now it's only two.
- We got company.
- Shit.
He's at the car.
[Memphis On Radio]
Bird, comeback.
- Stand by, unit one.
- What ?
- Where areyou ?
- Where doyou think I am ?
I'm at the casino, picking up
pit boss's lady. What doyou want ?
- The ladies are dirty. Walk away.
The ladies are dirty.
- What ?
I want everybody to get back
to the garage now.
Oh, so she's havin'
a baby right now ?
I guess I better get
to the hospital then, huh ?
Something's got him spooked.
Mywife is havin' a baby.
Gotta get--
I'm nervous ! This ain't even my car !
Way over here--
He's heading away
from the vehicle.
- [ Sighs ]
- I seeyou.
[Dispatcherchatter
On Radio]
Pull in over there.
- [ Sighs ]
- [ On Radio ] Hello.
This is unit two. I lost them.
[ Sighs ]
Allright, it's time
to talk to Fuzzyagain.
check this out.
Laser-encodedkeys thatsend
amessage toareceiver...
inside the car.
You wanna tell me
whatyou're doin' with these ?
Yeah. These are from last week.
These are from the other boost.
[GuysArguing]
- Who is it ?
- [Arguing continues]
- Thekeys, thekeys, thekeys !
- Takeiteasy!
- Nowgimme this !
- What happened ? What happened ?
- Where'd you get these from ?
- What's theproblem ?
The Mercedes are dirty !
There's surveillance vans all over them.
- Where'd they come from ?
- Whoa. My guy in Southland.
The same guy I used last time.
- Same guy I used before.
- Before when ?
- When we-- When we took the other cars.
- Other Mercedes.
- Christ.
- Castlebeck.
He got to one ofthe guys
at the dealership, and he turned him.
That's what happened.
Eight hours left.
So what, we're gonna stand around and
have a meeting ? Wh-What's goin' on ?
Memphis, maybe it's time for us
to start thinking about...
- how to get theseyoung kids
out oftown, 'cause--
- [ All Objecting ]
Ifthere's no Mercedes,
there's no point in boosting
any other cars. You hear me ?
- That's it.
- 47 is not 50, Memphis.
You know that's what he'll say.
Yeah.
Hey, Memphis. Youknow, we stillhave
the Mercedes keys from thelastboost.
Hey ! Those cars are
at the police impound.
Okay ? The police impound. You want
us to go there and start stealin' cars ?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, let's do it.
- You're crazy.
- We're gonna get hectic. Let's go.
- No, Memphis, no. Don't do this.
Hey, Sphinx, I don't look
suspicious, do I, man ?
Otto, man, I think that
your dog ate thekeys.
-He usually goes for the license plates.
-[ Hemi Moans ]
- Areyou sure ?
- What ? Wait a minute.
The dog ate the keys ?
- Yes.
- [ Laughs ]
Howyou gonna get them out ?
- Not funny.
- I'm--
- [ Knife Clicks ]
- Hey, hey, don't even
think about it, Sphinx.
- It's all right.
- [ Knife Clicks Shut ]
Say, uh, Toby,
go see ifyou can get some,
uh, Alpo, and get some Ex-lax.
- No way, man.
- Bad dog !
- [ Barks ]
-[Memphis] Let's getback to work.
Hey ! Open the door.
-Ah,Jesus.
- Hurry up. Hurry up.
- End it, rock star. Get in.
-Jesus Christ.
Now what, man ?
What else ?
Fuzzy, you never called me.
So now we gotta stay down here...
till you tell me everything
you know.
I-- I told you everything I know.
I know that,
because I said,
''This is everything I know.''
Detective Drycoff, does
it seem like the suspect is
violating his parole right now ?
Why, yes, Detective castlebeck,
ifby violating hisparole...
you mean failing to cooperate
with a law enforcement officer.
A little trick I learned in
the car thiefretirement home.
Can you hold this ?
No, no, no. I'm not failing
to cooperate. It'sjust that--
Y-Y-Yeah. Okay. Okay.
Uh, word has it...
that Kip Raines took thejob
and he screwed up.
Uh, he screwed up pretty bad.
And who put out
the order for thejob ?
It's Raymond Calitri's order.
Nice.
come on, come on,
come on, come on.
- [EngineStarts]
- Yes.
[Memphis On Radio]
We have six hours left.
Has the dog doneits businessyet ?
Toby and Freb
are walking him right now.
- [ Dog Moaning ]
- He's not gonna go it.
It's not gonna happen, man.
Come on, dog.
What's wrong, Hemi ? Poop, dog.
- It had to be a girl car.
- Girl car, what kind ofa girl
drives a Hemi 'Cuda ?
I'll showyou.
Lipstick ?
Matches the car.
[ Laughs ]
- What's next ? Blush ? Mascara ?
- Next time...
I'll pull out the, uh, leather and
high heels and pink underwear foryou.
- Leather, high heels
and pink underwear.
- Pink underwear.
- Pink underwearworks.
Pink underwearworks.
- [ Laughs ]
Raymond Vincent calitri didfiiveyears
in South London formanslaughter.
- He immigrated in '98.
- Look at this.
Loan shark and extortion, fencing. Ha.
His front's a salvageyard.
Gonna have to
wait it out.
So, you seeing anybody ?
No. No, I had
a girl once.
- She was great.
- Mmm. So ifshe was so great,
why'd you leave her ?
I did askyou
to come with me.
No, you asked me
to be a different person.
I didn't want to see people get hurt.
I just wanted you to slow down.
Well, I couldn't.
'Cause I wasn't ready.
- You're straight now.
- Yeah, I am.
'Cause it wasn't the same
withoutyou.
- Excuse me, gentlemen.
- Hey, asshole. I was reading that.
- Watch your mouth, kid.
- What's goin' on ?
- This is a homicide fi le
from a homicide investigation.
-Allright.
It took us three months to get a
magistrate to give us a wiretap on 'em.
No otherdivision, including
GRAB, cangonearhisperson,
residence orplace ofbusiness.
All right ? Got it ?
Let me tell you guys something.
All right. Raymond Calitri
is going down for murder one. Boneheads.
Who gives a shit
about grand theft auto ? Really.
[RandallSighs]
Ican't watch this.
Come on, come on, come on.
Get it on. Get it overwith.
What doyou think is more
exciting, having sex, or stealing cars ?
Having sex or boosting cars ?
Um. Ooh!
Uh.
Well, uh, howabout, uh--
havingsex
while boosting cars ?
God, that's
a good line.
Oh, doesn't work on
alotofgirls, though.
I just blurted it out.
I'm s--
Butyou haven't
answered the question.
Well, you see,
the problem is,
how doyou get over
the shifter ?
- Oh. Oh, right. 'Cause the, uh--
- Because it gets in the way.
Becauseyou wouldn't want to disrupt
the, uh, synchromesh. Right ?
Or the throttle linkage.
§It'syourkiss, kiss, kiss§
[ Moaning ]
The clutch master cylinder.
§ The touch ofyour fingertips§
Double overhead cam shaft.
- I can't do this.
- Wait, wait.Just straight in-line six,
- triple Weber carburetors...
- [ Moans ]
boltedto each other's
bodystructures.
Oh, it's time to work.
Good brakes.
Good brakes too.
§I've stillgotyour face§
§Paintedonmyheart§
§Fastenedonmymemory§§
- There's nothin' happening.
- Maybe he's got indigestion.
- Well, dude, we'll give
him some more Ex-lax.
- He already ate two.
- Hey, little man.
- Oh, man.
I thought I told you this is our turf.
What, you wanna make a move ?
We don't want anything
to do with your turf.
Something wrong with
where we live ?
Oh, no, it's cool foryou.
I mean, it'sjust not for us.
Oh, so nowyou thinkyou're
better than us or something, huh ?
- Maybe we shouldcutyouup, doll ?
- Um--
- Dude, the keys. Freb.
- Excuse me a second, guys.
[Moans]
Man!
- Aw, I'm gonna throw up, dog !
- Man, that's disgusting.
What kind ofpervert gets theirjollies
off playing with dog shit ?
Look, man ! I got 'em.
All three, man.
- You guys are sick.
- I got 'em !
[ Truck Horn Honking ]
Wake up, man.
Check this out.
Every time I drive myVolvo
in Beverly Hills, they tow the shit.
- We ain't got anyVolvos here.
- There is a Volvo here. I know.
- They told me--
- Wait a minute. Wait, wait.
What I'm tryin' to tell you is,
there ain't no Volvos here.
Then get in your book, do something.
Find my damn Volvo !
Sphinx. Sway.
It's got to be somewhere
in there. Check it out, man.
Wait, wait.
There's nothing here. Look.
- There's another one--
- No, no ! Uh-uh, hey !
Tell you what, look at this.
Look at her.
§ She's a brick house §§
§§ [ Humming ]
Look, I'm sorry. Idon't
evenneedtobe outhere.
-[BeeperGoes Off]
- Hey, uh-- I got a midget
pagin' me right now.
- Wait--
- I gotta get outta here.
Hey, time is money.
[ Sighs ]
This is the worst damn day ofmy life.
'' Detective Castlebeck.
Glass shards...
''from the warehouse
from a black light bulb...
available at any
local hardware store.''
Allright.
What the hell is a black
light bulb doin' in a...
warehouse in Long Beach ?
Come with me.
- See this glass right here ?
- Let me guess.
- Black light ?
- Black light.
Take that wall.
I'll take this wall.
- Remembertheseventies ?
- Tooyoung, thank God.
Black lights were
all the rage back then.
You know, they had this ink,
these magic markers.
Only show up
under black light.
So ifyou got a whole lot ofinformation
thatyou don't want anybody to have--
- Like a shopping list ofcars ?
- Thereyou go. Whoa !
Yes. Yes !
Here is our list.
That's a big list.
We can't handle all these cars.
Maybe we don't have to. I'd saywhere
let's concentrate on the rarest ones,
and let'sjust hope
for some luck.
Let's get somebody on this right here.
You and I will take this one right her.
'67 Shelby Mustang.
- Can't be but a few ofthese in town.
- Yeah.
But how doyou know
he hasn't already stolen it ?
Oh, ifI know our boy, I believe
he'll leave this one till last.
- Why ?
- He's afraid ofit.
Yo, guys.
It's me.
- Oh, man. What areyou doing ?
- I want to come along
with you guys on a boost.
Come on. Let's go.
Later. Come on.
[ Beeps ]
[People chattering Nearby]
Go, go, go.
- [EngineStarting]
- What's the matterwith you ? Come on !
[Girl] Hey, callsecurity!
Someone's stealing the car!
- Go, go, go !
- What areyou doing ?
Whoa. I ought to leaveyour ass. You
know that ? What's the matterwith you ?
Hey, Sphinx. Check this out. Home boy
got ''Snake'' on the license plate.
Well, Snake willhave toslither
his ass all the way to thebus
stop in themorning.
Police officers.
We need to check the lot for a car.
Go ahead.
Check this out, man.
Here's some low-ridin' music.
It's a little bit different
than that cracker shityou used
to be playin'. Check this out.
- [ Tires Squealing On Curves ]
-§ Y'allgonnamakemelosemymind§
You like that. You feelin' it ?
Areyou feelin' it ?
-§§[continues]
- I knowyou're feelin' it.
Oh ! Snake !
Get this thing off me !
Snake ! Snake! Snake !
Get this thing off me, man !
It's a snake !
It's tryin' to kill me, man !
Get this thing off me !
Somebodyalways want tokill
abrother. Man, this is wrong.
What the hell areyou doing ?
Get the snake !
- Use the brakes !
- I am !
[Screams]
This snakeis crawlin'up myass, man!
This snake is up my ass !
This snake gonna swallow
my shit !
§ Y'allgonnamakeme
losemymind§
§ Up in here
Up in here§
§ Y'allgonnamakeme
go without§§
God, I love that car.
All right. Two ladies, home safe.
He's tucking in Vanessa,
andBernadinejust tookme foraride.
What's the count ?
- Forty-eight.
- Yes !
But Mirror and Sphinx
had some unexpected visitors.
- Castlebeck ?
- I think so.
- Everything cool ?
- Yeah, yeah, they're fi ne.
They're on theirway back to Otto's.
Donny and Freb are already there.
- What about Kip and Tumbler ?
- No word yet.
[Tumbler]
Lostin suburbia. Hell, where are we ?
- What doyou mean ?
You don't know whereyou're going ?
- Which way is out ?
I don't know where I am.
Everything looks the same to me.
You don't know
whereyou're going ?
-[Toby] Thatis a cop.
- No, it's not. That's rent-a-cop.
- Slow down. Slow down.
- He's pulling a U-turn.
[ Siren Wailing ]
Oh, man,
we're in big trouble.
[OffiicerOn Radio]
Inpursuitofstolen cadillacS. U. V.,
traveling west
on Murray Drive.
- Roadblock, Kip. Oh, shit.
- Look out for the roadblock !
- Go, go !
- Go !
- [ Car Horns Honking ]
- Oh, man.
- [ Crying ] Motherfucker.
- Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
- I need help, man.
-[Tumbler] What ?
- He's been shot ! Oh, shit. Oh, shit.
- Don't touch me !
- We need to go to the hospital, man !
People ask questions
in hospitals, Kip.
- Go to thehospital!
- You should useyour head.
We're in a stolen car !
-[Shouting]
- Now, this does not look good.
- You're gonna be all right.
- [ All Shouting ]
- Oh, man !
- What happened ?
- We ran into security patrol.
- He hid in the van.
We didn't know he was there.
We gotta getyou to a doctor, private.
I knowjust where to go.
- Let's get him to a car.
- No ! Ow !
Lie in the back.
Lie down in the back.
Tumbler, you and Kip take
the last van back to Otto's.
-[Atley] Youallright ?
-[Toby] Yeah, go.
- What areyou doin' ?
- I'm goin' with him.
- Ifsomething should go wrong,just--
-[Kip] Let's go!
I'll take care ofhim, man.
Let's fi nish this.
- What's up ?
- What's the storywith that Humvee ?
- Gone.
- Cadillac ?
The same.
Where are we goin' ?
The only '67 Shelby
in the area is registered...
at a place called
the International Towers in Long Beach.
Let's go to Long Beach.
I know we got a history, Eleanor,
and that that history has not
been great, but I promise--
you take care ofme,
I'll take care ofyou.
[EngineStarts]
Shit.
The easyway or the hard way,
Raines. Easyway or the hard way ?
- Hey !
- I think he's choosin' the hard way.
- [ Kiss ]
- All right.
[ Honking ]
One-Baker-eleven.
In pursuit of'67 Ford Mustang, gray.
- That sign said '' Do Not Enter.''
- Yeah. You noticed, huh ?
-Jesus !
- Keepyour pants on.
Suspect now traveling east
on Fourth Street.
correction.
Make thatnorth on Main.
Move ! Get the fuck--
Just move !
Get out ofthere !
Oh, you wanna get
crazywith me !
- [Siren Wailing]
- Come on, boy.
[ Screaming ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
One-Baker-eleven. Unit threeinvolved
in a T.A. atSt. Vincent's andSeventh.
[Dispatcher]
All units, pursuithas enteredflood
controladjacent to 710 freeway.
- Where's that air unit ?
- Requesting air unit. Same location.
[HelicopterOffiicer]
Air One. We're overthepursuit.
Suspect travelingsouthbound
at90miles anhour.
- [Drycoff] Stay with him, Air One.
- I'm all overhim.
- Suspecthas increasedspeedto 120.
- Maintain visual, Air One.
[Air One]
140miles anhour.
- [Drycoff] Donotlosehim.
- This is anA-Star, sir, notanApache.
One-fiifty. One-sixty.
- He's gone.
- God !
- Man, this guy can drive.
- What, what ?
It's probably mostly the car.
Hey, what time is it ?
7:30.
I think I'm gonna have to get
you out oftown or something.
Your brother's the best boost
in the world, but I don't know
ifhe's gonna make this one.
I'm not like my brother, you know.
I just don't abandon my friends.
Oh, man. I ought to
smackyou silly, boy.
You know, your brother ran away,
is that whatyou think ?
You better getyour story
straight.
Well, go on then.
Straighten it out.
Your mother told him to go.
SheknewifMemphis stayed,
you were gonna walk his line.
You were gonnajoin
his crew.
Butshe toldhim
topick up andgo.
And he did, thinkin'
it was best foryou.
He leftall ofus.
Foryou.
Guess it wasn't that big a deal
for him though, really.
Wasn't that big a sacrifice, leavin'
everything he'd ever known behind.
And sixyears later,
ain't life grand ?
You became a car boost anyway.
How about that ?
I sedated him.
He's sleeping.
He's gonnabejustfine.
It'sjust a scratch, Eleanor.
It can be fixed.
-[Engine Falters]
- No, no, no, don't.
Don't do this to me.
Don't-- Don't start with me.
-[Engine Halts]
- Don't-- No, no-- No, start !
Start, start, start.
Come on. Come on.
[Startercranking]
- Ineedyou, Eleanor.
Ineedyounow, now.
- [EngineStarts]
[Dispatcher]
All units, beadvised.
Suspect vehicle headedsouth
on Henry FordBoulevard.
We should hit him at Ocean Avenue
at the end ofthis bridge.
There he is.
There he is ! Yeah.
I gotyou, Raines !
I gotyou, boy !
[ Worker]
That's it. Keep it comin'.
Whoa ! Shit !
Shit.
[Air One] One-Baker-eleven,
beadvised. Suspectheading westbound.
Headeast tointercept.
One-Baker-eleven, maintainyour course.
Suspectheading inyour direction.
One-Baker-eleven, he's at the end
ofthepierturning towardsyou.
[Worker]
Wait!Hang on!Hang ontoit!
Oh, shit.
- Move, move !
- [ Yelps ]
- Is he okay ?
- [ Moaning ]
- How areyou doing ?
Areyou all right ?
- Yeah.
- Areyou okay ?
Just sit back. You all right ?
- I think so.
Areyou sure ?
'Causeyoujust went through a wall.
Long Beach Tower, this is L.A.P.D.
Air Oneinpursuitofsuspect,
requestingpermission
to cross airfiield.
[controller] Negative, Air One.
Incoming aircraftonapproach.
Holdyourposition.
Irepeat, do notenter
airportairspace.
[Man]
Hey!
[ Workers Chattering ]
[Man]
Thatone's gotabrokenleg !
[Siren Wailing]
There he is.
- [Guns cocking]
- Get outta the car, man !
[Engine Revs]
Raines !
[ Gasping ]
- Where's, uh-- Where's Memphis ?
- I don't know, man.
- He's not backyet.
- What doyou mean, he's not backyet ?
- It's 8:00.
-[Phone Ringing]
- Atley.
- [ Calitri ] Time's up, Atley.
I've got 49 cars.
That's one less than required.
- Bring the kid, and we'll settle this.
- What kid is that ?
Oh, you know.
The Cincinnati Kid, Billy the Kid.
Which kid did you think I mean ?
Oh, gee, I don't know.
I think that maybeyou mean Kip Raines.
Well, gee.
I thinkyou're right.
Yeah. Well, you know,
it's a funny thing.
That little son ofa bitch evaded me.
- Find him, Atley.
- Well, what ifI can't fi nd him ?
Then big brother takes the fall for the
slipup. It doesn't matter much to me.
One Raines is as good as another.
It never rains, but it pours.
Son ofa-- !Just-- Well, you know,
I thinkyou can thankyour big brother.
I think hejust tookyour place
under the guillotine.
Sorry, mate.
We're all done here.
- No, we're not done. This is number 50.
- You're late.
So sod off.
You got a problem with that,
take it up with Calitri.
- You're late.
- Wait. You're gonna argue
with me over 1 2 minutes ?
I just stole 50 cars foryou
in one night !
All right ? I'm a little tired.
I'm a little wired !
And I think I deserve
a little appreciation.
I said 50 cars, not 49 1 /2.
49 1 /2 ? She's not so bad,
man. She's got, what ?
You know, some paint and, uh--
Some fiberglass.
Yes, indeedy.
You know, and the book
on her is 60, 70, call it 80.
Soyou take 80, all right ?
You subtract it from 200.
All right. And we make a deal.
You take 80 from 200,
and we call it even.
Done.
All right. Good. And this thing
with my brother's over.
It's over.
It's done.
It's fi nished.
Done. Finished.
Nobody insults me.
Nobody puts a gun to me head.
Kill him.
Shred the car.
All right. Where's
Raymond Calitri's place ?
Exeter Salvage and Steel.
It's on the water. Why, are we goin' ?
Because, you know, homicide specifically
ordered us not to interfere.
To hell with homicide.
Unicorn.
- What ?
- Nothing.
So, where would
you like it, sir ?
In the head
or in the chest ?
- The chest.
- My pleasure.
[Atley]
Hey, waitaminute, fellas ! Holdit.
- Big change ofplan here.
- That's far enough, Atley.
What areyou doing ?
No, no, no !
I said stop there, Atley !
No, no. calitrijustsentme
up here toaskyoua question.
Allright ?Everything's
gonnabeallright. We gotitcovered.
Get my brother outta here.
Hey.
You made a mistake
pickin' a kid to doyour dirtywork.
Made an evenbiggermistake
pickin'mykidbrother.
And now, youjust made
the biggest mistake tryin' to kill me.
[ Grunts ]
- No. Be careful with that.
- This ?
-Just put it down.
- That's right.
You got a thing about wood.
Just put it down.
No ! No !
- No !
- I-- I--
- Oh, no.
- Psst.
- I'm good.
God ! Jesus !
God.
- Who areyou ?
- I'm a police officer.
You don't wanna do that now.
- Yeah, I do.
- Listen to me.
You walk outta here with me,
you got some options.
You kill me-- nowyou think about this--
I'm a police officer.
Your life will be over.
No, you've got that the wrong way
around. IfI kill you, your life's over.
Notallbad, though. Funeral
willbe on the telly. Everybody
out there, pressedanddressed.
Guard ofhonor. Twenty-one gun
salute and the Stars and Stripes
draped all overyour coffi n.
It'll be the greatest day
ofyour life.
[ Yelling ]
Here I am smack dab in the middle
ofa moral dilemma, Randall.
You've torn this town to shreds
with that little escapade
ofyours. You and your Eleanor.
But I understand
what broughtyou back here.
A brother's love
is a brother's love.
You saved my life,
didn'tyou ?
So whatam Igonna do ?
It's your call,
Detective.
Get outta here, Randall.
I'll clean this up.
Go, Randall, before
I change my mind. Go.
Oh, uh, there's
a container ship. at pier 1 4.
You might want to
check it out.
Oh. Look here.
Can a good-lookin', hard-workin'
chefget a beer around here ?
Come on, Tumbler. You ain't
doin' nothin'. Hand me a beer, baby.
All right, Memphis,
guys, food ! Thankyou, sir.
Damn.
- Ow, ow.
- Wait, wait, wait.
PoorToby, man. Sure looks
like he's in a lot ofpain.
Ifthat's pain,
you can shoot me anytime.
-[Laughs]
- Sexy, sexy.
[ British Accent ]
Ifhis unpleasant wounding...
has in some way enlightened
the rest ofyou...
as to thegrim finishbelow
theglossy veneerofcriminallife...
andinspiredyou to change
your ways,
then his injuries carrywith it an
inherent nobility and a supreme glory.
We should all be
so fortunate.
You say, '' PoorToby.''
[ Scoffs ]
I say, '' Poor us.''
- He spoke.
- Yeah.
Hey, man, I thoughtyou were
from Long Beach.
[All Laughing]
Hey, Memphis. Hey.
I have something foryou.
- What is this ?
- Open it.
Keys. Keys are good.
What do I do with 'em ?
Hey, everybody.
Everybody.
Inside here. Let's go.
Everybody, come on. Let's go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's my great pleasure...
to present--
- Oh, man. Oh, man !
- Thereyou go. Eleanor.
- What ? What ? It's Eleanor.
-[Donny] Howabout that ?
- Look at his face.
- [Otto] Allyours.
Now it's a heap, but give me
a couple ofweeks and it'll look like...
a streamlined butterfly.
- You didn't--
- Oh, no, no, no.
I, uh-- I parted the chopper
out for that.
I'm blown away.
You bought me a car.
Well, yeah, you know. It'sjust
a token ofmy appreciation for, uh--
Foreverything.
-[clapping]
-[Donny] That's the wayitshouldbe.
That's the way it should be.
That's right.
- Yeah.
- Why don'tyou get in there
and go for a ride ?
I know whatyou did.
- And I thankyou.
- I'll seeyou later, man.
-§§[Rock]
-[EngineStarts]
- You wanna go for a ride ?
- Hell, yes.
§Ride on,Josephine
Ride on§
-§Ride on,Josephine, ride on§
- [ Cheering ]
§Ride on,Josephine
child, yougotarunnin'machine§§
[Eleanorcreaking]
[Engine Dies,
Startercranking]
-[Fails To Turn Over]
-[Memphis] Oh, don'tdo this tome.
[Male Soloist]
§I thoughtyou'dbe outofmymind§
§AndI'dfinally
founda way§
§ To learn tolive
withoutyou§
§I thoughtit wasjust
amatteroftime§
§ Till Ihadahundredreasons§
§Not to thinkaboutyou§
§Butit'sjustnotso§
§Andafterall this time§
§Istill can'tletgo§
§I've stillgotyour face§
§Paintedonmyheart§
§Drawn uponmysoul§
§Etcheduponmymemory, baby§
§AndI've gotyourkiss
stillburnin'onmylips§
§ The touch
ofyour fingertips§
§ You're stillso deep
inside ofme, baby§
§I've stillgotyour face§
§Paintedonmyheart§
§ Oh, yeah§
§Something inyour eyes
keeps hauntin'me§
§I'm trying to escapeyou§
§AndIknow
there ain'tno way to§
§ To chaseyoufrom mymind§
§I've stillgotyour face§
§Paintedonmyheart§
§Drawn uponmysoul§
§Etcheduponmymemory, baby§
§AndI've gotyourkiss§
§Stillburnin'onmylips§
§ The touch ofyour fingertips§
§ You're stillso deep
inside ofme, baby§
§I've stillgotyour face§
§Stillgotyour face§
§Paintedonmyheart§
§ Whoa§
§Baby§
§ come on, come on, come on
come on, baby§
§ come on, come on, mybaby§
§ come on, come on, come on
come on, baby§
come on, baby§§