## [Continues]
[Gunfire]
Hi, I'm Sidney. I'm a personal trainer
and Miss Orange County finalist.
- This is my TEC-9.
- That there is a TEC-9.
Little cheap-ass spray gun
made outta South Miami.
It retail for 380,
I get 'em for 200, sell 'em for 800.
They advertise this TEC-9 as
the most popular gun in American crime.
Can you believe that shit?
It actually says that in the
booklet that comes with it.
"The most popular gun in American
crime." Like they're proud of that shit.
[Sidney]
I love my TEC-9.
Let me run this up.
- Design emphasis behind this weapon.
- Check out this gun here.
This here
is a Styer Aug.
Styer Aug's a bad motherfucker.
Listen.
[Imitating
Machine Gun Fire]
Ooh.! That shit's
expensive too, man.
Made in Austria.
My customers don't know shit about it,
so there ain't no demand for it.
Baby, I really could use me
some more ice.
Hold it. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Let me tell you,
though, man.
You put this bad boy in a flick,
every motherfucker out there want one.
I'm serious
as a heart attack.
When them Hong Kong flicks came out,
every nigger in the world
had to have a.45.
And they ain't want one,
they want two,
'cause all them niggers
want to be the killer.
But what them flicks don't tell you
and what they don't know...
is that a.45 got a serious
fuckin'jammin' problem.
Now, I try to steer my customers
toward a 9 millimeter...
'cause it's damn near
the same weapon and it ain't
got half the jammin' problems.
But you know how them niggers is
out there. You can't tell 'em shit.
They want a.45.
The killer had a.45, they want a.45.
- Thanks, baby.
- Mm-hmm.
- Who's your partner?
- Cat named Mr. Walker.
Runs a fishing boat out of Mexico.
I get the merchandise to him,
he gets it out to my customers,
on all my bulk sales anyway.
Before I set that nigger up,
he didn't have a pot to piss in
or a window to throw it out of.
Now that motherfucker
rollin'in cash.
Got hisself a yacht with all kind
ofhigh-tech navigational shit on it.
Oh, uh-uh-uh,
here we go.
AK-47,
the very best there is.
When you absolutely, positively got
to kill every motherfucker in the room,
accept no substitutes.
Nothing gets
between me and my AK.
This here
is the Chinese model.
- I get 'em for 850 and double my money.
- [Phone Ringing]
Grab that for me,
would ya, baby?
- You know it's for you.
- [Ringing Continues]
Girl, don't make me
put my foot in your ass.
[Woman On Video] The AK-47 is the most
popular assault rifle in the world.
This is the Chinese model. You can tell
by the extra rivets running through...
- [Ringing]
- [Machine Gun Fire On Video]
Hello. It's for you.
[Gunfire Continues]
Yo, Junebug.
What's up?
Yep. Still hanging with
that stripper Chantelle?
Boring, isn't it?
I can sit through it once.
Thinks he's Joe Gunn now.
Well, I'm impressed.
He seems to know a lot.
He's just repeating shit
he overheard.
He ain't any more
of a gun expert than I am.
- You want?
- Sure.
[Woman On Video] It shoots
500 rounds of full metal jacket,
9- millimeter Luger
at 1,270 feet per second.
At ten pounds, it's really heavy
for such a small gun.
Demi Moore.
Really reduce muzzle lights
during firing.
[Gunfire]
I've never held anything
that felt so strong.
- So when'd you get out of jail?
- [Inhales]
Four days ago.
- Where at?
- Susanville.
How long?
About two months shy
of four years.
Four years?
- For what?
- Bank robbery.
Really?
- [Man On Phone] Ah-iight. Later.
- Shit, I'm impressed.
Ha-ha. See what
I'm talking about?
Now, that was about
a man in New York...
wants a 9-millimeter Smith and Wesson,
model 5946.
And why does
he want it?
'Cause it's the same gun that nigger
on New York Undercover uses.
'Cause of that nigger,
I'm gonna make 1,250 off of this nigger.
So... [Clears Throat]
What's your cost?
Low as two.
- You're serious?
- [Chuckles] I'm telling you, Louis.
Start adding these figures up, tell me
this ain't the business to be in.
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
[Gunfire On Video]
- Oh, I got me five
M-60 machine guns too.
- Hello.
Motherfuckers come straight
out the Gulf War.
I already sold 3 of them,
20 grand a piece.
- Wow, that's good money.
- I'm gonna make a million
dollars out of this, man.
I already got a half million
sittin' down in Mexico.
When I deliver this next load,
it'll get me another half mil.
- Then what?
- Then I'm out.
Spend the rest
of my life spending.
[Woman On Video]
Pull the trigger and let her rip.!
[Gunfire]
Hi, my name is Melinda.
[Continues, Faint]
- Well, you gonna tell me who it is?
- It's Beaumont.
Don't clown on me, bitch.
Beaumont, what's up?
What the fuck
you doin' in jail?
you doin' that for?
Goddamn, nigger.
Ain't you got better sense than to be
drunk driving with a goddamn pistol?
Beaumont.
[Sighs]
Listen to me. Yeah, number one,
you gots to chill.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
'course you're scared.
That's what the motherfuckers get
paid for, to scare the shit out of you.
That's their
motherfucking job.
[Man] Thejudge doesn't
give a fuck about that.
He's ready to habitualize you.
Is that what you want?
You wanna look at ten years?
Tomorrow I'll get you out,
I promise, but that means
I gotta pick you up tonight.
Reggie, there ain't
no two ways about it.
You're gonna spend the night in jail,
but I already told you
I'm gonna get you out tomorrow.
- Now, where are you?
You're at your mother's?
- [Car Alarm Beeps]
Put your mother on.
Miss Gilmore. Miss Gilmore,
this is Max Cherry.
This is Reggie's...
That's right, his bail bondsman.
Look, Reggie
is in big trouble.
I want to pick him up, and I want you
to be responsible for him before l...
Sit down.
Yeah, I'd like you to make sure
that he's there when I get there.
- And look, this is
a second chance for him.
- [Keys Jangling]
They don't get...
That's correct.
All right. So I'm counting on you
to help me help your son.
Thank you very much.
Put him back on the line, please.
All right, Reggie, we're clear on this.
You got it? Good.
Do yourself a really big favor
and be there when I get there.
How can I help you?
Where can I put my ash?
Use that cup there,
if you like.
Oh, and I need me a bond
for 10,000.
- You all right out there?
- Yeah.
- Have some coffee?
- Go right ahead.
Who's that big,
Mandingo-looking nigger you got
up there on that picture with you?
- That's Winston. He works here.
- Damn.!
He's a big 'un, ain't he?
Y'all tight?
- Yeah.
- But you're his boss, though, right?
Yeah.
Bet it was your idea to take
that picture, too, wasn't it?
All right,
you want a $10,000 bond?
- What have you got
to put up for collateral?
- I'm gonna have to use cash.
- You have it with you?
- Got it right here in my rapper bag.
- You have cash. What do you need me for?
- Come on, man.
You know how they do.
Black man show up with 10,000 cash,
first thing they wanna know is
where I got it.
Then they gonna want
to keep a big chunk of it,
start talkin' that court-cost shit.
Fuck that noise, Jack.
I go through you.
Cost you a thousand
for the bond.
I can do that.
Who's it for?
A relative?
A fellow named Beaumont.
They got him down in County.
Started out drunk driving,
but they wrote it up
as possession of a concealed weapon.
- Dumb monkey-ass had a pistol on him.
- Ten thousand sounds high.
They run his name, got a hit.
He been inside.
Plus, he from Kentucky, and I think
they're kind of prejudiced...
against brothers
from down South out here.
If he runs, and I have to go
to Kentucky to bring him back,
you pay the expenses.
You think you can do that?
I've done it.
What's his full name?
Beaumont.
That's all I know.
Would you say that Beaumont
is his first or his last name?
Uh, if I had to guess,
I'd say Beaumont's his Christian name.
- [Ringing]
- Records office.
Hello, this is Max Cherry,
Cherry Bail Bonds. Who's this, please?
- Ordell, I'm gonna wait in the car.
- Hi, Vicki.
All right, man. Cool.
We're almost done here, right?
- Gettin' there.
- Yo, yo.
You check out some music while you're
sitting in the car. Take the keys.
- Which one's for the car?
- Uh, this one right here.
Use that little black thing to turn off
the alarm and unlock the door.
- What do I do?
- You ain't gotta do nothing, man.
Just point it at the car, push the
button, you hear a little "ooh-ooh-ooh."
- That means the door's unlocked
and the alarm's off. Get in.
- Okay.
Play the volume loud as you want to,
but don't touch my levels now.
- I got them set just like I like 'em.
- Okay.
[Three Beeps]
Beaumont Livingston.
Livingston, huh?
[Chuckling]
On his prior, he served nine months.
He's working on four years'probation.
- You don't say.
- You know what he's on probation for?
- Ain't got a clue.
- Possession of unregistered
machine guns.
Damn. Now, they're gonna consider
that a violation ofhis probation?
They do consider this
a violation of his probation.
- Your boy's looking at ten years,
- Mm.
Plus the concealed weapon.
He ain't gonna like that. Beaumont ain't
got a doing-time kind of disposition.
- I need your name and address.
- Ordell Robbie.
O-R-D-E-L-L...
R-O-B-B-l-E.
1436 Florence Boulevard,
Compton, 90222.
- Is that a house or an apartment?
- That's a house.
- [Buzzing]
- Who the fuck is this?
It's your benefactor, nigger.
I'm comin' up.
Come on up, nigger.
It's open.
My pleasure of living...
demands that I have
a good-looking woman,
that I'm with a good-looking woman.
I couldn't go out with a woman
old enough to be my wife.
- O.D.!
- Ah-ha-ha!
- Look at you and your free ass.
- What's up, man?
Come here, boy.
Give me a motherfuckin' hug.
- I didn't know you were coming by.
- [Laughs] Yeah.
My nigger.
Good lookin' out, man. I don't know
what to say. Thank you, thank you.
- Uh-huh. Who was there
for your ass, huh?
- You was there.
- Who? Who? Who?
- You. You, nigger. You.
You goddamn right. See?
That's how that shit works.
You get your ass in trouble,
I get your ass out.
That's my motherfucking job.
And I don't mind telling you,
nigger, it's steady work.
Hey, look here, man, I'm still scared
as a motherfucker, O.D.
They talkin' like they
serious as hell...
givin' me time for
that machine gun shit.
Oh, come on, man. They're just
trying to put a fright in your ass.
If that's what they're doin',
they done did it.
- How old is that machine gun shit, huh?
- About three years.
Three years? Come on, man,
that's a old crime, man.
They ain't got room in the joint
for all these niggers out here
killing people now.
How they gonna
find room for you?
That ain't what
they're telling me.
That's why they call it
"fuckin' with you." Now, let me
tell you how we're going to retaliate.
All right? Tomorrow I'm gonna pick
you up, take you over to Century City,
introduce you
to my lawyer.
Let me tell you
something about my lawyer.
This brother's name is Stacin Goins.
This nigger
is a junkyard dog.
He my own personal
Johnny Cochran.
Matter of fact,
he kicked Johnny Cochran's ass.
And likeJohnny Cochran,
this nigger hate cops. I'm serious, man.
He live to fuck
with the police.
Now, as a favor,
I had him look at your case.
He say you ain't got shit to
worry about. They just fuckin' with you.
So we're gonna sic
the junkyard dog on their ass
and make 'em stop fuckin' with you.
- Good lookin' out, man.
Good lookin' out.
- Hmm? Mm-hmm.
- Come on in, man, and let's celebrate.
- No, no. Uh-uh.
Look here, I'm really
supposed to be somewhere.
Matter of fact, I was kind of hoping
you could come run with me.
What you mean?
You know, man,
I hate to be the kind of nigger
that do a nigger a favor,
then bam... hit the nigger up
for a favor in return,
but I gots to be
that kind of nigger.
- What? What you want?
- I need a favor, nigger.
- That requires me to go out tonight?
- Just a bit.
Aw, man, I wasn't plannin'
on goin' no place tonight.
It is late as hell, man.
I'm home, I'm high, man. Come on.
Uh-huh.
And why are you home, huh?
You home because I spent $10,000
to get your ass home.
Now, look, I got a little problem,
all right?
I need some help,
and you can help me out.
Go in the house and throw some shit on.
Let's walk out to the car.
Come on.
I'm ready, man. What's your problem?
There ain't no problem.
It's more like
a situation.
You remember them three
M-60 machine guns I sold
last year outta the five I got?
- Yeah.
- Well, I'm gonna sell
the other two tonight.
There's this group of Koreans
over in Koreatown startin' this
little Neighborhood Watch thing.
They need some weapons so they
can show the neighborhood niggers
they mean business.
Now, I'm gonna sell them the other
two machine guns, all right?
The problem is, I ain't never done
business with these Koreans before.
I ain't worried, 'cause by and large
Asians are very dependable.
They don't want no trouble.
You might argue with them
about price and shit,
but you ain't gotta worry about
them shootin' you in the back.
But I got me a rule:
Never do business with people
you ain't never done business
with before without backup.
That's why I need you.
Backup.
Look, all you've got to do is lay in
here and hold on to this motherfucker.
All right? I'm gonna tell 'em I'm goin'
in the trunk to show 'em the goods.
When I open the trunk, you pop up
and rack this motherfucker.
Man, fuck that shit.
I ain't for shootin' nobody.
I ain't said nothin'
about you shootin' nobody.
All you gotta do is hold on to it.
They'll get the idea.
You must be out of your mind
if you think I'm gonna get
in this dirty-ass trunk.
We ain't goin' nowhere
but to Koreatown, man.
You ain't gonna be in here
no more than ten minutes.
I ain't ridin' in
no trunk for no minute.
Why can't I ride up front with you?
You can't ride up front with me.
The surprise element is 90% of it.
I'm sorry, man, but I ain't
gettin' in no goddamn trunk.
- I can't believe you'd do me like this.
- Do you like what, man?
I just ain't climbing in no goddamn,
dirty-ass trunk, man.
I got a problem
with small places.
I got a problem with spending
$10,000 on ungrateful niggers
to get them out of jail,
but I did it.
How small was that
jail cell, motherfucker?
- I know I owe you,
you got to bring all this up.
- Then get your ass in this trunk.
I want to help you, but I won't be
locked in no goddamn trunk of no car.
You think I wanted to spend
$10,000 on your ass, huh?
- I know you helped me out.
- Do you think I wanted to spend
$10,000 on your ass?
- Yes or no?
- Of course you didn't,
but look, in the trunk?
That's the only way I could help you,
right? So that's what I did.
Now, look, man, all I'm asking
you to do is get in the trunk,
hold this fuckin' shotgun,
point it at these Buddha-heads
when I open it, all right?
- You're catching a nigger
off-guard with this shit.
- Look here. I tell you what.
When we get through fucking
with these Koreans,
me and you go to Roscoe's
Chicken and Waffles on me.
Think about it now.
That 'Scoe's Special,
smothered in gravy and onions,
side of red beans and rice,
some greens.
That's some good eatin'.
Man.
[Sighs]
Exactly how long do I gotta
be in this motherfucker?
Hey, you said ten minutes.
Hey, motherfucker, you like
to hit my goddamn head!
You ponytail-wearing
motherfucker.
What the hell's wrong
with you?
[Engine Starts]
#Hello, my love
I heard a kiss from you #
#Red magic satin
playin'near #
# Too #
#All through the morning rain
I gazed #
[Volume Up]
# The sun doesn't shine #
#Rainfalls and waterfalls
run through my mind #
#In the garden I see #
# Washed purple
shower bells and tea #
# One early bitter cousin
Misty green #
#Pretty music I hear #
#So happy in mind #
##[Fades]
##[Resumes, Faint]
##[Continues]
##[Stops]
[Car Door Closes]
- [Beaumont] Do a nigger a favor...
- [Two Gunshots]
- [Trunk Closes]
- [Dogs Barking]
[Car Door Opens,
Closes]
- [Engine Starts]
- ##[Resumes]
# Ooh, ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh #
# Ooh-ooh, ooh-ooh-ooh #
# Ooh-ooh,
ooh-ooh-ooh ##
# Ooh, ooh #
# Baby love
my baby love #
# I need you
Oh, how I need you #
# But all you do
is treat me bad #
# Break my heart
and make me sad #
#Tell me
what did I do wrong #
#To make you
stay away so long #
# 'Cause baby love
my baby love #
- # I'm missin' you, miss kissin' you #
- [Phone Rings]
- [Diana Ross On Stereo]
#Instead ofbreakin'up #
- Excuse me, baby.
- #Just want some kissin'
and makin'up #
- [Ringing Continues]
#Don't throw
our love away #
- # In my arms, why don't you stay #
- ## [Humming]
- Hello.
- # Need ya, need ya #
- Hello, baby.
- #Baby love #
Well, you know, I'm just doin'
that thing I do, baby.
Oh, no. Okay.
Hold on.
[Sighs]
Uh, Louis, baby. It's Ordell.
Oh, I'm just
gonna go pee.
#Separate, my love #
#All of my
whole life through #
- #I never loved no one but you ##
- Hello.
Louis, my man.
What ya doin'?
Okay. Okay.
I'm just hanging out with Simone.
Oh, yeah?
She doin' that show for you?
- Yeah.
- Uh-huh.
I can hear the Supremes in
the background. She ain't bad, is she?
- No, she's pretty good.
- She do Mary Wells for you yet?
Nah, I don't know
the names of everybody,
but she's done a whole bunch of them.
Uh-huh.
Well, guess where I am?
I don't know.
I'm in the cozy confines
of an Oldsmobile...
parked right outside
Simone's house.
- Oh, you're outside?
- Yeah.
- Come on in.
- Ah, no, man.
I already caught that show.
I got some for-your-eyes-only shit
to show you. Why don't you step outside?
[Siren Wailing
In Distance]
- Who was that?
- That's Beaumont.
Who's Beaumont?
A employee
I had to let go.
What'd he do?
He put hisself in a position
where he was gonna have to
do ten years in prison.
That's what he did.
And if you
know Beaumont,
you know there ain't no goddamn way
he can do ten years.
If you know that,
then you know Beaumont's
gonna do anything Beaumont can...
to keep from doin'
them ten years,
includin' tellin' the federal government
any and every motherfucking thing...
about my black ass.
Now, that, my friend,
is a clear-cut case...
of him or me,
and you best believe...
it ain't gonna be me.
Now, Louis,
if you gonna come in
on this thing with me,
you've got to
be prepared...
- to go all the way.
- [Clears Throat]
Now, I got me, so far,
a half million dollars in lock boxes...
in a bank down
in Cabo San Lucas.
I make this delivery,
I'm gonna have me
over a million.
Hey, you think I'm gonna let
a little cheese-eatin' nigger
like this fuck that up?
You best think again.
Before I let that happen,
I'll shoot this nigger in the head...
and ten niggers
look just like him.
You understand
what I'm saying?
Yeah.
- So we on the same page then?
- Yeah, I follow.
My nigger.
[Chuckles]
[Airplane Engines Roaring]
[Man]
Miss Brown.!
Hi, I'm Detective Mark Dargas,
L.A.P.D.
- Can I ask what you have in that bag?
- The usual stuff.
You know, I'm a flight
attendant for Cabo Air.
- Can I help out here?
- Who's this?
Sorry, this is Special Agent Ray Nicolet
with Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms.
- Oh, yeah? May I see some I.D.?
- Yeah. Sure.
Would you mind if we just
took a look in that bag?
Do I mind?
Do I have a choice?
- Yeah. You have the right to say no.
- No.
I have the right to make you wait here
with Ray while I go get a warrant.
If I don't want to go to
all that trouble, I'd just
take you in on suspicion now.
- Suspicion of what?
- Uh, could I say something?
He just wants to peek
inside the bag for a minute.
I'll keep my eye on him
so he doesn't take anything.
- Go ahead.
- Thanks a lot.
[Groaning]
Bad knees.
You have a good flight?
It's a shitty flight down to Cabo.
I went down there one time
with Susan, my wife.
Fuckin' turbulence
was unbelievable.
Hey, can I look
in this envelope?
Ah.
[Wolf Whistle]
[Laughs]
Goddamn.
I'd say there's
about, oh, uh,
$50,000 here.
What would you say, Ray?
Looks like about 50,000
from here.
- Is this your money?
- What if I say no?
You should know if you bring in anything
over 10,000,you have to declare it.
You forget, or what?
You can get a $250,000 fine,
plus two years in prison.
You want to talk to us about this,
or do you want to talk to Customs?
- I'm not sayin' another word.
- Jackie...
I hope you don't mind
if I call you Jackie.
Those guys down in Customs?
They're a bunch of pricks.
Excuse me, but they are.
There's something about
that job makes those people
really hard to get along with.
You can go down and talk
with those guys...
who are really suspicious
and really disagreeable human beings,
or you can talk with a couple of
good-hearted guys like Mark and myself.
It's up to you.
[Dargas] Let's take a look here
at the file on Jacqueline Brown.
According to this, this isn't the
first time you've run afoul of the law.
In 1985, while
a stewardess for Delta,
you were busted while
carrying drugs for a pilot?
That pilot was my husband,
and I got off.
You mean they offered you a deal,
and you grabbed it.
- He did time, you did probation.
- [Siren Wails]
I didn't hear you ask permission
to smoke in my office.
- May I smoke?
- No, you may not.
So you get off
with a slap on the wrist,
but all this criminal activity
fucks up your shit for good
with the big airlines.
Cut to 13 years later,
you're 44 years of age,
flying for the shittiest little
shuttle-fuckin'piece of shit
Mexican airline there is,
where you make what...
$ 13,000 a year?
I make 16,000,
plus benefits.
You been in the service industry
19 years, and all you make is 16,000,
plus benefits?
Didn't exactly set the world
on fire, did you, Jackie?
Jackie, you have
a good lawyer?
[Dargas] Can she afford
a good one, is more like it.
Otherwise you'll be
in Sybil Brand three weeks...
before the public defender
gets around to ya.
- [Siren Wails]
- Hey, Jackie, do you know a guy
named Beaumont Livingston?
Yeah? No?
- [Pours Coffee]
- Because he knows you.
Well, he knew you.
He doesn't know anybody now.
He's dead.
They found him in a trunk
of a car this morning,
shot twice.
Once in the chest,
once in the head.
Here you go.
So I guess I'm wondering.
If you don't know Beaumont,
why do you suppose Beaumont
knows you?
[Clears Throat] Look, Miss Brown,
we don't give a fuck about you.
You know who we want.
If you cooperate, tell us what we want
to know, we'll help you get out of this.
If you refuse to cooperate,
continue to cop a shit attitude
like you're doing now,
we will give you to Customs
and they will take you to court.
With your prior, thejudge
will give you two years.
Now, you'll probably only end up
serving a year and some change,
but if I was
a 44-year-old black woman...
desperately clinging on to this
one shitty, little job I was
fortunate enough to get,
I don't think that I'd think
I had a year to throw away.
So let's start again now,
shall we?
Who in Mexico gave you this money, and
who in America were you bringing it to?
I'm not sayin'
another goddamn word.
[Clears Throat]
I'd like your permission
to look through this again so
we'll know how much we're talking about.
Sure. Go ahead.
While we're at it,
let's see what else is in there.
Do you mind?
Beauty case.
- Mm-hmm. What's in it?
- Beauty products.
Alarm clock.
Glass case.
Birth control.
- [Dargas] What's that?
- My diet shit.
Let's see what else
is in there.
Here. Here. Here.
- What's this?
- What's that shit?
[Engine Rewing]
Let's go, ladies.
First door on the left.
[Woman] #Ninety-nine years
is a long, long, long time #
#Ninety-nine years is such
a long, long, long time #
#Ninety-nine years
is a long, long time #
# Well, look at me #
#I'll never be free #
#I'm a long-time woman ##
Brown, case 70032.
The charge is...
possession of narcotics
with the intent to distribute.
- How does your client plead?
- Uh, Your Honor,
she wishes to stand mute.
Very well.
Detective... Varga.
- Dargas, Your Honor.
- Sorry.
Uh, you were the arresting officer
in this case?
- That's correct, Your Honor.
- And do you have a bail recommendation?
- Yes, I do, Your Honor.
- And that would be?
Based on the defendant's
prior conviction...
and the extreme possibility of flight
due to the occupation,
the state requests a bond
of no less than 25,000.
[Judge]
You people are fine with this?
I'm gonna set bond
at 10,000...
and set the date
of August 21...
for the prelim.
Your Honor,
when will that be?
That's six weeks from now.
We'll continue this matter then.
Owens, case 72242.
The charge is possession
of a concealed weapon...
and striking an officer.
- How does your client plead?
- I thought it'd be 25.
[Female Lawyer] Uh, my client
would like to plead guilty, Your Honor.
[Judge] Is the arresting officer
here in the courtroom?
[Toilet Flushing]
Uh-uh-uh. I didn't hear you
wash your hands.
- Comfortable?
- Yeah.
- Door was open, so I just come on in.
- I can see that.
- Why?
- Got some more business for you.
Oh, yeah?
What did he do?
She is an airline stewardess.
Got caught coming back
from Mexico with some blow.
They set her bond
this afternoon at $10,000.
Now, I'm figuring you could take
that $10,000 you owe me from Beaumont,
move it over
to the stewardess.
- The bond for possession's
only a thousand.
- Hmm. Yeah.
Man, they fuckin' with her. They callin'
that shit "possession with intent."
A 44-year-old black woman
caught with less than two ounces,
they calling that shit "intent."
The same thing happen to a movie star,
they call it "possession."
Still sounds high.
Well, um, she had on her,
I believe it was 50 grand in cash.
All right, before we start
talking about stewardesses,
let's get Beaumont
out of the way first.
You know, I think
somebody already did.
- What?
- You ain't hear?
- Hear what?
- Somebody with a grudge
blew Beaumont's brains out.
Oh, shit.
That shit rhymes.
Blew Beaumont's
brains out.
Police make contact
with you?
Oh, hell, yeah.
First motherfucking thing they did.
You know, they see I pay
a big money bond for my boy,
they start thinking that "where there's
smoke there's fire" logic.
Rousted my ass out of bed
10:00 in the morning.
Scared the shit out
of my woman Sheronda.
She thought they was gonna
take my ass away for sure.
- This stewardess...
You know her last name?
- Mm-hmm.
Brown.
Jackie Brown.
- What does she do for you?
- Who said she do anything for me?
She's my friend. My friends get
in trouble, I like to help them out.
Beaumont worked for you.
This you and me talking,
like lawyer-client thing?
You can't tell nothing
I say to you?
You're not my client till you
get busted and I bond you out.
Well, we ain't got no, uh...
What you call that shit?
Confidentiality.
Why should I
tell you anything?
'Cause you want me to know
what a slick guy you are.
You got stewardesses
bringing you 50 grand.
And why would a stewardess
be bringing me 50 grand?
Now you want me to speculate
on what you do.
I'd say you were in the drug business,
except the money's moving
in the wrong direction.
Whatever you're into, you seem
to be getting away with it,
so, uh, more power to you.
All right.
You want another bond?
You want to move the 10,000 you got
on Beaumont over to the stewardess.
That means paperwork.
I gotta get a death certificate,
present it to the court,
make out a receipt for
return of bond collateral,
I type up another application,
- Hey, hey, hey, hey.
- Another indemnity agreement.
- I haven't got time.
- I'm telling you what I have to do.
What you have to do,
in case you forgot,
- is come up with a premium
of a thousand bucks.
- I can do that.
You know I got the money.
I just ain't got it with me.
Come back when you do.
I'll bond out the stewardess.
Look, you got to look at this
with a little compassion, all right?
Jackie ain't no criminal. She ain't
used to this kind of treatment.
Gangsters don't give a fuck,
but your average citizen,
a couple of nights in County
get to fuckin' with their mind.
Ordell, this isn't a bar.
You don't have a tab.
Listen to me, all right?
You got a 44-year-old, gainfully
employed black woman falsely accused...
Falsely accused? She didn't come
back from Mexico with cocaine on her?
Falsely accused
of"intent."
If she had that shit...
and mind you, I'm saying if...
that was her own personal shit
to get high with.
Is white guilt supposed to make me
forget I'm running a business?
Oh, it's like that, huh?
All right.
I got your little
thousand bucks.
- Hey, Candy.
- Hey, Max.
Dropping off Lopez, Anita.
Picking up Brown, Jackie.
- Okay, no problem. You armed?
- You bet I am.
[Buzzes]
[Candy]
Max, here she comes.
# Why do I keep my mind #
# On you all the time #
#And I don't even know you #
#I don't know you #
# Why do I feel this way #
# Thinking about you #
#Every day #
- #And I don't even know you #
- [Gate Buzzes]
[Max]
Miss Brown?
- Yes?
- # Take me in your arms #
- I'm Max Cherry. I'm your bail bondsman.
- # Thrill me with all #
- # Of your charms #
- I could give you a lift home,
if you like.
- #And I'll take to the sky
on a natural high #
- Okay.
- #Loving you more till the day I die #
- # On a natural high #
- # Take to the sky on a natural high #
- #I want you to be mine #
#Loving you more #
- [Keys Jangling]
- [Car Beeping]
- #If you have anything to do #
- [Engine Starts]
# Call me and I
will do it for you #
You really
a bail bondsman?
Well, who do you
think I am?
- I showed you my card in there.
- Can I see your I.D.?
You're serious?
# That wish would be
for you to live #
#Forever and ever #
Who paid my bond?
- Ordell?
- In cash.
#My heart skips a beat #
- #And I take to the sky
on a natural high #
- #I just take to the sky #
- #Loving you more till the day I die #
- # On a natural high #
- # Take to the sky on a natural high #
- #I don't know you #
#Loving you more ##
You got any cigarettes
in here?
You won't find
any cigarettes in there.
- Can we stop and get cigarettes?
- Sure.
Have you ever been
to the River Bottom?
- I don't think so.
- It's all right. It's a cop bar.
Can we just stop
at a 7-Eleven or something?
- I thought you might
like to have a drink.
- I'd love to, but not there.
How 'bout the Hilton
by the airport?
- Is it dark?
- Kind of a sports bar.
It doesn't sound dark.
Why does it
have to be dark?
Because it looks like I just
got out of jail, that's why.
You're dropping me off at my place.
There's a joint near me.
[Metallic Rattling]
[Metal Ball Rattling]
No, thanks.
I quit three years ago.
- Gain weight?
- Ten pounds.
- Take it off and put it back on.
- [Scoffs]
That's why I don't quit.
Mm.
If I can't fly, I'm gonna have a bitch
of a time trying to find my rent.
You know,
the other day I figured out
that I must have written about...
15,000 bonds since
I've been in the business.
I figure about 80% of those
were drug-related, so...
if you want, I could help you
figure out your options.
So far, they told me
if I cooperate,
then I'll get probation,
maybe.
Or if I stand mute,
I can get as much as five years.
Does that sound right?
I'd say that if they try you
and convict you, you won't get
more than a year and a day.
That's state time,
prison.
But they won't
want to do that.
They'll offer you simple possession,
a couple of months of county time...
and a year or two
of probation.
Do you happen to know who
put the dope in your bag?
Yeah.
But that's not
what this is about.
They were waiting
for my ass.
They knew about the money.
- They even knew the exact amount.
- What did they want to know?
Who gave me the money
and who I was givin' it to.
They found this guy in the trunk
of a car with his head blown off.
They said it was him
who told them about me.
That would be...
Beaumont Livingston.
How do you know
about him?
I wrote him on Monday.
They found him dead on Tuesday.
Ordell pick up his bond?
Same as you... $10,000.
[Johnny Cash On Stereo]
#Back about 18 and 25 #
#I left Tennessee
very much alive #
- [Jackie] Thanks for the drink.
- [Max] You're welcome.
- The legal advice and the ride.
- You bet.
- # On a Tennessee stud #
- Good luck. We'll be in touch.
#Had some trouble
with my sweetheart's pa #
# One ofher brothers
was a bad outlaw #
#I wrote a letter
to my Uncle Fudd #
#And I rode away
on a Tennessee stud #
# The Tennessee stud
was long and lean #
# The color of the sun
and his eyes were green #
#He had the nerve
and he had the blood #
- # There never was a horse like the...##
- [Tape Ejects]
[Knocking On Door]
How ya doin',
Miss Jackie?
Come on in.
- Do you got some booze?
- I got some vodka in the freezer.
- Got some O.J.?
- Mm-hmm.
Why don't you be
a good hostess...
and hook a brother up
a screwdriver?
Sure.
Well?
- You gonna thank me?
- For what?
Who the hell do you think
got your ass out of jail?
The same guy that put my ass in jail.
Thanks a lot.
Hey, you got caught with blow.
That's your business.
- It wasn't mine.
- What?
Oh, shit.
[Chuckles]
I bet that was that present
Mr. Walker was sending Melanie.
Yeah. If you didn't put it in there,
he must have.
Damn. That shit wasn't called for.
Baby, I'm sorry.
Bet they asked you a whole shitload
of questions about it, huh?
And all that money,
where it came from.
Probably asked you who you
was bringin' it to too.
They asked.
And you said?
- "I want to talk to my lawyer."
- [Laughs]
You sure you didn't get nervous
and kind of let somethin' slip?
I mean, if you did,
I ain't mad at you.
I just gotta know.
You ain't asking
the right questions.
You should be asking
why they picked me up.
They were waiting for me.
They knew about the money
and they knew the exact amount.
- [Lighter Clicks]
- They tell you how they happen
to come by this information?
Hmm.
[Exhales]
Beaumont Livingston?
I knew it.
They even asked me
if I knew Mr. Walker.
Yeah?
I didn't tell them
anything about him.
My name come up?
Mm-mm.
- You ain't said nothin' about me?
- Mm-mm.
Ah, that's mighty noble
of you.
They tell you what happened
to this Beaumont fellow?
Yeah, they told me.
Yeah.
Somebody must have been
real mad at old Beaumont.
Or else they pretty scared about what
he might say to keep from doing time.
Yeah, I bet they asked you
a whole shitload of questions.
And you ain't givin' them
no kind of answer?
- Mm-mm.
- You scared of me?
You got any reason
to be nervous around me?
[Gun Hammer Cocks]
Is that what
I think it is?
What do you think it is?
- I think it's a gun
pressed up against my dick.
- Well, you thought right.
Now, take your hands
from around my throat,
nigger.
- What the hell's wrong with you, Jackie?
- Shut the fuck up.
Don't you move. Oh, what is this?
What the fuck is this?
Hey, that ain't got nothing to do
with you. I carry that all the time.
You been talking
to them police too much.
- The police didn't try
and strangle my ass.
- Come on, girl.
- I was just playing with you.
- I ain't playing with you.
I'm gonna unload both
of these motherfuckers if you
don't do what I tell you to do.
- You understand what I'm saying?
- Jackie, stop acting crazy.
- Do you understand
what the fuck I'm saying?
- Yeah, woman. Damn!
Now, sit your ass down
on that sofa.
See? Police start fuckin' with your
mind, start pittin' black against black.
- That's how they do.
They been doing this since...
- Shut your raggedy ass up.
Sit the fuck down!
- [Sighs]
- And put your hands behind your head.
- This is gettin' silly now.
- Oh, silly? You want to see
some motherfuckin' silly?
If I have to tell you to shut up
one more time, I'm gonna shut you up.
- I just came over here to talk to you.
- To talk?
The way I see it, you and me got one
motherfucking thing to talk about.
One thing,
and that's what you
are willing to do for me.
- I can get you a lawyer.
- No, let's be realistic.
Now, sooner or later they're gonna
get around to offering me a plea deal,
and you know that.
- That's why you came here to kill me.
- I ain't come over to kill you.
No, that's all right.
It's okay.
Now, I forgive you.
Now, let's say,
if I tell on you,
I walk.
- If I don't, I'll go to jail.
- Uh-huh.
I want $100,000...
in a escrow account
in my name...
if I'm convicted up to a year
or put on probation.
Now, if I have to do
more than a year,
you pay another $100,000.
I can do that.
- You know I got that problem.
All my money is...
- In Mexico.
- Right.
- Well, I been thinking about that too.
I got me an idea.
Uh...
Let me hear that.
We friends again.
Why don't you point that
motherfucking gun somewhere else?
- I'll talk to the cops tomorrow
and tell you if it's on.
- All right.
[Door Tapper Knocking]
You want your gun back?
Come in and I'll
get it for you.
[Children Shouting,
Chattering]
Max, look,
I am so sorry about this.
You know,
I was afraid to ask to borrow it,
'cause I was afraid you would say no.
I mean, you'd have to.
Would you like
some coffee?
- If you're having some.
- I am. Come on in.
Why don't you make
yourself at home.
Just, you know,
have a seat.
Did you get a chance
to use it?
I felt a lot safer
having it.
Oh, the milk went bad
while I was in jail.
- Black's fine.
- Cool.
Would you, uh, care to
hang on to it for a while?
It wouldn't be legal, but if it
makes you feel better, I guess...
Well, thanks.
I got one now.
- You went out this morning
and bought a gun?
- [Water Running]
- What? I didn't hear you.
- You went out this morning
and bought a gun?
Well, let's say
I got one now, okay?
- Somebody loan it to you?
- Yeah.
[Water Pouring]
All right!
We're on.
It might be a little black.
Would you like to hear some music?
Sure.
Cool.
You know, I couldn't wait
to get home last night...
and wash the jail
outta my hair.
- It looks nice.
- Thanks.
You never got into
the whole CD revolution?
Oh, I got a few, but I can't afford
to start all over again.
I mean, I've invested too much
time and money... [Blows]
In my albums.
Yeah, but you can't get
new stuff on records.
I don't get new stuff
that often.
[Lighter Clicks]
# I gave my heart
and soul #
#To you, girl #
#Didn't I do it, baby #
- #Didn't I do it, baby #
- It's pretty.
Mm-hmm.
- Who is this?
- The Delfonics.
- #Didn't I do it, baby #
- It's nice.
- Mm-hmm.
- #Didn't I do it, baby #
I called in sick today. As far as
the airline knows, I'm still available.
- Are you?
- I don't know. I'm gonna go in
and talk with Nicolet and Dargas today.
I'm going to do what you suggested...
offer to help and see what happens.
What I meant was to have a lawyer
do the negotiating for you.
No, I want to talk to them first.
I know more now about Ordell's money.
Well, if it's the A.T.F. Guy
that wants you, that'll only
interest him up to a point.
I know, but it's
a lot of money.
It's a half a million dollars
all in Cabo, and more coming in.
- How'd you find that out?
- Ordell told me last night.
- He called?
- He came by.
- What'd you do?
- We talked.
Do you think
he still trusts you?
He had his doubts at first,
but he's always trusted me.
And he wants to believe more than
anything else that he still can.
- Why?
- Because he needs my ass.
Otherwise, that money's just gonna sit
over there in Cabo. You want some sugar?
No, thank you. There's gotta be
other ways of getting it out.
Maybe, but I'm the only one
he's ever used.
I mean, he can't use his other people.
They're crooks.
I mean, he might try to...
bring the money in himself,
but he ain't gonna wanna
stand in no customs lines.
So, either he recruits another Cabo
stewardess or he continues to trust me.
And I made him feel
like he still can.
Are you gonna offer
to set him up?
Yeah, if I get off.
Otherwise, fuck 'em.
It's very possible that
Ordell's killed somebody.
Do you realize that?
Well, I ain't going back to jail and I
ain't doing that probation thing again.