(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
(CAR APPROACHING)
MAN: What are you
doing out here?
I'm lost.
MAN: This is
a restricted area.
Oh, I didn't know that.
There's no signs.
MAN: They're everywhere.
Let's see some ID.
Why? (CHUCKLES)
MAN: There's a broken
gate back there,
and you're trespassing.
Excuse me, sir,
that gate was open
and I was under the opinion
that this was a detour.
Let me see the ID.
Take it out.
What kind of uniform is that?
I'll ask the fucking questions.
It's a private outfit,
huh? (CHUCKLES)
I tried to get
one of those jobs.
I like guarding things.
Really?
Here you go, sir.
I think what
must have happened
is I just must have
gotten turned around.
(MAN GRUNTING)
(TRAIN HORN BLOWING)
WOMAN: (ON RADIO)
Is it in the high-end
or the low-end range?
MAN: (ON RADIO)  Oh,
there's no question it's up!
(MAN LAUGHS)
WOMAN:  Yes, but 20%?
MAN:  Foreclosure,
foreclosure, foreclosure!
We're talking about over
two-thirds of the market,
and, of course,
it's linked to unemployment.
WOMAN:  So, the opportunity
for the average
investor with
the right know-how...
MAN:  Is all in the book.
In the seminars. (CHUCKLES)
WOMAN:  Very little doubt?
MAN:  Yes, their
distress sales makes them
want them off the books.
WOMAN:  Oh...
MAN:  They need to sell them.
They have to, right?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
...you name it,
we teach them all.
LOU:  I guesstimate
that I have about
50 pounds
of copper wire,
100 pounds of
chain-link fence
and two manhole covers.
The nice thick ones.
I'll give 50 cents
a pound for the wire,
15 for the fence,
and 10 for the covers.
That's below market value.
Market value?
You know the cops
came by asking
about manhole covers?
I'd like to counter
at a dollar a pound
for the copper,
30 cents a pound
for the fence,
and 20 cents per
for the covers.
Ah, sell them somewhere else.
I'd feel good at 75,
25, and 15.
I'm not negotiating with you.
I think we're close.
I'm done.
I'm willing to take less
to establish
a business relationship.
If that's your
last best offer,
then I guess I accept.
All right.
Drive around back
and unload them.
Excuse me, sir?
I'm looking for a job.
In fact,
I've made up my mind
to find a career that
I can learn and grow into.
Who am I?
I'm a hard-worker,
I set high goals
and I've been told
that I am persistent.
Now,
I'm not fooling myself, sir.
Having been raised with
the self-esteem movement
so popular in schools,
I used to expect my
needs to be considered.
But I know that
today's work culture
no longer caters to
the job loyalty that
could be promised to
earlier generations.
What I believe, sir,
is that good things
come to those who
work their asses off.
And that people
such as yourself,
who reach the top
of the mountain,
didn't just fall there.
My motto is if you
wanna win the lottery,
you have to make the money
to buy a ticket.
(CHUCKLES)
Did I say that I
worked in a garage?
So, what do you say?
I could start tomorrow,
or why not tonight?
No.
How about an internship then?
A lot of young people are taking
unpaid positions to
get a foot in the door.
That's something
I'd be willing to do.
I'm not hiring a fucking thief.
(SIRENS WAILING)
MAN: This thing's gonna blow!
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
MAN: Crap! Gotta move!
Help!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MAN: This thing is
not budging. Hold on.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
WOMAN: I can't move!
(WOMAN COUGHING)
JOE: Let's go.
Let's go!
JOE: Let's go!
We're first!
No shit! Get a shot
on the other side!
MARCUS:
All right, all right.
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(OFFICER GRUNTING)
JOE: Get a shot
inside the car.
Go around.
Get inside the car.
The fuck am I paying you for?
OFFICER 1: Yeah, it's free.
OFFICER 2: Get back, Loder.
Get back!
JOE: I'm back,
I'm back, I'm back!
OFFICER 1: All units.
EMS, just past exit 31.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(AIRPLANE FLYING OVERHEAD)
Excuse me.
Will this be on television?
Morning news.
If it bleeds, it leads.
What channel?
Whoever pays the most.
What do you get for
something like this?
Not nearly enough.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
Enough to buy all that gear.
JOE: Let me
tell you something.
It's a flaming asshole of a job.
Can I ask you,
are you currently hiring?
Fuck, no.
Well, thank you
for taking the time
to discuss what you do.
You've been very helpful.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Any Compton unit,
Code Three response needed.
211 in progress.
239 Rose Crest.
Hey, we got a 211 on Rose Crest.
Hurry your ass!
(VAN STARTING)
Coming through.
FEMALE REPORTER:  There was
another drive-by shooting
today downtown...
(REPORTERS' SPEECH
OVERLAPPING)
MAN 1: (ON TV)
You're entitled to fear
and adequate compensation.
MAN 2: (ON TV)
We'll fight for you.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
MALE WOLF: (ON TV)
Potatoes!
FEMALE WOLF: (ON TV)
Okay, I give up. Potatoes!
WOMAN: (ON TV)
Any family would agree.
Bird's Eye turns vegetables
you want to serve
into vegetables
they want to eat.
Bird's Eye.
(BELL DINGS ON TV)
Now, dinner is complete.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
MALE ANNOUNCER: (ON TV)
Live from the CBS broadcast
center in Los Angeles.
This is CBS2 News
at 6:00 a.m.
Coverage you can count on.
Good morning, everyone.
Thanks for joining us.
I'm Pat Harvey.
Hope your day's
getting off to a good start.
I'm Kent Shocknek.
An unclaimed
Mega Millions ticket
sold at a 7-Eleven
in South San Diego
is worth
a whopping $266 million.
The question is,
is it yours?
(LAUGHS)
HARVEY:  We'll have
the numbers, coming up.
Evidence has police hunting
for one of their own.
A fast-moving
bank robber in Sylmar
didn't move fast enough.
And we'll explain how the FBI...
A landmark court decision,
Lisa, has cyber-music fans
singing the blues.
Ouch!
(LAUGHS)
I may have to budget
more for my music.
Closet space!
Twisted metal,
a shattered life.
All of it caught
on tape last night
at the scene of
a fiery one-car collision
out on the 110.
Melinda Flores of Yorba Linda.
She was severely injured,
but somehow
managed to escape with her life,
thanks to the bravery
of a couple of CHP officers.
The crash started
a fire that then
quickly consumed
the entire vehicle.
LISA:  And as we see in
this dramatic video,
CHP officers Mike Tilly
and John Wall
risked their lives to
save the single mom.
Flores was then transferred
to St. Joseph's Hospital
in serious but stable condition
after suffering
smoke inhalation.
(RAP MUSIC PLAYING)
I don't know.
I'll give you $500.
LOU: This is a custom
racing bicycle, sir.
Designed for
competitive road cycling.
This bike has
a light-weight,
space-age carbon frame
and handlebars positioned
to put the rider
in a more aerodynamic posture.
It also has micro-shifters
and 37 gears,
and weighs under six pounds.
I won the Tour de Mexico
on this bike.
SHOP OWNER: $700
is as high as I'll go.
It cost me over $8,000 new.
SHOP OWNER: $700.
$2,500,
and that's giving it away.
No bike has got 37 gears.
$2,000.
No.
Could I please
speak to your boss?
I'm the owner.
How about $800 in store credit?
What are you after?
A camcorder and
a police scanner.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
(ON RADIO)  7-X-76 Roger.
David 1099965.
Checking in C.I.C.
FEMALE OFFICER 1:
8859. One, Lincoln, Adam,
David, Young, John, one.
R.O. not on file.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Any northeast unit.
415 fight,
13932 Tularosa Drive.
Suspect number one,
male, black.
Suspect number two,
male, black, juvenile.
No further description.
Code Two, incident 3679.
ID 1125.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(WOMAN SHOUTING)
OFFICER 1: Hey!
Who the hell are you?
Freelance!
What are you doing?
Filming for TV.
No. Back away.
What's happening?
I said turn around and leave.
I'm fairly certain
I'm allowed to film this.
Film what?
I don't know.
What's happening?
Walk away, or get
arrested for obstruction.
Yes, Officer.
Hurry up.
Get out of here.
(WOMAN SHOUTING)
OFFICER 2:
Blow, blow, blow.
Almost. Almost.
Will you move that cam?
Man, you better back up.
Leave!
Do you think I'm
playing with you?
FEMALE DISPATCHER: (ON RADIO)
More street units,
ambulance to 11.
Just occurred.
Western and Third.
Suspect last seen
northbound Western on foot.
Code Three,
incident 4259. ID 703.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
MAN: All right, let's get
some blood pressure.
He's pretty shocked.
MEDIC 1:
Breathing is very shallow.
MEDIC 2: He's got a second
chest wound here.
MEDIC 1: Put pressure on it.
MEDIC 1: We got it.
Strap it on the other side.
MEDIC 2:
You got a dressing on it?
MEDIC 1: Yeah.
MEDIC 2:
GCS is 1-1-1, guys.
MEDIC 1: Give me pressure.
MEDIC 2: 90 over 60.
MEDIC 1: No radial pulse.
MEDIC 2: We're losing him.
MEDIC 1: He's bleeding out.
MEDIC 2: Can you bag him?
Let's start bagging him.
Keep on high flow, too.
MEDIC 1: Yep.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
MEDIC 2:
I got no pulse here.
MEDIC 1: Unresponsive.
OFFICER: Get back.
You. Get back.
Get the fuck back now.
Okay.
Shit. All right.
Get back,
100 feet back, now.
You get back, too.
100 feet.
Fucking asshole,
you shut it down.
I had a great
fucking angle back there
until you crowded in.
Get the fuck home.
There's people trying
to do their fucking job.
Fucking asshole.
Yeah. It's Ace Video.
Your lead's gonna be
at First and Western.
Yeah,
you wanna get there.
It's a shooting.
Yeah, I got some great
footage of a victim
being treated.
No, the LAPD hasn't released it
but a manager at
a Walgreens says
it's a carjacking and
the victim is the owner.
He's Asian and critical.
Right.
Look,
I got a 60-second cut
with the manager and a neighbor.
$500.
Then, make me a deal.
$400.
$300. All right, deal.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Get out of here.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
LINDA: Okay,
dip into graphics.
FRANK: I don't think
that's going to cover it.
LINDA: Frank,
it's not my call.
Oh, excuse me.
Excuse me.
I have video footage.
Uh, down the hall,
to the right.
MALE EDITOR: Right here.
NINA: Okay.
Put the neighbor here,
and the kids with
their mother by the door.
You can get it back
from 2:16.
MALE EDITOR: Yeah.
Then I want to lay
in some nat-sound.
Let's loop
the neighbor's dog
barking.
And then try taking
the crying kid from B-roll
and dropping that
in the background.
Got it.
You my fill-in operator?
I don't think so.
I'm Lou Bloom.
I have some footage for sale.
A stringer?
What?
Who do you work for?
At the moment,
I work for myself.
See Frank out there,
the way you came.
Uh, what's it timed to?
MALE EDITOR: 1:06.
What do you have?
Something
I'm fairly certain
you'll be very excited about.
What is it?
LOU: It's a shooting.
A man was shot.
Several times, in fact.
He's lying on the ground,
and he's bleeding
on the ground.
I'd be surprised if
he survived, honestly.
He was shot during a carjacking.
Western and First?
Yes, that's right.
We're getting that from Ace.
I was there.
I was much closer
to what happened.
(LAUGHS)
NINA: Okay. Okay.
Let's see it.
You can fast
forward through this.
(DOG BARKS ON TV)
Keep going,
keep going.
Walk away,
or I'll arrest you for...
(TAPE SQUEALING)
A minute-and-a-half in.
(GARBLED VOICES)
There.
(MEDIC SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
MALE EDITOR: Oh, fuck.
I need you to see something.
(PEOPLE SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ON TAPE)
FRANK: Yeah?
Lou Bloom.
Frank Kruse,
our assignment editor.
Play it back.
(TAPE REWINDING)
MEDIC 2:
I got no pulse, here.
That's the lead.
I want to break it up
and do a wrap-around
from the scene.
I want a walking stand-up,
teaser at five,
repeat on the half
and I want the copy to
start with a warning.
You're going to show this?
With a warning.
It's excessive.
We should have
packages like this
every day.
People are eating breakfast.
NINA: And they'll talk
about it at work.
Tie it in with the carjacking
last month in Glendale.
And the other one,
the van in Palms.
When was that? In March?
MALE EDITOR: March, yeah.
NINA: It's a carjacking
crime wave.
That's the banner.
Call the victim's family,
get a quote, mic it.
You know what to do.
Yeah.
How much?
I'm selling this
particular piece for $1,000.
Not even close.
This late, you have
nowhere else to go.
And the quality's for shit.
(SCOFFS)
I'll give you $250,
that's the most I'll do.
Now, let's get you paid.
Here you go.
Buy yourself some
better equipment,
a directional mic,
and get interviews when you can.
You have a good eye.
Thank you.
I'm just beginning,
so praise from someone
such as yourself,
well, you can imagine
that it means quite a lot.
I'll help in any way I can.
And, of course,
you can help me
by calling us first.
I want you to contact me
when you have something.
Something like this.
That's right.
Bloody.
Well,
that's only part of it.
We like crime.
Not all crime.
Carjacking in Compton,
for example.
That isn't news,
now is it?
We find our viewers
are more interested
in urban crime
creeping into the suburbs.
What that means
is a victim, or victims,
preferably well-off
and white,
injured at
the hands of the poor
or a minority.
Just crime.
No. Accidents play.
Cars, busses, trains,
planes. Fires.
But bloody.
Well, graphic.
The best and clearest way
that I can phrase it
to you, Lou,
to capture the spirit
of what we air,
is think of our newscast
as a screaming woman
running down the street
with her throat cut.
I understand.
I'm a very,
very quick learner.
You will be seeing me again.
I believe you.
(NEWS THEME MUSIC
PLAYING ON TV)
MALE ANNOUNCER:  Live from
the KWLA broadcast center
in Los Angeles.
This is KWLA 6 News
at 6:00 a.m.
Coverage you can count on.
A tragic drug store visit
to help his ailing wife
claimed the life
of a loving husband
last night near Hancock Park.
Reporting from the scene
is Ron De La Cruz.
RON:  An act of kindness
turned into
a savage deadly attack
just outside this market
on Western and First
around 2:00 a.m.
when 68-year-old
Richard Cho of Mar Vista
was walking towards his car
with a prescription
for his sick wife
when he was
confronted right here
by a man with
a 9mm handgun
police believe wanted
to take his vehicle.
The vicious
tragedy and senselessness
of the brutal shooting
as well as
the victim's final moments
were all caught in graphic video
which we are about to show.
Viewer discretion is advised.
Paramedics worked
feverishly to save
the life of Richard Cho.
But despite heroic efforts,
the husband and
father of three,
was pronounced dead
at Good Samaritan Hospital.
Alarmingly,
this is the third
violent carjacking
in the area in recent months.
And residents here
are growing concerned
as police are still
without any leads.
This is Ron De La Cruz,
reporting live.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
(ON RADIO)  Hollywood clear.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON SCANNER)
MALE DISPATCHER:
Rescue. 2249.
Engine 99 for Coldwater.
Acknowledge.
4220 South
Beverly Glen Boulevard.
Burglar alarm,
all companies return course.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Any Hollywood unit, Code 37.
Last seen northbound
La Brea at Oakwood.
Blue Prius.
No suspect description.
Code Two, incident 2475.
RD 693.
(CROWD CHEERING ON TV)
(LAUGHS)
Hey.
I'm sorry I'm late.
Are you Richard?
Uh, Rick.
I'm Louis Bloom.
Hey, Lou.
Louis. Sit down.
The situation is
that I lost an employee,
and I'm interviewing
for a replacement.
Okay. The ad didn't
say what the job was.
It's a fine opportunity
for some lucky someone.
(LAUGHS)
Okay.
I'd like to know about
your prior employment
and hear,
in your own words,
what you learned
from each position.
My old jobs?
I did landscaping
for a couple months.
Like, mow, blow, and go.
Uh...
I learned that I had
hay fever, so I quit.
Other jobs?
I don't know.
Like, a week here,
a week there.
Why hire you?
(LOU LAUGHS)
Sell yourself.
Okay.
Go.
I'm Rick. Of course.
Uh...
I took three buses to get here.
I finished high school.
I need a job.
I'll do pretty much anything.
That's me. Hire Rick.
So...
Hmm.
What's your address,
Richard?
I don't have one.
Not a permanent one right now.
You're homeless.
I was for a while.
You trick.
Work the street? No.
Wasn't a question.
I'm straight.
Plenty of straight guys trick.
Do you have a driver's license?
Yeah.
Do you know Los Angeles?
Yeah. I grew up
all around here.
Can you start tonight?
Doing what?
I run a successful
TV news business.
We film breaking stories.
Maybe you saw my
item this morning
of a fatal carjacking.
No. I don't have a TV,
but that sounds cool.
Do you have a cellphone?
Yeah.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Does it have GPS?
Yes, it does.
Congratulations.
You're hired.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
Your job will be
to listen to
the emergency radio,
learn police codes,
help navigate,
and watch the car.
Okay.
And what does it pay?
It's an internship.
Man, I, uh...
I can't do that.
I need money.
I'm giving you a chance
to explore career options
and get insight
into my organization.
It's not at all unusual for me
to make full-time job
offers to my interns.
No, I know.
I got to get paid,
like, something at least,
you know.
I'll give you
$30 cash per night.
Okay. Okay.
(LAUGHS)
Thank you. Thanks.
MALE OFFICER:
(ON RADIO)  4-A-27
at Main and Washington,
requesting Code Ten for one.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Calling back stand-by.
4-A-27, go ahead.
LOU: 4-A-27 is
requesting a Code Ten
to clear the frequency
for warrant information.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
4-A-1, prowler complaint,
Sixth and Rampart.
Female Hispanic
wearing a blue shirt.
Code 2,
incident 2156, RD 235.
Code Two is
"Respond immediately,
no lights and sirens."
And Code Three is?
With the lights and sirens on.
Very good.
(LAUGHS)
MALE OFFICER: (ON RADIO)
2-A-1 responding.
Sixth and Rampart, Code Two.
So, should we go?
No. We want victims
and not the kind
that live on
Sixth and Rampart.
(LAUGHS)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
FEMALE DISPATCHER: (ON RADIO)
Any Van Nuys unit, 415 man.
7227 Van Nuys Boulevard
at the Big King Market.
Inside the location,
the suspect
is a male Hispanic
wearing an orange
construction vest
and blue jeans.
In custody with
security guards.
I'm going to get some water.
You want anything?
No, thank you.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Rampart units,
domestic violence,
restraining order violation.
Suspect last seen on foot
on Fifth Street
towards Virgil.
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(GROANING)
(SCANNER BEEPING)
MALE DISPATCHER:
Structure fire.
Station 58. Engine 58.
Task force 58,
task force 43.
Engine 43.
Battalion 10.
1642 Rincon Avenue...
Structure fire!
Engine 58 on scene.
1642 Rincon Avenue.
Seat belt. Seat belt.
Seat belt.
Where are we going?
We're taking
the next right coming up.
Slow down, man.
That's too fast!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
LOU: Talk to me, Richard.
Talk to me, Richard.
What next?
Next left, coming up.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
RICK: (GRUNTS) Fuck!
I need more warning next time.
LOU: Where are we going?
Talk to me!
What's next?
Okay.
Keeping on this five...
No, six blocks.
Then a right.
On what?
(STUTTERING)
I made a mistake!
It's a right five blocks back.
It's just five blocks.
LOU:
Did they bring him out?
Ambulance left two minutes ago.
You're a lifetime too late.
Nice camera!
(JOE LAUGHS)
MAN: On to the next.
I bet I wasted
five dollars of gas
just getting here
or don't you think
that's a lot of money?
I'm sorry.
I couldn't see the screen,
you were driving so fast.
Okay, first of all,
Richard,
don't answer me by
telling me a problem.
I have enough of those already.
Bring me a solution,
and then we can make
a decision together.
Okay. Maybe if
you didn't rush me.
Don't rush you. Okay.
I can use that.
See, Rick,
they've done studies
and they found
that in any system
that relies on cooperation
from a school of fish,
say, or even a professional
hockey team, for example,
these experts have
identified communication
as the number one
single key to success.
LOU: You know what
"fear" stands for?
What?
"False Evidence
Appearing Real."
RICK: You're going really
fucking fast, dude.
Get out of your head,
Rick.
It's a bad neighborhood.
Now, when you get a chance,
I'd like to know
where we're going.
Uh, left on Third.
Six blocks.
(TIRES SQUEALING)
Find a more appropriate
place to park the car,
and don't get blocked in.
OFFICER: Are you the one
that made the call?
MAN: No, no.
I think...
WOMAN: I was trying
to go to sleep,
and I heard a sound.
It scared me.
That's why I called.
Sir, what's going on?
Who the fuck are you?
TV news.
What happened?
It was a shooting.
I told the cops
that he was
waving a gun last week,
but they didn't fucking care.
Can you try one more
time without swearing?
WOMAN:
I'm not doing it again.
(STUTTERING)
But this is for TV.
Yeah?
I don't have a TV.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
It's over.
Shot the place to shit.
OFFICER: All right,
guys, pack it up.
Let's move it out.
MAN: ...running out of
there as fast as we could.
Through that window there.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS
CONTINUE)
NINA:  Great shot.
Oh, that's fantastic.
Oh, that's a great
piece of tape.
You didn't get an interview
with the couple?
I have footage of them.
LOU: I have an interview
with a neighbor.
She curses, but
you can cut that out.
How did you get
inside the house?
The door was open.
They allowed you?
I heard somebody
yell to come in,
and when nobody
was inside, I left.
And the only shot of the
couple is through a window?
The police were
shutting it down.
I don't like it.
Like what?
The footage looks
like he broke in.
There's no close-up
of the homeowners
and he's giving us their name
off a piece of
private correspondence.
Excuse me,
that's junk mail.
Well,
I have a problem with that.
NINA: We'll knock out
a killer package.
This is my job.
No!
Your job is writing
the tweet of the day.
And getting Deb to turn sideways
during the weather forecast.
We're running it.
LOU: I like how
you handled Frank.
You didn't soften
the truth or dilute it.
I think being clear
with your objectives
is more important
than trying to
present your ideas
in a non-confrontational
manner.
Do you have
experience in an office?
Myself?
Not presently, no.
Where did you get all that?
I study a lot online.
Yeah? Like what?
LOU: All sorts of things,
actually.
I'm on my computer all day.
I haven't had what
you'd call much
of a formal education,
but you can find
most anything if you
look hard enough.
Last year, I took
an online business course,
for example.
And I learned that
you have to have
a business plan
before starting a business.
And that why you
pursue something
is equally as important
as what you pursue.
The site advised you
to answer the following question
before you decide
where to focus
your abilities.
The question was
"What do I love to do?"
The site suggested making a list
of your strengths
and weaknesses.
What am I good at?
What am I not good at?
Maybe I want to strengthen
and develop knowledge
about the things
I'm already good at.
Maybe I want to
strengthen my weaknesses.
I recently remade my list.
And I'm thinking
that television news
might just be something I love
as well as something
I happen to be good at.
On TV, it looks so real.
Yes. It does.
Well,
I have a show to do.
Your check is at the desk.
Outstanding work, Lou.
Really, just great.
Thanks, Nina.
That means an awful lot.
(LAUGHING)
Okay.
DEENA:  It's every
parent's nightmare.
Imagine singing
a lullaby to your infant
and tucking them into bed
and then having
to shield them
as a barrage of
high-caliber bullets
literally blast into your home.
For the Cahills of Echo Park,
that fear became
a terrifying reality
when an adjacent house
became the setting for a scene
right out of the Wild West.
(INAUDIBLE)
(MELLOW MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
MAN: (ON GAS STATION RADIO)
Dude!
Paying too much at the pump?
Well, sign up for
our super saver card
and you'll be saving
buckets of duckets
on every purchase.
Takes minutes to sign up
and you'll start
saving right away.
You'll also be eligible
for some sweet giveaways.
So sign up now
and start saving!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON SCANNER)
(GAS STATION RADIO CONTINUES)
Rick, I'm very pleased
with how you progressed.
You're doing a great job.
However, you just spilled
gasoline on my car
which will eat the paint.
I need you tighten
up a bit on this.
Because if you fill
it like that again,
I will terminate
you immediately,
I promise you.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON SCANNER)
"Bed, Bath & Beyond."
Oh, that's a good store.
Making peace
with what you don't have,
that's what it's all about.
Living with what
you ain't got, right?
Don't you think?
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Traffic units,
ambulance traffic,
Benedict Canyon.
Overturned vehicle
with injuries.
Crash with injuries.
Good neighborhood.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
TV news.
What happened?
I think it was
a head-on collision,
and there's a guy
who's dead over there.
There's a woman...
Did you see what happened?
Am I supposed to help?
I didn't see, I came after.
LOU: Can you tell me
exactly what happened?
Will you get the camera
out of my face?
Get it out!
I'm trying to talk to 911!
No, it's at...
The guy is down.
(SIRENS WAILING)
OFFICER: Make some room!
We'll block it off.
OFFICER:
Not getting through here.
Son of a bitch.
OFFICER: Let's go.
Fuck this.
NINA: Here you go.
LOU: Ben Waterman
wears the same gold tie
on Fridays.
We're leading with it.
That's your third
start this week.
I'm focusing on framing.
A proper frame not only
draws the eye into a picture
but keeps it there longer,
dissolving the barrier
between the subject and
the outside of the frame.
Is that blood on your shirt?
I don't think so.
I recently heard of
a Mexican restaurant
called Cabanita.
Have you heard of it?
It's also on your sleeve.
I didn't see that.
What I'm asking is,
do you like Mexican food, Nina?
Yes.
WOMAN: Stand by, people.
Here we go.
Cabanita has been called
"an authentic
taste of Mexico City."
Do you wanna go with me?
I think we could
have fun together.
Thanks, but I'm busy.
Saturday is your
night off, isn't it?
I have a rule, Lou.
I don't date people I work with.
And I'm twice your age.
I like older women.
Besides,
I don't work with you.
You're someone I sell to.
And I don't wanna fuck that up.
What if by saying no,
you fuck it up?
MAN: All right, 10 seconds
to go and back on.
Is that what you're saying?
I didn't say that.
(LAUGHING)
MAN: Eight, seven,
six, five...
Well, I don't know what to say.
MAN: ...three, two, one.
LISA: Good morning.
Thank you for joining us.
I'm Lisa Mays.
BEN: And I'm Ben Waterman.
First up on  This Morning
on KWLA News,
a horrible car crash
over in Benedict Canyon.
It's claimed the life
now of one man.
Severely injured a young woman.
JOE: Hey, Lou!
Hey, man.
Joe Loder, Mayhem.
Great get tonight.
They were closing it down
by the time we showed up.
Were you waiting
for me out here?
No, I was driving by
and I saw your car.
You're not dropping
your shit off, are you?
Nobody does that.
You need an air card
if you want to be
in the game.
Import the video to your laptop.
Cut the video.
Upload to your FTP site
and notify stations
you got something for sale.
Boom, boom, boom!
Otherwise,
it's a nice ride.
Listen, man,
you got a good run going
but there's valleys out there.
Take it from me.
I've been nightcrawling
for 14 years.
You heard I'm
adding a second van?
No. I didn't hear that.
Gonna be a game changer.
Cut my on-scene time
in half.
I'm setting up
a dedicated dispatch, too.
No more listening
and driving.
That's for suckers.
You like the Canon 305s?
Never used one.
Six thou a piece.
2.4 megapixels.
Night vision.
18:1 zoom.
I got one of those puppies
with your name on it.
I have a camera.
I want you
running my second van.
Two crews.
Half the area to cover.
Now, I know
what you're thinking.
Half the money, right?
You should be thinking,
twice the sales.
Because we're
going to be the first
at every scene.
Why compete when we
can work together?
You can share my press cards.
Puppy dog off my
police connections.
This is the big move,
the next level.
We can corner this whole thing.
I'm talking about
putting some heavy digits
in our pocket, brah.
Thank you for
offering me the position
but working for
myself is more in line
with my skills and career goals.
Take a few days
to think about it.
No.
You'll need to
hire someone else,
and I don't want to
hold up the process.
You want to be on
the inside of this, man
because I'm going
to be tag-teaming
every call.
You keep talking
like it's something
that I may be
interested in,
but I'm not.
You don't even
understand the offer.
If you did, you'd be
fucking sucking my dick!
You'd be asking me questions.
What does this mean?
What does that mean?
I feel like grabbing you
by your ears right now
and screaming in your face,
"I'm not
fucking interested."
Instead,
I'm going to drive home
and do some accounting.
Fuck you!
Twerp.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(MARIACHI MUSIC PLAYING)
(SIGHS) I didn't
wake up until 5:00.
My body is so off,
I feel like it's
time for breakfast.
(CHUCKLES LIGHTLY)
I bet you're beautiful
any time of the day.
In fact, I'd say
you're much prettier
than Lisa Mays.
(LAUGHS)
I like the dark
makeup on your eyes.
I also like the way you smell.
So, where you from, Lou?
The north end of the Valley.
Some of the calls sometimes
take me over there,
but nobody I know
still lives out there.
You're from Philadelphia,
Pennsylvania.
How did you know that?
It's online.
Everything about you is online.
Not everything,
but definitely a lot.
I've watched all the videos
from when you were a reporter.
I'm sure you look
at those, of course.
No. God, no.
Not without a drink in my hand.
I watch my work all the time.
Yeah? Do you want
to become a reporter?
No.
Most of you guys want air time.
Not me.
I want to be the guy
that owns the station
that owns the camera.
The business is going well,
but in order to
grow to the next level,
I need to stay
one step ahead
of my competition
and take risks.
I also need financial support
to implement expansion.
Would you like
another margarita?
One is enough.
Thanks for coming out to talk.
The place I'm in now
is that I want a relationship
with someone I can team up with
and share, like we share,
the same job
and hours and whatnot.
I could go down
a laundry list,
but you get the idea.
Yes.
Well, I hope you find someone.
Here's the thing
about that, Nina.
I'm quite certain
I already have.
Okay.
Let me put this politely.
I only came out to
dinner with you, Lou,
purely as
a professional courtesy.
Thank you.
I don't think it's any secret
that I've
single-handedly raised
the unit price of
your ratings book.
Our ratings book price?
Whoa! (LAUGHS)
I'm a very fast learner.
We had a conversation
where I specifically
mentioned that.
Do you remember that?
Well, do you?
Yes.
I recently learned,
for instance,
that most Americans
watch local news
to stay informed.
I also learned that
the average half-hour
of Los Angeles
television news
packs all of its
local government coverage
including law enforcement,
budget, transportation,
education and immigration
into 22 seconds.
(CHUCKLES)
Local crime stories,
however, not only
usually led the news
but filled 14
times the broadcast,
averaging five minutes
and seven seconds.
KWLA relies heavily
on such stories.
With Los Angeles
crime rates going down,
I think that
makes items like mine
particularly valuable.
Like rare animals. (LAUGHS)
I can only imagine that
your needs will increase
during next month's
rating sweeps period.
Ooh!
(BOTH LAUGH)
Yeah.
Well, we certainly
appreciate what you do.
There's certain good things
about being alone.
You have time to do
the things you wanna do,
like study and plan,
but you can't have
dinners like this
or be physical with a person.
I mean, outside
of flirtation-ship.
Where are you going with this?
I want that.
With you.
Like you want to
keep your job and
your health insurance.
Look, just for starters,
I don't need you to
keep my fucking job.
You're the news director
on the vampire shift
of the lowest-rated
station in Los Angeles.
We have what could be
considered an
almost-exclusive relationship.
There are many
other places I could go.
I have to think
that you're invested
in this transaction.
WAITER: Here you are.
Wow.
WAITER: Enjoy.
Thank you.
Where did you get
the balls to even suggest
something like this?
We're still talking.
No. There's nothing
more to say.
You can leave.
Okay, look.
You've done well. Okay?
And we pay you well,
very well.
We always have.
If you like,
I could get you
an exclusive retainer.
That would be on top
of your segment fees.
I could maybe even get
you a job at the station
starting as
a production assistant.
So that you could
learn the business
from the inside.
That's where you
said your interests lie.
Mmm-hmm.
You're not listening,
Nina.
I happen to know that you
haven't stayed at one station
for longer than
two years at a time,
and you're coming
up on two years soon.
I can imagine
that your contract is
for that length of time.
And that next month's ratings
directly affect that.
So, you're threatening
that if I don't...
I'm negotiating.
You're threatening
to stop selling to me.
That's your choice.
The true price of any item
is what somebody's
willing to pay for it.
You want something.
And I want you.
To fuck you.
And as a friend.
Jesus Christ, friends
don't pressure friends
to fucking sleep with them.
Actually,
that's not true, Nina.
Because as I'm sure you know,
a friend is a gift
you give yourself.
RICK: Okay,
a left on Roth,
and then six blocks to the ramp.
You're putting me on the 5?
Yeah, the 2 to the 5
to the 110 to the 10.
Did you read my
traffic memo yesterday?
Did I read it?
Yeah, I read it.
What did it say?
About the 5?
Okay. I looked at it.
What?
Well, for one thing,
it included that
the 5 has floating construction
in the fast lane for
the next three weeks.
So, given that,
I expect you to put me
on the 2 to the 101
to the 110 to the 10.
That's half of one,
six of the other.
It's half dozen of one,
What I'd like you
to do is admit that
you didn't read
what you said you did.
You know I'm
a reasonable person,
but nobody likes to be lied to!
Okay! When am I
going to get my raise?
That's reasonable, right?
You keep talking
about this
performance review.
When is it gonna happen?
I've been out here
two months already,
busting my ass every night.
I'm tired of your
promises for more pay, man.
I'm sleeping in a garage.
Rick, trying to
leverage your salary
in this economic environment
is near impossible.
Most firms have
set starting wages.
Ideally, you could
leverage with other offers,
but that's just not the case
in your situation right now.
MALE DISPATCHER:
(ON RADIO)  Test 498.
Engine 91. North division.
Battalion 12.
Heavy rescue. 56.
Air ops respond.
Reported plane down.
Whiteman Field,
south of Foothill.
Reroute us to that.
We're 22 minutes from Foothill,
and only five
from a hit and run.
They're rolling heavy rescue
and an air ambulance.
Get me there, please.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
MAN 1: It's good right there.
Stay on that spot.
Not getting through here.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
It's all over here, buddy.
Turn it around, let's go.
You're late.
JOE: Hey, brah!
Five fatals.
Come screaming out
of the fucking sky.
All lit up with
the brush on fire.
Mine. Exclusive.
I'm banging!
And my other van
is in Carson,
getting the jumper.
You know...
I was trying to
hook you up, man.
teach you something.
(LAUGHS)
Welcome to the future,
brah.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
NINA: A car crash.
Well, none of this is
gonna knock anybody out.
I can't use any of
this in my rundown.
Is this it?
No, I have a stabbing in Corona.
Where's the plane
crash at Foothill?
I don't mind saying
that I'm trying to
bring you stories
that happen here on the ground.
Two has it.
It'll be their lead.
Well, I hope that
works well for them.
Now, let me show you
the stabbing in Corona.
I don't give a goddamn
about fucking Corona!
You know how
important this week is.
This shit is
fucking death to me!
I understand your frustration.
I was just trying not
to be too hard on myself.
I sold you upstairs
as some kind of
fucking sweeps savior.
And I'm leading with
a goddamn stabbing.
In Corona!
So, you want that, then?
I want you to get
in the goddamn game!
I want something
people can't turn away from.
I want what you
fucking promised me!
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR SHUTS)
HARVEY: (ON TV)
Good morning, everyone.
Thanks for joining us.
I'm Pat Harvey.
SHOCKNEK:  Hope your day's
getting off to a good start.
I'm Kent Shocknek.
We begin with
a tragedy last night
in the foothills
of Santa Susana Pass
where a private plane crashed
with no survivors.
CBS2 has obtained
this exclusive video.
We want to remind you now
that what you're
about to see is graphic,
and viewer
discretion is advised.
(SCREAMING)
(RATCHETING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON SCANNER)
Since when did Coldwater
become faster than Laurel?
Huh? What was
the thinking there?
I didn't ask that
to hear myself speak.
Because, you know,
Coldwater only has
six lights.
Laurel has places to pass.
I can't get around
this person until Ventura.
It's the same
argument, man.
I said this route.
If you wanted to take Laurel,
you should have said something.
I thought that
you worked
in other factors.
If I didn't think
that you could do better,
I wouldn't ride you so hard
about the routes.
I think you know that, Rick.
I think it may just be possible
that I have
a higher opinion of you
than you have of yourself.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
RICK: What the fuck?
God damn it!
(CAR HONKS)
Seriously?
To get to a van crash
on Moorpark?
Who cares?
What's the rush?
Why aren't we at
the rape at Griffith Park
like everybody else?
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Oh, fuck! Oh, fuck me.
Oh, God! That's the fucking
Mayhem van.
Joe Loder
and the other dude.
What's his name?
Fucking Marcus.
Park the car
and get your camera.
MAN 1: Now, let's get
one guy inside.
Hold the seats back.
You can't get
that in right there?
MAN 2: No, there's no room.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
MAN 1: Here we go.
(CONVERSATION CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY)
What the hell happened?
LOU: According to witnesses,
they were driving at
a high rate of speed,
probably toward Griffith Park,
when, apparently,
they ran head-on
into this light pole.
No other car.
Single vehicle.
How did they just
run into a pole?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS
CONTINUE)
MAN 1: Get that backboard
right up against him.
Easy.
Hey, don't film that, man.
He's one of us.
Not anymore, Rick.
We're professionals.
He's a sale.
Got facial trauma.
Got lacerations
all the way down...
MAN 3: Yeah,
I'm calling it in.
MAN 2: Minimize
that movement.
MAN 1: Get him back
in the ambulance and
put some oxygen on him.
Drop him down.
MAN 2: Keep pressure on him.
MAN 3: Back that unit off.
MAN 1: Yeah, let's get
some four-by-fours
on there.
MAN 1: Bring the gurney
all the way up.
(JOE GURGLING)
MAN 3: Come on, let's go.
Stay with me.
MAN 2: I got him,
I got him.
Make sure
you size him right.
MAN 3: All right.
Man, we are way
the hell out here.
FEMALE DISPATCHER: (ON RADIO)
Any Mission unit.
Residential 211 in progress.
37 Bonhill Road.
Receiving 211 siren activation.
Armed response
on a home invasion.
We're five blocks away.
Pull a U-turn.
(CHATTER ON SCANNER
CONTINUES)
At the end of the street.
Coming up.
4808. Here!
We beat the police.
What do you want me to do?
You know what to do, Rick!
(CLICKS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
(MAN PANTING)
(ENGINE STARTS)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(CLICKS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
(ON RADIO)
3-X-21. Go ahead.
MALE OFFICER: (ON RADIO)
3-X-21, confirm address
on the 211 at Bonhill Road.
(MUSIC BOX PLAYING LULLABY)
(BREATHING NERVOUSLY)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(MAN COUGHS)
(GROANING)
RICK: What is going on?
We're leaving.
What?
(STUTTERS)
What's in there?
What's going on?
What happened in there?
You should have
walked in
and looked, Rick,
if you're that curious.
That's what
I'm paying you to do.
You need to show initiative.
There is no better way
to achieve job security
than by making yourself
an indispensable employee.
I heard gunshots!
All the more reason
you might have
helped me.
You might have
learned a new skill
that made you more useful
and put us on
a track toward growth!
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
(TIRES SQUEALING)
(SIREN WAILING)
Stay in the car.
Why?
Because I said so.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(LAPTOP BEEPS)
(TYPING)
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
MAN: We have
a hit-and-run
in Beverly Hills,
a car versus
pedestrian incident
and a robbery.
NINA: Do we have
footage of the crash?
MAN: Surveillance footage.
I've been trying
to reach you
for the last hour.
In the future,
when you don't
have anything,
man up and don't dodge
my fucking calls.
I do have something.
What?
Home invasion,
triple murder
in Granada Hills.
That's just breaking now.
We got there before the police.
You have it?
I'm not going to list
the many benefits
of this piece.
I think it's probably best
if you just watch it
for yourself.
I could have had
someone out there by now.
Why didn't you call it in?
To increase your need,
and improve
my bargaining position.
Frank, Jenny!
Bay 2, now!
(SIGHS CONTENTEDLY)
Get Linda in here.
(CLICKS)
Home invasion in Granada.
He got there before the cops.
We have 10 minutes to airtime.
How much of this can we show?
You mean, legally?
No, morally.
Of course, legally.
Have they been identified?
It just happened,
so you have to assume no,
and that's just
one of the issues.
We can't broadcast
their identities
without notifying
the next of kin.
We're not identifying them.
You are by proxy,
by showing their faces.
We pixelate the faces.
Where did you get this?
Stringer.
Hi, Linda. I'm Lou.
Um, Jesus. Is there
a dead baby
inside of there?
No. The crib was empty.
NINA: Oh,
for Christ's sake.
Are we breaking the law
by showing this?
Block the faces,
don't give out
the exact address.
Do that, I guess.
(STAMMERS) I don't know.
I wouldn't think so, no.
Journalistically and ethically?
This isn't Hartford.
We are beyond
all broadcast standards.
Have you seen the overnights?
I'll risk the fine.
What did you pay for this?
The price hasn't been
negotiated yet.
(SIGHS)
Give us a minute.
Thanks.
How much?
$100,000.
(CHUCKLES) How much?
$50,000.
I need a number.
Nine minutes.
I just gave you two.
$3,000.
I got $3,000
for the food truck
stabbings.
There were more dead.
Those were poor
Mexican people
in a roach coach.
Two of them were illegals.
These are three
wealthy white people,
shot and killed
in their mansion.
Including
a suburban housewife
shotgunned in her bed.
I know you, Nina.
I know your interest
and excitement
in this product
is greater
than the amount
you're offering.
(SIGHS)
$5,000.
$30,000.
$7,000.
$25,000.
$8,000.
$15,000.
$9,000.
$10,000.
$15,000.
Give me a serious number.
Can't do it. Never happen.
There's a matter
of precedent.
Ten is my last best offer.
Okay.
Really?
Where are you going?
Seven has approached me
at least several times.
The ND there gave me his number.
They'll make me
a better offer.
It's a five-minute drive.
Hold on!
(SIGHS)
Twelve.
Fifteen.
I can't spend
a month's budget
on a single story.
What if the story's not over?
The people who did this escaped.
They're still out there,
walking around
with the rest of us.
If I had a family
and I lived in a home,
that might make me nervous.
I'd want updates
on what was going on.
With this footage,
people would turn to
your channel for the story.
I like you, Nina.
And I look forward
to our time together.
But you have to understand.
$15,000 isn't all that I want.
From here on,
starting now,
I want my work to be credited
by the anchors and on a burn.
The name of my company is
Video Production News,
a professional
news-gathering service.
That's how it should be read
and that's how
it should be said.
I also want to go
to the next rung,
and meet your team.
And the station manager
and the director
and the anchors.
And start developing
my own
personal relationships.
I'd like to start
meeting them
this morning.
You'll take me around,
you'll introduce me
as the owner and President
of Video Production News
and remind them
of some of my many
other stories.
I'm not done.
I also want to
stop our discussion
over prices.
This will save time.
When I say that
a particular number
is my lowest price,
that's my lowest price.
And you can be
assured that I arrived
at whatever
that number is
very carefully.
Now, when I say that
I want these things,
I mean that I want them.
And I don't want to
have to ask again.
And the last thing
that I want, Nina,
is for you to do the things
that I ask you to do
when we're alone together
in your apartment.
Not like the last time!
So...
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
I'll tell you what.
(SNIFFLES)
I have the van crash
on Moorpark tonight.
It was a couple of
stringers, actually.
That could lead by itself
on an average night.
I'd be willing to
throw that in for free.
So what do you say,
do we have a deal?
Lisa Mays,
Ben Waterman, Lou Bloom.
Hi.
Hello. How are you, Lisa?
You remember Lou from
the Benedict Canyon crash.
BEN: Oh, yeah.
Amazing stuff.
That was my company,
Video Production News.
I would just like to say
that I think that
what the two of you do
is incredibly valuable.
Thank you.
That's nice of you
to say.
We appreciate it.
(STUDIO BELL RINGING)
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR:
I don't know how long
this tape runs,
we might dump out.
Twenty seconds to back.
Ben and Lisa,
20 seconds to back.
Set up a sting dig,
Camera Two on a two-shot.
Where's the banner?
Did we decide on one?
Horror House.
What did we talk about?
A.D.: Can you build that?
Put it on CG-one.
Back in 10 seconds.
Nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three,
two, one. Sting it.
(NEWS THEME PLAYING)
A.D.: Mics. Dissolve. Cue.
Hello, everybody.
This is KWLA
with breaking news.
Over the last
half-hour or so,
we've now received word of
an apparent home invasion
triple homicide
in the Granada Hills area
of the San Fernando Valley.
(EXHALES)
Now, at present,
the number of those dead...
Preset Camera Two.
...have not been
confirmed yet
by the police
but KWLA has obtained
exclusive footage
from inside the crime scene
in which at least
three bodies
can be observed.
Now, we're going to show you
segments of that footage
throughout the
rest of this broadcast,
but also throughout the day.
Ben, Lisa, I have a tape.
When you're ready,
throw to it.
I'll follow you.
Again, we're about to
show you
exclusive KWLA video
from inside
the actual crime scene.
It's graphic. Repeat it.
And before broadcasting
this video,
we want to warn our viewers
that these are
extremely graphic images.
And I'm hearing
from our control room
that we have that video,
and we're going to show it now.
BEN:  This is footage
that we have obtained
exclusively by KWLA
from Video Production News.
This is a professional
news-gathering service.
This is what appears
to be a shotgun,
something you might use
for home defense.
You can see the pistol grips
on the front
and the back there.
Quite possibly
the murder weapon.
And now,
Lisa, as we move inside,
this is a beautiful home.
A beautiful home
in a very safe
neighborhood.
Or, what most people think
is a safe neighborhood.
It appears that
that is the first body.
BEN:  A young woman,
I'm guessing,
from this angle.
A young woman on a sofa, there.
All of the faces, though,
have been blurred out.
They've escaped.
They're on the loose.
That is the first
of what we understand
are three bodies
in the home
in Granada Hills.
And this was
committed by a suspect,
or suspects
who are still out there.
They're believed
to have escaped.
And if you think about that,
that is a very
frightening thought.
Repeat that.
BEN:  Yes, scary,
and very concerning,
particularly given
what we're
looking at here.
The savagery
of what these
pictures show.
And now, look,
there on the floor.
Lisa, what is that?
A bloodied
article of clothing?
LISA:  It looks like
a silk shirt.
Maybe a woman's silk blouse.
BEN:  It's just so sad.
A.D.: Stand by
to dissolve, Two.
BEN:  And, obviously,
there is the second body.
NINA: They've escaped.
Repeat it.
BEN:  The person or people
who committed
all of this brutal
home invasion robbery,
they're presently
unidentified and at large,
still on the streets.
Hit it again. Harder.
BEN:  This has got to be
a huge worry
not only to the residents
in this neighborhood,
the Granada Hills area as well.
LISA:  All of Los Angeles,
if you think about it.
BEN:  Yeah, the entire
Southland, really.
Tonight, absolutely.
An apparent
family attacked,
savagely killed.
We believe this is
their own home.
In what is one of the quieter,
I think
a frankly more upscale
and affluent neighborhoods
in the whole Valley.
LISA:  In all of Los Angeles.
BEN:  And now,
as we're moving,
this is a nursery.
And you hope to God...
Build it.
...that there's not
a baby in that crib.
Yeah, you're just praying
that that crib is empty.
Because this is
definitely a child's room.
BEN:  And, now,
as we look, thank goodness.
Absolutely great.
In fact,
our understanding
right now
is that there was
no baby found
in the house.
Or any baby that
was seen at all
by the people
who filmed this for us.
LISA:  Thank goodness.
BEN:  That's Video News,
this is a professional
news-gathering
service that we use.
Apparently,
what we're hearing
from their photographer
is that they arrived
even before the police did.
And then entered
this home to help,
or at least offer
some sort of assistance
and then came upon
what you're
looking at here.
LISA:  They came upon
three bodies.
And that, right there
is the third body
on the floor.
This is a man, gray hair.
What would you think, Lisa?
Maybe 40s, 50s?
Yeah, 50s. Maybe even 60s.
"Vicious attack."
LISA:  We've been looking
at all this graphic footage
and just the viciousness,
the severity of violence.
Master control,
we're going to
come to a break.
We're going to commercial,
then cutting to Joel
and a police statement.
LISA:  I'm getting
word right now that police
are getting ready
to issue a statement
from the scene
and Joel Beatty
is there for that.
Right now, we're going
to take a quick break.
A.D.: Ready to break
in five, four...
Sneak in your music.
(NEWS THEME PLAYING)
Three, two, one.
Fade to black.
Roll your break.
That's a 10-share.
(STUDIO BELL RINGING)
(CHUCKLES)
NINA: I want theme music
on the return,
the cut we used for
the Simi rail crash.
Audio, cut 32, please.
Cut 32 when we come back.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Hello?
Rolling with your banner.
NINA: Thank you.
Actually,
he'd like to meet you.
A.D.: Come back,
One, and key on Ben.
JOEL:  Hey,
heads up, you guys.
The police spokesman
is making an announcement
in 60 seconds.
I gotta go.
Nina, we are getting
a ton of heat
from the police out here
about that video.
Tell them to call the station.
A.D.: Fifteen seconds.
They want to talk to
the person who shot it.
I shot it.
Joel,
it's Video Production News.
Tell them to call me.
Lou, they can't hear you.
A.D.:
Coming back in five,
four, three, two, one.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
A.D.: Fade up.
(NEWS THEME PLAYING)
FEMALE REPORTER:  We have
more information coming in
from the Granada Hills area
and the scene of
an apparent home invasion
that has left
a husband and wife
and their housekeeper...
What we know at
the moment is that
at some time around
5:00 this morning,
gunmen broke into
this upscale...
Residents are disturbed
and concerned by the brutal
triple murder...
BEN:  The way
we got it, though,
is a video production crew
that we work with
from time to time.
They, apparently,
arrived on the scene
in Granada Hills
before the police
got there.
Before anybody.
The photographer
who took those pictures
told us earlier that
he walked up to the door,
he saw what we all saw
in his videotape.
And then
he started to look inside,
so that he could help
or render assistance to someone.
That's when
he walked into the house
and started shooting the video.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
LISA:  He found the three
deceased in the house.
The two females
and the one...
(TV TURNS OFF)
Hello.
Hi.
I'm Detective Frontieri.
This is my partner,
Detective Lieberman.
Are you Louis Bloom?
Yes, I'm Lou.
You live here?
Yes, that's right.
May we come inside?
Why?
FRONTIERI: Why not?
You want to?
Yes.
I don't care.
(CHUCKLES)
Wonderful.
You were in
Granada Hills last night.
LOU: Yes, that's right.
You shot the video in the house?
Yes, ma'am, I did.
That's right.
You went inside the house?
You filmed
all through the house?
You even filmed the bodies.
All before the police came.
That door was open, ma'am.
Detective.
The door was open
and what I did was
I went in to see
if I could help,
because the alarm was ringing.
An active crime scene.
I didn't know
it was a crime scene.
LIEBERMAN:
You knew what it was.
LOU: I know that
an alarm means
someone is in trouble.
And you sold it
to be shown on TV.
We're a professional
news-gathering service.
LIEBERMAN:
What did you see
when you arrived?
Uh, two men
leaving in a vehicle.
You saw two men?
(STUTTERS) They were
just shapes, really.
I was afraid, so I hid.
And then I saw
the shapes of two men
moving inside the vehicle,
if that helps.
Describe the men.
LOU: It was dark.
And then they drove away.
Black? White? Tall?
LOU: I couldn't see.
LIEBERMAN:
What were they driving?
An SUV.
Dark-colored.
Rims? Tinted windows?
Maybe. Not that I saw.
Do you have any film
on the men or the car?
No, I don't. I only
started filming
when I was inside.
FRONTIERI: Mmm-hmm.
I'd like a copy of that footage.
Do I have to
give it to you?
(CHUCKLES)
Is there any reason
why you wouldn't?
No, no, I made you a copy.
I expected someone to come.
(CHUCKLES)
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUNSHOT)
(KEYBOARD CLACKS)
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
(SCRIBBLES)
(TYPING)
RICK: What's up, man?
(GROANS)
I'm tired.
Aren't you tired?
Why are we
starting so early?
(SEAT BELT CLICKS)
One of the people
in the house
last night was alive.
I cut that part out.
I also cut out the men
leaving in their car.
I have a name and an address.
We're gonna drive there.
We're gonna find the person
that drove that car.
So you know
who killed those people?
One of them,
quite possibly, yes.
You gotta call the cops.
And we will,
at the right time.
I'm offering you a real
opportunity here, Rick.
To do what?
I don't usually share
my business plan with you.
(CHUCKLES)
But a moment has arrived
that could allow the company
to make enough money
to expand to the next level.
We could call this
the critical moment.
I'm inviting you, Rick,
to be a part of the team
that pounces
on this opportunity.
You've been asking
a lot about
your performance review.
Yeah.
Well.
For starters,
I've been seeing
a great improvement
in your overall focus
and order-following.
Given complex problems,
you're developing
a real ability
to find clear
and simple solutions.
I'm also aware of
your increased enthusiasm.
It's great to see
your eyes light up
when you're working
on a new idea.
(CHUCKLES)
I hope you'll be
inspiring us
with your
innovative thinking
for years to come.
Thank you, man.
I'm trying. You know?
Which is why I'm promoting you
to Executive
Vice President
of Video News.
What am I now?
You're an assistant.
That's... Big.
Does it come with a raise?
Absolutely.
(BREATHES SHARPLY)
How much?
Pick a number.
You pick a number.
A... (STAMMERS)
$75 a night?
Agreed.
(CLAPS HAND)
What about more? You know?
Not now.
(SHIFTS GEARS)
We closed the deal.
I could have
gotten more, couldn't I?
Absolutely.
RICK: All right.
It's coming up on the left.
Halfway down the block.
1701 North Burns.
RICK: Is that the car?
That's the car.
Oh, shit.
(INDISTINCT SCANNER CHATTER)
Do you think there's a reward?
There is a reward.
How much?
$50,000.
Do I get any of that?
I just gave you a raise.
That's salary.
I mean, a bonus.
Bonuses come
at the end of the year.
(SCANNER CLICKS OFF)
So, we're gonna call it in?
We're gonna wait.
For what?
First, we want to see
if he's actually inside.
And then, we want to find
a more interesting place
to film the arrest.
Like where?
Anywhere we want.
What we're going to do,
is we're gonna wait
and then we're gonna follow him.
Then, when he reaches
what would be considered
a better or more
populated neighborhood,
then we'll report
his location to the police.
He's a violent,
wanted criminal.
I can't believe
that he's just going to
peacefully surrender.
(CHUCKLES IN DISBELIEF)
Okay. I want more money.
A lot more.
What makes a job
desirable, Rick,
isn't just
the dollar amount
attached to it.
You're at the ground floor
of a growing business.
Your reward is a career.
Fuck that.
You're talking about some
seriously messed-up shit.
You're expecting me
to just go along
with it. I want more.
I can't make people
do things, Rick.
You have a choice
if you wanna do this.
And I have a choice
if you don't.
Are you threatening to fire me?
Hey, I...
I got something, too.
How about
not calling in criminals,
waiting for them
to start some shit
so you can film it?
That's against the fucking law.
Yeah, cops would be
majorly interested
in that, no doubt.
Okay? So, I...
I want more money.
We can re-open
negotiations, Rick.
But, remember,
when it comes to
your work reputation,
you can't un-ring the bell.
I want half of
whatever we make tonight.
How did you arrive
at that number?
There's two of us out here.
So, 50-50.
I'll counter at $10,000.
You don't set
the numbers on this.
I want half.
If you're saying
I can't negotiate,
then I guess I'm...
I'm just gonna have
to give it to you.
Well, all right, then.
Oh... (STUTTERS)
Now I can feel good
about it, at least.
Now, I'll go the extra mile.
That's what
you never understood, man.
It's been the problem
the whole time.
You gotta bring
people in, Lou. Seriously.
You gotta talk to them
like they're
fucking human beings.
I'm saying this for you, dude.
For the future,
to help you.
Because you got
a seriously weird-ass
way of looking at shit.
You know you do!
(CHUCKLES)
You know what
your trouble is, man?
You don't fucking
understand people.
Okay?
Mmm-hmm.
I'll take the first watch.
Okay.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
LOU: Rise and shine.
He's leaving.
(CAR ALARM BEEPS)
(HONKING)
RICK: Is that him?
That's one of them.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
(ENGINE STARTS)
RICK: You're too fucking
close, man.
Oh, shit.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
You're too fucking close.
This guy might have
already seen us,
and he's bringing
us here as a trap.
You ever think of that?
(DOOR CLOSES)
RICK: Oh, shit.
(ENGINE STARTS)
They're gonna see us.
We're in a red fucking car.
Lower your window, please.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Keep your window down.
I'm fucking cold.
RICK: Shit,
they're parking.
Keep going.
(LINE RINGING)
MALE OPERATOR:
911, what's your emergency?
Uh, yes, good evening.
I'd like to report
the location of two men
responsible for
the triple murder in
Granada Hills last night.
MALE OPERATOR:
What's your address?
Uh, I followed them,
and they just pulled into
the Chinatown Express
at Western and Third.
Um, I can see them inside.
Okay, it's a restaurant
called Chinatown Express
at Western and Third.
That's right. I can see them
at the counter
and they're ordering.
These men are wanted
for the triple murder in
Granada Hills last night.
What's your name, sir?
Louis Bloom.
Do you have
a description of the men?
Uh, yes, I do.
They're both
Latin American men.
Uh, probably what
you would call Hispanic.
Uh, one is big,
very much on the heavy side.
And the other's
face is scratched.
He has scratches on his face.
How old are the men?
Uh, thirty.
Perhaps, maybe, 35.
What are they wearing?
The big man is
wearing light pants
and a striped sweater,
and the man with scratches
is wearing brown pants
and a vest.
He looks like he has a gun.
You said the suspect is armed?
I believe so, yes.
I'm sorry, I have to go.
Otherwise,
they might see me.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON SCANNER)
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
All west units,
possible 187.
Suspects there now.
Western and Third.
Western and Third
at Chinatown Express.
Suspects are two male Hispanics.
Number one, large build.
Number two with
scratches on his face,
inside the location.
Possibly armed.
Code Three,
incident 357 and 9753.
There's fucking people in there.
I count six.
So, they could start shooting.
They could.
So you said we were waiting for
(STAMMERS)
a better neighborhood
with more people,
not a fucking restaurant.
We work with what we're given.
OFFICER: (ON RADIO)
Unit 14, responding to
that Code Three.
You're going to
go down the street,
get an angle inside
from over there.
Steady hands.
Use the zoom.
No fast pans.
I'll be filming from here.
Fuck that. I'm not
getting out of the car!
I need a second angle
from down the street.
We'll cut it together.
Two angles.
Believe me,
it's more dangerous
here in the car.
I don't believe
anything you say.
Man, this is fucked!
Do you know I've
never once sworn
in front of an employer?
I am not doing it!
I'm not getting
out of the car.
You're making a mistake.
I don't care about
the fucking job title.
What if my problem
wasn't that I don't
understand people,
but that I don't like them?
What if I was
obliged to hurt you
for something like this?
I mean, physically.
I think you'd have
to believe afterwards,
if you could,
that agreeing to participate
and then backing out
at the critical moment
was a mistake.
Because that's what
I'm telling you.
As clearly as I can.
(SCOFFS)
(SEAT BELT CLICKS)
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(NERVOUS BREATHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER
ON SCANNER)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
OFFICER 1: (ON RADIO)
7-A-14. We're Code Six
to location.
OFFICER 2: (ON RADIO)
7-A-21. Show us backing
7-A-14.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Oh, God.
OFFICER 2: (ON RADIO)
7-A-21. We're Code Six
with 7-A-14.
RICK: Oh, God.
Oh, God.
OFFICER: Gun!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Oh, God! Oh, fuck!
OFFICER: We have a gun!
Two of them!
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
OFFICER 2: Call it in!
OFFICER: (ON RADIO)
Shots fired. Shots fired.
Officer down.
Officer needs help.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(PANTING)
OFFICER 1: One's down!
In pursuit!
Go, go, go!
(WOMAN SOBBING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Oh, my God!
(SIREN WAILING)
OFFICER 1: (ON RADIO)
Suspect leaving
in a black Escalade
and out of the location,
heading north.
Fuck! (GASPS)
Did you get it?
There's people dead in there!
OFFICER 2: (ON RADIO)
7-A-27. I'm behind vehicle,
we are in pursuit.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
(ON RADIO)
7-A-27, roger.
All units
at all frequencies,
stand by.
Aim the camera at the car
and start filming.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
7-A-27 in pursuit,
northbound through
the alley of 187.
Suspect vehicle is
a black Escalade.
Rick. Start filming!
Oh!
OFFICER 2: (ON RADIO)
7-A-27. We just turned
northbound on Western.
Stay on the police car.
You're right up his ass.
LOU: Wide angle.
We want all of this.
OFFICER 2:
Requesting backup
and an air unit.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Any air unit, come in
on Wilshire frequency.
Lou, Lou, Lou!
I got it.
(RICK YELLS)
OFFICER 1:  Northbound.
70 miles an hour.
Approaching a fresh red.
Steady hands, Rick.
It's a red light!
Red light!
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
...approaching
a red light.
RICK: Oh, shit!
OFFICER 1:  Six,
North, Charles, Queen,
5-3-2. Black Escalade.
(STAMMERS) Fuck!
Give me an ETA
on an air ship.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
Air A team responding
with a light for mission.
Stand by.
(SIREN WAILING)
OFFICER 1:
Heading northbound Western,
south of suspect.
Approaching another fresh red.
Suspect is turning...
Oh, shit!
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
7-A-27, come in.
Oh, my...
Did you see that?
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
No acknowledgment
from 7-A-27.
RICK: Lou, look out,
look out!
OFFICER 2: (ON RADIO)
7-L-0-7. I'm now primary.
Suspect is behind me.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
7-L-7 is now primary.
Lou, Lou, please.
We're way too close.
This guy's crazy.
Fucking shit!
OFFICER 2:
He's ramming my vehicle!
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
All units.
Officer needs help.
Northbound Western.
Suspect now ramming
a police vehicle.
No matter what,
keep shooting.
OFFICER 2:
Continuing northbound.
RICK: (WHIMPERS) Fuck!
(GASPS)
RICK: Oh, shit! Shit!
Oh, my God!
(TIRES SQUEALING)
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
7-L-7, come in.
LOU: Turn off the car.
(SCANNER CUTS OFF)
He's dead.
Get this shot.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
Steady hands.
Use your zoom.
(GUNSHOTS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(GRUNTS)
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
(PANTING)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
OFFICER:
Hold it right there!
Put the gun down!
(GUNSHOTS)
(GROANS)
(RICK GASPING)
OFFICER 1:
He had a weapon.
That was a just fire.
OFFICER 2:
He's not moving.
(GASPING)
(OFFICERS CONVERSING
INDISTINCTLY)
OFFICER 1:
Let's seal this off.
You saw him.
You saw him! (GASPING)
I can't jeopardize
my company's success
to retain
an untrustworthy employee.
You're crazy.
You're crazy!
You took my
bargaining power, Rick.
You used it against me.
You would have done it again.
Just admit it.
I don't know.
I know.
(SOFTLY) I know.
OFFICER 1: Don't touch that
unless it's for prints.
Make a clean sweep.
OFFICER 2:
Go around the vehicle.
Let them through,
here they come.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Hello, Juliana.
(CHUCKLES)
Hello, Willy.
Hello, Ben.
Hello, Lisa.
LISA: Hi!
Hey. It's Lou, right?
Yes, that's right!
Video News?
That's right.
You got something
good for us tonight?
I think so. I'm about
to show Nina right now.
I can tell by your tie,
it's Friday.
(BEN LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(GUNSHOTS)
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(NINA SIGHS)
(SIGHS)
You can leave.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Wasn't that your partner?
As a matter of fact,
that's him.
Oh, I'm floored.
I mean, it's amazing.
Thank you.
I mean, just amazing.
No, thank you.
Thank you for bringing it to me.
You're welcome.
I want it, obviously.
How much do you want it?
You tell me.
Get this to graphics.
FRONTIERI:
Who's in charge here?
Who are you?
LAPD. Major case.
Pull the footage
from these screens.
Round it up.
Let's go. All copies.
Excuse me.
I'm the news director.
Can I help you?
FRONTIERI:
You can help yourself
by collecting up
every copy of the shootout
the chase, the crash,
all of it. Now.
It's KWLA property.
It's evidence.
Of what?
I got a cop near death
in the hospital,
three dead, four wounded,
and a dozen major crimes
stretching a mile of Third.
This tape is evidence.
It's news footage
bought and paid for
from an independent contractor.
And how do you think he got it?
NINA: If there's an issue,
speak to him.
FRONTIERI: Don't get in
the way of this.
Unless you have a judge's order,
we're going with it
in four minutes.
Hey.
Isn't that him?
(STUDIO BELL RINGING)
A.D.: Camera One,
stay centered up.
Camera Two,
we'll do a zoom out
when we come out.
Joel has got
a source on the taskforce
who says they found drugs
at the Granada Hills house.
Cocaine in wrapped packages
hidden in crawlspaces.
Over 50 pounds.
He confirmed it
with an investigator
at the scene.
It wasn't a home invasion.
It was a drug robbery.
Give it to the noon crew.
This is news.
It detracts from the story.
It is the story.
The story is urban crime
creeping into the suburbs.
That's the story.
Jesus, you sound like Lou.
A.D.: Ten seconds to back.
I think Lou is
inspiring all of us
to reach a little higher.
A.D.: Five, four, three,
two, one. Sting it.
(NEWS THEME PLAYING)
A.D.: Mics. Dissolve.
(DOOR CLOSES)
You understand that
you've been
read your rights,
and you're here voluntarily?
That's right. Yes.
And this is being
recorded and filmed?
Yes, from the camera up there.
Wide angle.
Mmm-hmm.
Would you tell me
how it is you were
at the Chinatown Express tonight
and called the 911?
Of course.
It began earlier in the day.
I was watering my plant.
I looked out my window
at my apartment.
The one you visited.
I saw a dark-colored vehicle
with two men inside
parked across the street.
I didn't think anything of it,
otherwise I would have
reported it then.
We began our night,
my employee and myself.
And around
approximately 12:38,
I looked in my rearview mirror
and I saw what looked
like the same men
in the same vehicle
following us.
I made an evasive maneuver.
I circled back
and tailed them
to the restaurant.
At which point,
I saw them go inside
and recognized them
as the same men
from the home invasion.
You told me
you didn't see the men.
That you didn't get
a good look at them.
Well, it all came back to me
when I saw them going in.
Their shapes
and their movements.
And then I saw
that one of the men
had a gun under his shirt,
so I immediately
got my phone
and dialed 911.
That's your story?
That's what happened.
That's why
I'm sitting here with you.
I think that
the men saw my footage
and they tracked me down.
You want to know
what I think?
Yes, please.
I think you withheld
information.
I think you saw the two men
in the murder house
in Granada Hills
and you saw the car
and you sat on it
to get something you could film.
What do you think about that?
I think that would be
a very unprofessional thing
for me to do in my business.
It would be murder.
I can understand why
you're looking into it,
but I didn't do
anything like that.
Nothing that could
be considered wrong.
You don't fool me for a minute.
I'm glad.
I think everything
you said is a lie.
I wish my partner was here
to back up what happened.
You left your dead partner.
No, the ambulances arrived.
They're trained professionals.
Yeah, and you seem
real broken up
about that.
No, um...
He died doing what he loved.
You filmed him dying.
Yeah. That's what I do.
It's my job.
I like to say that
if you're seeing me,
you're having
the worst day
of your life.
FEMALE DISPATCHER:
(ON RADIO)
Any Rampart unit,
ambulance to 11 Rampart
on Second Avenue.
Victim, female, white.
Unknown property taken.
LOU:  Congratulations.
Congratulations.
Your selection by
Video Production News
is evidence of the hiring
committee's recognition
of your employment history
and unique
personal qualities.
It is my hope that
through hard work
and commitment,
you will move through
the intern program
and continue to
pursue your career goals
as full-time employees
of Video Production News.
I can tell you from experience
that the surest way
up the ladder
is to listen carefully
and follow my orders.
You may be confused at times,
and other times, unsure.
But remember,
I will never ask you
to do anything
that I wouldn't do myself.
(DISTANT SIREN WAILING)
(HELICOPTER HOVERING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER
CONTINUES)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)