[Show Theme Plays]
And now from New York...
with Jerry's guests--
Tony Randall...
Richard Dreyfuss,
Rodney Dangerfield...
Dr.Joyce Brothers,
Lou Brown and the orchestra...
and little ol' me--
Ed Herlihy.
And now say hello toJerry!
[Band Plays Jazzy Theme]
[Audience Applauds]
- Whoo.!
[Cheering And Whistling]
[Laughter, More Applause]
Whoo.!
[Applause Tapers Off]
Thank you. Good evening to you.
You look like a great audience.
Louie, how are you?
Lou Brown, ladies and gentlemen...
and the marvelous
Langford orchestra.
Group. Group.
Um...and, Ed,
how are you tonight?
- Very well.
- Wonderful. Sorry I woke you.
[Laughter]
I shall adhere
to your request, sir.
O.K. You wantJerry's autograph,
give me the books!
Have him write
something personal!
Give me the books!
O.K., O.K.!
Have him write
something personal.
Half an hour!
Half an hour! Goodbye!
- Come on!
- Ohhh!
It'll bejust on a card.
That's all I'm giving you.
I just don't feel like
wasting my time going
in by myself to get it.
- Hiya, Rupert.
- Hello, Rupert.
- Hey, Rupert, who'd you get?
- Nobody.
I got Rodney Dangerfield,
Richard Harris.
I'll trade them for Barbra.
Alan Alda, Robin Williams.
I'll give you anyone you want.
Sydney, I'm really
not that interested.
It's not my whole life.
What's that mean?
That's my whole life,
me and Sydney's?
That's not my whole life.
It's yours, but not mine.
[Cheering And Shouting]
Jerry!Jerry!
[Pounding On Car]
Jerry! [Shouting Indistinctly]
I love you!
Don't--
Don't go,Jerry!
No! No!Jerry!
Jerry!
Would you stop shoving?
-Jerry!
- Would you stop pushing?
I'm not going to take--
Jerry! No! No!
[Soft Jazz Music Plays]
I'm gonna love you
Like no one's loved you
Come rain or come shine
High as a mountain
Deep as a river
Come rain or come shine
I guess when you met me
Ohh ohh
It was just one of those things
Ohh ohh ohh
Ohh
But don't ever bet me
'Cause I'm gonna be true
Well, if you let me
You gonna love me
Ohh ohh
Like nobody's loved me
Come rain or come shine
Ohh
Happy together
Ohh ohh
Unhappy together
Wouldn't it be fine?
Days may be cloudy or sunny
We're in or we're out of the money
Yeah
I'm with you always
I'm with you
Rain
Or shine
Yeah
Rain
Or
Shine
Jerry!Jerry!
Please.
Aah! Wait!
O.K.! Stand back!
Stand back! Please...
let Mr. Langford get some air!
Just stand back!
Come on,Jerry!
Did you get my message?
All right, now--
Jerry!Jerry! Aah!
Hey,Jerry.
-Jerry!
- [Woman] Aah! Aah!
Come on, people!
Jerry, I'm sorry.
I don't mean to disturb you.
- I just want a minute
to ask your advice.
- Not now.
If we could just drive away--
You could drop me
off anywhere.
We could talk
while we're driving.
I don't do this.
I don't mean to be rude...
but I did put myself
on the line for you.
Drive, Harvey.
-Jerry!Jerry!
- [Horn Honks]
-Jerry!Jerry!Jerry!
I love you,Jerry!
I love you!
Here.
Thanks.
- Is that your initials?
- Yeah.
I just want to tell you.
My name's Rupert Pupkin.
I know the name
means nothing to you...
but it means an awful
lot to me, and...
- believe--
- Calm down. Take your time.
I'm a little nervous.
You might've wondered who I am.
I've been outside your show
many, many times.
I'm in communications
right now...
but the point
I'm trying to make is...
by nature,
I'm a comedian, you know?
I know what you're going to say.
""Oh, not another one.''
But believe me,
I'm very good. I'm dynamite.
I wouldn't take
one minute of your time...
if I wasn't absolutely convinced
that I'm dynamite.
You're wondering,
""If he's so good...
why hasn't he caught
my act somewhere?'' Right?
Good question.
I'll tell you why. You know why?
Up to now,
I've been biding my time
slowly and carefully...
so that when my big break
finally came...
like the nightJack Parr got sick?
Your big break?
That night convinced me
that I wanted to be a comedian.
I walked out of that show
like I was in a dream.
After that,
I started catching...
all your guest appearances
on Sullivan.
I studied everything
you ever did--
the way you built to your
one-liners, nice and relaxed...
how you deliver jokes without
leaning too much on them...
how you didn't say, ""Hey, folks,
here's the punch line.''
You know,Jerry?
You know what I'm talking about?
You don't say,
""Folks, here's the punch line.''
You just do the punch line.
Exactly. That's what
I loved about what you did.
What I'm trying to say is,
now I'm ready.
I'm ready, and--
I finished the course.
And I'm thinking
as I'm sitting here now...
""Maybe this is my big break,
my big chance.''
Know what I mean?
What do you think?
[Chuckles]
- Look, what's your name?
- My name's Rupert Pupkin.
All right.
Look, pal, got to tell you,
this is a crazy business...
but it's not unlike any other business.
There are ground rules.
Yeah.
And you don't just walk
onto a network show
without experience.
Now, I know it's
an old hackneyed expression...
but it's the truth--
you've got to start at the bottom.
- I'm at the bottom.
- That's a perfect place to start.
I know, but I'm not--
there's got to be--
It looks so simple
to the viewer at home--
those things that come
so easily that are so relaxed...
and look like it's a matter
of just taking another breath.
It takes years
and years and years...
of honing that and working it.
I don't mean to interrupt you...
but there's a little problem.
I'm 34 years old.
That's why I'm asking
you to just listen--
To listen to my act and tell me
what you think about it.
Why don't you
call my office--
All right, O.K. I could?
You ask for Cathy Long.
She's my secretary.
And we'll make time to listen
to what you're talking about.
You don't know
how many times...
I've had this conversation
in my head. This is beautiful.
- Did it always end this way?
- Yeah, it did.
I really believe this.
Once you get over
the initial shyness, you'll be O.K.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Hope it works
out for you, Rupert.
Thanks,Jerry.
Thanks a lot.
It's a pleasure
meeting you,Jerry.
Jerry. I'm a little short on cash...
but if you don't
mind just appetizers...
I'd love to take you
to dinner sometime.
I don't know my schedule.
Maybe we can.
O.K. Thanks,Jerry.
Thanks.
Jerry. Let me show you
a picture of my pride and joy.
That's good.
- Good, huh?
- Yeah, it is.
Hey,Jerry, take it.
Take it.
Go ahead, take it.
Consider it a gift.
It'll work for you.
I will.
Not that you
need the help.Jerry!
Seriously.
You ever want lunch--my treat.
Call my office.
O.K., O.K., O.K.
O.K.Jerry,you're a prince.!
Hey, Rupe,
before I forget...
I really appreciate you
meeting me for lunch.
I know how busy you are
and how tired you are.
What are friends for,Jerry?
Talking about schedule,
you're the one who looks tired.
Yeah, I know.
It's the show.
The pressure, the ratings.
The same guests,
the same questions.
I'm just not
enjoying it anymore.
That's...the worst.
Listen, I...I really wish you
would think about it again.
Wait a minute.
You--you're starting again.
You're starting up again.
It's not that big a deal to think.
I'm asking you to think.
I'm thinking.
All I do is think day and night.
How can I not think about it?
We're here at lunch together...
which I knew is why
you invited me...
and I'm here eating
to get guilty with you, right?
I'm asking you to take
over the show for six weeks.
What's six weeks?
I'll give you anything,
but don't ask me to do six weeks.
I can't take over
the show for six weeks.
I can't even take over
my own life for six weeks.
You're asking for something
that's impossible! It's impossible!
- [Woman] Rupert.!
- Don't you understand--
What?
What are you doing
down there so late?
It's impossible!
I'm trying to tell you that.
What, you want me to cry?
There must be a way to work it out.
It's just six weeks.
Ex$cuse me. Um, Mr. Pupkin?
You think you could--
Yeah. Sure.
What's your name, dear?
- Dolores.
- Dolores? That was my father's name.
""To Dolores...
who sensed greatness.''
There you go, sweetheart.
- Thanks, Mr. Pupkin.
- Don't mention it.
[Woman] Rupert.!
Rupert, who you talking to?
- Mom!
- What is it?
Please stop calling me!
It's terrific.
It's great.
There's only one problem, though.
He made--he made
you bigger.
Would you answer me?
All right!
You've got the six weeks!
Don't bother me!
I'll give you the six weeks!
What can I say?
You happy now?
You're a tough man, Rupe.
You got to be in this business.
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
[Telephone Rings]
[Ring]
Hello.
Hello. It's Masha,Jerry.
- Who?
- Did you get my note?
Who's this?
Masha.
Didn't you get the note?
I left it on the back seat...
before they dragged me
out of the car.
You know, those guys
really hurt me,Jerry.
How did you get this number?
Don't be angry with me,Jerry.
I don't know what else to do.
I've been calling your--
How've you been, Rita?
- Do I know you?
- I think you might.
Rupert.
- Rupert Pupkin, right?
- Right.
I brought you a little present.
Oh, yeah. I remember.
- Mr. Romance.
- Heh.
Put an aspirin in that.
It'll last longer.
So what are you
up to these days?
You're looking
as beautiful as ever, Rita.
Well, here I am.
Local cheerleader makes good.
You know...
it's funny, but I...I, uh...
- I voted for you ""most beautiful.''
- Did you? That's sweet.
I didn't have the nerve
to tell you then, but--
Yeah, now you can tell me.
It's O.K. We're both adults.
Isn't that funny?
You know, when you're younger...
you're afraid to say those things,
but when you get older...
you can say those things
that you should've said
1 5, 20 years ago.
Isn't that the final irony of life?
Isn't it?
I guess.
Are you happy
in this place, Rita?
- Why? You got something better?
- Maybe.
Oh, really? Like what?
Well...what are you
doing tonight?
What am I doing tonight?
- Ha ha!
- Yeah. What's so funny?
Isn't it just a little late asking me
for a date after 1 5 years?
Ha ha ha ha!
Really? Ha ha! Well...
Waiter?
Can I have a fresh one?
- Rita.
- Hmm?
Who is your favorite
movie star?
What is this,
some kind of a game?
You going to tell me
something about my character...
- my future?
- You'll see. Tell me.
Everybody has
a favorite movie star.
I better think of somebody,
or we'll never get out of here, right?
That's a little test.
Oh, let's see.
Marilyn Monroe.
Perfect.
""Talent Register,'' huh?
That's her name.
She signed this in New York...
during her publicity tour
for The Misfits.
- That was her last movie, you know.
- Yeah.
She wasn't a great actress...
but she did have
a real gift for comedy.
You know,
she died tragically alone...
like many of the world's
most beautiful women.
I don't want to see
that happening to you.
- Who's this?
- Burt Reynolds.
- This?
- Mel Brooks. He's what
you call ""on funny.''
Others are just regular.
Oh, that's Sid Caesar.
He's remarkable.
I really like him.
He's great.
Woody Allen. Nice guy.
Personal friend of mine.
Of course he is.
Ha ha! No, he is.
Oh, that's Ernie Kovacs.
He was wonderful.
He was a...great comedian,
great innovator.
That was a great, great loss.
I bet some of these
are worth money.
Oh, yeah.
Especially this one.Just hold it.
- Who's this?
- Well,just take a guess.
- Huh. Looks like ""retard.''
- Ha ha!
The more scribbled the name,
the bigger the fame.
That might be true,
Rupert, but who is it?
""R'' is the first letter.
Come on, Rupert,
who is it? I'm tired.
I'll give you a little hint.
- Oooo--
- Robert Redford.
Ha ha. No.
Ha ha ha ha.
No, no.
That's ""Rupert Pupkin.''
Rupert Pupkin.
I surprised you, didn't I?
Take this as a gift.
Take good care of that.
Soon everyone's going to want one.
Rupert, you have not changed.
Just a couple of hours ago,
you know who I was talking to?
- Guess!
- Your shrink?
Ha ha!
That's very funny.
No.Jerry Langford.
That's right. TheJerry Langford.
He gave me the go-ahead, Rita.
Would you believe it?
And you know what?
Don't tell anyone yet...
but you're looking
at the new king of comedy.
- Ha ha ha ha.
- Why not me?
Why not? A guy can get
anything he wants...
as long as he pays the price.
What's so funny about that?
I mean, crazier things have happened.
You don't understand
what a shot on Langford means.
That's coast-to-coast national TV,
a bigger audience...
than the greatest comedians
used to play to in a whole lifetime.
A shot at a free ticket
on the comedy circuit.
My own comedy show--
The Rupert Pupkin Show.
Everything!
And all that leads
in one direction, Rita--Hollywood.
A beach house in Malibu
on the ocean.
And we'll keep a suite
at the Sherry.
Everybody stays there
when they make it big.
Up top so we can shout down,
""Hey, tough luck, suckers.
Better luck next time.''
Come on. What do you say?
It sounds wonderful, Rupert.
I wish you the best of luck.
But it's getting late,
and I'm a working girl.
- I got to go home.
- I--I don't get you!
Here I am,
offering you a way out.
Rita. Every king
needs a queen.
I want you to be mine.
This is a nice street.
Nice building.
- Thanks for your jacket, Rupert.
- Oh.
I guess you're entitled to come up
and have some coffee.
I wouldn't want
to impose, really.
- I know I can--
- What do you want?
What?
- What do I want?
Rita, you still don't understand?
I love you. I want to
help change your life...
if you'll just
give me a chance.
What if I set something up
between me, you, and Jerry?
What if we went out
to dinner one night?
You know what's even better?
A summer house for a weekend.
He wouldn't want to meet me.
That's not true.
Jerry is a very nice guy.
He's a very, very nice guy...
and we had
a terrific meeting.
And you shouldn't
sell yourself short.
You have too little faith,
and you're a wonderful person.
Why don't you go to sleep
and get a good night's rest?
O.K.?
O.K.
- Good night.
Go to sleep right away.
[Baby Crying]
I'll tell you, boy.
Hiya, Liza.
Good seeing you.
Jerola. Good seeing you.
Jerry. Don't get up.
Ahh, boy, I'll tell ya...
every time you come back
from a tour...
something must be in the air.
The tour really becomes you.
It's like you
become rejuvenated.
I don't know what it is.
Isn't that so, everybody?
Isn't that so?
Hey, hey, there.
Well, that is amazing.
It's amazing. You look wonderful.
And I know.
You look wonderful, too,Jerry.
I wasn't leaving you out.
Bro? Yeah!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Oh, ha ha ha ha ha!
Oh,Jerry!
I love this guy!
Always coming up
with these great lines.
I love 'em. I love 'em.
You're wonderful.
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
Rupert.! The bus is here.!
It's early.!
Try to be on time for once.!
I can't believe this.
I got to go.
I got to catch a bus.
Jerry.
Take care of yourself.
Baby, be good.
Good luck in Rio.
Good morning, Rupert.
- Good morning.
- How are you?
- This is for you.
- Work.
- What time is it?
- It's 1 0:00.
1 0:00? Could I use the phone
for one second?
Is it local?
Sure.Just dial 9 first.
Make it short.
Hello.Jerry Langford, please.
Rupert Pupkin.
Thank you.
Yes. Uh, is Jerry there, please?
Rupert Pupkin. Yes.
Just tell him
it's Rupert calling.
He'll know what it's about.
Oh. Oh, he is?
Well, that's O.K.
I'm in a meeting myself.
Um,just tell him I called, O.K.?
Thank you very much.
And I'll call later.
Thanks. Bye.
Is that the Jerry Langford?
I'll see you, Roberta.
Yeah. Bye.
Hello.Jerry Langford, please.
Rupert Pupkin.
Yes. Rupert Pupkin calling
Jerry Langford, please.
Which? The first name
or the second name?
P-u-p-k-i-n.
It's often mispronounced
and misspelled...
so that's why--yes.
Yes,Jerry knows I'm calling.
He knows what it's about.
Oh, sure. Sure.
I see. I see.
I see.
Yes,you can call me.
I'll be here for
the next hour and a half.
I'm at my office,
and the number is J L5-43 21 .
Yo. Come on, man.
If you don't mind...
I am waiting
for a phone call.
It will only take a few minutes.
All of these phones don't work.
I am not making a phone call.
I am ex$pecting a phone call.
I'll show you how
to make a phone call.
Wait. Let me just slide
in here and make a call.
Let me just make a call!
Uh, it's important.
This phone don't work either.
Don't do that!
[Siren]
Hold on a second.
Yes, sir?
Yes.Jerry Langford, please.
Your name, please?
Pupkin. Rupert Pupkin.
Rupert?
Pupkin. P-u-p-k-i-n.
People often misspell it
and mispronounce it.
There's a man here by the name
of Rupert Pumpkin.
He wants to see
Mr. Langford.
I'm sorry, Mr. Pumpkin...
but Mr. Langford's secretary has
no record of your appointment.
Pardon me?
We have no record
of your appointment.
I don't have an official
appointment with Jerry...
but he did ask me
to call him personally.
I was in the neighborhood.
I thought I'd just stop up.
I had trouble calling
for some reason.
The lines seemed to be busy.
He has no appointment.
Mr. Langford's secretary
wants to know...
what this is in reference to.
Mr. Gangetti, go right in.
Hello? Yes.Jerry and I...
discussed my being
on the show last night.
He told me to call. Yes.
Oh, sure. Sure.
- [Wham]
- I'm supposed to wait.
Is that cork?
I don't know what it is.
Is it dripping on you?
No. I was looking
at the patterns.
You know,
cork is good for sound.
- It's very quiet in here.
- [Telephone Rings]
Reception.
No. You've got an hour
before they come in.
No. He hasn't come back
from the meeting yet.
- Mr. Pipkin?
- Pupkin.
Sorry. I'm Cathy Long.
Can I help you?
- You are?
- I'm Bert Thomas' assistant.
He's our executive producer.
Sorry. I've already spoken
toJerry directly...
about my being on the show.
He said to talk to him
personally.
What is it exactly that you do?
- I--standup comic.
- Where are you working at?
I'm just working
on new material.
As soon as you
start working again...
call, and we'll send someone down
to check out your act.
Thanks for stopping by.
Jerry and I went over
all this last night.
Does Jerry know your work?
Yes. I don't think he does.
You have a tape
I could listen you?
A tape? Oh, naturally.
Whatever you'd like. Sure.
Drop by a tape.
I will. I can see
whyJerry would need that.
Nice meeting you.
Nice meeting you, too.
This is really what's right.
This is great.
This is--
See you again.
Nice talking to you.
Goodbye.
Rupert. Hey, Rupert.!
We've got to talk.
What happened last night?
Did Jerry say anything?
- Nothing happened.
- Did he talk about me?
No. He talked about me.
He must have said
something about me.
Nothing.
What could he say...
after what you did
in the car last night?
You must be really loving this.
Yeah. You were schmucko
supremo last night.
I'm the schmuck? Me?
You're wrong, buddy!
If I hadn't gotten
in that car last night...
you wouldn't
have had the chance...
to talk toJerry.
Keep that in mind.
Not to be cruel,
but we're nearJerry's building.
God forbid he
should see me with you...
becauseJerry and I have a real
relationship, no fantasy world.
After what you did last night...
I don't want
to see you anymore.
Fine! If that's what you want!
Yes. That's what I want.
Just get it to him!
I'm not giving him anything.
No way,Jose.
You're so friendly.
You give it to him.
We're having
a communication problem.
That's what you call it?
You're always bragging about
how you broke bread with Jerry.
Give it to him.
Just do this for me!
I've done things for you!
What have you done for me?
What are you talking about?
How about Howard Johnson's?
I bought you food and coffee
night after night!
You're crazy.
You didn't get me anything.
- I bought my coffee.
- You never bought anything!
I did things for you
that no money can buy.
How about when
I gave you my spot?
I let you get
right next toJerry!
I waited for eight hours.
You were crying because
you wanted next toJerry.
You got next to him!
What about giving
you my last album...
of The Best ofJerry.!
I didn't even
ask you for money...
and I can't even pay my rent!
I live in a hovel.
You live in a townhouse!
O.K., you want to do that?
I got money for you!
I can't believe how long
I've hung out with you...
and listened to your tired,
stale, boring jokes.
- Here's $900. No! No!
- Be quiet.
Take this and give it toJerry!
This is the last time.
When will he get it?
Because you're a wacko.
I'll know if you don't.!
I know where you
and Jerry are.!
I cover the waterfront!
Remember that!
What are you looking at?
Beat it.!
You scum.!
You're street trash.!
First of all, Miss Long...
thank you very much
for your help at the office...
and for passing this
ontoJerry.
I appreciate it
more than you know.
Jerry, before I begin...
thank you for listening
to this material...
and for the opportunity
you've given me.
Lots of people think
that people who've made it...
lose their feeling for
struggling young talent,
such as myself.
Now I know from experience...
that those people
are just cynics...
embittered by their own failure.
I know,Jerry, that you are
as human as the rest of us...
if not more so.
There's no point
in going on about it.
You know how I feel,
so let's get on with the show--
The Best of Rupert Pupkin.
Jerry, I've sketched out
this little outline...
to save you time.
It's a little introduction.
So close your eyes,
imagine it's exactly 6:00.
You're standing in the wings...
and we hear Lou Brown
and the orchestra...
strike up your theme song.
[Theme Song Plays]
And now, from New York...
it's theJerry Langford Show...
with Jerry's guests
Richard Pryor...
Ben Gazzara...
Elizabeth Ashley...
Carol Burnett...
and the comedy find
of the year...
making his television debut...
Rupert Pupkin,
the new king of comedy!
[Woman]
Rupert.! Rupert.!
-Are you crazy?
-Say hello...
What's wrong with you?
- People are sleeping.!
-Aw, Mom.!
Lower it.!
What's the matter with you?
Mom!
Take it easy.
Lower it.
I'm not going to lower it!
I have to do this now!
I don't mind you playing it...
but lower it.!
Now, you come on,Jerry,
and you do your monologue.
Then when the time comes...
this is how
I see you introducing me.
You could say
something like this.
Will you please give
your warmest welcome...
to the newest
king of comedy...
Rupert Pupkin!
[Applause]
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
My name is Rupert Pupkin.
[Laughter]
I was born in Clifton,
New Jersey...
which is north of...
[Loud Laughter]
Is there anyone here from...
But the fact is...
[Laughter Swells]
Mr. Pipkin...
Pupkin. You'll get it
right one of these days.
How are you?
I'll bet you have a tape.
- Right here.
- O.K. Got your name on it?
We'll listen and get
it back to you soon.
Thanks. When Jerry
finds a moment. Good.
When will that be?
Uh...Actually,
you can try me tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
- I might know something by then.
- Otherwise, Monday.
- Monday? Hmm.
What I might do
is just wait here awhile.
MaybeJerry will find a minute.
You're really
just wasting your time.
We won't know anything
till tomorrow at the earliest.
I don't mind.
I'm not wasting my time.
I'm glad to do it.
It's important to me.
- It'll probably be Monday.
- Monday?
Monday.
Well, I'll still wait.
Really, I don't mind.
It's O.K.
Tell you what.
Why don't you try me
tomorrow afternoon for sure?
- Tomorrow?
- Mm-hmm.
- What time?
- 4:30.
4:30. I'll be here.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- And thankJerry. O.K.
- I will.
Goodbye.
At least once in his life,
every man is a genius.
I'll tell you something, Rupe...
it will be more than once
in your life for you...
because you've got it.
From what I've heard here,
yeah, you've got it...
and you're stuck with it.
If you wanted to get rid of it,
you couldn't.
It's always going to be there.
I know there's
no formula for it.
I just don't know
how you do it...
and I'm not curious, mind you...
because I want to use
the material.
I'm curious because
I don't know how you do it.
I really have to ask you that.
How do you do it?
I think it's that
I look at my whole life...
and I see the awful things
in my life...
and turn it
into something funny.
It just happens...
but what about
the first few one-liners?
Were they strong enough?
If they were any stronger,
you'd hurt yourself.
They're marvelous,
you daffy bastard.
Leave them alone.
They're beautiful.
A man said--
Listen to me.
A man said something
very profound some years ago...
which I later originated.
If it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
Want to know how
I know it's so good?
- Yes.
- 'Cause I envy you.
I hate you, but I envy you...
because it's purity, it's marvelous,
it's humor based on you.
No one else
could do it, but you.
I wouldn't lie.
I wouldn't lie to you, Rupe.
This weekend is perfect for you
to come to the house, if you care to.
We'll hash it around...
only 'cause I want to know
how you do it.
There'll be people there,
but we can still work.
It sounds great.
- Terrific.
- I would really like to come.
Could I bring somebody?
Ayoung lady?
A very special young lady.
Of course.
I'd like to meet her.
[Honk Honk]
Hey,Jerry, how you doing?
How are you?
You're looking good.
You should see me
in my white taffeta.
Ha ha ha!
You're doing some
great shows,Jerry.
Thanks a lot.
How about putting me
on your show?
I could have used you
last night.
Ha ha ha!
[Whistling And Applause]
- Hey,Jerry.!
Come on down!
Hi,Jerry, how are you?
Hi, there.
Morris, you will not believe...
who's coming down here.
Jerry Langford, right?
Right.
Oh, Morris, please hold on.
Jerry, please sign
my magazine for me?
- Yeah.
- You're wonderful.
I've watched you
your entire career.
You're a joy to the world.
Please say something to my
nephew Morris on the phone.
He's in the hospital and--
I'm sorry. I'm late.
You should only get cancer!
I hope you get cancer!
Jerry, an autograph?
I can't. I'm late.
I can't believe
that kind of a person!
[Car Horns Honking]
Yes, sir. Oh, hi.
Hi. How are you?
Not bad.
Good. Good. I'm fine.
Can I help you?
Yes. I'd like
to seeJerry, please.
You are...
Pupkin.
Rupert Pupkin.
Mr. Potkin is here.
That's right. O.K.
She'll be with you
in a minute.
Who was that?
Miss Long.
Oh, well...I'd...
prefer to seeJerry.
Miss Long will take care of you.
O.K. I'll wait right here.
And as a surprise...
to Rupert being on the show
with us tonight...
we'd like to present
to you someone...
in a form that we've
never presented before,
a mystery guest.
Please welcome
our mystery guest.
Let's hear it for him.
[Applause]
Jerry,
this is the mystery guest?
This is the mystery guest.
Let's see if I can place him.
I think I know.
Don't you remember me?
No, I don't.
I'm George Cap.
George Cap,
my high school principal.
You guessed it.
You used to fail me
all the time.
What do you have him on for?
He's an enemy.
Because you deserved it.
-[Audience Laughs]
- Oh, thank you.
I'm a justice of the peace now.
- I perform weddings.
- Do you?
[Band Plays Wedding March]
Jerry.
[Audience Applauds Wildly]
Jerry, what are you doing?
I can't believe this.
Believe because
it's part of the surprise.
How would the audience...
like to see
the king of comedy...
marry his queen
right here on the show?
I don't know what to say.!
Thanks a million,Jerry.
That's too much.
[Audience Laughs]
[Plays Wedding March]
Dearly beloved...
when Rupert here
was a student...
at the Clifton high school...
none of us--myself...
his teachers...
his classmates--
dreamt that he would amount
to a hill ofbeans...
but we were wrong...
and you, Rupert,
you were right...
and that's why tonight...
before the entire nation...
we'd like to apologize
to you personally...
and to beg your forgiveness...
for--for all the things
we did to you...
and we'd like to
thank you personally...
all of us...
for the meaning
you've given our lives.
Please accept our warmest wishes,
Rita and Rupert...
for a long and successful
reign together.
We'll be back to marry them
right after this word.
- Mr. Pupkin.
- How are you today?
- I'm fine.
- Good. Good.
I want to thank you
for your tape.
We listened to it
with great interest.
We see a lot of good things...
in what you're doing.
We think you have
a very good potential.
Good.
Which is why
we're being honest.
You should be.
We just don't think
you're ready yet.
Don't think I'm ready?
Now you're not right forJerry.
Right forJerry. Mm-hmm.
Some of the material is good...
but some of the one-liners,
for instance...
are not very strong.
In other words,
you didn't like some of the jokes.
That's right.
I can take care of that.
Tell me the ones you dislike,
and no problem.
That's a great help.
This is great.
You have a good potential.
Your timing was excellent...
but you should keep
developing your act.
Test it
in a few live situations.
That would be very good for you.
There are clubs you can try.
When you start working
in one of those, call.
We'll send someone
to see you. Promise.
Thanks.
- You're welcome. Bye-bye.
- Thank you.
May I ask you a question?
Yes.
Are you speaking forJerry?
Yes, I am.
He has complete faith
in our judgment.
I'm sorry to have
to say this...
and don't take it personally...
but I don't have faith
in your judgment.
I'm sorry that
you feel that way...
but there's nothing
we can do about that.
I'm afraid I'll have to
disagree with you again.
Well, that's your privilege,
Mr. Pupkin.
Would you excuse me?
I have a great
many things to do.
Miss Long,
when willJerry be back?
Mr. Langford won't be in
until very late this afternoon.
We mean what we say...
when we thank you
for coming...
and we mean it when we say...
you can call
when you start working.
All right? Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Ahem.
Is there anyone else
you'd like to see?
No. That's all right.
I don't mind waiting.
Which reminds me about
the man who waited so long...
he forgot what
he was waiting for.
Well, would you mind
waiting outside, Mr. Pupnick?
This is a reception area
and not a waiting room.
I understand.
You asked him to leave?
Yeah, but he won't go.
- What's his name?
- Rupert Pumpkin.
- Hi.
I'm Raymond Wirtz, in charge of security
for the Langford Organization.
Let's go outside and talk.
Is this your bag?
Yes. I'm waiting forJerry.
- We'll discuss that outside.
- I know he's expecting me.
Listen, we'll talk
about that outside.
Please take your bag.
I'll explain company policy
to you on the way, O.K.?
I'm pretty sure
you understand...
that we have
certain rules here...
that are essential to
the smooth functioning
of our operation, right?
Right.
Right. Good.
I can just say--
Just listen, please.
And that without these rules...
we really wouldn't be able
to function at our best.
You follow my point?
I get the point except--
Please, Mr. Puffer, please.
No. After you.
After you, sir, please.
If I could just say thatJerry's--
Just listen.
I checked with Miss Long.
You do not
have an appointment.
Now, company policy is that
only authorized personnel...
and those persons with official
business with our organization...
are permitted on our premises.
In other words, you want me
to leave the building?
Well, did you get it to him?
What?
Did you get my letter to him?
He's not in there, O.K.?
Now that you're in with him,
you can't do me a favor?
Don't bother.
Just give me the letter.
- He wasn't there.
- I saw him go in.
- Who?
-Jerry.
He's up there.
Want to see him?
That's impossible, because
they assured me that he was out.
And you believed them?
You're so naive.
I would expect that from you.
You're so inexperienced.
You're such a chump.
He went up there just now?
Of course. Go back up.
Assert yourself a little bit.
He's up there right now.
Would you tellJerry
I'm here to see him, please?
I'm sorry. He's not in.
I happen to know that he is.
O.K., you're putting your job
on the line, lady.
Security...
You, too.
[Telephone Rings]
Mr. Pupkin,
what are you doing here?
Mr. Pupkin.
Shelly, get security
on the telephone.
There he goes.
Aah! Hold on, right.
Grab his other arm.
Hold on to him, right.
All right.
Right out the door.
Come on.
You wouldn't listen, eh?
Jerry,Jerry!
Nobody's going to help you.
You're going to have a lot
of explaining to do, Mr. Wirtz.
You had your warning, Krupkin.
My lawyer will be calling you.
Make sure
he gets my name right.
Say goodbye to our guest,
Miss Long.
Wait tillJerry hears about this.
Don't worry. I will mention
your name toJerry.
Now listen good, because
if we see your face again...
I--I understand.
We're going to call the police.
Thank you.
Thank you very much. Ha ha.
- Terrific.
- Thank you.
I suppose you got
the letter to him.
No. I'll get it later.
When?
You just got thrown out.
I didn't get thrown out
of the building.
Excuse me. I wasn't getting
thrown out of the building.
You're a constant embarrassment.
They walked me outside.
Just a moment.
You can't handle
the simplest thing.
I'll tell you something else.
I'm going toJerry's for the weekend.
He invited me.
That's how much you know.
Do I look O.K.?
You look wonderful.
Does this look all right?
That, I'm not sure about...
but you look wonderful.
What do you mean?
What's wrong with it?
I don't think you need it.
That's all.
You don't think it looks nice?
No. It looks wonderful.
Hello.
Hello. You must beJonno.
Yes.
My name is Rupert Pupkin.
This is Rita Keene.
LetJerry know
that we're here.
Mr. Langford ask you to come?
Oh, no. We just thought we'd
drop in uninvited for the weekend.
Oh, what a view.
The blue bag is mine.
But Mr. Langford's not here.
Where is he?
Out playing golf?
Yes.
I hope he's finally
going to break 1 00.
1 00?
Perhaps better you come back.
We'll just wait.
But Mr. Langford's not here.
No. That's O.K.
We'll just wait.
It's O.K.
We don't mind waiting.
Is this lovely?
The table's only set for one.
How you like it?
I could live here.
Mr. Langford,
I'm sorry to disturb you, sir.
Uh, what's wrong?
Everything's wrong.
There a couple over here.
His name is,
uh, uh, Pumpkin.
Pumpkin, yes.
Do you know a name Pumpkin?
So, didn't you tell him
what time we'd be getting here?
We didn't have time
to iron out the details.
Yeah, but that butler
wasn't even expecting us.
Jerry has more important
things to think about...
than what he's going to
tell his houseboy.
Oh, really?
Well, excuse me.
He knows everything.
He knows you're playing golf
and everything.
He want to spend
a weekend over here.
Yes, and you better come back.
He's, uh,
he's touching everything.
He's ruining the house.
Hey, I'm getting
a heart attack already.
Here's a famous one...
with the youngest clown
in the world--Zippo.
Remember this one with
Ray Charles on Jerry's special?
- That's famous.
- I know.
Here's a famous one when
he was a kid, 1 2 years old.
Someone sent this in.
It was part of the show--
""I knew you when'' section.
Someone sent that in as a joke.
Jerry shows it
to everyone on the show.
If I should take a notion...
Let's get a little life
in this place.
It's like a funeral parlor.
Rita, you should
really turn that off.
You shouldn't put that on now.
It's not polite.
How about a spin, handsome?
I can't really dance
in the house.
A little fun
never hurt anybody.
What ifJerry walks in?
He'll be happy to see us
having a good time.
You're his friend.
He won't mind.
Ain't nobody's business
if I do
Oh, one day...
Wonder what the rest
of this place is like.
Well, I'm sure it's very nice.
Oh, that--no, Rita.
I wouldn't go up there.
Rita, Rita, Rita,
I don't think it's a good idea.
Rita.
They're watching us.
You don't have the right
to go upstairs.
Rita, please don't go.
[Doorbell Chimes]
You going to open
the goddamn door?
Mr. Langford.
Standing out there eight minutes.
What was with the door?
Jesus.
Where are they?
I was going to call the police.
Hi,Jerry. Hi,Jerry.
How are you?
We were just
freshening up upstairs.
Rita, I want you to meet
the Jerry Langford.
Jerry, I want you
to meet the Rita Keene.
Come on down.
That a girl.
What's your pleasure,Jerry?
It's kind of hot out there.
I want something nice to drink.
Jerry, what would you like?
Jerry.
Excuse us for taking the liberty,
but it's not every day...
that a girl like Rita
meets a man like you.
This is part of your success.
What can you do?
How was your golf game?
Did you finally break 1 00?
[Jonno] I told them
you were not here.
[Rita] That's right. He did.
They did,Jerry.
They were very helpful.
We took an earlier train
because there wasn't
anything until after 1 :00.
Anyway, I brought the work.
It's right here...
all ready and set to go.
So...
where is everybody?
What everybody?
The guests,Jer.
To tell you the truth,
we're getting a little hungry.
You know I could
have you arrested?
Ha ha ha.
He could have us arrested.
Of course. There's no way that
we can prove that we belong here.
When he comes up with an idea,
he's terrific.
Really?
I never thought of that.
You should have.
We could set up a story...
where you invite your friends
out for the weekend...
and you throw them all in jail.
Ha ha ha.
That's terrific.
What's the matter?
Lighten up.
Let's work on that
after we work on this.
How did you get here?
Walked in the door.
What do you mean?
What's the matter with you?
How did you get here?
I think you're upset.
I'm going to leave
my material here.
We'll talk later.
You've got more important
things to worry about.
We'll take a stroll
until lunchtime.
Did anyone ever tell you
you're a moron?
You know,Jerry,
I want to tell you something.
Ordinarily,
I wouldn't allow anyone...
to speak that way about Rita...
but since it's you,
I know you're only kidding.
He's a real character.
Rupert.
He's saying he wants us to go.
No. He's not saying that.
Jerry, tell her
you're not saying that.
He's not saying that at all.
Call the station,Jonno.
Where you going, Rita?
There'll be a cab here
in 1 0 minutes.
I'd appreciate if you'd use it.
Why? You going someplace?
You are.
Did I say something wrong?
'Cause if I did...
could we chalk it up
to inexperience.
Rita?
I have my stuff right here.
We could do it
in a half an hour at the most.
You'd have the afternoon
to yourself.
I want you out of here.
I want you out of here now.
Is that plain enough?
- I understand.
- Is that clear?
Yeah, yeah,Jerry,
I understand.
Look, you're tired.
That's O.K.
I'm going to leave the stuff here.
Let me know what you think.
Rupert, don't be so dopey.
The man is telling us to go.
He's not.
Will you stop that?
Mr. Langford,
I want you to know...
Tell her she's wrong.
I don't even know this guy.
He told me you were friends.
- Rita, Rita!
- I feel terrible about this.
I'm so humiliated.
If there's anything I can do
to make this up to you...
Don't listen to her.
She wants to spoil everything.
Come on, Rupert.
Let's go.
Jerry--
O.K., come on. Come on.
Come on. Let's go.
Sorry, Mr. Langford.
Do you understand English?
Take your things and go!
I just want you
to listen to my stuff.
Is that asking too much?
Yes, it is.
I have a life, O.K.?
I have a life, too.
That's not my responsibility.
It is when you tell me
to call you...
I told you to call
to get rid of you!
- To get rid of me?
- That's right.
I can take a hint.
If I didn't tell you that...
we'd still be
at my apartment!
So I made a mistake!
So did Hitler!
All right. This is the way it is
when you're famous.
Do you understand now?
That's how you guys are?
No, not them. Me, yeah.
That's how you are
when you reach the top?
I was that way before.
Now I know how
people like you are.
Goodbye and good luck.
And Jerry,Jerry...
I just want to say
one more thing,Jerry.
I'm glad what you did
to me today...
because now I know
I can't rely on anybody.
Not you, not anybody...
and I shouldn't
rely on anybody.
Right.
I'm going to work
50 times harder...
and I'm going to be
50 times more famous than you.
Then you'll have idiots like you
plaguing your life!
That's right. Yes.
Come on, Rita.
We're wasting our time.
[Door Slams]
Jonno, lock that door.
You did good, Mr. Langford.
Thank you.
It looks real.
That's the whole point.
[Whistle Blows]
Is that him?
No.
You sure?
Sure, I'm sure.
- It looks too much like him.
- What?
When it's him,
it doesn't look like him.
[Car Horn Honks]
God, it feels like
it's taking him forever.
How much longer?
It's him.
Yeah. That's him.
- Don't go too fast.
- O.K., O.K.
Stay on this side
so you're not all over him.
I'm getting over soon.
Get in the nex$t lane...
when we cross
at the light here.
O.K., O.K., O.K.
There are too many people.
I know. I know.
Keep going.
He walks in the most
crowded areas.
Well, because he doesn't
want to be alone.
Why? Tell me. Tell me why.
I know. You tell me why.
Don't get an attitude
with me right now.
Explain it to me, 'cause
you know so much about him.
Fill me in.
Let me learn from you.
All right.
When he walks on crowded streets...
he feels safe.
That's why.
Is that what it is?
Thanks for telling me.
When you're losing sight
Lost in your eyes
O.K., go past him and stop.
Hey,Jerry.
Get over here.
Get in there.
I'm not fooling around.
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Get in,Jerry. Get in.
Hi,Jerry.
[Tires Screech]
She's going to hold
the gun on your head.
Don't make any false moves.
I'd hate to have to
do anything drastic.
Now, if everything
works out...
you should be out of here...
by the very latest,
1 2:00, 1 2:30.
Oh, maybe 1 :00.
1 :1 5 the very latest.
What I want you to do
is call your producer.
Call what?
Bert Thomas.
I want you to call him.
I'll give you the phone now.
Get him on the phone...
and I'll tell you
exactly what to say, O.K.?
Now, if you don't do it...
I don't know what to say.
There could be a problem.
Now watch your eyes,Jerry.
I'm going to take these off now.
It's a little
bright in here, O.K.?
O.K.
Are these yours?
Jerry, these are yours?
Yeah.
Do you mind if I have one?
- I don't mind.
- Thank you.
- Masha, do you want one?
- Save it for me.
You want one?
Yeah, I'd love one,
but will you save it?
It's a little inconvenient
at the moment.
Do you want one?
No.
I'll just take one
for later, then.
You know, there's no reason
to get mad about it.
I'm just trying
to ease the tension.
Even though this is
a strange situation...
there are moments
of friendship...
and moments of sharing,
or whatever.
O.K., let's go.
Jerry, I mean business.
Get on the phone.
Let's go.
The fun is over.
Let's go. Come on.
Bert Thomas, please.
Jerry Langford.
What happened?
They hung up.
Call them again.
Why did they hang up?
Probably thought it was a gag.
We get that all the time.
Well, I find that strange...
but it's typical...
'cause that's the way
they treat even you...
'cause I'll let you in
on a little secret.
That's the way
they treated me...
and now look where we are.
Bert Thomas.
Audrey, this is Jerry Langford.
Get Bert Thomas
on the phone quickly.
I'm too busy for fun
and games today. Goodbye.
Did you hear what I said?
This is Jerry Langford.
Get Bert Thomas.
This is serious. Now move it.
Why don't we have
somebody else?
Like what?
It's Mr. Langford.
He says it's urgent.
Tell him I'll call him back.
I'm busy.
It's that Martino kid
the impressionist.
O.K.
Will you do what I tell you?
Do it quick.
I'm sorry, Mr. Thomas.
He absolutely insists
on talking to you.
O.K., I'll take it.
Martino,
you know better than--
Bert, I said this is Jerry.
Jerry Langford,
and I'm in deep trouble.
Now, you'd best pay attention.
Yeah. I am listening.
Would you give me that again?
Now, wait a minute.
Um, I want to
ask you something.
What do we call our
second camera man?
We call our second camera man
Helen Keller.
His favorite color is plaid.
Helen Keller, plaid?
What is that?
When someone imitates me
on the phone...
the only way they know
it's me is by that clue.
And if I didn't know
the name we call him--
Say no more.
I understand.
Now, listen, Bert.
Listen carefully.
""I have a gun...''
""at my head.''
""If a man who identifies himself as...''
""the king...''
The card's upside down.
Sorry.
""Is not allowed to be
the first guest on...''
You got a blank card there.
Hold on, Bert.
I'm reading from cue cards.
"Tonight's show... '
"you'll never see me... '
Go back.
"Alive again. '
It--it's not
grammatically correct...
but I think you have the idea.
It's clear, but let me
break in for a minute.
Don't you do anything silly.
O.K., I'm O.K.
I'm O.K., Bert.
Just get it done.
He wants you to call at 5:00.
I'll give you
the private number...
and they'll do
whatever you want.
O.K., that was very good,Jerry.
Turn around
and see how it looks.
Oh, I love it.
I'm sorry. The sleeves
aren't quite right.
Do you like it on him?
What do you think?
I think it looks pretty good.
To guess on it,
have it turn out like this.
I'm very pleased with it.
The color's great.
I like to see him
a little more casual for a change.
This is a look
I like to see on him.
Not so uptight.
Not so...
I got to get started here.
It's wonderful.
It's very good.
- Be honest with me.
- I'm being honest.
Would you wear it?
I like it. I'm so glad
I went with red.
It looks so good on him.
It looks good,Jerry.
- Come on.
- What?
Take it off and let's go.
Oh, O.K., fine.
You want me to take it off?
Yeah.
Can't he wear it
for a little while?
Will you take it off,
please?
I know he's in a meeting.
This is an emergency,
and I've got to talk to him.
You'll interrupt him or I'll come
busting into that meeting.
No. Forget calling me back.
I'm on my way.
Why didn't you
just listen to the tape?
It wasn't that hard...
a few minutes of your time
to listen to something...
that I worked
on my whole life.
Let's go to my office...
and we'll play
the tape right now.
Do you know what would
happen if I went there?
You know, I'm not stupid.
Nobody's calling you stupid.
You pulled this off.
That makes you smart.
You know,Jerry,
I'm going to tell you something.
Friendship is a two-way street.
Do you know that?
And you couldn't
care less about me.
Am I holding this
till next Shavuot?
You going to make
some decisions?
You going to knock off the talking
for two minutes?
You put the sweater on him.
Yeah. It took one minute.
- You have a long night
ahead of you.
- I have something to say.
You've got enough to say.
- You're driving me nuts.
-Just a minute.
Can you be quiet
for one goddamn minute...
and let me rest
with this gun?
You're driving me crazy!
You haven't shut up
since we've walked in.
This is my house.
This is my domain.
Jerry is my guest,
and you're my guest.
And you're lucky to be here.
You change in my house.
You get to get your head together
for the show tonight.
Give me a little break.
-Shut up.
- Why don't you shut up?
I listened to you
talk about that sweater.
Worrying about the sleeves,
the color.
Did I say anything?
I made it forJerry...
and it looks
fabulous on him.
Whose idea was this anyway?
If it wasn't for me,
you wouldn't even be here.
Why didn't you just listen
to the tape when I asked?
I'm sure you can understand.
Doing the kind of show I'm doing,
it's mind-boggling.
There's so much stuff
that comes down...
you can't keep
your head clear.
And if that's the case,
I'm wrong.
You're right.
If I'm wrong, I apologize.
I'm just a human being...
with all of the foibles
and all of the traps...
the show,
the pressure...
the groupies,
the autograph hounds...
the crew,
the incompetence...
those behind-the-scenes
you think are your friends.
You're not sure if you'll
be there tomorrow...
because of their incompetence.
There are wonderful pressures
that make every day...
a glowing, radiant day in your life.
It's terrific.
O.K., if all of
that means nothing...
if I'm wrong,
in spite of all that...
then I apologize.
I'm sorry.
If you accept my apology...
I think we should shake hands.
We'll forget the whole thing.
I won't press charges.
You could be
in deep trouble...
but I will not
press charges.
That's easy for you to say.
But I mean it.
I'll go to the office...
and tell them all it's a gag.
They'll understand that.
If I tell them, they'll buy it.
Then we'll put the tape on.
Sit down.
I said, ""sit down.''
You heard what he said.
With a gun on him,
he wants to be friends.
What happens
when he walks out the door?
What happens then,Jerry?
You get to his office,
and they jump you.
Is that what happens,Jerry?
Not if I tell them not to.
No one's going to jump you.
If I tell them to,
they do it.
No one's going to jump you.
Now, that's the truth.
Take my word for it.
If you think
I'm not telling you the truth...
then don't respond.
If I'm telling the truth,
let me out of here.
He gives me his word.
And what else?
And what else,Jerry?
There is nothing else,
just my word.
Now, isn't my word
good enough?
I'm sorry,Jerry.
Suppose we tape him,
he doesn't talk...
it gets to be 1 1 :30...
do we put him on
no matter what?
Go ahead and tape him.
It won't hurt anything.
You can always erase it.
We may learn
something from it...
and it'll also buy us time.
But under no circumstances...
will we put this man
on the air.
This lunatic
is threatening Jerry.
You're not putting him
on the air?
Gentlemen,
let's not get excited.
I don't think you understand.
We'll tape at 7:00.
We won't have
to make a decision...
about putting him
on the air till 1 1 :30.
This gives us
four hours to move in.
Hopefully, by that time...
we'll have your
Mr. Langford back safely.
Harry, that's it.
We're suing.
We're going to sue everybody.
Who is this man?
Jerry's lawyer.
That's who he is.
Who am I?
I'm the one who's suing.
I'm the lawyer.
Jay.
Don'tJay me, please.
Jay, who are you
going to sue?
We're suing you personally.
Who else are you're suing?
The FBI.
We have a serious situation.
I want it dealt with rationally.
Unless we start talking politely...
there's going to be
serious consequences.
There's nothing polite
about kidnapping.
It's one of the most
stupid offenses ever created.
Where's the defense
of kidnapping?
How can you say,
""I was crazy,''
""I didn't know
what I was doing,''
- "I did on the spur
of the moment'?
- Who cares? Who cares?
Only an idiot kidnaps...
and decides to do
what you're doing.
Jerry, I'm going to go now.
Pretty soon,
you'll be able to go...
about 1 2:00 as I said.
Have a good time.
I know you will.
Bye.
First of all,
we don't know...
whether we're dealing
with kidnappers or terrorists.
Terrorists?
You might have this man
go on the air...
deliver a coded message...
and very possibly 50 people...
around the country
would lose their lives.
You're out of your mind.
I'm not out of my mind.
That guy will be taped.
We'll listen to what he says.
And unless something horrendous
is on that tape...
we'll put that tape
on the air.
Because all we're dealing
with is 1 0 minutes...
of talk show time
against a man's life.
And I don't see that
as any argument.
Hello. How are you today?
Well, I'm calling--
Mr. King calling collect
long-distance for Mr. Thomas.
Mr. Thomas,
there's a long-distance call.
Let's go.
This is it.
Remember.
Keep him talking.
Uh, hi there.
Who is this?
This is Mr. King.
I'm calling for Mr. King.
Well, you're right on time.
Yes. Of course.
We're always punctual.
We're fine. Thank you.
I want to make it brief--
Could I break in and ask...
could I speak toJerry?
Jerry's not with us now.
We're at a pay phone.
So, don't try
and have the call traced...
which I noticed you did.
It's kind of important,
you know...
so that we know that
he's in your care.
We're bringing along
an article of clothing...
that I know you'll recognize.
It will be satisfactory
to everyone.
It's not as easy as you think...
just to walk in the studio--
No, Bert,
if I could call you--
Well, if I could just say,
there is no problem.
The material is clean material.
Do you know
standards and practices?
No. But that can be discussed.
Now, all I can say is...
don't have any press leaks.
You must keep the audience
there until 1 1 :45 or 1 2:00...
after it has been
aired nationally.
Thank you.
We'll discuss the other things.
Nice talking to you.
One--
Boy, he's shrewd.
He just, uh,
wouldn't buy anything.
I feel completely
impulsive tonight.
Anything could happen.
I have so much to tell you.
I don't know
where to start.
I want to tell you
everything about myself...
everything you don't know.
Do you like these glasses?
Crystal. Beautiful.
I bought them just for you.
There's something about them...
the simplicity of them.
If you don't like them...
if there's a doubt
in your mind...
[Glass Shatters]
You know,
sometimes during the day...
I'll do the simplest things.
I'll be taking a bath
and I say to myself...
""I wonder ifJerry's
taking a bath right now?''
And I just hope...
that you're not drowning
or something.
I get really worried about you...
like something terrible
is going to happen.
I have these daydreams...
like I'm with you
at the golf course...
driving your cart...
just driving around.
Need a putter,Jer,
you know?
Need an iron?
I don't even know
how to play golf.
I played with my parents once...
but, uh, but I love you.
I never told my parents
that I love them.
They never told me
that they loved me either...
which was fine with me.
But I love you.
You want some wine?
No, O.K.
I'm not in the mood to drink
either, though.
I'm in the mood to
be alone with you.
Why don't we just
clear off the table?
I was thinking...
why don't we go upstairs?
But that's so predictable.
Let's just take
everything off the table...
and do it right here.
That would blow your mind.
It would blow my mind.
I've never done
anything like that.
I never even had anybody
over for dinner.
Let alone,
made love on the table.
I want to do that.
I just want to dance.
I want to, like,
put on some Shirelles.
I want to be black.
Wouldn't that be insane?
God,you know
who I wish was tonight?
I wish I was Tina Turner...
just dancing
through the room.
Ooh ooh
Thank you. Thank you.
Please have
your tickets ready.
Good evening, Officer.
My name is Clarence McCabe.
Are these people with you?
Yes. This is my wife.
And these are her parents...
the Saunders
from Cleveland, Ohio.
I'll check your name, sir.
I'm going to be on third.
I'm sorry, sir.
I don't see your name, sir.
You just went pass the N's.
I'll go back again, sir.
Here it is again, sir.
Let me just check.
No. This is impossible.
Did Miss Long call you at all?
No, sir, she didn't.
She didn't tell you
about my book?
Listen, I follow this list.
She told me
to present myself at 5:45.
It's now 5:50.
I've only got 1 0 minutes.
Only authorized personnel
allowed in here.
That's the rules
and regulations.
You never heard
of the book?
The Vanishing Siberian Tiger.
Well, can I call Miss Long?
You cannot call
Miss Long at all, sir.
Can you call Miss Long?
Your name isn't on the list.
I cannot let you in.
That's the rules of the place.
I'm going to try to get her.
Stop him.
Miss Long.
Hold on.
Let go of me.
What is this Clarence McCabe?
That's who I am.
Is that your real name?
Well, technically,
it's my real name.
No, it's a pseudonym,
an alias.
Why did you use
the pseudonym?
I'm an author.
That's my business.
Author of what?
I wrote a book called
The Vanishing Siberian Tiger.
I spent two years in Russia...
two years in China
researching that thing.
Russia? China?
Does that make me
a Communist?
Up in control, we have
one more light to pre-set.
Hello. I'm the king.
What?
The king.
What can I do
for Your Highness?
Really. I'm the king.
Oh, yes, sir.
You're dressing room is backstage.
Your throne is in there also.
Very funny.
Is there someone in charge?
Mr. Ding.
He's a little fellow
with an ice cream cone.
- Miss Long.
- Mr. Pipkin?
No, it's Mr. Pupkin.
How are you?
What are you doing here,
Mr. Pupkin?
I'm the king.
I think you're expecting me.
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Mr. Thomas around?
[Glass Shattering]
[Cat Meowing]
You're going to love me
Like nobody's loved me
Come rain or come shine
Happy together
Unhappy together
And won't it be fine?
Days may be cloudy or sunny
We're in
and we're out of the money
I'm with you always
I'm with you
Rain
Or shine
Mr. King.
I'm Inspector Gerrity
from the FBI.
Do you understand?
What is your name?
Rupert Pupkin.
What is your real name?
That's my real name.
Rupert Pupkin.
Well, Mr. Pumpkin,
are you going to tell us...
whereJerry Langford
is or not?
Are you from the show?
I'm not from the show.
This is my assistant
Agent Giardello.
This is Captain Burke
of the police.
I'd like to meet
someone from the show.
You don't see anyone...
until I get to see Langford.
I'd like to see
someone from the show.
You won't see someone unless
you tell us where Langford is.
Well, then Jerry Langford is dead.
Get Thomas.
I'm Bert Thomas.
Are you Mr. King?
Yes. How do you do?
Did we talk
on the phone today?
We spoke a few moments ago.
Then Jerry spoke
to you earlier.
Where did you get this?
That's Jerry's as you can see.
- What's that?
- That's my blood, notJerry's.
I'll buy this.
What do we have here?
Now, this is
my introduction...
I'd like Mr. Randall
to speak it word for word.
This is Randall's introduction
to your monologue?
Could I have a copy
of your monologue?
Well, actually,
I have it memorized.
So, I don't have--
There are reasons
that I need a copy.
We have to make sure
we don't say anything obscene.
No. It's all right. Really.
Yeah. It's a wholesome monologue.
- You guarantee that?
- I guarantee it.
Make sure that audience
lasts till 1 1 :30.
Everything he needs,
anything he asks for.
Nice meeting you.
Sit down, Pupkin.
Mr. Pupkin,
I got to tell you this.
From this point on...
you have the right
to remain silent...
'cause anything you say
from here on out might be used...
- against you later on
in a court of law.
- I'm aware of that.
Say you understand.
I understand that.
Did you participate in
the abduction ofJerry Langford?
Yes, I did.
I abducted him.
You abducted him?
Yes.
Do you know where
Mr. Langford is right now?
Will you lead us
to Mr. Langford?
No, I won't.
Well, at this time,
Mr. Pupkin...
I want to advise you...
to consider yourself under arrest.
Fine. I think
I should get made up.
You need some makeup.
Put some color in his face.
I'd like to put some color
in your face.
Really. I should get made up.
Tony, did you want to see me?
Have you seen this stuff?
I think it's fine.
You think this is fine?
My writing staff was
executed in Central Park
by the network firing squad?
You're laughing at that?
It's very good.
Do it, please.
Why do I?
Exactly as it's written.
It'll be good for you.
Trust me.
You're the director.
Can you help me?
Take the tissues
out of your collar and let's go.
Turn the cards fast.
Are you listening to me?
Let's do something
crazy tonight.
Just get insane.
I want to be crazy.
I want be nuts.
I want some fun.
My doctor says
don't have any fun.
You're not allowed
to have a good time.
I have to be in control.
I'd like to see myself
out of my head.
Wouldn't you like
to see that?
Wouldn't that be great?
Wouldn't that be fabulous?
I'm having a good time.
I'm having fun.
Fun is my middle name.
That's right.
Having some fun.
I never had
this much fun before.
That's right.
Good old-fashioned,
All-American fun.
And now,
direct from New York...
it's...
with guest host
Tony Randall...
and his special guests...
Shelley Winters,
Gore Vidal...
Tony Bennett...
as always,
Lou Brown and the orchestra...
and little old me--
Ed Herlihy.
And now,
say hello to Tony!
[Audience Cheers
And Whistles]
[Orchestra Plays
Theme Song]
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you very much.
I have some
sad news for you.
Earlier today,
my writing staff...
was executed in Central Park
by the network firing squad...
so there will be
no sensational...
Randall monologue this evening.
[Audience Cheers]
No embarrassing display
of emotion, please.
Instead we're going
to do something...
a little bit different
this evening.
A lot different,
if you ask me.
We're going to give you
a glimpse--
turn it over, please--
into the future.
It isn't often you can
call someone a sure thing...
in the entertainment
business.
After all, the verdict
is always in your hands.
I think tonight,
after you've met...
my first guest...
you'll agree with me that
he's destined for greatness!
In one way or another.
So will you please
give your warmest greetings...
to the newest
king of comedy--
Rupert Pupkin!
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Let me introduce myself.
My name is Rupert Pupkin.
I can't believe
I'm going to kiss you.
Masha, take the tape off.
Really?
Go on.
Take it off.
Ready now.
Take him back down.
Why did you do this?
Tell me and maybe
I'll be able to believe in you.
You know what time it is?
Yes, it's 5 minutes to 1 1 :00.
I think we'd better go.
I don't like
to say it like this...
butJerry's going to be
unavailable.
You'll understand when we go.
I'll understand?
Why will I understand?
Where are we going?
That's part of the bargain.
I want to see it
somewhere else--
Part of what bargain?
Well, that's my understanding.
I just want to see it
in this other place.
Once I see it,
I'll give you Langford.
You don't understand
my position.
I have you right now.
Having you,
I have a shot at Langford.
But you don't haveJerry.
I understand that.
I'm doing this as fast as I can.
Good, Masha.
Yeah?
Good.
You all right?
I'm fine.
I know you are.
All right. Come on.
Let's go.
Oh, one more thing.
I can't walk in here with you.
If you just wait here...
and let me walk in by myself.
I'll break your ankles
if you make a wrong move.
O.K., I promise, O.K.?
Make believe
you don't know me, too.
Go ahead.
O.K. Here you go.
[Pop]
[Pop Pop]
[Crash]
Jerry, you seem a little bit--
Jerry!Jerry, wait!
Jerry!Jerry!
Jerry, come back here!
Jerry!
Oh, God.
What do you want now?
What are you doing?
I'm watching that.
It's almost over.
Just a minute.
It's theJerry Langford Show.!
With guest host
Tony Randall...
and his special guests
Shelley Winters...
What's going on here?
Do you know him?
Unfortunately, yes.
Well,just sit tight. Relax.
Everything will be O.K.
[Audience Laughs]
My first guest...
you'll agree with me that...
he's destined for greatness.!
In one way or another.
So will you please give
your warmest greetings...
to the newest
king of comedy--
Rupert Pupkin.!
Good evening,
ladies and gentlemen.
Let me introduce myself.
My name is Rupert Pupkin.
I was born
in Clifton, NewJersey...
which was not at that time
a federal offense.
[Laughter]
Is there anyone here
from Clifton?
[No Response]
Oh, good.
We can all relax$ now.
I'd like to begin by saying...
my parents were too poor
to afford me a childhood.
But the fact is that...
no one is allowed to be
too poor in Clifton.
Once you fall
below a certain level...
they ex$ile you to Passaic.
[Laughter And Applause]
My parents did put...
the first two down payments
on my childhood.
Don't get me wrong,
but they did also...
return me to the hospital
as defective.
But, like everyone else...
I grew up in large part
thanks to my mother.
If she were only here today...
I'd say, "Hey, ma,
what are you doing here?
You've been dead
for nine years.!'
But seriously,
you should've seen my mother.
She was wonderful.
Blonde, beautiful,
intelligent, alcoholic.
We used to drink milk
together after school.
Mine was homogenized.
Hers was loaded.
Once they picked her up
for speeding.
They clocked her doing 50.
All right,
but in our garage?
[Applause]
And when they tested her...
they found out that
her alcohol had 2% blood.
Ah, but we used tojoke together,
mom and me...
until the tears
would stroll down her face..
and she would throw up.!
Yeah, and who would
clean it up?
Not dad. He was too busy
down at O'Grady's...
throwing up on his own.
Yeah.
In fact, until I was 1 6...
I thought throwing up
was a sign of maturity.
While the other kids...
were off in the woods
sneaking cigarettes...
I was hiding
behind the house...
with my fingers
down my throat.
The only problem was
I never got anywhere...
until one day
my father caught me.
Just as he was giving me...
a final kick in the stomach
for luck...
I managed to heave
all over his new shoes.!
"That's it, 'I thought.
"I've made it.
I'm finally a man.!'
[Audience Applauds Wildly]
But as it turned out,
I was wrong.
That was the only attention
my father ever gave me.
Yeah, he was usually too busy...
out in the park playing ball
with my sister Rose.
But today, I must say...
thanks to those many hours
of practice...
my sister Rose has grown
into a fine man.
Me, I wasn't especially
interested in athletics.
The only ex$ercise I ever got...
was when the other kids
picked on me.
Yeah, they used to
beat me up once a week...
usually Tuesday.
And after a while...
the school worked it
into the curriculum.
And if you knocked me out,
you got ex$tra credit.
There was this one kid,
poor kid...
he was afraid of me.
I used to tell him...
"Hit me, hit me.
What's the matter with you?
Don't you want to graduate?'
Hey, I was the youngest kid...
in the history of the school...
to graduate in traction.
But,you know,
my only real interest...
right from the beginning,
was show business.
Even as a young man,
I began at the very top--
collecting autographs.
Now, a lot of you
are probably wondering...
whyJerry isn't with us tonight.
Well, I'll tell you.
The fact is he's tied up.
I'm the one who tied him.
Well, I know you think
I'm joking...
but, believe me,
that's the only way...
I could break
into show business--
by hijacking Jerry Langford.
Right now,
Jerry is strapped to a chair...
somewhere in the middle
of the city.
Go ahead, laugh.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
But the fact is, I'm here.
Now, tomorrow you'll know
I wasn't kidding...
and you'll think I was crazy.
But, look,
I figure it this way.
Better to be king for a night...
than schmuck for a lifetime.
[Wild Applause And Cheering]
Thank you.
[No Audio]
[Wild Applause]
[Siren]
[Man]
How'd you do that?
Did you like it?
Thank you.
I'd like to buy
everyone here a drink.
I hope you all
enjoyed the show.
Rita, you keep the change.
Just because I made it big,
I won't forget about you.
Come on. Come on!
[Man]
What's happening here?
[Rita]
Take care of yourself, Rupert.
That's the same guy who
was just now on television.
Just now. Same guy.
I'm just getting even.
No jokes. No jokes.
You murdered.
You didn't like my show?
No. No.
Matter of fact...
I'm looking for the guy
that wrote the material.
I'll pick him up
and take him along with you.
I wrote the material.
I disagree with you.
I thought they were
very good jokes.
If you wrote that material...
I got one piece
of advice for you.
Throw yourself on your knees
in front of the judge...
and beg for mercy.
That's very funny,
but you'll see.
In what has to rank
as the most bizarre debut...
in recent times...
a self-styled comedian
named Rupert Pupkin...
appeared on
theJerry Langford Show...
There's no doubt
the incident has made...
Rupert Pupkin a household word.
Pupkin's performance
has been viewed...
by a record 87 million
American households.
Rupert Pupkin,
kidnapping king of comedy...
was sentenced
to six$ years imprisonment...
at the government's
minimum security facility...
in Allenwood, Pennsylvania,
for his part...
in the abduction of
talk show hostJerry Langford.
On the anniversary of
his appearance on the show...
Rupert Pupkin told
a gathering of reporters...
he still considers Jerry Langford...
his friend and mentor.
He reported he had been
spending his time...
writing his memoirs,
which have been purchased...
by a leading publishing house...
for in ex$cess of $ 1 million.
Rupert Pupkin was released
today from Allenwood...
after serving 2 years
and 9 months...
of a six$-year sentence.
Hundreds greeted the 3 7-year-old...
comedian and author...
among them his new agent
and manager David Ball...
who announced
King For A Night...
Pupkin's best-selling autobiography...
will appear as a major
motion picture.
Pupkin said he used
his stay at Allenwood...
to sharpen his material.
He said he and his people...
were weighing attractive offers...
and he looked forward
to resuming....
his show business career.
And now,
ladies and gentlemen...
the man we've all
been waiting for...
and waiting for.
Would you welcome home
please...
television's
brightest new star--
The legendary, inspirational...
the one and only
king of comedy--
Ladies and gentlemen,
Rupert Pupkin.!
[Cheering And Whistling]
Rupert Pupkin,
ladies and gentlemen.!
Let's hear it
for Rupert Pupkin.!
[Wild Applause]
Wonderful.!
Rupert Pupkin,
ladies and gentlemen.!
[Applause Continues]
Rupert Pupkin,
ladies and gentlemen.!
Let's hear it
for Rupert Pupkin.!
[Wild Applause]
Wonderful.!
Rupert Pupkin,
ladies and gentlemen.!
How can you stand the silence
That pervades when we all cry?
How can you watch the violence
That erupts before your eyes?
How can you tell us something
Just to keep us hanging on?
Something thatjust
don't mean nothing
When we see it,you are gone
Clinging to some other rainbow
Or standing waiting in the the cold
Telling us the same old story
Knowing time is growing old
That was a wonderful remark
I had my eyes closed in the dark
I sighed a million sighs
I told a million lies
To myself
How can we listen to you
When we know your talk is cheap?
How can we ever question
Why we give more and you keep?
How can your empty laughter
Fill the room like clouds ofjoy
When you're only playing with us
Like a child does with a toy?
How can we ever feel the freedom?
Or the flame lit by the spark?
How can we ever come out even
When reality is stark?
That was a wonderful remark
I had my eyes closed in the dark
Yeah
I sighed a million sighs
I told a million lies
To myself
Believin'to myself
Ooh
To myself