.. [ Piano: ''The Entertainer'' ]
.. [ Band Playing ''The Entertainer'' ]
- [ All Chattering, lndistinct ]
- Let's see what you got.
- l need more runners. l can't
write the business fast enough.
- You gotta see Granger.
[ Chattering Continues ]
8720. Yeah. Yeah.
Hold it a minute.
Beat it, Mottola ! Mr. Granger ?
Chicago's on the line.
Yeah.
This is Combs. Why haven't we
heard from you ? Everybody else is in.
We had problems
with the law this morning.
The mayor promised
to get tough on the rackets,
so l shut everybody down for
a couple of hours to make it look good.
- Nothing serious. lt just
put us a little behind.
- Been making your payoffs ?
Hell, yes ! He does this every year.
There's nothing to worry about.
Finish your count and get it up here.
l don't want to be here all night.
The man's going
to be real happy.
- Looks like we cleared
over ten grand this week.
- We cleared 22 here.
What the hell !
You got the whole Chicago South Side.
How do you expect the eight lousy spots
l got to compete with that ?
They did 14 grand in Evanston,
16.5 in Gary, and 20 in Cicero.
Looks like you're
bringing up the rear.
l just got the count.
l'll put the take on the 4:15.
We'll be waiting.
Mottola !
Take this up to Chicago
on the 4:15.
They'll be waiting for it
at the clearinghouse.
And don't stop for any entertainment.
Get a cab over on 7th.
- Aw, cut it out !
- [ Phone Ringing ]
8720.
[ Car Horn Honks ]
Hey, you there ! Stop !
Hey, you ! Stop that man !
Stop him ! He's got my wallet !
Stop him ! Stop that man !
He's got all of my money !
Stop him !
Goddamn nigger-lover !
l'm gonna get you someday for this !
Sucker egg !
Don't let him get away ! He's got
my wallet ! He's got all my money !
- My wallet ! He's got my wallet !
- We got it !
- What happened ?
Did he get you with the knife ?
- Give it to me, please.
- You need a doctor. l'll call a cop.
- No, no ! No cops !
You wanted by the law
or something ?
No, it's okay.
Are you nuts, carrying a wad like that
in a neighborhood like this ?
Thanks. l'm obliged to you.
l gotta get going. [ Groans ]
You ain't going nowhere
on this leg.
l gotta. Gotta run some slots
in West Bend for a mob here.
l got a little behind in the payoffs.
They think l've been holding out on 'em.
They gave me 'til 4:00
to come up with the cash.
- lf they don't get it, l'm dead.
- lt don't look good, Gramps.
lt's almost 4:00 now.
l'll give you and your friend
a hundred bucks to deliver it for me.
l don't know. That mug that hit you
is mad enough at me already.
What if he's around the corner,
waiting with some friends ?
He won't know you're carrying it.
You've gotta help me.
l'm sorry, pal. l'm gonna
maybe help you get to a doctor,
but l ain't about to walk
into no knife for you.
How about you ? All you gotta do
is put it in the door slot.
l'll give you the whole 100.
- What makes you think you can
trust him ? He didn't do shit.
- Butt out, chicken liver !
l gave him back the wallet.
How far is this place ?
1811 Mason. Put it in box 3-C.
You won't have no trouble.
There's $5,000 there,
and here's
a hundred bucks for you.
Okay, l'll make your drop for you.
And don't worry, you can trust me.
Hey. Hey !
lf those goons search you, you ain't
gonna get far carrying it there.
- What'll we do ?
- You got a bag or something ?
- How about a handkerchief ?
- Here's a handkerchief !
Give it to me.
Give me the money.
Just hurry, will you ?
You got any more ? Better give it
all to me if you want to keep it.
They think l've been holding out
on 'em. My wife got sick,
and l had to pay the bill.
- l wasn't holding out on 'em.
- Stuff it down your pants here,
like that.
- Got it ?
- Uh-huh.
- Hurry, will ya ?
- Ain't a tough guy in the world
that's gonna frisk you there.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
[ Car Horn Honking,
Trolley Bell Dinging ]
- [ Engine Starting ]
- Where to ?
- Which way is Mason ?
- Twenty blocks south.
- Go north, Joliet Station, fast !
- Right.
[ Laughing ]
- What's so funny ?
- l just made the world's
easiest five grand !
[ Chuckling ]
- Come on, Luther ! Come on !
- Hold on, man ! Okay !
- Hustle !
- [ Panting, Laughing ]
ln here !
[ Laughing ]
Man, was that beautiful !
l thought for sure
he was on to us.
l had him all the way.
[ Laughing ] All the way !
[ Laughing ]
Ah !
Wai-- Luther.
Good God !
We're millionaires.
- Jesus ! Did you know
he was that loaded ?
- Hell, no !
l just cut into him. l would've
settled for pawning one of them shoes.
- [ Both Laughing ]
- Oh, God !
- Do you-- [ Laughing ]
- [ Laughing ]
- Whoo !
- Come on. Let's get out of here.
We'll split it up tonight.
[ Heels Clacking ]
Heya, Marge !
.. [ Band Playing Striptease Tune ]
[ Scattered Applause ]
- Hi, kid.
- Hi, Hooker. She's on stage.
Hi, Hooker.
Gettin' married or something ?
Get used to it, Leonard.
l'm going to look this good from now on.
- Whaddaya say, Ed ?
- Hi, Hooker.
[ Man Whistling ]
- [ Whistles ] Hey ! Psst !
- [ Man Whistles ]
l wanna talk--
[ Scattered Applause ]
Hey, Hooker, you gettin'
married or somethin' ?
[ Man Whistling ]
For Christ's sake, Ed,
did you hear that ?
Harry drops four beats
in the middle of my goddamn routine !
- How long do l gotta put up with that ?
- Crystal ! Leonard, you're on.
You wanna get outta here tonight ?
l come into some dough.
l can't. l got a 10:00.
l need the five bucks.
l'll spend 50 on you.
- Yeah ?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- ...opens up his pants,
the duck sticks his head out.
One lady says to the other,
''See what l see ?''
She says, ''So what ?
You've seen one, you've seen 'em all.''
- She says, ''Yes, but this one's
eating my popcorn.''
- [ Men Laughing ]
[ Patrons Chattering, Shouting ]
You see that guy Harry,
he can't keep time.
Supposing there's
some Hollywood movie agent out there.
- All those years of training
right down the drain.
- Whaddaya say, Jimmy ?
- Ain't seen you in months.
Thought you took a fall.
- Just a little hard times.
- Everything's jake now.
- How about a ten spot on the line ?
There's a lot of action there
on 28th Street. Pay you 35--
Three grand on the red.
- $3,000 ?
- Are you nuts ?
- [ Hooker ] No, l feel lucky.
- Hooker, l can't accept that.
lt's too big a bet.
- There's a house limit.
- Take it.
- But Hooker here--
- Take it !
[ Ball Rolling ]
- [ Crowd Murmuring ]
- Twenty-two, black.
Tough luck, kid.
Lucky for me it came up black.
A fella could get in trouble here,
losin' a bet like that.
Listen, Jimmy,
can't we do it again, huh ?
[ Dealer ]
Seven !
Don't worry about it. There's always
more where that came from.
Oh, don't worry about it, he says.
Three thousand dollars !
Thanks, Hooker.
[ Crystal ] Comes in here with $50
he's going to spend on me !
[ Patrons Shouting ]
- Thanks for the evening, Hooker.
- lt's not over yet.
- Next time you wanna
spend $50 on me, mail it.
- Come on, would you--
Listen, will ya pl--
They found Mottola, drunk in a dive
in Joliet. He never got on the train.
l don't wanna hear about his day, Greer.
What happened to the money ?
He lost it to a couple of con artists
on his way out of the spot.
- How much ?
- Eleven thousand.
Okay, l better get
on the phone to New York,
see what the big mick
wants to do about it.
l have a pretty good idea, though.
[ lndistinct Chatter ]
Oh !
[ Man ]
Come on !
[ Dealer ]
Ace. Bet the ace.
- Bet the ace. Ace bets a deuce.
- Ace says two.
- Two.
- [ Chips Clacking ]
On his right.
Four fives, two spades,
ace six, ace deuce.
- Ten--
- Ace, l'll bet ace. Two again.
- Doyle, can l talk to you ?
- l'm busy, Floyd.
lt's important. We had
a little trouble in Chicago today.
One of our runners
got hit for 11 grand.
What makes you think
he just didn't pocket it ?
We checked his story with a tipster.
He was cleaned by two grifters.
- They working for anybody ?
- l don't know. Could be.
We're running that down now.
Have some local people
take care of them. Nothing fancy.
Got to discourage
this kind of thing.
You follow ?
[ Radio Show, lndistinct ]
[ Radio: Machine Gun Fire ]
- Johnny Hooker ! Aah !
- [ Radio Show Continues, lndistinct ]
-lf you ain't a sharper in them linens !
-Evenin', Louise.
- Hey, Ma !
- lf l didn't know you better,
l'd swear you had some class.
- [ Laughing ]
- Johnny, Luther said you was
something to see today !
Oh ! l don't know, Alva.
l gotta get faster tyin' up
that bundle. l'm still giving
'em too much time to think.
Bushwah ! l used to make that switch
with slower hands than you got.
'Course, the Up and Down Broadway
was my best game.
Me and Luther didn't make much on it,
but it wasn't so touchy.
Them marks can beat you up bad
when they catch you makin' that switch.
- Come on, Leroy.
We'll be late for church.
- Aw, Ma !
- They were closin' in
on Machine Gun Kelly.
- Who you rootin' for anyhow ?
- Hey, Hooker !
- Can't help you, Leroy.
You can't beat the house.
- Nuts !
- Since when do you go
to church at night ?
Since they started late bingo.
l'm gonna ask the Lord for some of
that cash while He's still payin' off.
- Luther, look in on the baby
from time to time, will you ?
- You too, Louise ?
Child, yeah, got to go pray.
See ya.
Hey, Erie.
- Mmm, gimme !
Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme !
- There's your cut.
- [ Chuckling ]
- Guy turned out to be an oil well.
- Which way'd he go ?
- Due north. He was gonna take it all.
Ah, the bastard.
He can blow his nose all the way.
[ Giggling ]
There you go, Luther.
Six G's.
- You're late. Where you been ?
- l had a couple of appointments.
How much did you lose ?
[ Grunts ]
All of it.
ln one goddamn night ?
What are you spraying money
around like that for ?
You could've been nailed !
l checked the place.
There were no dicks in there.
But you're a con man,
and you blew it like a pimp !
Didn't teach you to be no pimp.
What the hell's eatin' you ?
l've blown money before.
- No class grifter
would've done it, that's all.
- You think my play is bad ?
l think you're the best.
l wouldn't be getting out,
otherwise.
What the hell
are you talkin' about ?
l'm getting too old
for this racket.
You hang on too long
and you start embarrassing yourself.
We just took off on the biggest score
we've ever had.
lt's nothing compared to what you
could be making on the big con.
But you played the big con.
You told me yourself it was some
dumb game for mama's boys and flakes.
[ Laughs ]
Hell, l never played no big con.
l hung around
and picked up a few things.
Ain't no rich boys gonna trust
a hungry nigger enough to be conned.
But l'll tell you,
l've been looking for this one
all my life, Johnny.
Now l have a chance
to step out when l'm ahead.
Come on ! What would
you do with yourself ?
l have a brother in K.C.,
runs a freight outlet.
l can go halfsies with him.
lt ain't too exciting,
but it's mostly legal.
l got an old friend in Chicago
named Henry Gondorff.
l want you to look him up.
There ain't a better inside man alive.
- He'll teach you all you gotta know.
- To hell with that.
l want to work with you, Luther.
l'm out, Johnny.
Yeah, sure.
lf that's the way you want it.
That's the way l want it.
- [ Can Rattling ]
- How do you like that Coleman ?
After five years.
- lt was the only thing to do.
He knew he was holding you back.
- Yeah, but we were partners.
lf it weren't for Luther, l'd still be
hustling pinball at Gianelli's.
l don't need more
than what l got.
You ain't gonna have anything if you
don't lay off the games of chance.
- There's a depression on.
- Yeah, there's always a depression on.
- lf you saved a little, maybe you
wouldn't have to grift so much.
- l like griftin'.
- Maybe you could
buy yourself some things.
- What ?
- New clothes, a car.
- l got clothes, and l
don't know how to drive.
- What else do you got to sell ?
- [ Brakes Screeching ]
Hey, Hooker !
Come on, you son of a--
- Okay. Come on.
- Oh, hi there, Snyder.
What's the matter ? Things a little
slow down at the bunco department ?
- Somebody lose the dominoes ?
- You scored blood money today,
and you need a friend.
Go find yourself
a shoplifter to roll.
You got the wrong guy, pal.
l've been home with the flu all day.
- You can stake out
my toilet if you want.
- Keep talkin' !
- [ Coughs, Spits ]
- l'll tell you what you did, smart boy.
You tied into a loaded mark
on 47th across from Maxie's.
You and Coleman played the switch for
him and blew him off to a cab on 49th.
lf he hadn't been a numbers
runner for Doyle Lonnegan,
it would've been perfect.
You're crazy.
l ain't stupid enough
to play for no racket's money.
Not intentionally, maybe.
That don't cut no ice with Lonnegan.
- He'll swat you like a fly.
- Yeah, well--
l'll square it
with the fixer.
Nobody can buy you a prayer
if l put the finger on you.
Now, l figure your end of the score
was at least three G's.
- l want two, no matter what it was.
- My take was only one.
Then you're gonna have to come up
with another grand somewhere.
All right.
You're a smart egg, Hooker.
No sense getting dead
over two grand.
Relax, Erie.
l'll bill ya.
- l thought you blew all your money.
- l did.
The stuff l gave him
is counterfeit.
They'll spot it the first place
he tries to spend it.
Are you crazy,
giving him counterfeit money ?
Hey ! Wait up !
Where you goin' ?
Aw.
- [ Shouts ]
- Hey, you--
- [ Coin Rattles ]
- [ Phone Dings ]
[ Dialing ]
What the hell are you gonna do
if Snyder puts the finger on you ?
- You're committin' suicide, kid.
- What difference does it make ?
lf Snyder knows about us,
so does everybody else.
He never gets anything first.
Hey, listen to me.
Don't go back to your place tonight.
Don't go anyplace you usually go.
You hear me ?
Damn !
There's no answer at Luther's.
Look, you better get out
of town or something.
- [ Woman Shouting ]
- [ Erie ] Hey, lady, lady, let go !
- Ma'am ! Ma'am ! Hey !
- l want my nickel back
for that telephone !
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Man ]
No, sir. Nobody here did.
1521 North Bryant.
[ Baby Crying ]
- [ People Murmuring ]
- Luther !
- ls he dead ?
- l don't know. There was a big fight.
l don't know.
Somebody must've pushed him.
- Ah, Jesus !
- Luther !
- Luther ! Oh !
- Jesus !
God ! No ! No ! No !
[ Sobbing ]
Luther ! Luther !
What happened ? God, who would do
such a thing to you, Luther ?
- [ Siren Wailing ]
- Luther ! [ Sobbing ]
Come on. Come on !
Let's get out of here.
- [ Car Tires Screeching ]
- Luther !
Come on ! lf Snyder
catches you here, you're dead !
Talk to me, honey !
Say something !
- Get outta here !
- [ Officer ] Outta the way.
Help me, help me, help me !
[ Sobbing Continues ]
[ Car Horn Honking ]
[ Car Horn Honks ]
Uh... excuse me.
l'm looking for a guy named
Henry Gondorff. You know him ?
No.
You sure ?
- Beat it.
- Luther Coleman sent me.
- Are you Hooker ?
- Yeah.
Why didn't you say so ?
We heard about Luther last night.
Come on.
l thought maybe you were a cop
or something.
lt's the room in the back.
He wasn't expecting you
so soon, though.
Thanks.
[ Train Rumbling Overhead ]
[ Rumbling Grows Louder ]
[ Rumbling Stops ]
[ Snoring ]
[ Snoring Continues ]
The great Henry Gondorff.
Turn it off !
You sober ?
Turn it off, will ya ?
[ Sighs ]
Glad to meet you, kid.
You're a real horse's ass.
Luther said l could learn
something from you.
l already know how to drink.
Sorry about Luther.
He was the best street worker
l ever saw.
He had you down as a big timer.
What happened ?
l conned a senator from Florida
on a stock deal.
A real lop-ear; thought he was gonna
take over General Electric.
Some chanteusie woke him, though,
and he put the feds on me.
You mean you blew it.
Luther didn't tell me
you had a big mouth.
He didn't tell me
you was a screwup either.
[ Feet Sloshing ]
You played any big cons
since then ?
l lammed around a bunch of bohunk towns,
one kick ahead of the G-men.
Would be still,
if Billie hadn't set me up here.
Don't kid yourself, friend.
l still know how.
You gonna stay for breakfast,
or do you already know how to eat ?
l picked something up
along the way.
ls Lonnegan after you too ?
l don't know.
l ain't seen anybody.
You never do, kid.
[ Water Stops Running ]
[ Gondorff Groans ]
[ Water Bubbling ]
Doyle ?
Yeah.
We just talked to Chicago. They got one
of the grifters last night-- a nigger.
- How about the other one ?
- They're still looking for him.
- Who did Combs put on it ?
- He gave it to Riley and Cole.
They staked out the other guy's place
last night, but he never showed.
They figure maybe
he skipped town.
You wanna keep after him ?
You see that fella
in the red sweater ?
His name's Danny McCoy.
Works a few of the protection
rackets for Canarro when he's
waiting for something better.
Danny and l have known each other
since we were six.
Take a good look
at that face, Floyd.
Because if he ever finds out
l can be beat by one lousy grifter,
l'll have to kill him
and every other hood...
who wants to muscle in
on my Chicago operation.
- You follow ?
- Yes, sir.
Good lad.
- You feeling all right
this morning, Henry ?
- Yeah, fine.
You mind opening up the round
a little early today ?
- We got some business
coming in before hours.
- Sure.
And check the main gearing,
will ya ?
Man O' War started rattling yesterday
and threw a kid on its head.
[ Clicks Tongue ]
Great little countess, that Billie.
She runs a spiffy house up there too.
- You plan to spend
the rest of your life here ?
- l could do a lot worse.
- Listen, am l gonna learn
to play the big con or not ?
- What's your hurry ?
- l wanna play for Lonnegan.
- You know anything about the guy ?
Yeah, he croaked Luther.
Anything else l gotta know ?
[ Sighs ]
All right. He runs a numbers racket
on the South Side.
He owns a packinghouse,
a few banks--
Yeah, and half the politicians
in New York and Chicago.
Not a fix in this world is gonna
cool him out if he blows on you.
- l'll get him anyway.
- Why ?
'Cause l don't know enough
about killing to kill him.
[ Train Rumbling ]
You can't do it alone, you know.
lt takes a mob of guys like you
and enough money to make 'em look good.
- l know plenty of guys.
- lt's not like playing winos
in the street.
- You can't outrun Lonnegan.
- l never played for no winos.
You gotta keep his con
even after you take his money.
He can't know you took him.
- You're scared of him.
- Right down to my socks, buster.
You're talking about a guy
who'd kill a grifter...
over a chunk of money
wouldn't support him for two days.
You're gonna go for him.
Just don't want a hothead looking to
get even, coming back halfway through,
saying, ''lt ain't enough,''
'cause it's all we're gonna get.
Can you get a mob together ?
After what happened to Luther,
l don't think l can get more
than two, three hundred guys.
.. [ Calliope ]
Luther said you learn fast.
l hope he's right.
.. [ Piano: Ragtime ]
.. [ Calliope ]
Lonnegan gets most of his income
from the numbers,
even though he's been putting more money
into his savings and loan business.
- [ Gondorff ] Think he's
moving out of the racket ?
- No.
He owns most of the stock,
and it's traded.
My guess is he's just trying
to build himself a respectable image.
He came out of Five Points,
but he's been telling everybody
he was born in Forest Hills.
He knows the market, though. l don't
think we can take him on a stocks deal.
Twist, what about the numbers ?
Tipsters say it's run
out of a packinghouse
on 14th by a guy named Combs.
Lonnegan comes out every three weeks
or so to check on it, but...
he stays away from the day-to-day stuff
in case it's raided.
These are two of Combs's
favorite torpedoes: Riley and Cole.
You ever seen 'em ?
No.
They're the ones
who hit Luther.
They also got the numbers runner
you conned: a guy named Mottola.
Found him in a quarry
with a knife in his eye.
Lonnegan's had seven or eight people
rubbed on his way up.
His pattern has been
to get close to a racket boss,
learn the operation,
then move in on it.
He's done it to Gorman,
O'Donnell, Buchalman;
took the numbers from Sharkey.
All four of these guys are dead.
He's vindictive as hell, Henry.
Kills for pride. Doesn't add up
he'd let Hooker get away from him.
You see anything, kid,
you let us know.
lf they put you on the spot,
we gotta fold the con. You got that ?
Yeah. You sure it's gotta
be one of these two guys ?
Nope. They're just
the only ones we know of.
Okay.
.. [ Calliope Continues ]
Time.
[ People Chattering, Laughing ]
Set me up five more beers,
will you, Danny ?
.. [ Humming ]
- You the owner here ?
- That's right.
Lt. Snyder, Bunco.
That's a Joliet badge, Snyder.
Don't cut much up here.
Looking for a guy on the lam
from a counterfeiting rap.
Thought he might've come here.
Don't think so.
l know everyone in the place,
and l always bounce the lamsters.
All right
if l look around in here ?
No, but you're welcome
to a free beer before you go.
l don't really need
your permission.
l don't know what to do
with this guy.
He's an lrishman who doesn't drink,
doesn't smoke and doesn't chase dames.
He's a grand knight
in the Knights of Columbus,
and he only goes out
to play faro.
Sometimes plays 15, 20 hours at a time;
just him against the house.
- Roulette, craps ?
- He won't touch 'em.
The croupier at Gilman's says
he never plays anything he can't win.
- Sports ?
- He likes to be seen
with fighters sometimes,
but he doesn't go
to the fights or bet on 'em.
- Jesus. Does he do anything
where he's not alone ?
- Just poker.
And he cheats.
Pretty good at it too.
Where does he play ?
The porters say he runs a braced game
on the Century Limited...
when he comes out here
from New York.
$100 minimum, straight poker.
A lot of high rollers ride that train
just to play him.
That sounds good, J.J.
[ Laughter, lndistinct Chatter ]
Which way are the rooms ?
- Who told you this guy was in here ?
- Nobody.
l just know what kind of woman
he likes.
l'm gonna check all the joy houses
'til l find him.
Maybe l could help you
if you tell me his name.
l doubt it.
Which way are the rooms ?
Right through there. But l
wouldn't go in there if l were you.
- What are you gonna do, call the cops ?
- l don't have to.
You'd be busting in on
the chief of police just up the hall.
.. [ Calliope ]
[ Banker ] We'll play it out here.
A huge duke is too simple.
With no fix, we're gonna need a con
with a surefire blow-off.
[ J.J. ] l think we ought to
play this guy on the payoff.
lt's the tightest game we got,
and it's not all over the papers yet.
Lonnegan is a fast egg. He's not going
to sit still for a standard play.
[ Banker ] What does that leave us ?
We can't con the payoff to a banker.
We'll use the wire.
Haven't known a poker player
didn't wanna beat the ponies.
- The wire's been out of date
for ten years.
- That's why he won't know it.
l'm not sure l know it.
lt'll take two of us
working the inside.
Any objections to Hooker
as second man ?
All right. We'll give Lonnegan
the hook on the train and play him here.
J.J., you think l can get
in that poker game ?
All you gotta do is show up with
a lot of money and look like a sucker.
l also gotta win.
By the way, any of you guys
been passing bad money lately ?
lf he comes in again,
stall him so l can get a look at him.
[ Billie ]
Mm-hmm.
Fella by the name of Stenner had
this place 'til about six months ago,
but he had to give it up.
lt doesn't look so good, but maybe you
can fix it up a little bit.
Watch your step when you come in.
There's a dip down to the left.
- How does it look, Eddie ?
- lt looks all right, Kid.
lt's big enough,
and it's off the street.
lt's kind of short notice. l'm not sure
we can get it done by Saturday.
Got to. Gondorff's riding the mark down
from New York on the Century.
We'll take it. That building at the end
of the alley, do you manage that ?
- For 15 years.
- l'll need a corner room
facing this way.
- How much a week ?
- Only rents by the month.
Two hundred and fifty
for the two of them.
- Last time l expect
to see you down here.
- Never heard of the place.
[ Old Man ] lt's been a while
since l stocked a wire store.
Not many mobs
playing that anymore.
[ Eddie ] All we'll need
is the bookie setup for now.
[ Old Man ] l'll rent you everything
l got in the warehouse for two grand.
That'll give you phones, cages,
blackboards and ticker gear.
lf you want a counter and bar,
that's another grand.
-That's pretty steep, Benny.
-[ Benny ] Gondorff's still a hot item.
- Where would l be if he gets hit ?
- Just give us what you can.
We'll send a truck. How do you want to
work this ? Flat rate or percentage ?
- Who's the mark ?
- Doyle Lonnegan.
Flat rate.
The guy in the black hat
with the gimp.
He's not as tough as he thinks.
Neither are we.
- Mr. Shaw ?
- Right.
You wanted to see me ?
l hear there's a friendly poker game on
this train. You know anything about it ?
- Oh, a little.
- Thank you, sir.
- Can you get me in that game ?
- Oh, l don't know.
There's usually
a waiting list.
That'll get you
first alternate, sir.
l'll see what l can do.
- [ Men Chattering ]
- Hey, Twist !
Patty, me boy !
How are you ?
- How are you, Twist ?
- Hey, Champ, you're
lookin' like a million !
- Yeah, so do you.
- Good to see you !
Goldie, you old
son of a gun. Hey !
l saw the Kid in Denver.
He says to say hello to you.
- Joiner, are you still
workin' those shapes ?
- Any number you want, Twist !
- Good to see you again.
- Okay, Lacey. Good to see you.
- lt's good to see you. Come on in !
- Dukey, how are you ?
- When did you get back in town ?
- A couple of days ago.
You heard about Luther Coleman,
didn't you ?
Yeah. Some of the boys were
passin' the hat for Alva and the kids.
- l never seen the guys so worked up.
- Don't worry about it, Dukey.
We're gonna send a little
calling card of our own.
Gondorff is setting up
a wire store.
l'm gonna need
a 20-man boost right away.
l got plenty of talent out there
tonight. Take your pick. Lace !
This is a tough one.
These boys have got to be the quill.
Get me the sheet.
Let's see who's in town, huh ?
Hey, Patty,
give me the sheet.
- Sure.
- [ Door Opens ]
[ Chattering Stops ]
Gondorff's already on--
Twist, you know this guy ?
No, l never saw him before.
He's a dick, though.
Hello, Snyder.
- What are you doin' up here ?
- l'm on vacation.
Hey, you seen that friend
of yours lately ?
No, no.
He, uh, packed it in.
- Enrolled in detective school.
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Glass Breaks ]
lf you see him,
you tell him he better pay up
before l get to him.
That son of a bitch.
Ah, thanks, Lace.
Let's see what we got here.
Let's see, Horse Face Lee,
Slim Miller,
Suitcase Murphy and the Big Alabama
are in from New Orleans.
Cryin' Jonesy and the Boone Kid
from Denver.
Dippy Burke and Limehouse Chappie
from New York.
Well, these and the guys outside should
give you 30 or more to choose from.
Good, Dukey.
Have them down at Stenner's
old pool hall before 6:00.
- We're gonna run the route tonight.
- Okay, Twist, but...
if this thing blows up, remember,
l can't do you no good downtown.
Gondorff is federal.
Dukey, if this thing blows up,
the feds will be
the least of our problems.
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Whistle Continues ]
[ Train Crossing Bell Ringing ]
- [ Knocking ]
- Yeah ?
- You in ?
- Yeah, l think so.
- l gave the kayducer a C-note.
Did you find out the deck ?
- Mm-hmm.
He usually plays with a Tallyho Fan
or a Tallyho Circle.
l got you one of each. He likes to
cold deck low, eights or nines.
That's nice work, J.J. Here.
[ Train Whistle Blows ]
- Oh, l'm sorry.
- Don't mention it, mum.
[ Man Talking, lndistinct ]
- He'd like to join us.
- Yes, Clyde is a member of our firm.
[ Door Slides Opens ]
She picked him clean.
He never missed it.
My God, it looks like
he's expecting a big night.
Must be 15, 20 grand here.
He's waiting for you
in the card room.
Let him wait.
- [ Train Whistle Blows ]
- Just worry about your end, kid.
lf we ever get to it.
- [ All Laughing ]
- Excuse me.
You sure you checked
this guy out ?
He seemed like a pleasant man;
a lot of cash on him.
Two-hundred-dollar suit,
expensive luggage. l'll vouch for him.
Why isn't he here then ?
- Don't worry. He'll be here.
- All right.
What're you doin' ?
Always drink gin with a mark, kid.
He can't tell if you cut it.
- Two thousand for you, Mr. Clayton ?
- Thank you.
All right, gentlemen.
Should we not wait for him ?
- Let's go.
- l think that's a good idea.
Mr. Clemens, give me the cards.
[ lnhales Deeply, Blows Out ]
Sorry l'm late, guys.
l was takin' a crap.
- [ Door Slams ]
- The name's Shaw.
- Mr. Shaw,
meet Mr. Jameson from Chicago.
- How are ya ?
- Mr. Lombard from Philadelphia.
- Yeah !
- And Mr. Lonnegan from New York.
- Pleased to meet you.
Mr. Clayton, Pittsburgh.
Any of you guys want to make a little
book in Chicago, l'm the guy to see.
Game is straight poker,
$100 minimum, table stakes.
Uh, Mr. Shaw,
this is a gentleman's game.
We assume you're all good
for your debts.
- How much would you like, Mr. Shaw ?
- l'll start with 5,000.
Mr. Shaw, we usually require
a tie at this table.
lf you don't have one,
we can get you one.
Hey, that'd be real nice of you,
Mr. Lonneman.
Lonnegan.
[ Burps ]
[ Man Yelling ]
Name's Curly Jackson.
Worked for Gad Bryan outta Baltimore.
Jackson ?
Jackson, Jackson.
Oh, yeah.
Ever play the wire, Curly ?
Roped for it long ago. l can shill,
mark board, anything you want.
l don't run with riffraff,
and l only drink on weekends.
Me specialty's an Englishman.
We got a rack of suits over there.
Pick yourself a nice tweed one.
That's all right.
l've got all my own stuff.
[ Chuckles ]
Doyle ?
One.
Bill ?
l'll take one.
- Shaw ?
- Three.
And the dealer will take one.
Bet 500.
l'll call.
Call and raise.
- Three hundred.
- [ Jameson ] l'm out.
[ Lombard ]
Fold.
Your three...
and raise... 500.
That's eight to me.
Call.
Jacks on top.
Beats me.
Three tens.
Tough luck, Lonnihan.
But that's what you get
for playing with your head up your ass.
Couple more like that,
we can all go to bed early.
The name's Lonnegan.
Doyle Lonnegan.
You're gonna remember that,
Mr. Shaw, or you're gonna
get yourself another game.
You follow ?
Bring it right up here !
Hey, Eddie, we brought you a tap
into Moe Anenberg's wire.
You'll get race results, odds,
scratches, pole positions, everything.
And just as fast
as Western Union gets 'em.
- Does J.J. know how to use that thing ?
- All he's gotta do is read.
The name is Joe Erie.
[ Sniffles ]
Joe Erie.
You, uh, played
for any particular mobs ?
No.
- You ever play the wire before, Erie ?
- No.
l never played
no big con before, but, uh,
Luther Coleman was a friend of mine,
and l thought maybe...
there'd be somethin'
l could do.
You get that nose
in Duke Boudreau's tonight ?
Yeah.
You got moxie, Erie.
Get yourself a suit.
Thanks.
[ Sneezes Loudly ]
[ Groans, Sniffles ]
l'll bet three.
Call and raise 200.
- [ Snorts ]
- [ Lombard ] Call.
- No.
- [ Clayton ] l'm out.
Call.
Aces over.
Three cowboys.
All red, queen high.
- Well, that finishes me.
- Don't worry about it, pal.
They wouldn't have let you in here
if you weren't a chump !
Lombard'll be joining you
in a couple of minutes.
- Now, look here, Shaw--
- l've had enough of this game...
and quite enough of this company.
Check me out, Clemens.
l guess that just leaves
the three of us.
Yes, Mr. Shaw.
That just leaves us three.
Mr. Clayton, l think we should
take a break for five minutes.
Tempers seem to be
running a little high.
Ah, come on, Linneman,
l was just startin' to do good.
[ Laughing Continues ]
- Stack me a cooler.
- We'll be in the station
in another hour.
The other guys are the big losers.
You're still okay.
Fix me a deck-- threes and nines.
l'll cut it in on Clayton's deal.
- What do you want Clayton to get ?
- Nothin'.
l want him outta there early. l'm gonna
bust that bastard bookie in one play.
[ Whistle Blowing ]
Four hundred to you, Mr. Jameson.
You're even.
Well, it just wasn't my night.
[ Jameson ]
Oh, l need it.
- You know what time we get in ?
- No, l don't.
Hey, where's your ante ?
[ Lombard ] Every time l had anything,
he stayed in front of me.
Five hundred.
Your five.
One thousand.
l'll fold.
l'll play.
[ Clayton ]
Cards ?
Two.
Three.
Five hundred.
Your five hundred,
and one thousand.
Your one thousand.
l'll raise you two thousand.
Your two thousand.
Mr. Clemens,
give me $10,000 more.
[ Gondorff ]
l'll call.
Four nines.
Four Jacks.
You owe me 15 grand, pal.
Must've left my wallet
in my room.
Don't hand me any of that crap !
When you come to a game like this,
you bring your money !
-How do l know you won't take a powder ?
-No, no, no, no. Now !
l'll tell you what l'll do.
l'll send a boy around
to your room in five minutes.
You better have the money, or it's gonna
be all around Chicago that you welched.
You won't be able
to get a game of jacks !
Cash me in
for the rest of these bums.
[ Sighs ]
You're on, kid.
But l gotta tell you,
it's a hard act to follow.
- How'd it go ?
- We got working money.
- Hey ?
- Yeah ?
- He's steamin'.
- Yeah.
Watch yourself.
[ Floyd ]
Doyle, l know l gave him four threes !
He had to make a switch !
We can't let him
get away with that.
What was l supposed to do ?
Call him for cheating better than me ?
[ Knocks On Door ]
Name's Kelly.
Shaw sent me.
Your boss is quite a card player,
Mr. Kelly.
- How does he do it ?
- He cheats.
Well, in that case, l'll keep my money,
and we'll have another game.
You don't have any to keep.
Here's your wallet.
He hired a dame to take it from you.
Shaw's been plannin'
to beat your game for months.
He's been waiting for you to cheat him
so he could clip you.
[ Grunting ]
Who do you think you're talking to,
errand boy ? Nobody sets me up !
Take him back to the baggage room !
Put one in his ear !
- [ Floyd ] There were four witnesses
at that table !
- Then go back,
get that other goddamn son of a bitch
and dump 'em in the first tunnel we hit.
We're gonna be in the station
in a couple of minutes !
lt ain't gonna look too good
killing a guy you owe money to.
[ Panting ]
There's better ways of takin' him down.
What do you think Shaw would do
if he knew l was tellin' you this ?
Okay.
Why the rat ?
l wanna take over his operation,
and l need you to help me break him.
- Where's my money ?
- Shaw's got it.
How the hell
could l ask him for it back ?
- [ Knocks ]
- We're pullin' in.
l'm givin' you a lift home.
- l was supposed to go with Shaw.
- Explain it to him somehow.
- But he's expecting me.
- l'm givin' you a lift home.
You follow ?
Yeah, sure.
Sure thing.
[ Car Horn Honking ]
- [ Honking Continues ]
- [ Car Doors Closing ]
What makes you think
you can beat him ?
l've been planning this
for two years.
l know his organization
backwards and forwards,
and l need somebody who's respectable
but not completely legit.
l'm a banker, Kelly.
That's legit in this state.
All you gotta do is put down
a bet for me at Shaw's place.
l'll do the rest.
l'll supply the money.
l'll supply the information.
- What about the money
you come to collect ?
- l'll tell him you paid it.
l keep his books.
He trusts me.
lf you help me, l'll pay back the money
he stole out of my own pocket.
- lt's worth that much to you ?
- Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Maybe a couple of million.
Where do you come from, Kelly ?
From the east side of New York.
A place called Five Points.
- But l got out of there.
- Out and up, huh ?
Hey, Floyd ?
l'm gonna have to keep you away from
this guy. You're liable to get ideas.
l'll be at Klein's Drug Store,
660 South Marshall at 1:30,
if you're interested.
lf l'm not there
by quarter to 2:00, l'm not comin'.
[ Gunshot ]
Hey, Hooker, how'd it go ?
Jake.
- Everything go okay ?
- Yeah, sure. Hell, easy.
- No sign of trouble, huh ?
- No.
- What about Lonnegan ?
- l gave him the breakdown
just like you said.
- And ?
- He's good. He threatened to kill me.
Hell, kid, if they don't do that,
you know you're not gettin' to 'em.
Hello, Doyle.
All right, Riley,
what the hell happened ?
We missed him.
Whoever he is,
he made a fool out of you.
There was no way he could've
known we was in that room.
Somebody must've wised him up.
What does Cole say about that ?
l don't know.
He took it hard.
Get out of here, Riley.
Put Salino onto it.
Salino ? Why waste our best people
on a small-time job ?
This is a nickel-and-dime grifter
we're after, Doyle.
- They'll get him next time.
- They had their chance.
All they did was shoot up
a neighborhood, wake up a few cops.
- Yeah, but--
- l told you to put Salino onto it.
lt may take a little more time,
but there won't be any holes.
Tell Cole l wanna see him
when he comes in.
He won't be comin' in;
not to get bounced off a job anyway.
This is Salino's job, Vince.
Cole wants to muscle in,
that's his business.
But he's breakin' the rules and Salino
won't like it. Now, get me the books.
[ Cash Register Rings ]
[ Men Chattering ]
[ J.J. ]
Those odds on the third race are wrong.
Just a minute.
l'll get 'em.
Don't worry so much.
You're gonna be all right.
Just stay to the back
the first time around.
Put a little of this
on your nose.
[ Lonnegan ]
Kelly ?
You should always look
to the back, kid.
l was afraid you wasn't gonna show.
We haven't got much time.
Get on with it then.
Sometime after 2:00,
a guy's gonna call on that phone
and give you the name of a horse.
All you gotta do is take this
two grand across the street...
to Shaw's place,
and bet it on that pony.
Don't take too much time. We've only got
four minutes after you get the call.
You'll not break him
with a $2,000 bet.
This is just a test.
The big one comes later.
Be careful with that.
That's all l got.
- You were gonna pay me back
out of your own pocket ?
- l am.
After the race.
l gotta get back before Shaw misses me.
Good luck.
[ Quiet Chatter ]
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Twist ]
Yeah ? Go ahead.
[ Woman's Voice On Phone ]
The horse is Blue Note to win.
- Fourth race at Narragansett.
- Got it.
[ Hangs Up Receiver ]
[ Dialing ]
[ Ringing ]
Yeah ?
Blue Note to win in the fourth race
at Narragansett.
[ J.J. On Speakers ] Turning for home,
it's Lady Scout by a length.
Speed Queen a half,
Lady Trust and Miss Petrina.
lnto the stretch, it's Lady Scout ahead,
Speed Queen a half.
- And at the wire,
it's Speed Queen the winner !
- [ Cheering ]
Lady Scout placed
and Miss Petrina showed.
Post numbers
two, five and one.
Taking off at 23.
Look at that.
He's got his apes with him.
Yeah, we're gonna have to
do something about that.
[ J.J. ]
Bubblesome is 10, Beefsteak, 7,
Vote Boy, 6,
Kerry Patch, 12.
Blue Note is 7 to 1.
This is your last call
for the third race at Lincoln Fields.
They're going to the post.
- You may still wager if you hurry.
- There he goes.
At Detroit, the winner,
Speed Queen, paid $7.20,
4.60 and 3.40.
Lady Scout,
$7 and 4.20.
Miss Petrina
paid four dollars.
Last flash at Narragansett.
Lady Higloss, 6 to 5.
l'd think you'd get tired
of losing, Harrigan.
[ Cashier ]
Thank you, Mr. Williams.
Blue Note, $2,000 to win.
Fourth race, Narragansett.
Make sure you see the cash, Eddie.
He's got a name for bettin' money
he doesn't have.
[ J.J. ] We'll give you the results
on that one in a minute.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Arnold Rowe,
your caller for the fourth race.
The mile and one-sixteenth handicap
at Narragansett Park, Rhode lsland.
Thirteen thousand dollars
added for three-year-olds and up.
The flag is up,
and they're off and running.
lt's Bubblesome going to the front,
followed by Lady Higloss,
Vote Boy, Chancing,
Beefsteak, Kerry Patch,
and Blue Note trails the field.
Around the clubhouse turn,
it's Bubblesome ahead,
Chancing a half,
Lady Higloss by one,
followed by Vote Boy, Beefsteak,
Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
lnto the second turn,
it's Chancing by a length.
Lady Higloss driving
on the rail and Vote Boy...
followed by Bubblesome, Beefsteak,
Kerry Patch and Blue Note.
- Come on, Chancing !
- Hey, uh--
Lady Higloss a half,
Vote Boy by one.
Lady Higloss is a hell of a finisher.
Chancing's gonna have to open up.
Know anything about a horse
named Blue Note ?
He never done much. Probably in there
just to round out the field.
Chancing's where you
want to have your money.
Great tip you handed me, kid.
- Just give him time.
- [ J.J. ] Chancing by one.
And here comes Blue Note
driving on the outside !
- Nice work, Erie. He loves ya.
- He's third !
Chancing is shortening stride,
and now it's Lady Higloss and Blue Note.
They're head to head.
They're neck and neck.
lt's Lady Higloss, Blue Note;
Lady Higloss, Blue Note.
And Blue Note wins it by a nose !
Lady Higloss is second by three,
and Chancing is third by one.
Who in the blazes is Blue Note ?
The winner, Blue Note,
paid $16, 9.40 and $6.
So you want to have
your money on Chancing, huh ?
[ J.J. ]
Chancing paid 3.80.
Time for the mile and 1/16th:
1:44 and 1.
[ J.J. ]
They're going to the gate at Belmont.
And here are the late odds.
Those garbagemen belong to you ?
Get 'em out of here and don't
bring 'em back. This is a class joint.
- Hey, you, Kelly !
- Yes, sir ?
Run those bums out of here.
- Uh, Mr. Shaw, could l--
- Don't give me any of your lip, kid.
Now, run 'em out of here.
[ Sighs ]
Uh--
[ J.J. ] Time for
the three-quarter mile: 1:11 and 4.
The winner, Panic Relief,
paid 12.40, 8.20 and $5.
Barbara A., 6.20 and 4.
Wilder paid four dollars.
They're at the post
at Belmont at 38.
We're waiting on one.
l'll call Belmont next.
- That's it, fellas !
- [ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
- l wanna repeat that--
- All right, J.J.
[ Sighs ]
What do you say, pal ?
[ Rings ]
Yeah ? Mm-hmm.
He's on his way.
Hi, Mutt.
Say, Jeff.
- What'd l tell you ?
- You got lucky once.
That's not enough.
Ah, lucky, hell.
l can do it every time.
- Why don't you then ?
- 'Cause it's better
to do it all at once.
We're gonna put down
400 grand next week.
At five-to-one odds,
that's two million.
- Twenty percent is yours.
- Got a system, Kelly ?
No. You can still lose
with a system.
You're past-posting, aren't you ?
Could be.
- How ?
- You're gonna stay in ?
Not 'til l get some answers.
l got a partner downtown.
He runs the central office
of the Western Union.
Race results from all over
the country come in and go
across his desk to the bookies.
All he does is hold 'em up 'til he can
call us, get a bet down on the winner.
Then he releases the results
to the bookies.
We clean up on a race that's
already been run. You can't miss.
Unless the Western Union dicks
get ahold of it.
You got the 400 grand yet ?
No, not yet, but--
- There's only a grand here.
- Make another bet tomorrow.
Where's my money ?
- l got 16 grand coming.
- You owe me 15 grand already.
lf your setup's as good as you say
it is, there's plenty more to come.
l decide when to place the bets !
Not if you want me
to keep making 'em.
l gotta talk to my partner.
We can't afford to expose too much.
- l'll talk to him myself.
- No !
You've been waiting
a long time for this.
Don't ruin it for yourself.
l'll pick you up tomorrow
at 3:00. You follow ?
Twist, l told him the tale,
but he didn't go for it.
He wants to see my partner
tomorrow at 3:00.
- 3:00 ?
- Yeah.
We'll never get a telegraph
store set up. Any chance
of talking him out of it ?
None. l would've stalled him, but l
didn't have many friends in the room.
Yeah. All right, we'll have to
play him on the fly.
l'll get Eddie looking
for a place.
- Let me know when you got something.
- Sure thing, tootsie.
All right, Hooker !
[ Grunts ]
Stop him !
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Train Passing Overhead ]
- [ People Grumbling ]
- [ Man ] Hey !
Hooker ! Hooker !
l'll get you, you rat !
Hooker !
Why didn't you tell me
about Snyder before ?
- l thought l'd lost him.
- You found him again.
We're gonna have to
do something about it.
-What else haven't you been telling me ?
-Nothin'. That's all.
Hold still.
Why'd you move out of your room ?
lt was too noisy.
You can't play your friends
like marks, Hooker.
You know how easy it would be
for Lonnegan's guys to get you ?
All we need
is a couple of days...
and we can get
the son of a bitch and nail him.
[ Exhales ]
You just won't learn, will ya ?
l come in here, teach you stuff
that maybe five guys in the world know;
stuff most grifters
couldn't do even if they knew it.
- All you wanna do is run down a bullet.
- l'm askin' a couple of days.
l can stay clear that long !
Christ, they'll probably
miss you and hit me.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- [ Sneezes ]
- What'll you have ?
Give me
the, uh, blue plate special.
One blue plate special.
[ Cash Register Rings ]
- You're done ?
- Yeah.
- Guess l should've had the meat loaf.
- lt isn't any better.
- Hey, where's June ?
- She quit.
l'm fillin' in for her
a couple of days...
until l can get a train
out of here.
Yeah ?
Where are you going ?
l don't know.
Depends on what train l get on.
- Keep it.
- Thanks.
Let's go.
Excuse me, ma'am,
but we're looking for Mr., uh--
- Harmon.
- Uh, Mr. Harmon's office.
- Mr. Harmon ?
- Yeah. Got a work order
for a painting job.
- For Mr. Harmon's office ?
- That's right, ma'am.
Well, hold on.
Just a second.
[ Knocks On Door,
Door Opens ]
Hiya.
- Where to ?
- 110 South Wabash.
110 South Wabash.
Get going.
What happened to your face ?
Ah, got into a fight
with a raggle down on 13th.
Cut me with her ring.
You oughta lay off the skirts.
You don't find any of my boys
messin' around with that kind of trash.
Brigham signed it, all right. l can't
understand why he didn't tell me.
Ah, he's like all
them supervisors.
They think they're
too good for regular people.
He says he was in here awhile ago
and the place was a mess.
[ Twist ] We'll hurry
so we don't keep you out too long.
Why can't l work
with you in here ?
We gotta cover the floor,
the furniture, everything,
so we don't spill on nothin'.
lf you want to sit in here with a tarp
over your head, you're welcome to it.
- How long will you be ?
- An hour or two at the most.
lt's a small job.
We'll go in the side door here.
[ Knocks ]
Hiya, Les.
Uh, Les, this is Doyle Lonnegan.
- Mr. Lonnegan, this is Les Harmon.
- How do you do ?
- Could we, uh--
- What did you bring him here for ?
l thought it would be a good idea
for him to see the operation.
l'm having the place painted.
We can't talk in here now.
Oh.
We'll have to find someplace else.
Excuse me, Mr. Lonnegan.
Miss Barnes,
l'm going home a little early.
lf there are any calls, tell them
they can reach me here tomorrow morning.
Mr. Lonnegan ?
l wanna see it one more time.
l can't do it. We got
telegraph inspectors all over the place.
One more time isn't gonna
make much difference.
We got 400 grand
coming in from the coast next week.
You gonna risk that
on a lousy 15 G's ?
lf it works again tomorrow,
l'll finance the whole thing.
Half a million dollars.
Sixty-forty, we split.
What are you talking-- We've already
got a guy. He's gonna give us half.
- What am l supposed to say to him ?
- Say to him what you want.
What l know about your operation,
if l were you,
l'd be worried
about making me happy.
Your guy says a week.
How do we know it won't be a month ?
Lonnegan here's a banker. He can get
the money without any questions asked.
We can't keep goin' into Shaw's place
and cleanin' up on long shots.
- He's bound to get wise.
- All right. We'll go for short odds.
- But it's still--
- You follow ?
Are you
Lieutenant William Snyder ?
l don't know.
What's up ?
F.B.l.
Special Agent Polk
would like a few words with you.
You got a couple of minutes ?
Yeah, sure.
No, no, no.
lt's got to be south of the river.
Probably this section in here.
31st, 39th, Morgan and Halstead.
Now, that's this section here.
Now, let's break it
into two sections along 35th.
What the hell is this ?
l got work to do.
Sit down and shut up, will ya ?
Try not to live up
to all my expectations.
Take two men with you.
Work your way south from 31st
to 35th, Morgan and Halstead.
Go into every place
and let me know what you find.
We've been told you know
a hustle artist named Johnny Hooker.
- You know him, or don't you ?
- Yeah, but l don't know where he is.
Well, we do. He's chumming around
with a big C named Henry Gondorff.
Ring any bells ?
Every bunco man in the country
knows Gondorff.
Well, there's word he's gonna run a con
on the South Side here.
We've got a year-old Florida warrant
on him, but it's a thin beef.
He can beat it in court
unless we catch him cold.
All we want you to do
is pick up Hooker for us.
Why don't you
pick him up yourself ?
lf word gets out the feds are in on it,
Gondorff will fold up the whole thing.
Wouldn't that be too bad.
Then you'd have to move
out of this nice office you've got here.
Don't crack wise with me, flatfoot.
l spent too much time in dumps like this
eating Gondorff's dust...
while you guys in the bunco squads
get rich tipping him off !
That's not gonna happen
this time.
We're not gonna tell
the police we're here.
You keep your mouth shut and do a job,
there'll be reward bucks in it for you.
And you better take it, 'cause l
can make you work for us without it.
What the hell good
is Hooker to you ?
He's gonna set up Gondorff for us.
- He'll never do it.
- l think he will.
[ Buzzing ]
He's there.
Let's get on it.
What's the line on Exponent ?
Uh... 5 to 1. Aah.
- How's it going ?
- Ah, nothing yet.
l had a good one on the lead
at Lincoln Fields, but he faded.
Best we had the last hour
was Love Potion at Rockingham,
and she was 5 to 1.
All the long shots
coming in today.
Take 4 to 1 if you have to.
Okay.
[ Henry ]
You can forget the boodle, Eddie.
He could hit us for 15 grand at 4 to 1.
We can't handle that.
- Give him the shutout.
- Okay.
Okay, Billie, here we go.
At the wire, it's Wrecking Crew,
the winner by five.
Black Mischief, second;
Whichaway, third.
Wrecking Crew was... 3 to 1.
That's our boy.
Yeah.
Henry ?
Here we go, Henry. We got
a 3 to 1 at Belmont-- Wrecking Crew.
[ Phone Ringing ]
Yeah ?
All right. Okay.
[ Phone Rings ]
- Yeah ?
- ln the sixth race at Belmont.
Wrecking Crew to win;
Black Mischief to place;
Whichaway to show.
Wait here.
[ J.J. ] The winner,
Time To Go, paid seven dollars,
5.40 and 3.80.
Joy Flag, $6 and 4.20.
- Readily paid 3.80 to show.
- [ Phone Ringing ]
The weather's threatening, but the track
is fast there in Salem, New Hampshire.
[ Ringing Continues ]
Here's a late jockey change
there in the fifth at Rockingham.
R.C. Stark will ride
ltsie-Bitsie.
- Thank you, sir.
- That's R.C. Stark.
Five thousand on Black Mischief,
across the board.
Sixth at Belmont.
Would you hurry up there, please ?
[ J.J. ] Wrecking Crew is 3 to 1;
Vale Of Tears, four;
Black Mischief, five;
Whichaway, six;
Chief Yeoman, 12;
Peerless Pal is 20;
and Mariato is, uh, 40.
And here we go
for the sixth at Belmont.
lt's five and a half furlongs.
They're at the post.
- Now.
- The flag is up.
- And they're off !
- Sixth race, Belmont, 15,000.
Excuse me, sir. We can't take
any bets once the race is started.
You can bet on another race
if you care to.
[ J.J. ] Going into the backstretch,
it's Wrecking Crew by two.
Whichaway a half, Black Mischief and
Vale Of Tears driving on the outside.
- Nothin', thank you.
- What happened ?
l didn't get the bet
down in time.
Jesus !
[ J.J. ] Heading for home,
it's Wrecking Crew all alone
by six lengths,
Whichaway a length,
and Vale of Tears.
lt's Wrecking Crew,
Whichaway and Black Mischief.
And at the wire, Wrecking Crew
wins it by six lengths.
Black Mischief is second
by a head, Whichaway is third,
followed by Vale Of Tears.
You should've had your money
on Wrecking Crew.
[ J.J. ] lt's raining and the track
is sloppy at Riverside Park.
There's a late scratch there.
Transmutate is scratched
in the fifth at Riverside.
At Belmont,
the winner, Wrecking Crew,
paid $6, 4.20 and 2.80.
Black Mischief,
4.60 and 3.20.
l'll have half a million
here by post time tomorrow.
Lay it on the first race
where the odds are 4 to 1 or better.
- Make sure l get
to the window this time.
- How am l gonna do that ?
l don't know.
Figure it out for yourself, Kelly.
- [ Clears Throat ]
- Finished ?
Yeah. Meat loaf, apple pie
and a cup of coffee.
- Say, what time you get off work here ?
- 2:00 a.m.
- Yeah ? Doing anything tonight ?
- Yeah. Sleepin'.
Eighty-five.
[ Rings ]
- You got a back door to this place ?
- What's wrong with the front ?
There's a guy out there
l don't need to see. Don't look around.
- What does he want ?
- He'd like to kill me.
Do me a favor. Go into the bathroom,
open the window and wait there.
- Why should l--
- Do what l tell you,
and everything will be jake.
Please.
Thanks.
Good night.
[ Woman ]
lt's taken.
Thanks. See ya.
Shit.
Salino.
Hey, l wasn't--
Hey ! Gotcha, Hooker !
Hey there, Snyder.
Long time no see.
Get goin' !
Chuck,
get this off
to the department right away.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Hooker.
Take them off.
Special Agent Polk, F.B.l.
- [ Sighs ]
- Have a chair.
- You want a drink or something ?
- No.
We want to talk to you
about Henry Gondorff.
Yeah ?
l don't think l know him.
Give yourself a couple of seconds.
You wouldn't want to lie to me.
Lt. Snyder here says you've done
a lot of confidence work in his town.
Oh, yeah ?
Lt. Snyder doesn't know shit.
- You ain't got nothin' on me.
- Yeah ?
How 'bout counterfeiting ?
We've got a tip that Gondorff is gonna
run a con on the South Side here.
All you've gotta do is tell us
when he's gonna play his chump.
We come in at the sting,
make the pinch, and...
you walk out
free as a bird.
No.
You wanna spend the next 20 years
in a federal penitentiary...
starting tonight ?
l'll make parole.
Like hell.
You won't even get a review.
l'll chance it.
Okay. lf that's
the way you want it.
We might even provide you with a little
company on your way up the river.
That wife of Luther Coleman's--
what was her name ?
- Alva.
That's it.
Alva Coleman.
Pretty fair grifter
in her time.
Snyder's given us
quite a folder on her.
Nothing major by itself,
but, uh,
put 'em all together,
it could add up to a lot of years.
- You stink, mister.
- Don't be a sap.
lt's not her l want.
lf you're too dumb
to save yourself,
there's no sense
dragging her down with ya.
lt's over, Hooker.
You can save me
a lot of trouble.
But l'm gonna get Henry Gondorff
whether you help me out or not.
- Will you wait
'til the chump is played ?
- Hell, yes.
We don't care about the mark.
He deserves what he gets.
l mean completely played. You come in
before we beat him, and l'll kill him.
All right, Hooker.
But you try to take it on the lam,
and we'll shoot you down on sight.
As long as l get
to finish the play.
[ Sighs ]
What is it, kid ?
You're not saying much.
- Just got the jumps.
- [ Knocking ]
- Come in.
Things are a little slow.
l wanna open the round for the girls.
Sure.
Take it easy, kid.
We're not gonna lose him now.
We had him ten years ago
when he decided to be somebody.
Believe me, l've seen
enough to know. Ten.
- Twenty.
- Thirty.
- Go.
- Thirty-one.
Aagh.
How many guys you conned
in your life, Henry ?
l don't know.
Two, three hundred.
Sometimes we played two a day
when l was with O'Shea's mob.
Of course,
Chicago was a rigged town.
The fix was in; the dicks
took their end without a beef.
We had it down to a business.
[ Chuckles ]
And it really stunk, kid.
No sense in bein' a grifter if it's
the same thing as bein' a citizen.
l got packin' to do. l'm gonna be
a hot number again after tomorrow.
.. [ Calliope ]
l wouldn't ask you to do this, you know,
if it weren't for Luther.
Nothin's gonna make up for Luther.
Revenge is for suckers.
l've been griftin' 30 years.
l never got any.
Then why're you doin' it ?
lt seems worthwhile,
doesn't it ?
See ya.
- .. [ Calliope Continues ]
- [ Women Shouting ]
[ Door Closes ]
Looks like he missed you.
Yeah, yeah.
This time, anyway.
Good night, Mrs. Hillard.
l was wonderin' if you might
want to come out for a while,
maybe have a drink
or something.
You move right along, don't you ?
Hey, l don't mean nothin' by it.
l just don't know many
regular girls, is all.
And you expect me
to come out just like that ?
lf l expected somethin', l wouldn't
still be standin' here in the hall.
l don't even know you.
You know me.
l'm just like you.
lt's 2:00 in the morning,
and l don't know nobody.
Come on, Henry.
Knock off.
- You've done everything you can.
- Hmm.
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Train Rumbling ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Cash Register Rings ]
[ Rings ]
- Yeah ? Polk.
- Polk, this is Hooker.
- Ready ?
- Yeah, go ahead.
Everything's all set.
There'll be a guy or two at the door.
Nobody's carrying any heaters,
so you shouldn't have any trouble.
Okay. See you there.
She was gonna kill you, kid.
Her name's Loretta Salino.
Lonnegan's people set her up
in the diner. Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Come on !
She could have killed me last night.
Too many people could have
seen you go in her room.
She was a real professional.
Used to work in the Dutch Schultz mob.
Who are you ?
Gondorff asked me
to look after you.
Snyder, we just got a tip
that Gondorff's mark...
is some big New York wheel.
As soon as we're inside,
you get him out of there fast...
before the reporters show up.
l don't want any big shots around
to mess this up for me.
All right, let's go !
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Buzzing ]
Let's go, guys !
The flag is up, kid.
- Anytime, J.J.
- l'm workin' on it.
We got one, Billie.
Here we go.
[ Phone Ringing ]
- Yeah ?
- Place it on Lucky Dan,
third race at Riverside Park.
[ J.J. ]
1:11 and 3/5ths seconds.
They were off at 21.
Last call on the third
at Riverside Park.
They're at the post.
At Havre De Grace,
the winner, Light Chatter,
paid, uh, 5.40, 3.80...
and 2.40.
- Blacksod--
- $500,000 to win.
Lucky Dan,
third race at Riverside.
- [ J.J.] Post time
for the third race...
- You heard me.
- is 2:27.
- Hold on, sir.
- There's a jockey change...
- l'll get the manager.
in the fourth at Belmont.
Jay Stout will ride Flying Cross.
See that guy over there ? He just bet
a half million dollars on Lucky Dan.
[ J.J. ]
The winner at Rockingham Park,
Enfin, paid 6.10,
4.30 and 2.50.
What's your problem ?
l'm putting half a million
dollars on Lucky Dan to win,
third race at Riverside.
Can't lay that off in time.
A bet like that could break us.
Not only are you a cheat,
you're a gutless cheat as well.
- What are the odds ?
- Four to one.
Take all of it.
[ People Murmuring ]
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is Arnold Rowe calling
the third race at Riverside.
This is a claiming race
for $1,500 for three-year-olds and up.
lt's been raining,
and the track is muddy.
The flag is up,
and they're off and running.
Dr. Twink is going to the front,
followed by Lucky Dan,
lma Dreamer, Orkin,
Josie G., Chi Chi
and Little Star.
Around the clubhouse turn,
it's Lucky Dan ahead,
- Dr. Twink a length, Orkin a half,
- [ Shouting ]
followed by lma Dreamer,
Josie G., Chi Chi and Little Star.
lnto the backstretch,
it's Lucky Dan a length,
Dr. Twink a half,
Orkin a head,
lma Dreamer by one.
Sorry, l couldn't wait.
Everything going all right ?
You got nothing
to worry about.
- Dr. Twink a length, Orkin a half.
- l put it all on Lucky Dan.
Half a million dollars to win.
- lnto the far turn,
Lucky Dan still a length.
- To win ?
l said place !
Place it on Lucky--
That horse is gonna run second !
lma Dreamer a half, Dr. Twink a half and
Orkin by two, followed by Little Star.
lt's a driving finish !
- There's been a mistake.
Give me my money back !
- No, l'm sorry--
l tell you there's been a mistake !
Give me my goddamn money back !
All right, everybody. F.B.l. !
Don't anybody try to leave.
Stand on your feet, put your hands
over your head and move nice and slow.
Snyder !
Get 'em up against the wall.
Make sure they're not carrying anything.
Hello, Henry.
lt's been a long time.
But it's over.
Okay, kid, you can go.
[ Polk ] All right,
l said hands up. Keep 'em up !
Come on. Move 'em back !
Put 'em up !
[ People Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Get him out.
Get him out !
Come on !
Gotta get you out of here !
- Come on !
- But my money's in there !
There's a couple
of dead guys in there too.
You can't get mixed up in that.
You don't understand. There's
a half a million dollars in there !
He's gone.
Okay, Henry, all clear.
[ Laughter ]
Can you believe it ?
We pulled it off.
lt's a nice con, Hickey. l thought you
were the feds myself when you came in.
No trouble, Henry.
Snyder went for it all the way.
You should've seen the rag
he lit under Lonnegan !
Well, kid, you beat him.
You're right, Henry.
lt's not enough.
But it's close.
Okay, guys,
let's take this place apart fast.
You can pick up your splits from Eddie
at Boudreau's tonight.
Nice goin', J.J.
Ohh, Henry !
[ Man ] Comin' through.
Comin' through.
You're not gonna stick around
for your share ?
Nah. l'd only blow it.
[ Man ] One, two.
One, two, three.
.. [ Band Playing Ragtime ]