What's that?
Ah, it's nothin'.
Does Jenny know?
I'm the man of my house, Tom.
I don't have to hide things
from my wife.
I won't tell her.
I appreciate it.
Try this.
The nicotine's not your problem.
It's your oral fixation.
You just need
something else to suck on.
I read it in some magazine.
What kind of magazines
you been reading?
Easy.
A man's gotta be able
to have something of his own.
How many shooters you count?
Five, six.
Somebody tipped them off.
All I know is we just lost
two whole fucking years of work.
Want to take a look?
As long as it's just a look. On three.
Three.
Son of a bitch.
Hey Tom. Backup's on its way.
FBI! Freeze! Tom!
Jesus Christ!
Don't jump off!
No!
John! You all right?
Yeah.
Come on.
Did you get him?
I got him.
You sure?
He took one in the face.
He's dead. Relax.
Hey, the morgue's full of people who
thought they got that son of a bitch.
What are you talking about, John?
You sound like you know this guy.
Yeah, but there's talk the Yakuza
hired a rogue independent contractor
to deal with the Triads.
He's supposed to be the best.
The same guy the CIA used
in Jakarta that time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The same guy that turned on his
handlers and then killed three agents.
I heard it was five.
That's a bullshit story, John.
You know that, all right?
The Rogue's a phantom; he's a myth.
Somebody at the Agency's
yanking your chain.
Titanium shells.
The penetrating bullets.
It was his signature.
You really think
Rogue was working for Yakuza?
That's the trouble with this business.
You never know who's working for who.
This is the San Francisco Police.
Remain where you are
with your hands in the air.
Yeah, he's right here,
he's right here, John.
Hang... yeah, see you soon.
Okay. Bye-bye.
[In Chinese] You tell him that
he cannot smoke in front of the kids.
If he's going to smoke
he can do it in the yard.
Okay.
I thought he was quitting it.
I thought he was, too.
Yo, Tom.
I gotcha!
Uh, Daniel, please.
- Danny, Danny. I'm on the phone.
- Daniel, come on. Come on.
You'd better be on the road.
Game starts in thirty.
I'm running a little behind.
Figure if we don't hit traffic,
we'll make it up there by half-time.
John.
It's an oral fixation.
Ecch! Hey. Come on.
Get your coat.
So uh, how's the case going?
Look forget about the case.
Enjoy your sick leave.
Any ideas who blew the op?
No. Investigation's underway.
So far... zip.
Somebody talked.
Somebody inside. Close to us.
Any word on what happened to Rogue?
No, we never found a body.
They dragged that bay
for three days and nothing.
And he's fish food by now.
Okay.
Well, it's game day, right?
Yeah, I know it's game day.
Just tell me you haven't
forgot the steaks, okay?
No, asshole,
I didn't forget the steaks.
Christ, when are you
going to let that go?
Diane asked me to check.
You know she also asked me to...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I heard.
No smoking in front of the kids.
Honey, we got to stop off
and get some steaks.
Diane, they here yet?
Please.
Diane, what was that?
Diane.
Oh please!
Don't! No!
No!
John. John! Honey.
Honey. Honey.
Oh, my God!
Stay with Daniel, honey.
Hey, where do you
think you're going?
What the hell happened?
I'm gonna have to...
We got three fatalities.
What?
One male, one female, and one child.
Hey, wait a minute, pal. FBI or not...
Sir, CSI needs to finish.
We gotta let them do their thing.
Sir? You gotta clear out of here now.
SAN FRANCISCO
THREE YEARS LATER
CLUB ZERO
YAKUZA DISTRICT
Hey, baby. How're you doing?
[In Japanese] Get him!
Kimo!
Daito, heel
What the fuck!
Rogue do you know
what Shiro does to traitors?
Wow! These Japs sure
know how to party, huh?
Yeah. Smells like a deli in here.
Oh, shut up, Gleason.
You see all this ink?
Japanese Yakuza.
Each one of those rings...
is supposed to represent
some poor bastard they've killed.
These are some
bad ass characters here.
Yep. What's that make the people
who did this to them?
Make a hole.
Get these people out of here.
And just who the hell are you?
Asian Organized Crime Unit.
We'll be taking over from here.
On whose authority?
Mayor. President.
Take your pick.
- You don't look very Asian to me.
You know, I'm amazed you two don't have
this whole case wrapped up by now.
Check these yet, Einstein?
Yeah. Someone cut the feeds.
There's nothing on there.
Agent Crawford found these
in the back room.
We found him hiding
underneath one of the dead bodies.
He's in pretty bad shape.
Yeah, what's he been saying?
You're kidding me, right?
Who can understand that shit?
Some people come into this country...
you'd think they'd at least
learn to speak American.
You'd think a couple of cops
working a district...
that's crawling with Yakuza
might learn to speak a little Japanese.
[In Japanese] If they weren't complete fucking idiots.
Give me a minute here would you?
Hi. I'm a cop. What happened here?
Know what I do when I'm not a cop?
I play doctor.
Hey! You can't do that.
If I don't get this shrapnel out
it will get infected.
I got it. No, it's a bone. Sorry.
If you want me
to go back to my day job...
Give me something to do!
I want to die before he comes back.
Well...
I can see it's gonna be
a real picnic working with you.
You're not working with me.
This is the FBI's case now.
You want to help,
take my shirts to the cleaners.
So what'd he say?
Ah, a bunch of
Japanese mumbo jumbo.
Vengeful spirits.
Ghost stories
Jen?
Yeah, did I wake you?
It's almost nine.
Oh, no,
I was working late last night, that's all.
Oh, well, I just called to remind you
that it's Daniel's first
basketball game this Friday.
You forgot, didn't you?
No.
- I've just been tied up with work.
- See ya.
I've got a lot on my mind right now.
Yeah, so what's it this time?
I've found him, Jen.
Found who?
The guy who killed Tom.
He's back.
I can feel it.
This time I'm taking him down.
John, it's been three years.
Look, your obsession with
this man has cost you our marriage.
Don't lose your son.
Tell Daniel I'll be there.
No, you tell him!
And if you say you're gonna be there,
then be there.
Those of you who didn't get to meet
last night, this is Agent Goi.
Just graduated Quantico.
What's his specs?
Oxford.
What's so funny?
In otherwords, you're a spectator.
What about you?
D.T.
Defensive Tactics.
That's right.
I like to get up close and personal.
Yeah, well, my gun's bigger than yours.
Pick a desk.
Still getting set up here ourselves.
The back of the bus.
These are all the photos
anybody has of Rogue.
Bastard re-cuts his face
every six months.
Come on, John, anybody can use
titanium shells and DU bullets.
The ones we found-
The ones we found last night matched
the ones we found three years ago.
Rogue's back.
Okay, but if he works for the Yakuza
why would he kill Yakuza?
Maybe he switched sides.
Wouldn't be the first time.
What sides are we talking about?
Shiro Yanagawa.
Fronts all Yakuza activity from Japan.
Probably the most
powerful man in San Francisco
and yet he's never even
set foot on American soil.
He's half the reason this task force
was put together.
Li Chang is the other half.
Unlike Shiro, Chang lives here.
Nice big mansion in Marin.
Thinks he's J.D. Rockefeller
or something.
He's a Four-Eighty-Nine.
Triad boss.
Into everything. Bribery, extortion,
murder, you name it.
But years ago
Shiro butchered Chang's family.
Actually had the balls
to fly over to Hong Kong,
and wipe out the whole fucking clan.
He spent the next thirty years
selling every
heirloom in Chang Dynasty
to collectors' museums.
All that's left now is a couple of horses.
Statuettes. Two of them.
About this big.
Word on the street is that Shiro is
looking for a buyer as we speak.
Chang's loss of honor
means more than his financial loss.
I don't care about the horses.
I don't care about blood lines
or ancient family feuds.
First time in three years
we got a real shot at getting Rogue.
All we have to do, ladies and
gentlemen, is pull the fucking trigger.
CHANG MANSION
MARIN COUNTY, CA
She's a very rare breed.
Andalusian. That's my wife, Maria.
In my father's day, such a union
would not have been possible.
But times change. Those of us
who change with it survive.
Come.
I am really impressed, Mr Shaw.
Now that you have spilled
the blood of my enemies...
let's drink to our new partnership.
I have to admit...
I was somewhat skeptical when you
first came to me with your proposal.
- By leaving Shiro's service...
- That was a wise move on your part.
But it makes me wonder.
How could one truly trust a man
who has betrayed his master?
I have no master.
So I have betrayed no one.
So, tell me...
My horses, they arrive tonight?
It's been thirty years.
All this time my family
has lived in shame and dishonor.
All because of Shiro's treachery.
Tonight, I will take back
what was stolen from my family...
and everything
will change from here on.
Shiro's men will protect his
treasure with their lives.
Are you certain you can deliver them?
I said I would.
These two are the Ti brothers.
They will give you everything you need.
I'll be in touch.
Watch him closely.
SHIRO'S ESTATE
YAKUZA COMPOUND
TO-DAI, JAPAN
[In Japanese] I beg your forgiveness.
The fault is not yours, but mine.
I left myself unguarded.
I trust you have
news from San Francisco...
Yes, everything is
proceeding as requested.
...and the Horses?
We've shipped them out.
They will arrive
in San Francisco tonight.
You must return to San Francisco
in advance of my arrival.
But, Father...
I don't trust our people there.
They have become
too lazy to be useful.
I was hoping to stay here
and further my role in the clan.
Nothing in the history of our clan
has ever been more important.
I will not fail you.
Go now.
Oversee the sale of the Horses.
CHINA TOWN
SAN FRANCISCO
Hey, what's up, dude?
I need to see Benny.
No Bennys here.
Again!
What are you doing?
No!
Yeah!
Again!
Come one. Oww! Ooh!
Hey, babe.
We need to talk.
Cabron, I don't talk to the Feds.
Go!
Somewhere private.
Now.
Okay.
My guy's losing anyway, so...
I'm paying for this shit. Come on!
Business is good, I see.
Yeah. So much
for Homeland Security, right?
So how's the family?
Daniel's fine. But Jen.
That's another story.
Yeah, I really like her. I mean,
how could you fuck that up?
Well, it wasn't hard.
By the way, thanks for that out there.
Made me look good.
Well, hope it helps.
Yeah, well, the people I'm tracking,
they expect the FBI
to pay me some visits like this.
Makes me look legit.
Was that in the Interpol handbook?
Come on, John, there no science
to catching crooks you know that.
Yeah. You said
you had something for me.
Yeah.
Our friend over in Brussels,
the guy that makes
those titanium bullets
found him two days ago.
Then I ran a check.
It seems everyone associated
with Rogue is having some bad luck.
Just last week...
plastic surgeon down in Panama
accidentally impaled himself...
with a kitchen knife
making a turkey sandwich.
Week before that another one of our
scalpel friends down in Florida
went skinny-dipping with some gators.
Guess he didn't read the signs. Anyway.
These guys, they both
specialize in facial reconstruction.
Both of them.
Our man's tying up loose ends.
Yeah, well there's another surgeon
unaccounted for.
Think he might be still alive,
maybe hiding out.
You let me know
the second he surfaces.
Right. Thanks Benny.
Button up, this isn't a disco.
Is that our contact?
Yes my contact.
Get rid of him.
He's my brother. He's with me.
Who the fuck does this guy think he is?
Go back to your car.
Wu, please. He's an outsider.
Go! Don't make me say it again.
After this is done
you and I are going to talk.
The Horses are intact.
Shiro will be pleased.
We will contact you when we get there.
Are the Horses safe with this crew?
Of, course, as far as they know
they're just delivering cars.
Stay calm and cooperate.
It's just a routine check.
I need you out of the car, both of you.
Put your hands where I can see them.
Officer, we're with
Shiro Yanagawa Enterprises.
You are making a huge mistake.
We have made arrangements.
Out of the car!
Do it. Turn around.
We work security.
We have licenses to carry firearms.
Call your Captain.
- Shut up. Shut up.
- He'll vouch for us.
- Fucking rent a cops.
- Shut up.
Good evening.
Captain Andrews,
what the fuck is going on?
What about our arrangement?
Just a little change in plan.
I need my money. Now.
So, we are good to go?
Oh, yeah. You're good to go.
Just wait here for a sec.
Let me and the boys clear out.
Let's go.
Do it.
Mr. Chang sends his regards.
No-o-o!
CHANG'S WAREHOUSE 16
Compliments of Mr. Chang.
Some serious shit here, brother.
Yakuzas. All of them.
All lined up, shot through the back.
Execution-style.
Excuse me, Forensics wants to know if
you're ready for them to come in yet.
It was a heist.
What?
Check the space between these sedans.
These guys were
escorting something big.
Whatever it was,
it must have been important.
These guys were the guard dogs.
But they left their guns in the cars.
There's only one thing that would stop
these guys from throwing down.
Cops.
At least they thought they were cops.
Hold on just a damn minute. Are you
trying to say that cops did this?
If they didn't, they were involved.
No fucking way!
For all we know
it could have been one of you guys.
I'm assuming that
you know who the fuck I am.
You're a bitch for Shiro Yanagawa
aren't you, Captain?
You're the one who gives his boys
free passage to smuggle in shit.
And you're the one
who sold them out last night.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I've never met Yana...
Hey-hey-hey-hey.
This is a Federal matter.
Look at it. Look down the barrel.
Tell me if you see the bullet.
- Can you see it?
- I see it.
He said he'll kill me.
He said he'll kill my family.
Who?
Who said that?
I don't know who!
Who?
I don't know who. He's with the Triads.
He works forthe Changs.
He knows where I live.
He knows where my kids go to school.
You stupid bastard.
What do you think
Shiro Yanagawa's gonna do
when he finds out you fucked him?
Get a statement. Call the marshals.
Put his family under protective custody.
Down, down, down! Everyone down!
A shooter on the! roof!
Guys!
This is Agent Wick.
I need Chase Squad backup
and an ambulance
to Sloan's Steakhouse. Now!
Hang on, motherfucker.
Nothing!
This motherfucker's out.
YAKUZA HEADQUARTERS
SAN FRANCISCO
The Triads made us look like fools.
Kill. Kill them.
Give me the word...
...and I'll make them disappear.
Do it. Find them.
I want all the heads
of every one of them.
Nobody told me
you two were in charge now.
Kira-san. Welcome home.
Your presence honors us.
And your stupidity insults my father.
We were just discussing...
I've brought word from Shiro directly.
You are to do nothing
until he instructs you to.
The Horses have been stolen!
If we do not strike back...
Are you disobeying my father?
Good. I'd like a salad.
I just got off a fourteen hour flight.
I'd like a salad.
Will somebody get me a salad?
What? What kind?
Chef. No blue cheese.
No blue cheese.
Takada...
With dressing on the side, please.
Hai.
Bitch.
Yeah.
Special Agent Crawford.
Who is this?
A messenger.
A messenger, huh?
The police captain in the restaurant,
was he part of your message?
He was a crooked cop.
I just did what you want to do.
What the hell do you know about
what I want, you fuck?
I saw it in your eyes, John.
Yeah, what did you see?
Pain. Rage. Loneliness.
I'll tell you what,
why don't we meet at
my shrink's office and discuss it.
You want the stolen shipment?
Warehouse Sixteen. One hour.
CHANG'S WAREHOUSE 16
This is the FBI.
Remain where you are and keep
your hands above your heads.
What? Not happy to see us?
This is private property.
RSVP. We came to party, baby.
Li Chang.
You still pretending to be legit?
Watch your mouth.
You forget who you're talking to here.
Open it.
I said, open it.
Open it!
Put your hands
on the back of your head.
Now, motherfucker.
Get your fucking hands up.
No weapons. He's clean.
Victor Shaw.
So that's what
you call yourself now huh?
Hong Kong passport but
security license out of Tokyo. Fine.
Check the warehouse.
Make sure nothing's hidden.
It's you, isn't it?
I remember your eyes.
There's something
real familiar about them.
It's the one thing the surgeons
can't change, can they?
The eyes.
They did a helluva job
on the rest of you, though.
Wouldn't even know
you're the same man.
But you are, aren't you?
I know you are.
So what's the Yakuza hit man doing
working for the Triads?
I know you understand me.
It was you on the phone, wasn't it?
What, don't remember?
Maybe you remember my partner.
You do, don't you?
Remember his name? Tom Lone.
Remember his wife, Diane?
His four-year-old daughter, Amy?
Remember a cabin in the woods.
A cabin that you burned to the ground
with their bodies still inside?
Remember that?
Do you remember that?
Say it. Say it. Say you remember.
Say you fucking remember blowing
my partner's goddamn head off!
You will find only pain,
living in the past.
Crawford, there's nothing here.
He checks out.
It's him, Terry. I fucking know it.
So what if it is? Hm?
Look, right now we got nothing.
Come on, man,
it'll be another day. All right?
But right now we wait.
We play it smart. And we do it right.
Another day.
Another day you and I
are going to finish this.
Count on that.
Everyone move out.
How in the world
did you know the FBI were coming?
Experience.
You have impressed me
once again, my friend.
As you see,
the FBI has declared war on us.
Well, fuck them!
I trust you have secured my Horses?
They are safe.
I still have a lot of work
for you to do, my friend.
I think you'd better
stay in my house for a while.
Keep an eye on things.
Understood.
Oh, Victor.
This FBI guy, Crawford, he is trouble.
He's chasing ghosts.
Give me a new one.
I said put up a new one now!
Mommy.
Did I scare you?
Where is the mother?
Do you want to play?
We could play tag.
Go find your mother.
I have things to do.
What's that?
Wow! Do it again.
Ana.
He's showing me a magic trick.
Why don't you go downstairs
and play for Mommy.
But we were playing.
I know but I'll be downstairs
in just a minute, okay?
Bye.
I understand you have business here
but I am warning you
to stay away from Ana.
My husband's work and our family
are two separate things.
Do we understand each other?
Yes, Mrs. Chang.
Good.
Don't think I don't know
what you're doing.
Mr. Chang might think
you're his man right now
but I'm still the one
who looks after things around here.
At every moment
in the world things change.
- TRIAD DISTRICT-
Don't make me say it again!
...he fucking tells me.
- Do you know how much-
- Relax.
What the fuck?
Mother fucker!
Fucking Yakuza. Let's go!
...teach that fucking Jap a lesson.
YAKUZA DISTRICT
Triads are coming!
Triad motherfuckers get 'em!
Buddha-heads!
Fucking Yakuza!
You fucking bastard.
I knew we should
never have trusted you.
Subtle, ain't it?
It's got Shiro's trademark.
So what now?
Get ready for a war.
Joey Ti. Got your ass.
Park, I want you outside
Chang's place in Marin.
Daniels, you get Yanagawa Motors.
Kinler, you get Warehouse 16.
Wick, take Goi.
Keep an eye on the Sayu Teahouse.
I get the new guy, huh?
I think I know
how to look through a night scope.
Hey, eyes open, everybody.
The shit's gonna go down somewhere.
Be ready to move
when you get the call.
Binoculars. No night scope.
The authorities are
expecting us to retaliate.
We strike now, we risk everything!
What if it was your family?
What the fuck is wrong with you?
You forgot?
Once it was my family.
Joey was like a son to me.
Revenge is a must.
But you've got to learn to be patient.
I will allow nothing
to put our family at risk.
I want you to do nothing.
Is that clear?
Shiro knows his days
are coming to an end.
One thing's for sure...
more blood will be spilled
before this is over.
Mr. Shaw...
I want your word that my wife
and daughter will be safe.
No harm will come to them.
A man should never give up his honor.
Or the honor of his family.
Keep them.
I don't smoke.
SAYU TEA HOUSE
YAKUZA DISTRICT
Oh, man!
I didn't know your mama
was working tonight.
Keep your eye on the mark, Goi.
Yo, heads up!
Looks like Takada's having
a little tea party, huh?
Have some spicy tuna.
Shit! Get Crawford and call for backup!
It's going down now!
Crawford.
We got trouble.
Wu just showed up just like you said.
I'm on my way.
Copy that.
Get down!
I'm going in. Cover me.
This is for my brother.
He's dead! Come on!
On three.
What?
Three!
Oh! Shit!
Wick!
Shit!
FBI. Drop your weapons.
Drop your weapons!
Hands on the counter
where I can see them.
Closer.
Situation secure.
All units stand down and cease fire.
Damnit, Goi!
He said cease fucking fire!
Shit.
Look. Goi's right there.
We got a shooter guys.
I got him!
Don't fucking move!
Get the other one!
Fuck you!
In Japan! You'd be dead!
This isn't Japan.
I said no. No-no-no.
Yes.
Wu and his boys shot up
Takada's teahouse last night.
What?
Wu Ti? Uh, are you sure?
I tried to stop them.
Goddamnit!
I told him not to do anything.
He leaves me with no choice.
You've done well.
My father is very pleased.
He now asks one more thing of you.
After I kill Chang
his operation will be destroyed.
What more could Shiro want?
The heads of the wife and child.
Why?
That's the order.
There is no why.
You never had a problem
killing women and children before.
Would you dare disobey your master?
I have no master.
These are my guards.
They will assist you on this task
as you best decide.
If I refuse?
You dropped this.
What is happening, John?
There are men with guns
in my front yard.
Just a precaution.
A precaution? For what?
What've you gotten us into?
Oh, my God.
It's him. Isn't it?
He's coming after us.
That's not gonna happen.
I'm sorry, Jen.
Not just for this. For everything.
I tried to do the right thing.
Make a good life for you and Daniel.
To give you the things you needed.
It never had anything to do
with what we did or didn't have.
It was the job.
The job always came first, even now.
Even knowing you might be
putting us in the same danger
Tom and his family were in.
You know...
I'm not even mad at you anymore.
Most days I just feel sorry for you.
For what you've become.
It's Benny.
Say hi to Benny for me.
What've you got, Benny?
We found your plastic surgeon.
Tijuana, Mexico
Welcome home, Dr. Sherman.
Hey Jefe, what's cooking?
Step in here.
Let's have a talk. Come on.
Agent Crawford, is that?
I don't-I don't-I don't know anything.
Really. I don't know anything.
Come on, you kidding me?
Can you explain to me...
why one of the world's most
brilliant nip-and-tuckers
is hiding out in the slums of Mexico?
What are you,
a fucking Nazi war criminal?
Look, I were you,
I'd be lapping up that pussy
on South Beach stretching it out.
Come on, now.
Look, I could give a shit about
whatever laws you've broken.
That's not why we're here.
I need you to identify this man.
You know what happened
to the other two doctors.
We know you could be next.
We can protect you.
You don't know him. Protect me?
You can't protect me.
You can't stop him.
You found me here,
he can find me here.
I can stop him.
All I need from you is a yes or a no.
Is this Rogue?
We uh, we-we...
We used to get uh, commissioned
by the U.S. government
and we'd all do our surgeries on him
when he was with the CIA.
We changed his face a lot of times.
He, uh he came to me
three years ago.
His face was almost torn off.
I just did what I could.
I repaired the muscle,
the nerve tissue.
Then I reconstructed the facial bones.
I never saw him again.
This is what I made him look like.
Look, Doc,
we're going to take you with us.
We're going to protect you,
understand?
Now why don't you go get
somethings together and we'll go.
Doc!
What? Yeah. Is it okay if l-if I...
Yeah-yeah-yeah. Go ahead.
You believe in fate Benny?
Fate?
Yeah.
You know, no matter what you do
your future's already decided?
I don't know about that.
I always thought your future
depends on what choices you make.
I have made all
the necessary arrangements.
I will join you as soon as I finish here.
Okay?
Don't worry.
Okay, I'll be back to walk you out.
I love you.
My crew's gone.
My brother is dead.
You brought it onto yourself.
And how did I do that?
I gave you my trust.
I gave you my loyalty.
I sacrificed everything for you
and this is how I'm treated?
You've got a lot of nerve
to talk to me about loyalty.
You're a fucking traitor!
Die!
That piece of shit.
He tells me that he's loyal.
That he's my friend.
I trusted him.
He's right. He was loyal.
He was your friend.
What?
Shit.
AOC base from Clark.
We got some major action
at the Chang mansion.
What's going on? Is the boss okay?
Mommy loves you, okay. Just...
No!
Chang is dead.
And the woman and child?
Take me to the bodies
so I can take their heads.
No. I killed them.
I should have that honor.
Come on! Kill him!
Are you okay? Where is my husband?
Where's Clark?
He's on his way back.
He send the photos?
Yes, sir.
What the fuck happened up there?
Looks like Rogue took out Chang and
turned on Shiro's assassins.
He's using them.
Playing both sets against each other.
Why would he do that?
John! You're never gonna believe
who just flew in.
Father, I'm so happy to see you.
And I am happy to see you.
This country looks very beautiful.
Your English is improving.
I have been practicing.
This is my new home after all.
Rogue insisted on
delivering the Horses himself.
You've made me very proud.
I must ask for one more thing of you.
Anything.
Return to Japan.
But I want to stay with you.
If I am to oversee our expansion here
I need someone
who can insure our interests in Japan.
The only person
I can trust is you, Kira.
Shiro Yanagawa!
FBI Special Agent John Crawford.
Step back
Welcome to America.
Now don't unpack.
You won't be staying long.
Agent Crawford...
I'm a busy man.
Oh, we got a lot of business,
you and me.
I think you know that.
Three years ago
Rogue killed my partner and his family.
And you know what?
Rogue was working for you.
Rogue is a myth. Just a rumor.
You think so, huh.
You can't always trust rumors, can you?
Rogue turns around and fucking slices
up the heavy hitters you sent with him.
Now you gotta ask yourself, now
why would he do something like that?
I've never seen this man
before in my life.
Look...
I don't care if you fuckers slaughter
each other till you're all dead and buried.
Truth is it makes my job a lot easier.
But if I find proof that
ties any of this shit back to you...
you ain't never gonna see Japan again.
And neither will that
pretty little daughter of yours.
Thanks for the tip
Agent Crawford.
Finally! My most loyal stranger.
We meet face to face.
Yanagawa-san, I've waited
a long time for this moment.
It's all because of you
that we now have this opportunity.
Kira enjoyed working with you here.
One day she'll make a fine leader
of Yanagawa clan.
Yeah, one day.
I'm reminded of the Sengoku...
when the Daimyo warriors fought
each other to unite Japan.
The one who finally succeeded was
a man by the name of Oda Nobunaga.
And do you know how he did it?
He killed everyone who opposed him.
Thanks to you all those
who oppose me here are dead.
I exist but to serve you.
In Asia these could never be sold.
But the fortune
they will bring here in the West...
will be more than enough
to continue our American expansion.
And now it is time for your reward.
Open it.
One must remove all future threats.
You allowed that threat to remain
by not killing the woman and child.
You have disobeyed me
and broken my most sacred code.
Your code, not mine.
Betrayal cannot be forgiven.
Take him downstairs.
Persuade him to tell us
where the wife and child are.
They are truly magnificent.
So many dead for such small trinkets.
Fakes!
Find the woman and child...
They'll lead us to the real Horses.
Yanagawa-san!
After all these years...
why do you do this?
You ordered the hit.
I ordered many hits.
This one was different.
You should have left
the wife and daughter alone.
I left none to seek revenge.
You left one!
Your assassin, Rogue,
never made it out alive.
So, you are Tom Lone?
Changing your face, your voice.
All so you could get to me.
Pain can be a weapon,
if you so choose.
How do you think we found out
you were FBI in the first place?
It was Crawford.
You killed my family.
He's the one who gave you up.
Crawford works for me.
Because of him your family's dead!
Somebody talked.
From inside. Close to us.
You never know who's working for who.
Somebody talked.
Crawford?
Shiro's dead.
Get out of this business
while you can, Goi.
From America? Leave me.
Crawford.
Remember the night we met?
I remember my partner
blowing your face off.
You live today
only because of what he did.
I live today only to kill you,
you miserable prick.
Meet me there.
Goi
Where are you?
Show yourself!
I got your surgeon.
He made a positive ID.
Come on, Crawford. Flush him out.
It's over, Rogue.
Can you hear me?
Why did you do it?
What did Shiro promise you
that was worth my life
and the life of Diane and Amy?
No, you're not him. It can't be.
You don't even sound like him.
Look at my eyes, John.
The one thing the surgeons
can never change.
Oh, Jesus, Tom.
Is it really you?
Yeah.
Why didn't you tell me?
It was the only way
I could get the man responsible.
But all along...
I never thought it would
bring me back to my best friend.
I didn't know they'd send Rogue.
For Christ sakes,
I thought he was dead!
They said they wanted
to teach you a lesson.
For shooting Rogue.
Just rough you up a bit, that's all.
Is that what they told you?
Shiro ordered everything.
I tried to stop working for him,
to get out, so many times.
I thought if I could make
that son of a bitch
pay for what he did to you, somehow
it would make things right again.
You think you could forgive me, Tom?
Tom Lone is dead.
My name is Rogue.
No...
Shit!