[ Roaring ]
[ Heart Beating ]
- [ Heart Continues Beating ]
- [ Heavy Breathing ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Disco Music, Faint ]
- [ Disco Music Continues, Loud ]
- [ Breathing Continues ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Music Continues, Loud ]
[ Woman ]
Hey, will you guys shut up in there!
Barbara!
Oh, shit.
- [ Heavy Breathing ]
- [ Heart Beating ]
[ Pounding On Door ]
What the hell is going on in here?
I am trying to study for a final!
Yeah, we have finals too.
Ever hear of Modern Dance?
- Can't you study to music?
- No, I can't study to music!
Are you gonna turn it down,
or do I have to go to Sue?
Oh, go to Sue then! Fuck off!
- I'm going to Sue!
- "I'm going to Sue!"
[ Barbara Muttering ]
[ Moaning ]
- Aah! Aah!
- [ Boy Moaning ]
- Get off of me!
- What?
[ Gasping ]
Oh! There's somebody out there!
- Oh, come on! There's somebody out there!
- What are you talking about?
- There's nobody out there.
- There is!
[ Heart Beating ]
- Calm down.
- I can't calm down.
You'd better take care of it,
'cause I can't study with this disco music.
[ Heavy Breathing ]
- All right, move.
- Come on!
- [ Disco Music ]
- Oh, look.
The little fink
brought back the master fink.
- [ Girls Arguing ]
- [ Sue ] What's going on?
[ Arguing Continues ]
- The music's not loud.
- Yes, it is.
[ Music Continues ]
- [ Moaning ]
- [ Heavy Breathing ]
- [ Barbara ] Look, it's not that loud!
- [ Sue ] Yes, it is loud!
[ Heavy Breathing ]
[ High-pitched Warbling ]
[ Laughs ]
Oh, God, that scream is terrible.
- What cat did you strangle to get that?
- The cat that you hired. That's her voice.
- You didn't dub that?
- No.
- That's hers?
- Yeah.
- Oh, really.
- Yes.
Run that back again.
I wanna hear the scream.
[ Film: Audio in Reverse ]
All right. Yeah.
[ Audio Slows, Resumes Forward ]
- [ Suspense Music ]
- [ Heart Beating ]
Kill all the effects except for the scream.
[ Various Sound Layers Going Silent ]
[ High-pitched Warbling ]
- Kill it!
- [ Audio Slows, Stops ]
You're right. It's hers.
And it's shit!
Look, Jack, I didn't hire that girl for her scream.
I hired that girl for her tits.
Then what are you worried about? With those
tits, who's gonna be watching her scream?
- Let's move on.
- W-Wait a minute! Wait a minute!
Come on, J -- I-look, how many years
have we worked together?
- Let's see. I met you on Blood Bath, right?
- Yeah.
And then we did Blood Bath 2.
And then we did Bad Day at Blood Beach.
Then we did Bordello of Blood.
And then -- well, that brings us up to date.
Coed Frenzy.
By the way, I didn't tell you this,
but, uh, I --
I'd like to think
this is our finest film.
- Almost two years.
- Oh, God. Two years.
Five films in two years.
How did we do it?
You know what I can't figure out?
I can't figure out what a smart guy like you
is still doing that shit for.
- Oh, come on! You do the shit. I do the sound.
- Oh, no, you do the shit.
- Oh, is that right?
- Yeah, like that wind in the trees.
- It sounds like you're whistling in the crapper!
- That's the library stuff.
- We used it a million times.
- That is the trouble. I have heard it a million times.
- Now get something new.
- New wind.
- Yeah.
- Got it.
- And what about that scream? We gotta dub that.
- All right. You know any good screamers?
- I got a few ideas.
- Yeah, I'll bet you do. [ Laughs ]
Just worry about the scream.
Will ya, huh?
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Heart Beating ]
[ Heavy Breathing ]
- [ Electronic Feedback ]
- [ Tape Audio Rewinding ]
[ Static Crackling ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
- [ Bang ]
- [ Air Hissing ]
[ Tires Squealing ]
[ Car Horn Honking ]
[ Tape: Thunder Rumbling ]
- [ Click ]
- It's a sweeping condemnation...
of White House policies.
Well, the same poll gave evidence
of a groundswell of nationwide support...
for Governor George McRyan
and his bid for the party's nomination.
If an election were held today...
the poll concludes Governor McRyan
would be the hands-down winner...
drawing a remarkable 62% of the vote
to the president's 23.
The president's campaign manager, Jack Manners,
told reporters earlier today --
Well, the president's had to make
some tough decisions.
But when these policies are carried out...
and the economic climate improves,
as we confidently expect it will...
the people will rally
to support the president...
- [ Tape: Thunder Rumbling ]
- in the upcoming primaries.
- [ Tape: Beep Tones ]
- A lot can happen between now and then.
Meanwhile leaders in congress
are waiting anxiousIy...
for Governor McRyan
to declare his candidacy.
- Well, they may not have much longer to wait.
- [ Tape: Audio Rewinding ]
The governor's now at the ballroom
of the Bellevue-Stratford...
where in just a few minutes he's expected
to address the kickoff dinner...
of the Liberty Day celebration.
Some people are guessing that he will use
the occasion to throw his hat into the ring.
What about it, Joan? Is there any word
from the Bellevue-Stratford yet?
Not yet, Bill, but as soon as there is
we will be going there live.
As we all know, Liberty Day is one of the most
eagerly awaited of all Philadelphia celebrations.
But this year
it's going to be extra special.
It is exactly 100 years since
the Liberty Bell was last rung...
and to honor this centennial...
- [ Tape: Footsteps ]
- there will be a parade on Saturday...
down Market Street.
It will end up at Penn's Landing where
there will be a spectacular display of fireworks.
In addition, a full-sized replica
of the Liberty Bell...
has been made from pennies
donated by schoolchildren...
from every state in the union.
Joan, I understand that they'll be ringing it
after the fireworks at Penn's Landing.
That's right -- Hold it, Bill.
- [ Tape: Ticking ]
- I think we're getting something from the Bellevue-Stratford right now.
Let's go live to our Eye on the City
political correspondent Frank Donahue...
at the Liberty Ball
at the Bellevue-Stratford Hotel.
- [ Tape: Audio Rewinding ]
- [ Joan ] Frank, you look fabulous.
Have you spoken
with the governor yet?
Yes, Joan, but only briefly
as he arrived only moments ago.
- [ Tape: Glass Shattering ]
- I did pose to the governor a question...
regarding his impression so far
of this year's Liberty Day Jubilee.
The governor said that
he was honored to be here...
that he plans to attend the parade and, of course,
the ringing of the new bell on Saturday night.
The governor went on to say he felt it a shame
the Liberty Bell had been silenced for so long...
- [ Tape: Gunshot ]
- and that he was looking forward to hearing...
a new voice of liberty
throughout the land.
The governor is now busy
greeting some old friends...
and we understand, Joan, that he will be
enjoying a meal here in the ballroom.
But his people have told us that he will indeed
speak to us at greater length...
- when he finishes that meal.
- [ Tape: Thud ]
I'm Frank Donahue, Eye on the City News,
Bellevue-Stratford.
Thank you, Frank. We'll be getting back to you
later on in the broadcast.
Meanwhile, there is other news
this evening.
There has been a teachers' strike --
- [ Wind Gusting ]
- [ Leaves Rustling ]
[ Man, Faint ]
Beautiful night for a walk.
[ Woman, Faint ]
Oh, yes.
[ Man ]
Let's take a walk along the river here.
Mmm. Nice.
[ Woman ] David, look.
There's someone on the bridge.
- Oh, let's not worry about that.
- He's staring right at us.
- Who cares?
- I care!
- Betsy --
- I don't wanna stay here anymore. Let's go.
- Yeah, okay.
- What is he doing?
- I don't know.
- What is he, a Peeping Tom or something?
Oh, who cares?
Come on, let's walk down here.
[ Clicking ]
[ Frog Clicking ]
[ Winding, Clicking ]
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Hooting ]
[ Rustling ]
[ Tires Squealing ]
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
[ Vehicle Approaching, Louder ]
[ Loud Bang ]
[ Tires Squealing ]
Jesus Christ.
Oh, God, please help me!
Oh, get me out of here! Please!
[ Sobbing ]
Oh! Oh, God!
[ Coughing ]
[ Chattering ]
- A bang?
- Yeah, some sort of a bang.
- Where?
- I'm not sure where.
- You were facing the car?
- Yes.
- Well, you heard the blowout.
- Yes, I heard the blowout.
- But the first sound I heard was a bang.
- Well, that's some kind of an echo.
No. [ Chuckles ] Look, I know what
an echo sounds like. I'm a sound-man.
And, uh, the bang was before
the blowout. All right?
- What were you doing up there?
- I was recording sounds for a movie I'm working on.
- You recorded the accident?
- Yes.
Well, what happened after that?
Well, then the car went off the road
into the creek and I ran --
- What did you do then?
- I'm trying to tell you what I did.
I ran down, jumped in the creek
and pulled out the girl.
- There was a girl?
- Yes, there was a girl.
What girl?
The girl that I brought here.
The girl in the room.
She was inside the car?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
[ Scoffs ] I wasn't bobbing for apples.
Of course I'm sure.
Look, it can get pretty dark
under eight feet of water.
What are you doing? Is this known as
obtaining objective eyewitness testimony?
Because if it is, forget it.
Gotta get the stretcher to turn now.
Come on, people, step back.
[ Chattering ]
Doctor. How is she?
Very lucky.
Mild shock, some cuts and bruises.
No major injuries.
- Well, can I see her?
- She might be asleep. She has been sedated.
- I'll just say good-bye.
- Don't stay too long.
How you doin'?
[ Slurred ]
You have my purse?
No. But I-I'm sure the police'll find it.
I wouldn't worry about it.
I know.
- Where you goin'?
- I have to leave now.
W -- [ Chuckles ] Wait a minute.
I think you'd better go back to bed. Really.
I don't think
they're finished with you yet.
Come on, up. Up.
- Just for a minute.
- All right.
So how do you feel?
- He said I -- I was lucky, the doctor.
- Yeah.
Yeah, he should have been there, huh?
- Thanks for getting me out.
- Yeah, no problem.
I didn't realize you were this pretty
with all that mud all over your face.
I don't have any makeup on!
Well, don't worry about it.
It's fine. It's a hospital.
Who are you?
I'm Jack Terry.
- Sally.
Nice to meet you, Sally.
Are you leaving?
Yeah, I gotta go.
But, um, what do you say when you get out
of here we have a drink sometime, huh?
In a glass.
- Sure.
- Okay. You take care.
How 'bout tonight?
No, I don't think so, Sally. Not tonight. But I'll tell you what I'll do: I'll check with the doctor, see when you get out.
- No. They want to keep me for observation.
- Wait a minute.
- Sally, you really gotta stay in bed.
- I don't like to be observed.
Well, I'm sorry, but there's really
nothing I can do about that.
Please. I really don't like hospitals.
- Wai -- All right.
- I have to get out of here. It's making me n --
I'll make you a deal. Okay?
This is the deal.
You stay here, I'll get your clothes, and then
when I come back we'll go out and have a drink.
Okay? All right?
Well... I need shoes and a coat.
Yes, I'll get them.
But if you don't stay, I'm not coming back.
- Okay.
- All right.
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Phones Ringing ]
[ Man ] Looked like it was gonna be all right,
but this guy Jack Terry --
He took her out of the car.
That's him over there.
He's being a real horse's ass and I don't know
how we're gonna keep the lid on this guy.
Get some men out there. I want this place sealed.
I'm not gonna have this turn into some kind of a circus.
Sir, this is the guy here.
He was right there when it happened.
- Now he saw the whole thing.
- He's the one who saw it?
Yes. His name is Jack Terry.
He says he pulled the girl out of the car.
I want to talk to you.
And to the girl too. Where is she?
- She's in there.
- All right, she's asleep.
If you wanna talk to me, make it quick,
'cause I've had enough tonight. I wanna go home.
Is there a room some place around here
we can talk in private?
Yes, sir, I'll take care of it.
Thornwall, would you secure that room for us?
- Captain, I want these men checked out.
- Officer.
- What's going on here?
- Car accident. Guy got killed.
- I know that. But what's the big deal?
- Did you know the guy was McRyan?
That's Governor McRyan?
That stiff on the stretcher
was probably our next president.
- Hell, he had my vote.
- [ Quietly ] Jesus Christ.
Let's talk in here.
- You pulled the girl out of that car?
- Yes.
Well, I would like for you to forget about her,
forget you ever saw her.
Wait a minute.
Wh-Who are you?
My name is Lawrence Henry.
I work for Governor McRyan.
Oh.
He was also a friend.
He was my friend.
Well, look, I-I'm -- I'm very sorry
about the governor...
and I-I -- I obviously would have
loved to have saved his life too, but, uh --
I mean, I was there and she was there.
Yeah, well, we know what happened,
but the governor is dead now...
and... we don't want to
embarrass his family.
Do you have any idea what the press would do
if they got ahold of a thing like this?
What do you want me to do,
just say she wasn't here?
- I already told the police.
- That's already taken care of.
All right, what about the girl?
I'll talk to her.
I'm sure she'll cooperate.
So one playmate just vanishes
from McRyan's car just like that? Pfft!
- That's right.
- Oh, Jesus. I don't know. I don't --
C-C-Can't you keep your mouth shut?
It's better the governor died alone.
I just don't know if I can do that.
I mean, I was there, she was there and --
Who gives a damn that you were there?
You want to tell his wife that he died
with his hand up some girl's dress?
Or maybe you'd rather
she read it in the papers!
Well, that is what happened.
I mean, that is the truth, isn't it?
Well, what difference
does that make to you...
when it would make a great deal of difference
to his family?
[ Exhales ]
- All right.
- Good.
I'll slip you and the girl out the back.
How about your place?
You don't want to go home, do you?
[ Yawns ] They told you
who was in the car, right?
Yeah.
Well, some smart reporter could figure
I was there too, you know.
They've got my purse
with my name, my address.
They're gonna be camped
on my doorstep.
What about my doorstep? I'm the one
who pulled you out of that wreck, didn't l?
[ Yawning ]
Yeah, right.
Let's go to a motel.
[ Chuckles ]
First it's a drink. Then it's my place.
Now it's a motel.
Boy, things are really moving fast tonight,
aren't they, Sally?
Whoops.
Stop over here for a second.
Fourteen. All right.
- [ Tape: Wind Gusting ]
- [ Tape: Leaves Rustling ]
[ Tape: Man ]
Beautiful night for a walk.
[ Tape: Woman ]
Oh, yes, it is.
[ Man ]
Let's take a walk along the river here.
- [ Man ] Mmm. Nice.
- [ Woman ] David, look.
- There's someone on the bridge.
- Oh, let's not worry about that.
- He's staring right at us.
- Who cares?
- I care!
- Betsy --
I don't wanna stay here anymore.
Let's go.
- Yeah, okay.
- What is he doing?
- I don't know.
- What is he, a Peeping Tom or something?
Oh, who cares? Come on,
let's walk down here a little further.
[ Clicking ]
[ Winding, Clicking ]
[ Owl Hooting ]
[ Hooting ]
- [ Hooting ]
- [ Tires Squealing ]
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
- [ Loud Bang ]
- [ Air Hissing ]
[ Tires Squealing ]
[ Jack ]
Jesus Christ.
- [ Loud Bang ]
- [ Air Hissing ]
Shit.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Factory Horn Blowing ]
[ Winding, Clicking ]
[ Winding, Clicking Continues ]
[ Winding, Clicking Stop ]
[ Sally ]
So, uh, you want some coffee?
Huh? You want some coffee?
Mmm. Good morning.
- Hi. How you doin'?
- I'm fine. How are you?
Pretty good.
There you go.
What are you doin' here?
You -- You listenin' to some music?
Mmm. No.
This is my, uh -- this is my job.
- I do sound effects for movies.
- Oh, movies, huh?
Matter of fact, last night I was --
I was out recording some sounds.
What do you mean, sound effects?
Well, you know, when you see a movie
and you hear a door slam...
or a bird chirp, or wind, or whatever --
I record those actual sounds
and then I put them in a movie...
and then you see the movie.
- Wow.
- Last night, I --
- Big movies?
- No. Just, uh --
- Just bad ones, unfortunately.
- Oh.
I really love movies, you know.
It's -- It's a very interesting subject to me
because, uh -- because I do makeup.
- Do you?
- Yeah.
I mean, right now it's only
behind the counter at Korvette's...
but I have this dream
about doing makeup for movies.
I mean, like, I've seen these big movie stars --
like Barbra Streisand, you know?
- They don't do it right.
- No?
- I know how to fix a face.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- That's good.
I want you to hear something.
Look.
- [ Click, Tape Reels Rewinding ]
- Last night I was recording some sounds...
and I recorded your accident.
I got the whole thing on tape.
- [ Click, Tape Reels Stop ]
- Oh. You recorded the accident.
Yes, I did, except I don't think
you had an accident.
I think your tire was shot out.
- Oh, that's crazy.
- No, it's not. Listen to this.
All right, now you're gonna hear two sounds.
The first is a gunshot.
And the second is the blowout.
All right? Listen up.
[ Vehicle Approaching ]
- [ Loud Bang ]
- [ Air Hissing ]
- [ Tires Squealing ]
- Listen again.
I mean, I heard a noise.
I don't know, maybe that was a gunshot.
But I'll tell you the truth -- I don't really
feature listening to a replay of last night.
It's -- It's kinda depressing.
- [ Tape Deck Clicks Off ]
- Can I ask you something?
- What?
- What were you doing with him? With McRyan?
That's a very personal question.
That's none of your business.
No -- [ Chuckles ]
I don't mean the details.
- I just wondered why --
- I think I'm getting a cold here and I don't have my makeup or anything.
- Hey, come on, Sally, forget it.
- The personal questions. I mean, I don't even know who you are, you know.
Well, I'd like you to get to know who I am.
Hey, how about that drink?
Some other time, okay?
Sally, I'm -- Hey, look, I saved your life.
The least you could do is have a drink with me.
- Come on.
- All right.
You can call me at my girlfriend
Judy Demming's. I'll be there.
- She's in the book.
- All right. You telling me the truth?
- Yeah.
- All right. I'm gonna call ya.
- Okay.
[ Sirens wailing ]
[ Buzzer Sounding ]
[ Film Soundtrack: Heart Beating ]
Hey, Jack, they got movies of McRyan
getting killed. I just heard it on the radio.
- Maybe they got it on the midday news.
- They got what?
Movies of McRyan getting killed!
Incredible as it may seem,
a local photographer, Manny Karp...
was on the scene of the accident
last night with his camera.
Eye on the City News has learned...
that Mr. Karp sold his film to News Today
magazine late this morning...
- News Today --
- Shh!
for an undisclosed sum of money.
Our own Frank Donahue spoke with Mr. Karp
just a few moments ago...
outside the magazine's offices.
Well, I'll tell ya. I had gone out there
to try out this new film stock, right?
It's a very high speed.
It's good for night shooting.
I, uh -- I do a lot of work at night.
So, uh -- so anyway, I'm standing out there,
and all of a sudden...
I-I hear this car
barrelin' down the road, you know.
I didn't pay too much attention
till all of a sudden I hear it startin' to skid.
Well, I, uh -- I wasn't even thinkin'.
I just turned around, my camera's still runnin'
and, bam, I catch him goin' through the railing.
- Mr. Karp! Mr. Karp!
- [ Reporters Clamoring ]
- Frank Donahue, Eye on the City News.
- Yeah, yeah.
Was the governor driving the car?
Was he in control?
Control? [ Chuckles ] It went into the drink,
didn't it? He wasn't in no control.
- Was he alone? Was he alone in the car?
- Well, I didn't see anybody.
[ Female Reporter ]
Why didn't you go to the police that night?
- Oh, no. No, no, no, no.
- [ Karp ] Lady, no cop ever did anything for me.
- Hey, Jack.
- They ain't gonna give me the kind of money these guys here are givin' me.
- Wh-where are you goin'?
- I gotta go.
- You gotta go? What about the auditions?
- [ TV: Karp Continues ]
[ News Dealer ]
Exclusive photos. McRyan's death.
One at a time, please.
- It's about time you showed up.
- Is Rick here?
- No, but Sam's here and he's got those girls he wants you to hear.
- Let me have the key. Come on, come on.
- What about Sam and the girls?
- I'll do it later.
- [ Projectors whirring ]
- [ Tape Audio: Sound Effects, Musical Cues ]
[ Chattering, Faint ]
- [ Knocking ]
- [ Sam ] Jack?
Yo, Jack!
Come on, open up! It's Sam.
Jack?
[ Footsteps Receding ]
[ Shutter Clicks ]
This is the pivotal moment in the film.
You gotta realize that.
Hey, Jack!
Where the fuck are you going?
- Sam, I'll be right back.
- I need you now! Now get in here!
Aah!
- Aah!
- What do you think?
- Keep lookin'.
Keep lookin'?
Hey, Jack, what are you talking about?
- Sorry, Jack. I'm all stacked up.
- Please, just this once, as a favor to me.
All right?
Well, I'll see what I can do,
but you'll have to come back after midnight.
Sally? It's Jack.
See, I-I told you I'd call you.
How 'bout that drink you promised?
Where you going?
Why don't I meet you at the station?
[ Sighs ]
Sally! Hi.
- Hi!
- I'm so glad I caught you.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah, I was out the door.
Look, I only got 20 minutes.
That's fine. We'll have a quick drink
and you'll be on your way.
Well, I -- I wanna get
a good seat, you know.
Aw, come on, Sally.
You promised me.
- Okay, but just 10 minutes.
- Okay, come on. Let me take this.
- Okay. Thanks.
- [ Woman On P.A., Indistinct ]
- How you feelin'?
- Pretty good.
[ Woman On P.A. Continues ]
Stopping at Trenton, Newark, New York...
Rye, Stamford,
New Haven, New London...
Providence and Boston.
Stairway 3, Track 4.
Now what's the first thing you see...
when you meet somebody?
Legs. I'm a leg man.
No! [ Laughing ]
Come on!
All right, all right. Face.
You see their face. Right?
- Exactly.
- Okay.
So -- So if your face
doesn't look right...
no one -- I mean no one
is gonna look at you again.
Yeah, but I don't think your face
needs any makeup.
Every face needs makeup!
- But it shouldn't look like makeup.
- Oh, I see.
You see, I've worked on this face.
I've hidden everything
so you don't see the makeup.
You got makeup on right now?
- I do.
- I don't believe it.
- Yeah.
- I don't believe it!
Absolutely.
And you see, this took me two hours.
And this is the no-makeup look.
Really? Well, I would like to see
what the makeup look looks like.
- I bet that's good, huh?
- Well, I --
I only do that for special occasions.
How about a broken nose? How --
How would you deal with a broken nose?
Well, that's easy.
You just take, like, a little --
Wait a minute. Let me see.
I can even show you in here.
- Yeah, like, you get a brush like this, right?
- Yeah?
You take a little brown powder.
- You just kinda make a little brown --
- [ Laughs ] What are you doin'?
Hey, now wait a minute.
This is serious business here.
- You interested or not?
- Oh, yes. Okay. Sorry.
Okay. Make a brown line
and kinda smudge it in right here.
It has to be real subtle
so no one notices or anything like that.
But -- what are you smiling about?
Wh -- I-I'm impressed. I'm impressed
that you know so much about this.
- You're not interested in this at all.
- Yes, I am.
No, you're not. You just kept me
sittin' here, talkin' so I'd miss my train.
Wait, now, that's not true, Sally.
- I just didn't want you to go.
- Why?
Because I like you, and I just met you,
and you're goin' off on me.
I don't know.
I don't know anything about you.
Well, what do you want to know?
I'll tell you anything you want to know.
All right.
You're a sound-man, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay, how'd you get that job?
That's a good question.
I don't know.
[ Laughing ] No, I'll tell you.
All right, it all started in school, okay?
I mean, I was, uh, the kind of kid
who fixed radios...
made my own stereos,
won all the science fairs.
You know the type.
Well, after that I went into the service --
went into the army -- and I refined my skills there.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Were you in any wars or anything?
- No, no.
I was such a communication whiz
they wouldn't let me leave New Jersey.
See?
Then I went into the police for a while,
and after that I, uh, went into movies.
Wait a minute.
You were a cop?
- No, no. I worked for the Keen Commission.
- What's that?
It's just a group of politicians that got together
to try to stop police corruption.
- Oh.
- Then I quit that and, uh --
- Well, what'd you do?
- Well, it's a long story.
- You really don't want to know about it.
- Oh, I do.
I really do.
This is very interesting.
How about movies?
I thought you wanted to know about movies.
Yeah, movies are great,
but I mean, this is --
this is, like, real life
on the streets, you know.
It's exciting.
All right.
I, um -- I wired
their best undercover cop.
Guy by the name of Freddie Corso.
And one of Freddie's cases
was to set up a corrupt police captain...
who was trying
to shake down a mob guy.
My job was to rig a wire on him
so I could record the conversation.
Wait a minute.
What do you mean, "wire"?
[ Jack ] Well, it's just a tiny little mike
that's attached to a transmitter...
that I strapped around Freddie's waist.
Mackey, hand me the tape.
Okay, Freddie, give me a sound check.
Count to 10.
One, two, three, four, five, six --
[ Jack ] It was a great wire. I mean, it was one of
these deals where you could be blocks away...
and you could hear everything
within 10 feet of him -- Fantastic!
- [ Freddie ] Hey, Milt, how you doin'?
- [ Milt ] Hello, Freddie. How you doin'?
- [ Freddie ] Good to see ya!
- [ Milt ] Nice seein' you. You look good.
[ Freddie ] Yeah, so do you.
You look like a million in that getup.
[ Milt ]
Thank you.
[ Freddie ] So, uh, I brought
someone here I want you to meet.
Captain Kennedy, this is Milt.
[ Milt ] Who the fuck
wants to meet Captain Kennedy?
[ Freddie ]
Milt, take it easy.
[ Milt Speaking Italian ]
I don't wanna meet him.
[ Freddie ] Hey, take it easy.
This man could put the cap on everything.
You won't be able to go
to the bathroom alone.
- [ Milt ] All right, come on in the car. We'll take a ride, we'll talk a little.
- [ Freddie ] All right.
[ Jack ] And the first thing that the captain
says to the mob guy, he says, uh --
[ Captain ] Look, I understand
that the man has a brother-in-law. Okay?
Now, I happen to see him
talkin' to his brother-in-law.
Now, the brother-in-law
is a known felon, Freddie...
and MiIt's out on parole,
and that's a parole violation.
Now, I'm gonna have to tell
the parole officer. Okay?
If I tell the parole officer,
he's goin' back in the can.
But, uh, I think I could work something out
that I don't have to tell him for, uh, 5,000 bucks.
[ Milt ]
$5,000?
Freddie, you little prick!
We started this thing for $1,000!
- $1,000?
- Now wait a minute!
[ Jack ] I'm getting this
clear as a bell on tape...
when I start to hear this static.
[ Milt ] If you think you're gon -- [ Static ]
the two of ya are outta your -- [ Static ]
- [ Freddie ] We could work this thing out!
- [ Milt ] I mean wha -- [ Static ]
[ Static Continues,
Voices Breaking Up ]
- He's goin' up the river. You understand?
- Right. Right.
- You told me -- What's the matter?
- You're sweatin', Freddie. What's the matter?
[ Jack ] The one thing the fuckin' whiz kid
didn't think of...
was maybe that Freddie
would get nervous and sweat.
He was sweating so bad
that the battery in the transmitter...
was shorting out
and burning a hole in him.
Hey, pull over at this gas station.
I gotta take a piss.
[ Groaning ]
- Shit.
- What's wrong, Jack?
- The battery's arcing.
- The battery's arcing?
My battery in the transmitter's arcing.
It's burning him. I gotta get in there.
You can't go in there.
You're gonna blow the guy's cover.
- I gotta go in there.
- You can't --
- My fuckin' battery's burning a hole in him!
- I don't give a damn. You're gonna screw things up.
[ Jack ]
Shit.
[ Engine Starts ]
Jack, I think you're nuts.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, no.
[ Groans ]
It wasn't your fault.
Yeah, well, you tell that to Freddie.
Shit.
- Are you okay?
- No. There's something buggin' me.
This whole thing with Henry -- you know,
the guy that's the governor's assistant?
Oh, he talked to you too, huh?
That's why I'm leaving town.
He gave me some money
to disappear for a couple months.
I thought so. Look, they are covering up
a lot more than you being with McRyan.
I mean, I know that tire was shot out.
How can you be so sure?
- Did you see News Today magazine?
- Yeah.
The photographs? Well, I figured out a way
of puttin' my sound with those photographs.
When you see it,
I'm sure you'll see it was no blowout.
- I don't know.
- Would you do me a favor?
- Would you stick around for a couple of days?
- What for?
I just think you could
help me with this thing.
Jack, I don't know.
I'm in a hell of a lot of trouble already.
- Wait --
- If I stick around here --
If I can just clear myself of this,
look, we could go away together.
I mean, wh -- why not? What the hell's
the sense of going away by yourself?
- I don't know.
- Come on.
I'll have to think about it or something.
[ Whispering ]
I'll think about it.
Excuse me.
[ Wire winding ]
[ Gasping, Panting ]
- [ Click ]
- [ TV: Organ Music ]
[ TV: Wolf Howling ]
[ Muttering ]
Hey, Sal, how you doin', huh?
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, it's good to s --
No, I was just hangin' around here
watchin' this great movie on TV.
You look terrific, babe.
[ Chuckling ]
Yeah, so, uh -- so wh-wh-what are you
doin' in my neighborhood?
- Hmm?
- [ TV: Wolf Howling ]
Uh, listen, you want somethin' to drink?
Huh? How about some scotch?
[ Knocking ]
- Yeah?
- It's Sally.
Hey, hey, Sal! Hey, come on in!
Come on. Come on in.
Hey, you look great, babe.
What are you doin' around here, huh?
- [ Lock Clicks ]
- Jesus, Manny, don't they ever clean this place?
Yeah, weIl, you gotta get up
really early to catch a maid, you know.
I haven't made it yet.
[ Chuckling ]
Hey, I'm sure glad
you come by, you know.
Listen, how'd you --
how'd you find me?
Come on, Manny.
We worked this place a million times, you know.
Oh, yeah, yeah, that's right.
Hey, you want a drink? Huh?
- This isn't a social visit, Manny.
- Oh, no, huh? Oh.
You know, you almost got me killed
the other night.
- Dead. You understand?
- Hey, babe, I didn't have nothin' to do with that.
- That was an accident.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Like, what happened to you?
What do you mean
what happened to me?
I took off as soon as I saw that kid
jump into the creek.
He did a hell of a lot better job
than I could have ever done.
[ Chuckles ] You know -- You know,
I don't know if I ever toId you this before...
but, uh, I can't even swim, babe.
[ Soundtrack: Wind Gusting,
Leaves Rustling, Accelerated ]
[ Soundtrack: Frog Clicking, Accelerated ]
[ Soundtrack:
Owl Hooting, Accelerated ]
Tires Squealing, Accelerated ]
[ Soundtrack:
Vehicle Approaching, Normal Speed ]
[ Soundtrack: Loud Bang ]
[ Soundtrack: Audio Toggles
Back And Forth On Loud Bang ]
[ Soundtrack:
Loud Bang, Tires Squealing ]
[ Soundtrack: Loud Splash ]
[ Soundtrack: Audio Toggles
Back And Forth On Loud Splash ]
[ Soundtrack: Audio Running Backward ]
[ Soundtrack: Splash ]
[ Soundtrack: Loud Bang ]
[ Soundtrack: Audio Rewinding ]
Great.
[ Soundtrack Whooshes ]
[ Gunshot Thuds ]
[ Whoosh ]
[ Bell Tolling ]
Terry, do you realize how many
conspiracy nuts I've already had in here today?
No.
Well, I'd like to have a fuckin' dime
for every goddamn one of them...
because I'd buy the whole state
of Florida, and I'd retire in peace.
Look. It's very clear in all these photographs.
The flash and the smoke.
Could be a lot of things.
It don't mean nothin'.
Listen. Why the fuck does everything
have to be a conspiracy, huh?
A man has a couple too many drinks,
he drives off the road, falls into a creek.
- Accident. Plain and simple. Accident.
- It was not an accident.
Look. Let me tell you something.
I was there.
That tire was shot out.
I heard it, I recorded it.
So you're an "ear witness" to an assassination.
That's good.
It's got a nice ring. I like that.
Are you heading up the investigation?
- Yeah.
- All right. Did you check McRyan's tire?
No. Why should I?
Because there's a bullet hole in there
because he was killed.
- Says you, Terry. Everybody else says accident.
- Who? Who says accident?
I got a whole special commission forming here
that's gonna say it was an accident.
Oh, that's gonna say it was an accident?
Come on. They don't have the evidence.
They don't have the tape, the tire.
They didn't speak to me.
I know all about you and your fuckin' tapes.
You put a lot of good cops away.
- [ Phone Rings ]
- That has nothing to do with this.
- That's a separate issue, and I resent it.
- Yeah, well, I think you stink.
- Yeah, you stink too.
- That's what it's got to do with it. Hey, you.
Just because I don't like you,
does not mean I'm not gonna do my job.
Now give me that tape. I'll send it over
to the lab, and I'll have it checked out.
All right. Look. I want you to look at that film I made
from those photographs. I think you'll get the idea.
But if we can get a hold of Karp's original film,
this gunshot's gonna be a whole lot clearer.
Karp is making a bundle selling
his pictures from one magazine to another.
Now what the hell makes you think
he's gonna give 'em to us?
- He's got to. It's evidence.
- I can't find him, Terry.
- Find him! It's your job, man!
- Don't tell me how to do my goddamn job!
Do you know that he could answer
some questions...
like what the fuck he was really doing
with his camera up there?
Nobody wants to know.
Nobody cares.
No sordid details.
No political assassination. Accident.
This guy's dead, for Christ's sake.
None of this shit's gonna do him any good now.
This isn't for him.
I know he's dead.
Don't you understand that if they can get away
with this and kill McRyan, who's next?
Who's "they"?
First I want you to tell me who "they" is.
What is that,
a communist conspiracy of some kind?
Or maybe -- maybe it's a couple of ayatollahs
running out here in the street with blowguns.
- Oh, will you give me a break.
- Save your paranoia for public television.
Fuck you, Mackey. I'm gettin' out of here.
Put that stuff down. Put those pictures down,
or I'll have you arrested for withholding evidence.
Is that right?
All right.
I'll be at the office all day.
You can get me there.
I'll call you. Don't call me.
[ Dialing ]
It's Burke, sir.
What?
Burke? What have you done?
I don't understand the question, sir.
Are you crazy?
You were just supposed to
get some pictures of --
Are you aware of what you're saying, sir?
Where are you?
I'm calling from a secured
public phone booth, sir.
I suggest you call me back on the same.
Excuse me.
Is Mr. Karp in?
- Well, can I go in?
- What for?
- I just have to pick up some pictures, and I'll be on my way.
- Are you anybody?
- I'm one of his customers.
- [ Chuckles ]
You know, he had a lot of customers.
You're a reporter, ain't ya?
- No.
- Yeah, you want to get a piece of Karp's film, don't ya?
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- Too bad there ain't a law against lying.
I could have made
a hell of a lot of collars today, Mr. Customer.
- Look. I am a customer, and I'd like to pick up my pictures.
- Yeah, he's a customer too.
- He offered me a thousand bucks.
- Really?
Yeah, his wife offered me three.
Doesn't seem worth it,
but I guess you had to be there, huh?
Looks like Karp did
a little divorce work on the side.
[ Jack ]
Yes.
Sure didn't give a shit about his customers though.
I found these piled in a heap under his bed.
Boy, that's some baby picture.
You were supposed to get
some pictures of McRyan, not kill him.
I understood the objectives of the operation.
I never concurred with them.
But I didn't kill him.
It was an accident.
You accidentally shot out the tire of his car?
As you may recall, this was my initial plan
as proposed in our meeting of June the 6th.
We rejected that plan.
Don't you remember?
Of course, I do admit I had to exceed
the parameters of my authority somewhat...
but I always stayed within
an acceptable margin of error.
After all, the objective was achieved.
He was eliminated from the election.
Burke...
I don't know you.
I've never seen you.
Don't ever call me again.
Just a minute, sir.
We got some loose ends.
I changed the tire,
made it look like a blowout.
I erased the sound guy's tape
so everybody will think he's a crackpot.
Karp's disappeared, but I'll find him.
But that still leaves the girl.
I've decided to terminate her and make it look like
one of a series of sex killings in the area.
This would completely secure our operation.
What operation?
[ Screaming ]
Come on, Betty. Try again.
- Take 28.
- [ Beeps ]
[ Screaming ]
Cut.
Cut!
Remember, you have to speak into the mike.
They can't hear you.
Oh, Christ. Cut!
All right. Uh, switch.
Betty, you pull the hair.
Jean, you scream.
[ Man ]
Take 29.
[ Fake Screaming ]
[ Beeps ]
- Sam, I'll be in my room if you need me.
- Hey. Where the fuck have you been?
- I had some business to take care of, all right?
- [ Fake Screaming Continues ]
Shut up!
- Hey. I thought you were working for me.
- I am. What's the problem?
We need the effects for the other reel.
We made a list last week, remember?
- All right. Fine. I'll get 'em.
- You'll get 'em?
- I haven't even got the scream for the first reel.
- Yes.
[ Clicks ]
[ Speakers: Rhythmic Thumping Sound ]
[ Rhythmic Thumping Continues ]
[ Objects Clattering ]
[ Clicking ]
[ High-pitched Rhythmic Thumping ]
[ Rhythmic Thumping Continues ]
[ Third Reel: Low, Slow Thumping ]
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
[ All Thumping Continues ]
[ Fourth Reel: Rhythmic Whooshing ]
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
[ Rhythmic Thumping Continues ]
- [ Ringing Continues ]
- [ Rhythmic Thumping Continues ]
Why don't you answer your phone?
It's the police.
- Who's been in here today?
- Some guy. He said he wanted --
- Who? What guy? What guy?
- I don't think I like your tone of voice.
- [ Ringing Continues ]
- [ Rhythmic Thumping Continues ]
- Yes.
- [ Mackey ] What the hell is the matter with you?
- What?
- That fuckin' tape you gave me didn't have nothing on it.
All my tapes are blank.
You know, I don't get you, man.
First you feed me all this nutty assassination shit.
Then you give me a blank tape. What for?
Because somebody erased it.
They've erased all my tapes.
Oh. Oh, yeah. "They."
"They" erased your tapes.
What are they gonna be doing,
tryin' to kill you next?
You're fucking nuts.
[ Tape Ends Flapping ]
Sally, it's Jack.
Listen to me.
I have to show you that film that I made.
So just stay there.
I'm comin' right over.
- [ Man ] Jack Terry. Is he here?
- [ Debby ] Jack? Sure. Yeah.
- Frank Donahue. Channel --
- [ Jack ] Debby.
- Wait a minute. There he is now.
- [ Jack ] I'm going out for a while.
Jack. How are ya? I'm Frank Donahue.
Eye on the City News.
- Oh, yes. Yes.
- Could I talk to you a couple of minutes?
- No, no. Not -- Not right now.
- Come on, Jack. Two minutes. That's all I need.
Two minutes. I came all the way over here
to talk to you. Two minutes, I'm gone.
- What do you want to talk about?
- Well -- it's sort of private.
- Can we go back here and talk?
- Uh, yeah.
Oh, great. Great, great, great.
So you make movies here, huh?
[ Chuckles ]
I think I'm a frustrated actor myself, Jack.
What do you want?
You told the police that someone
shot out the tire on McRyan's car.
Who told you that?
No, no. Who told you that?
Jack, that's not important.
I'm a reporter. I-I -- I've got my sources.
No. All right. Why would a guy like you be interested
in some kind of assassination nut like me?
- Uh, Jack, I don't think that --
- [ Tape Ends Flapping ]
- Can we talk in here?
- No. No, no, no, no. Over here.
What do you mean "a nut"?
I-I -- I don't think you're a nut.
- In fact, that's why I'm here.
- Sit down.
You see, I've looked into this thing myself...
and there are just a hell of a lot of things
that don't add up about this, uh --
[ Chuckles ]
What are the cops calling it? A freak accident?
I mean, how about that girl?
Everyone's pretending she wasn't even in the car.
- Now you saw her --
- What else did this source of yours have to say?
Well, among other things, that, uh --
that you recorded that gunshot.
That's great work, Jack.
I'd sure like to hear the tape. Have you got it here?
What good would it be?
I mean, I could have made it in the recording studio.
You could have, but, uh --
[ Chuckles ]
I don't think you did.
I think you've got a tape, Jack,
and I think it's the real thing.
Let me put you on the air. There you can
tell everybody what you saw that night.
You tell 'em what you heard,
and then, boom...
we play that tape.
- It's a great story. What do you think?
- It's bullshit. Nobody'll believe it.
Hey! Frank Donahue believes it.
And he's got eight million people, Jack.
Eight million people
every night that watch him.
Go along with me on this.
I guarantee you, by 8:30 tomorrow night...
every one of those eight million sons of bitches
are gonna believe Jack Terry's story.
I promise you that.
[ Film Projector whirring ]
[ Gunshot ]
Yeah. That's what I heard,
just before the tire blew out.
You're right. It was a shot.
You took this to the police, huh?
Yes, I took it to the police, I gave them a copy,
they sent it to the lab, and then it came out blank.
- So somebody's erased it.
- Are you sure?
I transferred it myself, I heard it played back,
and now it's blank, like the rest of my tapes.
Okay. Okay. Calm down.
Now the sound is very clear.
It's the picture that's a little fuzzy.
Shit. Nobody'd believe it. They'd say
I made it up in a lab, and they'd be right.
Well, whosever in on this thing
has contacts with the police...
'cause they want McRyan
to sink without a trace.
They don't want to hear about my gunshot.
- Gee, what are you gonna do?
- What?
- What are you gonna do?
- What do you mean, what am I gonna do?
- What are we gonna do?
- What do I have to do with this?
Will you cut the shit, Sally?
I know what you were doing in that car.
What do you know?
That you and your friend Karp
were setting up McRyan to be blackmailed...
getting scummy pictures of you and the candidate
getting laid after the Liberty BalI, right?
What'd you do, tell him that running water
under a well-lit bridge gets you hot?
- Who told you that?
- I got a look at your earlier work.
Some motel candid camera shots.
You got nice tits.
Who was paying you to flash 'em for McRyan?
I wasn't in the car.
Or haven't you been reading the papers?
How long do you think
Henry's cover-up is gonna last?
I just talked to a reporter
who knows everything.
They have erased my tapes, they've made you
disappear, and next it's gonna be me.
- But I'm not disappearing. I'll tell you that.
- Yeah? I am.
- Yeah? What makes you think it won't be permanent?
- What's that supposed to mean?
Didn't I meet you in a car wreck
10 feet underwater?
Yeah, but that was an accident.
Manny wouldn't get me hurt.
- Didn't he get you into the car?
- Yeah, but-but-but he didn't know --
Yeah, but he didn't know that the tire
was gonna be shot out. He didn't know that.
- He-He couldn't have.
- Oh, come on, Sally.
If I hadn't been there to pull you out of the river,
you'd be dead right now. Don't you get it?
Sit down. Come on.
Sit down. I want to hear everything.
Just start right from the top.
Come on.
It was just a job like all the others.
I get 'em into bed,
and Manny'd get it all on film.
All right. "Them." who's "them"?
I don't know. Husbands. City officials.
- Mostly small-town guys.
- Why?
- The money.
- Oh, you need the money that bad?
Come on. You know where I work.
I get paid to smile my ass off and show
the 27 different color lipsticks they're pushing.
You know how much I make?
Shit is what I make.
And I sure as hell can't type,
so it doesn't leave a hell of a lot, you know.
So I did it.
I didn't really have to do anything,
like screw 'em or anything.
Just make it embarrassing.
I know.
Yeah, right.
Anyway, Manny said it served 'em right.
I mean, if a guy stuck his hand in the cookie jar,
he deserves to get it cut off.
Oh, can't cheat an honest man, right?
I guess I wanted to believe it.
Just made it easier.
- You know?
- Okay. McRyan. What about him?
Manny got me into the Liberty Ball.
I went over to McRyan.
I told him what a great guy he was,
and he was very hot to show me.
So we slipped out the back
and took off in his car.
All right. Now who hired Manny
to take these pictures?
I don't know.
Well, don't you think that Manny knew
that his client was planning to shoot out the tire?
No.
- Well, it wouldn't pay to tell you, now would it?
- Manny wouldn't do that.
- Well, didn't he want to make an extra buck?
- Yeah, right.
Yeah, 'cause he's making big bucks
selling them pictures now. What's your cut?
- I got paid.
- Yeah, underpaid probably.
- What do you care?
- I'm sick of being fucked by these guys. That's what I care.
I mean, look. First Henry gets me to shut up
to preserve the reputation of the great governor...
and then I find out instead of getting laid he gets
murdered, and nobody wants to know about it.
I mean, nobody wants to know
about conspiracy. I don't get it.
Let me tell you something. All right?
I know what I heard and what I saw.
And I'm not gonna stop until everyone in this
fuckin' country hears and sees the same thing.
And you're gonna help me.
Yeah, you.
You're gonna find your pal Karp,
and you're gonna get that original film.
'Cause this isn't any good.
I need the original.
'Cause if we don't get this out
and on television for everybody to see...
they're gonna close the book, and any loose ends
that happen to be hanging out...
like you or me,
are gonna be cut right off.
So you got your choice.
You can be crazy or dead. Either will do.
All right. All right. Look.
I'll try and get the film.
Now will you just leave me alone about all this?
I wish I was the only one
you had to worry about.
You know, if you're trying to scare me,
you're doing a good job.
- I am trying to save our asses.
- I'll look after my own ass, thank you.
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Bottle Clinks ]
- [ Sally ] Things aren't adding up, Manny.
- Yeah? Like what?
- Here you go.
- How did I end up in that car?
Come on. Sit down. Have a seat.
Take a load off your mind.
How did I end up in that car
in the bottom of the creek?
Well, listen. What do you think?
I mean, uh, the guy's driving along,
and all of a sudden he has a blowout.
It wasn't a blowout, Manny.
Somebody shot out the tire.
Oh, what the hell are you talkin' about, huh?
How do you know that?
I know. I know. I just know.
- Now, who was it?
- It was nobody.
Come on, Manny.
Just level with me.
[ Sighs ]
All right. This, uh -- This nut --
He-He calls me a couple of weeks ago...
and, uh, he says he's working
for some candidate --
some, uh -- some candidate that's interested
in gettin' McRyan out of the race, huh?
Sounds like a normal joe, right?
He says he's heard all about our fine
divorce work, and he offers me six grand.
Six? You told me three.
Yeah. Well, uh, three before
and-and-and three after.
So when were you gonna tell me
about the three after?
After I collected it.
When do you think?
Yeah. Sure.
Hey. Hey, what's the matter with you?
You think I'm pulling your leg or some --
You don't believe me?
Listen. How was I gonna be sure
that this guy was gonna come through?
l mean, uh, six grand --
that's a lot of money for this kind of a job, huh?
I'd say he got his money's worth.
He wasn't supposed to die, for Christ's sake.
He wasn't even supposed to get hurt.
That was an accident, huh?
You know, I figured it out later.
This nut's idea was to, uh --
to shoot out the tire of McRyan's car...
cause a little crack-up.
- The police show up, they pull him out of the car --
- With me?
Yeah, yeah. With you. And, uh --
And I'd get it all on film.
Some little crack-up.
He wasn't supposed to die.
That part was an accident.
How many times I gotta tell you that?
Manny, we got him killed.
Oh, hey. Wait, wait. "We"?
What do you mean "we," huh?
We didn't do nothin'. "We"?
I-I -- I was in the woods. You were in the car.
l didn't shoot out no tire.
You didn't either.
So, uh -- So, please, don't give me
none of this, uh -- this conscience shit, huh?
Besides, I mean,
uh, nobody is exactly crying...
over the way things turned out,
if you know what I mean.
what would have happened
if the guy had have lived, huh?
His career was finished, thanks to us.
- This way, uh, the guy comes out ahead, huh?
- [ Urinating ]
[ Chuckles ]
He's a saint. A martyr.
Christ, they passed
one of his bills this morning.
- [ Chuckles ]
- You're a pig, Manny.
And I'm a pig too.
Hey. What-what the hell is with this "pig" shit?
what's the matter with you?
We gotta tell the truth before the books are closed
and the loose ends are cut off.
Hey. Wh -- what are you talkin' about?
McRyan was murdered,
and everybody should know that.
Are you crazy?
We got him killed.
Do you want to go to jail?
Yeah, but -- but I was in the car,
and you were in the woods.
You think anybody is gonna believe that?
l don't know, but I gotta do somethin'.
Yeah, like just keep your mouth shut
and take the money.
Hey, babe. Listen. This is the biggest thing
since, uh -- since the Zapruder film.
- I don't care.
- It's bigger.
l mean, this is --
this is history we got here, girl.
l mean, this is gonna be a goddamn fortune.
Listen. It's gonna be in every newspaper.
It's gonna be in every magazine. It's gonna be
on the -- on the fuckin' six o'clock news.
They're gonna build TV specials
around this thing...
and they're gonna ask a goddamn fortune for it.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey. Hey, don't you understand, sweetheart?
Hey. We're set.
I don't care, Manny.
l don't want any part of this thing.
You can keep your three after.
Hey. Don't be such a dope, huh?
Money's money.
We sound like a couple of vultures.
[ Chuckles ]
What, pigs, vultures -- you swallow
a whoIe box of animal crackers or what?
[ Chuckling ]
l need a drink, Manny.
Come on. Give me a drink.
Ah, yeah. Sure.
l can get us a drink.
Just give me the bottle.
Girl --
[ Chuckles ]
Hey. Now you're thinkin', babe.
Go over to, uh, Atlantic City maybe, huh?
- You ever been to Atlantic City?
- I don't like Atlantic City.
- No. Hey. I'Il show you around.
- Manny, stop. Come on.
- We'll have a lot of good times.
- Manny, stop.
- Hey, sweetheart. We'll have a lot of laughs.
- Please, Manny, don't.
- Oh, baby.
- Please don't do it.
No, Manny. Come on. Please!
[ Karp ]
Relax, baby.
[ Sally Grunting, Shouting ]
[ Sally Screams ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Whirring ]
- [ Gunshot ]
- Fantastic! Oh!
[ Tires Squealing ]
- Great.
- [ Crash ]
Well, now what?
You're great. I'm gonna call that TV guy,
we're gonna get it on the air.
- Can I make you something to eat?
- Yeah, that'd be fine.
- How about some cornflakes?
- Anything.
[ Plates Clink ]
Frank Donahue, please.
It's Jack Terry.
- Yeah.
- [ Woman ] Mr. Donahue, Jack Terry calling.
One moment, please.
- Mr. Donahue.
- Jack, yeah.
Listen. Uh, l-I've changed my mind.
l want you to hear that tape.
I've also got ahold of Karp's original film...
and if you run them together,
anyone can see it wasn't an accident.
That's great, Jack.
Look. I can't talk now.
Can I get back to you in about 20 minutes?
What's your number?
[ Burke Sobbing ]
l don't know why.
She -- she wanted me to do it.
She asked for it.
[ Sobbing ]
She begged me for it, the bitch.
[ Moans ]
l -- I didn't want to do it.
[ Sobbing ]
She made me do it.
No. You ask her.
Sh-Sh-Sh-She'll tell you.
- [ Man ] Okay. Where is she?
- [ Engine Starts ]
- I don't know. Somewhere.
- [ Engine Revving ]
In that big hole.
You know, near the Reading Market
where they're -- they're building something.
But don't listen to her.
She made me do it.
Okay. Just tell me where you are.
Where --
- [ Phone Rings ]
- Listen, Jack.
You realize this won't mean a thing
unless you come on the air...
and you say it's what you saw
and what you heard.
- I'Il say it's what I heard.
- Okay. That's great.
- [ Children Chattering ]
- Jack, what about that girl?
She was there. She must have heard it.
Could we get her on?
No. Look.
She did, but don't involve her, okay? I mean --
Why not?
Well, because she's just --
She's not exactly proud of what she did.
Okay. No problem, Jack. No problem.
But could I at least talk to her?
Well, that's up to her. I-I -- I --
Okay. Look. I'll take care of that.
Uh, Jack, could you hold on just one second?
[ Whispering ]
Jack, when can we get together?
When can I see the stuff?
- [ Jack ] Anytime.
- Okay, great.
Look. Can I give you a call this afternoon sometime?
Where can I reach you?
- I'Il be home all day.
- Okay, I'll call you then.
So long.
Oh, hi. How you doing?
- Listen. I just spoke to Donahue.
- Who's he?
You know, he's a TV newsman
who does alI the investigative pieces.
Oh, it doesn't mean anything to me.
l don't watch the news.
- [ Siren wailing ]
- What?
- [ Sally ] What's he want to do?
- Well, he said that he'd put it on the air...
- he'd call me later and set up a meeting.
- That's great.
[ Jack ] He also said he'd like me to go on TV
and say that it's what I saw and heard.
He said a tape really wouldn't be
any good without it.
But he'd also like you to go on too.
Oh, no. Forget it.
l don't want any part of it.
Well, uh, I know you didn't want to get involved,
but would you at least speak to him?
No, I don't want to.
Come on, Sally.
Look. They can't say we're both hearing things.
l mean, if we get this out in the open,
l mean, there's no one that can hurt us.
All right. Look. I'll think about it, okay?
At city hall this morning...
Chief Inspector Mackey
of the Philadelphia Police held a news conference.
He said a preliminary investigation
into Governor McRyan's death...
revealed that he was the victim
of a freak accident.
- Bullshit.
- Also in the news today...
is the bizarre sex killing of Mary Robert...
a 22-year-old receptionist
from the Center City area.
Her body was found at 10:00 a.m.
in the Reading Terminal excavation site...
after police received a tip
from an anonymous caller.
[ Beeping ]
[ Busy Signal ]
The girl had first been strangled...
then repeatedly stabbed with a pointed
instrument across her stomach and groin.
The stab marks were in the pattern
of the Liberty Bell.
Police are at a loss to explain
this grotesque mutilation.
We asked forensic psychologist
Dr. Joseph Fuchs...
what connection there might be between
the bell-shaped pattern of the wounds...
and the upcoming Liberty Day celebration.
- Hi. This is Sally.
- Hi, Sally. Frank Donahue here.
Yeah. You were supposed to call Jack.
You know, Sally, it's the damnedest thing.
l can't get Jack on the phone to arrange a meeting.
His line's been busy all day.
So, uh, I thought I'd give you a ring.
Yeah, so?
[ Dog Barking ]
Something's wrong with your phone.
I've been trying to call you alI day
and I kept getting a busy signal.
What are you talking about? I've been here
aIl afternoon. I've been waiting for Donahue's call.
- Oh, yeah. He's been trying to call you too, but he was getting a busy signal.
- How do you know that?
He called me. He wants to meet me
at 30th Street Station at 5:00.
Well, how did he get your number?
- Didn't you give it to him?
- No.
Well, what difference does it make?
Reporters have a way of getting numbers, you know.
So I'm gonna meet him, I'll give him the tape
and the film, and that'll be it.
What do you mean you're gonna give him the tape?
Why didn't he call me back?
He wants to meet with me alone.
He's trying to talk me into going on the air.
No. He should have called me back.
This isn't right.
- Your phone is out of order.
- My phone is not out of order.
I've been here alI day.
I made a phone call.
- [ Dial Tone ]
- Here. Listen.
- Maybe the phone company's in on the conspiracy too.
- No, no, no. Something's not right.
I mean, what difference does it make?
Let's just meet him.
I'll give him the tape and the film
and get it over with.
Once he's got the film, that's it.
All right.
- All right. He wants to meet you, right?
- Yeah.
Okay, you're gonna go,
and you're gonna meet him.
Okay, and if he sounds okay,
you'll give him the film and tape.
- Where are you gonna be?
- Close.
I don't get it.
I'm gonna wire you.
Wire me? What for?
I'm gonna cover alI the bases.
Nobody's gonna fuck me this time.
This way if he disappears with the film...
he can't pretend he didn't take it,
'cause I got him on tape.
Aren't you gettin' a little paranoid here?
He's a newsman.
This is a very big story.
Why isn't he gonna put this on the air?
Look what happened when I took it to the police.
They erased it, right?
- What are you doin'?
- I'm making a copy.
- There's nothing wrong with covering ourselves.
- Yeah? Well, what about the film?
What about the fiIm?
I can't make a copy now. I don't have time to do that.
Okay, okay. Bring on the wire.
- Take off your coat.
- Okay. Let's get it over with.
[ Woman On P.A. ] May I have your attention, please?
Now boarding, Stairway 5, Track 5...
Amtrak's 4:50 Metroliner service...
stopping at --
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
Capital Beltway and Washington.
Now boarding, Stairway 5.
[ Woman ]
I guess you get to travel a lot, huh?
[ Man ] Oh, yeah, yeah. I've been
all over the place. You know what I mean?
[ Woman ]
Yeah, I traveled once.
So, uh -- so, you got
about 60 minutes and about $60?
- Oh, no. Did I say that? Uh --
- Yeah, you did say that.
No. I think I have, uh, about 20 minutes
and about, uh, $20 is what I've got.
Gee, it's too bad you don't have
about 40 minutes and about $40.
- Yeah, that's too bad. That's really too bad.
- Yeah, that's too bad.
[ Sailor ] what I've got is about, uh,
20 minutes and about $20.
[ Winds ]
[ Woman ] weIl, you know, the trains never
come in on time. They're always running late here.
- They're notorious. You know what I mean?
- Uh-huh. Yeah. I know what you mean.
- [ Woman ] I bet you at least got 30 minutes. At least.
- [ Winding, Clicking ]
- [ Sailor ] Do I have to have 30 minutes?
- At least 30 minutes.
[ Sailor ] Well, you know, I believe I --
I believe I do have...
about 30 minutes and about, uh, $30.
Great. I'll tell you what.
I'll make a quick phone call...
and I'll meet you in the back of the waiting room
in about two minutes. Okay?
You know, that should be two dollars off,
but, uh, we'll let you go this time.
- You know what I mean? Huh?
- No. I don't know what you mean.
- You know what I mean? See ya.
- Yeah.
I know what you mean.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, Ralphie.
[ Men Chattering ]
- Yeah. You got a girlfriend, right?
- [ All Chattering ]
Yeah. Just enjoy your puppet show, you know.
- What are you doin'?
- Have a good Liberty Day.
- [ Zipper Unzips ]
- [ Whistling ]
[ Thumping ]
[ Sailor ]
Oh, slower. Ah, shit!
[ Woman ] Jesus. Some hotshot sailor you are.
That's ridiculous!
Why don't you grow up
and learn a thing or two, sailor boy?
Yeah, well, I've been on a sh --
It's 10 for you, baby. Ten.
Hey, what about my $30? You fuck!
[ Sailor ]
You blew it. You know what I mean?
Shit.
- [ Woman On P.A. ] Now boarding, Stairway 3, Track 3.
- Jesus Christ.
- [ Tapping ]
- Amtrak 5:00 New York Express.
[ Tapping ]
Stairway 3, Track 3...
for the 5:00 New York Express...
stopping at North Philadelphia...
Trenton, Princeton Junction...
- New Brunswick, Metropark --
- [ Mouthing words ]
- [ Mouthing Words ]
- Newark and New York.
Stairway 3, Track 3,
5:00 New York Express.
[ Phone Booth Door Rattles ]
[ Winding ]
[ Yelps ]
[ Woman On P.A. ]
May I have your attention, please?
- [ Banging ]
- This will be the last call...
for the Broadway Limited...
to Pittsburgh and Chicago.
All passengers traveling
all the way to Chicago...
and passengers holding space in car 4140 --
You don't think you're overdoing this
a little bit, do ya?
We've got nothing to lose.
You know, if I had any sense, I'd take this stuff,
and I'd dump it in the trash, and that'd be it.
Yeah, but then I got the original at home. So --
So why all of this?
Because of Manny's film.
I toId you. We gotta be careful with it.
You know, the onIy real trouble
I ever got into was when I was too careful.
All right.
Here.
Okay. Give me a sound level.
Count to 10. Slow.
- One, two, three, four --
- No, no, no. Just normal.
One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten.
- All right. All right.
- Come on. We gotta get goin' here.
Okay. Now look.
Don't forget you got this on, okay?
- Okay.
- If you need me, just talk to me.
- You got that right there.
- Okay. Affirmative.
- Sally. Come here.
- What?
Thank you.
Over and out.
[ Woman On P.A. ]
Stairway 3, Track 4...
for the Merchants Limited...
stopping at Trenton, Newark, New York, Rye --
[ Sally ]
Hello, Jack. Can you hear me?
You know, like I was saying before, you know,
about goin' to New York and stuff...
we could see some shows, like, uh --
you know, like Sugar Babies and stuff.
And I know this great hotel
in the Times Square ar --
Sally?
- Hi. I'm Frank Donahue.
- Oh, hi. Nice to meet you.
Listen. Uh, would you mind
just walking with me for a moment?
- [ Sally ] Where are we goin'?
- Well --
I think we got a little problem.
- What's that?
- It sounds crazy, but, uh -- [ Chuckles ]
l think we're being followed.
Yeah. No problem.
[ Soft Chattering ]
[ Woman ]
Hold the elevators.
- [ Man Chattering ]
- [ Woman #2 Laughs ]
[ Sally ]
Gee, you're a fast walker.
- [ Train whistle Blows ]
- Well, in my business, you gotta be fast on your feet.
- Where's Jack?
- Uh -- Oh, he's at home, resting.
- Ah, I know what the pressure can do to you.
- Gee, which train are we takin'?
- I don't know yet. You got the tape and the film?
- Yeah, it's right here in my bag.
- [ Chuckles ] That's wonderful.
- [ Turnstile Rattles Loudly ]
So I guess we lost 'em, huh?
Well, we can't be too careful.
I tell you what.
Why don't you just walk slowIy down to
the end of the platform right in front of me, okay?
Gee, now I don't know why you'd think
anyone would want to follow us anyway.
Ah, you'd be amazed what some people
would do for a story like this.
- Yeah, I guess so.
- No, no. Don't turn around.
We don't want to give ourselves away, huh?
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Sally chuckles ] Yeah, right.
Just pretend like
nothing's happening, all right?
Just look at this place.
This is disgusting, you know.
- Yeah. It's a real shame.
- And it's not even safe anymore, you know.
It reminds me of that story about that guy
in New York. You remember that one?
Yeah, I think we did a piece on him.
Yeah, he's the guy.
He'd ride the subways at rush hour...
and he'd stand in the corner real quiet,
so as nobody'd notice him, you know.
And then they'd pulI into a station...
and he'd open up his coat,
and he'd pull out this big old meat cleaver...
and wham, he'd whack 'em
right over the head with it.
- Let's go, SalIy.
- Yeah. And then they had this transit strike, and --
and he just disappeared.
It was like he went on strike too, you know.
That's why I don't ride the subways anymore,
'cause it's just not safe, you know.
I mean, I wouldn't even come down here
if it wasn't for you. [ Gasps ]
- Come on. Speak up. Come on.
- [ Sally ] You see what I mean?
You see that creepy character?
That's what I'm talkin' about.
It's just not safe anymore.
[ Clicks Tongue ]
[ Train Approaching ]
[ SalIy ]
Oh, the train's comin'.
- [ Train Grows Louder ]
- [ Indistinct ]
- Is that where we're goin'?
- Where? Come on.
- They're having the fireworks tonight?
- [ Burke ] That's right.
Hey, listen. They got a nice bar down there.
Why don't we have our drink and our little chat...
and take in the fireworks at the same time?
- What do you think?
- Sure. Okay.
- [ Burke ] Would you like to help me cover the story?
- [ Chuckles ] All right.
[ Chuckles ]
- It'd give us the woman's angle.
- Yeah.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sally ]
Franklin Bridge Express, huh?
Where are you goin' there?
[ Muffled ]
Sally!
So what's the big deal with Liberty Day?
- Did you see our story about it?
- No, I don't watch the news. It's too depressing.
[ Engine Starts ]
- [ Marching Band Music ]
- [ Cheering ]
[ Music Continues ]
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Horse whinnies ]
- [ Whinnies ]
- Whoa!
[ Marching Band Music ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Tires Squeal ]
[ Chattering ]
Somebody get an ambulance!
- [ Woman Shouts ]
- Try that back door!
[ Woman ]
Is he aIl right?
[ All Chattering ]
[ Marching Band Music Continues ]
In 16 or 35?
- What do you mean?
- [ Chuckles ]
The gauge of the film.
They've only got, uh,
16 mm equipment out at the station.
- Yeah. I think that's what it is.
- Why don't you let me have a look at it?
- Oh, sure.
- Here. Come on over into the light.
- [ All Shouting ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
- [ Shouts ]
- [ Honking Continues ]
- Here it is.
- [ Foghorn Blows ]
- Got the tape too?
- Yeah.
Yeah, that's 16 all right.
What, are you wrapping it up?
- What did you do that for?
- [ Splashes ]
Jack's gonna kill you.
Oh, God. No.
No! No! Jack!
[ Screams ]
One more sound and you're dead.
[ Sally Grunts ]
[ Sobs ]
Come on, Sally.
We're gonna cover the fireworks.
Remember?
[ Arguing, Indistinct ]
[ Garrote Winding ]
[ Sally Grunts ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Sally Screams ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Sally Grunting ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Burke Grunts ]
Jack, please!
Oh, God!
Jack! Please!
No!
Oh, Jack!
[ Screaming ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Groans ]
[ Fireworks Popping ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
- [ No Sounds ]
- [ Instrumental Piano ]
[ Sally's Voice ]
Hello, Jack. Can you hear me?
You know, like I was saying before, you know,
about goin' to New York and stuff...
we could see some shows, like, uh --
you know, like Sugar Babies and stuff.
And I know this great hotel
in the Times Square ar --
[ Man ] Two more young women were killed
by the so-called Liberty Bell Strangler.
But the tragedy ended
when the final victim, Sally Bedina...
killed her attacker in a bloody struggle
on the top of the Port of History Building...
during the Liberty Day fireworks celebration.
The identity of the strangler
has not yet been determined.
The tragedy of Governor McRyan's death...
continues to send shock waves
throughout the nation.
[ Sally Sobbing ]
Oh, Jack!
Oh, God!
- [ Burke Shouts ]
- Oh, why?
[ Burke ] Come on!
[ Grunting ]
- [ Sally Sobbing ]
- [ Burke Grunting ]
[ Burke Grunts ]
Yeah. Yeah.
- [ Grunts ]
- Jack, please!
- Oh, God!
- [ Burke Grunts ]
God, Jack!
[ Sally Screams ]
Now that's a scream!
- [ Man Speaks, Indistinct ]
- More, more, more on the scream.
- Come on. Bring it up. Bring it up.
- [ Man ] All right. I'll give --
That's wonderful.
[ Man ]
What did you think of the rest of the mix?
O-Okay. We-we --
On the beginning --
It's a good scream.
[ Sally Screams ]
[ Screams ]
[ Sobbing ]
No!