[ Screaming ]
This is Andy Barclay.
Eight years ago
he touch off the scandal...
that nearly
crippled, this copany,
claiming that his Good Guydoll,
Chucky, was possessed by...
Charles Lee Ray,
the notorious
Lakeshore Strangler.
Now l ask you,
Iadies and gentlemen,
after the lawsuits
and negative publicity,
when the company is finally
getting back on its feet,
where is the wisdom in
putting the Good Guy
back on the market?
Mr. Sullivan,
before this happened...
the Good Guy outsold
our other toys 2 to 1 .
Even now, interest in the
marketplace is at its peak.
The factoy is up
and running again.
We should be in stores
by next week.
We cannot let the fantasies
ofone disturbed boy...
influence company policy.
What if the doll
somehow...
affects anotherchild
in a negative way?
You could have
a public relations nightmare.
One ofthe hardest things
about this business is...
that it is
a business
Doesn't matter
what we're selling.
Whether it's cars
nuclear weapons...
or yes, even toys.
The bottom line
is the bottom line
And what are children
but consummer tranees?
Andy Barclay is ancient histoy.
No one remembers him.
Nobody cares.
l have made up my mind.
We're moving ahead.
Thank you.
Okay.
Al l right.
Mr. Sullivan.
lf there's nothing l can
say to convince you,
then l must
go on record.
l'm completely
against this.
Your position is
cystal clear, Miles.
And you can be sure
l won't forget.
Just a minute, folks.
Mr. Sullivan,
we have a surprise.
Guys at the factoy
sent this over.
First offthe assembly line,
the Good Guy of the '90s.
[ Clapping ]
lf there's nothing else,
l'm gonna get going.
Fine.
it's just, my wife's expecting me.
lt's our anniversay.
Fine, Petzold.
l could review the Larrabee
report after dinner.
Good night,
Mr. Sullivan.
Good night.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
Ahh_
Despite a downdraft
in the bond market,
stocks were able
to post a rally on friday...
thanks to a couple
of different factors.
Not only did the employment
report allay recession fears,
but also there was
a technical rebound in buying...
and a resurgence in deal stocks
helped set the tone.
Here's a look at the numbers.
The Dow industrial's up 16.
The transportation
average up 3.
Utilities bouncing up--
ln a moment's time --
Oh, shit.
[Tv]
Bonds headed south on the economic data,
which served
to bolster the U.S. dollar.
The dollar index
up a quarter point.
The CRB index up...
point 43 at
two-thirty point 43.
March crude up...
[ Yelling ]
[ Siren Blaring ]
rTrain Whistle l
[ HelicopterWhirring ]
Hi, my name is Larry.
Hi, my name
is Pauly.
- Hey,wanna play?
- Hey, wanna play?
- l like to be hugged.
Hi, my name is Lary.
Hi, my name is Pauly.
Hey, wanna play?
l like to be hugged.
Hi, my name is Lary.
Hi, my name is Pauly.
Hey, wanna play?
l like to be --
[Yelling ]
[ Laughing ]
Don't fuck
with the Chuck.
Oh, my God.
- Owww!
- Bull's-eye.
_www!
[ Yelling ]
Just like
the good old days.
Nothing like a strangulation
to get the circulation going.
You're my only
ticket out of here, Andy.
l gotta get out of
this goddamn body.
Where are you,
you little shit?
lnward hut.
Come on, come on.
Yeah, you can do it.
You can do it,
Jackson, hurry up.
Come on, let's go.
Yeah, come on.
Get moving.
go to the end of the line.
[ Drum Playing ]
,Left, left
Ieft, left.
l see for the past
eight years...
you've been in one
foster home after another.
Mind if l ask why?
They took me away
from my mother.
She's under special care.
l knnw that.
How come you never
got settled anywhere?
Adiustment problems.
l can read, Barclay.
l'm asking you.
l never felt comfortable
with those people.
They weren't family.
They were strangers.
All right,
listen up, Barclay.
l'm willing to cutyou some slack,
because you've had it rough.
But you're a troublemaker.
And l got a problem
with troublemaker.
They don't fit
into the system.
So here's my advice.
Grow up!
You're not
a kid anymore.
lt's time to forget these
fantasies of killer dolls.
Yes, sir.
''When l was a child,
''l thought as a child.
''When l became a man,
l put away
childish things.''
First Conrinthians.
Look alive.
On your feet.
At Kent, we take
bed wetters and
turn's them into men.
Oh, yes.
Yes, oh.
Yes, we're seeing some
skin now, aren't we?
Presto, you're bald.
Always feels
weird at first.
Next.
Kiss it good-bye.
The Romans invented
the militay cut.
You know why?
Why?
To keep
their hair short,
so their enemies couldn't
grab it in battle...
and slit
their throat.
Ha, ha, ha.
Now hold still.
Oh, shit.
Ha, ha, ha.
[Tv]
We're back and we're better than ever.
No one will
play with me.
Uh-oh, there's
a friend indeed
[Tv]
Hey, cheer up.
Who are you?
l'm a Good Guy.
[ Echoing ]
Good Guy, Good Guy, Good Guy!
l've just come from
the Good Guy clubhouse...
and l'll be
your friend to the end.
You will?
[ Echoing ] Wow.
Sure l will.
Hi-de-ho.
All aboard for
high-flying fun with me,
your friend to the end,
the Good Guydoll from Play Pals.
[ Thumping ]
Are you okay?
Bastards!
Fucking bastards!
What happened?
Shelton!
That's what happened!
Shelton and
his goddamn lackeys.
Thankyou.
l'm fine
l'm Andy.
You must be new.
Otherwise...
you'd know they don't
tolerate individuality,
nothing as personal
as the first name.
Right. l forgot.
- Barclay.
- Whitehurst.
Harold Aubrey,
for the record.
So, who's this Shelton?
Cadet lieutenant Colonel
Brett C. Shelton.
He's God around here
Don't expect mercy from him.
Welcome to hell, Barclay.
All present and
accounted for, sir.
Thank you, Major Ellis.
You're new boy, huh?
Yeah.
How you doing?
Pretty good.
Who said you
could look at me?
Doyou know
who l am?
Shelton?
That's Lieutenant Colonel
Shelton to you, asshole!
[Andy]
Lieutenant Colonel Shelton.
Lieutenant Colonel.
Shelton
sir.
Lieutenant Colonel
Shelton, sir.
-What's your name, dipweed?
- Barclay.
- Sir.
- Louder
- Louder!
- sir!
That's much better,
new boy.
That's much better.
Shit, Whitehurst.
You are
without a doubt...
the most pathetic thing
l have ever seen!
Wouldn't you agree?
l asked you
a question, nimrod.
No, sir!
l don't agree, sir!
Areyou contradicting me,
you sory-ass sack of shit?
You asshole.
- What did you say?
- l said, ''You asshole." sir!
Think you're pretty funny,
don't you, De Silva?
Yes, l do, sir.
Drop and
give me 25.
Right now.
25 what, sir?
25 push-ups,
De Silva.
One, sir! Two, sir!
Three, sir!
You women might think...
that because you're
so much delicate...
you deserve
special treatment...
and once a month
we're gonna
get out ofyourway.
You can forget it!
1 3, sir!
1 4, sir!
The same rules
apply for eveybody.
18, sir!
Only the fittest
survive.
22,sir!
23,sir!
One-handed.
24, sir!
25....sir!
Recover.
How you doing,
Tyler?
Sory, nothing
from your dad.
Maybe tomorrow.
Listen, he's busy flying jets,
defending the county.
He'll write when
he gets a chance.
l know.
Hey!
l got a iob foryou.
Give this to
the new kid gfor me.
- Barclay.
- Yes, sir.
That a boy.
Out ofthe way.
Watch it, kid.
Hey!
look out!
A Good Guy.
[ Yelling ]
Who the fuck are you?
l thoughtyou guys
only said three sentences.
l'm new and improved.
l never saw
a doll like you before.
All right, kid.
Fun's over.
Where the hell's Andy?
Andy?
Can't you read?
He was supposed to get this package.
Tampering with the mail
is a federal offense.
Sorry.
Is he your best friend?
He's more than that.
He's my new lease
on life
Wait a minute.
l got a new body...
and l ain't told anyone
about my little secret yet.
So, what's your name,
kid?
Tyler.
What's yours?
Chucky.
But my real name...
is Charles Lee Ray.
[ Shooting ]
Whitehurst,
What am l doing wrong?
ls there anything
you can't do?
Yeah.
l can't get thrown
out ofthis place.
Barclay,
meet De Silva.
Hi
Hi. So, you
want to show me?
Yeah, sure.
Okay.
No, put the elbow
like that.
And like this.
No. Keep both
eyes open.
Keepyour sights
on the target.
Hold your breath.
Squeeze the trigger.
Don't pull it.
(Gunshot )
You're not
concentrating.
lt was great what you
did for us at formation.
Shelton's a maior dick.
Te me about it.
[ Gunshot ]
[ Chucky]
Hold still.
What doyou call
this game?
''Hide the Soul.''
Trust me, you're gonna love it.
Whateveryou say,
Charles.
Ade due
Damballa!
Give me the power,
l beg of you!
[ Thundering ]
Leveau mercierdu bois
chaloitte..
secoisse entienne
mais pois de--
[ Door Closing ]
Shit!
[Tyler]
Charles,
stop swearing.
We're gonna need the
Springfield aught-threes...
Yes, sir.
marked for both the
red team and the blue team.
What areyou doing,
Tyler?
We're playing
''Hide the soul.''
l'll catch up with you.
l'll start loading
the paint guns.
We don't play with dolls,
do we?
Dolls are forgirls.
But Charles
is my new best friend.
You know better than to
talk back to a superior.
Yes, sir.
Clean that up.
l'll take care of this.
[ Good GuyVoice ]
l'll be back!
Left, left
Left, right, left.
Left, left.
[ Shelton ]
Get that weapon up, Barclay.
Platoon, halt.
Left face.
New boy! Fall out.
Fall out!
[ Shelton ]
Order, hut.
Port arms!
Right shoulder...
Arms!
Left shoulder...
Arms.!
Right shoulder,
arms.!
leftshoulder,
[ Shelton ]
Port arms.
[ Echoing ]
left shoulder, arms.
Port arms.
[ Echoing ]
Right shoulder, arms.
Port arms.
Barclay!
lt's not a baton,
Barclay.
You look like a goddamn
majorette over here.
l'm not used
to guns, sir.
Does this look like
a gun to you, Barclay?
lt's a rifle.
- Major Ellis!
- Sir!
Show the new boy
the difference.
This is my rifle.
This is my gun.
This is for shooting
and this is for fun.
A soldier's rifle
is his best friend.
Remember that.
Stop!
Shit!
[ Chucky]
Help!
Please, mister!
Please,
somebody!
Jesus!
l'm stuck, mister!
l'm in here!
Hold on!
l'm coming!
Where are you?
l'm coming.
Yell!
Make a noise!
Where are ya?
[ Gasping ]
Oh, my God!
No, stop!
[ Laughing ]
Stop!
[Yelling ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Shelton ]
fall out!
You get back there.
Finish
unpacking.
Shelton's notorious
for surprise
inspections.
What areyou doing?
What it's look like?
l'm polishing
Shelton shoes.
He makes you polish his shoes?
No, l offered out ofthe
kindness of my heart.
Whitehurst,
did you see Cochrane
with that doll today?
No, what doll?
He was carying
a Good Guy doll...
iust before the accident
with the garbage truck.
Good Guys.
l remember those.
Yeah, me too.
[ Spitting ]
Lights out
in a few minutes.
l'm gonna go
get washed up.
l almost forgot.
Sgt. Clarkwanted to know
ifyou got that package.
What package?
He said you got
a package in the mail.
Tylerwas supposed
to bring it toyou.
Didn't you get it?
No.
Who would have
sent me a package?
Owww!
Hey, long time
no see, pal!
No, you're dead!
We killed you!
You know what they say.
''Youjust can't keep
a good guy down.''
[ Laughing ]
Andy,
how you've grown.
You're not gonna kill me.
You need to transfer your soul.
Wrong again, wimp.
l got some fresh meat lined up.
l'm not gonna let
you spoil it this time.
- Tyler?
- Yeah.
Just think.
Chucky's gonna be a ''bro.''
l'm not gonna let
you get away with this.
you near that kid.
Agh!
[ Laughing ]
What's the matter?
You home sick?
You miss
your mommy?
What the fuck is this?
l'm sorry about your shoe.
l'll polish it.
Give me back the doll.
No, you
listen to me.
Tell Whitehurst
he's off the hook.
l got myself
another slave.
Clean up this mess.
You got five demerits.
What about the doll?
My kid sister's
birthday's coming up.
l think she's gonna
love it, don't you?
[ Closet Door Creaking ]
[ Whispering ]
Oh, shit.
Andy.
What the fuck?
No, stop!
What the fuck you
doing in my room?
You wouldn't believe me.
J
Where's the doll
Barclay?
Where's
the fucking doll ?
- You took it, didn't you?
- No!
What's going on?
Somebody sure as hell took it.
lt's almost midnight.
Is this necessay?
l'm tying to weed
out a thief. sir.
You've always told me
how important it is...
to uphold the school's
code of honor.
All right,
make your point.
But l want eveybody
back in at 01:00 hours.
Yes, sir.
By the time we get
through with Barclay,
he's gonna be living
in the world full mof shit.
We got an hour,
so let's make it count.
Yes, sir.
Ladies, get those
weapons in the air.
l want to see them high.
Higher!
l think
l'm gonna throw up.
You're dead, new boy.
fucking geek.
''Dear Charles,
you're it.
Come and find me.
Your best friend''
Shit!
Charles
Come and
find me.
Goddamn it.
Platoon!
[ Cadets ]
Hut.
Double time!
Knees up,
ladies.
Whitehurst, where
do the kids sleep?
Above the portico.
[ Ellis ]
You're wearing combat boots,
not ballet slippers!
[ Ellis ]
Come on, movet
Barclay.
[ Ellis ]
It's gonna get
worse than this.
Get the lead out.
Come on, move it.
Faster, faster.
Get those knees in the sky.
Owww!
You son of a bitch!
Hell of a punch
there, Barclay.
Now l'll see what kind
of a tough guy you are.
Get your head
around here.
[ Giggling ]
Tyler, come out,
come out, wherever you are.
[ Chucky]
Olly olly oxen free!
Get out here,
you little son ofa bitch!
[ Ellis ]
Three! You're not sounding of_
Fnilr! Fiv_!
All right, Barclay.
You got me curious.
What areyou
tying to prove?
Forget it.
l want to know.
All right.
The doll's alive.
- He's after Tyler.
- Right, forget it.
l hope he can
take care of him self.
Shh, shh.
Quiet.
[ Gasping, Laughing ]
[ Whispers ]
Shut up!
l can't believe
l let you talk me into  this.
Just stay here and
keep an eye out.
Oh, l live for this.
l know, Ivers.
Now go, go.
Shh, shh.
l don't see what
you see in that guy.
He's just different
from eveybody else.
Oh, please.
Well, he's cute too.
Okay.
[ De Silva ]
forster homes.
No wonder
he's so quiet.
[Thumping ]
What was that?
So, you took
the doll?
Shelton
will have you court-martialed.
We're playing
hide-and-seek.
What are you doing?
We couldn't sleep.
Oh, he is...
so cute.
He was mine first.
Give him back.
Shh, you guys.
Please be quiet!
Can you go
stand guard?
Yes, sir.
What's his name?
Ask him yourself.
Oh, right.
What is your name?
[ Good GuyVoice ]
Hi, l'm Chucky and l'm
your friend to the end.
Hi-de-ho.
Ha, ha.
I love it.
His real name
is Charles Lee Ray.
Oh, is that so?
Give me your lipstick.
What for?
Just give it to me.
What areyou doing?
Wait, stop.
You'll see.
[ De Silva ]
Here you go, little baby.
[Tyler]
You're messing him up.
You're so cute.
Don't do that.
He looks stupid!
You're making him
look like a wuss!
He looks sweet.
What are you doing?
Someone's coming.
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Wait. Stop!
What about Charles?
Yuck!
This means war.
What the hell?
- l like to be hugged.
- Go--Jesus!
[ Chuckles l
[Crash]
Aaah!
Aw, you gotta be
fucking kiddin' me.
[ Gasping ]
The man lives through
two tours in Nam...
and then one night
he just drops dead.
Doesn't make
any sense.
## [ Reveille ]
[ Shelton ]
At ease.
We will now take a moment of silence
to honor Colonel Cochrane.
He was a fine man
and he will be sorely missed.
Bowyour heads
for prayer.
[ Shelton ]
Take...seats!
lt's gettin'
pretty shaggy, Carlson.
l want to seeyou
on Friday.
Yes, sir.
Monday, Fabrizzio.
My man.
Tuesday.
Look atyou, Whitehurst.
You're a disgrace.
When's the last time
you had a trim?
Two weeks ago,
Sergeant, l think.
Ynll think?
l want to seeyou
right after breakfast.
Yes, sir,
Sergeant Botnick, sir.
What'reyou looking at,
new boy?
Wednesday.
Barclay,
what're you doi ng?
You can't just get up
in the middle of mess.
Major.
At ease!
Tyler.
H i, Barclay. What's up?
l've got to talk
to you about Chucky.
You mean Charles.
Have you seen him?
Not since last night.
He's hiding somewhere.
He's gonna lay low until he knows you're alone,
and he's gonna come after you.
He wants to play.
Listen to me.
No matter what he says,
no matter what he promises you,
you've gotta
stay away from him.
Don't let him fool you.
He's bad.
Charles isn't bad,
he's a Good Guy.
lt says so on his shirt.
He lies, Tyler.
Believe me, he's bad news.
He's hurt a lot of people.
l think colonel Cochrane was one of them.
You're just jealous because
he's my best friend now instead of yours.
Look,
you better keep this.
Whitehurst, you are,
without a doubt
the sorriest excuse
for a soldier to ever
disgrace these walls.
Face it, you're not
cut out for this life.
Why don't you do
yourself a favor and get
the hell out of Kent?
lf l had any choice
in the matter, l would, sir.
Smart ass.
Presto...
you're bald.
[ Whistling ]
What the hell?
How'd you
get in there?
That haircut ain't
regulation, soldier.
When's the last time
you had a trim, huh?
Kiss it good-bye.
Presto...
you're dead.
Ha,ha,ha,ha.
lt's definitelyyou.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
l just forgot my --
Boo!
The annual war games...
have been an unbroken tradition
here at Kent for over 50 years.
Colonel Cochrane was a man
who believe in tradition.
He not only would have
wanted us to go on,
He'd have
ordered us to go on.
Therefore...
The war games....
will proceed
as scheduled.
Lieutenant Colonel Shelton..
will command
the blue team.
Major Rawlings
will head up the reds.
The obiective is simple.
To capture
the other team's flag...
and bring it back here
safely to base.
Rawlings.
You will pick up
your weapons...
in the armoy
before moving out.
You will be using the standard
issue Springfield aught-three.
Your ammo--
Shelton.
lf you get hit,
you are dead.
Hike back to base.
Commanders..
take charge
of your teams.
May the best team win.
Good luck,
men and women.
Nice of you to join us.
Looks like Botnick's in
a pretty bad mood today.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing's wrong.
l'm fine.
This oughta
slow the pricks down.
[ Instructor ]
Left, left, left.
Here we goagain.
Here we go again.
Same old stuffagain.
Marching down the avenue.
Two more miles
and we'll be through.
l'll be gettin' rid of you.
l'll be gettin' rid ofyou.
Same old ugly stum.
Same old ugly stuff.
Here we go again.
Herewe go again.
Marching down the avenue.
One more mile
and we'll be through.
l'll be gettin'
rid of you.
What's going on,
Whitehurst?
You saw something,
didn't you?
You saw Chucky.
Don't wimp out on me!
l need your help.
That kid needs
your help.
l didn't see anything.
Okay? l didn't
see anything at all.
Your left, right,
your left.
Your militay left.
Ellis, let's make sure all
the perimeters are secure.
Yes, sir.
She checks
the windows.
And the baby-sitter hears
this thump, thump, thumping.
Like something's being dragged
across the floor upstairs.
Suddenly she thinks, ''l haven't
checed on the children''
So she hurries to
the top of the stairs,
and when
she gets there...
she sees her boyfriend
completely dismembered,
dragging himself across
the floor by his chin.
Thump, slide.
[ Ivers ]
That was gross.
****
Hey, you guys,
l got a better story...
and it's true.
lt's about this
mental institution...
and it's a few miles
away from here.
Hey.
Hope it wasn't
something l said.
[ Chuckles ]
No. l'm sory.
Where doyou think the
red team's camped out?
Could be anywhere.
Shelton'll find 'em, he always does.
By the way,
you can call me Kristin.
What?
Kristin.
lt's my first name.
Do you have one?
Andy.
Come on, Andy.
l want to show you something.
Pretty cool, huh?
Yeah, l almost forgot there
were places like that...
where peoplejust
go to have fun.
[Twig Snaps ]
listen!
Somebody's
out there.
lt's probably just
a chipmunk or something.
Nothing scares you,
does it?
No.
Man, l really got to
get out of this body.
l'm going
afterTyler.
Are you crazy?
You'll never find him.
Wanna bet? l swiped
this from Shelton's tent.
He sent out a reconnaissance mission
right before we pitched camp.
The red team is
somewhere around here.
That kid's a sitting duck, Whitehurst.
Are you with me...
nr nnt?
l'm sory, l can't.
[ Ellis ]
Up and at 'em, ladies. We're movin' out.
l want this camp to be a ghost town
in five minutes.
l thought we weren't
going till dawn, sir.
Someone stole the
reconnaissance map,
so we're making
our move now.
Get going, Hanley.
You wouldn't know anything about
a missing map, would you?
Where the hell's
Barclay?
Whitehurst!
Colonel Shelton,
you better have
a look in here, sir.
What is it, Ellis?
Barclay's gone
AWOL, sir.
He stole the map.
That little fucking traitor's
doubling for the reds.
Where's Tyler?
He went AWOL with
some guy named Charles.
Where's Andy?
Whitehurst,
where is he?
[ Shelton ]
Platoon, halt!
All right.
De Silva, you're gonna
take the right flank.
Siegel, take the left.
Check in on the radio
evey five minutes.
Yes, sir.
All right, move it.
The rest ofus are gonna
spread out and meet up
with Ellis at Split Rock.
Move out.
Whitehurst, move!
Thanks for coming after me.
What are friend for?
Duck!
That was a close one.
Now we can play
''Hide the soul''
l'm tired. l don't wanna
play that dumb game anymore.
You're a fuckin' drag,
you know that?
- Watch your mouth, Charles.
- Stop calling me that!
What's
the knife for?
A good soldier
is always prepared.
Barclay was right.
You're not a good guy.
Sorry kid. You got me.
l'm bad
Now..
assume the position.
No!
Aaah!
Get abck here!
Barclay! Barclay!
Tyler!
You fuckin' traitor.
Give me my map!
Listen --
You got any idea what we
do to traitors, Barclay?
Tyler's in trouble.
Whitehurst, back me up.
Major Ellis,
call in the flanks.
Yes, sir.
De Silva, Siegel,
do you copy?
De Silva,
[ Radio ]
De Silva, come in.
Aaah!
Siegel's on his way back.
No word yet from De Silva.
Keep tryin'.
Yes, sir.
Help!
Tyler!
Barclay!
Are you okay,
Tyler?
Looks like we got
ourselves a little P.O.W.
You're right,
Charles is bad.
He tried to hurt me.
Who the hell Charles?
[ Chucky]
Come in, Barclay.
Who the hell that?
lt's Charles.
Who is this?
Put Barclay on,
jarhead.
[ Ellis ]
It's the reds. They're up to something.
What do you want?
l want the kid.
Bring him up to the old Jeep
or there'll be hell to pay.
[ De Silva ]
Andy, don't do it.
De Silva!
You hear that, Barclay?
Don't touch her,
you son of a bitch.
Now bring me the kid
or l'll waste her.
Red team, red team.
come in, red team.
This is red team, over.
We got a situation up
here at the old Jeep.
Blue team sighted.
Advise you to move your troops in.
Hope they like
the taste of lead.
Now just sit back
and watch the sparks fly.
All right, you two are
gonna go on up ahead.
The rest ofus are
gonna circle around.
Shelton, this is no game.
This guy is dangerous.
Relax, Barclay,
it's only paint.
All right,
All right let's do it.
l'm scared, Barclay.
Yeah, me too.
All right, kid.
Get over here!
No!
Don't fuck with me!
l'll blow all
of you to pieces.
Beat it!
Now just get down
and shut up.
Yeah!
Ow!
Hold your fire!
De Silva, where the
hell is eveybody?
Hi, soldier.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Fuck me.
All right!
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Shit!
Stay down!
They're using
live rounds!
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Hold your fire!
Oh, God,
he's not breathing!
Get away from him!
You did this, didn't you?
You sick son of a bitch.
Now l'm gonna
kill you!
Get off me!
Get offofhim,
he didn't do it!
Let go of me!
Sayonara, suckers.
Look out!
No!
Oh, my God, what happened?
[ Ellis ]
It's Whitehurst.
What the hell happened?
Who fucked with the rifles?
I don't know.
[ Ellis ]
Get Clark on the radio...
Yes, sir.
and get me a medic
up here right now!
[ Ellis ]
All right, eveybody stay calm.
Epstein, l want that radio!
Oh, God.
[ loud Rock Music ]
This is the last time
l'm gonna tell you.
Give that thing a rest or
you're out ofhere, both ofyou.
We're not bothering anybody.
You're bothering me.
Keep it down!
Geez!
Mister,
you gotta help me!
What's wrong?
Charles, Charles
he's after me.
Who's Charles?
He's a Good Guy.
He wants to play ''Hide the Soul.''
Have a seat over there.
Are you from Kent?
Yes, sir.
What's your name,
son?
Ronald Tyler.
Private first class, sir.
Have a seat.
How 'bout some gum, Private?
l know how
it must hurt...
when a friend does
something bad to you.
Sure does.
But l bet your friend --
what's his name, Charles?
l bet you Charles
didn't mean it.
l bet you
he's really sorry.
No, he isn't.
He wants to hurt me.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
l know what'll cheer you up.
Look what
l found.
There you go.
Thank you, Daddy.
Let's go on
the Super Loop.
Hey, maybe
somebody's seen him.
Oh, God.
Come on.
Wait.
Mommy, Mommy,
l love it!
Wereyou scared?
No!
Let's have some popcorn and
we'll go on one more ride.
[ Chucky]
Perfect. In there.
Don't even
think about it.
Come on.
Okay.
ln there!
[ Clock Chiming ]
Aaah!
Ha ha ha ha!
[ Wicked Laughing ]
Oh!
rThunder ]
[ Chucky]
Time to play.
This looks good.
Park it.
r Clock Chimes l
Duck!
Aaah!
Ha ha ha ha !
Shit!
Ha.
Tyler!
Barclay, Barclay,
ii here!
He's got a gun!
Shit!
Aaah!
Are you okay?
Oh, God.
Here... take it
You can do it.
l'll be okay.
[ Roaring ]
[ Yelling ]
Help!
Yeah!
You're m i ne now, Tyler.
[ Roaring ]
Oh, God!
- Aaah!
- Tyler!
- Barclay!
Tyler, watch out!
Shit!
[ Screaming ]
This is it, kid.
End of the line.
Ade due Dammballa.
Leveau mercier
du bois chaloitte...
secoisse entienne
mais pois de morte.
Mortis mais le cant
de monsoir.
Adelez porque
tu hacer Damballa!
Leveau mercier
du bois chaloitte...
secoisse entienne
mais pois de morte.
Mortis mais le cant
de monsoir.
Give me the power,
l beg of you!
Leveau mercier
du bois chaloitte...
secoisse entienne
mais pois de morte.
Mortis mais le cant
de monsoir.
Adelez porque
tu hacer Damballa!
Keep both eyes open.
Hold your breath.
...Damballa!
Ahhh!
Adelez porque
tu hacer Damballa!
Aah!
Yeah!
- Are you okay?
- Yeah_
Come on,
let's get out of here.
Hold on, Tyler!
Gimme the fuckin' kid.
He's mine!
Hold on!
Barclay!
Take the knife!
Take it. here!
Hold on!
Reach for it!
No!
Ahhh!
Come on, l got ya.
We're on
our way in.
You'll have to come
with us now, son.