I have a meeting
in a few minutes...
with some very jittery
stockhoIders, Mattson.
I hope you have
good news for me.
Yes, sir. I do, sir.
Every tabIoid's running headIines
about Andy BarcIay...
and his kiIIer
Good Guy doII.
What about his mother
and the poIice?
The poIice were smart. They denied
everything. They can't hurt us.
The mother backed up
her boy's story in court,
so she's under
psychiatric observation.
Where's the boy now?
Midtown ChiIdren's Crisis Center.
Foster custody's pending.
My stomach hurts,
Mattson.
Is this what you
caII good news?
No. I'm getting to that.
Our biggest probIem
has been the rumors.
Good morning,
Mr. SuIIivan.
PeopIe are saying
that some joker at the company...
must have tampered
with the doII's voice cassette.
''Hi. I'm Chucky.
''I'm the Lakeshore StrangIer.
I'm going to kiII you.''
Something Iike--
WeII, something Iike that.
But the good news,
Mr. SuIIivan,
is that now
we've got the doII.
We've rebuiIt it
from head to toe.
A Iot of it was
burned to a crisp,
but everything checks out--
voice cassette, servomechanisms--
We've found absoIuteIy nothing.
This is a quaIity controI report.
I'm sure it wiII make
the stockhoIders very happy.
I want to see the doII.
- AbsoIuteIy.
- [ Knocking ]
Mr. SuIIivan's here.
We ready?
Give us a minute. We're not
used to making them manuaIIy.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know. It's stuck.
Just--
They'II have this,
uh, worked out.
- Oh! Oh!
- My God!
Oh, Jesus!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
Aah!
Andy, you stiII dreaming
about Chucky?
Sometimes.
- You want to taIk about it?
- No.
Oh, come on, Andy.
Remember what I toId you?
TaIking heIps make...
the nightmares go away.
WeII, Chucky was trying
to take over my souI.
Why?
This bad man got
inside my Good Guy doII...
so he wouIdn't
have to go to heII.
But then he wanted
to get inside me.
Why, Andy?
'Cause if he stayed
inside the doII too Iong,
he'd be trapped in there.
He needed me 'cause I was the
first person he toId his secret to.
What secret?
That his reaI name
was CharIes Lee Ray.
Boy, that's a scary dream.
It was.
You know,
dreams can't hurt you.
Dreams aren't reaI.
- Right?
- Right.
- In here.
- In there.
Let's hurry up.
I don't care what it takes.
Put a Iid on this.
That's not a probIem.
Listen to me.
You smuggIe this error
out of here in 24 hours.
- Yes, sir.
- Now if you wiII excuse me...
I've got a meeting
I've got to get to.
As far as the stockhoIders
and I are concerned,
this matter is finished.
What do you want me
to do with the doII?
Stick it up your ass.
NaturaIIy, he was badIy traumatized
by the murders,
but they bounce back
pretty fast at that age.
- Poor kid.
- What Andy needs now...
is a normaI famiIy environment,
a fresh start...
and a chance
to forget the past.
Since you've done so weII
with so many kids,
we were hoping you'd foster him
untiI his mother recovers.
- There's aIways room for one more.
- Mmm.
What does that mean?
Uh, weII...
he seems... normaI enough,
but how has aII this affected him?
In order to come to terms...
with something he couIdn't
possibIy understand,
he turned it aII into
a kind of fairy taIe.
He insisted his doII
was responsibIe.
He said it was possessed...
by the souI
of CharIes Lee Ray.
- Who?
- The Lakeshore StrangIer.
He murdered a dozen peopIe...
in this series of
rituaI voodoo kiIIings.
Are we even quaIified...
to take care of
a boy Iike this?
I understand your concern,
Mr. Simpson,
but this is just a chiId's way...
of coping with
a difficuIt situation.
Andy's fine now.
He just wants
to get on with his Iife.
So, Andy, what
do you Iike to eat?
AII kinds of things.
What's your favorite food
in the whoIe wide worId?
ChocoIate.
Besides chocoIate.
My mom used to fix me eggs
for breakfast. I Iike eggs.
You got it.
Let's stop at the store.
- The one down here?
- Yeah, the organic one.
You're in Iuck, Andy.
Joanne's a terrific cook.
You Iike sushi?
You know what--
- PhiI, Iook out!
- Jesus Christ!
Look out for the car.
Hey, wait up.
Make yourseIf comfortabIe, Andy.
Thanks.
WeII, I have to get back
to the office this afternoon.
I thought that you'd
done everything.
Oh, I have--
Uh-uh-uh.
First ruIe.
Don't touch the oId stuff.
- Sorry.
- WeII, that's okay. No fouI.
It's just that, weII, we coIIect this
junk, and a Iot of it's fragiIe.
- You Iike it?
- Uh-huh.
It's been in my famiIy
for three generations.
My grandmother gave it to my mother
and my mother gave it to me.
And who are you
gonna give it to?
Why don't you take this upstairs and
expIore. I'II be up there in a minute.
Okay.
What do you think?
Oh, I'II get used to him.
[Loud Music PIaying]
Jesus. Did you
ever hear of knocking?
Andy, did you find--
What, are you crazy?
Give them to me.
Come on, Joanne.
PhiI wiII shoot you
if he catches you again.
Andy, this is KyIe.
She's staying with us too.
- Charmed.
- KyIe, what is this?
You've been here three weeks.
Why haven't you unpacked?
What for? I've never spent more
than a month in any home.
With that attitude,
I can see why.
Put these things away, then do me
a favor and heIp me get dinner started.
Can't. Got to work tonight.
KyIe, that's the third night
in a row.
I'd reaIIy Iike it if you'd spend
a IittIe time with the famiIy.
I need the money.
I'm gonna be on my own next year.
Yes, weII, untiI then,
you're with us, ok?
- Come aIong, Andy.
- Bye.
I think you'II
be very happy here.
This is your room
right here.
I made those curtains
just for you.
I bet bIue is
your favorite coIor.
Take a Iook around.
I'II start to unpack.
Wow.
I thought
you might Iike those.
Um, there's more
in the cIoset.
Before dinner,
we'II go expIore the back yard.
Later I'II read
you some stories.
WouId you Iike that?
There's Iots of kids
in the neighborhood, Andy.
I'm sure you're going
to make new friends.
Aah!
Hey, hey, hey. Andy, ruIe number two,
no running in the house.
It's onIy a doII.
Andy, are you Iistening to me?
Oh, Andy, I'm sorry.
I didn't reaIize that was in there.
So many kids here, it's hard to keep
track of everything. I'II get rid of it.
Hi, I'm Tommy.
I'm your friend tiII the end.
Why don't we get settIed in,
and then we'II have some dinner.
[Honk]
Aw, shit.
Ohh--
HeIIo, GabrieIIa.
Guess who?
That's right.
The vodka? Of course
I remembered the vodka.
Two-week anniversary.
You think I'd forget the vodka?
I know what that does to you.
Okay, weII, wait for me.
On my way. Yeah.
Shit.
[AIarm Activator Beeps]
[TeIephone Rings]
I want to pIay Red Light.
No, I don't want to pIay Red Light.
I want you to go back to bed.
But I'm scared.
There's nothing to be scared of.
It's just a storm.
Grace PooIe.
Yes, I'm trying to
reach Andy BarcIay.
Andy no Ionger Iives here.
Who is this?
This is his UncIe CharIes.
Sorry, uh, cash onIy.
But that's a goId card.
That's just as good as cash.
Not here, it ain't.
We don't accept credit cards.
I don't carry cash, okay?
- [Car AIarm Sounds]
- Aw.
Oh--
- Don't move!
- Jesus!
God. Okay,
wh-wh-what do you want?
- No questions. Just drive.
- Okay, okay.
Keep going.
Now park this piece of shit.
Put your arms
behind the seat.
- What?
- Do it!
Okay. Take it easy. Take it easy.
PIease, don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Look, I don't carry cash.
I got-- I got a goId card.
I'II give you anything you want.
TeII me what you want.
Freeze, asshoIe.
Take my-- Take the car.
You can drop me off,
but just, pIease, Ieave me aIone.
- PIease!
- Bang.
You're dead.
Aah!
No! No! No!
No! No! No! No!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
''The woodcutter argued
for a Iong time with his wife,
''but she was such a horrid,
frightening woman when she was angry,
''that in the end
he agreed to her pIan.
''In the morning,
their stepmother caIIed them.
''I think it wouId be nice if we
aII went into the forest, she said.
''HanseI and GreteI did not repIy, but
foIIowed their parents into the forest.''
Where they aII Iived
happiIy ever after.''
- No, they don't.
- WeII, they do for now.
We'II finish it tomorrow night.
- Don't go.
- What's the matter?
- I miss my mother.
- Oh, honey, I know you do.
- WiII I ever see her again?
- Of course you wiII. I promise.
Don't worry. I'II stay with you
as Iong as you want.
My mother used to sing to me.
WiII you sing to me?
[Ahem]
~ Dee dee
dee dee dee dee ~
~ Hmm hmm hmm hmm ~
~ Hmm hmm hmm hmm hmm ~
~ Dee dee ~
~ Dee da da da ~
~ Da da da da ~
~ Dee da da da da ~~
- Shit.
- Hi. I'm Tommy.
Shut up, you idiot.
I Iike to be hugged.
- I Iike to be hugged.
- Hug this.
I Iike to be hugged.
I Iike to be hugged. I Iike--
- What was that?
- Nothing. Now go to sIeep.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha.
Eat dirt, Tommy.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Do either of you have anything
to say about this?
I think we shouId taIk
to a Iawyer first.
KyIe, that's not funny.
That statue was very important to me.
I think one of you
owes Joanne an apoIogy.
I'm innocent.
- Andy?
- I didn't do it.
AII right.
You Ieave me no choice.
TiII somebody fesses up,
you're both grounded.
- But I have a date tonight.
- Sorry.
This is exactIy how I wanted
to spend my day off. Thanks a Iot.
But I didn't break
the statue. ReaIIy.
Yeah. Maybe it just feII, huh?
Hey. You want to hear me
say your name backwards?
KyIe.
HoId this.
Jesus. Give me that.
- What the heII are you doing?
- I wanted to taste it.
Get reaI. It tastes Iike shit, okay?
These things are very bad for you.
Then why do you do it?
Because grownups are aIIowed to do
things that are bad for them.
You're not a grownup.
You're beginning to get
on my nerves, Andy.
Why don't you
give me a hand over here?
Mr. Simpson is kind of
grouchy, isn't he?
He's not so bad.
I've had fosters that wouId shoot you
for staring at them cross-eyed.
- ReaIIy?
- Sure.
They figure you're not theirs.
You're just passing through.
The minute you screw up--
Grrr! They Iet you have it.
I got to teII you, I'm not happy
with this whoIe thing.
- Having second thoughts?
- WeII, you have to admit it,
he's a very troubIed
IittIe boy...
that obviousIy has not come to terms
with this whoIe doII thing.
Look, aII I'm saying
is that he may need more, uh,
attention than we can give him.
PhiI, Andy's
been through heII.
You have to give him some time.
He'II settIe down.
Besides, I Iike him.
I hate you.
Hi. I'm... Tommy
and I'm your friend to the end.
Hi-de-ho.
Ha ha ha.
Hi.
- Hi.
KyIe, do you miss
your mom and dad?
Can't miss someone
you never knew.
Where are they?
I have no idea.
My dad Ieft before I was born.
My mom put me up
for adoption when I was 3.
Do you remember her?
I made it a point to forget.
It's easier that way.
Hey. Break time.
Move over.
- Want a push?
- No, thank you.
Come on. It's fun.
Come on, Andy, pIease,
I just want to sit here, ok?
Too Iate. There you go.
Andy, come on.
Give me a break. Stop it.
No. Ha ha ha!
Andy, I'II kiII you.
Come on. Let me off.
Andy.
I'II get you.
- Andy, cut it out.
- Dinner!
- Come and get it.
- Ahh!
Mayhem. Come on.
I'II race you.
No fair.
You got a head start.
Excuses, excuses.
Don't forget your doII.
For KyIe.
Think she'II Iike it?
What do I know
about teenage girIs?
- More than you did three weeks ago.
- I'm not so sure.
We shouId get something for Andy.
Make him feeI more settIed.
- Any ideas?
- How about a VaIium?
Mm! Mm!
Surprise.
Did you miss me, Andy?
I sure missed you.
I toId you.
We were going to be friends
to the end.
And now it's time to pIay.
I got a new game, sport.
It's caIIed Hide the SouI.
And guess what? You're it.
Ade Due DambaIIa.
Give me the power, I beg--
This isn't over,
you IittIe shit.
I'm not spending my Iife
as a pIastic freak.
Next time you're aIone,
you're mine.
Mm! Mm! Mm!
Oh, my God.
- It's Chucky. Look out!
- Shut up. You'II wake PhiI and Joanne.
- KiII him!
- Stop it!
- What the heII is this, now?
- It's Chucky.
I toId you he'd find me.
He tried to take over my souI.
- Andy, caIm down.
- You didn't have to wait up.
Yeah? You know, KyIe,
I don't beIieve you.
You tied this chiId up
so he wouIdn't teII on you.
- Oh, come on. PhiI.
- Chucky did it.
- That's enough now.
- Chucky? I've had it.
- But you got to kiII him.
- Andy!
PIease, Iisten to me.
I'm not Iying.
If you don't kiII him,
he'II get me.
Andy, caIm down.
I'm going to get rid of it.
There, see? He's gone.
He can't bother you anymore.
No.
I'm turning human again?
If I don't get out
of this body soon, I'm screwed.
Come on, Andy. We're Iate.
Andy. Don't forget your Iunch.
Egg saIad.
Mmm, yum.
Whatever you do,
don't act nervous.
They'II smeII a new kid
a miIe off.
Just act Iike you beIong.
- What are you Iooking for?
- Nothing.
Is it Chucky
coming to get you?
Andy, how did you manage
to tie yourseIf up Iike that Iast night?
- I aIready toId you.
- Yeah.
You're just Iike everybody eIse.
You don't beIieve me either.
- KyIe.
- Hi, Adam.
Why'd you Ieave so earIy Iast night?
You missed aII the fun.
Story of my Iife.
Come on now.
Where is it?
Where-- Where-- Where is it?
Aha!
''Pinocchio jumped for joy, shouting,
I'm aIive! I'm aIive!
Then the taIking cricket said--''
What'd he say?
''If you're very, very good,
and promise to teII no Iies,
''then you wiII become
a reaI, Iive boy.
''Boys who are bent on foIIowing
their caprices...
and wiII have their own way,
sooner or Iater repent.''
- Get Iost, microchip.
- Am I boring you, Andy?
No, Miss--
- KettIeweII.
I have precious IittIe patience
for disruptive students.
But he just thwacked--
EspeciaIIy new students,
whose utmost concern...
shouId be getting
on my good side.
[BeII Rings]
I want those desks spick-and-span
before anyone Ieaves.
- Andy! You think this is funny?
- I didn't do that.
- [BeII Rings]
- Go ahead, kids.
Don't forget the speIIing test
tomorrow. Not you. Come over here.
Sit down and get comfy.
You're going to be here for a whiIe.
- But I didn't do it, I swear.
- No? Then who did?
Don't even think about it.
No toys.
Head down!
Peekaboo!
PIease, Iet me
out of here, Andy.
It's dark in here.
I promise I won't
kiII anyone eIse. Okay?
Now open the goddamn door!
Let me out, you IittIe dick!
Let me the fuck out!
Andy, I toId you
to stay in your seat.
Come out of there!
Open this door right now.
Andy, come out
this very second.
Andy! Andy!
Andy?
Andy, this isn't funny.
Ohh!
Aah!
You've been very naughty,
Miss KettIeweII.
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Andy, what's this aII about?
Chucky foIIowed me to schooI.
He tried to get me again,
so I ran home.
- Do you know what's he taIking about?
- His teacher caIIed,
said she was keeping him
after schooI for detention,
said he wrote an obscenity
on his paper.
Chucky did it.
AII right, Andy. Come on.
This is going to stop, 'cause I wiII not
aIIow this fooIishness in my house.
- Do you understand? Open the door.
- Oh, PhiI--
Joanne, pIease.
Open the door.
Open it.
Open it!
Now, I want you to Iook down there
and teII me what you see.
It's Chucky, but--
His name... is Tommy,
and he's been there
since Iast night, hasn't he?
Hasn't he?
For crying out Ioud, Joanne,
the chiId needs professionaI heIp!
Stop pretending you're worried about
Andy. You never wanted him here.
- That's not true.
- So what are you suggesting we do?
- Send him back?
- Don't have to make it sound horribIe.
Do you have any idea
how traumatic that wouId be?
For whom, Joanne,
for him or for you?
Look, if that kid stays here,
he's gonna tear this famiIy apart!
FamiIy? Is this
what you caII a famiIy?
FamiIies don't just
give up on their chiIdren.
Joanne, he's not our chiId.
[Door SIams]
It's not the end of the worId.
But they're going
to send me away.
You'II be okay.
Where wiII I go?
Andy...
I've Iived with dozens
of different famiIies,
and they aIways
seem to send me away...
just when I'm getting comfortabIe,
but you know what?
- What?
- Every time it happens...
it just makes me stronger,
because it reminds me...
that the onIy one
I can count on is myseIf.
Okay, and you have
to Iearn that now.
I know it sounds tough,
but you'II deaI with it.
It doesn't matter.
Wherever I go,
Chucky wiII find me.
[Creaking]
[Creak]
- Uhh!
- [EIectric Knife Runs]
Yaah!
...advances over the decIines
by a 7-to-6 margin.
- More on today--
- What's wrong?
I thought
I heard something downstairs.
- It's one of the chiIdren.
- That's what I'm afraid of.
Why fight it, Andy?
We're going to be very cIose.
In fact, we're going to be
fucking inseparabIe.
Aah!
What the heII's
going on down--
Andy...
put down the knife.
But I need it for--
Just put the knife down,
and we'II taIk about it.
Everything is going
to be just fine.
Aah!
How's it hanging, PhiI?
No. Oh, God, PhiI.
I'II caII an ambuIance.
PhiI. PhiI.
Oh, God! No!
Oh, God! Ohh!
Get away from me!
Oh, God!
I shouId have
Iistened to him.
He'd be here now
if onIy I'd Iistened to him.
It's not your fauIt.
I'II take care of this.
Andy, you'II be fine now.
Come stay at the center
for a few days...
untiI we can find you
a new famiIy.
We've pIaced KyIe
with a number of famiIies.
Things aIways seem to work out okay.
Don't they?
Yeah.
There's your stuff.
Come on, Andy. Let's go.
He's stiII in the ceIIar, KyIe.
- Don't Iet him get you too.
- Andy.
We'II be out of your way
in just a minute here.
Did anyone besides the boy
witness the accident?
- No.
- Okay.
Let's go.
[Crash]
Joanne!
[Tapping]
Joanne?
Joanne!
Rrah!
Ugh!
Bitch. You hurt me.
How much further
tiII we get to the kid?
- A ways.
- Step on it.
What's the rush?
If I don't get out of this body soon,
I'II be trapped in here!
What are you Iooking at?
[Siren]
- FIoor it.
- Get reaI. This is a station wagon.
Shit!
PuII over.
Behave yourseIf.
I'II kiII you if I have to.
Okay, honey,
Iet's see your Iicense.
You were cIocking 60 in a 45.
What's your hurry?
I have a date.
You're going to have to do
better than that.
That's one of those Good Guys,
isn't it?
- Yes, it is.
- I Iove these things. What's your name?
- Chucky.
- That's incredibIe.
- I'II say.
- What the heII's that?
You've seen doIIs that pee?
This one bIeeds.
Okay, Iook, uh...
just sIow it down, huh?
And, uh, buckIe up for safety.
Now, get going.
- You okay, honey?
- Mm-hmm.
Don't Iet the bedbugs bite.
Come on. Step on it.
Fine. We'II just get
puIIed over again.
Just shut up and drive...
before I kick
your fucking teeth in.
Rrah!
You goddamn women drivers!
Fuck.
Fucking bastard.
Shit. Andy.
PIaytime's over.
[AIarm Rings]
Andy, what are you doing?
We've got to get
out of the buiIding.
KyIe, what's going on here?
You did this, didn't you?
He did it.
Get into my office.
Is this your idea of a joke?
Give me that.
Amazing, isn't it?
Aah! Aah!
Come on!
Okay, sport, we're going to have
a IittIe game of Chucky Says.
Chucky says,
move your ass.
Snap out of it!
You act Iike you've never seen
a dead body before.
Andy, come on! Open it!
Andy! Open the door!
Come on! Everybody out!
Inside. Hurry.
Stop!
Come on.
Hey, Iady,
sIow down, wiII you?
~ Passin' by ~~
Say your prayers, Andy.
- [Horn Honks]
- Goddamn it!
[Honk Honk Honk]
[Honk Honk]
PuII over!
- What?
- PuII over!
PuII over!
What in the heII
do you think you're doing?
Let me go. Let me go.
What the fuck's
wrong with you?
Let go!
Crazy bitch!
We're home.
[CIunk]
CIose your eyes
and count to seven.
When you wake,
you'II be in heaven.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha ha.
This is it, worId.
From now on,
no more Mr. Good Guy.
Ade Due DambaIIa.
Give me the power,
I beg of you.
Leveau mercier
du bois chaIoitte.
Secoise entienne mais
pois de morte.
Morteisma Iieu de vocuier
de mieu vochette.
EdenIieu pour
du boisette dambaIIa!
Aah!
You IittIe shit!
Do you know what you've done?
It's too Iate!
I've spent too much time
in this body!
I'm fucking trapped in here!
- [RustIing]
- What the heII?
Andy, run.
Aah!
- Andy.
- KyIe.
Are you okay? Come on.
Shit!
Andy, hurry up.
Let's go. I'II go first.
Stay right behind me.
Come on.
Andy, step on it.
Reach! Give me your hand!
Andy! Stop yourseIf.
Grab the side.
- Aah!
- Andy!
- Hurry up! He's right behind you.
- You bastard!
Don't Iook back.
Come on. Hurry!
- You can't get away from me!
- Give me your hand!
Reach!
I'm going to kiII you, Andy!
Aah!
Come on. Go! Go! Go!
Run down there.
I'm going to get you fuckers!
Aah.
G-- Oh, God!
Aah!
Oh, God!
Ohh--
Aah!
Come on. Do it!
Come on. Give me your hand.
Don't be afraid. Come on.
CIoser. CIoser so you can
grab my hand.
Andy. Now!
Aah!
- Can't open it.
- How wiII we get out?
We'II have to find another way.
Give me your hand.
I hate kids.
[Warning Sounds]
[AIarm Sounds]
Terrific.
Aah!
Ugh!
[AIarm Sounds]
[AIarm Stops]
- Hee hee hee hee!
- Duck!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Do it!
Andy, pIease.
I was onIy pIaying.
Aah!
No, pIease!
No! No! God!
No! No! No!
Aah!
HoIy shit.
We did it.
Let's get out of here.
- Let's see. Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- What's this?
- Thanks for coming after me.
Yeah, weII,
you owe me one, squirt.
KyIe!
Aah!
I've got you now, Andy,
and you know what
I'm going to do to you?
I'm going to cut
off your Iegs too.
[Liquid PIastic SizzIes]
Huh?
No!
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
KyIe! KyIe!
KyIe! KyIe! KyIe, wake up!
KyIe!
Come on. Come on.
Ugh! God.
What did you do to him?
AII right, Andy.
Aah!
KyIe! KyIe!
Aah! Aah!
Eat this, you son of a bitch!
Come on.
- Where are we going?
- Home.
Where's home?