[shouting]
[growling]
[screaming]
Aah!
[shouting]
[roaring]
[screaming]
[shouting in native language]
[monster growling]
[Man]
Growing up was tough for me.
I was always getting in trouble.
All right, Jack. Get in here.
I was told that I suffered
from aggressive behavior.
I hated to admit it, but it was true.
[boy crying]
And I pretty much had no control over it.
How many is that?
Ten.
Good. Now apologize.
He elbowed me in the face,
and no one even called it.
And retaliation's going to fix that.
Apologize now.
[boy crying]
I'm sorry that l...
I'm sorry that I
whipped the ball at your head.
As soon as I'd get pissed off,
I'd feel something
start to build up inside me.
Watch it, buddy.
It was something I couldn't stop,
and then I'd just snap.
[bell rings]
But I wasn't always like that.
When I was a kid, I was fine.
## [pop jazz]
[Bobby Darin]
# Somewhere #
# Beyond the sea #
In fact, things were perfect.
I had a great family.
I was just like any regular kid.
I liked race cars and video games.
Shit, I even liked dancing sometimes.
Every summer, my folks
used to take us up camping.
I'd spend most of the time
hanging out with my kid sister.
I guess I kind of looked out for her.
- [girl humming]
- Cindy, sit down.
Yeah, life was a real slice back then.
But one night,
something happened
that changed things forever.
Oof!
Ha ha ha ha!
[young Jack]
Get up.
Come on. Calm down, Cindy. Stop.
Hey, Jack.
[Cindy giggling]
Watch this one.
# I know #
# Beyond a doubt #
# My heart will lead me there soon #
Try this, okay?
Whee!
- Cindy.
- No.
Whee.
Cindy! Come back!
[giggling]
Whoa! Whoo!
# Beyond the sea #
Whee!
# And never again #
# I'll go sailin' #
Aah!
[monster growls]
Cindy!
- [Cindy screams]
- [monster growls]
- [roaring]
- woman screams]
[screaming continues]
# I know #
Jack!
# Beyond a doubt #
[animal roars]
# We'll meet, I know we'll meet #
# At the shore #
Run, Jack.
Run!
[screaming]
# Beyond the sea #
# And never again I'll go sailing #
# No more sailing #
[roars]
[growling]
I was never the same after that,
And by the time I was in my 20s,
I figured I needed some counseling.
[phone rings]
Yes?
[Woman]
Jack Brooks is here.
He didn't call. Do you have time?
[sighs]
Uh, okay. Let's do it.
Send him in.
Jack. Didn't think I'd see you again.
Yeah, you know, I was
on my way over to Wal-Mart,
so, uh,
[clears throat]
I thought I'd just stop in, you know,
and see what's going on?
What's going on?
You know, I'm still working.
Still... I'm still plumbing.
And, uh, Eve's got me
taking this stupid night class.
It's science. It's the only one
they offer right now,
so, uh, that kind of blows,
but, uh...
I mean... You know, it's...
I've been good.
I haven't really, uh...
I haven't snapped in a while.
- So it's been good.
- That's good.
That's great.
Yeah.
[clears throat]
Yeah, you know, I guess
I kind of did a couple days ago,
but, uh, you know,
it was nothing serious,
and, uh, you know,
I got through it, so, um...
You know, I'm fine.
How are things going with you?
I'm fine.
Good. That's good.
Well, Jack,
what happened to the hand?
What happened to my hand?
[mutters]
Nothing.
I mean, you know,
it wasn't even really my fault.
I was over at Wong's.
You know, Wong's Egg Rolls.
I was doing some work
on their little shit-hole toilet.
It was pretty much
a fucking favor, you know?
They said they were gonna pay me
with a bunch of egg rolls,
and I figure that's cool, you know,
because I actually like their egg rolls,
so I didn't mind doing it for them.
So, you know, anyway, I finish up,
and I'm heading out to my van,
and out comes Mr. Wong
saying that apparently the toilet
exploded or something,
and it's my fault!
You know, like, my fault
that his toilet exploded!
So there I am, getting grilled, after
I tried to do the guy a fucking favor!
He's yelling at me in Chinese!
I don't even fucking speak Chinese!
So, you know, I-I-I punched him hard,
and he fell back, you know!
Fucking busted my hand!
My egg rolls went all over the place!
I go home, and I try to do that breathing
thing you were telling me about.
- You know, the count to three and...
- Yeah.
That doesn't fucking work, man!
I don't know why you tell me
to do these bullshit exercises!
They don't fucking work!
You know what I mean?
I ended up busting the fuck
out of my toaster!
I was kicking it around my apartment!
My neighbors started complaining!
So, now, you know, l-l-l...
Now I gotta go to Wal-Mart
and get a new fucking toaster.
You know, I'm gonna go,
'cause I can see you're pretty busy.
You know... I'm sure... I appreciate
you squeezing me in, though.
You know, I'm...
Look, if I don't see you again, then,
you know, good luck with everything,
and, uh...
If you get a chance,
maybe you should even check out
those egg rolls at Wong's,
'cause they're actually pretty good.
[door closes]
Jesus.
## [rock]
[radio off]
## [Man singing in foreign language]
- Hey.
- [speaking in foreign language]
Hey!
[foreign language]
[film projector whirring]
Well, Mr. Brooks.
As long as you're by the door,
you mind hitting the light?
You missed the film, Jack.
But don't worry.
Wasn't very interesting.
- Was it, class?
- [Man mutters]
Hope you all brought your textbooks.
Everybody turn to Chapter 6.
[teacher mutters]
[screen clattering]
Damn screen.
Mmm!
So, just to see if everyone
was paying attention,
who can tell me what the symbol
for the element of sodium is, hmm?
- [snaps fingers]
- Yes, Janice.
It's capital N, small A.
Very good.
And, uh, what is sodium?
It's salt.
Well, not exactly.
You see, sodium
is actually an alkali metal.
Uh, a very interesting fact
about the origin of the name sodium
is that it was referred to
as "soda" by the English.
Uh...
[clears throat]
Uh, it was isolated in 1807
by Sir Humphry Davy
through the electrolysis
of caustic soda.
- Uh, capital N, small A...
- Pay attention.
...comes from the Latin word for...
- You should be taking notes.
...a common sodium compound
- I don't have a pen.
...called natrium.
[huffs]
- Uh, derived from
- You're kidding me.
...the Greek "natron."
- Deal with it.
Now, when we combine
chlorine with sodium,
we get what is known
as sodium chloride,
which, of course, we all know as, uh...
- Hmm?
- Table salt.
Very good, Janice. Very good indeed.
Now, sodium by itself
can be highly malleable
and reacts explosively with moisture.
So, in order to protect the sodium,
we've surrounded it with oil.
Now, I am going to cut off
just a very small piece here.
Uh, no reason to be alarmed.
It's all quite safe.
Yes.
Oh.
Now, as you can see,
even with the minute amount
of moisture in the air,
the sodium is already reacting.
When I put it in this dish of water,
it should react violently.
Cool.
[chattering]
Uh, well, that's all for today,
uh, ladies and gentlemen.
Next class, we will be discussing
molecular deconstruction.
- Until then.
- [chattering]
You missed
the whole friggin' class, Jack.
And you were supposed to be
my ride here.
You specifically said last Thursday...
Thursday...
that you wouldn't do that anymore.
I know. I just...
I got caught up in things. I'm sorry.
You know, maybe you should just
try balancing your life, okay?
And call me if you're
not gonna pick me up.
I had to get my dad to drive me
for the second time this week.
Do you know
how embarrassing that is?
All right.
I said I'm sorry, you know?
I don't wanna hear it.
Just drive me home now, okay?
God damn, this stuff is so fascinating.
Eve, babe, what'd I tell you?
You gotta come by my place
sometime and smoke hash, you know?
Let our souls dive into the stuff.
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Yeah! I-I'm there.
Listen... Whoa, buddy.
Buddy, I can't help but notice
you're having a tough time
getting to class on time.
I happen to type up
all my notes on my laptop,
so if you wanna catch up,
you let me know, I'll burn you a disk.
What do you think?
No, I'm cool, man.
Thanks. Thanks for the offer.
Dude, don't be shy.
Why's he getting shy? Don't get shy.
- I'm not being shy.
- You're getting all shy.
I'm not, all right?
I'm not getting shy. I'm okay.
- I just don't want your...
- Mr. Brooks, may I have
a moment with you, please?
Ohh! Detention time.
You better go.
Jack, are you kidding me? I have to
work out with my sister in 20 minutes.
What do you want me to do?
He wants to talk to me.
Dude... Dude,
keep your cool head on.
I'll give her a lift.
I'm taking off right now anyway.
- No way!
- Uh, yeah way.
Perfect! Um, okay.
Well, I'll, um...
I don't know.
I'll call you later, Jack.
You better go.
So you work out.
You know, sometimes.
Sometimes.
Like, how many times a week?
That's it. That's it.
That's it. That's gotta be it.
[teacher muttering]
Uh, Jack... Jack, how are you?
I'm good, you know. How are you doing?
Uh... Uh, great. Spectacular.
Hey, you just barely
made it today, didn't you?
Yeah, you know, I'm sorry. I just...
I got caught up with things,
and I didn't expect to be that late.
So...
You must be a pretty
busy guy, then, huh?
Not really.
Jack, uh, I noticed your van
out in the parking lot.
You're a plumber, right?
Yeah.
Well, uh, I'm having
this problem with my pipes.
I was wondering if perhaps
you could, uh, stop by my place
and, uh, take a look.
Sure. Yeah. When?
[chuckles]
Well, the sooner, the better.
Pipes are driving me nuts.
- I'll come by tonight, if you like.
- Oh, that'd be great. Great.
Listen, I'm about
a 20-minute drive from here.
Number 12 Watson Road.
Just past the old quarry trail.
You think you can find it?
Number 12 Watson Road.
Yeah, I got it.
[snaps fingers]
Thanks. Thank you very much.
I really appreciate it.
I'll see you later, Jack.
[animal howling]
Jack! Oh, am I glad to see you!
Come on in.
- So, this is it.
- [dog barking]
Totally secluded. No distractions.
- [barking continues]
- Just me and Waldo here.
Slowly getting around
to fixing the place up.
Well, it looks like it, uh,
certainly has potential.
Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
Got the place real cheap, too.
Apparently, the old house
has some pretty nasty history.
Something about some crazy guy
that lived here way back in the day.
But, hell, I couldn't pass on the price.
You know what I mean?
Watch that first step.
So, anyway,
I figured I need a substance
that would promote coagulation
of the dispersed
colloidal contaminant.
So I purchased myself
a bottle of suitable flocculant,
and I went to town.
Yeah, like, uh, Draino.
Hmm. Liquid-Plumr.
[water bubbles]
Anyway, I-I-I discovered
a reduction in hydrocarbons,
which obviously resulted in
the formation of carbon residue.
- Yeah, well, you know... I mean, it...
- [bubbling continues]
It looks to me like
your main line is clogged.
Uh, main line, huh?
You see, uh, this pipe here
runs all the way out to a well.
Probably in your backyard.
With the pump
being shut off for so long,
you probably just built up
some rust on the insides.
- Rust, huh?
- It's typical of an older place like this.
So just a simple clogging, huh?
- Yeah. I mean, that's the way I see it.
- Hmm.
Look, uh, this
might actually take a bit,
so, uh, why don't you
go ahead upstairs?
And I'll do my best to fix it up.
And I'll call up on you
when I need you to try the sink.
Oh. Sure.
Uh, whatever you say, Jack.
You're the professional.
[chuckles]
I'll, uh... I'll just go upstairs.
Me and Waldo.
[whistling]
- Come on, boy!
- [Waldo barking]
- [grunts]
- [water gushing]
[water bubbling]
[grunting]
[sighs]
[whirring]
All right!
Looks like we're pretty much
all cleaned out down here!
- Go ahead and try the sink!
- Uh, will do!
- Come on.
- [growling]
[whirring continues]
- [grunts]
- [pipes creaking]
[creaking continues]
- [thud]
- [water gushing]
[mutters]
[creaking, intensified]
Still not working!
[creaking continues]
[rumbling]
[cries out, groans]
Son of a bitch!
[groans]
[creaking stops]
[barking]
- [groaning]
- [Waldo whining]
Jack? Jack!
Are you all right?
Jeez! Something zinged you
real good there.
Yeah, this goddamn valve blew
and popped me right in the head.
Here.
[sighs]
These pipes must be clogged
all over the place.
Your pressure switch shorted
along with your switch box,
and looks like I'm going to have to get
a replacement for this valve now.
[sighs]
Look, I hope you can without water
for a couple more days here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Listen, it's not like I got much choice.
Listen, I'm terribly sorry
about this, Jack,
but every step is progress.
I-I mean, at... at least you found
the heart of the problem, right?
Yeah, I guess.
Uh, what do I owe you
for the visit?
Nah, don't worry about it.
It's all right.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No, I insist.
Nah, it's all right. You know,
I'm not gonna charge my teacher.
How else am I supposed
to get an A in your class, right?
[chuckles]
You're too kind, Jack.
Thank you.
Uh, come on.
Let's get you fixed up.
- Waldo, lead the way.
- [Waldo barking]
Come on.
[engine grinding]
- Come on.
- [grinding continues]
Come on!
[sighs]
[yelling]
- [sighs]
- [engine starts]
## [rock]
[thunderclap]
- [snoring]
- [Waldo barking]
[barking continues]
[snoring continues]
[coughing]
[snores, sniffs sharply]
[thunderclap]
[heart beating]
[heart beating continues]
[therapist]
So how's your personal life?
Hey, you still with, uh, Eve?
That's her name, right?
Mm-hmm.
How's that going?
[exhales forcefully]
I don't know.
I think l... I think I might hate her.
But, uh,
I can't tell if it's that or,
you know, if I hate myself.
[sighs]
I see.
Look, you know, I'm-I'm... I'm sorry
about just busting in here
the other day and being a total dick.
I just... Look, I appreciate the things
that you're doing for me.
So, you know, are you just gonna,
like, fix these problems
that I have somehow,
because I'm-I'm dying here, man.
Look, Jack,
your anger comes out
very sporadically, very intense.
Maybe... just maybe...
you need to try to find
a method of relaxing.
I don't need to relax, all right?
I just need to quit getting
so mad all the time!
- Like, fuck, man!
- [sighs]
I broke a bottle over my head once
'cause I couldn't open it, you know?
I mean, that doesn't even
make any sense!
[sighs]
I need to find some way
to calm myself down
when I start getting like that.
I need to find some way to relax!
Uh-huh.
[sighs]
All right. You know, so how do l...
how do I start relaxing?
Well, there are a lot of ways.
You could try meditation.
A lot of people find that that is
a way to control their emotions,
or you could try...
You could try playing a sport.
You know, that... that would get
your mind off of things.
You could try Tai Chi
or yoga or... or Pilates
or Yogalates,
which is like a fusion of the two.
Yeah, you know, maybe...
maybe the next time, uh,
some asshole cuts me off
on the highway,
I'll pull over, and I'll meditate.
Or maybe I'll just
join a badminton team,
and that'll make me stop, uh,
you know, headbutting people.
Or maybe the best thing is,
I can, uh...
I can pick up
some gay exercise tape,
and I can spend the night
with my sweet pea,
sprawled out on the floor
like a fucking gazelle in Spandex!
Yeah!
That ought to solve my issues!
Holy... Holy shit.
I think I'm cured!
[Waldo barking]
- [barking continues]
- [groans]
[groans]
What the heck happened last night?
[barking]
Unbelievable!
[sharp thud]
- Come on! Come on!
- [barking]
Yeah, yeah.
[engine revving]
[engine revving, sputtering]
[Waldo whining]
[crying out, yelling]
[mutters]
[grunting]
[coughing]
- [cries out]
- [tools clattering]
Son of a bitch!
Here you go, boy.
[gasps]
Sweet Jesus.
Right there.
Well, I'll be.
[barks]
Relax, boy.
There's nothing to be afraid of here.
Incredible.
[gasps]
[growling]
[chuckling]
Did you see that, boy?
[chuckles]
- [straining]
- [whining]
[Waldo growling]
[barking]
[muffled grunting]
[barking continues]
[gurgling]
[heart beating]
[door chimes]
- Jack.
- Hey, Herb.
[snoring]
Excuse me.
[snoring continues]
Howard?
[clearing throat]
What can I do you for, boy?
I was hoping to get
a replacement for this valve.
I'll be a son of a bitch.
That's an Ironmaster.
One...
Two hundred.
I ain't seen one of them in,
oh, well,
uh, a hell of a long time.
I'll have to order one
in for you special.
It should be in tomorrow.
Say...
where you been plumbing, boy?
Uh, it's this, uh, big, old place
up on top of Watson Road.
Boy...
I'll tell you.
You don't want to go
messing around up there.
No, sir.
Bad idea.
That place is cursed.
All right.
What are you talking about?
Let me ask you this.
Do you believe in monsters, boy?
I don't got all day, Howard.
I'll tell you what.
Why don't you come on by
tomorrow evening
when things are quieter?
I'll have your valve by then.
Maybe I'll fill you in on the legend
on that cursed old place.
Next.
[burp]
Oh. Perfect. I want to talk
to you about something.
- Okay.
- Okay. Saturday night,
Jen's having a party.
I don't know how I feel about that,
but are you going?
[Girl]
I don't know. I don't really like Jen.
Neither do I. But I think
I'm gonna need a car.
Do you have yours?
[Girl]
Yeah. I think I can get mine, yeah.
And Friday night, um...
Oh, shit.
[grunts]
I think it's broken.
Oh, whatever. I don't care.
I really never use it anyway.
[chuckles]
I'm... I'm really just here for the credit.
Well, you got me beat.
I don't even know what I'm doing here.
[chuckles]
So, uh...
this class is pretty lame, isn't it?
Yeah, I guess it is.
[loud banging]
[clears throat]
[burp]
[student chuckles softly]
[student giggling]
[stomach growls]
[giggling]
[stomach gurgling]
[girls giggling, muttering]
Professor Crowley?
- Yeah?
- Are you sick?
[chortles]
Sick. Yes.
Sick. Sick, sick.
Just... sick. A little.
A little. A little sick. Lesson time.
A little sick. It's time for the lesson.
Time for the lesson.
[muttering incoherently]
Mmhh! Mmhh! Mmhh! Mmhh!
Mmhh! Eyah! Aiee!
[burp]
[breathes unevenly]
[begins retching]
[students]
Ohh!
[class muttering]
[gurgling]
[deep bubbling]
[high-pitched gurgling]
[low-pitched gurgling]
I'm starving!
Class dismissed!
[chuckles]
You're just like me.
You care about people.
There's nothing you can do
about it. That's just...
It's the way we are, right?
Yeah!
You know, you're right.
You're right.
I know.
You get me.
I get you.
Eve.
Let's go.
Okay. Jack, I'm just
going to finish my cigarette.
Yeah.
All right. Whatever.
I'll just wait in the van.
- See?
- Hold on. Hold on.
Hey. Hey, bro. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on a sec, bro.
Come on, man.
Why are you being like this?
[sighs]
What are you talking about?
Come on. Look at her.
Huh?
Look at what you're doing to her.
I mean, it's happening
right in front of you,
and you're not seeing it.
She is not okay.
I can tell when people aren't okay.
Are you listening to me?
Yeah. You are not okay.
It's making her not okay.
And you know what?
I think it's making me a little not okay,
and it's not okay, okay?
[chuckles]
Yeah.
All right. Okay. Yeah. Good talk.
So that's how it's gonna be?
You're j... You're gonna
walk away from me?
You are walking away from someone...
- Look, I'm trying to... Whoa!
- Take your hand off me, guy.
I'm just trying to help you relax.
Can you relax?
See, you gotta relax.
And maybe smoke some nice stuff,
right?
[snickers]
Look, Eve, can we get out of here?
All right, this guy's a clown.
No. Eve. Eve, I'm not a clown.
Eve, you're staying right there.
Dude, she not going anywhere
until you calm down.
- Okay?
- All right, look,
you get out of my face.
Okay? You don't know me.
Jake, I know you. We know each other.
- It's "Jack."
- Jake,
calm down. Okay?
Hey. Big guy.
You just need to smoke
some hashish... Ooh!
Jack!
You're a monster!
What the hell is wrong with you?
You can't just go around punching
out everyone who pisses you off!
Are you kidding me? All right,
did you even see what happened?
- [choking]
- Take me home!
Take me home now, Jack!
I'm sorry! Did I hurt your girlfriend?
[Eve]
Shut up! Take me home!
[gasping]
Help!
[car motor stalling]
[motor starts]
[dog barks]
- Uhh! Oh!
- [barking]
[barking]
- [continues barking]
- [sniffles]
[breathes heavily]
[groans]
Ah!
[squishing, splattering]
[breathes erratically, groans]
Aah!
[gasps]
[gasping]
Aah! Uhh!
[grunts, groans]
[creature whines]
Uhh! Aahh!
Uhh! Uhh! Aahh!
[blood dripping]
Ah.
[barks]
[chuckles]
[plop]
[slow breathing]
[low growl]
[crash, clattering]
[barking]
[whimpering]
[whining]
[dog whimpers]
[dog whines, Crowley munching]
[munching, whining stops]
[munching]
I think I've figured something out.
Yeah? What's that?
Well, I'm thinking about moving away.
Where are you going?
I was thinking probably Brazil.
Why Brazil?
I don't know. I mean,
you know, it's far away.
Figured it'd be good to,
uh, to just get away...
from everything for a while.
Well. If you want to go really far away,
why don't you go to, uh, Australia?
I don't want to go to Australia.
All right, I know this guy that went there,
and he said it sucked.
So, you know,
why would I want to go there?
So you think by going to Brazil
you're gonna get away
from all your problems.
I didn't say that.
You know, I just figured
maybe a change of scenery
would be good.
Forget it.
Look, Jack,
I know this is
a touchy subject for you.
But it really might help us
if we can at least
talk about the death of your family.
No.
All right? I told you.
I don't want to talk about that.
It's not healthy to ignore your past.
What do you remember?
Anything else.
You know, I used to
tell people what I saw.
And everyone just thought I was nuts.
So now I don't even know
what I believe anymore.
All I know is that my family's dead.
And I ran away.
Of course you ran away.
You were just a kid. Right?
Yeah, but I should've stayed.
You know. I could've done something.
What would you have done?
I don't know! All right.
But anything would've been better
than just running away like a little pussy!
Well, Jack...
I think we hit the nail on the head.
You see, sometimes
our anger and frustration
are cause by very real
and inescapable problems
that occur in our lives.
You ran away from something
you couldn't do anything about.
And now you hate yourself for it.
I know it's tough.
But at some point, you're gonna
have to confront that memory.
And you're gonna
have to try to find a way
and to forgive yourself.
[shop bell chimes]
Thanks.
[snoring]
- [snoring]
- Howard.
Howard.
[snorts]
- Howard!
- Christ!
Oh, my lad.
Oh, well, you just about made me
piss my goddamn drawers.
Now, what can I do you for, boy?
Here to pick up that safety valve.
The Ironmaster? 200?
Ironmaster 200.
Heck, I haven't seen one of them...
What... No, wait. No, w...
Wait a minute. One of them
came in this afternoon.
[sighs]
[softly] 2...
3...
Up.
[bones cracking]
Ohh...
You all right?
Yeah.
[bones creaking]
[groans softly]
What the...
[bones crack]
What the hell do you need
one of these for anyway?
The old place.
Remember? Watson Road?
[whispers]
Watson Road?
Not that old place up on the hill?
That's the one.
No. You don't... You don't want
to go messing around up there.
That place is cursed.
Is that so?
You're damned right.
[exhales heavily]
When I was a boy, I went there
to live with my uncle. Emmet.
He was a researcher.
Used to travel the world collecting things,
all sorts of strange and rare artifacts.
One in particular was a little item
he picked up in Japan, I think.
It was a heart.
[Howard, narrating]
A black heart...
sealed up tight in a glass case.
I became fascinated with it.
I was just a boy at the time
my uncle told me the legend.
He said hundreds of years ago,
a demon had crept its way
into our world...
straight from the bowels of hell...
with one purpose...
to spread its evil
amongst all humans.
[Man]
Howard!
[clattering]
Howard! Are you down there?
[footsteps descending]
[gasps]
[footsteps]
[thunder]
Boy, get your ass out of here.
How many times do I have to tell you?
Keep out of this room!
Now, get up there
and clean those dishes!
Yes, sir.
[thunder]
[Howard]
As the story goes,
a group of men had gathered
to destroy the demon.
Many lives were lost.
But it was finally killed.
The heart was kept as a trophy.
But it was said the evil
still lurked within.
Over the years, it was
passed on to relatives,
sold in auctions,
purchased, and then sold again,
until it showed up
in a small antique store,
where my uncle bought it.
[hissing]
[low moaning]
But then,
somehow,
that heart got inside him.
Mmm.
[stabs at food]
Yeah.
[mutters]
The next day, he looked different.
[muttering incomprehensibly]
Boy! Pass me your plate!
He was acting mighty strange, too.
Had an appetite
like I'd never seen before.
[growling, muttering]
Yeah. Good.
[chortles]
I started fearing the worst.
[hinges creaking]
The story of that godforsaken heart
was racing through my mind.
I started wondering
if that ancient demon
had found its way back once again.
- [dog yelping]
- [gasps]
[dog yelps, whines]
The next night, I awoke
to something horrible.
[Emmet growls,
shouts incomprehensibly]
That's when I knew my uncle
was changing into...
[Emmet growling, muttering]
... something else.
Uncle Emmet?
[Emmet growling]
[growling, munching]
Yah!
- [growling]
- Uncle Emmet.
Are you all right?
- Aah!
- [growling]
- [crunch]
- [screaming]
[growling]
[screaming]
[shouting indistinctly]
[growling]
[sobbing]
No.
[Emmet shouting]
[loads rifle]
[growling]
[screaming]
[cocks rifle]
[yelling]
[gunshot]
I did what I had to do.
I dragged him out to the backyard.
Dug a hole 6 feet deep.
Tossed the body
in a big, old crate,
and I locked it up tight.
I buried him.
But I'll tell you this.
As I closed up that big, old crate,
I could hear the heart.
[loud heartbeats]
It was still beating!
So he... he ate your hand?
How'd you dig the hole?
Well, God damn it, it wasn't easy.
All right. Look, uh,
now, don't get mad or anything,
but, uh...
No, I just... I don't know
what you want me to say.
You know, I mean, can I just, uh,
can I just pay for this thing so, uh,
I can get the hell out of here?
You little son of a bitch.
Here I am,
speaking my mind,
and nobody gives a crap.
[opens cash register]
9.25.
Just, uh, keep the change. All right?
[grabs valve]
Wait till you...
Well, it's $10.
Thanks, Daddy.
Eve.
Eve, um, I'm sorry.
Okay? You know?
I mean, I didn't mean
to snap the other night.
It's just he... he was getting in my face.
You know? l... #
Jack! Just stop.
Okay? l... I don't...
I don't get you.
I still don't get you.
You make everything so difficult!
You know what you are?
You're high maintenance.
[sighs]
All right. Eve, I'm coming
to say that I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
You are not sorry.
You know, you never,
ever think about me.
You never think
about what I need!
Do you?
- Uh, yeah. All right? I do, a lo...
No, no, no. I'm sorry, you don't.
Okay? You don't.
You have no concept
about what I have to do.
I have a lot of stuff going on,
okay?
J-Just so much stuff.
Like, school.
I have to watch my marks in school.
l... I watch my figure.
I'm learning how to cook.
[snickers]
Get the fuck out of here.
Okay? You don't cook.
Uh, I'm learning to. You know what?
This is just a perfect example
about how you don't even
pay attention to me anymore.
[sighs]
You know, sometimes
I think we should just
see other people or something.
Uh, I mean, if that's what you want.
You know, I mean I...
I'm... I'm sorry. What?
Well, I thought you...
Are you breaking up with me?
- No. I didn't say that.
- [sighs angrily]
- You know, l...
- Huh!
Hmph!
I didn't say that.
[snoring]
[snorts, snores]
[whispering softly]
[whispers]
Eve.
Hey, Eve?
What?
How you doing? You feeling okay?
Uh, yeah.
[chuckles]
You?
[hoarse voice]
Yeah. Oh, yeah. No.
There was a lot of karaokeing last night.
Fucking huge party.
It was sick.
Huh.
I think he's still gooched
from last night.
Yeah, dude. He looks messed up.
I put in a formal complaint this morning.
I don't think he's marking us correctly.
Trev, pass me that book.
[thump]
[loud, slow belch]
[groaning]
[gurgling]
[loud gurgling]
Ohh.
[chuckles]
[sniffles]
[grunting]
[stomach growling]
[sniffles]
[clears throat, sniffles]
- Bohh!
- [clattering]
- [Crowley gasps]
[coughing]
[stomach growls]
[sniffles, grunts]
It's all right. It's all right.
Class, please.
Please, uh, be seated.
Everybody, down,
[exhales]
so that we can, uh, uh...
[stomach growls]
begin, begin.
[retches]
[students]
Oh!
[laughs]
[grunts]
[sighs, chuckles]
[coughing]
[coughs violently]
Uhh! Ahh.
Well. Well. Well.
Let's get started.
[stomach growls]
[sputters]
[burp]
Ohh!
[stomach growling]
[soft gurgling]
Aah! Aah!
[pounding]
[screaming]
Oh!
[grunting]
Professor. Are you okay?
[stomach growling]
[burp]
[gurgling]
Ohh!
[breathes shakily]
- Ohh!
- Professor?
- Oohh!
- Aah!
Holy shit! Run!
[screaming]
[gasps, whimpers]
No!
Jack, stop!
Forget about her!
We need to friggin' get out!
[groaning]
[screaming]
Jack, hurry the hell up!
Wait! Thanks, Eve.
Just grab her other arm!
Aah!
[whimpering]
- In here.
- What?
[whimpering]
[growling]
[Jack grunting]
[Jack]
Ah!
Ohh!
[Eve sobbing]
[screaming]
[growling]
[girls screaming]
Ugh!
[screaming]
[panting]
Help. Help.
Hel...
Come on.
I think I broke my thumb.
[growling]
Aah!
[screaming]
[doors banging]
[whimpering]
[growling]
- [screaming]
- [gasping]
[sobbing]
[choking]
[all screaming]
[growling]
[growling loudly]
[heartbeat]
[screaming]
[growling]
[panting]
[choking]
[growling]
John!
[screaming]
[muffled screaming]
[gurgling]
What if that doesn't work, Jack?
It's... It's not going to work. It's a cable.
You're tying it up with a friggin' cable.
My leg! It hurts!
We have to get out of here, okay?
How are you going to get us
out of here, huh, Jack?
It hurts so much! Is it bleeding?
Jack! How... What are we going to do?
We have to get out of here!
How are you going to get us out of here?
We're going to get out of here,
Eve, okay? Just don't worry!
- How? Huh, Jack?
- I don't know, all right?
[sobbing]
Oh, God, I think it's bleeding!
Shut up!
[wailing]
[growling]
[screaming]
[both growling]
[both screaming]
John!
[growling]
All right. I'm going
to have a look, okay?
[screaming]
Shh. It's going to be okay.
[footsteps approaching]
[girl whimpering]
[growling loudly]
[screaming]
No.
[wailing]
[grunting]
[screaming]
[munching]
- [screaming]
- [munching]
[munching continues]
[panting]
[sobbing]
[growling]
[screaming]
Ah!
[sobbing]
[muffled sobbing]
[growling]
- [growling]
- [muffled screaming]
[screaming]
[growling]
Run! Come on.
[screaming]
[singing indistinctly]
Open up!
[growling]
- Open the door!
- [speaking foreign language]
[speaking foreign language]
Hey, hey, hey!
- [yelling in foreign language]
- We got to go!
We got to get the hell out of here!
Ah! Ow!
[munching]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
[engine stalling]
They're coming!
Why do you have to drive
such a piece of shit?
- Come on!
- [engine stalling]
[engine starts]
[Man on radio]
It was a big hit way back in the day.
So put your arms
around your sweetie,
- kick back, relax, and enjoy...
- Drive faster!
... this blast from the past.
## [pop jazz]
[Bobby Darin]
# Somewhere #
# Beyond the sea #
[tires screeching]
Why are you
stopping the car?
Hello? Jack, why are you
Are you mentally deranged?
Why the hell did you stop the car?
Jack, what's wrong with you?
Are you in a coma?
- [Eve yelling indistinctly]
- # Somewhere #
# Beyond the sea #
Run!
# She's there watchin' for me #
# If I could fly like birds on high #
# Then straight to her arms #
[Eve]
Are you awake? Wake up!
This isn't funny, Jack! Turn on the car!
Turn on the fucking car!
Jack, are you crazy?
Jack, you are acting really crazy.
Get out!
No, I'm not getting out of the car!
- Are you insane?
- Get out!
[whispering]
Why?
Now!
[whimpering]
Are you kidding me?
What are you doing?
You can't leave me!
[tires screeching]
[hacking]
[growling, munching]
[growling]
[growling loudly]
[grunts]
[growls]
Aah!
[grunts]
Ugh.
- [growling]
- Aah!
[banging]
[grunts]
[growling]
Aah!
[screaming]
- [screaming]
- [growling]
[growling]
- Aah!
- Ooh!
[both growling]
Aah!
[panting]
[growling]
[punch]
Hello.
[grunting]
Ugh!
[panting]
Aah!
[growling]
[sighing]
[girl screaming]
[heartbeat]
[screaming]
[whimpering]
[gurgling]
[growling]
[all screaming]
Oh, shit.
[screaming]
[muffled screaming]
[munching]
Oh!
[screaming]
[distant growling]
[growling]
[Jack grunting]
[screaming]
Aah!
[growling]
[grunting]
[screaming]
[high-pitched whirring]
[blows]
[grunting]
[clanging]
Ah.
[distant screaming]
[screaming]
[growling]
[gurgling]
[screaming]
[growling]
Go!
[growling loudly]
[growling]
Get out of here! Just go!
[grunting]
[growling]
[groaning]
[screaming]
[gasping]
[growling]
Go!
[groaning]
[shrieking]
[grunting]
[growling]
[shrieking]
- [laughing]
- [shrieking]
Ah!
[laughing]
[shrieking]
Mmm?
[groaning]
Ah!
[grunting]
[growling]
[gurgling]
[gurgling, growling]
[growling]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[growling]
[gurgling]
Oh, you...
Aah! Ugh.
[sighing]
[panting]
[growling]
[screaming]
[heartbeat]
[grunting]
Aah!
[yelling]
[gurgling]
[exhales]
[clatter]
[whimpering]
[panting]
[Jack, narrating]
Something changed for me that day.
I felt different,
and I needed to feel that way again.
I knew just where to start.
[munching]
[rustling]
[growling]
[shrieking]
[choking]
After that,
I couldn't stop.
Turns out, old Howard was right.
Monsters do exist.
- [knife sharpening]
- But I'm not running from them anymore.
Now I spend most of my days
looking for situations like this.
- [cheering]
- I guess I'm hooked.
And as for that anger problem of mine,
well,
I got that under control now.
[growling]
[bone snaps]
[screaming]
[growling]
[roaring]
[screaming]
Subtitles by LeapinLar
[Man]
Hell,
yeah!