[Thinking]
Eight years ago,
my visions began...
terrifying fantasies
of things to come.
Through them I found you, Mike,
and your friend, Reggie.
[Male]
First, he took Mom and Dad.
Then he took Jodie.
Now he's after me.
Mike, that Tall Man of yours
did not take Jodie away.
Jodie died in a car wreck.
He had a dream...
just a nightmare.
Seems so real.
You know, partner, what we need
is a change a scenery.
Where'll we go?
Well, I don't know.
I guess we can figure
that one out when we get there.
Okay.
Well, get on upstairs,
get your gear together.
'Cause we leave
when the sun comes up.
[Thinking]
But I also found him.
The Tall Man.
[Gasps]
Boy!
[Yells]
[Glass shattering]
[Clicks]
[Roaring]
[Shrieking]
Ow! Ow! Ow!
[Whispers]
Shit.
[Growls]
[Whispers]
Burn, you son of a bitch.
Shit!
[Yelling]
Stay down, it's okay.
[Clunk]
[Female] I don't know
where he comes from...
maybe another dimension.
His army of creatures.
He destroys towns
and plunders their graveyards
to enslave the dead.
Each day, I can feel him
coming closer.
He knows I see him.
We've both seen what he can do.
Mike, we've grown up together.
I know you're out there.
Soon, my grandfather will die.
And my visions will become real.
I need you.
Mike, help me.
[Male groaning]
[Male] Well,
I guess you could say I just
really went over the deep end.
I mean, I got to the point
where I couldn't distinguish
fantasy from reality.
[Male voice]
That's good, keep it up.
And I don't blame Redge anymore.
I mean... what could he do?
I mean, the dreams were really
just taking hold of me.
[Male voice] Just tell him
what he wants to hear.
And besides,
since... I lost my family,
Redge is really the only...
person I've got.
- He's the only one that stood by me.
- I gotta get outta here.
She needs me.
And now that I'm not having
these dreams,
I'm really looking forward
to just moving back in with him
and getting on with my life.
There are a lot of things
I want to do.
It's been a tough seven years.
But you've come a long way.
Be well, Michael.
And remember...
it was all in your imagination.
The fuck it was.
[Clunk]
Uh!
I was afraid I'd find ya here.
Come on, Mike.
Get up outta there.
This whole place is empty.
So, uh, come on,
lets' go home.
Look at this,
God damn it!
Now, that's the third one
I dug up!
Now, does it strike you
a little strange, Redge,
that every single corpse
in this entire graveyard's missing?
Well, what do you want, Mike?
I wanna stop him.
The Tall Man?
That story about me
blowing up my own house
because it was infested
with midgets.
Mike, that wasn't real.
Your doctor said it was
your own paranoid delusion.
Hey, fuck the doctors and fuck you too,
if you don't want to help me!
God damn it, Mike,
I've tried to help ya!
What the hell
am I supposed to do?
He showed me things.
I think he wants me
to come to him.
Why you?
I'm not the only one,
there's others.
There's a girl.
She's drawn to him too.
But I'm telling you, man,
without our help, she's gonna die.
He's gotta be stopped
and I'm going after him.
I know I can find him.
But to kill him
I'm gonna need your help.
[Whispering]
Shit, Mike.
If they catch you here
diggin' up graves,
they'll put you away
and you'll never get out again.
Come on back to the house.
Come on, man,
we can talk it out there.
[Redge]
Dinner's waitin' for ya.
Aunt Martha came down
and Celeste baked a turkey.
And you know, little Bonnie,
she just can't wait
to meet her Uncle Mike.
God, she's been talkin'
about it all day.
Man, she's really,
really high on seein' ya.
[Male voice]
Welcome home, boy.
Redge, we gotta get the people
outta your house, man!
The gas in there's gonna go off
and it's gonna blow!
Ah!
No, no, no!
Redge!
Get 'em out.
Gotta get 'em out!
Come on,
we gotta get 'em out!
No, no, no!
You couldn't save 'em.
You knew.
Before it happened.
I'm so sorry, Redge.
[Sighs]
Let's go, Mike.
We got things to do.
[Redge] Mike didn't need
to ask me anymore.
I enlisted for the duration.
[Engine whirs]
He told me it might take us years
to find the Tall Man.
And if we did,
we'd probably die.
Yeah, maybe.
But not without a fight.
Lets' go shopping.
Redge, long guns are no good.
Let's go to work.
This guy worked
at close range.
There's no use tryin'
to tell anybody.
They'd lock us up
and throw away the key.
We'd spent a long time
on the road.
Northwest mostly.
It wasn't hard
to pick up his trail.
Places he'd been
always look the same.
Small towns are like people.
Some get old
and die a natural death.
Some are murdered.
[Heavy breath]
[Mike]
We have to be careful.
'Cause sometimes
he sets traps for us.
Too damn late.
Let's get the tools
and scope it out.
[Chainsaw revs]
[Whispers]
I'll check it out.
All right, I'll go this way.
Okay.
[Splashing]
[Knocking]
Mike!
Down here, Mike.
[Whispering]
Hey, Mike, he left one.
Who are you?
[Whimpering]
[Whispering]
Where do we find him?
Oh, my God.
Liz, what has he done to you?
[Whines]
Redge,
this is the one
I was telling you about...
the... the girl in my...
well...
[crackling]
Ohh, you play
a good game, boy.
Come east, if you dare.
Get the fuck back!
[Groaning]
[Redge]
It wasn't the first time
the Tall Man had left
one of his calling cards.
But that one was
the worst, so far.
He must know we're on his trail
because that hunchback apparition
looked just like the girl
in Mike's head.
We're moving east
toward the state line.
There's one more town...
Perigord.
[Female] I buried my grandchild
and both of my children.
Now my husband.
It's so hard to live past
the ones you love.
Hey, Grandma,
you still got me and Jeri, okay?
I don't see much of Jeri,
but how are you?
Are you still having
those nightmares?
Um, no.
No, not any more.
Oh, I can't.
You've gotta be strong, Grandma.
You know Grandpa
would have wanted it that way.
I'll try.
In the name
of the Father and the Son
and the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
I know how hard it is for you.
But remember,
he's left a life of pain
and trouble.
And he's gone to God.
He's going to rest now.
The last train leaves at six.
I've gotta be on it.
Damn it, Jeri,
I need you to be here.
With us.
Just one more day.
I have to get back
to Bruce and Stevie.
I've gotta get going now.
It's 20 miles back
to the station.
[Whispering] Besides,
Grandma's a tough cookie.
Thanks, Jeri.
I'm sorry, hon,
I really do have to go.
Look, if there's
any problem, just call.
Okay?
Take care.
Jeri?
[Rustling]
[Thinking]
Damn!
It's not a dream.
Mike.
Where are you?
Redge,
she's in danger.
Who?
The other, the girl.
Well, you said that
six months ago.
Yeah, well,
this time I'm certain.
We're close to her
and the Tall Man.
Come on, let's go.
Geez, I slept half
the day away.
I don't know, man, you say she's here,
you say she's there.
She's everywhere.
So, maybe so.
But I'm still not so sure
she's not just a wet dream.
Listen, Redge,
we're close.
And soon,
I'm gonna find her.
And him.
All right then.
[Car starts]
[Tires squeal]
My darling,
I love you so much.
[Sobs]
I'll miss you,
I'll miss you.
Forgive me, Lord,
but I must end the sacrilege.
I can't close my eyes
to the things I've seen.
It must be stopped.
[Gasps]
[Creaking]
You.
The graveside service
is about to begin.
[Banging]
[Banging continues]
[Wind blowing]
[Whimpers]
[Scraping]
Blessed Mother.
It's just a tree limb.
Wind.
[Clang]
Damn this wind!
[Yells]
[Click, click]
[Kiss]
[Scraping]
Lizabeth?
[Sighs]
[Yells]
[Screams]
Finally up, huh?
Yeah.
I had this dream
about this girl.
Hi.
Oh, sorry to startle you, pal.
I... I picked her up
about 50 miles back.
Uh, Mike, this is Alchemy.
Chemy for short.
It's nice to meet you, Mike.
Hey, uh, Redge,
could you pull over?
I gotta take a leak.
Sure.
Redge,
this girl's in my dreams.
Except, when she's in 'em,
she's dead.
I think, for her sake,
she shouldn't get involved with us.
Well, your dreams
always come true?
No, not exactly,
but pretty damn close.
[Sighs]
Shit, Mike,
have you looked at her?
You know,
we been out here a long time.
And besides,
it gets hard on the road.
Redge, you're thinkin'
with your wrong head.
This girl... she's in danger.
Okay, okay.
So, she's in danger
with us or without us.
Or at least with us
we can protect her, right?
I mean, isn't that logical?
Yeah, in a horny sort of way,
I suppose it is.
Works for me.
So, uh, Chemy,
where you headed?
Um, to my hometown, Perigord.
It's about 20 miles
down the Interstate.
Perigord here we come.
[Car starts]
Grandma?
[Ticking]
[Male voice]
If you want her, come tonight.
[Alchemy]
Looks like a ghost town.
Things sure have changed
since I left.
Oh, yeah, how long
has that been?
I don't know,
must be ten years now.
We're gonna have
to find a place to hold up.
You know, my uncle owns
a bed and breakfast
on the other side of town.
And, uh, you guys
have been really nice to me
and I'm sure he wouldn't mind
giving you a room.
That'd be great.
[Male voice]
I've got them both.
Not my grandma.
[Alchemy]
Jesus, what the hell?
I'm gonna go take
a look around, okay?
[Creaking]
Maybe we can
get in a window.
[Redge]
See it?
Yeah.
Trapped.
Too scared to come out.
Nothin' to do
but watch and wait.
Yeah.
[Sighs]
Damn!
I can't believe they just
abandoned the place.
And I don't have a clue
as to how the hell
we're gonna get in here.
Allow me.
[Chainsaw revs]
[Click]
[Creaks]
I've been tracking this guy
a long time now.
And we're gettin' close.
Uh-huh.
Believe it or not,
you're gonna sleep safely tonight.
As long as I don't sleepwalk, right?
Yeah, well, just stay in bed.
We'll be back before dawn.
Will you wake me
when you get back?
Sure.
[Clunk, clunk, whirring]
[Click, clink]
[Bang]
Gravers.
I've seen 'em before
in my dreams.
They're the ones that exhume
the bodies for 'em.
Looks like just one?
Yeah, well, I'm gonna circle
around and make sure.
All right.
[Whispering]
[Praying]
[Bang]
Oh!
They have no need
of your services.
Who are you...
to question the word
of God's servants.
[Whipping]
Whah!
You think that when you die
you go to heaven.
You come to us!
Ahh, ahh!
[Muffled scream]
For God's sake, girl!
What are you doing here?
I have got to find
my grandmother.
Your grandmother's gone!
He's taken them all!
- He's harvesting the entire town.
- What?
Your grandmother, your grandfather...
we've got to warn people!
What's that sound?
You stay here.
[Whooshing]
[Click, click]
[Whirring]
Uh!
[Yells]
[Thud]
[Groaning]
[Whirring]
[Yells]
[Whimpers]
Hello again.
And good-bye.
[Yells]
[Alien voice]
Lizabeth?
Elizabeth?
[Harsher]
Oh, my God, Grandma.
[Yells]
[Screams]
I'm sorry, Grandma.
[Door slams]
[Yells]
[Screams]
Michael.
What the hell's going on here?
- Huh?
- Uh, Redge.
Uh, this is Elizabeth.
- I'll get the car.
- Okay.
Wow.
[Chuckles]
So, then what happened?
Well, the priest saved my life
and just a few minutes later
I saw him get sliced and diced
by some...
flying Cuisinart.
So, you've seen it...
his sphere?
She's seen it, Redge.
I told ya, I had a funny feeling
about this place.
And he took my grandma.
- Turned her into some kind of...
- dwarf.
Yeah, I know,
we've seen it before.
He... he crushes them down and...
you know, ships them off
to God knows where.
Yeah, he got Mike's brother.
He got my whole family.
Well, I don't think we oughtta
wait around this place,
just waiting for him
to come and get us.
You're right.
But I think we only got
a couple more hours 'til daybreak.
And the traps on the doors
should keep us safe.
I'll tell you what... um, why don't
we just get some shuteye,
and then we'll just bang outta here
in the morning.
Yeah, I could use some sleep.
Come on,
I'll watch over you.
[Sighs]
And I'll watch over you.
[Chuckles]
[Giggles]
[Female voice whispering]
Michael.
I love you.
[Michaels voice]
Her lips aren't moving.
[Elizabeth]
We're chaining.
[Mike]
Wow, this is great!
[Elizabeth]
We're different, Mike.
That's why he wants us.
Because we're the only ones
who can see what he's doing.
I prayed so hard
that you'd find me.
You did.
[Mike]
I love you.
Mm-mm.
God, Redge, I love your head.
[Clang]
[Yells and screams]
[Explosion]
What the hell was that?
[Chuckles]
Redge.
Grenade went odd.
Shit!
Forget it, Mike.
There's nobody out there.
Looks like Chemy's uncle had a...
a cat or a dog or somethin'.
I... I can't tell.
Redge,
who are we kidding?
I'm a 19-year-old kid.
You're a bald, middle-aged,
ex-ice cream vendor.
Thanks, Mike.
Can't kill him alone.
No way.
How 'bout our families?
We just gonna forget
about them?
We're never gonna forget
about them.
But Redge, come on, we got people
who are alive right now
who are depending on us.
[Screams]
Ah, Mike!
Come on!
[Sighs]
I'll get the gear.
Wait.
Redge?
Wait, wait, let me go
with you, okay?
No way.
Take Liz's car and drive south
a hundred miles.
- Now go!
- Well, what's gonna happen to you?
How are you gonna find me?
I'll find you...
if I'm able.
What's that supposed to mean,
if you're able?
All right, load up.
You got it.
Well, shoot the fucker!
[Yells]
[Groans]
Reggie!
Aww, shit!
- God damn, son of a fuck...
- Redge!
Hey, hey, seat belt's jammed, man.
Give me a knife.
[Groans]
[Whispers]
Great.
Hey, man, ju...
just give me the knife.
And there's no sense
in both of us fryin'.
- No way, partner.
- Oh, come on.
I'm not leavin' you now.
Damn it!
- Okay, I'm free.
- Come on!
- I'm clear, man.
- Come on, man, let's go!
I'm goin'.
[Creaks]
Shit.
Come on.
Let's go kick some ass.
[Gas flowing]
Hey.
Ready?
[Klunk]
[Redge]
Hydrochloric acid.
Let's just see him try
to reanimate anybody
that's embalmed with this shit.
Hey, Redge.
Come here.
What's that look like to you?
Well, it's round
and it's got a couple a slits
like one a those...
brain suckers.
It's a keyhole.
Only this must be
a doorway to his world.
We gotta catch one of those things
so we can get in here.
[Knocking]
Yeah, sure, Mike,
you catch one.
Come on.
We gotta find Liz.
All right, I'll take the north wing,
you take the south.
I'll meet ya back here
in 15 minutes.
Right.
Ah!
[Yells]
[Screams]
Liz?
Come on, let's go!
Oh!
[Screams]
Ahh!
[Moans]
[Yells]
[Screaming]
Ahh!
[Klunk]
[Yells]
[Chainsaw revs]
Come on, you mother!
I think it stopped it.
Shit, I hope so.
[Squeaking]
[Yells]
[Explodes]
Don't move, be still.
[Squeaking]
[Squeals]
Those should hold it.
Let me get the other door.
[Sighs]
[Screams]
No!
[Explosion]
Ahh!
[Clicking]
[Moaning]
[Whirring]
[Yells]
[Intermittent whirring]
Come on, Mike,
let's go, okay?
- Are you okay?
- Mm-hm.
Ahh!
[Snarling]
God damn it.
[Yelling]
[Sighs]
Damn it.
Here, hold this.
Hell do you want with that thing?
- Don't worry.
- Be careful!
Don't worry!
I'm hopin' as long as it's
embedded in flesh, it's safe.
Hey!
Ah!
Where's the rest of the guy?
I'll tell ya later.
Hand me this.
[Splintering]
Here, I'll trade ya'.
Come on.
- Here.
- Uhh.
[Barking]
[Engine starts]
All right, let me have it.
All right, here goes.
[Bang]
[Humming]
Come here,
let me show you somethin'.
Come on.
Let's torch this place
and get the hell outta here.
Uh!
[Yells]
Mike.
Behind you.
[Cries]
[Moaning]
Help!
[Yells]
Hey!
Suck on this.
[Whirring]
[Groans]
[Coughs]
Ah!
Uh!
[Machine starts]
[Yells]
Mike.
Go and get the hell outta here!
Chemy.
Come on, get in, let's go.
Come on.
Come on, get in,
it's Chemy.
[Laughing]
[Whooping and yelling]
We really nailed
that son of a bitch!
Hey, hey, wait, wait,
Mike, Mike, Mike.
Check out that coffin
and make sure
that whatever is in there
is dead, all right?
[Bangs]
Empty!
That's the way I like 'em.
[Laughing]
Hey, babe, you know
you coulda run.
But thanks for stickin' with us.
You know,
I been thinkin' about us.
[Yells]
[Laughs]
[Screaming]
Redge!
- Redge!
[Both]
Redge!
Michael!
[Screams]
[Engine starts]
Listen to me,
this is not happening.
We're gonna wake up...
It's a dream.
It's only a dream.
No, it's not!
[Yelling]