(Riddick)
They say most of your brain
shuts down in cryosleep.
All but the primitive side,
the animal side.
No wonder I'm still awake.
Transporting me
with civilians.
Sounded like 40, 40-plus.
Heard an Arab voice,
some hoodoo holy man,
probably on his way
to New Mecca.
But what route?
What route?
Smelled a woman.
Sweat, boots,
tool belt, leather.
Prospector type.
Free settlers.
And they only
take the back roads.
And here's my real problem.
Mr. Johns,
the blue-eyed devil.
Plannin' on taking me
back to slam,
only this time
he picked a ghost lane.
[clanking]
A long time between stops.
A long time
for something to go wrong.
[alarm beeping]
[grunting]
[alarm beeping rapidly]
[groans]
Why did I fall on you?
He's dead.
The captain's dead.
I was looking right at him.
The chrono shows
we are 22 weeks out,
so... so gravity was not
supposed to kick in
for another 19.
Why'd I fall at all?
Did you hear
what I said?
The captain's dead.
[electricity buzzing]
[computer beeping]
1550 millibars...
dropping 20mb per minute.
Shit! We're hemorrhaging air.
Something took a swipe at us.
Come on. Just tell me
we're still in
the shipping lane.
Just show me all those stars.
Come on!
Those big, bright...
[alarm beeping]
What?
(Owens)
This is an emergency dispatch
from merchant vessel
Hunter Gratzner
en route to
the Tangier system
with 40 commercial
passengers onboard.
We have been knocked out
of our shipping lane
and are currently entering
the atmosphere
of a planetary body
in this position:
X- 38-stroke-5,
Y- 95-stroke-8, Z-21...
[rumbling]
Fry, where the hell's
our comms?
[gasps]
(electronic voice)
Rate of descent
beyond known limits.
beyond...
They trained you for this,
Fry, right?
(computer)
Deploy lower air brakes now.
Deploy lower air brakes...
(electronic voice)
Center of gravity too far aft.
Recommend
purging ballast now.
What the...
Was that a purge, Fry?
Too heavy in the ass.
I can't get
my fucking nose down.
(Owens)
Crisis program selected
number 2 of this system
because it shows
at least some oxygen.
Maximum terrain 220 meters
over mean surface,
largely cinder and gypsum
with some evaporite deposits.
[clanging]
Fry, what the hell
are you doing?
I gotta drop more load.
[beeping]
Look, I tried everything else.
I still got no horizon.
Better try everything twice,
'cause we don't
just flush out...
Look, If you know
something I don't,
get up here
and take the chair.
Listen, company says
we are responsible
for every single one
of those people, Fry.
What, we both die
out of sheer fucking nobility?
Don't you touch
that handle, Fry!
[beeping]
[grunting]
[clanging]
I'm not gonna die
for them.
(electronic voice)
Air-lock doors not secure.
Owens!
[alarm beeping]
70 seconds, Fry.
You still have 70 seconds
to level this beast out.
Shit. Shit!
Pull him up.
Air lock doors not secure.
Air-lock doors not secure.
Air-lock doors...
[glass shattering]
What the fuck is
happening up there?
[explosion]
[man chattering]
[woman yelling]
[people coughing]
Yeah, I-Imam?
(woman)
Zeke?
[both grunting]
Somebody's gonna get hurt
one of these days.
It ain't gonna be me.
[grunting]
Here, Shazza.
So I guess
something went wrong.
I'm sorry.
Get it out of me!
[panting]
Don't touch it!
Don't... Don't you
touch that handle!
Get it out of him!
No, no, no,
it's too close to his heart.
There's some Anestaphine
in the med-lock
in the back of the cabin.
[groaning]
Not anymore,
there's not.
Get out of here, everyone.
[moaning]
Get out of here.
Allahu Akbar
Allahu Akbar...
[praying in Arabic]
That'll teach me
for flying coach.
Interesting.
(Paris)
Is anyone else having
difficulties breathing?
Yeah, I feel one lung short.
All of us.
I feel like I just
ran or something.
There was talk of
a scouting party
looking for other people,
but then we saw this.
What the bloody hell
happened?
(Fry)
It could have
been a meteor storm.
Might have been a rogue comet.
I don't know.
Well, I, for one,
am thoroughly grateful.
This beast wasn't
made to land like this,
but I think
you did well.
Actually, the only
reason we're alive
is because of her.
Yes, I suppose
you're right.
Thanks very much.
(Jack)
Yeah, thanks
for saving our dicks.
No, really.
Thanks awfully.
Well done.
He just escaped
from a maximum prison.
So do we just keep him
locked up forever?
Well, that
would be my choice.
[whispering]
Is he really that dangerous?
Only around humans.
(Paris)
The whole bloody container's
upside down.
It's all topsy-turvy.
[sighing]
Well, thank God
it's not a total loss.
Booze?
This is what
you have to drink?
I'm gonna need
a receipt for that,
for all of these.
This is
my personal stuff.
Mmm-hmm.
I don't suppose
this will help you at all.
Unfortunately it
is not permitted,
especially
while on hajj.
You do realize
there's no water,
don't you?
All deserts
have water.
It only waits
to be found.
I hope you're right.
All the more for me then.
[grunting]
[panting]
Motherfucker.
What the hell
are these?
Maratha war picks
from northern India.
Very rare.
And this?
That's a hunting
blow-dart pipe
from northern
Papua New Guinea.
That's very, very rare
since the tribe
is now extinct.
They couldn't hunt shit
with these things,
would be my guess.
What's the point anyway?
If the man is gone,
he's gone.
Why should he bother us?
Maybe to take
what you got.
Maybe to work your nerves.
Or maybe to just come back
and skull-fuck you
in your sleep.
He sounds like a charmer.
For you.
Let's just get...
Here we go.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Imam, if we're
looking for water,
we should leave soon,
before nightfall,
while it's cooler.
Ali.
Excuse me.
I think
you should see this.
3 suns?
Bloody hell.
So much for your nightfall.
So much
for my cocktail hour.
We take this
as a good sign.
A path,
direction from Allah.
Blue sun, blue water.
Ever wondered
why I'm an atheist?
It's a bit of a bad sign.
That's Riddick's direction.
I thought you found
his restraints over there,
towards sunset.
Right. Which means
he went towards sunrise.
Zeke.
Fully loaded clip.
Safety's on.
One shot
if you spot him, ok?
Don't tell me
you're going, too.
Yeah.
What happens if
Mr. Riddick spots us first?
[laughing]
There'll be no shots.
[Imam chanting in Arabic]
Allahu Akbar...
(Johns)
Quiet!
Shh, shh, shh.
[crackling]
[Hassan shouting]
7 stones
to keep the devil at bay.
You're on a trip
to New Mecca, right?
Once in every lifetime,
should there be a great hajj.
A great pilgrimage.
To get to know Allah better?
Yes, but to know yourself,
as well.
Yeah.
We are all on
the same hajj now.
[gasps]
[gun clicking]
Sorry.
So did you
see anything?
No Riddick.
Trees, and trees mean water.
You comfy up there?
It's amazing how you can do
without necessities of life,
provided you have
the little luxuries.
Just keep your
bloody eyes open.
I don't want that dog
sneaking up on my bloody ass.
Yes, well,
you dig the graves.
I'll hold the fort, old boy.
[gasps]
Christ!
He could probably get you
right here, right under
the jaw
and you'd never
even hear him coming,
'cause that's how good
Riddick is.
Tell me something,
did you run away
from your parents
or did they run away
from you?
[men speaking Arabic]
(Imam)
It's a communal graveyard,
perhaps like
the elephants of Earth.
[man speaking Arabic]
He asks what could have
killed so many great things.
Is this
whole planet dead?
Drink?
Probably shouldn't do this.
It dehydrates you
even more.
You're probably right.
Mmm.
You know, you could have
stayed back at the ship.
Probably should've.
If we don't find water,
you know what happens.
I wanted to get away.
I've never seen a captain
so ready to leave her ship.
I think we should
keep moving.
What did Owens mean
about not touching
the handle?
It's just between you and me,
Carolyn. I promise.
I'm not your captain.
During the landing,
when things were
at their worst,
Owens was at his best.
He's the one that
stopped the docking pilot
from dumping
the main cabin.
The passengers.
And the docking pilot being?
I guess I'm a little more glad
to be here than I thought.
[gun clicking]
Hassan. Suleiman.
Captain.
[speaking Arabic]
[whirring]
[man chattering in Arabic]
(Jack)
Is there anyone here?
[rattling]
There was water here.
Lights?
Lights on?
Ok.
[speaking Arabic]
They are saying
God is great.
Allahu Akbar. Yes.
This is the source
of the water.
No darkness.
No lights
because no darkness.
[whooping]
Hello, Mecca!
[clanging]
Tell me that was you
just now.
What are you
going on about?
He's been right here
helping me.
Back of the ship.
That noise.
You trying to tell me
that was someone else?
[inaudible]
No!
[gasps]
Oh, my God.
I thought I was the only one
who got out
of the crash alive.
[gun firing]
(Paris)
Christ!
It was just somebody else.
It was just somebody else
from the crash!
Crikey. I thought
it was him.
I thought it was Riddick.
No juice.
It looks like
it's been laid up for years.
We might be able
to adapt it to...
Shut up.
Sorry. I thought
I heard something.
Like what?
Gunshots.
[grunting]
[panting]
[gun firing]
[Zeke screaming]
Zeke!
[panting]
[grunting]
Piece of shit!
(Shazza)
What did you do to Zeke?
(Jack)
What did you do to him?
Just kill him.
Just somebody
goddamn kill him
before he...
So where's the body?
Well, do you want to tell me
about the sounds?
Look, you told Johns
you heard something.
That's fine.
You don't want to talk to me,
that's your choice,
but just so you know...
there's a debate right now
as to whether
we should leave
you here to die.
You mean
the whispers?
What whispers?
The ones telling me
to go for the sweet spot
just to the left
of the spine.
4th lumbar down,
the abdominal aorta.
It's a metallic taste,
human blood.
Copperish.
If you cut it
with peppermint schnapps,
it goes away...
Do you want to shock me
with the truth now?
All you people
are so scared of me.
Most days, I'd take that
as a compliment.
But it ain't me
you gotta worry about now.
Show me your eyes, Riddick.
You'd have to come
a lot closer for that.
Closer.
Where the hell
can I get eyes like that?
You gotta kill a few people.
Ok, I can do it.
Then you gotta
get sent to a slam,
where they tell you
you'll never see
daylight again.
You dig up a doctor
and you pay him
20 menthol Kools
to do a surgical shine job
on your eyeballs.
So you can see
who's sneaking up
on you in the dark?
Exactly.
Leave!
Leave.
Cute kid.
Did I kill
a few people?
Sure.
Did I kill Zeke?
No.
You got the wrong killer.
He's not in the hole.
We looked.
Look deeper.
(Johns)
Let me tell you
what I think happened.
I think he went off
on the guy,
buried him in the hills.
Now he's got you believing
there's something there.
Well, let's just be sure.
Look, murders aside,
Riddick belongs
in the asshole hall of fame.
He loves to jaw-jack
and loves to make you
feel afraid,
because that's all he has.
You're playing right into it.
Why try to
explain this to you?
You're a cop. For God's sake,
we've got to find his body.
Hey! I'll go.
Look, no one is going.
Stay here.
Look, being ballsy
with your life
doesn't change
what came before.
It's stupid.
What, do you think
I'm trying to
prove something?
Well, are you?
They're hollow.
[grunting]
[yells]
[screaming]
(Fry)
I'm in here!
I'm in here. I'm inside!
I thought
I heard something.
Please, can you hear me?
[Fry yelling]
Help me.
Give me your goddamn hand.
I heard you, Fry.
I heard you first.
Come on.
Fry, are you ok?
What's down there?
What is it?
Did you find Zeke?
(Paris)
You're all right.
Fry, are you ok?
Ok.
Fuck!
That was so fucking stupid.
I don't know
what the fuck is in there,
but whatever it is,
it got Zeke
and it nearly got me!
[yelling]
Get it off me!
Watch it. Watch your head.
Finally found something
worse than me, huh?
So here's the deal.
You work without chains,
without bit,
and without shivs.
You do what I say,
when I say it.
For what?
The honor of going back
to some asshole of a cell?
Fuck you.
The truth is
I'm tired of chasing you.
Are you saying
you'd cut me loose?
I'm thinking you
could have died
in the crash.
My recommendation: Do me.
Don't take the chance
that I'll get shiv-happy
on your wanna-be ass.
Ok.
Ghost me, mother-fucker.
That's what I'd do to you.
I want you
to remember this moment.
The way it could have gone
and didn't.
Here.
Take it easy.
Fuck you!
Do we have a deal?
I want you
to remember this moment.
Just one?
For now.
So, click your fingers,
and he's one of us now?
I didn't say that,
but at least this way,
I don't have to worry
about y'all, uh,
falling asleep
and not waking up.
So, can I talk
to him now?
(both)
No.
Blast.
Paris P. Ogilvie.
Antiquities dealer,
entrepreneur.
Richard B. Riddick.
Escaped convict,
murderer.
That's... That's
a particularly good Shiraz.
It's... It's
a lovely drop.
very expensive.
By all means,
please help yourself.
I mean, normally I can
appreciate antiques.
But this,
this is something else.
It'll work.
It's nothing
we can't repair,
so long as
the electrical adapts.
Well, it's not
a star-jumper.
(Riddick)
It doesn't need to be.
Take a 2-seater
like this back up
to the Sol-Track
shipping lanes.
Stick out her thumb,
bound to get picked up.
Ain't that right, captain?
Can I have
a little help here?
I got it.
Come on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Do me a favor.
Check these containers out
and, uh,
see what we can patch
these wings up with.
All right?
[squeaking]
[chuckling]
Mine!
Insha Allah!
All right, all right.
My turn.
Are you all right?
[speaking Arabic]
Ok.
[whirring]
[beeping]
And we are getting there.
So we've got enough power
for a sys-check,
but we'll still
need more cells.
How many are we
talking about?
Um.
Let's see,
we got a 90-gig draw.
The other ship
takes 20-gig cells.
That would be 5.
5 total to launch.
35 kilos each, huh?
Fuck.
Well, that's
pretty heavy.
Well, you know that old
sand cat out there?
Mmm-hmm.
I might be able
to get it going.
Yeah. Do it if you can,
but if you need a hand...
Where did Riddick go?
Let's go.
[rattling]
[Johns whistling]
You're missing the party.
Come on, boy.
[gasps]
You're missing the party.
Come on.
Oh, man.
[whirring]
[Imam speaking Arabic]
All praises be Allah,
for His many blessings to us.
What?
It's the winner
of the look-alike contest.
[beeping]
Who were these people anyway,
miners?
I don't know.
Looks like geologists.
You know, an advance team,
moves around
from rock to rock.
Nice of them
to leave so much stuff here.
Why'd they leave their ship?
[whirring]
It's not a ship,
it's a skiff.
And it's disposable, really.
It's more like an emergency
life raft, right?
Yeah, they probably had
a big drop ship
take them off planet.
These people didn't leave.
Come on.
Whoever got Zeke
got them.
They're all dead.
You don't really think
they left
with their clothes
on the hooks,
photos on the shelves.
Maybe they had weight limits.
You don't know.
I know you don't prep
your emergency ship
unless there's
a fucking emergency.
He's fucking right.
Watch your mouth.
He's just saying
what we're all thinking.
So what happened?
Where are they?
Has anyone seen
the little one? Ali?
Has anyone checked
the coring room?
[screeching]
[yelling]
Ali.
Come on.
[screaming]
[gasping]
[panting]
[gun firing]
Ali.
Slowly.
Jack, wait. Wait!
(Imam)
Ali.
[gasps]
Ali?
[yells]
[creatures screeching]
(Johns)
Imam?
[speaking Arabic]
(Riddick)
Other buildings
weren't secure,
so they ran here.
Heaviest doors.
Thought they'd
be safe inside,
but they forgot
to lock the cellar.
Here.
What, it's broken?
No. There's still
a few hits.
Actually, you asshole,
I'm trying to say
that I'm sorry.
Ok, let's board this place up
and get the hell out of here.
Whatever the fuck
those things were,
they seem to stick
to darkness.
So, if we stick to daylight,
we should be all right, ok?
Let's go.
22 years ago.
What?
These coring samples
are dated.
Last one's 22 years ago
this month.
Is there something special
about that, Carolyn?
I don't know.
There could be.
An eclipse.
You're not afraid
of the dark, are you?
So we gotta get
the power cells.
I've still gotta
check on the hull
and patch the wings.
Wait on the power cells.
What? Wait for what?
Until it's too dark
to get back?
We don't know
when it'll happen.
Let's not get overexcited.
Just get the fucking cells
here, Johns.
What... What
is the discussion?
Maybe I should tell you
how Riddick escaped.
(Fry)
He can pilot?
(Johns)
He hijacked
a prison transport,
made a hell of a good run
before I tracked his ass down.
Ok, ok,
maybe that's a good thing.
Maybe we can use him
to help us navigate
or something.
He also figured out
how to kill the pilot.
Look, you told me
we could trust him.
You said that
we had a deal, Johns.
Now, you may have noticed
that chains don't work
on this guy.
Now the only way
you people are truly safe
is if he believes
he's going free.
Let's just say
he stops believing...
You mean if he realizes
that we're going to royally
fuck him over.
I want you to listen
to me for a second.
If we bring the cells up
at the last possible minute
when the wings are ready
and we're ready to launch...
He hasn't harmed any of us.
He hasn't even lied to us.
Let's just stick to the deal.
He's a killer.
The law says
he has to do his bid.
There's nothing
I can do about that.
You hear me?
You're dancing
on razor blades here.
I'm not gonna
give him a chance
to grab another ship
or slash
another pilot's throat.
Not on my watch.
[groaning]
(Riddick)
Bad sign.
Shaking like that
in this heat.
I thought
I said no shivs... shivs.
This?
This is just a personal
grooming appliance.
Thanking you.
Looks like we're a few shy.
Power cells.
They're coming.
It's strange,
not doing a run-up
on the main drive yet.
Unless...
Unless he told you
the particulars
of my escape.
I got the quick
and ugly version.
Now you're worried
about a repeat of history.
It has entered
our minds.
I asked what you thought.
You scare me, Riddick.
That's what
you want to hear, isn't it?
Now can I just
get back to work?
I've been meaning
to catch up with you alone,
unrestrained.
Do you think...
You think Johns
is a do-right man?
You think I can
trust him to cut me loose?
Why? What did you hear?
Well,
guess if it were trickeration,
he'd just "X" me out, huh?
He'd kill me.
Then again,
I am worth
twice as much alive.
Oh, you didn't know that?
Your Johns ain't a cop.
He's got that
nickel-slick badge
and that blue uniform,
but he's just a merc.
And I'm just a payday.
That's why
he won't kill me, see?
The creed is greed.
Don't waste my time.
We're not gonna
turn on each other,
no matter how hard you try.
[clicking]
I don't know truly
what's gonna happen
when the lights
go out, Carolyn.
But I do know
once the dying starts,
this little
psycho-fuck family of ours
is gonna
rip itself apart.
Ever wonder why
Johns shakes like that?
Ask him.
Ask why your crew pal
had to scream so painfully
before he died.
So who are you,
really?
You're not a cop,
are you?
I never said I was a cop.
No, you didn't.
And you never said
you were a hype, either.
You have caffeine
in the morning,
I have a little morphine.
So what?
You got 2 mornings every day.
Wow, you were born lucky.
It's not a problem unless...
No, it becomes a problem
when you let
Owens die like that.
We have enough drugs here
to knock out
a fucking mule team.
Owens was already dead.
His brain just hadn't caught
on to the facts.
Is there anything else
I should know
about you, Johns?
You know, I...
I'm letting you
roll the dice on our lives.
It is not unreasonable...
Do you feel that?
That's my first
run-in with Riddick.
He went for the sweet spot
and missed.
They had to leave a piece
of the shiv in there, Carolyn,
and I can feel it
pressing against the cord.
So maybe the care and feeding
of my nerve endings
is my business.
It's just that you could've
done something,
and you didn't.
Yeah, well, look to thine
own ass first. Right, Carolyn?
(Hassan)
Captain! Captain!
[speaking Arabic]
I'm not
your fucking captain.
What are
my eyes seeing?
If we need anything
from the crash ship,
I suggest we kick on.
That sand cat's solar.
Where's Riddick?
Leave him.
He wouldn't wait for us.
Thought
we'd lost you.
Johns!
[grunting]
Hey! Where are you going?
I'm just gonna
get a couple things.
I'll only be a few minutes.
You wouldn't leave
without me, would you?
[chattering]
[muttering]
Shit.
[wind howling]
[creature wailing]
How many are there?
Beautiful.
Allah.
People,
just a suggestion.
Perhaps you should flee!
Let's go!
Come on, run!
Shit!
Come on!
[creatures screeching]
(Fry)
Get in!
Get down!
[grunts]
No.
Stay there! Stay down, Shazza!
Just stay down.
Come back here!
[gasping]
Shazza, stay down!
[screaming]
Please, I really think
we should go inside.
We have to be inside
to be able to close the door.
Come on, let's go!
Go, go, go.
[creatures wailing]
[rumbling]
What is it, Riddick?
What is it now?
Like I said,
it ain't me
you gotta worry about.
(Jack)
She should've stayed down.
If she only would have
stayed down, she'd be ok.
She wouldn't have died.
(Johns)
You remember the boneyard?
These just might
be the fuckers
that killed every
living thing on this planet.
(Jack)
What are we gonna do now?
(Paris)
Are these the only lights
we have? Is this everything?
There's a cutting torch
on the floor here somewhere.
I just can't find it.
(Imam)
Quiet, please, everyone.
[creatures wailing]
Why do they do that,
make that sound?
Perhaps it's the way
they see
with sound
reflecting back...
[rattling]
Could be a breach in the hull.
I don't know.
Come on, Johns.
You got the big gauge.
(Johns)
I'd rather piss glass.
Why don't you
go fucking check?
(Paris)
I'm not staying here anymore.
Where you going?
Hey! Hey!
(Fry)
Paris!
(Johns)
Sit him down.
You don't know
what's out there.
I know what's in here.
[grunting]
[speaking Arabic]
Hurry!
(Paris)
Now we're trapped in a much
smaller space. I hate this!
[yelling]
[gun firing]
[grunting]
[gasps]
Extremely bad timing.
Just don't run.
Riddick?
Don't stop burning.
Take this.
Take that.
Ok.
Hassan.
Where is Hassan?
[screeching]
[yells]
[gun firing]
[screaming]
Is it alive?
[sizzling]
It's like
the light is scalding it.
It hurts them.
Light actually
hurts them.
[gasping]
[creatures squealing]
Hassan.
We'll burn
a candle for him later.
Come on,
let's get out of here.
(Fry)
So we got one cutting torch,
we got 2 hand lights.
There's gotta be something
we can rip out
of the crash ship.
(Paris)
Spirits.
Anything over 45 proof
burns rather well.
How many bottles
you got?
I don't know. Maybe 10.
Ok, Johns,
you got some flares.
So, maybe we've got
enough light.
Enough for
fucking what?
We stick to the plan.
We get the 4 cells back
to the skiff,
we're off this rock.
Look, I hate to ruin
a beautiful theory
with an ugly fact,
but that sand cat is solar.
It won't run at night.
So we carry the cells.
We drag them,
whatever it takes.
You mean tonight, with all
those things still out there?
All right,
how long can this last?
A few hours? A day, tops?
I have the impression
from the model.
The 2 planets
were moving as one,
and there would be
a lasting darkness.
Mmm. These suns gotta
come up sometime.
And if these creatures
are phobic about light,
then we just sit tight,
and we let the sun come up.
I'm sure somebody else
said that
locked inside
that coring room.
We need to think
about everybody now,
especially the kid.
How scared will
he be in the dark?
Don't use him like that.
Like what?
As a smoke screen.
You deal with your own fear.
Why don't you shut
your fucking mouth
for 2 seconds
and let me come up
with a plan
that doesn't involve
mass suicide.
[creatures wailing]
I'm waiting.
How much you weigh, Johns?
What's it matter, Carolyn?
How much?
Around 79 kilos.
'Cause you're 79 kilos
of gutless white meat.
That's why
you can't think...
Is that fucking right?
Where are you going?
This solves nothing.
Ok.
They're afraid
of our light.
That means we don't have
to be so afraid of them.
And you are sure
you can get us there,
even in the dark?
No, I can't.
But he can.
[whispering]
Stay close.
Ok, wait. Wait!
Riddick.
Looks clear.
[screeching]
You said "clear."
I said it looks clear.
What's it look like now?
Looks clear.
I'll be running
about 10 paces ahead.
I want light on my back,
but not my eyes.
And check your cuts.
These bad boys
know our blood now.
Are we actually
going to do this?
We stay together,
we keep the light burning.
That's all we gotta do
to live through this thing.
Are you ready, Johns?
Yeah.
Look, we're just
wasting light here.
You give him
the cells and the ship
and he'll leave you
all out there to die.
He'll leave
all of you.
I don't get it, Johns.
What is so goddamn valuable
in your life
that you're worried
about losing?
Is there anything at all
besides your next spike?
Stay close.
Wait.
Jack!
[screeching]
[chattering]
[grunts]
Jack.
[gasps]
This can't be happening.
Paris, get back here!
Are you all right?
This can't be happening.
[creature hissing]
[gasps]
I was supposed
to die in France.
I never even saw France.
[creatures screeching]
Well, it's good
to see you're ok.
Do I even wanna know?
Are we getting close?
Can we pick up
the pace?
[speaking Arabic]
Wanna tell me
what the hell's going on?
We crossed our own tracks.
Why have we circled?
Are we lost?
Listen.
Do you even know
where we are?
Listen!
Canyon ahead. I circled once
to buy some time to think.
I think we should go now.
Oh, I don't know
about that.
That's death row
up there.
Especially
with the girl bleeding.
What?
What are you
talking about?
She's not cut.
Not her.
Her.
You've gotta be kidding me.
I... I just thought
it'd be better if people
took me for a guy.
I thought they'd
leave me alone
instead of always
messing with me.
[sobs]
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
Are you really bleeding?
You could've left me
at the ship, Fry.
That's why I didn't say
anything sooner.
They've been
nose-open for her
ever since we left.
In case you haven't noticed,
they go off blood.
Look, this is
not gonna work.
We're gonna have to go back.
What'd you say?
You're the one who got us
out here in the first place.
I was wrong. I admit it.
Ok, can we just get back
to the ship?
I don't know, Carolyn.
Nice breeze,
wide-open space.
I'm starting to enjoy
my fucking self.
What, are you high again?
Just listen to yourself,
Johns.
No, no, you're right, Carolyn.
What's to be afraid of?
My life is a steaming pile
of meaningless shit anyhow,
so I say mush on.
The canyon's only
a couple hundred meters,
after that it's skiff city.
So why don't you butch up,
stuff a cork in
this fucking kid,
and let's go.
She is the captain.
We should listen to her.
Listen to her?
When she was so willing
to sacrifice us all.
What's he
talking about?
This does not help us.
During the crash,
she tried to blow
the passenger cabin,
kill us in our sleep.
Shut your mouth.
We are fucking disposable.
We're just
walking ghosts to you.
Shut your fucking blowhole!
Fine. Fine!
You've made your point.
We'll all be scared.
Oh, Carolyn,
how much do you weigh now?
The verdict's in.
The light moves forward.
Ain't all of us
gonna make it.
Just realize that?
6 of us left.
If we can make it through
the canyon
and lose just one,
that'd be quite a feat, huh?
Not if I'm the one.
What if you're one of 5?
I'm listening.
What are they doing up there?
They're talking about
the canyon, I suppose.
How to get us through.
Battlefield doctors decide
who lives and dies,
it's called triage.
You kept calling it murder
when I did it.
Either way,
I figure it's something
you can grab onto.
Sacrifice play.
Hack up a body, leave it
at the start of the canyon
like a bucket of bait.
Trawl with it.
We got extra
cable on the sled.
We drag the body
40, 50 feet behind us.
Nice embellishment.
Well, I don't wanna feed 'em.
I just wanna keep 'em
off our scent.
So, which one
caught your eye?
No, no, don't look.
Christ. What the hell's
wrong with you?
Imam, slow down.
Just a little
more space between us
and them.
All right,
enough of this shit.
You do the girl, and I'll keep
the others off your back.
It's not too big a job
for you, is it?
I'm just wondering
if we don't need
a bigger piece of bait.
Like who?
Leave the sled!
Let's move!
[gun firing]
(Fry)
Let's go! Let's go!
[both grunting]
[creature hissing]
One rule.
Stay in the light.
[both grunting]
Remember that moment.
[groaning]
You should've never
taken the chains off, Johns.
You were
one brave fuck before.
You were really bad-ass.
The chains.
The gauge.
The badge.
I told you to ghost me.
[creatures wailing]
[grunting]
[gun clicking]
[yelling]
[crunching]
[screams]
Back to the ship, huh?
Just huddle together
until the lights burn out.
Get away from us.
Till you can't see
what's eating you.
That the big plan?
Where's Johns?
Which half?
We're gonna lose
everybody out here.
We should've stayed
at the ship.
He died fast.
If we have any choice
about it,
that's the way
we should all go out.
Don't you cry for Johns.
Don't you dare.
Blind spot.
Shall we pray together?
I have already prayed
with the others.
It is painless.
It's pointless.
Because you do not
believe in God
does not mean
God does not believe in you.
Think someone can spend
half of their life in a slam
with a horse bit
in their mouth
and not believe?
Think he could start out
in some liquor store trash bin
with an umbilical cord
wrapped around his neck
and not believe?
You got it all wrong,
holy man.
I absolutely believe
in God.
And I absolutely
hate the fucker.
He is with us, nonetheless.
2 of your boys
are already dead.
How much faith
do you have left, Father?
I only see one way.
That way.
It's the only way
off this rock.
Just keep the girl
between you.
What about the cells?
I'll take those.
Move.
Are you sure
you can keep up?
Move!
[creatures squealing]
[gasps]
Do not look up!
They're killing
each other.
(Riddick)
Move! Keep moving!
Keep moving!
[yelling]
[shouting in Arabic]
[screeching]
Riddick! Wait!
Riddick!
[yelling]
[screaming]
Get off her!
[yelling]
(Fry)
It's ok.
[grunting]
[creatures squealing]
He did not know
who he was fucking with.
[creatures wailing]
(Fry)
Pull him up.
Come on.
Stand up.
Get up. Come on.
Oh, no.
[Riddick laughing]
So, where the hell's
your God now?
[groaning]
Riddick!
Are we close?
Just tell me
that the settlement
is right there.
We can't make it.
[yelling in Arabic]
[creature hissing]
Hide here! Now!
Why is he
still out there?
He's not coming back,
is he?
[scratching]
[creature wailing]
[whirring]
That's the last
I could find.
[thudding]
Strong survival instinct.
I admire that
in a woman.
I promised them
that we would go back
with more light.
Did you?
Hmm.
What, are you afraid?
[laughing]
Me, afraid?
Come on, Riddick.
There's gotta be
some part of you
that wants to rejoin
the human race.
Truthfully,
I wouldn't know how.
Well, then just give me
more light for them.
I'll go back by myself.
Ok.
There you go.
Please just come with me.
I got a better idea.
Come with me.
You're fucking with me,
I know you are.
You know I am?
You don't know
anything about me.
I will leave you here.
Step inside.
I can't.
Sure you can.
Here, I'll make it easy
on you.
Take my hand.
Come on.
[crying]
Look, no one's
gonna blame you.
Save yourself, Carolyn.
Come on.
That's it.
Good girl.
[creature wailing]
[screaming]
You listen to me!
I am the captain
of this ship
and I am not leaving
anyone on this rock
with those
fucking things,
even if it means...
[grunting]
Get that thing
off my neck.
Shut up!
You'd die for them?
I would try for them.
You didn't answer me.
Yes, I would, Riddick.
I would.
I would die for them.
How interesting.
[thudding]
Never had a doubt.
Anyone not ready
for this?
There is my God,
Mr. Riddick.
[screeching]
[wailing]
Don't stop. Don't stop!
Come on! Move! Move!
You know the way!
On board!
Come on! Get on!
[wailing]
Carolyn.
Come.
Now.
[Riddick yelling]
Wait.
Riddick.
[gasps]
[panting]
Ok, hold onto me.
Hold onto me.
We're gonna get out of here.
I got you. Come on.
Come on, Riddick!
Get up! Get up!
Get up!
I said I'd die
for them, not you.
Let's move.
Come on. Come on.
All right.
[gasps]
Not for me.
Not for me!
With so much prayer
to make up for,
I scarcely know
where to begin.
I know where I'd start.
Riddick, what are you doing?
[clanging]
Can we just get the hell
out of here now?
We can't leave
[gasps]
without saying good night.
[creatures screeching]
A lot of questions,
whoever we run into.
Could even be a merc ship.
So, what the hell
do we tell them about you?
Tell 'em Riddick's dead.
He died somewhere
on that planet.
THE END
Movie & Captions Presented By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You've Liked & Enjoyed The Movie !!! "
Movie & Captioning Presented By :
KoushiK DaS
[ koushik-das@wassup.co.in ]
[ koushik@moviefan.com ]
" Hope You'll Like & Enjoy The Movie !!! "