Morning. Morning.
ELECТRONIC VOICE ON ТOY:
Can уou spell "Parakeet"?
Parakeet.
B-I-R-D.
Wrong. Try again. Wrong?
Wrong, Aunt Trish. Try again.
What's for breakfast?
My turn, huh? Mmm-hmm.
Darlin', Donna has locked
herself in our bathroom.
Would you get her the hell
out of there, please?
My favorite role,
the wicked stepmother.
Absolutely.
It's kind of chilly in
here this morning, huh?
Yeah. I’ll check it out.
You makin' breakfast?
Aunt Trish said it's my turn.
Shh with that
"Aunt Trish" stuff.
I have been begging you since you
got here not to call her that.
It's been a month already.
Bruce, old habits
die hard, you know.
Right, they do.
My mom always calls her Trish.
My grandma
always called her Trish.
But Aunt Pat hates it.
She thinks it's declasse.
Declasse?
Call her Pat, will you?
I’ll try. You wanna
help me make breakfast?
Yeah, I'd love to. Come on.
What does "declasse" mean?
Come on. I heard Mom and
Pop called last night.
CAROL ANNE: Yeah, they did.
PAT: Donna?
Donna? We're gonna be...
Just a second, Pat.
We're gonna be late again,
and you still have to use
my eyeliner, which I have.
Here. Thanks.
You look great.
Now remember, less is more.
Okay. We got eggs, sausage, bacon,
dill pickles. What’ll it be?
Toast'ems.
Oh, no! Not again.
I cook. You set the table.
Done.
A masterpiece.
A veritable Picasso.
No! He would have put
your nose over here.
Can I borrow this?
You look like an Eskimo.
Well, I'm a California person.
I'm not used to
wearing all this stuff.
Listen, surfer girl, the
week before you got here,
the temperature got above
zero for about six minutes.
If it's this cold inside,
you're gonna appreciate all those
things when you get outside.
Doesn't it ever
get warm in Chicago?
You are gonna regret that
remark come August, young lady.
August? I'm supposed
to go home before August.
If I had my way, I'd
keep you here forever.
Pat? What are you
gonna wear tonight?
Oh, I got...
Last year's salary.
It wasn't that expensive.
Ah! Oh, yeah?
And what are you
gonna wear, Dad?
My tux.
The one you wore
to your wedding?
Yeah, the one
I wore to my wedding.
You know, fashion's never
been your father's thing.
It's a year old, dear.
I think he looks handsome
in his wedding pictures.
There you are.
The voice of sanity.
I agree.
Handsome, but conservative.
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
you're on my side, remember?
A woman's entitled
to change her mind.
Uh, no, thanks.
We’ll take the next one.
Okay.
Who's driving me to work? Me.
Let's go.
AII aboard!
Thank you, my lady.
Vroom! Fasten your seat belts.
You better be careful, honey.
Remember what happened
to Narcissus.
Nar who?
Greek mythology.
He was a guy who loved looking at
his reflection so much in a pond,
he fell in and drowned.
Only a boy could be that clumsy.
You got that right. BRUCE: Hey!
What's wrong?
Well, every new building
has its problems.
But we’ll get those problems
before they get us, right? Huh?
Right?
Right.
Hold it, please!
Bye, honey.
Have a good day.
Thanks for the lift.
Bye, Dad.
Morning, there, Gene.
How you doing?
Morning, Bruce. Mornin'.
Morning, Mr. Gardner.
Morning, Bill.
What's with the heat, anyway?
I don't know.
I'm checkin' it now.
Probably got a thermo
on the fritz.
Well, get it fixed and have somebody
check out freight elevator 15.
Got a bit of a stutter in it.
15? Sure.
Morning.
Helen!
Wait up!
PAT: Helen! Helen!
Great! I don't have to go
to that creepy school today.
Oh, no.
Come on, we’ll cut
'em off at the pass.
MAN ON PA: Our 50 elevators...
Excuse me!
...will be carrying approximately...
DONNA: Watch out, please.
...12,000 passengers a day...
Carol Anne, come on, hurry up.
...swiftly and conveniently,
to our many shops, offices...
Hold on, guys, I'm coming!
Wait! Donna!
...condominiums,
and restaurants.
Come on!
DONNA: Come on!
MAN ОN PA: Welcome,
ladies and gentlemen,
to a glimpse of the future.
Oh, hi. How are you? MAN: Taxi!
Fine.
WOMAN: Oh, I'm so glad.
It's hotter than hell out here.
There they are!
Helen!
Look. There's that snot Donna
and her yucky little cousin.
They're late again.
Cool it, Marcie.
Hi, Donna.
Scott.
Sorry, Helen.
It's okay. Your turn on Monday.
You get two fun-filled weeks
to pilot the Enterprise.
Two weeks?
Two kids, two weeks,
just like me.
Come on, Mom.
We're gonna be late.
Okay.
Bye.
MAN ОN PA: In faсt, we like
to think we are a city.
А safe, efficient metropolis
that will take us
into the 21 st century.
BOY: No way.
GIRL 1: I like it.
GIRL 2: Ugly?
MAN ОN PA: Welcome,
ladies and gentlemen...
WOMAN: Uh, one minute.
Good morning.
Tell him I'm here.
Hi, Mary. Hi.
Did you forget to pay the heating bill?
It's freezing in here.
I know, it's strange.
It's warmer outside.
Why are they moving the Tods?
Takamitsu doesn't want them
intermingling with his work, darling.
Oh, yeah? Is he gonna
be responsible
for $26,000 worth of
postmodern neo-abstraction?
Well, you're the one
who gave him carte blanche.
Is everything set with
the caterers? Yes.
The brochures, the music?
Yes, yes.
Everything is set. Calm down,
go sit down and relax.
Nothing is gonna go wrong.
Okay.
Hey, not over there!
MAN 1: That's where
he told us to put it.
MAN 2: Take it easy.
MAN 3: Watch it!
It's okay. We got it.
No problem here.
Okay, whoo!
Nothing's gonna go wrong, huh?
KANE: Patricia.
Оh, Тrish.
Carol Anne.
So, are you coming
to my party tonight?
I don't think so.
How come?
She can't come
to our party tonight.
She has to stay upstairs
and take care of Carol Anne.
'Cause her mother's having
her own party tonight.
I heard her mother tell Mom.
It's my party, not ours.
Listen, mouth,
Pat's not my mother.
And if I wanted to come to
your brother's party, I could.
Hey, Bruce. You got a second?
Yeah, what's up, Nate?
Come here, let me
show you somethin'.
Okay.
AII right. Where we goin'?
What? Somebody broke
the mirror. Replace it.
Oh, not just this panel.
Every panel from the concourse
all the way up to the top.
Hey, Nathan.
Bill. Mr. Gardner.
You guys have to see this.
BRUCE: Ice.
Now, how the hell
could that happen?
Kind of hoped you'd
tell us, Mr. Gardner.
Sally, call the heating and
air conditioning contractor,
and tell Stan to
get down to my office
with a schematic for the
ventilation system. Pronto.
SALLY ON WALKY-TALKY:
Yеs, sir, Mr. Gardnеr.
How come you go to the
Seaton school for weirdos?
It's for smart kids,
not weirdos.
Yeah, that's why you
don't go there, mouth!
Martin!
There she is.
Yeah, okay.
Thank you, Mrs. Moyer.
Boo! Seen any ghosts lately?
Leave her alone.
You a cop or somethin'?
Hey, watch it,
you little asshole!
Scott! Shut the door!
You're so declasse.
Damn.
Carol Anne.
Yeah, I know.
The kids have
started teasing her.
I was hoping we could keep
her ghosts in my closet.
This doesn't make
my job any easier.
That's why you get
the big bucks, Doc.
Funny, Deborah.
You could call in an exorcist.
Funnier.
Donna! I'm really sorry you're
not comin' to the party.
I kind of hoped you...
You were.
Oh, Scott!
My knight in shining acne.
HELEN: Marcie, shut up
and leave them alone.
Maybe we could catch
a movie tomorrow night.
Maybe. Call me.
Excuse me. Thanks.
He's still panting.
You know, I wish Dusty would,
like, pant that for me, you know.
Jeff's constantly in heat.
I practically have to
muzzle him every night.
It's a real drag.
Maybe he could,
like, give Dusty ideas?
I don't know
if you could handle it.
Well, it'd be totally
radical to try.
Get a grip, girls.
This is the Second Piano
Concerto by Chopin.
I’ll bet all of
you probably think
this was written by some old geezer
who looked like Dr. Seaton, hmm?
Well, it wasn't.
In fact, Freddy
Chopin composed this
when he was only 19 years old.
And he'd already written a lot.
He'd been playing by ear and
making up tunes since he was six.
At eight, he had written his
first of several polonaises.
And at the ripe old age of 12,
he was asked to play
for the Czar of Russia.
Pretty scary, huh?
Even for an old-timer of 12.
But in a school like this,
where we're dealing
with gifted children
with emotional problems,
what we have to
do is open them up.
So, we try to make
them aware of the fact
that other famous child prodigies
shared similar problems.
It makes them comfortable to
know they're not that different.
These kids are about to find out that
Chopin was almost crippled by shyness
and used his music
to overcome it.
Excuse me, Dr. Seaton.
That little blonde girl
keeps staring at the
mirror as if she sees us.
Do you think she can?
MAN: No.
But you think she's
staring straight at you?
Yeah.
That seems to be one
of her dubious talents,
making people believe things.
Has she ever...
Let's talk in the hall.
SEATON: She's a very interesting
case, our Carol Anne.
Reasonably well-balanced,
extremely intelligent,
IQ well into the 150s,
and one hell of an imagination.
MAN: Most bright kids do.
True, but even
the brightest ones
allow adults to intimidate
them back to reality.
"Hey, Dad, there's a
purple cow in our yard."
"What, are you nuts?
Get out of here."
But Carol Anne's different than
most of our other little geniuses.
She seems to be able to
project her imagination,
convince others that the purple
cow in the yard is real.
Apparently, she actually
convinced an entire neighborhood
that it was haunted.
Yep, there's a talent.
You think she's able to create
some sort of mass hysteria?
No, not really. It's
more like mass hypnosis.
As I work with her... Try to work
with her, the child's impossible.
The more I'm convinced she actually might
be capable of inducing mass hypnosis.
Have you put her under?
Only once. It was terrifying.
MAN: For her? For both of us.
I started to experience
what she was seeing.
Tangina.
My God.
He found her.
Oh!
I'm sorry.
Stay, finish your tea.
I've got to go.
Mommy, where are you? I can't see you!
Where are you?
He's after me, Mommy!
He's after me! I'm scared!
Yes, I am running!
I'm running, Mommy!
I can't find you!
He's getting closer!
Who?
The man! The ugly man!
Shh, I've got you, Carol Anne.
You're safe. Shh.
You're in your room in Cuesta Verde.
You're safe.
Everything's calm.
Carol Anne,
tell me about
what's just happened.
The man wanted me to
lead him into the light.
It's so cold there.
I heard them talking.
He said it was my daddy's
fault 'cause of the houses,
the houses my daddy
built on their graves.
He said I had to lead
'em into the light.
Into the light!
Why do you have to
lead them, Carol Anne?
I was born in that house.
Robbie! Robbie!
The tree's eating Robbie!
Sleep.
I'm going to count
to three, Carol Anne.
And when I snap my
fingers, you will awaken.
You will not remember
any of this.
One, two, three...
How do you feel?
Okay.
Carol Anne, one word.
How do you feel
deep down inside?
One word.
I don't know.
Well, lonely, maybe.
Lonely, huh?
Sure, why not?
It gets lonely being away
from home, doesn't it?
Yeah. Aunt Tri... Pat.
Pat and Bruce and
Donna are real nice,
but I miss my mom and dad.
And even my brother.
That's very good.
What?
They way you made
me look in the mirror.
I didn't
make you look at anything.
That's what he meant.
Manipulation.
What were you looking
at that made me turn?
Nothing.
Carol Anne, you were
looking at something.
I don't wanna talk about it.
When you talk about things
that bother you, they go away.
No, if you talk about
things, they happen.
Who told you that?
Go away!
Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
WOMAN: What happened?
What broke the mirror?
A little demonstration
in mass hypnosis.
She made me believe I saw a coffee
mug fly off my desk into the mirror,
while giving you a
suggestion to smash it.
Beautiful sight, isn't it?
Mmm-hmm.
Did I ever tell you how to
make a little girl laugh?
I never did, huh?
Well, it takes
a lot of practice.
First thing you got to do
is tickle right
here under the ribs.
Hey, don't worry about that seven years'
bad luck stuff. That's old wives' tales.
I didn't break it.
Hey, I believe you. But
I’ll tell you a secret.
If that old nerd were my
doctor, I would have done it.
I didn't. He did.
Dr. Seaton?
No.
I don't wanna talk
about it, okay?
Okay.
See you, slugger.
How's Carol Anne?
I don't know.
How would you feel if some quack told
you you had supernatural powers?
Do you remember that guy that
was on all the talk shows?
What was his name? He was
from Israel or someplace.
He used to bend keys,
fix watches,
took Polaroids of himself in the dark.
Maybe Carol Anne...
Pat, please. Not you, too.
Give the kid a break,
will you, please?
First your crazy brother-in-law
uses her as a scapegoat
for those $250,000 collapsible
homes he built...
Oh, Steven didn't...
Steven and your sister have put
that poor thing through hell
with those weirdo psychics
and witch doctors.
"Weirdo psychics
and witch doctors?"
Come on!
Pat, darling,
you are the only sane person
in your family. Please.
Don't let that pompous-ass
shrink tell you
she's Carrie or Houdini
or some damn thing like that.
Look, Bruce,
nobody really knows
what happened there
this afternoon.
Maybe we shouldn't leave
the girls here alone tonight.
Yeah, well, maybe we should just
forget the opening altogether, huh?
Don't be stupid.
AII right, all right.
We're both bein' stupid.
You've got opening night jitters and
I got a building falling apart.
Exactly, and we really
needed my sister
pressuring us
into taking her kid
like we needed
a hole in the head.
I really don't mind a house
full of beautiful women.
The more the merrier.
Yeah, then hire us a maid.
Swedish? About 24?
Five feet two?
Talk about pressure.
Will you go get dressed?
What did I say? What did I say?
Hi, sweetie. Can I have
a good night kiss?
Ah.
Mmm.
AII set.
Have a good night's sleep.
Good night. Night.
Be right with you.
She's got the hots
for him. I'm serious.
No, I see her every single day.
Look for her at the beginning of the day.
I'm dead serious.
She follows him all the time.
Will you...
Yeah, well...
Will you do me a favor?
Hmm?
No ghost stories
tonight, all right?
Gotcha.
Yeah? Yeah.
Okay. Good night.
Bye.
My dad. I don't know
what he's talking about.
Not bad at all.
Forget it.
However, after the opening...
Sandy, I know it's gonna be a
great party, but I can't come.
No, I'm brat-sitting.
She's not even a relative.
Well, she's sort of a
relative, but not really.
Yeah, well, if Scott wants
to call me from the party,
I might talk to him.
Okay.
Bye.
What you doin'?
Eavesdroppin'.
Why don't you go
to Martin's party?
You know I can't.
I’ll cover for you.
They’ll never know.
If I get caught, we’ll
both get in trouble.
I can take the heat.
Listen, Carol Anne, I didn't mean
what I said to Sandy on the phone.
Oh, I don't mind being
"sort of a relative,"
as long as we're friends.
Good.
Takamitsu, there are some people
over here I'd like you to meet.
Hey, looks like the show
is a success, darling.
Pat, Bruce! Like the art.
Love the sushi.
It's nice to see you.
Excuse me. Pat, come here,
I gotta talk to you.
Hello, Mary.
Uh, Bruce, you tryin' to
save money on the heat here?
Oh, I wish that were the case.
You know, new equipment.
Tryin' to work out
the bugs and all that.
Good to see you.
Hey, you look great.
Anne Klein II.
Remember, less is more.
Hey, you look great.
Look, maybe I ought to
stay home with you tonight.
Just go already. I’ll be fine.
How come you're taking
your dad's passkey?
I'm gonna use the
emergency stairs
so nobody sees
me in the elevator.
You got Martin's number, right?
Yes. I won't stay long.
Have fun.
Okay.
Bye. Be good.
I will.
Hi. Hi.
What's the matter?
Is the stereo broken?
No, it's my parents.
I thought they weren't
going to be home.
Tell me about it. My
father's not feeling well,
and my mom says if she
can hear the party,
the party's over.
I thought you couldn't come.
Couldn't stay away
from hot Scott, huh?
Marcie, back to your cage.
It's feeding time.
Psst.
50 bucks, and she's history.
You're on.
Hi, Donna.
Scott.
DONNA: Hey, there,
hi, there, ho, there.
I can't believe I risked
getting into trouble for this.
I bet we could
find some trouble.
Your parents aren't home.
Yeah, sounds great. How
many bedrooms you got?
Shut up, Jeff.
Carol Anne's up there.
Is there something open
down in the galleria?
Uh, forget it.
Didn't bring my fake ID.
What?
That's where my stepmother's having a party.
I can't go down there.
You're a real killjoy
tonight, aren't you?
Hey, isn't there a pool
somewhere in this building?
It's locked at night.
But...
ELECTRONIC VOICE ON TOY:
G-O-R-I-L-L-A.
That is correct.
Can you spell "Pheasant"?
P-H...
KANE: Carol Anne.
Carol Anne.
KANE: We're back!
Leave me alone!
KANE: I've got you!
Let go of me!
KANE: You can't get away.
I've got you.
KANE: You can't get away!
You can't get away now.
You can't get away.
Carol Anne.
We need you.
Comе hеrе, Carol Annе.
Closer.
You can't get away.
I've got you!
TANGINA: Break the mirror.
Break the mirror.
KANE: I've got you!
No!
Hello?
Dr. Seaton?
Who is this?
Carol Anne needs your help.
Kane found her, and
it's all your fault.
Carol Anne, are
you on this line?
This is one of your
little pranks?
Hello?
Dr. Seaton?
Who was that? A pest.
Bruce Gardner, please,
on Michigan Avenue.
My little pest from the west,
playing her little tricks.
Thank you.
Ah! Jesus Christ!
What did that?
It's not a what, it's a who.
And I'm gonna nip that little
prank right in the bud.
Where are you going?
To that art gallery opening
we decided not to go to.
Put dinner on a low flame.
And don't forget the cilantro.
CAROL ANNE: Hello, Mrs. Moyer?
This is Carol Anne.
Is Donna there?
Are you sure?
Okay, and thank you.
Shh!
Okay, guys, there's
a camera in the hallway.
We’ll go in twos.
I’ll tell you when to go.
Run under the camera and
stand against the door.
You ready?
Go.
Ah!
Ready?
Go.
Get ready.
Let's go.
Hurry up! Ah!
Shh!
Watch the camera.
When the red light goes off,
then go into the locker rooms.
There's always suits
on the clothes lines.
Who needs a suit?
You do.
Come on.
KANE: Carol Anne.
Carol Anne.
Carol Anne!
Comе to mе, Carol Annе.
We need you.
Carol Anne. Carol Anne!
Carol Anne!
Sam, the stairway alarm
just went off on 70.
SAM ON WALKY-TALKY:
Anything on the monitor?
It looks like that camera
ain't workin' either.
Better go check it out.
Come on.
Okay, we knock on the door,
tell Burt we saw some
creepy guy walkin' on 67.
And as soon as he
leaves, we’ll go in.
He's coming out.
Where's he going?
He just got in the elevator.
Wait.
Okay, let's go. Okay.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna run the
videotape back two hours,
then I'm gonna change the
monitor from camera to VCR.
Then when he comes back in,
he’ll be watching two hours
of videotape on the monitor.
Okay, let's go.
Have you got a key for that?
Yeah. Why?
Beer.
I'm not gonna steal...
I got money.
No.
Yes.
No, I... Yes.
No. Yes.
No.
Yes?
KANE: Carol Anne.
I'm your friend, Carol Anne.
Carol Anne.
Carol Anne!
Carol Annе, Carol Annе.
Carol Anne.
Carol Anne!
We need you to lead us
into the light.
Carol Anne.
Lead us into the light.
Carol Anne!
Come on. Let's go.
Shh!
Come on.
Wanna see real panic?
JEFF: Pretty impressive.
Тhis is the police.
We have you surrounded.
Come out with your hands
up and your pants down.
Hello,
this is your camp director.
Jeff, quit pissing in the pool.
JEFF: Scott had a girl
and Donna was her name
ALL: Оh, Donna
Оh, Donna
JEFF: Can we try
that again, please?
Oh, shit.
KANE: Carol Anne.
Don't be afraid.
We won't harm you.
We love you.
You are the only angel
who can lead us into the light.
We would never hurt you.
Never.
Don't run away from me.
We need you, Carol Anne.
Lead us into the light.
Carol Anne.
Carol Anne!
Let go of me! Let go of me!
Help!
Carol Anne?
CAROL ANNE: Donna! Help!
Help me!
Donna! Quick!
Help me! Donna!
Help!
Holy shit.
Donna, help!
Carol Anne! Donna, help me!
Carol Anne!
Help me! Carol Anne!
Donna, help me!
DONNA: Carol Anne!
Please help me! Grab on to me!
Donna, pull!
SCOTT: Pull her! I got her!
I got her! Help me.
Carol Anne! SCOTT: Come on, pull!
Hold on!
Carol Anne.
SCOTT: Hold on to her!
Hold on to her!
Hold on to me!
Pull!
Pull! Hang on! Hold on!
Scott!
Oh!
Donna!
Smoking more now
and enjoying it less?
Thinking more
and enjoying it less.
Pat, there's
something wrong. I...
Tell me about it.
Takamitsu offended everyone
he talked to tonight.
Excuse me, Mr. Gardner.
Just got a call.
There's a bunch of kids
partying up in the pool
who claim they're guests
of your daughter.
Excuse me.
BRUCE: Okay,
so you all left the party together
and they let you in here,
went to the security room
to turn off the camera,
and then where did they go?
I don't know where
Scott and Donna went.
We didn't hurt anything. AII
we were doing was swimmin'.
Where was Carol Anne
through all this?
Not with us.
Okay. Thanks, guys. Take
the kids back to 56E.
I’ll have a talk with
the parents later.
Right, Mr. Gardner. Come on!
Great. My parents are going
to ground me till I'm 40.
Hey, it’ll give
you time to study.
You might pass something
besides Auto Shop this year.
Donna.
Scott?
They... Scott!
They... They got Donna.
Who? Who's got Donna?
They got Donna and...
What're you saying?
And they got Carol Anne.
Who's got Carol Anne?
They got 'em.
Who, damn it, who?
What happened?
He just came up
through the ice.
What ice?
The ice in the...
Pool.
She's gotten to you, too. It's
a suggestion, Mr. Gardner.
A posthypnotic suggestion.
They got 'em. They got Donna
and they got Carol Anne.
They got them both.
They've got 'em.
They got 'em.
CAROL ANNE: Aunt Trish,
help me!
Help!
Aunt Trish, help me, please!
Help me!
Carol Anne? Carol Anne!
CAROL ANNE: Aunt Trish, please!
Help me!
KANE: She's mine!
Bruce!
CAROL ANNE: Aunt Trish!
Please help me!
Help me!
Bruce! CAROL ANNE: Help me!
Hang on, I'm pullin'.
Hang on. I'm pullin'.
CAROL ANNE: Help me!
Aunt Trish, help!
PAT: Carol Anne, hold on!
I've got you.
I've got you, Carol Anne.
Hold on!
CAROL ANNE: Help!
CAROL ANNE: Help me!
PAT: Hold on, Carol Anne!
We've got you!
CAROL ANNE: Get me out of here!
Pull!
Grab hold of her! Grab hold of her!
I've got her.
I've got both of you! Pull!
Don't let go! Pull!
PAT: Hold on.
TANGINA: Get away!
That's not Carol Anne!
KANE: Damn you!
TANGINA: Stay back.
Stay back. He's got the
girls and now he wants you.
What are you talking about?
The preacher Kane.
He knows that as long
as there's someone
on this side that loves them,
you can get them back.
How did you know
that wasn't Carol Anne?
What surprised me, dear,
is that you didn't.
Who the hell are you?
I'm one of your
brother-in-law's
weirdo psychics.
Shh.
Carol Anne and Donna
are not in that room.
Well, some goddamn thing is.
Oh, yes.
Anger, rage,
evil, they are in that room.
Can you feel the cold?
He's devouring the heat,
the energy.
He's gathering his strength.
We must find the girls before
he becomes too strong.
If Donna and Carol Anne
aren't in that room,
then where are they?
The other side.
Before we can find the girls,
we must find out
where they entered.
Where did Dr. Rasputin
take Scott?
WOMAN: Excuse me, Dr. Seaton?
Excuse us.
Do your stuff.
Okay, Scott,
I want you to
look at the light.
Look at the light.
Security.
Burt, this is Gardner.
Could you get your
guys together, please?
My daughter and niece are
roaming the building somewhere,
and I'd like them found
as soon as possible, okay?
What?
Oh, damn it.
Yeah, okay.
Terrific.
First, the heating,
then the electrical problems.
Now the security monitors.
Oh, Bruce, this is really
happening, isn't it?
Depends on who
you want to believe.
Tweedledum or tweedle-dumber.
Scott,
you and Donna are
at the swimming pool.
SEATON: You're leaving.
Where are you going?
The security room.
We saw Carol Anne
on the monitor.
Which monitor?
She was in the garage.
The puddle.
Hands came out of the puddle!
They grabbed us, the hands!
Keep her away from me!
Shh.
What puddle?
What puddle, Scott?
The... In the garage.
In the garage.
In the garage!
They're between dimensions,
behind reflections,
behind mirrors,
stealing images.
Carol Anne.
Carol Anne!
CAROL ANNE: The light!
Тhe light!
It's so cold.
Тhe light, it's so cold!
Carol Anne,
listen to me.
Find your way
back to your room.
You must go back to your room.
He won't let me.
I'm so cold!
Find Donna and go back to your room.
Run, Carol Anne, run!
Enough. Stop this
stupid sideshow.
Oh, it's a great act.
Carol Anne creates the
fire and you feed it.
You made this happen.
You made her talk about him,
you made her remember him.
He was lost.
You brought him here.
Ludicrous.
It's your choice.
Tweedledum
or tweedle-dumber.
Tell us what to do.
Pray that Carol Anne
heard me and listens.
We must get up there
as fast as we can.
SEATON: This is
stupid, idiotic!
What's the matter
with you people?
Can't you see that
Carol Anne's behind this?
She's making us believe
this is happening.
It's... It's all a hypnotic...
It's about as stupid
and idiotic
as you hypnotizing that coffee
cup through the mirror.
That's good.
He’ll try to trick you.
He’ll try to separate you.
Don't let him.
Your love, your bond,
your caring for these two children,
is our most valuable weapon.
Let me take the chances.
What's that?
Some sort of mystical amulet?
A tool of your trade?
It was a gift.
From a good friend.
A powerful medicine man who
walked among the spirits
and returned.
There's power here.
I only pray it is enough.
Because Kane still
thinks he needs her.
He was insane when he lived,
and now, in death,
that insanity
has become the beast.
He wants Carol Anne now,
before she grows up.
Youth is a strong life force.
Innocence is pure life force.
We lose strength as we
lose our innocence.
You see, innocence is the only
gift we're given in life.
AII else must be fought for.
In that gift is purity.
In that purity
lies strength.
That's a lot of crap
that doesn't mean anything.
Shut up, Seaton.
Unlock it.
ELECTRONIC VOICE:
Can you spell "Gorilla"?
G-O...
Carol Anne?
...R-I-L-L-A.
That is correct.
Now try "Pheasant."
BRUCE: Look at the mirror.
P-H...
...E-A...
...S-A...
...N-T.
That is correct. Can
you spell "Parakeet"?
Carol Anne?
B-I-R-D.
Wrong. Try again.
TANGINA: Come back to
this side, Carol Anne.
Come through the mirror.
We want you to come join us.
We miss you.
You can come back through
the mirror, Carol Anne.
Please, Carol Anne, come
back through the mirror.
Come back to this side,
sweetie.
Carol Anne?
Come to me, Carol Anne.
Don't be frightened.
Don't be afraid, sweetie.
Come to us.
Won't you join us, Carol Anne?
Carol Anne?
Carol Anne, come here!
No!
KANE: Тangina!
Seaton, don't just stand there!
Get over here,
for Christ's sake!
I got you, baby.
It's okay, it's okay.
There you go.
Carol Anne! I got you.
You're all right.
Carol Anne! Where is she?
Carol Anne's drowning!
She's drowning!
Where? Where?
Carol Anne!
Donna... Carol Anne!
You're safe now.
Carol Anne!
Where? Carol Anne!
Where is she? Darlin'...
She's drowning!
What does it matter anymore?
Who the hell goddamn cares?
Baby...
Carol Anne! Take care of
her for a minute, please.
Carol Anne!
Shh. It's okay.
DONNA: Carol Anne's
drowning! She's drowning.
Baby, you've got to get
a hold of yourself.
I can't deal with this anymore.
Bruce, I love you and Donna.
That's our family.
Let's get out of here.
Let Dr. Seaton
deal with Carol Anne.
Baby, she's your niece.
I don't care.
I can't take these sick
little games anymore.
I never should have let Steven
and Diane send her to us.
Carol Anne! Bruce!
Bruce, please!
Carol Anne!
Bruce!
Dad! Dad!
Relax, Donna. Relax.
You're safe.
You're just having a bad dream.
We're all having a bad dream.
Where's my dad? I want my dad.
Lie here and relax
and I’ll go get your dad.
SEATON: Mr. Gardner?
Mrs. Gardner?
Hello?
Carol Anne.
DONNA: And they
thought it was her.
Carol Anne?
Carol Anne!
PAT: Bruce!
Bruce?
Carol Anne?
Carol Anne!
Bruce!
I saw her.
You think you saw her.
I saw her, damn it.
Your daughter's upstairs, a
shivering, emotional wreck.
Then you run out on me to chase
after that evil little brat again.
Don't you understand? Don't
you see what she's doing?
It's just like Dr. Seaton said.
Nothing Seaton said explains
what happened tonight.
Come on.
CAROL ANNE: The man!
The ugly man!
Remember what Tangina said.
Open!
Help! Help us!
Help us!
Oh, God!
BRUCE: Help!
PAT: Help!
Help!
TANGINA: Outside in!
PAT: Help! Help us!
Help! Help!
Outside in!
Tangina gave this to me.
She gave this to us!
She's trying to save us.
She's trying to
bring us through this!
It's a lie!
It's not true, any of this!
Oh, baby.
It's not true. You're a liar!
This... None of it's
true. You're a liar.
She's trying to
get us through, Pat.
She's trying to save our lives!
You're a liar.
Just hold on, Pat. Just hold on.
Just hold on, baby.
Just hold on.
No!
Who are you?
What do you want?
You!
Bruce!
It's not cold anymore.
She said we could do it!
She said we could beat 'em!
It's over, baby!
It's over, darlin'!
Oh, I want to believe that.
What? Oh, believe it!
Believe it!
It's finished and
we did it together.
Look at you.
You two are pitiful.
You know what? No, I don't wanna know.
I understand these things.
Anyway, everybody went home.
And it went fine. I locked up.
You two can read about it
tomorrow in the society columns.
Newlyweds.
Oh! Donna's been lookin' for you.
She called.
She and Carol Anne are
upstairs with that shrink,
what's-his-name
from the school.
Maybe, you ought to
talk to him, honey.
He's probably never met
anybody with a garage fetish.
Manana, y'all.
Oh, Mr. and Mrs. Stanley,
how are you tonight?
I, uh... I have been
doing some plumbing.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
What inconvenience?
We didn't have a problem.
Well, if there was a problem,
I'm really very sorry.
But the hot water's
gonna be on very soon.
Well, I had to say somethin'.
I mean, look at us.
I know. I didn't get much use
out of last year's salary, huh?
I think you look great wet.
Well, you can lie like
that anytime you want to.
I usually do.
I know.
I can't wait to get upstairs,
stretch out in bed and...
Act normal.
Oh, getting upstairs
sounds great.
What have you got in mind?
Packing up everything that
belongs to that little brat
and sending her
home to my sister.
It wasn't her fault.
KANE: Yеs, it is!
Oh, my God.
Outside in. What?
BRUCE: Damn it, that's it! Outside in.
That's what Tangina said.
He controls the inside,
but not the outside.
We can still get to him.
Come on!
Don't look down.
AII right, hold onto this.
No matter what
happens, don't let go.
Okay.
Fuckin' son of a bitch.
Bruce!
Carol Anne!
Go away, Pat!
He doesn't want them!
He only wants me!
You don't love me. You
don't want me here!
My parents
don't love me either.
They sent me away.
Kane loves me! Kane wants me!
Give me Tangina's necklace and you
can have Bruce and Donna back.
They're your family.
I’ll go with Kane.
Your mom and dad do love you!
They love you very much,
and I love you, too!
It's hard for me
to show it sometimes,
but I do love you.
No! Save your family!
They're the ones who mean
something to you, not me.
That's not true!
You are part of my family!
You and Donna
are like my children.
I love you, Carol Anne, and
I’ll do anything to prove that!
You've got to believe me!
No! Go away!
Carol Anne!
KANE: Go away!
Bruce?
Bruce!
Donna?
Carol Anne?
Tangina!
Bruce!
Oh, God!
Where are you, Kane?
Where have you taken my family?
I want them back!
Tangina said
you can't take them
as long as someone
here loves them.
I love them.
And I have this to protect me.
KANE: The necklace!
KANE: Give me the necklace.
No!
The necklace!
TANGINA: Kane!
Give her back her family.
You don't need them!
You don't need Carol Anne!
I can lead you into the light!
I have the knowledge
and the power!
No! Tangina, don't!
Tell me how to use the necklace,
so I can save all of you.
Thank you, Pat,
but this is the
way it has to be.
Say goodbye to
Carol Anne for me.
Tell her I’ll always love her,
and that her nightmare is over.
Tangina!
Tangina.
Tangina, wait!
Where are they?
BRUCE: Pat.
Bruce.
She did it.
She saved us.
© anoXmous
@ http://thepiratebay.sx/user/Zen_Bud