[Hissing]
What are you doing?
Not up here.
Get back down there.
Jesus. Morons.
Hey, do you think
you could speed it up?
I got another load of sheets
coming from county hospital
in one hour.
You! I'm talking to you!
You, come on!
Jesus.
Hey, move it! Move it!
Yes, sir.
[Groaning]
Good morning,
Mrs. Frawley.
Good morning, dear.
You're looking good
today, Sherry.
Hi.
Good morning.
You ought to watch
yourself, dear.
Let me help you with that.
Take care of number one.
Don't let the
pressure get to you.
What do you think
about the new girl?
Lin sue?
Oh, she's O.K.
If you're not careful,
you'll end up like me.
I'll keep that in mind.
I wonder where the
boss found her.
I wish she'd go back to whatever
sewer she crawled out of.
[Man] Let's get that
second boiler working.
Do you understand me?
Watch that pressure Gauge!
What are you doing?
[Man]
I'm fixing the boiler!
Coming through!
Back off now.
We're coming through.
Steady now.
You better tighten the belts.
What?
The belts... tighten
them with clamps
so we can get a bigger load in.
[Man]
Now, steady.
[Man] Come on. We're way behind.
Ow!
What are you doing?
Watch out!
Aah! Aah!
[Man]
Stanner!
Sherry!
Sir! Yes, sir!
Ow!
[Man] Holy shit,
what was that about?
Goddamn sons of bitches.
These two idiots
almost killed Sherry.
Damn it!
Jeez, I'm sorry.
Are you O.K.?
Moron! You could have
killed her!
It's nothing. I'm O.K.
Sherry.
You may need stitches.
No.
I'm O.K. Now.
Mr. Gartley, sir.
Do something.
Get 'em back to work!
Work 'em like
there's no tomorrow.
You boys with that
piece-of-shit icebox,
get it out of here! Move!
Deliver on time,
or you'll lose our business.
Move it!
[Gartley]
Stanner,
time's a-wasting.
Ticktock, ticktock, tick.
Ha ha ha!
It's alright, George.
You know, life's a bitch,
then you die.
Get 'em back to work.
Yes, sir.
We're behind schedule
as it is, goddamn it.
I got deadlines, George.
Never enough time
around here... never.
You heard the man!
Let's go! Move it!
Don't look at me!
You, get back to work.
Come on, get back to work.
Get back to work.
Come on, work with me, ladies.
Good morning.
Good morning, officer.
How are you?
Have a nice day.
Shit... shit... shit.
Got the address?
[Shifts gear]
It's 1216 lake,
or is it 1218?
It's over there.
[Tires screech]
[Honks horn]
Oh, fuck!
What did I miss?
Shit!
[Tires screech]
Hey!
Idiot, what was that?
Hey, what was that?
Hey, idiot, I'm talking to you.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
No, I'm talking
to the other idiot.
What was that? What? Can't you drive?
Move the truck.
Sir, we're just
delivering an icebox.
I don't give a fuck if you're
delivering a pizza to the pope.
You looking
for trouble, asshole?
That's officer asshole to you.
Move the truck, and
then we'll talk, O.K.?
O.K.
[Man] Sorry about
your hand, Sherry.
[Man] Boss, you're not kidding.
This icebox is hot.
Alright, Mr. gates,
it's time to talk.
It seems that your driver's
license has expired.
Watch out!
Shit! Uh!
[Gates] Oh, I'm really
sorry, officer.
Get this goddamn thing
off of me!
Shit!
Numbnuts! Jesus!
Ow!
Are you O.K.?
Frawley! There's no
time for daydreaming.
I've got another load coming in.
Now, both of you, back to work!
Ow!
Bring the ratchet.
Oh!
Aah!
Oh, god!
Aah! Oh, god! Help me!
Help me, please!
My god!
Please, help!
No!
Aah!
Hell's bells, Adelle!
Shut it off! Aah!
I don't know how!
Aah!
It won't shut off!
Shut it off!
No!
Aah!
[Gartley]
Goddamn!
Uh! Uh!
Get back!
Mrs. Frawley!
Oh, my god!
Jesus! Oh, god!
Aah!
Out of my way!
Oh!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
[Panting]
Oh, Frawley!
You stupid old bitch!
Always getting in the way.
Goddamn it! Goddamn it!
Goddamn it!
Now, what's that for?
Reckless driving, illegal parking,
blocking of a public street.
Come on, pal.
Give me a break.
What do you want? Insulting an
officer?
Or being an arrogant,
ignorant son of a bitch?
Since when is that a crime?
Help me, boss!
Aw, you broke my damn watch.
I'm all pooped out.
[Police radio] Officer
Hunton, come in.
Damn it.
You're a moron.
Officer Hunton, come in.
Officer Hunton.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, Molly, what have you got?
Good morning, Johnny.
How's your day so far?
Oh, my day's peachy,
Molly. What's up?
We've got a death
at the blue ribbon laundry.
It's a bad one.
Sheriff Hughes got called
away to an urgent meeting.
[Delivery man]
I need some help.
What's going on, and how
many did you take this time?
Right side up.
Come on.
Alright, Molly, I'm on the way.
Thanks a lot.
[Crying]
Oh, my god!
No!
Sherry, it's O.K.
Get away from me!
Her worries are over.
Holy shit.
Hello.
Is Mr. Gartley here?
Mr. Gartley
is unavailable.
I'm Stanner.
I'm the foreman.
Mr. Stanner,
I'm, uh...
I'm officer Hunton.
Can you show me what happened, Mr.
Stanner?
Do I have to?
Yeah, you have to.
She's down there. I... I
can't look at it again.
It makes me sick.
She's down there. I can't. I'm sorry.
I can't look at it.
Yeah, right, you can't look.
Run a loose shop, cut
corners... what do you expect?
People get hurt
or killed, right?
And then he can't look.
No, he can't look at it.
Oh.
[Gulp]
Hell of a mess, huh, Johnny?
You know, me and my old camera
were doing this long before
you even came to this town.
Never did get used to it.
[Hunton]
Yeah, right.
Oh.
[Gulp]
Um... pictureman...
Make sure I get
some copies of that.
Like always.
Have I ever let you down?
Yes.
Oh!
Oh.
Shit.
I feel like it's all my fault.
I just wasn't strong enough.
I tried to help her.
O.K., it's alright.
It's alright. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
It's O.K.
Ex... excuse me.
I know how you feel.
Have you seen that machine?
It makes me sick to my stomach.
These will help.
Mrs. Frawley
used to take 'em.
Oh, keep the bottle.
Thank you.
Annette Gillian.
Uh, John Hunton.
How do you do?
Hi.
Oh, poor Mrs. Frawley.
Oh, god!
[Crying]
[Car approaching]
Hey, what's going on?
Nothing, Johnny. We're here
to settle a safety issue.
What's the emergency, anyway?
There's been an accident
with a speed ironer.
Let's go in.
[Engine starts]
[Man] If the safety
features on this machine
meet state and local standards,
then you may resume operation.
[Hughes] Yes, thank
you, judge bishop.
O.K., Martin,
start her up.
Stand clear, boys.
Let's start with the safety bar.
When I lift this up,
the machine
should stop. Uh!
Put it down, it should start.
What is your conclusion,
Mr. Martin?
Well, I'll tell you,
judge bishop,
the safety bar seems to
be working fine.
Then I declare that this was
a case of accidental death.
This inquest is closed.
[Man] I know what you
think of my work.
Look, there's no such thing
as empirical truth in
theoretical parapsychology.
If you saw Seraphims and Cherubims
falling out of the sky,
singing hallelujah,
you wouldn't believe it.
You want proof, right?
Oh, you'll never change.
You haven't eaten much.
Why? You're not
feeling well?
There was an accident today...
The worst one I've ever seen.
Messy?
[Groan]
So how long is it now
you've been chasing corpses?
14 years.
Oh, man, 14 years.
You know, you need to spend
some more time with the living.
Ha ha ha!
Jesus, you sound
just like Sandy.
Sandra really loved you.
Whatever.
Uh, I just... I just
got to hang in there
and get my 20 years in
so I can retire
and get the fuck
out of this town
before I turn completely numb.
Yeah, well, uh,
you know, Johnny,
you really do
need to get a life.
I got a life.
What I need is a beer.
Come over if you want.
I don't suppose you know anything
about industrial laundries?
You know, I used to work
in an industrial laundry
when I was an undergraduate
at Berkeley.
Get out of here.
I did, man.
Really?
Yeah, sure.
Well, look,
do you know that machine
they call the speed ironer?
Oh, man, yeah. It's
called a mangle.
A mangler?
Mangle.
That's the one.
It mangled a woman
this morning...
Oh!
Over at Mr. Gartley's
blue ribbon laundry.
It...
There was hardly
anything left of her.
No way. No way, man. That can't happen.
You've got a safety bar.
If someone's feeding the machine
and get their hand underneath,
the bar snaps up and turns
the damn thing off.
Well, that's how I remember it.
Yeah, it's got a safety bar,
but it happened anyhow.
Oh, god. Man,
what a way to go.
I hated that machine.
Oh, fuck me!
I can't do this!
Well, it is what it is, right?
Johnny, don't.
I mean, you can't...
What? A woman's dead, mark.
It folded her like a sheet.
They carried her out
in a basket.
Whose ass is on the line?
Nobody's ass is on the line.
Gartley owns judge bishop.
Judge bishop owns the sheriff.
I mean, it's all dirty.
It's all dirty.
Yeah, but why are you
fighting it, man?
I mean, wake up.
I've been in this
town long enough
to know that there's some
strange shit going on.
It's always been
narrow-minded and corrupt.
Hell, they used to burn witches
just 10 miles from here.
This puritanical ethic
is still hanging over...
Look, don't start
with the sprout-breath
political mystical
bullshit, mark.
I'm not in the mood
this evening. Thank you.
The woman's dead,
and that machine
is running right now,
alright, like nothing
happened... business as usual...
6 miles from here...
6 miles.
Oh, whatever.
What are you supposed to do
about it, huh?
Have a beer.
That's what I'll do.
You're going to take the sins
of the world on your shoulders?
I mean, you have to
live a little.
You can't just take
everything in.
Yeah, you're right.
Come on.
Just live a little.
You're going to get a
goddamn nervous breakdown.
I'm worried about you.
You want some yogurt?
I got some yogurt.
Is it whole-wheat?
Granola? I got granola.
Yeah, is it organic?
No.
Are you O.K.?
I wish I could go home.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Move away!
Move away from there!
Do something!
Aah! Aah! Aah!
[Gartley]
Shut that damn thing off!
Inside.
[Crying]
[Door slams]
I'm sorry.
Chaos abounds, my dear.
You'd better get used to it.
Like I told you,
there's no free lunch,
no sirree, Bob, not in this lifetime.
Uh-uh.
Still, life must be better
here than on the streets, hmm?
Here, the predators are few.
The benefits are many, hmm?
Hmm? Mmm.
For I am a generous man.
I...Am a man
of my word.
Now, then...
Why don't you go in there
and freshen up for
your uncle Billy?
Go on now. Draw your bath.
Skedaddle.
O.K.
Shoo.
Shoo. Shoo fly.
[Gartley clearing phlegm
from throat]
[Pop]
Would you like to come in here
and keep me company?
Uh!
Lin sue, Lin sue,
you sweet
young woman.
I'll tell you,
the one thing worse than
the devil within...
Is the devil without.
[Telephone rings]
Save my seat.
[Ring]
Hello.
Yeah.
What?
What? What is it?
There's been another
accident at the laundry.
A steam hose broke loose
on that machine,
burned three women.
One of them is at the hospital.
Hey, can I come with?
[Hunton]
Hey, Pascal,
how you liking public service?
Oh, you know.
Can you tell me what room
Annette Gillian is in, please?
Room 132.
Thank you.
[Moaning]
Annette!
Remember me?
I'm officer Hunton.
Oh, I thought
you were the doctor.
Well, go get a goddamn doctor!
Wh-where is he?
Where's the doctor?
Oh, god!
What took you so long?
That's it. Take
it easy, Annette.
Take it easy.
Annette, Annette, take it easy.
This is going to take
the pain away, huh?
No pain allowed
in this hospital.
There we go.
That's it.
What do you want?
I'm officer Hunton. I'm here to
ask Annette about the accident.
I don't think she's up to it.
I don't think I want
a second opinion.
Annette, what happened?
We was running sheets,
and the ironer just blew up.
Mr. Stanner said
there must have been
a surge from the
boiler or something.
I don't know.
Has anything like this
ever happened before?
It all started happening
when Sherry cut her hand
on one of the clamps.
On the mangler?
Yeah.
Was there blood?
Well, I mean, did she
bleed on the mangler?
There was blood everywhere,
and then later...
Mrs. Frawley...
I think she's had enough.
She needs some rest.
Annette, thank you very much.
Sherry Ouelette...
Mr. Gartley's niece,
just out of high school.
Mr. Gartley watches
her like a hawk...
Has all her life.
Won't let her have
any boyfriends
or go on dates.
You know, it's almost
like that machine
had tasted blood
and found it liked it.
Don't women get funny
ideas sometimes?
Thank you very much, Annette.
You'll be fine.
Bye-bye. Thanks.
Come on.
Annette, I just wanted to ask...
Mark...
Come.
Safety inspector barely had time
to check the machine. They
railroaded that inquest through.
Said, "everything's O.K.
Put those kids back to work."
And then, kapoom...
Three women burned,
one kid's disfigured for life.
Now, that's against
the law in my book.
So, what do you think?
Mark?
What?
What's going on in that
jelly-roll head of yours?
Nothing.
Right. That would
be a first.
Barry!
Was that
Mrs. Ellenshaw?
Yeah.
Take it easy, man.
Right. You, too.
Hey, man...
Why don't you come on over?
There's something important
I want to show you.
Six-pack of beer?
No. Come on.
Are you hungry?
No. I'm going
to bed.
Come on. It's really
important. Come on.
Ah, what the fuck.
Cold beer? Is that
all I'm good for?
You know how to hurt a guy. That's
no way to treat your brother-in-law.
I suppose you'd follow me to the
ends of the earth if I asked.
That's right. I'd follow you
to the ends of the earth.
[Door closes]
Come.
Frazer's golden bough...
Check it out. You might
learn something.
"Frazer's golden bough...
"The definitive work on magic
and the occult."
Check it out.
Have you considered
the possibility
that the machine
might be haunted?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, yes, mark. Yes.
That's the first thing
that popped into my mind.
No. Play along
with me.
Maybe "haunted"
is not a good word.
Let's say
"possessed."
Possessed.
Yeah. Yeah, man.
Possessed?
Yeah! Possessed.
By the parrot demon, right?
O.K., O.K.
We're going to grab that
bad boy by the throat,
shove a couple cloves of garlic up
his butt, that'll be the end, right?
Man, this stuff's for real.
I'm serious about this.
Check it out. This
stuff is for real.
If you just look in here, I
mean, everything is pointing...
Mark...
Check it out.
First there is god,
then there's country,
and then there's the law.
Alright?
The rest is bullshit.
O.K.?
This is bullshit, mark.
Reality, bullshit.
Bullshit, reality.
This is bullshit.
[Bang]
Aah! Help!
Whoa! I got you.
I got you.
Aah!
[Stanner] It's O.K.
It's O.K. Shh.
It's alright.
You'll be O.K.
Bring her up here, George.
But, Mr. Gartley,
she's hurt, sir.
Mr. Gartley, she needs a doctor.
She needs help.
My finger!
Bring her to me.
[Mark]
All spells can be reduced
to simple common denominators.
European spells mention
the hand of glory,
and that's real trouble.
Spells need a catalyst...
Either herbal or human or both.
The answer is in that book.
Just go for it!
Carry on. Come on. Come on.
Read on, man.
Belladonna, hand of glory...
Blood of a virgin!
Now, that's supernatural.
Supernatural is a really
misleading word, man.
Witches, demons, spirits...
All part of nature.
Like, um... O.K.
A demon is a kind of
energy like electricity...
Or fire.
Sometimes it gets out of
control, and people get hurt.
Thought you might
want something to eat.
Thank you.
The most powerful spells
always incorporate belladonna.
What is belladonna?
The hand of glory,
or deadly nightshade.
The plant?
Yeah.
And the most common ingredient
in all these spells
is, uh, the blood of a virgin.
You must admit the way
Annette describes Sherry,
she sounds the type.
[Laughing]
Oh, come on. Come on.
Go with the flow.
Think of the possibilities.
Could be fun, huh?
Alright. Hey, mark,
tell you what.
I'll run right on over
to Sherry Ouelette's house, O.K.?
Knock on the door.
"Sherry? Hi.
"My name is officer John Hunton.
"I'm with the police
department here,
"and I am investigating
"a laundry machine
"with a bad case
of demon possession,
"and I need to examine you
to determine whether or
not you're a virgin."
Right?
Mmm... mm-hmm.
Huh?
Mark, I could
just see my report.
They would tar and feather me
and run me out of
this town on a rail.
You think so?
Ha ha ha!
That sounds like a whole
lot of fun to me.
Oh, yeah!
Oh, boy!
Why don't we just go
there and talk to her?
Do it for me.
Come on.
[Police radio] Johnny? Johnny,
I got that info for you.
Yeah, Molly, go ahead.
Let's see.
Sherry Ouelette...
Parents died in a car
accident on 7-10-83.
William Gartley
is her legal guardian.
Is that it?
Yeah. Who's picking up
the tab for my overtime?
Take it out of my pension.
You're the best, Molly.
You got that right.
Oh, man.
So who's going to
pop the ques...
You don't say a word.
Right? Not a word.
Far out.
Gothic.
[Rings doorbell]
[Sherry]
Who is it?
Sherry? Hi.
It's officer John Hunton
from the police department.
Hi. Remember me?
Mm-hmm.
I'm here to ask you
some questions
about the accidents that have been
happening at the blue ribbon laundry.
Are you a policeman, too?
No. I'm
a theoretical...
Um, this is mark Jackson.
He's a student...
An observer.
Then I guess it's alright.
Thank you.
It won't take long.
Is your uncle here?
I'm alone.
Oh, hey, look at those.
They're beautiful.
Look at that little face!
Are they yours?
No, they're not really mine.
My uncle says they'll
be mine someday.
[Johnny]
Um...
Sherry, I'm really sorry to
disturb you at a time like this.
I just have
a few questions. O.K.?
O.K.
[Johnny]
It's O.K.?
Alright.
Now, Annette said that you
cut your hand on a clamp.
How did that happen?
Getting out of the
way of that icebox.
These two guys lost control.
I guess it...
It hit the feed belt.
On the mangler?
Yeah. Then it bounce off
and almost hit me.
Did this icebox
hit the safety bar?
I think it did.
There were bright
sparks everywhere.
What? Sparks like
a wire had been cut?
I saw a big flash like
lightning or something.
That's it, then.
There it is.
[Sherry crying]
I really loved
Mrs. Frawley.
Shh.
She was like a mother to me.
I tried to help her.
I pulled as hard as I could,
but I was too weak.
It's O.K.
Sherry, Sherry.
Sherry. Sherry, you're a
very brave young woman.
O.K.?
Sherry...
I just want...
Mark!
The icebox hit the safety bar.
That's it.
Thank you very much.
Bye-bye. It was
a short circuit.
That's all there is to it.
Let's go.
Mark! Mark!
Sherry, are you a virgin?
Excuse me?
What is this?
Just get out!
Just get the hell out!
What did I tell you?
I'm right!
I'm right.
She's definitely a virgin.
Jesus Christ! I can't
believe you did that...
Talk to a little girl like that.
God! Have fun? Shit,
I hope you had fun.
It's not a question of fun.
I know I'm right.
Shut up, goddamn it.
No more about virgins.
I'm right.
What are you... some
kind of pervert?
Doesn't matter
whether I'm a pervert...
[Siren]
What is this?
Oh, Christ.
What is going on
at Mrs. Smith's house?
Whatever it is, you stay
the hell out of it.
[Shouting]
There he is!
Stop him!
Mark!
Stay in the car.
Alright.
You stay in the car!
Alright!
Hey, Steele, what is this?
Hi, Johnny. It's really bad.
The boy's suffocated.
It's Barry Ellenshaw.
Been missing all day.
Mrs. Smith just learned
10 minutes ago.
I found that icebox when
I got here this morning.
He never got in any trouble.
He'd no more play in a
refrigerator than...
Alright.
The boy's dog was barking
outside the icebox.
That's why I had a look inside.
Oh, Barry.
Suffocated, poor kid.
He's been missing
since 11:00 this morning.
Come on, honey.
Rest in peace, Barry.
Barry Ellenshaw...
Oh, man.
Poor kid.
Hell of a shame, huh, Johnny?
Get him out of here.
[Man]
Stand back there.
[Dog whimpers]
Stand back.
No! No!
No! No,
Maryanne. No!
[Mrs. ellenshaw] Barry!
Stop! Oh, my baby!
Stay there.
No!
[Mrs. ellenshaw]
Barry!
It's not my fault.
I had nothing to do with it.
It was here when I
came home from work.
What?
It's not yours?
No. I don't know
where it came from.
[Mark]
Hey, Johnny,
come have a look at this.
Wait a minute.
What? This is
the son of a bitch
that almost hit Sherry?
After it hit the mangler.
[Thud]
Transference.
It's transference of evil.
[Johnny]
Oh, bullshit.
Evil. Bullshit.
[Bird cooing]
Easy.
What?
Shit.
It's alright.
It's alright, little baby.
It's alright, baby.
Come on.
Aah!
Jeez!
Let go!
Aah! Aah!
[Johnny]
Are you alright?
Yeah. I think so.
Oh, shit.
Jesus Christ.
A hammer...
You got a hammer?
It's in the garage.
[Johnny]
Ow!
Miserable piece of dogfuck!
Goddamn you!
Oh, oh, god.
God!
Jesus Christ!
Lend not thy sight to idols
nor make gods of thyself!
Nice work, Johnny.
I always knew you had it in you.
Where did you learn
to do magic tricks?
That was the first ghost
I have ever seen.
Thank you, my boy.
Just when you thought
you'd seen it all,
life bites you in the ass.
See you later, Johnny.
I'll be waiting for you.
What the fuck was that?
Jesus Christ.
[Hammer hits icebox]
Get that thing out of my sight!
And burn it...
Then bury it.
Drive a fucking stake
through its heart.
[Tire screeching]
[Mark] So, what
do you think now?
[Johnny] Do you
know any priests?
No, man. Do you?
No. I knew
a rabbi one time.
They'd think we're nuts.
We are nuts.
It's our play, Johnny.
It's up to us.
Why don't we just
get some dynamite
and blow the shit
out of the pig?
Brute force isn't
the answer, man.
I mean, a demon may be trapped
in that piece of machinery.
There's a chance it could get out,
it would love to get out, to kill
oh, good. Good.
Virgin blood.
That's the key. It's got to be.
The trouble is
there's many different
kinds of demons.
I don't know what
we're dealing with.
It could be in the
cycle of bubastis,
pan, Dionysius.
You following me?
No... but go on.
I have to isolate
the exact cause.
We have to make sure
that we use the right ritual
because the rites of exorcism...
I don't know if you understand
but that's really heavy stuff.
That's like controlled
nuclear fission.
We make one mistake,
that's it. We're dead.
We're destroyed.
If you ask me, this is just an
act of random possession.
It's got to be.
Hey, mark.
I got to do some thinking.
Oh, Johnny,
listen, man,
don't worry, O.K.?
I'm with you 100%,
man, O.K.?
Alright, mark.
That's a relief, man.
100%.
That's real reassuring.
[Engine starts]
Belladonna,
demonic possessions...
Oh, I'm having fun.
I'm with you, man.
There are stranger things
in heaven and earth,
John Hunton, than are dreamt of
in your philosophy.
Ha ha ha!
Hey, Johnny, what do you know?
Not much, Tyrone.
Just going to the morgue.
Whew. Not much.
[Man] Barry, it's
been a hell of a day.
Fix you up in the morning.
He's a brave kid, he put up a hell of
a fight, broke his arm in six places.
It was suffocation, right?
Mr. Hunton,
we've been expecting you.
You've come to see
Mrs. Frawley.
She was a real challenge.
I had practically
nothing to go on.
Hardly recognized the
parts... the ones that came in.
You look at her now.
I think I did a pretty good job, considering
the raw materials I had to work with.
Can you keep a secret? I had
to fill up her body with...
I hate secrets.
O.K.
O.K., yeah.
You need to be alone.
You've come to do some thinking.
I'll be in my office.
Okay, I'll call you
if I need anything.
She's headed to the
cemetery in the morning.
Until then, she's all yours.
Great, thank you.
Oh, her personal possessions.
They're right here.
Great.
That's all they brought in.
Cherry tomato?
No, thank you.
Bye-bye, now.
Oh, Jesus.
You won't mind, will you?
Jesus, I got to get a life.
Boo.
Got you.
Very funny.
She looks... pretty good,
don't she?
Oh, yeah.
She looks great.
Johnny. Johnny!
You want to come downstairs?
We'll finish off that gin game
we started three years ago.
I've still got a drop
of that Irish whiskey.
You know, I get the feeling
you don't like me anymore.
No.
It's my job I don't
like anymore.
Oh.
Well, it doesn't
matter much anyway.
You won't have to look at my ugly
mug around here much longer.
Why?
Don't tell me you're moving
out of this hellhole.
Oh, something like that.
The doc says I'm going fast.
I'm being
eaten up... inside.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Ah, don't be.
We all have to go sometime.
Johnny, you and I...
We share the same ghosts.
To forgive is divine...
Especially if you can
forgive yourself.
Oh, did you get pictures
of that icebox?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I'm off down
to the darkroom now.
What was that?
What?
That ghost.
We live in strange
times, Johnny...
Very strange times.
I'll have the photos
ready later tonight.
Come on by.
I'll be waiting for you.
You know, I'm 50 points
up on you in that game.
I've got an Ace up my
sleeve I'm dying to play.
You know where to find me. You're
going to lose to an old hack like me.
Shit.
Fuck.
Aah!
What are you doing?
Where the hell is Gartley?
He's out of town.
Yeah, right.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Come back here!
Hey, stop! Goddamn it,
he's out of town.
Get your hands off of me,
you lying sack of shit.
You want to go downtown?
[Gartley]
Boys! Boys!
All right. Knock it off.
Get out, George.
I'll deal with you later.
Come in, Mr. Hunton.
I've been expecting you.
So sorry I missed you earlier.
[Door slams]
You know, Stanner tells me
you're quite the detective.
A regular Sherlock Holmes
of the dead, hmm?
Why don't you
shut that thing down
before somebody else gets hurt?
What, am I going to
have to shut you down?
Tsk tsk tsk. I wouldn't
do that if I were you.
Mmm. Bad career move.
Are you threatening me?
Is that a threat?
Go on, threaten me. I'll shove
them crutches up your moldy ass.
Ha ha ha!
I like that. Threaten?
Uh-huh.
No, no, no. Threaten
is far too... kind a word.
This goddamn machine
tried to kill me!
Breaking and entering
is a serious crime, officer.
Perhaps I should have
you arrested, hmm?
Yeah. O.K. O.K. Hey. Yeah.
Have me arrested.
I'm going to shut you down,
you sick son of a bitch.
I will not have you
tamper with my affairs.
I'll have you suspended!
Hey, all your powerful
friends and all your money
don't mean shit to me, Gartley.
Ha ha ha!
My power has nothing
to do with money.
Power is energy.
Power is motivation.
Power is what
holds things together
when they would
rather fly apart.
It's a complex world
out there, sporty.
Many things you
do not understand.
But... understand this.
There's a little bit
of me in that machine
and a little bit of it in me.
We are the lifeblood
of this town.
Gartley, what are you
talking about?
We all have to make sacrifices.
You're right.
Everything has its price.
Yeah. Yes, it does.
Well, do come again. This
has been delightful.
And, uh... drive
carefully, won't you?
Fuck you!
What?
That s.O.B.
He thinks he's going to
shut down our machine.
Ha ha ha!
Well, sir, I've been thinking...
Maybe it should be shut down.
Yeah... how long you
worked here, George?
15 years.
15 years. Well, you're...
You're practically
part of our little family,
then, aren't you, hmm?
I assume you'll be helping
us run this town, hmm?
I've known that machine
since I was a little boy.
My daddy bought it.
Best business decision
he ever made, I'll tell you.
My god,
Mr. Gartley, sir.
That... that machine
killed your daughter.
Look what it's done to you.
Yeah. Sacrifices, George.
We all have to make them.
Hell, boy. You could say that machine
out there made me what I am.
Mr. Gartley, if you're not
going to deal with it,
then... maybe
I should.
Oh, don't be a fool, George.
Don't throw away
a bright future here.
I'm worried.
Worried, uh...
It's been troubling me.
Well, George, let your own
conscience be your guide.
[Bang]
[Dialing]
Good evening, Martha.
Bill. Bill Gartley.
Sorry to call so late.
Let me speak to the good
sheriff, won't you, Martha?
Thank you.
Evening, Hughes.
Now listen,
I'm having a little problem
with one of the boys.
Yeah. That's the fellow.
That's right.
Now you deal with him.
O.K, nighty-night.
Fuck him.
[Hughes]
John?
What?
Take some time off.
There's no case here, son.
Take a vacation!
O.K., Mr. Gartley.
Now you're suspended,
officer Hunton.
Hey, how much is he
paying you, Hughes?
O.K., pal.
You're terminated!
And kiss that
pension good-bye.
How are we feeling,
my dear, hmm?
Strange.
I'm getting sick.
Are you ready for bed?
Yes.
No! No.
There's something
I must show you.
Come.
Must be here somewhere.
Aha!
Yeah.
My baby daughter's
death certificate.
Her passport to hell.
She was only 16.
Hmm. Well, survival of the
fittest is the way of things.
I mean, surely, my child,
you must have noticed
how Rikers valley
is so ideally perfect, hmm?
There's something I want to show you.
Just a moment here.
Ah! Ah.
This... is my contract...
My deal...
With the beast...
The beast in the machine.
What's happening to me?
My child,
there's a little piece
of you in the mangler
and the essence of it in you.
You're one of us now.
My signature.
See? Hmm?
Oh. Understand now?
Do we?
Hmm?
See?
Welcome to the club.
Oh, precious.
Fuck!
I've been studying, man.
Virgin's blood.
Definitely virgin's
blood. It's got to be.
Now, look.
A little holy water,
a smidgen of Eucharist...
That ought to do it.
We'll read some leviticus.
Christian white magic.
Listen, I'll tell you the truth.
I was really worried about that
hand of glory... belladonna.
That's black Ju Ju.
Strong magic.
Hey, mark?
I looked down this son
of a bitch's throat.
Holy water ain't going to do it.
Yeah, well, a demon conjured up
in conjunction with
the hand of glory can...
I mean, that could eat a stack
of bibles for breakfast,
but we don't have to
worry about that.
Thank god.
Alright.
You know, I hope you're right.
I know I'm right.
I don't.
We got to go talk to somebody.
Come on.
Hold up!
Damn it, hold up!
I don't know about this, George.
What the hell took you so long?
I'm sorry.
Are you sure we're doing
the right thing?
Yeah. Now, don't start
arguing with me now.
Go over there, cut all power,
and pull the breakers.
I'll start on the feeder.
[Sherry crying]
Sherry?
What are you doing here?
I have to see my uncle.
That's not a good idea.
He's very upset.
I can't work here anymore.
The police came and asked me questions.
I got to speak to him.
Police. That figures.
Just don't go up there.
He's busy.
Lin sue's with him, isn't she?
Sherry, go on home now.
I have to talk to him.
Oh, oh, oh. I'm caught!
Mr. Stanner!
I'm caught!
Help! Aah!
[Sherry]
Mr. Stanner!
The fuses! Jesus!
Aah!
Mr. Stanner!
Aah! Turn it off!
Oh, god!
Aah!
Mr. Gartley!
Aah! Oh, help me!
Help me! Oh, please!
Please!
Do something!
Do something?
I'll do something.
I'll dance, that's what I'll do.
I'll do a little
dance for you, Sherry.
Oh, god. Mr. Gartley!
A little jig.
I need your help now.
We're running out
of time. Come on.
[Sherry screaming]
Please! Please! Aah!
Uncle bill, please!
Move like there's no tomorrow.
We're on the clock.
Aah!
Do it! Do it!
I can't!
Do it now!
Oh, Christ.
I can't, George.
Do it! Aah! Do it!
Do it! Do it!
Christ!
Do it!
[Gartley]
Very good, children.
Come here to your uncle bill.
Sherry! Sherry!
Oh! Oh!
[Engine starts]
I used to have all...
The time... in the world.
Damn her. Damn her.
Oh! Oh!
Hey, hey. Hey, man, where
the hell we going?
We're going to
go talk to an old man.
Oh, no. What
the hell was this?
No. Take me back.
[Pictureman] Joey, stop! Don't argue.
Just do it.
I was just drinking
my tea, and...
[Coughing]
You're alright.
You'll be O.K.
You're going to be alright.
Thanks for coming and
visiting me, Johnny.
You made an old man very happy.
Just breathe.
Downstairs...
In my office.
Present for you.
You have to exorcise your demon.
Don't let it possess your soul.
Oh.
Shit!
[Teapot whistling]
Oh, man.
[Mark] It wasn't your fault.
I was driving the car.
Accidents happen.
People make mistakes,
but they carry on.
Johnny.
Take a look at this.
This is my present.
"Maryanne Gartley, daughter
of William Gartley,
"was killed at the blue
ribbon laundry yesterday
"when she apparently fell
into the new speed ironer.
"She died on her birthday.
She was
16 years old."
There's Maryanne.
"Sarah Krandel was
reported missing yesterday
"when she failed to show up
at her 16th
birthday party."
That's Sarah.
"Suzanne bishop still missing.
"Suzanne bishop, daughter
of judge bishop,
"was reported missing yesterday.
She was last seen at her
16th birthday party."
"Lois Hughes...
Chatterton..."
Well, these are all
the rich people,
the old money...
The people who want nothing,
need nothing more...
Power. Power.
What is this?
Wait a minute.
Everything has its price.
The price of power...
Gartley said something about...
No, Gartley said...
That we all have to
make sacrifices.
Human sacrifices.
Sherry?
Jesus Christ.
[Ring]
Hi. Sherry? This is
officer Hunton.
Mr. Stanner's dead.
I just went to see my uncle.
Um, listen, Sherry.
I want you to stay inside.
Want you to stay in
the house. Lock the doors.
You'll be safe as long
as you stay inside.
What's going on?
How old are you,
Sherry? 16?
Really?
Stay inside. Do what
I told you, O.K.?
I'll explain everything
when I get there.
I'll be there as
soon as I can, O.K.?
The mangler got the foreman.
Today's her birthday.
She's 16.
It's her birthday?
We're running out of time.
[Gasp]
Happy birthday, my child.
Surprised to see
your uncle bill?
What do you want?
Why, you, of course.
Leave me alone.
Ohh...
Aren't you going to
blow out your candles?
Come on.
Go ahead, Sherry.
Make a wish.
I wish you were dead.
Ha ha!
No doubt about it,
girl's got true Gartley spirit.
Ugh!
[Moaning]
Oh, what a waste,
but then,
we all...
Have to make sacrifices.
Heh heh!
[Gartley]
Now, now, now.
Uh, no!
Oh, I'm so sorry
it had to be you,
but I must not be selfish
when I make my decision,
so it's time
to turn in your dance card.
Heh heh!
I do hope you'll accept
my apology,
but I must choose
between you and me,
and of course, I choose...
Me.
Come, darling.
We're running out of time.
Stop! Stop!
We haven't got time, mark.
I have to rehearse.
We haven't got time!
Alright. Fuck!
O.K., I'm going to read.
I might read from the Latin,
or the English,
but I'm going to read anyway.
O.K.,
this... this...
[Thunder]
This, my friend, is holy water.
Holy water. Fine.
When I give you
the signal, you take this,
and you sprinkle it
on the machine,
and you say, "in the name
of the father,
"the son, and the holy ghost,
get thee from this place.
Thou art unclean."
This is the host.
You break the host.
You put it on the machine.
You repeat the incantation.
Oh! The hand of glory...
We don't have to
worry about that.
Get in the car.
Get in the goddamn car!
You always do this to me!
Wait up!
[Gartley wheezing]
God of all machines,
god that meshes good and evil...
Accept this blood of my blood,
because I am signing off...
Payment in full!
See you later, Sherry.
Sherry!
No!
Piss off!
Get on out.
You've got no right!
You have no right!
[Sherry]
Oh...
You have no right!
Agh!
No right!
No right! No...
[Groaning]
Aaah!
God!
Goddamn you!
[Machine grinding]
You miserable piece of dogfuck!
How dare you!
[Mark screaming]
No!
So this is the price of power?
This is the price of power?
Ugh! No!
No! No! No!
Here's the truth,
Gartley. It's done.
[Gartley gasping]
[Crunching]
No! No!
Lin sue.
[Screaming]
Aaah!
Lin sue!
O.K.?
Stay with me.
[Sobbing]
Trespassers!
Lin sue!
My Lin sue!
Off the clock.
Out of time?
[Screaming]
[Speaking Latin]
Aah!
[Mark reading in Latin]
My god, who art in hell,
cursed be thy name...
[Groaning]
Why, you lying
son of a b-b-b...
Fuck you.
[Mark reading in Latin]
Stay back! Stay back!
What do you want me to do?
Help me.
When I point to you,
take the holy water,
sprinkle it in the machine,
and you say, "Gloria in
excelsis spiritu omnibus."
Omnibus.
O.K., alright.
Gloria in excelsis
spiritu sancto omnibus.
Then you put the host in.
Repeat the incantation.
[Reading in Latin]
Gloria in excelsis
spiritu sancto omnibus.
[Reading in Latin]
In the host!
In the name of the father,
the son, and the holy ghost,
get thee from this place!
Thou art unclean!
[Mark reading in Latin]
Holy shit! This ain't working!
Shit.
[Reading in Latin]
Our father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done
on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses...
Trespass against us,
and lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil,
for thine is
the power, the goodness
and the glory forever...
...sight to idols
nor make gods of thyself,
for the land will vomit you up
for defiling it
as it vomited up
nations before thee!
Amen, goddamn it!
[Rumbling]
[Machine stopping]
[Electrical crackling]
[Sherry sobbing]
Look! Yeah!
We did it!
Huh? We did it!
We did it.
Ha ha ha!
It's dead!
Uh...
Oh, man. Now I know where you
get your flaky stomach from.
Let me take those I don't do
drugs, but I need this.
You O.K.?
Really?
What's in this?
I don't know.
They're antacids.
I got them
from Mrs. Frawley.
Belladonna?
You got these
from Mrs. Frawley?
The hand of glory?
I think we may be fucked.
Ah!
Oh, god!
Oh, what's this?
Aah!
Oh, shit!
Oh. Oh.
Oh, god!
No! Agh!
[John]
Run! Run!
Mark!
Out! Get out! Out!
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Do you know a way out of here?
No! No!
[Pounding on door]
Run! Run! Go!
We're fucked!
Oh, god!
No! Ohh!
No! John!
Mark!
It... it won't open!
[Hissing]
If I walk through the valley of the
shadow of death, I fear no evil.
Aaah!
John! No!
Johnny!
Mark!
No! Mark!
[Crash]
No!
[Shrieking]
Come here!
What are you doing?
Let go! Save yourself!
It wants me!
Over my dead body!
Are you crazy?
No, I'm a policeman.
But it wants me!
It wants me!
Sherry!
[Screaming]
Jump!
[Rumbling]
[Machine hissing]
Leave her alone, goddamn you!
Leave her alone!
[Groaning]
No! Goddamn you!
Leave her alone!
[Machine gurgling]
Sherry's alright.
She's lost a lot of blood,
but she'll recover.
Thank god.
Mind telling me what happened?
Yeah, I do mind.
Can I go see her?
No.
She's resting.
Maybe tomorrow.
O.K. Thank you,
doctor.
Thank you.
Tomorrow.
[Wind chimes tinkling]
Morning, officer.
Have a nice day.
[Pictureman]
Dearest Johnny,
in this envelope
you'll find vital information
that may save your life.
The old-timers in Rikers valley
had a saying...
Beware of people
with missing parts.
There's a piece
of each of them in the demon
and a dose of the demon
in each of them.
"Faithfully yours,
J.J.J. Pictureman."
[Woman] Herb! I've got a big load
of sheets coming within the hour!
Now, get a move on!
Come on, ladies!
Move it up!
There's never enough
time around here!
I'm not running a
charity here, herb!
Tell them to get their
lazy asses in gear!
[John]
Sherry?
You heard the boss!
Keep moving!
[Engine starts]