(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
All right. You can go on in.
You know the way?
- Yes, I do. Thank you.
- Okay.
Oh, I'm sorry I'm late.
I had car trouble again.
Would you believe it?
I'll think up something
for you tonight.
- Are you sure?
- Oh, yeah. Bye-bye.
(LOCK CLICKS)
(KISSES)
(SIGHS)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, Bill,
you left the lights on again.
The dishes are on the table.
The refrigerator door
was open.
I hate this.
The whole place is a mess.
Hi, Mom.
- (SIGHS) Hi.
- Hi.
Any calls?
No, your boyfriend did not call.
- You sure?
- If he called, I'd tell you.
Phone didn't ring.
How would you hear it if it did
with the radio going like this?
I've got good ears.
What's that all about?
Hmm?
(SIGHS)
I don't know.
What do you mean
you don't know?
What's your school counselor
want to see me for?
I don't know, Mom.
Your halo's burning.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Are you in trouble?
Look, Mom, believe me,
this is meaningless, okay?
Just don't worry about it.
Throw it away.
You going to come in soon?
Yeah. I'm just gonna finish up.
I'll be in in a minute.
(CLOCK TICKING)
- (SLAPS)
- (GRUNTS)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SCREAMING)
- (GASPING)
- Mom!
- No, no, no! Oh, Billy!
- What? What?
Billy.
He's in the room!
Look around the room!
- Who? Who?
- Look around the room!
Come here. Come here.
Mommy!
(CRYING)
Mommy, what happened?
They're locked.
I'll look in the bathroom.
- Mommy!
- What happened?
Look in the closet!
- (WAILS)
- Mommy.
- (GIRLS CRYING)
- It's empty.
- Look around the house!
- Mommy. Mommy.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Mom.
Mom, there's nobody here.
Call the police.
Mom, there's no one
in the house.
The front door's locked.
No one came through the garage.
You didn't see anybody?
You didn't hear anyone?
No. Only when you screamed.
Mom, you must have had
a bad dream, that's all.
- Come on, stop crying.
- (CRYING CONTINUES)
Kim. Kimmy,
you've had bad dreams.
Now Mommy's had one.
That's all.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
I'm sorry.
(CRYING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(MUSIC PLAYING SOFTLY)
- You okay, Mom?
- Sure.
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(DOOR CREAKS)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(RATTLES)
(SNIFFING)
(SHIVERING)
(RATTLING)
(LAMP SHATTERS)
(SHRIEKS)
(SCREAMS)
Bill! Ohh!
- There's something coming!
- What?
- We've got to get out of the house.
- What are you talking about?
We've got to get the kids!
Come on!
- BILL: Come on.
- Come on, baby.
Come on, baby.
No. No. No.
We've got to get out of the house.
- BILL: What's happening?
- It's in my room.
- What?
- Come on. Come on.
Get her in the car.
(PANTING)
Here.
- Oh, my God. The keys.
- I'll get 'em.
No! Stay right here.
I'll be right back.
Come on. Stop crying.
Stop crying.
- Come on.
- Why are we leaving?
Don't worry about it. We're just
going somewhere, all right?
KIM:
But we don't want to leave.
I'm scared.
BILLY:
Shh. Shh.
Shit. Shit.
Shit.
(RATTLING)
(GIRLS CRYING)
Did you hear it?
Hear what?
I'll get some pillows
and some blankets.
Billy, honey, can you help me?
Ohh.
Good.
There. Now, let's see.
We'll put Julie over there
and Kim and Mom here.
And, oh, gosh, looks like
it's the floor for you, Bill.
MAN: Honey,
you coming to bed or not?
In a minute, George.
Here, here, here.
Here, we'll take care of this.
- What--
- You just--
Listen. Thank you.
(LAUGHS)
Nonsense.
What are good friends
for anyway, huh?
Don't you be bashful,
because there's plenty of food
in the refrigerator
for the morning, and...
- Yeah.
- You know. (LAUGHS)
Get a good night's sleep.
- You too.
- All right. Night.
(DOOR CLOSES)
You all right?
Yeah, if you're all right.
I don't understand, Mom.
I don't understand what's going on.
I don't either.
Are you all right?
Just go to sleep, okay?
Just go to sleep.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(CARTOONS PLAYING ON TV)
I've gotta find Captain Raccoon.
I have a telegram for him.
- (DISHES CLINKING)
- (WATER RUNNING)
- Good morning!
- (GASPS)
Carla, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to scare you.
- Hi. How you doing?
- How'd you sleep?
- Great.
- Good.
We helped ourselves to cereal,
and I made coffee.
- Great. Love some.
- You want some? Okay.
- Did you make it strong?
- Of course I made it strong.
- What do you think?
- Good girl.
- You want some milk and sugar?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Hey, this is pretty nice,
being served in my own home.
What about George and I?
We keep you awake last night
with all our snoring and stuff?
- No.
- The kids?
- Anybody fall off the couch?
- (GIGGLING)
No. They're used to it.
So...
what happened to you guys
last night, anyway?
Nothing.
- You want one or two?
- Two, please. Thank you.
Beautiful day outside,
isn't it?
Nothing like good old Southern
California for lots of sunshine.
- I was raped.
- Yeah--
- What?
- I was raped.
Oh, Carla, baby.
I'm so sorry.
I had no idea.
Oh, my God.
I feel all rotten inside.
Ohh. How did it happen?
Um...
well, I was alone
in my room, and...
something grabbed me
and smothered me.
Did you call the police?
- No.
- Why?
- There was no reason to.
- What do you mean?
There was nobody there.
Well, did you check the doors,
the windows?
Yeah, I checked everything.
Everything was locked.
There was nobody there.
Oh, Carla. Oh, wait a minute.
I-- honey, I don't
really understand this.
You were attacked,
or you weren't?
It happened.
And when he--
when it was over,
he vanished
like he'd never been there.
You see?
There's no answer, is there?
I mean, I have flipped out.
I've flipped out twice, Cindy.
Carla, are you taking drugs?
No. I'm not on drugs.
Well, then I think
you need to see a doctor.
(SIGHS)
Carla, you're one of
the most stable people I know,
and you are
definitely not insane,
but when men
who aren't actually there
come into your room
and have intercourse with you,
then it is time for you to see
a good psychiatrist.
- I can't afford it.
- Oh, yes, you can.
Betty Rivers, I happen
to know she goes over
to the walk-in clinic
at the university,
and payment is
whatever you can afford.
- I hate the thought of it.
- Oh, I know you do.
- I'm not crazy.
- Of course you're not crazy.
I'm not crazy.
You're not crazy.
- You may be crazy.
- (LAUGHS)
GEORGE: Cindy,
where's that coffee?
He's crazy.
- Sure.
- (LAUGHS)
Listen,
just think about it, huh?
You be honest with yourself,
and everything'll be okay.
- I'll think about it.
- Good girl.
GEORGE:
I'd like a cup of coffee, honey.
Coming, George.
Looky here. Nice and hot,
just like you love it.
GEORGE:
Is she going to leave today?
CINDY: Well, honey, I haven't had
a chance to talk to her about that yet.
GEORGE:
God damn it, Cindy.
You told me you were going
to tell her this morning.
CINDY: I am going to tell her, you see,
but first of all, I have to tell you.
What's happened to her
is just a terrible thing.
GEORGE: What happened?
She probably got her butt evicted
'cause she didn't pay
the damn rent.
We're not going
to lend her any money.
CINDY: George, don't raise
your voice to me like that.
GEORGE: I can raise my voice
in my own home if I want to.
CINDY: I just don't want
to hurt her feelings.
She's been through
enough already as it is,
and she is my best friend.
I've known her all my life.
GEORGE: Don't you cry on me.
Don't you cry on me.
- If you'd stop yelling at me...
- I'm going to set her straight.
(SEABIRDS CALLING)
(GIRLS TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Are we going to stay here
all night, Mom?
(DOG BARKING)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
You guys stay here.
Wow.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(METAL SCRAPES)
Do you hear that?
You did hear that, didn't you?
- I heard it, Mommy.
- What was it?
(METAL SCRAPES)
- The keys!
- It came from under the house!
- Don't go!
- Mommy, what's happening?
Bill, we've got
to get out of here!
- Mommy!
- Where are you going?
CARLA: No, don't do it!
Don't go under the house!
There's something there!
- Billy!
- CARLA: Don't!
- Mom, leave me alone.
- No!
Come back!
- Bill, come back!
- (GIRLS CRYING)
Here, here.
Calm down. Calm down.
Bill, we've got
to get out of here!
- (CRYING)
- Shh.
Will you answer me? Bill!
(METAL SCRAPES)
I've found it.
This is it. Look.
When I touch this pipe,
it makes a noise.
(SCRAPES)
See?
Then who touched it before?
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Mom. I'll leave
the door open, okay?
Great.
(CAR APPROACHING)
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
(CINDY LAUGHS)
Girl, didn't your mama
teach you any better manners
than to leave somebody's house
without even telling 'em goodbye?
Oh, I see the couch
is already taken.
Well, good.
I'll take the bed, then.
- What story did you tell George?
- Oh, that old sourpuss?
He thinks I'm with
my sister in Reseda.
Not that I give a particular
damn what he thinks
after the way
he behaved this morning.
Oh, that's all right.
Shoot. I ought to leave him,
you know.
If I had the courage, I would.
He's gotten to be
like a bad habit.
You know something, Carla.
I've been thinking.
Maybe you ought to just
move out of this old house.
How can I?
I can't afford it.
I haven't even paid
this month's rent.
I have a lease.
How can I?
When you've finished
that typing school thing,
you ought to be able to get
a real good-paying job then, huh?
I hope so.
I'm counting on it.
You know, Carly,
when he gets back into town,
you and Jerry really
ought to get married.
George says
he's making a bundle now.
He loves you so much, and he
absolutely dotes on the kids.
Hell's bells, girl.
Marry him, and you'll
be living on easy street.
Now, what's all this baloney
about you sleeping
on the couch?
Which side of the bed
do you want?
What side do you think?
The good side.
Well, doesn't make
any difference to me.
I am so tired tonight,
I could sleep on a rock.
- Good night, sugar.
- Good night.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(CREAKING)
(RATTLING)
(WIND BLOWING)
(CREAKING)
(RUSTLING CONTINUES)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(WIND QUIETS)
(CLOCK TICKING)
Julie likes the chips,
and Kim likes the Fritos, okay?
Mm-hmm.
Don't you worry about a thing.
I'm going to get them dressed
and fed and off to school on time.
You're great.
Here. I'll trade you.
- Okay.
- Okay. Thanks.
You're welcome.
You look so pretty.
- I'll call you later.
- All right.
Don't let Bill be late
for school, okay?
Won't do it.
- Bye.
MAN ON RADIO: That's right.
At Mr. Tibby's Car Radio/Stereo,
do we have boosters?
Do we have limiters?
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYS)
Ask yourself, "How much
should I give to the Lord?"
(TIRES SCREECHING)
- What's going on? Stop!
- (HORNS HONKING)
No!
Stop!
Stop! No!
(HONKING CONTINUES)
No!
(SCREAMS)
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Stop it!
Stop!
(CRASHES)
(HUBCAP ROLLING)
Hi.
I'm Dr. Sneiderman.
I'm one of the staff psychiatrists
here at the clinic.
Are you cold?
Sometimes there's a draft,
comes from the outer lobby.
Tell me, is this the first time
something like this
has ever happened?
No.
No, the first time was different.
I was raped.
Where? In your home?
You were raped by whom?
I don't know.
There was no one there.
Okay. So in other words,
it wasn't a real man
that raped you?
He evaporated.
I see. But you felt him
in you, though?
Definitely.
And he felt like a man?
A big man.
- Were you in pain?
- Yes, of course I was in pain.
He was foul.
You mean you smelled him?
I see. Did he ejaculate?
I...
I think so.
But when my son came in,
there was nobody there.
Right. And what did he think?
Your son.
He thought I was dreaming.
Mmmmm.
And what do you think happened?
Okay. That's okay, Carla.
Is this the only other time
something like that happened?
No.
It started to
a second time, and...
he didn't get me.
We went to my friend's apartment.
And then this morning,
I was driving to work...
And he tried to kill you?
What do you think?
Go ahead, and be honest.
Just tell me.
You think I'm insane?
Insane?
That means different things
to different people, Carla.
- So there's nothing you can do?
- Well, not at the moment, Carla.
First, we have to find out
what the problem is.
In the meantime, I'll be dead.
No, I don't think so.
Look, Carla, you've done a very good
thing by coming here.
You've already made
a commitment to get better.
Really, that's the first step,
and it's the hardest one.
Huh?
Look, I'd like you to take
a few medical
and psychological tests now.
They're very routine. Nothing hurts.
There's no surprises.
It takes about two hours.
Mostly it's just boring.
I'd appreciate it
if you did not fall asleep
while taking these tests.
(LAUGHS)
Right now?
Yeah, I'd like to,
if you can spare the time, okay?
Come on. I'll take you
down to the lab, okay?
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(SCREEN DOOR CLOSES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
What are you doing up?
I couldn't sleep.
I was worried about you.
Where is everybody?
Billy's out working
in the garage,
and Kim's already asleep.
Did the doctor hurt you?
No, baby. We just talked.
Mommy, what happened
to your hand?
No, don't worry about it.
You just get to sleep.
(SIGHS)
- Mommy?
- What?
Is everything going
to be all right?
Of course it is.
I love you so much.
I love you too.
You go to sleep now.
(DOOR CLOSES)
- Hi.
- How do you feel?
Oh, I'm all right.
I'm just stiff.
What about the car?
Can you fix it?
Yeah, I can fix it,
but it won't be cheap.
Listen. If Jerry calls,
don't tell him anything, okay?
Good night.
- (SIGHS)
- (WATER SPLASHES)
(EXHALES)
(DOOR CREAKING)
Oh, my God.
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
Please, God.
Carla, this is Mrs. Hilliard.
You want to hop up there now,
show us what you're talking about?
Right here.
There's one.
And right there.
And in back.
Do you see that?
Mm-hmm.
And right here.
You said something
about your thighs?
Yeah.
There...
and there.
How about those bruises on
your ankles? How did they happen?
Oh, thank you very much,
Mrs. Hilliard. That will be all.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Okay, look, Carla,
why don't you come down,
make yourself
comfortable, okay?
Okay.
Can you tell me about
those bruises
on your ankles now?
I'm not sure.
It felt like my legs
were being held,
almost as if he had help.
Uh-huh. Are you saying
that he wasn't alone?
It felt like there was
someone on each leg.
I see.
So what are you saying?
That there were
two more like him?
I guess so,
but they seemed smaller.
Mmmmm.
You mean like children?
Oh, no, no, no. These aren't children.
They're strong.
Dwarfs?
I don't know what they were.
I couldn't see them. I felt them.
They're real, aren't they?
- I mean, these...
- Mm-hmm.
- Bites and bruises are real.
- They're real.
- Yes, yes.
The bites are real.
The bruises are real.
All pain is real.
Your feelings? They're real.
Oh, no, no. These are in places
I couldn't have bitten myself.
Carla, I've seen
cases of hysteria
that have raised welts,
caused blindness,
loss of hearing.
Well, haven't your tests
told you anything?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
We know that there is nothing
wrong with you medically,
physiologically, that is.
And as far as we can tell,
your intellect
seems to function as well,
if not better than normal.
So that leaves only one area
for us to explore--
early psychological
development,
emotional development.
What does that mean?
Well, the general idea
is that certain phases
of our life never really die.
They continue to exist
within us, all of us.
Now I'm talking
about you, me, everybody,
and they affect us
the rest of our lives.
For certain reasons,
they come back.
By coming back--
And sometimes they come back
with a vengeance--
they can cause delusions,
anxieties,
hallucinations.
So simple.
Look, Carla,
what I'm going to do
is I'm going to give you
some tranquilizers, okay?
They won't knock you out,
but they will reduce your anxiety,
which can be as bad
as the delusion itself.
I want you to take two
before you go to sleep.
Now, when you go home tonight,
I want you to take
a long, hot bath, relax,
get your kids in bed early,
and I want somebody to be
with you at all times, okay?
I don't want you to be alone.
I want you to get some sleep tonight.
That clear?
It's going to take a long time,
isn't it?
It could.
Why don't we just take it one
step at a time, though, okay?
- (CLOCK CHIMING)
- WOMAN ON P.A.: Paging Mrs. Newman.
Call extension 376.
Carla?
What are you still--
wait a second.
I'll be right there. Wait. Wait.
- Gonna go late?
- Yeah.
- You gonna be on tomorrow?
Okay.
Then I'll see you in P.M.
- Good.
- Carla, what's wrong?
- No.
- What are you still doing here?
Oh, I called a cab twice.
It never came.
- Yeah? What else is new?
- I'd better call again.
Look, why don't I give you a ride?
I'm parked right down here.
- No, really. It's all right.
- No, come on. Don't be ridiculous.
I'm right here.
It's no problem.
Come on.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Thanks for the ride.
Sure. Hope my driving
didn't frighten you.
That's how I find out
if my patients trust me.
There's something there.
There's really something there.
Carla, I'd be interested in taking
a look inside. Would you mind?
- All right.
- You sure it's okay?
- Hi, Bill.
- Hi.
The kids get
to the Greenspans' all right?
Yeah, yeah. They all
went to get some pizza.
- They should be back soon.
- Good. This is Dr. Sneiderman.
- This is Bill.
- How do you do?
- How do you do? '64?
- Yeah.
What do you have in there?
215 or 235?
- A 235.
- All right.
(BILL CHUCKLES)
(MUSIC CONTINUES FAINTLY)
(SCREEN DOOR CLOSES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
This the girls' room?
Cute.
Would you like to show me
where those attacks took place?
All right.
- May I?
- Yeah.
Okay. You said something
about the bedroom, didn't you?
- Through there.
- That way?
Carla, your house isn't haunted,
no more than your car is.
Why do I see
and feel these things?
- I started to explain to you why--
- Yeah, I know what you told me,
that terrible things happened to me in
my youth might come back to haunt me.
Yeah, essentially.
Well, terrible things
did happen to me,
and I didn't have
a normal childhood, but...
- Mm-hmm.
- How many people do?
- Carla. Carla.
- I mean, did you?
- How many people have normal--
- Carla.
Some things are more terrible
than other things.
Some children are more
sensitive than other children.
Make yourself comfortable.
So, you really think talk
could fix all this, huh?
I don't know,
but it's a good start.
All right.
I'll talk a blue streak
if it'll stop all this
from happening.
As a kid, I experienced
every cliché in the book.
I was afraid of the dark.
I was scared of my father.
He was a minister,
if you can believe it.
He actually spoke
with "thee" and "thou."
I was six before I realized
not everyone talked that way.
It was quite a shock.
Why were you afraid of him?
Because when he held me,
it wasn't the way a father
should hold a daughter.
How did he hold you?
You know what I mean.
Mmmmm.
Did your mother know?
I think so.
So I ran away, and...
I got as far as New York,
and that's where I met Mario.
Billy's the spitting image of him.
It's very strange.
Really?
Must have been quite handsome.
- Billy's a good-looking kid.
- He was.
Can you tell me about him?
I was 16.
That says an awful lot right there.
I was--
I'd never met anyone like him.
He was exciting.
What do you mean, "exciting"?
Exciting in bed?
Yeah. He was exciting in bed.
He was exciting in many ways.
But you did like
making love with him?
Mm-hmm.
At first,
and then it turned bad.
The sex?
- Everything turned bad.
- I see.
I mean, I got pregnant.
Before I knew it,
he started drinking,
taking pills.
It was a mess.
Everything was a mess.
What happened to him?
He got himself killed
on his motorcycle.
- I see. How old were you?
- 16.
Gee.
So Billy wasn't born yet?
No. I mean, I was pregnant.
How did you feel when he died?
How do you think I felt?
I don't know.
Why don't you tell me?
- He was my husband.
- Yeah, I know that,
but I still don't know
how you felt.
I thanked God. I did.
I thanked God when he died.
I also thanked God
for Bob Garrett.
- Bob Garrett?
- Julie and Kim's father.
Ah, right, right, right.
He was older.
He knew a lot.
He made me see
that life was good,
that men and women loving
each other was good, healthy,
having children
was good, simple.
So Bob was your second husband?
Well, no.
We were never legally married.
Uh-huh. Where is he now?
I don't know.
He was never the kind
to stay in one place very long.
I'm impressed.
By what?
By what? Your independence,
knowing who you are,
what you want,
keeping your family together,
doing it the hard way.
I do need your help.
I really do.
And I won't fight you.
Because if it is me, if it's
really me creating all this,
if I'm that sick...
then I have to be stopped.
But if it isn't me...
then we have to make a deal,
you and I,
to accept that fact and find
about a way to stop it, okay?
Okay.
(DOOR OPENS)
- Mommy!
- In here!
Hi. Hi, you guys,
How you doing?
- Fine.
- This is Dr. Sneiderman.
- This is Kim. This is Julie.
- Hi, Kim. Hi, Julie.
- You guys full?
- Yeah.
Aw, you don't have
any room for dessert.
- Yeah, I do.
- I'm hungry for dessert.
Okay, okay.
I think it's time for me to go.
- Okay. I'll walk you out.
- Bye-bye, girls. Nice meeting you.
- BOTH: Bye.
- Bye-bye.
I'm nervous about tomorrow.
- What, about the staff meeting?
- Yeah.
Oh, don't be silly.
They're perfectly routine.
- Good night.
- Bye-bye.
But there's still
something here.
- (SPRAYING)
- Mommy, I can't wait.
- CARLA: Okay. Don't cheat.
- BILL: This is almost perfect.
- We're so hungry.
- This is the best part.
- Right, Mom?
- Okay, okay.
- Mommy!
- We got it. Okay.
Now hold on. Don't look yet.
Okay. Now look.
(GASPS)
Mommy!
Okay, I'm going to go
get a chair.
Hey. You can't use your hands.
Come on. Come on.
- Come on.
- Don't start without me.
(YELLS)
Bill.
- Bill.
- Mom!
Help!
(BILLY GRUNTS)
- (CRYING)
- (CARLA SCREAMING)
- BILL: Mom.
- No!
Help me! Help!
Get off her!
- (CARLA SCREAMING)
- Get off her!
(GASPING, GRUNTING)
CARLA: Stop!
Help me.
Mom! Mom!
BILLY: Mom!
- (ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
- Aah!
- (CRACKLING CONTINUES)
- (BILLY SCREAMING)
BILLY:
Mom!
(GIRLS CRYING)
Well, Dr. Sneiderman explained
it was like a very powerful dream.
Mrs. Moran...
did you believe him?
I tried to.
But you...
cannot. Hmm?
Why?
Because he hurt my son.
He broke his wrist.
Because my children feel it.
Because of the marks on my body.
They're in places I--
I can't do it to myself.
Even in a dream.
Why does he attack you, Carla,
not anyone else?
I don't know.
I suppose he chose me.
Chose you? Why?
I suppose
he finds me attractive.
Would it be a reflection
on you as a woman
if he left you,
or if you were cured?
No. It would not be
a reflection on me.
I hate this whole thing.
It's like a nightmare,
I can't wake up.
I want to get rid of him.
Of course you do, Carla.
And we're trying to help you.
Well, I'm not sure how much good
all this talking's doing.
Well, it's our way
of trying to understand.
Well, so far, it hasn't helped.
It hasn't with Dr. Sneiderman.
Look, you'll have to excuse me.
I have an appointment.
I have to meet someone at
the airport. Is that all right?
Certainly, and thank you very much,
Carla, for letting us talk to you.
- Sure.
- All right.
Quite a young lady.
- Yep.
- How did you meet her?
I was on call one night at
the clinic, she walked in.
Just came in out of the blue?
- Please.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- A walk-in.
That's how it happens.
- Yeah.
- She's masturbating.
This entire circus,
she has invented it
to cover up what
every little girl does.
Well, with all due respect, sir,
that was my initial diagnosis,
but I think we can all agree
that that's not some teenager
with an identity crisis,
and now she tells us
that her children are feeling
this thing too, so...
It's a mass illusion,
folie a quatre.
Hysteria is contagious.
Given the right circumstances,
anyone can see and feel things
that simply aren't there.
Her children are just
supporting Mama's delusions.
Okay, classically correct,
sir, but her mind
is giving her very strong
and explicit images.
Why is she going to such lengths
to support this delusion? It--
Phil, look at the record.
She believes that her father
has incestuous desires.
She falls in love with an adolescent,
a typical overgrown kid.
He tries to prove he's
a real man, and he's not.
After which,
she picks up with this...
- Jerry Anderson?
- No, Garrett.
- Oh, Garrett.
- Bob Garrett, right?
A man old enough
to be her father.
See a pattern here?
I think I know what you're suggesting.
I don't know that I agree, though.
- Safe sex.
- PHIL: Well--
It's the story of Carla's life.
She's consistently refused to
get involved in the real thing.
- She has three children.
- What does that prove?
It doesn't take sex
to make babies.
That is a fact
I wasn't aware of.
- Well, now you know.
- Not real sex.
Now, for 32 years,
Carla goes along very smoothly,
and all of a sudden,
she meets this fellow--
- What's his name?
- Jerry Anderson?
- Now you have it.
- Ah, now I'm on it.
Okay. And, pow,
she drifts into
a Dionysian fantasy.
Don't you see?
It's exactly the kind of situation
that can energize
this sort of breakdown.
What, Anderson?
Certainly. A real man. Sure.
She wants the real thing.
No more faking it
with kids and old men.
And faced with the real thing,
Carla buckles.
She falls back
into an infantile reality.
Now, I suggest
you dig a lot deeper.
I think you're
going to find out more,
and maybe you'll find out
that Carla is
not what she seems to be.
MAN:
Hear, hear.
(CARLA CHUCKLES)
You look different.
- How?
- I don't know.
The face,
this serious look.
- 80's yours.
- No, no.
Your eyes have...
changed or something.
What is it?
It's been a long time.
You know, it's been too long.
- Something's wrong?
- No.
- Billy?
Me, right?
Come on.
No. Just nothing.
It's...
I'm only afraid.
You know, I'm just--
when you're not around,
I'm afraid of losing you.
That's all.
You won't lose me, honey.
I go crazy thinking about it.
Don't go crazy either.
What if I did?
What if I went crazy?
Now, you're not going to go
and do that right now.
What would you do if I did?
Would you leave me?
You'd still be my Carla.
Why are you
carrying on tonight?
Are you ready for my surprise?
Yeah.
I'm going
on the road again, Carly,
but this is the last time.
When I get back, it's for good.
I'm taking over the LA office.
We're going to be
a family, Carly, all of us.
Take me with you.
Please?
Just put me in your pocket
and take me with you.
Honey, I can't.
You know that.
Don't ask that.
What the hell are you asking,
to take you with me?
Where? On the road?
Yeah. I'll go anywhere with you.
Okay, what about your job,
your school?
How about the kids?
Who's going to take care of them?
Yeah, all right. Okay.
You're right.
It was just a pipe dream.
You have to go on the road,
and I have to go through what...
I'm going through.
What you're going through?
You know, you're not
telling me everything.
What the hell
are you going through?
What I'm going through's
being without you.
That's really
what I'm going through.
Car, it's all going to change.
Oh, sure. When you get back.
Just one more trip.
Do you know it's been the way
it's been ever since we met?
"Just one more trip."
No, I'm sorry.
I don't feel like it.
I'm sorry.
Look, I have to--
I think I should go home.
It's late, and I have
to get up early. Okay?
I'll take you home.
No. You call me a cab.
You don't have to bother.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
(LOCK CLICKS)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(CLOCK TICKING)
(CARLA MOANS)
(MOANS)
Ohh.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MOANING)
Oh, God.
(YELLING)
Get out! Get out!
Get out!
(SOBBING)
Why did you tear up your room?
Why did you yell at Billy?
- Because I had an orgasm.
- What?
I had an orgasm.
An orgasm?
Yeah. But he tricked me.
I was asleep.
I was asleep,
and I was dreaming.
And I'm ashamed.
I'm ashamed.
Mm-hmm.
Carla, I want you
to sign yourself
into the hospital.
No. I won't let myself
be committed.
No, you're not being committed.
It's just going to be
for a two-week observation period.
That's all.
It amounts to the same thing.
You know it.
Carla, do you know
that if we wanted to,
we can insist
that you stay here.
- No, you can't.
- Oh, yes, we can.
Yes, we can,
for trying to commit suicide.
- What are you talking about, suicide?
- You know what I'm talking about.
What do you think you were doing
when you crashed your car?
- He was trying to murder me!
- It was a suicide attempt, Carla.
We could have you in here
before the day is out.
No, you can't.
There were no witnesses.
I won't say a thing.
It's my decision.
- What, to stay sick?
- To stay alive.
No matter what you think,
he's stronger than you are.
He'll kill me if he has to.
Why, to keep you
from getting better, right?
However you want
to call it, yes.
Yes, that's what I want
to call it. Exactly.
How about Jerry?
What are you going to do with him?
How are you going
to deal with him?
How would I deal with him
from a padded cell?
What about your kids, Carla?
Carla, listen to me.
You're running the risk
of harming your children.
No. They won't be harmed.
Billy has already
broken his wrist.
Beyond that, you're harming them
psychologically.
There's nothing wrong
with my children.
Carla, that's not the environment
they need. You know that.
Look, I know you think I'm crazy.
it doesn't matter about your theories.
Whether it's me or something
else is beside the point now.
What are you telling me? You're going to
stay home and be victimized?
- Yes. Yes.
- Yes?
I'll stay at home. I'll see you.
I'll go to secretarial school.
When I graduate,
I'll look for a better job.
But the one thing I won't do
is to go into any hospital.
Mm-hmm, and you'll
be beaten and frightened.
- No. No.
- No? No? Why not?
'Cause I'm going
to cooperate with him.
Carla, you're
a very intelligent woman.
I know you'll always
listen to reason,
so now I want to talk to you
reasonably, okay?
No more questions
and answers, hmm?
You know, there was a time when people
believed in the supernatural.
Here. I want you
to look at these pictures.
Pretty frightening, huh?
Bats, werewolves,
dragons, demons,
all sorts of goblins, okay?
They were supposed
to abuse people sexually.
to impregnate people.
Do you think these things
really exist in there?
- I am not stupid.
- I didn't say you were stupid.
But why do you think these
people saw these things, huh?
Why do you think
they saw them?
Hmm? Can you take a guess?
Do you know why?
Because it was a way of expressing
something that was frightening to them.
- It has nothing to do with me.
- Wait a second. Carla...
- it has a lot to do with you.
- It has nothing to do with me.
Oh, no, it has a lot
to do with you.
It has an awful lot
These ghosts and demons
were only ideas,
but people saw them.
Look, Carla, let's say
a man who wanted to be good
had a desire
for his neighbor's wife.
He knows it's wrong,
he feels terrible about it,
but the desire
is growing and growing.
Desire can be a very frightening
and powerful sensation.
How does he deal with it?
He invents a creature,
an evil, ugly,
evil-tempered creature
which is just a picture
of his own desire, Carla.
I have no need of inventing
anything, Dr. Sneiderman.
Come on, Carla, stop it.
You have a lot of need.
You were scared
of your daddy.
He was a minister.
He held you in a way
- he shouldn't have held you.
- Stop it.
- You were pregnant at 16.
- Oh, shut up!
A drug-crazed guy
went off and killed himself.
- Stop it!
- Another guy left you
with two kids.
Now, Carla, stop it!
Come on. Do the work, Carla.
What was evil to your family?
All sorts of things were evil
to my family. You know that.
Carla, we know your family well enough
to know what was evil to them.
As a child, you knew
what was evil to him. What?
- Sex. They were afraid of sex.
- Sex. Sex. Sex. Sex. Sex.
They were afraid of sex.
Exactly.
So let's use our imagination
a little bit, okay?
Let's try putting
some things together.
Like a dream,
it's getting all mixed up.
Your creature is
a symbol, Carla.
A symbol of what?
I don't know yet.
Maybe we'll find out.
Could be a specific person,
a fear of someone, a desire...
No, I'm not hiding
from anybody or anything!
Carla. Carla, let's talk
about your visitor friend, okay?
- Dr. Sneiderman, I'm so sick of this.
- Take a good look at him.
What do we know
about him, Carla?
Come on. Let's use your words.
What do we know about him?
We know that he is big,
we know that he is strong.
It's frightening how strong
this guy is, isn't it?
You told me,
unbelievably strong.
So why does he need help?
But he has two helpers, right?
Two little ones? Right?
Those are your words.
One big one
and two little ones.
- Oh, you're obscene.
- Billy's a good-looking kid.
What you're suggesting
is obscene.
- He's a strong kid.
- You're obscene!
You're having
trouble with Jerry, and--
- You're obscene.
- Carla, calm-- Carla!
- I'll calm down, but not here!
- Carla!
Shit.
He was talking about
two little ones and a big one.
He was implying that I wanted
to make love with Billy.
(SIRENS PASSING)
It was just obscene, you know?
- Really.
- It was obscene.
There's no other word for it.
No. I think
he just pushed too far.
He pushed too far. It was disgusting.
It was sickening.
I mean, I know he has to probe
into painful areas
- and everything, but...
- That's not probing.
I'm not going back.
I'm never going back.
Oh, no. Wait a minute.
Maybe you're overreacting
- a little bit, Carla.
- I'm never going back.
- Honey?
- What?
- You ready to go?
- Yes, I am, George.
Just give me a minute, please.
Well, I'm going to get the car,
'cause I don't want to be late.
Okay, honey.
No, we're not going to be late.
I don't want
to cause any trouble...
- No.
- between you and George.
I shouldn't have barged in.
I should have called.
No, no, no. We just have
- to make an appearance...
- I just wanted to talk.
At this boring wedding reception.
It's important to George, you know?
Well, I'm going
to see you tomorrow.
No, I want you to stay here.
We're going to be back
in less than an hour.
Now come on, Carla.
I need to talk to you
some more about this.
Carla...
will you wait here
until I get back?
- Yeah.
- Please. You look so tired.
Why don't you sit down
and have something to eat?
- (CAR HORN HONKS)
- Have fun.
Okay. I'll see you
in a little bit.
Okay.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(DIALING)
Hi, Bill.
How are the girls?
How's everything? Okay?
Dr. Sneiderman?
You didn't tell him where I was?
I don't want to talk to him.
Good.
Look, you have the number here.
If there's any problem,
call me, okay?
I'll be home
in a couple of hours.
All right.
(CLOCK CHIMING)
(CHIMING STOPS)
(WIND BLOWING)
(METAL CREAKING)
- What was that?
- What the hell? Was that our place?
(WIND BLOWING)
(CARLA PANTING)
(GASPS)
Carly? Ohh.
Oh, my God. Carly.
Christ, she tore
the fucking place apart.
No, she didn't.
You saw it.
She couldn't
have done all this.
We both saw it
with our own eyes.
We stood right there
and saw it, George.
You saw it?
Yes. Yes, we did.
We saw it.
You saw it?
Please forgive me, Carly.
Please?
I never should have
sent you to that clinic.
- You saw it?
- I'm so sorry.
Please forgive me.
You saw it.
(CRYING)
Ohh! You saw it!
WOMAN: Yeah, I need "The Empty Fortress"
and "Love is Not Enough."
Carla? Look.
"Improbability
of the impossible."
"Psychic Self-Defense."
- MAN: Is this a $12.95 book?
- This is great.
You look at that.
I'm going to go over
and check out
the psychology section.
All right.
Let's just look
at Rogers McGibbon, okay?
No. It's just
not that good a case.
There's just not enough independent
verification of the phenomena.
Yeah, but so much of it
fits the classic patterns.
There's cold spots.
There's the smell.
There's objects
moving around randomly,
and, in this case, there is
the appearance of an apparition.
Yeah, but that's just it.
The appearance of an apparition
and the sudden movement
of objects
just don't occur simultaneously.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. They do.
I have them all.
You do?
Everything broke loose
and went crazy,
and everything was shaking.
The bed was shaking,
and the walls were shaking.
Like an earthquake?
No, it wasn't
like an earthquake.
It was much stronger
than any earthquake.
And I tried to get out of here,
and I wanted
to get the kids out,
and I called Bill.
Bill was in his room.
And then the door slammed.
It was just a horrible thing.
- Where is Billy now?
- He's out in the garage.
- You can talk to him if--
- Door slam like that?
Stronger. Much stronger.
Hmm.
And the bathroom.
This is where--
well, you know
about that attack. And I--
this was the door. It was stuck,
and I couldn't get out of it,
and I tried, and I just
couldn't get out of it.
It was stuck that night.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
This is the girls' room.
They're asleep right now,
and I don't want to disturb them.
Did they sleep
through this whole attack?
Yeah, they managed
to sleep through it.
- Sound sleepers.
- They are.
It's one of the good things
about kids.
The living room.
This is where Billy
got the lightning.
It was like it was lightning
going into him,
and he fell down.
He broke his wrist--
By lightning, you mean
an electrical discharge?
I don't know what it was.
It was like lightning
was going into him
- and I was on the couch.
- Like an arc?
Was it kind of like...
(IMITATES CRACKLING)
You don't believe me, do you?
Mrs. Moran, please understand.
We want to believe you.
We want to believe you
very much, but it's--
It's just we want to do it
right, Mrs. Moran.
- You want some coffee?
- Yeah, sure.
Yeah. That'd be real nice.
(RATTLES)
(SNIFFING)
- Oh, my God. Do you smell that?
- (SNIFFING)
Jesus.
It's awful.
(SHIVERS)
You see?
I wasn't lying.
Mrs. Moran,
I think it might be worthwhile
after all for us to set up
some of the equipment
we've got with us in the car.
Yeah.
(CLOCK TICKING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
Joe!
Gene, let's get her out of here!
JOE: Mrs. Moran,
are you all right?
Mrs. Moran?
Gene, let's get out of here.
No, don't be frightened.
He's weak.
He's weak!
He can't touch us!
Gene, shoot it!
Ha! I don't believe it.
He can't touch us.
Die, you bastard! Die!
(CAMERA CLICKING)
(LAUGHS)
Die!
You can't touch us!
(LAUGHING)
Die!
(LAUGHS)
Die.
He can't hurt me anymore.
Not with you here.
He can't hurt me.
Oh, thank you, God.
- Did you see it?
- I think so, yes.
- Did you get it?
- Yes.
- Oh, thank you!
- (LAUGHING)
I'm going to go get the kids.
Gene, we're going
to need an ion detector.
Hey, wake up.
Wake up, everybody.
It's a gorgeous day.
Gorgeous day.
Come here. Come here.
- (LAUGHING) Wake up.
- (LAUGHING)
Isn't it a beautiful day?
Come here.
Did you check the wiring?
It could be a short circuit,
current leakage.
She spoke to it
as if it were real,
like it were alive
and she knew it.
Isn't it possible
she was hallucinating?
How do you photograph
a hallucination?
This looks like some kind
of electrical discharge.
What about this forking,
right here?
Couldn't this be a head?
Couldn't this be a shoulder?
We feel that this photograph
constitutes proof, Dr. Cooley.
I don't know.
Takes a long time before you can
come up with something reliable.
You have to check
every possible alternative.
What about the smell?
And the shaking?
That's classic
poltergeist activity.
It also could be
a dead cat and a tremor.
(GROANS)
I don't know what
you think you've discovered,
but you're playing with fire.
I suggest you start
with the traditional world
and move outward.
We'll need more equipment
to do that.
Maybe I'll authorize it
when the time comes.
You say she was seeing
a psychiatrist?
That's right.
I'd like to know
what the diagnosis was.
Well, that's no problem.
She was seeing someone right here.
MAN: I got it.
Get that blue one.
JOE: Yeah, well, we're doing
the best that we can.
Oh, we got a lot
of people here,
lot of folks, yeah.
Well, we're wiring
the place up
for any kind of movement
that we might get
and putting
x-ray plates up also.
No, we're hanging up
wires and stuff.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for Carla Moran.
Are you here
to observe the phenomena?
Observe the phenomena?
No, I'm Phil Sneiderman.
I'm a resident in psychiatry.
Carla's my patient.
Oh, hi. I'm Gene Kraft,
Department of Psychology.
How do you do?
Nice to meet--
what branch of psych you in?
Clinical? Dr. Morris?
No. Parapsychology.
Dr. Cooley.
- Gene.
- Oh, Parapsychology.
Gene, hand me a roll of tape,
would you, please?
Yeah.
What are you guys
doing with all this stuff?
We're trying to gather
some hard data
on the phenomena
that's occurring here.
Oh, really?
I take it you've already
looked under the beds
and in the closets.
(LAUGHS) Yeah. We're leaving
no stone unturned,
- but thanks for the tip.
- Sure.
As a matter of fact,
we got some highly interesting
- electrical formations...
- Did you?
Possibly caused
by the entity itself.
The entity?
You know, I hope you guys
will excuse me for saying so,
but if you guys want
to go on TV talk shows,
bend spoons, entertain people,
I'm all for that,
but this lady is under my care, and
what you're doing isn't helping her.
Well, thank you very much for
your professional opinion, Dr...
Sneiderman.
- Sneiderman.
- Uh-huh.
- Where's Carla?
- She's in the back.
CARLA: ...think it is.
I don't think so,
'cause you haven't
been here during it.
Just to line it up, huh?
- Yeah.
- Carla?
(TAPS FINGERS)
MAN:
Go over the doorway.
- Hi.
Boy, you got a lot of company.
You missed
your appointment yesterday.
I was worried about you.
That's very sweet of you.
You look terrific.
I've never felt better,
Dr. Sneiderman.
- Really?
- Mmmmm.
Look, is there someplace
that we could go and talk?
Yeah.
I can't blame you
for not coming back.
I really did push
a little too hard.
I think you need
to understand something.
I feel very fine now.
There are no more attacks.
I have no reason to see you.
Carla, do you remember
that book I showed you
in the office?
The bats and the dragons?
That's what those guys
are looking for, fantasies.
No, they have photographs.
Okay.
Look, Carla,
how about you and me,
we make a bargain, okay?
You can see me and still...
have your scientist friends
help you.
I don't see any point in that.
Well, it's like seeing
two different doctors,
you know,
getting different opinions,
a bone specialist
and a blood specialist.
- They work together.
- No, I'd rather not.
Why?
What have we got to lose?
I believed in you.
You know I did.
I really needed to believe in you.
But every time you discovered
something new about me,
something worse happened,
and I got sick of hearing
that it would all go away
as soon as we got down to the basic
problem, as though it was in me.
It is in you, Carla.
I think you better leave.
- Hi, Billy.
- Hi.
- Billy. Billy!
- Yeah?
- Look, would you do me a favor?
- What?
Don't pretend next time.
The next time your mother
thinks she sees something
or she hears something,
she wants you to corroborate it,
and when you do, it's that much
more difficult to convince her
that it's all in her head,
it's a delusion.
I didn't get a broken arm
by pretending.
Look, Billy, there's a lot
of logical explanations
that could have caused
something like this.
All I'm telling you, that is,
if you care about your mom,
you will not pretend next time.
I care about my mother, yeah.
But I was not pretending.
I'm not lying to you.
Want to know
why she's not coming back?
- Mmmmm.
- She's fallen in with some schmucks
who are supporting her fantasies.
You ought to see her house.
They're watching her visitations,
got it all wired to look for poltergei--
- Entities.
- Wait a minute.
That's what they called it,
an entity.
- What schmucks?
- I don't know.
They say they're
from the university here.
parapsychology.
Ooh.
A Dr. Cooley.
- Elizabeth Cooley.
- Yeah.
parapsychology.
It's fly-by-night psychology.
Okay. So how do we
get rid of 'em?
Well, not very easily.
I mean, these are
not snake-oil peddlers, Phil.
These are supposedly
academic brethren.
Academic brethren, bullshit.
Come on. They're dangerous.
They're feeding her delusion.
By the time
they get through with her,
she's really going to be
off her rocker or worse.
Well, there's not much
you can do,
not legally or medically.
It's her life, her house,
her delusions.
No, until she crosses
the line of legal sanity,
nobody can touch her.
(CLOCK TICKING)
Come on.
Come on, show yourself,
you coward.
Now that I've got
my forces here with me,
let's just see
how brave you are.
(ZAPPING)
Is that all
you got the guts to do?
A couple of itty-bitty lights?
Come on.
We don't want fireworks.
We want you!
Show yourself, damn you!
Are you trapped
in this environment?
COOLEY:
Will you appear to us now?
You won't appear.
You won't appear, because you're
a devil out of hell,
and you're afraid.
You'll wait till I'm alone,
won't you?
Then you'll come forth to hurt me,
to hurt my children.
Show yourself.
(HIGH-PITCHED WHINING)
(WHINING STOPS)
Joe, turn on the lights.
Did you see it?
Yes, Mrs. Moran.
We saw it.
Thank you.
Would you excuse us?
- Is it over?
- For now.
Yeah? Are you okay?
All right. Okay, then I'm going
to go to bed, okay?
- Okay.
- Good night.
- I'll see you.
- Good night, Billy.
- Excuse me.
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
Thank you.
We'll be leaving shortly.
What are you two doing up?
- Is everything okay?
- We heard you, Mommy.
Everything's fine.
Come on.
Well?
I've never seen
anything like it before.
Do you think that we were
in some kind of hypnotic state
and that this was
a mass hallucination?
I've always believed
that there were several planes
of existence,
distinct and separate...
and we, as human beings,
inhabit only one.
Isn't it possible that some sort
of external intelligence,
some discarnate entity,
has crossed into
our plane of existence?
How are we going to prove it?
We have to isolate it.
We have to draw it in somehow,
find a way to bring it into
a controlled situation.
MAN:
Yeah, me too.
- Put it in.
- Okay, we got it.
(SCREEN DOOR CLOSES)
Good night, Mrs. Moran.
- Good night, Mrs. Moran.
- Thank you.
We've got some real good ideas
on how to proceed.
Thanks a lot.
- You've got the tape, right?
- Yeah. Mm-hmm.
- Jerry.
- Hi, cutie.
Excuse me.
(LAUGHS)
- What gives?
- Why didn't you call?
I did. Every time, I got
a different voice on the line.
What's going on?
Those people
are from the university.
The university?
I missed you.
Look at me. I'm shaking.
I think we'd better
have a drink.
Got some good wine.
Um, yeah, well, you go ahead.
I don't think I'd really better.
No, no,
you're going to have one.
This is my homecoming.
Come on.
What was that all about?
They're trying to help.
- Help who?
- Me.
I don't know what you mean.
I've been sick, Jerry.
Sick? What kind of sick?
Things have come to me...
in the night.
- Nightmares, you mean?
- Yeah.
Like nightmares. Exactly.
I mean, those people
you saw in the house,
they're psychologists.
They're doctors,
and they have a theory
that there's something
in the house that...
is keeping me from sleeping,
and they're trying to fix it.
Some of them looked pretty young
to be doctors.
- Oh, you're mad.
- No, it's not a question of mad.
- Yeah, okay, since you ask.
- Yeah, you're mad.
I mean, who brings
a university full of kids
into their house
because they can't sleep?
You can't sleep, you take a pill.
You go see a regular doctor.
I'm not giving a party, Jerry.
I'm really not.
Hey, all I'm asking for
is a simple explanation.
I still don't know
what's bugging you.
- Yeah.
- Don't treat me like a jerk.
- I'm not a jerk, okay, Carly?
- I'm sorry.
Trust me. Just tell me
what the hell's happening.
I don't know.
I mean, I don't know--
I don't know the difference
between what is happening
and what I think
might be happening.
The only thing I know for certain
is that it started when you left.
And I don't say that
with any kind of blame
or accusation,
but that is when it started.
When what started, Carly?
What?
All right.
Okay. I was--
I was attacked.
And it's not happening now,
so don't worry,
but I was attacked.
You were attacked?
By who? Who attacked you?
- Nobody. Nobody.
- You were attacked?
No, nobody. Nobody.
Nobody you can see.
Oh, God.
This sounds so crazy.
I mean, it was like
a horrible dream.
Shit. I don't know
how to explain it.
It sounds crazy
every time I explain it.
- Ohh.
- It sounds crazy.
God, baby.
Oh, Carla.
Do you know, for a second,
you had me worried?
I mean, I thought
you were really attacked.
I thought that somebody
attacked you.
(LAUGHING)
JERRY: Honey.
I know why you can't sleep,
but I am with you right now.
I will guarantee you
that these dreams
or nightmares
or whatever the hell they are
will never bother you again.
Because I'm staying this time.
No more trips.
No more one-night stands, baby.
Starting tonight,
it's going to be forever.
Hey.
Let's go to bed.
Huh?
Hey, can we go to your place?
Uh-uh.
Remember, I'm with you,
and as long as I am,
nothing bad is going to happen.
Do you believe that?
I got something for you.
What? What is this?
You'll see.
Oh.
Aw, it's beautiful.
- Mmm.
- It's pure silk.
It feels good.
Go put it on for me.
Come on.
It's my homecoming.
Put it on.
(HUMMING)
Look, honey. You know what
I was thinking? If we--
Please. Help me.
Help me.
Help me. Help me.
Please, help me.
Help me.
Help me. Help me!
Help me. Help me.
(JERRY SCREAMS)
Help me.
Stop it. Stop it.
- Get off her.
- Help me.
- Stop it!
Stop it!
You son of a bitch!
You fucking bastard!
WOMAN ON P.A.:
Dr. Bronstein, Dr. Loomis...
Okay. She's going
to be all right.
- Yeah?
- She's still a little shaky,
so when you go in,
don't stay too long, okay?
- All right.
- Okay. All right. Go in.
Go in.
She's dying to see you.
Make a right
at the corner there.
- BILL: First right?
- First door on your right.
- Thanks a lot.
- You got it.
Don't stay too long.
Please don't.
Okay, Jerry,
she's going to be okay.
It was just
a slight concussion.
Thank God for that, Doctor.
Thank God.
Look, why don't you
go in and see her?
She'd like to see you.
No way, Doctor.
I can't be around her.
I can't handle
what's going on in there.
Come on, Jerry.
What do you mean
you can't handle it?
She needs you now.
I mean, I loved her.
I was going to marry her,
you know.
I could've taken anything,
I mean, a disease, cancer.
This is a disease, Jerry.
It's the same thing.
Not what she's
got living with her.
Jerry, it's just
a disease now, okay?
Now just get it
through your head.
It's just in her head.
There was nobody there.
Nobody was there.
Don't tell me that.
There was somebody there.
- Okay. Okay.
- I mean, there was.
Okay, okay.
Take it easy.
I couldn't see him with my eyes,
but there was somebody there.
I see this--
like something is pressing her.
It's pushing her.
I see her breasts
are being touched.
I mean, I see her breasts
are being squeezed by fingers,
only I can't see the fingers.
I'm sorry.
That's okay. That's okay.
Hey, what the hell
are you guys doing here?
We're visiting a friend.
- I got to go now.
- No, no. Oh, Jerry, look.
She needs you now.
She needs you now a lot.
It's okay. It's okay.
I really have to go.
Hey, Jerry--
- NURSE: Look at me.
- GENE: Thanks for calling, Billy.
- Come on.
- No. I want to stay with Mommy.
Come on.
We've got to go.
- I'll talk to you later, Mom.
- Okay.
I hope you're all right,
Mrs. Moran.
NURSE:
I'll be back.
We never should've left
the house. I'm sorry.
Maybe this doesn't seem
like the best time for this,
but we're afraid for you.
JOE: We have an idea
that might help.
We want to try to isolate
this thing and immobilize it.
COOLEY:
We need your consent.
That means going into it
with your eyes wide open.
What we have in mind
has never been tried before.
We'll take
every possible precaution.
I'll do anything...
to get rid of him.
That guy Jerry was
her only contact with reality.
I want those two guys
banished from her life.
I don't see what I can do.
Well, go to the dean.
Maybe he can do something.
Maybe he can
pull those creeps back.
Do you realize
what you're asking?
- That's a month-long debate...
- Right.
And it could get
very complicated.
All this for Carla Moran?
Somebody's got
to look after her.
Let her go, Phil.
You don't have any choice,
professionally or personally.
GENE: As you can see,
this is a freshly cut rose,
and this is a container
of liquid helium,
473 degrees below zero.
This is the coldest substance
known to man.
Anything frozen
at this temperature
will shatter
at the slightest touch.
What we are seeking
is to determine
if this entity has mass.
If in fact this is the case,
then we should be able
to freeze it,
verify its objective existence,
and prove that it isn't
just a psychic projection...
It's going to work great,
isn't it?
...but rather an independent
force from some other
level of reality
that has never been isolated.
Here she is.
Mrs. Moran.
Let me take your bag.
It's good to see you.
We're all very excited
to get the experiment under way.
- Welcome.
- GENE: Mrs. Moran.
See you later.
Have you made arrangements
for your children?
- They're with a friend.
- Good.
Let me show you
to your new house.
I'm afraid we're not able
to provide you
with all the conveniences,
but we hope
you'll find it comfortable
- and familiar.
- JOE: Watch your step.
I think everyone's done a terrific
job in recreating your home.
We did use different colors
on the walls.
And there are other differences.
No light switches.
We have to control
the electricity.
This, of course,
is the children's room.
Yeah, the bed's
in the wrong place.
Well, doesn't matter.
There are no ceilings
anywhere in the house.
That's for
the television monitoring.
Except, of course,
in the bathroom.
There is a ceiling,
but no plumbing.
We'll supply you
with all the water you need.
That's a chemical toilet.
Does this look familiar?
It's a good simulation.
And remember
not to change in here.
The television camera
will be watching you,
and Gene at the controls.
COOLEY: Now, in the kitchen,
we had a bit of a problem.
No gas, but we have a hot plate
and a well-stocked refrigerator.
It's like camping out.
Mrs. Moran, I'd like
to show you something now.
Looks a lot like your house,
doesn't it?
The living room.
Brought your books.
Just stand over here with me.
Mrs. Moran, this is the protected area
that we were talking about.
It's two pieces of double-thick,
heat-treated glass
with a vacuum
in between the panes.
Now, the system is fail-safe.
We can't activate the helium
until you're safely
behind this enclosure,
so when we tell you to go
to the protected area,
we want you to come
directly to this spot
as quickly as possible,
and we'll take care of the rest.
Okay?
Now we have to get ready.
You make yourself
as comfortable as you can,
but you're not alone.
If you need anything,
don't hesitate to ask.
I'm not afraid.
If you can get him,
Hey. Where do you think
you're going?
- Is this the Cooley experiment?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm with the Medical
Institute, Dr. Sneiderman.
- Go right on in, Doctor.
- Thank you.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Carla.
I'd like to talk to you alone.
Is there any place
that we could go talk?
That we could talk privately?
The bathroom.
This is quite a setup they have.
They made a natural environment
for him so he'll come here.
Really? Is that
what they're telling you?
That's what they're doing.
Uh-huh.
And you believe them?
Oh, yes.
They're dangerous frauds, Carla.
You're their guinea pig.
Carla, do you know
that there are tanks
of liquid helium outside?
Did you know that?
- Mm-hmm.
- You do?
Do you know
what liquid helium can do?
- Of course.
- Of course. Really?
You understand what it means
to stop all molecular motion,
paralyze atomic particles,
decompose matter?
- Okay,
- Okay?
What do you mean, okay?
I mean I'd rather be dead
than living the way
I've been living.
Do you understand that?
Yes, I can understand that.
Yes. I also understand
that I care very much
what happens to you,
very much.
And I know that, in your heart,
you know the difference
between reality and fantasy.
Carla, look at me. Carla.
Our reason, our intelligence,
that's the only thing
that distinguishes us
between any other species
of animal.
Carla, I care about you.
Carla, don't close
yourself off now.
It's real important, real important
that you maintain contact
with at least one person
that really cares about you.
- I don't know what you're saying.
- I'll tell you what I am saying,
that you and I
can make that contact.
I don't want
to make that contact.
Okay.
JOE: Hey.
Wait up a minute, will you?
Really.
I want to talk to you.
I got to hand it to you.
You just don't give up.
Look, get out, and stay out.
Okay. Now you listen to me,
Buck Rogers, okay?
If you or your trusty sidekick
harm one hair on her head...
- Officer.
- I will have your ass in court.
You're going to be looking
for your ghosts from prison.
Do you hear me?
You see this face?
I don't want to see it again.
- You got it.
- Hey, Mehan,
you may have them all fooled,
but not me.
I'm going to nail you
and that little creep.
I'll tell him.
Come on. Let's go.
- Yes, sir.
- Come on.
GENE:
Mrs. Moran, we are now going
to move into
the nighttime mode.
I want to get it so bad,
I can taste it.
Hang on, Gene.
Hang on.
And pray
Dr. Sneiderman is here
with me, Frank.
He tells me Cooley is using some pretty
lethal equipment up there.
Liquid helium.
God only knows what all else.
Frank.
Frank, let's not blow our tops.
I'm just trying
to sound you out on this.
Yes, I realize
it's your decision.
I can't figure him anymore.
Do we really need his approval?
You need to learn a lot
about campus politics.
Fuck campus politics.
Where are you going?
I'm going to get her away
from those lunatics.
Why not give her the option
of tripping that glass enclosure
- herself from down there?
- Too dangerous.
Hey!
- Hey! What are you doing?
- Carla!
- Hey!
- Carla?
- Carla!
- What?
Carla, come on. We're getting
out of here right now.
- No, I'm not.
- (GRUNTING)
- Don't do that. Let go of him.
- Get him out of here!
Take it easy. Take it easy.
Take it easy.
- GENE: Nobody has to be hurt.
- (YELLING)
COOLEY:
Let him go, Officer.
What is it you want, Doctor?
I want her out of here, Doctor.
That is not going to happen.
If you want to watch
this experiment,
you go up to the booth.
We have nothing to hide.
I'm very sorry
this had to happen, Mrs. Moran.
Everything is going
to be all right.
Yeah. I just don't like
to see anybody...
- Just try to calm yourself.
- hurt.
He's going to be upstairs
with us in the booth.
Just try to get some rest.
That's the important thing.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
(PHONE RINGING)
(CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Weber. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, all right, Elizabeth.
Take it easy.
I'll come and get him.
He's up those stairs, Doctor.
Thank you.
(WIND BLOWING)
- Someone open a door?
- He's here.
GENE: Mrs. Moran,
move to the protected area.
Mrs. Moran,
Mrs. Moran, move to
the protected area.
(MACHINERY WHIRRING)
GENE:
To the protected area.
(ALARM BLARING)
Don't be alarmed, Mrs. Moran.
We're moving
into the emergency mode.
Don't activate
the compressor yet, Joe.
- I didn't.
- What do you mean, you didn't?
It's been tripped.
(GAS HISSING)
Oh, my God.
(GAS HISSES)
- What have you got?
- It's no good.
GENE:
Let's run it in parallel.
(GASPING)
All right.
All right, bastard.
I've finished running.
So do what you want.
CARLA:
Take your time, buddy.
Take your time.
Really, I'm thankful
for the rest.
I'm so...
tired of being scared.
So it's all right, it really is.
It's all right.
You can...
do anything you want to me.
You can torture me,
kill me, anything.
But you can't have me.
You cannot touch me.
That's mine.
For God sakes.
Carla!
(WIND BLOWING)
(CREAKING)
(CRACKING)
We got it.
We got him trapped.
(CRACKING CONTINUES)
Oh, my God.
Carla?
We lost it.
We got nothing.
That's not true.
We got something.
We have a witness.
Isn't that so?
What?
You did see it, didn't you?
Something.
I--
I saw something.
But I don't know.
I just don't know.
With all that
going on down there,
it could have been anything.
You son of a bitch.
ENTITY:
Welcome home...
cunt
CINDY: We made it. Come on.
Okay, let's close it.
Good.
Now let's get these in.
- Mommy!
Carla, how in the world
did you beat us over here?
- We left right after you called.
- (LAUGHS)
Carla, take this.
Mmm. I'll pay you back.
I promise you.
- No.
- Thank you.
It's a gift.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
- Take care of yourself.
- Bye, Cindy.
Bye-bye. Bye-bye,
- BILLY: See you.
- Lock the door, girls.
Lock your door.
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)