RIPPED AND UPLOADED BY LUISUBS
FOR SUBSCENE.COM
[THUNDER]
Ezra, come and sit down.
Nothing's going to happen
on a night like this.
Oh, drink up, man.
No. That's what he wants.
Can you not see that?
But the storm--
damn the storm.
MAN: Come on, Micah.
Come on and have
a drink with us.
Micah!
Look!
[THUNDER]
Fetch our hats.
Tell the others to wait.
Quick, man!
Come on.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[THUNDER]
Do you believe me now,
Micah Smith?
Now that you've seen
with your own eyes,
do you believe me
when I tell you
that's the home
of Satan himself?
Aye, aye.
Then come.
[THUNDER]
[SPEAKING LATIN]
MAN: Somebody get hay!
Make sure it's dry!
And bring some oil!
Come on, let's go!
ALL: Yeah!
[SPEAKING LATIN]
[GROWLING]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
MAN: Kill the warlock!
Open this door!
Curwen!
Well?
Where
is she?
Who?
You know who.
The Fitch girl.
Do you deny
she's here?
Certainly not.
She visits us frequently.
Don't you,
miss Fitch?
Don't you?
Yes.
Of your own
free will?
Yes.
There now,
Mr. Weeden--
just a moment.
What's
your name, girl?
Really, this is
outrageous!
WEEDEN: Quiet!
Your name, child.
You see?
He's taken
her mind, her soul.
The good lord knows what
else--just like the others.
Well, what do
we do about it?
Let him go on with
his black magic
or send him back to the
hell he came from?
ALL: Send him back!
Then let's be
about it.
No, not the woman.
Leave her be.
She's been hexed.
It'll be right with us again when
he's gone, Hester. You'll see!
Hester!
[ALL SHOUTING]
MAN: Send him back
to Hades!
SECOND MAN: Burn him!
FIRST MAN:
Back where he comes from!
ALL: Burn him!
Burn him!
Have you anything
to say, warlock?
Only this...
as surely as the village of
Arkham has risen up against me,
so shall I rise
from the dead...
against the village
of Arkham.
Each one of you!
Ezra Weeden,
Micah Smith,
Benjamin West,
Priam willet,
Gideon Leach,
all of you and your children
and your children's children
shall have just cause to regret
the actions of this night.
For from this night onward,
you shall bear my curse.
WEEDEN: Burn the devil.
Burn him!
[SCREAMING]
Hester!
[THUNDER]
NARRATOR: "And travelers, now,
within that valley,
"through the red-litten
windows see
"vast forms,
that move fantastically
to a discordant melody."
Whoa, horse.
There you are,
ma'am.
Careful!
Oh, thank you,
Mr. Carmody.
It was a most
enjoyable trip.
CARMODY: Aye.
Thank you.
It isn't often I get
passengers for Arkham.
Begging you pardon, sir,
did you say you were going
to be staying here long?
Why do you ask?
Well, Arkham is
an evil place.
The village is cursed.
Mr. Carmody, don't tell
us you're superstitious.
Not at all.
And I'm not
a coward, either,
but you couldn't pay me to
spend a night in this place.
Why not, Mr. Carmody?
Ghosts? Spirits?
Well...perhaps.
I'm sorry, sir, but we don't happen
to believe in the supernatural.
And I don't think
you do, either.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, sir.
And good luck.
Well, it looks cursed.
I'll give it that.
Where are the people?
I can't imagine.
Look.
The "burning man."
Isn't that quaint?
Yes, very quaint.
Well, it is.
Now, where else would you find a
tavern with a name like that?
We were trying to find a
certain house here in town,
and we thought perhaps
you could help us.
Whose house is it?
Ours.
I know that
sounds silly.
It belonged to
the Curwen family.
We inherited it.
Curwen, you say?
Yes, that's right.
I don't know of
any such house.
Well, all right.
Thank you anyway.
Just a minute.
Why do you want to know
about the Curwen place?
Because it
belongs to us.
Your name is Curwen?
No, our name
is Ward.
Then...?
Joseph Curwen was my
great-great-grandfather.
So, can you tell us
where the house is?
I can, but I won't.
That's what I like about
you New Englanders--
you're so friendly.
Come, Ann, we'll
find it oursel--
Mr. Ward!
Don't go there.
It isn't a house.
It's a madman's palace
as old as sin.
Palace?
In America?
Brought over
stone by stone.
from where?
Europe somewhere. No one knows.
No one wants to know.
But if you value
your lives,
don't go there.
Why not?
MAN: What Edgar--
Mr. Weeden means is
that place is a ruin.
It hasn't been occupied
in over 100 years.
Is that what you mean,
Mr. Weeden?
What a strange man.
Yes.
He has had a bit, but
what he says is right.
Mr. Ward,
Mrs. Ward, please...
do yourself a kindness.
Go back to wherever
you came from
and forget you ever
heard about Arkham.
And what do you recommend
I do with the deed?
Just tear it up?
Yes.
Just tear up
the deed
to a palace
I've inherited
and forget all
about it,
without so much as laying
eyes on the property.
Is that
your advice?
WEEDEN: It's more
than advice, Mr. Ward.
Oh, come on, Ann.
MAN: Mr. Ward...
take the road out of town
about a quarter of a mile.
At the post road, turn
left past the cemetery.
You shouldn't have too much
difficulty finding it.
Here, I'll show you.
There's the Curwen palace
over there on the cliff.
Well, we certainly want to thank
you for being so nice, Mr...
Willet. I'm a doctor.
My office is down the street,
in case you need me.
I don't think we'll be
staying very long, doctor.
Oh, you've decided
that already?
It seems to have been
decided for us.
Thank you, anyway.
Come, Ann.
Thank you.
What do you think?
It's him, right enough--
the devil himself.
Nonsense.
And you helped him.
As I'd help
any stranger.
He's no stranger, Dr.
willet, and you know it.
I don't know anything of the
kind, and neither do you.
Are you blind?
Or do you tell me you've
never seen that face before?
Well, I'll admit there's
a strong resemblance,
but that's a matter
of heredity, not magic.
Call it what you will.
One thing is certain...
Joseph Curwen has
come back to Arkham.
Why did you say that?
What?
That we wouldn't
be staying long.
Well, do you want to stay in a
town full of fools like that?
I don't think
Dr. willet was a fool.
All right, so Dr.
willet wasn't a fool,
Charles...
the poor thing.
Yes.
Well, let's get
this over with.
[DOOR CREAKING LOUDLY]
Charles, it's you!
It's absolutely fantastic!
Dear, is something wrong?
Hmm? Oh, no.
No. Let's see what the rest
of this mausoleum looks like.
Kitchen's over there.
[DOOR CREAKING]
[CRASH]
[SNAKE RATTLING]
[ANN GASPING]
Wait.
Hmm?
That doesn't lead
anywhere.
This way.
How would you know that?
Oh, just a guess.
I'll let some light
in here.
Good evening.
Who are you?
My name is Simon.
What are
you doing here?
I'm the caretaker.
I was preparing
your room.
In the dark?
One becomes accustomed
to the darkness here.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Ward,
if I startled you,
but I didn't know
you'd be here so soon.
Well, just a minute.
How is it you expected
us at all?
Why, your attorney,
Mr. Hutchinson, contacted me.
Since then, I've been preparing
the palace for your arrival.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'll go fetch your bags.
No! No, that won't
be necessary.
We're not staying.
But where would
you spend the night?
After all, Mr. Ward,
this is your home.
Get the bags.
Very well.
Dinner will be
served at 8:00,
if that's convenient.
Thank you.
Charles, you don't really
want to spend the night here?
No, no,
of course not, but...
but the old fellow
was right.
We have to spend
the night someplace.
Don't we?
[BANGING]
Quiet! Quiet I say!
Is it food you want?
[GROWLING]
[SCREAMING]
What's wrong
with him tonight?
Not him, woman,
it! It!
How many times
must I tell you?
It knows.
That's what's wrong.
It knows who's come
back to Arkham.
Charles,
I'm all packed.
Charles, you ready?
I have decided
to stay.
What?
Just long enough
to fix the place up.
With a little work, it
could bring a good price.
Don't you think?
I should imagine.
I don't know.
I estimate two weeks,
perhaps three,
to get things
started, anyway.
Do you mind, Ann?
No, not exactly.
I can't say
it pleases me.
Well, then you go home.
Charles?
I'm sorry, Ann.
It's just that I...
well, I...
I can't leave now
until I...
Find out...
some things.
[CLOCK CHIMES]
[CHIME]
WILLET: Nightmarish,
yes, but not a nightmare.
They're quite real,
I'm sorry to say.
ANN: But what
are they, doctor?
Human beings.
Very unfortunate
human beings.
They were born mutated.
You see, Mrs. Ward,
it requires an extraordinary
combination of elements
to form a normal person.
In their case, the
combination was wrong.
They were gathered
by Weeden, of course,
for the purpose of
frightening you away.
But why, doctor?
Why should we be treated as
though we have the plague?
Because you do.
To these people,
at any rate.
Understand, Mr. Ward,
Arkham is a strange community.
You see, it's haunted.
Not by ghosts,
but haunted nonetheless.
By fear, by guilt, and by the
memory of a particular night.
Particular night?
But what has this
to do with us?
Well, you see,
150 years ago,
a man named Joseph Curwen
moved to this village
and built this palace.
His first wife died
in childbirth,
so he selected the most
beautiful woman in the village
and took her
for his mistress.
Unfortunately, she was engaged to
marry an Arkhamite named Ezra Weeden.
Uh, no, thank you.
You spoke with his
descendent yesterday.
Oh, the man
at the inn.
Yes.
Well, according to legend,
a number of strange things occurred
when Curwen moved into the village.
Terrible noises
were heard in the night.
Thank you.
Young girls were said to have
disappeared from their homes...
To be gone until dawn,
and then reappear with no
memory of their whereabouts.
Weeden wasted no time in placing the
blame directly on this doorstep.
He and his coterie of friends
claimed that Curwen was a warlock.
ANN: Warlock?
Yes. One who
conjures up the dead.
They demanded punishment.
And one night, the people of the
village marched on the palace,
dragged your ancestor
into the yard, and burned him.
Burned him?
The "burning man."
Well, that explains
the guilt.
What about the fear?
Curwen put a curse
on the village.
He vowed
that he'd return.
You can see
the resemblance yourself.
Dr. willet,
I'm sure that
every warlock or witch who
died in America left a curse.
Why should Curwen's
be taken so seriously?
Why should it be remembered
after all these years?
I can't say.
He was a strange man.
There were terrible
rumors about him.
WARD: Such as?
It was thought, Mr. Ward,
that he had gained possession
of a book called
the necronomicon.
Have you heard of it?
No.
Well, it obviously
never existed,
except in the minds
of the superstitious.
But they claimed
it held enough secrets
to give a man
absolute power.
Of course, every mythology
has such a book,
but the necronomicon
supposedly contained formulas
through which one could communicate
with or even summon the elder gods...
the dark ones from beyond
who had once ruled the world
and now are merely waiting for an
opportunity to regain that control.
Cthulhu, yog-sothoth.
Dreadful rubbish, I know.
Still, the people
of Arkham believed it.
They claimed that Joseph Curwen
and two other warlocks
were trying to open the
gates to these dark gods.
Open the gates? How?
They claimed that
Joseph Curwen was trying
to mate those beings
with humans
to create a new race
through which the gods
could regain their control.
That's how they explained
the mutated births--
unsuccessful experiments passed
on from generation to generation,
carried in the blood.
What's your
explanation, doctor?
I don't have one.
I advise you, Mr. Ward,
to leave this village.
I advise you to flee it as you
would from a madman with a knife
who feels compelled
to destroy you
before you can
destroy him.
[THUNDER]
[BANGING]
[PEOPLE YELLING]
[GASPS]
It's a cold night, sir.
You'll need your coat.
Thank you.
You seem
troubled, sir.
Is something wrong?
You didn't hear them?
Beg your pardon?
The voices...
people.
Well, no, sir.
Must have been
the wind.
Perhaps you should
ask Mr. Curwen.
Curwen?
Yes.
Maybe he could
tell you.
[THUNDER]
Welcome, Joseph.
Simon?
How long?
110 years.
110 years?
And whose body is this
I'm now occupying?
His name is
Charles Dexter Ward.
My great-great-grandson.
Perfect.
All the others
were useless.
You would not
accept them.
No matter.
Where's Jabez?
JABEZ:
Here, Joseph.
Jabez, my old friend.
Well, we three...
together again.
But briefly, I fear.
I shan't be able
to hold him much longer.
He...he fights me.
When will you have
full control?
Soon, Simon, soon.
Keep him here
for a while longer,
and he will be all mine.
He has my blood.
I can feel it.
Ah...the book.
The book!
Good.
Now leave me,
my friends.
He fights me.
He fights
to leave me.
[CURWEN BREATHING HEAVILY]
What is it, Charles?
What's the matter?
Dear, what are
you doing down here?
I don't know, Ann.
I must have walked
in my sleep.
Please, dear, let's leave
here now, tonight.
I want to, Ann,
but...I can't.
Why not?
Charles, why not?
[THUNDER]
[DIGGING]
Over a whole week
he's been there,
and what's
he been doing?
That's what
I want to know.
What's he been doing?
Getting ready,
that's what.
And meanwhile,
we sit here like sheep.
Willet, I thought
you said he'd be gone.
I thought he would be,
but you made him feel
so welcome,
he's probably decided
to stay for good.
Go on, sneer.
You can afford to.
You have no halfwitted
thing locked in your attic
and no woman
to worry about, either.
Weeden, I've got this
whole town to worry about.
The man you fear
is dead!
Can't you fools get that
through your heads?
He died over
100 years ago.
He can't harm you
or your women.
Well, don't you
forget, doctor,
that the man who died
over 100 years ago...
He did this!
And now...he's back
with us again.
He'll...he'll be
doing more.
Unless we stop him.
[SIMON AND JABEZ GROANING]
ANN: Charles?
Charles, where have
you been?
Out walking.
At this time
of night?
Yes, at this time
of night!
Must I report my movements
to you like a schoolboy?
No, of course not--
then mind
your own business.
Charles,
what's happened to you?
Nothing whatsoever.
No, you've changed.
I've never seen
you like this.
Charles, if you won't
go back to Boston,
at least let me
call Dr. willet.
No.
I shall be calling
on Dr. willet
personally
within the week.
Well, now,
are you satisfied?
Yes--
well, then
go back to bed!
What will you be doing?
That is not your concern.
Good night.
Good night, Charles.
Ann.
CURWEN: Charles Dexter Ward.
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone!
CURWEN: I will never
leave you alone.
Your blood is my blood,
your mind is my mind,
your body, my body.
It will do you
no good to resist me.
Your efforts grow
weaker every day.
No. No!
You cannot
keep me out, Ward.
My will is too strong.
Too strong for you, Ward.
Too strong for you.
Why are you spying on me?
I heard voices.
Tomorrow you must leave.
Now, is that understood?
Yes, Charles.
Now go to your bed.
You lost him?
For a time.
He has a strong will,
stronger than we thought.
But you did well.
He has the curwen strain.
Hester.
[WIND HOWLING]
Charles?
Charles, where are you?
[DOOR CREAKING]
Charles?
[CREAKING]
[SQUEAKING]
[GASP]
Charles?
[CREAKING]
[GASP]
Charles?
Charles, is that you?
SIMON: Mrs. Ward,
I heard sounds.
Thought we
had prowlers.
Vivat. Vivat. Vivat!
It was his wife.
Where is she now?
In her room.
Did you lock it?
Yes.
Stupid woman.
She doesn't know
what it is to love.
[SPEAKING LATIN]
[WOLF HOWLING]
Charles!
Joseph, it has
been too long.
No. No, we will
continue trying.
Yes, Joseph, as you say.
We'll continue trying.
Simon.
Simon, help me
upstairs quickly.
Oh, yes.
JOSEPH: Quickly,
quickly, quickly.
[KEY RATTLING IN LOCK]
Charles!
Charles, I've
been so afraid.
Oh, Ann...Ann...
What is it?
What's happened? Tell me.
I don't know.
It's this house.
I think I must be
going out of my mind.
Ann, where have I
been tonight?
Don't you remember?
No. I'm so confused.
Ann, we've got to get out of
here before it's too late.
Yes, dear.
Tomorrow morning.
Yes, we will.
Mr. Ward?
Yes?
Leaving so soon?
That's right.
Any objections?
Why, certainly
not, sir, but I...
well...
Well, you see
I can make no plans
until I know what you want
to do with the palace.
We're selling it.
Oh, I see.
Well, sir, could
you issue a check
for the week's
expenses?
All right. How much?
I'll get
the receipts.
No, that won't
be necessary.
How much?
We're in a hurry.
It'll only take
a moment, sir.
You go out
to the coach.
I'll...I'll join
you in a minute.
Mrs. Ward.
Oh, doctor.
You almost missed us.
We were just leaving.
Very wise decision, particularly
under the circumstances.
What do you mean?
Did something happen?
I'm afraid so.
In fact, I was on
my way to warn you,
but it doesn't matter now.
Doctor, please,
I'd like to know.
There was a rather ugly
occurrence last night.
In Arkham?
In the cemetery.
A grave was dug up
and a body stolen.
Nobody knows who did it,
but the people,
as you might well imagine,
are blaming it
on your husband.
Why?
The grave that was opened was
that of Hester Tillinghast,
Joseph Curwen's mistress.
And...they
think Charles...
Oh, what's wrong
with those people?
They're stupid to the
marrow of their bones.
You know who robbed that
grave, don't you, doctor?
No.
They did.
They?
Weeden and his dirty
little friends.
Why would
they do that?
Why? Well, isn't
it obvious?
To frighten me.
To drive me away
from my home.
WILLET: It's
a possibility...
but you don't think I
did it, do you, doctor?
No, but it's a good thing
you're leaving, all the same.
But I'm not leaving.
Charles,
you promised.
You can go back to
that village, doctor.
You can go back
and tell those people
that Charles Dexter Ward
has decided to stay.
Charles.
How long has he
been like this?
It...it started
the first night...
just for a little while, and
then he was himself again.
But it kept
happening.
What kept happening?
This...this change.
I'm so afraid. I've never
seen him like this.
Mrs. Ward, I want you to tell
me exactly what has happened
since your arrival
in Arkham.
I have him now.
Are you sure?
Charles Dexter Ward
is dead.
Then we can
begin our work.
Not quite yet.
There are a few little
things I must do first.
Oh, Joseph, can't you
forget what happened?
Forget?
Forget that my flesh
was burned from my bones
while I was yet alive? No.
No, this village will pay for
its crime, just as I vowed.
But the work.
The work?
There can be no work
without my knowledge.
We've waited 110 years.
We can wait a bit longer.
I'm not an alienist,
Mrs. Ward,
but there can be little doubt
as to what's happening.
Your husband is reacting
to the legend of his ancestor.
The attitude of the village,
the remarkable resemblance
between him and the figure
in the portrait,
the atmosphere of the castle
are all working together
to cause this aberration.
Then I--I've got to
find a way to help him.
You're not going
back in there?
Yes. What else can
I do? Leave him?
I would advise it.
But, then, of course,
you can't.
No.
Promise me one thing,
Mrs. Ward--
that you'll contact me if
things get out of hand.
Yes, I will, doctor.
Thank you.
Why have you
returned?
Because you
need me.
Perhaps
you're right.
Come here where
I can see you.
Do you love me?
Yes.
Then kiss me.
Why do you
hesitate?
Surely a husband
has certain rights.
I demand
that you kiss me!
Oh, what delights
we'll share,
we two! What tender,
intimate delights!
[LAUGHING]
Maybe it was
a leprechaun.
It's nothing to
laugh at, Bruno.
I say, who but the devil
would do such a thing?
SMITH: Well, he couldn't
have lifted it alone.
Sure not, but remember the
two that worked with him.
They was never caught.
MAN: Aye, or maybe it was Dr.
willet gave 'em a hand.
WEEDEN: Naw. Willet's a fool,
all right, but he's one of us.
Remember--it was his
great-great grandfather
who helped with
the burning.
And yours that
held the torch.
And it was yours
that did the burning,
and don't be
forgetting that!
Forget it?
I'm proud of it!
In fact, I've been thinking
along the same lines myself.
I'll be no part
of murderin'!
Who said murdering?
Me? Did I say
murdering?
MAN: Well, what
are you talking about?
Self-protection.
That's what I'm talking about!
A man threatens
your life
and you have
the means to stop him,
what do you do?
He's done no
threatening.
Not yet,
but he will!
First this unholy business
at the cemetery.
Next, our women
will start wandering out
late at night,
eyes all glassy,
bellies filled
with God knows what.
Then you'll see!
I say this to you,
all of you.
If we do nothing but sit
around and talk about it,
then we deserve
whatever we get!
[COINS RATTLE]
Now, good night
to you!
[GROWLING]
[SNARLING]
Get away!
Get away, you damned thing!
MINISTER:
The lord giveth,
and the lord
taketh away.
Blessed be the name
of the lord.
In this veil
of tears...
we suffer much
and sin mightily.
Yet we take solace
in the promise
of thy eternal
forgiveness.
CONGREGATION:
Amen. Amen. Amen.
Oh! Ah!
[SCREAMING]
Joseph, have
you not gorged
yourself enough
on revenge?
You do not know the extent
of my appetite, Simon.
I will not have
my fill of revenge
until this village
is a graveyard...
until they have felt,
as I did,
the kiss of fire
on their soft, bare flesh.
All of them.
Have patience, my friends.
Surely after
all these years,
I'm entitled to
a few...small amusements.
What do you want?
What do I want?
Merely to exercise my
husbandly prerogative.
Is there anything so
strange about that?
Charles, please--
please?
Please what,
my dear?
Oh, I know.
You're upset because
I've neglected you.
That's it, isn't it?
Well, I've been
very busy,
but I'm back now.
Charles!
No!
We have the whole
night before us!
Stop it! No!
No!
Stop! No!
You fool!
You stupid, weak
little fool!
Hester. Hester!
It is useless.
No...I will
try again!
Oh, doctor!
Thank God you've come!
Why? What's
happened?
I don't know.
Something terrible!
Well,
where is he?
I--
look, Mrs. Ward,
you must calm yourself.
Then you must
tell me everything,
sparing no detail.
Your life and your husband's
may depend upon it.
Yes, doctor.
Well, we were up
in the bedroom
a short time ago.
And then,
all of a sudden,
he...
Doctor, you've got
to help me
get him out
of here!
This place is
killing him!
Joseph Curwen--
he's killing him!
Look at him.
That filthy, horrible
old man! I hate him!
I hate him! I hate him!
Mrs. Ward!
I'm sorry, doctor.
It was a stupid
thing to do.
WARD: Yes, it was.
How are you, doctor?
Excellent, thank you.
Glad to hear it.
Well, this is a pleasant surprise.
What brings
you here?
WILLET: Nothing
in particular.
Oh, just looking
in, eh?
That's right.
Do you mind?
Mind? No. On the contrary.
I'm delighted,
and so is my wife.
Aren't you, my dear?
Here. A little glass of wine
will make you feel better.
ANN: I don't
want any.
The doctor and I are going
to have a little chat,
so you will just stay
here and rest, eh?
There you are.
Come, doctor.
She sent for you,
of course.
No, as I was--
there's no need
to lie, doctor.
In a way, I'm glad. I've been
terribly upset about her.
This house has a
strange effect on her.
How do you mean?
Well, you saw how
she acted a moment ago.
That sort of thing.
Fits of depression,
anger, hallucinations.
I hoped it would pass, but
she gets worse every day.
WILLET: I see.
I suppose she
told you how--
how I've begun
to change?
Yes.
Mm-hmm, part of
the pattern.
I scarcely recognize
her anymore, doctor.
My own wife.
What do you
want me to do?
Take her back
to Boston.
Get her out
of this house.
Why don't you?
She wouldn't
permit it.
She fears me.
Can't you understand?
Yes, I think I can.
Then you will help?
I shall try.
Thank you.
I appreciate it.
But remember--
discretion.
She mustn't guess that
you know the truth.
Well, my dear, I have
a surprise for you.
You won't have to stay
in this place any longer.
The good doctor is
going to take care of you.
ANN: Dr. Willet!
WARD: Yes, it's all
arranged.
He will see you
to Boston.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
Doctor, you don't
understand!
Come along,
Mrs. Ward.
No! I won't go!
Please, Mrs. Ward.
All right.
You needn't bother
to pack, my dear.
I'll send your
things along.
Goodbye, doctor.
Goodbye, my dear.
We'll be together
again soon.
I promise.
SIMON: What
of his woman?
We're rid of her.
Did you--
no, it was
not necessary.
I convinced
the good Dr. Willet
that she had begun
to lose her mind,
to imagine
strange things,
even that her own husband
had turned against her.
They'll
lock her away.
But if Dr. Willet
should return?
He will learn that
Charles Dexter Ward
has retired to his
new england estate.
WARD: Well, do you
know of any law
prohibiting a man from
residing on his own property?
Now, let us
begin again.
[SPEAKING LATIN INCANTATION]
MAN: Well, you can see what
happened to poor Gideon.
What are we going
to do about it?
MAN: Let's do
something!
Let's get him!
What's happened?
MAN: Don't you really know
what happened, Mrs. Curwen?
My name is Ward.
No, I don't know.
We came to see
Gideon.
Then come and see.
There's Gideon...
and each and every one of us
unless we do
something about it.
Just a minute. Do you
know how this happened?
It didn't just
happen, doctor.
It was caused
to happen.
WILLET: By whom?
Do you know
who did it?
Aye, and so
do you.
Who?
The man who
swore to do it.
The man you call
Charles Dexter Ward.
My husband would
never do such a thing!
MAN: She's lying!
They're all in this!
Mrs. Ward, you better
come along with me.
Where are we
going?
Back to
the palace.
We've got to get
him away from there
before these people
decide to take
matters into
their own hands.
Vivat...Vivat...
Vivat.
WILLET: Whoa!
Doctor, I'm going
with you!
Don't be foolish!
Wait here until I come back!
I'm going with you!
Then we must hurry!
MAN: Lucien,
you got the ropes?
Here!
Elijah?
Aye!
All right, then!
Let's be about it!
[MOB CHEERING]
WILLET: Mrs. Ward!
ANN: Did you
find him?
No.
Well, what about
Simon?
Who?
The caretaker.
I didn't see
anyone.
I know Charles
is here!
Is there any more
to the place
than we've seen?
I don't know.
Wait a minute.
When you tried to
destroy the picture,
suddenly he was
in the room.
Did you see him
come in?
No.
Neither did I.
[HOLLOW KNOCKING]
WILLET: Ward?
Ward!
Charles Dexter Ward!
Are you down here?
Don't!
It's only a book.
It's much more
than a book.
Oh, my God!
What did you see?
WARD: What a pleasant surprise.
Well, now that you've
seen all of the palace,
Dr. Willet, what do
you think of it?
It's quite old,
you know--
older than you
might imagine.
Torquemada spent many a happy
hour here a few centuries ago.
It was old then.
WILLET: Mr. Ward--
WARD: Well, I'll
admit the furnishings
do leave something
to be desired,
but, uh, it has a lived-in
quality, don't you think?
After all, home is
where the heart is.
Isn't that so,
my dear?
Ward, listen to me!
I'd be happy to,
doctor,
but my friends
grow impatient.
WARD: Oh, please
forgive me.
May I present
miss Hester Tillinghast,
Mr. Simon Orne, and Mr. Jabez
Hutchinson I believe you know.
They are my associates.
You see, we began
a project a few years ago,
but, unfortunately,
it was--it was interrupted,
and we're most anxious
to take it up again.
WILLET: What sort
of a project?
The most important ever attempted
of humans, Dr. Willet--
more important than you
can ever imagine,
and therefore, I fear,
beyond your understanding.
As a matter of fact, we don't
fully understand ourselves.
We obey. That is all.
We obey.
Simon!
Come!
Come, I said!
WARD: Hester! Jabez!
No! Stop!
Charles!
[SOBBING]
[SPEAKING LATIN]
Charles!
What are you
doing to her?
Honoring her,
Dr. Willet.
Honoring her.
[GROWLING]
Aah!
ANN: Charles!
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
MAN: Joseph Curwen!
Joseph Curwen!
Maybe we'll just
smoke him out!
[ANN SCREAMING]
Ann!
[ANN SCREAMS]
WARD: Ann! Ann!
Ann!
Charles!
Ann! Poor Ann!
ORNE: You traitor!
WARD: Dr. Willet,
get her away from here!
Get her away from here,
Dr. Willet!
Take her away!
Get her away from here!
WILLET: Quickly!
Quickly!
ANN: What about Charles?
I'll come back
for him!
[COUGHING]
They're
finished.
No!
[MOB MURMURING]
Charles!
WILLET: Are you
all right?
WARD: Yes...thanks
to you and to my wife.
I don't know
how I can ever repay you
for what you've done,
Dr. Willet.
But I intend to try.
Charles, are you sure
you're all right?
Perfectly sure, my dear.
Perfectly sure.