[Frogs Croaking,
Crickets Chirping]
[ThunderCrashes]
[Woman] Oh, thankyou.
They'reprettypeaches.
- Yes, ma'am.
- So, how you been ?
I'm pretty good,
I reckon.
You had any health problems
since I saw you last ?
- Ma'am ?
- Have you been sick ?
Well, back's been
hurtin' a little.
No, no, it's not your back.
Have you been
bleeding somewhere ?
Well--
- Yes, ma'am, a little.
- Yeah.
- Have you been to a doctor ?
- Oh, I--
I don't much like
going to no doctors.
Well, I think
maybe you should go.
No, it's not
a venereal disease.
I just think it's some kind of
kidney or some bladder infection.
But it's been around
for a while.
Could lead to some
more serious problems.
Do you want me
to call a doctor foryou ?
- All right.
- Okay.
You kidsget on to bednow.
It'snearIy 9.:00.
Ah, Mama, can I stay up
just a little bit ?
No.
You heard me, mister.
- Mama ?
- Hmm ?
What does ''fuck'' mean ?
It's a bad word, hon,
for something nice.
But what does it mean ?
Well, it means making love.
It's how your daddy and me
made your brothers and you.
Take his turtles off, hon.
- Mike, did you hear me ?
- What ?
I said get to bed.
Oh, Mike, your lip's
dragging the floor.
- It's gonna freeze like that.
- You act Iike I'm a kid.
You are a kid, honey.
VaIerie, you mayas weII
takeyourgIasses off.
-Iknowhe'sbeen hittingyou again.
-[ Chuckles ]
- I see your lip.
- Oh, no.
Oh, it--
itjust embarrasses me.
It's okay.
Come on.
Hegot worse.
I went to the store yesterday
'cause we's out ofsome things.
And he got home from work early,
before I could get back.
He was waiting with a razor strap.
My legs are all cut up.
And I got welts the size of
footballs on my back and my legs.
I feel guilty, you payin' me money
to tell you to get away from him.
You got to get help.
- Legal help.
- You don't know Donnie Barksdale.
He'll kill me if I leave him.
He'll fiind me.
He said he would.
No, he's not crazy enough
to kill anybody.
He'sjust
an insecure redneck.
What ?
Um,
I think he's got
a woman on the side.
Yeah, he's been
laying out at night.
[Knock On Door]
Excuse me,
but the school's on the phone.
Theysay Mike's
in some kindoftroubIe.
Mrs. Wilson.
Hi. Come on in.
Have a seat.
- Uh, where-- where's Mike ?
- He's in the infiirmary.
Now, it's nothing to get
worked up about. He's fiine.
He's got a few, um--
Sit down.
He's got a few,
uh, nicks and bruises.
I think he might have a-- have
a pretty good black eye by tomorrow.
But he's, uh--
he's okay.
- He was in another fiight ?
- Yes, he was.
His grades are, uh-- are getting
worse too. How's he doing at home ?
Um, not much better.
He's real distant.
Mm-hmm.
Well, Mrs. Wilson,
I don't pretend to be
a psychologist, but, um,
it's obvious to me that your boy's
got a lot ofanger in him.
Well, um, it's about this time
last year his daddy passed away.
He's still real
messed up over it.
Yeah. I never knew your husband.
I understand he was a fiine man.
Yes, he was.
Well, I don't know how you
feel about therapy, but, uh--
Ifyou think Mike needs somebody to
talk to, I know a gentleman over--
Mike doesn't need a therapist,
Mr. Collins. He can talk to me.
Do you think he will, though ?
I'm sorry, Wayne. Ididn 't know
you hadanybody in here.
- Oh, hi. Um--
- Ruby wasn't at her desk.
Yeah, she's out sick today. Uh,
Mrs. Wilson, this isJessica King,
- my fiancee.
- Nice to meet you.
You too.
We'rejust going to be
a couple of minutes. Okay.
Uh, I gotta go anyway.
I got people waiting.
Thanks a lot,
Mr. Collins.
- I'm real sorry about all this.
- Oh, it's myjob.
He'sjust a boy,
that's all.
You're not that Wilson that's
a fortune-teller, are you ?
I don't call myselfthat.
- I'd love you to read my fortune.
- I'm pretty booked up.
Do you think we'll live
happily ever after ?
[Jessica]
What's the matter?
You see something bad ?
Ofcourse not.
No, I'm sureyou'II
be reaIhappytogether.
[ TV Chatter,
Indistinct ]
[ Television Continues ]
- Hey, how you gettin' along today ?
- I'm fiine, Buddy.
Except the fact Ican't keep mycar
doorfromjust flying right open.
Have you got the time
to fiix it ?
I-I-I can get to it, uh,
about an hour or two.
Uh, you wanna wait ?
Uh, no. Uh, I got to get home.
I got people coming.
Hey, you just want--
you just wanna leave it here,
and I'll--
I'll carry you on home ?
I can have it to you by-- probably
by 6:00. That gonna be all right ?
- Yeah, yeah, that's fiine.
- All right. All right.
- Buddy ?
- Yeah ?
Uh, I'm a little-- I'm
a little low on my money this week.
-I wasjust wondering if--
-Don't you worry about-- No, really.
- No, stop it. Oh, come on, look.
- I feel bad.
For all that
you've done for me,
I just-- I just think
the world ofyou.
You're about the only one
I call a friend to me.
Thankyou.
Yeah, you know.
Annie.
I'IIget the truck.
Take your time.
[Annie]
Howyou been, Buddy ?
I've been having some, uh--
some bad thoughts lately.
But I, you know--
Yesterday, I was feeling so happy.
- Yeah ?
- I was feeling on top ofthe world.
Good on you.
I-I-I didn't even feel
like I needed my medicine.
I took it anyway.
[ Laughs ]
You know, I'm getting--
I'm getting hooked on that stuff.
Well, I thinkyou're gonna have
a lot of happy days, Buddy.
Yeah, you're gonna
get better and better.
Well, uh, I believe you
when you say so.
Buddy ?
Honey ?
- Honey, what's wrong ?
- [ Exhales ]
You have to tell me.
You have to tell me now.
I'll-- I'll tell you, hon.
If I look
into a blue diamond...
and I think
a negative thought,
am I gonna die ?
No.
Mm-mmm.
You're not gonna die.
You're not gonna die,
Buddy.
[ Crying ] Oh, my God !
Oh, my God ! Oh, my God !
Oh, look--
Okay. Well, thankyou.
'Cause ifyou had said ''yes,''
I would have to kill myself
before the sun goes down.
- Oh, Buddy. Oh, honey.
- [ Sobbing ]
You don't have
to kill yourself, honey.
- You know I'll always tell you.
- Oh, man.
- I'll always tell you, Buddy.
You're fiine. You can always
talk to me, Buddy. Always.
- Oh, don't use that, honey.
- I feel embarrassed.
- No. Here. Huh ?
- Oh, no.
- I can't soil that.
- Buddy, I want you to have it.
- This one'sBen's. Idon't--
- He'd want you to have it.
Thankyou.
- You all right ?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, I'm all right.
- All right.
I-I can walk home. You don't
have to drive me. You can--
No, no. No, I'm-- I'm good.
I'm good. [ Laughs ]
- Yeah ? You sure scared me, hon.
- Oh, yeah.
No, I'm all right.
I'm all right.
All right. You just take it
nice and slow.
- Nice and slow.
- [ Exhales ]
[Tapping]
[Knock On Door]
Could I help you ?
Yes, ma'am.
I'm Donnie Barksdale.
I'm sorry to botheryou so late, but
I believe you know my wife Valerie.
Yes, I do.
I know who you are.
Can I come in
and talk to you ?
It's about my wife.
Something's happened to her.
What's happened ?
She okay ?
Well, no, she's not, ma'am.
Ma 'am, Ipromise.
I'IIjust take a minute.
All right.
Come on.
What's happened is she's getting
her head fiilled full ofshit...
by a goddamn
Satan worshipper.
Ora damngoodcon artist,
one ofthe two.
Iknowshe'sbeen coming over
to seeyou andyourdamn voodoo.
You tell her bad things
about me, don't you ?
You ain't no better
than aJew or a nigger.
Do you know
what this is ?
It's a voodoo doll.
I'm going to use this voodoo doll
on you, some ofyour own medicine.
Ifyou don't stop
seeing my wife,
I'm stickin' me a pin
in this thing every night...
till you learn
to leave folks alone.
Go back to bed.
Everything's fine.
I bet you love those
little children, don't you ?
And I bet they need
their mama, don't they ?
- What's your name ?
- Get your ass out of my house !
Don't you threaten me or my kids.
Now, what I do here is my business.
Ifyour wife has any sense,
she'll leave you so far behind,
you'll never fiind her.
Now you get out of here
before I have you thrown in jail.
Messing with the Devil
is gonna get you burned.
Everybody knows that.
I'll see you soon, boys.
Go back to bed.
Come on.
[EngineStarts]
[Tires SqueaIing]
- Something smeIIs Iike catpee.
- It'sperfume, Ben.
And you're not supposed to cuss
in front ofappointments.
Something smells like cat pee.
- Something smells like cat pee.
- Be quiet!
[ Chuckles ]
He's got a great sense of humor.
- Oh, he loves you.
- [DoorOpens]
[Annie] VaIerie. Oh, honey,
y-you know, youshouIdn 't be here.
I'm sorry about
the other night.
Oh, that's okay.
I can take care of myself.
And I hate
coming over here, but--
I really need
to talk to you.
Maybe you could read for me.
Under a bridge or something.
All right, I'll read foryou. But
you got to start listening to me.
I can't leave him.
Don't you understand ?
Hon, he's gonna keep hurting you
till he puts you in the hospital.
I don't have anything
to look forward to.
Maybe you can
give me some hope.
Oh, Valerie, hon, I don't know
how to make myselfany clearer--
- [Donnie] VaIerie !
- Oh, Annie ! Annie, it's him ! No !
- Calm down. I'll call the law.
- No. No.
No, Annie, no ! Ifyou're
my friend, you won't ! No !
I'll deal with you later,
you goddamn bitch !
You witch !
Get your ass in the truck !
That ain't fast enough !
- ItoIdyou not to come here !
- [ Screaming ]
- You let her go !
- All right ! All right !
- [Donnie] Get in !
- Mike, you stay there !
[ Donnie ]
What did I fucking tell you ?
[ Valerie ]
All right ! Ow ! Ow !
SweetJesus.
Mike ? Y'all bring
Miss Francis her clothes.
Thanks, hon.
Granny.
[Woman]
Hey, AnnabeIIe.
Gran-- Granny,
what are you doing here ?
I brought you
some persimmons, hon.
Remember how you liked persimmons
when you was little ?
Hmm ?
Granny, you're not
supposed to be here.
How-- How'd you get here ?
Oh, it ain't far to walk.
Ohh !
That boy's got
your granddaddy's eyes.
Well, hon,
I better get back.
Looks like
there's a storm coming.
No, Granny,
it-- it's clear.
Uh-uh.
[WindBIowing,
ThunderRumbIing]
Annie, aIways use
yourinstinct, honey.
@ I've been asleep
when teardrops come to stay @
@ It hurts me, but I know @
@@@It'sjust
mysentimentaI way@@@@@@
Now you tell Miss Francis
I'll be home by 9:30, okay ?
- [ Ben ] Bring back something.
- All right, I promise.
- I love you too, Mama.
- I know. And I love you too, hon.
- Be good. Bye.
- [ Boys ] Bye, Mama.
- [ Sighs ]
- You ready ?
I don't know why
I let you talk me into this.
'Cause it's time you quit
living like a nun, that's why.
Don't worry. You're going to be
the prettiest girl here, next to me.
You still a married man ?
I don't know about that.
- Oh, thankyou.
- Thankyou very much.
- Do we pay him now or--
- Uh-uh. I sign for it later.
- Is it good ?
- Mmm.
- Annie, there he is.
- Who ?
Thatguy I-- ThatguyI was
teIIingyou about. Lookat him.
He's right overthere bythe bar.
Don't he IookIikeAntonio Banderas?
Oh, my God ! He saw me ! Shit !
He saw me staring at him.
All right, get your cards out. Tell
me if he's gonna come over here.
I don't have my cards with me.
I am off-duty.
HeIIo, Mrs. WiIson.
- It's Annie.
- Sit down. You're bIocking my view.
Oh.
- Sorry. You rememberJessica ?
- Hi, Annie.
I didn't know you were a member
ofthe country club.
I'm not.
I kind oftagged along with Linda.
- How nice. It's a great outfiit.
- Thankyou.
- What's Mike up to tonight ?
- Moping around his baby-sitters.
Yeah ? He's--
He's a great kid.
I was actually thinking you should
have him come down to school and--
Come on, Wayne. Let's not talk
shop tonight, all right ?
- Let'sjust have fun.
- Okay.
- Hi there, fun-seekers.
- Hey, there.
- How about a dance with Daddy ?
- Ofcourse I will, handsome.
[Wayne]Mr. King, Idon't know
ifyou know, uh, Annie WiIson.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
I think I've seen you at church.
- That is quite a dress, Miss Linda.
- I'm glad somebody noticed.
- You want to give it a try ?
- Oh, no. No, I don't think so.
No, thankyou.
Come on. I asked you to dance,
not walk on hot coals.
When was the last time
you danced ?
I think it's so long,
I've forgotten how to do it.
Well, I'll make you look good then,
'cause I'm a terrible dancer.
[Linda]
Wayne.
I'll dance.
- Good luck.
- Yeah.
Missed your big chance.
@@@@@@[Country]
@@@ WeII, I'm doin'mybest not
to open with ''I Ioveyou''@@@@@@
@@ [ Stops ]
Thankyou.
Ohh !
Somebody
might come in here.
I guess you
better fuck me fast.
[Jessica Moans]
You having a good time ?
- Me neither.
- [ Laughs ]
YouseenJessica around?
She up and disappeared on me again.
She's got a way ofdoing that.
- What do you think ofJessica ?
- She's-- She's very beautiful.
Yeah, the main thing
about her, she'sjust...
so full of life.
We're a little different
in that respect.
Oh.
I'm used to tennis shoes.
This kind of reminds me
when I was a kid.
I'd sit out on that porch.
I'd have so many thoughts,
just couldn't count 'em.
How'd you
wind up in Brixton ?
My husband. He got a job here
at the cable plant.
Right.
What ?
Did-- Did you know...
something was going
to happen to your husband ?
In an E.S.P. kind ofway ?
- Well, I don't know--
- You don't believe in it.
I don't know.
I guess I just--
I don't believe there
are any great mysteries in life.
Ikindoffigure what
yousee is whatyouget.
Well,
I didn't know that there
was going to be an explosion.
But... the night before,
Ihadthis reaIbad,
bad dream, you know.
I dreamt that I was all by myself.
That Ben--
He wasn't
around anymore and...
tried to stop him going to work
the next day, but--
So you can't keep
a good man from work, right ?
Mm-hmm.
You kind
of remind me of him.
[Jessica]
Wayne ?
- I've been looking foryou.
- I've been right here.
I see.
- Hi.
Let's go talk to Daddy.
He's feeling real depressed tonight.
That big deal
he's working on went bad.
Oh, we got a major crisis
here, Annie. Excuse us ?
- Okay.
- Bye.
[Ben]
Seeyou Iater, aIIigator.
- In a while, crocodile.
- Good night, boys.
Go to sleep for Mama.
- What's that, hon ?
- Blueberry muffiins.
Whatcha doin' with muffiins
in your pockets ?
Miss Francis cooked them.
Yeah, but what are they
doing in your pockets ?
They're in my pockets 'cause I put
'em there when she wasn't looking...
so I didn't
have to eat them.
- Her blueberry muffiins is terrible.
- [CIunking]
Uh, y'all wait here a minute.
Take Ben, hon.
[PreacherOn TV,
Indistinct]
[CIanking]
When God's fighting foryou,
everysoIdier's important.
Goddoesnotgive
one to the DeviI.
IfeverychiIdofGod
obeyedGod,
the DeviIcannot
wipeyou out.
He cannot takeyou out
beforeyourtime.
Ifyou obey God,
Idon't care what the DeviI...
haspIaceduponyourIife,
Jesus can deIiveryou.
Jesus came to bringyou
out ofyourprison house.
- Mama, is everything okay ?
- Yeah, everything's fiine.
- You sure ?
- Yeah. Time foryou to go to bed.
I know him. He's
a squirrel-hunting buddy of mine.
- But I-I don't think that Donnie--
- I'm telling you it was him.
What makes you think he'd want
to bust into your house ?
Well, his wife,
she's a client of mine,
and he thinks I'm trying
to break up their marriage.
Are you ?
Listen, um,
Donnie's high-strung.
Uh, you know,
ain't no doubt about that.
But I don't think he's the one
that busted into your house.
Listen, I appreciate the coffee
and everything. Take care.
[Buddy] Ijust can'tget through
a waIIofsome kindin myhead...
or, uh-- ormysouI.
Sometimes I don't
even know the difference...
between my head or my soul.
I think everybody
has that trouble, Buddy.
All right.
Your daddy--
He took things
away from you when you--
when you were a little boy.
Do you understand that ?
He-- He seen me playing around with
something, like a toy or something,
he'd just
take it away from me.
Did he take other things
away from you ?
[ Laughs ]
Buddy--
- Um--
- You got to fiind out, hon,
why you hate him so much.
My daddy's a good man.
I don't hate my dad.
He's good to Mama and me.
Every kid needs a hit with a belt
sometime. I mean-- [ Chuckles ]
Buddy, you got to try to get past
this wall that you're talking about.
Hon, you need to talk
about your daddy.
Why don't you tell me why I hate
him ? You're the goddamn psychic !
Huh ?
You're the goddamn psychic !
I think I better go.
I-I have to go home,
um,
right now.
I'm sorry
I yelled at you.
It's all right.
I-Ijust need--
Ijust needyourheIp.
Ijust keep thinkingabout that bIue
diamond. Ikeep thinkingabout--
Buddy, ifyou think about these
things in your childhood, hon,
and you face up to them,
then I will be able to help you.
Iknow, hon.
Ijust--
I thinkyou got to do
some thinking on your own.
Okay.
Oh. [ Laughs ]
You-- Ahh !
- [Phone Rings]
- I'll help you there.
- Okay, you put it up there.
- Hey, Ben.
- Hello ?
- You got a lot of pretty things.
I liked looking at them.
You ever seen anybody
skin a squirrel ?
You stick a knife
in its belly and zip.
That's what I'm going to do
to you and your children...
you ever call
the police again.
I did not.
Ow ! Ow !
Ow ! Ow ! Ow !
[ Both Laughing ]
Mama ?
Hey.
- How come you're not asleep ?
- Idon't know.
- What's that bat for?
- Oh.
Don't worry, honey.
I'm-- I'm just working on my swing.
How come we never go
to the cemetery and see Daddy ?
Well, we went out there
just last month on his birthday.
Honey, I'm real busy,
you know that.
Well, it seems like you have time
for a lot ofstrangers.
Ifwe're talking about my
appointments, they're not strangers.
They're the ones
that put food on our table.
But howcome we don't
even taIkabout Daddy ?
Go on, Mike.
I'm trying to read.
[ Gasps ]
[ Bell Clanging ]
- Annie ?
- We're going to have to frame that.
- It'sjust a painting.
- That's beautiful.
- Annie.
- Hey.
Hey, listen. I know why Kenneth King
wasn't in church today.
- Put your belt on. Why ?
- 'Cause his daughter disappeared.
-Jessica ?
- Mm-hmm.
What do you mean
she disappeared ?
Well, Kenneth woke up this morning
and Jessica wasn't there,
and her bed
hadn't even been slept in.
Annie, you think
she ran off ?
I know her and Wayne were
supposed to be married inJune.
- Maybe she got cold feet.
- Maybe.
Maybe this will clear
the way foryou and Wayne.
- What are you talking about ?
- Oh, come on.
I saw the way y'all were looking
at each other Friday night.
Y'all both just
had stars in your eyes.
Oh, Linda, that's nuts.
- Yeah. Annie, love is nuts.
- Come on. Go home.
[ Laughing ] Listen,
I want you to get some rest.
You look terrible, okay ?
Bye, boys.
- I got to go.
- [Boys]Bye, MissLinda.
Ben, get your hand
out ofthere !
That's fory'all's
cake tonight.
-What am I gonna ice the cake with ?
-I like icin', Mama.
Yeah,
I can see that, punkin.
Miller !
Miller, hon, would you
go ask Miss Francis...
ifshe's got another
can of icing, please ?
- [Ben] Mama !
- I'm coming, Ben.
[ Engine Starts ]
Where you going, son ?
You wanna ride
in the truck ?
I got a question foryou.
You know my wife Valerie ?
She been around
to seeyourmama IateIy ?
Hey, boy,
I asked you a question.
Get my hat.
You know, I feel sorry
foryou and your brothers.
I mean, your mama
being a witch and all.
Ifshe don't stop
her evil ways,
some day somebody's
gonna burn her up.
And then you boys
are gonna be without a daddy...
or a mama.
Hey, MiIIer?
You aIIright ?
He said mama's a witch
and they're gonna burn her up.
Oh, he did ?
- You better mind your own business.
- I intend to, Donnie.
[ Yelling ]
[Donnie]
Motherfucker!
Goddamn it! Fuck!
- Look, fucker !
- [ Cocks Gun ]
Shoot me !
Shoot me,
you motherfucker !
Shoot me ! Shoot me !
You aIIright ?
[Annie]
Tuscan Rouge.
What was I thinking ?
I want icin', Mama.
Hon, you've had icing enough
to put you in a coma.
Andfrom nowon,
I want to know where you all are
every minute ofthe day.
All right ?
Mike, I'm gonna start
driving you and Miller to school.
I wish Daddy was here.
Well, he's not, hon.
But Mama is. Okay ?
[Phone Rings]
Eat your cake.
- Hello.
- Uh, this is Kenneth King.
- Mr. King.
- I imagine you, uh,
heard about
my daughter's disappearance ?
- Yes.
- Well, um--
Mrs. Wilson,
I don't believe in what you do.
I'll just be
straight with you.
Not only that, I don't like it. But
we've got to the end ofthe road...
andourinvestigation Iookedunder
everyrock there is to Iook under,
and we'd like you to tell us
what you can to help us.
Now, no hocus-pocus
and chanting and carrying on.
We knowyou taIk to a Iot offoIks,
knowa Iot offoIks'business.
You might have heard
something orsomething.
[Mr. King]
The onIything we knowis, uh,
one ofSheriffJohnson's men
found my daughter's car...
sitting out on the parking lot
ofthat honky-tonk called AyJay's.
But nobodythat was there
on Saturdaynight...
admits to havingseen her.
So I'm afraid she might have been
kidnapped or something ?
Oh, Mr. King,
I'm-- I'm sorry.
I don't know anything about
your daughter's disappearance.
I think
we werejust hoping--
Is there anything
you can tell us ?
I could read foryou.
But that-- that's
about all I could do.
I need you
to cut the cards for me.
Oh, boy.
Thankyou.
All right.
You ready ?
Okay.
When were you
getting married again, Wayne ?
-June 20--
- We're supposed to ask questions,
- notyou.
- Shut up, Pearl ! Goddamn it !
Look, I have a hard time
concentrating...
with more than one person
in the room.
Well, I'm staying right here. I'm
the law, and I need to hear this.
Please, ma'am, just--
just try to tell us
what you see.
I'm trying.
All right.
All right,
all I'm picking up--
it's like a--
it's a fence.
Like a split rail fence.
Do you know how many fences
there are in this county ?
And some pillars, like,
with an opening going through.
And there's lots ofwhite flowers.
I can-- I--
Y-Yes. And, uh,
is that whereJessie is ?
Oh.
Well, that's-- that's, um, all I'm--
all I'm seeing.
This isjust mishmash. I told you
this wouldn't lead to nothing.
You're right. It won't.
I can't concentrate.
- I can't do this now. I'm sorry.
- Please, ma'am.
I really do hope
you fiind your daughter.
But I'm-- I'm just not the person
to help you with this.
@@@@@@[FiddIe]
[ Playing Frantically ]
Hey, Butch.
[ Whimpers ]
[Annie]
Andit washorribIe.
But that same chain that was wrapped
around her when she was floatin',
you know, up in my tree, it was the
same chain that I had in my dream.
- Idon't know. Ijust thought--
- Dave ?
Yes, sir ?
IcouIdhavesworn there
wasan ecIairin there.
- I didn't get it.
- Uh-huh.
Tim was in
a little earlier.
So you saw all this
in a dream ?
It wasn'tjust a dream.
I don't investigate
somebody's dream.
I think she's dead, Sheriff.
And I think she's in a pond.
What do you know about this
you ain't telling me ?
Hmm ? You canget in serious
troubIe withhoIding information.
Does it sound like
a place you know ?
Yeah,
a bunch of places I know.
Split rail fence, a pond,
a stretch ofwoods.
- Every rawbone ol' boy got that.
- What about the fiiddler ?
Well,
ol' Tommy Lee Ballard
plays a fiiddle.
But he wouldn't kill nobody.
I've known him since he's a kid.
No, no, it's not the fiiddler.
Who are his neighbors ?
Well, his closest neighbor
would be, uh--
Well, let me see here.
I guess-- [ Inhales ]
Well, his property borders,
uh, Donnie Barksdale's place.
Doyou know
Donnie BarksdaIe ?
Ma 'am ?
Tim ! On the gate !
[Mr. King] You didget
a search warrant, didn 'tyou ?
I want everything
to be IegaIandproper.
Didn't have to.
Got permission from the owner.
Donnie BarksdaIe
gaveyoupermission--
His wife did.
I told her it was routine.
We're checking all the ponds
in the county.
[SheriffJohnson]
Donnie'sgone fishing today.
[ Chattering ]
[ VaIerie]
Excuse me. SheriffJohnson ?
- How much longery'all gonna be ?
- Long as it takes.
All right. You just said you're
gonna be a few minutes.
And we're
going on two hours.
Hey, Pearl !
I think I got something !
False alarm.
It'sjust an old bicycle.
None ofy'all brought a Thermos
ofcoffee out here ?
That day at school.
You looked kind ofstrange
at me and Jessica.
Did you think
something bad then ?
Shit.
Come on.
- Donnie, he called. I told him--
- Pearl !
Shut your mouth !
Goddamn it, Pearl,
what are you doing on my property ?
I'm on Sheriff's business, Donnie.
I got permission from your wife.
You think I let that
little ninny talk for me ?
How'd your arm
get all scratched up ?
Stray cat. She didn't like it
when I killed her.
- Now what brought you here ?
-Just routine investigation.
We're checking
all the ponds in the county.
- Iknewit wasyou.
- No ! You-- Uhh !
Hey ! I'm on County business,
Donnie. Don't fool with me.
- Hey, Pearl !
- What ?
- You need to take a look at this.
- Watch him.
HauIit up, boys !
- It's her !
- Donnie ?
Get those hooks
out of my baby !
- Get her offthem hooks ! Ohh !
- Cuff him !
- No ! No !
- Mr. King !
- No ! Ohh !
- Get an ambulance !
I think he's
having a heart attack !
- I didn't do this !
- Get him out of here !
This ain't right !
Pearl !
Bitch ! [ Spits ]
Bitch ! Bitch ! Pearl !
Come in.
Somebody might
come in here.
I guess you better
fuck me fast.
You want some coffee ?
Mrs. Wilson ?
No, thankyou.
Have a seat.
Why-- Why have you
called me here ?
Tomorrow Donnie Barksdale goes
on trial for murder...
and I feel
that we have a powerful case.
In fact,
today the coroner verifiied...
Donnie's tissue
under the victim's fiingernails.
Now, I only have one weak link
I got to worry about.
- What ?
- You.
Yousee, you're how we foundout
where the victim 'sbody was.
And how you found out,
well,
that might open up
a real can ofworms for us.
Psychic phenomena,
E.S.P., dreams, visions.
The defense
couIdgo to town onyou.
Andifthat'snot badenough,
Iunderstandthere wasbadbIood...
between you
and Donnie Barksdale.
Yeah.
He threatened my kids.
That's what Iheard. IaIso heard
thatyou threatenedhim right back.
ToIdhis wife
to Ieave him.
Donnie's quite
a ladies' man.
Wereyou invoIved
with him ?
- What ?
- Ican deaI with any reveIation...
right now.
But at the trial
there can't be any surprises.
So, is there anything I need
to know about you or Donnie...
orDonnie's wife
orthe victim ?
No.
Will that be all ?
Yes, ma'am.
You know, Mr. Duncan,
the victim had a name.
It wasJessica King.
Mr. Hawkins, howIonghaveyou
workedout atAyJay's ?
About ten years.
Now, were you working at AyJay's
on Saturday night, April 8 ?
- Yes, sir.
- Anddidyousee the defendant,
-Donnie BarksdaIe, there that night?
-Yes, sir.
Could you describe the circumstances
when you saw him ?
The circumstances were I come
outside to throw out some trash.
Anddoyou recaII
what time it was ?
About midnight,
I reckon.
Anyhow, Iseen Donnie BarksdaIe
out there byhis truck...
havin'an argument
with this white Iady.
Shescratchedhisarm
andhesIappedthe tarout ofher.
About that time,
Igo backinside.
Is this the woman
you saw with Donnie Barksdale ?
- Yes, sir.
- Your Honor, let the record show...
that I'vejust shown Mr. Hawkins
a photograph ofJessica King.
You just said that your attention
was drawn to the defendant's pond.
Drawn in--
Well, drawn in what way ?
Me, Wayne Collins
and Kenneth King...
went to see a woman,
name ofAnnie Wilson.
What made you think this woman
would be able to help you ?
Well, word around town
was that she was a,
uh--
- WeII, Idon't knowthe right word.
- Isn't it fortune-teller ?
-Iguessso.
-What didthis fortune-teIIersee...
when she looked into
her little crystal ball ?
Well, she didn't have no ball.
She had these, uh, special cards.
What did she see when she looked
into her little special cards ?
Uh, she didn't actually
see nothing then.
But next day,
she come to see me and...
told me
she had this dream.
- She had a dream ?
- Yes, sir.
She'd seen this pond and it looked
a lot like Donnie Barksdale's and...
then she woke up
from herdream...
andshe went outside
andIookedup in this tree.
I'm all ears.
She seenJessica King...
floatin' in the tree,
half-naked, with a chain
wrapped around her.
Floatin' around a tree ?
Yes, sir.
Floatin' in a tree,
haIf-naked,
with a chain
wrapped around her.
Thankyou, Sheriff.
That little squirrel,
Weems, isjust mean and skinny.
Neverhave known
a Weems worth a damn.
Well, he was
just doing hisjob.
Uh, Mrs. Wilson ?
Can I talk to you for a minute ?
- Um--
- Uh, just call me later on, okay ?
- Oh, okay.
- Okay, bye.
Buddy, I got a lot on my mind.
It's not a good time, okay ?
Um, Mrs. Wilson ?
You did tell me to do some thinkin'
and talkin'. And I've been thinkin'.
What ? What ?
Can you tell me why
I do things to myself...
when I think
about my daddy ?
All right, well--
Bud, you call me later, hon,
and we'll talk, all right ?
- I need to talk to you.
- Buddy.
I've been thinking about my daddy
and I've been touching myself.
- Touching yourself? How ?
- Why do I do that ?
It's not a good time.
- Something's bad wrong with me.
- Look, Buddy--
And I-- I keep thinking
about that blue diamond.
You look into the blue diamond,
you won't think a negative thought.
I promise. Now, hon, I'm going
through a hard time myself. I'm--
I just-- I can't talk
to you now, okay ?
[Man] You'regonna burn
in heII, Annie WiIson !
Now, Mike, Iknowyouskipped
schooIand went to that triaI.
- How'd you know ?
- A little bird told me.
It's time you started making things
easier on me instead of harder.
- [Phone Ringing]
- I'm very disappointed in you.
- The phone's ringing, Mama.
- Second ofall,
I'm gonna have to testify
at that trial tomorrow.
- The phone's ringing, Mama.
- I'm not deaf, Miller.
Let the machine get it.
Donnie Barksdale's side, they're
gonna try and give me a hard time.
They're gonna call me names
and I--
I just want y'all
to be prepared...
ifyou hear any bad stuff
about me, all right ?
Now, we're all gonna have to
be sticking together on this one.
[Woman]
Annie WiIson, it'sBuddy'smother.
Buddy's donegone crazy.
He's threatening to kiIIhis daddy!
He's got Odell tied up
in the backyard,
accusing him
of horrible things.
- Have you called the police ?
- He said if I did he'd kill Odell.
He wants you.
[ Buddy Sobbing ]
Hey, Buddy.
Buddy, put that strap down and
tell me what he's done to you.
I'm here, Buddy. Like you said,
you can talk to me, honey.
It's too late for that !
It's too goddamn late !
Thishere isa criminaI.
And he's gonna be punished.
Bud-Buddy.
Buddy, it's Annie.
- You shut up ! You shut up !
- It's all right.
- Get away ! Where were you ?
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You knew everything
and you did nothing.
You ruined me.
You ruined me !
I wasjust a little boy, Daddy.
It got so I was embarrassed
to go to school, Daddy.
How could you do that
to your little boy ?
No, Buddy. You put that down.
No, Buddy.
You put that down, Buddy.
You put that down. You listen to me.
You get away !
You get away ! Get away !
All right, Buddy. All right.
It's all right. Come on.
Why-- Why didn't
you help me, Annie ?
What ?
Why didn't you
help me ?
- I had you for a friend and then--
- I am your friend, Buddy.
Now I have nobody.
I have nobody !
But I'm gonna--
I'm gonna kill this thing.
- No !
- No, Buddy !
No !
Help me !
- HeIp me!
- Look at that goddamn thing.
Andyou teIIme what kind
ofthoughtsyou have ?
You Iook!
You Iook
into that thing !
[Sirens WaiIing]
[Duncan]
Mrs. WiIson ? Mrs. WiIson.
Mrs. Wilson, your husband,
Ben Wilson Senior,
was one ofthe men killed last year
in the explosion...
out at the Reinhold
Cable Plant.
Yes, that's right.
Andyou were Ieft with threesmaII
chiIdren to raise onyourown.
Yes, sir.
How do you provide
foryou and your sons ?
I get a little bit
of money from Social Security...
as a result
of my husband's death.
And, uh,
I also give readings.
- Psychic readings.
- Yes, sir.
What doesbeingpsychic
enabIeyou to do ?
I see things...
and I, you know--
I sense... things...
that-- well, they
hadn't happened yet...
orthey were happening
somepIace eIse.
My granny told me that I--
I had a gift that runs in my family.
And she told me that
I shouldn't be afraid of it.
I should just always use my instinct
and I'd-- I'd be all right.
So, you'reswearing
before this court...
that you didn't get your information
about this tragedy...
from any other means
than your special ability ?
- Your gift.
- Yes, sir.
I'm swearing that. Yes.
- Thankyou, Mrs. Wilson.
- Yes, sir.
- I have no further questions.
- [Judge]Mr. Weems.
[Weems]
Mrs. WiIson.
How many fiingers am I holding up
behind my back ?
- Objection, Your Honor.
- YourHonor,
my client is sitting in this
courtroom on trial for his life...
partIybecause ofpowers
that this woman cIaims to have.
Now, in all fairness, I believe
I should be given the opportunity...
to test
the alleged powers...
instead of having to stand here
and take her word for it.
You have a good point.
Objection overruled.
Can everyone in thejury box
see how many fiingers I'm showing ?
How many fiingers,
Mrs. Wilson ?
I don't know.
You don't know ?
Seven.
Seven fingers.
That-- That doesn't
prove anything.
Your Honor, I can't do this,
you know, at the drop ofa hat.
Well, then, ma'am, how about doing
it at the drop ofa dollar bill ?
What are you trying to say ?
I'm trying to say maybe this special
gift ofyours doesn't work...
unless you're
being paid for it.
Like they say in the army,
''No money, no honey.''
No, that's not true.
Are you aware that in Hatcher County
it's against the law...
for a psychic to set up shop
and charge people money ?
Well, I don't charge money.
You just testifiied
that you do charge money.
No. I accept donations.
People give me gifts.
Oh. A distinction
worthy ofa lawyer.
Mrs. Wilson,
you a rich woman ?
- No.
- Why not ?
If I had psychic powers and could
read the future, I'd be fiilthy rich.
I'dbepIaying
theStockMarket.
I'dbe overin MobiIe
betting on the dogs.
I'd certainly warn my husband
not to go to work...
on the day I know the Reinhold
Plant's gonna blow up...
leaving three little ol' children
to be raised in a carnival sideshow.
Well, it doesn't work
that way, sir.
I can't use my gift
for personal gain.
Except for those, uh,
what you call 'em, donations ?
You've had some personal trouble
with Donnie Barksdale, haven't you ?
Yes, I have.
Just a few weeks ago, you told him--
I believe the exact words was...
you was gonna have
his ass thrown in jail.
- But he was threatening my kids.
- Ain't it also true...
that a few weeks ago in one of
those famous readings ofyours,
when you were doing
your so-called E.S.P.,
you told Valerie Barksdale,
Donnie's wife,
that Donnie wasjust
an insecure redneck...
and that he wasn't really
crazy enough to kill anybody ?
Yes, I did say that.
Then why today are you
saying he did kill somebody ?
Wait a second.
I've never said that.
You might as well have, ma'am.
You wanted his ass in jail.
-He's on trial for his life.
-I just told the sheriffwhat I saw.
And how could any of us
ever forget that ?
Jessica Kingjust
floatin' up in that tree,
naked,
with a chain...
wrappedaroundher.
It must be
so much fun foryou.
You must be having
the time ofyour life...
entertaining yourself
with your dreams and your visions.
You think it's fun seeing decomposed
bodies in my tree, do you, sir ?
You think that's fun ?
Do you think it's fun I have people
trying to strangle me in my sleep ?
NowI'm sittinghere
andI'm bIaming myseIf...
'cause some poor crazy man tried
to burn his daddy halfto death.
And you think I'm sitting here
having fun ?
I'm sorry, sir.
You're crazy ifyou think that.
No more questions,
Your Honor.
[Judge]
You're dismissed.
Like theysay in HoIIywood,
Iet'sjust cut to the chase.
Did you or did you not
kill Jessica King ?
I did not.
Did you or did you not seeJessica
King on the night she was killed ?
Yeah, I seen her.
Would you describe
the circumstances, please ?
Well, I'd been seeing her
for quite a while.
WouIdyou cIarify what
you mean by ''seeing'' ?
I mean, her and me
had been having sex.
Okay, go ahead.
WeII, she caIIedme
about 1 1.:00.
So I told her
I'd meet her out at AyJay's.
And I told my wife
I was going out for a beer.
- What happened after that ?
- Well, we got in an argument.
She told me she didn't
want to see me no more.
-Did she tell you why ?
-She said she was getting married...
in a couple of months and she
wanted to stop playing around.
At Ieast
tiIIafterthe wedding.
Andduring the course
ofthisargument with Miss King,
did you at any moment
strike her ?
Yes, sir.
What happened
afteryou struck her ?
WeII, she bangedherhead
prettyhard when she went down,
so I-- Idecided
to take herto the hospitaI.
- Did you reach the hospital ?
- No, sir.
Are you feeling okay ?
I'm fiine.
I wanna go back.
I don't wanna go
to the hospital. Someone--
Someone might see me.
Shesaidshe wasfeeIingbetter,
so Itookherback toAyJay's.
Idroppedheroff,
then I went on backhome.
Andthat was the veryIast time
thatyousawJessica KingaIive ?
- Yes, sir. The very last.
- Donnie,
are you guilty
ofthe charge against you ?
I'm guilty
ofcheating on my wife,
ofbeinga badhusband,
a badChristian.
But I ain't guilty
of killingJesse.
I swear to God.
No more questions,
Your Honor.
Mr. Duncan.
Mr. Barksdale,
you're a wife-beater, aren't you ?
I've swore to tell
the truth here today.
Yeah, I've hit
VaIerie before.
I guess
it ain't no secret.
So, you admit to havinga history
ofvioIence against women ?
You also admit to having
beaten up the victim...
on the night
that she was murdered.
I wouldn't exactly say
that I beat her up.
You're the expert. You teIIme.
Just howbadIy doyou...
have to beat a woman before it fiits
your defiinition of ''beating up'' ?
Now, yourstoryis thatyou've
been havingan affair...
with the victim.
But tell us why a beautiful
young woman likeJessica King...
from one ofthe fiinest
families in Brixton,
just about to be married to a good,
decent professional man...
and with a bright,
shining future in front ofher--
Why would a woman like that get
involved with something like you ?
I asked her that
myselfone time.
She said I was the only man
in town who knew how to fuck.
[Murmuring]
You're really disgusting.
You know that ?
- Objection, Your Honor.
- Objection sustained.
Mr. Duncan, you will refrain from
making those personal comments.
I apologize, Your Honor.
It won't happen again.
So, let's get this straight.
Let's clarify this.
You're saying it was
just a coincidence...
that on the very same night that you
physically assaulted Jessica King,
someone else put
her body in your pond ?
I'm not saying
it was a coincidence.
- What are you saying ?
- I'm saying I got framed !
Oh, well, what an original defense.
Did you think ofJessica King
as a stray cat ?
No.
Did you tell SheriffJohnson that
a stray cat had clawed your arm ?
- Yeah.
- Didn't you just tell the court...
-Jessica had scratched your arm ?
- Yeah, but--
Didn't you tell SheriffJohnson you
got scratched by the stray cat...
because she didn't like it
when you killed her ?
Yeah, but I was lying.
My wife was standing right there !
-How do I know you're not lying now?
-Because I'm not, goddamn it !
- It's her, goddamn it !
- Be seated, Mr. Barksdale !
She's the reason I'm up here !
She'sagoddamn witch !
She'sputting speIIs on
every-goddamn-body in town !
Witch ! Witch !
Yeah, you run !
[Judge]
I'IIhave orderin the courtroom.
In Brixton today, a sensationaI
murdertriaI was concIuded.
DonaIdJ. BarksdaIe
wasfoundguiIty...
in thesexandstranguIation
kiIIing ofJessica King,
daughteroftheprominent Brixton
businessman, Kenneth King.
Is everything gonna be
all right now, Mama ?
Yeah, hon.
We can get on
with our lives now.
I guess I'm the last
person you wanna see.
How you been ?
Terrible.
Annie, ifyou tell me to get going,
I will. I wouldn't blame you.
But I need you
to read for me.
Give me a hand.
I feel like I can't
hold on any longer.
I know Donnie's mean and everything,
but I feel real lost without him.
You know, I ain't never
been on my own before.
And I'm-I'm scared, Annie.
You don't need to be scared, hon.
You'll be fiine.
You see that
in the cards ?
Mm-hmm.
Right through here.
But can you see
what-- what I'm thinking ?
Can you see that
in the cards ?
What do you mean ?
Well,
I've been thinking
some real bad, bad thoughts.
Unchristian thoughts.
Like what ?
Like--
I'm glad that girl's dead.
Jessica.
She was messin' around with my
husband and deserved what she got.
No one deserves that.
Like I said,
I know it's unchristian.
What ? What, areyou
seeingsomethingbad?
I don't know.
It's not clear.
[Woman Crying]
- Fuckyou !
- [ Gasps ]
[CIattering]
Wayne ?
It's not normally
like this.
You need
to lie down.
I'm really not sleepy.
I think ifyou sleep,
you'll feel better.
Thankyou, Annie.
Oh. It's okay.
Wayne.
I don't think
this is a good idea.
No.
It's not.
I just thought we could
forget all this for a while.
You want to,
don'tyou ?
I know there's
something between us.
I can't.
I guess
I still feel married.
You're not, though.
- He's gone.
- I know.
You gotta learn
to deal with that.
The same way I gotta learn to deal
with the fact thatJessica's gone.
She's dead.
Oh, Wayne,
I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
No, it's not okay.
I-- I don't think
Donnie Barksdale killed her.
- No, no, Annie.
- I'm really sorry.
I can't-- I can't do this.
It's fiinished.
I know. I wanna let
that bastard rot in jail.
- But he's guilty.
- No, Wayne.
I see it.
I see he didn't do it.
- Do you see who did ?
- Uh, I'm trying, but I-- I--
I don't know yet.
What are we gonna do ?
Well, if I had
a piece ofclothing...
or maybe I could go
out to the pond or see if I--
It's not over.
Jesus.
[ThunderCrashes]
[ Knocking ]
Come on in.
Well,
what brings you out here ?
Well, I'll just come
straight out and say it.
I don't think Donnie Barksdale
killed Jessica King.
Well, sure he did.
It was an open-and-shut case.
I'm telling you he didn't.
The person that killed Jessica
is still out there someplace.
What's the deal ? The Barksdales
been threatening you ?
- No.
- I'll talk to Pearl Johnson.
This has nothing to do
with the Barksdales. Listen.
I know that Donnie
didn't kill Jessica...
the same way that I knew
that her body was in his pond.
And do you know
who did kill her ?
No.
So, what do you care ?
The son ofa bitch is in jail.
I got a warning today.
I think somebody is
gonna try and kill me.
What do you
want me to do ?
Reopen the case and fiind out
who really did it.
- I can't. He's been convicted.
- Well, you can talk to somebody.
I've got no basis to open this case.
I'd look like a fool.
I don't give a damn
how you look.
Now, you listen to me.
I know you had
an affair withJessica.
So how do you thinkyou're
gonna look if people fiind out...
you had sex with the victim
the night before she was killed ?
Do you want money ?
No. I want you
to reopen the case.
There's a saying about
letting sleeping dogs lie.
You thinkyou're in danger now ?
Look at it logically.
The real danger begins ifthis case
gets reopened and someone starts...
worrying that you're gonna have
another one ofyour damn dreams.
All I know is,
the wrong man's in jail.
I don't care how awful he is.
And I helped put him there.
I can't live
with something like that.
So you fiind a way
to reopen this case, sir.
Or I will.
Buddy !
Buddy, I'm here ifyou--
- [ Woman ] Hello.
- Hi, Miss Francis. I'm back.
- Good.
- How are the boys ?
They're fiine. They went to sleep.
You want me to bring 'em over ?
No. No. Listen.
Could we stay over
your house tonight ?
- Sure you can. You all right ?
- Oh, yeah, I'm fiine.
-[Creaking]
-Come over. I'll make a bed foryou.
- All right. I'm just gonna lock up.
- Okay, doll.
- Okay, thankyou.
- Bye-bye.
Buddy !
Oh ! Did you see
Buddy Cole ?
Buddy ? No. I thought he was
at the hospital over in Benton ?
- Oh, he is. Maybe I imagined it.
- Are you okay ?
I don't know
what I'm gonna do.
Ever since you told me what you told
me, I feel like I'm going crazy.
Annie, I can't stand
another night ofthis.
I need you
to read for me.
It's no good.
- Try it again.
- I can't make it happen.
How about
what you said today ?
What ?
Thepond.
What ifwe did
go back out there ?
Do you think
it might help you ?
I-- I--
I don't know.
Yeah. Uh, maybe.
Yeah, okay. Well,
it's worth a try, right ?
You mean tonight ? No, Wayne.
I can't-- I can't do that.
I got my kids. It's dark.
You know, it's, uh-- it is a pol--
it's a police matter now.
HowIong doyou think
that'sgonna take, Annie ?
It's gonna sit on somebody's desk
for months. Nothing's gonna happen.
It's over for them. They've got
their man. It's up to us.
I know that, Wayne. But I'm
telling you, I don't see anything.
I can't keep running
from things.
[ThunderCrashes]
Maybe ifyou just
sort ofwalk around.
All right.
Oh, shoot !
Jeez, you all right ?
You okay ?
Yeah.
What are you
doing here ?
Youseeingsomething ?
I've been thinking
some reaIbad, badthoughts.
Annie ?
I'm gIadthatgirIis dead.
Jessica.
She was messin' around with my
husband and deserved what she got.
I couldn't sleep.
Met the girls for a drink.
Take offyour clothes.
[Jessica's Voice]
Aren'tyou takingyours offtoo ?
[Duncan's Voice] There'sa saying
about Ietting sIeeping dogs Iie.
You just fucked him,
didn't you ? Hmm ?
Donnie Barksdale ?
So ?
Why would you do this to me ?
Hmm ? I love you.
Maybe I wanted to be
with a man for a change.
- Watch your mouth.
- You watch your mouth. Fuckyou !
- I'm sorry.
- We're through.
I don't like being spied on.
The only reason I'm with you
is 'cause my daddy likes you.
You horrible little bitch !
I'll show you a bitch ifyou
don't let go of me. Let go !
- I think we better go back.
- Nothing's coming to you ?
No.
Nothing.
You know.
I knew if I got you close enough
to it that you'd see it.
- Wayne, I told you--
- No, no. It's okay.
I swear to God, Annie,
it's okay. It's okay.
I wanted you to.
I swear to God.
I wanted you to see it so bad.
I mean, that's why we're here.
I'm not some killer, Annie.
I'm not.
You don't-- I mean, do you know
what it was like with her ?
She was so fucking hurtful
and spiteful and all of it--
Wayne, I'm not gonna--
But all of itjust happened
in this flash ofa moment.
- Wayne, I--
- Listen to me. I'm agoodman.
If it had been you instead of her,
none ofthis would have happened.
Wayne.
It's all right, you know ?
I won't-- I won't tell.
I-I-I won't--
I won't tell anybody.
No, Annie--
You all right, Mrs. Wilson ?
I thought you were supposed to
be in the hospital.
I escaped, Mrs. Wilson.
I'm free.
Buddy, I'm so sorry
I wasn't there foryou.
- I should've--
- Now, don'tyousayanother word.
You was the onIyone
that wasa friendto me.
And I love you.
You're the soul
ofthis town, Mrs. Wilson.
And you just need to keep doing
what you're doing.
I washed it.
Will you come back
into town with me ?
Yeah.
You know you're
gonna have to go back.
Yes, ma'am, I know.
Can I have your keys,
ma'am ?
WeII,
I just talked to Wayne.
He pretty much admitted
to everything.
I've known that boy
half my life.
Itjust goes to show,
you can know somebody and...
not know 'em.
How's his, um--
How's his head ?
Well, you put
a pretty good dent in it.
Oh, no, Sheriff,
I told, uh--
I told the deputy
it wasn't me who did that.
It was, um--
It was Buddy Cole. He saved me.
- No, ma'am. It weren't Buddy.
- Well, yes, it was.
- Why don't you just ask Wayne ?
- I did.
He don't remember
what happened.
Head injuries is funny.
-I'm telling you, it was Buddy Cole.
-What I'm tryin' to say is,
it couldn't have been Buddy.
I-- Ijust caIIedup
at theState HospitaI.
- He told me he escaped.
- Ma 'am.
Buddy Cole is dead.
He hangedhimseIf
in theshowerroom...
6.:00 this evening.