♪♪
(birds chirping)
(thunder cracking)
(thunder rumbling)
(thunder rumbling in distance)
(car engine turning over)
(thunder rumbling,
labored breathing)
(whispering)
Please, God, watch over
my babies.
Please, just come help them.
(bells jingling)
Hey, how's it going?
This way.
Put it down over here.
Woman on radio: it's hard
to say it enough.
This could really be a
problem with the communities
being cut off.
We're talking about roads that
are going to wash out.
The rain is
going to last and last
and that's going to
be the problem.
Bridges are going to become
tan-passable, so the...
(meat grinder whirring)
man: Can I help you,
Mrs. Parker?
(squishing)
man: Mrs. Parker?
Mrs. Parker?
Can I help you?
Are you okay?
It's the dampness, it, uh...
gets in my head.
(thunder rumbling in distance)
It's gonna get a lot worse
before it gets better.
♪♪
(hurried footsteps approaching)
(thunder booming)
(gagging)
♪♪
(groaning)
(squeaking)
(banging)
(thunder cracking)
♪♪
(thunder rumbling and cracking)
Snap Pops!
Sorry, buddy.
No Snap Pops.
Snap Pops!
It's the first day
with abstinence.
- You know the rules.
- Snap Pops!
Milk or tea.
Sorry, honey, it's only
until after Sunday.
Why?
Because it's a fast, which
means that we can't eat.
No flesh, no fruit, no grain.
Drink your milk.
It'll fill you up.
Now, don't chug it.
It's gonna give you
a bellyache.
(burping)
(chuckling)
girl: I don't know
what she was thinking
Leaving those clothes
out like that.
Her headaches
have been getting worse.
♪♪
I wish Daddy would
let her see a doctor.
You know how
he feels about that.
Man on radio:
reaching a rainfall rate
of two to three inches
per hour and it won't let up
until just before sunrise
tomorrow morning.
Stay alert.
Flash flooding is definitely
a likelihood
under these conditions
in sections of Greene,
Delaware,
and Sullivan counties
'til 4:00 tomorrow morning
at this time.
Rising levels of area
reservoirs
and local waterways
have residents on river watch.
Extreme flooding is expected
in local Hudsel Village
and widespread
power outages are likely.
In Orchard and Sullivan County
it already has started.
It is feared that
the worse-hit areas...
(latch locking)
(rain spattering)
(car approaching)
woman on TV:
...make everyone aware
that Delaware County is
now under a flood warning
and many surrounding areas
under flood watches
and this will
continue into the night.
Is this going to be
significant flooding?
- It is very likely going...
- man: Mr. Parker?
- ...to make a huge impact
- Mr. Parker.
...on our community.
So, Delaware County,
please be advised
you are currently under
a flood warning.
girl: Stay here.
...we expect those to go up
into the thousands.
girl: Dad?!
(thunder rumbling)
Daddy?!
(door creaking)
♪♪
- Dad?!
- Daddy?!
♪♪
Woman on TV: you should have
your emergency supplies ready
and certainty have a
radio with batteries because...
♪♪
(weather announcements
continues, rain spattering)
(clattering)
Spit it out.
(spitting)
(thunder rumbling in distance)
(siren blaring)
(police radio chatter)
- Hey, hi, Doc.
- Hey, Mike.
(girls whispering)
I'm so sorry I'm late.
The roads are a mess.
I'm Doc Barrow.
We know.
You delivered our
baby brother Rory
up at the house.
Oh, yeah, Rory, little Rory.
How is he?
He's, um, getting big.
Good.
Where's your father?
He couldn't make it.
He's still grieving.
Well, I can
understand that, sweetie.
It's tough.
They said that she drowned.
Well, I won't know, hon,
until I do
a full examination.
You mean autopsy.
Yes, an autopsy.
It's the law.
You know, I'm so sorry.
It's been a long time
and you've grown so much,
I just can't remember
your name.
Iris.
Iris, and you?
Rose.
Iris and Rose.
Well...
I only need one of you to
make the identification.
(whispering)
I'll do it.
Okay.
This way, sweetie.
Rose, we'll be right back.
(door creaking)
♪♪
(crying)
Mr. Parker...
Mr. Parker,
it's wet out here.
She's in a better
place, Mr. Parker.
We say that.
Do we believe it?
(squishing)
(thudding)
Emma Parker.
47 years old.
Liver healthy.
Moderate calcification
In the left
ventricular arteries.
Sign of pill-rolling.
Atrophy of
the right vastus lateralis,
suggesting early onset of
Parkinson's.
What about Lambs Day, Daddy?
We do it the way that
we've always done it.
Two days.
We will carry on.
But Mamma's gone.
What?
Mamma's gone--
It's what we do, Rose.
We continue.
Iris is the eldest daughter.
It's her responsibility now.
(distant cracking)
Okay.
Tree's down.
Creek's washed out.
Fetch some candles, Rose.
I'll let them know
what's going on
down at the trailer park.
You're not scared, are you?
Are you scared?
Don't be scared.
(humming)
♪ Jesus gonna be here ♪
♪ Oh he's gonna
be here soon ♪
♪ Jesus gonna be here ♪
♪ He's gonna
be here soon ♪♪
When's Jesus gonna be here?
Soon.
Yeah, he's gonna
be here soon.
That's my boy.
♪♪
(emergency flashers clicking)
Sing it.
Shh...
(whispering)
Sing it.
(humming)
(wind chimes rattling)
(humming continues)
(car door closing)
Daddy's home.
(humming continues)
(birds chirping)
♪♪
(door creaking)
(dog barking)
(sniffing)
What is it, boy?
Huh.
Come on, come on.
(birds chirping)
(phone ringing)
Mr. and Mrs. Kimble, uh...
In these situations,
99 times out of 100,
the missing person
is safe--
just can't
get to a working phone.
Your daughter's probably
at somebody's house,
a friend's house,
just as worried about you
as you are about her.
But she's our only child
and she never
hasn't come home before.
I understand that,
but I've got--
I've got roads closed,
lines down, bridges out.
Let's give it 24 hours.
If she doesn't make
contact by then, we'll--
we'll put out an alert, okay?
(crying)
Emily!
I need you to make copies
of that photo
and put out an MPR on
a Valerie Kimble, all right?
I'm on it.
Thank you.
(music playing)
(clanking in the distance)
(clanking)
(knocking)
I'm sorry.
I know it's
a bad time for you,
but... I'm finished with
this place.
Uh... there's no work.
And now this damn storm
washed half the town away.
So... we're gonna head
downstate
to my brother's and see
if we can start over.
I think that's everything.
Good luck, Mr. Parker.
♪♪
(sizzling)
(birds chirping)
I'm hungry.
(whispering)
Snap PO95-
♪♪
It's for you.
I don't under--
It's a token...
for last night.
"Kindness shall be
met with kindness."
Is that in the Bible?
It's in mine.
Thank you.
Funeral's this afternoon.
- So soon?
- It's our way.
I don't like to ask.
I was wondering
if you wouldn't mind
watching my boy for a spell?
Too young for these things.
Of course I wouldn't mind.
I'd be happy to,
Mr. Parker.
♪♪
Meeks on answering machine:
This is Sheriff Meeks.
I'm not here right now.
Please leave a message
and I'll get back to you
as soon as possible.
(answering machine beeping)
Hey, Bob.
Doc Barrow here.
I found something
strange this morning--
my dog actually dug it up.
I'd like to show it to you.
I can stop by your place
today if it's okay.
Let me know, please.
Thanks.
Where are you, pumpkin?
You're gonna have to
take care of them now.
You ready for that?
Iris: I'm the oldest.
That's the way it works.
The way it's always worked.
It just...
doesn't seem fair.
None of it.
That's for me to worry about.
Not you.
What if we refused to do it?
We just... we just
stopped?
He would make us,
wouldn't he?
I just want to
get this over with.
And then we have a whole year
to figure something out.
I just wish that we were
like everyone else.
Well, we're not.
(door creaking)
♪♪
(rattling)
(creaking)
(thumping)
(rattling)
♪♪
Woman: Help!
Help!
What are you doing?
You know you ain't
allowed down here!
I seen the monster, Daddy.
One day...
I'll teach you how not
to be afraid of the dark.
How'd that be?
Good.
Until then...
you stay out.
Don't go where you
don't belong.
Okay?
(groaning)
(rattling)
Boys need a watchful eye.
I'm sorry, Daddy.
Rose said he was sleeping.
Rose isn't in charge,
you are.
All we have is each other.
We need to stick
together now.
You understand?
"And the seed
shall become the tree
which bears the fruit."
"And feeds
the kindred."
- Amen.
♪♪
(water running)
Frank: When the earth has
claimed our limbs,
then shall we come home
to walk with Him.
To a better
place he calls us,
free from want
and hungry
desires of this earth.
But should some
urgent fate...
untimely lot...
bring you to meet your fate,
nameless elf that haunteth
the lone regions
where hath
trod no foot of man,
commend thyself to God.
Behold, the lamb of God
who taketh away
the sins of the world.
Amen.
(clattering)
He hasn't eaten
since Mamma...
Well...
take him home,
put him to bed,
let him get some rest.
If he wants something to eat,
give him something light.
Like soup or something.
I'll call you tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Iris.
Thank you for coming, Anders.
It was really sweet of you.
(whispering)
No, no, hon, she didn't
suffer at all, no.
Okay, thank you.
♪♪
We're home, Daddy.
She was the first.
Now... it
belongs to you.
Iris: "December 24, 1781.
"Papa has found our new home.
"It is a peaceful place,
"high on a mountain overlooking
the valley below.
"The forest
is rich with serenity.
"A land that knows not
the industry of men.
Iris: "Our harvest dwindles
as winter approaches early.
"Mother has forgone her rations
so that the children may eat.
"Father and Uncle Burnett left
yesterday in search of game.
"We pray for
their safe return,
as I fear we have not yet seen
the whole of nature's cruelty."
(knocking)
(door creaking)
- Hey.
I hope I'm not bothering you,
but I wanted to say that
when my dad died...
it was really
hard on our family.
Especially my mom.
Where have you been?
I haven't
seen you all summer.
Academy training, downstate.
Yeah, this is my first...
official week on the job.
They made you
cut your hair, huh?
Yeah, academy regulation.
- You wanna come in?
- Um...
No, it's, uh...
It's just, do you remember
Valerie Kimble?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, well, have you
seen her lately?
Mm-mm.
Not since school let out.
She's pretty.
Yeah, well--
well, she's gone missing
and, uh, it was just
before the storm.
So I thought that maybe,
since she had to
come by this way
on her way home every day,
that maybe
someone had seen her.
You could check up at
the trailer park.
Only the new girl left.
Business has been slow.
Yeah, it's been
slow for everybody.
All right, well--
well, I'll go ask her then.
Um...
I hope this doesn't
come off the wrong way.
I thought that maybe, um...
maybe after
everything calmed down,
we could-- you know, we could
go to a movie
or something sometime?
- A movie?
- Yeah.
Or a restaurant,
we could go eat.
You know,
whatever you wanna do.
Ask me again some other time
And we'll see, okay?
Yeah, of course.
All right.
I will-- I will--
I'll see you around, I hope.
Not if I see you first.
(door creaking)
That's the boy from school
that you liked, isn't it?
He's okay.
Nice haircut.
(engine turning over)
♪♪
Meeks: I don't know what's
keeping you here, Doc.
What you need...
is a good, long vacation,
someplace warm.
Shit, if I was you,
I'd retire and stay there.
She can stay here.
So what do you think?
There's been flooding
up at the cemetery.
Yeah, but, Bob, the cemetery's
downstream from me
and you know very well
nothing flows upstream.
How sure are you, Doc?
I'm not.
We'd have to
send it to Albany.
Have it tested to
be positive.
That's not gonna happen,
not with the flood.
What are we gonna do?
I got a state
of emergency here.
I can't start an investigation
based on a piece of bone.
I'm not even sure it's human.
- I'm not asking that, Bob.
- I know that.
Come on, Jim.
- You know what this is.
- What?
Ahh... I'm sorry, man.
It's all right,
you're probably right.
I'm probably clutching
at straws.
Believe me,
when Kimmy disappeared...
We did everything we could.
She was just gone.
It happens.
I wish to God
it didn't, but it does.
Yeah
"And the monster
lived happily ever after."
No, he didn't.
What?
The monsters not happy.
He's crying.
What do you mean?
I heard him in the basement
behind the locked door.
He's in there and he's sad.
You hush now
and go to sleep, okay?
Goodnight.
♪♪
Rose: "We lost Mrs. Burnett
last night.
"Mother is
weakening by the hour,
"and I fear that she will not
last the winter.
"Father returned
to us this morning
"with supplies of fresh meat.
"Uncle Burnett
continued further east,
"in hope of reaching
the outpost.
"He has not returned,
"and I believe
now that he never will.
Father says all is forgiven in
the eyes of the Lord."
Iris: Daddy...
What if we were different?
If we weren't like we are?
Come here.
What are we like?
It was God chose us
to be this way.
If we don't do as He asks,
we get sick, from the poison.
One by one we die.
You can't hide a doubtful
mind from Him, honey.
He knows all.
Sees all.
You're stronger
than you know, girl.
(sniffling)
I know, Daddy.
One more day.
I love you so much.
I love you so much...
I love you, too.
(sizzling)
(music playing)
(bells jingling)
Doc Barrow: Oh, excuse me.
Hey, Doc.
Mr. Anders.
What kind of bone
do you think that is?
Where'd you find this?
It washed down at the creek,
behind my house.
It's definitely not a deer.
My dad would have known,
he was real good with bones.
In my humble opinion,
I believe it's human remains.
Well... in that case...
I'll take your word for it.
You're a doctor.
Well, I'm here because
I went by to see Meeks.
I told him.
He just thinks
I'm some kind of a nutcase.
And he may be right.
But there's been three people
missing from this town
in the last 20 years,
one of which was my daughter.
I know.
I remember.
I was on the search party.
I know.
But if you extend the radius,
including
the towns within 50 miles,
there are 30 people
or more missing,
none of which
have been found.
I'm just a deputy.
Well, I know,
I'm just trying to help out.
I thought maybe it'd be
useful information.
A lot of good folk
in this town.
Nice people.
Those girls just put
their mother down
who just died recently,
down here to help out.
Father's a bit of
a wacko if you ask me.
(chuckling)
Hey, guys.
On the house.
We got the power back up but
one of our fridges won't start,
so we have to eat everything up
before it spoils.
Could we have
a cup of coffee, sweetie?
Sure.
I'll tell you what, Doc,
how about
I come over tomorrow
and you can show me where
you found this?
♪♪
(banging)
He woke up sick
and then got all hot.
Marge: Oh, he just
has a fever.
Children get fevers.
- Do you have any aspirin?
- Yes.
Can you crush one up in
a glass of milk, please?
And make sure you crush
it really good.
Is he going be okay?
Oh, yeah, he'll be fine.
We just got to get him out
of these wet clothes.
Sweetheart, do you have
some fresh things for him?
Yeah, I think.
(whispering)
Poor little thing.
So sweet.
(crunching)
Ow!
I'm hungry.
Frank: What's going on?
He's got a fever.
It's a wonder
we ain't all sick.
All this damn rain
gets in the bones.
♪♪
You're a good
neighbor, Marge.
I'll see you out.
(creaking)
Listen, maybe you ought to
take him to see a doctor.
That costs money
we ain't got.
We ain't used to
sickness in this house.
He'll burn it off, be fine.
- Good day, Marge.
- You're bleeding.
Well, look at that.
Must be dried out from
the stove in the shed.
It's the Maker...
telling us it's time.
♪♪
(door creaking)
girl: "Mamma has
gone to the Lord.
"Now it is just the three of us.
"Father has changed greatly
these past few weeks.
"He keeps to himself in
a back chamber of the cave,
"quoting scripture
and weeping at night.
"I suspect I know
the great secret
"Father has kept from us.
"As Father's mind unravels,
"our survival has now
become my burden.
♪♪
(rattling)
(woman weeping in the distance)
(woman weeping)
♪♪
"It is with love
that I do this.
"God's will be done.
"Alyce Parker.
"Lambs Day.
1782."
We're gonna have to
call the Kimbles.
(rattling)
(labored breathing)
Hold this.
(muffled whimpering)
(creaking)
(rattling)
(muffled whimpering)
(muffled screaming)
Iris: Help me.
- Help me.
- Rose: I can't do this.
I can't--
I can't do this.
We have no choice now.
You're gonna leave me
for that police boy.
Nothing comes between
this family, okay?
Nothing.
I need you.
I cannot do this alone.
Please, help me, Rose.
Go, please, help me!
(muffled screaming)
(grunting)
Come on!
(muffled screaming)
(muffled crying)
(muffled whimpering)
I'm sorry,
Mrs. Stratton.
I promise you're going to
a better place.
(screaming)
Get off me!
Get her off me!
(thudding)
(splattering)
(chains rattling, grunting)
Iris...
make it stop.
Make it stop.
Please make it stop, please.
Please, Iris!
Please, please...
(groaning)
Did you kill the monster?
Yeah, yeah, yes, I did, yes.
♪♪
(crying in the distance)
(crying)
♪♪
(blade scraping)
(water running)
(crickets chirping)
(bubbling)
Tell Daddy suppers ready.
Are you okay?
I didn't know it was
gonna be like that.
I won't do that again.
He can't make me.
Nobody can, not even God.
♪♪
(knocking)
Hi.
I came by to see how
the little man is doing.
He's fine.
Better.
I brought you some lasagna.
You'll have to use it
before it goes bad, so...
It's vegetarian.
Sweet of you.
I heard somebody down
in the shed earlier.
It must have been Daddy.
He's the only one allowed
down there, ever.
Well, it sounded
like a girl crying.
I don't know what
you think you heard,
but you must be mistaken.
Thanks.
Good night.
(music playing)
♪♪
Thank you...
for the sustenance
we receive.
Blessed are the lamb,
for they are His offering.
Amen.
All: Amen.
♪♪
It's good.
Your mother would be proud.
Eat your food, Rose.
Yes, Daddy.
It's just hot.
Blow on it.
It takes more than a flood...
to bring this
family to its knees.
(slurping)
(birds chirping)
It looks like pot glow.
And what is pot glow?
Means it's been boiled.
Listen, you find anything else,
you give me a call.
I'll be at my
office at the morgue.
Fucking pot glow.
- Thanks!
- Yeah.
♪♪
(whispering)
Iris, Iris.
Get up, get up, wake up.
Shh.
Get up.
♪♪
Iris: You should call a girl
when you're gonna make a visit.
Morning, Iris.
What are you doing
in my creek, Anders?
Wasting my time,
getting my feet wet.
I don't mind so much now
that you're around.
I can get you a pair
of my Daddy's socks.
You think so?
I know so.
Come on up.
So...
What are you looking for?
I, uh...
I probably shouldn't say.
- It's-- it's nothing.
- You can tell me.
Hell.
You were the first boy
I ever kissed.
Though you probably
don't remember that, do you?
No, no... I remember.
So...
You can tell me, what
are you looking for?
(sighing)
Well...
The storm, um,
just washed some...
things, uh, way down creek.
Well, what kind of things?
Bones.
Well, we've been finding
bones around here
since I was a little girl.
Deer and coons mostly.
No, but Doc Barrow thinks
that these are human.
You're just funnin' me.
No, I swear to God,
that's what he thinks.
But the sheriff,
he's not buying it, so...
So I don't know.
Let me get you those socks.
Hey-- hey, Iris?
Could I get a glass of water?
Iris?
(cell phone beeping)
(creaking)
Jesus!
What you doing here, Anders?
Is something wrong?
No.
No, I just got my socks wet.
Iris is getting me a dry
pair from upstairs.
What is that?
Oh, looks like some sort of
old tooth or something.
I found it out in the creek.
Thanks.
So... how old
are you now, Rose?
- 14.
- 14?
You're growing up.
It happens.
Yes, it does.
Catch.
Mmm.
Thank you.
What's this?
Some kind of bone,
I found it out back.
My daddy would know.
He's good with bones.
So was mine.
You know,
there's an old family cemetery
up the creek a bit.
We used to go there
when we were little.
Even some stones left.
How-- how far?
Not far,
just below the falls.
Maybe I should take a look.
This could be from
one of our relatives.
I'll show you where it is.
Okay, I'd appreciate that.
You're growing up
really pretty, Rose.
Just like your sister.
I'll see you later.
See you.
♪♪
(footsteps approaching)
(lighter flickering)
♪♪
(birds chirping)
I think your sister's
worried that I'm gonna
steal you away.
Are you?
(bugs buzzing)
Listen.
What?
(buzzing continues)
My daddy
called them heat bugs.
They mean summer's coming.
Anders: Oh...
Damn it.
What?
Nothing.
Come on.
Almost there.
♪♪
Some have signs of scorching
and Y-shaped patterns...
indicating a serrated blade.
T-structured incision,
indicating a flat blade,
for scraping or filleting
tissue from bone.
♪♪
(twig snapping)
This is all your dad's land, huh?
Mm-hmm.
♪♪
Don't.
Why?
It's just a flower.
I'm not worth it, Anders.
I'm not what you think I am.
I don't think you're anything
but a pretty girl...
who I like a lot.
- I'm not pretty.
- Yes, you are.
Not inside.
Maybe I should
just take you home.
(sniffling)
♪♪
(moaning)
(moaning continues)
(groaning)
(gurgling)
♪♪
(scraping)
You filth.
Rory's alone.
I don't know where
your sister's made off to.
Get your ass home
and look after your brother.
Now!
(thunder cracking)
(flames crackling)
(Iris crying)
Rose: Shh...
(door creaking)
Get out of my sight.
Both of you.
(cell phone vibrating)
man on answering machine:
Hi, you've reached Deputy Anders.
Sorry I can't-
Meeks on answering machine:
This is Sheriff Meeks.
I'm not here right now-
♪♪
(crying)
Shh...
(whispering)
Rose: We'll take the truck
once he's asleep.
And we'll head to the city
and just start all over.
Stop, okay?
It's going to be okay.
You're so beautiful.
Okay?
You're gonna be fine.
We're gonna be fine.
(crying)
Shh...
(sniffling)
It's okay.
Daddy's mad.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures.
He leads me in the paths of
righteousness for His namesake.
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil,
for He is with me.
His rod and His staff,
they comfort me.
Surely goodness and...
♪♪
(splashing)
(groaning)
(thunder cracking)
(yelling)
(knocking)
(door creaking)
- Hi, Emily.
- Hey, Doc.
Is Anders in?
Nope, just me.
Been trying to
call him all afternoon.
There's a new storm
coming-bad reception.
He might be over at
the fireworks.
Is Meeks in?
He's out on call.
Accident on 28.
Listen, hon, would you mind
watching my dog for a bit?
(gasping)
Oh, my goodness,
he's so cute!
I left something in Meeks'
office, can I get it?
Oh, yeah, door's unlocked,
help yourself.
- Thanks.
- Hello!
Can you sit down?
You're such a good dog!
Are you thirsty?
Oh, my goodness.
Okay.
Let's give you some water.
Here you go.
(loud clanking)
Yeah, I want
a puppy just like you.
Lay down.
Can you lay down?
You're a good puppy!
Hey, thanks.
- You be a good dog, Zip.
- Did you get what you needed?
- Yes, I did, thank you so much.
- Oh, good.
Yes, you shake.
That's a good boy.
♪♪
Have you seen Deputy Anders?
No, not today.
You haven't seen Deputy Anders,
have you?
Frank: I've seen the sign.
We're coming home to you now.
Coming home to you now.
Coming home to
you now, sweetie.
Is Meeks around?
Man: I haven't seen Meeks.
Frank: Father...
we have kept our tradition...
in its purity.
And seek our reward
in the hereafter.
(fireworks exploding)
Oh, come on, Kidd.
Come on, buddy, let's go.
Come on, let's go.
Good boy.
Rose: Pretty, isn't it?
Honey, listen to me.
You're gonna have to
be a brave boy, okay?
You're going to have to
listen to me.
To what I say, when I say it.
Can you do that?
All right, that's a good
little man.
Frank: Get ready for supper.
♪♪
Good boy, Kidd.
(thunder rumbling)
♪♪
(fireworks exploding)
(rain spattering)
(thunder rumbling)
(engine turning over)
(thunder rumbling in distance)
(music playing)
(cell phone vibrating)
(thunder cracking)
(music playing)
(whispering)
Iris.
Father...
lift us from
this world of goatishness...
together, as one
and raise us to righteousness
and heavenly laity.
We have kept our tradition...
in its purity,
and seek our reward in
the hereafter.
- Amen.
We were lost,
like the lambs...
but have found the light
that will lead us home.
Let us eat.
(whispering)
Iris...
♪♪
(cracking)
(clattering)
♪♪
(knocking)
Iris.
- Yes.
- Get the door.
(door opening)
Doc Barrow: I need to
see your father.
Iris: Come in.
Dr. Barrow.
Mr. Parker.
You hungry, Doc?
We have plenty.
No, thank you.
What's on your mind?
Well...
It's rather delicate.
Leave me and the doctor
to have some privacy.
(light bulb buzzing)
Let there be light.
(thunder cracking)
Mind if I smoke, Doc?
How long have you had that
hand tremor, Mr. Parker?
You didn't come here
to discuss my health,
did you, Doc?
No, I didn't.
What then?
You seen Anders?
Who?
The deputy... Anders.
Oh...
Yeah... him.
Was he here?
This morning.
But he left.
Is there anything else?
Yes, as a matter of fact.
Your wife suffered...
from a rare disorder of
prion disease.
It's usually found in
the native tribes
of New Guinea.
And it comes from
eating human flesh.
(thunder rumbling)
No, no...
Did you kill my daughter?
What?
Your daughter's
wearing a hair clasp.
It was a gift to my girl
when she turned 16.
Did you...
eat my daughter?
I've been meaning to ask you.
Are you a religious man, Doc?
Tell me about my daughter.
It's not too popular
these days, is it?
Tell me about my daughter.
Tell me about my daughter!
Daddy, no!
(gun firing)
♪♪
(thunder rumbling)
(whispering)
Son of a bitch.
Okay, my sweetie.
You're gonna be okay,
don't you move.
You're gonna be all right.
Don't you go anywhere.
(clanging)
Oh...
(pan rattling)
I'm sorry, honey.
I love you.
I'm gonna go get your...
your brother and your sister.
(thunder rumbling)
♪♪
Come on, go, go!
Oh my God, okay...
Get out!
(groaning)
Marge, Marge!
Marge!
(dog barking)
Marge, please open up!
Open up!
Marge, please!
(dog barking)
Please.
Marge... Marge!
What the fuck is happening?
(dog barking continues)
(crying)
(dog whimpering)
(screaming)
Get out, get out!
No, no!
No!
(thudding)
(crying)
(door knob jiggling)
(panting)
(thunder rumbling in distance)
(crying)
Rory...
Come here.
It's all right, it's okay.
It's all right.
Rory.
Please come here.
You don't have to be
afraid of the dark.
I'll teach you.
(thunder rumbling)
Rose.
- No!
- It's okay.
- Come home now.
No!
- No, no.
Daddy loves you.
- No.
- Iris needs you.
Iris needs you.
Iris?
Yeah
She's safe.
Come on.
Come home, okay?
Come on, yeah.
That a girl, it's okay.
(thunder rumbling)
It's okay,
I'll take care of you.
I'm gonna take care of you.
(crying)
It's okay, it's okay.
I got ya, I got ya.
I got ya.
(thunder rumbling in distance)
(crying)
(thunder rumbling)
♪♪
All is forgiven...
in the eyes of the Lord.
(crying)
You look just like your mother.
Shh...
(thunder rumbling)
Frank: No reason to cry.
No reason to cry.
Shh...
- I love you, Daddy.
- I love you, too.
(growling)
(crunching)
(yelling)
(panting)
(crunching)
(yelling)
(screaming)
(panting)
(crunching)
♪♪
(thunder booming in distance)
(crunching)
(groaning)
♪♪