Synch and correct by JustFuckingShit (or teftel)
www.addic7ed.com
This is not me accepting. Take him.
You and your bitch will regret this.
Mark my words.
I didn't fetch you back here
to do anything. Just...just be here.
All I've got is you.
When we transformed, did...
did we...?
THIS PROGRAMME CONTAINS
SOME STRONG LANGUAGE
& SCENES WHICH SOME VIEWERS
MAY FIND UPSETTING
INDISTINCT SPEECH
Blood pressure dropping.
FLATLINE TONE
LOW GROWL
What the bloody hell
do you think you're doing?!
Aaah!
HE SIGHS AND GRUNTS
DOOR OPENS
FOOTSTEPS
George.
Mm-hm?
Where's Annie?
Mm...er...probably off
on one of her midnight rambles.
She doesn't need sleep,
unlike some of us.
Can I have a word?
But...oh.
Can't it wait until the morning,
or at least until after I've peed?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. After you pee.
I can't go now.
MUSIC PLAYS
AND CHATTER
SHE COUGHS
NEARBY LAUGHTER
< I want a go.
HE SIGHS
I think Annie might fancy me.
Finally.
You knew?
Oh, Mitchell, Annie is many things
but subtle she is not.
You've rescued her from hell.
That kind of thing tends
to turn a girl's head.
How long have you known?
I don't know. A couple of weeks.
Pretty much since she came back.
And, for future reference,
no-one says "fancy" any more.
And you didn't think to tell me?
Um...no, because I'm not 12.
Did you...did you seriously
not pick up on any of this?
That whole guardian angel business.
OK, so she hasn't actually told you.
Oh, wow. We are 12, aren't we?
No, she hasn't told me
she "fancies" you.
She doesn't need to.
Her body language is deafening.
Jesus. What a mess.
MUSIC PLAYS
Get off me!
Oh, yeah, you're the big man, aren't
you? Hitting, pushing a woman!
Arsehole! Yeah, and I wasn't
stealing, by the way!
Those drinks were dead!
Clear off, love.
Oh, why don't you take a picture,
you nosy bitch?
You can see me?
What?
Ah! You think
you're better than me, do you?
Little Miss Sodding
High-And-Mighty, is it?
Is it? Come on, then!
No, not today, thank you.
But who knows? You... you two
could be good for each other.
She could be good for me. But...
And you'll be good to her.
Of course. I'd never...
If you're thinking about doing this,
don't go into it lightly.
This is no little thing.
This is Annie we're talking about.
George.
You've got to know
I would never hurt her.
HE CHUCKLES
Yeah, I know.
Sure, I was just...
So, are you...
are you gonna ask her out?
This could be so cool!
I don't know.
I mean, how would it even work?
With a ghost?
What do you mean?
Er...
Guys, I'm in trouble.
There's a dead woman after me.
What...what happened? Are you OK?
I was walking past this club
on Westland Street.
You know, that...
that down-market version of Ritzy's.
Yeah, I know, like that's really
possible.
Anyway, this dead woman got thrown
out of the club, but...
but she could see me.
BANGING ON DOOR
And she followed me home!
Why didn't you just
"Rentaghost" home?
That would be...that would be
because...
BANGING ON DOOR
I was under a lot of pressure, OK?
I just got up for a pee.
Slag!
DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE
I know you're in there! Snobby cow!
SHE SNARLS
All right, come on, then!
What have we got?
Get out here and show yourself!
A drunk dead woman, shouting.
You! I know you're bloody in there!
That's not a ghost. I can smell her.
Come on!
You think you're so bloody...
What, from here?
GIRL SHOUTS
Oh, yeah,
even without the whole wolf thing.
Well, of course you can smell her.
She's got a body.
I'm sure I mentioned that.
So, she's dead but she's got a body?
Which is rotting.
This is not good.
That's why I'm so scared!
If she was just dead dead, no
problem. But that is just weird!
No, hold on. Hold on a second here.
I...I think she's gone.
FLOORBOARDS CREAK
SHE SCREAMS
Oh! I thought we were
supposed to be the scary ones.
Go and check the window.
Go!
Go on.
She's mental! Of course she is.
There's a car slowing down.
I think people can see her!
Well, of course they can see her!
She's got a body!
We've got to let her in.
BOTH: What?
We have a shouting pissed corpse
on our doorstep.
Right, and you want
a shouting pissed corpse inside?
She's gonna draw attention
to the house, Annie, to us.
What if somebody calls
the police, huh? Oh...!
Come on!
Well, she...she's stopped shouting.
What's she doing now?
GIRL SOBS
Crying, I think.
And then just sitting.
But she's still quite loud.
She stinks.
SHE SOBS
Um...um...
Would...would you like some tea?
Huh?
DOOR SHUTS
SHE SNIFFS
Oh!
Straighteners!
Oh, God.
What...?
What...what can we get for you?
Straighteners!
Straighteners?
Yeah.
Oh, good. Great.
Because that will solve everything.
Mm-hm.
Nina... um...
can I borrow your straighteners?
Yeah, sure, course.
THEY GIGGLE
Er...George?
A dead woman with a body
followed Annie home.
Of course.
Here.
You do it, babe.
So, um...what do we call you?
Anything you like, sweetheart.
Ow! Oh, sorry! Look,
you got caught there.
Caught a little bit of your hair.
Sorry. Don't worry, babe.
I can tell
you're not used to a beauty regime.
Well, um...I'm Mitchell.
Oh, hi, Mitchell. I'm Sasha.
HER BONES CRUNCH
Like the Beyonce album.
CRUNCHING AND SQUELCHING
SASHA GIGGLES
I'm Nina.
Oh, my gran was called Nina.
Oh.
Oh! Aren't you short?
Um...that's a...
that's a beautiful dress, Sasha.
What a wonderful cut. Have you, have
you been to a hospital recently?
OK. Confession time.
I was involved in a car accident.
But, you know, it wasn't my fault.
I was texting while I was driving,
but that's not making a phone call.
In my Beemer, Prussian blue,
heated seats, all the extras.
I love my little extras.
SASHA GIGGLES
So, you died, did you?
SQUELCHY CRUNCH
Well, no. Obviously I didn't.
Yeah, but apparently
it was touch and go.
Oh, and let me tell you, the
doctors were very interested in me.
Wouldn't leave me alone.
Kept on prodding and poking me.
And I said, "You'd better warm
that up before you put it near me."
SHE LAUGHS
Ooh. I know, what is that smell?
I think someone's in denial.
How can she not know she's dead?
It solves one mystery, anyway.
The mortuary suddenly
being off limits.
No, that was a chemical leak.
Or they were hiding a zombie.
Oh, Christ.
Are we really gonna call her that?
Well, dead body moving about?
Can I just take a little step back
to point out how insane this is?
Mitchell, what the hell is she?
How should I know?
At least she's not attacking us.
Don't they usually attack people?
No, they don't usually do anything,
because they don't usually exist.
What about eating brains?
I don't know the rules. I know that
she can be seen and she's rotten.
Mm-hm, I can vouch for that.
Do you think she'll continue rotting
until she's, you know, soupy?
Oh! We should take her back. Whatever
she is, she's not our problem.
She's the hospital's problem.
Oh, I hate to say it, but I agree.
Really?
Well, medically,
we can't do anything for her here.
If anyone can help her,
they're at the hospital.
OK, so we're all agreed.
Yeah, all of us but Annie.
Sorry about all that earlier,
calling you a bitch and that.
It was out of order.
Oh, no, don't worry about it.
I was a bit pissed.
I wanted to get a bit of
Dutch courage before I went home.
Home?
Yeah, yeah.
I thought, you know,
bit of a drink, put on a bit of slap
and then go and
see my fella, Gethin.
He's a scrum half
for the Cardiff Blues, you know.
Ah, that's nice.
SQUELCHING
Anyway, um...you got a mirror?
Um...I don't actually
think we do, no.
I don't... I don't think
your friends like me much.
What? No! Don't be...don't be
so silly.
They're just like that.
Oh, it's all right.
Happens all the time, you know.
Guys get awkward, start showing off,
and the girls get jealous.
I get it a lot.
So, um...what's Mitchell's story?
Is he single?
No. No, he's my boyfriend.
Really?
Yep.
Really.
Wow!
You did well there, didn't you?
Didn't I?
Annie? Do you want to...
Please, yes. Good.
..and I'll take over for, um...
She has got to go.
Wow! That was easy.
Yeah, we thought
we'd have to persuade you.
What with you both
being dead and all.
She may well be dead,
but that is pretty much all
I have in common with that...
that...chavalanche.
Great. That's settled. I'll leave
it all in your capable hands.
I'm going back to bed.
Whoa, whoa. What?
Annie's invisible to normals.
You can't be seen on CCTV.
I think you can manage sneaking one
zombie back into a hospital.
Now, I am taking my lady friend
back to bed.
Good night.
What?
Aw.
Good night. Night.
SHE GIGGLES
Ooh.
What's that?
That's the tag from her toe.
It was stuck to her shoe.
Oh.
SHE HUMS A TUNE
So, um...how are we gonna convince
her to go back to the hospital?
We're not.
Not yet.
What? Why?
Check out the time
and date of death.
Let's pay a visit to the morgue.
HE URINATES
Oh.
HE STOPS URINATING
TOILET FLUSHES
DOOR OPENS
Nina. Nina?
Mm-hm?
Is this yours?
I thought, it can't be Mitchell's
because he's a man,
nor Annie's cos she's dead, it can't
be Nina's cos she's on the pill.
You're on the pill.
Why would you be needing
a pregnancy test? Are you late?
When were you thinking
about telling me? Look...
I was looking for the right moment.
OK, I'm not busy now. Are you busy?
Fine. I'm pregnant.
Oh, my God. But you're on the pill.
Yes. I am.
But we had sex when we weren't
exactly ourselves
and apparently, the pill wasn't
designed with werewolves in mind.
But you know
these tests can be wrong.
Look... Oh, I've done three tests.
I'm pregnant, George.
It's happening.
Or rather, it's not.
I can't... I can't...
I can't let this go any further.
Um...I'm sorry.
OK, so, um...let me get this
straight.
If I hadn't have found this,
would you have just had an abortion
without telling me? No.
I was planning...
God. You were just going to do it.
No discussion, no nothing.
Don't you dare judge me.
This isn't some...
some teenage mistake, George.
This is a child of...monsters.
I mean, who even knows
what it could be?
Just the idea is terrifying.
It could be fine.
We're both fine! Most of the time.
It's my body, George.
Yeah, well, part of it isn't.
Excuse me?
There is part of me in there.
As the father, I have as much right
as you to decide what
happens to our child.
HE HUFFS
I only got up for a pee!
DOOR HANDLE RATTLES
Is that blood?
Oh, that can't be good.
SHE PANTS: I'm already dead.
I'm already dead. I'm already dead.
'I'm already dead.'
What's that?
Where?
There.
Hey.
Bingo.
I don't think it was just Sasha.
I've got four subject sheets here.
All came back to life
all at the same time.
I think they were testing them,
trying to find out what they were.
How they worked.
If it could spread.
SCREAMS ON CAMCORDER
I think they were scared.
'SCREAMS'
I know the feeling.
Does it say anything
about anaesthetic in there?
Yeah.
Um...anaesthetic ineffective.
How did you know?
They did it anyway.
SCREAMS ON VIDEO CAMERA
What did they do...
with them afterwards?
Incinerated them...
as a biohazard.
Were they still alive
when they burned them?
I don't know.
Well, doesn't matter anyway,
does it?
Because they weren't really alive,
were they?
And the dead don't feel
real pain.
HE SIGHS
SASHA RASPS
SHE WHEEZES
SIREN IN DISTANCE
Funny, somehow I thought
you'd be taller,
you know, close up, like.
I'm sorry, do I know you?
Oh, no. No, no, no. No. God, no.
No, it's just that, um...
well, um... it's just that
I'm like you, you know.
OK, all right, easy, easy.
So, you're a vampire? Yeah, yeah,
I am a brother of the blood.
Name's Graham.
Well, Graham was my mortal name.
But when I was reborn to the night,
I took the name of Siddion.
Graham's fine.
Siddion, I don't know what I was
thinking. It's a shit name.
Yeah, um...all right, Graham.
Um...I'm kind of busy right now
so can I help you with anything?
Oh, God, I feel a little bit
embarrassed now,
but I am a little bit
of a fanboy.
Or I could say fang boy.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I get it.
And I was a massive
Neil Diamond fan.
Do you know Neil Diamond?
No, doesn't matter. But, um...
that kind of gave me the idea.
So, now I'm on a sort of pilgrimage,
you know, like a star tour,
and I'm visiting all the legends in
our little world, so naturally...
You came to see me.
Oh, my God.
You are up there with the greats.
What you did in Bristol,
it was just...
Remind me again. No, wait.
You don't need to be modest.
You got a whole chapter of vampires
to renounce blood. Amazing.
Are those boots Paul Smith?
Excuse me? Just wondering
where you got your boots.
Yeah, listen, um...Graham, I have
stuff that I really need to do, so...
Oh, God, yeah. No, of course.
Of course.
Well, it has been such a privilege
to meet you, Mitchell.
And, um...maybe
I could catch you again some time?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, maybe.
Maybe some time.
SOFTLY: Brilliant.
CLUNK
Yaaah!
SHE GROANS
Oh.
Hungover?
Yeah, yeah, just a bit.
BONES CRUNCH
Er...where did you two
disappear to last night?
Oh, to the hospital.
We went to find out
what happened to you.
We know about the others
and we know about the experiments.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I think someone else
has been drinking.
Oh, look, it's OK.
You're not alone.
We're all a bit...
different in this house.
How do you mean?
OK.
Well...
I'm a ghost,
Mitchell's a vampire, and
George and Nina are both werewolves.
BOTH GIGGLE
Fuck off!
Werewolves!
HE SNIFFS
Oh, no.
I'm ju... I've g...
Mitchell, wake up.
She's still here.
Who?
Who? Who do you think? She's a
little bit mouthy, little bit dead.
There have been developments.
What kind of developments?
Um...won't be a tick.
Mitchell, is she still here?
Yeah, there's been developments.
I was asking Mitchell.
Can you guys keep it down?
She can hear you.
Oh, great. Come on in. Apparently,
we're having a house meeting.
Look, so...so what's changed?
There were others like her
at the hospital.
They were experimenting on them.
Basically, they tested them to
destruction. They burnt them up.
Well, look, that's
a really horrible story,
but is this really the best place?
She's got nowhere else. We do have
a spare room. This was a B&B.
Oh, what? We're a supernatural
hostel now, are we?
What next, a mummy?
Look, I have had
ghost friends before.
This one just happens to be
in a dead body.
Oh, so you're friends now, are you?
You bloody hated her last night.
Shh! This is not about
whether or not I like her.
This is about
trying to do the right thing.
Look, she is rotting!
She smells like off meat.
Don't be so deadist.
Excuse me?
It's like racist,
but for dead people.
Have you just spent the whole night
making up words?
No, I have spent the whole night
watching footage
of screaming people
being dissected.
We owe her, George.
We owe her? Why do we owe her?
She came back to life two weeks ago.
All of them did, when I was
on the other side. Saving me.
So, hang on, what are we saying?
That death's door was engaged?
Her spirit couldn't pass over
because of me.
We made her.
We owe her. All of us do.
Guys?
OK, the address
is 37, The Mount, Cyncoed CF23.
WHEELS RATTLE
Have you got it?
Hey. Nice boots.
Mitchell, this is brilliant,
the two of us working together.
Oh, my God. I wish I had a camera.
Not that it would do me much good,
because we don't show up on photos.
Which is doubly ironic, considering
what I used to do for a living.
Go on, guess, Mitchell.
You can't work here.
Bingo, photographer.
SEAGULLS CRY
Hey. You gave us a bit of a scare
there, wandering off like that.
Oh, yeah, sure I did.
You don't have to worry about me
any more. I'm home. Do you like it?
It's Gethin's money but my taste.
This is not happening.
Cara says hello.
What did you say?
Yeah, she got over that whole
pretending to kill
and bricking her up thing.
You'd have to ask her, though.
Where is she?
Don't know.
She's around, though.
Digging up trouble somewhere.
What do you want?
All I want to do
is mop a few floors, Mitchell.
Is that too much to ask?
Bring it on!
BEEPING AND THUDDING
Oh, and the brilliant Welshman's
dominated this round.
Here comes the big finish.
It's a straight right.
GETHIN CHATTERS
AND GAME BEEPS
No, no, Gethin's got him.
He's got him.
Gethin's gonna finish.
BEEPING
Oh, he's got him.
He's got him. He's got him again.
You bastard!
HE GASPS
This is how you do grief, is it?
Playing on your bloody video games?
You should be in your bed,
crying your eyes out!
Um... maybe we should... Sasha!
Jesus! God! That's you, innit?
That's really you.
What's happened to you?
What's happened to you...?
They told me you died.
Yeah, well, plainly they were wrong.
I was suing them. They'd lost
the body. Consider it found.
Sasha, maybe we should... Yeah,
hang on! Did you mourn me at all?
Course I did, course I did!
We had a wake and everything.
A lovely big party.
You'd have been pleased as punch.
Oh. Do you still love me?
Course I do.
Mm.
Stay back!
What? But it's just me, babes.
Don't do that. I'm just the same
as I always have been.
Your little pumpkin.
Get away from me!
Oh!
Eurgh. Eurgh.
Gethin!
Geth!
Shall I, um...?
SQUELCHING
Uh. Oh.
Mm.
Oh.
Wow.
Right, I'm gonna just...
SHE GASPS
Um...we should probably go, Sasha,
cos he's bound to call the police.
No, he's not. What's he gonna say?
"My dead girlfriend came back..."
Oh, cos I am dead.
Aren't I? I keep saying I'm not.
But...oh, I can smell myself.
Oh, God.
Well, there are worse things
than being dead.
Just look at me. You can
be seen and heard by others.
And I can't.
What, you're really a ghost?
Yeah.
But you've stayed so pretty.
Like the dead stay pretty
in our memories.
You don't think of them like me.
You never picture them rotting.
But I can feel it happening inside
me like heat, like a compost heap.
And I know what happens when
things rot. They don't last.
No, no, you don't know that.
I mean, who knows
what the rules are to this?
I thought when I died that would be
it for everything and it wasn't.
And it doesn't have to be for you.
No, we can...we can help you
find your way. It'll be fine.
DOOR OPENS
HE SIGHS
Nina, I'm sorry.
I really wish we were normal.
I really wish we were having
a nice normal argument
about the pros and cons
of unwanted pregnancy
but...
we are not normal.
And maybe... It's not always
about the wolf, George.
So, what are you saying?
I've got other stuff, old stuff,
going on in my head.
It's...
SHE SIGHS:
It's not you.
It's not you, it's me.
No, it's becoming a mother
and, um...all that means.
You see, um...
...my mum used to hit me.
All the time.
For my own good, you know, and she...
SHE SNIFFS
...always reminded me that,
um, I was a mistake
and, er...I'd ruined her life,
and I was worthless,
and I would never amount to anything.
She...
she made me hate myself.
I'm sorry. You've...
you've never said.
No, there's never really a good time
to bring up that conversation.
See, this...this thing inside me,
whatever it is...
..it's a baby...
and I will become a mother,
and that terrifies me
more than any werewolf bullshit.
SHE LAUGHS
You see, I was...I was pretty messed
up even before you scratched me.
No, you're not.
You are strong
and you are beautiful.
You are not in this alone.
I will always be there.
I'm sorry.
It's not enough, George.
MUSIC PLAYS ON RADIO
Are we having a party?
Er...not quite.
It's getting-ready music.
Girlie night out.
Thought Sasha needed something
to cheer her up,
such as getting pissed in a loud,
dark room that smells of sick.
Yeah, it is a fine tradition,
but, er...
Mm-hm?
..won't she be seen?
Ah. Make-up.
Works wonders. Mm-hm!
HE SNIFFS
And how are you?
Me?
Uh-huh.
Oh, you know me.
Always chipper.
I never use the word chipper.
I don't know why I used it then.
And you? Yourself? You.
Are you...are you great today?
Are you milking a cow in there?
Ha-ha-ha!
So funny. Oh.
I must say, Mitchell, your old
friend is very, very interesting.
Two sugars, just like Mitchell. Oh,
cheers, love. All right, big fella?
Graham was just telling me
about the time you went skiing.
Funny. I don't remember that at all.
Well, it was more
falling than skiing.
We spent more time that week on
our backs, with snow in our mouths,
than on the skis.
I don't remember it
because it didn't happen.
Yeah, he was tough back then too,
when he was training me.
Such a hard taskmaster. All he used
to say was, train, train, train.
Train, bloody train.
You remember that, Mitchell?
Bloody train?
Yes!
Yes, I do, now that you mention it.
I don't know how I forgot about
that. That's really weird.
We don't want to bore
Annie with that.
Why don't I give you the tour?
Tour?
Great.
We have a tour?
Yeah.
Oh.
After you.
And this is the cellar!
You...are in my home with my friends.
That is a big no-no.
They could be my friends, too.
No, they couldn't!
And you've got a spare room.
I could move in.
Be nice to have Annie
down the corridor.
Don't you even think about it.
That girl, she's really
holding a torch for you.
And I'm thinking she doesn't know,
does she, about his greatest work.
About all those people
you ripped apart on that train.
The Box Tunnel 20.
And I think she needs to know.
I think she needs to know
about the real Mitchell.
See how she feels about him then.
Or we could maybe...
..just maybe forget
about the whole thing.
Sit down, watch a bit of Wipeout.
Have a biscuit.
I think that'd be for the best,
don't you?
HE SIGHS
Listen, er...
I've got a lot of stuff on tonight.
So, um...I'll catch you soon, yeah?
Come on, shake hands.
I'll teach you the cool one.
Shake.
OK, so first it's the normal one,
then clasp the thumb,
bit of that, bit of that,
bump the fist, and we're done.
Not really feeling the friendship,
though.
But we can work on that.
Mitchell.
All right, mate.
See you later.
MUSIC: Pretty Woman by Roy Orbison
♪ Pretty woman
Walking down the street
The kind I like to meet
♪ Pretty woman
♪ I don't believe you
You're not the truth
♪ No-one could look as good as you
♪ Yeah, she's walking back to me
♪ Yeah, oh... ♪
SHE GIGGLES
♪ Pretty woman. ♪
Wow.
Wow. Wow, look at that.
That is something else.
You'd better believe it, baby.
Let's go and shake our moneymaker.
BOTH LAUGH AND SQUEAL
You look great.
You all do.
Um...don't worry, I'm not drinking.
Uh-huh.
Got to keep an eye on...
Priscilla over there.
I'm the designated woman
with a pulse.
I just thought it'd be good to,
um... get out for a while, you know.
SASHA LAUGHS
Oh, yeah, no, no. No, it's great.
It's just...it's just a nice,
normal night out with the girls.
Mm-hm. Or this.
SASHA GIGGLES
How's she coping, do you think? Has
she come to terms with what she is?
Say it loud, I'm dead and I'm proud!
Deal with it!
VEHICLE SOUNDS TOOTS
Ooh! Right, come on, ladies.
Those fellas
aren't gonna shag 'emselves! Ha-ha!
Shag 'emselves!
Come on, Nina!
OK.
VEHICLE MOTOR RUNS
See you.
Bye.
Good luck.
Mitchell...
Shall we get pissed?
You...are a genius, George.
Mm-hm.
♪ ...Don't make a sound, voices in my
head playing like an echo, echo... ♪
Five years we were together.
Gone, like that. That's men for you.
Right, I am gonna show you
how it's done.
You stay there
and watch the master at work.
♪ Doo-doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo
♪ Bang, bang, bang, on the wall
♪ From dusk till dawn
♪ Doo-doo-doo-doo, doo-doo-doo-doo
♪ Bang, bang, bang, on the wall
♪ From dusk till dawn
♪ Doo-doo-doo-doo
Doo-doo-doo-doo... ♪
Oh, this is so not healthy.
She's just flirting.
She has every right to have fun.
Come on.
Oh, no.
Oh, come on.
No.
Nina, come on. It'll be good for
you. No, Annie. Please, no!
♪ Bang, bang, bang, on the wall
From dusk till dawn... ♪
SHE SIGHS
They should be back by now.
They're all adults.
And two of them are dead.
I think they've seen the worst
that life has to throw at them.
If you're worried,
call Nina's mobile.
I'm not worried.
Mitchell, it's OK to care.
It's...it's just when we lost Annie,
it's like that old cliche, isn't it?
You don't miss someone until
they're gone. And I missed her.
I really missed her. And I've got
this fear that I'll lose her again.
So, tell her.
Then I could really lose her.
And it would just make
our friendship weird.
Or, just maybe, your friendship
could become something else.
Something better.
MUSIC PLAYS
♪ Do it, do it, do it
Do it, do it, do it, do it now... ♪
SHE GIGGLES
♪ Do it, do it, do it
Do it, do it, do it, do it now... ♪
What? What?
Was I a bet?
BONES CRUNCH
SHE SOBS
Oh! Aah! Ow!
Oh! Oh!
GLASS BREAKS
Aah! Aah!
Help me. Please.
Help me!
Oh! Aah!
BONES CRUNCH
Uh! Aah!
SHE WAILS
All right, Sasha.
OK, you're OK.
OK.
MUSIC: "No Surprises" by Radiohead
♪ No alarms and no surprises... ♪
DOOR OPENS AND SHUTS
A bit of help here, please!
What's happened?
Don't know. She just collapsed.
Nearly there. All right, onto the
couch. What's wrong with her hands?
Oh, my goodness.
We don't know.
SHE WHEEZES
None of the others
lived long enough for this to happen.
Her body's still decaying.
Maybe whatever it was
that was keeping her moving
just can't fight the decay any more.
I think we may have another problem.
OK, Mitchell.
I need you to go back
to the hospital
and borrow a little wheelchair.
Why?
For Sasha.
I'm gonna take her on a little jolly
to the Millennium Stadium.
And then we may well go on to
the bay. It's lovely around there.
All the restaurants and boats and
stuff. This is...
Mitchell, I know what you're gonna
say and I don't want to hear it.
She has as much right to live a full
and active life as the rest of us,
and her condition should not
be an issue,
frankly, I'm a little disappointed
in you for even bringing it up.
Annie, it's OK.
I don't... What are you doing?
I don't want a hug.
It's OK, it's OK.
Shh.
Mm.
You know, I hated her
when we first met.
It seems weird now.
You're doing all you can for her.
You're a good friend.
DOOR CLOSES
Annie?
Oh, hey, Mitchell.
Graham just popped by and wanted
to know if we wanted anything.
What?!
Mitchell, what are you doing?
No, no, no, it's fine!
It's fine. It's just a...
it's a long-running joke we have.
Ha-ha! The neck-grab game.
He loves it! Isn't that right,
Graham? Yeah, he got me!
Oh, ho-ho, ho-ho!
You little monkey!
Why don't me and you have a nice long
chat about the good old days?
You'd like that!
It's a vampire tradition. Chill out.
Look at him go!
Oh, I don't know.
Vampires.
It's over. We are done here.
You forgotten what I know about you?
Screw it! Tell her.
I don't think you want me to talk.
I don't care any more.
Maybe it's time
they knew what I really am.
I don't deserve them as friends.
I never have.
So, how about this, right?
You tell them what I did, or I will.
You're bluffing.
Oh.
If you think that, then you really
don't know me at all, do you?
I will not be your puppet any more.
You are just a fat, pathetic wannabe
with no friends and
no personality of your own.
You are nothing.
SHE MOANS
SHE SIGHS
SASHA WHIMPERS
Annie.
OK, I'm here.
Don't let them take me, Annie.
Don't let them burn me.
Promise me you'll bury me.
I promise. Promise.
Oh, Mitchell. I, er...
I met your oddball friend.
What?
Graham?
He's been looking for you.
He seemed in a bit of a weird mood.
What did he say?
Um...he said, "Tell Mitchell
I'm going to make him proud."
Like you were his dad or something.
What's that about?
Oh, it's nothing. It's just a running
joke we have. Forget about it.
Bye.
♪ You're bad, you know... ♪
MITCHELL PANTS
You don't have to do this.
You think I can't.
You think I haven't got it in me.
It isn't hard to do.
The hard part is not doing it.
And I failed, and I've regretted that
every minute of every day since.
Then you are weak.
Who shall I do first?
Maybe I'll take the child.
Make the father watch.
I killed my own children, you know.
Ripped out their little throats.
Drained 'em dry.
Nothing's quite seemed
real since then.
I'm sorry for what's happened to you,
I really am.
I'm sorry I rejected you.
But...
this isn't the way.
You don't get it, do you?
I want to be the new legend that
vampires whisper about in the night.
The new king of blood.
Starting from now.
Apologies, ladies and gentlemen!
Undercover ticket inspector!
Get your tickets out!
Get off me!
He didn't have the right ticket!
Bitch!
Shut up, shh.
GRAHAM GASPS
So, what now, eh? You gonna kill me?
Cos you don't kill other vampires,
Mitchell. Cara proves that.
D'you wanna throw me off the train?
Go on, that's fine.
Cos there's plenty of other trains.
There's plenty of other targets.
And I swear to you,
what I am gonna do will make
your little massacre
look like a fucking paper cut.
How messed about are we, huh,
are vampires as a species,
that my story
can be seen as inspirational?
It has to end.
This story...has to die.
And it's gonna hurt.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Tell...tell people
that you liked me.
I will.
SASHA WHEEZES
Do you know what I wish?
I wish I'd done more.
You know, of everything.
Even the stupid stuff.
Like, every night that I went
home early cos I was a bit tired,
I just wish I'd stayed out
and danced and laughed
and lived.
Cos nights like that
won't come your way again.
Even Gethin.
I just wish I'd loved him more.
And kissed him more.
And held him more.
We talked about having a baby.
I just kept on putting it off.
Saying, you know, can't afford to
this year. We're going to Belize.
We're buying a new rug. A new car.
What does any of that matter now?
You got to promise me you won't
let those chances pass you by.
I promise.
Cos it all goes. It all falls away.
The looks.
Money.
Lovers, friends.
Not all your friends.
No.
And the ones that are there at the
end are the real ones, aren't they?
Yeah... Yeah.
Thank you...
for being my friend, Annie.
It's easy.
SHE SNIFFS
Live, Annie.
Seize the day.
I will.
How is she?
She's gone.
Sorry.
George.
SHE SIGHS
Would you like to have...
a little...
hairy baby with me?
Yes, I would.
HE CHUCKLES
Are you OK?
No.
No, I'm not.
Listen, I need to...
I need to tell you something.
I've done such things, Annie.
I've done such terrible...
..unforgivable things.
And I need to tell you.
No, you don't.
I need to do this.
Mitchell, listen.
I know what you are.
I've known since day one.
But all those things you've done,
they're in your past, right?
It's who you are now that counts.
And...and what you've done for me,
..for George, for all of us...
..that's the man I know.
That's the man I trust.
And...
..that's the man I want.
Do you forgive me?
We need to know if the baby
will survive the transformation.
I've been such a bad girl.
You can't outrun me.
Definitely can't outfight me.
You can't even outlive me.
HE SNARLS
Synch and correct by JustFuckingShit (or teftel)
www.addic7ed.com
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd
E-mail subtitling@bbc.co.uk