Male narrator: 25 years
ago, God disappeared.
His angels held man responsible,
and declared war on humanity.
The Archangel Gabriel led
this war of extermination,
hoping to rid the world of humans
and claim dominion over it.
Some higher angels refused to take sides,
but the lower angels joined Gabriel.
These lesser spirits lacked bodies,
so their first line of
attack was to steal ours.
But Michael, the greatest
of all archangels,
chose to fight for man.
With his help, the survivors struck back
and built strongholds to defend themselves.
Soon, word spread of a
baby Michael had saved,
a child who would grow
up to be mankind's savior.
This chosen one would be known
by the markings on his body.
Finally, Gabriel and his army retreated,
and we were left with the realization
that not only are angels real...
they are our most hated enemies.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
[Bats chirping]
[Electronic feedback whines]
[Bell dings]
[Woman speaking indistinctly]
[Objects clattering, bell dings]
[Objects clattering]
[Woman chuckles]
[Growling]
- Join us.
- [Giggles]
We have an empty seat.
- [Gunshot]
- [Gasps]
[Snarls]
[Shrieks]
[Squealing]
[Squeals]
A. Lannon, pass code 2271.
Open the gates.
2271. Respond!
A. Lannon, pass code 2271.
I've got an angel in pursuit.
- What have you got?
- 2271, respond!
Distress call, sir. One of ours.
Where the hell are you guys?
Open the damn gate!
Should I let him in, sir?
Open the gate!
2271. Open the damn gate...
[Screeches]
[Squealing]
A. Lannon! Passcode...
Warning, perimeter breach.
[Tires screeching]
[Gunfire]
[Explosion roars]
Now entering security zone five.
All right, all right, easy.
Yeah, okay.
Possession negative.
Lannon!
What the hell were you
doing outside the city
without authorization?
It was two-for-one
buffet at the Flamingo.
I just couldn't miss it.
What do you think I was doing?
You saw the eight ball.
It wasn't just one of 'em.
There was a whole group of 'em.
- We need to tell Riesen.
- No.
Take him to the archangel.
He's one of his men.
- Aw, man.
- I'll report to Riesen.
[Woman singing opera]
♪
You were a naughty boy tonight.
You shouldn't indulge me.
These evenings would be much more enjoyable
if you didn't hate yourself after.
Any risk, no matter how small,
that I might have children is too great.
Would it be such a bad thing?
Vega needs children.
Not children like that.
This has to stop.
Then stop.
♪
[Indistinct radio chatter]
Market access is
restricted to V-4 and above.
[Indistinct chatter]
Market access is
restricted to V-4 and above.
[Coins rattling]
[Meditative orchestral music]
♪
A regal Jubilee,
only at the Whele Arena.
Don't miss it!
[Indistinct shouting]
[Tires screech]
[Indistinct chatter]
This city's going to hell.
Exiting the city with a vehicle
is a realigning offense.
You're gonna get purged
down to V-0 for this.
It's an untouchable.
It's better than making
a home in Michael's ass
to be a V-3 like you.
How'd you do it?
You reprogram one of the gates?
Crack the surveillance?
Leave the whip.
You know the rules and why they exist.
Everything in Vega has a purpose.
That's how the city survives.
Founding law.
"For the protection and good of all,
gates are inviolable."
We have a right to leave. We all do.
No, you don't.
Tell me about the angels.
There were three of 'em, all eight balls.
But something about them was different.
One of them could change his body.
A soldier.
He had wings.
Where were they?
A couple miles down the strip.
- What were they doing?
- Playing Texas hold 'em.
Not kidding.
And what were you doing out there?
You know the punishment
for going outside the walls.
I'm gonna be purged?
No, you're Archangel Corps.
But if you ever do
anything like this again,
I'll not spare you.
Do you understand me?
Stand up.
- [Whip cracking]
- [Grunts]
I think that's enough, Michael.
He's learned his lesson.
Right, boy?
Tell no one about what you saw.
Not a word about the eight balls to anyone.
Now, go report for duty.
He shouldn't be outside the walls.
The ruins are too dangerous.
The boy has been sneaking
out since he was a child.
He knows Vega better than anyone.
- He needs discipline.
- Perhaps.
But after what he did for Claire,
I owe him.
The eight ball came right up to the gate.
They're back.
In the war,
the entire lower rank
of angels joined Gabriel,
but unlike archangels,
Gabriel's lower angels, the dogs of heaven,
they were lesser spirits
without a physical form,
and they couldn't visit
earth without a body,
so they stole ours.
Then came whispers of a chosen child
who would grow up to lead
mankind out of darkness,
and his legend quickly
spread, giving humanity hope,
a reason to fight back,
and the angels hated it.
Now, it's said that Michael acted alone,
saved the child, and hid him in such a way
that not even Michael knows where he is.
- You're late.
- Yeah, sorry, I got held up.
- Asshole.
- You're an asshole.
We continue to hope...
No, to believe that the chosen one,
our savior,
will someday reveal himself to us.
Is there anything else
I can help you with tonight, ma'am?
What happened to your head?
There were eight balls by the truck.
What?
Your father told me not to say anything,
so you have to keep quiet.
Alex, they attacked you.
That's what they do. I'm fine.
You need to speak to your dad.
I know. I know. I will tonight.
I've asked to see him.
I'll tell him about us,
and I will get his permission to marry.
But you still have to do
the knee and the ring thing.
It just so happens I
have a knee and a ring.
What?
Alex, he'll say yes. Trust me.
I know him.
You're my shield. You took a knife for me.
There is no me without you.
We're different, you and I.
Yeah, what?
You think you know him better than I do.
I know the system better than you.
Claire, the truck is ready.
We have enough supplies to
easily make it to Delphi.
Claire, they don't have numbers there.
Everyone is equal.
We could start a new life,
but it's got to be tomorrow night.
The city will be busy with the Jubilee,
and you could slip out.
But it won't come to that. He'll say yes.
But if he doesn't,
wherever you go,
I follow.
Okay?
What's your name, soldier?
Alex Lannon, V-2. The
House Riesen, AA Corp.
Alex Lannon.
It's against our law for you
to be alone with Claire, Alex,
so next time make sure
you're accompanied by another guard.
[Clears throat]
- Principate.
- Please, Claire, not you.
I'm still the same William
you played marbles with in this room.
Yes, and always be.
Yeah, maybe you should call me Principate.
It does sound much better
when it comes from you.
You missed services tonight.
- I was teaching.
- That's right.
You know, I admire your work
with Vega's less fortunate.
You of all people know how important it is
that our faith must be nurtured.
It must be kept like a promise.
It troubles me that so
many of Vega's citizens
have forgotten this simple truth.
Yes.
- Well, let us pray.
- Yes.
Hey, Bix.
What'd you do now?
I got on the wrong side of the peacock.
Riesen stepped in.
You should keep out of
anything to do with the tops.
Yeah, they're no different than us.
They just got a better number.
When's the last time you ate?
Here. I ate at the palace.
You want to know a secret?
One day, we're gonna live somewhere
where there aren't any numbers,
where we aren't told
what to do, what to eat,
where to sleep, and whom to marry.
One day, we're gonna be free.
- Promise?
- I promise.
Stay close the next day or so.
Something big's gonna happen,
and whichever way it goes,
you're coming with me.
- Consul.
- General.
Oh, lookee here.
I asked the horticulturist
to grow these on the agri-towers.
I never much cared for berries.
There was an angel attack on a soldier
outside the walls today.
Small group, three angels.
Easily destroyed.
Not all of 'em. One survived.
Don't worry. It's been taken care of.
But the archangel is concerned,
and you should be too.
Michael sees evil portent
in everything and everyone.
[Chuckles]
It was an isolated incident, nothing more.
No further sightings
on our long-range scans.
We deployed the drone.
All clear.
We don't want it getting out.
It could cause panic.
Perhaps that wouldn't be a bad thing.
We've done our jobs too well.
Vega has grown complacent, lazy.
So are you looking forward
to the announcement at the Jubilee?
Yes.
Tomorrow, then.
I've been guarding David
Whele for six months.
I finally saw what he
feeds that tiger of his.
It's not a tiger. It's a lion.
Is there a difference?
- Yeah, stripes.
- Whatever.
It gets steak for dinner...
dry-aged porterhouse.
When was the last time
you even tasted beef?
Cat's one of a kind. We're a dime a dozen.
Speak for yourself.
- Hey, boys.
- Both: Noma.
Hey, Ethan, can you weasel your way
into a bottle of Scotch for me tonight?
"Weasel"? Really?
- She means charm your way.
- Nooo... I mean "Weasel"!
[Laughs derisively]
You know what goes great with Scotch, Noma?
Porterhouse steak, and I can get some.
My gift to you.
Alex, I'll grab one for you too.
We're gonna eat like tigers tonight.
- Lions.
- Tigers.
You've been logging some serious overtime
- at House Riesen.
- I go where I'm told.
So General Riesen's just
decided to tighten security?
Why wouldn't he? He's lord of the city.
The man's concerned about
his daughter's safety.
Who said anything about his daughter?
No one.
It's just you know how he is about Claire.
Yeah.
He cares a lot about her, doesn't he?
[Mechanical whirring]
Don't the Wheles ever sleep?
Not if there's money to be made.
It's a delegation from Helena.
It's been a while since you seen anyone
from Helena around in these walls.
Have you ever seen one
of their kids before?
They keep 'em hidden. It's their law.
You think that kid's the one?
The chosen one's a myth.
That's something they tell children
to give them hope.
I don't understand why you'd have me travel
all this way to see
another of your factories.
Well, this isn't one of our factories.
Has Evelyn considered my proposal?
She's not ready to join
in a treaty with you
which may pit us against New Delphi.
Trading, yes.
Armaments, a mutual defense pact,
not now.
Evelyn wished to give you this.
A derringer.
One of these killed Abraham Lincoln.
[Gasps]
[Chuckles]
A thoughtful gift.
You obviously learned a lot
about me on your last visit.
A passion for weapons is hard to forget.
I would prefer you remember me
for something more inspiring.
- And what would that be?
- Hope.
Gone are the days when
darkness is something to fear.
With this technology,
the lights of Vega will
shine as a beacon of hope
for 1,000 years.
Along with food and our medicines,
I can offer 500 brides,
all of childbearing age,
in exchange for the technology
to build our own reactor.
There'll be time to negotiate later.
My men will show you the bungalows
where you can rest and freshen up
after your flight.
Thank you, David.
And tomorrow night,
you'll be my guests at the yearly Jubilee
in the Grand Arena.
It's a small gesture
the house of Whele makes
to inspire and entertain the city.
- Good night, Arika.
- Good night.
I wonder if the brides she
was offering would be spies.
Possible. We have so much that they don't.
Helena has the only
air force in the cradle,
a fleet of aircraft
they inherited from hill air force base.
The cripple Riesen won't
be an obstacle much longer.
Once we have consolidated our position
and you've been made lord of the city,
we'll want her as an ally.
[Dogs howling and barking]
Jeep.
I see you still like the highest perch.
It's been 15 years.
- I thought you were dead.
- Hmm.
14 1/2, but who's counting?
- What does everyone else think?
- The same.
David Whele built you a statue in memoriam.
That's creepy.
It's not a good likeness.
It looks more like Whele than you.
[Chuckling] He hasn't changed.
We all assumed the tattoos were lost to us.
No.
Have you deciphered any of them?
It isn't just a language to decipher.
It's something else.
And from what I could find,
there's no historical equivalent.
Much of the last 14 years was
spent on wild goose chases,
looking for the names of
prophets I'd misspelled
or tasks I thought I was
commanded to carry out.
Unfortunately, the
tattoos are indecipherable.
How is he?
What's he like?
Undisciplined, strong-willed,
passionate, mercurial.
Good.
- Can you bring him to me?
- Yes.
Everything's about to change.
War's coming.
People have lived inside these walls
so long they've forgotten
they're not prisoners.
Father, there's something
that I need to tell...
I'm stepping down from ruling Vega.
The city's strong enough
to give power back to the people.
Let them make their own way going forward.
The people are not ready.
Vega is not ready.
And Senator Whele will never
give up power that easily.
He won't allow the people
to govern themselves.
Father, if you step down
in the name of democracy,
he will turn this city into a dictatorship.
And what do you think it is now?
You're a good man.
Am I?
Why now?
We have worked so hard to build this city
into what it is.
You can't just give up.
I'm not giving up. I'm moving forward.
So should you.
You have the strength of character
that Vega desperately needs, Claire.
You'll be important to its survival,
and soon, you'll be
called on to protect it.
So what was it you wished to tell me?
Nothing. It was nothing.
You're as paranoid as ever.
If that were true, you'd be dead.
Tell me about the boy.
I've never seen any of
your children before.
Why bring him here?
Roan isn't one of our children.
He's favored by Evelyn.
She dotes on him like an adopted son.
Oh.
Why?
He's a savant.
Knows 20 languages, can
play a Bach piano concerto,
recites Shakespeare.
His knowledge of history is astonishing.
He's amazing, teaching us many things,
but he's painfully shy
and needs to be treated gently.
Roan wanted to see the great city of Vega,
and Evelyn denies him nothing.
She believes he's special,
very special.
And you?
I've never seen a child quite like him.
A boy with those gifts
could be useful to Vega.
[Chuckles]
He's not for sale.
Everything has a price.
[Gasps]
She wants to see you upstairs.
Needs some stuff from the supply center
for tonight.
Yes, ma'am.
I need these filled by early afternoon.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Listen.
Something is happening with my father
that could change everything.
I couldn't bring it up to him.
So tonight after the Jubilee,
we leave as planned.
That'll be all. Thank you.
Come with me.
[Blade scraping]
[Both grunting]
Okay, okay, okay.
You've trained him well, Michael.
Dad?
How did you get here?
I came back last night to see you, to talk.
I'm not interested in
anything you have to say.
You gave me up.
A scribbled note left in
the night made that clear.
Do you remember what it said? I do.
"You'll be an orphan now, Alex."
I didn't think I'd make it back.
I was 11. You left me alone.
You had Michael.
[Scoffs]
He isn't even human.
Human enough to side
with us against his own.
The only one to fight for us.
Without Michael, we would've lost the war.
Alex! Nothing's been done
that wasn't necessary.
"Necessary"?
Do you realize by making me an orphan,
you put me in the lowest caste?
A 1.
If I hadn't become a soldier,
I wouldn't have had anywhere
to sleep or anything to eat.
You basically left me to die.
It isn't the life I
would have chosen for you.
None of it is.
You. You knew this all along.
Alex.
You go back to whatever
hole you crawled out of.
You don't have a son.
We need to bring the council together today
before the Jubilee.
Did I do the right thing for Alex?
That remains to be seen.
They found this at the altar.
I don't understand.
The angels took everything from us,
and there are idiots
who still worship them.
I know, but the acolytes are still
a small and secretive group.
- They can't hide forever.
- Good.
My followers will find them.
Keep them searching.
Come on inside.
[Raspy breathing]
[Snarling]
[Gasps]
He was caught outside the
city walls this morning,
trying to find a way inside.
You... you brought one into the city?
People need to be reminded
of what we're up against
and who's protected them all this time.
You're sharpening that like
you're gonna kill somebody.
Yeah, you. You're late.
I was working in the laundry,
and they wouldn't let me go.
I'm sorry. I had a bad day.
You want to talk about it?
It's in the past.
Bixby, gonna meet me at
south entrance of the arena.
Access is restricted to V-2 and above.
- Can you get in?
- Yeah.
10:00 P.M. tonight.
Do you understand? You can't be late.
- What's going on?
- You'll see.
And, Bixby, you can't tell anyone.
You got it?
[Gun cocks]
She's more of a man than you.
What's Michael being so cryptic about?
Yeah, I'm alive.
How?
Thick-headedness.
I haven't been able to
decipher anything of substance
from the tattoos.
- Can Michael?
- No.
But more importantly, I found Gabriel.
What?
I guess it was wishful thinking
that he might have died in the bombings.
He built a fortress and
an army of the possessed
in the mountains outside of Boulder.
They seem to have adapted.
Gabriel is massing for another war.
It gets worse.
A few of the higher
angels have joined Gabriel,
and they can appear perfectly human.
In the same way as Michael and Gabriel?
Yes.
They belong to the second sphere of angels,
the powers.
They were born to be warriors
to keep the other angels in line,
and like Gabriel,
some of them have always hated man.
The powers are far more dangerous
than the angels that possessed mankind
during the extermination.
I had hoped they would sit out this war.
Gabriel's obviously persuaded
some of them to join him.
His name is Furiad.
We should cancel the Jubilee.
- Alert the city.
- Agreed.
All of this has convinced me
it's time to reveal the chosen one.
- You know who it is?
- Yeah.
Who?
We will tell you soon enough.
[Scoffs] I don't have time for this.
There's no chosen one,
no one coming to save us.
Never was.
We're the chosen ones,
not some imaginary savior.
That isn't true.
The savior's real.
The baby lived.
That's your delusion, not mine.
So the baby lived.
Many babies lived. We lived.
Hear them out, David.
Michael has never misled us.
Michael may not be a
mystery to you, Madam Consul,
but he is to me.
What were you planning on doing?
Find some random child,
and tell us he's the baby?
What proof do we have?
How do we measure him, on your word alone?
You have faith.
[Chuckles]
Oh, that died a long time ago, Archangel,
when your kind laid waste to my planet.
And "War Is Coming"?
Not news to me.
It never ended.
We are the angels' natural enemy.
It won't be over until
they're extinct or we are.
And what we have to do is prepare everyone
for that inevitability.
Lead them!
And we lead them by attending the Jubilee.
People need a release from
the stress of this city,
but more important,
they need something to inspire them.
So, General, tonight has to go forward.
We cannot cancel.
After that, I mean,
I'll be the first to reconvene here,
roll my sleeves up,
and do whatever it takes to keep us safe.
But don't ask me to put
my faith in some child god.
A savior.
I'll never do it again.
[Cheerful music playing]
♪
[Laughter]
[Cheers and applause]
♪
- How could you allow it?
- Allow what?
- Allow him to have you.
- It's work, nothing more.
Evelyn won't see it that way.
[Cheers and applause]
I've got nothing to say to you.
Then I'll do the talking.
I never knew there were any pictures
of my mother.
This is the only one.
It's been my good luck
charm all these years.
Now it's yours.
Welcome, Vega!
[Cheers and applause]
Tonight we celebrate our
resilience, our fortitude,
and our collective courage!
[Cheers and applause]
Every year we use this, our Jubilee,
to be reminded of the past,
but also to look forward,
and it is in that spirit of looking forward
that I have an announcement to make
of incredible importance
to this, our beloved city,
to Vega!
[Cheers and applause]
Tonight... tonight our
city will become stronger.
It will become unified,
because tonight it is my great pleasure
to announce the engagement
of Claire Riesen...
[Cheers and applause]
to William Whele.
Come on, son. Come and take a bow.
Come.
Come on, Claire. Stand up.
[Cheers and applause]
Through their marriage,
we will join Vega's two greatest houses,
the house of Riesen and Whele,
thus securing the safety and future
of this wondrous city.
[Cheers and applause]
Now, as is our custom,
at the Jubilee,
we celebrate the soldiers
who stand on our walls,
who protect us,
keep us safe so that
we can enjoy this life,
but tonight
we have something extra special.
Thomas Ford is one of
Vega's greatest champions,
a legend for killing
22 eight balls in battle
with nothing but his knife.
Let's hear it for Thomas.
[Cheers and applause]
[Horns play fanfare]
Well, Thomas, it's time to meet the 23rd.
[Cheers and applause]
[Suspenseful music]
♪
[Snarls]
[Snarling]
[Crowd exclaiming]
Okay, settle down now.
There's nothing to fear.
We are in complete control.
You allowed him to bring one into the city?
But it's good. It's always good...
I had no idea.
To be reminded of what we face,
what is out there waiting for us,
the thing that asks nothing but takes all.
It must be destroyed.
Gabriel.
[Shouting]
- [Crowd screaming]
- Oh, my...
[Squeals]
Let's go. Come on.
Let's go!
[People screaming]
[Dramatic music]
♪
Warning, security breach.
How did they get that
close without us knowing?
Warning, security breach.
Ah, hell. Fire!
[Gunfire]
[People screaming]
Code Red.
A citywide attack is imminent.
Get Claire and Riesen to bunker eight.
Stay there until I come and get you.
Go, go! Bunker eight!
Code Red. A citywide attack is imminent.
[Screaming]
Bixby!
Code Red, Code Red.
Report to designated safe area.
Get back! Get back!
[Siren wailing]
[People shouting]
Let's go! Move, people, this way!
Come on!
Bixby!
- Come on, come on!
- Alex!
Claire!
I'm so sorry. I didn't know.
Listen, we don't have
enough time right now.
We gotta get out of here.
No, no, no, no, no!
Claire, Claire, this way.
Go this way!
[Suspenseful music]
♪
- What am I looking at?
- Three angels, sir.
They breached the city's defenses.
We managed to destroy one of them,
but two made it over the wall.
- Where are they headed?
- The reactor, sir.
Incoming!
♪
Fire! Fire!
[Gunfire]
[All groaning]
_
[Both grunting]
Let's go.
Leave right now, tonight.
Leave the city? It's under attack.
- This is a Code Red.
- It's perfect.
By the time they begin looking for us,
we'll be half way to Delphi.
I can't.
Not right now.
My father needs me, and Vega needs us.
We have to stay and protect the city.
We'll work this out.
Nobody is gonna tell me who to marry, Alex.
What makes you think you're
gonna have a choice, huh?
If we go through that door, Claire,
we're staying.
We're never gonna leave.
Alex, I promise.
I promise I will make this right.
Trust me.
Please, don't leave me.
[Indistinct chatter]
Sir, what's...
[Grunts]
[Growls]
[Electricity whirring]
Sir, every camera in the city is dark.
- What are you doing?
- Michael needs my help.
- Michael can handle himself.
- Get out of my way.
If this bunker's breached,
all of Vega's leaders
are within these walls.
Claire? She's your responsibility.
- You're needed here.
- I'm needed out there more.
You can't help him now. No one can.
It won't take long to
restore power to Vega.
We'll soon get our defenses back online.
I have every confidence in you, David.
I was so worried.
Thank the savior you're all right.
I am.
[Grunts]
[Gunfire]
Stop firing!
Cease fire!
[Somber orchestral music]
♪
I need a med kit!
You're ready.
I believe in you.
You... you are the chosen one.
The last words from a dying brain.
The man was hallucinating.
Ridiculous.
Get up.
Arrest her.
You have to believe me,
David. We had no part in this.
- And round up her entourage.
- I had no idea what Roan was.
He was deceiving all of us.
What would we have to gain?
- Please think.
- I am.
General, please, you must listen to me.
Go! Go!
I don't want her hurt.
Arresting Arika could spark another war.
We're already at war.
They brought that thing into the city,
and it killed Jeep.
And you unleashed that
monstrosity at the Jubilee.
How is this any different?
You knew what you were doing.
It's not sure that she did.
Vega has become unfocused, and so have you.
My little demonstration
couldn't have worked any better.
Now we'll all be ready for
the battle that's coming.
So, Alex Lannon,
show us your arms.
Who's that?
Bixby.
- Designation?
- V-1.
V-1... What... what is she doing here?
She's with me.
She's under my protection.
The protection of House Riesen.
Well, she better be able to keep a secret,
because no one here is
gonna breathe a word of this
to anyone until we've
figured out what it all means.
- Is that understood?
- She'll be quiet.
I promise.
I'm fine.
What happened?
The reactor was damaged,
but containment held...
for now.
The boy was an angel,
another member of the powers.
That's why he was able to
pass through our scanners.
Jeep was right.
More than one higher
angel has joined Gabriel
in his war against us.
Cover up.
Make sure none of the tattoos show.
Alex is the baby I saved
all those years ago.
He's under my protection.
I don't believe this Alex
Lannon is the chosen one
or even that the baby was ever real.
You saw the tattoos. You saw what happened.
I saw the tattoos
transfer from Jeep to Alex,
but I've seen more
extraordinary things happen
since this insanity began.
The tattoos are a
harbinger of what's to come.
They will usher in a period of hope.
Save it for your flock, William.
Religious theater is one thing.
This is politics.
My faith is not a theater,
nor is it a delusion.
I don't know what it all means,
but I'm not bowing to anyone,
and you aren't either.
Alex Lannon is now our greatest threat,
and Claire Riesen is in love with him,
which makes your union that much harder.
What? You're wrong.
Oh, William, come on.
I'm sorry, but your feelings for Claire
have obviously blinded you
to what was plain to see in that room,
which makes it more imperative than ever
that we take full control of Vega.
Evelyn isn't gonna like
us holding Arika in prison.
Riesen thought she was innocent.
She seemed to be speaking
the truth when she said
she had no idea what Roan was.
I don't care.
That city is full of assassins.
How do you think Evelyn came to power?
You know Arika is Evelyn's wife, don't you?
Don't agree with Riesen about anything
ever again.
You were never alone.
What?
When Jeep left, you were never alone.
I watched over you.
I made sure you joined the army.
I formed the Archangel Corps
so that I could stay close to you
without arousing suspicion.
Everything was done so
you could train in secret.
No one could know who you were.
Am I supposed to thank you...
thank Jeep... for all of this?
No, it just is.
As your father, Jeep held
the tattoos on his body
for when you were ready.
He knew it might mean his death.
I'm not ready.
- I'm no savior.
- You are.
It's up to you to decipher the tattoos.
I bore them on my body
before they were transferred
onto Jeep's,
but they were always
meant for the chosen one.
First the tattoos were on
you. Then they were on Jeep.
Then they're on me.
How do I know they're not
meant for someone else?
What are they?
Our fate...
Our hope...
written in a language long since forgotten,
one even I don't know.
Can you show them to me?
Can you read them?
- I can't.
- You must.
This is war, and only one side can win.
What's in those tattoos will guide you
through what's to come.
They will lay out the path
through which mankind can be redeemed
and Gabriel and his legions pushed back,
but this path will not be easily traversed.
At every step,
you must choose which course to take.
I believe you are the only one
that can end this war.
I'm just a man, Michael.
How can you be sure?
Nothing is ever certain,
but Jeep had hope, Alex.
He had faith in you,
and so do I.
Try.
Can you discern anything?
No.
My son,
William.
We found him.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com