SAM: Angels got to
have something to do, right,
now that
we're post-apocalypse?
Raphael and his followers,
they want him to rule Heaven.
I...
and many others...
the last thing we want
is to let him take over.
You're talking civil war.
Balthazar.
It's so good to see you.
You stole the Staff of Moses.
I stole a lot of things.
- I need the weapons.
- Don't ask that.
If we can beat Raphael,
we can end this!
Tell, uh, Raphael...
...to bite me.
BALTHAZAR: Hey!
No.
[Salt clatters]
Until next time.
I've got to make a call.
I got a cell you can use.
It's not that kind of call.
Ugh!
[Gasping]
Yes, father.
Ruby?
Stop it!
Good to see you again, Dean.
She's a demon, Sam, period.
They want us dead.
We want them dead.
Look what she did to you!
She's poison, Sam!
[Thunder crashes]
Where's Bobby?
In town, supply run.
In this?
Yeah, man's a hero.
We were officially
out of hunter's helper.
[Bottle clanks,
thunder crashes]
[Electricity crackles]
[Thunder crashes]
BALTHAZAR: Hello, boys.
You've seen
"The Godfather," right?
Balthazar...
You know, the end,
where Michael Corleone
sends his men
to kill his enemies
in one big, bloody swoop?
Hey!
"Dead sea brine."
Good, good, good.
You know, Moe Greene
gets it in the eye,
and Don Cuneo gets it
in the revolving door?
I said "hey."
You did.
Twice.
Good for you.
Blood of lamb.
[Thunder crashes]
BALTHAZAR: Beer, cold pizza.
Blood of lamb. Yes!
Blood of lamb!
Why are you talking
about "The Godfather"?
Because we're in it...
right now, tonight.
And in the role
of Michael Corleone...
the Archangel Raphael.
[Thunder crashes]
DEAN: You mind telling us
what you mean?
[Sighs lightly]
No, no, no, no.
[Metal clatters]
Yes.
Bone of a lesser Saint.
This vertebra will do
very nicely.
Your Mr. Singer
does keep a beautiful pantry.
Wait, Raphael is after you?
Raphael is after us all.
You see, he's consolidated
his strength.
And now he's on the move.
- And where's Cass?
- Oh, Cassie?
He is deep,
deep underground.
So, good old Raffy
put out a hit list
on every last Samaritan
who helped our dear Cass...
including both of you.
And so much more importantly,
me.
[Coughs]
See, he wants to draw Cass
out in the open.
And you expect us
to just believe you?
Oh, don't.
You'll go where I throw you
either way.
What's that supposed to mean?
[Electricity crackling]
That's all the time
we have, gentlemen.
[Thunder crashes]
[Exhales sharply]
Where is it?
- Whoa.
- What happened there?
Oh. Garish, I know.
You see, Uncle Raffy sent
one of his nastiest to handle me.
I'm flattered, actually.
And down a lung at the moment,
but that's all right.
Oh, here's for you.
- What am I supposed to do with this?
- Run with it.
[Thunder crashes]
[Grunts]
[Groans]
Virgil!
I said, run!
[Grunts]
BOB: Cut!
Real good solid fall.
Way to go.
Jared, Jensen! Outstanding!
That was just great.
"Supernatural,"
scene one echo, take one.
Tail slate. Marker!
Season 6 Episode 15
"The French Mistake"
[Bell rings]
[Hammering]
So... no angels?
[Cranking]
No angels, I think.
But that was great!
[French-Canadian accent]
It's not a problem with the stunt.
It's a problem
with the... signal.
Should we be killing anybody?
SERGE: Interference.
- I don't think so.
- Well, how much did we get?
- Running?
SERGE: About half.
- Where?
KEVIN: Gets us right up to where they...
Just before
they hit the window.
You know, the part
where they hit the window
was the good part.
Well, we can clean up,
reset the window,
takes about 95 minutes,
basically.
So, we'd have to
blow off the scene
where they sit on the Impala
and talk about their feelings.
Ha. Right.
You answer the hate mail.
Or we could have them
fly at the window,
then freeze frame.
Then cut to black, act out.
Freeze frame.
Um... yeah.
[Inhales sharply]
Serviceable.
[Sighs]
Fine.
Whatever.
Season Six.
Moving on.
Moving on!
That's a wrap
on Jared and Jensen!
W... who the hell are...
Jared! Three minutes, okay?
Great.
Where are we going?
Jensen, there you are!
Let's just get you
in the chair.
"The chair"?
Okay, hon,
we're just gonna get
this makeup off your face.
Wha... [Laughs]
I'm not wearing any ma...
Oh, crap!
I'm a painted whore!
Trish Evian here
with Jared Padalecki
from TV's "Supernatural."
So, Jared, Season Six.
What?
You beat the Devil,
lost your soul,
and got it back again.
So tell us, what's next
for Sam Winchester?
Look, I... I... I really don't...
Oh, and if you could include
the question in your answer?
Thanks.
[Chuckles nervously]
Hey.
Dude, they put
freakin' makeup on us!
Those bastards!
- Look, I think I know what this is.
- Okay. What?
- It's a TV show.
- You think?
Yeah. I mean, here...
wherever "here" is,
this... this twilight zone
Balthazar zapped us into.
For whatever reason,
our life is a TV show.
- Why?
- I don't know.
No, seriously. Why?
Why would anybody want to watch our lives?
Well, I mean, according to that
interviewer, not very many people do.
Look, I'm not saying
it makes sense.
I'm just saying, we...
we landed in some dimension
where you're Jensen Ackles,
and I'm something
called a "Jared Padalecki."
So what, now you're Polish?
Is any of this
making any sense to you?
Oh, hey.
Least my baby made it.
[Chuckles]
Hey.
Hey! What...
I feel sick.
I'm gonna be sick.
I want to go home.
I feel like this whole place
is bad-touching me.
Yeah, I know.
Me too.
So, what do you think?
Cass?
He's our best shot,
if he's still alive.
Dear Castiel,
who art maybe running his ass
away from heaven,
we pray that
you have your ears on.
So...
breaker, breaker...
Cass? Cass!
Hey, Cass!
Oh, thank God.
What is all this, huh?
W... w... what did
Balthazar do to us?
[As Castiel] To keep you
out of Virgil's reach,
he's cast you
into an alternate reality,
a universe similar to ours
in most respects
yet dramatically different
in others.
Like... like bizarro earth,
right?
Except instead
of having Bizarro Superman,
we get this clown factory.
Um...
Yeah, well...
Anyway, no time to explain.
- Do you have the key?
- Yeah.
So, uh, what does
this thing do, anyway?
It opens a room.
What's in the room?
Every weapon Balthazar
stole from Heaven.
He gave it to us?
To keep it safe
until I could reach you.
With those weapons, I have
a chance to rally my forces.
Oh. Okay, good. Yeah.
So, now, uh, what's the deal
with all this TV crap?
Pardon?
Yeah. Amen, Padaleski.
- Uh, "lecki."
- What?
Lecki. Pretty sure.
[Sighs]
[Normal voice] Man.
- Did they put out new pages?
- New what?
I mean, is this some kind
of cosmic joke?
Yeah, 'cause if it is,
it's stupid,
- and we don't get it.
- Yeah.
[Chuckles] Are you guys okay?
Give me that.
What is...
these are words in a script.
- This isn't Cass.
- Dude, look at him.
You guys want
to run lines, or...?
His name's Misha.
Misha?
[Sighs heavily] Oh, wow.
Just... great.
Misha? Jensen?
What's up with the names
around here?
[Groans] You guys!
You really punked me!
[Laughs]
[Chuckles]
I'm totally
gonna Tweet this one.
"Hola, mishamigos.
J-squared...
got me good."
I just want to dig my finger
in my brain and scratch
until we're back in Kansas.
"Really...
starting to feel...
like one of the guys."
Hey.
"J. Ackles."
- That's fake me!
- Yeah.
This must be fake mine.
[Door squeaks]
[New-age music plays]
[Door slams]
Dude, I have a helicopter!
[Scoffs]
Oh.
All right, who puts a 300-gallon
aquarium in their trailer?
Apparently, Jensen Ackles.
Huh.
All right, here we go.
Let's see who this guy is.
Well, he's not a hunter,
but he plays one on TV.
Oh.
Come on.
Look at these male-modelin'
sons of bitches.
Nice "Blue Steel," Sam.
Hey. Apparently, it's our job.
All right, uh, here goes.
Um... it says
you're from Texas.
- Really?
- Yeah.
And, uh...
Oh.
Says you were on a soap opera.
What?
NICOLE:
If I didn't have cancer,
and I wasn't married,
and I had plenty of money...
would you... would you want
to run away with me?
Money?
What, you think I really care
about money, Nicole?
I care that you're healthy.
Well, I'm no quitter, Eric.
I... I...
[Laptop slams]
Don't like this universe, Sammy.
We need to get out
of this universe.
Yeah. No argument here.
But I don't think our...
our prayers
are reaching Cass.
Or the real Cass.
Well, I agree.
I think we are definitely
out of, uh, soul-phone range.
But...
SAM: What?
If we can reverse
Balthazar's spell...
I watched every move.
We just, uh,
get the ingredients, right,
get back to that same window,
and...
...there's no place
like home.
Backbone of a lesser Saint.
Got it.
Uh...
[Scoffs]
It's rubber.
Check this out.
[Sighs] [Knife clatters]
Hey, look. It's fake.
It's all fake!
Well, at least they're talking
to each other. [Sighs]
What are we supposed to do
with this crap?
SAM: 'Course everything is fake.
We're on a film set.
We got to get back
to the real world.
Yeah, now you're talking.
[Engine turns over]
[Engine squeals]
All right, we go round up
the genuine articles,
bring 'em here for the spell.
[Engine sputtering]
What the hell is going on?
What is wrong with this thing?
- Mr. Ackles! Mr. Ackles, please!
- Uh, Dean?
God, Mr. Ackles, please!
- Dean, it's not the Impala.
- Please!
Stop.
- You think?
- Please!
It's a frigging prop!
Just like everything else.
[Engine stops] Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for...
How the hell are we supposed to
get out of here?
CLIF: You know whereabouts
you want me to drop you off?
Jensen?
Me? Yes.
I... I'll just tag along
with, uh...
- Jared. Jared.
- ...Jared here.
Huh. Since when
are you guys talking?
Yeah, uh, y... you know
what, Clint, uh...
Uh, uh, Clif.
Y... yeah.
Yeah, of course.
[Scoffs]
Clif. Obviously.
Um, so, uh, I think we're gonna
go back to my place
a... and do some...
work.
Work on our acting.
- Yeah.
- For our characters.
- For the show.
- Yeah.
All right. [Laughs]
Where the hell are we, anyway?
Dude, we're not even
in America.
Nice modest digs, Jay-Z.
[Door closes] Wow.
I must be the star
of this thing.
[Scoffs] Yeah, right.
Check it out.
What am I, Dracula?
[Door creaks]
George Hamilton Dracula.
Oh.
Now we're talking.
[Animal bleats]
[Bleating intensifies]
Dude, you have a camel
in your backyard.
It's an Alpaca, dumb-ass.
Ruby?
[Alpaca bleats]
"Ruby." Right.
That one never gets old.
How was work today, hon?
[Alpaca bleats]
Wait.
You and Ruby?
Do you honestly think
that's funny, Jensen?
Right.
'Cause you're not Ruby.
You...
I mean, how could you be?
Of course! You are the lovely
actress who plays Ruby.
[Chuckles]
And you are, uh, in...
Jared's house,
uh, because you two are...
...married!
You married fake Ruby?
What are you doing?
Work.
Work. [Chuckles]
Yeah, just, uh,
thought I'd pop in, say "hey."
Hey.
Uh, and... and...
and maybe run some lines.
It's...
You've never even
been to our house.
[Chuckles nervously]
Well, now that I know
there's an Alpaca out back,
I'm definitely coming back.
Well, Alpacas
are the greenest animal.
Right. Right.
That is so important.
Well, there's that thing
I have to get to.
Oh, yeah. Of course, yeah.
The thing.
The International Otter
Adoption Charity dinner?
Oh.
[Inhales deeply]
Okay, well...
Well, I'm glad you two
are talking, anyway.
Yeah.
Well, looks like
you did all right.
[Laughing] Yeah.
Yeah.
I should figure out her name.
"Wrist bone of Saint
and holy reliquary.
Museum-quality,
from diocese in Oaxaca."
- Looks legit.
DEAN: All right.
Auction house
is in Mexico City.
We could be there
day after tomorrow.
We, uh, case it, yank it, be back
here by the end of the week.
Or we could just buy it.
What?! Dude, that thing's
over a hundred thou...
Hello, Jared Padalecki.
[Laughs]
Cubrirá a su amigo
en la aduana.
¿No?
Bueno.
Triple rush. No problemo.
Because money is no ob...
[Computer bloops]
This baby's maxed.
Wow.
They said it should be
at the airport
first thing in the morning.
[Laughs]
Money, man.
There is nothing like it.
[Computer pings] All right.
Couch.
TV star.
Beauty rest.
Ahh.
[Door opens, closes]
[Sam exhales sharply]
Hey!
Hey. Hi.
Hi, uh, Gen...
Genevieve.
- Gen?
- Gen.
Gen. Of course. Yeah.
Um, so, h...
how was the...
Otter thing?
It was good.
Yeah?
Everybody missed you there.
Oh. Wow. Wow.
I bet.
So... so listen,
I... I got to ask you a question.
Do you remember, uh, uh,
year before last,
all those disasters?
- Disasters?
- Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, the whole
earthquake spike.
You know, the...
the 9.2 in Rome?
I mean, the...
the 8.5 outside Boston?
The whole east/west
Tsunami chain?
Yes.
I remember all of those
from last season on your show.
No, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
I... I know.
I know.
That... that's what I mean.
That's what I was... talking about.
You have been Sam Winchester
way too long.
Thanks. [Grunts]
CLIF: So I don't mean to pry,
but, uh,
why are we picking up
packages at 8:00 a.m.
that haven't
cleared customs yet?
Just saving time.
All right, here we go.
CLIF: We're not doing
anything illegal, are we?
Would it make you feel better
if we said no?
CLIF: No!
Whoa. What?
We finish today in 12 hours
if it kills us all.
Get "A" and "B" Cam
for scene 12.
What is this?
Here for the first run-through,
before anyone else?
Dedication.
Uh, can I talk to you
for a second?
Um, we're gonna need
the, uh, set cleared
for... safe side,
an hour or so.
You need it cleared.
Yeah.
Yeah. Me and, um...
Jared were gonna do
some actor stuff.
Jensen,
we're thrilled to see you
collaborating so creatively.
And your enthusiasm
is refreshing.
Dean Cain was like that
on "Lois,"
and that man's a real actor.
And we will clear this set
exactly when we shoot
the 2 3/8 pages
we are scheduled to shoot
on this set.
So you do your "actor stuff"
and we'll do
our "camera stuff" and, uh...
Ooh, "priority."
What's in it?
I bought
parts of a dead person.
Oh, cool.
Uh, so, bad news.
Uh...
Looks like we're gonna
have to do a little acting.
[Chuckles] What?
"Supernatural" scene 36,
take 1.
Marker!
Action!
[As Castiel]
Balthazar is no hero.
But he knows Raphael
will never take him back.
BOB: Cut!
"Supernatural" scene 36,
take 8.
Marker!
Action!
Balthazar is no hero.
But he knows Raphael
will never take him back.
Dean, grimly.
And yet, somehow you got
no problem with it.
Cut!
Action.
That's because...
that's because we have
no other choice.
Don't look at the camera.
What?
Look anywhere but the camera.
That's because
we have no other choice!
Cut!
For the love of...
Action.
Cut!
If there's a key,
then there must also be a lock.
Cut.
Action.
If there's a key...
...then there has to be a lock.
And when we find the lock,
we can get the weapons,
and then we can have
the weapons.
And the lock. We'll still
have the lock, I imagine,
because we've opened it, and,
of course, the initial key.
[Deep voice] We need to get
all three of that crap.
What?
- That's how he talks.
- Oh.
[Normal voice] Do we really
need all these lines?
I mean, I... I... I... I think
we've covered it.
- Right?
- Cut!
What is happening?
What's happening?!
An atrocity is happening.
Seems like they should stop.
They can't stop.
Nobody stops.
Did we get anything we can use?
Well, uh, technically,
we have them saying everything
in bits and pieces.
Could be sort of experimental?
Whatever.
Season Six.
Who wrote this?
Nobody says "penultimate!"
Gun, mouth.
Now.
[Sighs]
Moving on!
[Bell rings]
Thank God.
[Normal voice] "I-M-H-O,
'J' and 'J' had a late one
last night."
All right, damn it.
We earned this.
"R-O-T-F-L-M-A-O."
SERA:
Spell it out for me, please.
What is our
terror-alert level here?
I don't know, Sera.
Orange, maybe?
They started talking
to each other.
What?!
But that's a good thing.
Right.
I thought so.
But now Jensen's living
at Jared's house.
- That's it?
- Plus, Clif says they're smuggling
- illegal stuff in from Mexico.
- That's it, Toto.
Misha's celebrity Tweet
says it's a black-market
organ thing.
I'm betting drugs.
Anyway, as far as I can see,
I think they've lost any
shred of talent they ever had.
[Both groan]
Oh, that one hurt.
Drugs.
[Sam groans]
Maybe we did it wrong.
No.
No, that...
that spell was perfect.
It should have worked.
What if it can't?
Look, I was up all night,
looking online.
There's no sign
that anything like
the apocalypse happened here.
Ever.
And as far as I can tell,
monsters, ghosts, demons...
they're all pretend.
- So nobody's hunting them?
- No hunters.
Look, maybe that's why our spell
didn't work, Dean, you know?
M... maybe here,
there's no supernatural,
no magic.
No demons, no Hell,
no Heaven, no... no God?
Something like...
even better...
no angels.
Okay, maybe we can't
get out of, uh, you know,
earth number two right now,
but the least we can do
is get the hell out
of the Canadian part of it.
[Scoffs] Yeah.
I hear one more conversation
about hockey, I'm gonna puke.
Wait a minute.
This way, this way, this way.
No, no, no, no, no.
It's this way.
It's this way!
No, Dean, look, I really...
I really think that we should...
Dean!
You think you can run?
No!
Sorry, dude.
Mojo-free zone.
[Grunts]
No magic in the house.
Which makes you
nothing but a dick.
You know,
I oversee all the stunts,
coordinate all the fights.
That's exciting.
Is that one of yours, then?
Guys!
Not good!
No, no, no, no!
Stop!
You don't understand!
No, no, no!
DEAN: You're dead, Virgil!
Virgil!
[Shouting]
- I'm gonna break your friggin' neck!
- Hey!
SERA: I'm trying
to understand, Bob.
Well, uh, Sera, we don't really
understand it ourselves,
but, uh, it appears
that Jared and Jensen
were seen beating
an extra to death.
Huh.
This is Jim here, Sera, and
it wasn't all the way to death.
Only partway, so that's a plus.
He could definitely still run.
And we'll certainly
follow up on that,
but I think the real issue
here, Sera,
is that the boys appear to be
on some kind of extended
psychedelic acid trip.
Well, uh, o... okay.
Maybe it'd help if I...
I'll fly up and talk to them.
You know, I'm not sure
Jared and Jensen...
know who she is,
strictly speaking.
She's, you know, new.
No offense.
Right.
Yeah, I think what
we might need at this stage
is for Kripke
to come up himself.
He created the show.
They'll listen to him.
How's that make me look?
I'm supposed to be
running this thing.
Besides, Eric is off
in some cabin somewhere
writing his next pilot.
- He sold "Octocobra"?
- Yes!
Mother of God.
They'll buy anything.
I don't know. I mean,
Virgil broke through.
Maybe he's got a way
to get back.
Or he has no juice here,
and now he's stuck, like us.
Yeah, either way, I want
to finish kicking his ass.
Good night, Misha.
'Night, little fella.
[Alarm deactivates]
[Car door closes]
[Creak]
"Ever get that feeling...
someone's in the backseat?"
Frowny face.
Aah! Aaaah!
Aah!
- Drive.
- Oh.
There you are, guys!
You got a minute?
- Actually, we're... we're looking for, uh...
- For that extra you tried to kill?
So, is it money?
Is this the kind of act
that goes away
if we can scare up
some coverage on a raise?
More money?
[Chuckles]
- You already pay these two jokers
enough as it is. - Yeah.
'Cause I'd like to think
that over these years,
we've grown closer.
That you don't think of me
as "Director Bob"
or "Executive Producer
Bob Singer,"
but as "Uncle Bob."
Wait, you're kidding.
So, the character in the show,
Bobby Singer...
what kind of douche-bag names
a character after himself?
Oh, that's not right.
Okay, guys, let's begin again.
- Yeah.
You know, I don't think Virgil
would have shagged out of here
- without getting his mitts on that key.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I agree.
Guys...
You can't
come to work on poppers
and smuggle kidneys in
from Mexico
and make up your own lines
as you go!
You cannot
make up your own lines!
Good God,
what about your careers?
You know what?
Screw our careers, Bob.
What?!
You heard my brother.
That's right,
I said "brother."
'Cause you know what, Bob?
We're not actors.
We're hunters.
We're the Winchesters.
Always have been,
and always will be.
And where we're from,
people don't know who we are.
But you know what?
We mattered in that world.
In fact, we even saved
the son of a bitch once or twice.
And yeah, okay, here, maybe
there's some... some fans
who give a crap
about this nonsense.
I wouldn't call it nonsense.
But, Bob Singer...
if that even is your name...
tell me this...
what does it all mean?
Okay. This is good.
I mean, we've all had
our psychotic breaks, right?
I can work with this.
Dean.
Virgil...
I think he has the key.
We quit.
Okay, okay, okay.
Easy, easy.
[Whimpering]
How do you do it?
[Sobbing] Please.
Live in this grubby,
shabby desert?
Nothing greater
than yourselves.
Ohh.
Nothing but dirt when you die.
What? Aah!
Aah! Aah!
Oh, oh.
No power, no magic.
I'm so...
I'm not following you at all.
There's no magic
in your universe!
[Sobbing] I'm sorry!
Please!
- Nothing but a bag of strings and pulleys.
- What?!
You should thank me
for what I'm about to do.
Why?
What are you about to do?
I need to make
an important call.
I pray to God
that it even goes through.
[Gags]
[Choking]
This is what
I've been reduced to.
[Choking]
Raphael.
Maybe if we get inside
the police dispatch system.
Put out an A.P.B. on Virgil.
Might work,
if he stays obvious.
It's not like we have
a lot of time.
Oh, my God!
What?
[Sobbing] Misha!
He's been stabbed to death!
- Where?
Where?!
[Dog barking]
[Police radio chatter]
Yeah, yeah, Raphael.
Like the Ninja Turtle.
He was calling someone name
of Raphael, up in heaven.
Yeah, yeah.
That's right.
The... the scary man killed
the attractive crying man,
and then he started to pray.
And the strange part...
after a while,
I s... swear I heard
this voice, answering.
What did it say?
Well, it didn't make any sense.
Try us.
The voice said,
"for Virgil to return tomorrow
at the place
where he crossed over,
at the time of the crossing.
And Raphael would
reach through the window
and take him
and the key home."
Uh, okay. Hey...
thank you.
Dean, if Virgil
gets back with that key,
Cass is dead,
and our world is toast.
Well, then we stop him.
I mean, how bad can an angel
with no wings be?
[Safety clicks off]
I'd like to see
that pump-action tactical,
12-gauge.
You bet.
[Bell chimes]
Nice choice.
[Bell rings]
You really know
your ordnance, mister.
I am the weapons keeper
of Heaven.
Excuse me?
[Grunts] [Body thuds]
It's my job.
[Gun cocks]
[Man grunts]
You know that if we drop Virgil,
get the key,
then this might be it.
We might be stuck here.
No, we'll figure out
a way back.
Yeah, you wouldn't be that
broken up if we didn't, though.
What?
Don't be stupid.
Well, I'm just saying.
No Hell below us,
above us only sky.
Dean, our friends
are back there.
Yeah, but here,
you got a pretty good life.
I mean, back home,
the hits have been coming
since you were 6 months old.
You got to admit,
being a... a bazillionare,
married to Ruby,
the whole package.
It's no contest.
[Inhales sharply]
No, you know, you were right.
We just don't mean
the same thing here.
I mean, we're not even
brothers here, man.
All right, then. Let's get
our crazy show back home.
Bob, dude.
What the hell, right?
- Eric. Thanks for coming.
- Of course.
I know you're busy. It means a lot that
we can still, you know, call on you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Misha, right?
Oh, I know, I know.
It's just awful!
It's totally,
totally awful. Yeah.
It got us the front page of Variety,
though. Did you see that?
- Front page? Really?
- Yeah, yeah.
But tragic.
Yeah, tragic.
That's what I was gonna say.
How's "Octocobra"?
Oh, I think I really
had a breakthrough.
I'll tell you all about it
over lunch, though.
I can't wait.
Yeah.
Okay, so I am just gonna
bust in their trailer,
guns blazing, and then take care
of this whole mess and...
what's the matter?
What?
That guy.
I think that's the extra!
Oh, fantastic.
We can nip this bud
right out of the gate.
Hey, extra!
Over here!
Gun! He's got a gun!
Noooooo!
[Western music plays]
[Body thuds]
I don't think we have gunfire
on the call sheet today, hmm?
Hey!
[High-pitched whine]
Dean, got it!
[Whine intensifies]
Raphael. Run!
[Glass breaks]
You two...
have the strangest luck.
Raphael?
Nice meatsuit.
Dude looks like a lady.
[Groans]
The key.
And that will open you a locker
at the Albany bus station.
Really.
You see, I needed a modest decoy
to make it more convincing.
Give me the weapons.
Sorry, darling.
They're gone.
What?!
I said, too bloody late.
You see, they were
so well-hidden
that I needed time
to find them.
So, I volunteered
these two marmosets
for a game of fetch
with Virgil.
You two were
such an adequate stick.
Thank you.
Thank you, boys.
RAPHAEL:
You've made your last mistake.
Oh, I've got a few more
up my sleeve,
honey.
CASTIEL: Step away
from him, Raphael.
I have the weapons now.
Their power is with me.
[Thunder crashes]
Castiel.
If you don't want to die tonight,
back off.
Well, Cass...
...now that you have your sword,
try not to die by it.
Cass, what the hell?
[Thunder crashes]
Wait, you were in on this,
using us as a diversion?
It was Balthazar's plan.
I would have done
the same thing.
That's not comforting, Cass.
When will I be able
to make you understand?
If I lose against Raphael,
we all lose.
Everything.
Yeah, Cass.
We know the stakes.
That's about
all you've told us!
I'm sorry about all this.
I'll explain when I can.
[Thunder crashes]
Friggin' Angels.
[Sighs]
[Exhales sharply]
[Thud]
[Chuckles lightly]
Solid.
It's real.
Nice.
Yeah.
Yeah, real, moldy,
termite-eaten home sweet home.
Chock full of crap
that want to skin you.
Oh, and, uh,
we're broke again.
Yeah.
But, hey...
at least we're talking.
[Thunder crashes]
== sync by elderman ==
== corrections by elderman & gloriabg ==
== www.addic7ed.com ==
Edited by Scooby