(announcer): Previously, on
AMC's "The Walking Dead."
(automatic weapons fire)
What the hell is he doing?
I know where Daryl's going!
Carol's still out here...
And I will find her, you go.
(groaning)
Ahhh...
Ah, ahh!
Hey!
(sing song whistling)
Hi, Daryl...
(gunshot)
(whistling)
(heavy breathing)
- Morgan: Hey.
- (whickers)
Hey, boy.
- (horse snorts)
- Oh, you're fine.
You are fine.
Hey.
Hey, come here.
You... are alive.
(groans)
(whistling)
(panting)
(whistling continues)
Glenn's still not back.
I need to be there for Maggie.
- I said no.
- Carl.
Look, you were wrong before.
This place isn't too big to protect.
And you need to stay back
and help protect it.
This place is ready.
Most of us have been
trained, you know that.
If you were worried about an
attack, you wouldn't be leaving.
You know how far the Hilltop is?
You know what could happen?
(whistling continues)
Carl: Those Saviors are out there.
You know what they did to Denise,
what they tried to do
with Maggie and Carol,
to Daryl, to Rosita, to Eugene.
That's not happening
to you, all right?
I'm not gonna let it.
Sasha:
Any change?
She's getting worse.
Abraham: Good call
on the transport.
Well, I figured she'd
be more comfortable.
It also means you got room for more.
They're out there, so I'm
gonna be there with you.
We are.
Package deal.
(sighs)
Uh, what she said.
You want to run into them, right?
You hope they show up.
Jesus, this is about getting
Maggie to a doctor, not about...
Screw you, I'm going.
Enid, stop.
Just wait.
Look, it's a long trip,
and you're just getting over--
It's a superficial graze,
proteins are binding, plus we need
to discuss ammunition production
and manufacture, so let's roll.
I already tried. Give him an
inch, he's taking a mile.
I'm only asking for 23, give or take,
depending on the route.
I know I can be of some help.
Now's the time and here's the place.
Don't shine me.
I'll be your anchorman.
Yes, I damn will.
(panting)
Man:
Why the face?
I hope you're not putting this on us.
Huh? I mean, we showed your
people the way forward.
We gave you rules.
You broke the rules,
so folks had to die.
The one who fired the first shot,
we strung him up
to make an example of him.
It could've stopped there.
But you people still didn't listen.
You wanted to fight us.
So this is how it has to be.
(grunts)
Get out of my way.
Carl!
(sighs)
Just grab some pistols
from the closet.
But hurry.
We've gotta go now.
- (door closes)
- (furniture scrapes)
(doorknob rattles)
Carl!
Damn it!
Please, please.
No, no, please--
oh! No!
(groaning) Please, don't.
Oh! Please.
- (grunting)
- Please!
Carl! Carl!
What happens if you don't come back?
How am I supposed to live with that?
What the hell am I supposed to do?
Just survive somehow.
(banging)
We're ready to protect this place
and the Saviors know it.
That's why they grabbed Eugene.
Look, it's not up for discussion.
Then you're just gonna have
to punch me in the face
and tie me up again.
'Cause that's what
it's gonna take to stop me.
(mouths)
Go on.
We have 24-hour shifts set up
on each of the watchtowers,
each one of them
fully supplied and ready.
In the case that we're incurred upon,
we have drivers assigned,
evacuation and distraction,
and the rendezvous we discussed.
In the event of any emergency,
my first priority is Judith.
I will not fail you.
Are you comfortable leaving me in
charge of Alexandria's defense?
(chuckles)
Yes.
Hey, Rick.
If the Saviors do show up...
I don't know, I'm thinking,
if it's not too late,
should we try and make
some kind of deal?
Tell them to wait for me.
I got a deal for them.
Let's go.
(gate squeaking)
(gate clangs)
Whoa, whoa.
(whickers)
(footsteps approach)
Morgan:
Carol?
Hey.
(whispers)
I told you not to come.
And I'm gonna start
listening to you real soon.
Here, let me see.
(groaning)
What is this?
This is us about to make
an example out of you.
To who?
My people--
everyone at the library,
they're dead.
(grunts, coughs)
(man groaning)
(theme music playing)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
(Maggie breathing deeply)
Hey.
We're gonna get there.
The doctor at the Hilltop,
he's gonna make things better.
Hey.
How do you know?
Everything we've done,
we've done together.
We got here together
and we're still here.
Things have happened, but
it's always worked out for us
'cause it's always been all of us.
That's how I know.
'Cause as long as it's all of us,
we can do anything.
(whickers)
(gasps)
(metal clanging)
It's a walker.
It's hard to get.
I was going to, but I
was too busy bleeding.
- (chuckles)
- (clanging continues)
Pressure should help,
but you need stitches,
antibiotics to make sure
you don't get an infection.
Be dark in a few hours.
I'll walk the camp, make sure
we're safe for the night.
And at dawn, we will head back,
get you some help.
Okay?
No.
What the bitch?
Rick:
What?
Enemy close.
Abraham:
We doing this?
No.
(gearshift clicks)
He's someone who was with a whole
lot of someones who didn't listen.
We can make a deal
right here, right now.
That's right, we can.
Give us all your stuff.
We'll probably
have to kill one of you.
That's just the way it is,
but then we can start
moving forward on business.
All you have to do is listen.
Yeah...
that deal's not gonna work for us.
Fact is, I was about to ask
for all of your stuff,
only I'm thinking I don't
have to kill any of you.
Any more of you.
(can rattling)
Savior: Sorry, my deal
is the only deal.
We don't negotiate.
Me and my people are leaving.
Okay, friend.
Plenty of ways to get
to where you're going.
You want to make today
your last day on Earth?
No,
but that is a good thing to bring up.
Think about it.
What if it's the last day
on Earth for you?
For someone you love?
What if that's true?
Maybe you should be extra nice
to those people in that RV,
'cause you never know...
(snaps fingers)
Just like that.
Be kind to each other.
Like you said...
like it was your last day on Earth.
You do the same.
(door closes)
(groans)
(engine starts)
- (muffled voices)
- (people breathing heavily)
(muffled voices continue)
Why didn't you stay back
and help guard the place?
I owe her.
Why did you come?
I owe them.
Logrun Road's a straight shot.
Sasha:
We want visibility.
There, you got it on Shelton.
Golf course, country
clubs, sloping terrain.
No bum rush from the bogeyman.
We'd see them from a good piece.
It is a longer trip by a third,
but we'd get the scenic safety
of clear-cut dingles
and glens.
You're being serious, right?
As coronary thrombosis.
- You got a route?
- Yeah.
(walker thudding, growling)
Let's go.
Wasn't just me.
Rick came looking, too.
Daryl, some of the others...
they would've.
They were gone before
they even knew about you.
Gone?
They'll be back by the time we are.
Probably back already, wondering.
You think I'm being dramatic here?
Do you really think
you could just come here
and tell me to come back
and that's how it'll go?
Those people, your people,
they care about you.
I know they do.
And I care about them.
That's why I can't be there.
That's why you have to be there.
- (distant clanging)
- (distant walker growling)
Do you really just not get it?
After everything that's happened.
If you care about people,
there are people to protect,
there are people
that you will kill for.
If you don't want to kill...
or if you can't...
then you have to get away from them.
You do not get both.
You-- you should know that.
No, everything's about people.
Everything in this life
that's worth a damn,
that's what I know.
And out here on your own...
you'll die.
Then let me die.
No, I can't do that.
It's not your decision.
Just go.
I'm not leaving you.
(gun hammer clicks)
I said go.
Please, just go.
If you care
about anyone, M--
There is a price, Morgan,
and you're gonna pay it.
I have, and I can't anymore.
- (distant walker snarling)
- (distant clanging)
Think we could do it?
What?
What they did, Glenn and Maggie?
Just asking if you could do that.
If you're doing something
as big as that...
if that's living.
Could you?
Yeah.
I could.
Now.
Just so you know.
Bitch nuts.
We making our stand?
Yeah, we end it.
No, not now.
They've been waiting.
They're ready.
With one of us behind the wheel,
that's five on 16.
We're gonna play it our
way, how we want it.
Right?
Right.
All right, go slow.
(gearshift clicks)
(gunshots echo)
(walkers growling)
(growling)
(growling continues)
(snarling)
(knife cutting)
(body thuds)
(walkers growling softly)
Carol?
(whickers)
Let's go.
(walkers growling)
Rick:
How are we on gas?
Abraham:
Half a tank.
I pulled some more cans
before we left.
Those weren't the same men who
blocked the road the first time.
Same outfit, different soldiers.
They got numbers.
Yeah, we keep driving,
we get her there.
We will.
If we have to shove each and every
one of them up their own asses.
(brakes squeal)
(Rick sighs)
(walkers growling)
We can't go through it.
Can't risk the RV.
You stay behind the
wheel, just in case.
(gun clicks)
We'll clear it.
- (walkers snarling)
- (chains rattling)
Putting together a red rover
like that takes people.
A lot of them.
Come on, let's do this.
Dad.
That's Michonne's.
That's Daryl's.
(automatic gunfire)
Get back to the RV!
Go!
(gunfire continues)
Abraham:
Start it up!
(RV door closes)
(RV squeals)
Sasha:
What's that sound?
Eugene: Undercarriage
could've caught a bullet.
Or could be transmission.
It could be nothing.
They were firing at our feet.
(RV squealing)
They blocked the road, but they
weren't trying to stop us.
They want us in this direction.
Barton Road takes us north,
but they gotta know
we wanna go north.
Meadows.
Could take us east a piece,
but we can get back
on track on Mayhew.
We're down to a third of a tank.
We could top off at the next stop,
- but no refills after that.
- Rick: All right.
She's burning up.
(RV squeals)
Abraham:
Rick.
(brakes squealing)
Go back.
Where?
Whoa, whoa.
Whoa.
Come on.
(kisses)
(walkers growling)
(panting)
(banging)
(banging continues)
(snarling)
(walker snarling, banging)
No, get away.
(grunting)
Ah!
(panting)
(yells)
Hey, hey.
No, no.
(grunts)
(panting)
(hammer clicks)
Each breath is getting harder.
I probably don't have
too many more in me.
So I'm gonna make each one count.
So, here's how it's gonna go.
You're gonna lie there and I'm
gonna watch you die slow,
just like my friends did
back on that road.
Just like I'm gonna.
Let's see who wins, bitch.
- (gunshot)
- (groaning)
You see that?
That's a pretty good start, huh?
Huh?
(people breathing heavily)
(muffled voices)
(muffled voices continue)
(RV squealing)
Are we close?
Yeah, we're--
we're getting there.
Were there--
I heard shots.
Yeah, the Saviors, but they're gone.
We are.
We're gonna get you there.
I know.
You're gonna be okay.
The baby's gonna be okay.
This isn't it.
There's more.
There's gonna be more.
(RV squealing)
I believe in you, Rick.
(panting)
(laughing)
What do you got
to smile about, bitch?
What the hell's wrong with you?
(Carol laughing)
There's nothing wrong with me.
I'm gonna die, so...
there's nothing wrong
with me anymore.
- (gunshot)
- (screams)
You think you've suffered enough now?
No, probably not.
Oh, God.
(no audio)
Carol:
What, are you done?
Unless you kill me now,
I'm not gonna die!
(walker growling)
You decide!
The world doesn't decide!
You don't get to walk away
and get what you want!
(panting)
- Morgan: Stop.
- (hammer clicks)
Drop it.
You can survive this.
You can.
Drop it.
Please.
No.
(gunshots)
Would you please just let me go?
Hey, it's not your time.
You are gonna come back from this.
- (horse whickering)
- (hoofbeats approaching)
What happened here?
I found your horse.
Found my friend, too.
She needs help.
Then let's get you some help.
Eugene:
These tracks...
they would indicate
they not only have people,
but some big-ass toys
and capabilities.
What it indicates
is we are neck-deep
up shit creek with our
mouths wide open.
(screams)
(gasping, gagging)
- Abraham: Don't.
- I can try and break the chain.
It won't work.
- Aaron: I can try.
- It won't work.
(man choking)
And we need the bullets.
Savior: You're treating
your people good, right?
Like it was your last day on Earth?
Or maybe one of theirs?
You better go.
It's gonna get hot.
You go get where you're going.
Go, go.
Get on.
(engine starts)
Abraham:
So, what's the play?
She needs a doctor.
Sasha: There are two more
routes north from here.
They're probably
waiting for us right now.
(exhales)
So, they're ahead of us,
probably behind us.
But they're not
waiting on us, per se,
they're waiting on this rust bucket.
And they don't know the
moment-to-moment occupancy
of said rust-bucket.
And the sun sets soon.
That's the last of it.
If you see a car,
try to siphon the gas.
Other than that, you keep moving.
I'll have them thinking
we're playing their game.
All phases of the turn,
level after level,
move after move, I'll keep them spun.
I assure you, I will.
I got something for you.
It's a recipe, and it ain't gazpacho.
How to Build Bullets 101.
Abraham can show you
where, just in case.
Thank you for this.
For all of it.
We're lucky you're here.
I won't argue with that.
(chuckles)
You go steady on the pedal.
You don't make that thing gulp.
How come you never
let me drive the truck?
I didn't think you could do it.
I was wrong.
You're a survivor.
(soft laugh)
You always were.
We just didn't know it.
Me and you both.
Thank you.
(engine starts)
(RV squeals)
(growling)
(twig snaps)
(footsteps approaching)
Maggie:
Aaron, please.
Just let me walk it.
Relax.
Just a few more miles.
Carl: I heard what you told
her when we were leaving.
We can do anything,
'cause we'll do
anything we need to do.
We have and we will.
What happened to Denise,
I'm not gonna let anybody
die like that again.
- Son...
- What?
(men whistling)
Go! Go!
(whistling continues)
Ah!
(all whistling together)
(whistling continues)
Savior:
Good.
You made it.
Welcome to where you're going.
We'll take your weapons.
Now.
- We can talk about--
- We're done talking.
Time to listen.
That's yours, right?
Yeah, it's yours.
Okay.
Let's get her down and get
you all on your knees.
Lots to cover.
Hold up.
We got it.
Sure, sure.
Gonna need you on your knees.
(people breathing heavily)
(muffled voice)
- Savior: Dwight!
- Dwight: Yeah.
Savior:
Chop-chop.
Dwight:
Come on.
You got people to meet.
(grunting)
Maggie?
Dwight:
On your knees!
Savior:
All right!
We got a full boat.
Let's meet the man.
(knocks)
Pissing our pants yet?
Boy, do I have a feeling
we're getting close.
Yep.
It's gonna be pee-pee pants
city here real soon.
Which one of you pricks
is the leader?
Savior:
It's this one.
He's the guy.
(sighs)
Hi.
You're Rick, right?
I'm Negan.
And I do not appreciate
you killing my men.
Also, when I sent my people
to kill your people
for killing my people,
you killed more of my people.
Not cool.
You have no idea
how not cool that shit is.
But I think you're gonna
be up to speed shortly.
Yeah.
You are so gonna regret
crossing me in a few minutes.
Yes, you are.
You see, Rick, whatever you do,
no matter what, you don't mess
with the new world order.
And the new world order is this,
and it's really very simple.
So, even if you're stupid,
which you very may well be,
you can understand it.
You ready?
Here goes.
Pay attention.
Give me your shit...
or I will kill you.
Today was career day.
We invested a lot
so you would know who I am
and what I can do.
You work for me now.
You have shit, you give it to me.
That's your job.
Now, I know that is a mighty big,
nasty pill to swallow,
but swallow it
you most certainly will.
You ruled the roost.
You built something.
You thought you were safe.
I get it.
But the word is out.
You are not safe.
Not even close.
In fact, you are pegged,
more pegged if you don't
do what I want.
And what I want is half your shit.
And if that's too much, you can
make, find, or steal more,
and it'll even out sooner or later.
This is your way of life now.
The more you fight back,
the harder it will be.
So, if someone knocks on your door...
(chuckles)
...you let us in.
We own that door.
You try to stop us
and we will knock it down.
You understand?
What, no answer?
You don't really think that you
were gonna get through this
without being punished, now, did you?
I don't want to kill you people.
Just want to make that
clear from the get-go.
I want you to work for me.
You can't do that if
you're dead, now, can you?
I'm not growing a garden.
But you killed my people,
a whole damn lot of them.
More than I'm comfortable with.
And for that, for that
you're gonna pay.
So, now...
I'm gonna beat the holy hell
outta one of you.
This--
this is Lucille,
and she is awesome.
All this, all this
is just so we can pick out
which one of you gets the honor.
(Negan inhales sharply)
Huh.
Ugh, I gotta shave this shit.
You got one of our guns.
Whoa. Yeah.
You got a lot of our guns.
Shit, kid, lighten up.
At least cry a little.
(chuckles)
Ahem.
(sniffles)
Jesus.
You look shitty.
I should just put you
out of your misery right now.
Glenn:
No! No!
- (blows landing)
- Stop it!
God--!
(grunting)
Nope.
- Nope, get him back in line.
- Glenn: No.
(grunts)
No.
(groaning)
(sobs, yells)
Don't.
(chuckles)
All right, listen.
Don't any of you do that again.
I will shut that shit down,
no exceptions.
First one's free.
It's an emotional moment, I get it.
Sucks, don't it?
The moment you realize
you don't know shit.
This is your kid, right?
(laughs)
This is definitely your kid.
- Just stop this!
- Hey!
Do not make me kill the
little future serial killer.
Don't make it easy on me.
I gotta pick somebody.
Everybody's at the table
waiting for me to order.
(whistling)
I simply cannot decide.
(chuckles)
I got an idea.
Eenie...
meenie...
miney...
mo...
catch...
a tiger...
by...
his toe.
If...
he hollers...
let him go.
My mother...
told me...
to pick
the very best one...
and you...
are...
it.
Anybody moves, anybody says anything,
cut the boy's other eye out
and feed it to his father
and then we'll start.
You can breathe,
you can blink,
you can cry.
Hell, you're all gonna be doing that.
(all scream)
- (ringing)
- Negan: Ho! Ho!
Look at that.
Taking it like a champ!
(thuds)
- (blows landing)
- Negan: Damn!
- (squelches)
- (screaming continues)
(blows continue landing)
(ringing continues)
- (blow lands)
- (silence)
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com