But mommy got mad and said
I couldn't play anymore.
I said it was an accident,
but she didn't believe me.
If daddy was home, he would have listened,
but daddy's gone. Daddy's always gone.
Mommy says his job is very important.
He's a scientist. He looks at stuff.
I can't remember what now,
but he said when I'm older
he'll show me the funny-looking buildings.
No, I can do it... I promise!
Amanda: Harper, time to get out
of those wet clothes.
No, I don't want to! I'm still
learning all the rules!
Who are you talking to?
A friend.
[Chuckles]
- What's your friend's name?
- Drill.
That's an interesting name.
Do you think Drill would like
to join us for lunch?
[Whispering]
He said that would be very amenable to him.
"Amenable." Okay.
[Whispering]
Uh, no running in the house, please.
- [Cellphone ringing]
- I know but the game already started!
Hi, Liz!
- [Feedback]
- Hello?
- Liz?
- [Feedback stops]
Oh, no, I can hear you.
No, just some interference.
Yeah.
[Wind gusts]
[Children playing]
[Birds chirping]
[Wind chimes ringing]
So, Harper has a new friend.
He's what you might call imaginary.
I know. Adorable, right?
I wonder why some kids
have them and others don't.
Yes!
[Whispering]
I know.
I remember.
Yeah, he flew out this morning.
One of the reactors was having problems.
- [Thud]
- Oh, my God.
Harper? What happened?
I'm okay!
No.
Oh, yeah, just Harper playing.
Um, I got to go, Liz, okay?
I'll call you back later?
- Okay.
- [Beep]
Harper?
Time for lunch!
[Scoffs] Not cool, Harper.
[Wind chimes ringing]
Harper?
This isn't funny! Where are you?!
I'm here! Hi, mommy!
You know you're not allowed
up there without me!
It isn't safe!
I tried calling you,
but you weren't listening.
You're always talking on the phone, mommy.
That's no excuse! Come down now!
No, you need to come up!
The game isn't over.
Harper!
Harper! [Exhales sharply]
She's coming.
Harper.
Who are you talking to?
You know, Drill,
but you're not allowed to talk to him.
He says you're "it."
Well, tell him
I'm not in the mood to talk to him either.
Now let's go.
I already told you, mom.
- You never listen.
- [Whispering]
Not until we finish the game.
"X" marks the spot.
You're supposed to step on it.
Why aren't you playing, mommy?
You don't want me to win?
Okay, okay.
I'll step on it, and then we go down, okay?
[Floorboards creaking]
[Loud creaking]
[Gasps, screams]
[Thud]
I did it! I did it!
Drill?
Where are you?
I won.
Mommy?
You can wake up now.
The game's over.
Mommy, wake up.
Please?
[Whispering]
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com
- Claire: Let's go, Henry!
- [Bat clangs]
Whoo! [Crowd cheering]
Woman: Yes! Run! Whoo!
Run, Henry, run!
- Whoo!
- [Applause]
- [Indistinct shouting]
- [Cellphone ringing]
Oh.
This is Agent Bennigan.
Alex: Claire, it's Director Myers.
Hello, sir.
- Umpire: Strike one!
- Oh, damn it.
- Hey, where are you?
- I... I'm sorry.
I'm at my... [Sighs]
My son's baseball game.
Oh, that's great. Well, look.
I know you're still on leave,
but we just got a case.
A 6-year-old girl tried to
kill her mother. Come on.
And all signs point to premeditation.
Strike two! Well... ohh.
Well, that's horrible,
but it sounds like
it's something for the locals.
Well, as it turns out, the kid's dad
heads up the nuclear regulatory commission.
So by jurisdiction,
the case turns over to us.
- Be a hitter now. Be a hitter.
- National security.
Sir, with all due respect,
we both know that these cases,
they're just a formality.
Any specialist can take it.
Why are you calling me?
- Ball one!
- [Crowd groans]
Claire, it's been three months.
I thought a case might do you good.
Okay. Okay, I'll be right in.
Great! Okay, I need you to get in here now.
- [Bat clangs]
- Oh! Whoo!
- [Cheers and applause]
- Let's go! Make it home!
Hello? Hello? Okay.
Run, Henry!
Run!
Safe!
Yes! Safe! Safe! [Laughs]
Hey, hey!
Hey, you did it.
Yeah.
That was the office.
They want me to come in.
_
[Chuckles]
Yeah, I guess that's true.
And it's what your dad would have wanted.
I'll tell grammy to take you home, okay?
Umpire: Batter up.
But promise me something.
Hit another one for me.
- [Indistinct conversations]
- [Telephones ringing]
Alex: Thanks for coming in.
Hi.
Who won?
Oh, it isn't over yet.
Agent Rollins,
this is our child specialist.
- Agent Bennigan.
- Hello.
Your reputation precedes you.
Alex: The crime scene...
clear signs of tampering
with the tree house.
Please sit.
Claire: You're telling me a
6-year-old did this by herself?
You know kids these days.
Probably learned it on the Internet.
Clearly you don't have kids, Agent Rollins.
Has she said anything?
We were waiting for your expertise.
You guys don't have a lot of time.
The grandmother has given us
permission to question the girl,
but the dad's on his way
back from a trip, so...
Let's get started.
Rollins, a word, please?
Sir.
I know there's some talk going
around about Agent Bennigan.
I'm gonna take a guess and say
it's the same folks talking about you.
Two disciplinary actions will
- do that around here.
- Sir...
and for God's sake,
she just lost her husband.
So do me the courtesy
of rising to the occasion
and doing your damn job,
because I assure you
that's what she's gonna do.
- Do I make myself clear?
- Loud and clear, sir.
Good. Go clear this case.
I want it off my desk. Minx: Mommy, look.
[Children playing]
That was amazing, Minx!
[Chuckles] Looks like those
gymnastics classes are paying off.
Yeah, it does, doesn't it? [Chuckles]
Wish I could say the same
about Noah's piano lessons.
I totally caved in.
I did the whole bribing thing.
Hey.
Is everything okay?
[Sighs] I'm sorry.
[Chuckles] You were saying?
Lena, how are things going
with you and Wes?
You know, we're still working through it.
The new job is helping.
He actually got called
to Africa this morning.
What's he doing again?
He's with the defense
department, special projects.
Hmm. Not really sure what he does,
but at least he's not around her anymore.
I know I shouldn't say this,
but he's lucky you stayed.
I still love him. [Chuckles]
[Spits]
[Indistinct shouting in distance]
Mr. Wes Lawrence, General Damba.
This is my assistant, Peter kim.
[Clears throat]
I have to admit, general,
when you called this morning,
we weren't expecting a trip
- across the desert.
- Yes.
I do apologize for the rush notice.
But I assure you,
the matter's of utmost urgency.
[Shouts in native language]
[Man shouts in native language]
Hey, uh, wait a minute!
They are not authorized
to be on the premises.
Why don't you tell me what's going on?
Your question will be answered in a moment,
but I must warn you, Mr. Lawrence,
more questions will be coming.
Harper.
Tell me about this game.
I'm not supposed to say.
You're not supposed to say?
This is a safe room, Harper.
You can say anything
that you want in here, okay?
It's just us. The door is closed.
But he said grown-ups wouldn't understand.
You're not gonna believe me.
Who said that? Who is this person?
My friend Drill.
Is Drill from school?
He a grown-up, like me?
What does he look like?
I don't know. I can't see him.
You can't see him?
[Chuckling] Well, Harper,
how do you know when he's there?
How do you know when to talk to him?
He speaks through the lights sometimes.
What kind of stuff does he say?
Lots of things...
he says, if I won the game,
we were gonna have a "domba..."
"Domino-tion."
Now I can't remember the word he used.
Was that word "domination"?
Yeah, that's the word.
That's the word.
That's a pretty big word.
Drill knows lots of things.
He even told the questions
you were gonna ask,
but I think I forgot them.
Harper...
is Drill here right now?
He's gone. He's not here anymore.
Do you know where he is?
The game isn't done yet.
He's looking for a new friend.
[Children playing]
[Whispering]
Minx: Yeah, I can hear you.
Yeah, I'd like to play.
[Whispering]
Jessup: So, what do you say?
Time to turn it back over to the locals?
I don't know. Something doesn't feel right.
I'm sorry. Am I missing something here?
You heard her.
6-year-olds don't talk like that.
Someone's coached her.
Oh, you mean like her imaginary friend?
Listen, I get that you want to impress
on your first case back...
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
that is not what this is about.
- Are you sure?
- [ Door opens]
Harper.
Daddy!
Come on. Let's go see mommy.
Alex, I need more time.
What's the problem?
Agent Bennigan thinks there's a case here.
- And you don't?
- No, sir, I don't.
Claire?
Claire?!
- [Door opens]
- Hey, wait a minute.
Rollins?
- [Elevator bell dings]
- Can I get an answer, please?
- [Indistinct conversations]
- Harper.
Here. Come... wait. Hey, hey.
- Is this Drill?
- Harper: No.
This questioning is over.
I suggest you get a warrant.
Harper, Drill... he's real, isn't he?
I swear, but, you know,
I wasn't the only one.
Drill said there was another boy.
- What boy?
- I don't know, but
he couldn't win the game.
[Elevator bell dings]
Rollins: Why can't you accept
the kid was playing you?
And you saw the crime scene.
That's the work of a disturbed mind.
And yet she exhibits none
of the traits of a psychopath.
Nor is she or her imaginary friend
a national threat.
And that's what our job
is to determine here.
- We're not on some rescue mission.
- Take a look at this.
Jackson Bellings, age 10.
One month ago,
he detonated a homemade bomb
at Westings Designs.
He died that day.
But his mother, she survived.
Yeah, I remember that case.
Structural engineering firm,
government contracts.
"The subject believed
he was under the influence
"of an imaginary entity named 'Drill.'
claimed he was playing a game."
So maybe there's some game that's
spreading around the playground.
One kid hears about an imaginary friend,
the next thing you know...
No, no, it doesn't work like that.
For children with imaginary friends,
these... these... these
connections, they're sacred.
And besides, most kids
with imaginary friends,
they know that they're not real.
Harper, on the other hand...
So someone's communicating
telepathically with these kids?
No, what I am saying is
that there are some children
who are easily manipulated
into believing what is real
is not and vice versa.
Whoever is getting to these kids,
he knows that.
Boy: What are you doing?
Playing a game with a friend.
Can I play?
[Whispering]
Okay, he says you can play.
I didn't hear anything.
You coming or what? If not, go away.
[Sighing] I'm coming. I'm coming.
Lena, you know you can call me anytime.
Thank you.
I think it's just gonna take some time.
[Boy screams]
[Breathing heavily]
What is wrong?
I... I... I want to go home now, mommy.
Minx?
What's going on?
Tell me what happened.
[Grunting]
[Wind whistling]
It's one of ours.
Yeah, but what's it doing here?
And what happened to the pilot?
Damba: We found no trace of him.
But we were curious, as well,
why an unauthorized American military plane
would be found within our borders.
You know I can't answer these questions.
This isn't a special projects affair.
This is air force. Why did you call me?
Unfortunately, there's more.
I... [Electricity crackling]
It's happening again.
[Indistinct shouting]
[Conversing in native language]
[Wind howling]
[Electricity crackling]
What's going on here?
I'd like to introduce you to Dr. Karif.
He's a geologist
from the University of Algeria.
Why is a geologist interested
in a crashed fighter plane?
He's not interested in your plane.
There's something else we need to show you.
But first, we need to suit up.
[Indistinct shouting continues]
[Wes breathing heavily]
What is that thing?
Wes.
[Electricity crackles]
- [Rumbling]
- [Groans]
Electricity from the plane
trapped inside the rocks somehow.
It seems to be affecting
the current from our light.
- Any idea how long it's been here?
- We questioned some nomads
who passed through the area
four months ago.
Nothing was here then.
Unfortunately, that's the best
timeline we have.
The plane...
Looks like it never
touched the ground here.
You're saying it did not crash?
I'm saying it looks like it was
grabbed from the sky and ripped to shreds.
By what?
Or by who?
So, what are they saying?
- Excuse me?
- [Bells tolling]
The office. What are they saying about me?
Listen, I'm sorry about your husband.
I should have said something before.
That's not what people
are talking about, is it?
Let's just say it hasn't
escaped people's attention
that you took your leave of absence
before your husband died,
the same time the assistant director did.
There are those who don't think
that's a coincidence.
How about you? What do you think?
I think marriage is complicated.
How long have you been divorced?
Technically, not.
Becomes official next month.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah.
Well... Happens.
- Said you had a son?
- Yeah.
Henry.
How's he handling everything?
Two years ago, he got sick.
He lost his hearing.
Three months ago, he lost his dad, so...
How do you think he's handling everything?
Agents Rollins and Bennigan?
I can let you see her now.
Ms. Bellings?
My name is Claire Bennigan.
I'm with the FBI.
I'm sorry to do this, but I need
to ask you about your son.
This morning, a little girl
tried to hurt her mother.
She said she was playing a game.
"You'll get through this."
That's what people say, don't they?
They said it to me.
It really pissed me off.
What exactly does it mean
to "get through this"?
Through what? What's on the other side?
I didn't want to get through it.
I wanted to die... In it.
And then my mom,
she said that grief is like
a suitcase that sits
at the bottom of your bed.
And no matter what, without fail,
you have it pick it up
every day, take it with you.
Some days, it will be filled with rocks,
and you won't think you can carry it.
And then other days...
Light as a feather.
That, she said, is "getting through it."
It made sense to me.
My husband was killed three
months ago in a plane crash.
I'm sorry.
And I'd be lying
if I said I knew
what you were going through.
I don't. I have my son.
I can't imagine what
I'd be like if I lost him.
Well, you're looking at it.
[Monitor beeping]
[Whispering in foreign language]
[Indistinct talking over P.A.]
He was found this morning
unconscious in an alleyway.
No ID.
[Whispering continues]
That part... Something about "time,"
something like "it's too late."
- Too late for what?
- I'm not sure.
"Lights."
"Searching for lights."
He's saying, "it's too late."
They're searching for the lights."
What does it mean?
[Chuckles] You're asking me?
What happened that day at Westings?
That day [exhales sharply] I went to work.
I supposed Jackson was at school.
But when I got up from my desk
to go to the bathroom,
there he was in the hall.
I said, "Jackson, what are you doing here?"
And he said, "mom,
I think I'm doing a bad thing."
I don't think this is a game."
And before I could ask him what he meant,
he ran into the supply closet.
And the next thing I knew...
[Breathes deeply]
Did he ever tell you about
his friend, Drill?
Yes, he tried.
When I found out
Drill wasn't real, I got mad.
[Sniffles]
I told him he was too old
for that kind of stuff.
You should have seen the look on his face.
Someone is behind Drill.
Wait.
You think Drill is real?
We have to find this person.
Is there anything
that you remember, anyone?
What?
There was someone across the street.
A-a man watching the building,
like he was waiting for something.
Can you describe this man?
His eyes...
it was like there was nothing there.
He had all these tattoos.
His body was covered with them.
We need a sketch artist ASAP.
Your son.
Hold on to him.
Don't let him go.
[Monitor beeping]
- [Gasps]
- It's okay. It's okay.
- I need assistance here!
- [Grunts]
You're safe! You're safe!
No one's hurting you! Listen to my voice!
Wherever you are, come back!
Come back.
That's good. That's good.
I'm Dr. Maria Benavidez.
You're at Capitol University Hospital.
Get resident back. I need him to translate.
It's okay.
I don't know.
- I don't know.
- You speak english?
We want to help you, okay?
In order to do that,
we need to know your name.
What's your name?
My name?
I don't know.
Lena: Hey, Minx. Tell me what
happened on the playground.
- Why was that boy so scared?
- I don't know.
- Probably 'cause he's turning.
- What does that mean?
You're not gonna understand, mommy.
- You're old.
- Okay.
[Chuckles]
Try me. I might surprise you.
When a kid gets old, they turn.
And they think about stuff too much.
And that's a bad thing?
- Mm-hmm.
- Well, what about you? Are you turning?
No.
My friend says I'm never gonna turn.
He thinks I'm special.
Oh, Minx, that is incredible.
I did it all by myself.
Well, mostly. My friend,
he helped a little.
What's that?
That's where the light comes from.
Your dad is gonna love this.
No, I don't think he'll care.
Daddy doesn't like us.
What are you talking about?
Your dad loves us.
That's not what my friend told me.
He said that daddy did a bad thing.
You're still mad,
even though you pretend not to be.
Okay, Minx, I'm gonna
have to meet this friend.
You will, I promise.
But first, I got to go to the bathroom.
Wes: Hi, you've reached Wes Lawrence.
Please leave a message.
[ Beep]
Wes, you need to call me right away.
Minx knows.
She knows... What you did.
- [Beep]
- Told you, mommy.
[Gasps]
You scared me.
Daddy doesn't want to talk to you.
Woman: You have one new message.
- Peter: Wes!
- [Beep]
You got to take a look at this.
So, that F-22?
- Mm-hmm.
- 94th fighter squadron.
Three months ago, it was sent out
on a classified surveillance run.
The mission was to gather
photographic evidence
of Chinese and Russian military
buildup in the arctic circle.
- Mm-hmm.
- But get this.
As soon as the pilot reached its target,
he radioed in he was losing control.
Two minutes later,
the plane disappeared off radar.
The arctic circle? You're sure?
Yeah, that's what it says.
That's... that's almost 4,000
miles away from the wreckage.
And according to the fuel log here,
the plane took off with only
300 miles worth of fuel.
So no way it could have made it
to that desert on its own.
No.
The pilot.
What?
I know him.
So, nothing?
No name, no home, no memory?
Is that what you're saying?
It's all fuzzy.
It's, uh... [Breathes deeply]
It's like it's there,
just I can't reach it.
- But I've been having these dreams.
- Uh-huh.
I don't know what they mean,
but they're important.
I know,
you think I'm crazy.
[Exhales deeply]
While you were out,
you were saying something in Arabic.
You said... It's not possible.
I don't speak Arabic.
But we heard you.
We even had someone come and translate.
So what did I say?
"It's too late.
They're searching for the lights."
You know what that means?
No.
Okay, I'm gonna order a C.T. scan,
and hopefully it will tell us something.
[Pen scratching]
[Echoing ticking]
[Echoing] Hello? Are you listening?
- [Snaps fingers]
- [Gasps]
What just happened?
I just... I just got this feeling.
I think something's gonna happen.
Hi. Are you lost?
No, my mom's here. She's not feeling well.
I'm sorry, but this is a private room.
I'm looking for my friend.
I don't think your friend's here.
Let's call a nurse, and maybe
she can help you, okay?
No, she won't be able to find him.
But you know where he is, don't you?
[Whispering]
Oh.
[Sighs]
Hi.
- [Chuckles]
- Hi.
_
No, I'm okay.
I just... I missed you today.
_
[Chuckles]
Thanks, mom.
Nothing I would rather do.
- How was your day?
- It was good.
It was actually kind of nice to be back.
_
Yeah.
A kid got in trouble today.
I'm trying to figure it out.
Hey, what is it?
_
I miss him, too.
[Smooches]
[Sighs]
[Water running]
[Electricity crackles]
[Laughs] That tickles!
[Laughs]
Hi! My name is Noah!
[Swipe!] Come here! Come here! Come here!
[Vocalizes]
[Swipe! Swipe!]
[Vocalizing] I'm a little alien!
Whoo-hoo!
- Minx: [Groans] Not now, Drill.
- [Swipe!]
Come here! Come here!
[Vocalizes]
I know. The game never stops.
[Whispering]
[Motor buzzing]
[Computer start-up tone sounds]
[Sighs]
[Whispering]
[Keyboard clacking]
That's easy.
It's the day the Baltimore Colts
won the Super Bowl.
Okay. Now what?
[Indistinct conversations]
When's John Doe expected
to be back from his tests?
Uh, hasn't gone in yet.
Still waiting for the machine
to be available.
Call security now.
Tell them we have a runaway.
[Monitor beeping]
[Computer beeps]
Oh, my God.
Okay.
Yes.
[Sighs]
[Cellphone ringing]
- Rollins.
- Wes: Claire.
- Rollins, I think he's after a new target
- Claire, it's me, Wes.
Are you there?
Why are you calling?
There's something I need to tell you.
No, it's over. We both agreed.
It's about Sean.
Don't say his name. Please.
Believe me, I wouldn't be
calling if I didn't need to.
I want to put the past behind us
as much as you.
Well, then, why are you calling?
[Sighs]
Because we found Sean's plane.
When?
Today. The Sahara Desert.
No, that's impossible,
because he crashed in the arctic, so...
That's what everyone thought.
We're trying to figure out
how his plane got there.
There's... Something else.
Sean's body, it's... It's missing.
Wes, what are you saying?
I'm saying Sean Bennigan can
no longer be presumed deceased.
He's now considered missing.
[Gasping]
Peter: Wes!
I have the secretary on the line for you!
- Claire, I have to call you back.
- No!
No, Wes... Wes, don't hang up.
Please, I don't understand.
You need to explain.
- I don't un...
- I'm sorry.
- I have to go.
- [Beep]
[Gasps]
[Breathing heavily]
uh, uh...
[Sighs]
So, Wes, what in the hell am I looking at?
A fulgurite.
Sometimes known as "petrified lightning."
It happens when large bursts
of energy hit the sand.
And you thought it was necessary
to pull me out of a meeting...
Sir, this is what
a traditional sample looks like.
And this is what we found
at the crash site.
So the heat from
the plane's impact created...
No, I had my team run that scenario.
There's, uh, nowhere near enough
energy to make that happen.
- So what do you propose did?
- I don't know.
A weapons test from a rogue state.
The locals, n... No one's talking,
no one saw anything?
Well, I believe someone did.
Well, who?
Whoever left these.
How could anyone have survived that crash?
I agree, sir.
But I'd like to stay and run some tests
on Captain Bennigan's plane.
Come home, Wes.
- But, sir...
- That's an order.
Come home.
There's something you need to know.
[Crickets chirping]
[Wind blowing]
[Dog barking in distance]
[Train whistle blows in distance]
[Car alarm chirps]
I can't believe it.
[Train whistle blows in distance]
This is the best present
in the whole wide world.
Thank you for fixing me.
[Whispering]
Okay.
I promise.
It'll be our little secret.
Goodnight, Drill.
I love you.
[Electricity crackles]
Synced and corrected by oykubuyuk
www.addic7ed.com