Previously on AMC's
"The Walking Dead"
- Was he bit?
- Shot
I have to open him up,
find the bleeder and stitch it.
You need a respirator.
The thought of her,
out here by herself...
We're gonna locate
that little girl.
She's gonna be
just fine.
Two miles down is our farm.
You'll see the mailbox...
Pressure's dropping
We can't wait much longer.
If Shane said he'll be back,
he'll be back.
( Water draining )
( Clippers buzzing )
( Theme music playing )
The Walking Dead S02E03
"Save The Last One"
Made by Mikhel for: Subtitulos.es
Opensubtitles.org
Lori:
Rick, just...
You've got to keep
your strength up.
Rick:
Lori, did you...
I mean,
it was legendary.
Did you ever hear
about the time Shane
stole Kingsley's car?
Lori: Yeah.
Rick:
The Principal's car
right out of
the teacher's lot
in the middle
of a school day.
Shane steps out of lunch
and makes a beeline
to Kingsley's Hyundai...
( Chuckles )
Wires the ignition, peels out,
drives down Dylan drive
to that chicken farm
out there.
You've heard
this before, right?
So he pulls it into one
of the big holding pens.
Kingsley, he waxed
that thing every month;
had the auto shop
vacuum it out every week.
Shane, he parks it
in this huge pen
with a couple of hundred
Rhode Island reds.
He busts open bags of seed
in the back seat,
rolls down all the windows,
and then starts sprinting
back to school.
It's three miles
away easy.
He's back in time
to finish his sandwich
before the bell.
And then the bell rings.
Shane gets up and when
he runs into Kingsley
in the hallway
he looks out the window
and says,
"Principal Kingsley,
your coupe's gone."
( Chuckles )
Coupe, like chicken coop.
I get it.
Of course you do.
You've heard this story
1000 times.
What you said before,
you're right.
Shane's gonna make it back
with what the doctor needs.
He'll make it back.
Hershel said
you need to eat.
Carl's gonna be all right.
Please, for me.
You've got to keep
your strength up.
( Metal clinking )
( Carol sobbing )
I need my clip now.
I'm gonna walk the road,
look for the girl.
I'm coming too.
I'm going for a walk.
Shine some light in the forest.
If she's out there,
give her something to look at.
- You think that's
a good idea right now?
- Dale.
( Moaning )
Those windows,
what's on the other side?
About a 20-foot drop
with nothing to catch you,
maybe some bushes,
- then the athletic field.
- We just need enough time.
We got to get up there.
We got to get 'em open
and get out.
- Not me. Maybe you.
- Hey hey hey.
Come on, man, look at me.
You really think I can
squeeze through
one of them tiny windows?
They'd be all over us.
Look, we lay down some fire
to get a head start.
You stay here.
I hop down and draw them away.
That gives you the chance
to get up the bleachers
and out a window.
And where do you go?
Locker room
down those steps.
Looks like a good way
to get trapped.
It's got windows too,
and more my size.
I get out through one,
I double back, we meet up
out on the field.
You're a crazy son
of a bitch, ain't you?
Just trying to do right
for that boy.
You take three shots
and you go.
After that I fire.
I'll lay down a cover for you.
- I'll get you a lead.
- All right.
Oh God.
( Screams )
( Grunting )
( Panting )
( Groans )
( Gunshots )
( T-Dog shivering )
So do we ring the bell?
I mean it looks like
people live here.
We're past this kind
of stuff, aren't we?
Having to be considerate.
Did you close the gate
up the road when you drove in?
Uh, hi.
Yes, we closed it.
Did the latch
and everything.
Hello.
Nice to see you again.
We met before briefly.
Look, we came to help.
There anything we can do?
It's not a bite.
I cut myself pretty bad though.
We'll have it looked at.
I'll tell them you're here.
We have some painkillers
and antibiotics.
I already gave him some.
If Carl needs any.
Come on inside.
I'll make you
something to eat.
( Air hissing )
Hey.
Um, we're here, okay?
Thank you.
Whatever you need.
They don't get back soon,
we're gonna have a decision
to make.
And that is?
Whether to operate on your
boy without the respirator.
- You said that wouldn't work.
- I know.
It's extremely unlikely.
But we can't wait much longer.
You really think
we're gonna find Sophia?
You got that look
on your face
same as everybody else.
What the hell's wrong
with you people?
- We just started looking.
- Well, do you?
It ain't
the mountains of Tibet.
It's Georgia.
She could be holed up
in a farmhouse somewhere.
People get lost
and they survive.
- It happens all the time.
- She's only 12.
Hell, I was younger
than her and I got lost.
Nine days in the woods
eating berries,
wiping my ass
with poison oak.
They found you?
My old man was off on
a bender with some waitress.
Merle was doing another
stint in juvie.
Didn't even know
I was gone.
I made my way back though.
Went straight into the kitchen
and made myself a sandwich.
No worse for wear.
Except my ass itched
something awful.
( Laughs )
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, that is
a terrible story.
( Both laugh )
Only difference is Sophia's
got people looking for her.
I call that an advantage.
Maybe this isn't a world
for children anymore.
Yeah well,
we have a child.
Carl is here
in this world now.
Maybe he shouldn't be.
Maybe this is how
it's supposed to be.
You can't mean that.
Okay.
All right.
I can understand that
thought crossing your mind.
It didn't cross my mind, Rick.
I can't stop thinking it.
Why do we want Carl
to live in this world?
To have this life?
So he can see more people
torn apart in front of him?
So that he can be
hungry and scared
for however long
he has before he...
So he can run and run
and run and run
and then even if he
survives he ends up...
he ends up just another
animal who doesn't know
anything except survival?
If he...
if he dies tonight,
it ends for him.
Tell me why it would
be better another way.
What changed?
What?
Jenner offered us
a way out.
You asked him
to let us keep trying.
You begged him.
"For as long
as we can," you said.
What changed?
There was a moment
the other day...
it was just a second
but I forgot Jacqui was dead.
I turned around,
I wanted to tell
her something.
I almost said her name.
It was just a second
and then I remembered.
But then I realized she
didn't have to see any of it.
The highway, the herds,
Sophia, Carl getting shot...
she didn't...
She doesn't have
to be afraid anymore.
Hungry.
Angry.
It hasn't stopped
happening, Rick.
It's like we live with
a knife at our throats
every second of every day.
But Jacqui doesn't.
Not anymore.
And then...
I thought,
"maybe Jenner was right."
I don't accept that.
I can't accept that.
That man surrendered.
It doesn't Matt...
it doesn't matter
what he said.
None of it.
You really think it would
be better if Carl...
if we just gave up?
Tell me why it would
be better the other way.
Please.
( Walkers moaning )
( Gunshot )
Man, I thought
I'd lost you.
That was my last
rifle round.
- Mine too.
- Come on.
Come on.
( Carl coughing )
- Where are we?
- Hey, little man.
That's Hershel.
We're in his house.
You had an accident.
- All right?
- It hurts, a lot.
Oh baby, I know.
I know.
- You should have seen it.
- What?
The deer.
It was so pretty, mom.
It was so close.
I've never been...
Carl?
What is happening?
- ( Grunting )
- Don't. It's a seizure.
If you hold him down,
you could hurt him.
- You can't stop it?
- He has to just go through it.
( Lori sobbing )
His brain isn't
getting enough blood.
His pressure is bottoming.
He needs another transfusion.
- Okay, I'm ready.
- If I take any more
out of you
your body could shut down.
You could go into a coma.
- Or cardiac arrest.
- You're wasting time.
Come on, man.
We need a way out.
( Gasping )
- Just let me
catch my breath.
- Come on.
- ( Growling )
- ( Gasps )
( Stairs clinking )
Can't sleep?
I'm gonna wait for them
to come back.
You can go down and sleep
if you want to.
No, we can
keep watch together.
Which way did they go?
( Rustling )
What the hell?
( Gagging )
"Got bit.
Fever hit.
World gone to shit.
Might as well quit."
Dumbass didn't know enough
to shoot himself in the head.
Turned himself into a big
swinging piece of bait.
And a mess.
- ( Groans )
- You all right?
Trying not to puke.
- Go ahead if you gotta.
- No, I'm fine.
Let's just talk about
something else for a minute.
- How'd you learn to shoot?
- Gotta eat.
That's one thing these walkers
and us have in common.
I guess it's the closest
he's been to food since
he turned.
Hanging up there
like a big pinata.
The other geeks came and ate
all the flesh off his legs.
( Vomits, coughs )
I thought we were
changing the subject.
Call that payback for
laughing about my itchy ass.
There wasn't a lot
that came up.
Huh.
Let's head back.
Aren't you gonna...
No.
He ain't hurting nobody.
Ain't gonna waste
an arrow either.
He made his choice.
Opted out.
Let him hang.
You want to live now
or not?
It's just a question.
An answer for an arrow.
Fair?
I don't know
if I want to live
or if I have to
or if it's just a habit.
Not much of an answer.
Waste of an arrow.
You don't need to worry.
She's with Daryl.
If something happens
he can protect her.
You hear what I'm saying?
Sorry, all I heard was
if something happens.
You mind keeping watch?
I don't know how
to use that.
I won't be gone long.
If you see anything, call out.
I'm not going far.
I'll hear you.
You got here
right in time.
This couldn't go
untreated much longer.
"Merle Dixon."
Is that your friend
with the antibiotics?
No, ma'am.
Merle's no longer with us.
Daryl gave us those...
his brother.
Not sure I'd call
him a friend.
He is today.
This doxycycline might have
just saved your life.
You know what merle
was taking it for?
The clap.
Um, venereal disease.
That's what Daryl said.
I'd say merle Dixon's
clap was the best thing
to ever happen to you.
I'm really trying
not to think about that.
Are you praying?
Why do you sneak up
on people so much?
You're easy
to sneak up on.
I was praying.
I was trying to.
You religious?
You pray a lot?
Actually this was
my first try.
Ever?
Wow. Sorry.
I didn't mean to wreck
your first time.
God probably got the gist.
- Praying for what?
- My friends.
Looks like they could all
use a little help right now.
You think...
you think God exists?
I always took it
on faith.
Lately I've wondered.
Everything that's happened,
there must have been a lot
of praying going on.
It seems quite a few
went unanswered.
Thanks.
This is really helping.
Sorry.
Go ahead.
Really.
You gonna watch?
I'll get you
a refill instead.
I know it's not my business,
and feel free
to believe in God,
but the thing is
you've got to make it
okay somehow
no matter what happens.
Before it happened
we were standing there
in the woods
and this deer
just crossed
right in front of us.
I swear it just
planted itself there
and looked Carl
right in the eye.
And I looked at Carl
looking at that deer,
and that deer looking
right back at Carl.
And that moment just...
( Sighs )
Slipped away.
It slipped away.
That's what he was talking
about when he woke up,
not about getting shot
or what happened
at the church.
He talked about
something beautiful,
something living.
There's still
a life for us,
a place maybe like this.
It isn't all death
out there.
It can't be.
We just have to be
strong enough
after everything we've seen
to still believe that.
Why is it better for Carl
to live even in this world?
He talked about
the deer, Lori.
the deer.
Shane:
Oh, shit.
( Both groan )
Got to get to the street,
double back to the truck.
- Look, we ain't
gonna make it, okay?
- Got to try, man.
- Come on, get up.
- You're gonna take these bags
- and you're gonna go.
- I ain't leaving you behind.
Okay.
How many rounds
you got left?
Four. You?
Five and one in the pipe.
( Snarling, growling )
( Gunshot )
He's still losing blood
faster than we can replace it.
And with the swelling
in his abdomen
we can't wait any longer
or he's just going
to slip away.
Now I need to know right now
if you want me to do this,
because I think your boy
is out of time.
You have to make a choice.
- A choice?
- A choice.
You have to tell me
what it is.
You have to
tell me what it is.
We do it.
Okay, get the corner
of that bed.
Let's get the sheets down.
Get the I.V. bag
on the sheet.
Okay, on three.
One, two, three.
Rick, Lori,
you may want to step out.
( Truck approaching )
Rick:
Oh God.
You stay here with him.
- Carl?
- There's still a chance.
Otis?
No.
We say nothing to Patricia.
Not till after.
I need her.
They kept blocking us
at every turn.
We had nothing left.
We were down to 10 rounds.
Then he said...
he said he'd cover me
and that I should
keep going.
So that's what I did.
I just...
I kept going.
But I...
I looked back and he...
I tried.
He wanted to make it right.
( Crying )
Andrea.
Wait.
What do you want, Dale?
To give you this.
I care about you
so I made a choice
for you...  choices.
I know why I did it,
but this is not my gun.
And the choices
that I made for you
were not mine to make.
But I can still ask,
and this is not
to make you guilty
or put me ahead of you,
but I can still ask,
please...
Don't make me regret this.
I'll take watch.
So do you forgive
me for...
do you forgive me?
I'm trying.
I've known Otis
since I was a kid.
He's run this farm
since before my mother died.
Who else?
Who'd you lose?
You told me I had
to make it okay somehow.
That's what you've been
trying to do, right?
Which ones?
Stepmother.
Stepbrother.
He seems to have
stabilized.
( Exhales )
Oh God.
I don't have words.
I don't either.
Wish I did.
How do I tell Patricia
about Otis?
You go to Carl.
I'll go with Hershel.
( Patricia sobbing )
( Sobbing )
Stay.
The bathroom's upstairs.
- I brought you some clothes.
- Thank you.
They won't fit well.
They were Otis's.
Shane:
How many rounds
you got left?
Otis:
Four. You?
Shane:
Five and one in the pipe.
( Groans )
Come on.
( Panting )
- Down to my last.
- Me too.
I'm sorry.
- ( Gunshot )
- ( Screams )
( Growling )
Will you give it...  ah!
Give it!
( Otis screaming )
I'll kill you.
( Shane screams )
( Screams )
Let go of me!
Let go!
( Otis screaming )
( Panting )
Made by Mikhel for: Subtitulos.es
Opensubtitles.org
Subtitulos.es
==SPREAD THE WORD==