(waves crashing)
(distant music playing)
(music stops)
(knocks)
Hey, get up.
It's time to check the buoy.
Come on, Josh.
(Josh grunts)
Oh, no.
So you regret
proposing to my sister?
What I regret is letting you
plan my engagement party.
(chuckles)
I know.
Here, get this into you.
It's my great-gran's
hangover remedy.
Oh--!
Smells like shit.
Oh, God.
You're spilling it.
You know,
once you get past the gag reflex,
- it's actually not that bad.
- Yeah.
Rory...?
I'll check the buoy.
Oh, my sister's down the beach.
She wants to show you something.
(sighs)
(car door opens, closes)
(car engine starts)
(car engine fades)
Rory: Looks like it's gonna be
a busy one. Want a hand with that?
What, you're actually gonna
get wet today?
Make a bit of a change,
wouldn't it?
(laughs)
Woman:
Hey.
I bet you've never seen
one of these.
Josh:
What is it?
Wow.
Were you looking at my butt?
No.
- No?
- Maybe.
(woman laughs)
Aww.
You look terrible.
Thanks.
It's your brother's fault.
But you smell nice.
You always smell nice.
Woman: Are you ready
to leave all this behind?
Where you go, I go.
Well, there won't be places like this
in Singapore.
Oh, we'll come back.
Lifeguard:
Shit.
Shark! Shark!
(voices shouting)
(siren blaring)
Get help!
Go get help!
Rory!
Get everyone out of the water!
Joe, give me a hand.
(yells)
Rory!
No!
- Shark!
- I can't hear you.
- What?
Give me your hand.
Rory!
I got you. I got you.
No.
(howls)
No!
Along with
the yearly southern migration
of the humpback whales
along the East Coast waters,
"Surfline" surfing spokesman
Jeff Tripp said
people should be very vigilant
this time of year,
as we've seen large gatherings
of sharks in the waters
following the whales
along the coast.
Now, what they're doing
is hunting the whale calves
and bait fish
surrounding the migration.
TV reporter: So if you are heading
to the beaches,
please observe the signs
and swim only between the flags.
Great whites are expected
in the area over the next month.
And now, on a brighter note,
it's been a picture-perfect day
here on the East Coast
with blue skies
as far as the eye can see.
TV reporter:
No signs improving
for the sailors
and the windsurfers, however.
We seem to be hit
with the doldrums,
which means there are
no surface winds.
(chimes tinkling)
(distant dogs barking)
(howling)
(birds screeching)
(crow cawing)
(seagulls squawking)
(crows cawing)
(screeches)
Man in hood:
We gotta move to the car park.
Can't stay here.
(engine starts)
(man announcing over PA)
Woman:
Yes, please.
- Josh: Hey.
- Hey.
- Jessup come by yet?
- Not yet. You're safe.
Good morning, by the way.
Yeah.
(pop music playing)
Shake your body
Shake your booty...
(music stops)
Why are we stopping here?
- Hey, Kyle.
- Shh.
(keypad clicks)
You're bad.
- (dog whines)
- Woman: Hey.
(dog yapping)
Shut up.
What are you doing here?
Woman:
You scared me.
Happy anniversary.
You remembered.
11 months, baby.
It's not very much. It's just a song
playlist for when we go to Sydney.
Thank you. Thank you.
Ooh, and...
happy anniversary
to you too.
- Tell me you didn't steal these.
- Oh, Ryan.
Yeah, okay, okay,
put them back.
But then I have
nothing to give you.
Doesn't matter.
It's the thought that counts.
Put them back, okay?
Come on.
Oops, I hope we're not
interrupting anything.
You know, that's a really
cool jacket.
Thanks.
Bet it's got lots of pockets, huh?
Mind if we take a little peek?
Ryan:
She's gonna pay for it.
Just take it out of my paycheck
if you don't believe me.
Paycheck?
You're living
in a dream world, kid.
You're fired.
And you-- shoplifting,
destruction of property.
I've already called the cops.
Did you see all those birds
this morning?
There must have been
thousands.
You know, there were crows
and magpies and everything.
When did you get back?
Tina, this is what you want?
Josh, this is--
Oh, Jesus.
Josh, look at you.
Go clean yourself up.
Jessup:
No, not the customer bathroom.
I got the call.
Oh, shit.
(dog yapping)
(Kyle moaning)
Kyle:
Whoa! Hello.
Man in hood:
You starting to hear something
stirring around
that head of yours?
The office is at the back
of the store.
Cash pickup's in 10 minutes,
so you've got five to get out.
(gun hammer clicks)
When this is done,
we're straight.
My brother's clean
and I don't want to ever see
your face around him again.
You understand me?
Man in hood:
Whatever you say.
(kisses)
(sighs)
I want her charged
this time.
She didn't steal this.
This is hers.
We both know you're not gonna
go through with it.
Just stop,
because I'm this close.
To what?
Arresting me?
Yeah, real A-plus
parenting, Dad.
- Jaimie, you're too smart to--
- Oh, you just dropped
to a C-minus
due to lack of originality.
Okay, okay, what about this?
I'm gonna process you
this time.
You can spend the day
in lockup.
And what do you think
that's gonna do?
Maybe it's the wake-up call
you need.
Piss off.
What do you think your mother
would have thought about all of this?
Piss off!
(sighs)
(car lock chirps)
Put that on.
That's it.
- Thanks.
- Great.
Jessup:
What the--?
Give me the money.
Shit, man, there's no money
in the safe.
Give me the money.
All right, just--
just take it easy, okay?
(beeping)
Jessup:
You see?
Where is it?
Cashier: Do you want
a separate bag for that?
(cocks gun)
Man in hood:
Hey, drop that fucking gun...
- (woman screaming)
-...or I'll do this bitch!
Where's the money?
You-- I said,
put the guns down!
Put 'em down!
(knocks rhythmically)
(knocking)
Thank you.
My dad was totally--
Your dad's right, Jaimes.
Not you too.
I lost my job today
because of you.
Who cares?
You hated that job anyway.
I care. I care.
Well, if it's that important
to you,
I'll go get your
stupid job back, then.
- Jaimie, just--
- No. Watch.
Oi! Freak boy
from history class, right?
(laughs)
(engine grinds)
(sighs)
(plumbing groans,
sputters)
(gunshots popping)
(women screaming)
You, get here.
- Get here.
- Tina: No.
You, get over there.
Stay back.
- No.
- Stay back.
Woman:
Do as you're told.
What the fuck did you do?
Tina:
Josh.
Get back.
Hood: Hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey.
Don't be a hero, mate.
Stay back.
Tina.
Josh:
No!
Hood:
Stop it.
(low rumbling)
Woman:
What was that?
(rattling)
What--?
Man:
Down! Down!
- Come on.
- (child screams)
(people shouting)
Oh.
Man on video: I should know,
I built the store.
Woman:
Hurry up. This way.
Man:
Come on, come on!
Go! Run!
(gasps, screams)
(screams)
(crashes)
(wires fizzling)
(gasps)
Hey!
Over here!
Josh:
Have you seen anyone?
Anyone else?
Anyone?
Man:
I need help.
Anybody?
Help!
- Josh: Hey.
- Here.
Where's Tina?
Jesus Christ.
Can you help him?
I don't know what to do.
- Just calm down.
- Can you help him?
Calm down.
What the hell's happening?
What just happened?
We gotta get him
out of the water.
Help me lift him
onto this shelf.
I need you to go and find
anything you can to wrap this leg--
towels, electrical tape--
I don't care.
Okay.
Jaimie:
Dad? Dad!
My God. Jaimie!
Dad?
- Jaimie.
- Dad!
Here, give me your hand.
Jaimie.
Da--
Dad.
How did you get out?
I was in the car.
I was in the car park, and...
Ryan-- Ryan--
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God,
Ryan's still in the car park.
- Forget it, kid.
- Ryan's still in the car park.
Forget it.
If it's flooded up here,
they've had it down there.
(gasps)
(grunting)
Tina?
Tina!
Okay, I need your help.
I need you to help
your dad, okay?
Put your hands here
and keep pressure on his leg.
Can you do that for me?
You'll be fine.
Tina.
Tina. Hey.
You're okay.
Look at me.
What-- what happened?
Where are all the people?
Hey, come on.
Here, give me your hand.
- Help me. Help me.
- Okay, okay.
- Help me.
- Calm down. Calm down.
(water splattering)
Kyle: Help!
We're trapped!
- Someone get us out of here!
- Heather: Is anyone there?
- Anyone? Anyone?
- Help!
Somebody help us, please.
- (dull thump)
- (gasps)
Did you hear that?
- Did you hear that?
- Shh. Stop talking.
(gasps)
Where did it go?
Do you hear it?
Not when you don't
shut up.
Well, excuse me
for helping, Kyle, really.
(thumps)
It's behind you.
Yeah, you find that noise.
You find it.
Good boy, Bully.
Good boy.
(Bully yapping)
(yelps)
(gasps)
Shit.
Fuck. Fuck.
(panting)
Fuck.
Can anybody hear me?
Hello?
(faint rumbling)
Is anybody there?
Oh, fuck.
Oh.
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
(gasps)
(cloth ripping)
Josh:
Are you ready?
(screams)
We've got to get out of here.
We can't stay here.
We've got to get help.
What--?
Oh, shit.
Don't let him
out of your sight.
The water's still rising.
No, no, it can't be.
The whole bloody town
must be flooded up there.
No, it's not.
Look, they're gonna come for us.
They know we're down here.
They're gonna come for us.
Doyle: That's assuming there's
someone still up there to come.
- You, this is all your fault.
- Not mine, boy, not today.
Today Mother Nature saw us all
as sinners down here.
Why don't you just shut up?
He can't swim anywhere
with this leg.
Josh:
I'll stay here.
You guys find a way out
and bring a rescue team back.
Tina:
What? No, Josh, wait.
Bob:
Well, how do we get out?
With the car park flooded,
that leaves only
the loading bay storeroom
and the front entrance.
Josh, you cannot stay here, okay?
You know as well as I do
this is gonna bring aftershocks with it.
It's gonna bring more--
More waves, I know.
So you'll have to be quick.
Okay, well, Steven and l
will check the front.
I'll take the loading bay.
I don't think so.
- Bob?
- Yep.
You go.
Okay.
Kyle: Oh, you've got to be
kidding me.
How could you not have
charged your phone?
I can't do everything, Kyle.
God, why didn't you charge it?
Uh, because it's not
my phone.
Oh, well, then where is your phone?
Hello.
Oh, well, that's much better.
- (Bully growls)
- What is it, Bully?
Why are you growling
like that?
Because he's
a fucking retard.
That is not funny, Kyle.
You're not a retard, Bully.
(low whistle)
(barking)
What the hell was that?
I have no idea.
(coughs)
(buzzing)
(cable buzzing)
What's that?
Where did it go?
Get everyone
out of the water.
Jaimie:
What?
Get everyone
out of the water now!
What's happening?
Tina!
Out of the water now!
- Bob: Can't get out that way.
- Josh: Hurry!
It's blocked.
Out of the water!
Quick, swim.
What's going on?
Josh: Tina, Steven,
get out of the water!
(gulps)
Collins?
Tina, hurry!
Where is he?
Where did he go?
(screams)
- Oh!
- Shit.
Jaimie, get back.
Help me!
Please help me!
(yelps, gasps)
Shit.
Where did it go?
Did you see it?
What the hell could do that?
What is in here?
(buzzing)
There.
(gasps)
(all scream)
Doyle:
Give me your hand.
Ow, my hand.
Jesus Christ.
- That had to be five feet.
- What had to be five feet?
- Six.
- Six? What do you mean, six?
Tina: Six feet from the tip
of the dorsal to the tip of the tail.
Jessup: So what the hell
does that mean?
It means there's a 12-foot
great white shark in here.
(panting)
Fuck!
- I can't see anything.
- Just keep calm, babe.
We have to get out of this car.
I can't stay here much longer.
Give me your shoes.
Excuse me?
Well, I need something with a point
to break the windscreen.
Give me your shoes.
Are you crazy?
These are $300 Gucci.
They're gonna get wet anyway.
Just give me your shoes.
- No.
- Heather, give--
- I'm not giving you my Gucci.
- (barking)
They're not Gucci.
Um, clue-- you gave them to me
for Christmas last year,
and you said that they were
$300 Guccis.
Um, clue-- I know I did,
and they're not.
(gasps)
You bought me fake Gucci.
You wouldn't have known
if I didn't just tell you.
I can't believe you.
Fake Gucci?
Just give me your shoes.
What are you doing?
- Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
Ryan:
Hey! Hey, over here.
Kyle:
Freak boy? Is that you?
Jesus Christ, I never thought
I'd actually be happy to see you.
Kyle: Yeah, no shit. Did you find
anyone? Is there anyone else?
Ryan: There's bodies everywhere.
There's no one alive.
Kyle: Well, did you check
the ramp?
Ryan: It's all jammed up.
I can't get through.
You got a phone
or something in there?
Kyle:
Uh, no.
Holy shit, Kyle. Kyle!
What? What?
Ryan:
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Oh, shit.
(Bully barking, growling)
(gasps)
It's okay.
- I think it's gone.
- (barking)
Oh, shit.
(screams)
Oh, man,
this is not happening.
This is so not happening.
You-- you're a cop, right?
You gotta do something.
For Christsakes, do something.
Do you have any ideas?
Oh, you think
this is funny, do you?
- More ironic, really.
- Oh, really? Well, please share.
I'm sure we could all do
with a good ironic laugh right now.
Doyle:
Think about it.
You bust your ass in here
eight hours a day, seven days a week.
Right?
You'll probably hump away like that
for the next 40 years.
So whatever way you cut it,
this place was gonna kill you.
Now it's just sooner
rather than later.
You son of a bitch.
I want you to know,
the woman you killed--
her name was Julie
and she was a friend.
- I didn't kill anyone.
- It makes no difference.
She died during your robbery,
so it's your fault, you bastard.
If we get out of here alive, I swear
I'm gonna make you fucking pay.
Enough!
It's coming back.
Why does it keep doing that--
just circling?
Tina: Because it's not sure
what we are.
It's curious.
Jessup:
Curious about what?
A shark's only curious
about one thing.
It's trying to decide
if we're food or not.
(rumbling, banging)
- What was that?
- Todd: Hang on, everybody.
Just hang on.
(woman yelps)
(buzzing, popping)
We have another problem.
(laughing)
Why are you laughing?
'Cause he just realized
when the water hits those cables,
this whole place will light up
like a Christmas tree.
Jessup, where do we
shut it down?
The storage room.
All the power mains
are in the storage room.
I'll go.
- What?
- Everyone go to the end of the shelf,
make as much noise
as you can.
I'll swim for it.
Tina:
Josh, no.
I mean, you can't.
Your arm-- look at your arm.
I mean, the shark will go
straight for you.
You can't, not with that.
I don't think we have
any other options.
Hold on.
I have an idea.
Do you see it anywhere?
Yeah, I see it, but I'm keeping it
a secret from you
because I want you
to be surprised.
Oh, well, thank you for your
thoughtfulness, Kyle, really.
It's what I always dreamed of
in a boyfriend.
Oh, I can't handle this
much longer.
It may surprise you,
but I am not equipped
to deal with this kind
of situation.
Here, Bully,
I need some space.
(Heather screams)
(Bully barking)
Kyle, do something.
You have to do something.
Like what?
Ask the fucking thing to go away?
- (screams)
- Oh, shit.
- Help!
- Help us, please! Help us!
Get down. Get down.
Get down.
Help us!
Do something!
- Okay.
- Help us!
All right, just get back
in the car.
Just stay as still and quiet
as possible.
- What, are you fucking insane?
- Just listen, listen.
Why don't you jump in the water
and do a couple of laps?
All right, just listen to me.
You gotta keep still, okay?
The more you scream,
the more the shark's gonna come.
Hey, hey, just get back in
and wait.
I'm gonna get the shark
to come to me.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
What?
When I get it over here,
you swim like hell
for my van over there.
You see it?
This is crazy.
Babe, look at me.
Don't move.
Stay here as still as you can.
Can you do that?
(buzzing, popping)
You think this will work?
Man:
Absolutely.
I wouldn't eat a cheeseburger
with its wrapping on.
But of course...
I'm not a shark.
(laughing)
Here.
Yeah.
Look...
you don't know me...
- but when Tina came to Singapore--
- I don't want to know about it.
Well, you should.
We were never--
The whole time she was there...
she missed you.
It wasn't your fault--
what happened.
That's what she said.
Hey, I found some water.
Good?
You come back, okay?
Just come back.
Ready?
Here you go.
(buzzing)
Oh, shit.
(grunts)
Oh, man, he's not
gonna make it.
(buzzing stops)
He did it.
- He did it.
- Where is he, Josh?
(gasping)
No!
(sobs)
No.
Fuck it. No!
Hey... are you okay?
Look,
we've got to try
to keep it together.
Okay?
Tina:
I know. I just--
(shudders)
When's it gonna end?
And why is this happening?
Why?
When my mom was dying--
she died two years ago--
she was so sick.
I tried.
A couple of months
before she died, I left.
I couldn't take it.
I just took off to America.
And...
I wasn't there
when...
So this is my payback.
Life saying, "Screw you.
How are you gonna
run away from this?"
(grunts)
Here.
There's a secret to it.
You have to do it gently.
Just peel the two
pieces of plastic apart
Iike that.
Thanks.
Was she a friend of yours--
the girl that got killed?
Julie?
No, not really.
I mean, I knew her
and everything, but--
It was just supposed
to be me, you know?
A quick in and out.
Nobody else, just me.
I guess it's true what they say--
"Let the devil take your hand
and God will make you pay."
Todd: We're not gonna make it
out of here, are we?
I don't believe that.
No.
We'll make it out of here.
Good.
(sighs)
(grunts)
Ryan: Oh, shit, it's working.
It's working.
Go now.
Go, go now, now.
Kyle:
Come on, go, go, go.
Fuck! Swim!
- Ryan: Swim!
- Kyle: Climb! Just climb!
Sorry, Bully.
- (Heather screams)
- Fuck!
Kyle:
Stay back!
Heather:
Bully! Bully!
(panting)
Fuck!
(faint muttering)
You need to
slide it through...
not fling it.
It's strong, but it can't
take much weight.
Screw this.
I'm out of here.
If you can get through,
you get help and bring them back.
Yeah, yeah,
all right, all right.
- Ready?
- Let's go.
Got it?
- (screams)
- Pull him up!
- I can make it. I can make it.
- Pull up now.
- I can make it. I'm okay.
(screaming)
(crunching)
Give me your hand.
Are you gonna talk to me
or what?
No.
- Heather, I didn't--
- Don't.
Don't even try.
Murderer.
I'm not a murderer.
Oh, yes, you are.
You're a dog murderer,
which is worse than a person murderer.
How could you?
Heather, I didn't have
a choice.
Bullshit.
You always have a choice.
Murderer.
Whatever.
(groans)
Argh!
Uh!
Ryan:
Hey. Hey.
Can that pipe
hold my weight?
I can't get out this way.
I want to get to that door.
What do you think?
Kyle: I don't know.
Give it a go.
- Kyle: You all right?
- Yeah.
Ryan:
Can you see it anywhere?
Kyle: I don't know.
You're the one with the bloody torch.
Shit.
Kyle:
Are you okay?
Whew.
Ooh, Jesus.
- Kyle: Are you all right?
- Yeah.
Good stuff.
Keep going.
Heather:
Is he gonna make it?
Kyle:
Babe, shut up.
Shit.
You're good. You got,
like, six feet. Keep going.
(grunts)
Oh, shit.
Hold on.
Grab on. Grab on.
Shit.
Both: Swim, swim, swim.
Quick, quick.
- Heather: Quick.
- Got you, buddy.
(Heather screams)
Kyle! No!
- Quick, quick.
- Give me your hand.
Give me your hand!
Doyle: We're not gonna just
sit around and wait for that thing
to pick us off one by one.
And what do you think
you're gonna do?
At the very least, I'm gonna die
on my own terms
and not when that damn fish
decides it's time.
So you think what?
You're gonna catch it?
Why not?
What are you gonna do
if you catch it?
Spark up the barbie
and crack open the tartare sauce?
I'm gonna tie it to this shelf
and we're gonna swim like hell
to the entrance.
Get the hell out of here.
All I need isa hook.
You can't save everybody, mate.
You must be getting used
to that by now.
Josh:
It's not that far.
If we can distract
the shark,
I'll swim it,
get the hooks.
I'll do it.
What? Dad, no.
Oh, you can't,
not with your leg.
My leg is exactly
why I should go.
Dad, no, please.
You keep
my daughter safe.
No matter what happens,
you get her out of here, okay?
(grunts)
Jaimie!
Jaimie! Jaimie!
Tina: Naomi, make noise,
get the shark to come toward us.
Josh: Hurry, quick,
make some noise!
Jaimes, are you okay?
Yeah.
Okay, hang on.
Doyle:
Jump!
(gasps)
Good work, kid.
So what's the deal?
Do you know her
or just want to?
I used to.
Used to, huh?
'Cause I can see by that look
in your eye,
whatever was there,
still is.
That was a long time ago.
Trust me,
after this shit here,
everything we knew
is a long time ago.
You still wear that.
Yeah.
- Tina--
- You don't have to.
- We don't have to do this, Josh.
- No, I do.
I wasn't fair to you.
I just--
I always set the buoy.
Rory did it for me that day.
But I should have been
the one out there.
Josh.
And I hated myself.
But...
before I knew
what had happened,
everything just...
slipped away.
And I'm sorry.
I just wanted to say that.
I'm sorry.
The thing is, Josh...
you never had to say
sorry to me.
All you had to do
was say it to yourself.
I would have been there.
Doyle: Hey, you all secure
down there?
Josh:
Yeah.
Why didn't it take it?
Well, if you ask me,
I think it's pretty obvious.
After the past
couple of hours,
it's decided it prefers
live bait.
That's not funny.
Do I look like I'm joking?
Get down!
You stay back.
Stay back!
I saved this last bullet
for you, Doyle.
- You son of a bitch.
- Todd: You.
What about the mask
on the body?
(gunman laughing)
Wasn't me, mate.
Now, how about
we get ourselves a shark?
It really is
a pretty good idea.
We just need better bait.
And this looks pretty tasty,
eh, Doyle?
Kirby, listen to me.
You don't want to do this.
Don't l?
No.
Todd: What you did earlier
doesn't matter right now.
So you let her go
and we can work something out.
Shut up, cop.
Don't bullshit me.
I shot someone.
That's not going away.
Now, I'm getting out of here
and I'm catching
this fucking shark.
And whatever happens...
happens.
- Get in there!
- (yells)
- Josh, no.
- Anyone thinks about touching her,
you go in too.
(grunts)
Tina:
Naomi, here.
You're okay. Okay.
So you want to help?
You think it needs live bait?
Well...
(screaming)
Let's give it what it wants.
(Kirby screaming)
Oh, my God.
It's worked.
Now let's get out of here.
I don't think
anyone's coming for us.
I think if they were,
they'd be here by now.
I don't know.
Maybe they're trying
and they're just dealing
with the same shit we are.
- (Bully barking)
- Bully?
Bully!
Oh, float over.
No, don't. No.
- Come on, Bully.
- Baby, swim.
Grab him quick.
(laughs)
Yay. Bully.
It's a sign.
I know it is.
Yay.
Heather:
You're a good boy.
Get up.
Todd: It's okay, sweetheart.
Come on.
(rhythmic banging)
(banging)
- What are you doing?
- I don't know. Call it a sign.
(bangs rhythmically)
What is that?
It's Ryan.
Oh, my God, it's Ryan.
I have to go get him.
Jaimie, no. Jaimes.
Go after her, please.
Josh.
I'll be back soon.
He's down there.
I know he is.
Wait here.
Is he there?
Did you see anyone?
All right, give mea hand.
We have to close this door,
so that when we open
the one downstairs,
we don't flood the car park.
- Jaimie!
- Ryan!
- There's a shark. Get out of the water.
- Quick, quick! Go, go!
Heather:
Go, quick!
(banging)
Give me your hand!
(yells)
Come on.
Josh!
Come on!
(screams)
It's Dad's car.
There's a gun.
- What?
- There's a gun in the back.
Go to the other side.
Get the shark to come to you.
Jaimie:
Hurry! Come on!
Hurry, quick!
- (both yelp)
- (barks)
Josh, quick! Josh!
Come on, quick.
Come on.
(Heather screams)
(yells)
Naomi:
No go this side.
(buzzing)
Make sure everyone's
out of the water, okay?
- Dad.
- Jaimes?
Jaimie!
Get everyone behind the ramp
and out of the water.
You know
what you're doing?
I'm gonna hook this up
and I'm gonna blow us
a way out of here.
(rumbling)
Hold on!
(women screaming)
- (women whimpering)
- (Bully barking)
Is everyone okay?
Todd:
Yeah.
- Tina!
- Josh!
Shit.
Get out of the water!
(clicking)
(yelling)
(buzzing)
(groaning)
Hit it.
(buzzing)
Josh.
(helicopter blades whirring)
What are we gonna do now?
Start over.
(helicopter blades whirring)
(rock music playing)
Oh, the shark has
Pretty teeth, dear
And he shows them
Pearly white
Just a jackknife
Has MacHeath, dear
And he keeps it
Way out of sight
When the shark bites
With his teeth, dear
Scarlet billows
Begin to spread
Fancy gloves, though
Has MacHeath, dear
So there's never
Ever a trace of red
(music continues)
On the sidewalk
One Sunday morning
Lies a body
Oozing life
Someone's sneaking
'Round the corner
Could that someone
Be Mack the Knife?
(music continues)
From a tugboat
On the river
A cement bag
Is dropping down
That cement there
is for weight, dear
You can bet then
Mack's in town
Oh, the shark has
Pretty teeth, dear
And he shows them
Pearly white
Just a jackknife
Has MacHeath, dear
And he keeps it
Way out of sight
Just a jackknife
Has MacHeath, dear
And he keeps it
Way out of sight.
(instrumental music playing)