(buzzer)
One, two...
- (buzzer)
- ...three, four,
five, six, seven...
- (unlocks door)
- ...eight, nine, 10.
(door opens)
(muffled screaming)
That was better.
- (grunts)
- (screaming stops)
(door slams)
(woman screaming)
- He got a book on puppy training.
- I know. I saw it.
(tsks)
Oh.
Maybe by Christmas
I can make it work.
- Really?
- Don't say anything yet.
Oh, my God, you are so sexy
when you make secret plans.
(laughs)
Thanks.
Okay.
(engine starts)
- Mom: Love you.
- Come on, guys. Let's go.
Mom: When you're at camp
this summer.
- Boy: I can still go to camp?
- Mom: Of course.
Your dad's working six days a week
and I'll be working again soon.
Dad: So let's not worry, huh?
You're going to camp.
Mom:
Thanks, sweetie.
- We'll see you tonight.
- Okay.
Hey, don't take the bus home, okay?
- Take a cab.
- Don't be silly.
- No.
You know how expensive
cabs are these days.
No. Another 40 bucks is not gonna
break the mortgage.
Seriously, no bus.
And you wonder
why I love you so much.
- 'Cause I'm a catch.
- I know that.
Hey, champ, you look after
your mom, okay?
Boy: 'Kay.
- In one ear and out the window.
- (mom laughs)
Boy: Oh, look.
"Shifter" is playing?
Hey, you wanna
go see that instead?
Dad said no way.
Well, Dad's not here.
It's just you and me.
- Really?
- Come on, let's do it.
You're gonna have to hold my hand
during the really scary parts.
- Boy: I'll hold it the whole time.
- (laughs)
Did you see when
that guy's face came off?
No. My eyes were closed
and my ears were shut.
Ugh. Aren't you worried
about nightmares?
- Mom, I'm nine now.
- Ha.
Hi. Can we get a taxi, please?
- Mom. Mom.
- Right away to the--
Oh, you know what? We're good.
We don't need one.
Thanks.
Come on.
Let's get you in.
Hey there.
Can we get 1085 Chestnut?
- The big park.
- Driver: Got it.
Mom:
Hey, hon. It's us.
We are in a cab
and we're on our way home.
- (video game beeping)
- Love you.
- Mom: Dude, what happened?
- Boy: I went through a door.
You watched the movie.
You should know.
Sorry.
Did your face fall off yet?
- No.
- (laughing)
I can't believe you missed that part.
Um, excuse me,
that was our exit.
"Don't take the bus," he says.
"Take a cab."
You gonna call Dad?
Well, I would, but now
I'm not getting any service.
I think if you just keep
going straight, then-- okay.
Um...
(chuckles)
You know where we are?
Sir? Could you just pull over?
Hey, listen, um...
I've got a child back here
and you're beginning to scare
the bejesus out of me,
so if you don't pull over right now,
then I'm not only gonna report you
to the cab company,
but to the fuckin' police as well!
Pull over!
Boy:
Mom, is everything okay?
Mom: Just let us out, please.
Just stop the car and talk to me.
This is scaring us.
- All right, just let us out here.
- Mom. Mom.
Mom: I won't report you.
I won't say anything.
- Just keep trying the doors.
- No, Mom, I'm staying with you.
Mom:
Open these fucking doors!
- Baby, baby.
- (door handle thudding)
Boy:
I can't! I can't!
- Mom: Let us out of the car!
- (pounding)
Damn it!
Let us out of the fucking car!
Oh, God.
(shouts)
Now, you fucker!
Motherfucker!
Oh, God.
Okay, he stopped.
- He's getting out.
- Boy: What is happening?
Mom: I'm gonna talk to him.
You're gonna take the phone.
When I scream, "Run,"
you're gonna run.
- It's gonna be okay.
- Boy: No.
- I'll find you.
- Mom, no.
- I will find you, baby.
- No, I'm not leaving without you.
It's gonna be okay.
- Oh, my God! Wait!
- (crying) Mom!
- Don't you--
- (punch lands)
(crying)
Mom? Please.
Mom, are you okay?
Mom:
Oh, my God.
- (door opens)
- Mom: Look at me. Look at me.
- We're gonna be okay, all right?
- Boy: What does he want?
We're gonna be fine.
Boy:
Leave her alone!
Mom!
No!
Just stay in the car!
- No!
- Mom! Mom!
(screaming)
Mom.
Please. Please. Please.
Mom?
- Mom?
- It's okay.
Mommy's fine, baby.
Mommy's fine.
Just stay in the car.
You're gonna be fine.
Don't worry.
You're gonna be fine, baby.
Stay in the car.
Cover your ears.
(mother screaming)
(sobbing)
Mom.
(screaming stops)
No. No!
Mom! Uh.
You look like your mother.
My dad's gonna find you.
If-- if that's what you believe.
(grunts)
Ah!
That is the last free shot
that you will ever get.
You will skip dinner.
(groans)
I want my mom.
Well, she's not coming back, ever,
so get used to it.
Boy: Mom.
(TV turns on)
(clock ticking)
You smell like piss.
I didn't ask for you.
But since you're here,
I'm going to make the most of it.
You will have one job.
(opens door)
You do what I say.
You clean up my house.
Garbage bags, mops,
bucket, broom--
they are your tools.
Breakfast.
You will serve me breakfast
every morning
for the rest of your life.
You will not eat or drink anything
without my permission.
You only eat after I have eaten,
and only what I have
left on my plate.
- (button clicks)
- (buzzer)
You hear that?
That means that
I'm bringing one back.
You have 10 seconds
to open these locks.
Every night I bring home
a newspaper.
After I finish reading it,
I want you to try and find stories
about missing people.
You cut them out
nice and neat...
The licenses.
...and you put them
in the scrapbook.
Cash. See?
There is no phone in this house.
The TV is off limits unless I offer it.
If someone knocks at the--
well, no one's gonna knock.
If you steal from me,
you get a beating.
If you try and escape
or you don't keep the house clean,
you get a beating.
If you make me nervous
or get in my way at all, a beating.
From now on, this is your world.
It is only you, me, and them.
I will call you Rabbit.
(wind howling)
On page 12,
there is a nice piece
about you
and your mother missing.
Put it in the scrapbook.
(door opens, closes)
(car engine starts)
(garage door opens)
(garage door closes)
(grunts)
You going somewhere, Rabbit?
You get an A for effort.
I know every move that you make.
Help!
Everything you do
I let you do!
Go ahead, let it out.
Help!
- Somebody!
- Let it out.
- Help!
- That's it.
- Let it go. Let it go.
- Help, somebody!
- Come on.
- Help!
Dad!
You are so fucking predictable.
Somebody!
And a fucking embarrassment.
Help!
Come on.
Come on, Rabbit.
Hey, Rabbit,
what are you gonna do with that?
Don't be a quitter.
Rabbit, you have to follow through.
Following through
is the key to life.
Come on down.
I'll tell you what--
you come down and I will
give you a running start.
Go ahead.
Come on.
Come on, kid!
Come on, kid.
That's it.
That's it. Go.
Come on,
give it all you've got.
Come on, let it go, kid.
Let it go, kid.
Come on.
You're a paper doll.
(scrubbing)
(crying)
(mock crying)
(door slams)
(Bob crying)
(TV playing)
Women love flowers.
Reporter on TV:
...aren't releasing any information
until they complete
their investigation.
A government bill that cracked down
on laboratory experiments on animals
is expected to become law today.
Animal rights activists have been
pushing for the bill for nine years
and have taken part
in mass demonstrations
throughout the nation.
Thanks.
2314 Grafton.
I'm... real sorry, Dad.
- Dad--
- Not a fucking word.
(slaps)
I've known you all your life...
and you're nothing special.
You're nothing special.
(grunts, slaps)
(door closes)
(chains rattling)
Did your dad toss a ball around
with you in the backyard?
You know, after school,
like-- or Sundays?
I mean,
did he do things with you,
teach you things?
Or was he just fucked?
Do you want to learn things?
To really learn?
Because it's important
as hell to know shit.
Otherwise, people will--
they will walk all over you.
I got things
that you should learn.
Okay.
You are not going to be ignorant.
You're going to study
and you're going to learn.
- About what?
- People--
what makes them tick,
what makes them work,
what's in the gut and the head.
Why?
Because without education,
you're fucked.
I mean,
you've seen some things.
I've showed you
some things for sure,
but you haven't understood them.
You ever do a puzzle?
You know, the kind of puzzle
that has the picture
on the outside of the box?
That's what people are--
pictures on the outside,
pieces inside.
This book is about
the human puzzle.
You study this,
you learn it,
and you know how to take people apart,
put them back together,
understand them.
Oh.
So study it and--
just study.
You don't want to be
shackled to this house
for the rest of your life,
do you?
- No.
- Good.
There's hope for you yet.
So, study hard,
and then maybe you and I can
work out a deal.
A deal for what?
Some freedom.
You know, get off the chain,
get out of the house,
get a girl.
You're older now.
I think that...
you should have a taste
of a woman real soon.
I won't take the puzzles apart.
I won't kill them.
(sighs)
I give you a gift of knowledge
and you fuck it away!
You are looking to be shackled
to this fucking wall
for the rest of your life, mister.
I wasn't gonna show you this,
but now that you're being a shit...
That's your dad.
He remarried.
Dad.
He's got a new wife, a new life.
You see this, kid?
That is not someone
that misses you.
You got me and no one else.
Here, have a beer.
No, thank you.
- Can I still study the books?
- Yeah, have at it.
That's good.
- Give me an answer.
- I-- I'm not sure.
That's not the answer I'm looking for,
not by a long shot.
But I'm not sure.
If we gotta stay here all night,
then that's what we'll do--
we'll stay here all night.
Bob: All right, give me
your best guess.
- It could be...
- Yes?
...small-cell carcinoma?
Yes. Nice. Good.
That's good.
(woman screams)
(screaming continues)
No!
(thuds)
(woman screams)
- (thuds)
- (man yells)
(door opens)
(murmuring)
How do I get out of here?
Which way?
Which way is out?
I'll take you with me.
I don't want your fucking blanket!
Please!
I just wanna go home.
How the fuck do I get out of--
(dull thud)
(crow cawing)
Go.
That's it.
Come on.
That's what you want
in a girl-- some fight.
There's no sport in easy.
- You thinking stupid thoughts?
- No.
No, I'm not thinking,
just listening.
Good.
Listening is good.
Come on.
She was quite a ride, too.
She sure could run.
Hey, let's play.
Come on.
Come on, one round.
Okay. Okay.
Okay.
All right.
Ellen Rand.
22 years old.
Her birthday:
February the 19th.
Lied like a rug
about her weight big time.
Thank you.
Jennifer Elizabeth Wyatt.
1642 Melvin Road, apartment 7.
Organ donor.
Born September 7th.
And you said that she was honest
about her weight.
She put 126.
I don't know about weight.
Well, you will.
You'd better go in.
Well, there they are now.
Your mother's been
worried sick about you boys.
- Man: School good today, Bobby?
- Yeah.
Lying sack of shit!
(bangs)
You think you're better than I am
just because I got laid off?
Aren't you, Bobby?
Big man making money.
(groans)
(Bob groaning)
You're such a big man now.
Let's see you in action.
(Bob crying)
Get your fuckin' clothes off,
Bobby, now!
(shouting)
Man:
Take him, Joanne.
Put him inside you.
Let him show you how big he is.
(crying)
It's okay.
(shouting)
(crying)
You're a fucking whore, Joanne.
It's okay.
Get off me.
Honey.
(Bob shouts)
(screaming)
(panting)
(girl giggling)
Hi. Hi.
I'm Mary.
(hiccups)
Mary.
I need to pee.
(laughing)
Which way is the powder room?
Which way?
I gotta go.
Please?
Show her where
the powder room is, Rabbit.
Show me.
Oh.
Not that powder room.
The other one.
- Oh!
- (chains rattling)
Ooh, kinky.
You're gonna tie me up?
(laughing)
You guys.
That's not cool.
Gotta be...
I guess you could smoke.
I'd rather you didn't.
(laughs)
You'd rather I didn't?
Okay, well, I have to pee.
So if you're gonna hold out
on the powder room,
I'm gonna smoke.
- That's what I'm gonna do.
- (lighter clicking)
Remember I saw you dancing?
- Yeah.
- Remember?
I love dancing.
But you didn't dance.
(humming)
- It's--
- (girl laughs)
It's okay. Everything is--
it's gonna be okay.
(pats)
I think I'm too drunk.
I'm drunk.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Don't be silly.
Everything will be okay, right?
(giggles)
Well, say it.
Say, "It's okay."
- It's okay.
- Now come here.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
(gagging)
- Carotid artery.
- Yes, carotid artery.
(gasping)
Mary.
(whimpers)
(cries out)
(Rabbit cries out)
(grunts)
(Rabbit grunts)
(Rabbit cries out)
(shouts)
(Rabbit panting)
No!
(sobbing)
Bob:
I got something for you.
This is a school yearbook.
You see?
It has...
Tell me when you see
something you like.
Pick it up.
I don't want it.
Where do you think that you are
right now on the food chain, Rabbit?
I won't do it.
No kid of mine is gonna grow up
uselessly educated.
I'm not your kid.
The fuck you're not.
Pick it up.
Look around.
What do you see?
Do you see anything that says
that you aren't my kid?
That we aren't family?
Do you see?
Now pick it up.
Pick it up.
Yeah.
Good.
I don't wanna hear a sound
out of you the rest of the night.
I don't wanna know that you exist.
(door opens)
- Thank you.
- (door closes)
Bob:
We made the news again.
They don't know anything,
the cops.
We are a mystery.
No evidence.
In one ear and out the window.
It is a good day to be me, Rabbit.
I'm done with this scrapbook.
Good. Right.
It's full.
Well, I will get you another one.
It's good to keep a record.
Why do you do what you do?
What the fuck?
I asked why you do what you do.
- Why do you do what you do?
- You make me.
Well, that is a good answer.
Then I guess they make me
do what I do.
Who does?
Them...
under the dirt, in the book.
Them.
They never asked to be murdered.
Oh, you are
growing a pair all of a sudden.
And they did.
- They asked.
- When?
The day that they were
fuckin' born.
I don't understand.
Oh, you fuckin'...
You are f--
are you trying to make me
fucking insane?
Do I have to spell it out for you?
They are all fucking whores!
They are all fucking sluts!
They seemed like
nice people to me.
(mocks) "They seemed
like nice people to me."
Oh, you are--
oh, you gotta get laid.
You are getting fucked up
in the head.
Gotta get your taste
of a woman for sure.
Nothing like the taste of a woman
to make you clear.
(silent)
Did you find one yet?
We'll see.
(clears throat)
Somewhere...
Somewhere in here
there is a Mrs. Right.
Somewhere in here.
(whimpers)
Find her. Come on.
Pick one.
Don't be shy.
Come on.
Find one.
Find one. Look.
That's it.
Where, oh, where could she be?
Pick one!
Come on.
I think that's a good choice.
Oh, yes.
(banging)
(muffled yelling)
- (banging continues)
- (Bob humming)
(door opens)
(door closes)
She's ready.
Come on.
Rabbit.
(patting)
(sighs)
You're scared.
That's okay.
Everyone's scared the first time.
Yeah.
(gasps)
(whimpering)
Bob:
You said to me that
you didn't want to be chained
to the wall your whole life,
didn't you?
Come on.
Let's go.
Come on. That's it.
Come on.
Yeah. Come on.
That's it.
There's only one
real way out for you
to prove to me
that I can trust you.
And there's only--
there's only one way to do that.
Yeah.
Let's go.
You gotta prove it to me.
You gotta prove it.
Come on.
(crying)
(groans)
Come on.
- Okay.
- (muffled whimpering)
Be quiet.
Quiet to keep the mood.
- Quiet.
- (whimpering stops)
- Yes?
- Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
Come on.
Bob:
It's his first time...
so he's a little shy.
Yeah.
You remember
what we talked about?
If you can't do it, I will.
And you know how that
will turn out.
So you keep your head straight.
Have some fun.
(knife clatters)
(clock ticking)
(TV playing)
I'm Angie.
I'm 18.
What's your name?
I'm Rabbit.
Are you gonna hurt me, Rabbit?
I don't want to.
But he's expecting you to.
But you have a knife.
Can't we-- can't we just
get out of here?
We can't get out.
How long have you been here?
Since I was nine.
I'm sorry, Rabbit.
He hurts you, doesn't he?
When he feels like
he should, yes.
If you-- if you wanna have sex,
I'll have sex with you.
I'll do any-- anything you want.
I don't want anything.
This isn't about sex.
Then-- then what is it about?
I guess it is about sex
if sex involves killing.
Oh, shit.
But I haven't done either.
Have you ever touched a girl?
You can touch me, Rabbit.
You can touch me
however you want.
I can show you--
I can show you
how my body works.
I already know
how your body works.
You can have me.
We will do whatever you want.
Am I hurting you?
Are you okay?
Shh, shh.
Shh.
- Look at me. Look at me.
- Shh.
Shh, shh.
(muffled speech)
Rabbit.
- Rabbit!
- Please.
Rabbit!
(knife pierces)
Go away!
(clock ticking)
(door opens)
(door slams)
I want to hunt.
God damn.
Look who's all grown up.
(footsteps approach)
Look at you.
Turn around.
Good.
What do you think?
- About what?
- The chair.
- Mine?
- Graduation present.
- It's good.
- Good.
Front passenger side
of the vehicle.
Mom's voice:
Hey, hon. It's us.
We are in a cab
and we're on our way home.
Love you.
Young Rabbit's voice:
Leave her alone! No!
- Mom!
- Mom's voice: No! Stay in the car!
(overlapping shouting)
Bob: Let's go.
Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go.
Um, so you have to tuck down
until we get into town.
There we go.
That's good.
Bob:
I feel energized.
At night is the best time to hunt.
My vision is clear.
I'm good
being here with you now.
This is good.
You're a good kid.
The first thing that
you have to be clear about
is your type.
If you're into prostitution,
maybe get a few of them
under your belt,
and then move
onto something else.
If you come across
one like that--
look at her,
all buttoned up like she's never
sucked on a cock before.
Well, you can bet that she has.
No.
Okay.
Rabbit:
Where next?
Going to a college campus.
Girls your age.
- Like Angie?
- Yes, like Angie.
l-l don't know.
Maybe this is too much too soon.
We'll go back home.
We could watch the movie
of your first time.
You made a movie
of me and Angie?
Yes, I did.
I haven't watched it yet.
That-- that's my private thing.
I-- I don't want you to see
what I did.
I told you, I will watch it,
and you will watch it with me.
It's important.
You won't like it.
I-- I don't do it--
I'm not good at it like you are.
You'll be mad.
You can't do it wrong, Rabbit.
I'll drive by the college campus,
then we'll go home.
(police radio chatter)
Bob:
Get down.
Okay.
Bob:
What did you do?
No, nothing.
I did everything you wanted.
- Shut up!
- (punches)
Have some fun.
- Am I hurting you?
- If you can't do it, I will.
Go away!
- Angie. No, shh!
- (gasping)
- (whimpering)
- Shh, shh.
Okay, okay.
Shh. Shh.
I know-- I know
I hurt you real bad,
but you just gotta
stay quiet, okay?
You stabbed me.
I know.
I had to or he would have.
I tried to miss the vital organs.
I think I did okay.
How do you know?
Look at me. Look at me.
I told you.
I know how your body works.
I've been studying.
You'll be okay.
You'll be okay
for about two days,
and then you're gonna get
really sick.
Two days?
- (cries out)
- Shh!
Shh.
Okay, shh.
I have to hide you.
I have to-- I have to make him
think that you're dead.
(crying)
Oh, God. No.
Okay, you have to trust me.
Okay?
You have to trust me.
Go limp.
Just go limp.
And don't you make any noise.
Don't make any noise.
Dead girls don't make any noise.
I've seen a lot of dead girls.
Take this.
It's sharp.
Please. Please.
(crying)
(garage door opens)
(garage door closes)
You need to fix this, Rabbit.
I'm really disappointed.
You need to make it right.
And don't further insult me
by pretending
like you don't hear me!
You fuck her?
Probably not.
I mean, you could have
at least fucked her.
You didn't have to lie to me.
I would have done the rest.
I gotta do it now anyway.
I don't like that
you fuckin' lied to me!
Angie!
Angie.
I got a surprising little secret.
How are you doing, young lady?
Angie!
- Angie!
- How're you doing, Ange?
Rabbit:
Angie! Don't hurt her!
Bob:
Angie!
Ah, fuck!
(screaming)
Rabbit:
Angie!
Angie. Angie!
Come here, you fucking whore!
Rabbit: No!
(yelling)
- Get off of me!
- What did you do?!
(groaning)
Fuck.
I knew that you were thinking it.
Shut up.
Rabbit,
you can't do this.
Rabbit.
(dog barking)
(doorbell rings)
Marie, the dog should be out back.
What you selling?
You don't recognize me?
No, I don't.
Should I?
I always wanted a puppy.
Yeah, well, I'm about ready
to give you ours.
- Come on, Marie.
- You said we couldn't afford it.
I said what?
- Tim?
- I'm so sorry.
- Tim, is that you?
- Tim?
Your son Tim?
My, God, Tim, you're alive.
Take the puppy out back.
Go on.
Take the puppy.
Go, go, go.
Come in, then.
Come in.
Marie: Come in, hon.
Please, come.
Come in, son.
Come in.
(door closes)
How-- how did you find me?
Where have you been?
Where have you been, Tim?
He-- he killed Mom.
I'm so sorry.
You're safe now, honey.
I just wanna know why, Dad.
- You gave this to your brother.
- Oh, no.
Honey, he doesn't have a brother.
You're confused.
He doesn't-- you--
you don't have a brother.
- No, I don't have a brother.
- Like old hand-me-down clothes,
you just-- you just gave us away.
Tim, I don't know
what you're talking about.
You told me to look after Mom.
I was just a kid
and I couldn't save her,
and you knew I couldn't save her.
- You knew.
- Boy: Mom, Dad,
is everything all right?
I have a brother.
Hey, Marie, take Colin upstairs.
Tim and I need to have a little talk.
Go on.
Go up the stairs.
In one ear and out the window.
Get up the stairs, Marie.
Now! Get up the fucking stairs!
I found your letter.
I know where you came from
and I know everything.
Robert Fittler,
your older brother--
you paid him
to make us go away.
And I'm gonna tell.
You're gonna tell on me?
Hmm?
Go on, get out of here.
You should never have come
to my house.
Go on.
I don't even wanna look at you.
Brad, Brad!
- Please! Please!
- Rabbit: I'm gonna tell.
- Goddamn, disgusting piece of shit.
- Marie: Stop! No more!
Stop!
Marie: Okay, okay.
Okay, baby.
Baby, baby.
- (panting)
- Quiet.
It's-- it's--
it's okay.
It's o-- ah!
- (muffled screaming)
- Be quiet.
- Don't hurt her!
- (gasps)
(gurgling)
Okay, okay.
Colin:
Mom? Mom?
Stay in your room, Colin!
(clatters)
(crying)
You need to go.
Go now, okay?
Go.
Go!
Go! Go!
(door opens, closes)
Colin:
Mom, what's happening?
- Mom?
- Don't you dare come down here.
Stay in your room, Colin.
Some man broke into my house.
I-- I think they killed my husband.
Colin:
No! Daddy!
(clangs)
(footsteps)
(door opens)
(clock ticking)
(footsteps)
(door closes)
(clock ticking)
(footsteps)
- (fridge door opens)
- (bottles rattle)
(fridge door closes)
- (drawer opens)
- (thuds)
(paper rustling)
(scissors cutting)
(water pouring, sloshing)
(door opens, thumps)
- (light switch clicks)
- (rustling)
(light switch clicks)
(footsteps)
(thuds)
- (car door opens)
- (thuds)
(car door closes)
(garage door opens)