You were lucky. You just have
mild hypothermia and some frostbite.
What were you doing out in the cold?
I couldn't find the toilet.
If you can't find the
toilet, Marie, just ask me.
- How's the old lady?
- She just gets a little frostbitten.
It looks nice.
Are you with the closure committee?
Celebrating that we're being shut down?
No. Not everyone's a
bitter old man, Hermann.
- I'm celebrating our time together.
- Some of us might want out.
What a fuss.
Hey, Camilla. Do you think Ole
would want some of this scrap?
No, just throw it out.
We have a garage full of stuff.
Okay.
Hi.
You're being friendly.
How come?
Ole, are you there?
Ole here.
I've got a message about an
abandoned car near Stehøtinn.
I'll check it out.
Where were we?
Heard anything more about the job?
I got an offer at Ullevål,
and I said yes.
I know we haven't finished talking
about it, but it just slipped out.
- Say something, please.
- It's best I check on that car.
Thanks.
Two to three days, judging by the snow.
Has anyone been reported missing?
No, there aren't any
cabins around here.
At least you have the
license number. Bye.
Damn!
I wrote to him yesterday.
His mother called and asked
if he could stay the night.
- How is it?
- It itches.
Itches? That's good.
That means it's healing.
Trouble with Ole?
You know, Ole. He thrives
in an igloo in the mountains.
I'm more for two rooms
and a kitchen in the city.
There's snow and trees in Oslo, too.
Have you tried to tell him that?
It's Ole.
Hi.
I don't see any external injuries,
but there's a lot of blood.
It's not mine.
Right.
Exactly.
You say that you and four friends
were on a snowboarding trip?
A broken leg.
So you broke into an abandoned
hotel to find shelter.
And at the hotel your
friends were killed.
And he that did it was a kind of ...
... abominable snowman
who lived in the basement.
And now he and your friends
are at the bottom of a deep crevasse.
Why did you bring this?
In case he came back, I thought.
What do you think?
- Is she sane?
- It's a bit early to say.
We'll go up and check, in any case.
Kim, get the snowmobile and climbing
equipment. Arne, get the snow cat.
- Sverre, stay here and keep watch.
- Keep watch?
Keep an eye on her until we
know what this is all about.
Ole, will you help?
- Sure.
- Good.
Bye.
See you at the garage.
That's ok. I'll heat
it up in the microwave.
Ragnhild, will you record
"Around Norway" for me?
Is it true, you think?
We'll soon find out.
Could you have a chat with her?
She needs someone to talk to.
- Shouldn't we call someone?
- I called, and they're coming tomorrow.
Until then, I think you're
the best option, Camilla.
Sorry. I just thought
I'd take your temperature.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
It's getting better.
I brought you some soup.
I made it myself.
I know how hospital food tastes.
Yes.
- Please let us know if ...
- Yes.
- Hi.
Well ...
- I couldn't find the toilet.
- Let me help you.
Kim?
How much more time do you need?
The wind's starting to blow.
I'm done now.
Are you very sick?
No, not really.
Neither am I. I just have to
wait for Mom to come and get me.
- Did you break your arm?
- Yep.
- Did it hurt a lot?
- Yes, but I didn't cry.
- Want to try my cool fighting game?
- No, thanks ...
I'm a little tired right now.
Ok.
Hey...?
What's your name?
Daniel.
I'm Jannicke. Maybe we can play
a little tomorrow, if you want to.
That was the last.
Let's pack up and go back.
You and Johan stay here.
We have to seal off this area.
Here?
That's what the crime lab
people would want, you know?
And when you're done with that,
check out the hotel. I'm sorry.
Sorry.
- Criminal police, this is security.
- This is Einar Stolen, the sheriff.
We need some help. We've found five
bodies in a deep crevasse. Suspected murder.
- Did you track the culprit?
- Yes. He's as dead as the others.
It's a bit too late now, but we
can be there tomorrow morning.
Until then, you're on your own.
I can probably handle five bodies.
Is that a black eye he has?
It looks more like a birthmark, I think.
What's happening? Should I continue
looking after her, Einar? Einar?
Someone ought to tell her
that we found her friends.
Here. Put the clothes and
jewellery in these bags, -
- and then remember to
mark them properly, Audhild.
- I should do it by myself?
- I'll be right back.
Missing Persons
Unsolved Cases
"No trace of lost boy"
Hello?
- Sorry. Am I disturbing you?
- No, not at all.
Oh, damn...!
It's not exactly the average
Norwegian Easter tourist.
Looks more like a Dane who
took the "Rule of 5" literally.
Yes. "Be prepared against bad
weather even on short trips."
You know the rules.
Do you like mountain climbing?
No, but an idiot tried to convince me -
- that number four was: "Stay
with experienced mountaineers."
Did you want something specific?
No, I'm just out to
reconnoitre ...
Not reconnoitre. I'm just checking
that everything's in order.
Maybe I'll see you later. Bye.
"Your friends are down in the morgue."
How am I supposed to say that?
It'll work out.
You're good with people.
No. Why do you say that?
I'm not even good with you.
Come here, Camilla.
- I thought you were sleeping.
- No.
They've come down from the mountains.
They brought your friends.
Would you like to see them?
- Would people stop doing that?
- Excuse me.
- Did you come to help?
- I brought someone with me.
He's ice cold.
You bastard! I hate you!
Damn. Is that blood?
- Kim, come in.
- Sverre.
- Where are you?
- We just entered the hotel.
- You have to go back to the crevasse.
- Damn ...
I think there may be
something else there.
Understood.
"Skiers disappear"
"Without a trace"
"Young people
lost in the mountains"
You ...
- I ...
- It's okay.
Thanks.
May I speak with you, Camilla?
- I'll be right back, ok?
- Yes.
What the hell were you doing, Camilla?
Sightseeing in the morgue?
- I think it helped her.
- Tell her these are vitamins.
- You want to drug her?
- She attacked a corpse, Camilla.
- Hermann ...
- Do as I say.
Johan?
Find anything?
What is it, Johan?
I have a bad fucking' feeling.
Yikes.
What happened here?
Audhild!
- Ok, come on.
- It's stuck.
Stuck?
What the hell do you mean?
Get back.
On the skin.
Clear, clear, clear.
It's happened before. Hypothermia can
prevent cellular breakdown.
There are cases where the heart rate
was down to 10-20 beats per minute.
- And when it comes to the wounds ...
- But he was dead.
Now, who's going to take care of this?
There.
- Yuk.
- The blood?
I thought that all nurses loved ...
Why did you become a nurse?
Because of the uniform.
Guys like nurses.
- That's why I became a policeman.
- You attract many guys in uniform?
No, no.
I'm just kidding.
You look very good in it.
Haven't you heard that before?
Yes, once.
It was my mother who said it.
Hey ...
You look pretty good
in your uniform, too.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
- Bye.
- I thought you quit.
- I did.
She seemed very alert for someone
given 60mg of tranquilizers.
I understand that you're not
happy with me today, Hermann.
I'm sure you'll be a
fantastic doctor, Camilla.
Hello?
Sverre?
No!
So I didn't know ...
But it wasn't like that.
Ok ...
Shouldn't the emergency
lights have come on?
He went out to play, like usual.
And then didn't come back.
- Has he ever done that before?
- No.
He went out to play, like usual.
And then didn't come back.
... to play, like usual.
"Skinned dog
found on mountain"
"Grazing sheep massacred
animal grave in the mountains"
"Grotesque incidents
threaten hotel operations"
"Survived the fire
in abandoned mountain hotel"
"He was hanging on by a hair
says medical officer Haldor Mækland."
This is Haldor.
- It must local. The streetlights are lit.
- I'll turn on the generator.
See to the patients.
Hello?
Oh, God.
What?
Did they...?
Audhild?
What the hell?
Stay away.
You stay away from me!
We'd been searching for the family
for five days without result.
Everyone was tired
and wanted to go home.
Most had already been
looking for the boy for weeks.
So you were alone at the
hotel when the fire broke out?
Yes, as far as I know.
Another beer, Haldor?
We're closing now.
The police report concluded
that they died in an avalanche -
- while looking for their son.
That was at least the
official explanation.
The boy was never completely normal.
You didn't know?
He was stillborn.
In my 40 years as a physician, I've
never experienced anything like it.
He was officially dead for four hours.
A death certificate was written.
Then suddenly his heart
began to beat again.
He didn't cry once when he
woke up. He just lay there.
Quiet as a mouse.
- Is the power out?
- Hi, Daniel. Can you help me?
Help me out of these.
Look in the closet for
a sharp pair of scissors.
- Why did they tie you down?
- Quiet. Try to find some scissors.
There.
But if the doctor has done it,
maybe you should stay there.
It's not necessary any longer.
I was just a little restless when I slept.
Go and get the scissors. Come on.
There. Great.
Just cut here.
There.
Daniel, is the rest of the
hospital dark like it is here?
Yes.
Now we're going to go on a little
tour, but you must keep very quiet, ok?
- Hey ...
- I'm alright.
Come on.
What is it?
- Hey ...
- Was there someone there?
No.
Come on.
But ...
Sit there in the corner. There.
Listen, I have to go out into
the corridor and try to ...
- Did I do something wrong?
- No.
Just wait here a bit and
I'll be back to get you.
It's almost like playing hide and
seek. Do you like to play that?
Be quiet.
Good. Bye.
Do you think it will snow tonight?
Hey, you've reached Ole and
Camilla. Leave a message.
Ole? Ole, where are you?
Things have gone to hell here.
People have been killed.
You have to get help.
You have to get help, ok?
- Jannicke.
- Stay completely still.
It's alright. Nothing came out.
It's alright.
The telephone ...
Hello?
- How many are here?
- Besides us, there are five.
- A little boy.
- Daniel?
An old lady, and Audhild.
No, there's only four.
- Did you count the policeman?
- Three.
- And the doctor?
- He went to turn the power on.
Ok. We'll get Daniel first,
and then the old lady. Ok?
Ok.
- Come on.
-I have to look for Hermann.
- No.
Come on!
What are you doing?
Hi.
Come on.
- We've locked him in the basement.
- Who else is in there?
You can't do that. Kim!
- Now you calm down.
- You have no idea what's in there!
I know more than you think.
- There are people alive in there.
- Calm down and get in the car.
She just saved my life in there.
We can't give weapons to civilians.
Tell me what happened.
Does it fit properly? Good.
Ole, what are you doing?
Ole, don't go in there.
It's going to be alright, ok?
Trust me.
I'll be alright.
Don't contact me before you hear something,
so you don't give away our position.
Clear.
Ole, cover me.
- What do we do now?
- We pull out.
What about the civilians?
And Sverre?
I hear what you're saying, but
that door tells me something else.
We pull out and wait
for reinforcements.
- We're coming out.
- Roger.
- Did you get him?
- No, he wasn't in the basement.
Roger.
- Repeat last message.
- Ok.
Roger.
Cover the front.
Ole, cover the rear.
Fuck.
- It's Sverre.
- Kim, wait!
Ole, behind me!
Kim!
Einar!
Ole, watch out!
Einar?
Einar, come in.
Einar, can you give me a report?
Come in, Einar.
Einar?
Einar, damn it, come in.
Let me out and we'll go in together, ok?
I was in the bathroom.
Ok. Ok.
Let's go in.
Shit!
Camilla, get the gun!
On the floor!
Camilla, you have to get the gun!
Come on.
Come on!
No!
Ole!
Hi ...
Shit! Damn it!
Come on, then, you fucking bastard!
Are you crazy?
You're going to die, Jannicke.
"Guestbook
Stehøe Mountain Lodge"
"12-13 February 2006"
"Were here."
Fuck.
What?
Camilla.
Jannicke.
He's dead now.
I've killed him before.