My name is Alissa Vincent.
I may be the sole survivor.
We encountered an alien life form.
They have taken over
the bodies of the crew.
The colony was lost.
My team is dead.
It is my belief that the artifact
we discovered on the surface
is somehow responsible.
If you find this recording,
the Ishimura and the artifact
must be destroyed.
- must be destroyed.
[whirring, beeping]
30 meters.
Whatever it is, it's just up ahead.
Any idea what it is?
Not a clue.
This planet is ripe
with unusual seismic activity.
Protocol says we're required
to check it out,
so we're checking it out.
All right, heads up.
We've got a small impact crater ahead.
Watch your footing.
Toggle your flares.
Let's take a look
at what we're dealing with.
[Man] There's something strange
about these walls.
There's evidence of chemical weathering.
And there's symmetrical
45 degree scarring on these walls.
Anybody else think these marks
resemble the ones made by an E-34?
Well, I would if we weren't
several million light years from home
on a previously unexplored rock.
Yet, we have E-34 drag lines as well.
Nobody's used an E-34
elephant drilling rig in over 150 years.
Hell, I've only seen them in books.
I'm going to radio the colony.
Somebody's been messing around out here.
Jen, you're going
to want to look at this.
Oh, my God.
We've got to call this in.
[Man]
This is Aegis Colony.
Artifact discovered.
Could be a second Marker.
Please advise.
[Man #2]
Unitologist Church has been notified.
They're awaiting specs.
Earth, you should have an image.
Files are uploaded.
My God, we've found it.
Launch of Ishimura on schedule.
Arrival on station: one month.
Prepare the artifact
for transfer to the ship.
Artifact removed from discovery site.
Strange interference generated.
Unexplained violence
reported among colonists.
Planet security handling it.
Artifact is quarantined
and ready for removal.
Acknowledged.
Ishimura will be on station
and ready for transport shortly.
Our expert, Dr. Kyne, is aboard
and will coordinate the experiments.
Altman be praised.
That's odd.
What the hell's been
going wrong down there?
Chief Vincent,
you're wanted on the bridge.
What's up?
The captain is ready to see you.
On my way.
Audio off.
About fucking time.
Lights out.
So I tell her, artifact or not,
in the grand scheme of things,
we are all alone out here.
Might be a long time ago the universe
had all kinds of life, but now...
You know what I think?
I think the thing is cursed.
I mean look what's happened
since they found it.
I don't remember you getting paid
to think, Jackson.
Now go help secure those gravity tethers.
We've got a whole operation
waiting on this thing.
Someone or something
put that thing here for a reason,
that's all I know.
It's a good thing no one asked you.
Come on, Collin.
You telling me that the thing
ain't creeping the shit out of you?
I mean, the suicides, the murders?
Seems like everyone on this rock
is losing their shit.
This is deep space.
Weird shit happens.
The faster we do our jobs,
the faster we get home.
Your wife discovered it
and she still has no theory
about where it came from?
The Unitologists seem to have an idea
that this is what created us,
or something stupid like that.
Jen is a geologist and a site surveyor,
not an anthropologist,
archeologist, or Unitologist.
- [door whirring]
- Besides, she hasn't been well.
That's more the reason to get this thing
aboard ship and go home.
[Man on radio] What the hell
is going on down there, Barrow?
We've got a timeline
and a planet to crack.
Everything is fine, Ishimura.
Securing the last anchor now.
We'll be moving out momentarily.
What secrets do you have for us?
Dr. Kyne...
you're needed in the med lab.
On the way.
[men chattering]
Steady now.
- Captain.
- You wanted to see me?
As chief of security on this ship,
I would like to severely protest
bringing the artifact aboard.
You've already made your protests heard,
and I have already taken them
into account, thank you.
Captain.
You've given me
the incident counts for the colony,
and I say that this colony has been
in operation for two and a half years.
That much time in deep space
is inherently dangerous.
And the people attracted
to this line of work are, too.
You're forgetting one thing, Captain.
A spike in serious violent incidents
have been reported over the last week.
We pulled that thing up a week ago.
I have my orders and you have yours.
Just tell me this.
Why is this thing so important?
Alissa, don't fight me on this.
Once Kyne has studied the Marker,
you can have your team run a full analysis.
Yes, sir.
Gravity tethers full tension
and stable, Captain.
All systems are go, sir.
All right, Mr. White.
Pop the cork.
[monitor beeping]
[grunting]
I had to kill.
You understand?
They need bodies.
They need us to turn.
All right, Mr. Leggio.
Sometimes the sedatives
cause hallucinations.
Just relax, okay?
Why is this man still awake?
I told you to give him a sedative.
I did. 500 cc's, just like you ordered.
He's fighting it.
You don't hear that?
My God, make it stop!
[groaning]
Kill me!
[beeping increases]
Nurse, help me restrain him!
Kill me! Just fucking kill me!
Hold him still, Nurse.
That should do it.
[beeping decreases]
What the hell just happened?
I've never seen someone resist
a sedative of that quantity.
It's not possible.
I have no idea.
Two weeks ago, this man
was healthy and mentally stable.
Then out of nowhere,
he kills two members of his dig team.
None of this makes much sense.
Some kind of toxin, maybe.
Something in the colony?
Maybe.
This rash of unusual cases
coming from the planet puzzles me.
I need full blood work done ASAP.
Test for anything and everything.
Yes, Doctor.
Good work, people.
She's coming up nicely.
- [alarms sounding]
- [rumbling]
Normal electromagnetic surges.
The magnetic field of the planet
is bleeding out.
Nothing to worry about.
- [alarm sounds]
- [rumbling]
What's happening?
I'm not sure.
The entire system is rebooting.
Our power cores are shielded.
Yes, I know.
Another wave of disruption just broke
from the surface and smacked into us.
It's a temporary glitch,
not an attack, Alissa.
Down, girl.
- Asshole.
- Break it up, you two.
Chic, can you raise the colony?
Well, things are choppy at best.
We've lost 40% of the comlink signal.
Can you isolate the problem?
I've never seen interference like this.
I have, when I was a pilot back Earth-side
and my radar was being jammed.
You think this is intentionally
directed at us?
That's a dead planet
and we're the only people out here.
How in the hell is something
intentionally jamming us?
I'm just saying what it looks like.
It could just be excess magnetic feedback
from the planet crack.
Chick, get me Foreman Barrow.
I want to know what's happening down there.
Captain, I don't know
if you can hear me,
but we must have pulled
too closely to the core.
Things are shaking
like a mother down here.
We've got heavy interference.
Over.
You reading me, Ishimura?
Nothing.
Barrow, come in.
Barrow.
Barrow, this is the captain.
Report in.
Barrow.
[roaring]
[groaning]
- The planet is pushing back.
- What?
Something I read about the danger
of harvesting planets.
You got another line of work
you're looking to get into?
It says that the planet cracking procedure
is extremely dangerous
to the overall harmony of the universe.
What a bunch of Unitologist bullshit.
The only planets we ever found
in all of space are dead.
Earth was a fluke.
It's a ghost town in here.
Where the hell is everybody?
I'm going to check on Jen.
Catch you later.
[woman screams in distance]
[creature roaring]
[woman screams]
[roaring continues]
[panting]
Jen?
Where are you?
What the fuck?
These symbols are the same as...
Honey, what are you doing?
They want our bodies.
This is mine...
my flesh, my bone, and my blood.
No!
No, no, no!
Jen?
Oh, baby.
Fuck. Why?
Jen.
My last analysis of the Marker
suggests a psychosomatic energy field
unlike anything I've ever seen.
This interference is rising from the planet.
The Marker's not the problem here.
I know, it... it's just...
Just what, Doctor?
- [computer beeping]
- Something's not right.
Communications just came back up.
I'm reacquiring the colony's signal.
We're pulling scattershot low-res images
from the personal cams.
- [gasps]
- What the...
Put it on the main monitors.
We need to send a security team
down there now, Captain.
Captain, I'm getting
multiple flat lines across the board.
[alarms beeping]
Good God,
they're being slaughtered.
- By what?
- I'm going down there now.
Not until I know what the hell is happening.
Chic, get someone on the com.
I want a sit-rep ASAP.
[panting]
Hold on, baby.
We're going home.
[engines whirring]
I've raised one of the dig crews.
Ishimura, can you hear us?
Something's down here,
killing everyone.
My dig crew has changed.
I think there's something down...
Help us, God damn it!
This is Ishimura.
We are reading you.
Who is killing everyone?
- Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
- [creature roaring]
Dig team, come in.
This is Ishimura, come in. Over.
Start scanning frequencies.
Don't fuck with me right now.
Get on the horn and get me the colony.
Captain, we need to call for help.
We don't have the forces
to protect the ship.
I don't need to remind you
that this is a restricted system,
and we're not supposed to be here.
You don't.
But the circumstances have changed.
My orders haven't.
Then at least let's contact the church.
- They must know about...
- About what?
The effects of the Marker are like nothing
documented in the religious texts.
And your crew is being wiped out
as we speak.
I have a feeling that we have at least
something very dangerous down there,
and we need guidance.
- Do you think they know?
- Who?
The crew.
Most of the key officers
are sympathetic to the church.
Maybe a third of the crew
are with the church. Why?
We're going to abandon the colony
and return the Marker to Earth.
It's the only thing to do.
I cannot afford a mutiny on my ship.
Sir, I need to take a team down there.
At the very least we need to know
what we're dealing with.
Denied. No one is allowed
on or off the colony.
You're condemning innocent people.
You want me to put the entire ship at risk?
Is that your brilliant idea?
Captain Matthius,
we've got an incoming shuttle.
Just picked her up on radar.
She's close.
Lock the bay doors on every level.
They're survivors.
Maybe they can tell us
what's happening down there.
Do what I say, and do it now.
[Man on radio]
Shuttle Seven, this is the Ishimura.
You are ordered to return
to the surface immediately.
Do you read me?
You cannot land on board the Ishimura.
- Over.
- Fuck you, Ishimura.
Landing, crashing, or shot down.
Pick one.
But there's no way in hell we're going back.
[roars]
Captain, the shuttle just
slipped through Bay 17
before we could secure the doors.
Get down there now.
Arrest everyone on board that shuttle
and quarantine them.
You sure you don't want me
to shoot them first?
[groans]
[shuttle hissing]
Eyes up, people.
What exactly are we
dealing with here, Vincent?
Asked as if I had a fucking clue.
Clear right.
Clear left.
Jesus, what the hell happened here?
There's a hell of a lot of blood,
but no bodies.
Sounds like one of your parties.
Or your sex life.
Cut the chatter, people.
This thing didn't crash itself.
If someone was piloting this bird,
they ain't here.
Blood trails.
Someone got off this shuttle.
Where the hell are they?
We're moving out.
[monitor beeping]
[beeping increases]
[gasping]
[splash]
No. No.
[creature chittering]
[roaring]
You don't look well.
Vincent's team has secured the dock.
There's no sign of the shuttle crew.
They're beginning a search of the ship.
- And...
- And what?
We've lost all contact with the colony.
I want you to check on the artifact.
Make sure it's secure.
We are in over our heads.
You need to contact Earth and find out
what our next course of action should be.
I think this is a test of our faith.
What?
Nothing.
Just get down there, Doctor.
Get back to your stations.
We have a right to see it.
You can't lock it away.
It's a holy relic.
We have the right.
Clear this area immediately.
This is a secure area,
and Captain Matthius
wants the artifact left alone.
[crowd clamoring]
Excuse me.
I'd like to talk to them.
l... I think I can help.
Who are you?
Samuel Irons, Engineering Specialist.
Are you a rock worshiper, too, Irons?
It may be useful to have
one of their own speaking to them.
Your presence might be
misinterpreted as hostile.
This is me being cordial.
You want to see hostile?
Let the man speak with them.
All right, play the piper
and lead the flock out of here
before someone gets
their nuts stomped on.
Thank you.
Brothers and sisters,
there will be plenty of time
to observe the holy relic
when we return to Earth.
The church must first interpret the markings
if we are to be enlightened by their words.
Interfering with the captain's orders
will not help resolve our current crisis.
Right now we must pray
for our fellow pilgrims
on the surface of the planet
whose lives may be in danger.
Set the example that we Unitologists
are not hysterical fanatics.
We respect the orders of our captain.
See?
They are reasonable people
when not confronted by violence
and threats of arrest.
Oh, perhaps in light of my help...
You'll get your chance
to see it in due time.
I understand.
[snarls]
metal clatters]
[chuckles]
Hey.
What the fuck is going on?
I count 15 sets of footprints,
give or take.
The log says there were 20 corpses
set for chryo-storage.
Maybe they had a miraculous recovery.
Here's a crazy idea.
Don't say it, Dobbs.
Hey, I don't mind shooting
the living dead
as long as I get
to shoot something.
I've got one.
I'm no doctor, but it looks like
something's been chewing on him.
This shit is getting weirder
by the second.
Sounds like a date with Shen.
Fuck you, rookie.
Has it occurred to you jokers that
whatever did this could still be in here?
I'm going to call this in.
Stay sharp.
Security Chief Vincent to bridge.
Come in, over.
This is Captain Matthius.
Give me a sit-rep Vincent.
Dobbs, look out!
Vincent! Vincent!
Ah, get him off!
Give me a hand, God damn it!
Shoot this fuck!
[Alissa]
Hold your fire!
Vincent, report!
Dobbs is dying.
We've got to stop the bleeding.
Damn it, Vincent, what is going on?
I've got a man down.
We're in the morgue, A Deck.
We were attacked by something.
Not sure what.
Shit! Shen, look out!
What the fuck was that?
I don't know.
Fuck this shit.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
Man up, Shen.
You got a job to do.
Dobbs is fucking dead!
Get a hold of yourselves.
Whatever these things are,
they're loose on the ship.
Secure this room
and get ready to move.
Vincent to bridge. Over.
I want a report, Vincent.
Something's going on, sir.
Something alien is attacking us.
- We need to talk.
- Not now.
Captain, whatever was on the planet
has made it aboard ship,
and it's somehow connected to the Marker.
I think the church may have been mistaken.
[steam hissing]
[creature chittering]
[man roaring]
[roaring]
[panting, whimpering]
Sir, I just lost telemetry
on 10 crew members.
Five more just flat lined.
Where are they?
Mess hall, A Deck.
Get me a visual.
- [creatures roaring]
- [men screaming]
Sound the alarm!
Vincent, get your team
to A Deck mess hall on the double.
On our way.
Get full mags in those weapons.
I think we're about to walk
into a world of shit.
Jeez, Shen.
[creatures roars]
Over there.
[creatures munching]
Get ready to fire on my command.
Fire!
- [gun clicking]
- Huh?
Get the fuck off.
Get it away! Get it away!
Get it away!
[screams]
[gun clicking]
Holy shit.
Pendleton.
Who are you?
Samuel Irons, mechanics division.
Thanks for the assist, Irons.
No problem.
These things seem
to handle bullets just fine.
But a couple rips
from this bad boy
and they don't get up.
We've noticed.
Where'd you get that?
There's a store room down the hall.
I busted open a crate.
It was a divine discovery
at a time like this,
don't you think?
Ah, shit.
You another Unitologist?
Shut it.
Ramirez, Shen,
go grab us some weapons.
Bridge, this is Vincent,
come in. Over.
Shit. Com is down.
I think we should consider
abandoning ship.
If these things have spread,
there's no stopping them.
Our job is the safety of the crew.
The way I see it,
we have two options.
Fight or die.
We don't have the luxury of running.
I've lost contact with the bridge.
We're going to head there now.
- [cocks gun]
- Anything gets in our way,
cut first, ask questions later.
Got it?
- Got it.
[beeping]
Sir, systems are failing
all over the ship.
Shipboard communication
is all but down.
Plot a course for Earth.
We're getting the hell out of here.
What?
Lock down any sections of the ship
affected by this disturbance.
I want it contained, do you understand?
We have to get the artifact home.
That is our only mission now.
Captain, listen to me.
We're not in control anymore.
I'm not sure we ever were.
What are you talking about?
The artifact, the mission.
It's a trap. It has to be.
We've brought something aboard
that we didn't understand.
Something alien, and it's trying to kill us.
We cannot bring the artifact to Earth.
Have you lost your mind, Doctor?
The holy artifact must be
delivered to the church
if humanity is to be delivered
into the welcome arms
of the universal awakening!
Keep your voice down.
Don't tell me what to do.
I'm the captain. This is my ship!
You are being irrational.
People are dying.
We are all in danger!
The faithless want to destroy the artifact
because they fear it.
I won't allow it, Kyne.
I will not allow it!
The Marker is making us
paranoid and delusional.
It's the only explanation
for the irrational behavior
that has been plaguing the colony,
the crew, and now the officers.
This is not irrational, Doctor.
This is religious persecution.
And I'm not going to allow you,
or anyone else, to destroy the artifact.
White, have the doctor restrained!
Sir, he's right.
He's speaking heresy.
He's a spy, planted on my ship
to destroy any hope we
have of transcending death.
You need to calm down.
I gave you an order, Mr. White!
Nobody cares if you're a Uni, Cap.
We just want to get out of this alive!
What is that supposed to mean?
Captain, please.
Let me give you a sedative.
Wait a minute.
You... You're all with him.
He's going to poison me, isn't he?
Fuck this, he's lost it!
You'll all be arrested for mutiny.
He's out of his mind, Kyne.
Give him something.
Get your filthy...
Get off of me!
We have to bring the artifact
back to Earth.
The church needs it.
Kyne, you traitor! You're one of us.
You were sent here by the church,
specifically, to retrieve the Marker.
Just like me!
You bastard!
This is a sedative.
Don't fight us.
- It's for your own good.
- Bastard!
[screaming]
Get away from me.
Hold his head.
I'm trying.
My God.
Is he...
The sedative must have
punctured his brain.
You killed him, Doc.
You all saw it.
He killed the captain.
It was an accident.
Arrest the doctor.
[alarm blaring]
Launch sequence
for escape procedure's initiated.
Who is doing this?
I don't know.
Shuttles 1 through 25
have launched.
The shuttles are all empty.
There is only one thing left to do.
Stop the launches!
I'm trying.
Shuttles 26 through 50
have launched.
That's all of them.
All emergency shuttles are gone.
We need another way
up to the bridge.
If there still is a bridge.
There's a utility lift ahead.
We could move up to hydroponics
and cross to the bridge from there.
[pounding on door]
Some time today!
I got it.
Get inside.
Ramirez, slow them down.
- [gun clicking]
- I'm out.
Hansen, come on.
What happened back there?
I don't know what you mean.
You froze up.
Do I need to worry
about you, Hansen?
You falling apart on us, Sarge?
Maybe Irons here can sign you up
with the Unitologists.
They seem pretty at peace
with this bullshit.
I'm okay.
Mind your own fucking business.
[door opens]
Seems quiet enough.
Famous last words.
One way to find out.
Move out.
We're not far.
[whispering]
It's okay, it's okay.
Keep an eye on Hansen.
You can handle it together.
Come on, come on.
- [screaming]
- Shut the fuck up, Hansen.
We don't need
any attention right now.
Fuck you, Vincent!
This is your fault!
You've killed us, you fuck!
We're all dead.
Hansen, shut your fucking mouth.
You've clocked out, man.
Pull it together.
They want our bodies.
And they're going to get them.
- What the...
- [laughing]
[laughing continues]
[creature roars]
Shen!
[creature screeching]
[gun clicking]
Yah!
These guys ain't that tough.
- [screaming]
- [laughing]
[laughing]
Shen!
Sorry, boss.
I wasn't fast enough.
Not your fault.
They turn us on ourselves.
If they don't kill us all,
we will kill ourselves.
Let's go.
The captain's body
is secure in the morgue.
What do we do now?
The captain's dead.
We lost control of the ship.
No escape shuttles.
Communication array's
been incapacitated.
There's no way of contacting home.
It's only a matter of time
until those things reach us.
All for a fool's errand.
[generator powering down]
[pounding on door]
Can they get through?
- Probably.
- [cocks gun]
[pounding continues]
You guys expecting someone else?
You're a sight for sore eyes.
Is that a compliment?
Now I know things are fucked up.
Where's the captain?
He's dead. Kyne killed him.
It could have been an accident.
Well, it doesn't really matter.
[generator powering up]
What's the ship's status?
I was hoping you'd tell us.
Communication has been shit
since the crack.
We're not really sure
what's going on.
Most of my team was lost, I haven't
been able to raise any other squads.
These fuckers are mean,
but they're beatable.
Don't you see? It's over.
Ain't nothing over.
There are still people out there
fighting to survive.
It's our job to help them survive this,
or die trying.
You're an officer for Christ's sake.
- Do your job.
- [alarm blaring]
Oh, what now?
The guidance computers
are losing power.
Can you fix it?
The computer core mainframes
are on D Level.
Whatever's doing it is down there.
Can you get me an image?
Seems like the link is still intact.
- It's Kyne.
- What the hell is he doing?
What happens
if those computers go down?
The engines will stop firing correctly.
The weight of the rock we're hauling,
combined with the planet's gravity,
will cause this ship to fall out of orbit.
We'll basically just crash
back into the planet.
He's trying to scuttle the ship.
We've got to stop him.
That's suicide. You'll never make it.
I told you.
We save these people,
or we die trying.
[creature roaring in distance]
You hear that?
Yeah.
[Woman]
Help. Please.
Please.
[Man]
Help! Help!
There are people
trapped somewhere
Irons, you know where
this vent leads?
This is the main cooling duct
for the personnel barracks.
Okay, we're going to
get these guys out of here.
- What about Kyne?
- We'll get to him.
These people need our help.
Come on.
We need a diversion.
I'll get their attention
and lead them away from the hatch.
You two enter through the cooling vent
and get the survivors
moving towards the bridge.
No. I'll get their attention.
You two get those guys out.
No time to be a hero.
I'm not a hero.
Just a man.
[whistles]
We're here to help. Come on.
[crew chattering]
[woman whimpering]
Come on, we've got to move quickly.
You got a boyfriend?
You want to see him again, right?
Mm-hmm.
Good girl.
Must have faith.
Where's Irons?
Holy creatures,
transform me into your humble servant.
Show me the path to enlightenment
as you alter my flesh
and free my soul.
So that's how they work.
Let's go.
Shit.
Shh.
They haven't seen us yet.
The entrance to the computer core
should be up ahead.
[alarm beeps
We got a problem here.
Hmm. The lock's been
disabled from the inside.
Kyne.
I can bypass it. I need some time.
We don't have time.
Hey Vincent, you know why
I really took this job?
You can tell me later.
My old man always said
I was chicken shit.
He wanted me to join the service.
But I wasn't big on the idea
of getting my ass shot off
in some war zone back home.
Ramirez, they're getting closer.
Give me the all hope is lost
speech another time.
I've always been afraid
of getting into a fight.
- Can you believe that?
- Ramirez, I swear I'll...
I guess it makes sense
as to why I took
a security job, you know?
Badge and a gun
pretty much makes it easy
not to get into a fight.
Will you shut the fuck up
and open that door?
- [keypad beeping]
- It wasn't until all this shit went down
that I realized it ain't
like my old man says.
I'm not a coward.
I just don't like confrontation.
Yeah, that's great. Let's go.
I'm losing it, Alissa.
They're in my head,
and I want to hurt you.
What the...
What are you doing?
The door won't hold them for long.
I'm giving you a head start.
Knock it off, they'll kill you!
It's been an honor
to serve with you, boss.
[Ramirez screaming]
Ramirez.
You stupid bastard.
[Female voice]
Warning, orbital integrity compromised.
Planet fall estimated in three hours.
Get away from
that control panel, Doctor.
Alissa?
I'm doing what has to be done.
The Marker must not return to Earth.
So you're going to kill us all instead.
We have been deceived into believing
that there are space gods.
Unitology is a lie.
That is the mechanism of control,
the lies that brought us here
under false pretenses.
Get out of my way!
You don't understand!
This is an infection designed
to take over our entire race.
It will do anything it can
to spread anything!
No.
An infection can be stopped.
Defiant to the end.
I wouldn't have expected
anything different from you, Alissa.
A good soldier never admits defeat,
even when it's staring you in the face.
Guidance system offline.
Access denied.
What's the access code?
Kyne. Kyne!
Bridge. Are you there bridge?
This is Alissa Vincent.
If you can hear me,
stabilizers are back online,
but we need to move
farther away from the planet.
White? Chic?
Anybody.
Looks like I'm hoofing it.
[creatures snarling in distance]
Great.
What's wrong?
I'm right here!
You can't get close to it, can you?
This is what kept you sealed up
in that God forsaken rock.
[Man]
Vincent. Vincent.
Boss, you got to wake up.
There's one more thing you got to do.
Finish the job.
Save the ship.
How?
My name is Alissa Vincent.
I was... am the Security Chief
on board the Ishimura.
I may be the sole survivor.
We encountered an alien life form,
they have taken over
the bodies of the crew.
The colony was lost.
My team is dead.
The Ishimura is under their control.
It is my belief
that the artifact we discovered
on the surface
is somehow responsible.
It has driven us mad.
Turned us against each other.
If you find this recording,
the Ishimura and the artifact
must be destroyed.
Tell those on Earth
that many people fought
and died bravely.
Don't let us be forgotten.
This is Chief Alissa Vincent
signing off.
[creatures roaring]
Venting sequence initiated.
Warning, venting in 20 seconds.
Here we go.
[silence]
# Twinkle, Twinkle, little star #
# How I wonder what you are #
# Up above the world so high #
# Like a diamond in the sky #
# When the blazing sun is gone #
# When the nothing shines upon #
# Then you show your little light #
[Man on radio]
Ishimura, this is the Kellion.
What is your status? Over.
Ishimura, come in, over.
Is anybody there?
Ishimura, are you reading?
Ishimura,
prepare to be boarded.
# Twinkle, twinkle little star #
# How I wonder what you are #
# Up above the world so high #
# Like a diamond in the sky #
# When the blazing sun is gone #
# When the nothing shines upon #
# Then you show your little light #
# Twinkle, twinkle all the night #
# Then the traveler in the dark #
# Thanks you for your little spark #
# Though I know not what you are #
# Twinkle, twinkle little star #
Subtitles by LeapinLar