LOOK, THAT'S
A BRIGHT ONE!
WHOA!
A FIREBALL.
HEY, LOOK.
THERE'S MARS.
WHERE?
RIGHT OVER THERE.
SEE IT?
IT'S PRETTY CLOSE.
IT'S AT
THE PERIHELION,
ONLY 30 MILLION
MILES FROM EARTH.
ONLY 30 MILLION?
WELL, NO WONDER IT
LOOKS SO CLOSE.
[Laughs]
SMART ASS.
HEY, LOOK.
HERE THEY COME.
MORE THIS YEAR
THAN LAST.
THIS SHOULD BE
THE HEAVIEST SHOWER
THIS YEAR.
HOLY SHIT!
JESUS,
THAT'S BRIGHT.
THAT ONE'S NOT
GONNA VAPORIZE.
IT'S GONNA MAKE IT
THROUGH THE ATMOSPHERE.
WOW.
IT'S A HELL
OF A TAIL, HUH?
IT'S TIME FOR BED.
MOM, YOU
MISSED IT.
IT WAS
INCREDIBLE.
WELL, COME ON,
IT'S BEDTIME.
BUT IT'S JUST
GETTING STARTED.
YEAH, BUT YOU HAVE
SCHOOL TOMORROW.
WELL,
SO DO YOU.
YEAH. THAT'S WHY
WE'RE ALL GOING
TO BED, RIGHT?
UH-UH, NOT ME.
ME, NEITHER.
[Chuckles]
HEY.
YEAH.
[Making spaceship noise]
OH, MY GOD.
WHAT IS THIS?
DOO DOO, YOU'RE DEAD,
50 LASERS IN YOUR HEAD.
ALL RIGHT, AND NOW
IT'S TIME TO GO TO BED.
HOW CAN I BECOME
AN ASTRONAUT
IF I CAN'T
STAY UP LATE?
DID YOU FINISH
YOUR HOMEWORK?
DID YOU
FINISH YOURS?
[Both make squeaking noise]
GOOD NIGHT.
REQUIRED
READING?
HEY, GIVE
ME THAT.
LOOK, DON'T KEEP HIM
UP TOO LATE. OKAY?
THE BASE COMMANDER
CAME TO MY SCHOOL
TODAY.
"MAD DOG" WILSON.
WHAT WAS HE
THERE FOR?
PUBLIC RELATIONS,
I GUESS.
[Laughs]
YOU GUESS?
[Rumbling noise]
HEY, YOU HEAR THAT?
HEAR WHAT?
THUNDER, DAD.
YOU MUST BE
GETTING PRETTY OLD.
WISE GUY, HUH?
OH, HEY,
I ALMOST FORGOT.
A PENNY...
'58 D.
MINT CONDITION.
WOW! THANKS!
I'LL PUT IT
IN YOUR JACKET.
GET UNDER
THE COVERS.
COME ON,
COME ON.
LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, TOO.
GOOD NIGHT.
SWEET DREAMS.
GOOD NIGHT, DAD.
[Loud thunderclap]
[Thunderclap]
[Metallic humming]
UHH!
AAH!
AAHH!
MOM AND DAD!
MOM! DAD!
MOM! DAD! DAD!
QUICK, GET UP!
GET UP!
DAD! DAD! DAD!
WHAT?
COME ON, YOU
GOTTA COME SEE.
A UFO LANDED RIGHT
BEHIND THE HILL
WITH ALL THESE
RED LIGHTS.
COME ON! COME ON!
[Loud thunder]
LOOK AT
THAT LIGHTNING.
RUN! AND IT
WAS REALLY BRIGHT.
I'M SO GLAD YOU
GOT HIM A TELESCOPE.
IT WAS HUGE
AND REALLY BRIGHT,
WITH ALL THESE
STRANGE LIGHTS.
IT LANDED
RIGHT BACK THERE,
BEHIND THE HILL.
I BET IT WAS
BALL LIGHTNING.
NO, DAD. I KNOW WHAT
BALL LIGHTNING IS.
IT WASN'T THAT.
IT WAS SOMETHING ELSE.
A UFO. IT MUST
HAVE BEEN.
COULD IT HAVE BEEN
SOMETHING FROM THE BASE?
NO, IT WASN'T
A PLANE.
I'VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE
THIS BEFORE.
MAYBE IT WAS
A METEORITE.
NO WAY, DAD.
YOU
GO BACK
TO BED
RIGHT NOW.
[Making crashing noise]
I'LL LOOK WHEN
IT'S LIGHT, OK?
OK.
GO BACK TO BED.
ON THE JOURNAL SIDE,
WE HAVE OUR RECEIPTS,
LITTLE SALES AND INVOICES.
INVOICES.
OKAY, ON OUR LEDGER
WE HAVE ACCOUNTS
RECEIVABLE,
PAYMENTS...
HI, MOM.
WHERE'S DAD?
DID YOU
MAKE YOUR BED?
HUH, IT'S MADE.
WHAT ARE
YOU DOING?
IT'S NOT
WHAT YOU THINK.
[Laughs]
DON'T GET CAUGHT.
NO, NOT ME.
GEORGE, WHY AREN'T
YOU DRESSED?
Y-YOU WANT COFFEE?
UH, YEAH.
UH, WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR OTHER SLIPPER, DAD?
WHAT?
I LOST IT.
OH, NOT YOUR NICE
LEATHER ONES.
IT'S KIND OF MUDDY
OUT THERE.
WHAT'S WRONG
WITH YOU,
SWEETHEART?
DO YOU FEEL
ALL RIGHT?
I'LL GET YOU
ANOTHER PAIR
WHEN I'M AT
THE FED MART.
ARE YOU SURE
THERE WASN'T ANYTHING
OVER THE HILL, DAD?
NOTHING.
IT WAS JUST
A BAD DREAM.
THAT'S ALL.
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR NECK?
SIT DOWN, DAVID.
EAT IT WHILE
IT'S HOT,
YOU GUYS.
I'M GOING.
BYE, DARLING.
BUT, MOM--
OH, LOOK, EAT THAT
OR YOU'LL BE LATE.
LET ME WALK YOU
TO THE BUS STOP.
YOU WERE
RIGHT, SON.
THERE IS
SOMETHING...
OVER THE HILL.
WHAT?
COME ON.
I'LL SHOW YOU.
NO, DAD.
[Horn honks]
HI, DAVID.
...SO HAVE YOUR PARENTS
SIGN THEM
FOR THE FIELD TRIP,
AND RETURN THEM TO ME
FIRST THING IN THE MORNING.
[Frog croaks]
YOU KNOW
THIS IS FROG WEEK.
I COLLECTED THESE
FRESH SPECIMENS
THIS MORNING
AT THE MARSH AREA,
AT COPPER HILL.
NOW, WHO CAN TELL ME
WHAT THESE 2
RED SACS ARE?
WHICH ONES,
MRS. McKELTCH?
WILL YOU SHOW
ME ON MINE?
YES.
[Boy]
THIS IS GONNA BE GREAT.
OH, YEAH.
OOH! SICK!
OW!
WANT IT BACK?
[Class]
OOH!
DAVID GARDNER.
THIS MAY BE THE WAY
YOU BEHAVE AT HOME.
BUT HE THREW--
THIS IS NOT THE WAY
YOU BEHAVE IN MY CLASSROOM.
[All laugh]
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
THANK YOU.
LOOK,
HE'S BLEEDING.
HEATHER, YOU SUPERVISE
WHILE I TAKE THIS
UNCONTROLLABLE YOUNG MAN
TO THE SCHOOL NURSE,
AND I HOPE YOU
NEED A TETANUS SHOT.
[All laugh]
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
MMM-HMM.
YEAH.
MISS MAGNUSSON.
DAVID GARDNER
HAS GONE AHEAD
AND CUT HIMSELF.
IT PROBABLY
SERVES HIM RIGHT.
OH, YES.
THANK YOU.
WHAT? I'M SORRY.
I SAID THIS SILLY BOY
HAS CUT HIMSELF.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOT INTO HIM.
HE'S UNCONTROLLABLE.
I'LL TAKE IT
FROM HERE,
MRS. McKLETCH.
McKELTCH!
I THINK
YOU'LL LIVE.
LATER, DAVID.
BYE-BYE.
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
[Door slams]
[Clock ticking]
DAD.
[Static]
[Robotic noises]
[Robot]
DAVID GARDNER,
FEED ME.
MOM,
GOD.
DON'T EVER
DO THAT.
WHERE'S DAD?
I DON'T KNOW.
HE'S PROBABLY
AROUND HERE SOMEWHERE.
NO. I LOOKED
ALL OVER.
HE PROBABLY GOT
A RIDE TO THE BASE
WITH SOME
OF THE GUYS.
NO, I DON'T
THINK SO.
SOMETHING'S
WRONG.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
DAD'S WEIRDED OUT.
OH, HONEY,
YOU KNOW YOUR DAD.
HMM.
DON'T WORRY.
[Clock ticking]
[Sighs]
NOW, I'M WORRIED.
HI, CHIEF.
THANK YOU
FOR COMING.
SURE, MRS. GARDNER.
DO YOU KNOW
OFFICER KENNEY?
MA'AM.
WELL, GEORGE
ISN'T HERE.
HIS CAR IS HERE,
BUT HE'S NOT HERE.
UH, YOU HAVE ANY IDEA
WHERE HE MIGHT BE?
UM, MAYBE HE WENT
BACK OVER THE HILL.
NO, DAVID.
EXCUSE ME?
COPPER HILL.
HE WENT UP THERE
THIS MORNING
TO TAKE A LOOK.
DAVID THOUGHT HE SAW
A PLANE CRASH THERE.
NO, I DIDN'T. I SAW A UFO.
HUGE LIGHTS, EVERYTHING.
DAVID, STOP IT!
I'M SORRY.
I TELL YOU WHAT, WE'LL
GO UP AND HAVE A LOOK.
OH, THANK YOU.
IT'S JUST
BACK THERE.
LET ME SHOW YOU.
I DIDN'T HEAR NOTHING
ABOUT A PLANE CRASH.
ME EITHER.
I HAVEN'T
BEEN UP HERE
SINCE I WAS A KID.
[Bird squawks]
OH, MY GOD.
GEORGE, YOU SCARED
THE HELL OUT OF ME.
THIS IS ED.
ED...
THIS IS MY WIFE.
THIS
IS MY SON.
HOW DO YOU DO?
COULDN'T DO
MUCH BETTER.
AND YOURSELF?
JUST FINE.
GEORGE,
WHERE WERE YOU?
WE CALLED THE POLICE.
I GUESS I'D
BETTER BE GOING.
I HAVE TO PICK UP
ALICE AND HEATHER.
SEE YOU LATER, ED.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
AND WHERE DID
THAT GUY
POP UP FROM?
THAT'S HEATHER'S DAD.
SHE SITS NEXT
TO ME IN CLASS.
I THINK HE'S
WEIRD, DAD.
ED WORKS FOR
THE PHONE COMPANY,
THE SWITCHING DIVISION.
SINCE WHEN DO YOU WORK
FOR THE PHONE COMPANY?
WE HAD
A SPECIAL MEETING.
THE NEW HOOKUP
AT THE BASE.
WELL...
I'M HOME NOW.
I SEE
YOU'RE BACK.
YOUR LITTLE LAD'S GOT
QUITE AN IMAGINATION.
YES.
I KNOW.
THANK YOU
FOR COMING, CHIEF.
LOOKS LIKE WE
FOUND HIM OURSELVES.
EVERYTHING'S
FINE NOW.
THANKS.
OUR PLEASURE.
GOOD-BYE, MA'AM.
GOOD-BYE.
YOU KNOW...
MOM.
IT CERTAINLY IS
BEAUTIFUL UP THERE
OVER THE HILL.
WE'LL TAKE A WALK
AFTER YOU
DO THE DISHES.
AFTER I DO
THE DISHES?
GEORGE, YOU'RE
ACTING VERY STRANGE.
[Door opens]
[Door shuts]
[Door opens and closes]
[Footsteps]
MOM!
NOT HUNGRY, DAVID?
YOU FEEL ALL RIGHT?
I DON'T THINK HE'S
FEELING WELL.
HMM.
I HAVE AN IDEA.
WHY DON'T WE ALL
GO ON A PICNIC
UP AT THE HILL?
MOM, YOU'VE
GOT CLASSES.
WE'LL GO
THIS AFTERNOON.
IT'S WONDERFUL
UP THERE.
YOUR FATHER
SHOWED ME A PLACE
YOU'VE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE.
IS THIS A JOKE?
WE'LL HAVE
A WONDERFUL TIME.
I'LL PACK US
A LUNCH,
HAMBURGERS.
YOU LIKE THAT,
DON'T YOU?
I DON'T WANT TO GO.
HEY,
LITTLE FELLOW,
GIVE YOUR MOM A HUG.
[Horn honks]
LATER.
[Child] HELP ME,
HELP ME, HELP ME.
[Loud clang]
YOU WERE
SHITTING ME
ABOUT THAT SPACESHIP
CRAP, RIGHT?
JUST FORGET IT.
ALL THE GUYS THINK
YOU'RE REALLY SPACED.
THAT'S JUST GREAT.
SURE YOU DON'T
WANT TO PLAY?
NO.
OKAY.
WE GO TONIGHT.
THERE MUST
BE NO MISTAKES,
OR WE'LL BE DESTROYED
AT 12:00 MIDNIGHT.
NO PROBLEM.
GEORGE GARDNER
HAS BEEN DELEGATED.
[Floor creaks]
[Gulps]
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING, DAVID?
HEATHER!
DAVID GARDNER.
STOP!
STOP RIGHT
WHERE YOU ARE!
LINDA! LINDA!
MISS MAGNUSSON!
DAVID,
WHAT'S WRONG?
I'VE HAD IT
WITH YOU!
MRS. McKELTCH,
WHAT IS THE PROBLEM?
I TOLD YOU THIS
BOY WAS TROUBLE.
HE NEEDS TO BE
SEVERELY PUNISHED.
DAVID, WHAT'S
THE MATTER?
HE KNOCKED OVER A
DEFENSELESS LITTLE GIRL,
AND HE'S
A LITTLE SNOOP.
PLEASE,
MRS. McKELTCH,
WHY DON'T WE JUST
TALK WITH EACH OTHER?
GIVE HIM TO ME.
PLEASE LET ME
TALK TO HIM.
DAVID, GO INSIDE
MY OFFICE.
YOU'RE PUSHING
IT, SISTER.
I'LL BE BACK FOR HIM
IN 5 MINUTES.
5 MINUTES.
[Child]
GIVE ME THAT!
IT'S OKAY, DAVID.
JUST RELAX.
RELAX!
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT?
WHAT DON'T
I UNDERSTAND?
YOU KNOW, DAVID,
THAT WHATEVER
YOU TELL ME
STAYS IN THIS ROOM.
I'M A NURSE.
I'M HERE TO HELP.
I MEAN, I'M SUPPOSED
TO SAY THAT, BUT...
IT REALLY
IS TRUE, DAVID.
OKAY, FIRST, CAN I SEE
THE BACK OF YOUR NECK?
OKAY.
[Laughs]
EATING A FROG?
I DON'T KNOW,
DAVID.
THAT'S SOME KIND
OF STORY.
IT'S NOT A STORY.
A UFO LANDS IN THE BACK
OF YOUR HOUSE
AND PUTS SOMETHING IN
YOUR MOM AND DAD'S NECK,
THEN IT GETS
YOUR TEACHER
AND THE POLICE
AND YOUR FRIEND, HEATHER,
AND HER FATHER, ED,
FROM THE TELEPHONE
COMPANY?
HOW DID IT GET
MRS. McKELTCH?
SHE SAID THE FROGS CAME
FROM AROUND COPPER HILL.
SHE MUST HAVE
BEEN THERE.
STAY RIGHT THERE
A MINUTE.
[Typewriter]
WELL?
MRS. McKELTCH,
DAVID SEEMS CONCERNED
ABOUT AN INJURY
TO YOUR...
TO YOUR NECK.
MY NECK?
YES, HE SAYS THAT YOU'RE
WEARING A BANDAGE.
WHY, YES. I HAVE
A BOIL ON MY NECK.
A BOIL?
A BOIL.
I COULD HELP YOU
CLEAR THAT UP
IF YOU'D LET ME
LOOK AT IT.
DON'T TOUCH ME!
I WANT THE BOY.
IF YOU DON'T
GIVE HIM TO ME...
YOU HAVE A LOT
OF NERVE, SISTER.
OH, BOY.
THIS IS GOING TO
BE A MESS.
OKAY.
GO OUT THE WINDOW.
NOW, THIS IS THE KEY
TO MY BACK DOOR.
YOU WAIT FOR ME,
AND I'LL COME AND SEE YOU
WHEN CLASSES LET OUT.
WHERE DO YOU LIVE?
462 SOUTH ROYAL.
OKAY. BYE.
WHERE'S DAVID?
HE'S NOT FEELING
WELL, HEATHER.
WHY DON'T YOU
COME BACK LATER?
[Clamor]
HE'S STILL
WITH THE NURSE.
HIS PARENTS
WILL TAKE HIM.
HE'S NOT WELL.
HE MAY BE
IN DANGER.
WE'LL SUE.
WHAT KIND
OF NURSE
ARE YOU,
ANYWAY?
I'M SORRY,
MR. GARDNER.
I JUST LEFT THE OFFICE
FOR ONE MOMENT.
WHEN I GOT BACK,
HE WAS GONE.
WHAT DID HE
TALK TO YOU ABOUT?
HE WAS UPSET.
HE'S HAVING A PROBLEM
WITH ONE OF THE TEACHERS.
I TOLD YOU.
HE NEEDS
PSYCHIATRIC HELP.
IS THAT
ALL HE SAID?
YES.
IT WAS ONLY
A SMALL PROBLEM
WITH ONE
OF THE TEACHERS.
[Bird squawking]
[Monkey screeching]
[Cat hissing]
[Birds cawing]
[Creature]
OOOH!
OOOOOH!
A, E, I, O, U.
YOU GET ME A PILE,
THEN YOU GET ME WHITTLES,
YOU BRING THEM
BOTH TO ME,
OR I'LL HAVE YOUR HEART
AND LIVER OUT, DAVID GARDNER!
DAVID GARDNER!
I'LL GET YOU.
AAH!
DAVID GARDNER.
I'LL GET YOU.
[Knocking]
I FOUND THEM!
KEEP IT DOWN.
THEY'LL SEE US!
I WAS DOWN THERE!
I FOUND MRS. McKELTCH.
CALM DOWN.
WE'RE IN
BIG, BIG TROUBLE!
I SAW THEM.
THEY'RE BIGGER THAN
ANYTHING I'VE EVER SEEN!
THEY PROBABLY THINK
I'VE KIDNAPPED YOU!
NO! THEY TRIED
TO CATCH ME.
THEY CHASED ME
THROUGH THEIR TUNNELS.
THEY ALMOST KILLED ME.
WHAT? WHO?
THESE THINGS.
THEY'RE HUGE, UGLY, SLIMY,
GIANT MR. POTATO HEADS!
HOLD IT.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
COME ON.
I'LL SHOW YOU.
DAVID!
YOU'RE NOT JUST
A CRAZY CHILD, ARE YOU?
THIS IS WHERE
THE TUNNEL OPENING WAS.
I DON'T SEE
ANYTHING.
IT'S GONE!
BUT I'M POSITIVE
IT WAS HERE.
I'M POSITIVE!
I SWEAR IT!
BUT IT'S NOT,
DAVID.
THEY MOVED IT.
THEY CAN MOVE TUNNELS!
DAVID, IT'S JUST
TOO CRAZY FOR ME.
BUT YOU SAW THE BAND-AIDS
ON THE BACK OF THEIR NECKS.
YES, BUT THEY'RE
JUST BAND-AIDS.
OKAY, WE HAVE TO
GO TO THE HILL.
WE DO?
DOES IT LOOK TO YOU
LIKE ANYTHING'S
LANDED THERE?
DAVID, WE'RE ALREADY
IN TROUBLE, BOTH OF US,
BECAUSE OF MY
HELPING YOU RUN AWAY.
NOW, I CAN
MAKE UP A STORY
THAT'LL SMOOTH
THINGS OVER.
YOUR HOUSE IS
RIGHT DOWN THERE.
LOOK!
[Male voice]
UNLOAD THE MAGNOTOMETER.
COMING UP.
CAN YOU TELL US
WHERE THIS IS, MR. GARDNER?
STRAIGHT UP
THE HILL
AND OVER
INTO THE CANYON.
JOHNSON, YOU
GOT EVERYTHING?
ALL SET.
RIGHT OVER HERE, MAN.
YEAH.
OVER THE HILL,
HE SAID.
ANYTHING?
NOT YET.
DOES GARDNER SEEM
A LITTLE WEIRD TO YOU?
WHAT'S HIS STORY?
I DON'T KNOW.
DOWN HERE.
COME ON.
YOU GOT ANYTHING?
NOT YET.
REAL STRONG
READING HERE.
YEAH, I'M
FOLLOWING YOU.
I'M PICKING
IT UP, TOO.
YEAH. YEAH,
I'M PICKING IT UP.
WHAT?
FOUND SOMETHING.
OH, NO!
NO, NO!
NO!
OH, MY GOD!
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE!
[Horn honks]
OH, NO!
THE FIELD TRIP!
MRS. McKELTCH TOOK
THE WHOLE CLASS
TO THE SANDPIT!
WHAT ARE WE
GOING TO DO NOW?
I'M GOING TO
MAKE A CALL.
WHO ARE YOU CALLING?
THE STATE POLICE.
YOU MISSED
THE FIELD TRIP,
DAVID GARDNER!
LINDA!
STOP!
COME BACK!
I'LL GET YOU FOR THIS,
DAVID GARDNER!
DAMN!
MY GOD, WHAT DID
SHE DO TO YOU?
IS YOUR NECK ALL RIGHT?
YES, IT'S FINE.
DID YOU GET
THE STATE POLICE?
NO, THEIR LINES
WERE BUSY.
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
YES.
DAVID, THERE IS
ONE PLACE WE CAN HIDE
WHILE WE CALL
THE FBI.
DAVID!
I'M COMING,
I'M COMING.
THE PHONE'S DEAD.
IT'S HEATHER'S DAD.
HE MUST BE MESSING
WITH THE LINES.
DAMN.
GET DOWN.
LET'S GET
OUT OF HERE.
WHERE DO WE GO?
COME ON.
I KNOW A PLACE.
YOU CHECK IN THERE.
SHH.
IN HERE.
[Crash]
DAVID!
COME ON,
THIS WAY.
[Clang]
WHAT IN GOD'S NAME
AM I DOING HERE?
BUT YOU SAW
THOSE 2 GUYS--
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
I SAW ANYMORE, DAVID.
I'M SORRY.
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'S OKAY
TO BE AFRAID.
I'M NOT AFRAID.
I'M PETRIFIED.
ME, TOO.
[Door opens]
PLEASE, PLEASE.
SHH. SHH. SHH.
[Rumbling sound]
YOU HEAR SOMETHING?
AAH!
IT'S OKAY.
WE'RE THE POLICE.
WE'RE HERE TO HELP.
AAH!
[Gunshots]
THEY MUST BE TUNNELING
UNDER THE WHOLE TOWN!
I KNOW THEY ARE!
WE'VE GOT TO
STOP THEM.
HOW? THEY'RE
EVERYWHERE!
LET'S JUST GET OUT OF
THIS CRAZY PLACE!
NO. WE HAVE TO FIND
MY MOM AND DAD.
WELL, WE'RE NOT
GOING BACK ALONE.
WE NEED HELP.
GENERAL WILSON.
WHO?
GENERAL WILSON!
[Guard]
ALL RIGHT,
SLOW DOWN.
WHERE'S
YOUR PASS?
[David]
WE HAVE TO SEE
GENERAL WILSON.
IT'S AN EMERGENCY.
BASE COMMANDER'S
OFFICE.
SGT. MAJOR
RINALDI SPEAKING.
YES, SIR,
HE'S HERE.
WHO?
GENERAL.
PROVOST MARSHAL'S
ON THE PHONE, SIR.
YES.
UH-HUH.
SOUNDS LIKE
ANOTHER CRAZY.
WHAT?
GEORGE GARDNER'S SON?
THOSE ARE
THE 2 GUYS
THAT GOT SUCKED
UNDER THE SAND.
OH, MY.
I DON'T LIKE
THE LOOK OF THIS.
OKAY, MISS MAGNUSSON,
DAVID.
NOW, WHAT'S
THIS ALL ABOUT?
DAVID,
HAS THIS GOT ANYTHING
TO DO WITH YOUR FATHER?
I DON'T MEAN
TO BE RUDE,
BUT I HAVEN'T
GOT MUCH TIME.
WHAT HAPPENED WAS--
NO!
LET ME SEE
THE BACK OF
YOUR NECK FIRST.
THE BACK OF MY NECK?
YES.
PLEASE, GENERAL.
HE'S SERIOUS.
I HAD TO
MAKE SURE FIRST.
I GUESS
I'M NEXT.
OKAY, GO ON.
IT'S WIRED.
THE DETONATOR IS SET.
YOU BETTER HURRY,
OR YOU JUST MIGHT
BLOW IT.
I UNDERSTAND HOW
IT MUST SOUND, GENERAL,
BUT I CAN ASSURE YOU
IT'S ABSOLUTELY TRUE.
I DON'T KNOW.
PEOPLE BEING SUCKED
UNDER THE SAND.
A LOT OF ALIENS
RUNNING AROUND LOOSE
UNDERNEATH THE TOWN.
IT'S A LITTLE HARD
TO SWALLOW.
EXCUSE ME, SIR.
NASA DOES CONFIRM
A VISUAL SIGHTING,
A UFO,
2 NIGHTS AGO DURING
THE METEOR SHOWER.
BUT RADAR
REPORTED NO STRIKE.
IN FACT, RADAR REPORTED
NOTHING AT ALL.
GENERAL,
WHAT IF THE SHIP
ABSORBED ENERGY?
IT WOULDN'T
SHOW UP ON RADAR
BECAUSE NO ENERGY
WOULD BOUNCE BACK, RIGHT?
SEARCH TEAMS WERE SENT
OUT TO FIND SIGNS
OF IMPACT OR LANDING.
SIR.
THE MEN WHO CHECKED
THE COPPER HILL AREA
GAVE IT
A CLEAN REPORT.
THAT'S BECAUSE THEY WERE
SUCKED UNDER THE SAND!
THEY'RE ALL PART OF IT!
WALKER, WOULD YOU
PLEASE COME IN HERE?
MA'AM, I'D LIKE YOU
AND THE BOY
TO LEAVE US
FOR A MOMENT.
YES, SIR.
SIR?
[General]
WALKER, I WANT YOU TO
TO ESCORT THESE 2 PEOPLE
TO THE BRIEFING ROOM.
YES, SIR.
PLEASE, FOLLOW ME.
RINALDI, I WANT YOU
TO NOTIFY NASA
THAT WE'RE GOING TO DO
JUST A ROUTINE SECURITY CHECK
ON THEIR MEN.
DON'T WANT TO MAKE
AN ISSUE OUT OF THIS.
YES, SIR.
[Walker]
THE GENERAL'S READY
TO SEE YOU NOW.
SORRY TO
DISTURB YOU, BOYS.
JUST HAVE A COUPLE
OF ROUTINE QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE
COPPER HILL SEARCH.
[Gunshot]
PLACE THESE MEN
UNDER ARREST!
TELL ME WHAT
THE HELL IS GOING ON!
GENERAL--
KEEP BACK!
MY GOD.
WHAT?
THEY'RE DEAD.
JESUS!
STAY CLEAR!
DON'T TOUCH THOSE THINGS!
SEAL THE BASE PERIMETER.
ALERT SECURITY!
GET THOSE NASA HOTSHOTS
BACK OVER HERE RIGHT AWAY.
MAYBE THEY CAN
EXPLAIN THIS.
BRING THE NURSE
AND THE KID BACK,
RIGHT NOW!
LOCK OFF THE LAUNCH AREA.
YES, SIR.
DAVID,
THIS IS DR. STOUT,
SENIOR SCIENTIST ON
THE MILLENNIUM PROJECT.
THIS IS DR. WEINSTEIN.
HOW DO YOU DO,
DAVID?
WE WORK WITH
YOUR FATHER.
HI, DAVID. YOUR DAD'S TALKED
ABOUT YOU A LOT.
THIS IS LINDA MAGNUSSON,
DAVID'S FRIEND.
DOCTOR, I DIDN'T THINK
THE VIKING MISSIONS
FOUND ANY SIGN OF LIFE,
EXCEPT FOR THIS PHOTO
I SAW IN A MAGAZINE
OF THESE THINGS
ON THE SURFACE
THAT LOOKED
LIKE PYRAMIDS.
I SAW THAT
PHOTOGRAPH.
AND WHAT ABOUT
THAT HUGE THING
THAT KIND OF LOOKED
LIKE A MONKEY'S HEAD?
IT WAS IN ALL THE PAPERS.
THAT WAS FAKE, RIGHT?
ON THE CONTRARY,
THERE WERE OTHER PHOTOS
TOO SENSATIONAL
TO BE MADE PUBLIC.
BUT THERE'S NOT ENOUGH WATER
TO SUPPORT LIFE.
ON THE SURFACE.
WE'RE LOOKING BELOW GROUND.
IF THERE IS,
DAVID,
IT MAY NOT WANT
TO BE FOUND.
THE TUNNELS!
IT MAY NOT
WANT US UP THERE.
THERE REALLY IS
NO OTHER CHOICE.
NO, PLEASE, GENERAL WILSON,
ANY FURTHER DELAY,
WE'LL MISS
THE LAUNCH WINDOW.
MARS WON'T WAIT
FOR US, GENERAL.
I UNDERSTAND,
GENTLEMEN.
WE WILL
GO TONIGHT,
BUT WE MUST BE ABLE
TO GUARANTEE SECURITY.
WE STILL DON'T KNOW
WHAT THE HELL
WE'RE DEALING WITH.
WHAT WOULD YOU
SUGGEST THAT WE DO?
I WANT TO PUT
A TEMP FREEZE
ON COUNTDOWN
UNTIL WE'RE
ALL CLEAR.
THEN IT'S
YOUR SHOW.
YOU GOT YOURSELF
A DEAL.
NO, IT'S
A TEMP FREEZE.
WELL, TELL MISSION CONTROL
I'M AUTHORIZING IT.
I KNOW, I'LL BE
RIGHT DOWN.
GOOD, DOCTOR.
GENERAL, WE'RE GOING
DOWN TO CONTROL.
WE'LL BE BACK SOON.
GENERAL, LISTEN!
WE HAVE A BREAK
IN SECURITY, SIR!
THERE'S AN L-O-X TRUCK
ON THE RUNWAY, SIR.
[Alarm rings]
GENERAL, BASE SECURITY
ARRESTED 2 TECHNICIANS
TRYING TO STEAL
EQUIPMENT.
STEAL WHAT?
COPPER WIRE, SIR.
A LOT OF IT WAS LOADED
ONTO A BASE TRUCK.
COPPER WIRE?
SIR, OPERATIONS REPORT
SPACE RADAR
BACK IN SERVICE.
ANYTHING COMING IN?
NEGATIVE, SIR.
THEY'RE ALREADY HERE,
GENTLEMEN.
DAVID, CAN YOU TAKE ME
TO THE SANDPIT?
YEAH, IT'S
RIGHT BEHIND MY HOUSE.
IS ALERT FORCE
STANDING BY?
READY WHEN
YOU ARE, SIR!
CAPT. CURTIS,
TAKE A PLATOON
AND GET DOWN
TO THE SCHOOL.
DON'T WORRY, BOY.
WE ARE NOT OUT
OF OPTIONS YET.
MARINES HAVE NO QUALMS
ABOUT KILLING MARTIANS!
GO, GO, GO, GO!
GO!
MOVE IT!
LET'S GO!
MOVE IT,
MOVE IT, MOVE IT!
GO, GO, GO!
GO, GO!
SECURE THE HOUSE!
FIRE TEAMS 1 AND 2!
CHECK YOUR
FIELD OF ACTION!
PLATOON LEADERS,
CHECK YOUR FIELD OF FIRE!
CELLARS, LET'S GO!
LET'S GO!
[Helicopter]
[Beeping]
HOPE YOU KNOW
WHAT WE'RE DOING.
YES, I DO.
[Growling]
MY GOD.
LET'S GO!
[Growling]
SIR, THAT CIVILIAN HOUSE
IS ALL CLEAR.
GENERAL WILSON!
YES, DAVID!
I HAVE AN IDEA.
IF WE JUST TRY
TO TALK TO THEM--
SIR, WE JUST
RECEIVED CONFIRMATION
OF A TELESYSTEM
BENEATH THE SCHOOL.
CAPT. CURTIS HAS ENTERED
AND HEADED DUE WEST
WITH NO RESISTANCE.
DUE WEST!
THAT'S TOWARDS US!
SIR, THE DEMO
CHARGES ARE IN.
YOU WANT TO SHOW US
WHERE YOU WANT THE WINCHES?
LET'S TAKE
A LOOK!
DAVID! DAVID!
PLEASE STAY PUT.
SGT. LANCE.
SIR!
SEE THAT THOSE MARINES
ARE SECURE!
YES, SIR!
ALL RIGHT, MOVE IT!
LET'S GO!
FIRST SECTOR OF FIRE
IS 11:00, 2:00.
[Helicopter]
GO!
CHECK OUT 11:00.
HE'S GOING TO FALL!
RINALDI!
[Gasps]
UH!
STAY THE HELL
AWAY FROM THERE!
[Rumbling]
OH, RINALDI!
AH!
AH! AH!
AAH!
RINALDI!
READY THOSE WINCHES!
[Beeping]
[Explosion]
HIT THE DECK!
[Loud footsteps]
[Growls]
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
GET DOWN, DAMN IT!
WE CAN'T JUST BLOW AWAY
AN OPPORTUNITY LIKE THIS.
LOOK AT THESE CREATURES.
WE DON'T KNOW
MUCH ABOUT THEM,
OR WHY THEY'RE HERE.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
BOYS.
IT'S--
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
HOW'S HE KNOW
THEY'RE BOYS?
SHUT UP!
I THINK I HAVE SOMETHING
THAT BELONGS TO YOU.
[Growling]
THIS IS YOURS, RIGHT?
THIS IS YOURS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
UH...
I'M MARK WEINSTEIN,
DR. WEINSTEIN.
I'M FROM SETI,
S-E-T-I,
THE SEARCH FOR
EXTRATERRESTRIAL INTELLIGENCE,
AND--
YOU DO
UNDERSTAND ME...
DON'T YOU?
YOU DO.
THEY DO UNDERSTAND ME.
YOU SEE?
[Roaring]
FIRE!
[Squealing]
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S RECON
THESE TUNNELS.
DAVID, IT'LL
BE ALL RIGHT.
DAVID,
WHAT'S WRONG?
NO, DAVID!
DAVID!
I GOT TO FIND
MY MOM AND DAD!
NO! DAVID, STOP!
DAVID!
DAVID,
COME BACK HERE!
OH, NO!
DAVID!
DAD!
JUST COME
BACK HERE!
I HAVE TO FIND
MY MOM AND DAD--
LINDA, STOP!
NO!
AAH!
DAVID!
ALL RIGHT!
LET'S GO IN!
SET THE CHARGES!
LET'S DO IT!
BUT, GENERAL,
THE WOMAN AND THE CHILD!
WE'LL JUST HAVE TO
RISK IT.
THERE'S NO OTHER WAY.
MOVE IT IN!
HUSTLE, HUSTLE, HUSTLE!
GET UP!
[Helicopter]
COME ON!
HURRY UP!
HURRY UP AND
GET OUT OF THERE!
GET THE HELL
OUT OF THERE!
GET THE HELL OUT OF--
START THE WINCHES!
COME ON, MEN,
YOU CAN GET UP!
PULL, PULL, PULL!
[Growls]
COME ON!
YOU CAN DO IT!
GET OUT!
[Marines yelling]
THIS WAY!
KEEP IT UP!
LET'S GO!
WE GOT TO GO DOWN THERE!
RECON! GET READY!
GO!
LINDA.
LINDA!
DON'T LET HIM GET AWAY.
HA HA HA HA!
CHECK INSIDE NOW.
MAN, THIS STUFF
SURE STINKS.
YEAH, IT SMELLS
LIKE SULFUR DIOXIDE.
KEEP MOVING.
WHAT THE HELL
YOU DOING, MAN?
IT'S CUPRIC OXIDE.
THERE'S NO TIME FOR THAT.
LET'S MOVE!
THEY'RE
SMELTING COPPER.
COME ON! MOVE!
BE CAREFUL.
UH!
COME.
WHERE'S LINDA?
LINDA'S VERY BUSY
RIGHT NOW.
LET HER GO!
YOU'RE A LUCKY BOY,
DAVID GARDNER.
NOT EVERYBODY
GETS TO MEET
THE SUPREME
MARTIAL INTELLIGENCE.
CAN I--
CAN I TALK TO YOU?
PLEASE,
DON'T HURT LINDA.
AND IF YOU COULD
GIVE ME MY MOM--
YOU'VE BEEN QUITE
A BIT OF TROUBLE
ALREADY, DAVID GARDNER.
THEY DIDN'T
DO ANY HARM TO YOU,
MY MOM, DAD, LINDA,
ALL THE OTHERS.
THEY'RE GOOD PEOPLE.
THEY WOULD NEVER
HURT YOU--
IT'S TOO LATE.
SHUT UP!
I'M TALKING TO HIM!
PLEASE.
IT'S TOO LATE.
I'LL STAY AFTER SCHOOL
EVERY DAY FOR
THE REST OF MY LIFE
IF YOU WOULD JUST SHUT UP!
HA HA HA HA!
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
YOU CAN'T DO THIS
TO PEOPLE.
YOU CAN'T
CONTROL THEM.
IT'S WRONG!
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
GET AWAY WITH IT--
1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
PLEASE.
CAN'T YOU GIVE ME
MY MOM AND DAD BACK?
AND LINDA AND HEATHER.
I'LL LEAVE MRS. McKELTCH.
[Growling]
IT'S YOUR TURN NOW,
DAVID GARDNER.
NO WAY.
POOR LITTLE GUY.
I'LL FIX YOU!
YOU DICK BRAIN!
UUUH!
YOU BAD BOY!
AAH!
OH!
ALL RIGHT!
LINDA!
HA HA HA HA!
GO BACK!
RINALDI!
STOP.
GENERAL.
OH, CHRIST, NO.
NO, RINALDI.
NO!
GENERAL, STAY BACK!
[Cocks gun]
AHH...
DON'T DO IT,
RINALDI!
AHH...
SHOOT ME.
FIRE!
[Gunfire]
[Gurgling]
CAPT. CURTIS!
LOOK OUT!
[Grunting]
CAPT. CURTIS,
GEN. WILSON,
UP HERE!
DAVID,
ARE YOU OKAY?
THEY'VE GOT LINDA!
THERE'S THIS HUGE MACHINE
THEY USE TO GET EVERYBODY.
IF WE DON'T GET THERE FAST,
THEY'LL GET HER.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, DAVID.
JUST STAY CALM, BOY.
SKIPPER,
MUSTER YOUR TROOPS.
WE'VE GOT TO GET
TO THE SHIP TO SAVE HER!
LOCK AND LOAD.
I WASN'T
TRAINED FOR THIS.
LINDA'S OVER THERE!
CHARGE THEM!
[Gunfire]
DRAGON! DRAGON!
GET OVER, SET!
DAVID, GET OVER HERE!
STAY BY ME, BOY!
STAY BY ME!
[Gunfire]
ARE YOU READY
TO FIRE?
DRAGON, FIRE!
FIRE ON THE BACK FLANK AREA!
CAPTAIN!
LINDA!
MEN, GET THE REST
OF THOSE CHARGES IN.
LET'S GO, GUYS, MOVE IT!
STOP, STOP!
DAVID, STOP!
LINDA,
ARE YOU OKAY?
AH!
DAVID!
WHERE ARE WE?
[Door slams]
THE ENTRANCE!
THE SPACESHIP'S
LEAVING!
DAVID'S OKAY.
BUT WE'VE GOT TO
GET OUT OF HERE RIGHT AWAY!
TAKE HER
INTO THE TUNNELS.
WE'LL MEET
YOU THERE!
MOVE IT!
COME ON!
THE CHARGES
ARE IN, SIR.
JUST GIVE ME A TIME.
I WANT 5 MINUTES
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
SKIPPER,
YOU GOT 5 MINUTES
TO GET
EVERYONE OUT.
COME ON, BOY!
MOVE!
KEEP MOVING, LINDA!
MOVE OUT!
OUT!
CHARGE OUT!
AAH!
DAVID, GET UP!
WE GOT TO
MOVE OUT!
COME ON! BEAT IT!
COME ON!
LET'S GO!
KEEP MOVING!
BASTARDS!
THEY'VE SEALED OFF
THE ENTRANCE.
START DIGGING!
WE CAN'T DIG OUR
WAY OUT OF HERE.
WE CAN'T EVEN BLOW
OUR WAY OUT!
CAPT. CURTIS!
YEAH.
GENERAL WILSON!
WE HAVE ONE
OF THEIR WEAPONS.
I KNOW IT
SOUNDS CRAZY, BUT--
THAT JUST MIGHT
DO THE TRICK,
IF WE CAN JUST
MAKE IT WORK IN TIME.
GENERAL WILSON.
FUEL. IT NEEDS
SOME COPPER.
COPPER IS WHAT THEY USE.
I SAW THEM LOAD IT.
MAYBE A PENNY
WILL DO IT.
DAMN, AND I HAD
A WHOLE BAGFUL.
HASN'T ANYBODY
GOT A PENNY?
YOU DON'T
CARRY CHANGE
INTO COMBAT, SIR.
SIR, A MINUTE
AND 15 SECONDS.
DAD'S!
'58 D, MINT CONDITION.
YOU AIM.
I'LL FIRE.
[Linda]
AAH!
[Wilson]
HELP HER, CURTIS! HELP HER!
KEEP MOVING, MEN.
DAVID!
DAVID, THIS WAY!
I'M COMING!
KEEP MOVING, MEN.
KEEP MOVING.
DAVID!
OVER HERE.
MOM?
DAD?
COME WITH US.
HURRY, DEAR.
THEY'LL LEAVE
WITHOUT US.
NO, NO. PLEASE.
HEY, LITTLE GUY.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE MISSING.
OH, YES, I DO.
COME ON,
LITTLE GUY.
MOM, DAD,
I LOVE YOU.
PLEASE UNDERSTAND,
I CAN'T
COME WITH YOU.
DAVID!
DAVID.
KEEP MOVING.
WHERE'S DAVID?
DAVID!
COME ON!
RUN!
COME ON, DAVID!
NO!
AAH!
MOVE IT! MOVE IT
FOR CHRIST'S SAKE!
NO!
DAVID!
COME ON! MOVE IT!
LINDA, COME ON!
DAVID!
HE'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
GET DOWN THERE!
HANG ON!
COME ON, LINDA,
YOU CAN MAKE IT!
AAAH!
NO!
DAVID!
COME ON, DAVID!
AH!
AAH!
UH!
OH!
[Explosion]
DAVID!
HURRY!
MOM!
MOM! DAD!
HELP!
DAD!
DAVID, WHAT IS IT?
NO, NO!
LEAVE ME ALONE!
DAVID,
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S OKAY.
YOU'RE AWAKE NOW.
HONEY!
HEY, IT'S OKAY.
OH, DAVID.
THEY CHASED ME,
AND THEN THEY GOT YOU AND DAD.
OH, THEY DID?
OH, CALM DOWN,
HONEY.
CALM DOWN.
NOW, WHO CHASED YOU?
DAD, LET ME SEE
THE BACK
OF YOUR NECK.
IT MUST HAVE BEEN
SOME DREAM.
PLEASE, LET ME SEE.
IS IT OKAY?
IT'S OKAY.
WHAT ABOUT ME?
YOU'RE FINE, MOM.
WHEW.
OH, DARLING.
YOU SEE,
THE SPACESHIP LANDED
RIGHT IN BACK
OF THE HILL.
WHAT DID?
AND YOU STARTED
CHASING ME DOWN THE HILL.
THEN EVERYTHING EXPLODED
INTO A GREAT BIG WHITE LIGHT.
THAT IS
REALLY WEIRD, DAVID.
ACTUALLY,
I LIKE THE STUFF
ABOUT THE MARTIANS
COMING TO STEAL
THE COPPER.
BUT IT SEEMED
SO REAL.
COPPER FOR
ENERGY, HUH?
WELL, DAVID.
YOU GOT NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
YOUR PENNY COLLECTION
IS STILL HERE.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT SEEMS TO ME?
IT SEEMS TO ME LIKE
YOUR DREAM WAS FULL
OF ALL SORTS OF THINGS
THAT HAPPENED
TO YOU TODAY, LIKE,
YOUR PENNY COLLECTION.
EVEN "MAD DOG" WILSON
COMING TO YOUR SCHOOL.
BUT I WAS
SO SCARED.
THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE AFRAID OF,
DAVID GARDNER.
MOM!
TOMORROW, WE'LL
TAKE A PICNIC
UP AT THE HILL.
FEEL BETTER NOW,
BIG GUY?
YEAH.
OKAY.
YOU BETTER
GET SOME SLEEP.
YOU'LL BE TIRED
AT SCHOOL TOMORROW.
GOOD NIGHT, SON.
GOOD NIGHT, DAD.
GOOD NIGHT,
SWEETHEART.
UH...MOM?
DO YOU WANT ME
TO LEAVE THIS OPEN?
UM...
NO, THAT'S OKAY.
GOOD NIGHT.
[Thunder]
[Rumbling]
AAAH!
MOM! DAD!
NO!