23.976 English for HI
Hi. How ya doin', sweetie?
Come on in.
I already prepared
everything for you...
just the way you like it.
Geez, it's so hot tonight.
[ Woman ]
Are you ready?
You want me to play dead?
Do you want me to die, honey?
Please. Please,
let me die for you.
# Give the dog a bone
This old man
came rolling home #
# This old man
he played seven #
#He played knickknack
up in heaven #
- # With a knickknack,
patty-whack #
- Why'd you close the windows?
- # Give the dog a bone #
- You know I don't scream.
# This old man
came rolling home #
- # This old man
he played eight #
- What are you doing, honey?
- #He played knickknack
on my gate #
- Is there something wrong?
# With a knickknack
patty-whack
give the dog a bone #
- # This old man
came rolling home #
- [ Zipper Zipping ]
- What's that?
- # This old man ##
[ Grunts ]
Uh, you're--
you're hurting me.
[ Screams ]
Uh, get off!
Oh, God! No! No!
[ Crying ]
[ Shrieking ]
Please, get off me!
- No! No!
- [ Twittering ]
[ Heavy Breathing ]
[ Woman Laughing ]
- Oh,yeah.
- [ Man ] What do you know about
the killer at this point?
We know that it's a male, probably
between the ages--[ Indistinct ]
- Any indication--
- Is there a possibility
there's more than one killer?
- No comment.
- [ Woman Laughing ]
- You sound confident.
- I am.
- Any indication of the killer's race?
- Not definitive, no.
We are in the process
of analyzing skin samples...
taken from underneath
the fingernails of two of the victims.
- Results of those--
- [ Woman Laughing ]
- ...determine the killer's race.
- Inspector? Inspector?
How do you respond to claims
that police aren't working
as hard to find the killers...
because the victims
were prostitutes?
The suggestion that we're not
treating this case with all
the diligence we can muster...
is not only false
but offensive.
We've already spent
1,800 man-hours on this case.
- # Happy birthday to me #
- #Happy birthday to you #
# Happy birthday to you ##
What do you know about
the killer at this point?
I can't tell you all that we know, but
he's male, probably between the ages--
- You got the job. That job?
- Yeah.
-Jesus.
- Whoo-hoo.
That sounds disgusting.
Don't you think? Don't you think
it's just disgusting?
All-All I gotta do...
is sit on my ass all night
and read a book.
[ Laughing ]
- You're drinking too much.
- Martin's already very drunk.
My feeling is one person is responsible
for these crimes.
- And why do you say that?
- That's my business.
Don't you see? That's it.
That's all I gotta do.
- I just gotta sit on my ass.
Sit on my ass.
- [ Man Laughing ]
- Inspector.
Inspector, how do you
respond to claims...
that police aren't working as
hard to find the killers because
the victims were prostit--
The suggestion-- The suggestion
that we're not treating this case...
with all the diligence we can muster
is not only false but offensive.
- Any possibility that
there's more than one--
- ...male.
My feeling is one person's responsible
for these murders.
[ Laughing ]
We can't tell the public
everything we know.
Not definitive. We're in
the process of analyzing skin samples...
taken from underneath
the fingernails of two of the victims.
The results of those tests--
- [ Woman Laughing ]
- Any possibility that there's
more than one killer?
No comment.
[ Laughing ]
[ Overlapping Chattering ]
- Staying over tonight?
- [ Pouring Liquid ]
Do you want me to?
Do you want to?
If you want me to.
Marie, if I've ever done anything
to make you happy, I truly apologize.
In some cases, these markings
could have occurred after death
while the body was being--
Sources inside the police
department have confirmed...
that the victims were sexually assaulted
after the deaths took place.
- Any possibility that there's
more than one killer?
- My feeling is--
It's gotten so hard
to talk her into things.
She's become
less and less...
receptive.
- When will the results
of the tests come in?
- Very soon. Maybe tomorrow.
That guy's
supposed to be amazing.
- We can't tell the public everything.
- Receptive to what?
Were the victims
sexually assaulted?
What do you think
of the killer, Inspector?
I think his time
is running out.
[ Screaming ]
Katherine!
Katherine?
I'm in the bathroom!
- Oh.
- What?
Nothing.
You had strange dreams
last night.
I did?
Mm.
You were breathing
really heavy.
You kept kicking your legs
and moaning.
You sure we weren't
having sex?
Pretty sure, yeah.
Call me and tell me
how it went.
Yeah.
- Good night.
[ Muffled Music,
Static ]
Mr.Johnson?
- Mr.Johnson.
- How did you get in?
The front door was open.
Oh, damn door
never closes.
[ Muttering ]
[ Television ]
[ Man On Television ]
Well, gotta be killed.
Here, Roger.
Here's a hatchet.
[ Man #2 ] Yep, we gotta do it.
No use wasting time.
That's what
we're out here for.
Let's not fool around anymore.
Now take the hatchet
and chop the turkey's head off.
Isn't there
an easier way to do it?
- [ Television Continues ]
- So, this is you?
Oh, yeah, this is me.
Welcome to Mars.
- Sorry?
- They weren't kiddin' ya.
About what?
I'll leave you the coffee machine.
The radio is mine.
- You got a radio?
- Uh, no.
Get yourself a radio.
What did they tell you, exactly?
N-Not a lot.
At this time there's
very few people around,
but at night,
this place is like Mars.
- So, what have you heard?
- Pardon?
What, exactly, did they tell you
about me? Nothing.
- They told me nothing.
- Come on. They told you why I quit.
No, honestly,
not at all.
[ Knocking ]
May we come in a moment?
Turn the key
till you hear the click.
Registers on a piece
of punch tape,
verifying you were here
every hour.
- I see.
- Do you?
Thank God we don't need
to check this room. The key's outside.
Come, have a look.
- No.
- It's all right. Come on.
- You know what's in those tubs?
- No. What?
Smell the formaldehyde.
You can smell it, can't you?
Should never go
in there. Never.
I never have.
Disgusting.
[ Door Opens ]
So, I'll be alone
here at night.
Didn't they tell you?
Well, sometimes, an ambulance
or police comes in,
but apart from that,
it's just you... and them.
The morgue.
I don't know why
they put a key in there.
Ah, the hell with it.
Let's get on with it.
Just keep your eyes
on the key.
Just keep looking at it.
Don't look at them.
Damned idiots. Why in the hell did they
put a key in here?
What are the cords for?
Just a precaution...
in case one of them wakes up.
- If you pull it,
then the alarm goes off.
- Wakes up?
Then you call the duty doctor
from the guard's station.
Just call. He'll be here
in five minutes. Don't worry.
It'll never happen.
It's cold in here,
but you can still smell 'em, can't you?
Yeah.
Make sure the door doesn't close.
No handle on the inside.
- Why would it close?
- Don't forget to turn out the lights.
This is where it happened...
supposedly.
What?
Some years ago, scandal,
terrible scandal.
Night watchman.
Many years ago, he did it.
He did it?
Did it with them.
- Oh, you mean, he--
- The guy had his very own harem.
Well, I never knew anything +++
about it firsthand,
but the rumor was,
they caught him doing it,
and they hushed
the whole thing up.
Who knows?
Lots of weirdos out here.
God.
Oh-oh, hey, I-I'm not a weirdo.
[ Chuckling ]
After you start working here a while,
your breath'll begin to stink.
You can test it by holding your...
hand up to your mouth and breathe.
[ Breathing ]
Am I right?
Oh,Jesus.
God, you're right.
Goes with the territory.
Nothing you can do about it.
These are the staff files.
We're all in here somewhere.
Dead ones, over there.
Staff, over here.
Meaningless.
Here's your duty roster.
Come on at 8:00,
be relieved at 4:00.
Is that the alarm from--
It'll never happen.
Have you got a radio?
- Actually, I'm gonna study.
- Get a radio.
- Like I said, I'll get a radio.
- Good.
Who is that picture of?
I don't know.
It's always been there.
Oh, uh, one more thing.
There's nothing
to be afraid of, but, uh--
I think it'd be
a good thing to have.
And then the radio--
It'd be a good idea
to buy yourself a radio. [ Chuckles ]
Okay.
Okay, you have a choice
of seeing two movies.
One, 90 action-packed minutes
of two heroes...
spending time together, having these
incredible adventures through the summer.
The other movie has 45 minutes of
one hero having incredible adventures...
and the other 45 minutes
is a guy sitting in a desk,
um, reading a book, okay?
Which one do you go see?
Well, who's playing the guy
reading the book?
There is definitely
loss of consortium,
but how about
mental anguish?
- Does anybody remember--
- What happened to us?
What?
- ...a case in which--
- I can't breathe in here.
The fuck we doing here?
- We're getting older.
- No, we're dying.
- Same thing.
- No, no, no, no, no.
[ Professor Continues ]
- You know this movie
that I was talking about?
- Uh-huh.
- Okay, the two heroes start
challenging each other.
- Is that a fact?
Yes, that's right. And the one
who backs down loses.
- Why would they want
to do a thing like that?
- Because they're dying,
and they wanna play before
destiny puts 'em in bed with
the fucking establishment.
- Okay, okay, so what are the stakes?
- Freedom.
- If I lose, I'll marry Marie.
You lose, you marry Katherine.
- What?
- Why?
- Get some fun.
You are totally insane.
No, I'm not.
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Clicking,
Tinkling ]
[ Clears Throat ]
## [ Techno ]
##[ Continues ]
[ Music Stops ]
[ Timer Ticking ]
[ Ringing ]
[ Electrical Current Buzzing ]
Shit.
[ Sighing ]
Shit, the lights.
Oh.
- [ Sighing ]
- [ Woman ] Weren't you afraid?
No. No.
And then I saw these tubs.
I don't know. There was something
in them. I don't know. Spare parts.
- I saw shadows or something.
I don't know.
- [ Groaning ]
Oh, that's really sick.
When you're dead, you're dead.
What difference does it make
what someone does to you?
I just think it's sick,
okay?
I have to go
to the bathroom.
Yeah, I'll go with you.
So, listen.
- Yesterday, I'm down
at Camden near Hyde.
- What are you doing there?
I see this very attractive-looking girl
standing at a bus stop, all right?
But I notice that she's
not getting on any of the buses.
So?
Come on, counselor.
She was a prostitute.
Seventeen years old.
Joyce.
How do you know
all that?
Excuse me, those are my quarters.
I got the next game.
Tough shit.
All right, I'll get
the manager, okay?
I'm gonna go get Satan.
- It's okay, yeah.
- Sure?
Let us just play one game,
me and my friend over here,
and then you guys can play,
all right?
Man, why you look so scared? I'm just
kidding. You all right? You okay?
What'd you do to him?
Shake my hand, bro.
I'll just play one game
and that'll be it, okay? I'm sorry.
[ Shouting ]
[ Screaming ]
Damn, baby.
Do fries come with that shake?
Please, get out of my way.
Maybe we should
do something, huh?
Let me know if you're interested
in nine inches, baby?
I'm very interested
in nine inches.
I'm just not interested
in fucking you three times to get it.
Such nasty things coming
from such a pretty mouth.
- Where you going?
- Ow!
Did I hurt your feelings,
bitch?
Hi.
I hope that our little altercation there
didn't interrupt your beer drinking.
Actually, Martin and I were just
discussing if we should do something.
- Let's go.
- No. We're gonna stay.
No, we're not.
No, no, no, I didn't mean you and me.
I meant me and Martin.
Maybe for just
a little while, huh?
- Fucking assholes.
- I hope you know what you're doing.
- [ Laughs ]
- You know, if this was the movie,
and you were playing
the exciting guy,
you'd go over
and show those guys up.
-James.James.
- Excuse me.
James.
Four. QuadrupleJack,
please.
- What are you doing?
- I'm getting ready.
- For what?
- You challenged me.
I take it back.
What, are we in grade school?
You can't take it back.
James, don't--
Excuse me?
Hi. I-I-I wanted
to thank you.
Yeah, what in the fuck
is you talkin' about, fool?
I wanted to thank you. You realize how
long we've been looking for you two?
You're not telling me I'm the first
person to approach you about this.
No, I'm totally serious.
You guys are gonna be on talk
shows from now until forever.
- Talk shows?
- Oprah, Phil, Sally. You name it.
- You like Ricki Lake?
- What the fuck are you
talking about, man?
Listen, when I say we've been lookin'
for two guys like you, I mean it.
No one's approached you
about this? Not one soul?
No, nobody's approached me.
That's unbelievable.
Un-fucking-believable.
Now, listen. When you guys go
on these talk shows--
there's gonna be a lot of them--
you're gonna be
on the road for weeks, so--
You know, these guys are gonna ask the
same opening questions over and over.
Maybe we should
run through it now.
You know,just so you're prepared.
What do you say?
[ Sighs ]
Huh?
Okay.
Yeah? All right? Great. Okay, now, it's a
multipart question, so answer carefully.
- Okay? All right?
- Yeah.
Now, we know for certain...
that your parents communicated
through a series of clicks and grunts.
Now, what we wanna know is
how and when did you acquire
the facility of speech, huh?
[ Chuckles ]
All right.
Were you the only one in your group
to exhibit this facility, huh?
And when did the majority
of your body fur fall out?
I tell you what.
Answer the third part first.
Sure.
Come on. Come on back.
This place is cool, man? Where you going?
- Nonverbal communication.
- You motherfucker!
- Let's do it. Come here!
- You can't be domesticated.
Whoo! God!
Did you see their faces?
That was great! That was great!
"When did the majority of your
body fur fall out?"
You see 'em? Huh?
- Fuck!
- You all right?
- Goddamn it.
- What, are you hurt?
Let's get out of here.
You know,
I fucked her.
Who?
The hooker,Joyce.
I fucked her.
You f-- You fucked
a prostitute?
Jesus, what was it like?
It was fascinating.
She did everything I asked.
Everything.
I'd say, "Stand over there,"
and she'd say, "Yes, Martin."
- I'd say, "Lay down, "
and she'd say, "Yes, Martin. "
- What? She'd say what?
- I told her I was you.
- You said you were me. Why?
How the hell should she know
who the fuck you are, man?
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, yeah.
Back there at the bar,
you were excited by that, right?
- It was a rush. You felt good.
You felt alive, didn't you?
- Yeah, sure.
Yeah, well, see,
I didn't feel anything. Nothing.
Ayear ago,
I would've felt like you.
I would've felt hyped up,
flushed.
But it's, like,
my tolerance is increasing,
and I can't get that feeling anymore,
Martin, and I have to get that feeling.
I just don't get that feeling,
and I need it.
I have to too.
Do you?
Hey, challenge me.
- Okay, do it with Joyce. Do it.
- What?
- Yeah, yeah. [ Chuckling ]
- Come on.
Come on, what do you think, this is
just for fun? We invite her out, okay?
- Katherine.
- Katherine will never know.
Come on.
Find an excuse, okay? Friend?
Buddy?
Okay.
You told her you were me.
Fuck.
[ Siren Wailing ]
Why'd you have to rehearse
in the morning? I thought
all artists were night people.
[ Katherine ]
Alan likes morning rehearsals.
- Yeah, but that guy's a moron.
- Well, he speaks highly of you.
Like I said,
the guy's a genius.
- Come on. You know I can't be alone.
- You can.
Ooh, you got bad breath.
Call me tonight.
You'll be asleep.
Wake me.
Ooh.
#I've got the house #
#All to myself #
#I've got the world
all to myself #
# Out of my body #
# Out of my mind #
#I've got the house #
#All to myself #
##[ Continues, Faint ]
#Playin'inside my head #
Shit.
[ Man Clearing Throat ]
Did I scare you?
No.
[ Clears Throat ]
I'm sorry.
Inspector Cray.
Martin Bells.
- You new here?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Law school?
- Yeah, yeah. Last semester, I hope.
Hmm.
[ Martin ] That's fascinating
for some reason.
It has something to it.
He's dead,
and he's going to die.
[ Inspector ] I think his name
was Louis Paine,
if I'm not mistaken.
Sitting on Death Row,
waiting.
[ Timer Ringing ]
We could really use one
right now.
- A Death Row?
- No, a murderer.
Wait a minute.
There's been another?
They're bringing her
in now.
- Have you been in there?
- No.
- You should have a look.
- Nah.
No, no, no, you should.
Otherwise you'll just be haunted
here working at night.
Nothing cures a fantasy like
a quick dose of reality.
You think so?
Go on.
Okay.
Are you all right?
That was just feet.
Just feet.
Yeah.
I've been meaning to ask
what they do with them.
By the way,
I saw you on TV.
- Yeah? How was I? [ Chuckling ]
- [ Chuckling ]
- Are you on to him?
- We're getting closer.
[ Woman Laughing ]
How do you know
it's just the one guy?
- Can I trust you?
- Well, yeah, absolutely.
- Can I trust you with a bit
of privileged information?
- Oh, yeah.
- He has a signature.
- Signature?
He takes their eyes.
Good evening, guys.
This one
just quit smoking.
Deputy Inspector Bill Davies,
this is the new night watchman--
What's your name again, son?
- Martin Bells.
Deputy Inspector Bill Davies.
Bill, Bells.
Bells, Bill.
[ Heavy Breathing ]
Most people, when they see
something like this,
their immediate reaction is to ask:
How could somebody do this and why?
Even when we catch the killer,
they wanna know the how and why.
In movies or television, the killer
always explains the how or why.
He always has some reason,
however crazy.
A mad gleam in his eye.
I've interrogated murderers
like this one before.
Let me tell you. They are well
beyond the need to justify what they do.
They just do it.
Explanations are just a fiction
to make us feel safe.
Because if it can't be explained, then
it's just meaningless chaos.
It could touch any one of us
at any moment.
Which is exactly what it is.
- I would've been sick.
- I have a pretty high tolerance
for that sort of thing.
I still think it's weird.
- Why?
- You don't think it's weird?
Well, why shouldn't I see
the body? I work there.
How do you know
it's the same guy?
Ah, some of us just know.
What is that
supposed to mean?
- Nothing. Look, I'm sworn to secrecy.
- Come on.
I can't tell you.
Wait a minute.
You can't tell me.
Katherine, you wouldn't wanna know.
Believe me.
Jerk.
[ Alarm Bell Ringing ]
- [ Woman ] Duty nurse.
- This is night watchman from 03,
and the alarm just went off.
- The alarm?
- The-The alarm from the morgue
just went off.
- You said-- What was that?
- The alarm from the morgue,
it's going off.
- Oh, well, um--
- Well?
Well, you should just go
and check it then.
The doctor on call, he'll be there
in about 30 minutes.
What!
But-But what-what if it--
You're just gonna have to go down
and check it out. Find the defect.
Hey, what if
it's not a defect?
Don't worry.
It is.
[ Gasping ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Screaming ]
Are you crazy? Bastard, you're insane!
What the hell are you doing?
- Easy. Take it easy.
- Who the hell do you think you are?
- I couldn't help it.
-Jeez, I almost had a heart attack.
- But you didn't.
- Christ, I almost shit myself.
- [ Bat Taps Floor ]
- How the hell did you get in here?
- ## [ Radio: Opera ]
- The front door doesn't close right,
and you got your nose
buried in that book.
I mean, I stood and watched you
for five minutes.
You scared ten years
off my life.
You made me call the duty doctor.
Now they're gonna think I've gone crazy.
##[ Continues ]
You know, it's a really
beautiful place you got here.
- It's cozy.
- [ Laughing ]
Oh, I talked toJoyce.
Remember, your name is James.James.
I don't think I can handle
anymore of your ideas.
All you have to do
is show up. I promise.
Mm.
Dress nice.
Like I'm gonna tell Katherine I'm
getting dressed nice to study with you.
[ Sighs ] Tell her that we're
studying opera.
Figaro. Figaro.
#Figaro #
[ Mumbling ]
# Figaro, figaro
Figaro, figaro
Figaro, figaro ##
You're a fucking nutcase!
That's Mr. Fucking Nutcase
to you, pal!
Uh, where's the fire?
Um--
It was my fucking
alarm clock.
I'm sorry.
What a shock.
Can I offer you
something?
Excuse me?
Have you ever spent any time
with the "Zine" family?
What?
Thorazine, Stelazine,
Compazine.
[ Chuckling ]
No.
They're really very nice.
They will make you sing hymns while
you watch a baby fall under a train.
No, thank you.
I'm fine. Thanks.
Listen, we don't have time
for screwed-up kids.
Just don't freak out again.
Okay?
Okay.
Those'll kill ya.
Thank you.
[ Martin ]
She's probably not coming.
Impatience is an early indicator
of boringness.
What? " Boringness"?
That's not a word.
Here we go.
Joyce.
Friend to the working man.
Good luck,James.
- Oh, my God. Oh,Jesus.
- Oh, for God sakes.
- [ Man ] What are you staring at?
- Hello.
- Hi. I'm Joyce.
- I'm James.
Good evening. Allow me
to congratulate you both.
- Congratulate us?
- On your engagement.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, why, thank you.
- Would you care to order now?
- Sure.
[ Stammering ]
I didn't get a chance to--
I-I think we'll have
the cod fish, please.
- Very good.
- I don't like fish.
Oh, of course.
Well, the filet mignon.
And how would you
like those?
- Medium. Rare.
- Rare.
Of course.
Thank you.
Hey, hey, hey.
- So, uh, where do you come from?
- Home.
Oh, no, I meant--
Oh, San Diego.
Wow, San Diego.
- How did you get here?
- Walked.
No, I-I meant
from San Diego.
I drove.
Oh.
Do you like it here?
It's okay.
I was on my way
to Nepal.
Nepal. Wow.
What's in Nepal?
Monks.
Oh, right.
Hey, what are you doing?
- Martin said I had to do it right away.
- M--
Martin said--
[ Moaning ]
Ah.
You called?
No. No, actually,
we're fine.
[ Moaning ]
[ Continues Moaning ]
I'm sorry, sir, but I'm gonna
have to ask you to leave.
What?
Excuse me. Uh, can I have a word,
please? [ Chuckles ]
Just for a second.
Thanks.
You went too far this time,
Martin.
What do I--
What do I owe you?
- Fifty.
- [ Laughing ]
Cheers.
- Oh, I don't drink. It makes me sick.
- Really?
Um, how much...
to drink a glass of whiskey?
Twenty.
Twenty bucks? Yeah?
Okay.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
I didn't say how big it would be.
Bottoms up.
I guess you hear that phrase
quite a bit, huh?
Mm-mm,Joyce,
you're dribbling.
Joyce, that wasn't
part of the deal.
All right.
I'll give you $100-- $100--
if you can tell me
that you will love me...
- I love you.
- and make me believe it.
- No, come on.
It was too fast.
Didn't ring true.
I didn't believe it.
Did you believe that?
- I don't--
- Okay, I'll tell you what.
I'll add another 50.
That's all my allowance now.
It's all yours
if you can make it sound real.
- I love you.
- No. Come on.
- No, make me believe it.
- I--
- Make it sound fucking real.
I love you.
No.
I didn't believe it.
Sorry.
How ya feelin',Joyce?
Okay.
- Why the hell do you take all this shit?
- What's it to you?
- Tell us about your customers.
- Why?
Tell us about your clients, the weird
ones. Tell us what they do.
- Why?
- Curiosity.
Answer the fucking question.
One dresses up like a baby
and makes me change his d--
That's not weird enough.
- One guy makes me pee--
- Weirder.
- One guy makes me pretend I'm dead.
- Yes!
He covers me in a sheet, and
he puts a tag on my toe, and then he--
Then he what?
- Then he--
- Then he what?
Tell us what's wrong,
Joyce.
My friend, Leanne,
brought the psycho home.
- And?
- And she--
They, uh--
- I'd rather not.
- Tell us.
No. Please,
can I go now?
Please, tell us.
They made me
identify her body.
He took her eyes.
Do you think that there's
a relation between the guy--
the guy that makes you pretend--
What the hell do you care?
Can I go now?
You think you've met him?
[ Grabs Money ]
[ Groans ]
How was
your evening?
Oh, okay, you know.
- TypicalJames.
- Hmm.
I don't know
how Marie takes it.
[ Chuckles ]
Me neither.
Who's Joyce?
-Joyce?
- Mm-hmm.
I don't know.
Why?
She called late,
asking for you.
For me?
Mm, yes.
I don't know.
I don't know
who that could be.
Did she say
what it was about?
No.
Sh-She leave a number?
Hmm.
I don't know.
##[ Rock Music Playing ]
[ Screaming ]
##[ Continues ]
Here's Johnny!
Boo!
And the question still remains, ladies
and gentlemen of the jury,
what did
the defendant know?
When did he know it?
And if he's
so fucking smart--
[ Breathing Heavy ]
- [James On Telephone ] Hello.
- Have you been here tonight?
- What? Speak up. I can't hear you.
Come to think of it,
I'm not even home.
Leave a message.
[ Laughs ]
[ Clicking,
Tinkling ]
The boy
who cried zombie.
Just you wait.
She's down there.
Oh!
Okay, which one
was it?
Think you can
still remember?
- It was the prostitute.
- Ah.
Prostitute.
Well, good morning,
Miss Singer.
This young man claims
that you've been up and about.
Well, isn't that strange?
She appears to be as dead
as a fucking doornail.
But I saw her there.
I saw her like I'm seeing you.
Hello?
Miss Singer? Hello!
Is this thing on?
[ Giggles ]
Still dead.
Listen. I saw her--
- What's going on?
- I'm sorry, Inspector,
but I thought
I might need some backup.
Did you have a problem?
- Yeah. I saw this g--
- His problem is,
he's under-medicated.
I saw her
in the hallway.
I've gotten rid of people
for much less.
- This is like one of those
movies on the USA Network.
- What do you mean?
You know, the hero
sees something weird...
- and then no one will believe him.
- [ Chuckles ]
You know,
sometimes, Martin,
when you get overly
tired, the lines get a little blurry.
No, but I saw it.
Mmm.
[ Martin ] And now that guy
thinks I'm crazy.
No, no, no.
Forget the doctor.
I think he has too much access to
the medicines he so freely prescribes.
You saw what you saw.
Here, Martin.
You can always
reach me here.
Oh, okay.
Try and take it easy.
- [ Thunder Rumbling ]
- Don't go back.
[ Martin ]
We need the money.
We can borrow
from my mother.
We don't want
your family's money.
By the time
my father was 22,
he was married
to a woman he didn't love,
and he was having an affair
with the woman he did.
[ Thunder Continues,
Rain Falling ]
And what does that
mean to you?
That he was afraid.
- Of what?
- Of life.
[ Thunder, Rain
Continue ]
- Yes.
- Will you marry me?
Yes.
Shit, I hate
that place.
[Joyce ]
Are you Katherine,
Martin's--
Martin's girlfriend?
[ Sniffling ]
I can't--
I know I'm supposed
to memorize it,
but I-I forget.
Maybe, uh,
maybe you could
write it down for me.
You-You're not gonna
give it to me until I remember.
I know.
If-If you write it down,
I'll remember. I swear.
Are you Katherine?
- Yes?
- Martin's girlfriend?
Yes.
Please make him
stop it.
Won't you please
make him stop?
[ Door Opens ]
- Hello?
- [ Katherine ] Hello.
- How was it?
- We finished early.
Ow! What was that?
Let's get one thing straight,
you dumb shit. I'm not Marie!
And if you want to treat someone the way
thatJames treats Marie,
you'll have to find
somebody else.
- You understand what I'm saying?
- What are you talking about?
- I met your little slave girl today.
- Who?
Joyce.
Yeah. Go ahead.
Tell me she's some little lying junkie
whore who makes up stories. Go on!
Look, I--
I--
Do you want me
to play dead?
- Is that what you want?
- What?
- You screwed her, didn't you?
- No!
No, I mean, it was
just a game, I swear!
Now, what did
she say?
Do you want me
to play dead?
Is that what
turns you on?
What?
Is that how you like it?
Wh-- No, Katherine.
Katherine, what--
- What are--
- Did you enjoy it?
Shit.
What?
Did you enjoy it?
Excuse me?
- Hello, Martin.
- Hi.
How are you?
I don't know.
Tell me, Martin.
You did your rounds last night?
- Yeah, of course. Why?
- Uh-huh.
Come with me.
[ Camera Clicking ]
What can you tell me
about that?
I don't know.
- Paul.
- I see a dead girl,
turned over
on her stomach...
with her legs
spread apart,
as though she's been
sexually assaulted.
[ Clears Throat ]
Now, the doctor tells me...
you're the only one
that's been in here.
[ Man ]
Cray?
You might want
to have a look at this.
[ Camera Clicking ]
Martin, what can you tell me
about the drops of semen over there?
[ Martin ] I think someone's
trying to frame me.
[ Inspector ]
I'm just as confused as you are.
But the murder victim
has played tricks twice now,
and you've been
involved both times.
- Do you have any enemies?
- Not that I know of.
Any debts? Old grudges?
Angry drug dealers? Anything?
Wait a minute.
There was someone.
This hooker,Joyce.
I-I went with her.
I see.
The girl down there
was her friend.
She had to identify the body.
The police must know her.
- Young girl. Redhead, skinny.
- Yeah, right.
Yeah. I remember
interviewing her.
What happened?
Well, first she called
my house one night.
Then she went and saw
my girlfriend...
and said I'd done
a bunch of stuff that I never did.
Why would she want
to do that?
- How'd you meet her?
- It was through a friend.
It was just a joke.
Friend? Which friend?
Just some guy--James.
You know, it was supposed to be a joke.
So many things are.
What's your friend's full name?
[ Sighs ]
James Christian Galman.
- Martin.
- Yeah?
If all this
is what I think it is,
there's someone very dangerous
standing right behind you in the dark,
breathing down your neck.
And maybe you've unwittingly
become his link toJoyce.
What do you mean,
"his link"?
I think the murderer
wants the murder to be exposed.
- I still don't get it.
- Well, I think he wants to stop.
I think he's tired
of killing.
Wants to be free.
But he won't be free
as long as we're looking for him.
And how long will we
continue looking for him?
Till we catch the killer.
So what's the solution
to his dilemma?
Get somebody else
caught in his place.
He chooses a new victim,
and then he makes someone else
look guilty when he kills her.
He's already gained
Joyce's trust.
Now all he needs to do
is find her "killer."
Her killer?
No, this is too absurd.
Why does Joyce
suddenly call you?
Why does she go see
your girlfriend?
Think about all that's
been happening in here.
Think about that doctor that looks
at you without doubt in his mind.
Even Deputy Inspector Bill
is starting to suspect you.
No, you can't be serious.
Don't worry, Martin.
I know it's not you.
It has to be someone
that knows his way around here.
Okay? So, what about
the old night watchman?
I'll look into it.
What about the semen
down in the morgue?
What about it?
Yes, well, the lab
is gonna analyze it,
but in the meantime,
can we have a sample from you?
[ Sobbing ]
Martin, it's Joyce.
I need to see you.
It's im-important.
There are some things
I need to tell you...
that I couldn't tell you
the other night.
I need to see you
in person,
tonight at 8:00.
Excuse me?
My address is
92 48 Second Street,
- number 3 22.
- Excuse me!
Fuck this!
He wasn't at home.
It was the answering machine.
Hey, buddy.
How ya doin'?
What's the matter
with you?
What are you doing
with Joyce?
- What?
- The police can't find the murderer.
Someone raped
one of the victims.
- Someone threatenedJoyce.
- Shit.
- So, they know who it is?
- They have a suspect.
- Who is it?
- The wrong guy, I guess.
I guess they got
the wrong guy.
Ya wanna narrow that down just
a little bit? Which wrong guy is it?
It's me.
You?
They think it's you?
[ Laughing ]
Oh, boy!
Boy, they got
the wrong guy.
I'll just ask you
this once, okay?
And then I'll just walk away and then
I'll just forget all about it, okay?
Okay.
Is it you?
[ Laughing ]
Martin!
Oh, come on.
[ Man Speaking On Radio,
Indistinct ]
[ Man On Radio
Continues ]
[ Man ]
#This old man He played one #
#He played knickknack
on my thumb #
# With a knickknack patty-whack
Give the dog a bone #
# This old man
came rolling home #
He played two #
#He played knickknack
on my shoe #
- ##[ Continues ]
- Do you know--
##
Do you know where
the Himalayas are?
##
I have always wanted
to go to the Himalayas.
#He played knickknack #
# This old man
came rolling home #
He played four #
#He played knickknack
on my door #
# With a knickknack patty-whack
Give the dog a bone #
# This old man
came rolling home #
He played five #
#He played knickknack #
- ##[ Continues ]
- [ Baby Crying ]
- #He played six #
- I've always wanted to go there.
##
I've always wanted
to go to the Himalayas.
# Give the dog a bone #
- # This old man
came rolling home #
- [ Gasps ]
- # This old man
He played seven #
- [ Gasps ]
- #He played knickknack
up in heaven #
- [ Gasps ]
# With a knickknack patty-whack
Give the dog a bone #
# This old man
came rolling home #
##[ Continues ]
# This old man
came rolling home #
- # This old man #
- Hello?
#He played five #
#He played knickknack
on my hide #
# With a knickknack patty-whack
Give the dog a bone #
- # This old man
came rolling home #
- Hello?
# This old man
he played six #
#He played knickknack
on my sticks #
# With a knickknack patty-whack
Give the dog a bone #
# This old man
came rolling home #
- # This old man
He played seven #
- Hello?
#He played knickknack
up in heaven #
# With a knickknack patty-whack
Give the dog a bone #
# This old man
came rolling home #
He played eight #
#He played knickknack
on my plate #
# With a knickknack patty-whack
Give the dog a bone #
# This old man
came rolling home #
He played nine #
#He played knickknack
on my vine #
# With a knick #
Spine?
# Give the dog a bone #
# This old man
came rolling home ##
[Joyce On Answering Machine ]
Martin, it's Joyce. I need to see you.
It's im-important.
There are some things
I need to tell you...
that I couldn't tell you
the other night.
I need to see you in person,
tonight at 8:00.
My address is
92 48 Second Street,
number 3 22.
[ Weeping ]
Damn! What if you
wouldn't have gotten out of there?
Can you imagine
what he would--
Katherine, we have
to call the police.
We can't let her
just lie there.
They found her.
[ Man On TV] A 17-year-old girl
was found dead this evening,
the third in as many weeks,
and the sixth in the last two months.
We have all the evidence we need.
We'll have closure very soon.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
[ Martin ] Yeah, I'd like to speak
to the duty doctor.
[ Woman ]
One moment.
- [ Doctor] Hello?
- Yeah, hello.
This is Martin Bells. You know,
the screwed-up kid from Forensics.
-Joyce asked me to say hello.
- Who?
Joyce--your playmate.
Listen. I have personally asked
for your removal.
- Go home.
- Well, I thought you'd want me to stay.
Go and see
a psychiatrist.
Do you think
I'm a psychopath?
Well, you wouldn't be the first
night watchman who was.
[ Dial Tone ]
"The first."
Deputy Inspector
Bill Davies, Homicide.
- I'd like to speak
to Martin Bells, please.
- Yeah, well, Martin's not here.
- I'm afraid we don't know where he is.
- [ Phone Rings ]
- Hello.
- Yeah, hi. It's me.
Martin,Joyce
has been murdered.
The cops are here
looking for you right now.
- I'm going over there.
- I'm afraid that's too dangerous.
- He didn't do it!
- Keep your ears open.
I'm gonna try something.
[ Katherine ]
Martin is not a murderer.
[ Davies ]
We don't make up the evidence.
He's a suspect because weird things
happened at work?
[ Sighs ]
[ Davies ] Listen. She exposed
him herself, okay?
- She wrote his name.
- What did she write?
- His name.
- Yeah, but what name?
- Martin.
- No. No. We changed the names.
Joyce thought he was James, so if it
was him, she would have written "James. "
- Well, that makes you our
prime suspect then, doesn't it?
- [ Marie ] This is ridiculous.
No.
There was no name.
[ Davies ]
What?
- Katherine was there.
- You were there?
- When?
- There was a lot of blood.
But there was
no name.
And the murderer...
was still there.
What?
Katherine.
[ Line Ringing ]
[ Man ]
Hello.
Yeah, hello?
This is Martin Bells--
The new-- n-new--
new night watchman.
You showed me
around here.
You know what
time it is?
Inspector Cray, please.
Well, where'd he go?
The hospital?
Alone?
You remember the story you told
me about the night watchman
who did it with-- You know.
- W-What year was it?
- The guy with the corpses?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Before I started, in the late '60s.
- Do you remember his name?
- No.
And what happened to him?
- Nothin'.
- What?
The embarrassment.
The hospital couldn't press charges.
No. I guess he's out there
somewhere.
Where is she?
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
Cray.
Hello?
Martin, it's
Inspector Cray.
We have
a situation here.
- Yeah?
-Joyce has been murdered.
Oh.
We have to talk.
Well, I'll, uh--
I'll come down to the station.
We really have to get
to the bottom of this.
I think it might be better
if I pick you up.
Martin?
- Are you still there?
- I-I'd prefer to come down to the station.
[ Cray ]
I'll come and get you.
Tell me something, Martin. Are you still
gonna maintain your innocence?
- Yeah.
- Who else could it be, Martin?
The killing has to stop, Martin.
Don't you want it to stop?
Maybe I could talk
to Deputy Inspector Bill.
Why wouldn't you
want to talk to me?
You're under arrest,
Martin.
Would you please
put this on your desk?
[ Gasps ]
We have all the time
in the world...
- to wait for your confession, Martin.
- [ Sobbing ]
All the time
in the world.
I want you to do me
a favor, Martin.
- [ Whimpering ]
- Hit me.
- What?
- Come on, come on.
Hit me.
How much more
can you take?
You know what they're going to do
to you, Martin?
They're going
to snuff you out, like a bug...
hitting a windshield.
You're going
to die anyway, Martin.
Don't you know
that you're going to die?
Now, come on, Martin.
You've got to do something.
Protect yourself.
Save yourself.
Martin, this is
your last chance.
Do something!
Or I'll take your girlfriend's eyes.
Martin?
Martin!
He's gone mad! Get in the hall!
Get in the hall!
No!
No! Katherine!
I shouldn't be
telling you this,
but she wrote his name
before she died.
I know. Deputy Inspector Bill
told me.
Deputy Inspector Bill
told you?
That's highly unorthodox.
Ahhh!
I'm very glad
you told me this.
This changes everything.
All right, let's go through this
one more time.
Why didn't you call
from Joyce's apartment?
'Cause the murderer
was still there.
The murderer
was still there?
She was already dead.
She was already dead?
- She hadn't written anything, so--
- Yes?
Someone else
must have written it.
Trying to frame
Martin, right?
Trying to frame Martin?
Yes.
Where are we?
Interesting theory.
What do we do now?
## [ Whistling
"This Old Man" ]
## [ Continues Whistling ]
- [ Katherine Screaming ]
- Katherine!
Katherine!
- [ Katherine Screams ]
- Katherine!
- [ Screaming ]
Katherine!
Martin, I'm waiting.
[ Bat Clatters To Floor ]
[James ]
Martin!
- Martin!
[ Indistinct Radio Chatter ]
[ Pounding ]
Hey, hey, I was worried
about you.
- He knocked me out and escaped.
- Something's wrong.
Nothing's wrong.
Who's this?
This is James.
- Where's Katherine?
- How should I know?
Her bike's outside.
She must be in here somewhere.
Well, she's not
in here. He, uh--
He probably
took her with him.
Martin!
[ Screaming ]
Help us!
[ Panting ]
Listen, take him
to the station.
I'll take one last look atJoyce.
I'll meet you there.
Wait a minute.
Why would they try to escape?
Take it easy.
Handcuff him.
What?
You're under arrest
for suspicion of murder.
I don't understand this.
This is bullshit.
You have some
doubts too. Tell him!
Doubts?
Doubts about what,
Deputy Inspector Bill?
Nothing.
[ Groaning ]
I don't like it when you keep things
from me, Deputy Inspector Bill.
I've always encouraged you
to have your own ideas...
and share them,
haven't I?
Yeah. It's nothing.
He's babbling.
You said you felt
something was wrong.
Well, something is
definitely wrong.
Take him away.
[ Spits ]
[ Alarm Bell Ringing ]
[ Alarm Continues ]
[ Sharp Groan ]
No!
- [ Davies Groans ]
- No!
[ Alarm Continues ]
[ Panting ]
Have you ever
been killed before?
I'll be back in a minute.
[ Screaming ]
No!
[ Alarm Continues ]
[ Alarm Bell
Stops Ringing ]
No. No. No.
[ Whimpering ]
[ Screams ]
[ Katherine ]
Oh, my God!
This just doesn't happen.
It's not happening.
Cray, why are
you doing this?
What the hell
are you doing?
Stop asking for the how
and why, Martin.
[ Grunts ]
[ Mechanical Whine ]
[ Metallic Clanking ]
[ Both Whimpering,
Moaning ]
[ Screams ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Katherine Whimpering ]
[ Gunshot ]
[ Both Sobbing ]
[ Helicopter Approaching ]
[ Siren Blaring ]
[ People Chattering ]
Does it hurt?
Let's grow old together.
Yeah.
Let's get older.
There's a challenge.
James, we're gonna
take a little ride now, all right?
Keep that up.
Can you walk?
#I want to feel the fire #
#But I want to be the fire #
#I know you'll be ready #
# When my daughters fly #
# You rush to kill
the feeling #
#But you will now
need healing #
# Will you be ready
oh #
# To do or die #
# 'Cause pain can't hurt you #
#Pain can't hurt you #
# Can't hide behind
your manhood #
# With the
tears on your face #
# You can't escape
your demons #
#For the pain
ends up schemin'#
# Yeah the pain's
like a demon #
#For your empty soul inside #
# Oh #
#Ah #
#Ah-ah-ah-ah #
#I'll never be
too happy #
#My only friend's
confusion #
#I'm only half human
oh #
# When the day is done #
#My only friend's
black coffee #
#She tells the walls
to back off me #
#My only peace of mind
will come #
#From a smoking gun #
# 'Cause pain can't hurt you #
#Pain can't hurt you #
# Can't hide behind
your manhood #
# With the
tears on your face #
# You can't escape
your demons #
#For the pain
ends up schemin'#
#And the pain's
like a demon #
#For your empty soul inside #
#And the pain
can't stop movin'#
can't stop drivin'#
#And the pain's
like a demon #
#For your empty soul ##