(MAN) Hello, I'm Ronald Merrick,
and I'm here to invite you
aboard our Starliner.
Yes, it's true! Day-to-day
living becomes a luxury cruise
when you've made your home
at Starliner Tower apartments.
Although downtown Montreal is
only 12 and a half minutes away,
once you've crossed the
bridge to Starliner island,
the noise and the traffic of the city
might as well be a
million miles away.
Leave your car and the
tension of the city
in a space reserved for you in
our vast underground garage.
If friends have followed you home,
there's convenient parking for them
on ground level.
Invite them up to share
the breath-taking view
from your balcony or picture window.
Gracious hospitality is easy
in any Starliner apartment.
They all come fully equipped
with the most modern name
brand electrical appliances,
and cable TV is standard too.
Relax by the side of our heated
Olympic-size swimming pool
and watch the Saint Lawrence river
flow by on its way to the sea.
Exercise the fun way
on our nine hole golf course,
designed by international golf pros.
Or if tennis is your game,
you won't have to wait for playing time
on our multiple courts, day or night.
Explore our island paradise,
secure in the knowledge
that it belongs to you
and your fellow passengers alone.
Cruise the seasons,
the sun and the stars
without ever leaving the
great ship Starliner.
It's all here!
A restaurant complete
with take-out service,
a variety store,
delicatessen,
boutique,
drugstore,
dry cleaning service.
They're here to serve you.
And don't forget our own premises
dental and medical clinics
staffed by the world's
finest professionals.
Sail through life in
quiet and comfort.
Cruise Starliner.
Studios, one bedroom and
two bedroom apartments
are now available from Starko,
a division of General
Structures Incorporated.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
Good morning. Can I help you?
Yes, we are looking
for the rental agent.
- We have an appointment with him.
- I'll just give him a little buzz.
(TELEPHONE BUZZES)
(BANGING)
- Do you ever use that?
- This?
No, never had it out of the holster.
A rival company has them,
so we've got to have them.
It's just an advertising gimmick.
(CLATTERING)
Mr Merrick is coming.
Welcome to Starliner Towers.
- And you are?
- Kresimer and Benda Sviben.
Ah yes, Mr and Mrs Sviben.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Now, are we talking about
one or two bedrooms?
I assume we're not
talking about bachelors.
(FRANTIC FOOTSTEPS)
(THROBBING HEARTBEAT)
(GASPS)
(MUFFLED CRIES)
Now, Benda, you take
a look at this one
and tell me if that doesn't suit
you right down to the ground.
This is the one with the big view.
The panoramic view.
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(DISCORDANT MUSIC)
(CLATTERING)
(DISCORDANT MUSIC CONTINUES)
(CHOKES)
- Did you say something, Nick?
- No.
Breakfast is just about ready.
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
Can I call you at the office?
What do you want to
call me at the office for?
I don't know.
I just thought I might
like to call you.
I'm not going to be at the
office, except to sign in.
I've got claims to check out.
Garages and more garages.
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(FIZZING)
(CRIES OUT)
(FALLS TO THE GROUND)
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
We're going up.
Well. I'll just take a little ride.
As I was saying, we have
quite an exciting variety
of completely furnished
apartments ready and waiting.
You could almost move in
this afternoon, if you wanted.
(LIFT DOORS OPEN)
Notice how the entranceways
to all the apartments...
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
(LIFT DOORS OPEN)
(KNOCKING)
Annabelle, it's Nick.
Are you in the bedroom?
(COUGHS)
It's probably nothing at all.
Actually, it's probably some form
of fatty cyst or something like that
that could easily be removed
at the doctor's office.
Hasn't Nick seen a doctor?
He hates doctors.
Doctors and lawyers.
He never goes to doctors.
Look, why don't you do this. Go down
to the clinic and see that nice doctor.
What's his name? St. Luc?
Go down to the clinic and explain
to him that Nick is very ill
and he has to stay in bed.
Ask him to come and see him.
And then when he's there they
can fight it out between them.
- He'll be really mad.
- So what?
You can relax. You'll find
out what's wrong with him.
Let him be the uptight
one for a change.
Really, this is ridiculous.
OK.
Bravo!
(QUIET DISCORDANT MUSIC)
(CLICKING OF TYPEWRITER)
Nicholas! I didn't
expect you in today.
I've been telling everyone
to call back tomorrow.
(DOOR SLAMS)
It was Dr Hobbes who paid
the rent on the apartment.
But actually it was her name that
appeared on the residency list
and on the intercom board.
Annabelle Brown.
A very civilised young lady.
Never complained about anything.
That was her? Annabelle Brown?
Without a doubt.
This is the man who
called you up here?
Yes, the doctor, Roger St. Luc.
He's the director of our
little medical clinic here.
- Medical clinic?
- Yes. We're on an island, you see.
We have to be as
self-supporting as possible.
OK. Let's have a talk to the doctor.
Dr St. Luc?
Dr St. Luc? Detective
Sergeant Heller, homicide.
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
- You're the one who found the bodies?
- Yes.
Did you touch or move
anything before we arrived?
I removed some surgical
tape from the girl's lips.
I examined the inside of her mouth.
I gave the tape to your detective...
the man over there with the canvas bag.
And I looked at the abdominal wound.
Yes, well, the department will be
getting back to you about that.
Now, you knew these people?
I knew the man, Emil Hobbes, a doctor
and a professor at the university.
I saw the girl around the building.
I didn't know her.
She never came into the clinic.
So you came to visit this man Hobbes,
and you found them like that?
No. I haven't seen Dr Hobbes
since medical school.
He taught me. He was my
professor at university,
in urology and venereology.
He also conducted some seminars in
psychopharmacology. That's about it.
I never really had any idea he ever set
foot in Starliner Towers until today.
What brought you up here?
He called me at six
o'clock this morning.
Hobbes called me.
I thought I was dreaming.
I haven't heard that voice in so long.
He said, "Meet me at apartment 15..."
- ...11.
- Thank you.
"At noon we go out for lunch.
It's time you furthered your education."
How did he sound? Depressed? Nervous?
He sounded fine.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
1511?
No, you've got the wrong man.
Just a moment please.
Dr St. Luc, it's for you.
Someone wanting to know why
didn't you turn up for lunch.
I know it is not the kind of lunch
that Hobbes had in mind for us,
but it's all I got.
Isn't it beautiful?
This is Hobbes' and my project.
What we were trying to find was
an alternative to organ transplant.
Am I keeping you up?
You're bored, right?
To you, organ transplant is just
yesterday's kishkas, right?
Look. You've got Man, right?
And you've got parasites that
live in, on and around Man. Right?
So, why not breed a parasite
that can do something useful?
A parasite that can take over
the function of a human organ.
For example, you breed a parasite that
you implant in the human body cavity.
It hooks around the
circulatory system
and it filters the blood
just like a kidney does.
It takes a little blood for itself
once in a while. What do you care?
You've got enough.
You can afford to be generous.
- Huh? Are you following me?
- I am, I am.
Look, you've got a guy
with a bad kidney. Right?
You put the bug in him.
The bug goes to work on the kidney,
dissolves it, so the body assimilates it.
Now, what have you got?
You've got a perfectly good parasite
where you used to have a rotten kidney.
Right? I know you're going to say.
You're going to say it's crazy.
Actually, I was going to ask
if you have any mustard.
Come on Roger, really.
What do you think?
- I think it's crazy.
- It's crazy, but who cares?
I mean, look, Hobbes
was a lousy teacher.
We've got to face the facts of life.
He was dull, academic, just plain lousy,
but he had a genius for one thing...
that was getting grants.
He could raise money
for crazy projects.
For example, who do you suppose
is paying the rent on this place?
- Not you.
- No.
The Northern Hemisphere
Organ Transplant Society.
That's for something that's supposed
to put them out of business.
Here is a partial list of some
of the other research projects
that we are underwriting,
but with their money. Smart?
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
Ashen and Gaunt Insurance Appraisals.
Mr Tudor?
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
One moment, please. I'll buzz him.
(MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
Nicholas? There's a call for you.
It's that man whose Lamborghini
caught fire on St Catherine.
He's very angry.
Nicholas? What's wrong?
We're going to get you to a hospital.
It's probably an ulcer.
- I'm going home for the day.
- But Nicholas...
I'm all right, Mona.
Call me a cab... Now.
All right, Nicholas. All right.
How did Hobbes know this girl?
Who is she?
Some chick he met while he
was lecturing at a girls' school.
And what happened?
They caught him examining
her titties for breast cancer
in the faculty lounge.
She was 12 years old.
Talk about crazy.
He used to bring her
up here once in a while.
I'll never understand how he
could do what he did to her.
Well, I think I'm going to have
to go back and open up the store.
It's been great seeing you.
Roger?
You'll think about what I just talked
to you about? About joining me on this?
- Sure.
- See you. Right.
How about the pickle?
(LAUGHING) It's used!
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
Good afternoon, Mr Tudor!
...that the ageing process
is in any way reversible.
I don't think for a moment that
it is, but it might be stoppable,
and that's where
mega-vitamins come in.
Mrs Tudor? Are you ready now?
- Yes. Excuse me, Brad.
- Sure.
- Be with you in a minute.
- Right.
No, I don't see any change
in this company report I did
on your husband last year.
I see a few too many escargots
and too many crepes with vanilla
ice-cream and strawberries
and a dash of Grand Marnier.
I don't see any chance of any cancer
developing. Not like you're describing.
I think it might be some
swollen glands or something.
Can you come up and
take a look at him?
That's what I'm here for.
I don't think I can do it until about
9:30 or 10 o'clock. Is that OK?
- That's terrific.
- Not too late?
That's fine.
Thank you so much, doctor.
- Don't worry about it.
- OK.
Mrs Emmenthal is ready, doctor.
Tell Mrs Emmenthal I'll be
right with her, will you?
(QUIET MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(CHOKES)
(RETCHES)
(VOMITS)
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
(LOUD DISCORDANT MUSIC)
- You see how beautiful the grass is?
- Yes.
I take a walk nearly every day.
(CHOKES)
(GASPS)
Good heavens! Look!
Oh, poor birdie.
They're always crashing
into tall buildings.
The windows fool them, you know.
- Come along, Olive.
- It's such a shame.
- Come along, dear.
- The poor little bird.
Maybe it's only hurt.
Don't be silly, dear.
It's in heaven now, whatever it is.
Now come along. I'll get you tucked
into bed before the colour TV.
You know what a restless...
Kriedler seemed to think that
the mega-vitamin therapy
is the answer to the
question of ageing.
That's not to suggest that the ageing
process is in any way reversible.
- They're ready for you now, Brad.
- OK. Bye.
Now, you just take your shirt off
and the doctor will be in
to see you in a minute, OK?
You don't have to go. I'm not shy.
Now, don't be a tease, Brad.
- I'm still working, you know.
- Yes, I know.
(SUDDEN DISCORDANT MUSIC)
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
(SCREAMS)
(DRAMATIC MUSIC)
(FRANTIC CRIES)
Looking good. Put your feet up.
Let's see what the problem is.
Ow! Better take it easy.
There's a lot of pressure in there.
Do you want me to breathe deeply?
Not just yet. Just breathe normally.
Good shape for an old man, eh?
Yes.
Better than me, my man.
Better than me.
Erm... Mr Parkins, I understand that
you got these lumps from a young lady.
Is that right?
What makes you think that?
She had some just like them.
Right here. Near her belly button.
You could push them around too.
I thought it was kind
of sexy, myself.
- Did she live in the Starliner Tower?
- Yes. In 1511.
- Annabelle Brown?
- Yeah, that's the one.
OK, I tell you what,
put your clothes on.
I'm going to send you to the
hospital to take a few X-rays.
I'm going to give you
a little piece of paper,
- right here with the address.
- Are they going to cut me open?
I don't want you thinking you've
got a problem when you don't.
(GENTLE MUSIC)
Hi.
- Hi.
- Want a drink?
- No thanks.
I just wanted to tell you, Dr St.
Luc is going to come and see Nick
about 10:00.
That's terrific! Was he nice to you?
- Mm-hm.
- Great.
After you've found out that there's
nothing that a vacation won't cure
why don't you come
and join me for dinner.
Everything from Filipe's.
I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
Why don't you come and join me?
I loathe to eat alone.
It makes me feel so fat and lonely.
- I always order for two.
- OK.
Nick? Are you home?
(SCREAMS)
(DISCORDANT MUSIC)
Come on, sweetheart. We'll get
you into bed. You'll be all right.
Come on.
(DISCORDANT MUSIC)
You go there and I'll go here.
(SHOUTS)
Forget it.
I don't understand why
there's no-one home here.
Maybe in that apartment.
(MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTS) What is it?
(SHOUTS) It's sickening! What is it?
(SHOUTS) Let's get out of here!
(SCREAMS)
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(SOBS)
(FAST-PACED DISCORDANT MUSIC)
Come on, boy.
Come on, buddy.
Come on, fella.
You and me.
You and me, we're going
to be good friends.
Good friends.
Atta boy!
(JANINE) Nick? Did you call me?
Did you say something?
How are you feeling?
Does your stomach hurt?
- Can I feel those lumps on your tum?
- Go away.
Leave me alone.
(SOBBING)
Why won't you let me help you?
(MAN ON TV)
The time is seven o'clock.
This is John Woodhouse with
Mediascope news, sports and weather.
A bizarre murder-suicide has
Montreal police baffled today
as they attempt to untangle
events leading to the discovery
of two bodies in the Starliner Island
apartment complex, early this afternoon.
The body of a 68 year old
retired professor of medicine
was found lying in a pool of blood
by an unidentified former student.
The professor apparently
committed suicide
by cutting his throat with a scalpel
after performing an as yet
unexplained operation
on a 19 year old woman.
The woman's nude body
was found lying on the dining
room table. Badly mutilated.
Police are not releasing any names
pending notification of next of kin.
On the labour front, talk of an
impending steelworkers strike
has the municipal officials
on the defensive.
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
Spokesmen for the steelworkers union
are asking for a 20% pay increase.
A government official says negotiations
with the union will continue
until a settlement is reached.
Olympic construction has been
suspended for two weeks...
(WATER RUNNING)
(MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
I got those things you asked for.
The files on Horsfield, Velakofsky,
Swinbird and Brown.
And those papers published
by Hobbes and...
Those are from the American
Journal of Psychiatry.
- All of this.
- Yes, this is Hobbes' paper.
As an extra, these are some
things that were compiled
before your time here. I thought
they might be of interest to you.
And now how about a kiss?
- Hey, how about a kiss?
- Sure.
That's the best thing I heard all day!
How about another kiss?
- Do we have more people on the list?
- No, Dot is the last.
(TELEPHONE RINGS)
- Yes?
- Rog? It's me, Rollo.
Interesting you should call.
I'm just looking over this material
you did with Hobbes. It's interesting.
That's flattering but I don't think
you'll find much real meat on them.
- No? How come?
- I always thought Hobbes was funny,
But I told you that before. Right?
I just never knew how funny, until now.
So when he kicked off, they sent
all his personal notes and stuff.
After all, I'm his partner, right?
Anyhow, I've been going through his
papers and what it adds up to is this:
Hobbes was shafting us all.
Me, the university, the foundations,
the council, everybody.
- I don't quite get it.
- Hobbes believed that "man is an animal
"that thinks too much.
An over rational animal
"that has lost touch with its body and
its instincts." How do you like that?
In other words, too much
brain and not enough guts.
So what he came up with
to help our guts along
was a parasite that's...
a combination of aphrodisiac
and venereal disease
that will hopefully turn the world
into one beautiful, mindless orgy.
Well, I think it sounds
a little crazy to me.
Look. The important thing
to you, Rog, is this.
You know Annabelle? Well,
he was using her as a guinea pig.
- A guinea pig?
- He implanted her with a parasite,
and once it took over,
apparently she went berserk.
I guess Hobbes wasn't ready for that,
- so I guess he just had to kill her.
- What was the point?
Well, the point was...
he wasn't trying to burn her.
- He wasn't?
- No.
He was trying to burn
the things. All of them.
- Yeah, well, he didn't make it.
- What?
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
Maybe Hobbes didn't know,
but Annabelle Brown was a popular girl
around Starliner Towers.
I've got three men here, maybe four,
hosting large, free-moving, apparently
pathogenic, abdominal growths
that nobody I've tried can identify.
Listen, I'd like to come over
and take a look at those guys.
Well, why don't you?
I'm going to meet one of them soon.
A fellow by the name of Tudor.
It's on the directory there.
You can just meet me
up at the apartment.
Yeah, look, I'll be right over.
Listen, Rog, I don't want
to panic you or anything,
but the way Hobbes
designed those things,
they get out of hand pretty fast.
So you've got to be careful,
before you even have a chance
to know what's happening to you.
Once they start pumping that juice into
the blood stream, well, I don't know...
The point it, if you see anybody
doing anything compulsive,
you know, any kind of
bizarre sexual things, well...
once we can get at them,
there are a lot of things we can use.
Maybe we'd start with a kind of basic
tropical kit and work up from there.
I'll bring a bag full over,
but the point is,
you've got to get at them. And fast.
(SUDDEN BURST OF DISCORDANT MUSIC)
(EERIE MUSIC)
(MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
(CRIES)
(GLASS SMASHES)
(WATER SPLASHES)
(SCREAMS)
Listen, I'm going to stay. I've got
to meet Rollo at the Tudor apartment.
- It's going to be pretty late.
- Why don't you come to my place
for something to eat
when you're finished?
It's going to be very late...
It doesn't matter to me how
late it is. I'll keep it warm.
Is anything wrong?
I mean, with the Hobbes thing?
Yeah. But nothing we can't handle.
Well, how about supper at my place?
- OK, but late.
- OK. See you later.
(SOFT MUSIC)
(WATER RUNNING)
(GLASS CRUNCHES)
Delivery for 416,
from Filipe's restaurant.
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
I'm hungry!
I'm hungry for love!
(RUSTLING OF PAPERS)
Mm-hm. OK...
Hot!
Pretty good.
It's lovely!
(KNOCKING)
Yes? Can I help you?
Yes, you can help me.
(SCREAMS) Wait a minute...
(SUDDEN BURST OF MUSIC)
(SCREAMS)
(CRIES)
(DISCORDANT MUSIC)
(SOBBING)
- What's wrong?
- This man, I think I recognise him.
I think he lives in
the apartment house.
He just attacked me
for no reason at all.
- It's all right.
- I opened the door.
I was fixing your dinner.
He grabbed me and tried to kiss me.
- Where is he now?
- I don't know. I think I killed him.
I stabbed him with
something and he fell.
Just stay here and I'll
go and check it out.
- Just stay here.
- No, no.
I'm not going to stay here
by myself, I'm going with you.
Listen to me. It'll be safe for you here.
Just stay here and I'll be right back.
OK?
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(CLATTERING)
I'm sorry. I didn't
mean to startle you.
I just couldn't let your dinner burn.
(EERIE MUSIC)
(FRENCH ACCENT) It's strange!
Go away!
(CRIES OUT)
Get it off me!
Get off!
Get away from me.
(WOMAN ON TV) Yes, Gunther, how many
times do I have to tell you, yes!
(GASPS)
Sometimes, Gunther, I wonder if I
should try to get along on my own
- and not owe you anything.
- Don't be that way.
You're always helping me Gunther
but you don't miss the
chance to remind me...
(BACKGROUND MUSIC GROWS LOUDER)
Now, I want you to describe
him to the doorman.
Maybe he'll know who he is or
where he lives, and his apartment.
- How are you feeling?
- OK.
(FRENCH ACCENT)
Hey, doctor, please help us.
- What happened?
- Please pardon me.
I am Maurice Guilbault.
I am a resident here.
We were walking in the
hallway and Doris my wife,
- she was attacked by this thing.
- Where is this thing?
I hit it! Then, I hit it with
the cane, down to the garbage.
This is a nurse.
This is Nurse Forsythe.
She is a nurse. She is a nurse.
Take them back to their apartment.
Treat her for second degree burns.
- What is the number of your apartment?
- Yes, we live in 703.
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
I'll meet you back there.
Don't leave until I get there.
Look the door. Don't let
anyone in except me. OK?
- But where are you going?
- Down to the garbage.
No, dear, it's not our floor.
(EERIE MUSIC)
(SCREAMS)
The Savlon, does that
make it feel any better?
(MAN) Janine?
Janine?
Nick? Are you up?
Hello, Darling! I feel wonderful.
Come here. Come and
join me on the bed.
You're absolutely beautiful.
Your eyes! Your mouth!
You're absolutely the
most sexy thing alive.
Do you want to make love?
Nick, you're so strange.
You'll make love to me,
won't you, Janine?
You're my wife.
You start it. I think
I've forgotten how to.
- Nick, I can't take this.
- Janine.
(SLAP)
(SCREAMS)
Make love to me, Janine!
You're my wife!
(CLATTERING)
(GASPS)
(CRIES)
Ah!
(CLATTERING)
No! Nick! Stop!
Please stop!
Make love to me.
I want to be able to see
us when we make love.
I want to put my contacts in.
Is that OK, Nick?
I'm going to put my contacts in.
(CHOKING)
(SOBBING)
Nick, I'm here.
(RETCHING)
(CRYING)
Betts?
(BUZZING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(GASPING)
(UPBEAT MUSIC ON TV)
(MAN ON TV) Come on.
Faster!
(SCREAMS)
I'm going to call the police.
She's calling the police!
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH) Je ne sais pas!
Qu'est-ce qui se passe?
What's going on?
Hey, miss! Nurse, come back!
My wife, she needs something!
Roger?
(FOOTSTEPS)
Roger...
(FRANTIC FOOTSTEPS)
Roger, where are you?
Roger...
(EERIE MUSIC)
Doctor! You look awful.
What happened?
Never mind how awful I look.
Here's what I want you to do.
Call the police. You got that?
Call them and tell them the head
of the medical centre needs help.
Listen to me!
Tell them I need help and to
make it fast. Right away.
OK.
- Yes? Who is there?
- Mr Guilbault.
- Who is this?
- Dr St. Luc.
I need to talk to the nurse, please.
The nurse? She went away. I think
she went to look for you, doctor.
- You stay where you are, all right?
- Stay where we are?
- Understand? Stay where you are.
- Yes, OK. Goodbye.
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(WAILING)
Who are those people?
(LOUD WAILING AND BANGING)
My God!
Go away! Leave us alone!
(CRIES)
(CAR ENGINE SOUNDS)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(SCREAMS) No!
Forsythe?
(SCREAMS)
(LOUD SCREAMS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(TRYING TO START CAR ENGINE)
(BRAKES SCREECH)
Hold on while I try and
crash through the door.
(BANG)
(CRASH)
(QUIET EERIE MUSIC)
Dr St. Luc?
Oh, here he is.
Ah, good evening,
Mr Wolfe, Miss Lewis.
(BANG)
Mr Merrick, why don't you do
something about all that noise?
We like parties,
but this is ridiculous!
Well, there might be a connection.
You see, it's about your locker...
I'm afraid somebody broke
into it earlier in the evening.
- Oh, what a drag!
- Are you serious?
I'm afraid so.
I have some of the things that they
were throwing around in my office.
If you'd care to come
and identify them...
What's going on? Let's get out.
(SCREAMS AND SHOUTS)
(SOFT MUSIC)
(QUIETLY) Baby...
Do I feel good to you?
(SOBBING) Yes, very good.
(WHISPERING) Do you know what I want?
I want you to make love with me.
Make love to me, Janine.
- You can't...
- Make love to me.
- You can't be saying that.
- Let's kiss and make up, baby.
Make love to me, make love to me.
Let's kiss and make up!
(LOUD SINISTER MUSIC)
(QUIET MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
Rollo and the police
will be here by now.
So all we have to do is avoid these
people till they find us or we find them.
(NIGHT-TIME INSECTS)
(WIND HOWLING IN BACKGROUND)
(EERIE MUSIC)
Dr St. Luc?
Roger?
Dr Linsky here!
Roger, Rollo here to have that
consultation we talked about.
Roger?
Hey, Rog?
Mr Tudor?
Mr Tudor, I'm Dr Linsky.
All right...
(GASPS)
Ah!
(SUDDEN LOUD MUSIC)
(WAILING)
Help! Roger!
(CRIES)
(BANGING)
- No.
- Take if off!
(SHOUTS) No... No! Tudor!
(GROANS)
Roger, I had a very
disturbing dream last night.
In this dream, I found myself
making love to a strange man.
Only, I'm having trouble, you see,
because he's old, and dying.
He smells bad and I
find him repulsive.
But then he tells me that
everything is erotic.
That everything is sexual.
You know what I mean?
He tells me that even
old flesh is erotic flesh.
That disease is the love of two alien
kinds of creatures for each other.
That even dying is
an act of eroticism.
That talking is sexual.
That breathing is sexual.
That even to physically
exist is sexual.
And I believe him.
And we make love beautifully.
(CHOKES)
(SLAPS)
(EERIE MUSIC)
(SUDDEN SCREAMING AND SHOUTING)
(LOAD GROANS)
Go back!
(GROANS)
(SUDDEN BURST OF MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
(GUNSHOTS)
(DOGS BARKING)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMS AND SHOUTS
IN THE BACKGROUND)
(MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
Hey, come on out!
Do you want to go to a party?
(LAUGHING)
Hey, come on out.
Have you met my daughter, Erica?
She's a beautiful girl.
Come here, Erica.
I think you'd really
like my daughter, Erica.
(LAUGHTER)
(MUSIC INDICATING SUSPENSE)
(GROANING)
(GROANING GROWS LOUDER)
(LOUD WAILING AND GROANING)
(MUSIC DISTORTED, UNDERWATER SOUNDS)
(LOUD GROANING AND SPLASHING)
(NIGHT-TIME INSECTS)
(ELECTRIC GARAGE DOOR OPENS)
(SLOW, MYSTERIOUS MUSIC)
(GENTLE MUSIC)
(MAN ON RADIO) The time is 5:26am.
This is Gerald Keys with the
Mediascope sunrise news bulletin.
There is still no confirmation
by Montreal City Police
concerning alleged reports of a city
wide wave of violent sexual assaults.
The assaults,
believed to have originated
in the vicinity of Starliner
Island, began late last night,
and have spread with increasing
frequency this morning.
Reports of the attacks have been
termed irresponsible and hysterical
by a Montreal City Police spokesman.
Stay tuned for further details
on Mediascope News at 6.00.
(CLOSING SEQUENCE MUSIC)