You're not looking at me, Mike.
You're not looking at me in the eyes.
That's weak.
Only weak people do that.
I could look you in the eye if...
if I wanted to, Daddy. I...
I just...
I just don't want to look you in the eye.
I guess you're just a weak person, hmm?
Must have got that from your mother.
It probably would have been better for you
had you been born a girl.
Then we could have named you Michelle.
Hmm?
You see, weakness is more
acceptable in a girl, Michelle.
Oh.
Oh, I'm sorry. I mean Mike.
I keep forgetting.
Wait a minute.
Why don't I call you Michelle
all the time? Hmm?
Then I wouldn't have to be so goddamn
fucking ashamed of you and your weaknesses.
I could just think of you
as a girl all the time, couldn't I?
Buy your frocks and your dresses and
your frilly hats and your frilly scarves.
And you could be...
You could be Daddy's little girl.
I wouldn't have to be so fucking ashamed
of being seen with you in public, would I? Eh?
What do you think of that, Michelle?
Sound like a good idea?
Don't, Daddy. Don't.
What? Did you say something?
Such a soft, little girl's voice.
I couldn't hear what you said.
I hate you, Daddy. I hate you.
- Speak up, girl!
- I hate you!
I hate you... because I love you.
It makes me feel guilty inside... hate.
I can't hardly speak.
Then don't speak.
Don't speak to me. Show me.
Don't tell me about it. I'm not interested
in what little girls have to say anyway.
Show me! Show me your anger!
Show me!
Then I can understand it.
- [Screams]
- [Observers Gasping]
There you are, Daddy.
There you are.
I see you, Michelle.
I see everything.
This is me, Daddy.
This is what you do to me inside.
Go all the way through it, Michelle.
Go all the way through it to the end.
Come out the other end.
Don't stop in the middle.
I'm watching you.
I'm watching everything you do, Mike.
[Sobbing]
Oh, Daddy.
- [Sobs]
- [Kissing]
[Sobs]
- [People Murmuring]
- Wow.
The man is a genius.
Dr. Raglan would like to thank you all
for coming this afternoon.
I believe your bus is waiting outside now.
Thank you.
[People Murmuring]
[All Chattering]
Candy? It's me, honey.
Mmm!
Oh, Daddy. Daddy.
[Chattering]
Okay, honey.
Warm enough?
There we go.
Okay, put the whale down, honey.
Turn around.
Hold your hair up now.
Oh, my God.
[Knocking]
Yeah.
Sorry, Hal, but, uh,
Mr. Carveth is still here.
He's starting to get, uh,
passionate about the whole thing.
Okay. Send him in.
Mr. Carveth.
Thanks a lot.
Frank, it's been some time.
What can I do for you?
I want to see Nola.
I want to see my wife now.
You know she's still undergoing
intensive therapy.
I can't let you break that isolation.
Well, you let her see Candice
on the weekends, don't you?
Yes, Frank, I do.
But then that's different.
Regular visits from her daughter was built
into her program from the very start.
Yeah? Well, her program has just changed.
What do you mean, Frank?
You sound hostile.
Well, my daughter has been beaten...
severely.
And scratched and bitten.
And her mother did it.
Her mother who's under
your psychiatric care.
That's an incredibly heavy accusation
to make, Frank.
Did Candice tell you that?
Huh. Candice won't talk about it.
She pretends the whole thing
never happened.
But it was Nola.
Or some other crazy
you have stashed away up here.
Either way, no more weekends with Mummy.
The kid stays with me.
To take Candice away from her
at this stage...
could send Nola over into the deep end.
It's a critical time for her, Frank.
Yeah, well, I happen to think that Nola's
been in over her head for a long time now.
You have no legal right to deny access.
Anytime you'd like
to test the matter in open court...
I'd be more than happy to oblige.
For the ultimate good
of your own family, Frank...
we'd be prepared to do just that.
But don't you force it.
You bring Candy back to her mother
next weekend.
She won't harm the child.
There must be some other answer
to what you've seen.
Well, until you give me that answer,
Candy's not coming back.
Yes, Hal.
Chris, prepare Nola Carveth-Kelly
for another session tonight, will you?
Sure.
Oh, and, uh, Chris,
make it phase two after supper.
- Okay, Hal.
- [Intercom Clicks]
This guy Raglan
is strictly an emotional opportunist.
He's a legit MD, right?
He's a real psychiatrist.
[Sighs]
Yes.
Goddamn it! Psychoplasmics is a rip-off!
It's a sideshow. I've seen it in action.
Frank, it doesn't matter what you think.
Now you listen to me.
You call up this Raglan
and you be a real mensch with him.
Otherwise, it's just a matter of time
before the cops show up at your door...
and you lose your kid for good.
The law believes in motherhood.
If I can dig up enough testimony
to prove that Raglan's a dangerous fraud...
that Somafree is crawling with crazies...
It's no place for a kid anytime.
[Deep Breath]
You're getting warmer.
But, you know, when Candy doesn't show up
at Somafree next weekend...
your wife can take
legal action immediately.
You could find yourself belted
with a writ in seven days.
If I give Nola enough time,
she'll really hurt the kid.
I know she will, Al.
I'll do anything I have to.
[Children Laughing, Chattering]
[Mothers, Children Chattering]
Oh, here's your daddy.
Oh. [Chuckles]
I'll bet he knows all about this zipper.
There we go.
All set now.
I'd like to talk to you
sometime soon, Mr. Carveth...
about school activities and... Candy.
You missed the last open house.
Yeah.
Okay. Soon.
Oh.
Thanks.
See you tomorrow, Candy.
[Woman]
Thank you very much, Frank.
- For what?
- For bringing me my grandchild.
I know if it were up to Nola,
I'd never see Candice.
Juliana, that's not true.
Nola and I both know how much
she needs her grandma.
Especially now.
You're sweet.
I guess you know now what it feels like.
What it feels like?
Being a parent.
Being blamed for everything.
To have the past distorted
so you don't even recognize yourself in it.
Your child's version of the past, that is.
Juliana, Candice is only five.
She's working on it right now, believe me.
Thirty seconds after you're born,
you have a past.
And 60 seconds after that,
you start to lie to yourself about it.
Juliana.
I guess I've been indulging in a horrid
bout of nostalgia these last few days.
- Must be the weather.
- [Clock Chiming]
At least now I have a partner in crime.
- I gotta go.
- Of course.
Bye, Daddy.
Take your time. We'll both be just fine.
[Door Opens, Closes]
I'll be with you in a second, sweetie.
I'm just going to get a refill...
and then we'll look
at those lovely old pictures.
[Raglan]
Mummy.
Yes, Candice?
Yes, sweetie?
Mummy, you hurt me.
You hit me with your fists,
and you scratched me with your nails. You...
You hurt me.
No, I didn't, sweetie.
You must have had a bad dream.
Mummies don't do that.
Mummies don't hurt their own children.
They don't?
They never do?
They sometimes do.
Sometimes, but then they're bad mummies.
They're fucked-up mummies.
Like whose?
Like whose mummy?
Like mine was.
Fucked-up and bad.
No, I'm not, Nola.
You're being so unfair, sweetheart.
Mummies never do that.
Mummies never hurt their own children.
You did hurt me.
You beat me, and you scratched me.
You threw me down the stairs.
Show me what I did.
Don't stop it now, darling. You show me.
Show me your anger, Nola. Show it to me.
Go all the way through it.
Go all the way through it to the end.
Right to the end.
That one's my favorite.
- This one's your favorite?
- Yes.
Mummy in the hospital
when she was a little girl.
[Juliana]
Hmm. That's right. I remember this picture.
Your Grandpa Barton took this picture.
Tell me the rest of the story
that goes with the picture.
Why was Mummy in the hospital so much?
Well...
Some days she would wake up...
and she would be covered
with big, ugly bumps.
And the doctors were very worried...
because they could never find out what
those bumps all over her skin really were.
- [Milk Box Clattering]
- [Candice] Then as soon
as she became a teenager...
the bumps went away for good
and she never saw them again.
[Juliana]
That's right.
[Clattering, Pounding]
Oh.
I guess I didn't stack
the dishes too well.
I better go see what the damage is.
While I'm there,
I think I'll freshen up both our drinks.
[Glass Shatters]
- [Objects Clattering]
- [Glass Shattering]
[Glass Shatters]
[Clattering Continues]
[Creature Snarling]
- [Creature Screeching]
- [Screaming, Groaning]
[Groaning, Screaming]
Please let me go!
[Snarls]
- [Hammering]
- Jerry.
Hi, Frank.
You're really falling behind on this,
you know.
The Brenleys think that they're gonna be
moving in here by May.
Nah, we're not gonna make that for sure.
Maybe by June.
I just found out this morning that
the city plumbing permit got held up...
- because of a change in the building code.
- [Frank Groans]
Mr. Carveth.
Telephone call for you.
All right.
- Hello?
- [Man] Is that Mr. Carveth?
- Yes.
- Mr. Frank Carveth?
- Yeah, this is Frank Carveth.
- This is Sergeant Markle of 78 Division.
One of our officers noticed
a broken kitchen window...
while on a routine patrol
of the neighborhood.
Found your mother-in-law's body
in the kitchen.
The murder weapon
was on the floor next to her.
He then found your daughter upstairs,
sound asleep in the bedroom.
It seems she missed the whole thing.
Where is she now? I'd like to see her.
She's with our police psychologist,
Dr. Birkin.
Psychologist? Why? Was she hysterical?
No. No. On the contrary.
She was very cool
throughout the whole thing.
A little too cool, I thought.
So I asked Dr. Birkin to talk with her,
just for an opinion.
In the meantime, can you think
of the names of any persons...
who would have a motive
to murder this woman?
You see, it doesn't seem to me to be
a simple case of an interrupted break-in...
or, say, a rape-murder.
Juliana had a long series of lovers.
I never met any of them.
What about her husband?
His name is Barton Kelly.
He works for the government out in Halifax.
- [Knocking]
- They were divorced over 10 years ago.
Dr. Birkin.
- You must be Candice's father.
- Yeah. I'd like to take her home now.
Mr. Carveth, please.
Give me just two minutes with you.
It's important. Have a seat.
Speaking bluntly, I don't think that your daughter
escaped this incident entirely unscathed.
- You think she saw what happened.
- I suspect she did.
Or she saw something
which traumatized her...
confused her, disturbed her in some way.
The officer who found her said
that she was very difficult to wake up.
To me, that indicates
a kind of abnormal deep sleep...
which a lot of people, even children...
will use to escape something
that's too painful to face.
And she still says that she doesn't remember
being brought to her grandmother's...
or seeing her at all.
Do you think she'll remember eventually?
Mr. Carveth, I think you must
encourage her to remember.
Why?
My concern is that the child could have
a very serious breakdown...
if she doesn't come to terms
with what she's experienced.
You see, these things tend to express
themselves in one way or another.
I've seen five-year-olds
like your daughter...
with ulcers as bad
as any middle-aged businessman.
Okay, okay. I get the picture.
Now can I take her home?
- I think that's fine.
- No problem.
[Man On TV, Indistinct]
What we're gonna do is we're gonna get
Ralph to stand straight up in the air.
But only with your help.
On the count of three...
I'll say "One, two, three.
Stand up, Ralph. "
Then I want everybody to clap loudly.
He'll stand right up in the air.
Everybody ready?
One...
- [TV Clicks Off]
You're sure you don't want a story?
We don't have to read, you know.
I can make one up for you.
Do you want to tell me a story?
About what happened today at Grandma's?
[Phone Ringing]
You go to sleep, honey.
I'll leave the hall light on.
[Ringing Continues]
[Rings]
[Dial Tone]
Damn.
Nola, no outside calls.
You're in isolation. You know that.
I tried to reach Dr. Raglan.
- He hasn't come.
- He's on his way.
Chris...
is something wrong?
Anything?
[Nola]
Then it's me again.
Nothing's wrong, except with me.
No, no, that's Frank...
Frank talking, Frank twisting my words.
He won't be patient.
He won't trust me.
He won't wait until I get well.
He thinks that I'm...
that I'm turning into my mother...
day by day, moment by moment.
He thinks that I'm trying
to make Candy into... into baby Nola.
Is he right?
No, no, no, no.
That's the last thing on earth I...
[Door Opens, Closes]
Who's that?
It's Daddy.
Oh!
Frank hates me, Daddy.
He despises me.
He thinks that I'm trying to harm
our little girl...
and I know that he's thinking of a way
to take her away.
And that's very unfair of him.
That's very arrogant of him.
You mustn't be too hard on him,
Nola, sweetheart.
He's just trying to be
a good, protective father.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes.
He's just doing
what a good father should do.
He's protecting his little girl.
Now, there's...
There's nothing wrong with that, is there?
He doesn't want to see her hurt.
He doesn't want to see her hurt by anybody,
not even her own mother.
Now, is there anything wrong with that?
Is there?
No.
No, there isn't.
[Kisses]
After all, that's just
what I did for you, isn't it?
Hmm?
Frank's protecting Candy
the same way as I protected you, isn't he?
Well, isn't he?
No.
No? What do you mean no?
- What do you mean when you say no?
- I love you, Daddy.
What do you mean when you say no?
I don't want you to think
that I don't love you.
What do you mean when you say no?
I mean you didn't.
Didn't?
Didn't what?
You didn't protect me.
You didn't.
You didn't. You didn't. You didn't.
And you should have.
You should have.
You shouldn't have
looked away when she hit me.
And you shouldn't have walked away
from the table when she twisted my words.
You should have stopped her.
You should have hit her when she hit me!
You should have slapped her
when she slapped me!
Oh, God, I love you.
But you didn't protect me...
and you should have.
You pretended it wasn't happening.
You looked away.
And you should have.
Why didn't you?
Didn't you love me?
[Whirring]
- Look, there he is.
- [Woman On PA, Indistinct]
There's Grandpa Barton.
Barton.
Oh, hello, Frank. How you doing?
- Good to see you.
- Let me take that.
Hello. How you doing, Candy?
I guess you don't remember
your old granddad, eh?
Right this way.
You didn't have to come way out here, Frank.
We could have met later at the hotel.
I just didn't like the idea
of you coming in alone.
How long are you planning to stay in town?
Well, I guess we could have
the funeral tomorrow, but, uh...
Juliana's parents might want
to come in from Arizona.
Then there's that sister in Vancouver.
I don't know just how
it's going to work out.
- What hotel are you staying in?
- Park Plaza.
You know, I was even thinking about
going out to that old house again.
[Chuckles]
I still have the key after all these years.
Juliana used to make a big fuss
about never having changed the locks.
I could never understand why.
Maybe it's because she really couldn't
admit that we were finished.
Ah, Frank, when I think
about you and Nola...
and this sweet child...
having to go through the same heartaches
we went through, it's...
it's enough to make you cry.
Yes, it is.
Uh, I'm here to see Mr. Hartog.
Mr. Jan Hartog.
Come in. Step right in.
[Man Grunting]
Sit down. Yeah. I'll be right there.
Sit down. I'll be with you in a second.
Goddamn son of a bitch.
I don't know. I don't know.
You know, I just don't know.
- [Alarm Ringing]
- Okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
[Alarm Stops]
[Exhales Sharply]
That's my, uh...
my heart over there on the floor.
- Your heart?
- My second heart.
I mean, your first heart makes your...
makes your blood circulate, right?
But what about your, uh, lymphatic fluids?
Well, I don't know.
Well, movement... walking, running, fucking,
rolling on the floor, anything.
I mean, people have this whole other
system they don't even know about.
The lymphatic system.
It's just like the blood system with
its own style of-of veins and arteries...
but... but no heart.
You have to keep moving.
You have to circulate.
And, uh, they've just given me pills.
They do that every day!
[Chuckles]
And, uh... And I've gotta...
I've gotta move 'em
through the lymphatic system.
Goddamn it.
[Sighs Loudly]
Pardon my sweat.
I'm gonna take a bath real soon.
So, uh, Mr.... um, uh, Carveth...
how did you get my name?
My lawyer knows your lawyer.
Oh, I see. I get it.
And is your... is your lawyer...
preparing a case against Raglan too?
Basically, yes.
Uh, slightly different from yours.
Yeah? How different?
Well, my wife is still
in therapy with Raglan.
Uh, I'm claiming psychological damage,
uh, not physiological.
Oh, I see. Well, give him
some more time with your wife...
and you'll be able to claim
physiological damage too.
Won't this look impressive in court?
- [Groans]
- Hmm?
You like it? I do.
That's Raglan. That's Psychoplasmics.
[Chuckles]
It's called lymphosarcoma.
[Singsongy]
And it's spreading.
It's a form of cancer
of the lymphatic system.
You blame Raglan for that?
Oh, Raglan did it.
I mean, Raglan encouraged my body to-to...
to revolt against me, you know.
And it did.
Now I have a small
revolution on my hands...
and I'm not putting it down
very successfully.
Then your lawyer really thinks he can
prove Raglan's responsible?
Are you kidding me?
You can't prove a thing like...
like that in court.
Right from square one, you're into...
you're into, what, metaphysics.
Mmm.
I mean, how do you know
I'm not gonna get cancer at age 32...
whether I'd gone into
Psychoplasmics therapy or not?
No, no, no.
We'd get laughed out of court.
Well, then why are you going into court?
[Whispers]
Revenge.
Yeah, revenge.
Even if we lose, people'll get nervous
about Psychoplasmics.
It will be bad publicity.
You know?
They won't even remember
whether we won or lost.
They'll just remember the slogan...
"Psychoplasmics can cause cancer."
Catchy, huh?
Is that gonna help?
Maybe.
I'm not alone, you know.
I mean, I'm in touch with a lot of people
who did Psychoplasmics.
We might form a club.
I... I... I want to help you.
Okay. Thanks.
Dr. Raglan?
Yes.
I'm Barton Kelly, Nola Carveth's father.
I'm glad to meet you.
I'm sorry to, uh, accost you like this...
but, uh, your receptionist
wasn't too helpful.
Yes, well, she probably knew
I was on my way to...
Did you know that Nola's
mother died yesterday,
that she was murdered?
Yes. The police spoke to me.
- Then you've told her?
- No, I haven't.
Well, then,
that's why I'm here... to tell her.
Mr. Kelly, your wife's death
was a tragic and shocking thing.
That's why Nola must not be told.
What?
Nola is going through
a very critical stage in her therapy.
I'm not sure she could take it.
Are you saying that I'm just supposed
to bury the girl's mother...
and not tell her about it?
Yes, that's what I'm saying.
You are one ignorant
son of a bitch, Dr. Raglan.
Now, I have left my phone number
on your front desk.
If I don't hear from my daughter
by tomorrow afternoon...
I'm coming back up here to get her.
Shall I have him stopped?
No, no, that's all right.
He's drunk.
[Engine Starts]
[Panting]
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
You two look like you're having fun.
[Together, Laughing]
We were!
Daddy, Miss Mayer said she was starving.
Can we feed her at our place tonight?
[Chuckling]
Candy.
We could if she wanted to.
What do you think?
Well, I...
We could talk after Candy goes to bed.
Sure.
As soon as Candy realized
she had me alone...
she got me to play
mother and daughter with her.
She obviously needs mothering
and isn't getting it.
Yeah.
Sometimes it just kills me to think that
I might have screwed my kid up already.
She's not even six.
It's not just you.
No.
No, sometimes when I'm being easy
on myself, I say, "Well, it's not your fault.
You got taken in.
You got involved with a woman
who married you for your sanity...
hoping it would rub off."
Instead, it started to work the other way.
[Phone Ringing]
Excuse me.
Hello.
It's Barton Kelly, Frank.
How are you?
Just mediocre.
I made a mistake, Frank.
I came back to the old place.
[Inhales]
It's got me, Frank.
I'm depressed as hell.
Barton, get in a cab, will you?
- Just tell him to take...
- That's not all.
There's Nola too.
How do you mean?
I went up to that place to see her.
They wouldn't even let me talk to her.
They said no to me, her own father.
Jesus.
So I'm going back up there to Somafree.
We'll leave just as soon
as you get here, Frank.
As soon as I get there?
I'll be waiting for you.
I know you'll want to go up there with me.
You're not far from here, are you?
Barton, listen to me.
I don't think that's
a very smart thing to do.
Well, I'm doing it, Frank,
with or without you.
Okay, okay.
I'm only about 15 minutes away.
Wait for me, Barton.
I'll be there.
You're a good lad, Frank.
We'll go up there together
and kick their ass.
I'm waiting on you, Frank.
[Clock Chiming]
I've a feeling I've just
been recruited to babysit.
Please, would you? It'll take 45 minutes.
He's drunk.
He'll drive his car off a bridge or something
unless I talk some sense into him.
- Forty-five minutes?
- That's all it'll take.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
Help yourself to some coffee.
Oh, here.
Look at this while I'm gone.
If you like it, I'll give it to you.
Forty-five minutes.
[Sniffles]
[Tires Squealing]
[Sniffles, Gasps]
[Breath Quavers]
[Sniffles]
[Sighs]
[Breath Quavering]
[Sniffles]
[Sniffling]
[Whimpers]
[Sobbing]
Oh, Juliana.
I never meant it to be this way.
[Sobbing]
[Sighs]
[Voice Quavering]
[Sniffles, Sighs]
[Snarls]
Nola?
[Screeching]
[Barton Groaning]
[Engine Stops]
Barton.
It's me.
[Glass Shatters]
Barton!
Oh, no.
Oh, shit.
[Sighs]
[Screeches]
[Gasping, Wheezing]
[Wheezing Stops]
I can't get over it.
The thing was in the house.
It was in the house all the time.
We searched the place.
But we weren't looking for anything
that small, and we missed it.
We were spending our time
checking out an Estonian musician.
Have you found out
who it belongs to... the kid?
No.
My guess is some crazy woman didn't want
anyone to know she had a deformed child.
She's had this kid locked up in an attic
for years and never told anybody.
Wouldn't be the first time.
[Rings]
Hello.
- Hello?
- [Nola] Who's this?
Ruth Mayer.
Did you want to speak with Frank Carveth?
Ruth Mayer?
From Crell Street School?
Yes.
Is this Mrs. Carveth?
Are you and my husband having your own
private PTA meeting, Miss Mayer?
I won't even bother to answer that.
You bitch!
You're killing my family!
[Ringing]
[Ringing Continues, Muffled]
[Man]
Our friend has very strange eyes.
They have irises, but no retinas.
I should think his vision of the world
is very distorted.
And I'm pretty certain he sees things
only in black and white.
No colors.
The upper lip is cleft.
A real harelip.
But the palate is not.
And the tongue is too thick and inflexible
for proper speech.
He has no teeth...
but you can get a pretty nasty bite
from these strange beak-like gums.
[Frank]
Why did it die?
[Coroner] Well, I found
some sort of collapsed, fleshy sac...
between the little f..low's shoulder blades.
It contains traces
of a solid nutrient material...
a bit like the yolk sac of certain fish...
or a... camel's hump.
Basically, it's a gas tank.
It was full at birth.
Once the hump material
is completely assimilated...
I think the creature
simply starves to death.
Runs out of gas, so to speak.
And that brings us
to the last point of interest.
There's an external deformity.
I mean, apart from
the lack of sexual organs.
It's extremely subtle
and extremely provocative.
I wonder if either of you have noticed.
- It has no navel.
- No what?
No belly button.
The thing has no belly button.
That's right.
And that means this creature
has never really been born.
At least not the way
human beings are born.
Jesus.
You're the beginning
of the end, Miss Mayer.
The beginning of the end for me,
my family, my dream.
So sad.
And I feel so guilty for my part in it.
I wish it had never happened.
I wish we could be together again,
just the three of us.
You're kidding yourself.
Right now you're dreaming.
From what Frank tells me,
it was lousy from the very start.
You never had anything real together.
It would be better for everybody if you...
well, if Frank divorced you
and married me.
We'd still let you see Candy
at the weekends.
That stinks!
That stinks.
We had a lot. We had beautiful things,
things that you couldn't understand.
And we'll have them again
if you'd just leave him alone...
and stop poisoning him against me
and taking advantage of his loneliness.
Then he'd wait for me.
He'd help me to get better
instead of abandoning me.
He would do that
if you would just leave him alone.
If you'd just leave him alone.
If you'd just leave him alone!
Leave him alone!
[Sighs] Hey, listen, I'm sorry.
I called a few times. You didn't answer.
I didn't want to talk to your wife again.
That's why I didn't answer.
- Once was enough.
- Nola called? What did she say?
Look, I have to go.
[Sighs]
Your life is just a little too complicated
for me right now.
I'll, uh... I'll see you
at the next open house.
[Sighs]
[Exhales]
[Car Door Closes]
[Car Engine Starts]
- [Candice Whimpers]
- [Gasps]
[Exhales]
Daddy?
Oh, Candy.
What's the matter, sweetheart?
Why aren't you sleeping?
'Cause I had a bad dream.
A scary bad dream.
What was the dream about, honey?
- I'm afraid to tell you.
- Why?
The dream doesn't want me to.
Candy, listen to me.
I know what happened at Grandma's.
I know what you saw there.
I just came from the police...
and, when I was there,
I saw the thing that hurt Grandma.
And, Candy, it's dead.
I saw it lying on a table.
And the police were there, and it's dead.
It can't hurt you now.
And it can't hurt me or anybody else.
Do you understand me?
It's dead?
Yes.
It's all right now, baby.
It's all right.
[Chris]
What do you think?
How many people do we have
at the main house?
Twenty-seven.
Okay, I want them out by this afternoon.
And the house closed.
It'll be hard on them, Hal.
Especially Mike.
Then do it gently.
But get them out.
All right.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Just put your suitcases
in the compartment.
I don't want to go.
- I don't want to go.
- Michael, you have to go.
- I just want you to get on the bus.
- No!
You'll see the doctor. Michael. Michael.
- No. I don't want to go.
- Michael.
- Don't make me leave.
- I'm not making you leave.
Just be a good boy and get in the bus.
All right?
[All Chattering]
Hi, Jan.
Frank, hi.
Look, I think we got ourselves
a real live one.
Come on upstairs.
There's somebody I want you to meet.
- [Clears Throat]
- Is this the guy from Chicago?
[Chuckles]
Nope. Nope. No.
He's a... He's a local boy. Lives a lot
closer to home than you ever expected.
[Man Whimpering, Crying]
- Hi. Sandra, I've been thinking that...
- Hello, Joe.
- [Whimpering]
- [TV Program Continues, Indistinct]
Um, Trellan.
[Whimpering Continues]
Mr. Carveth is here to see you.
Look who's here.
Nola's old man.
The queen bee's favorite drone.
He's pretty far gone, huh?
He'd be dynamite in court.
What did you mean when you said
Nola's the queen bee?
Oh, she's the queen bee, all right.
She's the star.
She's the one he's interested in.
And the rest of us don't count anymore.
She doesn't even have to pay for it.
And that's because she's the one
who was born to prove...
that Psychoplasmics is...
[Together]
"the ultimate therapeutic device."
- [Mike] That's a quote.
- [Hartog] Mm-hmm.
Will you be my daddy?
He won't do it anymore.
And my real daddy won't do it.
And that bastard, Dr. Raglan,
won't do it anymore.
You see, my real daddy
rejected me, and my...
And my... my surrogate daddy
rejected me.
That's just fuckin' wonderful.
Don't you think?
Calm down, Mike. Cool it
and tell him what happened at Somafree.
Look...
[Exhales]
I'll make a deal with you. Okay?
Just...
be my daddy.
Please.
I'll tell you anything you want to know.
I'll bleed for you. Want me to bleed?
No. That's silly, right?
It repulses you. I-I can see that.
You're not into it. So why do it, right?
Besides...
nobody could do it like Dr. Raglan.
Not even real Daddy.
And he knows it.
Dr. Raglan knows I'm addicted to him...
and he doesn't care.
[Whimpering]
He's such a hard man.
I was at that demonstration last Monday.
You and Raglan seemed... very close.
What happened?
He threw us out, all of us.
Locked the door.
Yeah, it's true. I've been in touch
with some of the others.
They've all been thrown out of Somafree
and all therapy suspended.
All except for your wife.
She's still there.
Doesn't anybody know why?
Sure, somebody knows! I know!
He wants to be alone with her!
Dr. Raglan wants to be
alone with your wife.
- [School Bell Rings]
- [Children Chattering]
- Bye, Daddy.
- Bye.
Frank?
- Hi, Frank.
- Oh, hi. Hi, Wendy.
[Humming]
Work quickly but quietly, children.
[Ruth] Rebecca, wait until I hand out
these papers, please.
[Children Chattering]
Teacher!
[Child Exclaiming, Indistinct]
Rebecca, do you want to pass out
the blue papers, please?
And, Clayton, how about you
pass out the purple ones?
Okay, let's see.
How about this?
[Children Chattering]
[Child Singing]
- This person here?
- [Boy] Yes.
Do the snowflakes too. That's a good idea.
We'll do this larger. Is it...
[Chattering Stops]
- [Screeching]
- Stop!
[Groaning, Shouting]
- [Screeching Continues]
- Help! No! [Grunting]
[Ruth Screaming]
Oh, my God!
[Whimpering]
Help!
[Panting]
- What's the matter?
- They're hurting Miss Mayer!
They're hurting Miss Mayer!
The bad kids are hurting Miss Mayer!
The bad kids knocked her on the floor
and they're hitting her!
They're hitting Miss Mayer! They made her
fall down! They made her fall down!
[Children Whimpering, Crying]
[Whimpering, Crying Continue]
Candy!
Candy?
- Nola.
- Hmm?
It's all right. It's Hal.
Oh.
Hal, where's... Where is Chris?
Chris usually wakes me up.
Chris had to go into the city.
- Mmm.
- You've been dreaming.
Yes, I was having a wonderful dream.
Wonderful.
And painful at the same time.
My daughter was coming back to me.
And Frank.
And Ruth Mayer...
was she in your dream?
Candy's teacher?
I don't remember.
Then maybe we should talk about her.
But I don't feel the need
to talk about her.
You don't? Why not?
I don't know, Hal.
I think I must be
getting stronger because...
somehow, I just don't feel
threatened by her anymore.
Candice!
[Exhales]
This is where my wife and kid
lived for nine months...
before Nola moved out to Somafree.
- [Train Horn Blowing]
- This is the first time I've seen the place.
Frank, what are we doing here?
Tell me again.
- [Train Passing]
- I don't know.
[Sighs]
I thought Candy might come back here.
No.
It's not a coincidence.
Those things, those creatures...
they all disappeared together.
They've got her.
[Static On Radio]
[Sighs]
[Sips Liquid]
[Liquid Splashes In Sink]
[Static Continues]
[Switching Radio Stations]
[Man] The best way to insulate
and finish your basement...
[Clicks Off]
[Sighs]
[Door Rattles]
[Mike Gasps]
You gotta help me.
Somebody's following me.
Somebody's always following me.
Did you find out anything?
Did you find out why they moved you out?
I gotta have something to eat. Anything.
I gotta have something to eat.
Anything.
What did you find out?
Why did they close Somafree down?
Talk to me now!
[Whimpering] Okay.
Raglan's onto something very, very big.
Something to do with the kids.
- He just got bored with the rest of us.
- Kids?
What kids?
The disturbed kids in the work shed.
The ones your wife's taking care of.
[Owl Hooting]
What have you done with my kid?
Where is she?
Carveth, what the hell
are you talking about?
They took her.
They killed Ruth Mayer,
and then they brought Candice back here.
They killed Ruth Mayer?
Raglan, I want my daughter back.
Now.
They bring her back here,
back to Nola?
No, no.
If they brought her back here, then she'd...
then she'd be up there in the attic.
That's where they live.
Frank, I've got a gun.
They'll kill you...
if you try to take her away from them.
Why?
Because in a sense, she's one of them.
You're insane.
Frank, they exist. You've seen them.
They're just freaks, deformed children.
You've got Nola taking care of them.
I'm sure she just loves
being their surrogate mother.
She's not their surrogate mother, Frank.
She's their real mother.
Their only mother.
Raglan, I'm not gonna listen.
They're her children, Frank.
More exactly,
they're the children of her rage.
They're motivated only by her anger...
whether that anger
is conscious or subconscious.
I mean, when... When Nola got cross
with Candy last weekend...
annoyed really...
the brood beat her.
But when she released her rage
against her parents under therapy...
then they killed them.
Now, I didn't want to believe that.
But now they've killed Ruth Mayer.
And they could kill you or me,
and she wouldn't even be aware of it.
I mean, she doesn't even
know that Candy's here.
I want Candice back.
Then do it my way.
Please. It's the right way.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to go back into that hut...
and persuade Nola
that you want her back...
that you want your family back.
I want you to play the role
of apologetic lover and husband.
Why?
Because if you can
keep Nola calm and happy...
then the brood's neutral.
If she's mellow...
then I can just walk into that attic...
pick up Candy,
tuck her under my arm and walk out.
Now, can you do that?
I don't know.
Frank, if things go wrong...
if Nola gets angry, if the kids get angry...
You understand?
I'm not going to be the only one
to pay for that anger.
Raglan, I don't trust you.
What does it matter?
I'll move up there
30 seconds after you're in.
Frank, be nice to her.
Hal?
It's me, Nola. It's Frank.
Frank?
Am I dreaming?
I thought you said you weren't going
to come and see me while I was here.
Well, I think that was a misunderstanding.
That's why I'm here.
I want us to understand each other.
You're the only woman in the world for me.
You always have been. You always will be.
That won't ever change.
I want you to know that.
I wish it were true.
God, I wish it were true.
We've lost touch.
That's the only reason
all this ever happened.
All we have to do is make sure
we don't lose touch again.
Isolation is part of my therapy, Frank.
What's been happening to me
has been just too strange...
too strange for me to share
with anyone from my old life.
Then make me a part of your new life.
Let me be part of it.
Show me, educate me, involve me.
I'm ready now.
I wasn't before, but I'm ready now.
Candy.
Are you ready for me, Frank?
Are you really?
I seem to be a very special person.
I'm in the middle of a strange adventure.
Let me be with you.
I want to go with you wherever you go.
Do you?
Yes.
Then look.
- Candy?
- [Creatures Hissing]
Candy?
Daddy?
Is it time to go to school yet?
No, sweetheart.
It's Dr. Hal.
Your daddy's downstairs talking to Mummy.
He wants to see you.
[Creatures Hissing]
Oh, God, Nola.
No. I disgust you.
I sicken you.
You hate me.
[Creature Screeches]
You didn't come here because you love me.
You came here to take our daughter away
and give her to somebody else.
[Creatures Snarling]
I wouldn't do that.
I wouldn't do that to you.
[Snarling, Hissing]
Candy.
You go out of that door.
You find your daddy.
[Creatures Snarling, Hissing]
You liar.
You're lying.
You're lying! You're lying!
I know!
[Creatures Screeching]
[Raglan Groaning]
- [Pounding Overhead]
- [Gunshot]
[Creatures Screeching]
[Raglan Screaming]
- [Screaming Continues]
- [Blows Landing]
[Raglan Screaming]
I know you so well.
And it won't work. It won't work.
I'd kill Candice before I'd let you
take her away from me.
Do you hear me?
I'd kill Candice
before I'd let you take her!
[Hissing, Snarling]
- [Creatures Screeching]
- [Pounding On Door]
[Pounding Continues]
Make them stop.
[Screeching]
[Screaming]
They're doing what you want them to do!
You want them to kill Candice.
You make them stop, or I'll kill you!
Kill me! Kill me! Kill me!
Kill me! Kill me!
[Gasping]
[Choking, Gasping]
[Screaming]
[Candice Screaming]
[Screaming Continues, Stops]
[Murmurs]
We're going home, Candy.
We're going home.