( Wordless
vocalizing )
Woman: Sometimes,
late at night,
you can still
feel the loneliness...
Like an animal
in the dark,
ready to pounce.
It can make
a warm memory
seem empty
and unfamiliar.
Past things
seem insignificant.
And even faith
can seem trivial
and worthless.
My dear Leon.
I remember
the day you were born.
You were
my little angel.
Always
so full of joy.
So full of life.
And then,
one day...
( Growling sound )
Everything changed.
Man: Our father
who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
More than anyone,
you deserved
an explanation.
You needed to know
why your father
did what he did.
But that is
God's secret.
You were too young then,
too angry to accept it.
Too stubborn to see
that the soul lives on
long after death.
You closed yourself
away,
and as you grew,
i prayed that
your faith would return.
But you only became
more distant.
And sometimes,
late at night,
you still feel
the loneliness,
and you've learned that pain
doesn't give up that easily.
That despair is an affliction
of the godless.
( Busy signal
beeping in phone )
My dear Leon,
you are in
a terrible danger
unless you can recognize
that your soul lives on
long after death.
It is the only thing
that can save you...
And bring us
together again.
( Phone ringing )
Man: Hi. This is bill Phillips
with tribal trade.
I'm not available
at the moment.
Please leave a message,
and I'll return your call
within 24 hours.
Thank you for
using voicemail.
Bill, it's Leon.
Give me a call.
Woman: I wish we could talk
like we used to.
But once you left,
you never came back.
It's been so long
since you even called.
It's so hard
being alone.
There are always
strangers at the door,
and they always
want something.
( Pounding )
This house
is a holy place.
And even though you never
visited me here...
I have left behind
a few reminders for you.
I leave everything I have
to the only person
in my life.
( Door closes )
You.
( Door hinge squeaking )
( Car starts,
drives away )
( Loud scraping sounds )
( Brief low growl )
( Leon speaking
indistinctly )
I spent the entire week
preparing for this,
and I walk in,
and it's all right here.
Bill: I don't know
what to tell you, Leon.
I had strict orders
to buy everything you sold.
And you didn't think
that I'd find that interesting?
Uh, had no idea.
You don't think
it's a little weird
that somebody is only
interested in items
from my personal
collection?
I'm a broker,
you know the drill.
Confidentiality
is always assured.
Listen to me.
I swear,
i had no idea
it was your mother
who was buying up
all your items.
You gotta believe
me, Leon.
Hello?
You there?
Yeah.
I got enough on my mind
just getting the best price,
never mind keeping tabs
on who's buying.
- You know what
I'm saying?
- Yeah.
When was the last time
you saw her anyway?
It's been a while.
I'm sorry. I know
it's a tough time.
Listen, if you wanna put
any of that stuff
back on the market,
just let me know, okay?
I can move it for you all over
again, double your take.
Okay. Yeah.
Um... thanks, bill.
Yeah. Don't mention it.
Call me if you need
anything, okay?
Yeah.
Bye.
( Leon chuckles )
Woman: Come back here.
( Sharp intake
of breath )
( Leon gasps )
( Clicking light switch
on and off )
( Woman whispering )
Believe.
( Remote clatters
loudly )
... angry God!
Ours is
a fearful God!
We have the signs.
- We have the word...
- ( Volume lowers )
Of his ministers
on the earth,
and by our faith,
we see
what the unbelievers
cannot.
...hosts of angels.
The world is full
of atheists,
and sinners
of the mind,
but we are
people of the faith...
( Loud banging
on door )
Hi.
Man: Hello.
I'm from next door.
I was a good friend
of your mother.
Oh, hi,
I'm Leon.
I know
who you are.
She spoke about
you often.
We're very saddened
by what happened.
We mourned her long,
and miss her deeply.
Thanks. I appreciate that.
May I come in?
Now's not really
a great time, but...
Perhaps later then?
Yeah.
We are a close
community here.
We've had many
special moments
in this old house.
It is
truly blessed.
Do you believe
in angels, Leon?
Your mother
believed in them deeply,
as do we.
Perhaps you will join us
once you're settled in.
Yeah, sure.
Thanks for stopping by.
One more thing.
There's an animal
that's come out
of the woods.
It's probably sick,
so it might
be dangerous.
You should
be careful.
Okay, I will.
The woods
belong to God,
but every so often,
something bad
comes out of them.
Okay, I'll keep
that in mind.
Bye, Leon.
God bless you.
Yeah.
( Sighs )
( Thunder crashes,
rain falling )
( Cell phone ringing )
Anna.
Leon, what's up?
Hey. Uh, not much.
How are you?
Well, I'm busy,
as usual.
Yeah. Uh...
You called.
Yeah. I, uh...
( Laughs ) I... I can't
remember why I called.
Um...
Look, I really don't
have time for this.
Okay, no, no, no.
It's just, um...
I'm at
my mom's place now.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, it's...
I had no idea.
- Um...
- ( Anna sighs heavily )
Something happened that
I can't really explain.
What are you
talking about?
Um...
You know, I was
just around and settling in,
and, uh, I left
the room for a second,
I came back,
and there's this statue
on the TV when
I didn't put it there.
In fact, I distinctly remember
seeing it in the basement.
- And you're sure?
- I'm positive.
How are you feeling?
How am I feeling?
( Laughs )
Uh...
I wanna know why
that statue's on the TV.
Tunnel reality.
Tu... what?
I'm surmising,
but the statue has
connotations for you.
Probably not
positive ones.
Is that true?
- Yeah.
So look, you didn't
see the statue,
because you didn't
wanna see it.
It's probably because
you didn't feel
emotionally ready
to see it, and yet,
you clearly have a need
to come to terms with it
since you were the one
that brought it up the stairs,
and put it in plain view
so that you would notice it.
It's the statue your mother
gave you, isn't it?
Yeah, yeah.
Same one she used
to punish you?
It wasn't...
It was more of a test.
No, you don't test
a nine-year-old boy
by lighting candles
and asking him
if he believes in God.
Could've said yes.
Yes, but you said no.
And then, she'd start to
blow out all the candles,
and what would she say
was gonna happen
when all the candles
were blown out?
Leon.
What?
I want to hear you
say it.
Said the angel would
turn its back and...
Stop protecting me.
And that's why
i never liked your mother.
Well, you cleared
it up for me.
Well, it's far from
clear to me.
Okay. I think you need
to give it some more thought,
and allow the feelings
associated with the statue
to express themselves.
Yeah, yeah.
You need to.
So is that all?
You still talk
like a doctor.
I am a doctor.
Good night, Leon.
Night, doctor.
( Keys jingling in lock )
( Low growling )
( Thunder rumbling )
There was a time
when I was everything to you.
A time when
you loved me
as much as
i loved you.
A time when you sought
my comfort
whenever you were sad,
or afraid.
But you never liked
the game of candles.
You never could
forget it.
And a desperate thought
entered your head.
That's when you
started to hate me,
your own mother.
You left me
all alone.
The funeral was empty
without you.
( Thunder crashes )
( Tape hissing )
Man: When communicating
with the dead,
it is not necessary to resort
to elaborate techniques
or obscure
occult rituals.
Spirits communicate through
the most refined apparatus
known to us--
our senses.
It is merely a matter of
tuning ourselves
to the right
frequency
to achieve discourse
with the dead.
All that is required
is a quiet place
close to the deceased,
focused concentration,
and a bit
of patience.
Find a comfortable place
and a relaxing position.
Close your eyes.
Empty yourself
of all your thoughts.
All of your feelings.
All of your worries.
Empty yourself now.
All that is left
is yourself.
The self you know.
The self that is
pure and safe.
You are exactly where
you want to be.
You are aware
of your self
in a way you have
never been before.
Spread out into it.
Feel the warmth
of your living self.
Feel it.
Someone else
is here.
Woman: Leon.
- You know who it is.
- ( Mouths word )
Feel them.
Feel their presence.
Do not rush it.
Think of what
you would like to say.
Think of what you would
like to say to that person,
and say it.
( Gasps )
( Low growling )
( Rattling )
( Sighs )
( Low growling )
( Voices chanting
indistinctly )
( Voices continue )
We can see
what the unbelievers don't.
Raise your arms.
Raise your arms,
and ask the holy host
to look upon us
as he has in the past,
and by his gaze,
strengthen our faith.
Ask, children.
Ask, sister.
Look upon her.
Ask, brother.
Look upon him.
Look upon her.
Look upon us.
Raise your arms, sisters.
Ask the holy host.
Look upon this brother.
This brother of faith.
Look upon us.
Look upon us!
( People screaming
and exclaiming )
Look upon us.
- ( Rewinding tape )
-Look upon us.
Look upon us.
Man: Believe
or suffer.
This is the message
we've been handed.
Our God is a loving God,
but he is also
a God of wrath and anger.
A God of punishment.
Mother: I remember
the day you told me
that you didn't
believe anymore.
( Low growling )
That people
don't have souls.
We come from nothing
and go to nothing.
That's what you said.
How, in one second,
you were alive,
and in the next,
you were gone.
Just like your father.
( Clock ticking
loudly )
And all the time you spoke,
i listened patiently...
( Clock chiming hour )
And then,
it was time to play
the game of candles,
but you got angry
and blew them all out.
That's when you felt
the darkness touch you,
and it felt cold
and empty.
I re-lit it
just in time.
But you were scared,
and you blamed me
for scratching you.
But I was only trying
to protect you.
Only trying to stop you
from making
a terrible mistake.
( Loud crashing )
( Strange animal
noises )
Woman:
Leon.
Hello.
Hello! Anybody there?
( Low growling )
( Pounding on door )
( Deep growling )
( Loud bang )
( Loud banging )
( Ferocious pounding
and growling )
( Breathing heavily )
Woman: Hello, Mr. Leigh.
How can I help you
tonight?
I just had a disturbance
a few minutes ago.
I think, um, someone
may have been trying
to break in my house.
Would you like me to call
the police, Mr. Leigh?
Uh, no, no.
It's okay now.
Okay. Very well, then.
You said this happened
a few minutes ago.
Yeah, that's right.
If you like, we can
review your data online
- with one of our
surveillance experts.
- Yeah, that'd be fine.
- Please hold.
- Thank you.
( Hold music plays )
Woman: And that was
"and the angel said unto them,"
from Philip fournier's
grey childhood.
You are listening to
ascension,
music for
your salvation.
Man: Good evening,
Mr. Leigh.
I understand
you've had an incident
- occur outside
your home.
- Yes.
I also understand
you would like to review
- the data online.
- Yes.
Are you currently in front
of a working computer?
Yes.
Please access our site
at Winchester surveillance now.
Okay.
Please click on
the account tab.
Okay.
Can you tell me
your password, please?
L-e-o-n.
Thank you.
You have been connected.
You have a single camera
outside your home.
- Is that correct?
- Yes.
I will pull the data
beginning from midnight.
Does that sound
reasonable to you?
Yes.
You should be able to see
our data on your screen.
I'm afraid the lighting
is not very good.
I will try to
enhance the image.
Just a moment, please.
What is that moving?
It appears to be
an animal.
What kind of animal?
I regret to inform you
that our information
is incomplete.
Just a mo--
hello?
Hello.
( Loud creaking )
( Creaking )
( Creaking
intensifies )
( Ragged breathing )
Fuck.
All right.
How are you, Leon?
- ( Loud thud )
- Leon.
Hello?
( Breathing heavily )
Um... there's something
happening.
Calm down.
What's the matter?
There's... there's
somebody in the house.
- Who? Who is it?
- I don't know. I just...
Have you called
the police?
No, no, no.
It's, um...
It's not that kind
of somebody.
- Okay, Leon?
- Yeah.
- I want you to do
something for me, okay?
- What?
I can tell you're upset,
so I want you
to trust me, okay?
( Shakily )
Yeah. Yeah.
I want you
to close your eyes.
- Oh, no...
- Trust me, Leon.
Can you do that for me?
( Loud creaking )
- Yeah.
- Okay, good.
- Now listen to me.
- ( Exhales heavily )
- Leon, I want you
to picture
- ( Loud banging )
A pool of water
inside of you.
Can you do that
for me?
- Yeah.
- ( Banging continues )
The water is warm
and calm,
and every second,
it is rising in you.
Feel it rising
in your body,
through your chest.
Can you feel it?
- Yeah.
- ( Banging
continues )
Okay. Can you feel it
spreading out from you,
warming and calming
everything around you?
Can you feel it, Leon?
Yeah.
Flowing through you,
calming you,
washing away
everything around you,
until the only thing
that is left
is the calm.
Now open your eyes.
( Leon breathing
raggedly )
( Silence )
- Leon, are you there?
- ( Exhales shakily )
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah.
Good. Now listen,
it's late,
and I really need
to get some rest.
Okay.
So no more calls, okay?
No.
Good night, Leon.
Yeah, good night.
Thank you.
( Exhales heavily )
( Low growling )
( Floorboards creak,
growling continues )
( Growling )
( Growling and ferocious
pounding on door )
( Loud bang )
( Exclaims )
( Growling
and snorting )
( Ferocious loud growl )
Mother: Leon.
Believe.
No.
- Believe.
- No!
Believe.
No.
I don't believe it.
( Phone ringing )
Tribal trade.
Bill Phillips here.
Bill, it's Leon.
Leon?
What time is it?
I wanna sell everything.
I want it all gone.
I'll send you
a full inventory
in a couple of days.
Um... yeah.
Sure.
Okay? Thanks.
Sorry for waking you up.
Don't go.
There's so much
i want to say to you.
So much
i need to explain.
I waited so long
for you to come back.
I waited so long.
Until I realized
you never would.
That night, I saw
something through the window,
and I told myself
it was just a cat.
I tried to occupy myself,
but I was afraid.
I could feel it
watching me.
I wanted to talk to you
to tell you
that I'd made a mistake,
that you were
more important to me
than anything else
in the world.
But my thoughts
were confused,
and I kept thinking
it was too big
to be a cat.
That's when I realized
what I'd been trying to ignore
for so long.
That you had turned
your back on me.
That you abandoned me.
That you
no longer cared.
That my little angel
would no longer protect me.
( Gasping )
And when faith is gone...
Loneliness can be
a monster.
I thought you would
come to me then.
But you never did.
The funeral
was empty without you.
The loneliness
is worse now
than it ever was.
And all I can do
is remember
the way you were,
and make believe.
Make believe that
you came looking for me.
Make believe
that you felt.
that you hoped.
Make believe
that you remembered.
Remembered that
the soul lives on
long after death,
eternally,
and without end.
Make believe that
you cared.
you miss me...
As much as
i miss you.
( Operatic vocalizing )