(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
MAN: Yeah,
we'll see about that.
(LAUGHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
I wanna be traded.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
SKYLAR: Oh, here's Tommy.
Tommy, Tommy, Tommy.
Happy Halloween!
(SKYLAR LAUGHING) I thought we
were all dressing as babies.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
LAUREN: Sorry. Sorry.
Hey, baby, you're behind me.
I just wanna tell you
I love you!
No biking in the video.
Here.
Doesn't make sense. ALLISON: Oh, gosh.
All right.
(ALLISON EXCLAIMS)
Ow!
(LAUGHING)
Enough. Dan, why are
you so flexible?
(LAUGHING)
(GROWLING)
WOMAN: Let's get out of this...
(ALL SCREAMING)
Did you see that?
JACK: There it is!
(YELLING)
Oh.
TOMMY: It's really cold!
JACK: No, you don't.
TOMMY: I think I'm filming.
Are you filming? Thanks.
TOMMY: So, Jack, anything
you wanna say to Dan?
'Cause this is it, buddy.
JACK: Tommy?
Don't you think if you're
shooting the wedding
you should, uh,
wear some pants?
Hi, how are you?
Dan, today is
your day, my friend,
and we are
happy to be here.
Tommy even wore
his lucky boxers.
We're here for you,
brother, and we love you.
TOMMY: Lauren is late.
(SIGHS) She's gotta be
freaking out that I'm late.
Any pre-wedding advice
for Dan and Skylar?
Put the other person's
needs first.
TOMMY: Hmm. Maybe
that's why I'm still single.
Quit chasing after the wrong girls, buddy.
(TOMMY CHUCKLES)
TOMMY:
How you feeling, buddy?
Do not film me
while I'm peeing.
That's not gonna
make the video.
TOMMY: on, it is, it is.
(SIGHS)
I left my car running
outside if you wanna bolt.
Your car wouldn't make it
out of the parking lot.
It's a piece. What? Just
put some new tires on it.
Could always, uh,
hijack the limo.
You need to find yourself
a girl like Skylar.
Groom wisdom. Nice.
I'm serious.
There's nothing better than
being in an honest,
committed relationship.
Hmm. Coming from the guy
who just joined the church
because his fiancee wouldn't
have married him otherwise.
Hey, the girl gets
what she wants, bro.
(TOILET FLUSHES)
Gentlemen.
Mr. Chapman.
Congrats.
Hey, nice wedding.
Okay, if this is as compelling
content as you're getting,
we're gonna be in trouble.
TOMMY: Oh, I got great stuff with Dan.
Wait till you see it.
I'm sure.
Get out of the way.
Just trying to capture the
good, the bad and the ugly.
(ALLISON GASPS)
Did you just use the word
"ugly" at Skylar's wedding?
(WHISPERS) I did.
You know, you could help.
I am.
I got you in focus.
TOMMY: Mmm.
You, uh, gonna
catch the bouquet?
Yeah, she is.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
♪ Hand in hand
♪ Our hearts
will beat as one
♪ We've only just begun
♪ Time
♪ Still
♪ You're the only one I see
♪ Forever faithfully
♪ When I close my eyes
♪ Moments with you
are surrounding me ♪
All right, let's do this.
Do you, Dan,
take Skylar
to be your
lawfully wedded wife,
and, forsaking
all others,
keep thee
only unto her,
so long as you
both shall live?
I do.
And do you, Skylar,
take Dan to be your
lawfully wedded husband?
ROBERT: I do.
The rings?
I give you this ring
as a sign of my
promise to you.
With all that I have
and all that I am,
I honor you.
SKYLAR: (CRYING)
I give you this ring
(SNIFFLES) as a sign
of my promise to you.
And with all that I have
and all that I am,
I will honor you.
ROBERT: And now,
by the power vested in me,
I now pronounce you husband and wife.
(MOUTHING)
You may
kiss your bride.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
JACK: Dan! Come here!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Hi.
Hey.
Are you the videographer
or something?
Documentaries. I'm doing
it as a favor for Dan.
I was, uh, his wingman
throughout LSU.
Sorry, my name, uh...
I'm Tommy.
Ashton. Nice to meet you.
Nice meeting you.
I'll facebook you.
She's taken, Tommy.
Story of my life.
MR. CHAPMAN: Father,
we come here today to thank
you for Skylar and Dan
and the gift they are
to all of us here.
We ask that you
keep them close
and keep them in your
heart and bless them.
Amen.
(ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Uh...
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
What?
(ALL CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
It's on me.
I will never forget
when Dan called me
and said,
"I'm gonna ask
Skylar to marry me."
Dan said to me, "When
you find the one,
"whether you believe in God,
"whether you believe
in fate or whatever,
"you act on it."
And you did,
and I tip my hat to you
for doing just that.
So let's give a warm round of
applause for the bride and the groom.
(ALL CHEERING)
(CHEERING)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Aw!
GUESTS: Aw!
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
Cake for the girl
at table one.
Is it diet?
Come on, you gotta be done starving
yourself. The Wedding's over.
Mmm. Good point.
Hmm.
Look at that.
Mmm.
So cute.
I've seen you in action at
weddings before, all right,
and currently you're not dancing
on a table or breaking glasses.
Come on. It's me.
I'm at my
best friend's wedding
and I'm upset
because my boyfriend
just gave a speech
on how important it is
to act on it when you cross
paths with the right person.
It was a pretty
good speech.
Mmm-hmm. I crossed paths
with Jack seven years ago.
No, no, I get it.
I get it. I get it.
Mmm.
I'm so lame. I'm sorry.
No, you're not lame.
Okay? You are a catch.
Yeah. Most amazing
girl I've ever met.
What?
Top 100 for sure.
Good. Funny.
But probably number one.
Thank you.
Yeah.
MAN: It's time for the bouquet toss.
Come on, ladies.
One! Oh...
Two!
WOMAN: Throw it
over here, Skylar.
Three!
(WOMAN EXCLAIMS)
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
SKYLAR: Let's get Jack here!
Jack, get up here!
Hey, baby.
You okay?
I gotta go.
Why?
What happened?
Don't worry about it.
Is everything okay?
I love you, and I show it.
So I don't get it.
Either you don't
love me, or you have
a really crappy way
of letting me know it.
Am I missing something?
Seriously,
I don't know what...
You rolled your eyes.
It was a joke.
Honey, I'm sorry.
I can't do this anymore.
Wait. Hold on. Please don't leave.
Please.
I love you.
I'm sorry. We...
Tommy. Really?
Come on, man.
Tommy, please?
What's going on?
Come on, man. I know you got
a camera, but... Ally! Ally!
(SIGHS)
What's going on?
Um...
We'll just talk after.
We'll give her some
time to cool down.
Let's go back and party.
Come on.
You sure? Yeah. Come on.
Let's go.
Thanks for heading up to our
room to get the presents, Tommy.
TOMMY: Yeah, no problem.
Now that I have you guys
trapped, let me ask you this.
What is the secret to staying
married so many years?
I'm always right.
Mmm-hmm.
That's actually correct.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Skylar, if you're
watching this now,
your wedding was
absolutely perfect.
TOMMY: Oh, would she
have it any other way?
It should have
been at the church.
Ah, it was her choice,
even if it's not
what we wanted.
TOMMY: And Skylar always
gets what she wants?
Like mother, like...
Did you feel that?
It just got so cold.
TOMMY: Mr. Chapman... Mrs.
Chapman, what's wrong? You okay?
You okay, Mr. Chapman?
Somebody help me! Help me!
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(WOMAN CRYING)
Somebody help me!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
WOMAN: What's happening?
MAN 1: She's not breathing.
MAN 2: Does anyone know CPR?
JACK: Tommy! Tommy!
Jack, I'm coming.
Stay there. I'm coming.
Sky!
WOMAN: I can't find her!
(CRYING) She's dead.
She's not waking up.
Have you seen my parents?
My mom? Please?
Hey, Jack.
Jack. Jack.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Jack.
I was with Skylar's parents in the
elevator, and they just fell dead.
JACK: What?
They fell over.
They just fell dead.
What?
Skylar, your parents were in
the elevator, and they just...
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
(WHISPERS) I'm so sorry.
Allison. Allison.
(EXPLOSION)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Sounded like a missile.
Come outside. Come on.
MAN: So close!
(SOBBING)
(SIREN WAILING DISTANTLY)
JACK: Look out! Get back!
(CRASHING)
TOMMY: Did you see that?
Jack, Jack, come on!
(RUMBLING)
TOMMY: Earthquake!
Watch out! Watch out!
Run!
JACK: Tommy, look out!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(PANTING)
Run! Come on, Sky! (SCREAMS)
(MAN SCREAMING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Stay with me, Sky!
(GRUNTS)
(SHRILL TRUMPETING)
(SCREAMING)
DAN: Get away
from the window!
(GROANING)
What is that?
Okay?
I need to find Ally.
We don't know
where she is.
(RUMBLING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING)
My phone doesn't
have any service.
Does yours?
Check my phone.
It says she's at 45 North.
When did she text you that?
About a half hour ago.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
We gotta go.
Tommy!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(GAS HISSING)
(SIREN WAILING)
So what do you think
killed all those people?
SKYLAR:
Why are we still alive?
The fact that there
was an earthquake
and the lightning
like that.
I've never seen anything like that.
Did you see their eyes?
Maybe it's aliens!
Yeah, Dan,
it's aliens!
(LOUD RUMBLING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
TOMMY: Look, guys,
over here.
Over here, over here!
MALE OFFICER: I'll stay
right here with you, ma'am.
Keep your head up.
DAN: You okay, Sky?
Does that hurt you?
(GROANING)
I heard my parents talk
about this for years.
What?
It's the biblical
end of the world.
Don't be ridiculous.
It's not
ridiculous.
All the good people
are gone
and all the bad people
are left here.
Whatever's happening is rooted with
science, all right, not fantasy.
No. You're wrong.
Am I? You go
to church, right?
You're a good person,
you're still alive,
so it's obviously not the
biblical end of the world.
Guys, enough with
the religious BS, okay?
It's happened, it's done,
and we all survived. It's
not the end of the world.
We have to get to safety,
'cause things are
gonna get really bad.
What do you call this?
(OBJECT THUDS)
(SKYLAR GASPS)
TOMMY: It's hail.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
JACK: Go, go, go!
(CLAMORING)
Don't let go
of my hand!
(SKYLAR WHIMPERING)
JACK: Here!
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
JACK: Come on!
Get in the library!
Keep going!
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
(SKYLAR SCREAMS)
DAN: Skylar! No!
(SKYLAR GROANS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Where's Skylar?
What?
What do you mean?
Sky!
Get back. Skylar?
Skylar?
JACK: You go that way.
You go that way.
Skylar?
JACK: Skylar?
Where are you?
Skylar?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SHRILL TRUMPETING)
(EXCLAIMS)
He's dead.
He won't bite.
Sam.
Yeah, I was kind
of looking for...
Skylar?
Skylar? Skylar?
Skylar? Sky!
(GASPS)
What's going on?
There's got to be a Bible
in here somewhere.
I'm gonna prove to you
guys what's going on.
Five rows over.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Sky, what are you doing?
JACK: Storm's passed.
We need to find Ally.
Skylar, seriously?
Is this what
you wanted?
See this?
Is that a Bible?
Yes, it's a Bible, Jack.
Mmm. It's not in here.
What?
Rapture. It's not in here.
Rapture?
SKYLAR: Hail.
She's looking for Rapture.
Hail. Hail.
Bro, come on.
We gotta get Ally.
Hail.
"When the first one
blew his trumpet,
"there came hail and fire
mixed with blood."
Sky, that's not helping.
That's not helping us.
I shouldn't be here. I went to church.
I did everything right.
You'll be okay.
We're gonna be okay.
Stop.
It's okay.
We're gonna be okay.
Let's get out of here.
SKYLAR: You guys, please!
We can't leave!
We're going
to 45 North.
We're not going.
No!
You don't understand.
We can't go out there.
She might be at
the church on Camp Street.
She texted you 45 North.
(STAMMERING) You're right.
You're right.
But I know she likes to go to that
church when she's upset and I'm...
When does Ally
go to church, Tommy?
Every time you guys get in a
fight, she ends up there.
What are you talking about?
I'm her best friend.
It's a new thing
for her.
We're going to
45 North.
The church is closer, all right?
And it's on the way.
I think we should
maybe check it out.
What are you guys
talking about?
We have to stay
here where it's safe.
Fine. We're gonna
go to the church.
We're staying.
Sky, this place
isn't safe, all right?
What if there's
another earthquake?
There's no food.
There's no supplies.
We gotta get going,
we gotta stay together.
No, I'm not going.
There's safety
in numbers.
He's right.
We should go.
Wait, "we"?
Yeah, we.
All right, well, we gotta get moving.
Let's go.
This is a bad idea.
We have to
stay together.
Come on.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SHRILL TRUMPETING)
JACK: The church is on
the other side of First...
TOMMY: What is going on?
What could have brought
down these planes?
SKYLAR:
Do you believe me now?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
DAN: (LOW) Stay together.
Stay together, guys.
SAM: ls the church up ahead?
JACK: Come on.
Keep moving, guys.
(WHIMPERING)
TOMMY: Okay,
where is everybody?
Where are the people? What's that?
(HOOFBEATS)
TOMMY: Shh, shh, shh.
SKYLAR: It's the
carriage to our...
Oh, my...
TOMMY: I don't understand.
(LOW RUMBLING)
Dear God,
please help me.
I don't understand
what's going on.
What are you doing?
Sky, praying
isn't gonna help us.
I'm sorry for
not believing in...
Can you hold up?
We gotta keep moving, Dan.
Come on.
It's gonna be okay.
All right?
Please.
JACK: Keep moving.
Just don't let go of me, okay?
I won't.
Did you hear that?
No.
Exactly.
It just got quiet.
(SHRILL TRUMPETING)
(EXPLOSION)
What was that sound?
JACK: I don't know.
Let's keep moving.
(CHURCH BELLS TOLLING)
SKYLAR: Something's wrong.
(TOLLING CONTINUES)
(FLUTTERING)
(GASPS)
TOMMY: Something just flew by.
Feel that?
SKYLAR: God, please
be with us.
Keep going.
Lord, we really need you right now.
(SCREECHING)
Something's in the tree.
(BRANCHES CRACKING)
TOMMY: What is that?
(GROWLING)
(SKYLAR SCREAMS)
I didn't let go. I didn't let go!
She was right here.
She was right here! I didn't let go!
I didn't let go!
What are you talking about?
Where did she go?
SKYLAR: Dan!
JACK: Sky?
DAN: Skylar! Skylar!
(CREATURE SCREECHES)
TOMMY:
The church is right there!
(SKYLAR SCREAMING)
JACK: Let's get inside! Go, go, go!
(CREATURE SNARLS)
DAN: Help! Help!
(CREATURE GROWLS)
JACK: Hey!
(SCREECHING)
(JACK BANGING ON DOOR)
Help!
Get in. Get in.
Is she all right?
(SCREECHING)
Do you know
what did this to her?
what's happening?
SAM: You dropped this.
All the words are missing.
Let's get her into the sanctuary.
(SKYLAR WHIMPERS)
SHAY: Help them, Doug.
Sanctuary, please.
DOUG: Inside. Inside.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
Put me down. Put me down. Are
we gonna be safe in here?
Yes. I think so.
I'm Pastor Shay.
And you are?
Tommy. This is Jack.
Tommy. Jack.
Sam.
Sam, Skylar, Dan.
Let's get some
help for your friend.
(WHIMPERING)
SHAY: I'll find Nurse Rachel.
Rachel! Nurse Rachel!
We need help!
Ally?
Jack!
(SOBBING) Jack! Tommy!
Sky! Is she hurt?
She's okay.
Are you okay?
You came looking for me.
I tried to call.
Everything was dead.
It's okay. It's okay.
How did you know
I was here?
Tommy.
(SOBS)
Oh, where's Lauren?
Where's everyone else?
(MUMBLES)
They're dead, honey.
They're all dead.
(SOBS)
(WHISPERS)
I'm sorry, honey.
(SHUSHING)
RACHEL: What happened?
What did this to her?
We need to
clean out that wound.
(WINCES)
Looks like a stab wound.
(GASPING)
(WHISPERING)
It's okay. It's okay.
(GASPS)
Remember when you
walked into Jack's party?
My jaw literally dropped.
Yeah.
I never saw anybody so
beautiful in my whole life.
I love you, Ms. Gardner.
I'm gonna have to
lift the arm to reset it.
(SOFTLY) Mrs. Gardner.
RACHEL: Ready?
(LOUD SNAP)
(SCREAMS)
(SOBBING)
Good. Now the left side.
Can we maybe
give her a minute?
No. Just do it.
Okay, hey, hey, hey-
You remember when we went to
go get our marriage license
and the office was
over that crazy deli, huh?
We had to wait for a copy
looking at pig's feet.
(LOUD SNAP)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SOBBING)
(WHISPERING)
Hey. Hey. Hey.
(SNIFFLES)
(SOBBING)
(PANTING)
It's okay. It's okay.
(SIGHS)
(SHAY TAPPING PIANO KEYS)
Do you have any idea
what's going on out there?
The Rapture.
Right out of the New
Testament of the Bible.
(SCOFFS)
Oh, come on.
You mean the thingy where Jesus
teleports the good to heaven...
The believers.
...and leaves us heathens...
The nonbelievers.
(SIGHS)
We are all presented
with the same evidence.
I guess it's
what conclusion you
wish to draw from it.
I don't draw
anything from it.
What do you think
attacked your friend?
Aliens, maybe.
(STAMMERING) I don't know.
(LAUGHING)
I can't really explain it.
Aliens?
We'll find out soon enough.
(BELLS TOLLING)
There's more
survivors coming in.
Bring them inside.
One of them's pregnant.
(WOMAN GROANING)
(PANTING)
RACHEL: Wet some towels.
(WOMAN GRUNTING)
It's all right.
Just breathe.
Remember, breathe. Breathe.
There we go. Breathe.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
One more.
HUSBAND: Hold my hand.
(SCREAMS)
Yes!
RACHEL: One last one.
One last one.
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
It's a boy.
(PANTING)
Can I hold him? Please?
Why isn't he crying?
SHAY: Shh.
(SOBBING)
(SHAY SHUSHING)
(SHOVEL SCRAPING DIRT)
SHAY: Follow me.
You, uh...
(SNIFFLES)
You knew the baby was
gonna be a stillborn.
I knew.
He was an innocent.
(MUMBLES)
Why would God kill all these
people and an innocent baby?
He didn't.
He left their mortal bodies
behind and he took their souls.
That baby,
he didn't get death.
He got eternal life.
Bliss.
I was at home with my family
when they all were taken.
Then I heard
the first trumpet.
First trumpet?
You didn't hear it?
I froze.
Knew instantly.
And all I could think
to do was come here.
I'm, uh...
I'm sorry for your loss.
Wasn't my loss.
It was their gain.
Why weren't you taken?
Why wasn't I taken?
You know, just because you
have a church and a title
(CHUCKLES)
doesn't mean that
you have real faith.
I had no relationship.
I just had comfort.
(EXHALES)
And that is how I failed.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
TOMMY: All right, guys,
come on, come on.
Circle up. Circle up.
LAUREN: All right, all of us.
Come on. Whoo!
(VIDEO CONTINUES PLAYING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
(CAMERA BEEPS)
So how's Skylar?
She's all right.
Ally and Dan are
back there with her.
So what do you
want to do?
Hole up here.
Hole up here?
Hole up here until what?
We don't know what's
going on out there.
So at least in here
it seems like we're safe.
So you just wanna sit in
here and see what happens?
Until we figure out
a better plan, Tommy.
Maybe we should move,
find another place.
To where? Can't exactly
move Skylar, can we?
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
(LOUD CRASHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
MAN: Let me in! Let me in!
(CRASH)
MAN: Help me! Help me!
(SCREECHING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GLASS CRACKING)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
(GROWLING)
My name's Tommy Covington.
If you are watching this,
then I'm probably dead.
It's been 10 hours
since everything started,
and we made it to
a church, found help.
Um...
If anything happens, Ally,
there's something I wanna...
I wanna say. (SIGHS)
What are you doing? l don't
like people filming me.
Says the guy
filming everyone.
So, what's so important
you need to tell Ally?
It's complicated.
Complicated.
Don't you think fire and
ice falling from the sky
should uncomplicate things?
Yeah. Probably.
Then tell her what
you wanted to say.
I'll show it to her
if something happens.
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
Allison, I, uh...
When I met you
seven years ago,
we just clicked.
Truth is,
I've loved you
every day since.
And if it's not me,
I just want you
to be happy.
Feel better?
Hmm.
MALE REPORTER:
Video footage has
been streaming in
on a worldwide
mysterious illness
that strikes
without warning
and has caused millions of
fatalities in the past hour.
MAN 1: Oh, my God. Geez.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
People are...
BOY: Help!
MAN 2: Say something.
MAN 1: Oh... This isn't right.
This isn't happening.
What in...
MALE REPORTER: Leading
experts from around the globe
have been unable to determine the
cause of what is being labeled
"instant death syndrome."
(STUDENTS FALLING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
MALE REPORTER: The syndrome
strikes without warning
And has universally caused death
in children and infants worldwide
as well as random segments
of the adult population.
WOMAN 1: Are you okay?
MAN: The car's on fire.
MAN: Get the extinguisher!
(WOMAN GASPS)
(SIREN WAILING)
WOMAN 1: What's going on?
WOMAN 2: We need help over here!
MAN: Give me a hand!
She's hurt!
WOMAN: Are you okay?
She's not breathing.
Go get it, Max. Yeah.
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
MAN: Talk to me.
Are you guys okay?
MALE REPORTER: We will continue to
upload videos as the story progresses
and we'll bring you breaking
updates as soon as we have them.
ALLISON: I'm so sorry about
how I left the reception.
It's okay.
It seems pretty stupid now.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm sorry that I was
the reason you left.
You came looking for me.
That's all that matters.
So how long you been
going to this church?
About six months.
Mmm-hmm.
I don't know, it's not like an
every Sunday thing or anything.
(CHUCKLES)
How come
you never told me?
I knew you'd laugh.
Or roll your eyes.
(SCOFFS)
Yeah, I probably would've.
Then.
Not anymore.
ALL: Surprise!
(SCREAMS)
MAN: Happy birthday!
SAM: Happy birthday, Mom!
MAN 1: We got you.
MAN 2: Aw.
WOMAN: Happy birthday!
SAM'S MOM: I love you all so much,
and you're so wonderful.
So, uh,
where are your parents?
(TURNS CAMERA OFF)
Killed.
Taken.
Whatever they're calling it.
Sorry.
(STAMMERING) I hope
you don't mind crunchy.
You wanna add anaphylactic
shock to our day?
I'm allergic.
Note to self.
So, uh,
why are you here? You're
obviously a good person.
I am a good person.
Just not a churchy
good person.
You never went?
I'm not really a "sit
in a pew" kind of girl.
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
Guess I blew that one.
Yeah, yeah,
I guess I did, too.
Are you this comforting
all the time?
No, no, just...
Just when
the world's ending.
(CHUCKLES)
MALE REPORTER: We have received
several eyewitness accounts
of unusual weather patterns.
Reports and images
from around the world
are both troubling
and foreboding.
The National Weather Service
has issued storm warnings
and travel advisories
from coast to coast
in the wake of this
unprecedented devastation.
Federal, state
and local officials
Are asking all individuals
to stay indoors.
Stay in your homes
for the time being.
Safety is of utmost importance
at this very unpredictable time.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
WOMAN 2: We're safe, okay?
We're almost...
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
I don't know
what I was waiting for.
I think I was
waiting for a sign,
some "eureka"
moment to happen.
And all you gotta do
is make a choice.
I love you.
And I know
that I wanna marry you.
Guys. You gotta see this.
(ALLISON SNIFFLES)
(ALLISON SIGHS)
(STAMMERING) I was filming
and I caught it on tape.
(SKYLAR SCREAMING)
DAN: I didn't let go.
I didn't let go!
She was right here!
May I see what
you're looking at?
TOMMY: Yeah.
(GROWLING)
(SKYLAR SCREAMING)
Revelations 9.
DAN: I didn't let go!
And the fifth angel sounded his
trumpet and opened the abyss.
The sun and sky
were darkened
and locusts
fell upon the earth.
(TAPE PLAYING)
SHAY: Their hair was
like women's hair,
their teeth were
like lion's teeth,
and their wings
made the sound
like the thundering of many
horses rushing into battle.
(FLUTTERING)
TOMMY: Look, you can see it
when I go frame to frame.
SHAY: They were
given stingers
like that of scorpions
to torment people.
JACK: What is this thing?
One of the fallen.
And what do they want?
To torture. To destroy.
Can we fight them?
SHAY: No.
This is the first season
of bad things to come.
What, the first?
It's only gonna
get worse.
(GROANING)
It's not right.
What's not right, baby?
How do you feel?
I've given you
the last dose of Vicodin,
so your pain should come down
just a little bit. Okay, sweetie?
No. Don't touch that.
Let me look.
Just let me look.
SKYLAR: No, stop.
It's burning.
DAN: No, it's okay.
Please, no, it's burning.
I gotta get up. Stop! I wanna get...
Get out of here.
I gotta get out of here!
DAN: Calm down. It's okay.
It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
DAN: Shh.
Listen to me.
It's already
getting infected,
and I don't have any antibiotics
in here to help her.
Where do I get her
the medicine she needs?
My car. I have some
sample packets of amoxicillin,
but it's just too dangerous
to go out there.
Give me the keys. It's not
safe to go out there.
I'm going with you.
l'll go too.
We got this.
Let's go.
RACHEL: It's a green
Chrysler minivan blocked in
on the Sixth Street side.
Just out of
the parking lot.
There's an SUV there,
I think.
(STAMMERING)
Wait. You think?
I'm sorry.
I got blocked in.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
We'll find it. It's okay.
Keys?
(KEYS JANGLING)
Thanks.
Listen. The sample
packets of amoxicillin
are in a duffel bag
at the back of my van.
Hey, you sure you
don't want me to go?
No, we're good.
(EXHALES)
TOMMY: You sure about this?
DAN: Yeah.
Whoa, whoa.
(LOW GROWL)
(WHISPERS)
You hear that?
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(GLASS BREAKING)
(ALARM BLARING)
(HORN HONKING)
DAN: You should get in
the church where it's safe.
Here's the SUV.
Here it is!
TOMMY: Unlock it.
DAN: Why isn't it opening?
TOMMY: Unlock it!
I have an idea.
(ALARM CHIRPING)
(BOTH SIGH)
DAN: Tommy, lights!
MAN: (ON RADIO)
I know what's going on!
Don't believe what the
government is feeding you.
There was no viral outbreak.
Turn that off!
No terrorist attack.
(LOWERS VOLUME) There are
millions of dead all around us.
All the children are dead.
This was the Rapture.
You need to understand that
there is only one way to God.
Only one way to eternal life.
You listen to me.
Stop what you're doing,
get down on your...
I got it, I got it!
(THUD)
(GROWLING)
(PANTING)
Something hit the front.
(LOW GROWL)
(BOTH PANTING)
(GROWLING CONTINUES)
(SCREAMS)
(GROWLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
MAN: You don't act for God.
The power of
Christ compels you!
Run! Go!
(GROWLING)
(ALARMS BLARING)
Run, Tommy! Come on,
Tommy, come on!
(GROWLING)
JACK: They're coming.
Run, Tommy! Run!
Run! Run! Run!
(HONKING CONTINUES)
Open the door!
Tommy!
(DOOR CLOSES)
(HONKING STOPS)
(COUGHS)
JACK: You made it. Oh, good.
You got it. You got it.
(PANTING)
(TURNS CAMERA ON)
TOMMY: What do you
want to say to camera?
I don't know.
Like a confession?
Sure. Yeah. Get something
off your chest.
I don't have
anything to confess.
What do you
want to say, Jack?
(SCOFFS)
Tommy, why are
you still filming?
'Cause if we don't
make it out of this,
somebody needs to know
what happened.
Don't say that.
We're gonna make it
out of this, okay?
(SIGHS)
(CLICKS TONGUE)
My name is Jack Turner.
I don't know why
this is happening.
Don't know why.
But it's not
gonna beat me.
I'm not ready
to call it quits.
I don't know why
you're filming.
Tommy, come on!
Do you love Allison?
Of course.
And it's taken you seven
years to figure that out?
What?
TOMMY: I just want to know
how you feel.
Tommy, what are you doing?
I almost lost her today. How do
you think that feels, Tommy?
TOMMY: (STAMMERING) So it takes
losing her to feel something?
That's not love, Jack.
She deserves somebody
who loves her, all right?
She's a great girl.
Seven years?
What?
Stop it.
Do you know what
I think it is, Tommy?
I think you got a confession
you need to make, Tommy.
Huh?
ALLISON: Guys! Guys!
JACK: So go on. Say it.
Hmm?
I don't have one.
JACK: Come on. Say it.
Say What?
Say it!
ALLISON: Don't!
Say what?
JACK: You hang out
with her all day.
Guys, stop. Stop. Stop.
JACK: You don't date.
So say it, Tommy!
Say what?
Oh, it's not so fun now that
I got the camera, is it?
Say it.
Say it, Tommy.
Stop it.
Fine.
(INHALES)
I love you, Allison.
JACK: I knew it.
(WHISPERS) What?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Whoa! Jack, stop it!
Guys, stop it!
Stop! Now! Stop!
DAN: Katie Murphy.
What?
It was after the LSU-Alabama game.
I, uh, drove Katie home.
And, uh, it was just a moment.
We just got caught up in it.
We both did,
and it happened.
I tried to tell her
before we got married.
She deserves to
know the truth, right?
Dan, it doesn't matter now.
Everything matters now.
Don't you see that?
I'm sorry.
(SNIFFLES)
So, Tommy, confession time
was a good idea.
What'd we learn from that?
You're an idiot.
MAN ON TV: This is an
emergency notification alert.
During this emergency, please
seek shelter immediately.
Do not leave your home,
and avoid going out at night.
If you are unable to survive
under your current conditions,
search for a place of refuge set up
by civil and military authorities.
Civil and military authorities
are establishing relief centers
in major metropolitan areas.
You Okay?
All broadcast
and cable systems
shall transmit this
emergency alert message...
Yeah, I'm fine.
Let's see
how she's doing.
(GASPING)
(WHISPERING) There's nothing
I can do for her.
(SNIFFLES)
The antibiotics
aren't working.
What do you mean?
The infection, it's spreading.
It's acting like a venom.
You said
she needed antibiotics,
and now you're saying
you're not sure.
I've never seen
anything like this before.
She needs an antivenom like
Anascorp or a doctor who can help.
I'm sorry.
(SNIFFLES)
I'm going to the hospital.
No, wait, wait.
It's on the other side of
the freeway, all right?
On the other side
of the freeway?
We almost didn't
make it 30 feet.
I know it's not a good plan, all
right, but we got to save Sky.
It's a couple hours
till dawn.
What does that have
to do with anything?
Listen, those things, okay,
whatever they are,
they've only
attacked at night.
Maybe they're nocturnal.
Does she even
have a couple hours?
She's a fighter.
She's fought it this long.
I'd wait until morning.
Pastor Shay wants to talk
to everyone in the sanctuary.
We leave for the hospital
the second the sun comes up.
Yeah.
Thanks, guys.
(INAUDIBLE)
Come in.
You know, that was the first
real prayer I ever said.
Do you have any idea
how powerful it feels?
Can't say that I do.
It's not too late
for us to believe, Tommy.
God still loves us all.
And if I do make it...
If we make it out of this
mess, we'll be raptured?
No. The Rapture is over.
We missed that boat.
Well, that's no good.
But we have hope in
the path to the Father
and his gift
of eternal life.
You have to make
a choice, Tommy.
And what are you
going to do?
I'm going to be a pastor for
the first time in my life.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
For those of you
whom I haven't met,
l am Pastor Shay.
And I have been a fraud.
It's true.
I walk through this sanctuary
with my soul asleep.
In Matthew, Jesus said
there will be those
who use his name in
fancy speeches and sermons,
and Jesus said unto them,
"I never knew you."
Forgive me, Jesus.
I never knew you.
I was a charlatan.
I was a traveling salesman passing
through life hocking his wares.
Like you and you.
I needed something miraculous
to open my eyes to the truth.
To see clearly.
I hold myself responsible
not only for my failed faith,
but everyone yet
still stands here today.
This is our wake-up call.
The path before us
will not be easy.
It will not go unchallenged.
And this path will lead to pain
and suffering, even death.
But real life, eternal life,
is where the path leads.
But this is our opportunity.
(WHOOSHING)
I can now show
you the way.
We can share this
journey together.
(THUDDING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(THUDDING CONTINUES)
(RATTLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Everyone,
get to the basement!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
Come on! Keep running!
Keep running! Keep running!
Keep up with me!
(DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
(PANTING)
Where's Rachel?
JACK: Has anyone
seen Nurse Rachel?
Is Rachel in here? Rachel?
(PANTING)
(THUDDING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
DAN: It's right above us.
(LOW GROWL)
(THUDDING)
(SCREAMS)
SAM: Tommy?
Tommy, what is it?
(RUMBLING)
SHAY: Everyone be quiet.
TOMMY: Sam.
(THUDDING)
(SCREAMING)
(RACHEL SCREAMING)
JACK: Rachel!
RACHEL: Help me! Help me!
JACK: Rachel! Rachel!
Rachel!
Rachel! Rachel! Rachel!
(LOW GROWL)
(CREAKING)
SHAY: Forgive me.
There's only one way out.
They're here for me.
JACK: Shay,
don't go out there.
No, Shay!
(GROWLING)
(SHAY SCREAMING)
(FLESH RIPPING)
(GROWLING)
WOMAN: Please. Please.
(LOW GROWL)
I don't hear anything.
I'm gonna open the door.
You ready?
ALLISON: Yeah.
DAN: Come on, Sky.
The sun's up.
Let's get to the hospital.
(CREAKING)
ALLISON: (WHISPERING)
Baby, do you smell that?
(SNIFFING)
(COUGHING)
(SNIFFS)
(WOOD SNAPPING)
Look at me.
Hey. All right?
Don't look. Come on.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(CROW CAWING)
TOMMY: I think it's okay.
Come on.
(PANTING)
DAN: This is crazy.
MAN: Hey, there's
nothing that way.
It's gone.
WOMAN: Come on, let's just
get to the relief center.
JACK: Where are
these people going?
DAN: Let's find you a room.
JACK: There's got to be
a doctor here.
DAN: Help her.
Please. Please help her.
We're getting out of here.
There's a relief center
at the Riverfront Bridge.
There's nothing.
Nothing.
(WHEEZING)
You got her?
DAN: Yeah.
TOMMY: The place has been
ransacked, cleaned out.
There's nothing
in that pharmacy.
Guys,
there's nothing left.
(WHEEZING)
Hey. I'm gonna go upstairs
and find her a doctor, okay?
Someone who can help. There
has got to be a doctor here.
I'm gonna go with him. Sam,
Sam, you stay here, okay?
Tommy.
Be careful.
(WHEEZING)
(PANTING)
Jack!
Jack, wait up.
Jack.
Jack!
MAN: I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Look, I need this.
I can handle this
on my own, Tommy.
Yeah, I know.
(GROANS)
(RASPY BREATHING)
I read somewhere that the
light you see before you die
is just your brain
releasing massive amounts
of endorphins to ease
the pain of death.
Some people believe that.
There are others that believe the
light is a sign of God's existence.
Do you believe that?
I do.
(SIGHS)
JACK: Son of a...
Why do you have
to get to a point
where something's going
to be taken from you
for you to realize
how important it is?
No need to explain.
I know you love her.
Yeah.
(SCREECHING IN DISTANCE)
(WHISPERING)
Did you hear that?
(SCREECHING CONTINUES)
(SCREECHING)
Did you hear that?
(BANGING)
What was that?
Shh.
(SOFTLY) One,
two,
three.
(WATER DRIPPING)
(BOTH EXHALING)
(THUMPING)
Let's keep going.
(TOMMY SNIFFS)
(RASPY BREATHING)
Hi, sweetie.
Hey-
I'm right here.
Are you still hurting?
I don't really
feel anything.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I forgive you
for everything.
How did you...
I heard you.
I love you.
(SNIFFLES)
Dan...
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Where I grew up
if you didn't go to church,
people looked at you funny.
So that's what I did.
I never really believed.
(WHEEZES)
And that's okay.
I get it now.
I love you.
Do you see that?
It's so bright.
It's beautiful.
(INHALES)
(EXHALES)
DAN: (SOBBING)
No, please.
Stay with me, Sky.
Please stay with me.
Hey. Hey.
(SOBBING)
Don't leave me.
Somebody help her,
please!
Dan, there's no one
here to help her.
(SOBBING)
DAN: How can you sit there
and pray to a god that would
let this happen to her?
She was your friend.
Dan!
(CLATTERING ON FLOOR)
Will you do
something for me?
I was wrong,
and I realize that now.
I spent my whole life telling
myself that I was spiritual
and that was enough.
(VOICE BREAKING) Obviously,
that didn't work out too well.
(SOBBING)
DAN: I hate you!
I hate you!
What's Dan doing?
I hate you, you hear me?
(SCREECHING IN DISTANCE)
(KNOCKING ON GLASS) Come on! Give it to me!
I'm right here!
Dan!
JACK: Dan, stop!
I hate you!
Dan, no!
Give it to me, God!
Dan, stop!
God, are you even listening to me?
(PANTING)
(SOBBING)
Please.
(GRUNTING)
No, Dan!
(SOBBING)
We don't have much time
left on this earth.
We have to make a decision.
(GROWLING IN DISTANCE)
(GASPS)
JACK: Ally?
Ally?
Oh, no.
(TOMMY SNIFFLES)
(STAMMERING) Listen, maybe
they're looking for us.
This way.
JACK: Ally?
Ally?
No, please.
(VIDEO REWINDING)
(ALLISON SCREAMING)
ALLISON: Go! Sam, run! Run!
Run! Don't look back!
Don't look back! Just go!
Just go!
(ALLISON SCREAMING)
(SNIFFLES)
JACK: She's not here!
Ally's not there.
(SNIFFLING)
Tommy, what do you see?
What's wrong?
Oh, God, no.
No, no.
SAM: I was hiding.
(SOBBING) They didn't get me.
I was so scared!
TOMMY: You're okay.
You're okay.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're okay. You're okay. (SOBBING)
Let's go.
(SOBBING)
Listen, we got to go.
We need to get
to the relief center.
I'm not leaving her.
You can go.
No, you were my best friends
and I will not leave you.
I'm not leaving her!
You can go! No.
No, I won't.
Just go.
No.
Jack, she's gone.
I mean it. Go.
She's...
Shut up!
SAM: Stop! Stop!
Get off of him!
There's nothing
out there that I want.
Do you understand that?
Do you understand? (PANTING)
Then I'm staying, too.
So take all the time
you need.
We'll stay as long
as it takes.
(FIRE CRACKLING)
SAM: Do you think
we'll be safe there?
TOMMY: The military must be
at the Riverfront Bridge.
They'll have food, supplies.
They'll know what to do.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
There it is.
MAN: (OVER PA)
The governor
has issued an edict
asking all nonmilitary personnel
to check in at the main gate.
Food, shelter, donated
clothing and medical supplies
are available
to all those in need.
For those with more serious
medical conditions,
please report to the triage
area outside our hospital tent,
where you can be evaluated and
treated in a timely manner.
If you have any
further questions,
please ask any uniformed military
personnel stationed throughout the area.
You think that's where they're
setting up the church?
I heard they're
bringing in a chaplain.
It's the group
from the church.
You made it. Welcome.
Come and get warm.
Warm yourself here, huh?
WOMAN: It's good to see you.
Now what?
MAN: Get in line
right over there.
(MAN TALKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA)
OFFICER: Please get
this to the chapel.
I need to show
you guys something.
(SNIFFLES)
I was wrong,
and I realize that now.
I spent my whole life telling
myself that I was spiritual
and that that was enough.
(SNIFFLES)
(VOICE BREAKING) Obviously,
that didn't work out too well.
(SIGHS)
But now,
I found real faith.
These demons are here
to remove the Word of God.
(SNIFFLES)
Don't you see?
It has to be the truth.
Even they recognize it.
We all have to make a choice.
(SNIFFLES)
We can choose to
accept and believe
and get life like
we've never known it,
or continue to live
selfishly, ignoring God,
and end up dying anyway-
(SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
(ALLISON SNIFFLES)
We all have to
make a choice.
We don't have much time
left on this earth.
You have to
make a decision.
(RATTLING)
(SOBBING)
I choose God.
Go! Go! Sam, run!
Run! Run!
(SAM SCREAMING)
(TURNS OFF PHONE)
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA) (CLEARS THROAT)
SAM: Is he
going to be okay?
TOMMY: Give him some time.
CHOIR: (ON PA)
♪ Amazing grace
♪ How sweet the sound
♪ That saved a wretch
♪ Like me
Faith.
What'd you say?
They're drawn to faith.
We got to find Jack.
(CHOIR CONTINUES SINGING)
SAM: Wait! Tommy!
TOMMY: Turn off the music!
Turn it off! Turn it off!
Where's the PA? Where's the PA?
Turn off the music.
♪ 'Twas grace that taught... ♪
(SONG CONTINUES INDISTINCTLY)
TOMMY: Turn the music off!
Baptism is an outward sign
of an inward commitment.
Jack!
It's also like taking
the witness stand
to declare the truth
of the Gospel
to all who are present.
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
They're coming!
Jack!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(BONES CRACKING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
TOMMY: Sam!
Sam!
Sam, I got you. l got you.
(GROWLING)
There's only one way, Tommy.
We have to make a choice.
Jack did. Allison did.
And I think they made
the right one.
The choice is ours, Tommy.
It always has been.
Listen, don't go.
I choose God, Tommy.
You should, too.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(SHRILL TRUMPETING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(TOMMY SCREAMING)
(STATIC)
(BELLS TOLLING)
(WOMAN VOCALIZING)