(DISTANT HAMMERING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MINISTER: "...things I heard,
as it were,
"the voice of much people
in heaven, saying,
"Hallelujah.
"Salvation and glory
and power is to our God.
"For true and just
are his judgments,
"who hath judged
the great harlot
which corrupted...
"...with her fornication,
"and hath revenged the blood
of his servants,
at her hands.
"Come,
gather yourselves together
to the great supper of God.
"That you may eat
the flesh of kings,
and the flesh of tribunes,
"and the flesh of mighty men,
and the flesh of horses,
"and of them
that sit on them,
"and the flesh of all freemen
and bondmen,
"and of little and of great.
"And I saw the beast,
and the kings of the earth,
"and their armies
gathered together
to make war with him
"that sat upon the horse..."
Bring on some water!
"And the beast was taken,
and with him
the false prophet,
"who wrought
signs before him,
"wherewith he seduced them
who received
the character of the beast,
"and who adored his image.
"These two were cast alive
into the pool of fire,
burning with brimstone.
"And the rest
were slain by the sword
"of him
that sitteth upon the horse...
"...and all
the birds were filled
with their flesh."
MALE NARRATOR:
The year is 1645.
England is in the grip
of bloody civil war.
On the one side
stand the Royalist party
of King Charles,
on the other, Cromwell's
Parliamentary party,
the Roundheads.
The structure
of law and order
has collapsed.
Local magistrates indulge
their individual whims,
justice and injustice
are dispensed
in more or less
equal quantities
and without opposition,
an atmosphere in which
the unscrupulous revel
and the likes
of Matthew Hopkins
take full advantage
of the situation.
In a time
where the superstitions
of country folk
are still a powerful factor,
Hopkins preys upon them,
torturing and killing
in a supposed drive
to eliminate witchcraft
from the country
and doing so
with the full blessing
of what law there is.
However, his influence
is confined largely
to the eastern sector
of the country,
East Anglia,
which is held firmly
in Cromwell's grasp,
but not so firmly that
the Roundhead cavalry patrols
have everything
their own way,
for there still exists
an ever-present threat
from the remnants of
the Royalist armies,
desperately foraging
for food,
horses and supplies.
Stop that, Richard.
What?
What you're thinking.
What am I thinking?
Ungodly thoughts
of your Sara,
that's my guess.
Thoughts of Sara, yes.
Ungodly?
Depends on how
you look at it.
And you,
a supporter of Cromwell...
Hold your talking, you two.
Yes, sir. Of course, sir.
We'll be stopping
in a few minutes
to give the horses a rest.
You can gabble
all you want then.
15 minutes
and we'll be on
our way again.
(SCREAMS)
Get down. Royalist snipers.
Probably only a few of them
after food and horses.
We'll flush
the bastards out in no time.
Marshall, you stop behind
to keep an eye on the nags.
The rest of you follow me
and keep spread out.
SOLDIER: Captain, look!
There's one!
CAPTAIN: I see him! Follow!
(GUN FIRES)
(MAN SCREAMING)
CAPTAIN: Harcourt, this way.
Robert?
Captain?
Captain Gordon, is that you?
We're here,
trooper Marshall.
It's quite all right.
Getting a bit nervous,
were you, lad?
Aye, just a bit, sir.
Well, no need to worry.
We got them all, I reckon...
Not quite all.
One of them got away, sir,
though I put
my sword in him first.
We'd better move on
out of this wood, then.
If he has got away,
he could still be dangerous.
Swallow, bury Brace's body
as soon as you can.
Look out, sir!
(SCREAMS)
Thank you, trooper Marshall.
He was trying
to kill you, sir.
I gather that, trooper.
It was a lucky shot, sir.
Yes.
Nevertheless, it could have
ended my career for good.
Right, we move out.
Swallow, join us
as soon as you've finished
your business here.
Harcourt, give him a hand
to remove the bodies.
Yes, sir.
ROBERT: So, you granted
young Richard here
leave, did you, Captain?
I did.
Aye, two days.
Then you'll be away
to see your girl,
I suppose.
And how will she greet you?
Just promoted cornet
for killing King's men.
She knows my
reasons for fighting
and it's only
while the trouble lasts.
(ROBERT CHUCKLING)
What are you laughing at?
Leave him be, Robert.
Can't you see he's in love?
Aye, I'm not
ashamed of it, either.
A toast, lads,
to the lovely
women of Suffolk.
And may they
keep their beds warm
for General Cromwell's
gallant men.
(SOLDIERS LAUGHING)
Come on, boy. Nearly home.
Well!
Master Marshall, welcome.
I trust you're well, sir.
My body is as strong as ever,
but the war continues?
Aye, we still fight.
And why...
Well,
my company's recruiting.
I have two days' leave.
Then you must eat
with us this evening.
I thank you, sir.
We still have good food
for all you soldiers
take it from us.
And ale. Come,
we shall drink together.
After your experience,
it is likely
our village has grown
a little smaller
for you, eh, Richard?
Not so much smaller
as lacking in promise,
perhaps.
In Ipswich or Cambridge,
a man might find
better opportunities.
Richard,
if you took Sara to wife...
You mean,
you'd give us your blessing?
You would take her
away from here?
You honor me, sir,
but I only have a small farm
that belonged to my father
and my soldier's pay,
which is...
I am little concerned
with your ill kept lands.
And still less
for the silver you get
for killing good Christians.
Well, forgive me.
That was unjust.
But there is trouble
coming to this village
and I want Sara far away
before it arrives.
Surely Suffolk should be free
from the King's armies.
It's not only
the King's armies
which bring death this year.
A lack of order in the land
encourages strange ideas.
You mean more rebellion?
I'm sorry,
you have worries
enough already.
But give me your word
that you will soon take Sara
away from here
and you shall ask
her consent tonight.
You have my word
on that, sir.
Good, Richard. Good.
That's right, my dear.
Master Richard Marshall.
Farm boy into soldier.
Welcome back,
Master Marshall.
I'm glad to be back,
Mistress Sara.
By the way, Sara,
I expect the meal
at the usual time.
(CHUCKLING) Yes, Uncle.
Your uncle
has agreed to our marriage.
Richard.
(RICHARD LAUGHING)
Oh, the army has taught you
rough manners.
Sara, why is he frightened?
There have been threats to us
since you were last here.
Threats? Why?
We've been called
papists and idolaters,
and filth
chalked up on the walls.
They say
we're King's creatures
and should be
pilloried and worse.
Who says these things?
We've become outcasts
in our own village.
Rest easy.
Now, no one shall harm you.
I put my oath to that.
Have you arranged a day
for the wedding, Richard?
No, sir.
Much depends
on how the armies move.
Remember, it must be soon.
But how certain
are your fears
of this danger?
Perhaps just
an old man's bad dream,
and being an old man,
I must early to my bed.
Good night, my dear.
Good night, Uncle.
Oh, and Sara, remember to see
the doors are well bolted.
Yes, Uncle.
And Richard,
don't keep Mistress Sara
up too late.
Country women
need full eight hours
in their beds
if they're to be
proper wives and mothers.
Goodnight, Cornet.
Goodnight, sir.
And will you
make a proper wife
and mother, Sara?
I still have
much to learn, Richard.
I'll teach you.
Now,
didn't your uncle just say
you must early to bed?
He did.
And isn't he a wise man?
He is.
Right.
How much further, Matthew?
You will not call me Matthew.
I'm not one of
your drinking cronies,
carousing
and wenching in the taverns.
Aye, you're not that, sir.
Remember, John Stearne,
you ride with me
only because
you help me in my work.
Oh, you call it work?
It's the Lord's work,
a noble thing...
And a profitable one.
The Good Lord
paying in silver
for every hanging.
That is blasphemy, Stearne.
Hold your tongue.
I'm merely an honest man
who helps you get
your confessions.
The law
has prescribed due methods
of interrogation.
And I have been
blessed with the skills
to carry them out.
Oh, stop your gabbling.
We have work to do
in Brandeston.
Who is it this time?
The message
tells of a priest.
A priest?
One who gives
worship to Satan
and calls him Lord.
Oh, with the priest
himself a witch,
there'll be others
corrupted, too, I'm thinking.
You enjoy torture,
don't you, Stearne?
And you, sir?
Goodbye, sir.
LOWES: God be
with you, Richard.
Goodbye, Richard.
Goodbye, Sara.
I'll see you again soon.
(BELL CHIMING)
Given up ale for star-gazing,
Tom Salter?
Not star-gazing,
Master Marshall. Waiting.
What for?
Matthew Hopkins, a lawyer.
Must be important,
that you wait after dark.
It is, that.
Aye.
Well, if I see
a lawyer on the road,
I'll tell him you're here.
How far is it to Brandeston,
friend?
About three miles.
Thank you.
Are you the lawyer?
Aye.
Name of Hopkins?
Aye, Matthew Hopkins.
And this is my assistant,
John Stearne.
Why do you
want to know, soldier?
There's some men
from the village back there,
waiting for you.
Aye, they sent for us.
What would a lawyer
want in Brandeston?
A man who may not be
what he seems to be.
Come Stearne.
John Lowes is his name.
An evil man.
A papist.
Yeah,
burning candles and all.
That is no proof
of witchcraft in itself.
Dressed himself
in devil's garments,
he did.
And made unholy signs.
Yeah, he did. I saw him.
I will find out
the truth for you.
Have no fear, friends.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Yes?
John Lowes?
So, it has come to this.
You accuse me, a priest,
of working with the Devil.
We can only judge
by the evidence.
And there's a lot
of that, old man.
I reject
your accusations totally.
He's going to
give us trouble.
A simple confession, priest,
that's all we ask.
Help us.
We've got a lot of work to do
in Brandeston.
Leave my house,
the pair of you.
I told you he was
going to be difficult.
I reject your
foul suggestions!
Leave here at once!
All you reject
is the true God!
Take him, Stearne.
Look for
the Devil's marks upon him.
Right. Help us, you two.
(MUMBLING IN LATIN)
Look,
he still prays to Satan.
Get on with your task.
If the Devil made you
a priest,
he's going to have
hidden his mark
with a lot of care.
(SCREAMING)
To what purpose is this?
When the Devil buys a soul,
he marks
the person's flesh,
so we will know him.
If such a mark is pricked,
no blood will flow,
nor pain be felt.
(SCREAMING)
Mistress Sara?
They've come for him.
(BOTH CHATTERING)
Seems Satan has hidden
his mark well, Matthew.
Set him to running.
Quick, then,
you two, around the table.
And keep him moving.
You would be his niece.
Your name, child?
Sara.
I am Matthew Hopkins,
Witchfinder.
Being his niece,
you, too,
may be corrupted by Satan.
No, not his niece.
A foundling,
taken in by him
and his housekeeper.
Are you telling me the truth,
child?
Yes, yes, of course.
When she died,
I became his servant.
And you've remained innocent
all of these years?
Yes, sir, entirely.
I trust you know the old man?
Better than anyone.
In private talk,
we may shed some light
on his innocence.
Private?
Yes,
away from the distraction
of the crowd.
Perhaps in the quiet
of your room tonight,
you might be able to help me
prove him guiltless.
Would you release him now?
You might be
convinced tonight
that this is all needless.
And you will make
every effort to present
the facts to me?
You may come
to my room tonight, sir.
At what hour?
At 8:00,
if you'll release him now.
All right.
He can sleep in the jail,
and we'll be rid of him.
SALTER: Come on!
Get up, you papist bastard!
Has he confessed yet?
Not a word.
Well, then stop this.
But he hasn't confessed.
Take him to the jail.
We'll continue
the interrogation tomorrow.
LOWES: Jail...
You heard what he said.
Quiet down, you animal.
(WOMAN GIGGLING)
You know what, Marston?
There were these couple of
right filthy girls,
filthy they were!
Horrible to behold, horrible!
Witches?
Yes, both of them.
We hanged them,
Matthew and me.
Matthew. You know Matthew,
he's my partner.
Did it take you long to get
a confession
out of them, John?
Well, a couple of days
with one of them,
the other one...
Do you want more ale, sir?
SALTER: Go on, then? Come on.
What about the other one?
Tell us about her.
STEARNE: Oh, yeah,
the other one.
Now, she was a real
strange one, she was.
Loved us for it,
like she wanted
to get strung up.
Reckon that was the only bit
of excitement she ever had.
Well, go on, then,
Mr. Stearne.
Go on.
(GIRL SCREAMING)
HOPKINS: Sara,
I've come to question you.
You came here
for a purpose, sir.
I came here
to get your evidence
about the priest.
He's been kind to me.
Perhaps he had a motive.
Men sometimes
have strange motives
for the things they do.
I know.
My motive in coming here
was to find the truth.
How about the priest,
Master Hopkins?
We'll have done with him
in a day or two.
Have no fear, child.
He's been good to me
in his way.
He is an idolater.
He must confess and die.
Stearne will see to that.
Oh, no, please!
Don't let him be harmed,
please!
You seek to protect a witch
from rightful justice?
Oh, no, not that,
but couldn't he
be kept in a cell?
He could do no harm
from a prison cell.
Oh, please!
But justice
must be done, my dear.
Grant me this.
Please, Matthew.
HOPKINS: Past noon,
you unkempt lout. Get up!
Get away!
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
I need air.
(STEARNE RETCHING)
Where's the priest?
Where you put him,
in the jail.
We'll get him out
and start
questioning him, then, eh?
No.
What?
He stays where he is.
But we have
no confession at all.
I said
we'll leave him in the cell.
All right, then. All right.
What about the women?
When are we going to start
interrogating them?
I hear tell
they've a good few witches
around this place.
When you're in fit condition.
I'm fighting-fit as it is.
Oh, and where were you
last night, Matthew?
I hear tell
you've been a-wandering.
You hear tell too much, man.
(WOMAN CRYING)
You, there, old man.
Master Hopkins,
the Witchfinder,
he says you're
to be kept here,
interrogated no further.
Where are you off to, John?
I'm going for a walk.
By myself.
(DOG BARKING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
STEARNE: Tell me!
Tell me! Tell me!
Tell me that!
Come on! Tell me!
Confess, witch!
Tell us your foul iniquities!
No!
Your familiars, woman.
Confess!
(STEARNE LAUGHING)
Stop. For God's sake, stop.
Quiet,
old man, and be thankful
you're not getting the same.
(STEARNE YELLING AT WOMAN)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
How many of them?
A dog? A ferret?
Come on, tell them!
John.
The Witchfinder, he's coming.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
I trust you are using
the prescribed methods,
Stearne?
Naturally.
Has she confessed?
Well, give me time.
She's only been here an hour.
Continue with
the interrogation.
I shall be gone for a while.
You're always going
off somewhere, sir,
aren't you?
What do you mean?
Nothing.
I've been
called over the hill
to the next village.
I shall be back by tomorrow.
You will remain
in charge here.
Carry on your work
while you're away, aye, sir?
Indeed.
And the priest?
I said to leave him be.
(WOMAN CRYING)
(SLAPPING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
What do you want?
You.
Where's Master Hopkins?
Gone.
Gone?
Where?
Just gone.
He's left me in charge.
(SCREAMING) No! No!
No!
And don't think I don't know
why the old priest
is being spared, eh?
(STEARNE GRUNTING)
(SARA SCREAMING)
(DOG BARKING)
Stearne, the priest.
I've changed my mind.
STEARNE: Confess!
Confess.
He confessed.
You heard him.
I've heard nothing yet,
Master Hopkins.
Refresh Master
Salter's memory, Stearne.
You heard him.
You did, too.
Yes, Master Hopkins.
Witnesses.
(MOANING)
SALTER: Get up,
you blasted witch! Get up!
Come on!
(SOBBING)
(MAN YELLING)
(PEOPLE YELLING AND SCREAMING)
You are, all of you,
confessed idolaters.
However, these proceedings
shall be carried out
through due process of law.
What law demands,
we shall satisfy.
You will each be tied
in a prescribed fashion,
and cast into the moat.
Should you then sink,
we will know
that your confessions
are false.
If on the other hand
you are seen
to swim or float,
then your
confessions of witchcraft
are proven beyond a doubt
in the sight of God.
And you will be
withdrawn from the water
and hanged by the neck
until you are dead.
You can't hang me.
The law forbids it!
I'm with child.
And who would want
to make you pregnant, witch?
(CROWD LAUGHING)
Quiet. Stearne,
go on with your task.
(WOMAN CRYING)
WOMAN: Oh, God, help me!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
WOMAN: No!
No!
LOWE: Help me...
Hey, look!
One of them is gone already.
They swim.
The mark of Satan
is upon them.
STEARNE: Give us a hand here!
Come on!
They must hang.
She was innocent.
God forgive you,
Matthew Hopkins.
Jailer,
take them to the tree.
The money from the magistrate,
nine guineas in silver.
Good. Now we can leave.
Good morning, soldier.
Good morning.
What'll you be
after in the way
of horses, then, aye?
A dozen or so
for General Cromwell's
armies up north.
Well, lost a few, have you?
Aye, at Cheriton Wood.
That's a pretty
sorry looking bunch
of old nags
you got in there, friend.
The best we could find.
Then they'll have to do.
A dozen you say, eh?
Aye.
We'll be back
in Suffolk soon
where, thank God,
they still breed
strong horses.
Oh, I doubt you'll
find much better there.
I'm just back
from those parts.
The mounts up there
are much like these.
Have you been through
Brandeston at all, man?
Brandeston? Aye.
And a fine commotion
they're stirring up there.
What,
over you taking their horses?
No, nothing like that.
A mass hanging.
Who?
Witches, I heard.
Two women and a priest.
Where was
the priest from, man?
Brandeston, I suppose.
A brave old boy
for all his white hairs.
Was he a friend of yours?
Two troopers,
Gifford and Harcourt,
will be here directly.
Have them take
these horses here
back to the regiment
and report that I'm delayed.
I'll join them further north.
Do you understand?
Yes, but where
will you be going to?
Anything else?
(URGING HORSE)
Sara!
Sara?
Sara.
Sara!
They took him and killed him.
They said he was an idolater.
I know, I heard.
Sara...
One of them, the Witchfinder,
he...
He...
I didn't want to...
I thought I could save him.
I thought they'd have pity.
We kneel before thee,
oh, Lord, in humility
to ask for a blessing
on our union.
We ask for forgiveness
of our sins
and strength
to lead righteous lives
as man and wife.
We pray also
for the soul of thy servant,
John Lowes.
May he know eternal peace.
And it is in thy sight,
oh, Lord,
that I hereby swear
I shall not rest from
the pursuit of his murderers
till they stand before thee,
ready to answer
to thee for their sins.
Take this money and whatever
you need from the rectory
and go to Lavenham.
You'll be safer there.
I will, Richard.
Find lodgings and stay there.
I'll come to you.
I love you very much.
Oh, Richard!
(SOOTHING HORSE)
(SHEEP BLEATING)
Shepherd, I seek two men.
Witchfinders,
they call themselves.
They were said
to be headed this way.
Matthew Hopkins
and his assistant?
Aye.
I've heard
they're in Hoxne,
about four miles yonder,
but I can't be sure.
Thank you, Shepherd.
SHEPHERD: Get out!
(URGING HORSE)
Oh, come on, Johnny,
give us a kiss.
Oh, get away from me.
Stop it, you dirty rascal!
Stop it!
STEARNE: Here,
I'll bet you two pennies.
Ale, soldier?
Aye, to wash
the dust from my throat.
Another one for you?
Aye, get a move on with it.
She's got
a powerful thirst still.
Landlord,
I'm looking for a man
called Hopkins.
I heard he was
coming this way.
Matthew Hopkins?
Would you know
where he is, friend?
Aye,
he's gone to Cambridge today.
But you got
an accusation to make,
I'll get
your confession for you.
I do the pricking,
you know, not Matthew.
I'm your man, friend.
John Stearne, they call me.
(SCREAMING)
I'm husband to Sara Lowes.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You all right, friend?
Yeah.
You better get out of here.
Yeah, I'm going,
don't worry.
As for you, soldier,
you are coming down
to see the magistrate.
Am I? Not with you.
(URGING HORSE)
Quick, Matthew!
For God's sake, Stearne,
what have you done?
Who was that?
Richard Marshall.
Who?
He's married to the girl,
Sara.
How did he find you?
He was looking for you.
He found out
about Brandeston.
We're going to
have to separate.
I won't run from him.
We have work to do down south
in Lavenham.
Not me. He's after our blood.
Seems to me he's already had
some of yours.
Well, he's not
going to have any more,
you understand?
You're forgetting our powers.
He could be a witch.
He's a man who's out
to kill both of us.
Then it appears to me
that we should take steps
to see to his death first.
Come. We travel to Lavenham.
I full well understand
your feelings, Cornet,
but you're
an officer of the army,
a soldier,
and desertion
is punishable by death.
However, in this case,
there are two factors
which will stay me
from subjecting you
to a full court-martial.
One,
we are grouped here at Naseby
in preparation
for a major assault
on the Royalist armies.
We need every man we can get.
And you're
a pretty good soldier,
most of the time.
Thank you, sir.
Secondly, I would sleep ill
if I had to
send to the gallows
a man who had saved my life.
But, Cornet, remember this.
If you should leave
your command again,
I will have no alternative
but to throw the whole weight
of military law against you.
Understand?
Yes, sir.
Dismissed, Cornet.
And may God help you
in your search,
Cornet Marshall.
Robert, hello.
Richard, you're back.
Aye.
What happened
with the Captain?
Nothing.
I heard about Brandeston,
Richard.
Hopkins and Stearne.
I'll find them somewhere.
But what can you do?
What proof have you
that they
committed any crime?
I've got Sara's word on it.
Is that enough
for the magistrates?
There'll be no
magistrates involved.
What do you mean?
We'll talk more later,
Richard.
We must be on our way.
We're after horses
for this skirmish
that's coming up.
All right.
Hup. Come on. Hup.
Parliament men,
comrades of friend Marshall.
There's some good ones
coming now, look.
Hey!
Let's make a run for it,
shall we, while we can.
Be calm.
Yeah, but if they find out
who we are, they'll...
They won't. Come on.
That's a fine horse
you've got there, friend.
ROBERT: The army needs mounts
of such caliber.
I am not selling.
But you will get your money
when the war's over.
You don't appear
to understand.
I am not selling.
Oh,
but you are selling, friend.
And we'll take
that one, there, too.
So you filthy soldiers
can butcher my mare?
Sergeant, he thinks
we're filthy soldiers.
Do you hear?
Aye, I heard.
You can't go saying
things like that, friend.
What he needs
is a little army discipline.
I hear you need more pikemen
in your platoon, Sergeant.
You'll pay for this!
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Good horse you had, there.
Cost a pretty penny,
I reckon.
We robbed the canteen mint.
A right jester, he is.
Yeah, well, a day's fighting
in Cromwell's army
will soon
cure your wit, my lad.
I am not doing any fighting,
neither for the King
or your precious Cromwell,
either.
You mark that well, soldier.
Yeah, you coward.
Just like your friend.
Matthew Hopkins
is no friend of mine.
Hopkins?
The fancy boy
who just made a fool
of your cavalry, comrade.
You rode with him.
I had reasons.
He pays you?
We were partners.
In what business?
Extermination.
Eh?
And what does that mean?
(SCREAMS)
(GUN FIRES)
(PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
(STEARNE SCREAMING)
Now,
Matthew Hopkins, sir.
Adequate, very adequate.
We did our best, sir.
Lavenham has served me well,
Master Webb.
Now I must find out
how I can serve you.
They're all women, sir.
Strange,
isn't it, how much iniquity
the Lord
vested in the female?
Pardon, sir?
Who makes the accusations?
Myself, sir.
I'm representing the town.
How many?
Three, sir.
And what age?
Well, two are young, sir,
Elizabeth Clark
and Mary Reynolds.
The other's worn and old.
Fetch the young pair
here to me.
What of the other hag?
Well, the old ones
are more sensible.
It's the young ones
who are stubborn.
They require time.
Oh, I see.
Sir?
Yes, man?
Your assistant, sir.
We were told he, too,
would be coming to Lavenham.
He's engaged elsewhere.
He's fighting
for the Parliamentary cause.
Oh. He will be
joining you here, sir?
I really can't say.
You can manage without him?
Of course.
I apologize...
No.
Not only can I
manage without him,
but I intend to instigate
a new method of execution,
and you, Master Webb,
you shall aid me
in carrying it out.
What's that, sir?
You'll see.
It's a fitting end
for the foul ungodliness
in womankind.
Yes, sir.
Now,
fetch that young pair here.
Sir.
An excellent meal, gentlemen.
There is little
I find so satisfying
as good food
after a well-earned victory.
Wouldn't you agree?
Entirely, General.
The conflict at Naseby,
sir, will go down
as a triumph of your strategy.
Perhaps.
I would rather
that it went down
as a triumph
for the forces
of true godliness.
Nevertheless,
your name will symbolize
the victory, sir.
Whether I like it
or not, eh, Captain?
That cornet you so
highly recommended
to me, is he to join us?
He's coming now,
General Cromwell.
Good.
Amongst the most
pleasurable aspects
of victory, gentlemen,
is the opportunity it affords
to reward valor.
It ranks almost
with good food.
Cornet Marshall, sir.
Mmm. All right.
Rest, Cornet.
Your captain
has told me about you.
He says you're
a good soldier.
Thank you, sir.
He recommends
that I promote you
to captain.
I thank you, sir.
I have a special
mission for you, Captain.
Take three men
and ride back
into East Anglia.
The King has escaped us
and is rumoredto be making
for the Norfolk coast.
If that is the case,
find and apprehend him
before he can escape
to the continent.
It's an honor, sir.
Pick your men. Start at once.
If you find the King,
you will escort him then
to Norwich.
If not, join us in the west.
Good luck, Captain.
Shall we rest up
for the night, Richard?
We've got a job to do.
We'll go on
till we've done it.
Do you mean
looking for the King?
Or finding
Hopkins and Stearne?
Both.
Richard, you can't go off
and desert again.
I don't plan to desert!
But supposing you do find out
where they are?
Then I shall take
temporary leave again.
For God's sake, Richard,
I know how you feel,
but to risk court-martial
to kill
Parliament's own appointees,
you'll be hanged yourself.
Robert! I've taken an oath.
I won't break it!
It's madness!
It's justice!
It's my justice.
HORSE SELLER: And what about
one of them, sir?
You won't find
better horseflesh
in the whole of Suffolk.
So, how much you going to try
to drag out of me
if I take that one?
He's yours
for a couple of guineas, sir.
A guinea.
A guinea and a half
for getting me
out of bed
at this hour of the morning.
One guinea.
And a quarter?
I'll quarter you.
You drive
a hard bargain, sir.
Yeah.
And where would
you be heading
that you need a horse
in such a hurry?
To find my partner.
Your partner, eh?
And what line of business
might you be in?
God's business,
witch-finding.
Witch-finding.
Oh, that's nice.
That's very nice.
You wouldn't make it a guinea
and a quarter, would you?
Do you know a man
called Matthew Hopkins?
You know where he is?
I heard tell
of such a man down south.
Lavenham, I believe.
What's he doing in Lavenham?
Extracting confessions,
I don't doubt.
You let me have
that four-legged cripple now!
This happened three days ago.
Why didn't you report it
to the militia then?
How should we know
it was the King himself?
A stranger,
obviously a townsman,
tries to hire a boat
to cross to France
and you suspect nothing?
When the country's
torn by civil war?
I didn't know
there was a war on
till you
gentlemen told me so.
Oh, come on, Richard.
We'd better go back.
Aye, I suppose so.
I want to pass through
Lavenham and see how Sara is.
Lavenham?
Aye, how far is it from here?
About two days ride,
I reckon.
They got more
excitement over there
than any of your
city folk's wars.
What do you mean?
They're burning
witches there, I hear.
Some such rigmarole.
They're in Lavenham!
(RICHARD URGING HORSE)
Oy! Richard!
(SCREAMING)
Elizabeth! Elizabeth!
Oh, God!
All is ready, Master Hopkins?
Aye.
Proceed with the executions,
then.
Bring forth Elizabeth Clark.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Right.
Siegel, fetch the rope.
MAN 1: Get the rope.
MAN 2: Oh,
come on, you little bitch!
No! Help!
No!
(SCREAMING)
Lower away.
Slowly, now. Keep her slow.
Elizabeth!
Master Hopkins,
there are two more
to be burned.
Yes, Magistrate.
Master Webb, the others!
Here you are,
12 guineas in silver.
To be spent in the service
of our Lord, Magistrate.
We must thank you
for your good work,
Master Witchfinder.
Thank you, Magistrate,
for your aid.
Witchfinder!
Greetings, Stearne.
Is that all
you've got to say
after leaving me there
with Cromwell's men?
Well, I provided us both
with the opportunity
to escape.
Only you did
and I was captured.
Fortunes of war, Stearne.
You know me well enough
to know that I wouldn't
hesitate to fire and kill you.
Aye, you would that.
I hold all human life dearly,
Stearne, especially my own.
Oh, come now.
You've escaped
and all is well.
Maybe.
I even saved
your share of the pay
even though I did
all of the work myself.
Now,
are you going to be sensible
or do I kill you?
By the way, do you know
what they call me now?
What?
Witchfinder General.
There are those who think
that I should be
appointed such
for all of England,
appointed by Parliament.
Here! Look.
Sara. She's here.
Very nice, eh, Matthew?
No, you fool.
Don't you realize
that if she's here,
that trooper
must be around, too?
But he's away fighting.
Suppose he got leave
after Naseby.
Where do you think he'd go?
To see her, of course.
We better move along
then, eh?
No.
That man, Marshall,
is not going to give up.
He's proved
that to us already.
Then we have to get him
before he gets us, right?
We have the power
to do it, legally.
Prove him a witch, huh?
Exactly.
He'd never confess,
not that one.
On his own, no.
But if we had
him and the girl?
Yeah,
she's the niece of a man
we executed for witchcraft.
And Marshall is her husband.
I owe that jumped-up plowboy
a seeing-to.
Go out and ask around.
Find out if he's been seen.
If not,
we'll tarry here a while
until he does arrive.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Who is it?
RICHARD: Sara, open the door.
It's me.
Richard?
They were here,
Hopkins and Stearne.
I didn't know what to do.
I saw them in the street.
I didn't know
if they saw me or not.
I know.
Well, I'll be in the tavern
with the others, then.
He's here, Matthew!
Just arrived.
Where's he gone?
To see the girl.
Alone?
Yeah. The three others
are in the tavern.
Go and get us
an extra man to help.
Where are we
going to take them,
Matthew?
Up to the castle.
The magistrate here
is very helpful.
That's where you
interrogated the others,
is it?
Yes.
Now, hurry to it, man.
What are you going to do?
You say Hopkins
arrived two days ago.
Yes, and then
he was with the other one
in the street today.
And they haven't left yet?
I'm not sure.
I've been too scared to leave.
HOPKINS: Come on!
Open up in there!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Drop that sword, soldier.
This man accuses you,
Sara Lowes,
and you, Richard Marshall,
of consorting with the Devil.
Is that not so, Master Webb?
It is that, sir.
Will you describe
your evidence to us?
I observed
the accused talking
with their familiars
and making
the signs of Satan, sir.
And what were these familiars
to which you refer?
Black cat
and a stoat, sir.
You're a very
observing citizen,
Master Webb.
Well, Sara, do you confess?
And what do you
have to say, soldier?
I'm going to kill you,
Hopkins.
I don't think
you'll find that easy.
The law is with me, remember?
And what are you?
An accused witch.
They must be
submitted to the test.
Take them, Stearne.
Hopkins!
(SCREAMING)
HOPKINS: A Royalist
sympathizer, evidently.
But what are we
going to do with him?
Leave him. I'll inform
the magistrate later.
We have more
important work to do.
Come on.
Get moving.
Orders from the magistrate.
Suspected witches.
Yes, sir. Sorry, sir.
I heard them.
ROBERT: Where are they
taking them?
To the castle to test them.
Test them?
They're accused
of witchcraft.
Harcourt, you come with me.
Yes, sir.
Shall I look after him, sir?
Yes,
try and find him a physician.
I've heard much of how
Hopkins conducts
his interrogations.
Come on, Harcourt.
(COUGHS)
All right, Stearne.
(SARA AND RICHARD SCREAMING)
(SARA WHIMPERING)
(SCREAMING)
SARA: No!
Well, Captain Marshall,
do you now confess?
Keep at it, Stearne.
You're doing God's work.
(SARA SCREAMING)
Put her over here.
And you, Master Webb,
help him.
Master Hopkins
and his assistants,
are they here, man?
That they are, sir.
Well, let us pass, then.
You're here to
help the Witchfinder?
We're here to find him, yes.
Have you a signed pass?
Sara,
I'm going to place this iron
on your back.
Should you faint or cry out,
we can only take it
that Satan has intervened
to spare you your agony.
However,
I could show mercy if...
If Captain Marshall
were to confess
to witchcraft first.
But will you do it, sir?
I shall kill you.
So, you have no
proper authorization, then.
What do you mean?
From the magistrate.
Authorization.
Not here with us, no.
Well, we'll go
back and get one then.
All right.
Then I'll let you pass.
Master Webb,
go and see
what is the matter.
Yes, Master Hopkins.
What do we do, Matthew?
We shall carry on
with God's work
as before, man.
And fetch Captain Marshall
over here.
He shall kneel
before his wife
and watch her suffer.
But Matthew...
Go do it, man!
(SCREAMS)
Oh, God!
You took him away from me.
You took him from me.
You took him from me!
(YELLING) You took him
from me!
(SOBBING)
May God have mercy on us all.
(SCREAMING HYSTERICALLY)