[Birds Squawking]
[Squawking, Cawing]
[Wings Flapping]
[Chirping, Twittering]
[Squawking Intensifies]
[Cable Car Bell Dinging]
[Squawking Continues]
[Car Horn Honking]
[Boy Wolf Whistles]
[Squawking, Chirping]
[Birds Chirping]
Hello, Mrs. MacGruder.
Hello, Miss Daniels.
Have you ever
seen so many gulls?
What do you suppose it is?
There must be a storm at sea.
That can drive them inland,
you know.
I was hoping you'd be
a little late.
He hasn't arrived yet.
But you said 3:00.
I know.
I've been calling
all morning.
Oh, Miss Daniels,
you have no idea.
They are
so difficult to get.
Really, they are.
We have to get them
from India when they're
baby chicks, and then...
This one won't be a chick,
will he?
Oh, no, certainly not.
This will be a full-grown
mynah bird.
- And he'll talk?
- Well, yes, of course he'll...
Well, no, you'll have
to teach him to talk.
I guess maybe I'd better phone.
They said 3:00.
Maybe it's the traffic.
I'll call.
Would you mind waiting?
Well, maybe you'd better
deliver him.
Let me give you
my address.
Oh, well, all right,
but I'm sure they're
on the way.
Would you mind
if I called?
No. All right.
I wonder if you
could help me.
What?
I said, I wonder
if you could help me.
- Yes. What is it
you're looking for, sir?
- Lovebirds.
Lovebirds, sir?
Yes. I understand there
are different varieties.
Is that true?
Well, yes,
there are.
Well, these are for
my sister for her birthday,
and as she's only gonna be 11,
I wouldn't want
a pair of birds...
that were...
too demonstrative.
I understand completely.
At the same time, I wouldn't
want them to be too aloof.
No, of course not.
Do you happen to have
a pair of birds that are...
just friendly?
Oh, I think so.
Now, then, let me see.
[Chirping Continues]
Aren't those lovebirds?
No. Those are, uh...
red birds.
I thought they were
strawberry finches.
Yes. We call
them that too.
Here we are.
Lovebirds.
Those are canaries.
Doesn't this
make you feel awful?
Doesn't what make me feel...
Having all these poor, innocent
creatures caged up like this?
Well, we can't just let them
fly around the shop.
I suppose not.
I-Is there an ornithological
reason for keeping them
in separate cages?
Certainly.
It's to protect the species.
Yes, that's important,
especially during
the molting season.
That's a particularly
dangerous time.
Are they molting now?
Oh, some of them are.
How can you tell?
Well, they... get a sort
of hangdog expression.
Yes, I see.
Well, what about
the lovebirds?
Are you sure
you wouldn't like to see
a canary instead?
We have some very nice
canaries this week.
All right.
May I see it, please?
Oh! Oh!
[Mrs. MacGruder]
What is it?
Oh! Oh!
[Mrs. MacGruder]
Oh! Oh! Oh!
Oh! Oh!
There we are.
Oh, there.
Wonderful.
Back in your gilded cage,
Melanie Daniels.
What did you say?
I was merely drawing
a parallel, Miss Daniels.
How did you know my name?
A little birdie
told me.
Good day, Miss Daniels.
Madam.
Hey, wait a minute.
I don't know you.
Ah, but I know you.
How?
- We met in court.
- We never met in court
or anyplace else.
- That's true. I'll rephrase it.
I saw you in court.
- When?
Don't you remember one of your
practical jokes that resulted
in the smashing of a window?
- I didn't break that window.
- Yes, but your little prank did.
- The judge should've
put you behind bars.
- What are you, a policeman?
I merely believe in the law.
And I'm not too keen
on practical jokers.
- What do you call
your lovebird story...
- I really wanted the lovebirds.
You knew I didn't work here.
You deliberately...
I recognized you when I came in.
I thought you might like
to know what it's like to be
on the other end of a gag.
What do you think
of that?
I think you're a louse.
I am. Good day,
Miss Daniels. Madam.
And I'm glad you didn't get
your lovebirds.
I'll find something else.
See you in court.
Who was that man?
I have no idea.
[Cable Car Bell Dinging]
They said the mynah bird would
be here later this afternoon,
if you care to come back.
No, you'd better send him.
May I use this phone?
Why, certainly.
Daily News?
It's Melanie Daniels.
Could you get me the City Desk?
Just a minute,
Mrs. MacGruder.
Hello, Charlie.
Melanie.
I want you to do
a favor for me.
No, this is a small one.
Pressure you?
Why, Charlie, darling,
would I try to pressure you?
Would you call the Department
of Motor Vehicles for me?
Find out who owns
this license plate:
W-J-H-0-0-3.
Yes, a California plate.
No. I'll stop off
in a little while.
Is Daddy in his office?
No, I don't want
to break in on a meeting.
Tell him I'll see him later.
Thank you, Charlie.
Do you have any lovebirds?
Well, no, not in the shop,
but I can order them for you.
How soon?
Well... Well, when
would you want them?
Immediately.
Well, I could probably have them
here by tomorrow morning.
Would that be
all right?
That would be just fine.
[Chirping]
[Door Slides Closed,
Elevator Hums]
[Door Slides Closed]
Miss, is that
for Mitch Brenner?
Yes.
He's not home.
That's all right.
He won't be back
until Monday... I mean,
if those birds are for him.
Monday?
Yes.
I don't think you should leave
them in the hall, do you?
Well... Where did he go?
Bodega Bay.
He goes there every weekend.
Where's that?
Up the coast,
about 60 miles north of here.
Sixty mi... Oh!
It's an hour and a half
by freeway, or two hours
if you take the Coast Highway.
I'd look after them myself,
but I'm going away too.
I'm awfully sorry.
[Engine Revving]
[Tires Screeching]
[Bell Dings]
Good morning.
I wonder if you
could help me.
I'll try my best.
I'm looking for a man
named Mitchell Brenner.
Yeah.
Do you know him?
Where does he live?
Right here, Bodega Bay.
- Yes, I know, but where?
- Right across the bay there.
Where?
Now, see where
I'm pointing?
Yes.
[Shopkeeper]
See them two big trees
across there?
On the other side
of the bay? Yes.
And the white house?
Yes.
That's where
the Brenners live.
The Brenners?
Mr. And Mrs. Brenner?
No. Just Lydia
and the two kids.
The two kids?
Yeah, Mitch
and the little girl.
Oh, I see.
How do I get down there?
You follow the road
around the bay, and that'll
take you to their front door.
The front door. Is there
a back road I can take?
No. That's the only road.
You see, I want
to surprise them.
Oh.
I don't want them
to see me arrive.
Oh.
It's a surprise, you see.
Well, you could get yourself
a boat and cut right across
the bay to their dock.
Where would I get a boat?
Down by
the Tides Restaurant.
- Did you ever handle
an outboard boat?
- Of course.
- Want me to order one for you?
- Well, thank you.
What name?
Daniels.
Okay.
[Shop Bell Dings]
[Rotary Phone Dialing]
I wonder if you
could tell me...
Yeah.
Hold it a minute, please.
- The little girl's name?
- The little Brenner girl?
Yes.
Uh, Alice, I think.
[Shuffling Sound]
Harry, what's
the Brenner girl's name?
- [Harry] Lois.
- [Shopkeeper]
Alice, isn't it?
- [Harry]
No, it's Lois.
- It's Alice.
- Are you sure?
- Well, I'm not positive,
if that's what you mean.
I need her exact name.
Oh, uh... Just hold on
one more minute, please.
In that case,
I'll tell you what you do.
Go straight through town
till you see a little hotel
on your left.
Then you turn right there.
Now, you got that?
Yes.
Near the top of the hill,
you'll see the school,
and just beyond,
a little house
with a red mailbox.
That's where Annie Hayworth,
the schoolteacher, lives.
You ask her about
the little Brenner girl.
Well, thank you.
Save yourself a lot of trouble.
Name's Alice for sure.
Can I have the boat
in about 20 minutes?
How much for
the phone calls?
Oh, it's nothing.
Thank you.
[Children Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
[Engine Stops]
[Doorbell Rings]
[Woman]
Who is it?
Me.
Who's "me"?
Miss Hayworth?
Yes.
I'm Melanie Daniels.
I'm sorry to bother you, but...
Yes?
The man at the post
office sent me.
He said you could
tell me the name
of the Brenner girl.
Cathy?
The one who lives in the
white house across the bay?
That's the one. Cathy Brenner.
He seemed sure it was
either Alice or Lois.
Which is why the mail
never gets delivered to
the right place in this town.
I'm sorry.
Smoke?
Thank you.
Did, uh... you want to see
Cathy about something?
Well, not exactly.
Oh.
Are you a friend
of Mitch's?
No, not really.
I've been wanting a cigarette
for the last 20 minutes.
I just couldn't convince
myself to stop.
This tilling of the soil
can become compulsive, you know.
It's a very pretty garden.
Oh, thank you.
Well, it's something to do
in your spare time.
There's a lot of spare time
in Bodega Bay.
Are, uh, you planning
on staying long?
No, just a few hours.
Then you're leaving
after you see Cathy.
Well, something
like that.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to sound
so mysterious.
Actually, it's
none of my business.
Well, I better be
on my way.
Thank you
very much.
Not at all.
Did you drive up from San
Francisco by the coast road?
Yes.
Nice drive.
It's very beautiful.
Is that where
you met Mitch?
Yes.
I guess that's where
everyone meets Mitch.
Now you sound a bit mysterious,
Miss Hayworth.
[Chuckles]
Do I?
I don't mean to.
Actually, I'm an open book,
I'm afraid.
[Chirping]
Or, rather, a closed one.
- Oh, pretty. What are they?
- Lovebirds.
I see.
Good luck, Miss Daniels.
Thank you.
Can I get out this way?
[Engine Starts]
Go right around.
It'll take you back
to the main road.
Thank you.
[Engine Revs]
[Engine Starts]
[Seagulls Cawing]
Do you have a boat
for Miss Daniels?
Yes, ma'am.
It's the one
right below.
[Chirping]
[Motor Starts]
[Motor Stops]
[Motor Cranking]
[Motor Starts]
Are you all right?
Yes, I think so.
What made it do that?
That's the damnedest thing
I ever saw.
It seemed to swoop down
at you deliberately.
Oh, you're bleeding too.
Let's take care of that.
Okay?
That's a girl.
Come on.
What happened, Mitch?
Gull hit her.
A gull?
Oh. Let's try
up at the restaurant,
all right?
Might need a tetanus shot.
I had a booster
before I went abroad last May.
[People Chattering]
What happened?
Hello, Deke.
Young lady cut herself.
Shall I call a doctor?
I don't think it's
that serious. Let's see.
Helen, get some cotton
and antiseptic.
Um, you cut yourself
outside, miss?
Don't worry, Deke.
She did it in a boat.
I had a man trip and fall in
the parking lot once. Sued me
before I could bat an eyelash.
I don't think Miss Daniels
is gonna sue anybody.
Here.
Well, you're the lawyer.
Thank you.
What's that?
Just some peroxide.
I'll clean out the cut.
So you're a lawyer.
That's right. Of course,
I usually defend people,
but if I were prosecuting...
Do you practice here?
Uh-uh, San Francisco.
What are you doing up here?
What kind of law?
Criminal.
Is that why you want to see
everyone behind bars?
Oh, not everyone.
Only violators
and practical jokers.
That's right.
Ow!
Oh, sorry.
What are you doing up here?
Didn't you see
the lovebirds?
You mean, you came all this way
to bring me those birds?
To bring
your sister those birds.
You said it was her birthday.
Besides, I was
coming up anyway.
What for?
To see a friend of mine.
Careful.
Oh, sorry.
Uh... who's your friend?
Annie Hayworth,
the schoolteacher.
Annie Hayworth.
Well, small world.
Yes.
How do you know Annie?
We went to school
together... college.
Did you? Imagine that.
How long are you staying
up here?
The weekend.
Well, I think
the bleeding's almost stopped.
Why don't you hold that on...
So you came up
to see Annie, huh?
Yes.
- I think you came up to see me.
- Now, why would I want
to see you of all people?
I don't know, but you must've
gone to a lot of trouble...
to find out who I was
and where I lived.
It was no trouble at all.
I simply called
my father's newspaper.
Besides, I was
coming up anyway.
I've already told you that.
You really like me, huh?
I loathe you.
You have no manners.
You're arrogant and conceited.
I wrote you a letter
about it, in fact,
but I tore it up.
- What did it say?
- None of your business.
I can't say I like your
seagulls much, either.
I come all the way up here to...
You were coming up
anyway, remember?
[Door Opens]
Mitch?
I thought I saw your car.
What are you doing in town?
I had to acknowledge
a delivery.
A what?
Mother, I'd like you
to meet Melanie Daniels.
Miss Daniels, my mother.
How do you do?
How do you do, Miss Daniels?
Acknowledge a what?
A delivery.
Miss Daniels brought us
some birds from San Francisco.
Oh.
For Cathy for her birthday.
Where is she?
Across at Brinkmeyer's.
Miss Daniels is staying
up here for the weekend.
So I've already invited her
for dinner tonight.
- Well, you did go to the trouble
of bringing those birds.
-Oh, I couldn't possibly.
You did say birds?
Yes, lovebirds.
Oh, I see.
So we couldn't let you
get away without thanking you
in some small way.
And you haven't met Cathy,
and you are staying
the weekend.
Well, yes, but...
You are, aren't you?
Certainly, but...
Then it's all settled.
What time is dinner,
Mother?
7:00, the same as usual.
- I'll pick you up.
Where are you staying?
- With Annie, of course.
Oh, of course.
How stupid of me.
A quarter of 7:00?
Annie may have
made other plans.
I'll have to see.
Besides, I can find
my own way.
You're sure now?
You won't hire a boat
or anything?
I'm sure.
7:00, then.
Maybe.
We'll be waiting for you.
How's your head?
Much better, thank you.
A gull hit me,
Mrs. Brenner, that's all.
[Rings]
Oh, hi.
Did you find her all right?
Yes, I did.
I was wondering...
Uh, that sign there.
Do you suppose
I could have the room
for just a single night?
I was planning on renting it
for a longer time...
I would appreciate it.
I've tried
everywhere in town.
They're all full.
Well, all right.
Got your bags in the car?
[Chuckles]
Well, it's utilitarian,
I'll say that.
I just picked up
some things for the night
at the general store.
I hadn't planned
on staying very long.
Yes, I know.
Did something
unexpected come up?
Yes. May I use your phone?
I'd like to call home.
I just put some coffee
on the stove.
[Seagulls Cawing]
Don't they ever
stop migrating?
[Seagulls Cawing]
[Rings]
Hi!
Miss Daniels?
Yes.
Oh, they're beautiful!
They're just what I wanted.
Is there a man and a woman?
[Cathy]
I can't tell which is which.
Well, I suppose so.
Hello there.
Annie had no plans, huh?
No.
We're very glad
you could come.
Are you hungry?
Reasonably.
Dinner's just
about ready.
We've been looking
at the chickens. Something
seems to be wrong with them.
There's nothing wrong
with those chickens.
I'm going to call
Fred Brinkmeyer right now.
What good's that gonna do?
The chickens won't eat.
He sold the feed to me,
didn't he?
Caveat emptor, Mother.
Let the buyer beware.
Whose side are you on?
Merely quoting
the law, dear.
Never mind the law.
This won't take long,
Miss Dan... Hello, Fred?
Lydia Brenner.
I didn't interrupt
your dinner, did I?
How about a drink?
I'd love one.
That feed you
sold me is no good.
The chicken feed.
Well, it's just no good.
The chickens won't eat it.
They're always hungry.
I opened a sack for them
when I got home, and they
just wouldn't touch it.
You know chickens
as well as I do,
and when they won't eat,
there's something wrong
with what they're being fed.
No, they're not
fussy chickens.
Who? What's he
got to do with it?
Is that your father?
Mm-hmm.
Please sit down.
I don't care how many sacks
of feed you sold him.
My chicken...
Oh, I see.
Dan Fawcett.
This afternoon?
That proves what I'm saying.
The feed you sold us...
Oh.
Well, maybe I better
go over and see him.
You don't think
there's something
going around, do you?
No, never!
No, they don't
seem sick at all.
They just won't eat.
Uh-huh.
Well, I'll try
to go over and see him.
Maybe he...
Uh-huh.
All right.
Thanks.
He had a call from
Dan Fawcett a while ago.
His chickens
won't eat either.
It's what you said, Mom.
Mr. Brinkmeyer's feed
is no good.
No, Cathy.
He sold Mr. Fawcett
a different brand.
You don't think
they're getting sick,
do you, Mitch?
I still don't understand
how you knew I wanted lovebirds.
Your brother told me.
Then you knew Mitch
in San Francisco?
Is that right?
No, not exactly.
Mitch knows a lot
of people in San Francisco.
Of course, they're mostly hoods.
- Cathy!
- Well, Mom, he's
the first to admit it.
He's spends half his day
in the detention cells
at the Hall of Justice.
In a democracy, Cathy,
everyone is entitled
to a fair trial.
Your brother's
practice...
Aw, Mom, please!
I know all
that democracy jazz.
They're still hoods.
He has a client now
who shot his wife
in the head six times.
Six times!
Can you imagine it?
I mean, even twice
would be overdoing it,
don't you think?
- Why did he shoot her?
- He was watching
a ball game on television.
- What?
- His wife changed the channel.
Are you coming
to my party tomorrow?
I don't think so.
I have to get back
to San Francisco.
Don't you like us?
Oh, darling,
of course I do.
Don't you like
Bodega Bay?
I don't know yet.
Mitch likes it very much.
He comes up every weekend,
you know,
even though he has
his own apartment
in the city.
He says San Francisco's
like an anthill
at the foot of a bridge.
I suppose it does get
hectic at times.
Well, if you do decide to come,
don't say I told you about it.
It's supposed to be
a surprise party.
They've got
this whole complicated
thing figured out...
where I'm going to Michele's
for the afternoon,
and Michele's mother will say
that she has a headache, would
I mind if she took me home.
Then when I get home here,
all the kids'll jump out!
Oh, won't you come?
Won't you please come?
I don't think so.
She's a charming girl,
isn't she, Mitch?
Hmm? Yes.
Certainly pretty.
Mm-hmm.
- How long have you known her?
- Now, I told you, dear,
we met yesterday.
In a bird shop.
She was selling birds?
No, no. I just led her
into believing that I believed
she was, and then...
It's all very complicated.
But she did buy the lovebirds
and then drove all the way here.
Mother.
Yes?
Where did you
go to law school?
Forgive me.
I suppose I'm
just naturally curious
about a girl like that.
She's very rich,
isn't she?
Yeah, I suppose so.
Her father's part owner of
one of the big newspapers.
You'd think he could manage
to keep her name out of print.
She's always mentioned
in the columns, Mitch.
Yes, I know.
She is the one who jumped
into a fountain in Rome
last summer, isn't she?
Yes.
I supposed I'm old-fashioned.
I know it was supposed to be
very warm there, but...
Well, actually the newspapers
said she was naked.
Yes, I know, dear.
It's none of my business,
but when you bring
a girl like that...
Darling?
Yes?
I think I can handle
Melanie Daniels by myself.
Well... as long as you know
what you want, Mitch.
I know exactly
what I want.
Be able to find
your way back all right?
Oh, yes.
Will I be seeing you again?
San Francisco's
a long way from here.
I'm in San Francisco
five days a week with a lot
of time on my hands.
I'd like to see you.
Maybe we could go swimming
or something.
Mother tells me
you like to swim.
How does Mother know
what I like to do?
We read the same gossip column.
Oh, that... Rome.
I really like to swim.
We might get along very well.
In case you're interested,
I was pushed into that fountain.
Without any clothes on?
With all my clothes on.
The newspaper that ran
that story...
happens to be a rival
of my father's paper.
You were just a poor, innocent
victim of circumstances?
I'm neither poor nor innocent.
The truth of that particular...
The truth is, you're running
around with a pretty wild crowd.
Yes, that's the truth, but I
was pushed into that fountain,
and that's the truth too.
Uh-huh. Do you really
know Annie Hayworth?
No. At least I didn't
until I came up here.
So you didn't go
to school together?
No.
And you didn't come here
to see her?
No!
You were lying!
Yes, I was lying.
What about the letter
you wrote me? Is that a lie?
No, I wrote the letter.
- Well, what did it say?
- It said, "Dear Mr. Brenner.
I think you need
these lovebirds after all.
They may help your personality."
That's what it said.
But you tore it up?
Yes.
Why?
Because it seemed
stupid and foolish.
- Like jumping into
a fountain in Rome.
- I told you what happened!
You don't expect me
to believe that, do you?
I don't give a damn
what you believe!
- I'd still like to see you.
- Why?
I think it might be fun.
That might've been
good enough in Rome,
but it's not good enough now.
It is for me.
Well, not for me.
- What do you want?
- I thought you knew.
I want to go through life...
jumping into fountains naked.
Good night.
[Birds Chirping,
Squawking]
Miss Daniels,
is that you?
Yes.
Hi.
Is something wrong?
Is that cut beginning
to bother you?
No, it's not the cut
that's bothering me.
- Would you like some brandy?
- If you have some, I'd love it.
I'll get it.
Why don't you sit down.
Oh, would you like a sweater
or something, a quilt?
No. No, thank you.
Won't you call me Melanie?
All right.
Thank you.
Gets a bit chilly here
at night sometimes,
especially if you're
over near the bay.
Well, how did
your evening go?
Did you meet Lydia?
Or would you rather
I changed the subject?
I think so.
- Well, how do you like
our little hamlet?
- I despise it.
I suppose it doesn't offer much
to the casual visitor,
unless you're thrilled
by a collection of shacks
on a hillside.
It takes a bit
of getting used to.
Where are you from
originally?
San Francisco.
How did you happen
to come up here?
A friend invited me
up for a weekend
a long time ago.
Look, I see no reason
for being coy about this.
It was Mitch Brenner.
I guess you knew that anyway.
I suspected as much.
Well, you needn't worry.
It's been over and done with
a long time ago.
Annie, there's nothing
between Mr. Brenner and me.
Isn't there?
Well, maybe there isn't.
Maybe there's
never been anything
between Mitch and any girl.
What do you mean?
I think I'll have
some of that.
I was seeing a lot of him
in San Francisco.
One weekend, he invited me
up to meet Lydia.
- When was this?
- Oh, four years ago,
shortly after his father died.
Of course, things
may be different now.
Different?
With Lydia.
Did she seem
a trifle distant?
Mm, a trifle.
Well, then perhaps things
aren't quite so different.
You know, her attitude
nearly drove me crazy.
When I got back to
San Francisco, I spent days
trying to figure out...
what I'd done
to displease her.
- Well, what had you done?
- Nothing.
I simply existed.
So what's the answer?
Ajealous woman, right?
A clinging,
possessive mother?
Wrong. With all due respect
to Oedipus, I don't think
that was the case.
Then what was it?
Lydia liked me.
That's the strange part.
Now that I'm no longer a threat,
we're very good friends.
- Then why did she
object to you?
- Because she was afraid.
- Afraid you'd take Mitch?
- Afraid I'd give Mitch.
I don't understand.
Afraid of any woman who
would give Mitch the one thing
Lydia can give him: love.
That adds up to
a jealous, possessive woman.
No, I don't think so.
You see, she's not afraid
of losing Mitch.
She's only afraid
of being abandoned.
- Someone ought to tell her
she'd be gaining a daughter.
- [Chuckles]
No. She already
has a daughter.
Well, what about Mitch?
Didn't he have anything
to say about this?
Well, I can understand
his position.
He'd just been through
a lot with Lydia
after his father died.
- He didn't want to risk
going through it all again.
- Oh, I see.
So it ended.
Not right then, of course.
We went back to San Francisco,
saw each other now and then,
but we both knew it was over.
- Then what are you doing
here in Bodega Bay?
- I wanted to be near Mitch.
Oh, it was over and done with,
and I knew it, but...
I still wanted
to be near him.
I still like him
a hell of a lot,
and I don't want to lose
that friendship... ever.
[Phone Ringing]
Hello.
No, no, no,
I wasn't asleep.
Yes, just
a little while ago.
Sure. Hold on.
It's Mitch.
For you.
Hello? Oh, yes,
this is Melanie.
Fine, thank you.
No, no trouble at all.
I simply followed the road.
Well... There's
no need to apologize.
I can understand...
That's very kind of you.
No, I'm not angry.
Well, I couldn't.
I have to get back
to San Francisco.
No, I wouldn't want
to disappoint Cathy, but...
I see.
All right.
Yes, I'll be there.
Good night, Mitch.
[Hangs Up Phone]
He wants me to go to Cathy's
party tomorrow afternoon.
I said I would.
It should be fun.
I'll be there, too,
to help.
Oh, it seems so pointless.
Well, I think
I'll go to sleep.
It's been a busy day.
My luggage.
That's pretty.
Where'd you get that?
Brinkmeyer's?
Mm-hmm. Do you think
I should go?
Well, that's up to you.
No, it's really
up to Lydia, isn't it?
- Never mind Lydia.
Do you want to go?
- Yes.
- Then go.
- Thank you, Annie.
[Clattering Sound]
Oh. Wonder
who that can be.
Is someone there?
Who is it?
Look.
Poor thing.
Probably lost his way
in the dark.
But it isn't dark,
Annie.
There's a full moon.
[Children Chattering,
Laughing]
[Annie]
Cathy, that's very good.
Very good.
Okay. Here we go.
[Annie]
Attagirl. Come on.
Don't let him get you.
No, I really shouldn't
have any more.
I'm driving.
Well, actually, I'm trying
to get you to stay for dinner.
A lot of roast beef left over.
No, I couldn't possibly.
I... have to get back.
All right.
Cheers.
Why do you have to rush off?
What's so important
in San Francisco?
Well, I have to get to work
tomorrow, for one thing.
You have a job?
I have several jobs.
What do you do?
I do different things
on different days.
Like what?
Well, on Mondays and Wednesdays,
I work for the Travelers' Aid
at the airport.
Helping travelers?
No, misdirecting them.
I thought you could read
my character.
On Tuesdays, I take a course
in General Semantics
at Berkeley...
finding new
four-letter words.
- That's not a job, of course...
- You mean, you don't have to...
- And on Thursdays,
I have my meeting and lunch.
- In the underworld, I suppose.
I shall disappoint you.
We're sending
a little Korean boy
through school.
We actually raise money
for it.
You see, Rome...
That entire summer,
I did nothing but...
Well, it was very easy
to get lost there.
So when I came back,
I thought it was time
I began...
I don't know...
finding something again.
So, on Mondays and Thursdays,
I keep myself busy.
- What about Fridays?
- Fridays? They're free.
I sometimes go
to bird shops on Fridays.
I'm very glad you do.
A nice, innocent,
little day.
Oh, yes.
- I have an Aunt Tessa.
Have you got an Aunt Tessa?
- Mm-mm.
Mine is very prim
and straight-laced.
I'm giving her a mynah bird
when she comes back from Europe.
Mynah birds talk, you know.
Can you see
my Aunt Tessa's face...
when this one tells us
one or two of the words
I've picked up at Berkeley?
You need a mother's care,
my child.
- Not my mother's.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
What have you got
to be sorry about?
My mother?
Don't waste your time.
She ditched us when I was 11
and ran off with some hotel man
in the East.
You know what
a mother's love is?
- Yes, I do.
- You mean it's better
to be ditched?
No. I think
it's better to be loved.
Don't you ever see her?
I don't know
where she is.
Well, maybe I ought to go
join the other children.
[Children Chattering]
[Annie]
All right. Here we go.
One...
two...
three.
There you go.
[Children Laughing]
[Child]
Look! Look!
Hey!
No touching allowed!
[Squawking]
- Oh!
- [Birds Squawking]
[Children Screaming]
[Loud Pop]
[Squawking, Screaming
Continue]
Help me get the children
into the house.
There you go.
[Sobbing]
[Children Sobbing]
Have they gone,
Mitch?
I think so.
[Lydia]
Is anyone hurt?
[Woman]
Jenny got a scratch down
her cheek, but it's nothing.
That makes three times.
Mitch, this
isn't usual, is it?
The gull when I was
in the boat yesterday,
the one at Annie's last night...
Last night?
What do you mean?
A gull smashed
into Annie's front door.
Mitch, what's happening?
I... I don't know.
Do you have to go back
to Annie's?
No. I have my things
in the car.
Stay and have something to
eat before you start back.
I'd feel a lot better.
Would you like
some mustard with that?
[Melanie] No, thank you.
Why didn't Annie stay?
Said something about going home
to take a call from her sister.
[Chirping]
What's the matter
with them?
with all the birds?
Where did you want this coffee?
Here on the table,
honey.
Hurry up with yours, Mitch.
I'm sure Miss Daniels
wants to be on her way.
I think you ought to stay
the night, Melanie.
We have an extra room
upstairs and everything.
That road can be
a pretty bad one at night.
If I go across to Santa Rosa,
I'll come out on the freeway
much earlier, won't I?
Yes, and the freeway
is much quicker.
But she'll be hitting
all the heavy traffic
going back to San Francisco.
[Chirping Grows Louder]
[Cathy]
Just listen to those lovebirds.
[Chirping Stops]
[Twittering]
Mitch.
[Birds Screeching]
Cover your faces!
Cover your eyes!
That's a sparrow,
all right.
We know what it is, Al.
Did you have a light
burnin' or somethin'?
Yes, but there wouldn't
have been that much light
going up the chimney.
[Al] Sometimes birds
are attracted by light.
Sure is a peculiar thing.
All right, but we've
got to do something
about it!
I don't think I get you,
Mitch. Do about what?
[Mitch Sighs]
Well, the birds
invaded the house.
What's more likely...
they got in the room
and just panicked.
I'll admit a bird will
panic in an enclosed room,
but they didn't just
get in, : they came in,
right down the chimney.
[Al] My wife found a bird in
the back seat of her car once.
Tell him about the party.
We had a party here
this afternoon for Cathy,
for her birthday.
How old is she?
Eleven! In the middle
of the party,
some seagulls came down
at the children!
Miss Daniels was attacked
by a gull yesterday.
Yeah. Were the kids
bothering the birds
or something?
If you make any kind
of a disturbance near them,
they'll come after you.
Al, the children
were playing a game.
Those gulls attacked.
[Al] Now, Lydia, "attack"
is a pretty strong word,
don't you think?
I mean, birds just don't
go around attacking people
without no reason.
The kids probably scared 'em,
that's all.
These birds attacked.
You got quite a mess here,
I'll admit that.
Maybe you ought
to put some screen
on top of your chimney.
You want help
cleaning up?
No. I can handle it.
[Lydia Gasps]
[Mitch] It shouldn't be
too much of a job.
I'll take Cathy
up to bed.
I think I should stay,
don't you?
It would be nice
if you could.
My things are in the car.
Do you want to go with me?
All right.
[Al] Well, anything
else I can do, Mitch?
No thanks, Al.
We'll be all right.
Good night, Lydia.
Sure is peculiar.
[Door Closes]
[Shovel Grating]