(MONITOR BEEPS)
MAN: There you go.
Okay.
Ready?
(CLEARING THROAT)
JUDGE: Mrs. Porter,
what do you remember
from that night?
(WHEEZING)
It was dark,
but I could see.
The sky was so bright.
There was a full moon.
It was beautiful.
(SCREAMS) Stop!
Peter.
HENRY: Peter Porter,
come here please.
CLAIRE: Good work
on the fire, bud.
Look at this.
CLAIRE: This is a very
beautiful spot.
HENRY: What about
this full moon?
You could get a moon tan.
CLAIRE: So tell us about
the meteor shower.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
And do you know what
a meteor shower is?
It's the ice and
debris that's...
Well, actually,
the sun is melting
the ice off the comet
and that's when
the debris falls loose.
Do you believe him?
PETER: No.
I don't believe you either.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
HENRY: Check out
our campsite.
Are you guys hungry?
HENRY: Yeah, what'd
you bring to eat?
Hot dogs?
HENRY: "Sot" dogs.
This is the Porter family.
Can you turn the little...
Look at that!
(STATIC CRACKLES)
CLAIRE: ...yard this big
and our dog will
always be happy.
HENRY: Wow.
Okay. Oh! Hello.
(DOG BARKING)
Oscar.
HENRY: Oscar!
PETER: Oscar!
HENRY: What is he doing?
HENRY: Shit!
CLAIRE: Excuse me?
Crap. Don't repeat that.
Oscar! Oscar!
PETER: Oscar!
(CONTINUES BARKING)
HENRY: Oscar!
CLAIRE: Do you see him?
Is everything okay?
Baby?
JUDGE: Okay, do you
remember anything else?
I just remember
screaming.
(INDISTINCT SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
(STATIC CRACKLES)
Mom!
(SCREAMING)
(STATIC CRACKLES)
He was eating my boy alive.
(PETER SCREAMING)
(INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER)
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
FEMALE REPORTER 1:
Very, very sketchy
details here.
An American man
and his young son
holidaying in France
were brutally
killed last night...
MALE REPORTER 1:
The circumstances
are very graphic.
...what police
believe was a vicious
animal attack.
FEMALE REPORTER 2:
In what authorities believe
was a brutal animal attack...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
FEMALE REPORTER 3:
...an attack that has
shocked police officers.
Authorities have
confirmed the death of
36-year-old Henry Porter
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MALE REPORTER 2:
and Peter Porter.
FEMALE REPORTER 3:
...found mutilated.
MALE REPORTER 2:
He was just
seven years old.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MALE REPORTER 3:
The young mother is
the only survivor.
MALE REPORTER 4:
Claire Porter...
...taken by ambulance.
(REPORTER
TALKING FRENCH)
Authorities are hopeful
she will recover...
I have lived here,
my whole life.
Cannot remember
anything like this ever.
People are wondering
what type of animal...
A breed of animal has
yet to be determined.
Police are urging
people to be patient
as they continue with
their investigation.
He was tall and thin.
It had hair all over.
His hands, they were huge.
JUDGE:
You said "he."
A major turn in
this tragic case.
This is now officially
a murder investigation.
Now, suggesting
that there may
be someone...
...responsible for the death
of the Porter family.
This is not an animal attack.
What type of man
could be capable
of such things?
The question many in
France are asking...
MALE REPORTER 6:
One of the biggest manhunts
in recent times.
An entire community
living in fear.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
A very peaceful place
and what has happened
has shattered that peace.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MALE REPORTER 7:
Major developments
in the huge manhunt.
A local man was
taken into custody.
At 14:52, we
apprehended the suspect
at his residence.
FEMALE REPORTER:
Police have identified
a man...
MALE REPORTER 8:
...involved in
the Porter tragedy.
The suspect's
name is Talan Gwynek.
REPORTER:  ...Talan Gwynek.
The only suspect...
FEMALE REPORTER:
...accused of murder.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
FEMALE REPORTER:
This monster of a man...
MALE REPORTER:
...refusing to answer
police questions.
We also learned
that Gwynek's home
in Cerdon...
...is only two miles
from the location
of the attack.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
FEMALE REPORTER:
Gwynek has been transferred
from Cerdon to Lyon.
But the question,
the validity
of the charges.
MALE REPORTER:
No clear motive.
No prior criminal records.
Some legal analysts
are calling his arrest
an abuse of human rights.
Well, at this stage
there is no factual evidence
to indicate anything more
than an animal attack.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MALE REPORTER:
Gwynek's court-appointed
attorney...
There is a vague
description by a woman
who was very much in shock.
Europe has a long
and sordid history
of animalistic murderers.
To be honest, I'm not convinced
this is an act of murder at all.
The French legal system
values hard evidence
more than eye witness testimony.
That nuance is certainly
relevant to this case
and I believe
it will work
in our favor.
You're an American
living in France,
an expatriate.
Well, um, both my parents
were human rights lawyers.
My father was French,
my mother an American.
When they divorced
I spent every summer
in France with my father.
INTERVIEWER: Mrs. Moore,
were you hesitant
to accept this case,
considering the victims
are American and
the defendant is French?
What matters to me
would be to see an
innocent man sent to prison.
Okay.
I think we got it.
Great.
Hey.
You look great.
Yeah, you too.
How are you?
I'm good, good.
Mmm. Oh...
Uh, how was your flight?
It was fine.
So, uh...
Good.
So you're doing
TV interviews now.
Yeah, I'm not used to that,
that's for sure.
Did I look as nervous as I felt?
No, you looked like
you'd been doing it
for years.
(CHUCKLING)
Good. Um...
Oh, here,
let's just move
out here. Um...
Been a while. So...
Damn, I didn't want
this to be awkward.
(CLEARS THROAT) Mmm...
Oh, hey.
Problem.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Mmm.  Monsieur?
Oh, shoot, uh, Eric,
this is Dr. Gavin Flemyng.
Kate, come on.
It's Gavin. Gavin.
Oh, okay.
KATE: He doesn't
speak French.
Very well.
The Gavin, right?
GAVIN: Mmm-hmm.
Yeah, I heard
a lot about you.
Come on in.
Thanks for helping out.
Ah, of course. Um...
GAVIN: Didn't realize
you were American as well.
Do you have a PhD
in wildlife forensics?
ERIC: Yeah.
Probably just set up right here.
Kate said you did
an amazing job
on a similar case
where you helped
redirect the investigation
from murder to animal attack?
Oh, no, he more than helped.
His testimony was instrumental.
ERIC: Oh, I hope
you can do
the same for us.
Here's the initial stuff.
(GAVIN CLEARS THROAT) Oh.
I just wanted to
thank you
for your time.
Uh, if you need anything,
like bios, statistics,
police reports,
hash... Anything.
(CHUCKLES)
Anything. Anything.
Um, actually,
I've already put a request
to examine
the victims' bodies
as soon as possible.
Maybe you can make, uh,
a request to the judge
so we can get
a quick response?
I'll lean on him.
Okay, so, uh,
back to the Claire
Porter interview.
The investigative judge
agreed to let you
review the tape,
so we're good on that.
He's also okayed you
sit down with Talan.
KATE: All right,
and who's investigating?
Uh, yes,
Captain Klaus Pistor.
Ex-military pilot.
Been heading up
murder investigations
for nearly a decade.
Every Thursday
he eats lunch at Pierre's,
orders the Croque-Monsieur
with Bleu d'Auvergne cheese.
Hates raisins, like crazy.
I think there's an
allergy issue there.
So if you want to kill him
that's the way to do it.
(MAN SPEAKING FRENCH)
(RESPONDS IN FRENCH)
Hang on a second.
Is there a...
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
It's good to see
you again, Kate.
Mmm.
Give it time.
You just got here.
I just remember
screaming.
He was tall and thin.
It had hair all over.
His hands, they were huge.
JUDGE:  You said "he."
CLAIRE:  He was eating
my boy alive.
(TAPE WHIRRING)
(SOBBING)
(STATIC)
Voila.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I'm sorry, uh,
you don't speak French.
Of course, you're English.
But you see there was
a camera malfunction
and, uh, Claire Porter's
condition was so poor
that the judge concluded
the interview.
So, you took Talan
Gwynek into custody
based on her description?
PISTOR: Yes, I did.
He more than fit
the description,
don't you think?
I am aware his
appearance is unique,
but did you pursue
other leads?
Uh, yes,
apart from surveying
the crime scene,
the entry points and
the attacker's footprints.
Uh, footprints?
We didn't, um...
We didn't see that evidence
in the investigation dossier.
Were they photographed or cast?
No, the heavy rain
had washed them away,
but the measurements
matched the suspect's.
Okay. Um...
I do find it a bit unusual
that you took my client
into custody
based on an inconclusive
eyewitness account
and not hard evidence.
Uh, we have
the camera malfunction,
the footprints
being washed away...
This investigation's
had some issues,
Commissaire.
You agree?
The test results
for your client's DNA
at the crime scene
will be back in
less than 48 hours.
So, I suggest
we continue this
conversation then.
That is if Gwynek's
DNA doesn't show up
at the crime scene.
Very good.
So why don't we go
see your, uh, client?
Thank you.
Follow me.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Your team will stay in
the observation room.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
You all right?
Mmm-hmm.
Very important.
You do not touch him.
You do not
hand him anything
unless I say it's okay.
But your guards
will not be allowed
to be in here.
It's my client's right.
I guess it is.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Okay, you have, uh,
only five minutes
for the initial meeting.
Five minutes?
Yes, believe me,
it will be long enough.
He hasn't spoken a word
since we arrested him.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
You can angle these cameras?
(DOOR BUZZING)
(KATE SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(KATE SPEAKING GERMAN)
Take it off, now!
(CHUCKLES)
Okay.
(PISTOR SPEAKS FRENCH)
(LOCK CLICKING)
(PISTOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
Okay, he's all yours.
Good luck.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Bonjour, Talan.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Talan...
Pistor.
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(DOOR BUZZING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Uh, I would like to
remove his handcuffs.
Oh, no, no, no.
I take full responsibility
for my security.
Absolutely, not.
No, categorically not.
His feet are chained
to the floor.
And you have guards
right outside this door.
Don't let me
regret this,
Ms. Moore.
Okay, Rineaux.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What's she doing?
(CHAIN RATTLING)
(PISTOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(EXHALING)
Thank you.
You speak English?
Did your mother
teach you how
to speak English?
Yes?
My mother,
how is she?
She's very worried about you.
And your father,
I have yet
to speak with him.
My father...
He...
Your father?
(DOOR BUZZES)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Listen, everything
is going to be okay.
We will talk again soon.
Until then, do not speak
to anyone else
about this case but me.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Help me.
(BUZZER BUZZING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
GAVIN: (STAMMERING)
Everything happened
so fast.
I got in there,
scratched my arm.
My glasses went flying.
Are you okay?
ERIC: Jesus Christ.
GAVIN: No, I'm fine,
I'm fine.
The whole thing just
happened so quickly.
You all right?
Yeah.
You didn't get hurt, right?
Yeah, thanks for
that back there.
I'm just your regular
knight in shining armor.
Did you hear
what he said to me?
He said, "Help me."
ERIC: That's what
he said?
Yes.
Wow.
GAVIN: You sure this is
the right case for you?
Yeah, more than ever.
This doesn't make
any sense.
You could have
been really hurt
back there, you know?
The guy can barely move.
There's no way
he could have committed
these crimes.
If his mobility is as
limited as it seems,
and, you know,
with those attacks,
then there's no way
he could have done it,
you know?
KATE: There's no way.
Wait. Do you know
where you're going?
ERIC: God sakes, Katherine.
Yes, I know where I'm going.
I'm going to look
it up on my GPS,
because I know your whole,
uh, brain GPS is...
You're like an
old married couple,
you two.
What?
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(GASPS)
GAVIN: Bloody hell!
KATE: Jeez.
Nice driving skills,
Eric, really.
Thanks, I got the instinct.
You all right?
GAVIN: I'm good.
ERIC: All right.
Shall we?
(KNOCKING)
(DOOR OPENS)
KATE:  Mrs. Gwynek,
can you tell us
what you remember
about the night
the Porters died?
He was home that night.
He was very sick.
He did not leave.
He couldn't.
Sick, how?
Talan's condition...
He can't move.
Can't even get out of bed
for days sometimes.
What was he like
as a child?
MRS. GWYNEK: Mmm...
He was a happy boy, a kind boy.
Children made fun of him,
called him names.
He didn't ever want
to leave the farm,
so we choose to
school him at home.
I take it you taught
Talan English as well?
Yeah, but he speaks
much better than me.
He's very smart.
Mrs. Gwynek,
your accent is
Eastern European.
It's Moldavian?
MRS. GWYNEK:
Uh, Romanian.
I was born there,
but we moved to France
when I was young.
We had family all over Europe.
Not so much anymore,
but we still remember.
Do you see me?
(ERIC LAUGHS)
And this is
your mother?
Oh, Mama.
She's beautiful.
KATE: And what about
this gentleman here?
Oh, was my uncle, Tavis.
He had the same
condition as Talan,
only he died before
it became too severe,
in the war.
KATE: Uh, what can
you tell us about
this condition?
Well, it's sometimes
passed down to the men
in our family.
Their bones too long
and too weak
for their bodies.
GAVIN: Has there been
any official diagnosis too?
MRS. GWYNEK: No.
No, no one's ever
been able to help.
We tried, but...
KATE: I'm sure you did
all you could.
Yeah.
What was it like
for Talan growing up?
He spent the most time
with his father.
He died last year.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
ERIC: Mrs. Gwynek, um,
if you don't mind,
would you speak about
what happened there?
(STAMMERING)
It was a car accident.
Uh, he was just
driving home late,
lost control...
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
KATE: Mmm.
That must have been
very hard on you.
It was hardest on Talan.
Mrs. Gwynek,
I'm having a really hard
time understanding
why they've decided
to target Talan.
Do you know why
they are convinced
that he's guilty?
Our land.
Your land?
Mmm.
They've always wanted this land.
If I give up my land,
will they give me
back my boy?
(GASPS)
GAVIN: Holy shit!
Hang on.
What is it? You okay?
MRS. GWYNEK:
What is it? No!
KATE: "Killer."
It says "Killer."
MRS. GWYNEK: No!
No, he's not killer!
Please, please,
people need
to know that! No!
He's no monster!
People need to
know that, please!
We're gonna help him.
(PANTING)
ERIC: So,
the government wanted
to turn the Gwynek's land
into a storage site
for nuclear waste,
which would have
given the town
a sizeable contract,
but the Gwyneks refused.
What's so special
about their land?
ERIC: The clay down there
is extremely dense,
which makes it safe for storage.
For nuclear waste?
Yeah.
I mean, nuclear energy
powers about 80% of France,
so their land is unique.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Valuable, I bet.
How much was
the contract?
Um, about 30 million euros.
It also says here
that Klaus Pistor
is on a committee trying
to win that contract.
You think he had
anything to gain?
That's a lot of money.
Especially down there.
You thinking about
his father's death?
Yeah, I am.
Yeah, me too.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
I just remember...
GAVIN: Kate! Eric!
...screaming.
I just, uh...
I was speaking to
a doctor friend of mine
from Oxford and, um...
(COUGHS)
Excuse me.
Um, we were discussing
Talan's appearance
and symptoms,
and there's
a very rare disease
called porphyria.
Um, symptoms include,
um, excessive facial
and body hair
and receding gums
which obviously makes
the teeth look longer.
And yeah,
it also causes crippling
chronic joint pain,
muscle weakness,
all sorts of nerve damage,
even seizures.
So, people with
this can barely move?
Exactly and it's so rare
that some doctors
haven't even heard of it.
Okay, great.
Uh...
What's up?
Uh, my necklace, it's gone.
GAVIN: Oh,
I haven't seen it.
ERIC: Sure it's around.
Uh, anyway, um,
this condition,
how do we test for it?
It's actually
pretty complicated.
It needs a pretty
specialized facility in order
to handle the tests.
There's only one
hospital around here
that can handle it.
How does one...
Is it genetic?
How does one catch it?
GAVIN: I'm not too sure,
you're gonna...
But, uh,
it's certainly
a good start.
Okay, perfect.
We'll request
an evaluation for Talan
tomorrow first thing.
Good. Good. Good.
Um...
I'm gonna go home.
Okay.
Kate, do you want...
Do you want to just
go grab a drink,
catch up for a second?
Um...
I'm beat. It's just...
It's been a hell
of a day, so...
Okay.
KATE: Okay.
All right.
Um, all right.
Good night.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
What the hell
are you doing, man?
GAVIN: What's that?
What are you doing?
Here with her?
What's going on?
Um, look, Eric.
I don't know you,
and you don't know
anything about my
relationship with Kate.
Actually, I know
a lot about your
relationship with Kate.
(SIGHS)
I don't give a shit about
your personal life, man.
I really don't.
I just hope
you're not trying
to win her back here.
We don't need that
kind of distraction.
Right, well, first off,
it's been five years.
Mmm-hmm.
Besides,
I'm in a relationship
so you can rest easy.
No, you're not.
Yes, I am.
You looking into
my private life?
I'm just doing my job, man.
You mind your
own business, mate.
How do I know I can trust a man
who steals information
for a living?
Mmm.
And actually, that reminds me,
why is it exactly
that you don't work
in the States, Eric?
You should go home.
(TYPING)
HENRY:  Oscar!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(CLAIRE SCREAMING)
(PETER SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
Oh, by the way,
we received
the DNA results,
but, uh, unfortunately,
they were contaminated.
(SCOFFS) We're relying
on those results.
Of course, we all were.
Right. Are you familiar
with the offer made
on the Gwynek land
for federal storage
and nuclear waste?
Of course. Of course,
in fact, I talked to
the judge already
and he said it was irrelevant.
The land dispute
complicates
the investigation,
and personally I agree with him.
Uh-huh. Oh,
I'm still adding it
to the dossier.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Well, you know,
that is your right,
I know.
But remember this
is a murder case,
not a land dispute. Okay?
Okay, the offer
made on the land
would have brought
30 million euros
to this community.
That type of motive...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
The motive?
Ms. Moore, come on.
Let's remember
who's on trial here.
No one is on trial yet,
Commissaire.
Wow, he didn't want
to touch that, did he?
(SCOFFS)
No, he didn't.
Can you get me
the police report on...
Talan's father's
death. Got it.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Well, I hope you
have strong stomachs.
(SIGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, God.
You don't have
to be here for this.
Oh, no problem.
You all right?
I'm fine.
Want a glass of water?
No, thank you.
Okay. I'll try and do this
as quick as possible.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
GAVIN: Okay...
Bodies have been
preserved in a negative
temperature chamber,
so there's minimal
to no decomposition.
Very vicious clawed attack.
Um, the back of the skull
has been completely
ripped away.
(CAMERA WHIRRS)
There's also
a discernible
bite pattern,
consistent in
a large animal attack.
The left femur being
completely exposed.
(CAMERA WHIRRS)
Bottom jaw's been
completely ripped away.
Also the tongue been
partially consumed.
(CAMERA WHIRRS)
Moving down here to the femur,
there's evidence
of severe mauling.
(SCOFFS)
Once again,
no evidence of
any type of weaponry
and the same bite pattern.
An animal did this.
(SCREAMS)
Fucking hell!
Oh!
You okay?
Fucking hell.
(CHUCKLES)
Let's take a look at the boy.
Right.
(DOOR BUZZING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
KATE: No.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING FRENCH)
(DOOR BUZZING)
(EXHALES)
Okay.
(CLEARS THROAT)
So I had hoped
to bring you
some good news
about the DNA,
but the samples were
cross-contaminated.
It's nothing to worry about.
It was just a mistake
at the lab.
It happens all the time.
And they're running
the new tests now.
But I do have some
good news for you.
We may know
the condition
you suffer from.
It's called porphyria.
Did any doctors ever
mention this to you
or your family before?
No?
The symptoms of this disease
and what you suffer
from are very similar.
And if you do test positive,
it will help prove
that you were
not physically able
to commit these crimes.
Uh, we'll have to
move you to a hospital
for some tests.
Is that something
you'd feel
comfortable with?
Yeah?
Okay.
I would like to talk about
the night of the deaths.
Do you remember
where you were
that night?
I cannot remember things
when I am sick.
Okay, I understand.
We call those blackouts.
Uh...
(KATE STAMMERS)
I thought I lost that.
It was bent,
but I straightened it.
Thank you, Talan.
It was my father's ring.
I lost my father
not long ago also.
I know how that feels.
Thank you.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Hey.
Is that Talan's arrest video?
KATE: He didn't even
put up a fight.
His father's
accident report.
Oh, good.
Pistor investigated
this case and Rineaux
was first on the scene.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
Single car collision,
no foul play,
ruled an accident.
Yeah, but check out
the toxicology report.
He had Phenobarbital
in his system.
He had 15 times
any normal
prescribed amount.
Fifteen?
I talked
to Mrs. Gwynek.
So she swore that her
husband has no history
of drug problems.
No depression problems,
no medical problems at all.
GAVIN: Okay, guys,
do you want to come
in here a minute?
I've just sorted
through my findings
for the, uh,
Henry Porter examination.
Yeah, uh, so why didn't Pistor
investigate his death
as a possible homicide?
Money makes people
do strange things.
GAVIN:
It certainly does.
Right, so, um, Henry Porter...
For the bite marks,
first of all,
indiscernible.
I can't tell you
what animal
they're from.
Um, also, Henry Porter's
skull was crushed
and it takes 1400 PSI
to crush a human skull.
And obviously a human's bite
is maximum 200 pounds.
Good, so not human.
No, no...
Um, so...
Sorry, excuse me a second.
What's up with him?
I don't know.
(EXHALING DEEPLY)
Fuck.
(GROANS)
He's a prick is
what's up with him.
Okay.
I mean, he's an animal expert.
There are thousands of them.
Why him specifically?
'Cause he's best
for the case, Eric.
Is that right?
Yeah.
He can't even tell us
what animal that is.
Let me ask you something.
You tell him
what happened to me
in the States?
What happened?
No! Why, did he
say something?
It wasn't her, mate.
It was me,
I found out myself.
It wasn't difficult.
You sold privileged
attorney-client
information for cash.
Solid work.
Cash? You don't know
what you're talking
about, all right?
So, please, shut the fuck up.
Eric.
What's going on?
Did you get sick or what?
Yeah, I don't know.
Yeah, I think it's
just the food here.
Yeah, France
is really known
for shit food.
Eric.
ERIC:  Oui.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
So, right,
anyway, um...
Where was I?
Uh, the bites.
So, it's definitely
not human, then?
Oh, yes.
So, no, no.
Uh, no, this was
a huge animal.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Good.
Oh, my God.
The hospital...
Claire Porter went into
septic shock and died.
Oh, Jesus.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Okay.
(RECEIVER CLATTERS)
So the judge
authorized your request
for a medical evaluation.
It seems that you made
an interesting point
concerning your client's
physical deficiencies.
(PHONE BEEPS)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Uh, thank you, Ms. Moore.
We'll keep you informed.
Uh, actually,
Commissaire, if I may.
Uh, I was going over
the police report
issued for Jorge
Gwynek's car accident.
You investigated this, yes?
Yes, that's correct.
Then, I'm sure
you're well aware
that he had 15 times
the prescribed amount
of Phenobarbital
in his system.
What's your point,
Ms. Moore?
As the investigating officer,
I feel like you have
ignored certain elements
pertaining to my client.
Why didn't you
at least investigate
the crash further?
Because I think that
he's a drug addict.
There is nothing in
his medical history
to suggest that he had
any substance
abuse problems. Nothing!
If you have any requests,
why don't you
put it in writing?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(PHONE RINGING)
Wait, please.
(PUTS DOWN RECEIVER)
(PISTOR SIGHS)
A farmer from outside the city
reported that some kind
of animal attacked
his horses.
He was standing on two legs,
over two meters tall,
covered in hair,
and called it
a "monster from hell."
That sure sounds
like the animal that
killed Henry Porter.
KATE: We'll follow you.
Yes, why don't you do that?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
KATE: Oh, my God.
(COUNTING IN FRENCH)
(CAWING)
(GASPS) Jesus!
(ROARING)
PISTOR: That's impossible.
There hasn't been a bear,
a wild bear in
this region for...
A hundred years.
KATE: This has to be
the bear that attacked
the Porters.
It's all consistent,
the area, the size
of the animal. Gavin?
We'll have to run some tests,
but this is looking good.
DNA results.
We need Gavin.
KATE: Gavin.
I was just, uh, reading
that there are certain
strains of porphyria
that are not only
passed genetically,
but in rare cases,
they can be transmitted
through blood
or any mucous membrane.
ERIC: Just gonna turn
this light on.
KATE: So, um, I need you
to look at this.
Talan's DNA results,
cross-contaminated again.
Well, get them to
do the test again.
Actually, can you, um,
ask them to send me
both DNA analysis reports
for both tests?
KATE: Here.
Hey.
What's wrong?
(SIGHS)
I don't know.
I'm worried about you.
No, don't.
You should be worried
about the case.
(CHUCKLING) Right,
'cause I'm never worried
about my cases.
Nothing's changed there then.
Yeah. Mmm.
(TYPING)
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
KATE: Do you think
he could have
done it, Gavin?
(SIGHS)
Look, there is no way
a man could have done
anything like that.
Yeah. Yeah.
You're doing a great job, Kate.
Thanks for saying that.
And you were right to move here.
I should have come with you.
I miss you, Kate.
I miss you too.
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
REPORTER:  The day
has come for Gwynek's
specialized testing
which could produce results that
exonerate him of
all criminal charges.
Jesus!
(INDISTINCT YELLING)
Um...
Stop.
(KATE SIGHS)
Why are you helping me, Kate?
Mmm.
Because I was taught
from a very young age
that everyone
deserves to be heard.
Especially the ones
that think
they don't deserve it.
They'll get what they want.
Do you want me to quit?
(CHUCKLES)
You thought
about it though?
Mmm. Yeah.
(KNOCKING)
(DOOR OPENS)
Yeah, come in.
(CHUCKLES) Oh.
(KATE CLEARS THROAT)
Uh, Talan,
these are my partners
Eric and Gavin.
You haven't officially met yet.
Talan.
Uh, Gavin is gonna explain
a few of the specifics
about the exam.
So, okay?
Okay, so, um, Talan,
along with the normal
battery of tests,
the lead physician
is also going
to administer, um, uh,
a corneal impression
to get a cell sample
of one of your eyes.
Um, this will be
the early indicator
of the porphyria.
After that,
he's going to attempt
a photic-induced seizure.
A photic-induced seizure?
It's strobing lights
that will cause stress
and trigger an attack.
It's the only way to
confirm the porphyria
and allow it to be
admissible in court.
All right,
we should get going.
Guards!
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
It's gonna work, right?
It has to.
Mrs. Gwynek, okay.
(SIGHS)
(COUGHS)
Rineaux.
(MONITOR BEEPING)
Commencing the examination
of patient Talan Gwynek.
Okay, we will now do
the corneal impression.
GAVIN: Relax, Talan.
The early indicator
for porphyria is positive.
Excellent, excellent.
DOCTOR:  Now let's move on
to seizure induction.
(CONTINUES BEEPING)
(KATE SIGHS)
PISTOR: Hmm.
I will need you to stare
at the flashing light.
(BEEPING ERRATICALLY)
Uh, doctor?
No, no, it's normal.
(CONTINUES BEEPING)
We need to stop this right now.
This is unusual.
GAVIN: Doctor, please!
(CONTINUES BEEPING)
GAVIN:  Help, somebody!
(GROWLS)
(YELLING)
No, no, no!
Gwynek, don't!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(STATIC CRACKLES)
KATE: How did this happen?
He could barely move.
That was not Talan.
I hope you're happy,
I hope you're happy!
All this is on your head!
How the hell were
we supposed to know
that this was going to happen?
I knew! You got
him transferred.
He killed three people
and now he's gone!
I promise I was only
doing what I thought
was best for my client!
I don't give a fuck!
Just go! Go!
Let me do my job. Go!
(SHOUTING IN FRENCH)
Go! Go! You go!
Fuck!
REPORTER:  Reports from Lyon
indicate four more dead.
Gwynek's whereabouts
remain unknown.
COMMENTATOR 1:
Where would our
werewolf legends be?
Put "luna" in the word lunatic.
COMMENTATOR 2:  Researchers
tracked down more than
a thousand reported attacks
and compared the dates
with the lunar cycle.
The most dangerous time
following a full moon.
(CLICKING KEYS)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
KATE: Eric? You here?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING) Eric?
Hey.
Did you spend all night here?
Yeah.
How you doing?
You all right?
Listen, uh,
I'm glad you're here.
Um, you know how we were
wondering how it was even
physically possible
for Talan to destroy
that hospital?
Yeah.
Okay, so,
bear with me.
You know how people
say the full moon
can make people go mad, crazy?
Yeah?
Okay. So, watch this.
COMMENTATOR 1:
Put "luna" in
the word lunatic,
but do we really know
what effect the moon
has on our lives?
ERIC: Okay, look.
CLAIRE:
The sky was so bright.
There was a full moon.
There's been these
studies on epileptics
where a full moon
triggers these
prolonged seizures.
They have these
violent outbursts
and they get almost this,
like, super human strength.
It has something
to do with water.
You know how
like the moon affects
the tides, right?
Mmm-hmm.
Well, human beings
have almost 60% water.
I mean, it kind of
makes sense, right?
They even have a name for it.
It's called the Lunar Effect.
Okay, so...
So you think he
becomes what he is
under the influence of the moon?
GAVIN:
What are you saying?
Hey.
Last night the moon was 98%.
Tonight, full moon.
What's this?
REPORTER:
It seems there's no more
running for Gwynek.
Police have
the building surrounded.
However, details on
how he escaped
a heavily guarded
hospital wing
remain unclear.
I'm going. Yeah.
I'm going to
get my coat.
Why? Pistor doesn't
want you there.
He's my client, Gavin.
I have a responsibility.
But he's a murderer, Kate.
Leave it alone.
I know he's a murderer, Gavin.
I'm done defending him.
I don't know, I mean,
if this Lunar Effect...
ERIC: You coming?
You're making a mistake, Kate!
KATE: Yeah, I'm coming.
A lot of people have died.
I don't want them to die
because of me, okay?
Yeah, well, the person
you're trying to save
is a fucking animal!
I know that, Gavin!
What do you want
me to say to you?
Haven't you helped him
kill enough people, Kate?
What?
(SCOFFS)
All right,
you need to stay here.
I don't want to see you.
Can you pull your
shit together, please?
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
OFFICER: Go, go, go!
Uh, Katherine Moore...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
KATE: Pistor!
What are you doing here?
I told you to stay away.
He is my client.
I don't want to see
anyone else hurt either,
all right?
Don't worry.
He's on the eighth floor.
He hasn't killed anyone yet.
We have the situation
under control.
Control? You have
no idea what
you're dealing with here.
Oh, really? Why don't you
tell me, Mr. American.
What are we dealing with here?
I think he has this condition
where his behavior is
affected by the moon.
The moon?
What are you
talking about?
His violence
isn't naturally there.
Okay, okay, okay.
All I know is
I don't want any more
innocent people
killed by that maniac.
He moves, he's dead.
(SIGHING)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
(EXHALING)
(GROANING)
Fuck.
(GROANS)
Oh, fuck.
(STATIC)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(EXHALING)
Talan Gwynek.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Pull your men back.
Right now!
He's right.
I don't want anyone
else to die, all right?
We got it.
Get them out of there now!
You don't know
what you're
talking about, okay?
(STATIC)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(TALAN GROWLING)
(GROWLING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
What have we done?
(MAN SCREAMING)
(HORN HONKING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(REPORTER SPEAKING FRENCH)
(PISTOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
MALE REPORTER:
Based on
eyewitness reports,
authorities believe
he is headed to
his home in Cerdon.
ERIC: Get in.
Get in. Get in.
GAVIN: I tried
to tell you, Kate.
I know, Gavin!
Fuck, what happened to your eye?
GAVIN: I saw the news,
what happened?
The guy fell 10 stories.
It was like  Planet
of the Fucking Apes.
He was standing right
in front of us, Gavin.
That thing inside of him,
it was not Talan Gwynek.
It's like he wasn't even...
GAVIN: He wasn't
even human?
Exactly.
GAVIN: I don't think
he is.
I looked at
the DNA analysis reports
Eric sent back to me.
The results were exactly
the same both times.
The contamination
patterns were identical.
The DNA just
wasn't classifiable.
ERIC: He's non-human?
Yeah. He's non-anything.
I don't know what he is.
GAVIN: It looks like
we're too late.
(KATE SIGHS)
She's not here.
GAVIN: What's with
all the security?
I'd say she was afraid.
What was she afraid of, huh?
Now she's gone.
She probably left to
meet him somewhere.
Fuck!
What if that was
her plan all along?
ERIC: No. What choice
did she have?
What are you talking about?
ERIC: Hang on,
hang on, hang on.
Think about it.
If 500 years ago
someone saw a man
with Talan Gwynek's
same appearance,
that condition, okay?
And that man was under
the influence of the moon.
This Lunar Effect,
and it made him predatory
and it made him
this killer,
this man eater.
Wait, it sounds
like you're talking
about a  loup-garou.
A werewolf?
Yes, they'd say
that he was not human.
He was a man and a beast
like Talan Gwynek.
All the more reason
that his whole family
should be exterminated.
(STAMMERING)
What? For 50 years
they lived in peace.
And then something bad happened.
Talan's father was killed
so that you could
profit from their land.
(PISTOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
GAVIN: Kate.
Kate.
I just need some air.
All right?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(DOOR CREAKING)
Mrs. Gwynek?
Mrs. Gwynek,
are you in here?
It's Katherine Moore.
It's just me, okay?
I know about the secret
you've been hiding
about your family.
I know you're...
I know you're, um...
You're just trying
to protect your son.
If they killed
your husband,
we can help you.
But Talan has to be stopped.
Please come out.
Please.
(GROWLING)
(KATE GASPS)
(OINKING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Fuck!
ERIC: Sorry.
Eric.
Sorry.
You go. You're not
supposed to be here.
KATE: Eric, I have
an ax in my hand.
Don't sneak up on me.
ERIC: What are you
doing in here?
Nothing. I thought
I saw something.
Yeah, I was worried about you.
Let's get out of here.
Where did the cop...
(GROWLS)
(GROANS)
Jesus Christ!
(GROWLS)
OFFICER: Police!
Talan Gwynek!
(GROWLS)
(GUNFIRE)
(GROWLING)
PISTOR:  I don't know.
I don't know.
At the rate he's moving,
he could be anywhere.
I don't think he's going
to leave the forest.
It's his home.
The cave system here,
he and his father spent
a lot of time there.
He grew up in those caves.
PISTOR: Okay, we leave
in one minute.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
He trusts you,
so you're going to
help me bring him in.
Let's go!
(DOOR CLOSES)
I'm not going.
Why?
I just need to figure
some things out, Kate.
I can't explain
right now. I can't.
Gavin, come on.
What the hell is
going on, really?
What is this about?
Show us your arm.
(ENGINE STARTING)
KATE: Listen,
what's going on?
Mmm?
Let me see your arm.
(GROANING)
Gavin!
Gavin, let me go.
Let me go!
(SOFTLY) What is that?
Oh.
I got, uh...
(EXHALES)
I got infected by Talan, um,
in the police station.
And that's why
you're changing?
(SIGHING)
KATE: Where did
you get that?
It doesn't matter.
If I do anything,
you use the gun.
Okay?
I'm scared.
Me too.
(SOBBING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(PISTOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
I hope you know
who you're trusting.
(STATIC)
(EXHALING)
(BANGING NOISES)
Gavin.
If you decide to
meet at the convoy,
I'm ready to take you.
Thank you, Officer.
Shh!
(MAN TALKING FRENCH OVER PA)
They found something.
Let's go.
KATE: Oh, my God.
PISTOR: (SHUSHING)
Stop. Stop. Stop.
There's something.
It's coming from
that hole. Quiet.
Shh!
Hold on.
Come on,
you motherfucker.
Show yourself.
(BATS SCREECHING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Fuck!
(CLATTER)
PISTOR: What is that?
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(OFFICER SCREAMS)
ERIC: Oh, shit!
(KATE GASPS)
Talan! Talan.
Talan, you don't
want to hurt him.
Okay?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Talan.
(GRUNTS)
I know what this man did to you.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Just...
Just let him go.
That's right.
That's right, Talan.
No one else has to die.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
KATE: That's right.
(SNIFFLES) Okay.
(GROWLING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Kate?
KATE:  Hey, are you
feeling okay?
Yeah, yeah, I feel pretty good.
Listen, I've found
a basement here.
I think it was used as
a holding cell for Talan.
His mother knew all along.
(STATIC CRACKLES)
He's dead, Gavin.
Hang on, I can hardly hear you.
I tried to plead with him.
They're taking his body
to the morgue.
Listen to me. If you
start feeling anything...
GAVIN: Kate, come on.
I feel fine.
Just be careful.
Watch Pistor, Kate.
He can't be trusted.
Oh, Jesus! Let's see.
Come back here.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Okay, come here.
Come here.
Who did this to you?
Can you tell me
who did this to you?
Look, I'm gonna get
you some help. Okay?
(EXHALING)
You said you'd protect him.
Now look what you did.
What's gonna happen to me?
I don't know.
I'm not your mother!
(GRUNTS)
But you won't ever be like him.
Not with what you did.
Your son did this to me.
You all said you'd protect him.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
Your son did this to me.
(GROWLING)
(WHIMPERS)
(SIREN WAILING)
ERIC: So what did
Gavin tell you?
Is he all right?
He said he was fine,
but I don't know.
ERIC:  We don't know.
It might be
too late for him.
He could be turning
into what Talan is.
A fucking animal.
We don't know that.
I pulled Gavin into this
and I'm gonna help him.
No matter what it takes.
(INDISTINCT WHIMPERING)
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Pistor's gonna do
what he wants to do.
He's gonna kill him
and who's to say
he's wrong?
(GRUNTING)
This is all about
money to Pistor
and I'm not gonna let him
get away with killing
Talan's father or Gavin.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(INAUDIBLE)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Eric!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Get in the car!
Eric, fuck, what are you doing?
(PISTOR SPEAKING FRENCH)
ERIC: Sixty,
70 miles an hour.
I couldn't catch him.
I couldn't catch up with him.
And they shot him,
like, 10 times,
and he didn't die.
He didn't die, Kate.
What does that mean?
He can't be killed?
Is that what that means?
Maybe they have to
shoot him in the head.
Is that what it is?
Is that the only
way that he can die?
(GROWLS)
KATE: Eric!
No!
Kate, run.
Talan, it's okay. No!
(GROWLS)
It's fine.
Talan, please, come on.
None of these people
understand you,
and they never will.
They're scared of you.
But I can help you.
Please, Talan.
Talan. Talan, no.
Talan, Talan, please, Talan.
No, no, no, Talan, Talan.
Talan, no!
Talan, no! Talan!
(SCREAMS)
No!
(TALAN GROWLING)
KATE: No!
Fuck!
No! No!
No!
No! No! Please! Please!
(SNARLS)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
Gavin?
(TALAN GROWLING)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
(MAN REPLIES IN FRENCH)
(GUNFIRE)
(SCREAMS)
(GROWLS)
(SNARLING)
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
(TALAN GROWLING)
No.
(GRUNTS)
(SNARLING)
(GUTTURAL SCREAM)
(GUNSHOT)
(SCREAMING)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(GROWLING)
(LABORED BREATHING)
FEMALE REPORTER:
It's a case that
has horrified France...
FEMALE REPORTER 2:
This story raises such
questions about humanity
and what human beings
are capable of.
FEMALE REPORTER 3:
Gwynek is now responsible for
killing more than 40 people.
MALE REPORTER:
Including two dozen
law enforcement officers,
his own mother, whom
he bludgeoned to death,
and Eric Serran,
a member of
his defense team.
FEMALE REPORTER:
Gwynek is assumed dead,
however, officials have
not recovered his body.
MALE REPORTER 2:
Katherine Moore remains
in serious condition.
Doctors are cautious,
but remain hopeful
for her recovery.
FEMALE REPORTER:  Deceased
Judiciary Officer Klaus Pistor
has been implicated
in a conspiracy to commit fraud
and the murder of Jorge Gwynek.
Another disappearance
near the Luxembourg border.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
that Talan Gwynek
is still at large.
Another disappearance
near the Luxembourg border.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
MALE ANCHOR:  After being
released from the hospital,
he has agreed to
an exclusive interview.
I'm glad to be here.
Thanks for having me.
Yes, it's hard to believe
it's almost been a month.
A couple found mutilated.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
I'm fine, thank you,
and Kate's recovering well.
A pregnant woman
has been
reported missing.
No, no, I don't think
he's dead at all.
Family members
say their son was
on a backpacking trip...
MALE REPORTER:  ...son
was on a backpacking trip
across Europe.
But you ask how
a human can do that
and my answer is simple.
He isn't human.
A brutal slaying near Cologne.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
No, no, the reports are
not embellished at all.
I've seen what he can do.
You've seen what he can do.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
INTERVIEWER:
Have you felt
any side effects?
Have you been
affected in any way?
An entire community
is living in fear
of what they're calling
The Beast of Strasbourg.
I'm completely serious
when I say to you
that Talan Gwynek,
by the mere definition
of the word...
Is a werewolf.
(GROWLING)