Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
- We drove them out.
- We should go after them.
We should finish it.
How you live, how you die...
it isn't up to me.
We vote.
He gunned that kid down.
I did what I had to do.
No, we're all infected.
If I was to kill you,
you come back as one of these things.
Where is the Governor!?
He fired on everyone.
Killed them all.
You're gonna join us.
( birds chirping, cawing )
( sighs )
♪ As I travel ♪
♪ Down life's pathways ♪
♪ Knowing not what ♪
♪ The years may hold ♪
♪ As I ponder... ♪
- ( clanking )
- ♪ Hopes grow fonder ♪
♪ Precious sacred ♪
♪ Scenes unfold ♪
- ♪ Precious... ♪
- ( walkers growling )
( fence rattling )
( snarling )
♪ Precious father ♪
♪ Loving mother ♪
♪ Fly across ♪
♪ The lonely years... ♪
( theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
You didn't wake me up.
'Cause I knew you were up all night
reading comics with a flashlight.
Carl:
What's up with Violet?
Carl, I told you
not to name them.
They're not piglets anymore.
They're food.
I just thought,
you know, until...
Okay.
I don't know
what's going on with her.
Could be sick,
could be nothing.
( clicking tongue )
Feel better, Violet.
Come on, let's get to it.
- Morning, Daryl.
- What's up, Dr. S?
- Man: Morning, Daryl.
- Man #2: Morning, Daryl.
Woman:
Hey, Daryl!
Smells good.
Just so you know,
I liked you first.
Stop.
You know, Rick brought in
a lot of them, too.
Not recently.
Give the stranger sanctuary,
keeping people fed,
you're gonna have to learn
to live with the love.
- Right.
- I need you to see something.
Patrick, you want to take over?
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Dixon,
I just wanted to thank you for
bringing that deer back yesterday.
It was a real treat, sir.
And I'd be honored
to shake your hand.
( growling )
About today, I don't know
if we're gonna be able
to spare a lot of people
for the run.
That place is good to go.
We're gonna move on it.
Yeah.
The thing is, we had a pretty
big buildup overnight.
Dozens more
towards tower three.
It's getting as bad
as last month.
They don't spread out anymore.
With more of us sitting here,
we're drawing more of them out.
You get enough of those damn
fence-clingers, they start to herd up.
Pushing against
the fences again.
It's manageable, but unless we
get ahead of it, not for long.
Sorry, Pookie.
( scoffs )
( snarling )
You like that?
( sighs )
I don't think
you should go today.
Really?
Yeah.
We have the suits.
Yeah, but you don't have to go.
You shouldn't.
You know everything's
gonna work out, right?
Right?
Right.
But you're staying, okay?
Fine.
Hey, beautiful.
Hey yourself.
- You need an apron.
- Yeah.
Listen, can we talk?
I was thinking of going
on the run today.
Okay.
I don't like killing
them on the fence.
I hate it.
I mean, when they're
coming at you out there,
it's different.
You don't even think about it.
When they're stacked up
against the chain-link,
you're just face-to-face.
I...
I just wanted to do something
different to help out.
You always volunteered to do it.
That's because you
were always doing it.
( laughs )
Just thought I could
get to know you.
You did.
You be careful out there.
Hey.
I was just gonna come find you.
- Hi.
- What's up?
Well, the council pulled back
everyone on the coal crew
from going on the run.
They're shorthanded right now.
I figured I'd step up
to help, go with 'em.
Just, you know, wanted to make
sure that I saw you before.
Okay.
I just--
'cause, you know,
it's dangerous going out there.
I know.
( kisses )
Okay, are you
gonna say good-bye?
Nope.
It's like a damn romance novel.
Hey.
I'd like to start pulling
my weight around here.
Bob, it's only been a week.
That's a week worth of meals,
a roof over my head.
Let me earn my keep.
- You were out on your own
when Daryl found you. - That's right.
I just want to make sure you
know how to play on a team.
We ain't gonna do it
unless it's easy.
You know he was
a medic in the Army.
You a hell of a tough sell.
You know that?
Okay.
( engines start )
These leaves are gonna
be in the shade,
so we won't get
any good fruit from it.
So we just pinch it off here.
Things break,
but they can still grow.
These little bristles,
they'll take root
and we'll have
a whole new plant.
( whistles )
Rick:
Let's go.
( growling )
( grunts )
We're glad to see you.
Glad to see you, too.
Somebody hit the jackpot.
No way.
Awesome!
Thank you.
I get to read 'em
when you're done.
And I found this.
Your face is losing the war.
( chuckles )
You gonna stay a little while?
Just a little while.
( motorcycle revving )
Well, look who's back.
Didn't find him.
Glad to see you in one piece.
I'm thinking of looking
over near Macon.
It's worth a shot.
Daryl:
70 miles of walkers.
You might run into
a few unneighborly types.
Is it?
I'm gonna go check out
the Big Spot.
The one I was talking
about, just seeing.
Rick: Yeah, I got to go
out and check the snares.
I don't want to lose whatever
we catch to the walkers.
I'll go.
You just got here.
And I'll be back.
( revs motor )
( engine starts )
( growling )
- Going to check the snares?
- I am.
You're not.
Do your chores.
Read comics.
Maybe some books, too.
Hang out with Patrick.
Maybe go to story time.
Dad, that's for kids.
Yeah.
Now brush her down.
Nothing wrong with
staying close, Rick.
Everyone understands.
You're growing us enough food
so we won't need
to do runs soon.
But we do have to find you
a good pair of overalls.
You need to look the part.
A little piece of wheat out
of the corner of your mouth.
Maybe a bigger ass.
( laughs )
Yeah.
Listen, the rest
of the council--
Daryl, Glenn, Carol, Sasha,
all of them--
they wanted me to talk to you.
When you go out there,
you got to take your gun.
- ( horse snorts )
- Easy now.
It's just outside the fence.
I have my knife.
I get in trouble, six bullets
isn't gonna make the difference.
Rick, we want you to be safe.
Bring your gun.
( flies buzzing )
( grunting )
( rustling )
Wait.
Please.
Please?
Please help me.
I know you don't know me.
Okay, I know that.
But can you please help me
get this to my husband?
We haven't eaten in days.
Here.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Do you have a camp around here?
Yeah.
Could we possibly
come back with you?
We've been doing...
very badly on our own.
I'd have to meet him.
I need to ask him some
questions, both of you.
What questions?
Just three.
When we get there.
You have a gun on you?
Can I make sure?
Yeah.
Look, I don't know you,
so I'm just gonna
tell you this.
You try anything--
anything--
you're gonna be
the one who loses.
I don't have
anything else to lose.
No.
You do.
Go ahead.
( growling )
Child:
Nick, look over here.
Child #2:
This one's Wayne.
- Nick.
- Nick, over here.
Hi, Nick!
- Hi, Nick.
- Carl: You're naming them?
Well, one of them
has a name tag,
so we thought
all of them should.
They had names when they were alive.
They're dead now.
No, they're not.
They're just different.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Okay, they don't talk.
They don't think.
They eat people.
They kill people.
People kill people.
They still have names.
Have you seen what happens?
Have you seen someone
die like that?
Yeah, I have.
They're not people
and they're not pets.
Don't name them.
We're supposed to go read.
Come on.
You coming to
story time tonight?
Uh, yeah.
See you then.
I go sometimes.
I'm immature.
You wouldn't dig it.
It's for kids.
I'm gonna head up there, too.
I'll catch you later,
young sir.
Yep.
Army came in
and put these fences up.
Made it a place
for the people to go.
Last week when we
spotted this place,
there was a bunch of walkers
behind this chain-link
keeping people out
like a bunch of guard dogs.
( music blaring over radio )
So they all just left?
Give a listen.
( music continues playing )
You drew 'em out.
Put a boom box out there
three days ago.
Hooked it up
to two car batteries.
All right, let's make a sweep.
Make sure it's safe.
Grab what you can.
We'll come back tomorrow
with more people.
Come on.
( pounding )
Just give it a second.
Okay, I think I got it.
Got what?
I've been trying to guess what
Daryl did before the turn.
He's been trying to guess
for, like, six weeks.
Yeah, I'm pacing myself.
One shot a day.
All right, shoot.
Well, the way you are
at the prison,
you being on the council,
you're able to track,
you're helping people, but
you're still being kind of...
surly.
Big swing here.
Homicide cop.
( laughing )
What's so funny?
Nothing.
It makes perfect sense.
Actually, the man's right.
Undercover.
- Come on, really?
- Yep.
I don't like to talk about it
'cause it was a lot
of heavy shit, you know?
Dude, come on, really?
( clears throat )
Okay. I'll just keep
guessing, I guess.
- Yeah, you keep doing that.
- Mm-hmm.
( snarling )
- We're gonna do this, Detective?
- Let's do it.
( doors open )
All right, we go in, stay
in formation for the sweep.
After that, you all know what
you're supposed to look for.
Any questions?
Was there ever a time that
you weren't the boss of me?
You had a few years
before I was born.
( growling )
( birds chirping )
We were going
to Puerto Vallarta
for our honeymoon.
When they shut down
the airports,
our connecting flight
never connected.
They wouldn't let us
leave the terminal, so...
we slept next to these huge
marble sculptures
from Zimbabwe.
Then, on the fourth night,
the things just came through.
There were a lot of us and...
now it's just Eddie and me.
And I wouldn't have made it
if it wasn't for him.
And it isn't that...
he saved me over and over again
or that he showed me the things
that I had to do or...
to be willing to do.
If he wasn't still here...
I-- I couldn't be.
I just-- I couldn't.
What were they?
What?
The things you had
to be willing to do?
Um...
eating whatever
we could find--
animal carcasses
and rotten fruit-- and...
leaving people behind.
Hiding from people
who needed my help.
Unlike you.
This is not charity.
You have to have numbers.
People are the best
defense against walkers
or people.
We help each other.
You call them "walkers"?
( yelling )
( growling )
You all right?
You cut or something?
No, man, but my foot is caught.
All right. He's just caught.
Come on, help me up.
- What happened? - Everyone's all right.
We're over in wine and beer.
( roof creaking )
I was moving fast, man.
I drove right into the drinks.
Man, you lucked out. If this thing had
come down on you the wrong way...
( snarling )
Yeah, uh, we should
probably go now.
Bob's still stuck.
Get him out of there.
We'll get the others.
Hey!
I saw those sculptures
at the airport once.
My favorite was the kids
playing leapfrog.
Mine, too.
What Eddie and I had to do,
did you do things like that?
Did you?
Do you think you get
to come back from them?
I hope so.
Yeah?
I hope we answer
your three questions
to your satisfaction.
( growling )
( grunting )
( snarling )
( machine-gun gunfire )
( clicks )
Hey!
( growling )
Daryl, go!
( gunfire )
Let's get Bob.
- ( grunting )
- Bob: More, more.
Come on, time to go.
Let's go, now!
Come on! Go!
- Let's get out of here!
- Ah!
( shouting )
( screaming )
- Zack!
- ( screaming )
Go, go!
Come on!
It's just ahead.
Eddie.
Oh, thank God
you're still here.
This is Rick.
He's gonna help us.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Everything--
( breathing heavily )
- ( blade scrapes )
- ( shouting )
Damn it!
( sobbing )
I wanted to take the boar.
I just knew-- I knew I'd get
you here so much quicker.
He's starving.
He's slowing.
He needs something alive.
Please, I told you,
I can't be without him.
And so I kept him.
It was wrong.
( breathing heavily )
I can't do things like this.
And-- and you have to do
things like this.
Let me be like him.
Don't stop it.
Don't end it after.
- No.
- Let me be with him.
No!
( groans )
( gasping )
Hey.
What were...
the questions?
The three questions?
How many walkers
have you killed?
Eddie--
Eddie killed--
killed them all.
Until...
( gasping )
How many people
have you killed?
Just me.
Why?
( gasping )
You don't--
you don't get to come back.
You don't get to come back
from things.
You don't...
( gasping )
( growling )
"The children fastened their eyes
upon their bit of candle
and watched it melt
slowly and pitilessly away.
Saw the half inch of wick
stand alone at last.
Saw the feeble flame
rise and fall.
Climb the thin tower of smoke.
Linger at its top
a moment and then..."
Ma'am, should I take watch now?
Yes, Luke, you do that.
Today...
we are talking about knives--
how to use them,
how to be safe with them, and
how they could save your life.
Patrick: Ma'am,
may I be dismissed?
- What is it?
- I'm not feeling very well.
Sometimes you're gonna
have to fight through it.
What if you wind up
out there alone?
You just give up
because you're feeling bad?
No, it's just I don't want
to yack on somebody.
Go.
Okay, today we're gonna
learn how to hold a knife,
how to stab and slash
and where to aim for.
Please, don't tell your father.
( growling )
What?
I don't like going
out there, either.
( sighs )
Daryl's telling Beth.
There's nothing else to do.
I'll go see her.
I'm not pregnant.
- You know?
- I know.
- Oh, thank God.
- Yeah.
Oh, my God.
I didn't want to,
but we could have.
We can have lives here.
How can you say that
after today?
After Lori?
Because I don't want to be
afraid of being alive.
Being afraid
is what's kept us alive.
No.
It's how we kept breathing.
Hey.
Hi.
What is it?
( sighs )
Zack.
Is he dead?
Okay.
What?
I don't cry anymore, Daryl.
I'm just glad I got
to know him, you know?
Me, too.
Are you okay?
Just tired of losing
people is all.
I'm glad I didn't
say good-bye.
I hate good-byes.
Me, too.
You tried to help her.
You couldn't.
No one could.
Some people are too far gone.
You're not.
You tried to help her.
How that woman wound up,
I got close to that.
If I lost Carl and Judith,
if I lost this place--
Not then, Rick.
Not even then.
You came back.
Your boy came back.
You get to come back.
You do.
( sighs )
( coughing )
( breathing heavily )
( panting )
( wheezing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com