WITHIN THE SPREADING DARKNESS.
I EXCHANGED VOWS OF REVOLUTION.
BECAUSE I MUSTN'T LET ANYONE INTERFERE WITH ME.
IN THE FUTURE THAT THE FRUIT TOLD ME OF.
DREAMS, TURN INTO IDEALS
EVERYONE WISHED FOR AN END...
WITHIN THE SPREADING DARKNESS.
I EXCHANGED VOWS OF REVOLUTION
I MUSTN'T LET ANYONE INTERFERE WITH ME
SOMEDAY, I'LL SHOW YOU
A SHINING WORLD
Shinigami World
What ?
Two death's-heads ?
Hehe, I win again ! Lucky me !
Hey, Ryuk. Wanna play ? Join in once in a while.
No thanks. I'll pass.
So. I didn't even do anything but he got all pissed.
Really ? Then what ?
Yagami-kun...
are you listening ?
Will you translate that last part ?
You should follow god's teachings.
If you do, the sea will remain quiet and the storm will not come.
Today at 11a.m...
at an apartment complex in Yokoshama in the Karnagawa Prefecture,
a man in his 30's was found dead and covered in blood.
Police have ruled the killing to be a homicide and are...
Our next story...
Today in Shibuya, Tokyo.
Naoki Toiuji, age 35, was arrested for suspicion
of murdering his roommate, a 25-year old woman.
Day after day...
The same old thing.
What a waste...
This world is...
Rotten...
Rebirth
You went to see that ?
What a waste of time. I should get a refund.
"Death Note"... ?
A Notebook of Death ?
"How to Use It...
The human whose name is written in this note shall...
Die."
Ridiculous.
Really, talk about sick.
This is as bad as those chain-letters.
The person whose name is written dies, my ass.
Sheesh, there must be something wrong with me.
"This note will not take effect unless the writer has the person's
face in their mind when writing his or her name.
Therefore, people sharing the same name will not be affected."
"If the cause of death is written within 40 seconds
of writing the person's name, it will happen."
"If the cause of death is not specified, the
person will simply die of a heart attack."
"After writing the cause of death, details of the death should
be written in the next 6 minutes and 40 seconds."
Hmm. So you can let people die peacefully,
or make them suffer...
Impressive that someone would put so
much effort into a prank like this...
Write in their name, and they die... ?
Really, how stupid.
Wait a minute.
If someone actually dies, would that make me a murderer ?
Heh, as if it could really happen.
The man who indiscriminately killed and wounded
six people yersteday in Shinjuku...
is still barricaded inside this nursery school
with eight hostages including little children.
The Metropolitan Police have determined the man's identity
as Kurou Otoharada, 42 years old and unemployed.
They are currently trying to negotiate with him.
Forty seconds and it's a heart attack, right ?
...and we don't know that as of yet.
I'm so worried about the hostages.
Me too.
That's the report from the scene.
Thank you very much.
What are you thoughts, Hashimoto-san ?
I hope the situation is resolved soon.
In the end, nothing happened, I knew it.
What was I expecting ?
Ah, wait a minute !
We have a new development !
The hostages are coming out !
They all seem to be all right.
And noe the police are going in ! Will
they be able to arrest the suspect ?!
Yes !
This message just in !
The captor has died inside the nursery school !
It appears the suspect is dead !
Dead ?!
The police are emphasizing that they did not shoot him.
Could that mean he committed suicide ?
Well, the hostages are apparently
saying he suddenly collapsed...
A heart attack...
N-no ! A coincidence !
It has to be !
Light !
It's 6:30pm already.
You have your prep course today, right ?
Uh, yeah. I was just getting ready to go.
Death Note...
If this is real...
I should test it one more time.
So I guess it has to be a criminal after all...
But not anyone too major...
or the cops might keep it secret for a while.
I need the results right away.
Hey. Ryo baby.
Uh... what. Sudou-kun ?
Lend me some money. Two thousand will do.
Eep. Again ?
Sudou.
Try killing him ?
No. I should avoid anybody I actually know...
No, it doesn't even matter.
A guy like that, nobody's even going to care...
Sweet ! We're going to the arcade tonight !
Hey, Maki. Wanna go on a group date tomorrow ?
Yeah, totally !
My mom isn't here yet ?
What's that bitch doing, geez !
Damn...
Start looking around you...
And all you see are people the world
would be better off without.
Onee-san~ !
How 'bout havin' some fun with us tonight ?
Hey Taku-san, you got good taste, man.
My name's Shibuimaru Takuo, that's
Shibutaku for short, heh heh...
(Shibutaku = Cool Taku )
Come on, Onne-san, how about it ?
I... don't think so...
She doesn't think so, dude !
Aww, so cute !
Let's take off all her clothes !
Hah. You sure ? Hehehe !
Please stop !
STOP !!!
Now...
What will happen ?!
Wait !
Taku, watch out !
This... proves it !
The Death Note is real !
Oh... Taku !
God... damn idiot, what the hell were you thinking ?
'Bout time I got going.
It's been five days.
Hm ? Where you off to, Ryuk ?
Anyplace you go around here, it's all barren anyway.
I dropped my Death Note.
Whoops ! You really screwed up, man !
Hey, weren't you carrying around a second
one behind the Old Man's back ?
You sayin' you lost both ?
So, you got any idea where you dropped it ?
The Human World.
Ah ?!
Eh ?!
Welcome Home !
You're back early, Light.
Yeah.
I'm home, mother.
Oh, yeah. The results of the national exam.
Hurry.
Here.
Oh, my !
You placed first again !
Great job, Light !
Well. I'll be studying so don't bother me, okay ?
Sure, dear.
Oh, Light.
Is there anything you've been wanting ?
Anything at all ?
Nothing in perticular. Mom.
I already have what I want.
You seem to be enjoying it.
Why are you so suprised ?
I'm Ryuk, the Shinigami who dropped that notebook.
The way you were acting just now...
I can tell you know it just any old notebook... right ?
Shinigami, huh ?
I'm not surprised to see you, Ryuk.
In fact...
I've been waiting for you... Ryuk.
Oh ?
Not that I doubted that this was a "Death God's notebook",
but seeing things with my own eyes like
this lets me act with greater certainty.
I see.
Gotta say. I'm the one who's surprised.
I've heard of Death Notes reaching down
the human world a few times before...
But this is the first time I have seen someone
do so much in just five days.
Most people would be too scared.
I'm ready for anything, Ryuk...
I used the notebook, knowing it belonged to a Shinigami...
And now the Sinigami's here...
What happens to me now ?
You going take my soul or something ?
Huh ? What's that ?
Some fantasy you humans came up with ?
I'm not going to do anything to you.
The moment a Death Note lands in the humans world...
that Notebook belongs to the human world.
So it's yours now.
Mine...
If you don't want it, give it to another human.
So there really is no to pay for using the Death Note ?
One could say...
the terror and torment that only humans who've
used it, will experience is the price...
And when you die...
I'll be the one writing your name down in my notebook, but...
Don't think that any human who's used the Death Note...
can go to Heaven or to Hell.
That's all.
Something to look forward to when you die.
Light.
It'll be fine. Answer it.
What ?
I brought some apples.
You'll damage your eyes.
What's going on ?
She can't see him ?
That originally was my notebook.
Since you've used what was my notebook.
you're the only one who can see me.
Nobody else can hear me either, of course.
You could say that the Death Note...
is the bond between Light the human and Ryuk the Shinigami.
Yum.
Okay, one more question.
Why did you choose me ?
Hey, are you listening ?
Wow, human world apples are great.
What do they call this ?
Juicy ?
Answer the question.
Ha, I didn't choose you.
All I did was drop the notebook.
You thought I chose you cause you're so smart or something ?
It just happened to land somewhere around here
An you just happened to pick it up.
That's all.
That's why I wrote the instructions in English,
it's the most popular lamguage in your world.
Then why did you drop it ?
Don't tell me it was by mistake.
after you went wrote all those instructions.
Why you ask ?
Because I was bored, that's why.
Bored ?
THe fact is, Shinigami these days have a lot to do
All they do is nap, or gamble.
If they see you scribbling humans' names
into your Death Note, they say:
"What're you working so hard for ?" and laugh at you.
Writing names of those in the Shinigami realm won't kill them.
And killing people in the human world
while I'm up there isn't any fun at all.
It's more fun to be here, is how I figured it.
Gotta say, though, you really wrote a lot of names in here.
But how come you only specified the cause of death
for the guy who got hit by a truck and nobody else ?
If you don's specify the cause of death,
they all die from a heart attack.
That's the best thing about the Death Note, Ryuk.
Huh ?
I've already covered the most vicious criminals.
So now the level of atrocity is coming down.
So what about that ?
Even a fool is going to notice that somebody
is bumping off the bad guys.
I'm going to make the whole world know of my existence.
That somebody is passing righteous judgment !
But I was wondering why you would go through all that trouble ?
I... was also bored...
Of course. I didn't believe it at first.
But that notebook has a power...
that makes anybody want to try using it, at least once.
I... I've killed...
I've... killed... two people...
It's life...
It can't be so easy
Do I have the right to punish others... ?
No, wait...
This is waht I've been thinking all along...
This world is a rotten mess.
Those who are rotten should die !
Somebody...
Somebody, has to do it !
Even if it costs them their mind and soul !
This world needs to be cleansed !
Suppose someone else picked up this notebook...
could they get rid of the useless people of this world ?
Of course not !
But I can...
I can do it !
No, I'm the only one who could do it !
I'll use the Death Note...
to change the world !!
First, to cleanse the world
I wrote down the names of all the major criminals.
Soon, nobody will commit crimes anymore.
And, while people who obviously deserve to
be punished are dying of heart attacks...
I'll gradually be killing off immoral people, and people
who harass others, through illness and accidents.
Then the world will start to become a better place.
And I'll make this a world inhabited by
only the people I acknowledge as good !
But then you'll be the only bastard left...
What are you talking about, Ryuk ?
I'm a serious, straight-A student...
And I..
...will be the God of the new world !
I was right, humans are...
interesting !
To be continued...
I had a dream that no one else could have
and I threw away everything that I didn't need
Thoughts that I can't surrender dwel in my chest
Even if I'm still in the rift between reality and ideals
and my feet are bound by shacles of sacrifice
My overflowing impulses aren't fully repressed
Because I have a heart that yearns powerfully
"Lies" "Fear" "Facade" "Grief"
I won't be weak enough
To be apprehended by the various negative things
I'm a trickster who doesn't know loneliness
Preview
The whole world is watching...
to see what happens when you defy me...
L
Next Episode
Battle