Previously on "Hannibal"
Georgia Madchen was murdered
by whoever killed Dr. Sutcliffe.
- Dad? It's for you.
- They know.
He said he got so close to
Garret Jacob Hobbs
- he was becoming him.
- My name is Will Graham.
- You think he's mentally ill?
- Whoever killed Marissa Schuur
and Cassie Boyle wanted to copy
how Hobbs killed his victims.
- Now he has Hobbs' daughter.
- Who Hobbs intended to kill.
- Mind if I sit?
- Did Hannibal tell you?
- No, he didn't.
- How many people have you killed?
- Many more than your father.
- Are you gonna kill me?
(gunshot)
(moaning)
(catching his breath)
(dog barking)
- Oh!
(suspense music)
(Vehicle approaching)
I went to Minnesota.
I took Abigail.
We went to Minnesota and...
She didn't come back with me.
Show me.
I don't remember
going to bed last night.
But...
I must have.
I- I don't know, maybe I
got up to let the dogs out,
and, and, and then...
- When was the last time you saw Abigail?
- I woke up, my feet were muddy.
Will. When was the last time
you saw Abigail?
Yesterday.
At her father's cabin.
I had...
an episode.
Uh, she said something
was wrong with me.
She was afraid of me.
And she ran away.
What happened?
Why was she afraid?
I hallucinated
that I killed her.
But it wasn't real.
I know it wasn't real.
Will, we have to call Jack.
You can't run from this.
It'll only be worse.
Get dressed.
(Theme song)
Hannibal 01x13
Savoureux
Original Air Date June 20, 2013
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com
What are we gonna find
in Minnesota, Will?
I don't know.
Go ahead and process him.
(Dog whimpering)
Right rear pocket.
A leather wallet
containing 17 dollars cash.
Right rear pocket.
Leather wallet,
17 dollars cash.
Right front pocket.
One folding knife.
Folding knife.
I can't do the
silent treatment.
I can't pretend I don't know
you and I can't pretend
we both don't know what
I'm finding under your nails.
You called me once because you didn't
trust yourself to know what was real.
- This blood is real, Will.
- I know.
Do you know how it got there?
Not with any certainty, no.
Certainty comes
from the evidence.
I didn't want to find
any evidence on you.
I wanted to be certain
about who you are,
but you can't even be
certain with yourself.
Not anymore.
If you weren't certain with yourself,
you shouldn't have been here.
This is the FBI.
I thought I would get better.
You always said you interpret
the evidence, so do it, Will.
Interpret the evidence.
According to the evidence...
I killed Abigail Hobbs.
We analyzed the tissue.
It matched Abigail Hobbs.
It was her ear,
her blood under
Will's fingernails.
Scratches on his arms
are all defensive wounds,
like she fought back.
Shut up.
- I-
- stop talking.
"He won't get too close."
You said you would cover him.
- You could see he was breaking.
- Yes, I could.
And I kept pushing him
because he was
saving lives, Alana.
Not Abigail Hobbs' life.
You look me in
the face and tell me
that you couldn't see
that he was breaking?
Of course, I could see it.
I told you not to
put him out there!
Every decision I made
concerning Will's mental health
I made under advisement
of a respected psychiatrist,
who you recommended.
Hannibal had to know. He had
to see something was wrong.
Not until it was too late.
Just like everybody else.
(Sighing)
Hannibal said that Will was
exhibiting signs of dementia.
Dementia isn't a disease.
It's a symptom of disease!
We have to find out what's
causing it and treat it!
The concern is that there
may not be anything to treat.
Will had a brain scan.
They found nothing.
Well then, they don't know
what they're looking for.
This started with
Garret Jacob Hobbs.
Maybe Will just did
what Hobbs couldn't.
He killed his daughter.
Abigail's blood
is on all of us.
And so is Will's.
(Silent screams)
Hi.
You're flushed.
You been yelling?
- Screaming is more like it.
- I could use a good scream.
I can feel one
perched under my chin.
- Let it out.
- I'm afraid that if I started...
I wouldn't be able to stop.
I'm surprised Jack
let you in here,
given my romantic overtures.
Jack doesn't know about
your romantic overtures.
Didn't know.
(Whispering): I guess you
dodged a bullet with me.
I don't feel like
I dodged a bullet.
I feel wounded.
I've been in touch with,
um, animal services.
I'll go pick up your dogs
in a couple hours.
I'll take them back
home with me... (Sniffling)
and I'll take care
of them until...
whenever.
Whenever could be
a long time from now.
I'll take care of them
until then.
Thank you.
We have to do some tests.
They'll be the standard
psychopathology tests.
I suppose you're gonna ask me to
draw a clock while you're at it.
Did Hannibal
ask you to draw a clock?
Said it was an exercise...
to ground me
in the present moment.
A handle to help me
hold on to reality.
Was the clock normal?
Would I be here if it wasn't?
Draw me a clock.
You see?
It's just a normal clock.
Telling the time
isn't my problem.
(Sighing)
It's the least of
your problems.
Seems hard
to find words today.
(Sighing)
Despite the
overwhelming evidence,
I find myself searching
for ways
that Abigail
could still be alive.
Grieving is an
individual process
with a universal goal:
the truest examination
of the meaning of life
and the meaning of its end.
I know what life means.
We've existed for
a hundred thousand years.
In that time,
a hundred billion human lives
have had beginnings and ends.
A hundred billion lives
haven't impacted yours,
but clearly
Abigail Hobbs' life has,
and you seem
surprised by that.
I never considered
having a child.
But after meeting Abigail,
I understood the appeal.
The opportunity to
guide and support,
and in many ways,
direct a life.
You were having
influence on her?
I was hoping I was.
Young people are
supposed to be the lenses
through which we see ourselves
living beyond this life.
I think of my earliest memory
and project forward to what
I imagine will be my death.
I never think about living
beyond that span of time.
Except by reputation.
Even after this loss?
More so after this loss.
Will Graham is a loss, too.
You might grieve him
as a loss.
I haven't given up on Will.
If they do find him guilty
of killing Abigail Hobbs...
When.
Let's be honest.
I don't recommend
you participate in any
rehabilitation effort.
I was so confident in
my ability to help him...
To solve him.
To save him.
Saving him,
I lost Abigail.
It's hard to accept
that I could fail them both
so profoundly.
- Okay Jimmy, what have you got?
- Um, as you know,
Will is a big fly fisherman,
and he designs
all of his own lures.
Most anglers use feathers, fur,
twine, bits of shell.
They design each lure
to catch a specific fish.
This one caught my eye.
I noticed the hair color. Took me a
few to accept what I was seeing.
- I ran a chem-set to confirm the connection.
- What connection?
Four of the lures are made from
materials including human remains.
And we have a DNA match
for all of them.
This one is Cassie Boyle.
Bits of bone fragments
and pieces of lung.
Marissa Schuur. Antler velvet,
a fingernail,
wound with her hair.
Doctor Sutcliffe.
Crushed teeth, soft tissue
from inside his mouth,
bound with cartilage from his jaw.
All victims of the copycat?
And this last lure
was made with hair and fiber
- that matches Georgia Madchen.
- He took trophies of all his victims.
Trophies. So now Will Graham's a
serial killer who takes trophies?
Something's wrong with Will
physically, neurologically.
He's not a serial killer.
(Sound of a horse trotting)
(Suspense music)
You're sick, Will.
I - I wasn't consistent with
taking my antibiotics.
The fever came back.
We're gonna move you to
a secure medical ward.
We're gonna get to the bottom
of whatever it is that's wrong
with you and we're
gonna make sure
that you get whatever kind of
treatment you need.
And then what?
Baltimore State Hospital
for the Criminally Insane?
Have Chilton fumbling
around in my head?
This job doesn't generally
lend itself to optimism,
all right?
But I desperately
want to be optimistic
about an alternative to what every fiber
of the evidence is telling me you've done.
I can't confess to something
I don't remember.
The question is,
how much more is there
that you don't remember?
We found your fishing lures.
Yeah, I should hope so.
They-they were on my desk
right by the front door.
We found human remains
amongst the materials
that you made them from.
The human remains of
Cassie Boyle, Marissa Schuur,
Donald Sutcliffe,
Georgia Madchen.
(Whispering): No.
Yes.
(Whispering): I wasn't...
I wasn't sick when
Cassie Boyle was murdered.
I wasn't sick when Marissa
Schuur was murdered.
That's not an argument
you want to be making right now.
Not with me.
Because then,
I'd be a psychopath.
My biggest fear
is that we'll learn
that you knew what
you were doing the whole time.
Hey, you don't have to be
afraid of that, Jack.
There is something
you should be afraid of, though.
- Yeah? What's that?
- Whoever's doing this to me.
Someone's doing this to you?
They'll be close to you.
It could be someone here.
Working with you.
So that's it? It's a setup?
They know the cases.
They know forensics.
They know that I'm unstable.
Can you hear how
paranoid you sound?
Or it could just be you.
Then I'd be really
screwed, wouldn't I?
I wanted to be
the one to do this.
Will Graham,
you're under arrest for murder.
You have the right
to remain silent.
♪
Jack: He disarmed his guard.
He threw the guard and the
driver from the vehicle.
We found the ambulance
in an alley in Dumfries.
These are not the actions
of an innocent man.
They're the actions of
a man who's impaired.
I had Will draw a clock to test
for cognitive dysfunction.
That is extreme.
Now this is the clock
he drew for me two weeks ago.
It's normal.
What disease
progresses gradually
but plateaus for
lengths of time?
Will has periods of clarity.
We've seen him
lucid and aware one moment
and then the next he's not.
Could be some form
of encephalitis.
- Autoimmune encephalitis?
- It's hard to diagnose.
There are no tumors,
no lesions.
It wouldn't even show up on a brain
scan unless you were looking for it.
Look, just tell me if he could kill
five people and not be aware of it.
This doesn't feel
like dementia.
This is an
intelligent psychopath.
Look, this killer
called the Hobbs' house,
he warned Abigail's father.
I was with Will
that entire time.
Did he have an opportunity
to make a phone call?
Before we went to interview Garret Jacob
Hobbs, he was alone in the office while
I was outside loading the car with the
files, but that was only for a few minutes.
Dumb luck and bad bookkeeping.
That's how Will said
he caught Hobbs.
Now how would you
say he caught him?
We were looking
through the files
and it was as if
Will plucked his name
out of a hat, based on little
more than an incomplete address.
Let me play the devil here
for a moment, doctor.
This clock test, could Will
fake something like this?
Would he be able to do that?
Yes.
Hello, Will.
How are you feeling?
Selfaware.
You frightened Alana Bloom.
She's confused about
who I am...
Which I can relate to.
Are you confused
about who I am?
I'm not confused.
I'm skeptical.
Meaning I'm willing to change my
mind should the evidence change.
Do you believe
I killed Abigail?
I believe it's
entirely possible,
if not nearly indisputable,
based on how you
discovered her ear.
If it was just Abigail,
I would have believed.
I would have believed
that I got so far
inside Hobbs' head
I couldn't get out.
But it wasn't just Abigail.
I know who I am.
No.
All sense of who you are has
been distorted by your illness.
You know who you are
in this moment.
That's not always
the case, Will.
I didn't kill any of 'em.
And somebody
is making sure
that no one believes me.
If we're to prove you
didn't commit these murders,
perhaps we should consider
how you could have.
And then disprove that.
If you are this killer,
that identity runs
through these events
like a thread through pearls.
Cassie Boyle would have been
your first victim.
You said her crime scene was
practically gift-wrapped.
(Suspense music)
It told me everything
I needed to know
to catch Garret Jacob Hobbs.
You had seen one of Hobbs'
victims. You knew how he killed.
You may have been
exploring how he killed
to better understand
who he was.
I wasn't in Minnesota when
Cassie Boyle was murdered.
She disappeared on a Saturday.
She was found on a Monday.
You would've had the weekend
to do your work.
(Whispering): I know
I didn't kill her.
How do you know?
What did you think when
you first met Marissa Schuur?
How much like Abigail she was?
Same height, same weight,
hair color, same age.
- How could I resist?
- So much like his daughter.
You may have wondered why Garret
Jacob Hobbs didn't kill her himself.
Dr. Sutcliffe wasn't killed
how Garret Jacob Hobbs killed.
He was murdered how
you imagined yourself
murdering a woman
only days before.
How Georgia Madchen killed.
She dreamt she saw me
killing Sutcliffe.
But she couldn't see my face.
And then she was murdered.
You catch these killers
by getting into their heads,
but you also allow them
into your own.
I'm trying to help you, Will.
Then take me to Minnesota.
I want to see
where Abigail died.
Have you had any contact with Hannibal
Lecter in the last 24 hours?
He didn't make his session
this morning and he didn't
call in, which he
would consider rude.
- Is something wrong?
- I'm on my way to Minnesota.
I believe that Will Graham has taken
Hannibal Lecter to Minnesota.
Will thinks he's being framed
for these murders.
He's slipping in and out
of delusion.
He could kill Hannibal
and not even know he's doing it.
If anyone could've helped Mr. Graham,
it would've been Hannibal.
In fact, he may still be trying.
♪
(Phone ringing)
Hello?
Just a second. Dad?
It's for you.
Caller ID said it was blocked.
- Hello?
- Will?
- Yes.
We're here.
♪
Are we gonna
re-enact the crime?
You be my dad,
and you be my mom,
and you be the man
on the phone.
Are we gonna
re-enact the crime?
If that would help you.
It's as if Abigail was supposed
to die in this kitchen.
Her throat was cut.
She lost
great gouts of blood.
There's an unmistakable
arterial spray.
They haven't found her body.
Just the one piece.
If you were in
Garret Jacob Hobbs'
frame of mind when
you killed her,
they may never find her.
Cause I honored
every part of her?
Perhaps you didn't come here
looking for a killer.
Perhaps you came here
to find yourself.
You killed a man
in this very room.
I stared at Hobbs...
and the space opposite me
assumed the shape of a man
filled with dark
and swarming flies.
Then I scattered them.
At a time when other men
fear their isolation,
yours has become
understandable to you.
You are alone
because you are unique.
I'm as alone as you are.
If you followed the urges
you kept down for so long,
cultivated them
as the inspirations they are,
you would have become
someone other than yourself.
(Whispering):
I know who I am.
I'm not so sure
I know who you are anymore.
But I am certain...
one of us killed Abigail.
Whoever that was
killed the others.
Are you a killer, Will?
You.
Right now. This man
standing in front of me.
Is this who you really are?
I am who I've always been.
The scales have just
fallen from my eyes.
I can see you now.
What do you see?
You called here that morning.
Abigail knew.
And you kept her secrets...
until-until what?
Until she found out
some of yours?
You said it felt good
to kill Garret Jacob Hobbs.
Would it feel good
to kill me now?
Oh, Garret Jacob Hobbs
was a murderer.
Are you a murderer,
Dr. Lecter?
What reason would I have?
You, you have
no traceable motive...
Which is why you were
so hard to see.
You were just...
curious what I would do.
Someone like me.
Someone who thinks
how I think.
Wind him up...
and watch him go.
And apparently,
Dr. Lecter...
this is how I go.
Will.
Easy.
See?
You see?
The right hemisphere of
in his brain was inflamed.
They have placed him
in an induced sleep
and they are treating him with
antiviral and steroid therapies.
Is he responding?
More or less.
He's expected to make
a substantial recovery.
Would you have gone
to Minnesota with him
if he didn't have
a gun on you?
(Monitor beeping)
I would have wanted to.
I believe I've failed to satisfy
my obligation to Will,
more than I care to admit.
Well he's not
your victim, doctor.
Nor is he yours.
You know, in my time I've seen
people broken by the world.
I've seen them broken
in all kinds of hideous
and offhanded ways,
but never like this.
Never like this.
No one in this room
will be the same.
(Monitor beeping)
- Good evening.
- Hello, Hannibal.
Please come in.
Tête de veau en sauce verte.
Smells like a bonfire.
I smoked the veal
on a pyre of dry hay.
It imparts a unique
smoldering flavor to the meat
and to the room.
This is an unexpected treat.
Thank you for indulging me.
You seemed like
you needed to talk.
And since you refuse
invitations to my dinner table,
this is the only way
I could cook for you.
What's on your mind, Hannibal?
I'm going to see
Will tomorrow.
As a patient
or as a friend?
As a farewell.
Of sorts.
I thought Mr. Graham
was finally going to be
the patient who
cost you your life.
He didn't cost me my life.
He cost Abigail hers.
Your veal is getting cold.
Controversial dish.
Veal.
Mmm.
Those who denounce veal
often cite the young age
at which the animals are killed,
when they are in fact
older than many pigs
going to slaughter.
You have to be
careful, Hannibal.
They're starting
to see your pattern.
What pattern would that be?
You develop relationships
with patients who
are prone to violence.
That pattern.
Under scrutiny,
Jack Crawford's
beliefs about you
might start to unravel.
Tell me, Dr. du Maurier...
Have your beliefs
about me begun to unravel?
(Soft opera song)
Hello, Will.
Hello, Dr. Lecter.
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com