Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
You're growing us enough food
so we won't need to do runs soon.
- We need this prison.
- We can all live together.
Liar.
No!
Judith...
Don't look back.
Carl, just keep walking.
( theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Carl, slow down.
Carl, stop!
We need to stay together.
We got to find a place
with food, supplies.
Hey.
We're gonna be...
( crows cawing )
Wait outside, okay?
- Keep watch.
- You keep watch.
You can barely stand.
I'm not gonna let you
go in there alone.
- Excuse me?
- We've done this before.
I'm gonna help you clear it.
You should just
let me do it myself.
Let's go.
Kitchen's clear.
( snarling )
_
That might be all that's left.
- I can get it from here.
- No.
No, it's weak.
I'll draw it out.
_
Stay back.
Damn it.
- Don't.
- ( gunshot )
I said not to.
You couldn't do it with the ax.
I had it.
Every bullet counts.
What if you needed
that one later?
See what you can find.
Then let's move on.
Kitchen wasn't empty after all.
My haul.
You?
I win.
Hey.
That one's as good as any.
- Carl.
- I got it.
All the doors
down here are open.
Just stop!
- ( pounds wall )
- Hey, asshole!
Hey, shitface!
- Hey--
- Watch your mouth!
Are you kidding me?
If there's one of them down
there, they would have come out.
( coughs )
( chuckles )
( grunts )
I tied the door shut.
We don't need to take
any chances.
You don't think it'll hold?
- Carl.
- It's a strong knot.
Clove hitch.
Shane taught me.
Remember him?
Yeah, I remember him.
I remember him every day.
There something else
you want to say to me?
( wheezing )
This'll have to do
for the night.
You gonna have some?
You should eat.
We should save it.
Hey.
I don't want any.
Eat it.
Now.
( wheezing )
( wheezing continues )
Listen, I'm just being honest.
I thought
it was a bit... pedestrian.
- ( laughs ) Pedestrian?
- As in lame.
- And played.
- Played?
Where have you seen anything like it before?
Tell me that.
I've never seen a gorilla
drive a car before,
but if you put it in a museum,
I'm not gonna call it art.
( jazz music playing )
Mike, would you please talk
some sense into your lover?
Oh, my God. You did not
just call me that.
- Mm-hmm.
- I agree with my lover.
- I mean, the whole thing was--
- Very lame.
- And very played.
- Oh, wait, wait, wait.
No, no, don't do that.
Don't do that.
Don't start finishing
each other's sentences, man.
It's just gross.
I was going to say
that the whole thing
was like a monument to someone
trying too damned hard to be different.
Hallelujah.
Listen, I'm glad I saw it
even though I did not love it.
- ( giggling )
- Hope we're not boring you, peanut.
Come here.
I don't think that we
should stay at the camp.
No. I'm not taking
my son out there.
I don't know if this
place will work out,
but I know it won't
if we go out there.
Does it even matter anymore?
Are we just kidding ourselves?
Okay.
All right, I see what this is.
Really?
What is this, Michonne?
I mean, you've gotten
good with a sword.
You know how valuable
that is now?
- You know what that makes you?
- For what?
What are we going for? Where's
the happy ending here?
This isn't life.
This isn't anything
close, okay?
Not for me, not for us.
And for our son.
What's the answer here?
Well, what is
the damn question, Mike?
Why?
Okay.
That's good.
Now I have a question.
Who's gonna open the wine?
No. No.
No, no, no, no.
No. No!
No! No! No! No!
No!
( gasps, panting )
( walkers snarling )
( groans )
Dad?
Dad, wake up.
Wake up.
Come on.
Dad, wake up.
Wake up.
Wake up!
( thudding at door )
( snarling )
( thudding )
Hey, you!
Fresh meat right here.
Come and get it.
Let's take a walk.
Keep up.
That's it.
Keep coming.
Very good.
Come on, keep coming.
Come on.
Right here, look at me.
- ( snarling )
- There you go.
Come on.
That's it.
Just a little farther.
Come on.
- ( snarling )
- Oh, shit.
( grunts )
( gunshot )
( grunting )
( gunshots )
( exhales )
( panting )
( groaning )
( coughing )
I win.
Cool.
( sniffles )
I killed three walkers.
They were at the door.
They were gonna get in,
but I lured them away.
I killed them.
I saved you.
I didn't forget while
you had us playing farmer.
I still know how to survive.
Lucky for us.
I don't need you anymore.
I don't need you
to protect me anymore.
I can take care of myself.
You probably can't even
protect me anyways.
You couldn't protect Judith.
You couldn't protect...
( sighs )
Hershel or Glenn
or Maggie.
Michonne, Daryl,
or Mom.
You just wanted
to plant vegetables.
You just wanted to hide.
He knew where we were
and you didn't care!
You just hid
behind those fences
and waited for...
( sighs )
They're all gone now.
Because of you!
They counted on you!
You were their leader!
( sniffles )
But now...
you're nothing.
( sniffles )
( sighs )
I'd be fine if you died.
( grunts )
Damn it.
( door creaks )
( snarling )
( gunshots )
( gunshot )
( clicking )
Oh, shit.
Come on.
( grunts )
( whimpering )
- ( pounding )
- ( panting )
_
( walker snarling )
( panting )
( sobbing )
( raspy breathing )
( gasps )
( breathing heavily )
( hammer clicks )
( raspy breathing )
( bowl clatters )
( crying )
( crying continues )
I can't.
I was wrong.
Just do it.
Carl.
( wheezing )
Don't go outside.
Stay safe.
I'm scared.
( crying )
_
Mike.
I miss you.
I missed you even
when I was with you.
Back at the camp.
It wasn't you who did it.
( sighs )
You were wrong.
Because I'm still here.
And you could be, too.
And he could be.
( sighs )
I know the answer.
I know why.
( sighs )
( snarling )
Rick: You shouldn't
have risked it,
going out there like that.
It's dangerous.
I was careful.
It's good that
you found more food.
I found even more.
But I ate it.
What was it?
112 ounces of pudding.
( chuckles )
I know...
we'll never get things back
to the way they used to be.
What?
I only clung to that for you.
For Judith.
Now she's gone.
And you...
you're a man, Carl.
You're a man.
I'm sorry.
You don't need to be.
( sobs )
( knocking )
( cocks gun )
( chuckles )
What?
It's for you.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com