(announcer) Previously on,
AMC's "The Walking Dead."
(screaming in pain)
(Rick) Get the doctor at the hilltop.
He's gonna make things better.
We're gonna get there.
You gotta route?
Yeah.
There are two more routes
north from here.
They're probably waiting
for us right now.
Go back.
Where?
Hi, I'm Negan.
I don't wanna kill you people.
I want you to work for me.
But you killed my people.
For that, you're gonna pay.
I'm gonna beat the holy hell
outta one of you.
[Breathing heavily]
Negan: What?
Was the joke that bad?
I'm gonna kill you.
What?
I didn't quite catch that.
You're gonna have to speak up.
[Sniffles]
Not today...
...not tomorrow...
...but I'm gonna
kill you.
[Inhales sharply]
Jesus.
[Chuckles softly]
Simon...
what did he have, a knife?
Simon:
Uh, he had a hatchet.
A hatchet?
He had an ax.
[Chuckles]
Simon's my right-hand man.
Having one of those is important.
I mean, what do you have left
without them?
A whole lot of work.
Do you have one?
Maybe one of these fine people
still breathing?
Oh.
Or did I...
[Clicks tongue]
[Sighs]
Sure.
Yeah.
Give me his ax.
[Footsteps]
♪♪
[Inhales deeply]
I'll be right back.
Maybe Rick will be with me.
And if not, well,
we can just turn these people
inside out, won't we?
I mean...
the ones that are left.
[Sobbing]
♪♪
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
[Grunting]
[Breathing heavily]
[Both grunt]
[Sighs]
Let's go for a ride.
[Engine sputtering]
Wow.
What a piece of shit.
"I'm gonna kill you."
[Chuckles]
Are you kiddin' me?
Did you see what just happened,
what I just did?
You just...
[Sighs]
[Scoffs]
Your best chance...
is to stand up, grab that ax,
and drive it through
the back of my head.
See how you do.
Keep actin' tough.
Go ahead.
♪♪
Grab the damn ax.
[Chuckles]
Drop it.
[Grunts]
[Gasping]
Ohh.
[Ax clangs]
Don't make me get up again.
Well, look at that.
Dawn is breakin'.
It's a brand-new day,
Rick.
[Chuckles]
I want you to think about
what could have happened...
...think about
what happened,
and think about
what can still happen.
[Engine starts, revs]
♪♪
[Walker growls]
[Laughing]
Oh! Boom!
[Laughs]
That remind you of anybody you know?
Oh, yeah.
[Growling continues]
[Thuds]
♪♪
[Thud, brakes squeal]
[Engine shuts off, keys jingle]
[Walkers growling]
You are mine.
The people back there --
they are mine.
This...
This is mine.
[Growling continues]
[Grunts]
[Ax clatters]
Hey, Rick...
go get my ax.
Let's be friends.
♪♪
[Walker growling loudly]
Oh. [Chuckles]
[Sighs]
Get my ax.
♪♪
[Grunts]
[Door slams]
♪♪
[Walkers growling]
Aah!
♪♪
[Growls]
[Grunting]
[Walkers growling]
♪♪
Ohh!
[Grunting]
‭[Growling]
♪♪
[Grunts]
[Growling]
[Walkers growling]
♪♪
[Wind rushing]
[Walkers growling]
♪♪
Negan: Bet you thought you were
all gonna grow old together,
sittin' around the table
at Sunday dinner
and the happily ever after.
No.
Doesn't work like that, Rick.
[Walkers growling]
Not anymore.
Think about what happened.
[Walkers growling]
♪♪
Negan: [Echoing]
I simply cannot decide.
[Chuckles]
Negan:
I got an idea.
Eenie...
...meenie...
miney...
mo...
catch...
...a tiger...
...by...
his toe.
If...
he hollers...
...let him go.
My mother...
told me...
...to pick...
the very...
best...
one...
...and you...
are...
♪♪
...it.
Negan: Anybody moves,
anybody says anything,
cut the boy's other eye out
and feed it to his father,
and then we'll start.
You can breathe.
You can blink.
You can cry.
Hell, you're all gonna be doing that.
[Thud echoes]
Oh!
Look at that!
Taking it like a champ!
Suck...
my...
nuts.
[Thud echoes]
[Echoing blows landing]
[Walkers growling]
Negan: Did you hear that?
[Chuckles]
He said, "Suck my nuts."
Phew.
[Laughs]
[Blows landing]
[Grunting]
[Crying]
[Blows continue landing]
[Grunting continues]
[Man groans]
[Negan laughs]
Oh, my goodness!
Look at this!
[Blood splatters]
[Laughs]
You guys, look at my dirty girl!
Sweetheart...
Lay your eyes on this.
[Sighs heavily]
Oh, damn.
Were you --
Were you together?
That sucks.
But if you were, you should know
there was a reason for all this.
Red --
and hell, he was, is,
and will ever be red.
He just took one
or six or seven for the team!
So take...a damn look.
[Breathing shakily]
Take a damn look!
[Grunting]
Rick: Daryl!
No!
Oh, no.
[Chuckles]
That?
Oh, my!
That...
is a no-no.
The whole thing --
not one bit of that shit flies here.
[Woman crying]
Do you want me to do it?
Right here.
[Grunting]
No.
No, you don't kill them...
not until you try a little.
[Grunting]
And anyway...
that's not how it works.
Now,
I already told you people --
first one's free, then --
what'd I say?
I said I would shut that shit down!
No exceptions.
Now, I don't know
what kind of lying assholes
you've been dealing with...
...but I'm a man
of my word.
First impressions are important.
I need you to know me.
So...
...back to it.
[All gasping]
Woman: No!
[Groaning, gasping]
[Walkers growling]
Buddy, you still there?
[Grunting, sputtering]
I just don't know.
It seems like you're trying to speak,
but you just took a hell of a hit.
I just popped your skull so hard,
your eyeball just popped out,
and it is gross as shit!
Maggie, I'll find you.
[Sobbing]
[Grunting]
Oh.
Oh, hell.
I can see this is hard on you guys.
[Grunting continues]
I am sorry.
I truly am.
But I did say it.
No exceptions! [Grunts]
[Walkers groing]
[Blows landing]
[Thudding, squelching]
[All sobbing]
♪♪
[Walkers growling]
You bunch of pussies.
I'm just getting started.
[Grunting]
[Blows landing]
Lucille is thirsty.
[Laughs]
She is a vampire bat.
[Sobbing continues]
[Breathing shakily]
♪♪
Negan: What?
Was the joke that bad?
[Thumping]
[Walkers growling]
Negan:
People died, Rick.
It's what happened.
Doesn't mean
the rest of them have to.
[Growling continues]
Get me my ax.
Get me...my...ax!
[Walkers growling]
Negan: I thought
you were the guy, Rick.
Maybe you're not.
We'll give it one more go.
Now, I really want you
to try this time.
Last chance.
Bring me my ax!
[Gunshots]
♪♪
[Growling continues]
[Growling]
[Groaning]
Aah!
♪♪
[Growling continues]
[Gunfire]
Aah!
[Gunfire continues]
Clock is ticking, Rick!
Think about what can still happen.
♪♪
[Grunts]
[Walkers growling]
♪♪
[Growls]
[Grunts]
[Sighs heavily]
[Growling]
♪♪
[Horn honking]
[Grunting]
♪♪
[Grunts]
[Grunting]
♪♪
[Walkers growling]
[Rick breathing heavily]
Attaboy!
[Walkers growling]
[Breathing heavily]
[Growling fades]
[Engine starts]
[Brakes squeal]
[Engine stops]
[Keys jingling]
[Claps hands]
We're here, prick.
[Scoffs]
This must be hard for you, right?
I mean, you have been King Shit
for so long.
Losin' two of your own like...
[Snaps fingers]
Gettin' 'em clipped like that,
one nut, then the other,
and in front of your boy?
That is
some screwed-up shit!
Ah.
Oh.
Goody.
[Cap clatters]
[Sighs]
You were in charge.
Negan: [Grunts]
Hell...
...you were probably...
addic7ed to it.
And now, well, clip, clip --
that's over.
But...
...you can still lead...
a nice, productive life
producing for me.
I think you're gonna need it.
I just got a feelin'.
[Sighs]
So take it.
[Breathing heavily]
Here we are.
Let me ask you something,
Rick --
do you even know
what that little trip was about?
Negan: Speak when
you're spoken to.
[Breathing heavily]
Okay. Okay.
That trip was about
the way that you looked at me.
I wanted to change that.
I wanted you to understand.
But you're still looking at me
the same damn way...
...like I shit
in your scrambled eggs,
and that's not gonna work.
So...
...do I give you
another chance?
[Breathing raggedly]
Yeah.
Yes.
Okay.
[Chuckling]
All right.
And here it is --
the grand-prize game.
What you do next will decide
whether your crap day
becomes everyone's last crap day
or just another crap day.
Get some guns
to the back of their heads.
[Guns cocking]
Good. Now...
level with their noses,
so if you have to fire...
[imitates explosion]
it'll be a real mess.
♪♪
Kid...
Right here.
Kid...now.
You a southpaw?
Am I a what?
You a lefty?
No.
Good.
♪♪
That hurt?
No.
Should.
It's supposed to.
All right.
Get down on the ground, kid,
next to Daddy.
Spread them wings.
♪♪
Simon...
...you got a pen?
Yeah.
[Grunts]
Sorry, kid.
This is gonna be
as cold as a warlock's ballsack,
just like he was
hanging his ballsack above you
and dragging it
right across the forearm.
There you go.
Gives you a little leverage.
Please. Please.
Please don't.
Me?
[Chuckles]
I ain't doing shit.
Ahh.
Rick, I want you to take your ax...
cut your son's left arm off,
right on that line.
Now, I know --
I know.
You're gonna have to
process that for a second.
That makes sense.
Still, though,
I'm gonna need you to do it,
or all these people are gonna die.
Then Carl dies,
then the people back home die...
and then you, eventually.
I'm gonna keep you breathing
for a few years,
just so you can stew on it.
Michonne: You -- You don't
have to do this.
We understand.
You understand.
Yeah.
I'm not sure that Rick does.
I'm gonna need a clean cut
right there on that line.
Now, I know this is
a screwed-up thing to ask,
but it's gonna have to be
like a salami slice --
nothing messy,
clean, 45 degrees --
give us something to fold over.
We got a great doctor.
The kid'll be fine.
Probably.
Rick...
...this needs
to happen now --
chop, chop --
or I will crush
the little fella's skull myself.
It can -- It can --
It can be me.
W-W-- [Sniffles]
Y-You can do it
to me.
I c-- I can go
with -- with you.
No.
This is the only way.
Rick...
pick up the ax.
Not making a decision
is a big decision.
You really want to see
all these people die?
You will.
You will see every ugly thing.
Oh, my God.
‭[Groans]
Are you gonna make me count?
Okay, Rick.
You win.
I am counting.
3!
‭Please.
[Crying] Please.
[Gasping]
It can be me.
Please!
[Crying]
2!
Please, don't do --
[Sobbing]
[Dramatic music plays]
This is it.
Aaah!
1.
‭[Sobbing]
[Sobs]
Dad...
just do it.
Just do it.
[Sobbing]
♪♪
Rick.
[Breathing heavily]
You answer to me.
You provide for me.
You belong to me.
Right?
Speak when you're spoken to!
You answer to me.
You provide for me.
Provide for you.
You belong to me, right?!
[Breathing heavily]
Right.
That...
...is the look
I wanted to see.
We did it...
all of us, together...
even the dead guys on the ground.
Hell, they get
the spirit award, for sure.
[Sighs]
Today was a productive damn day!
Now, I hope, for all your sake...
that you get it now...
...that you understand
how things work.
Things have changed.
Whatev you had going for you...
...that is [Chuckling] over now.
Ah. Dwight...
...load him up.
[Vehicle doors close]
He's got guts --
not a little bitch
like someone I know.
I like him.
He's mine now.
But you still want to try something?
"Not today,
not tomorrow."
"Not today, not tomorrow"?
I will cut pieces off of...
Hell's his name?
Daryl.
Wow.
[Chuckles]
That actually sounds right.
I will cut pieces off of Daryl
and put them
on your doorstep --
or, better yet,
I will bring him to you
and have you do it for me.
[Chuckles]
Ahh!
Welcome to a brand-new
beginning, you sorry shits!
I'm gonna leave you a truck.
Keep it.
Use it to cart all the crap
you're gonna find me.
We'll be back for
our first offering in one week.
Until then...
ta-ta.
[Insects chirping]
Rick: Maggie. Maggie.
[Sobs]
Maggie...
you need to sit down.
Maggie.
No.
We need to get you to the Hilltop.
You need to go get ready.
For what?
To fight them.
They have Daryl.
They have an army.
[Breathing heavily]
We would die --
all of us.
Go home.
[Voice breaking]
Take everybody with you.
I can get there by myself.
You can barely stand up.
I need to go.
You need to go to Alexandria.
[Breathing heavily]
You were out --
out here for me.
We still are.
[Sobbing]
I can make it now.
I need you to go back.
I can't have you out here.
I can't have you all
out here anymore.
I need you to go back.
Maggie...
we're not letting you go.
Okay?
You have to.
[Sighs]
It's not gonna happen.
[Breathing heavily]
I'm taking her.
I'm gonna get her there.
I'm gonna keep her safe.
I'm not giving you a choice.
I'm taking him with me.
[Groans]
I'm gonna take him.
[Voice breaking]
That's what I'm gonna do.
[Sniffles]
[Exhales sharply]
[Breathing heavily]
I need to do this.
Please.
We need to help you.
I got it.
No. No.
Pl-- Pl--
Please let us.
He-- He's our family, t--
He's our family, too.
♪♪
[Sobbing]
You're okay.
All right.
On three.
1, 2...
[Sobbing continues]
♪♪
Yeah.
Negan: Bet you thought you were
all gonna grow old together,
sittin' around the table
at Sunday dinner
and the happily ever after.
No.
Doesn't work like that, Rick.
Not anymore.
[Slow music plays]
[Growling]
[Engine starts]
[Music continues]
[Growling continues]
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com