( tires screech )
Daryl: Beth!
Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
( groans )
Name's Joe.
Dr. Eugene Porter
is a scientist,
and he knows exactly
what caused this mess.
( walkers snarling )
( gunfire )
We'll find another vehicle.
We'll go with them until we do.
Michonne: - What do you think?
Rick: - Let's go.
_
He's a persistent son of a bitch,
saving the world is just more important.
I'm well aware
it sounds bananas.
But looking at the fossil
record, knowing what I know
about this infection,
you cannot say for certain
it isn't what killed off
the dinosaurs.
Now, do I believe
that's what happened?
No.
But it's enjoyable as hell to
think about an undead ankylosaur
going after a diplodocus.
That there is a video game
worth a preorder.
Oh, hell, yeah.
Score.
A few more of those,
a little aluminum foil
and some bleach, you got
yourself some volts, sister.
Homemade battery.
- Here.
- For reals?
You don't want it?
For reals.
Much obliged.
Speaking of video games,
what kind of gamer were you?
RPGs, shmup, sim racing?
( sighs )
Go to sleep.
I got this.
No offense, but I'm not leaving
Eugene's life in your hands.
You came with us
because you wanted help.
You're support, not point.
We'll move north with you till I find
the right vehicle just off the tracks.
Then five becomes three.
Or two.
We each have our missions.
You need to get some sleep.
I haven't seen you do it yet.
( chuckles )
Thought it was because
you were in love with him.
( chuckles )
A girl in love with a guy
she's trying to help
get to his girl.
If that were the case...
closing your eyes would be
just too damn tragic.
- If that were the case.
- Yeah.
I saw the way you were
looking down Rosita's shirt
while she was
serving you dinner.
Hey, the things
are damn near hypnotic.
( laughs )
Look, Eugene spends half the
day staring at her ass.
I'm not mad, it just means
my theory's shot.
I'm awfully sorry about that.
Well, I'm right and I'm wrong.
Something you did
or something you didn't do?
Something I did.
You were in the army.
I get the whole gung ho,
mission is your life bullshit.
Yeah, you do.
Yeah.
So we both got our reasons.
Both got our missions.
What do you do
when the mission's over?
Eugene: Been rubbing
me wrong, is all.
I'm an even-Steven
type gentleman.
You help me find the supplies,
we'll share the battery
and whatever juice we scare
up, minimal as it may be.
Deal?
_
( theme music playing )
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
( walker snarling )
( snarling continues )
( cans rattling )
Man:
I got it.
( grunts )
( urinating )
Looks like that Robin Hood cat
cut out on us after all.
I didn't think he had the
sack to go out on his own.
He don't.
Dude left his stuff here.
Probably just stepped out
to drop a morning deuce.
I think we got about
a day's worth of water left.
We're lucky it's cooled off
a little bit, but...
What are you doing?
- Winning a bet.
- In your dreams.
I'm still on.
( laughs ) You spoke
too soon, wise guy.
This might go on a while.
Maybe we can speed this up.
Yeah, you're right.
Shouldn't be fooling around.
We should probably--
Carl!
I win.
Pay up.
Is that really
the last Big Cat?
Oh, come on.
Hey, but you said
winner's choice.
Go ahead, take it.
It's yours.
You won it fair and square.
Come on, we always share.
Fork it over.
( squeals )
What the hell are you doing?
Catching me some breakfast.
That's mine.
My arrow's the one
that hit first.
Cottontail belongs to me.
Been out here since
before the sun came up.
You see, the rules of the hunt
don't mean jack out here.
Now, that rabbit you're holding
is claimed, boy.
Claimed whether
you like it or not.
So I was you, I'd hand it over.
Now before you get to wishing
you ain't never even
got out of bed this morning.
It ain't yours.
You know, I'll bet
this bitch
got you all messed up, hmm?
Am I right?
Got you walking around here
like a dead man
who just lost himself
a piece of tail.
Must have been a good'un.
Tell me something.
Was it one of the little'uns?
'Cause they don't last
too long out here.
- Easy, fellas, easy.
- ( laughing )
Let's just put
our weapons down.
See if we can't figure out what's
really the problem here, huh?
- Did you claim it?
- Hell, yeah.
Well, there you go.
That critter belongs to Len.
So let's have it.
Looks like you may be
wanting an explanation.
See, going it alone, that
ain't an option nowadays.
Still, it is survival
of the fittest.
That's a paradox right there.
So I laid out
some rules of the road
to keep things from going
Darwin every couple hours.
Keep our merry band
together and stress-free.
All you got to do is claim.
That's how you mark
your territory,
your prey, your bed at night.
One word, claimed.
I ain't claiming nothing.
We're gonna teach him, right?
The rules say
we got to teach him.
It wouldn't be fair
to punish you
for violating a rule
you never even knew existed.
There ain't no rules no more.
Oh, there are.
You know that.
That's why I didn't kill
you for the crossbow.
- Hey.
- Easy there, partner.
Claimed.
That's all you got to say.
Hey, ass end is still an end.
Hold up!
We're stopping here.
Tired is slow.
- Slow is dead.
- It's barely noon.
I don't give
a monkey's left nut.
None of us has slept more
than a couple hours straight
since we went all Casey Jones.
This place looks safe.
We need to rest.
I get it.
You have to find her.
Well, Rosita and me,
we got a mission, too.
It's keeping that man alive,
getting him to Washington,
and saving
the whole damn world.
So we're going in that tower
and we're going now.
( walkers snarling )
- Oh, crap.
- Hey, hey, hey, watch out!
Abraham:
Go, go!
- Go!
- Move! Move!
- Rosita: Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
We got to stay here. Who's
gonna help me carry her up?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
You wanna stop
or you wanna keep going?
No, keep going.
I'm good.
- You sure?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Look, if she can keep going,
we can all keep going.
Or you guys can stay here.
You don't need us,
we don't need you.
- It's okay.
- Rosita: Wow, you're an ass.
She will do whatever you say
because she thinks she owes you.
Man up.
Stay here for a few hours.
You just care about
keeping Eugene safe, right?
It's the only reason
you want to stop?
We go until sundown,
I give Eugene my riot gear
right here, right now.
- Everybody wins.
- Except her.
You're not her mama.
She says she can walk,
she can walk.
You got yourself a deal.
Okay.
- So what's the plan, Daryl?
- How so?
You're with us now,
but you ain't soon?
Yep.
So what's the plan?
Just looking for
the right place is all.
Oh, we ain't good
enough for you, huh?
Some of you ain't
exactly friendly.
You ain't so friendly yourself.
You know you need
a group out here.
- Maybe I don't.
- No, you do.
You should be with us.
( walker snarling )
Joe: People don't
got to be friendly.
We don't have to be nice. We don't
have to be brothers in arms.
( snarling )
We just got
to follow the rules.
You claim.
If you steal, you keel.
I know that sounds
a little funny,
but nobody laughs when
something goes missing.
And you don't lie.
'Cause that's
a slippery slope indeed.
What happens if you break 'em?
Oh, you catch a beatin'.
The severity of which
depends upon the offense
and the general attitude
of the day.
But that don't happen much
'cause when men
like us follow rules
and cooperate a little bit,
well, the world becomes ours.
( whistles )
Right there.
It's our abode for the evening.
Hey.
There ain't no us.
You leaving right now?
No?
Then it sure seems
like there's an us.
You a cat person, Daryl?
I am.
Loved 'em since
I was three years old.
Vicious creatures.
Anyway, I'll tell you,
and this is true,
ain't nothing sadder
than an outdoor cat
that thinks he's an indoor cat.
_
We're gaining on 'em.
Still wet.
We sure as Shinola
can't go up and over.
( walkers snarling )
How about around?
No.
That'll take a day, maybe more.
If Maggie went through,
I'm going through.
- We're close.
- Shut up a second.
-  ( snarling continues )
- You hear that?
That there
is a long, dark tunnel
full of reanimated corpses.
I don't have
full-on certainty
that I can get Eugene
through there alive.
My recommendation
would be take the day,
make the detour
and play it safe,
but I know you're not
gonna do that.
So this is where
we've got to part ways.
I'm sorry.
You're on your own.
No, you're not.
No, no, no.
Those are yours.
You guys will need them
for your trip.
You will, too.
Thank you.
Sorry, I...
hit you in the face.
I'm not.
I like to fight.
Good luck.
Try not to be an ass.
You're both good people.
I have to say that you
are seriously hot, Tara.
Yeah, I like girls.
I'm well aware of that.
Say you get into
trouble in there.
You turn around.
We're doubling back to
the first road we crossed.
Maybe you find us before
we find the right ride.
Thanks.
Hey.
I know what
you're going through.
After this all started,
after I realized
I'd never see my family,
my friends again,
I was numb.
All day long, just numb.
I'm just saying I get it.
When Brian told us he wanted
to take over the prison,
I knew it sounded bad.
When I found my girlfriend,
she was dead.
My niece.
My sister,
she was surrounded, pounced on.
I saw it happen.
But still, it wasn't
as bad as seeing
what he did to Maggie's father.
Because that's when I knew.
That second the sword--
I wanted to scream "no,"
but it just happened.
Brian said we might
have to kill people.
I was the first to jump in.
I was just hanging
on the "might."
They ain't here.
Nobody's been here for a while.
Whoever was,
they got all the gas.
That don't matter.
We're getting closer.
I can feel it.
Claimed.
( walkers snarling )
The blood is still wet.
This had to have
happened today.
Hold this.
Glenn.
What are you doing?
- She's not one of them.
- What?
There's no bodies
on the ground.
That means Maggie
made it through.
She made it through.
We have to get rid of them.
-  We don't have enough ammo.
- Then we'll push through.
We have to find another way.
( exhales )
( snarling )
( pounding )
You got him?
I got her.
( engine starts )
Gonna need to air
this baby out.
Good, it'll give us some time to
figure out how to get back on track.
_
- Yo, no, no.
- I'm the navigator.
Then learn to navigate.
Remember Thompson?
I'm formally requesting a
straight up do-over on that one.
I guided us here from Houston to
northern Georgia without incident.
I wouldn't say
without incident.
Minimal incident.
Navigation-wise,
at least.
Please?
I cannot abide a reality
where you are the chosen navigator
over a son of the South
who has successfully
negotiated the travails
and vagaries of journeys
both real and virtual.
All right.
We're going north.
Got it?
( snarling )
Tara. What is it?
What is it?
I can't--
( grunting )
Get up, get up, get up.
Eugene:
Turn left up here.
This is the third left turn
you've made me make
in the last five minutes.
- You're lost.
- I'm not.
Turn left.
If you're lost,
please just tell me.
The gas in this tank
is worth more than your ego.
If you want to talk fuel
efficiency, we could talk--
We are not rolling up
the windows.
- It smells like a damn carcass in here.
- Stop the van.
Why are we stopping?
( in Spanish )
Liar.
Ugh, liar!
Nope.
This wasn't your plan?
Why you insisted on navigating?
Why you told him
to go to sleep?
Nope. I never
claimed otherwise.
Now how about you
apologize for the slander
and we call it square?
What the hell
is wrong with you?
If Glenn and Tara
were still alive
and there were
no significant delays
and they continued traveling at
approximately three miles per hour
and I timed it
correctly in my head,
they might be
somewhere around here.
Those two are not the priority.
The only priority is
getting you to Washington.
After I save the world,
I still have to live
with myself.
I'm not leaving them behind.
Oh!
Son of a bitch!
Why the hell are we stopped?
If they made it out of that tunnel,
they'd be somewhere around here.
You're kidding me, right?
What's your problem?
- My problem?
- You're the one in the driver's seat.
You're the one who put
your damn foot on the brake.
- He told me to stop.
- You don't stop! You never stop!
- I know the rules. - If you know
the rules, the rule is never stop!
- When you stop...
- Guys!
- Both: What?
Len: You've got
to be kidding me.
Christ.
Give it here.
You step back.
My half was in the bag.
Now it's gone.
Now ain't nobody
around here interested
in no half a damn cottontail except you.
Ain't that right?
You're the only one still
thinking about that crap.
- Empty your bag.
- I said step back.
Did you take his rabbit, Daryl?
Just tell me the truth.
I didn't take nothing.
Joe:
What do we got here?
Come on.
-  Well, look at that.
- You put that there, didn't you?
When I went out to take a piss.
- You lied.
- Didn't you?
You lied.
You stole.
- We gonna teach this fool or what, Joe?
- Whoa, whoa.
Now, Daryl says he didn't
take your half of the rabbit.
So we got a little
conundrum here.
Either he's lying,
which is an actionable offense,
or...
( laughs )
or you didn't plant it
on him like some pussy,
punk-ass, cheating,
coward cop, did you?
'Cause while that wouldn't be
specifically breaking the rules,
it'd be disappointing.
- It would.
- Mm-hmm.
- I didn't.
- Good.
Well...
- ( groans )
- ...teach him a lesson, gents.
He's a lying sack of shit.
I'm sick of it.
Teach him all the way.
I saw him do it.
Why didn't you try to stop him?
He wanted to play that out.
I let him.
You told the truth.
He lied.
You understand the rules.
He doesn't.
-  ( blows landing )
-  ( Len groaning )
Looks like you get
the head, too.
( straining )
( panting )
Go. Go.
Find Maggie.
Go find Maggie.
No, no.
- No.
- Glenn, you can't save me.
( straining )
Even if you got this
off me, I can't run.
And if you help me,
they're gonna get both of us.
There's got to be a way.
There's got to be a different way.
Glenn, they're coming.
I'm not leaving.
I'm not leaving you!
Get out of here!
Go!
No.
( gun clicking )
Come on!
-  ( engine revving )
- Come on!
-  ( tires squeal )
-  ( gunfire )
Abraham:
Get down!
( gunfire )
( crying )
Oh, my God.
Hi.
God, you are so beautiful.
- How'd it go?
- End of the tunnel's secure.
If anything tries to come in,
we'll hear in plenty of time.
We didn't get
to officially meet.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Tara, this is Maggie.
-  Maggie, Tara.
- Hi.
Hi.
He's a big fan of yours.
I met Tara on the road.
Couldn't have made it
here without her.
Thank you.
When she heard what I was doing,
she said she had to help me.
She's just that kind of person.
What's up?
He just said
that he knows
what caused the outbreak.
Yeah.
He does.
Let me guess. He asked you
to go to DC with him?
I'm downright tickled
y'all found each other.
Should spend the rest
of the night celebrating.
Because tomorrow there's
absolutely no reason
why the eight of us
don't stuff ourselves
in that van and head up
to Washington.
Tara:
He's right.
I'm gonna go.
No, he's wrong.
We're 55% of the way
from Houston to Washington.
Up until now, we've had an
armored military vehicle
for transport
and we lost eight people.
- That wasn't our fault.
- They're gone.
Eugene: I can't imagine
we'd have better luck
with that grocery grabber
we picked up.
We're a day's walk
from Terminus.
Who knows what
they've got there?
Rosita: Look, it
couldn't hurt to check.
Load up on supplies, maybe even
recruit some of them to come with.
I'll go with you guys,
but after.
I have to see Terminus.
My brother could be there.
I got to know.
Me, too.
On both counts.
He tells me I'm wrong...
I listen.
Tomorrow we go
to the end of the line.
Then Washington.
I can't believe it.
I know.
We were right over there.
A whole swarm of them
came at us.
And we didn't have
enough bullets.
I tried to think what you
would do if you were here.
So I just emptied my clip
into the ceiling
and I hoped for the best.
That's unreal.
Kind of like asking
those guys to hold off
saving the world while you
go look for your wife?
( laughs )
I'm a persuasive guy.
Yeah.
Whoa, hey.
What are you doing?
Sorry.
This is the only picture
I have of you.
You don't need a picture of me.
You never will again.
( loud clang )
( door opens )
White Lightning.
Easiest thing to make with the
least amount of supplies.
I'd start slow if I was you.
Your stomach's probably
emptier than you think.
Mmm.
I ain't been lit at dawn since
before everything fell apart.
Fell apart. I never
looked at it like that.
Seems to me like things are finally
starting to fall together.
At least for guys like us.
Living like this, surviving.
We've been doing this
from the start, right?
Getting closer.
You seen this before?
Oh, yeah.
I'll tell you what it is.
It's a lie.
Ain't no sanctuary for all.
Ain't gonna welcome guys like
you and me with open arms.
Daryl: So is that
where we're headed?
- So now you're asking?
- That's right.
We were in a house
minding our own business
and this walking
piece of fecal matter
was hiding in the home.
Strangled our colleague Lou
and left him to turn.
Lou came at all of us.
He lit out.
We tracked him to these tracks,
one of those signs, and thus
we've got a destination in mind.
- You see his face?
- Only Tony.
That's enough for a reckoning.
Claimed.
( music playing )
♪ be not so nervous ♪
♪ be not so frail ♪
♪ someone watches you,
you will not fail ♪
♪ be not so nervous,
be not so frail ♪
♪ be not so sorry
for what you've done ♪
♪ you must forget them now,
it's done ♪
♪ when you wake up ♪
♪ you'll find
that you can run ♪
♪ be not so sorry
for what you've done ♪
♪ be not so fearful ♪
♪ be not so pale ♪
♪ someone watches you ♪
♪ you will not leave
the rails ♪
♪ be not so fearful,
be not so pale ♪
_
♪ be not so fearful,
be not so pale ♪
♪ be not so sorry
for what you've done ♪
♪ you must forget them now,
it's done ♪
♪ and when you wake up ♪
♪ you'll find
that you can run ♪
♪ be not so sorry
for what you've done ♪
for what you've done... ♪
Hi. I'm Mary.
Looks like you've been
on the road a while.
We have.
Let's get you settled
and we'll make you a plate.
Welcome to Terminus.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com