Is that Joanna Beauchamp?
What's she doing here?
Evening, Joanna.
Heading to the big
engagement party?
Calm down, Ollie.
It's okay.
Come on, let's go.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Freya, come on, let's go!
We're gonna be late!
I know, I know.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I hate this dress.
I should change, shouldn't I?
- I better go change.
- Stop it.
You look beautiful.
Plus, you've already
changed five times.
If you do it again,
I might have to smack you.
Why am I so nervous?
It's your engagement party.
Of course you're nervous.
No, no, it's not that.
I just... I feel off.
I had the strangest dream
last night.
There was this guy, and I
never seen him before,
but I felt like
I'd known him forever.
And then he kissed me,
and... the world exploded.
That is a classic anxiety dream.
You're worried about getting
married, it's a big step,
so create a dream scenario
about the perfect guy
who doesn't actually exist.
But I'm not anxious.
I know Dash is the one.
I love him so much.
I don't want anyone else.
Which is why I am
so freaked out.
You know about me and my dreams.
You're not psychic.
I might be.
I can read auras.
That's not a thing.
Scoff all you want, but
I know I have the gift.
You only have one superpower,
and it is your breasts.
Mom! Mom!
Where were you?
Scared the crap out of us.
In the car waiting for you.
You look beautiful.
I can't believe
my baby's getting married.
Mom, it's an engagement
party, not a wedding.
Come on, we have to go.
♪ Take a walk with me
♪ On the water
♪ Got the power
to make you a believer ♪
♪ Take you where
you never been before ♪
♪ Never been before...
So am I the only one who finds
this completely exhausting?
And it's not even our wedding.
I will marry you
in Vegas tomorrow if you want.
Really?
Wherever, whenever.
Aw.
Oh, and by the way,
I forgive you.
For what?
For being a half an hour
late tonight.
People were starting
to look at me funny.
I wasn't half an hour late.
You are always at least
15 minutes late
for everything you do.
Five minutes.
Did I mention
you're worth the wait?
Hi, Mom.
I was wondering
where you got off to.
Hmm.
Mm. Oh, look at that.
Why don't you come
back into the party.
This is such
an interesting dress, dear.
I like how you just
put it all out there,
and screw what other people
think is appropriate.
I really do appreciate
all you're doing for us.
You don't have to
be so generous.
Oh, it's nothing.
I want us to be close, dear.
I never had a daughter.
And I was always hoping
that when Dashiell married,
that she and I would have
the relationship
I always dreamed of.
Yes, I would love that.
Good. I hope we can.
I just have to say,
I know that you were raised in,
well, a certain way,
you know, through no fault
of your own,
and I would really like
to help teach you about
etiquette and-and style
and all the other things that
you never had a chance to learn.
But we can talk
about that later.
I'll take you to lunch,
and we'll go shopping.
I'll find you a bra
that actually fits.
Ooh, that's wonderful!
Look at that.
I hope you choke on it.
Mom? Are you okay?
Hey.
Dude...
Don't call me "dude."
You'll never believe
what I just did.
I made Dash's mother choke,
with my mind.
Is she okay?
You're totally
missing the point.
Am I?
Ingrid, she basically called me
a poor townie with bad
taste and no manners,
and then I wished for her
to choke, and she did.
So...
So I'm pretty sure
there's no way
that could just
be a coincidence.
Then you don't understand
statistics and probability.
I don't need to;
I have powers.
Choking powers.
Congratulations?
Oh, my God.
Ingrid, it's him.
Who?
The guy from my dream.
Okay, that
guy is fairly hot.
Are you blushing?
This can't be happening.
It's not.
You are experiencing something
called illusory correlation.
You had a dream
about a hot guy,
and now you see a hot guy,
so you retroactively turn him
into the guy from your dream,
so you can say
the dream is prescient
when it's really
just a coincidence.
You think everything's
a coincidence.
Because most things are.
Come on, Ingrid!
First Dash's mom and now this?
What's your explanation?
I would say you're losing it
due to wedding stress.
I need a drink.
Stop.
Creepy, right?
Yeah.
Extremely creepy.
Sorry.
Didn't mean to startle
you, Mrs. Beauchamp.
Dash.
Come on, we're at
your engagement party,
you're marrying my daughter;
you can call me Joanna.
Of course.
Joanna.
You know, it's-it's actually
the man who built this place
back in the early 1900s.
Archibald Browning.
You heard of him?
Yeah, he was a real
son of a bitch.
So I've read. He...
No, I mean, he was
into some weird stuff.
That's for sure.
I mean, the architecture
of this place,
it's, uh, well, it's
unique, I'll give it that.
The restoration process
was certainly a challenge.
Well, you did
a spectacular job.
Thank you, Mrs. Beauchamp.
Sorry. Joanna.
Please forgive me.
I... yeah, I grew up
with a lot of rules.
Well, you should know that
my daughter does not like rules.
And if you tell her
to do something,
she'll do the opposite.
That's what I love about her.
Well, you've only known her
for a few months.
Check back with me in a year
when you're ready
to strangle her.
I'll have a gimlet.
Dirty martini please.
Ingrid.
Adam.
Hey.
You look great.
So good to see you.
So, um, this house
is incredible, huh?
I've never actually been inside.
Yeah.
Did you know there are all
these tunnels and secret rooms
where they used to have
ritual animal sacrifices
and sadomasochistic sex orgies
with people writhing
around naked,
covered in goat blood?
Um...
I wrote a dissertation about it.
Oh.
About witchcraft
and occult practices
in post-Revolutionary New York.
Not about... goat orgies.
Right, um... Thank you.
Uh, sounds cool.
I'd love to read it sometime.
No, it's not that good.
Plus, I've been a little
blocked for the past few...
years or so.
Oh, that's too bad.
But, you know,
I'm sure you'll figure it out.
So, I was sorry to hear
about you and Emma.
I always liked her.
Wow.
Bad news travels fast, huh?
It's a small town.
Yeah.
Anyway, i-it's okay.
She wasn't really that...
Smart?
I was gonna say "nice" but...
Right.
She also wasn't that smart.
What can I say,
ever since you turned me down...
Turned you down?
What are you talking about?
Yeah, about a year ago.
I came into the library.
You helped me pick out
a detective novel.
I asked you to have dinner
with me, and...
you laughed in my face.
I thought you were kidding.
Why would I have been kidding
about that?
I, uh... Excuse me.
This is Detective Noble.
What?
Yeah. I'll be
right there.
Uh, I'm sorry. I have to go.
Uh, a couple was attacked
in Melrose Park.
Excuse me.
Attacked?
Oh, no. Like, mugged?
Like... murdered.
You okay?
Yeah. Fine.
You sure?
You just seem off.
Sorry. I just...
don't feel that great.
Too much champagne.
Killian?
How are you, man?
This is a...
little like seeing a ghost.
Well, I figured my big brother's
getting married.
I should come congratulate him.
You have a brother?
Yeah. I-I told you
I had a brother.
No, you didn't.
That's okay.
I'm not surprised he
wouldn't mention me.
It's been a long time.
I'm Killian.
It's nice to meet you.
Will you excuse me? I...
Ladies' room.
What is wrong with you?
I don't know
what I'm doing.
I shouldn't be here.
I know this is
going to sound...
But I had a dream about this.
I think I had the same dream.
What happened in yours?
What...?
I can't do this.
I'm sorry, I don't know
what's come over me.
I have to go.
It was a cat.
I'm telling you, I hit a cat,
not a woman.
Okay.
'Cause it looks a lot
like you hit a naked woman.
They interviewed the couple
who found
Bill and Mara Thatcher
last night,
and get this:
He said the murderer ripped out
Bill's eyeballs and tongue.
Ew, Ingrid.
Just ripped them right out.
Enough.
How gross is that?
And Maura's in a coma.
They think she's gonna make it?
So, did you have
a good time last night, Freya?
Holy shit!
There's my clumsy girl.
Did you guys just see that?
It-it spontaneously
broke for no reason.
Please, tell me you
just saw that.
I saw you knock
into the counter.
It was nowhere
near the counter!
Sweetie, are you okay?
You seem a little...
I'm fine.
...nervous.
No, I'm not.
I bet I know what it is.
- You do? - You're having second thoughts
about the wedding.
You're the one having
second thoughts, Mom, not me.
I just don't know
what the hurry is.
You're very young,
you barely know him.
What's the rush?
The rush is she has no idea
what she actually wants
to do with her life,
and getting married feels like
doing something with her life.
Even if it's the wrong thing.
Hey, I am perfectly happy
doing what I'm doing.
I like being a bartender.
I bring joy and drunkenness
to people in need.
Plus I am in love
with Dash Gardiner.
I've never felt this
way about anyone.
I know this is right.
We belong together.
And I don't care
what you guys think.
Freya, I just want to be sure
that you're thinking
this thing through.
Dash travels a lot for work.
How are you gonna handle that?
So, you think I'm
cheating on him?
What are you talking about?
Nobody said that.
I have to go see Dash.
Wow...
I must admit,
I hate leaving you...
but I do love our good-byes.
Why do you have to go
halfway around the world?
Can't you be a Doctor
Without Borders here?
I won't be gone that long.
I promise I'll cut back
on the traveling
once we're married, okay?
Okay.
I don't want
to be away from you.
I hate it.
Maybe we go to Vegas.
We'll just do it.
Or I could come on your trip.
We could elope.
You worried you're gonna
change your mind?
I will never change my mind.
Neither will I.
Good morning, Jim.
Morning.
Mysticum flamma
aperire pictura...
Mysticum
flamma aperire pictura...
Mysticum flamma aperire...
Hey, Barbie.
What's up?
Hey.
Hi.
I just talked to the doctor.
And our last try
with IVF failed.
And we don't have enough money
for another round, so...
The doctor said, at this point,
it would take a miracle
to get me pregnant.
Oh, sweetie, I'm so sorry.
Is there anything I can do?
Well, you studied witchcraft.
Do you know any
"get pregnant" spells?
Honey, I studied history,
not how-to,
but if there were such
a thing as real witchcraft,
and I somehow had
the ability to use it,
you would be the first person
I would help.
I know.
Wendy...
You don't look so good.
Well, I died this morning.
So I'm sorry if my
hair isn't perfect.
What are you doing here?
That's a fine welcome you give
your sister you haven't seen
in over a hundred years.
How much money do you need?
Actually, I came here
to save your life.
Okay, okay.
We'll see you tomorrow.
Oh, my God, my butt
is like eating my underwear.
Hi.
Hey.
Um...
listen, I'm really sorry for
rushing out the other night.
I realize I didn't
even say good-bye,
which was very rude
of me, and...
No, it's okay.
You're a cop.
If someone gets
brutally murdered,
you get a pass.
So, how's
the investigation coming?
Well, actually,
that's why I'm here.
I know you know a lot about
occult stuff, and, well,
there was this, uh,
weird symbol, uh, in the gravel
where the bodies were found.
I thought maybe you'd know
what it meant.
Uh, I-I have to warn you,
these are, uh...
these are graphic.
Whoa!
Yeah.
Gruesome, I know.
Do... do you recognize
the symbol?
It almost looks like a mixture
of several I recognize,
but they're all
from different cultures.
This is really strange.
Can I keep this?
I could check
some books if you want.
Yeah.
Yeah, that-that'd be great.
And, uh, and then...
maybe we could, um,
discuss it over coffee?
Sure.
Great.
Bye, Ingrid.
How you doing, lady?
Okay, I have an idea.
And it's incredibly stupid,
and I can't believe
I'm suggesting it,
but do you want to try
a fertility spell?
Are you serious?
Look, I'm still a
rational skeptic,
but what the hell, it might
be kind of fun, right?
Hey, you want to help
us cast a magic spell
to try to get Barb pregnant?
Only if I can make hats.
I can't believe
I got hit by a car.
That's almost as dumb as
the time I died from syphilis.
So how many?
Lives do I have left?
I don't know... a few.
Who keeps count?
Well, I would,
if I only had nine.
Well, you deal with your curses
and I'll deal with mine.
Joanna, I hate your clothes.
You know, for a
supposed artist,
you dress like a schoolteacher.
I am a schoolteacher.
I teach art.
Oh, sorry.
You know, I'm actually surprised
that you let me in.
Every time I call lately,
you hang up.
Lately?
You haven't called since 1972.
Well, I got sick of trying.
Plus I've been busy.
I moved to New Orleans.
I opened up this
cute little voodoo shop
in the French Quarter.
I got married, I got divorced,
I got married again,
I got widowed,
I got eaten by a crocodile.
I'm not even kidding
about that.
Plus I've been keeping
an eye on you from afar.
Even though you hate me.
I don't hate you.
I-I was just mad.
Anyway, I haven't seen
you in a century,
and suddenly you
turn up half-naked
on my doorstep,
telling me I'm in danger.
Care to elaborate?
Oh, yeah, I was getting
to that, but first...
where are the girls?
We're gonna need their help.
No, no. No way.
Whatever this is, I'm
keeping them out of it.
And no magic while you're here.
House rules.
What are you talking about?
The girls don't know
what they are.
What do you mean
they don't know?
I didn't tell them this time.
How could you not tell them?
I wanted to see if
I could change their fate.
You can't change fate.
That's why they call it fate.
It's fated.
I just got sick of it.
The endless cycle.
I watched my girls grow up...
grow into their gifts...
And then,
they die because of them.
And before I'm even
done mourning,
the cycle starts up again.
I'm suddenly
nine months pregnant
with Ingrid.
And then soon after
comes Freya.
And once again
my girls grow up.
They practice magic.
Then one way
or another...
they die by its hand...
over and over...
and over...
and over.
I've given birth to them
and watched them die
a dozen times and neither
of them's ever lived past 30.
I am sick of it.
I decided this life,
for once, they'd be normal.
So you're denying them
their birthright?
I'm trying to give
them something
they have never, ever had,
not in hundreds of years
of so-called immortality:
a long and happy life.
And you think you're cursed.
At least you got
to have children.
Having children is my curse.
You can't hide their
powers forever, Joanna.
They're gonna come out
one way or another,
whether you want
them to or not.
Be right with you, buddy.
I'm trying to make
this jar of olives
explode with my mind.
♪ Never meant to start a fire
So you just gonna
stand there scowling at me,
or can I have a drink?
What can I get you, sir?
What do you recommend?
I recommend
you leave now
and never come back.
Why don't you make me
the house special?
I hear you're an artist,
that your drinks are
practically... aphrodisiacs.
Well, but then
you'll just end up
all hot and bothered,
and alone and frustrated.
I'm already frustrated.
Get used to it.
So I'm staying in my boat.
Docked down at Fair Haven.
Little bit cramped,
but I think we'll make do.
What are you talking about?
You're coming by
after your shift, yeah?
No.
Why not?
Because I'm engaged
to your brother.
Didn't seem
to stop you last night.
That was a momentary lapse.
I bet you have a lot of those.
Go to hell.
Um... we're not
gonna, like,
awaken any evil
spirits, are we?
First of all, this
is white magic,
not black magic.
And secondly,
there's no such thing
as any kind of magic,
so I'm guessing not.
Oh...
Okay.
Yes.
So it says here
we should join hands
around Barb...
Mm-hmm.
and do the chant
while she massages
her uterus.
Here we go.
Nostri incantatores
facit fertilis semen...
Uh... "semen."
What are you, 12?
It's Latin.
It means "seed."
Ew.
Are we doing this or not?
Suddenly, Miss
I'm-Too-Good-For-Witchcraft
is kind of getting
into the witchcraft.
I believe if you do something,
you should do it right.
Now, come on.
Nostri incantatores
facit fertilis semen.
Nostri incantatores facit
fertilis semen...
Shouldn't there be,
like, flashes of light?
Or a puff of smoke,
or something?
From the fake spell
we got off the Internet?
I'm bored.
You guys want to go
grab a drink
at the Bent Elbow?
Yes.
Totally.
Please.
Hey.
I know you've been angry at me
these past hundred years.
Why would I be angry at you?
You only killed
my eldest daughter.
It was an accident.
Plus, Ingrid was reborn.
It's never the same.
She's always a little
bit different.
And every time I lose them,
it gets a little bit harder.
Oh, don't even act
like your curse
isn't way better than mine.
Oh, here we go...
Immortality?
Is that really even a curse?
Immortality with
endless motherhood.
Do you know how many times
I gave birth before they
invented the epidural?
Not to mention soap.
All right,
but even though you're "cursed"
with immortality,
you're not really immortal,
are you, Joanna?
I mean, if somebody
wanted to kill you,
really wanted to kill
you, they could.
Even with your girls,
the right spell
in the wrong hands
could not only kill
Freya and Ingrid,
but it could stop them
from being reborn.
What are you getting at?
Put out your cards.
I don't know where they are.
Yeah, you do.
I had a dream about you
the other night.
Your eyes were green,
they were glowing,
because it wasn't you,
it was a shifter,
somebody doing evil
in your name.
When I awoke,
I dealt a deck for you.
I couldn't believe what I saw.
I thought I made a mistake,
so I dealt them again,
and again, and again.
Every time, the same thing.
This can't be right.
Look here. The Impostor.
Look at the eyes.
And here, the cloak pulled back.
I didn't know what that meant
at first, but now I know.
It's the powers that you're
hiding from your daughters.
They're about to be revealed.
The life you built here, Joanna,
it's about to change.
Upheaval, death,
destruction, pain,
imprisonment, betrayal.
It's coming for you.
Like nothing you've ever seen before.
Hold on.
Don't get dramatic.
You're always so damn dramatic.
N... No, no, no, no, no.
This isn't happening.
your enemy.
The one who can make themselves look like you.
From the lay of the cards,
it looks like they don't have
the tools to kill you quite yet.
They're still searching,
so that gives us some time.
Do you have any idea
who it might be?
I have absolutely no idea.
You said somebody bought
Fair Haven.
The boy who's marrying Freya?
No, he's mortal.
How do you know?
Because
I tested him.
Ah!
Oopsie!
Mom, did you just stab
my fiancé?
So clumsy. Let me get
a Band-Aid.
Ow!
What is wrong with you?
Nothing. Be right back.
Baby, I'm sorry.
Dico me est hoc
creatura humana.
The test was definitive.
Dash Gardiner is
just an ordinary man.
Only very rich.
The cards don't lie.
You have an enemy, Joanna.
Somebody who wants to hurt you.
Somebody whose powers
rival your own.
And they're not gonna stop until
you and your girls are dead.
Forever dead.
I knew you'd come.
Why do you look so sad?
Because I've waited 400 years
for this,
and it's not even
really happening.
So you're saying she's crazy?
I'm saying she's eccentric.
Who's eccentric?
Our aunt.
We have an aunt?
I told you guys
about Aunt Wendy.
I'd always just assumed you made
her up as a cautionary tale
about what happens
when sisters fight.
No, she's very real.
She's upstairs
in the attic sleeping.
And you guys should know,
she's... a little off.
She also brought her cat.
Bad cat! If you're not careful,
I'm gonna have you spayed.
I'm a little off, am I?
Look, I do appreciate
you coming to help
with the whole "someone's trying
to kill me" thing.
But the one rule I ask you abide
while you're here is
stay in human form.
And don't involve
the girls in this.
Wait, that's two rules.
put on some clothes.
Were you not paying attention
last night?
The girls are gonna figure out
who they are,
whether you want them to or not.
Not if we stop this
ourselves first.
Now get dressed.
I'm tired of looking
at your nipples.
Well, then find me something
that doesn't make me look
like the old woman
who lived in a shoe.
Do you think it's possible
to have two soul mates?
I don't think it's possible
to have one soul mate.
I think "soul mates" is a
concept Hollywood invented
to sell tickets
to Meg Ryan movies.
Okay. Do you think
it's possible
to be in love with two men at once?
No.
I think romantic love is
a concept Hollywood invented
to sell tickets
to Katherine Heigl movies.
No, you don't.
So who is he?
I just meant hypothetically.
Hypothetically, who is he?
Hypothetically,
he's Dash's brother.
Freya, you didn't.
Oh, I know.
I love Dash.
So much. I do.
He's... safe and warm
and comforting
and familiar and hot
and funny and romantic
and sweet,
and I can totally see myself
spending the rest
of my life with him.
Good. 'Cause you're engaged.
But then there's Killian.
Oh, my God.
And I can't explain it,
but he is like...
lightning bolt passion crazy
amazing awesome
soul mate sexual insanity.
- Oh, Freya. Oh, Freya. - Don't say
"Oh, Freya." Please don't say "Oh, Freya."
I hate it when you say "Oh, Freya"!
Girls,
I want you to meet
your Aunt Wendy.
Freya. Hi, I'm sure you don't remember me,
Hi.
But we met a long time ago.
And, boy, did we have fun.
Oh, well,
please tell me some stories
about Mom
that I can use
against her later.
Oh, honey, I've got a million.
Ingrid.
You look so...
It's really nice
to meet you. I'm
late for work.
I've got to go.
What was that about?
I don't know.
Tell me about this boy Dash.
He's not a boy, Aunt Wendy.
He's a man.
And he's amazing.
But...
But nothing.
He's seriously perfect.
I couldn't be happier.
Or more conflicted.
You love him.
That's very clear.
But you're tempted by another.
Oh, my God. How did you know?
Your aura. It's, like,
12 different colors right now.
You can read auras?
Uh-huh.
I'm very intuitive.
Especially with other w...
family members.
I can read auras, too.
Or at least I can see them.
Sometimes.
I think.
Freya, there's something you should know
about your Aunt Wendy.
She's what people
in the psychiatric profession
call "a flake."
And you shouldn't listen
to anything she says.
Well, I guess I'm a flake, too.
Must run in the family.
You keep messing with my girls,
and that curse on your head'll
be the least of your worries.
What? It's not like
I levitated over
by the zucchini cart
or something.
We're gonna have
to work on getting
that broomstick out
of your ass, babe.
Mysticum flamma aperire
pictura.
Mysticum flamma
aperire pictura.
Mysticum flamma aperire
pictura.
Mysticum flamma
aperire pictura.
Mysticum flamma aperire
pictura.
Mysticum...
If you come with me,
I can help you get revenge on
the witch who did this to you.
Figured my not showing up
at your boat last night
would've been a hint.
It's not why I'm here.
Conceited.
Look, I decided we
should be friends.
You want to be friends?
Well, you are
marrying my brother,
so in a way we're
practically family.
We should at least be friends.
Hang out, get to
know each other.
Platonically, of course.
I don't really think
that's a good idea.
I get it.
You're afraid you won't be able
to keep your hands off me.
In your dreams.
True, but I promise
to be a gentleman.
All right, I'm game.
Cool.
We'll be friends.
You'll marry Dash
then spend the rest
of your life wondering what it
would've been like with me.
I'm sorry.
Who's the conceited one?
At least that's what
I'll be doing anyway.
So, can I get a drink or what?
Pal.
All right, chill out, buddy.
I'll go make you something.
♪ Yeah
♪ Yeah...
Hey, where have
you been all day?
Freaking out.
Why?
Wait, did you pee on this?
Yah-ha!
I mean, you don't think...
What, that it was the spell?
The doctor did say
that it would take a miracle.
Okay, besides the fact that
we got it off a Web site
that misspelled both
the words "fertility"
and the word "spell,"
it's way too fast for
that to have worked.
Well, all I know is,
yesterday I wasn't pregnant,
and then we did that spell,
and then Bob and I...
you know... twice,
and then I went to sleep
and I had this dream.
You were there.
You were handing me my baby.
But that was just a dream.
I know it was,
and it seems crazy,
but it also feels
kind of true, too, doesn't it?
Like, if this were
a movie, right now
would be the moment
where the girl who thought
she was ordinary
finds out she's actually magic
and the power was
within her all along.
I, I have to go.
Hey.
Well, what are, what
are you so upset about?
Yes.
Drink up.
You are kicking my ass.
Never play darts
against a bartender.
♪ You got me with your fingers
on my throat ♪
♪ And my head on the floor...
See, I, for one, think
this whole platonic thing
is going great.
It's not, not torture at all.
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
♪ Yeah, this is how
you want me to play ♪
♪ You know I love it,
but it's stopping today ♪
♪ I'm slipping away...
I don't care how drunk you are
or how hot he is.
Keep it friendly, Freya.
Friendly friends.
Whoa, hey, ladies' room.
Uh, ocupado, buddy.
Hello, Freya.
Hi, stranger.
You have quite
the sunburn there.
You know, I'd put
some aloe on that ASAP.
She said that
you'd be different,
that you wouldn't remember me.
Who said?
My benefactor.
She really hates your
family, even more than I do.
She said that I could
have you as my toy,
that I could do whatever
I want with you.
You're not the,
not the same Freya,
but you're still Freya.
Okay, I think
you have me confused
with a different Freya.
It's a very common name.
I asked you
to be my bride,
and you rejected me.
All I did
was get a little bit angry,
and what did you do?
You stuck me in a
desert for 80 years!
Well, guess what.
I'm gonna do a lot more
than hit you this time.
Killian, somebody!
♪ Take what you came here for
♪ I'm ready for you...
Stop that!
Somebody!
I said stop that!
Help me!
Quiet.
Oh, God, just let me go.
Just let me go, please.
My magic is a little bit rusty,
and I was never as
talented as you,
which is why you're gonna be
the one to cast the spell.
Take this.
Uh...
I'm gonna cast a magic spell
with a scented candle?
Yes, we are.
Okay, take a deep breath.
Repeat after me.
Mysticum pictura devorare nos.
I don't speak that.
Yes, you do,
Freya, yes, you do,
Now say it.
Mysticum pictura devorare nos.
Good, again.
Mysticum
pictura devorare nos.
Again.
Mysticum pictura devorare nos.
What?
Hey, I'm making a vision stew.
I used this once
to track down an old boyfriend
of mine who owed me money.
Thought we could use it
to find our imposter.
It's in the peyote family,
so don't be alarmed
if the walls start breathing.
Do you want a taste?
Freya, did you fall in?
Freya.
Freya?
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh
♪ So what you gonna say now?
Thanks.
I heard you were ready
to talk to me.
I know who killed my husband.
Oh, my God, what happened?
You stabbed me.
Plus I think I
ruined your towel.
Okay, it's okay,
I can fix this.
I can do a healing spell.
No, no, no, wait, no, no, it's too late.
Listen to me.
The imposter...
she's real.
I was right; she
looks like you.
I managed to eat some
stew after she left.
I had a vision.
Oh, man, walls are breathing.
Holy shit.
Listen, you have to save Freya.
The bar where she
works... in the bathroom,
there's a picture.
An old lover of
hers wants revenge.
Guys, what the hell is going on?
Shh.
He's going to
take her in there.
He wants to kill
her in the picture
because he knows if he does...
She can't be reborn.
I wish I could help you.
I don't understand
what's happening.
We don't have much time.
We have to help your sister,
but first there's something
I need to tell you.
It's the truth
about who we are.
Please don't tell me we're witches.
We're witches.
When you were little, I
put a spell on you girls
so you wouldn't figure
out what we were.
It barely worked on Freya,
but it worked too well on you.
Freya knew and you lied to her.
You sent her to therapy.
Oh, my God, she is going
to be so pissed.
Only if we can save her.
I don't believe you.
I am a rational skeptic.
I am a wallflower.
Baby, no, you're magic.
Oh, this isn't happening.
Wendy.
Detective Noble.
Joanna Beauchamp,
you are under arrest
for the murder of Bill Thatcher
and the attempted murder
of Maura Thatcher.
You have the right to remain silent.
Wait,
Adam, what the hell?
She was positively I.D.'d
by the victim.
I'm sorry.
Mom.
You have to save your sister.
You're the only one
who can do it.
Please don't tell me the power
was within me all along.
The breakfront
has a false back.
You'll find
everything you need inside.
Ingrid, hurry, please.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com