[Crew chattering]
[Parker laughing]
BRETT: This is the worst shit
l've ever seen, man.
PARKER: Have you got
any biscuits over there?
RlPLEY: Here's some cornbread.
PARKER: Cornbread. Yeah.
LAMBERT: l am cold.
Still with us, Brett?
BRETT: Right.
KANE: lfeel dead.
PARKER: Anybody ever tell you
you look dead, man?
Oh,yeah, right.
l justforgot something, man.
Before we dock...
l think we ought to discuss
the bonus situation.
BRETT: Right.
PARKER: Brett and l
think we deserve full shares.
BRETT: Mr. Parker and lfeel
the bonus situation...
has never been
on an equitable level.
You'll get what you contracted
for, like everybody else.
BRETT: But everybody else
gets more than us.
ASH: Dallas,
Mother wants to talk to you.
[Buzzer]
Yeah, l saw it.
Yellow light's for my eyes only.
OK, get dressed, huh?
Parker, let's go.
PARKER: Can lfinish my coffee?
lt's the only thing good
on this ship.
[Beeping]
DALLAS: Good morning, Mother.
RlPLEY: Right?
KANE: OK.
Plug us in.
ASH: Thank you.
Where's Earth?
You should know.
RlPLEY: lt's not our system.
KANE: Scan.
l can't believe this.
KANE: Contact traffic control.
RlPLEY: This is commercial
towing vehicle Nostromo...
out of the Solomons...
registration number
1-8-0-9er 2-4-6-0-9er...
calling
Antarctica Traffic Control.
Do you read me? Over.
Commercial towing vehicle
Nostromo...
out of the Solomons...
registration number
1-8-0-9er 2-4-6-0-9er.
-Nothing.
-Keep trying.
RlPLEY: Calling
Antarctica Traffic Control.
Do you read me,Antarctica?
Over.
lfound it. Just short
of Zeta ll Reticuli.
We haven't reached
the outer rim yet.
That's hard to believe.
RlPLEY: Calling Antarctica...
LAMBERT: What the hell
are we doing out here?
KANE: l don't know.
What the hell are you
talking about?
That's not our system.
l know that.
PARKER: You ever notice
how they never come down here?
l mean,this is
where the work is, right?
BRETT: The same damn reason we
get a half share to their one.
Our time is their time.
That's the way they see it.
Same old shit, man.
PARKER: l know why
they don't come down here.
lt's because of you.
You have no personality.
PARKER:
Wonder what they want now?
What's going on down here?
You happen to be in my seat.
Can l have it?
-Yes.
-Thank you.
ASH: Sorry.
PARKER:
What's happening now, baby?
DALLAS: Well, some of you
may have figured out...
we're not home yet.
We're only halfway there.
PARKER: What?
DALLAS: Mother's interrupted
the course of our journey.
KANE: Why?
DALLAS: She's programmed to,
should certain conditions arise.
-They have.
-Like what?
DALLAS:
Seems she has intercepted...
a transmission
of unknown origin.
She got us up to check it out.
RlPLEY:
A transmission? Out here?
DALLAS: Yeah.
What kind of a transmission?
DALLAS: Acoustical beacon.
lt repeats at intervals
of twelve seconds.
-S.O.S.?
-l don't know.
RlPLEY: Human?
DALLAS: Unknown.
PARKER: So what?
KANE: We're obligated
under Section B-two--
PARKER:
l hate to bring this up...
but this is a commercial ship,
not a rescue ship.
lt's not in my contract
to do this kind of duty.
You want to give me some money
to do it, l'll be happy to.
-Parker.
-The man's right.
PARKER: Let's go over
the bonus situation.
ASH: Can l say something?
PARKER:
Let's talk about the bonuses.
ASH: There is a clause
which specifically states...
any systematizzed transmission...
indicating a possible
intelligent origin...
must be investigated.
PARKER: l don't want to hear it.
l want to go home and party.
Parker,will you just
listen to the man?
On penalty
of totalforfeiture of shares.
No money.
You got that?
PARKER: Well,yeah.
All right,we're going in.
PARKER:
Yeah,we're going in, aren't we?
LAMBERT:
Approaching orbital apogee.
Mark.
Twelve, eleven...
ASH: Equatorial orbit nailed.
-Main stabilizzers in.
-Eight seconds on descent.
KANE:
Grids energizzed. Fields focused.
LAMBERT: Five,four...
[Voices overlapping]
Put the D.O.R.s in-line.
RlPLEY: How's the status
on the lifters?
DALLAS: Give me
an A.C. pressure reading.
ASH: Forty-eight seconds
and counting.
RlPLEY: SR-one stable.
DALLAS: Prepare to disengage
from platform.
LAMBERT: Twenty seconds.
Eighteen, seventeen...
sixteen,fifteen...
fourteen,thirteen...
twelve, eleven,ten...
seven, six...
five,four...
three,two, one, lock.
DALLAS: Disengage.
OK.
Money's safe.
Let's take her down.
KANE:
Roll 92 degrees port yaw.
RlPLEY: Prime the port.
RlPLEY: Prime ventral.
Prime dorsal.
DALLAS: Down a degree.
LAMBERT: Nine hundred meters
and dropping.
Thirty-nine thousand.
RlPLEY: Turbulence.
Locked andfloating.
Drop us any time now.
lnertial damping's going off.
Hold on, people,
there's gonna be a little bump.
[Screech]
What the hell was that?
BRETT:
Pressure dropping in deck three.
Must've lost a shield.
Let's go with it.
ASH: Dropping off now.
Still dropping.
There we are. We've got it.
Take her down.
Navigation lights on.
ASH: We've gotfive-three
still out. No problem.
Just down eleven percent.
Grid status...OK.
LAMBERT:
Fifteen meters and dropping.
Twelve, eleven,ten...
nine, eight...
seven, six...
five,four...
three,two, one.
Kill drive engines.
[Siren]
DALLAS: What the hell happened?
[Siren slows]
DALLAS: Somebody give me
a straight answer!
-ls the hull breached?
-We've still got pressure.
DALLAS: Hit the screens.
[Wind howling]
PARKER ON lNTERCOM: Secondary
load-sharing unit is out.
Three of the four cells
are gone.
RlPLEY: ls that it?
PARKER: Hold on.
We can'tfix it out here anyway.
We need to reroute
a couple of these ducts.
KANE: Dry-dock time.
BRETT: Dry-dock.
Tell them we need to dry-dock.
PARKER: We couldn'tfix it
out here anyway.
We got to reroute
all these ducts.
ln order to do that,
we've got to dry-dock.
DALLAS: [Sighs] What else?
PARKER:
Some fragments caked up...
and we've got to clean it
all out and repressurizze it.
DALLAS: How long
before we're functional?
PARKER: What?
BRETT:
Seventeen hours,tell him.
PARKER:
At least twenty-five hours.
RlPLEY: Get started.
l'll be right down.
PARKER:
What's she coming down here for?
BRETT: She'd better
stay the fuck out of my way.
PARKER: l'd like to see
what she'll do.
DALLAS: Any response yet?
ASH: Nope. Absolutely nothing...
except the same transmission
every twelve seconds.
All the other channels are dead.
DALLAS: Kick on the floods.
KANE:
We can't go anywhere in this.
DALLAS: Mm-hmm.
ASH: Mother says the sun's
coming up in twenty minutes.
DALLAS: How far are we
from the source of transmission?
ASH: Northeast,
just under two thousand meters.
KANE: Walking distance?
[Dallas chuckles]
DALLAS:
Can you give me an atmospheric?
ASH: Yes.
ASH: Oh.
lt's almost primordial.
There's inert nitrogen...
high concentration
of carbon dioxide crystals...
methane.
l'm working
on the trace elements.
DALLAS: Anything else?
ASH:
Yes. There's rock--lava base.
Deep cold,well below the line.
DALLAS: Mm-hmm.
KANE: l'll volunteer to be
in the first group to go out.
DALLAS: Yeah,thatfigures.
You,too, Lambert.
LAMBERT: Swell.
DALLAS:
Better break out the weapons.
[Blows]
LAMBERT:
l can't see a goddamn thing.
DALLAS: Ash, are you receiving?
ASH: Good contact on my board.
DALLAS: Clear andfree.
Keep the line open.
Let's go.
PARKER: Hey, Ripley!
Hey, Ripley,
l want to ask you a question.
lf they find
what they're lookingfor,
does that
mean we getfull shares?
Don't worry, Parker.
Yeah. You'll get
whatever's coming to you.
BRETT: Look, l'm not going to do
any more work...
till we get this
straightened out.
RlPLEY: Brett,you're guaranteed
by law to get a share.
PARKER: What?
Why don't you justfuck off?
BRETT: What did you say, Rip?
RlPLEY: lf you have any trouble,
l'll be on the bridge.
PARKER:
Don't worry about it, baby.
Hey, Ripley. Come back here!
BRETT: Ha ha ha ha!
PARKER: Son of a bitch.
BRETT: What's the matter?
LAMBERT:
l can't see a goddamn thing.
KANE: Quit griping.
LAMBERT: l like griping.
DALLAS: Come on, knock it off.
How's it going?
ASH: All right.
RlPLEY: Have you tried
putting that transmission...
through E.C.l.U.?
ASH: No.
Mother hasn't identified it yet.
Do you mind if l give it a shot?
ASH: Please do.
DALLAS: Ash, can you see this?
ASH: Yes, l can.
l've never seen anything
like it.
DALLAS: lt's very bizzarre.
KANE: You said it.
DALLAS: All right.
Moving on to second...position.
LAMBERT: What is it?
Let's get out of here.
KANE: We've come this far.
We must go on.
We have to go on.
Will you say that again?
Shit.
DALLAS: Ash, as you can see,
it's hard to describe.
ASH:
l'm going back to the console.
[Garbled voice]
DALLAS: [Faint]
Seems to be solid...
to walk.
You OK, Lambert?
[Garbled transmission
from Dallas]
Dallas?
Come on down here.
Something different
down here.
l don't know
what it is, but...
See if we can
get up that wall...
then get up that wall
behind there.
KANE: Amazzing.
DALLAS: An alien life form.
Looks like it's been dead
a long time.
Fossilizzed.
Looks like it's grown
out of the chair.
DALLAS: Oh.
Bones are bent outward...
like he explodedfrom inside.
LAMBERT: l wonder what happened
to the rest of the crew?
Let's get the hell out of here.
KANE: Dallas, Lambert!
Come on over here.
Come on.
-What have you got?
-See what you make of this.
Ash,that transmission.
Mother's deciphered part of it.
lt doesn't look like an S.O.S.
ASH: What is it then?
lt looks like a warning.
l'm going to go out after them.
What's the point?
l mean, by the time
it takes to get there...
they'll know
if it's a warning or not. Yes?
[Sighs]
DALLAS: You OK down there?
Can you see anything?
KANE: l don't know. A cave.
A cave of some sort, but l...
l don't know, but it's like
the goddamn tropics in here.
What the hell is this?
KANE: The pit
is completely enclosed...
and it's full
of leathery objects...
like eggs or something.
[Humming sound]
There's a layer of mist
just covering the eggs...
that reacts when broken.
DALLAS: Kane!
You all right?
KANE: Yeah, l'm OK. All right.
l'm OK. l just slipped.
lt appears
to be completely sealed.
[Hiss]
KANE: Wait a minute.
There's movement.
lt seems to have life--
organic life.
DALLAS: You there, Ripley?
l'm right here.
ASH: OK, Ripley,
l'm at the inner lock hatch now.
RlPLEY: Right.
-OK, Ripley.
-Right here.
DALLAS:
We're clean. Let us in.
What happened to Kane?
DALLAS: Something has attached
itself to him.
We have to get him
to the infirmary right away.
What kind of thing?
l need a definition.
DALLAS:
An organism. Open the hatch.
Wait a minute.
lt could infect the ship.
You know
the quarantine procedure--
twenty-four hours
for decontamination.
DALLAS: He could die
in twenty-four hours.
lf we break quarantine,
we could all die.
LAMBERT: Open the goddamn hatch!
We have to get him inside!
RlPLEY: No, l can't do that.
lf you were in my position,
you'd do the same.
DALLAS: This is an order.
Open that hatch. Do you hear me?
RlPLEY: Yes.
DALLAS: Ripley,this is
an order! Do you hear me?
Yes, l read you.
The answer is negative.
ASH: lnner hatch opened.
DALLAS: My God.
DALLAS: What the hell is that?
RlPLEY: How is he?
DALLAS: How are we going
to get that off him?
How are we going to get it off?
ASH: Just a minute.
Let me get some instruments.
RlPLEY: Oh, my God.
ASH: All right.
lf l go for an incision here...
to try and remove one
of the digitals from his face.
DALLAS: You're gonna do what?
ASH: Finger. l'm going to try
and get his finger off.
Get this on there.
DALLAS: lt's tearing his scalp.
ASH: l know!
DALLAS: lt's not coming off
without tearing his face off.
ASH: We'll have
to take a look at him inside.
PARKER:
How come they don'tfreezze him?
How come you guys
don'tfreezze him?
ASH: All right,
you can take your mask off.
What's it got down his throat?
ASH: l would suggest
it's feeding him oxygen.
DALLAS: Paralyzzes him,
puts him in a coma...
then keeps him alive.
Now,what the hell is that?
-We've got to get it off him.
-Just a minute.
Let's not be too hasty.
We don't know
anything about...it.
Now,we're assuming
it's feeding him oxygen.
lf we remove it...
it could kill him.
l'm willing to take that chance.
Let's cut it off now.
You'll take responsibility?
l'll take responsibility.
Get him out of there.
DALLAS:
Where do you want to do this?
ASH: We'll make an incision
just below the knuckle there.
-Right here.
-Stand by.
Good God!
DALLAS: That crap's gonna eat
through the hull.
lt's going to eat through
the goddamn hull! Come on!
BRETT: What's going on?
DALLAS: This way.
DALLAS: Next deck.
PARKER: There it is!
Don't get under it!
RlPLEY:
Looks like it's stopping.
PARKER:
Take a look at this, man.
DALLAS:
Brett,what do you got, a pen?
Give it to me, quick. Come on!
BRETT:
Don't get any on your arm.
lt stopped.
Haven't seen anything like that
except molecular acid.
BRETT:
lt must be using itfor blood.
PARKER: lt's got
a wonderful defense mechanism.
You don't dare kill it.
RlPLEY: What about Kane?
DALLAS: Here's your pen back.
BRETT: What do we do now?
DALLAS: Leave Kane to Ash.
You get back to work.
BRETT: Well,what--
BRETT: OK.
Try it.
l thought sure that was it.
PARKER: Try it again.
BRETT: lfeel like l've been
in this place a month.
We shouldn't have landed here
in the first place.
BRETT: Shouldn't have landed
on this damn ball.
l know that.
The sooner we patch this thing
up and get outta here...
the sooner we can go home.
This place gives me the creeps.
RlPLEY:
That's amazzing. What is it?
ASH: l'd say it's, um...
l don't know yet.
Do you want something?
RlPLEY: Yes, l, uh...
would like to have
a little talk. How's Kane?
ASH: He's holding. No changes.
RlPLEY: And, uh...
our guest?
ASH: Hmm.
RlPLEY: Hmm?
ASH: Well, as l said, l was
still collating, actually...
but l have confirmed...
that he's got an outer layer
of protein polysaccharides.
He has a funny habit
of shedding his cells...
and replacing them
with polarizzed silicone...
which gives him
a prolonged resistance...
to adverse
environmental conditions.
ls that enough?
RlPLEY: That's plenty.
What does it mean?
ASH: Please don't do that.
Thank you.
RlPLEY: l'm sorry.
ASH: Well, it's an interesting
combination of elements...
making him a tough little
son of a bitch.
And you let him in.
ASH: l was obeying
a direct order, remember?
Ash,when Dallas and Kane
are off the ship...
l'm senior officer.
ASH: Oh,yes, lforgot.
You also forgot
the science division's...
basic quarantine law.
-No,that l didn'tforget.
-Oh, l see. You just broke it.
Look,what would you
have done with Kane?
His only chance of survival
was to get him in here.
RlPLEY: Unfortunately,
by breaking quarantine...
you risk everybody's life.
Maybe l should have
left him outside.
Maybe l've jeopardizzed
the rest of us...
but it was a risk
l was willing to take.
lt's a pretty big risk
for a science officer.
lt's not exactly
out of the manual, is it?
l do take my responsibilities
as seriously as you,you know.
You do your job
and let me do mine.
RlPLEY: Where's Dallas?
ASH: ln the shuttle.
[lntercom buzzzzes]
Dallas.
ASH: l think you should
have a look at Kane.
Why?
ASH: Something's happened.
Serious?
ASH: lnteresting.
[Music stops]
Ripley, meet me
in the infirmary right away.
RlPLEY: Where is it?
ASH: l don't know.
We have to try andfind it.
DALLAS: Let's check it.
RlPLEY:
Dallas, please be careful.
RlPLEY: Aah!
DALLAS: Sorry.
ASH: No, not in the corner!
Have one of these...
just in case.
Kane?
Dallas? Aah!
DALLAS: You OK?
ASH: l didn't see it.
Was it in the overhead?
DALLAS: What?
lt was up there somewhere.
ASH: My God.
DALLAS: Cover the damn thing,
will you?
lt's alive!
ASH: That's a reflex action.
Well,we've got
to have a look at this.
ASH: Excuse me.
Seems dead enough.
RlPLEY: Well, good.
Let's get rid of it.
ASH: Ripley,for God's sake,
this is the first time...
that we've encountered
a species like this.
lt has to go back.
Tests have to be made.
RlPLEY: Ash, are you kidding?
This thing bled acid.
Who knows
what it'll do when it's dead?
ASH: l think it's safe to assume
it isn't a zzombie.
Dallas, it has to go back.
DALLAS: l'd soon as not
burn it at the stake...
but you're the science officer.
lt's your decision,Ash.
RlPLEY: Dallas!
DALLAS: l won't change my mind.
The decision's made.
RlPLEY: l'm not trying
to change your mind, Dallas.
l just want you to listen.
Will you listen to--
DALLAS: Oh.
RlPLEY: How can you leave
that decision to him?
DALLAS: l just run the ship.
Anything to do
with the science division...
Ash has the final word.
How does that happen?
DALLAS: lt happens because
that's what the Company wants.
Since when is that
standard procedure?
DALLAS:
Standard procedure is to do...
what the hell
they tell you to do.
Did you ever ship out
with Ash before?
l went outfive times
with another science officer.
They replaced him two days
before we left Thedus with Ash.
l don't trust him.
l don't trust anybody.
What's happening
with the repairs?
They're pretty much
finished now.
DALLAS: Why the hell
didn't you tell me so?
Because there's still
some things left to do.
Like what?
RlPLEY: We're blind
on ''B'' and ''C'' Decks.
-The reserve power system is--
-That's a bunch of horseshit.
We can take off without that.
RlPLEY: We can. You think
that's a good idea?
DALLAS: l just want
to get the hell out of here.
Dust in the intakes again.
Number two is overheating.
Spit on itfor two minutes,
would you,for Christ's sake?
RlPLEY: We're hot,
and we're getting hotter.
Engine room, red clip status?
One kilometer on ascension.
RlPLEY:
Engage artificial gravity.
LAMBERT: Engaged.
l'm altering the vector...now.
DALLAS: lnhibit CNG control.
LAMBERT: lnhibit CNG control.
-Struts retract.
-Struts retracted.
LAMBERT:
Max stress to fifth overload.
DALLAS: Ease it back.
Walk in the park!
We fix something,
it stays fixed.
Don't we, Brett, baby?
BRETT: Right.
PARKER:
l think we shouldfreezze him.
lf he's got a disease,
stop it where it is.
He can get to a doctor
when we get back home.
BRETT: Right.
RlPLEY:
Whenever he says anything...
you say, ''Right,'' Brett.
You know that?
BRETT: Right.
RlPLEY: Parker,your staff
follows you around...
and says, ''Right,''
just like a parrot.
PARKER: Shape up.
You some kind of parrot?
-Right.
-Knock it off!
DALLAS: Kane's going
into quarantine. That's it!
RlPLEY: Yes, and so will we.
LAMBERT: How about something
to lower your spirits?
DALLAS:
Thrill me,will you, please?
LAMBERT: Well, according
to my calculations...
based on time spent getting
to andfrom the planet--
DALLAS:
Just give me the short version.
-How far to Earth?
-Ten months.
-Oh, God.
-Great.
[lntercom buzzzzes]
RlPLEY: Yes?
ASH: Dallas, l think you
should come and see Kane.
DALLAS:
Has his condition changed?
ASH: lt's simpler
if you just come and see him.
RlPLEY: We're on our way.
BRETT: Right.
[Parker laughing]
LAMBERT: How are you doing?
[Kane coughing]
PARKER: How you doing?
Oh,terrific.
Next silly question.
KANE: Oh,thank you.
DALLAS: You remember anything
about the planet?
RlPLEY: What's the last thing
you do remember?
l remember some horrible dream
about smothering, and...
Anyway,where are we?
-Right here.
-On our way home.
Back to the oldfreezzerinos.
l've got to have something
to eat before we go back.
l need something myself.
DALLAS: Yeah. One more meal
before bedtime. l'm buying.
Hey,that's a break.
[Chattering]
PARKER:
What--what happened to this guy?
KANE: The first thing
l'm gonna do when l get back...
is to get some decentfood.
PARKER: l can dig it, man.
l've eaten worse food
than this...
but then l've tasted better,
you know?
LAMBERT: You pound it down
like there's no tomorrow.
PARKER: l'd rather be eating
something else...
but right now,
l'll stick to food.
KANE: Well,you should know.
You know what it's made of.
PARKER: l don't want to talk
about what it's made of.
l'm eating this.
[Kane coughing]
PARKER: What's the matter?
The food ain't that bad, baby.
-Are you choking?
-What's wrong?
DALLAS: What?
Kane,what's the matter?
[Kane screaming and gagging]
-Get the spoon in!
-Hold him down!
ASH: Get the spoon in his mouth!
PARKER: Damn it!
-Get it in his mouth!
-l'm trying!
KANE: Aaahh!
Aah!
LAMBERT: Aah!
KANE: Uhh! Uhh! Uhh!
[Screaming]
Uhh! Aah!
[Alien screeches]
LAMBERT: Oh, God!
ASH:
Don't touch it! Don't touch it!
[Screeches]
BRETT: Dallas?
-Yeah.
-Anything?
DALLAS: No. You?
BRETT: Nothing.
-Did you see anything?
-No.
DALLAS: lnner hatch sealed.
Anybody want to say anything?
BRETT: This is an ordinary prod,
like a cattle prod.
lt's got a portable battery.
lt's insulated
all the way up to here.
Just make damn sure
nobody touches the end of it.
Shouldn't damage
the little bastard...
unless its skin
is thinner than ours...
but it will give him
a little incentive.
LAMBERT:
Now we just have to find it.
ASH: l've taken care of that.
l've designed
this tracking device.
You set it to search
for a moving object.
Hasn't got much of a range,
but when you get close...
it gives off a signal.
RlPLEY: What's it key on?
ASH:
Micro changes in air density.
DALLAS: Give me a demo.
[Whistling sound]
-You see?
-Again.
[Whistling]
DALLAS: Gotcha.
Two teams--
Ash, Lambert, and l.
Ripley,
you take Parker and Brett.
Now, anyone see this thing...
catch it in a net
that Parker's holding.
Parker, l don't want any heroics
out of you, all right?
Catch it, put it in the airlock,
and get rid of it.
Channels are open on all decks.
l want you to communicate
at all times, all right?
Let's go.
RlPLEY: l thought youfixed
twelve module.
BRETT: We did.
l don't understand it.
PARKER: The circuits
must have burned out.
BRETT: What have we got here?
PARKER: Damn it. Hold your light
over here,would you?
Yeah,that's it.
l don't know if this will work.
Maybe l can just
put this in there.
BRETT: Right.
PARKER: Damn it.
BRETT: Check the insulation.
PARKER: Oh, shit.
[Tracker whistling]
RlPLEY: According to this,
it's within five meters.
PARKER: Let's open the door.
RlPLEY: Micro changes
in air density, my ass.
lt's within five meters.
PARKER: Be careful.
PARKER: Don't creep up on me
with that thing.
RlPLEY: You guys stick together.
[Whistling modulates
between soft and loud]
Don'tfail me now.
BRETT: What? What is it?
RlPLEY: Parker, Brett.
lt's in this locker.
Get the net.
l got it. l got it.
BRETT: Wait a minute.
RlPLEY: All right, Parker,
when l say.
All right, now.
BRETT: Easy.
RlPLEY: Wait! Don't let him go!
PARKER: What the hell
are you doing, man?
BRETT: lt's the cat, man.
[Parker laughs]
PARKER:
Hey, look now. We had to bag it.
Now we might pick it up
on the tracker again.
-l'll--l'll--
-Go and get it, man.
RlPLEY: All right,you get him.
We'll go on.
Here, kitty.
Here, kitty, kitty.
Enough of that kitty crap.
Jones!
Jonesy?
Here,Jonesy!
Meow, meow.
[Meow]
Jonesy?
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
Meow.
Here,Jonesy!
Jonesy.
[Meow]
Here, kitty, kitty.
[Cat screeches]
[Water dripping]
[Chains rattling]
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Here,Jonesy.
Jonesy!
Kitty, kitty.
[Clang]
Jonesy?
Hey, come on,Jonesy.
Come on, baby. That's a kitty.
That's a kitty. Come on, baby.
That's a kitty.
[Hisses]
Hey, hey,
l'm not going to hurt you.
Come on.
[Growling]
Aaaaaaah!
Whatever it was,
it was big and...
You sure it took him
into the air shaft?
Disappeared
into one of the cooling ducts.
PARKER: lt's using
the air ducts to move around.
LAMBERT:
Could he want Brett alive?
RlPLEY: What?
LAMBERT: Could Brett be alive?
RlPLEY:
No. l mean, l don't think so.
DALLAS: This air shaft
may work to our advantage.
Here it leads up to
and comes out...
in the main air lock.
There's only one big opening
along the way.
We'll cover that up...
then we drive it
into the air lock...
and zzap it into outer space.
The son of a bitch is huge!
lt's like a man. lt's big!
[Muttering] Kane's son.
RlPLEY: Ash,the science
department should help us.
What can we do to drive it?
lt's adapted remarkably well
to our atmosphere...
considering
its nutritional requirements.
We don't know about temperature.
RlPLEY:
What happens if we change it?
ASH: Let's try it.
Most animals retreatfrom fire.
DALLAS: Fire,yeah.
Parker, can you rig
three orfour incinerator units?
Give me about twenty minutes.
l'll do it.
-Who gets to go into the vent?
-l do.
DALLAS: No.
You and Ash...
take the main air lock.
Parker, Lambert...
you cover up that
maintenance opening, please.
LAMBERT: Right.
DALLAS:
l'm at the first junction.
RlPLEY: Dallas, l'm right here.
-Parker?
-Yeah.
DALLAS: Lambert?
LAMBERT:
l'm trying to get a reading.
RlPLEY: The air lock is open.
DALLAS: OK, Ripley.
RlPLEY: Ready.
DALLAS: Moving up.
LAMBERT: All right.
l've got a reading on you now.
[Machine beeping]
DALLAS: Uh, open the hatch
to the third junction.
OK, l'm through. Ripley?
Yes.
DALLAS:
Close all the hatches behind me.
l'm moving on.
LAMBERT: Dallas, hold it
a minute. l think l got it.
-Yes, l've got it.
-Where?
LAMBERT: Somewhere around
the third junction.
DALLAS: OK, moving on.
LAMBERT: lt is right
around there. Be careful.
DALLAS: All right.
l've reached...
the third junction,
and l'm going down.
PARKER: What the hell's
the matter with that box?
[Beeping]
LAMBERT: Dallas,
hold your position for a minute.
l've lost the signal.
DALLAS: What? You sure?
LAMBERT: Are you sure
that it's not there?
lt's got to be around there
somewhere.
DALLAS: Check that out, Lambert.
You may be getting interference.
LAMBERT: Are you sure
there's no sign of it?
lt is there.
lt's got to be around there.
Dallas?
[Muttering] l can't
believe this is happening.
All right.
Uh, am l clear?
l want to get out of here.
LAMBERT: Oh, God,
it's moving right towards you!
DALLAS: Uh...
LAMBERT: Move! Get out of there!
lt's moving towards you! Move!
Dallas! Move, Dallas!
Move, Dallas! Get out!
No, not that way!
The other way, Dallas!
[Screeches]
Dallas?
-No!
-Take it easy.
PARKER: Dallas?
[Static]
We found this laying there.
No blood...
no Dallas...
nothing.
How come nobody's
saying nothing?
RlPLEY: l'm thinking.
Unless somebody
has got a better idea...
we'll proceed with Dallas' plan.
What?
And end up like the others?
Oh, no,
you're out of your mind!
-You got a better idea?
-Yes.
LAMBERT:
l say that we abandon this ship.
We get the shuttle and
just get the hell out of here!
We take our chances
and just hope that somebody--
Lambert, shh.
The shuttle won't take four.
LAMBERT:
Then why don't we draw straws?
l'm not drawing any straws.
l'm for killing that thing
right now.
RlPLEY: OK.
Well, let's talk about
killing it.
We know
it's using the air shafts.
Listen to me, Parker! Shut up!
PARKER: Let's hear it.
Let's hear it.
RlPLEY:
lt's using the air shafts.
-We don't know that.
-That's the only way!
We'll move in pairs.
We'll go step by step
and cut off every bulkhead...
and every vent
until we have it cornered...
and then we'll blow it the fuck
out into space.
ls that acceptable to you?
PARKER: lf it means killing it.
Obviously,
it means killing it...
but we have to stick together.
How are our weapons?
The weapons are fine.
This one needs refueling.
RlPLEY: Will you get it, please?
Ash, go with him.
PARKER: No, l can manage,Ash.
Don'tfollow me.
Ash?
Any suggestions
from you or Mother?
ASH: No. We're still collating.
You're what?
You're still collating?
lfind that hard to believe.
ASH:
What would you like me to do?
RlPLEY: Just what
you've been doing,Ash--
nothing.
l've got access to Mother now...
and l'll get my own answers,
thank you.
ASH: All right.
ASH: There is an explanation
for this,you know.
RlPLEY: There is?!
l don't want to hear
your goddamn explanation!
l don't want to hear.
l...
Parker.
Lambert?
Ash.
Open the door.
Ash!
Will you open the door?
Let me by,Ash.
RlPLEY: Aah! Aah!
PARKER:
What the hell are you doing?
[Ripley gasping]
Aah!
PARKER: Get her up!
Get her up! Get her up!
PARKER: Jesus!
lt's a robot!
Ash is a goddamn robot!
God!
Holy shit!
Help me get
this fucking thing off!
LAMBERT: Aah!
PARKER: Oh, God! Oh,Jesus!
Oh, God. Oh, God.
PARKER: How come the Company
sent us a goddamn robot?
RlPLEY:
They must've wanted the alien...
for their weapons division.
He's been protecting it
right along.
Parker,will you plug it in?
PARKER: Uh, l don't know why--
RlPLEY: Because he may know
how to kill it.
RlPLEY: Ash, can you hear me?
Ash!
Yes, l can hear you.
What was your special order?
You read it.
l thought it was clear.
What was it?
Bring back life form.
Priority one.
All other priorities rescinded.
That damn Company!
What about our lives,
you son of a bitch?
l repeat--all other priorities
are rescinded.
RlPLEY: How do we kill it,Ash?
There's got to be a way
of killing it.
How do we do it?
You can't.
PARKER: That's bullshit!
ASH: You still don't understand
what you're dealing with.
The perfect organism.
lts structural perfection...
is matched
only by its hostility.
LAMBERT: You admire it.
l admire its purity.
A survivor--
unclouded...
by conscience...
remorse...
or delusions of morality.
PARKER:
l've heard enough of this.
l'm asking you
to pull the plug.
ASH: Last word, Ripley.
What?
l can't lie to you
about your chances, but...
you have my sympathies.
RlPLEY:
We're going to blow up the ship.
We'll take our chances
in the shuttle.
-Blow up the ship.
-Good.
PARKER: Come on.
RlPLEY:
When we throw the switches...
how long before the ship blows?
-Ten minutes.
-No bullshit.
PARKER: lf we ain't out
in ten minutes...
we won't need no rocket
to fly through space.
RlPLEY: We'll need coolant
for the air-support system.
RlPLEY: You two get
all the coolant you can carry.
l'll get the shuttle ready.
l'll give you about
seven minutes.
Come back up here,
l'll shut the switches off...
and we'll blow this fucker
off into space.
PARKER: OK. Come on.
-Ready?
-Take care of yourself.
RlPLEY: Seven minutes.
PARKER ON lNTERCOM:
Take it easy.
[Meow]
Jones?
[Coolant hisses
out of cylinder]
Jones?
LAMBERT: All right.
PARKER: OK, check the bottles.
Jones?
-How you doing?
-Fine.
RlPLEY: Kitty?
PARKER ON lNTERCOM:
OK, go ahead.
RlPLEY: Jones?
Psst, psst, psst.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Come here,Jones. Come here.
Jones?
Come here, boy.
[Kisses]
Come here.
Nice kitty.
Jones?
Come here.
Come here, sweetheart.
Jones.
Jones?
Jonesy.
Aah! Aah!
Jones! God damn it!
Now l got you.
Here, sweetheart.
Nice kitty.
Oh, my God!
PARKER ON lNTERCOM:
Get out of the way!
LAMBERT: l can't!
PARKER: Get out of the way!
lt's going to kill us!
LAMBERT: No, l can't!
PARKER: For Christ's sake,
get out of the way!
RlPLEY: Lambert!
PARKER:
Get out of the way, Lambert!
RlPLEY: Parker?
[Lambert sobbing]
Lambert?
Lambert. Parker.
LAMBERT: Uhh! Aah!
Aah!
Get out of the room!
[Lambert hyperventilates]
LAMBERT: No! No!
RlPLEY: Lambert!
LAMBERT: Aah!
Aah!
Oh, God!
Parker?
Ohh.
RlPLEY: Oh!
[Ripley breathing heavily]
MOTHER: Danger.
The emergency destruct system
is now activated.
The ship will detonate
in T-minus ten minutes.
The option to override
automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus five minutes.
[Siren blaring]
MOTHER: The option to override
automatic detonation...
expires
in T-minus three minutes.
MOTHER: The option to override
automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus one minute.
[Siren blaring]
MOTHER:
Twenty-nine,twenty-eight...
twenty-seven,twenty-six...
twenty-five,twenty-four...
twenty-three,twenty-two...
twenty-one...
twenty seconds.
Nineteen, eighteen...
seventeen, sixteen...
fifteen,fourteen...
thirteen,twelve...
eleven...
ten seconds.
Nine, eight...
seven, six...
five,four...
RlPLEY: Come on!
MOTHER: three,two, one.
The option to override
detonation procedure...
has now expired.
RlPLEY: Mother,
turn the cooling unit back on!
Mother!
MOTHER: The ship
will automatically destruct...
in T-minus five minutes.
RlPLEY: You bitch!
God damn it!
Jones.
MOTHER: You now have
one minute to abandon ship.
The ship
will automatically destruct...
in T-minus one minute.
MOTHER:
T-minus thirty seconds...
twenty-nine,twenty-eight...
twenty-seven,twenty-six...
twenty-five,twenty-four...
twenty-three...
twenty-two,twenty-one...
twenty seconds.
Nineteen, eighteen, seventeen...
sixteen,fifteen...
fourteen,thirteen...
twelve, eleven...
ten seconds.
Nine, eight, seven...
six,five...
four,three...
two, one.
l got you...
you son of a bitch.
[Meow]
Shh, shh, shh.
lt's all right.
[Meow]
Shh,Jonesy.
Silly boy.
All right.
lt's nice to see you,too.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
lt's OK.
[Jones growls]
Aah!
Come on.
[Singing] You
Are
My lucky star
You
Are my lucky star
Lucky, lucky, lucky,
lucky, lucky
OK.
Oh, come on.
[Singing] You are
My lucky star
You
[Alien screeching]
Are my lucky star
You,you're my lucky star
You are my lucky star
Oh, God.
OK.
[Breathing heavily]
Aah!
[Screeches]
Final report of the commercial
starship Nostromo...
third officer reporting.
The other members of the crew--
Kane, Lambert...
Parker, Brett...
Ash...
and Captain Dallas--
are dead.
Cargo and ship destroyed.
l should reach the frontier
in about six weeks.
With a little luck,
the network will pick me up.
This is Ripley...
last survivor of the Nostromo...
signing off.
Come on, cat.