RIPLEY: My mommy always said
there were no monsters.
No real ones.
But there are.
GEDIMAN: She's perfect.
WREN: Mm-hmm.
Careful.
Two centimeters.
OK.
Yeah.
Ready with that amnio.
Ohh.
And...
there it is.
Be careful.
[Screeches]
Jesus.
Clamp it.
GEDIMAN: What about her?
Can we keep her alive?
WREN: How is the host?
Doing well.
Sew her back up.
Excellent work, everybody.
WREN: How is
our Number Eight today?
GEDIMAN:
Appears to be in good health.
WREN: Hmm? How good?
GEDIMAN: Excellent...
as in completely off
our projected charts.
Look at the scar tissue.
See the recession?
WREN: This is from
three days ago?
GEDIMAN: Exactly.
WREN: Oh, this is good.
This is very good.
You're gonna make us all
very proud.
[Choking]
WREN: Don't! I'm all right!
Now try this.
Hand.
Close.
Glove.
SCIENTIST: Number Eight?
Fruit.
SCIENTIST: Good. Cherries.
WREN: lt's unprecedented.
GEDIMAN: Totally.
She's operating
at a completely adult capacity.
What about her memories?
WREN: There are gaps...
and some degree
of synaptic dissonance.
She's freaked.
It has connective
difficulties...
caused by
a biochemical imbalance...
causing emotional autism.
Certain reactions...
Wait a second!
"lt" has memories!
Why does "it" have memories?
Well, I'm guessing, but...
inherited memories
passed down generationally...
at a genetic level by
the aliens, like its strength.
Plus a highly evolved
form of instinct.
GEDIMAN: An unexpected benefit
from the genetic crossing.
Oh, ho ho ho! I see.
Stupid me. Of course!
An unexpected benefit
of the genetic process.
And I didn't even
think of that.
GEDIMAN: You're not thinking
termination?
PEREZ: Oh, boy,
am I thinking termination.
WREN: General, we do not
perceive this to be a problem.
PEREZ: Ellen Ripley died
trying to wipe this species out.
For all intents and purposes,
she succeeded.
I don't want her
taking up her old hobbies.
- That won't happen.
- We won't tell her.
PEREZ: Oh, I see.
And that's supposed
to comfort me.
COMPUTER:
ldentification, please.
[Exhales]
[Beeping]
COMPUTER: Please try again.
[Exhales]
COMPUTER:
Thank you, General Perez.
PEREZ: The bottom line is...
she looks at me funny one time,
I'm putting her down.
OK, as far as I'm concerned...
Number Eight
is a meat by-product.
Her Majesty here
is the real payoff.
When does she start producing?
Days. Less, maybe.
We need the cargo.
PEREZ:
I told you, it's on its way.
[Roars]
[Growls]
Fork.
Fuck.
It's... it's a fork.
How did you...
GEDIMAN: How did we get you?
Yes.
GEDIMAN: Hard work.
We used blood samples
from Fiori 16, on ice...
where you died.
We've remade you.
We cloned you.
Does it grow?
Yeah.
Very rapidly.
It's a queen.
How did you know that?
She'll breed. You'll die.
Everyone in the Company
will die.
GEDIMAN: In the Company?
WREN: Weyland Yutani...
Ripley Eight's former employers.
Terran growth conglomerate.
They had defense contracts
under the military.
I think you willfind
that, uh...
things have changed
a great deal since your time.
I doubt that.
WREN: We're notflying blind
here, you know.
It's United Systems Military,
not some greedy corporation.
Oh.
It won't make any difference.
You're still gonna die.
WREN:
How do youfeel about that?
I wish you could understand
what we're trying to do here.
The potential
for this species...
goes way beyond
urban pacification.
New alloys, new vaccines.
Nothing like this
we've ever seen...
on any world before.
You should be very proud.
Oh...
I am.
And the animal itself... wondrous.
The potential?
Unbelievable,
once we've tamed them.
Roll over, play dead, heel?
Mm-hmm.
You can't teach it tricks.
Why not? We're teaching you.
ELGYN: Time to enjoy...
some of the General's
hospitality, Christie.
CHRISTIE: Great. Army food.
Yeah. It'll do till we get
the family wagon up to spec.
Yeah.
That is,
if the natives are friendly.
How's that?
Good.
We expecting any trouble?
From Perez, I doubt it,
but you never know.
We've been there before.
Where's the others?
The cargo bay.
[Whistling
"I'm Popeye the Sailor Man"]
[lmitating monkey]
What is wrong with you?
JOHNER: Just a little
target practice.
Vriess isn't complaining.
Goddamn it!
Johner, you son of a bitch!
Come on, man.
You didn'tfeel a thing.
[lmitating monkey]
JOHNER: Whoa.
The knife.
Son of a bitch!
JOHNER: Don't push me,
little Call.
You hang with us for a while...
you'llfind out I am not the man
with whom to fuck.
ELGYN: Hey, son, l'll give you
my authorization code.
It's E-A-T M-E.
AUTHORIZING MAN: I'm sorry, sir,
could you repeat that?
ELGYN: Little prick.
You know, no matter
how many times you see it...
the sight of a woman strapped up
in a chair like that just...
What?
Just bring us in
on a 3-0 descent, would you?
And ride the parallel.
- Darlin', it is done.
- Good girl.
Hey, don't cut thrust
till about 600 meters...
and we'll give 'em
a little scare.
COMPUTER: I am Father.
Welcome to the USM Auriga.
Step forwardfor contraband
and weapons search.
Please report
any infectious diseases...
to the medical officers.
Levels seven through twelve
are off-limits to civilians.
Thank youfor your cooperation.
Go.
Put your hands up, please, sir.
What?
Could you get your hands up,
please?
[Beeping]
There are no weapons
allowed on board, sir.
My own recipe.
Way more dangerous.
ELGYN: Nice welcome, Perez.
What the hell is this?
Are you afraid the six of us
are gonna hijack your damn ship?
Just a minor concern...
that one of your asshole
crew members...
will get drunk and put
a bullet through the hull.
We happen to be in space, Elgyn.
No shit. How you been?
[Beeping]
Want to check the chair?
Elgyn, these were
very, very hard to come by.
So was our cargo.
You're not about to plead
poverty on me, are you, General?
No. I'm just saying...
very few people
deal in cash nowadays.
Just the ones don't like
to keep business records.
Yourself, for example.
Drink, Elgyn?
Constantly.
ELGYN: Now, I'm gonna take
a wild guess here, General...
but I'm thinking whatever
you got going on here...
it ain't exactly
approved by Congress.
Who's the new filly
you got on board, Elgyn?
Call?
Little girl playing pirates.
She makes an impression.
She is severely fuckable,
ain't she?
Ha ha ha!
Mind you...
I think she's just
a tad curious...
about this little
transaction of ours.
I mean,
I can't say as I blame her.
It's awfully
cloak-and-dagger stuff.
It's a military operation.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
ELGYN: Correct me if I'm wrong,
but, uh...
I was under the impression
that most army medical labs...
don't have to operate
outside of regulated space.
What do you want, Elgyn?
- Me?
- Yeah.
Two days bed and board.
Vriess might wanna
snag a part here or there.
Whatever. If it's not imposing.
Mi casa es su casa.
FATHER: Please direct cargo
to med lab center, area "G."
Follow the lit path.
Do not deviate.
FATHER: Cargo status... stable.
Life forms intact.
Stasis uninterrupted.
FATHER: Med lab center
is off-limits to civilians.
Thank you.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
JOHNER: Oh.
Oh.
Hey.
HILLARD: Oh, please.
JOHNER: You know I can't lay off
the tall ones.
How you doin'?
How about a little one-on-one?
What do you say?
You got some moves on you, girl.
CHRISTIE: Oh, man.
JOHNER: Mm-hmm.
Well, if you don't
wanna play basketball...
I know some other indoor sports.
[Sniffs]
Come on, now,
give me the ball.
OK. I got a new game. Tag.
Ripley?
Ripley. [Whistles]
WREN: You've had enough fun.
What the hell are you?
Something of a predator,
isn't she?
Yeah. She continues
to make us all very proud.
Ahh!
Mmm!
[Spits]
TV: We're coming up on just one
minute and 30 seconds left...
to order this unique
collector's item.
Jesus Christ, Johner!
What do you put in this shit,
battery acid?
JOHNER: Justfor color.
[Screeches]
[Growls]
So... we're a fast learner.
TV: Here's an item...
JOHNER: This is a really
good show, man.
TV: lt's from the Gut Cutter's
Celebration Collection...
makers of premiere knives
and edgeware.
The knife features
a stainless steel blade...
perfectfor any use
from hunting to the home.
The pro handle is made from
authentic antique plywood...
and stained in...
Hey, man, that shit
is not easy to come by!
Why don't you
take a walk outside?
[Drink spills]
Great!
CALL: I'm so sorry.
CHRISTIE: lf bitches
can't handle this shit...
bitches should stay away
from this shit!
FATHER: ldentification, please.
Please try again.
Thank you, General Perez.
RIPLEY: Well?
You gonna kill me or what?
There's no point, is there?
They've taken it out of you.
Where is it?
Is it on the ship?
You mean my "baby"?
I don't get it.
If they took it out,
why are they keeping you alive?
Well, they're curious.
I'm the latest thing.
Look, I can make it all stop...
the pain, this nightmare.
That's all I can offer you.
What makes you think
I would let you do that?
Who are you?
Ripley, Ellen...
Lieutenant First Class...
number36706.
Ellen Ripley died 200 years ago.
You're not her.
I'm not her.
Who am I?
CALL:
You're a thing... a construct.
They grew you in a fucking lab.
And now they brought it
out of you.
Not all the way out.
I can feel it...
behind my eyes.
I can hear it moving.
You gotta help me stop
this thing before it gets loose.
RIPLEY: lt's too late.
You can't stop it.
It's inevitable.
Not as long as I'm around.
You'll never
get out of here alive.
I don't care.
RIPLEY: Really?
I can make it stop.
Go on. Get out of here.
They're lookingfor you.
I think you're gonna find
that this was very ill-advised.
Where are herfriends?
SOLDIER: In the mess hall, sir.
Well, youfind them
now... quietly.
What the hell is going on here?
CHRISTIE: Smells
like a double-cross, boss.
Where's the other one
with the chair?
Don't ever touch me.
Ever!
You want to tell us
what this is?
Want to tell me
who you're workingfor?
What?
Wren, they got nothing
to do with this.
To do with what?
WREN: Know what the penalties
for terrorist activity are?
ELGYN: No goddamn terrorists
on my crew.
Call, there something
you wanna tell me?
WREN: I don't care if you knew.
You brought a terrorist
on board a military vessel.
And as far as I am concerned,
you all die with her!
Do you understand?
Yeah.
I understand.
Christie.
Freeze!
SOLDIER: Stop!
Drop your weapons!
And you, drop that piece of shit
or I blow his head off!
- Can't do that, man.
- Drop it now!
- They're attached to me.
- I'm notfucking with you!
You're under arrestfor
a Code 8... concealed weapons...
and a Code 12,which is murder!
- Release Dr. Wren!
- Kiss my ass.
SOLDIER: Put down your weapons!
ELGYN: Everybody OK?
ELGYN: Real easy, soldier boy.
GEDIMAN: Security!
There is a serious problem
in the mess hall.
You lie to me now,
little girl...
I will cut your throat
and leave you here to die...
you understand me?
Hello?
Goddamn it. Hello?
SECURITY GUARD:
We do not copy you.
- Hello?
- Please repeat.
Gediman!
He is conducting
illegal experiments.
He's breeding some sort of...
Listen to me!
He is breeding an alien species
more than dangerous.
If those things get loose...
it'll make the Lacerta Plague
look like a square dance.
Shut up!
Listen.
[Siren]
FATHER: Your attention, please.
Security breach.
Med lab, level 15.
Aah!
[Roars]
[Thud]
[Man screams]
[Gunfire]
Let's get back to the Betty.
Doctor and soldier boy here
can see us to the door.
CALL: What about Vriess?
ELGYN: Fuck Vriess.
FATHER: Your attention, please.
Unauthorized opening
of cage three.
Unauthorized opening of...
cages five, seven, eight, ten...
Move it! Now!
Go! Go now!
FATHER: Evacuation.
[Alien roaring]
FATHER: This is not a drill.
FATHER: Evacuation.
Go! Get on board!
FATHER: Your attention, please.
Nonhuman presence detected,
levels 21, 23, 27, 14.
Level 38.
Level 39.
FATHER: Evacuation.
Proceed to lifeboats.
This is not a drill.
Thank youfor your cooperation.
[Alien shrieking]
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
l'll give you holes,
you slimy bastard!
Aah!
PEREZ: Move it! Go!
FATHER:
Final lifeboat ready for launch.
PEREZ: Get on board!
Go!
FATHER: Complete evacuation now.
[Screaming]
No!
PEREZ: Grenade.
[Alien growling]
FATHER: Alert. Alert.
Evacuation incomplete.
Civilian presence detected
in Area "H."
Warning. Main vessel
declared uninhabitable.
CHRISTIE: Elgyn, come on,
let's move, man.
ELGYN: Yeah.
[Hiss]
HILLARD: Elgyn?
Elgyn, where are you?
[Clank]
HILLARD: Elgyn!
Oh, God. Elgyn!
CHRISTIE: Elgyn!
HILLARD: Elgyn!
JOHNER: Easy, Hillard!
- Christie, give me a hand here!
- Get him up!
Come on, get him up!
CHRISTIE: Move out of the way!
HILLARD: No!
JOHNER: Aw, shit.
What the fuck did this?
CHRISTIE: What's in this place?
[Alien roars]
- Call, get down!
- What the fuck is that?
DISTEPHANO: Don't shoot!
lt's in front of the hull!
What is that?
Come on, man. Time to go!
- Time to go!
- Get back!
DISTEPHANO: Damn!
CHRISTIE: Call, time to go!
Come on, Call!
JOHNER: Get the goddamn door.
DISTEPHANO: We can't open it.
No, we can't open it!
JOHNER: What the hell's wrong
with you?
[Rattle]
- We gotta go back!
- You're goddamn right!
JOHNER: I'm not goin' back!
You go back!
What the fuck?
Was it everything
you hopedfor?
HILLARD: Leave him alone.
JOHNER: What do we do now, man?
CHRISTIE:
Same thing we're doing.
We get the hell out of here.
JOHNER: What if there's more?
I say we stay here, man.
Let the army guys deal.
Where the fuck
are the army guys?
CALL: They're dead!
Then we don't need
this asshole anymore.
- Step back!
- No, you step back!
Stop it!
You got no authority here!
Doctor, that thing
that killed my partner...
that's your pet science project?
Yes.
- Let me do him right now.
- I should let him.
How many more are there?
Twelve.
JOHNER: Twelve?
There'll be more.
So...
who do I have to fuck
to get off this boat?
JOHNER: I can get you off.
Maybe not the boat, but...
CHRISTIE: Let's get out of here.
CALL: Wait a second. She was
the hostfor these monsters.
Wren cloned her
because she had one inside her.
She's not human.
She was part of his experiment,
and she will turn on us.
- I don't give a shit.
- She's too much of a risk.
We have to leave her.
She comes.
We can't trust her.
I don't trust anyone.
CHRISTIE: lf we're gonna
survive, we all stick together.
Agreed?
Hillard, we gotta go.
It's not over.
We gotta get to the Betty.
Make a nice souvenir.
CALL:
I can't believe you did that.
RIPLEY: Did what?
CALL: You killed one of 'em.
It's like killing your own kind.
RIPLEY: lt was in my way.
[Electronic beep]
Oh, man!
Who were you expecting,
Santa Claus?
[Sighs]
Thought you were toast
for certain, man.
VRIESS: Where's Elgyn?
Oh, shit.
What if we get to the Betty
and they're all over it?
WREN: All the activity's been
by the barracks.
- Why would they move?
- They won't.
If they send anyone out,
it'll be here...
where the meat is.
If we wanna make decent time,
I say we ditch the cripple.
- No offense, man.
- None taken.
Nobody is left behind.
Not even you, Johner.
What's the quickest way out?
After the cooling tower,
there's a freight elevator.
It runs from the top...
down to engineering
level one deck.
Take us straight to the dock.
Sounds reasonable.
Let's do it.
We're moving.
What?
RIPLEY: The ship is moving.
I can feel it.
The ship has stealthrun.
There's no way you can tell.
She's right.
Ship's been go since the attack.
WREN: That's a standard
emergency procedure.
DISTEPHANO: That's right.
Any serious problem...
and the ship autopilots
back to home base.
You were planning on
telling us this?
Nobody asked.
HILLARD: What's home base?
Earth.
CHRISTIE: Oh, great.
Bastard.
JOHNER: Earth? I'd rather
stay here with the things, man.
How long until we get to Earth?
Three hours almost.
We got to blow the ship.
Call, you're not
blowing this ship.
Not while we're on it, OK?
We get out of this ship,
you do as you please, all right?
Earth, man. What a shithole.
RIPLEY: lt's clear.
Hey, Ripley.
I heard you, like,
ran into these things before.
That's right.
Wow, man.
So, like, what did you do?
I died.
DISTEPHANO: Not that way!
CHRISTIE: Ripley.
Ripley, come on.
Ripley, we got no time
for sightseeing here.
WREN: Ripley, don't.
[Gasps]
Kill...
me.
Kill... me.
CALL: Don't do it, Ripley.
RIPLEY: Don't do what?
What's the big deal, man?
Fucking waste of ammo.
Let's go.
Must be a chick thing.
Am I dreaming...
or is this not the shit
we brought with us?
CHRISTIE: Yeah.
It's the same shit.
It stinks in here, man.
Let's keep moving.
Aah!
Get away from me!
CHRISTIE: Drop the rod, man.
- Get away from me!
- Do it!
Get away from me.
Who are you people?
What's happening here?
CHRISTIE: Calm down.
What's happening here...
is we're getting the fuck
off this ghost ship, OK?
Ship? What ship?
Where am I?
I was in cryo, right?
On my way to Xarem.
Work crew
for the nickel refinery, right?
I wake up.
I... I know I don't understand.
I woke up.
I... I saw horrible things.
Look, you're coming with us.
It's too dangerous for you here.
[Sniffs]
Leave him.
CALL: Fuck you.
We're not leaving him here.
He's got one inside of him.
I can smell it.
PURVIS: Inside me?
Inside me?
What's inside me?
I don't want one of those things
birthing anywhere near my ass.
It's a bad risk.
What's inside me?
We can't just leave him here.
CHRISTIE: I thought
you wanted to stop them.
- What's inside me?
- Can't you stop it?
CHRISTIE: Got no time for that.
WREN: Not here.
The lab is damaged.
CHRISTIE: I could do him.
Back of the head.
Painless.
It might be the best way.
What's inside me?
- Got to be another way.
- What if we freeze him?
What's in-fucking-side me?!
There's a monster
in your chest.
These guys hijacked your ship...
and they sold your cryotube
to this human...
and he put an alien
inside of you.
It's a really nasty one.
And in a few hours...
it's gonna burst its way
through your rib cage...
and you're gonna die.
Any questions?
Who are you?
I'm the monster's mother.
CALL: Look, he comes with us.
We freeze him on the Betty.
The doctor can remove it later.
JOHNER: lt's a mess down there.
Is this the only way?
CHRISTIE:
Vriess, we gotta lose the chair.
I know.
Kawlang maneuver, all right?
Yeah. Just like old times.
Yeah.
VRIESS:
Must be the cooling tanks.
Somebody must've opened
the valves.
CHRISTIE: The nasties couldn't
have done this, could they?
WREN: We're at the bottom
of the ship.
We have to go
through the kitchen...
maybe 90 feet...
to the freight elevator
on the other side.
I don't like it.
What's to like?
JOHNER: This sucks!
HILLARD: Wren, are you sure
about the distance?
Yes.
CHRISTIE:
You ready to get wet, partner?
VRIESS: Yeah.
[Coughs]
VRIESS: Christie, do me a favor.
When we hit the surface
on the other side...
no backstroke, OK?
[Gasps]
Jesus Christ!
JOHNER:
They set a goddamn trap!
It's a goddamn ambush!
[Roars]
Distephano!
[Snarls]
It won't break.
Give me your weapon.
You really are way too trusting.
No!
[Echoing]
VRIESS:
You killed her! You bastard!
VRIESS: l'll get you!
[Gun jams]
WREN: Father, lock the door!
Christie! Climb! Climb!
I'm doin' it, man!
Come on! Come on!
It's jammed! Move it!
It's jammed!
CHRISTIE: Die! Die!
Aah!
Get off my foot, bitch!
CHRISTIE: Get off me!
Aah! Johner!
Get off me! Get off me!
Johner!
Die, motherfucker!
Do it, man!
[Shrieks]
Ohh!
Real nice party, ain't it?
[Groaning]
Ohh!
VRIESS: Christie!
Christie!
No!
What are you doing?!
Don't do it!
Don't!
We can make it!
- No!
- Aah!
[Sobbing]
Damn!
[Warning buzzer]
This way.
Come on!
Baby, am I glad to see you.
I was sure that asshole got ya.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
You got body armor on?
Yeah. Come on.
You took it in the chest.
I saw it.
You're a robot?
JOHNER: Son of a bitch!
Our little Call's
justfull of surprises.
RIPLEY: I should have known.
No human being is that humane.
JOHNER: I thought synthetics
were supposed to be all logical.
You're a big old psycho, girl.
PURVIS: You're a robot?
You're a Second Gen, aren't you?
You're an Auton.
A robot...
designed by robots, right?
JOHNER: Hah!
That's right. I remember.
They were supposed to revitalize
the synthetic industry.
Instead, they buried it.
[Laughs]
They don't like
being told what to do.
The government ordered a recall.
Now, I heard that only a few
had gotten out intact.
Man! I never thought
that I'd see one!
Great. She's a toaster oven.
Can we leave now?
DISTEPHANO: Ha ha!
RIPLEY: How long before we land?
DISTEPHANO:
Just under two hours.
Hey, Vriess,
you got a socket wrench?
Maybe she just needs
an oil change.
FATHER:
I'm sorry. Access denied.
I can't believe
I almostfucked it.
Yeah, like you never
fucked a robot!
RIPLEY:
lf Wren gets in the computer...
he could really screw us.
JOHNER:
We gotta find a terminal.
DISTEPHANO: There's
no console on this level.
- We'd have to go back.
- We can't go back.
And I don't know any
of Wren's access codes.
Help me.
Call?
No... I can't.
Right.
You're the new model droid.
You can access
the mainframe by remote.
CALL: No, I can't.
I burned my modem. We all did.
VRIESS: Call, you can still
patch in manually.
You know that.
DISTEPHANO: There's ports
in the chapel up there.
Call...
RIPLEY:
You're programmedfor that?
CALL: Don't make me do this.
Don't make me make you.
[Sighs]
I don't want to go in there.
It's like my insides are liquid.
It's not real.
Get over it.
You can blow the ship
before it reaches Earth...
and kill them all.
Just give us time
to get outfirst.
Oh, damn it.
Anything?
Hold on.
[Robotic voice] Breach
in sector seven, sector three.
Sector nine unstable.
Engines operating at 41 percent.
Eighty-six minutes
until Earth-dock.
[Gasps]
[Normal voice]
We burned too much energy.
I can't make critical mass.
I can't blow it.
Then crash it.
I'm OK.
Really.
lfeel good.
CALL: [Robotic voice]
Ground level recalibrated.
Time until impact now
43 minutes,8 seconds.
Try to clear us a path
to the Betty.
And start her up.
OK.
[Robotic voice]
Please wait.
Emergency override in
console four-five-V, level one.
[Normal voice] lt's Wren.
He's almost at the Betty.
Father, locate the power drain.
Report.
Father?
Father!
CALL: [Robotic voice]
Father's dead, asshole.
Intruder on level one.
All aliens, please proceed
to level one.
You got a mean streak.
Aah! Damn it.
- Let me see.
- Don't touch me.
Come on.
You must think
this is pretty funny.
I'm finding a lot of things
funny lately.
But I don't think they are.
Why do you go on living?
How can you stand
being what you are?
Not much choice.
At least there's part of you
that's human.
I'm just... Look at me.
I'm disgusting.
Why did you come here?
To kill you, remember?
Before the recall...
I accessed the mainframe.
Every dirty little covert op...
the government ever dreamed of
is in there.
And this, you, the aliens...
even the crew from the Betty.
I knew if they succeeded,
it'd be the end of them.
Why do you care
what happens to them?
Because I'm programmed to.
You're programmed
to be an asshole?
You're the new asshole model
they're putting out?
- Come on.
- [Footsteps]
I guess we're almost there.
DISTEPHANO:
lt's not so far now!
PURVIS: God, I am so tired!
JOHNER: Sleep when you die, man!
PURVIS:
Oh, no. This is bad, right?
I think we're near the nest.
Well, then we'll go another way.
- We don't have time.
- We got nearly 90 minutes.
- Not anymore.
- What are you saying?
JOHNER: What did you do, robot?
Let's go. Come on.
Hey! You want to die here with
your brothers and sisters...
that's cool,
but I plan to live past today!
So if this little
hunk of plastic...
is pullin' any shit,
I'm gonna kill her!
Kill you! Does that compute?
Or do I have to draw you
a schematic?
Hey!
[Gagging]
You want another souvenir?
How far are the docks?
A hundred yards.
CALL: Ripley?
Ripley!
Come on!
Ripley, we have to go!
I hear them.
I hear them. They're so close.
Ripley.
RIPLEY: lt's the queen.
She's in pain.
Ripley!
Wait!
Oh, my God.
PURVIS: We got to be moving.
The best thing you can do
is pray for a quick death.
Come on.
CALL: lt's not right.
PURVIS:
I've been saying that all day.
VRIESS: lt's up to you, Call.
Patch into the ship again
and open the hatch.
CALL: Johner, we should
put Purvis in the freezer.
JOHNER: All right, little buddy.
Nap time.
Aah!
Nobody moves, or I put a cap
where this droid's brain is.
Distephano, take the weapons.
Begging your pardon,
sir, butfuck you!
Oh, fine, then I kill her,
and you kill me...
and we all die,
and nobody goes home!
Now drop the weapon!
Then this little
synthetic bitch...
is gonna plug
into the Auriga...
and she is gonna take us
right back to home base...
according to the standard
emergency procedures.
No, she's not!
DISTEPHANO: Are you crazy?
Bring those things to Earth?
Haven't you been paying
attention today?
Ah, the intellectual speaks.
- Stay!
- Listen! Lf you don't...
Don't you ever shut up?
[Loud gasps]
Eeeeyyyarrggh!
Aaaarrrgh!
Why does nobody listen to me?
Aaaahhh!
[Screeches]
[Screeching]
Aah!
GEDIMAN: I told you.
Atfirst, everything was normal.
The queen laid her eggs,
but then she started to change.
She added a second cycle, so...
so...
this time, there is no host.
There are no eggs.
There is only her womb...
and the creature inside.
That is Ripley's gift to her...
a human reproductive system.
She is giving birth for you,
Ripley!
And now she is perfect!
[Growls]
[Roars]
[Roaring]
Ohh...
[Growling]
[Roaring]
GEDIMAN: You are...
a beautiful...
beautiful butterfly.
[Roaring]
[Growls]
[Cooing]
No!
No... no.
[Roaring]
[Mewing]
[Growling]
[Roars]
[Snaps]
GEDIMAN: Ah, look.
Look. Beautiful, beautiful
little baby.
Look.
It thinks you're its mother.
Come on.
Yeah... yeah...
[Growling]
[Roaring]
[Groans]
[Roars]
FATHER: Civilian vessel on-line.
Emergency departure authorized.
All right, she's hot.
l'll open the Auriga's airlocks.
Pull the clamps on your mark.
Right. I just need to find
the... the vertical thrust lock.
Are you sure
you guys can fly this thing?
Yes!
[Thud]
FATHER: Launch status is go.
No!
Ripley!
Hi-yaaahhh!
Hey.
DISTEPHANO:
I thought you were dead.
Yeah. I get that a lot.
Why are we still here?
I'm justfinding
the, uh, manual override.
- For Christ's sake.
- Hey, Ripley.
Good memory. Excuse me.
JOHNER: Ripley's back, man.
- Is that it?
- Nope.
JOHNER: You can'tfly one
of these things, too, can you?
Are you kidding?
This piece of shit
is even older than I am.
VRIESS: Goddamn it!
We still got breach. The hatch.
I closed it.
lfixed the goddamn hatch
a hundred times, man!
CALL: l'll get it.
FATHER:
Approaching Earth's atmosphere.
Window of departure
now 46 seconds.
Call? We have to go.
RIPLEY: Call.
RIPLEY:
We've gotta get out of here.
[Roaring]
FATHER: Window of departure
now 20 seconds.
Grab on to something, Call.
We're outta here.
Come on, baby.
Aah!
This thing is gonna fall apart.
Pressure's unstable!
Go help Call turn on
the auxiliary pump!
[Roaring]
Ooh...
[Gasps]
[Mewing]
[Roars]
Distephano?
[Alien growling]
VRIESS: Come on! Step on it!
Hey!
I'm not the mechanic here,
lronsides!
I mostly just hurt people.
Shit!
Call!
Call, get back up here!
VRIESS: Call! Call!
Ripley!
Hey, Ripley!
Johner, where are you,
you son of a bitch?
Get on it, bastard!
What am I supposed to do?
Grab the sticks!
[Roars]
CALL: Ooh!
Put her down.
[Roars]
Ripley!
[Screaming]
I'm sorry.
FATHER: USM Auriga
will impact in five seconds.
Four...
three...
two...
one.
Thank you.
[Johner screaming]
- What's burnin'?
- Us!
Shit! You're right!
- Ohh!
- Whew!
Well, you did it.
You saved the Earth.
You sound disappointed.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
I didn't expect it to be.
What happens now?
I don't know.
I'm a stranger here myself.
Ripping & Subtitles
4EverPsycho
lovespiral@mail.ru