## [ "Lascia ch'io pianga" from Rinaldo:
Woman Singing In Italian ]
## [ Continues ]
## [ Ends ]
[ Casket Cart Wheels Rolling ]
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
- [ Staff Chattering ]
- [ Monitors Beeping ]
[ Silence ]
[ She ]
Hi.
Hey.
How are you?
Didn't we just talk about that?
That was yesterday.
Today is Tuesday.
So I've been here long?
A month.
Wayne says that...
[ Soft Groan ]
my grief pattern is atypical.
Yeah.
[ Pills Shaking ln Bottle ]
Had a talk with Wayne.
I think he gives you too much medication.
Way too much.
Stop it, please.
Trust others to be smarter than you.
- He's straight out of medical school.
- Just for once.
He doesn't know what he's doing.
I've treated 10 times as many patients as he has.
But you're not a doctor.
No, I'm not.
And I'm proud that I'm not
when I meet a doctor like him.
There is nothing atypical
about your grief.
It was my fault.
What about me?
l was there too.
I could have stopped him.
No.
You didn't know that he had
started waking up lately.
I was aware that he would
sometimes wake up...
and crawl out of bed...
and walk about...
just as you thought
that he was soundly asleep.
He could open the baby gate.
He -
He woke up...
and was - was confused and -
[ Sobbing ]
and - and alone.
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
Dr. Wayne says
you want me back home.
You couldn't leave it, could you?
Had to meddle.
This place leads nowhere.
On the contrary...
grief -
It's not a disease.
It's a natural, healthy reaction.
You can't just remove it.
You mustn't.
Wayne knows you're a therapist.
He says you shouldn't
treat your own family.
In principle I agree, but -
But you're just so much smarter,
aren't you?
I love you.
Nothing hurts more
than to see the one that you love...
subjected to mistakes and wrongs.
No therapist can know
as much about you as I do.
[ Sobbing ]
It's all right.
[ Sobbing Continues ]
It hurts.
- It hurts.
- I know.
There's no way around it.
I want to die too.
No, I'm not gonna let you do that.
Will it just go on and on?
No.
No, it'll change.
Will it get any worse?
Yes, it will.
You've always been distant
from me and Nic.
Now that I come to think of it,
very, very distant.
Okay.
Can you give me
some exampIes of this?
Hell, that's not that difficult
to understand.
Like last summer, for instance.
You were terribly distant
last summer.
As a father and as a husband.
And that was Nic's last summer
you missed out on.
Too bad.
I never interested you...
until now...
that I am your patient.
Perhaps I'm not supposed
to talk about these things.
There's nothing you can't talk about.
You're indifferent to whether
your child is alive or dead.
I bet you have a lot of clever
therapist replies to that, haven't you?
Well, actually...
it was to honor your wish.
You wanted peace to write.
Perhaps I didn't mean it.
What I understood...
is that you wanted to write alone...
that you and Nic were going to go to Eden,
just the two of you.
That way
you couId finish your thesis.
But I didn't.
You didn't?
You see?
You didn't even know that.
Why did you give up?
That's not like you.
The whole project
just seemed less important up there.
As you said when I talked to you
about my subject, glib.
I never called your subject glib.
Perhaps you didn't use that word,
but that's what you meant.
And all of a sudden it was glib.
Or even worse,
some - some kind of lie.
I see.
No, you don't see.
You see a lot of things,
but not that.
[ Panting, Gasping ]
lnhale on the count of five.
[ Gasping, Panting Continue ]
Calmly. Calmly. Just -
Follow me.
Do it with me.
Inhale.
Inhale on the count of five.
Inhale. Two.
- [ Gasping, Panting Continue ]
- Stay with me. Stay with me.
I'm gonna teach you how to breathe.
- Inhale.
- [ Inhaling, Exhaling ]
Two, three, four, five.
Hold.
- Exhale. Two, three, four - Good.
- [ Exhales ]
Imagine -
Imagine you're blowing
on your thistle blooms.
CaImly, quietIy.
- [ Blowing ]
- Yes, yes, that's good.
That's good.
That's very good.
I told you there would be a change.
You're still mourning,
but you're in a new phase.
- What phase?
- Anxiety.
- Anxiety?
- Yes.
This is physical.
- It's dangerous.
- No, it's not dangerous.
Just as your grief wasn't dangerous.
The main part of anxiety is physical.
Dizzy speIIs, dry mouth...
distorted hearing, trembling...
heavy breathing, fast pulse, nausea.
Hey.
Hey. Hey.
[ Grunts ]
Easy.
Never screw your therapist.
No matter how much
your therapist may like it.
I know it distracts you,
but it's - it's not good for us.
- Do the breathing.
- [ Inhaling, Exhaling Rapidly ]
- Hold.
- [ Breathing Stops ]
- Exhale.
- [ Exhales ]
Do you love me?
Yes, I do.
Then help me.
[ He ]
That's what I'm doing.
Exposure.
That's the only thing
that really works.
Everything else is just talk.
You have to have the courage
to stay in the situation that frightens you...
and then you'll learn
that the fear isn't dangerous.
Let's make a list of things
you're afraid of.
At the top,
we put the situation you fear the most.
But I don't know what I'm afraid of.
Just... take your time.
I'm thinking.
Okay.
I'm thinking, uh, but, uh -
Can't I just be afraid
without a definite object?
[ Door Opens ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Gasping, Panting ]
[ Thud ]
- [ Thud ]
- [ Groans ]
[ Groaning Continues ]
- [ Gasping Continues ]
- [ Thudding Continues ]
Hey. No. No! No!
- Calmly.
- [ Panicked Gasping ]
Oh, God.
[ Gasping Continues ]
[ Gasping Continues, Louder ]
- [ Moaning, Grunting ]
- No.
This won't do.
Stup - Stupidest thing
I could do to you.
If you can't tell me
what you're afraid of...
maybe it would be easier
for you to tell me...
where you're afraid.
Where would you feel most exposed?
What would be the worst place?
The apartment?
The street?
A store?
The park?
Visiting someone maybe?
The woods.
The woods?
The woods, yes.
It's funny, because...
you were the one that always
wanted to go into the woods.
What scares you about the woods?
What frightens you there?
Everything.
Tell me what you think
is supposed to happen in the woods.
I -
Is it any woods in particular?
- Eden.
- Eden?
Well, what do you say we put...
- [ Ballpoint Pen Clicking ]
- the garden around Eden...
at the top of the pyramid?
No.
Not quite at the top.
[ Chuckles ]
No.
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Laughing ] Don't you -
[ He ]
Stop it! Stop -
- Okay. [ Groans ]
- [ She Laughing ]
[ Blowing Raspberry ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
Ow! Ow.
[ Winces ]
It's -
- It's o - It's okay.
- I'm sorry.
It's all right.
- I don't know -
- Huh.
We can start by
working on your expectations.
Close your eyes.
Feel the seat underneath you.
Feel yourseIf sinking down into it...
enfolding you.
It's a nice feeling.
What you feel is a pleasant warmth...
and heaviness.
Your breath is deep...
regular...
easy.
Now...
imagine you're at Eden.
Imagine you arrive at Eden
through the woods.
Tell me what you see.
[ She ]
I'm at the bridge.
It's evening.
Almost no birds can be heard.
The water is running without a sound.
Darkness comes early down here.
I walk into it.
The littIe deers...
are hiding among the ferns...
as usual.
[ He ]
Is it difficult to waIk there?
[ She ]
No.
Not really.
In fact, it's almost okay.
In among the trees...
on the slope...
is the oId fox hole.
[ He ]
How do you feel there?
[ She ]
I can't really tell.
It should be easy passing...
and yet...
it's like walking through mud.
The trunk is thick.
The tree rots so slowly.
It has some strange
kind of personality.
I've aIways felt that.
[ He ]
Now -
Where are you? Are you -
Are you heading for the cabin?
[ She ]
Yes, I am.
I'm walking up the path...
through the tall grass.
[ He ]
No, don't go in.
Don't go in.
It's the outside you're afraid of.
Now look around.
No.
Lie down on the green.
[ She ]
You want me to lie down?
[ He ]
Lie down on the grass.
- [ She ] On top of all the plants?
- Y-Yes, lie down on the plants.
Are you lying down?
[ She ]
Yes.
[ He ]
Good.
What is everything like around you?
[ She ]
Green.
It's all very green.
[ He ]
Good.
Now will you do what I ask you?
[ She ]
Yes.
What do you want me to do?
I want you...
to melt into the green.
Don't fight it.
Just turn green.
No matter what happens,
you were there, you did it.
Let fear come if it likes.
Remember...
what the mind can conceive and believe,
it can achieve.
What's wrong?
The ground is burning.
The ground is not burning.
Gotta go.
I want to lie down.
Just for a minute.
Sure.
Yeah, we'll take a rest.
[ Wind Gusting ]
[ Wind Settles ]
Shouldn't we go on?
Yeah.
Yeah, we should.
Stay.
Stay with it.
I know it hurts. Stay.
Stay in it!
[ Thumping, Clacking ]
[ Objects Landing On Roof ]
[ Objects Continue Landing ]
It's just the stupid acorns.
[ Gasping ]
[ Sighs ]
What are you doing?
I'm just -
I'm setting up...
a little exercise.
It's -
It's like a -
It's like a game.
You cheated me yesterday.
Running's no good.
You have to reaIIy feel the grass.
I want you to go from this stone...
to this stone.
Pretty scary, huh?
[ Chuckles ]
You ready?
Here.
I'll give you a ride.
I'll put you on the first stone.
Stay with it.
Here we go.
Now put your foot down.
I got you. I got you.
I'm right here.
- I can't do this.
- Yes, you can.
You can and you will,
just like I will.
We're gonna walk together.
We're gonna walk together, okay?
Now - All right, now breathe.
- [ Inhaling, Exhaling ]
- Here. You're gonna step off the rock.
You're gonna step on that grass.
Step down.
See? What happened?
Nothing.
- [ Gasping, Panting ]
- Keep breathing. Bre - Keep breathing.
I've got you.
You're really doing great.
Okay?
Keep breathing.
Five, five and five.
[ Inhaling, Exhaling ]
We're almost there.
- We're almost there. You're doing great.
- [ Gasping, Panting Continue ]
[ He ]
You're doing fine.
We're there. See? We're there.
There you go.
[ Laughing ]
You did it.
You Iearned something.
Didn't you?
[ Sobbing ]
You did beautifully.
[ Hawk Cries ]
[ Sobbing ]
I miss him so much.
[ Liquid Pouring ]
I've been afraid up here before.
Yes, it seems likely.
I just didn't know it was fear.
I became afraid...
and I stopped writing.
What was different the last time?
I heard a sound.
[ Nic Crying ]
[ Crying Continues ]
- Nic?
- [ Crying Continues ]
Nic!
[ Crying Continues ]
- [ Crying Continues ]
- Nic!
[ Crying Continues ]
[ Crying Continues, Louder ]
[ Crying Fades, Becomes Distant ]
[ Crying Ceases ]
[ He ]
You didn't hear Nic screaming.
Apparently not.
And because you experienced something
that you couldn't explain rationally...
you placed Eden very high
on the pyramid chart.
Eden was the catalyst
that triggered your fear.
You jumped to conclusions...
and tied the emotionaI event
with the place.
When you feel threatened,
it's natural to react.
If the danger were real,
your fear wouId save your life...
because your adrenaline
wouId be used for fight or flight.
But what you're experiencing is panic,
nothing more.
The scream wasn't real.
[ Grunting ]
Stop!
- Cal - Calm -
- [ Both Grunting ]
You shouldn't have come here.
You're just so damn arrogant.
But this may not last.
Ever thought of that?
[ Acorns Landing On Roof ]
Oak trees grow to be
hundreds of years old.
They only have to produce
one single tree every hundred years...
in order to propagate.
It may sound banal to you, but...
it was a big thing for me to realize that
when I was up here with Nic.
The acorns fell on the roof then too.
They kept falling and falling...
and dying and dying.
And I understood that...
everything that used to be
beautiful about Eden...
was perhaps hideous.
Now I could hear...
what I couldn't hear before -
[ Acorns Continue Landing On Roof ]
the cry of all the things...
that are to die.
That's all...
very touching...
if it was a children's book.
Acorns don't cry.
You know that as well as I do.
That's what fear is.
Your thoughts distort reality...
not the other way around.
Satan's church.
Satan? Jesus!
Nature is Satan's church.
- What?
- [ Wind Whistling ]
Why, there you have him.
That was his breath.
[ Acorns Continue Hitting Roof ]
[ She ]
Nic.
He drifted away from me
the last time.
He was always out and about.
He might have made
more of an effort to be there for me.
[ Birds Chirping ]
You look like you slept well.
Thanks. I did.
I just wanted to say
how happy I am that you're here.
I love you, darling.
Did you have a good sleep?
I've just been having
a lot of crazy dreams.
Dreams are of no interest
to modern psychology.
Freud is dead, isn't he?
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah.
- What are you doing?
- Look.
I'm well again.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm cured.
You're so clever.
I'm fine.
You can't just be happy for me,
can you?
[ Wind Gusting ]
[ Deep Voice ]
Chaos... reigns!
[ Hinges Squeak ]
[ Rain Continues ]
[ Clattering In Distance ]
Um, I'd like to do one more exercise.
It's like role-playing.
My role is...
all the thoughts
that provoke your fear.
Yours is rational thinking.
I'm nature.
All the things that you call nature.
Okay, Mr. Nature.
What do - What do you want?
To hurt you as much as I can.
How?
How do you think?
By frightening me?
By killing you.
Nature can't harm me.
You're just all the greenery outside.
No. I'm more than that.
I don't understand.
I'm outside, but also...
within.
I'm nature of all human beings.
Oh, that kind of nature.
[ Sniffles ]
The kind of nature that causes people...
to do evil things against women?
That's exactIy who I am.
That kind of nature interested me a lot...
when I was up here.
That kind of nature
was the subject of my thesis.
But you shouldn't underestimate Eden.
What did Eden do?
I discovered something else
in my material than I expected.
If human nature is evil...
then that goes as well for the nature of -
[ He ]
Of the women.
FemaIe nature.
[ She ]
The nature of all the sisters -
Women do not controI their own bodies.
Nature does.
I have it in writing in my books.
The literature
that you used in your research...
was about evil things
committed against women.
But you read it
as proof of the evil of women?
You were supposed to be
critical of those texts.
That was your thesis.
Instead you're embracing it.
Do you - Do you know what you're saying?
Forget it.
I don't know why I said it.
I-I can't work anymore now.
[ Sobbing ]
Hit me.
- What?
- Hit me so it hurts.
No.
- Hit me, please!
- No!
[ Sobbing ]
I can't stand this!
[ He ]
I don't want to. I don't want to.
Then you don't love me.
Okay.
Maybe I don't love you.
[ Moaning, Panting ]
Again. Again.
[ Both Grunt ]
The sisters from Ratisbon
couId start a hailstorm.
[ Panting Continues ]
[ Moans ]
[ Wind Gusting ]
I'm not gonna continue this
if you don't listen to me.
Good and evil -
they have nothing to do with therapy.
Do you know how many
innocent women were killed...
in the 16th century alone
just for being women?
I'm sure you do - many.
And not because they were evil.
I know.
It's just sometimes I forget.
The evil you talk about is an obsession.
Obsessions never materialize.
It's a scientific fact.
Anxieties can't trick you into doing things
you wouldn't do otherwise.
It's like hypnotism.
You can't be hypnotized
into doing something...
you wouldn't normally do...
something against your nature.
Do you understand me?
- Yeah, I think so.
- You think so.
Well, you don't have to understand me.
Just trust me.
- What's this?
- It's from the medical officer.
It's a copy of the autopsy report.
The autopsy?
Did they perform an autopsy?
I didn't want to tell you
because you weren't feeling well.
Well, what did they find?
Nothing that would have
any bearing on the case.
[ He ]
"The only abnormality in the victim...
"is a slight deformity of the bones
in his feet of an earlier date.
We did not attach
any significance to this."
Are you aware that you put
Nic's shoes on wrong in this picture?
So I have.
How weird.
Slip of the mind that day.
[ Nic Crying ]
Herself.
Oh!
[ Grunts ]
Bastard!
You're leaving me, aren't you?
- [ Grunting ]
- You bastard!
- You're leaving me!
- I'm not.
- I'm helping you.
- You're leaving me, aren't you?
No!
[ Gasping, Panting ]
- I Iove you.
- I don't believe you.
- I don't believe you!
- [ Grunts ]
I don't fucking believe you!
Oh!
[ Panting ]
[ Hand Drill Squeaking ]
[ Hyperventilating ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Screams ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Moans ]
Ow!
[ Grunting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Grunts ]
Where are you?
You bastard!
[ Shouting ]
Where are you?
[ ln Distance ]
- [ Grunts ]
- Where are you?
You bastard!
Where are you?
How dare you leave me!
[ Shouting ]
You said you wanted to help me!
[ Screaming ]
Where are you?
- [ Crow Cawing ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Caws ]
[ Shrieking ln Distance ]
Where are you?
You bastard!
[ Cawing ln Distance ]
[ Caws ]
[ Cawing ]
- [ Blows Landing ]
- [ Cawing Stops ]
- [ Wings Flapping ]
- [ Cawing ]
[ Cawing ln Distance ]
[ Cawing Loudly ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Cawing ln Distance ]
[ Cawing Stops ]
Get out! Get out!
You bastard!
Get out!
Come out!
You bastard!
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts, Shrieks ]
[ Crying ]
I'm sorry.
[ Groans ]
We gotta get this thing off my leg.
I can't find the wrench.
[ He Grunts ]
[ Grunts ]
Did you want to kill me?
Not yet.
The three beggars aren't here yet.
The three beggars.
What does that mean?
When the three beggars arrive,
someone must die.
I see.
[ She Sobs ]
A crying woman is a scheming woman.
"False in legs, and false in thighs.
False in breast, teeth, hair and eyes."
[ Sobbing ]
[ Object Thuds ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
Hold me.
[ Mutters ]
[ Shrieks ]
[ Panting ]
[ He ] There's no such consteIIation.
[ She Gasps ]
[ Sobs ]
But none of it is any use.
None of it is any use.
- [ Screams ] No!
[ Hailstones Landing On Roof ]
[ Bell Jingling ]
[ Jingling ]
[ Crow Cawing ]
[ Caws ]
[ Cawing ]
[ Groans ]
[ He Shrieks ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Shrieks ]
[ Groans ]
[ Choking ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Muffled Moan ]
[ MuffIed Scream ]
[ Choking ]
## [ "Lascia ch'io pianga" from Rinaldo:
Woman Singing In Italian ]
## [ Continues ]
## [ Ends ]