[ OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYS ]
>> LARA, THE AGENT SHOWED ME
PICTURES OF THE LAKE VIEW --
AH, THEY LOOKED AMAZING.
I'M TELLING YOU, IT'S A GREAT
APARTMENT.
There's even a convenience store
on the ground floor.
And he said the station is five
minutes away, walking distance.
>> [ HUMMING ]
>> I CAN GET TO MY OFFICE IN
LESS THAN 20 MINUTES.
YEAH!
>> WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
JANET, SLOW DOWN.
HOW MANY DID YOU SEE?
>> I SIGNED THE LEASE.
>> I SAID LOOK FOR AN APARTMENT,
NOT SIGN THE LEASE ON THE FIRST
ONE THEY SHOWED YOU.
WELL, HOW MUCH IS IT?
>> IT'S ONLY $750 A MONTH.
THE GUY SAID IT WAS GONNA BE
GONE WITHIN THE HOUR.
>> YOU NEVER SIGN THE LEASE ON
THE FIRST ONE THEY SHOW YOU.
>> [ Sighing ] OH, GOD.
YOU ARE STRESSING ME OUT.
It really looked beautiful in
the brochure.
>> IS IT IN A SAFE PLACE AT
LEAST?
>> Come on, Lara.
>> LARA.
>> It's sure better there than
at home.
>> LET ME TALK TO JANET.
>> IT'S MOM. I GOT TO GO.
>> IT'S DONE ALREADY, OKAY?
IT'S DONE.
BYE. [ SIGHS ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
>> I WANT TO TALK TO HER!
WHAT IS GOING ON?
IS SHE MOVING OUT?
AND WHY AM I THE LAST TO FIND
OUT ABOUT THIS?
>> [ SIGHS ] WHY?
BECAUSE YOU NEARLY KILLED HER.
>> OH, MY GOD. SHE SAID THAT?
HA. WHAT A DRAMA QUEEN.
[ SCOFFS ]
I WAS STANDING, PLAYING MY
GUITAR, AND I TURNED.
I DIDN'T HEAR HER WALK IN, AND I
HIT HER.
>> BLAME THE GUITAR. WHY NOT?
>> OH, YOU REALLY THINK THAT I
WOULD, ON PURPOSE, TRY TO HIT
JANET?
>> MOM, YOU AND I BOTH KNOW YOU
WERE DRUNK.
>> OH, YEAH.
AND WHAT'S YOUR POINT?
MY BEST SONGS WERE WRITTEN DRUNK
ANYWAY.
LOOK, OBVIOUSLY, YOU WERE IN
CAHOOTS WITH HER ON THIS
WHOLE WHATEVER THIS IS.
I WANT YOU TO JUST...
GET HER OUT OF THAT -- WHATEVER
IT IS -- AND BRING HER BACK
HERE.
'CAUSE THAT IS JUST RIDICULOUS.
>> SHE'S 24 YEARS OLD.
SHE'S GOT A LIFE.
SHE HAS A JOB.
SHE -- SHE HAS A BOYFRIEND.
WHY CAN'T YOU JUST BE HAPPY FOR
HER?
>> OH, BE HAPPY FOR HER AND HER
DEAD-END JOB, WHEN SHE HAS A
REAL VOICE AND COULD HAVE A
CAREER JUST LIKE I HAVE.
>> YEAH, WELL, CLEARLY SHE
DOESN'T WANT TO FOLLOW IN YOUR
FOOTSTEPS.
>> 'CAUSE IT'S SO TERRIBLE TO
HAVE SUCCESS AT SOMETHING YOU
LOVE DOING THAT YOU'RE GOOD AT?
>> SUCCESS. [ SIGHS ] RIGHT.
WELL, DRUGS, DRINKING, REHAB,
FAILED MARRIAGES -- WORTH IT FOR
YOU, MAYBE, NOT SO MUCH FOR US.
>> YOU HAVE A LOT OF NERVE,
SUMMING UP MY LIFE LIKE THAT.
I HAD A NUMBER-ONE HIT...
WHEN I WAS YOUNGER THAN YOU ARE
NOW.
AND WHAT HAVE YOU EVER DONE,
HMM, EITHER ONE OF YOU?
TELL ME, WHAT ARE YOUR BIG
ACHIEVEMENTS?
HAVE A LITTLE RESPECT.
YOU TWO HAD IT GOOD.
>> YEAH. GREAT.
>> AND I AM NOT PAYING FOR ANY
APARTMENT!
>> HMM.
[ RAP MUSIC PLAYS SOFTLY IN
BACKGROUND ]
[ ELEVATOR WHIRRING ]
HI.
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ ELEVATOR CREAKING ]
HEY. HEY, LITTLE GIRL.
HOW DID YOU GET HERE BEFORE ME?
[ GASPS ]
WOW.
OH, MY GOD. THIS IS GREAT.
[ SIGHS ]
[ BIRDS CHIRPING ]
WHAT A FABULOUS VIEW.
THIS IS PERFECT!
THIS IS SO COOL!
>> [ HUMMING ]
>> HEY.
I BROUGHT YOU SOME GREEN TEA.
>> I DON'T LIKE GREEN TEA, LARA.
>> YOU KNOW THE MOVERS JUST LEFT
WITH JANET'S BOXES?
>> [ SIGHS ]
I SACRIFICE THE BIGGEST CHUNK OF
MY LIFE, THE MAJOR, MAJOR GOLDEN
YEARS OF MY CAREER, AND THIS IS
THE THANKS I GET.
[ SCOFFS ]
>> MOM, STOP IT.
>> SHE LEAVES WITHOUT EVEN
SAYING GOODBYE.
>> IT'S NOT ABOUT YOU.
>> HOW COULD IT NOT BE?
>> GIVE HER TIME.
SHE'LL FORGIVE YOU.
>> "GIVE HER TIME.
SHE'LL FORGIVE YOU."
DO YOU KNOW HOW STUPID YOU
SOUND?
HONESTLY, YOU HAVE A LITTLE PEA
BRAIN.
A CHANCE TO BE ON TOUR AS A
BACKUP SINGER WITH MADDIE SLATE.
[ ELEVATED TRAIN RUMBLING ]
>> MY NEW HOME.
[ UP-TEMPO POP MUSIC PLAYS ]
TA-DA!
[ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
YOU CAN'T BEAT THAT.
[ GRUNTS ]
AND THE BEDROOM STUFF.
I LOVE THIS PICTURE. AWW.
[ SMOOCHES ]
SO NICE.
I'M GONNA PUT IT HERE.
WHAT'S THIS?
HERE TOO.
[ Singsong voice ] HELLO.
OH, I KNEW PUFFYLUMP WOULD COME
ALONG.
[ GIGGLES ]
[ Normal voice ] YES.
YES.
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
>> [ GHOSTLY WHISPERING ]
>> HELLO?
[ RAPID FOOTSTEPS ]
[ CREAKING, RUSTLING ]
[ CREAKING, WATER RUNNING ]
[ THUD ]
HELLO, DID ANYBODY HEAR THAT?
[ POUNDING ]
OH.
[ SIGHS ]
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ GASPS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ CREAKING ]
>> [ CRYING ]
>> HELLO?
[ CREAKING CONTINUES ]
IS THERE SOMEBODY IN HERE?
[ POUNDING ]
AAH!
AH. OW.
OW. [ CHUCKLES ]
UGH, "MORON KILLED BY IRONING
BOARD -- NEWS AT 11:00."
WINE.
[ WIND BLOWING ]
[ GHOSTLY WHISPERING ]
[ POUNDING ]
OH, SHIT.
OW. [ SIGHS ]
OH, MY GOD.
[ SIGHS ]
OH, THIS APARTMENT IS FREAKING
ME OUT!
[ SIGHS ]
ALL RIGHT. [ SIGHS ]
[ DOOR CHAIN JINGLES ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ CHAIN UNLATCHES, DOOR OPENS ]
HI.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
>> EMILY.
IS YOUR MOM HOME?
>> WHAT DO YOU WANT?
>> WHAT DO I WANT?
I JUST CAME BY TO SAY HI TO YOU
AND YOUR MOM.
I'M YOUR NEW NEIGHBOR.
AND, ALSO, I WAS HOPING TO
BORROW A CORKSCREW.
MINE IS BROKEN.
>> A GIRL IN 1303 JUMPED OFF THE
BALCONY AND DIED.
HER NAME WAS JENNIFER.
IT'S A BAD PLACE.
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ ELEVATOR WHIRRING ]
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ MAN COUGHING ]
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ BREATHING DEEPLY ]
Oh, my God.
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ POUNDING ON DOOR ]
>> HELLO?
>> BUILDING SUPERINTENDENT.
OPEN THE DOOR.
[ LOCK DISENGAGES ]
>> MAY I HELP YOU, SIR, WITH
SOMETHING?
>> YEAH, THE, UH, THE POWER'S
OUT.
I NEED TO CHECK YOUR APARTMENT.
>> UH, IT'S ALL GOOD HERE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
>> [ CHUCKLES ] YOU ARE A --
YOU ARE A PRETTY GIRL.
SHOW ME YOUR TITS.
>> WHAT? ARE YOU INSANE?
>> NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
LISTEN. LISTEN.
IF YOU NEED ANY HELP AT ALL IN
PAYING THE RENT, YOU KNOW, WE
CAN MAKE AN ARRANGEMENT, OKAY?
>> GET OUT OF HERE, YOU PERVERT!
YOU FREAKING PERVERT!
[ CRYING ]
OH, GOD.
ALL RIGHT. STOP THIS.
[ SIGHS ]
I'M GONNA GET A DRINK.
[ SNIFFLES, SOBS ] HELP ME.
[ CRYING CONTINUES ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ SMACKS LIPS ] OHH.
THIS IS SUCH A BEAUTIFUL
APARTMENT.
[ SIGHS ]
THIS IS WHAT I ALWAYS WANTED.
LARA, I WISH YOU COULD SEE
THIS...
AND BE WITH ME HERE.
I'M SCARED.
[ SIGHS ] JUST STOP IT, JANET.
STOP. STOP, JANET! COME ON.
[ LAUGHS ]
I'M SO STUPID.
I'M SO STUPID. OH, MY GOD.
CAN YOU BELIEVE THIS?
THE CRAZY PEOPLE.
[ LAUGHS ]
[ SIGHS ] OH, MY GOD.
EVERYTHING WILL BE JUST FINE,
JUST FINE.
[ BREATHES DEEPLY ]
[ CREAKING ]
>> [ WHIMPERING ]
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
>> HELLO?
[ WHIMPERING AND
FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE ]
WHO'S THERE?
HELLO?
[ THUD ]
[ SCRAPING ]
WHO'S THERE?
[ RUSTLING ]
WHO ARE YOU?! WHO'S HERE?!
>> [ GHOSTLY WHISPERING ]
>> I'VE GOT A GUN, YOU KNOW!
>> [ WHISPERING CONTINUES ]
>> WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?!
COME OUT!
[ GLASS BREAKS ]
OH!
>> DO YOU WANT A SLEEPING PILL?
>> [ Slurring ] WHY WOULD I WANT
A SLEEPING PILL?
I DO NOT WANT TO SLEEP.
I REALLY AM VERY...WORRIED ABOUT
MY DAUGHTERS.
[ TRUNK DISENGAGES ]
[ DIALING ]
[ Cellphone ringing ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
>> HEY, I DON'T DO CLINGY, HUH?
>> I KNOW. [ SIGHS ]
UH, BUT I THOUGHT YOU WERE
COMING OVER HERE.
>> I'M SORT OF IN THE MIDDLE OF
SOMETHING RIGHT NOW, AND, NO, I
CAN'T COME OVER TONIGHT.
>> Mark...
THIS PLACE IS TRULY SPOOKY.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
THE SUPER TRIED TO FORCE MY DOOR
OPEN, AND I GOT HIS FOOT STUCK
IN IT.
AND THEN THERE'S THIS HORRIBLE
STENCH, LIKE SOMETHING
ROTTING -- DEAD MEAT.
>> WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
>> MY NEIGHBOR SAID SOMEBODY
DIED IN HERE.
I CAN FEEL IT. I CAN FEEL IT.
SOMEONE IS DEAD IN HERE.
[ WHIMPERS, SOBS ]
>> JANET, TALK TO ME.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
Insane! Are you stoned?
>> I'M FINE.
I'm okay. I'm okay now.
EVERYTHING'S FINE. [ CHUCKLES ]
I DON'T KNOW WHAT GOT INTO ME.
I THINK THIS WHOLE PLACE IS
FREAKING ME OUT.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
I-I JUST DON'T LIKE IT, YOU
KNOW?
AND I SIGNED A ONE-YEAR LEASE.
THE FIRST DECISION I MADE ON MY
OWN, AND I THINK I MADE A
MISTAKE.
>> IT'S ALL GOOD.
NO WORRIES, OKAY?
BUT I GOT TO GO.
ALL RIGHT. BYE.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ SIREN WAILS IN DISTANCE ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ WIND BLOWING ]
[ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ PILLS CLATTER ]
[ LID SNAPS ON ]
[ SETS BOTTLE ON NIGHTSTAND ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ CLATTERING ]
[ TENNIS BALL BOUNCING ]
[ BREATHES DEEPLY ]
[ GASPS, WHIMPERS ]
WHO'S THERE?
[ CRYING ]
[ BREATHING DEEPLY ]
Who did this to me?
What happened?
Oh.
"SIDE EFFECTS MAY INCLUDE
SLEEPWALKING."
[ Sighs ] OH, GOD.
I SHOULD ALWAYS READ THE LABELS.
[ KEYS JINGLE, LOCK ENGAGES ]
OH. HI, EMILY.
HEY, UM, WERE YOU PLAYING IN MY
APARTMENT LAST NIGHT?
WERE YOU PLAYING BALL IN MY
APARTMENT?
COME ON. LET'S GO SEE YOUR MOM.
>> DON'T TOUCH ME.
GO AWAY.
[ GUITAR STRUMMING MELODICALLY ]
>> ♪ OH, OH, OH, THAT'S WHAT
THEY'RE SAYING ♪
♪ OH, OH, OH, THEY DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ ABOVE LO-O-VE ♪
♪ UH-WHOA-OH-OH, THEY DON'T KNOW
NOTHIN' ♪
♪ HEY, HEY, AYE, AYE, AND THAT'S
WHAT THEY'RE SAYIN' ♪
♪ NO-O-O, THEY DON'T KNOW ♪
♪ THEY'LL NEVER KNO-O-W ♪
♪ AT ALL ♪
[ HUMMING HARMONY ]
♪ AND THEY'LL NEVER, MM,
MM, BUM, BUM, BUM ♪
♪ AND THAT'S WHAT THEY'RE
SAYIN' ♪
♪ OH, THEY DON'T KNOW ♪
[ ENGINE REVS ]
>> I CAN'T THINK OF ANYTHING
INTERESTING TO SAY ABOUT
HEADPHONES.
IT'S JUST...
I HOPE I SURVIVE THE NEXT ROUND
OF LAYOFFS.
IF I HAD KNOWN THEY WERE COMING,
I WOULD HAVE NEVER SIGNED THE
LEASE ON MY STUPID APARTMENT.
>> DON'T WORRY.
IT'S NOT LIKE THEY PAY US ANY
REAL MONEY ANYWAY.
>> [ CHUCKLES ]
>> WHAT IS THAT?
>> HMM?
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> OH, THIS?
OH, IT'S -- I COULDN'T SLEEP
LAST NIGHT.
M-MAYBE I TOOK TOO MANY SLEEPING
PILLS?
I DON'T KNOW.
I THINK I SLEEPWALKED INTO A
WALL OR SOMETHING.
[ CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY ]
>> OH, YOU GOT PUNCHED, DIDN'T
YOU?
>> WHAT?
IS THAT WHAT IT LOOKS LIKE?
>> IF MY BOYFRIEND SLAPPED ME, I
WOULD GO STRAIGHT TO THE POLICE.
>> SHH!
>> I WOULD BEAT THE MOTHERFUCKER
SENSELESS FIRST AND THEN I
WOULD GO TO THE POLICE.
>> LOOK. OKAY.
JOYCE, I SWEAR MARK HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS -- NOTHING AT
ALL.
AND IF HE DID, YOU THINK THAT I
WOULD PUT UP WITH THAT?
>> IF YOU SAY SO.
>> I REALLY DON'T KNOW WHAT
HAPPENED.
I REALLY DON'T, AND IT'S
FREAKING ME OUT.
ALL I REMEMBER IS THAT I WENT TO
BED LAST NIGHT, AND I HAD
HORRIBLE NIGHTMARES AND WHEN I
GOT UP THIS MORNING, I WAS
COVERED IN BRUISES.
>> WHEN YOU'RE READY TO TALK
ABOUT IT TRUTHFULLY, I'M HERE.
>> JOYCE, YOU'RE MY BEST FRIEND.
I JUST TOLD YOU THE TRUTH.
>> MOM, WE NEED FOOD.
DO YOU WANT TO GO GET IT
TOGETHER?
MOM?
WHY?
JESUS FUCKING CHRIST. WHY?
MOM! WATCH YOUR...
>> [ Slurring ] OH, HI, LARA
SWEETIE.
>> HEY.
>> [ MOANS ] OH, BABY.
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> NOBODY IS TWEETING ME.
>> OH.
>> I WORKED SO HARD.
>> WHAT?
DO YOU KNOW HOW INSANE THIS
SOUNDS?
COME ON. GET UP. UP!
>> NO, IT'S NOT INSANE AT ALL.
>> UP!
>> OW. OH, GOD. JESUS.
>> WE NEED FOOD.
>> [ SIGHS ] BABY.
>> JUST COME ON.
LET'S GO GET SOME FOOD.
>> OH, MY LARA. MY LARA.
>> MOM, COME ON. WE NEED FOOD.
COME ON. GET UP.
>> [ SIGHS ]
I'M NOT HUNGRY.
AND ANYWAY, I HAVE THE D.U.I.
SO YOU JUST GO GET SOME,
SWEETHEART.
>> I CAN'T KEEP SPENDING ALL MY
MONEY.
I ALREADY MAKE SO LITTLE
ALREADY.
>> THAT'S WHAT THIS IS --
THAT'S WHAT THIS IS ABOUT, ISN'T
IT?!
[ BOTTLE CLATTERS ]
THAT'S ALL YOU CARE ABOUT IS MY
MONEY!
YOU WERE PRETENDING THAT YOU
CARED!
YOU DON'T, DO YOU?!
LOOK AT ME!
YOU DON'T REALLY LOVE ME, DO
YOU?!
>> YOU'RE INSANE!
[ GLASS BREAKS ]
>> NO!
[ BOTTLE CLATTERS ]
YOU'RE SCARING ME!
[ BREATHING DEEPLY ]
YOU PROBABLY WISH I WAS DEAD.
>> [ Crying ] SHE'S DRIVING ME
CRAZY.
[ GLASS CLATTERING, BREAKING ]
[ DIALING ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
>> [ BREATHING DEEPLY ]
HEY, SWEETIE.
HOW WAS YOUR FIRST NIGHT?
>> NOT GOOD.
NOT GOOD -- IT WAS REALLY BAD.
I DON'T WANT TO GO BACK THERE.
I WANT TO COME HOME.
>> Tonight? Really?
>> YES. TONIGHT.
I-I CAN'T GO BACK.
>> YOU DON'T WANT TO COME BACK
HERE TONIGHT.
MOM'S ON ONE OF HER DRUNK,
PSYCHO RANTS AGAIN.
>> NO, PLEASE.
I CAN'T GO BACK THERE.
LARA, PLEASE.
Maybe I could stay in a hotel.
>> WHAT HOTEL? NO.
I DON'T HAVE ENOUGH MONEY TO PUT
IT ON MY CARD.
>> THAT APARTMENT IS VERY
STRANGE.
I CAN'T GO BACK THERE, LARA.
I WANT TO COME HOME, OKAY?
I WANT TO COME HOME.
And I don't need your
permission.
[ SIGHS ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ CELLPHONE DROPS ]
[ GLASS BREAKS ]
>> YOU'RE RIGHT, MOM.
I DO WISH YOU WERE DEAD.
>> HEY, MARK. IT'S ME.
I HAVEN'T HEARD FROM YOU ALL
DAY.
UH, CALL ME WHEN YOU GET THIS,
OKAY?
PLEASE? I'M STILL AT THE OFFICE.
[ TELEPHONE LINE CRACKLES ]
>> Hey, Janet.
Can you hold on a sec?
>> OH, HEY, MARK. IT'S YOU.
>> Hey, baby.
I just got back in town.
>> [ Sighs ] OH, THANK GOD.
I MEAN, YOU'RE BACK.
SO -- SO, ARE YOU COMING OVER
NOW?
>> No, I don't have the time.
>> WHAT? OH, COME ON.
PLEASE BE NICE TO ME.
MY SISTER WAS A SHIT.
COME ON.
PLEASE.
>> Okay, what was the address?
Lake View Residence, right?
>> YES.
MEET YOU IN THE LOBBY.
>> Okay.
[ CHUCKLES ]
WOW.
YOU WEREN'T KIDDING ABOUT THE
VIEW.
>> NO, THE VIEW IS GREAT.
>> WHAT'S GOING ON?
THIS IS GREAT.
>> YEAH, IT'S A NICE APARTMENT.
>> MM.
>> [ SIGHS ]
>> WOW.
I LIKE THIS ROOM.
>> [ CHUCKLES ]
[ LAUGHING ]
[ SMOOCHES ]
AHH.
[ GASPS ]
[ BOTH MOANING ]
OH, RAVISH ME.
>> AHH.
>> [ LAUGHS ]
[ BOTH MOANING ]
OH.
[ BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY ]
I'VE BEEN A NAUGHTY GIRL?
>> MM-HMM.
>> OH, YEAH?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO TO PUNISH
ME?
>> I'LL THINK OF SOMETHING.
>> YEAH. OH.
[ BOTH MOANING, BREATHING
HEAVILY ]
[ THUDDING ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ONCE ]
[ THUDDING CONTINUES ]
[ THUDDING STOPS ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ONCE ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
[ WATER RUNNING ]
>> MARK?
MARK?
WHAT'S THAT TERRIBLE SMELL?
DO YOU SMELL THAT?
MARK?
[ SCREAMS ]
>> [ SHRIEKS ]
>> [ GASPS ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
[ CRYING ] PLEASE.
[ GASPS ]
[ GROANS ]
[ CRYING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CRYING CONTINUES, MOANING ]
[ WAILS ]
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CRYING CONTINUES ]
I DON'T WANT TO DIE.
[ DISTANT SCREAMING ]
I AM NOT ALONE!
[ SCREAMS ]
[ FENCE SQUEAKING ]
[ CRYING ]
WHAT DID I DO TO YOU?
WHY? [ SOBS ]
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS TO ME?
[ SCREAMS ]
[ SCREAMING ]
[ THUD ]
>> [ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ HORNS HONKING ]
>> WHAT HAPPENED?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> IT'S TRUE THEN.
>> WHAT?
>> WELL, JANET'S FRIEND SAID
SHE WAS BEATEN BY HER BOYFRIEND
THE NIGHT BEFORE.
>> YOU SHOULD KNOW BETTER THAN
TO MAKE AN ACCUSATION LIKE THAT.
I LIKED YOUR SISTER.
>> [ SCOFFS ] YOU LIKED HER.
WHAT THE FUCK DOES THAT MEAN?
>> I DIDN'T HIT YOUR SISTER.
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
I DON'T DO THAT.
>> YOU SURE AS HELL DIDN'T LOOK
AFTER HER.
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ RATTLING ]
[ BIRDS FLUTTER ]
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
[ SNIFFS ]
[ SNIFFING ]
[ RUSTLING ]
[ BIRDS SQUAWK ]
[ BIRDS FLUTTERING ]
[ FLUTTERING ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ SHOWER CURTAIN SCRAPES ]
[ BIRDS SQUAWKING, FLUTTERING ]
[ WIND BLOWING ]
>> Detroit Storage.
>> HI, UM, I'M AT THE
LAKE VIEW RESIDENCE ON
JEFFERSON, APARTMENT 1303.
I NEED TO MOVE SOME BOXES AS
SOON AS POSSIBLE.
>> Hold on.
Didn't we just move you in
there?
>> THAT WAS MY SISTER.
>> Oh. What happened?
>> SHE DIED.
>> Can you pay cash?
>> CAN I CALL YOU BACK?
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ SCOFFS ]
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
[ LOCK DISENGAGES ]
>> DON'T COME BACK.
>> WHAT DID YOU JUST SAY?
HEY, MY SISTER DIED IN THAT
APARTMENT.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED THERE?
>> I TOLD HER TO LEAVE, BUT SHE
DID NOT.
>> DO YOU HAVE A NAME?
>> EMILY.
>> OKAY, EMILY, WHY WOULD YOU
SAY THAT TO HER?
>> A GIRL AND HER MOTHER LIVE IN
APARTMENT 1303.
THEY DON'T WANT TO SHARE IT.
>> HOW CAN THAT BE?
I MEAN, JANET SIGNED A LEASE.
THE PLACE WAS FOR RENT.
LOOK, DO YOU HAVE A SISTER?
I LOVED MY SISTER...MORE THAN
ANYTHING.
IF YOU KNOW SOMETHING ABOUT WHAT
HAPPENED IN THERE, YOU CAN TELL
ME.
I'LL KEEP YOUR SECRETS.
>> JENNIFER IS UPSET WITH YOU,
TOO.
>> WHO?
HEY, WHO ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
COME BACK HERE.
EMILY.
[ DOOR SLAMS ]
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYS ]
MARK, IT'S LARA SLATE.
I'VE JUST LEFT JANET'S PLACE
AND, WELL, YEAH.
IT'S PRETTY UNNERVING.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT I MEAN BY
THAT.
>> Yeah. I understand that.
>> DID YOU KNOW A JENNIFER?
I DON'T KNOW, MAYBE A FRIEND OF
JANET'S.
>> No.
Name doesn't ring a bell.
>> WELL, THE PLACE SMELLED
REALLY BAD AT ONE POINT.
DID YOU NOTICE THAT?
>> Yeah, I did.
It came and went.
Maybe old pipes.
>> YEAH, MAYBE.
WELL, ANYWAY, I'M GOING BACK IN
THE MORNING TO MEET THE MOVERS
AND BE DONE.
CAN WE MEET THERE?
>> Sure. Just tell me when.
>> TWO HOURS.
>> Yeah, that should work for
me.
If traffic's not too bad, I --
>> MARK?
[ Cellphone beeps ]
HELLO? SHIT.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
>> SORRY, LARA.
>> HEY. IT'S ALL RIGHT.
I'M NOT IN A RUSH TODAY, ANYWAY.
>> DO YOU THINK YOU COULD COVER
FOR ME ON SUNDAY, TOO?
>> UH, YEAH, PROBABLY.
I SURE COULD USE THE MONEY.
[ WIND HOWLING ]
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
OKAY, SEE YOU.
>> [ HUMMING, STRUMMING GUITAR ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
YOU WANT TO GET OUT OF HERE?
GO SEE A MOVIE?
>> WE JUST BURIED YOUR SISTER.
YOU'RE TALKING ABOUT GOING TO A
MOVIE?
I -- HOW FUCKING INSENSITIVE CAN
YOU GET?
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
I WROTE A SONG FOR JANET.
I'M GONNA PLAY IT FOR YOU.
>> NO, DON'T.
>> YOU'VE BEEN JEALOUS OF HER
SINCE THE DAY SHE WAS BORN.
SHE WAS ALWAYS SO GOOD AT
EVERYTHING.
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
BETTER THAN YOU.
DID I NOT SAY GET HER OUT OF
THAT LEASE AND BRING HER HOME?
HMM?
BUT, NO, YOU HAD TO ENCOURAGE
HER.
DID YOU ENCOURAGE HER TO JUMP?
>> I CAN'T TALK TO YOU.
I WISH I COULD, BUT I CAN'T.
>> HAVE YOU BEEN TAKING YOUR
MEDICATION?
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
'CAUSE YOU CAN DO SICK THINGS...
WHEN YOU'RE NOT ON YOUR
MEDICATION.
[ GASPING ]
>> AAH!
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
JANET?
WHO IS THIS?
>> Hi, Lara.
I miss you.
I don't want to live here alone.
>> JANET, IS IT REALLY YOU?
>> Can you come and get me?
Please.
>> WHERE ARE YOU?
WAIT.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
THIS ISN'T HAPPENING.
OH, MY GOD!
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
WAKE UP.
WAKE UP!
[ ELEVATOR DINGS ]
[ LOCK DISENGAGES ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
>> MOTHER WAS --
>> WHAT?
>> I'M SO GLAD YOU KILLED HER.
>> JANET?
WHAT...?
>> WHAT'S THE MATTER, LARA?
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
>> NO!
GOD! NO!
>> I'M YOUR SISTER, JANET.
>> [ SCREAMING ]
>> EVERYTHING FOR LARA.
>> [ GROANS ]
OHH!
>> 911.
>> I'M IN AN APARTMENT ON
JEFFERSON AVENUE.
I'VE JUST BEEN ATTACKED.
>> Is the perpetrator still
there?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
>> A police car is on its way.
Do you want to stay on the line
until they get there?
>> YES. I'M SORRY.
I'M REALLY SCARED FOR MY LIFE.
>> Just stay calm.
Are you hurt?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
SOMEONE WAS IN THE APARTMENT AND
ATTACKED ME IN THE BEDROOM.
>> MALE OR FEMALE?
>> LOOK, I DIDN'T SEE ANYBODY.
IT WAS LIKE...A FORCE.
>> A FORCE?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
>> I DON'T KNOW.
I GOT THROWN AGAINST THE WALL.
>> FOR WHATEVER IT'S WORTH, LET
ME GIVE YOU A LITTLE HISTORY ON
THIS PLACE.
IN THE PAST THREE YEARS, FOUR
PEOPLE, INCLUDING YOUR SISTER,
HAVE DIED HERE -- ALL WOMEN IN
THEIR 20s.
MAY 15th OF LAST YEAR,
SHAWN WILLIAMS, AGE 27, JUMPED
OR FELL FROM THE BALCONY FOUR
DAYS AFTER MOVING IN.
TWO YEARS AGO, NOVEMBER 30th,
DANA BAUER, AGE 28, FELL OR
JUMPED FROM THE BALCONY AFTER
THREE DAYS OF BEING THERE.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED TO
YOUR SISTER, BUT IT WAS THE SAME
THING.
TWO DAYS AFTER MOVING IN, SHE
DIED FALLING FROM THE BALCONY.
NOW, AS FAR AS WE CAN FIGURE
OUT, THESE WOMEN NEVER MET.
THEY DIDN'T KNOW EACH OTHER.
THEY HAD NOTHING IN COMMON,
EXCEPT FOR THIS APARTMENT.
AND APARTMENTS DON'T KILL
PEOPLE.
PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE.
>> WHY DIDN'T ANYBODY TELL US
THIS AFTER JANET DIED?
>> I SUPPOSE WE SHOULD HAVE DONE
THAT.
THERE ARE NO MORE ACTIVE CASES
GOING ON WITH ANY OF THESE
SUICIDES.
>> MY SISTER WOULDN'T COMMIT
SUICIDE.
[ RUMBLING SOUND ]
>> MS. SLATE, ARE YOU TAKING
DRUGS?
>> WHAT?
>> ANY KIND OF DRUGS?
>> NO. WHY WOULD YOU SAY THAT?
DIDN'T YOU SAY THERE WAS A
FOURTH PERSON?
>> YES. SHE WAS THE FIRST ONE.
AND IT WAS A CLEAR CASE OF
HOMICIDE-SUICIDE.
THERE WE GO -- MARY LOGAN,
RESPECTED SCHOOLTEACHER, BECAUSE
OF SOME PARENT-TEACHER DISPUTE,
LOST HER JOB AND SOON THEREAFTER
LOST HER HOUSE IN A BITTER
DIVORCE.
SO MARY MOVED HERE WITH HER
DAUGHTER, JENNIFER, WHO WAS THEN
12 YEARS OLD.
MARY BECAME A DRUNK AND A
PROSTITUTE, AND JENNIFER MUST
HAVE SUFFERED UNTOLD ABUSE FOR
YEARS.
AND THEN ON SEPTEMBER 17th,
ALMOST 20 YEARS AGO...
[ SCRATCHING SOUND ]
...NEIGHBORS REPORTED A FOUL,
AWFUL SMELL COMING FROM THIS
APARTMENT.
AND WHEN THE HEALTH DEPARTMENT
CAME TO INVESTIGATE, JENNIFER
JUMPED OFF THE BALCONY TO HER
DEATH.
THE POLICE FOUND THE DECOMPOSED
BODY OF HER MOTHER HIDDEN IN A
BUILT-IN CLOSET.
NOW, ARE ANY OF THESE NAMES
FAMILIAR TO YOU?
>> ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
DO YOU THINK I WOULD HAVE LET MY
SISTER MOVE IN HERE IF I KNEW
ANY OF THIS?
>> NO, I GUESS NOT.
I'LL REPORT YOUR CALL AS A HOME
INVASION, BUT YOU DIDN'T SEE
ANYONE.
YOU'RE LOOKING BETTER NOW.
I SHOULD GET BACK TO THE STATION
AND END MY SHIFT.
THOUGH I'D BE GLAD TO GIVE YOU A
RIDE HOME.
>> OH, NO, THAT'S OKAY.
[ CHUCKLES ]
LAST THING I NEED IS TO BE
COMING HOME IN A COP CAR AT 5:00
A.M.
I LIVE WITH MY MOTHER.
>> TAKE CARE, MS. SLATE.
[ DOOR OPENS, CLOSES ]
[ MUSIC PLAYING FROM
HEADPHONES ]
>> I THOUGHT I MIGHT FIND YOU
HERE.
>> HEY.
LOOK, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN TO ACCUSE YOU
OF...
THE POLICE KEEP SAYING IT WAS A
SUICIDE, AND I JUST -- I CAN'T
WRAP MY HEAD AROUND THAT.
MY MOM DROVE US NUTS, BUT NOT TO
THAT EXTENT.
>> I DON'T THINK IT WAS A
SUICIDE, EITHER.
>> YOU DON'T?
>> THAT NIGHT, WHEN I WAS
LEAVING THE BUILDING, I HEARD A
SCREAM, AND I SWEAR I SAW
SOMEONE WRESTLING WITH JANET ON
THE BALCONY.
I COULD HAVE BEEN WRONG.
I MEAN, IT WAS JUST FOR A
SECOND, AND IT WAS DARK.
>> DID YOU TELL THE POLICE?
>> YEAH, OF COURSE I DID.
THEY TOLD ME NOT TO TELL ANYONE.
AND I JUST DID.
>> WHY DID YOU LEAVE HER IN THE
MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT?
>> I'D RATHER WAKE UP IN MY OWN
BED.
>> THAT'S WHAT MEN SAY WHEN
THEY'RE MARRIED.
ARE YOU?
>> SEPARATED.
I HAVE A BOY.
>> DID YOU CARE FOR HER AT ALL?
>> YEAH, I DID.
LOOK, OUR RELATIONSHIP WAS NEW.
WE WERE JUST GETTING TO KNOW
EACH OTHER, BUT I CARED ABOUT
HER.
JANET WAS CONVINCED THAT SOMEONE
HAD ACCESS TO THAT APARTMENT.
SHE TOLD ME SHE HEARD THINGS.
SHE SAW SOMEONE IN THERE, SO I
TOOK A LOOK AROUND, AND THERE
WAS NOTHING -- NOBODY, AND
THERE'S NO WAY TO GET INTO THAT
APARTMENT UNLESS YOU GO IN
THROUGH THE FRONT DOOR.
>> YEAH, WELL, I'M THINKING OF
KEEPING THE PLACE.
>> THAT'S BRAVE.
THERE WAS SOMETHING WEIRD ABOUT
THAT APARTMENT.
IT'S NOT A GOOD IDEA FOR YOU TO
BE THERE ALONE.
>> LOOK, I GOT TO GO.
WHY DON'T YOU COME BY TONIGHT?
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT THEN.
>> TAKE OFF.
>> DID JANET SLATE KNOW YOU WERE
A COP?
>> NO.
>> DID ANYONE KNOW YOU WERE
GONNA SPEND THE NIGHT AT
APARTMENT 1303?
>> NO.
WHAT'S WITH THE QUESTIONS?
AM I UNDER INVESTIGATION NOW?
>> WELL, THAT JUDGE ON THE FIFTH
CIRCUIT DID GIVE US ACCESS TO
YOUR CELLPHONE.
ONE OF YOUR TEXT MESSAGES THE
NIGHT MS. SLATE DIED WAS, AND I
QUOTE, "WHERE THE FUCK ARE YOU?"
THAT WAS YOUR WIFE, RIGHT?
>> [ SIGHS ] JESUS CHRIST.
>> IS IT POSSIBLE SHE FOLLOWED
YOU AND CONFRONTED MS. SLATE
AFTER YOU LEFT?
>> NO, SHE DOESN'T GIVE A SHIT
WHAT I DO AS LONG AS I GET MONEY
FOR MY SON EVERY MONTH, ALL
RIGHT?
ARE WE DONE HERE?
>> WHY'D YOU GO SEE LARA SLATE?
>> WERE YOU FOLLOWING ME?
>> SHE'S A PERSON OF INTEREST.
>> AND WHY IS THAT?
>> WHY IS THAT?
YOU SAID YOU SAW TWO WOMEN ON
THE BALCONY, RIGHT?
IT'S IN YOUR REPORT.
>> YOU'RE GONNA MOVE IN TO WHERE
YOUR SISTER DIED?
ARE YOU SICK?
>> I'VE MADE UP MY MIND.
I'M MOVING OUT.
>> HA! ALL RIGHT.
WELL, GOOD LUCK WITH THAT.
YOU'VE MISMANAGED YOUR LIFE SO
FAR.
I CANNOT WAIT TO SEE WHAT
HAPPENS NEXT.
>> I WON'T COME BACK TONIGHT.
>> ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
WHAT IS IT YOU WANT, LARA?
YOU WANT ME TO PAY FOR THAT
COLLEGE -- WHATEVER THE FUCK IT
IS?
I'LL PAY FOR IT, ALL RIGHT?
YOU CAN JUST STAY HERE TILL TERM
STARTS, ALL RIGHT?
>> IT'S NOT GONNA HAPPEN, MOM.
>> I CANNOT BE ALONE, ALL RIGHT?
I DON'T HAVE ANYBODY...IN
BETWEEN BOYFRIENDS, BESIDES
WHICH, YOU KNOW, WHO'S GONNA
DRIVE ME?
WANT ME TO SPEND MORE MONEY ON
DRIVERS?
>> YOU PROBABLY SHOULD HAVE
THOUGHT OF THAT BEFORE YOU GOT A
D.U.I.
>> I LOVE YOU.
YOU'RE MY BABY.
AND I DON'T WANT YOU TO GO.
YOU LEAVE NOW!
DON'T YOU EVER FUCKING COME
BACK...EVER!
>> YOU THINK YOU'VE HAD ENOUGH?
>> IT'S COLD IN HERE.
I KEEP TRYING TO CLOSE THOSE
DOORS, AND THEY DON'T SHUT.
YOU KNOW, THE LITTLE GIRL FROM
NEXT DOOR...SHE TOLD ME THAT A
MOTHER AND DAUGHTER LIVED IN
HERE, AND THEY DIDN'T WANT THIS
PLACE RENTED.
SHE SAID SHE TOLD JANET TO
LEAVE.
>> DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE.
>> YEAH, I KNOW.
IN 1993, A MOTHER AND DAUGHTER
LIVED IN HERE.
THE DAUGHTER WENT CRAZY AND
KILLED THE MOTHER, PUT HER IN
THE CLOSET, LIVED WITH THE BODY
FOR SIX MONTHS, AND THEN SHE
FINALLY JUMPED OFF THE BALCONY.
[ CLACKING SOUND ]
WHY DO YOU HAVE A GUN?
EXPLAIN THE GUN.
>> I'M AN UNDERCOVER COP, OKAY?
>> WHAT THE FUCK?!
WHAT IS GOING ON HERE?!
>> NOTHING IS GOING ON.
>> MY SISTER DIED IN THIS
APARTMENT!
>> DON'T FIGHT ME!
LOOK, SIT DOWN. RELAX. OKAY?
JANET DIDN'T KNOW I WAS AN
UNDERCOVER COP, AND I HAD
NOTHING TO DO WITH WHAT HAPPENED
HERE.
BUT I WANT TO FIND OUT WHAT
HAPPENED JUST AS MUCH AS YOU DO.
YOU OKAY?
>> NO, I'M NOT OKAY.
>> YOU WANT ME TO LEAVE?
>> NO, I DON'T WANT YOU TO LEAVE
NOW.
YOU OWE ME.
YOU CAN SPEND THE NIGHT ON THE
COUCH AND GUARD ME.
>> [ GRUNTS ]
[ THUDDING ]
[ THUDDING INTENSIFIES ]
[ THUDDING CONTINUES ]
[ INSECTS BUZZING ]
[ GROANS ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
CINDY, YEAH, IT'S -- IT'S MARK.
YEAH, I KNOW.
I-I -- YEAH, I COULDN'T MAKE IT.
I...
J-JUST TELL HIM I'M SORRY, AND
I'LL BE THERE THIS AFTERNOON TO
PICK HIM UP FROM SCHOOL, OKAY?
YEAH.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
FUCK.
HEY.
I GOT TO GO.
ARE YOU STAYING, OR CAN I TAKE
YOU SOMEWHERE?
>> I'M OKAY.
I'LL STAY HERE.
>> ALL RIGHT.
I'LL SEE YOU TONIGHT.
BUT YOU GOT TO DUMP THIS PLACE.
STAYING HERE ISN'T GONNA HELP US
FIGURE OUT WHAT HAPPENED TO
JANET.
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ BREATHES DEEPLY ]
[ WATER SPLASHES ]
>> [ SCREAMING ]
>> [ PANTING ]
>> YOU GOT TO PAY RENT.
I'M THE SUPER.
YOU NEED TO SIGN THE LEASE.
YOU WANT TO STAY, YOU GOT TO
PAY.
>> HOW DID YOU GET IN HERE?
DON'T YOU KNOW IT'S ILLEGAL TO
ENTER A TENANT'S APARTMENT WHILE
THEY'RE IN IT?
>> YOU SHOULDN'T BE HERE WITHOUT
A LEASE.
>> MY SISTER JANET ALREADY
SIGNED A LEASE AND PAID FIRST
MONTH'S RENT.
FINE.
I'LL PAY FOR A NEW LEASE, BUT I
NEED YOU TO LEAVE.
>> I'M HERE NOW.
WRITE ME A CHECK.
>> UM...I NEED A GLASS OF WATER.
>> IF YOU NEED HELP TO PAY, WE
CAN MAKE AN ARRANGEMENT.
>> I DON'T NEED ANY HELP.
I NEED YOU TO LEAVE.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYS ]
>> HI, LARA.
I NEEDED TO TALK TO YOU.
YOUR MOTHER FILED A TEMPORARY
RESTRAINING ORDER AGAINST YOU,
AND HER SWORN STATEMENT IS VERY
TROUBLING.
DID YOU EVER KEEP HER LOCKED UP
IN HER ROOM?
>> IS THAT WHAT SHE SAYS?
>> SHE STATED THAT YOU HIT HER
ON SEVERAL OCCASIONS.
>> MY MOTHER IS A COMPULSIVE
LIAR.
SHE'LL SAY WHATEVER IT TAKES TO
GET WHAT SHE WANTS.
>> WHAT DOES SHE WANT NOW?
>> BESIDES A SLAVE, FOR ME TO
NOT MOVE IN TO APARTMENT 1303.
>> I CAN'T SAY I DISAGREE WITH
HER.
>> WHY?
>> WELL, YOU FIT THE PROFILE OF
THE WOMEN THAT JUMPED OFF THE
BALCONY THERE.
>> YOU'RE DRIVING ME CRAZY.
FIRST YOU SAID, "APARTMENTS
DON'T KILL PEOPLE.
PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE."
AND NOW YOU'RE SAYING THAT
APARTMENT HAS SOMETHING TO DO
WITH IT?
>> LARA, WHERE WERE YOU THE
NIGHT JANET DIED?
>> I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU'RE ASKING
ME THAT.
MY SISTER DID NOT COMMIT
SUICIDE.
I'M GONNA PROVE IT.
>> [ MAN ON TELEVISION SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ]
>> ♪ WON'T YOU BE MY ♪
♪ CEMETERY VALENTINE? ♪
♪ TILL THE END OF TIME ♪
♪ MY CEMETERY VALENTINE ♪
OOH, BABY.
THAT'S A HIT, THOUGH.
I THINK THAT'S A HIT.
>> JANET TOLD ME YOUR MOTHER'S A
HANDFUL.
>> PUT IT THIS WAY -- MY FATHER
REMARRIED RECENTLY.
WHEN I CALLED HIM TO TELL HIM
JANET DIED, HE SAID HE COULDN'T
COME TO THE FUNERAL ON THE OFF
CHANCE HE MIGHT RUN IN TO HER.
>> NICE.
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
>> OH.
SPEAK OF THE DEVIL.
WHAT DO YOU WANT, MOM?
>> [ Slurring ] I need you to
come home, baby.
I can't sleep with you in that
apartment.
>> YOU SHOULD HAVE THOUGHT OF
THAT BEFORE YOU FILED A
RESTRAINING ORDER.
>> No, that was completely
misinterpreted.
Just come home.
I want to talk.
>> I CAN'T JUST COME HOME.
IF YOU WANT TO TALK TO ME, YOU
KNOW WHERE I AM.
>> MOTHERS, HUH?
>> [ SNIFFS ]
DO YOU SMELL THAT?
>> NO.
[ INSECTS BUZZING ]
>> DO YOU THINK GHOSTS CAN
INTERACT WITH US?
>> I'LL TELL YOU...I DON'T KNOW.
>> HEY, LOOK, I'M DRUNK AND
TIRED.
IT'S TIME FOR ME TO GO TO BED.
THANKS FOR GUARDING ME.
>> MY PLEASURE.
SLEEP WELL.
>> LARA.
YOU MUST LEAVE NOW BEFORE SHE
KILLS YOU, TOO.
>> [ SCREAMS ]
>> LARA? HEY, WHAT'S WRONG?
>> [ Crying ] THERE'S SOMEONE IN
THE CLOSET.
THERE'S SOMEONE IN THERE.
[ SOBBING ]
>> LARA, THERE'S NO ONE IN THE
CLOSET.
>> I SAW THEM!
[ SOBBING ]
OH, GOD!
>> IT'S OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
>> I'M GOING CRAZY!
OH, MY GOD!
>> YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
>> MY MOM IS RIGHT!
WHAT IF I DO SEE THINGS THAT
AREN'T THERE?!
OH, GOD!
>> LARA, LISTEN TO ME.
YOU NEED SOME REST, OKAY?
AND TOMORROW, WE'RE GETTING OUT
OF HERE.
OKAY?
>> [ SOBBING ]
>> I'M GONNA BE RIGHT OUT THERE.
>> I SAW IT.
I...
[ WIND HOWLING ]
[ HOWLING CONTINUES ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
>> [ GRUNTS ]
[ GROANING ]
[ GROANING CONTINUES ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
>> [ SIGHS ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
YES, I GOT YOUR MESSAGE.
AND, NO, I CAN'T COME HOME.
OH, FOR FUCK'S SAKE.
YES, I'M ON THE JOB.
I WILL TAKE HIM TO SCHOOL.
OKAY, IT'S DONE.
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ SIGHS ]
[ DIALING ]
[ Ringing ]
CAN YOU HOOK ME UP WITH JOHN?
JOHN, MARK.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
YEAH, SHE'S ASLEEP.
THINK YOU CAN BOOK HER TOMORROW
OR NOT?
[ CREAKING ]
[ CELLPHONE BEEPS ]
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
>> THAT'S NOT GONNA HELP YOU,
HONEY.
>> AAH!
EMILY, HELP ME.
>> I TELL PEOPLE TO LEAVE, BUT
NOBODY EVER LISTENS.
>> THIS ISN'T HAPPENING!
NO!
>> 1304, 1303.
THIS IS...
>> MOM?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
GET OUT OF HERE!
>> LARA.
>> YOU NEED TO LEAVE!
GET OUT OF HERE NOW!
>> WHAT DID YOU DO?
>> I DIDN'T DO IT.
IT WASN'T ME.
>> SWEETHEART.
DID HE ATTACK YOU?
>> YOU! IT WAS YOU!
YOU KILLED JANET!
YOU DID IT!
>> SWEETHEART, SWEETHEART.
GIVE ME THAT KNIFE.
IT'S OKAY.
I-I'M HERE.
GIVE ME THAT KNIFE.
>> YOU DID IT!
AAH!
>> [ GRUNTING ]
>> OH, GOD!
OH, GOD!
NO! OH, GOD!
NO! MOM!
>> [ GASPING ]
>> NO!
MOM!
[ SOBBING ]
[ SOBBING CONTINUES ]
MOM!
[ SIRENS WAILING ]
[ POLICE RADIO CHATTER ]
[ HELICOPTER WHIRRING ]
I KNOW YOU DON'T BELIEVE ME.
I DIDN'T KILL ANYBODY.
JENNIFER LOGAN AND HER MOTHER
STILL LIVE HERE, AND THEY KILL
PEOPLE.
EVERYONE ON THIS FLOOR IS DEAD.
>> APARTMENTS DON'T KILL PEOPLE,
LARA.
PEOPLE KILL PEOPLE.
IT'S TIME TO GO HERE.
COME ON.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
ONE, TWO, THREE.
YOU HAVE THE RIGHT TO REMAIN
SILENT.
EVERYTHING YOU SAY MAY AND WILL
BE USED AGAINST YOU IN A COURT
OF LAW.
>> [ Rapping ] ♪ CHECK ♪
♪ WHEN I WAS 4, MY MAMA LOOKED
AT ME AND SAID I'D GO FAR ♪
♪ AND FROM THAT MOMENT ON, SHE
KNEW I'M A STAR ♪
♪ WHEN I WAS 4, MY MAMA LOOKED
AT ME AND SAID I'D GO FAR ♪
♪ AND FROM THAT MOMENT ON, SHE
KNEW I'M A STAR ♪
♪ I'M A STAR ♪
♪ AND FROM THAT MOMENT ON, SHE
KNEW I'M A STAR ♪
♪ SEE THE ICE, SEE THE CAR ♪
♪ SEE THE LIGHTS, SEE THE
BROAD ♪
♪ SEE MY LIFE GOING FAR ♪
♪ YEAH, YOU KNOW I'M A STAR ♪
♪ SEE THE LIGHTS FROM AFAR
SHININ' BRIGHT WHEN I BRAWL ♪
♪ EVERY NIGHT GOING HARD ♪
♪ YEAH, YOU KNOW I'M A STAR ♪
♪ I'M A STAR ♪
♪ LOOK HOW MY CHAIN HANG ♪
♪ SEE HOW MY GANG SPEAK ♪
♪ I'M ON THAT RIGHTEOUS
SUPERNOVA STAR FLAME DISH ♪
♪ YEAH ♪
♪ AND THAT'S EXACTLY WHAT I
CLAIM SHIT ♪
♪ MONEY OVER EVERYTHING AND FAME
OVER FAME ♪
♪ GREAT ♪
♪ PREFER THE DROP-TOP COUPE OR
OR THE RAIN STICK ♪
♪ WOOD-GRAIN PANELS TO THE FLOOR
WITH THE PAINT SLICK ♪
♪ MY FAN PAID AND MEETS FANDOM
MORE THAN MAKES IT ♪
♪ HELICOPTER DOORS AND THE SEATS
YOU CAN SAVE ♪
♪ AIN'T GOT TIME ♪
♪ YOU CHANGE CARS LIKE YOU
CHANGE DRAWERS ♪
♪ AND CHANGE RIMS ON TIRES LIKE
WE CHANGE BROADS ♪
♪ TWO OF MY BROTHERS STILL OUT ♪
♪ WE AIN'T GONNA CHANGE ♪
♪ FILES AND MUSIC FOR LIFE, AND
I'LL BET I SWEAR IT WILL
CHANGE ♪
♪ Y'ALL ARE SPITTIN' OUT ♪
♪ I'M THE BODY ON THE STREET ♪
♪ GET A GROUP, THINK YOU JUST
CONVENED, SWALLOWED BY A BEAST ♪
♪ MONEY ON THE MIND ♪
♪ WE AIM TO THE TOP IS WHAT WE
SEE ♪
♪ ZERO-GRAVITATIONAL PULLING,
RAMPING IN MY REACH ♪
♪ I'M A STAR ♪
♪ SEE THE ICE, SEE THE CAR ♪
♪ SEE THE LIGHTS, SEE THE
BROAD ♪
♪ SEE MY LIFE GOING FAR ♪
♪ YEAH, YOU KNOW I'M A STAR ♪
♪ SEE THE LIGHTS FROM AFAR
SHININ' BRIGHT WHEN I BRAWL ♪
♪ EVERY NIGHT GOING HARD ♪
♪ YEAH, YOU KNOW I'M A STAR ♪
♪ I'M A STAR ♪