First time giving blood?
Yes.
They pay cash here.
And there’s no limit
to how many times you give.
They even buy it
in the jar.
Jared Nomak,
we’re ready for you.
In the past 12 months,
have you gotten a tattoo,
or undergone any ear,
skin, or body piercings?
No.
Where did you get
that scar on your chin?
Childhood accident.
You say you don’t have
any immediate next of kin,
- is that right?
- Not that I’m in contact with.
Nobody to call in case
of an emergency?
No one.
- No family?
- I told you, no.
Are you telling me
I can’t be a donor?
It depends.
We came up
with some unusual results
on your blood test.
What?
How unusual?
Let me explain.
Your blood has
a very rare phenotype,
one we haven’t
encountered before.
What? What are you
talking about?
- Who are you? No.
- Sit down, please.
What is this?
This is a good news-bad news
scenario, Jared.
Good news for us...
bad news...
...for you.
Forget what you think
you know--
vampires exist.
My name is Blade.
I was born half human,
half vampire.
They call me
"The Daywalker."
I have all their strengths,
none of their weaknesses.
Except for the thirst.
20 years ago I met a man
that changed that.
Whistler.
He taught me how to hold
the thirst at bay.
Taught me the rules.
Gave me the weapons
to hunt with.
Silver, garlic,
sunlight.
Two years ago
he was attacked.
They took him,
and turned him into
the thing I hate most.
I should have
finished him off.
Now I’m hunting him.
I will find him.
And nothing will stand
in my way.
Daywalker’s here!
Stop him!
Where is he?
Hey!
No, no.
Take me to him, and I’ll
consider you a loose end.
Catch you later.
Old man... Look at what
they’ve done to you.
Let’s go home.
Lock up your daughters,
boys and girls,
the dark knight returns.
- Need a toke of the smokage, B?
- Later.
Cut the lights.
You found him.
You didn’t kill him.
Give me a hand.
I got a bad feeling
about this, B.
Listen to his breathing.
He’s already dying. He’s in pain.
Why don’t you just put him
out of his misery right now?
They had him on stasis
in a halfway house.
I’m giving him an accelerated
retro-viral detox.
Like a heroin addict.
Make him go cold turkey
in one night.
Shit ain’t
going to work, man.
I say you kill the motherfucker
right now.
Get out.
If there’s anything left
of you in there, Whistler,
Listen up.
In the morning those blinds
are going to open
whether you’re cured...
or not.
Hey, man,
I didn’t mean to call him--
Listen to me, Blade.
You’re going to have
to finish me off.
No.
Give me
that damn gun.
Now walk away.
Stubborn son of a bitch.
How do you feel?
Like hammered shit.
How’d you find me?
I started out in Moscow.
Then Romania.
- They kept moving you around.
- How long was I gone?
- Months?
- Too long.
Years.
They tortured me
almost to death.
And then let me heal
in a vat of blood
so they could go
at it again.
Sorry sons of bitches
could have at least
fixed my goddamn leg
while they were at it.
Where’s my arc welder?
What’s up? Nice to meet you.
I heard a lot about you.
I’m Josh. You can call me "Scud."
Everybody does.
Tell me something, Skid--
No, man, it’s "Scud,"
like "Stud."
Whatever.
- What are you doing here?
- The pimpmobile?
Just a little aftermarket
modification.
- Nitrous oxide and shit like that.
- Oh, yeah.
You gave it a more aggressive
exhaust profile ramping.
The whole package will crank
that Betty up, maybe 300 horsepower.
You’ll burn the thing out
before your next oil change.
Where did you dig up
this shitbird, anyway?
What the fuck
is your problem, Poppy?
My problem is I’ve been
sucking blood clots for two years.
I get out to find some jerkoff
fucking with my life’s work.
We jeopardized our whole
operation to save your ass!
- Our operation?
- Yeah.
Our operation? I built
this operation, you ass-wipe!
Motion sensors!
It’s on three, gentlemen.
Human?
Body temperature, 50.
I’d guess suckhead.
Fried. They’re using
magnesium flares.
They’ve got your security
system scoped out.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
I don’t trust you--
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Cool outfit.
Guard lights!
We represent the ruling body
of the Vampire Nation.
They are offering you
a truce.
They want to meet
with you.
Scud.
Take off your mask.
My name is Asad.
This is Nyssa.
You have been our most
feared enemy.
But now there’s something else
loose on the streets.
Something worse
than you.
What’s so funny?
They tell stories about Blade
as the Bogeyman.
Frankly,
I’m disappointed.
You hear that, B?
She’s disappointed.
He agreed
to come along so easily.
Come on, B, show her.
Pretty please?
Semtex.
Enough explosives
to level a city block.
You still disappointed?
The guards look human.
They’re probably familiars.
You sure about this?
Well, if I’m not...
The true power
of the Vampire Nation lies here.
Father?
Blade, this is
Overlord Eli Damaskinos.
It has been said,
"Be proud of your enemy
and enjoy his success."
In that regard,
I should thank you.
- For what?
- Eliminating Deacon Frost.
You did us a favor.
Karel Kounen.
- You’re human.
- Barely. I’m a lawyer.
European Health Consortium.
As you may know,
Vampirism is...
a horrible virus, carried
in the saliva of predators.
In 72 hours, it spreads through
the human bloodstream,
creating new
parasitic organs.
Like cancer.
Cancer with a purpose.
Unfortunately,
viruses evolve, too.
We’ve encountered
a new one.
We dubbed it
the Reaper Strain.
And like any good pathogen,
it appears to have found a carrier.
There...
Jared Nomak.
Born a vampire,
but an anomaly like you.
Unlike the rest of us,
however,
he feeds on not just humans,
but vampires as well.
- Looks like he was doing me a favor.
- You’re missing the point.
Their vampire victims
don’t die...
they turn.
They become carriers.
You’ve got to understand.
These things are like crack addicts.
They need to feed daily.
Nomak’s been up for 72 hours.
By our estimates, there are already
a dozen Reapers.
There’ll be hundreds
before the week is out.
Thousands within a matter of months.
Do the math.
Wait. Let me get
this right.
You want me
to hunt them... for you?
When they are finished
with us,
who do you think
they’ll turn on next?
Your precious humans.
Not one of them
will be left.
We spent two years training
a small tactical unit--
The Bloodpack.
We want you to lead them.
Two years?
We’ve been training
to hunt you.
So, B-man,
what do you think?
Sounds like a plan.
What do you really think?
They’re going to fuck us
the first chance they get.
So, we ain’t
gonna do this, right?
We’ll play along for now.
They’ll take us in deeper
than we’ve ever been.
Get a chance to see
how their world really ticks.
I had enough of their world.
They’re just shitting bricks
because they’re no longer
top of the food chain.
Damn, man,
I’m really worried about him.
I know he’s
your friend and all,
but I think you should
watch him.
Nobody goes cold turkey
from the thirst in just one night.
Looking to get
hooked up?
Maybe.
What do you have?
No problem.
Horse, Hawaiian Ice,
whatever you need.
Whatever I need.
I like that.
What if I need you?
So, so sweet.
They are ready
whenever you are, Daywalker.
Blade,
meet The Bloodpack.
Lighthammer,
Verlaine,
Priest,
Snowman,
Chupa,
and Reinhardt.
Hey, um...
me and the gang
were wondering...
What was that?
Can you blush?
Here we go.
Oh, I get it.
I see now.
You’ve been training for two years
to take me out.
And now, here I am.
Ooh, so exciting,
isn’t it?
Okay, here’s your chance.
Come on.
What are you waiting for?
Here I am.
Right here in front of you.
Adolf here gets the first shot.
Come on.
What are you looking at her for?
You need permission?
Maybe you need
a little bit of incentive.
Okay, I can help
with that.
What’s the matter?
Missed that?
It’s okay,
I can do it again.
Come on.
What, do you need a manual?
- Do it!
- Kill the bastard!
Now you’ve got an explosive device
stuck to the back of your head.
Silver nitrate. Rigged to go off
if anybody tampers with it.
I’ll have
the detonator with me.
And you-- if you so much
as look at me wrong--
From now on
we work as a unit.
You’ll be taking
orders from me.
Any questions?
Good.
You want to catch the hunter?
You start with the prey.
We’ll target all the night places
where vampires congregate.
Blood banks, safe houses.
The bigger the better.
So... what’s first?
The House of Pain.
Where’s the entrance?
I don’t see any signs.
No vampire glyphs.
No, because of you,
we’ve had to rethink our habits,
tighten our security.
Have a closer look.
Nice.
.38, .45
and 9mm caliber.
All with foil capsules
at the tip
filled with silver nitrate,
and garlic extract.
This hyper-velocity
stake gun
spits out a silver stake
at 6,000 feet per second.
Since you suckers
don’t like sunlight,
we’ve modified the gun’s
entry light with a UV filter.
Pop it open--
instant UV light.
Filter’s on,
no problem.
Yo, B, check this out.
It’s got an pneumatic
syringe delivery system.
The vials are filled with
an anti-coagulant called EDTA.
One punch with this, you’ll blow
your target up like a balloon.
The cartridge ejects.
Automatic reload.
Nice.
- Let’s go.
- You won’t pass for one of us.
- Like I give a shit.
- No, he’s right.
Why don’t you post up
on the roof over there?
Cover our backs.
So the Bloodpack’s calling
the shots now, huh?
Great.
Better curb that dog of yours
or we’ll do it for you.
Keep pushing, asshole.
[M] I ya, I against I [M]
[M] Flesh of my flesh
and mind of my mind [M]
[M] Two of a kind,
but one won’t survive [M]
[M] My images reflect
in the enemy’s eye [M]
[M] And his images reflect
in mine the same time [M]
[M] I ya, I ya, I against I [M]
[M] Flesh of my flesh
and mind of my mind [M]
[M] Two of a kind,
but one won’t survive [M]
[M] Survive, survive,
survive. [M]
We’re in.
You’re about
to enter our world.
You will see things--
feeding.
Just remember
why you’re here.
I haven’t forgotten.
What exactly
are we looking for in here?
Anything that looks
suspicious.
You got to be
kidding me.
Scud, do you read me?
- Scud, you reading me?
- Reading you loud and clear.
The whole place
is a safe house.
The windows are painted black,
one access door.
- 200, 300 suckheads in here.
- That sounds cool.
Hey, W, you got me?
W?
Tell me something,
how’s the weather up there?
Walkin’ on sunshine,
toad boy.
Look at them.
Half of these bastards,
they’re not even
pure bloods.
I tell you what, why don’t we
just fucking kill everyone?
Just to make sure.
God, it would be
so easy.
He’s got you.
Daywalker.
Mother’s milk.
I say we got about half an hour
till sunrise, Cinderella.
Hurry up.
I spotted one,
but lost it.
Be on the lookout.
Fuck.
Whistler, they’re
on the roof.
I got them on the roof
of my bus.
Shhh.
Nomak.
Daywalker.
What am I to you?
Is the enemy
of my enemy my friend...
or my enemy?
We’re under attack!
There’s three of them.
Probably more.
Daylight.
Silver don’t do jack shit.
Don’t waste the bullets!
- Motherfucker.
- You hear me, Chupa?
Say, "cheese."
Come on.
How about some daylight,
motherfucker?
Fuck!
Listen to me. If you’re under attack,
use your UV lights.
Use your UV lights.
They can’t take the light.
Priest?
We’re not dying here.
- Come on.
- Priest is down.
Daylight’s coming.
You’re on your own, Blade.
You want me so bad, Blade?
Here I am.
Why kill me?
You and I,
we have the same enemy.
We want the same thing.
We need the same thing,
Blade.
What happened?
Why didn’t you tell me
these things
- were immune to silver and garlic?
- I didn’t know.