[♪]
All kids are afraid
of the Boogeyman.
Henry and I
were no different.
Even before that night.
[RAIN FALLING, THUNDER RUMBLING]
[GIRL SCREAMS]
- It's the one I wanted.
- You sure?
We can always return it,
get something like school clothes.
I told them you wanted a dirt bike,
but they wouldn't listen.
Help me put it
together, Henry.
Sure, after I
use the bathroom.
- Who wants cake and ice cream?
- I do.
[CREAKING]
[FLIPPING SWITCH]
[BREATHING QUICKLY]
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[CLAPPING]
- Great job, sweetie.
- Thank you.
Didn't you go
to the bathroom, pal?
Yeah.
I thought we
talked about this.
You're 11 years
old now, bud.
The hallway light burned out again.
Will you fix it?
See? Nothing
to worry about.
[CREAKS]
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[ELECTRICITY SPUTTERS]
Daddy.
[PANTING]
[SCREAMING]
[SLASHING]
[CRYING]
Henry! I saw him.
I saw the Boogeyman.
He is real.
[MOM SCREAMS]
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
No, no!
[CREAKING]
No!
[SCREAMS]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
When the police came,
he was gone.
But only for
the time being.
Are you still afraid
of the Boogeyman?
No, of course not.
I just meant...
what happened to my parents
is still vivid to me.
I'm really sorry, Laura.
No one should have
to go through that.
Henry said that the
intruder wasn't caught.
Yeah.
Do you and Henry
ever talk about it?
No.
We talk around it.
It's what people do, you know.
It's not easy admitting you're
afraid of the Boogeyman.
Even to your
own sister.
The three months that
Henry's been here,
we've been able
to help him.
If you're open
to this program--
It's okay.
I'm 18 now. I'm fine.
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey.
Mmm!
[LAURA CHUCKLES]
I hope I'm, uh,
not interrupting.
Well, I'm gonna
miss you.
- I'm here if you need to talk, okay?
- Okay.
Either one of you.
Thank you.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
I can't even tell you
how much I miss this.
Seriously, I have not had
Marsha-Marsha-Marshmallow
since you left
for the clinic.
I meant you.
You know,
us hanging out.
I knew what you meant.
I just missed Marsha more.
So, tonight, your favorite
TV shows--
TiVo'd and ready to go,
your lasagna...
and I thought maybe
we'd stop by the mall
and get you
some shirts
that don't have paint and
sweat stains on them.
I, uh, I have
a job interview tomorrow.
Already? Where?
When did you do that?
It's a printing company
in San Francisco.
I applied online
at the clinic.
Wow.
That's great, Henry.
Yeah, yeah. I mean, it's perfect.
They do lithography.
It's like, uh,
like silkscreen,
but for, you know,
posters and stuff.
The guy saw my work
and he loves it.
He said I could use
some of his equipment
for my own stuff
if I wanted.
San Francisco's
just so far away.
I mean, you would have
to live on your own.
You sure you
could do that?
Well, yeah.
Yeah, you know.
I mean,
I can do it now.
The Hillridge Clinic, it really
made me a different person.
[SIREN BLARES]
It would've been nice if you
included me in your decision.
I'm including you now.
No, now you're
telling me.
You know,
we should go.
I shouldn't have had this ice cream.
It's freezing.
I'm sorry, all right?
It's just an interview.
We can talk about it
when I get back.
Just forget it,
okay?
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
[KNOCKS]
Want some help?
Look, I'm sorry
about earlier.
What, now you're not
gonna talk to me?
[CREAKING]
[SQUELCHING]
Henry?
Henry!
[BLADE RINGS]
No!
Shh, shh, shh.
It's okay, it's okay.
I'm here.
When did you do this?
While you were gone.
It got really bad.
Every time
I closed my eyes,
I could see him.
He's been waiting.
- Waiting?
- For us to be apart.
I always told you
that I could handle it,
that you were the one
that needed help.
But the truth is...
I don't want you
to go, Henry.
I can't do
this on my own.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
You can call me whenever you want.
You know that, right?
Yeah. I have
my cell phone.
That won't do you
any good out here.
You're just
gonna have to settle
for what us old-timers
call a landline.
Cut off from
the rest of the world.
No cell phone.
Lockdown every night.
I'm really starting
to reconsider.
Laura, the lockdown is just
an insurance precaution
for the hospital proper.
It helps the administration
sleep better at night
knowing that
the building is secure.
You mean making sure
the crazy people
aren't roaming
the halls. Got ya.
The night staff is here
if you need them.
And you will have
phone access 24/7.
What do you say?
You want
to see your room?
Sure.
Look, I'll--
I'll check in
as soon as my interview
is done tomorrow, okay?
You promise?
On my life.
You know,
the people here,
they're just like
you and me.
They're not as crazy
as you think.
Stay away from me,
you crazy bitch!
I'm just trying
to urinate!
- Whoa, Nicky, this is--
- Complete bullshit!
Talk to Dr. Allen and make
him call off his henchmen.
I'm sorry, Dr. Ryan.
We just finished her weekly weigh-in.
I found her sneaking
in the bathroom.
DR. RYAN: Let's talk
about this later.
Nicky, I want you to stop by
my office in a few minutes.
But I didn't
do anything.
I know. But I want you
to see me anyway.
This is Laura Porter.
She's Henry's sister.
- She's going to join our--
- Whatever.
There's really a nice girl
hiding inside of Nicky.
Yeah, well, maybe one of them
should try eating a sandwich.
I didn't realize
bulimia was a fear.
It's not. She suffers from
a fear of gaining weight.
So this is
Henry's old room.
He painted this
while he was here.
- Do you want me to take it down?
- No. Leave it up.
He always said when things
were too dark growing up
that you were the one
to pull him out.
Funny. I could say
the same thing about him.
Laura, I'm very happy
that you're here.
I'm gonna let
you unpack.
Then you can meet the other
patients and Dr. Allen.
Dr. Allen?
He's head of the hospital
psychiatric department.
I'll see you
in group.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[PANTING]
[SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
Sorry, sorry, I didn't
mean to scare you.
Your door was open,
so I just wanted
to come in and say hi.
Hi. I'm Mark.
Laura.
And this charming guy
behind me,
that's Paul.
- Hi.
Uh, germophobe.
Don't take
it personally.
Oh.
Um, my light
in my closet went out.
Would you mind
taking a look?
I'll get it.
Thanks, bud.
So, looks like we have
something in common, huh?
It's the dark.
He's terrified of it.
For me, it's not
so much the dark.
It's what lives
in the dark.
You must be
Henry's sister.
Pretty stupid, huh?
Everyone's afraid
of something.
Hillridge Clinic,
Santa Barbara County,
January 22.
Dr. Jessica Ryan's
severe phobia
group therapy session.
Dr. Mitchell Allen,
hospital administrator,
supervising.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
I'm afraid of losing control
of my life, so I cut.
Cut? You mean...
Most people try to deal with
their emotions internally,
but Alison finds
that overwhelming.
ALISON: It's really
more like impossible.
But with one cut, all the
internal stuff becomes external.
I can just deal
with it, you know.
But then if I stop...
I'm afraid to stop.
What about you?
What's your deal?
Same thing as my brother.
I saw my parents killed
when I was a kid.
The police
never found the guy.
Well, you can't catch
the Boogeyman, right?
He hasn't had
a problem finding me.
He? You continue
to see this he?
[BELL TOLLING]
I don't always see him.
- Sometimes you just--
- You feel him.
I felt him.
Here, in this place.
Alison, that's not
constructive in any way.
What? We're all here
because we have shit to
deal with from our past.
Just because somebody comes and
gives it a name and a face
doesn't mean
it's not real.
Laura's fear
is less ethereal.
She fears
a specific entity.
The clinical term
is bogyphobia.
[LAUGHS]
Bogyphobia?
Are you fucking kidding me?
Here I thought you were suffering
from some serious ailment,
like, uh,
Easter Bunny phobia.
Scared
of Santa Claus, too?
Okay, all right.
Are you guys finished yet?
Laura.
- Laura!
- I'm kinda scared of Santa Claus.
What the fuck
is wrong with you guys?
That's it? You're just
gonna throw in the towel?
Nicky's right.
I'm wasting everybody's time.
Shit!
You know, I've
lived with this
for ten years
and managed.
But when you're
really alone,
there may come a time
when you can't manage.
'Cause I know
I didn't.
Look, Laura...
My mother spent
her entire life
in an institution
battling schizophrenia.
And every month my dad would
take me there to visit her.
It was different then.
It was electroshock therapy
and sensory deprivation.
It turned her
into a vegetable.
She would just stare
at the wall and mumble.
It was probably the worst
sound in the world.
And then I found out
that it was hereditary,
and I was so scared I was
going to become her one day.
Until I faced my fear.
How?
By studying it.
I became
a psychiatrist
because I wanted to
understand the illness.
Laura, you just--
you have
to expose the fear
and really look at it,
and you will get better.
But it's
your choice.
[FOOTSTEPS WALKING AWAY]
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
Good night,
Gloria.
Buzz me out.
[BUZZES]
See you tomorrow.
[DOOR OPENS]
[HARD ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
- Yo, Mark.
- Yeah.
- That package arrived.
- It did?
- The one you've been waiting for.
- Halftime, all right?
- Thank you very much.
- Cool.
Hey, uh, not
on the floor.
I turned the basement lights on.
Yeah, sure,
no problem. Thanks.
[HAMMERING]
[LIGHT HUMMING]
Ahh.
Yeah.
Hey, ladies.
[METAL DOOR CLANGS]
Fuck, fuck, fuck!
Ow, fuck!
[SECONDARY DOOR OPENS]
Perry?
Hey, I'm still down here!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
I'm still down here!
Wait, I'm still down here!
Help me!
Jesus Christ! Help me!
I'm down here! Please!
Help!
[BLADE RINGS]
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
[METALLIC THUDDING]
[FIRE ALARM RINGING]
Is anybody there?
[ELEVATOR CLANGING]
Hello?
[POWER FADES UP]
[SCREAMS]
How did he--
I mean, you
just don't fall
into an elevator shaft.
You do if it's dark
and you're baked
on Perry's hydroponic
pick-of-the-day.
Sorry, I don't mean
to state the obvious,
but wasn't Mark
afraid of the dark?
The police think that Mark's
fear instigated his fall.
He turned off the lights
to avoid being caught.
Once it was dark,
he panicked.
He...
But I heard Gloria tell
the police that he was...
cut in half.
I mean, that doesn't sound
like an accident to me.
Apparently he tried to climb
out of the elevator shaft,
but he only got halfway
into the basement
before the car
came down on him.
[GASPS] Every time
I think about it
and all the blood--
Whose chair is this?
Doctor, this isn't my chair.
This isn't my chair.
Who stole my chair?
Who stole it?
Paul, right over here.
Is that it there?
Breathe. You need to breathe.
Come here, let me feel.
I've got it right here.
Let me help you and get that off.
PAUL: Mark was
the only one
who actually believed I could
get better. [SNIFFLES]
He made me
believe it, too.
We'll take as much time as is
needed to absorb Mark's accident.
No, don't.
It doesn't sound
like an accident to me.
I think somebody else
turned the lights off.
Like who, Laura?
Maybe it was
the Boogeyman.
Nicky.
Maybe it was.
This is
counterproductive.
Counterproductive?
Laura has as
much right as anyone
to share her fear
with the group.
I'm sorry.
Let's reconvene
later today, okay?
HENRY: Whoa, whoa, whoa,
slow down. Who's dead?
LAURA: Mark fell into
an elevator shaft.
I think maybe
somebody killed him.
- Henry?
- Yeah. I'm here.
Look, I've been
driving all night
and I just got
to my interview.
I'll head straight back there
the second I'm done.
- You don't believe me?
- No, I didn't say that. I just--
I've been there.
Whenever something bad happened,
I thought he was
coming back to finish
what he started
when we were kids.
But now you're ready
to leave the past behind
and throw me
away with it.
- No, Laura.
- I've gotta go.
If I drive
through the night,
I'll make it
there by 5 a.m.
Just sit tight, okay?
Hurry.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
I had maintenance
fix that for you.
I'm sorry if you were
upset this afternoon.
- I didn't intend--
- I'm fine.
I'm leaving tomorrow
morning anyways.
What you fear doesn't live
inside that closet, Laura.
It lives inside you.
Can you remove
it surgically,
or do I need
an exorcism?
You know, we've
always struggled
to understand
the darkness within us,
fears and anxieties
buried so deeply
that they're just
too painful to face.
And you think my darkness
is the Boogeyman.
But how does
that describe
what I've seen
with my own eyes,
what other kids have seen
throughout history?
Well, it's
a common scapegoat.
Our society will always
find a way to externalize.
Every culture
around the world
has a name for him.
The words
sound different,
but they all describe
the same being.
How does your theory
account for that?
We're all afraid
of the same thing.
The Boogeyman,
germophobia--
they're all masks,
masks that
we create to hide
what we're
truly afraid of.
What do you think
I'm truly afraid of?
Well...
If you're
willing to stay,
willing to accept
that your fear
comes from within,
maybe we'll find out.
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
Hello, Jessica.
I didn't know you
were still here.
I'm thinking about staying
overnight, actually.
We're short-staffed now
that Perry's been fired,
and I'm really concerned
how everyone's
been affected
by Mark's death.
Jessica...
The board's gonna have
a lot of questions
about what happened
here today.
Mark's accident
has nothing to do
with my program.
Your program?
Your experiment.
The board has always
thought that putting
this particular group
of patients
together
was a mistake.
And, quite frankly,
I'm beginning
to agree with them.
I'm really sorry
to hear that.
[WATER RUNNING]
[GURGLING]
- I'm sorry.
- Get the fuck out now!
[ELECTRICITY SPUTTERS]
Christ! Watch
where you're going.
Do me a favor.
Walk with me and follow me
in my room.
No, thanks, I'll pass.
Come on,
I'll owe you one.
Common sense dictates
I shouldn't ask,
but what's
the bucket for?
We all have
our own way
of dealing with
Mark's death.
Isn't that why you went
off on Henry earlier?
No, but thanks
for listening in.
Henry always
said you were
the reason he wanted
to get better,
because he didn't want
to hold you back.
He told you that?
Every day he was here.
I never meant
to hurt him.
I just...
You and Darren?
Once upon a time.
And he's in here
because...
he's afraid of being
anything but an asshole?
Agoraphobic.
Completely terrified
of the outside world.
You'd never know by looking
at him, though, right?
He's cute. I see why
you fell for him.
Don't think just because he
pays you a little attention
he's actually
interested in you.
- I was just saying--
- Will you leave?
- Whoa, Nicky.
- I wanna be alone!
- I'm not even interested--
- Get out!
[SCRUBBING]
Paul?
Paul, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
We missed you at dinner.
Yeah, well,
you see this mess.
Well, if you
want to talk,
I'll be
in my room, okay?
[COUGHING]
Hey, Paul?
Paul.
- Oh, God!
- Get help now!
Come on, buddy.
[SCREAMING]
- Oh, my God!
- Somebody yelled.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Paul!
Get help!
DARREN: I think
he's dead.
What happened?
Call down to the hospital.
I want some paramedics up here.
He must've swallowed it.
What, you mean,
like, on purpose?
You think he killed--
The phones are dead.
I can't get a dial tone.
I can't get
a pulse.
Jesus Christ!
Go down to the hospital.
I want you to find someone--
No, we can't buzz open
the doors with no phones.
Well, doesn't somebody
have a key?
Dr. Allen has
an overriding key.
There has to be
an emergency exit.
Do you know how much older this
place is than the hospital?
You're telling me we're stuck
here until the morning,
until Dr. Allen comes?
No! No, there's no way!
We have to get out!
Alison! Alison!
I'm sure the phones are
only out temporarily, okay?
Hey, Henry will be here
at 5:00 at the latest.
He'll get someone
to open those doors, okay?
Laura, take everybody
down to the rec room.
Okay, come on.
Go on, go on.
Come on.
I need you to help
me to cover him up.
Let's just leave him
right here, okay?
Go ahead.
You check on the kids.
Jesus, Paul, what the
hell happened to you?
It's still out.
Somebody is bound to
pass by sooner or later.
Why don't you go down
to the basement
and check
the computer system?
It integrates the phone lines
with the security system.
Maybe it just
went off-line.
I'd really appreciate
your help.
Okay.
If I see someone,
I'll flag 'em down.
How are you
holding up?
[SOBBING]
What was it
that Paul drank?
It was this mixture
that he made
out of industrial-
strength cleaners
because he
couldn't find one
that was
strong enough.
Why would Paul have
a cockroach problem?
He wouldn't.
He kept all his food in one
of those airtight things.
There was a cockroach.
It crawled under his bed.
There was food
all over his floor.
Well, that's
not like him.
No, food attracts bugs,
and bugs have germs.
And he would've been terrified
at the thought of it.
Just like Mark would've been
terrified of a dark basement.
Wait, you actually think
she makes sense?
Nothing that's happened
in the past 24 hours
really makes sense.
Jesus Christ,
what does it matter?
Paul killed himself,
someone killed Paul--
either way, it's just one less
person whining in group tomorrow.
You might wanna watch
how hard you sell that!
And what the fuck
were you doing
in his room,
anyway, Darren?
It was him.
I saw him in the
hallway earlier, okay?
He preys on our fears.
That's it.
I'm outta here.
[DOOR SLAMS]
It's what he does.
He knows what scares us.
[BELL TOLLING,
CRICKETS CHIRPING]
[DOOR OPENS]
[WIND WHISTLING]
Gloria?
Gloria.
[KNOCKING]
Hey, any luck
with the phones?
Gloria's reconnecting
the system.
Have you seen
Darren or Nicky?
A few minutes ago. Why?
It's not important.
Get some rest.
Gloria?
[DOOR CLOSES]
Gloria.
Oh, my God!
Who's that?
God, no, please!
Please, no!
[SCREAMING]
Someone there?
It's just me.
What the fuck are you
doin' in here?
I don't know
where else to go.
What are you
talking about?
Mark and Paul
are dead.
Yeah. I was there,
remember?
I know you, Darren.
It must have been terrible
finding Paul like that.
But you can't keep
shutting me out.
You're the only person
here that I trust.
Why did you end up
hating me so much?
- What did I do?
- You didn't do anything, Nicky.
Then it's the way
that I look?
Did I get too thin?
I'm the one
with the problem, not you.
Bullshit!
Nicky, what
I'm dealing with...
It's not just being afraid
of the outside world.
You know, it's...
It's the people
out there, too.
So you don't think
I'm disgusting?
I'm agoraphobic.
I'm not blind.
[SHRIEKING]
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
[MOANS]
[GROANING]
Alison?
Hey, are you awake?
[GASPS]
Oh, my God!
Alison, Alison.
Help! Nicky!
Somebody! Help!
Nicky!
Somebody!
Come on, somebody
out there! Please!
What was that?
I don't know.
Anybody!
Laura! What's wrong?
Somebody killed Alison.
We have to find Dr. Ryan.
- What are you talking about?
- DARREN: What's going on?
Alison's dead.
Somebody cut her open.
- Where's Dr. Ryan?
- I don't know. Everybody's gone!
Come on, I'll show you.
Right here.
There was blood
e-everywhere.
- He must've cleaned it up.
- Who cleaned it up?
It was...
Who, Laura?
Alison was lying
in this bed.
Her arms were cut
to shreds.
She was probably
in the middle
of a cutting session
and you interrupted her.
There were maggots crawling out
from underneath her skin.
It was like she was
trying to cut them out.
You know what? Just stop!
Where's Alison?
- I just told you.
- No. No, where's Alison really?
Hello?
I already checked
up here.
Everyone
is missing.
She's right.
I don't see anybody.
Gloria went to the basement
a couple hours ago.
Maybe she's
still down there.
It doesn't take a couple
hours to restart a computer.
Guys, Dr. Allen
didn't sign out.
What Laura said about
people being forced
to face their fears--
who did that sound like?
You don't think Dr. Allen
could be behind this?
He's been fuckin'
sadistic lately.
Look at the way
he treated Laura.
He was afraid we'd start
buying into her theory.
Maybe he was afraid
I was right.
What about the time he
locked Henry in the closet?
What?
He refused to let him out
until he faced his fears.
You know him and his
"darkness within" bullshit!
I'm the first one
to bash on Dr. Allen,
but he wouldn't do
something like this.
What else
did he make Henry do?
[DOOR SLAMS OPEN]
Help! Somebody get us
the fuck outta here!
Keys, keys, keys, keys.
"Patient suffers from
delusions and hallucinations
related to his
childhood fear."
"Experiences blackouts similar
to those of previous patients
in which she has no recollection
of her violent behavior."
"Patient is
once again unable
"to differentiate
his own personality
"from the one he has created
for the Boogeyman.
"Refuses to accept blame
for the crimes
he has committed."
Oh, my God.
Shit!
Who's there?
Nicky?
She's out here, Darren.
- What's that?
- I found it in Dr. Allen's office.
- Any keys?
- No.
But you're right about
Dr. Allen being sadistic.
Before he came to the Hillridge
Clinic, he treated others like me.
- One was this guy-- Tim Jensen.
- So?
One night Jensen killed
a bunch of people.
Claimed
the Boogeyman did it.
Like a split personality
or something?
That's what
Dr. Allen thought.
Jensen ended up killing himself
under Dr. Allen's care.
He almost lost
his license over it.
He's just as afraid
as the rest of us.
He's terrified
that he's been wrong
about the Boogeyman
all along.
And then
you show up...
Allen's bad memories
resurface
and people start
dying, right?
Fuck this!
Darren, wait!
- Darren!
- Darren, stop it!
Why don't you just stay
the fuck away from me?
Darren!
- Darren, calm down!
- Leave me alone!
Listen! We need to fix the
computers in the basement...
- ...so we can get out of here.
- You think someone wants to kill us?
It could be Dr. Allen
or either one of you.
I'm gonna lock
myself in my room
until the morning staff
gets here.
I wanna stay
with you. Okay?
You guys, please, I can't
go down there by myself.
[ECHOING]
What are you doing?
The second someone shows up,
I'm outta here.
You can't just leave.
Watch me.
Where are we gonna go?
"We," Nicky? I've got news
for you--there's no "we."
I thought things were gonna
be different this time.
Darren, look, I know what
happened between us scares you.
No, you don't know. That's the
problem is you think you know.
You think you know me.
You think you have me
all figured out, right?
You have no idea
what kind of person
I really am.
You know, Nicky,
you're always
so worried
about fixing me.
Why don't you try
fixing yourself first?
Take a good look
at yourself.
- Don't, Darren!
- Try fixing yourself!
You know what?
Just get the fuck
out of here.
Just get the fuck out.
Just get the fuck
out of my room...
- ...and stop being so fucking pathetic!
- Ow! You're hurting me!
Deal with it!
You're lying
to yourself, Darren!
You'll end up dead
on the inside.
One day your heart's just
gonna shrivel up and rot away
before you ever have the chance
to share it with someone.
Fucker!
Fuck!
[ELECTRICITY BUZZING]
DARREN: I didn't want
to hurt Nicky.
I was just
so fucking scared.
She said that
she loved me and...
and I just--I felt
like I couldn't breathe.
DR. ALLEN: Well, this
is how we do it, Darren.
We conquer our fears
by facing them head on.
No fuckin' way.
Your reaction,
I think, tells us
something about
your illness.
[SCREAMING]
I suspect what you're truly
afraid of is opening up.
Fearful that
if you do, she will...
rip your heart
right out.
[SPURTING]
[SCREAMING]
[CREAKING]
[SOBBING]
[SCREAMING]
Darren!
No!
Help!
[SCRAPING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[FLOOR CREAKS]
[PANTS]
[SQUEAKING]
[DOOR SLAMS]
[MOANING]
Dr. Ryan?
It's him, okay?
He is real.
Oh, my God.
What did he do?
He is real.
Just like your mother.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
You have to be quiet.
Please, shh.
[DRAWN-OUT MUMBLING]
You have to be quiet.
He's gonna find us.
[CHUCKLES]
[KEENING]
He is real.
I'm sorry.
[CREAKING]
[WHIMPERS]
I'm sorry.
[MUFFLED BREATHING]
[ALARM SOUNDING]
Dr. Allen!
How'd you...
What are you doing?
Laura, everything's
gonna be fine.
The police are
on their way.
Now you and me are
gonna go upstairs
and have
a nice little talk.
No, no, no.
The Boogeyman,
he's here, okay?
We have to go.
No, he's not, Laura.
You should see
what he did to Nicky
and Darren
and Paul, too.
I found them.
What is that?
It's just a sedative,
Laura, that's all.
It's a sedative.
All right?
Now, come on.
Wait, wait. Do you
think that I did it?
Now, Laura, please,
don't make this difficult.
[SOBBING]
Stop!
Okay, listen to me.
Listen to me, okay?
If you'd have listened
to Tim Jensen,
he'd still be alive!
Tim Jensen?
He's right behind you!
Look! Look!
- He's not behind me!
- Yes, he is!
- He doesn't exist!
- Yes, he does! Look!
[PANTING]
In time you'll see
that I'm right.
No!
No! No! No!
It's okay, Laura. I'm here.
No! It's not you!
Henry!
Don't hurt me, please!
Laura, I would
never hurt you.
You hurt
the rest of them.
No.
Not me.
DR. ALLEN: Henry!
Stop it!
Leave her alone!
Try to remember, Henry.
Try to remember what
actually happened
the night that your
parents were killed.
He was waiting for me.
He was hiding from
my family in the closet.
The Boogeyman
wasn't there, Henry.
He wasn't there
when you were 11,
and he isn't there now.
See?
No, no,
I can't do it.
You don't have
a choice.
Stop! Hey!
No! What are you doing?
- Stay right there.
- Please help me!
[HENRY BANGING ON DOOR]
This is how you do it.
If you want to conquer
your fears,
you have to face them,
and face them head on.
Face the darkness
on your own.
Look him right
in the eye.
[CREAKING]
He's not real,
Henry.
He's only
in your head.
[CLATTERING]
[YELPING]
He has power over you
because you allow it.
He's in here!
Help me! Oh, God.
Help me!
I saw him.
I saw the Boogeyman.
He is--
He is real.
He's not real,
Henry.
He's only
in your head.
The night Mom and Dad died,
I should've done something.
What could you do?
You were 11.
I can help you.
- Help me?
- Yeah.
Like you always have?
I'm your older brother.
I should've been
taking care of you.
I was--I was
always so scared.
But the Boogeyman...
I looked
into his eyes...
and saw that he's
afraid of nothing.
But you killed them.
Mark, Paul...
Alison.
He forced them
to face their fear.
- Henry.
- You thought the Boogeyman...
...was your greatest fear.
You're wrong.
- He'll show you your true fear.
- Henry!
Stop it, Henry!
Stop!
No!
DR. ALLEN: Henry.
Henry.
Now, you listen to me.
I hurt you much more
than I helped you.
I'm sorry for that.
You suffered
a psychotic break.
But you did help me.
I'm completely cured.
- [FENCE RATTLES]
- DR. ALLEN: Oof!
[PANTING]
Let me go!
[GRUNTING]
[BANGING]
[SHRIEKS]
[GURGLING]
[BONE CRACKING]
[SCREAMING]
[DISPATCH BUZZES]
Dr. Allen's
records indicate
that your brother
was released
several days ago
in positive mental health.
Did you find her?
You're the one
currently being treated
for Boogeyman-related delusions.
Is that correct?
Dr. Ryan--
did you find her?
I told you,
we searched twice.
Except for you,
we didn't find any survivors.
Detective, there's something
in here you need to see.
Well, I think
we found the last body.
No.
DETECTIVE: I think you're
gonna have to come with us.
No.
FEMALE COP: We're gonna
need some help in here.
Henry. He's still
in here, okay?
You have to listen
to me, okay?
Henry's still in here.
Henry's still in here!
You have to find him.
He's still in here.
Henry's still in here!
Listen to me!
[♪]