(LIGHTNING STRIKING)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO:
Tropical storm warnings
are now in effect
for all of
the Gulf Coast.
We're looking at
a strong Category 3,
so board up those windows
and get ready
for a wild ride.
Folks,
there are emergency shelters
being set up in King County
and Scarborough County.
(SWITCHING CHANNEL)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(OPENING CAR DOOR)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Howie!
Johnny Gavineau.
You got the permit?
Yes, I do.
(CLANKING)
This is against
my better judgment.
(SIGHS)
Okay. Let's get to it.
JOHNNY: Yeah, I gotta
get back to the coast.
(CLEARING THROAT)
There's a hurricane coming.
I got property there.
I gotta get the place
battened down.
(GROWLING)
Never touch the cage.
Was he trained?
Trained how?
Jump through a hoop
on fire?
He can do that?
No.
Well, does he
just sit there
and look pretty?
I thought he
was a circus cat.
Circus don't want him.
(TIGER ROARS)
Look, I'm starting
a safari ranch.
This is my
main attraction.
I need, you know,
a scary animal.
Scary?
Yeah. That's what
the tourists pay to see.
I don't think this
cat's scary enough.
I'm not paying top dollar
for an animal that
doesn't scare anyone
and doesn't know
any tricks.
Now, maybe if
I'm paying less,
say, $5,000 less...
Mr. Gavineau,
the only reason
we are talking
is because last month
this cat attacked
a circus horse
while 300 of
your tourists
ran screaming
for their lives.
Chased her down,
did he?
Went 16 feet over a cage.
Passed 11 other horses
just to get to this one.
Silver Dollar
was her name.
He broke her spine
so that she couldn't move,
and then
he ate her alive.
You ever heard
a horse scream,
Mr. Gavineau?
You want to know why
he went after that one?
Because
she was the pretty one.
And you're right,
Mr. Gavineau.
This cat,
he's not scary.
He's evil.
(BANGS CAGE)
(LAUGHING NERVOUSLY)
This is a waste of time
and my gas money.
I'll take it!
Plus your expenses.
Cat hasn't eaten
in two weeks.
That's how you show him
who's boss.
And when you move him,
you roll the cage
with this.
(TRUCK DOOR OPENS)
Safari park, huh?
Well, good luck
with that.
(TRUCK DOOR CLOSES)
(TRUCK STARTING)
Good luck with that.
Man makes his own luck!
Isn't that right,
Lucifer?
(TIGER GROWLS)
Tom, you there?
(FEEDBACK ON WALKIE-TALKIE)
Tom.
Tom, come on.
Remember? I told you
they have fish here.
You love fish.
They have all...
Come look at this.
See, look. Come here.
They have yellow fish.
Blue fish, purple fish.
I think they even
have clown fish.
Tom, come on.
You're gonna be
happy here.
Mom would have loved
this place. Okay?
It took me
a long time to find it.
I know you understand.
This is your home now.
You cannot come
to college with me.
Hey.
Please do not
screw this up.
(DOCTOR CLEARING THROAT)
DOCTOR: So, you've
been living with
your stepfather,
but you've
taken care of Tom
since your mother
passed away.
And after college,
will you once again
be taking on Tom's care?
Yes.
No red.
That depends on,
of course,
what's best for Tom
at that point.
I have custodianship,
so I will be
checking in on him.
Sorry,
he does not like red.
Well, then let's
get things settled.
Tom, would you like
to say goodbye
to your sister?
So, I'm gonna take off.
I'll see you in
a couple of weeks,
all right?
(YELLING) No! No touch!
No! No, no!
No!
I'm so sorry.
(CONTINUES YELLING)
I've got...
I got his stuff out.
He likes this...
He likes this
God's eye and...
When he's walking,
he might need it.
(SOFTLY) Tom,
I want you to be calm.
(STOPS YELLING)
Good.
Can you sit down for me?
Can you do that for me?
Can you sit down,
please?
Good.
Thank you.
You know,
who Tom is now
is pretty much who Tom
is always going to be.
People can sacrifice
their entire lives
taking care of
an autistic child.
Don't feel guilty
if you can't.
(DOOR OPENS)
(WHISPERING)
There seems
to be a problem.
Your check is being denied
due to insufficient funds?
No, that's...
That's not right.
That little...
(DIALING)
Do you have
another resource?
No.
What about
your stepfather?
No. There's money in there.
ON PHONE:
This is Mr. Fenton.
Hi, Mr. Fenton,
this is Kelly Taylor.
Hi, Kelly.
How are you?
Could you check the balance
of my account for me?
Your stepfather
withdrew all the money
from that account.
It's closed.
When?
Yesterday.
So...
He said he was
changing your house
into some sort
of safari ranch?
I hope that's
not a surprise.
Yeah, I don't...
I don't really care
about the animal thing.
That money was for Tom.
Kelly, sounds like
you should take
this up with Johnny.
Thank you.
MAN 1: Wait a minute,
wait a minute.
MAN 2: Okay!
Let's go! Unhitch it!
(BANGING ON CAGE)
(MEN CHATTERING)
Hey, .hombres,
I understand that
the power of hurricanes
has almost doubled
in the past 30 years.
Now, whether
that has to do
with global warming
doesn't much
matter to me,
but what does matter
is getting this place
battened down. Now.
(TIGER GROWLING)
(MAN 1 BECKONING TIGER)
(TIGER CONTINUES GROWLING)
(MAN 2 SPEAKING SPANISH)
(HISSING)
Hey!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MAN 2 SCREAMING)
Shit!
(MEN YELLING IN SPANISH)
Get me a rag!
Here, here, here. Shit!
I want you to keep
pressure on it, okay?
Like this.
Now, listen to me.
I want you to
go to the clinic
down the road.
Okay.
All right? They'll
take care of you.
They will not
deport you.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Now go.
And fast!
He's gonna lose
that finger!
God damn it!
I just said unhitch me.
We're staying here.
(BANGING ON CAGE)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
JOHNNY: Get this place
boarded up!
(MAN SHOUTING INSTRUCTIONS
IN SPANISH)
(SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
Johnny!
Where are you?
What is this?
Johnny?
Where did the freezer
come from, huh?
(TIGER GROWLING)
(BANGING ON CAGE)
Hey!
What the hell are you doing?
That's a carnivore in there.
(MIMICKING TIGER)
You understand?
Now, go back
in the house
where it's safe.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Out here, not safe.
In the house, safe.
Now, go on. Run.
Hey! Where's my money?
What money?
My bank account.
You closed it.
Wait a second.
That's not your money.
Of course it is.
I went to the bank,
I asked if there were
any other accounts,
they said just one,
co-signed by your mother,
so I took it out...
So, you stole it.
You doing drugs?
What?
Because drugs will damage
both the hippocampus
and the amygdala
portions of the brain.
That's where we
process memory.
Your memory's
a little foggy here.
I have to remind you
that your mom
didn't leave a will.
She did.
Hey.
She wanted me to
take care of Tom.
That's what she said.
Written on
a Post-it note.
Wasn't a Post-it note.
She wrote her wishes
for the future of you
and your brother
on a note.
Nobody's happy
your mom swallowed
a bottle of pills.
I also have
to point out,
in the absence of
any other information,
the money, this house,
goes to me.
Now, I don't know,
if she'd have
wanted it any different,
she might have
written another Post-it.
Just don't do that.
Don't talk about her.
(KELLY SIGHING)
Look, I don't care
what you bought.
I need what's left.
(CLEARING THROAT)
That's gonna be
a problem.
What?
I don't have it.
How? How could you
not have it?
You just got it out
yesterday, right?
I bought a tiger.
(SCOFFS) You're crazy.
People are gonna
pay to stay here,
they want the real deal.
A Bengal tiger
is the real deal.
That money was for Tom,
for his care,
so that I could know
that he was all right.
Kelly, you don't have to
put your plans aside
to help your brother.
Just leave Tom with me.
(SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
(DOOR OPENS)
JOHNNY: Damn it, Jose!
I said use the big screw!
Eat.
It's 5:30.
Want eat.
Right.
No!
No, no, no, no, no!
Look. Okay? There.
Okay, let's go.
Come on.
So, what are we
gonna watch today?
Want to try
something different?
Oprah? Ellen?
A little
History Channel?
Arrgh, matey!
Arrgh.
The Taylors.
Fascinating viewing,
even after the 785th time.
MOTHER:  Arrgh.
Kelly, come closer.
I see my
8-year-old boy today.
We got
an 8-year-old pirate.
There's two, Tommy,
three, four, five,
couple more, six,
my pirate, seven,
eight candles.
Let's light
those candles, Tommy!
Oh, it's a little
windy out here.
We got two.
We got two!
Make a wish and
blow them out.
Happy birthday,
my good boy.
I love you so much.
I just want you
to be happy.
Come on, nestle close.
ON PHONE:
This is Tom Lewis.
Hi, Mr. Lewis,
this is Kelly Taylor.
Hey, Kelly.
How's it going?
I'm glad I caught you.
Are you on campus already?
Is everything okay?
There's been a hitch.
(SIGHS)  Okay.
What's going on?
Yeah, I'm just...
I'm gonna need
a few months
to take care of
some family business,
and I'm just gonna
start second semester.
Kelly, you've deferred
the scholarship twice
already.
This is about
your brother, right?
You're not his mother.
He has a stepfather.
Now, you need to make
the right choice here.
Otherwise,
I am giving this money
to someone who needs it.
Mr. Lewis, I need it.
Okay, that's what
I want to hear,
because I am
really not kidding.
Kelly, if you don't show up,
there's nothing I can do.
That scholarship is gone.
Do you understand?
I understand.
This is
a big step for you,
but look how hard
you've worked for this.
Kelly, I really believe
you're making
the right choice.
Thank you. Me, too.
Okay. See you soon.
(STAIRS CREAKING)
Stop it, Tom.
I just need a minute.
This is my mad face,
do you understand?
Stop it.
(YELLING) Don't touch!
(SHOUTS)
Hey! Where did
you get this, huh?
This is Mom's.
Why have I not seen this?
What is this?
Have you taken
any of these, Tom?
Tell me right now.
Have you?
Seconal. Christ,
Mom, what weren't you on?
(SIGHS)
(SCREAMING)
God.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DROPS TOOTHBRUSH)
(WIND HOWLING)
(TIGER SNARLING)
Hey, Tom.
Time to go to bed.
(BANGING ON CAGE)
(TRUCK DOOR OPENS)
(TRUCK DOOR CLOSES)
(CHAIN RATTLING)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
ANNOUNCER ON RADIO:
After a night of
watching and waiting,
say good morning to
Hurricane Isabel.
Storm made landfall
just after 5:00
this morning.
We're talking
120-mile-per-hour winds
coming in
off the Gulf Coast.
If you're in
Montgomery County,
you are not in danger,
but don't worry.
We'll be here with
you the whole way...
Outstanding choice.
(CLANKING)
(RUSTLING)
(RUSTLING INTENSIFIES)
Hello?
Tom?
(SNIFFLING)
(GASPS)
(WIND HOWLING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Damn it!
(TIGER SNARLING)
Tom, wake up.
Tom!
This is serious.
Tom, wake up.
Damn it.
AUTOMATED VOICE: .You have
reached Montgomery County
Emergency Services.
We are currently
experiencing a hurricane.
Please enter
your phone number,
and we'll call you
as soon as we...
(ENTERING NUMBER)
(SNIFFLING)
(DIALING)
(RINGING)
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
Give me another.
(RINGING TONE)
(CREAKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(SOFTLY) Tom.
(TIGER GROWLING)
(GASPS)
(DOORKNOB RATTLING)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(TIGER POUNDING ON DOOR)
(DOOR BREAKING)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(PANTING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(TIGER ROARING)
(SMASHING)
(SNIFFING)
(ROARING)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
Where the fuck
have you been?
(SNIFFLING)
KELLY: Come with me.
(SOFTLY) Come on.
Jesus.
Tom.
(SHUSHING)
The tiger is
in the house.
(DOOR OPENING)
Come on,
play the quiet game.
It's the quiet game.
Quiet game.
Come on. Come on.
(KELLY PANTING)
Come on, come on,
come on.
Come on,
you piece of shit!
Damn it!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(TOM SHOUTING)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(ROARING)
(TOM SCREAMING)
(KELLY GRUNTING)
(TOM SHOUTING)
(KELLY SHOUTING)
Let's go!
Come on!
(TIGER GROWLING)
(TOM SHOUTING)
Eat now. Eat.
(BANGING ON TABLE)
Eat! Eat breakfast now!
Eat now! Eat!
Eat! Eat!
Want to eat!
Want eat!
Eat!
Want it!
Your breakfast.
(STAIRS CREAKING)
(GROWLING)
(TOM SHOUTING)
(SCREAMING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(TIGER MEWLING)
Get dressed.
(SOFTLY) Yes,
stay in your room.
(GRUNTING)
(GROWLING)
Tom.
Get dressed.
No touch. No touch.
I'm touching your shirt.
Look,
I'm not touching you.
(DOOR OPENING)
No touch.
Come here.
Get out of there.
Get out!
What is this?
Enough with Mom!
(TOM WHINING)
(GRUNTING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(CONTINUES WHINING)
Want her? Have her.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(SCRATCHING ON DOOR)
(DOOR BREAKING)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(ROARING)
(TOM SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GRUNTING)
Where's the gun?
Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Okay.
Move. Move.
Damn it!
(EXCLAIMS)
(SNIFFLING)
Please let there be
a way out of this.
Show me the way out,
please, God.
Let there be
a way out of this.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
KELLY: What?
You bastard.
Are you out of
your mind?
It's in a cage.
It's not like it would be
wandering around
the whole property.
How the hell are you
gonna keep this thing
under control?
Starve it.
How's that?
You have
to starve them.
Hasn't eaten
in two weeks.
That's how you show a cat
who's boss.
And that's you?
I'm just trying to make
a go of it here, Maurice.
Uh-huh.
When Kelly goes to college,
and she will.
You know how
young people are.
Who's gonna
take care of that boy?
Well, you...
You've been a godsend
to those kids, Johnny.
KELLY: It's gotta be here.
Where is it? Where is it?
No! No touching!
(EXCLAIMS)
I think we can go through
the laundry room, okay?
You understand?
Let me go first.
Be very quiet.
(GROWLING)
(GASPS)
No.
No, no.
(HOME MOVIE PLAYING ON TV)
(GROWLS)
(MOTHER SINGING ON TV)
(GUN CLICKS)
(TIGER GROWLING)
KELLY: Come on,
we gotta go.
No, stay!
(GROWLS)
(ROARING)
(FIRE ALARM BLARING)
(TIGER GROWLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(GROANS)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(ENGINE STALLING)
(SOBBING)
(GRUNTING)
(TIGER MEWLING)
KELLY: Oh, my God.
So sorry
Mom left you, Tom.
She left me, too.
I'm sorry she did that.
But I'm not gonna
leave you, Tommy.
We're gonna get out
of here, right now.
And wherever I go,
you are coming with me.
No touch.
Don't move.
(GROWLING)
Go to the laundry room.
(CLATTERING)
Go back. Go back.
We'll go around.
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
(THUDDING)
(SCREAMING)
(ROARING)
(GROWLING)
Get in the freezer.
I know you understand me.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(TOM WHINING)
(POUNDING ON FREEZER)
(KELLY SHUSHING)
Easy.
All right.
It's okay.
Tom, it's okay.
(WHIMPERING)
It's okay. It's okay.
Now, breathe slowly.
(BREATHING SLOWLY)
Just breathe.
(TIGER GROWLING)
(POUNDING CONTINUES)
Here's what's
gonna happen.
You're just
gonna fall asleep.
That's not so bad, huh?
I bet you're real tired.
Just close your eyes
and go to sleep.
(KELLY HUMMING)
(ELECTRICITY TURNS ON)
Tommy, come on.
Come on.
(SCREWDRIVER WHIRRING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
JOHNNY: Boy, Phil's
was a madhouse.
Everyone was there,
even Lindsay Bosier.
Tossing back
hurricanes.
Eight months pregnant.
You'd think she'd
have more sense.
Some people, right?
KELLY: Tom doesn't understand
what happened here.
He can't tell anyone.
So, you gonna
let us go?
You're not the only one
who wanted out.
Your mother was
gonna leave me.
You killed her.
Kelly...
(JOHNNY SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)