[Silence]
[Low, almost inaudible hum]
♪
Woman: My story can
never be told.
Never be told.
I write it over and over
i write it over and over
wherever we find shelter.
Wherever we find shelter.
I write of what I cannot
i write of what I cannot
speak-- the truth.
Speak-- the truth.
I write all I know of it
i write all I know of it
and then I throw the pages
to the wind.
To the wind.
Maybe the birds can read it.
[♪...]
This yours?
I often find them here,
i often find them here,
these scraps.
These scraps.
Must float down from
must float down from
someone's window.
Someone's window.
[♪...]
"She had meant to smother the
baby as soon as it was born,
but something made her look
at it.
At it.
She heard the thundering
she heard the thundering
heartbeat, she smelled the
baby's bloodied head and
love confounded her."
Love confounded her."
It's just a scrap, like you say.
But there's a story there.
You can feel it.
Shall we walk a little?
My story starts with Clara.
One day, it will end with her.
Clara... full of secrets.
My savior.
My burden.
My muse.
Woman: ♪ ...Won't you come
woman: ♪ ...Won't you come
and be with me
and see what I've got? ♪
And see what I've got? ♪
♪ 'cause what I've got
is what you need ♪
Is what you need ♪
♪ what I got
is what you need... ♪
Is what you need... ♪
man: Hey!
Man: Hey!
[Clara grunts, yells]
Fucking hell... Wendy!
I'll call you back.
You!
[Thud, man screams]
Clara: You bastard!
Did you see that?
He fucking attacked me!
Wendy: What's she done?
Really fucked his nose.
Yeah, well, he deserved it.
Come on. Oi...
Man: Ernie, get him out of
man: Ernie, get him out of
here, will you?
Here, will you?
My nose!
My nose...
Man: Would you care for tea?
Please come in.
I have been working here for
14 nights-- I want my pay!
You're not on the books.
What pay?
Woman: ♪ don't you wanna,
woman: ♪ don't you wanna,
wanna, don't you ♪
Wanna, don't you ♪
♪ don't you wanna see me
flaunt what I got? ♪
Flaunt what I got? ♪
♪ don't you,
don't you wanna, wanna... ♪
Don't you wanna, wanna... ♪
excuse me.
Excuse me.
Have you seen this girl?
No-- sorry, mate.
Sorry.
Woman: ♪ ...Flaunt
woman: ♪ ...Flaunt
what I got... ♪
What I got... ♪
no.
No.
[♪...]
Oi, what are you doing?
Sorry, babe, but they owe me.
No! Stop, you can't take
no! Stop, you can't take
money out of the till!
Money out of the till!
[♪...]
Hello, Clara.
[Bottle shatters, man grunts]
We get a lot of bitches in
we get a lot of bitches in
here, but she took the
fucking prize.
Fucking prize.
Shame. She was morbidly sexy.
[♪...]
Clara: Move!
Aah!
Clara: No...
[Screams]
[Grunts]
[Crashing, clattering]
[♪...]
Clara...!
[Siren wails in distance]
Shit! Fuck! [Whimpers]
[Glass shatters, Clara yelling]
[People screaming]
[Clara gasping]
[Man grunts]
The tedium I've experienced
the tedium I've experienced
in this pursuit! My time you
have wasted! [Clara gasping]
Have wasted! [Clara gasping]
You would sell nations with
you would sell nations with
your whoredoms.
Your whoredoms.
Come on.
You know who I'm looking for.
Where is she? Huh?
Where is she?!
I was him once.
And that girl...
Love confounded me for her.
I loved her my whole
i loved her my whole
life through.
Life through.
Your wife?
She was married to my
she was married to my
brother John...
Brother John...
Most happily.
She never knew the way I felt.
Nor did he.
There comes a time in life
when secrets should be told.
When secrets should be told.
[♪...]
You've got secrets, haven't you?
There was a story told when
there was a story told when
i was a boy about the
neamh-mhairbh, the revenants.
Neamh-mhairbh, the revenants.
Neither dead nor alive.
The priests used to tell it
the priests used to tell it
to frighten us.
To frighten us.
[♪...]
My name is Eleanor webb.
Eleanor webb.
I am ready.
Are you sure?
[Chuckles]
I've spent quite enough
time here.
Time here.
Believe me.
[♪...]
[Gasps softly]
I feel at great peace.
As if order is about
as if order is about
to be restored.
To be restored.
She is an aberration.
I don't know what that
means, sir.
Where do you think
you're going?
You're going?
I was going to clean
the wound, sir.
The wound, sir.
You've been cut,
you've been cut,
it's conspicuous.
[Water runs]
All the time you've had
all the time you've had
and you've learned nothing.
And you've learned nothing.
Truly you're base.
[♪...]
Close your eyes.
[Whir whips and whooshes]
[Clara grunts]
[Man gasping]
[Clara yells, exhales loudly]
[Eleanor pants, gasps,
breathes heavily]
Breathes heavily]
[♪...]
[Sighs]
[Door opens and closes]
Eleanor: Clara?
Get out.
How could you bring
someone here? He was
stronger than I thought.
Stronger than I thought.
This is our home.
Eleanor...
We have to leave.
I'm not moving on again...
I had to do it!
One day you'll understand.
What, when I'm older?
You have no idea,
you have no idea,
no fucking idea
of what I do for you!
Of what I do for you!
You did that for me?
Pack!
I liked it here.
I said pack!
[♪...]
[Water gurgles down drain]
[Gasoline splashing]
[Match scratches]
[Flames whoosh]
Who was he? No one.
[Flames roaring]
[Dog barking...]
[♪...]
[People laughing,
talking excitedly]
Talking excitedly]
[Sirens in distance]
[Brakes squeaking]
[Brakes hiss, engine idles]
[♪...]
♪ mother was bathing
her baby one night ♪
Her baby one night ♪
♪ youngest of 10
and a poor little mite ♪
And a poor little mite ♪
♪ mother was fat
and the baby was thin ♪
And the baby was thin ♪
♪ it was nought but a
both: ♪ skellington
wrapped up in skin ♪
Wrapped up in skin ♪
♪ mother turned 'round
for the soap from the rack... ♪
For the soap from the rack... ♪
[Engine idles]
Thank you!
All right, see you, girls.
[♪...]
[Birds chirping...]
Man: You'll have a look
man: You'll have a look
at the greenhouse, eh?
At the greenhouse, eh?
Man 2: Aye.
[Sheep bleating...]
[Birds chirping...]
[Choir singing...]
[Gasps]
[Choir continues...]
[Gulls cawing...]
[Panting nervously]
We've been here before.
Oh, don't be silly.
Come on.
But don't you remember?
[Music playing...]
It's going to be good for us
it's going to be good for us
here, I can feel it.
Here, I can feel it.
You said that about the
you said that about the
last place.
Last place.
What, that dump that we
what, that dump that we
just left?
Just left?
I've forgotten it already.
What's the matter?
You can't throw the past away
you can't throw the past away
as if it didn't happen.
As if it didn't happen.
My concern is now, o.K.?
Silly sod.
Why don't you go and play on
the amusements, yeah?
The amusements, yeah?
Gonna make us some money.
Man: Go on.
Eleanor: Clara is
never alone.
Never alone.
She finds money and company
she finds money and company
every day.
Every day.
It comes easily to her,
it comes easily to her,
like lying.
Like lying.
Man: Who's that?
You know her? No.
You seen her? No.
But I like solitude.
I walk and the past walks
i walk and the past walks
with me.
With me.
It lives.
[Waves crashing...]
[Laughter,
indistinct conversations]
[Playing slow melody...]
[Piano continues...]
[Rides clanking, people scream
[rides clanking, people scream
happily in distance...]
[Continues playing...]
[Piano continues...]
[Quietly] Hi.
It's 50 for a blow,
it's 50 for a blow,
100 for a full whack.
[Piano continues...]
[Finishes playing]
Did they hire you?
You're busking.
You could pass the hat around.
I don't mind.
That... was great.
Can you speak?
I haven't got a hat.
[Giggles]
How do you remember
how do you remember
all those notes?
All those notes?
I remember everything.
It's a burden.
So...
You know anything else?
Try and liven them up.
It's the valley of the stiffs
it's the valley of the stiffs
in here.
I have to go.
I finish at 10!
[♪...]
Come in.
[Door rattles]
[♪...]
50.
Lovely.
So, are you on holiday then?
[Quietly] No.
Oh, you live around here?
Yeah.
Fancied a bit of company.
[Tearfully] She...
Who?
Mum.
She, she died.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
There was a funeral.
I couldn't.
I ran away from it.
I've not been out.
I've not been out since.
[Cries]
But your grief, that shows
but your grief, that shows
how much you loved her.
How much you loved her.
And love is a very good thing.
I bet she'd be proud of you.
A lovely son like you?
No, I never made her proud.
I just...
I don't even answer the phone.
You know?
I messed up the business,
i messed up the business,
i can't pay her debts.
I can't pay her debts.
Found 50 quid in one of her old
found 50 quid in one of her old
books and what do I spend it on?
Books and what do I spend it on?
Human contact.
[Sighs]
Are you o.K.? Yeah.
Yeah?
I'm sorry, love.
I'm Camilla.
Noel.
So what sort of a business
so what sort of a business
did your mum have then, Noel?
Did your mum have then, Noel?
It was a guesthouse.
I trashed it.
Was it a big place?
Yeah, it was fairly big.
Well... do you... should we
well... do you... should we
go back to your place then?
Go back to your place then?
Yeah? Yeah.
Be nice. Yeah, you could
be nice. Yeah, you could
come back to mine. Yeah.
Come back to mine. Yeah.
[Waves crashing]
Glad you waited for me.
I didn't.
How did you learn to play
like that?
Like that?
I practiced.
For how long?
200 years.
That's how it feels anyways,
that's how it feels anyways,
doesn't it?
Doesn't it?
Passed around a teacup.
Raised some cash for you.
It's not much.
Thank you.
That piece of paper.
That's my phone number.
I don't have a phone.
So... ni... nice to meet you.
Good-bye.
[Waves crashing]
Ella! Ella!
Look who I found!
We're damsels in distress.
Noel: Oh.
Do you know what
do you know what
Noel is, Ella?
He's a knight in shining armor
he's a knight in shining armor
come to deliver us from evil,
aren't you? [Laughs]
Aren't you? [Laughs]
This is my little baby sister.
Hi.
Hello.
There we go.
Ah...
Been looking for you everywhere.
[♪...]
Can't find my keys.
Oh...
Oh-- I'll just open up.
Come in.
[♪...]
Look, I'm trusting you, Camilla.
[Clara giggles]
Don't.
I won't.
Look, I'm not saying
look, I'm not saying
it's tidy.
It's tidy.
[Gate rattles]
It was a hotel once.
And a boarding house.
[Gate clatters]
My mum had the top three floors.
Used to do b-and-bs, you know?
Families and that.
Then it was more, you know,
then it was more, you know,
the welfare lot.
The welfare lot.
It's a bit run down now,
it's a bit run down now,
but she wouldn't let it go.
But she wouldn't let it go.
Loved the views, you see.
[♪...]
Fantastic view of the pier
fantastic view of the pier
from up here.
From up here.
Clara: Lovely.
This is the dining area.
Well... it's nice.
Yeah-- it's lovely. It's a
yeah-- it's lovely. It's a
bit of a state, like I said,
but I wasn't expecting company.
But I wasn't expecting company.
[Clara giggles]
[♪...]
Tell my sister where
tell my sister where
her room is, love.
Her room is, love.
Yeah.
Ella?
I'll show you to your room.
[Waves crashing in the distance]
[Clara humming...]
I went 'round the house and...
Smashed things up.
I didn't wanna look at myself.
Camilla said that, um,
you lost your mum too.
You lost your mum too.
She's your legal guardian.
How brave of her.
[Clara singing softly...]
I understand what she's
i understand what she's
had to do.
Had to do.
Do you?
Well, she needs money.
Well, what I'm saying is, um...
I don't care.
You can stay.
Thank you.
[Clara continues singing...]
[♪...]
Clara: Only those prepared to
die will find eternal life.
Die will find eternal life.
[Kisses]
Go on, go on.
[♪...]
[Screeching, whooshing,
flapping]
Flapping]
[♪...]
This is the end.
Of what?
Of time.
[♪...]
[Gulls cawing...]
[Water splashes]
[Clara and Noel moan]
Clara: Good boy...
[Noel groans loudly]
Ooh...
[♪...]
[Sirens wail in distance]
[Wire zips]
Excuse me.
[Camera beeps, clicks]
[Wire clatters on floor]
[♪...]
[Whispers] Who was he?
It's in the past, Ella,
it's in the past, Ella,
let it go.
Let it go.
Who was he?
He was a fucking monster.
I should get a medal
i should get a medal
for what I did to him.
Will we move on today?
Are you tired, my love?
[Sighs]
Well...
I reckon that we should hang on
i reckon that we should hang on
here for a few days, don't you?
Here for a few days, don't you?
Yeah, we can lay low,
yeah, we can lay low,
get some rest, get some money.
Get some rest, get some money.
I could start up one of my old
i could start up one of my old
businesses like in the old days.
Businesses like in the old days.
You don't have to do that.
Oh, come on, Ella.
Look at this place,
look at this place,
it's perfect.
It's perfect.
We'd rake it in.
Why don't we find
why don't we find
another way?
Another way?
It's all right, angel.
I'll make sure you're
not involved.
Not involved.
[Roars]
[Noel shouts, Clara laughs]
I'm sorry, Noel. [Kisses]
Oh...
I was worried I dreamt you.
I thought I'd wake up and
i thought I'd wake up and
you'd be gone.
You'd be gone.
Why would I leave?
You've got everything I need.
[Waves crashing, ♪...]
[Rain pattering on window]
[♪...]
Eleanor webb.
Look at you.
Fair as a lily.
I know your mother.
My mother is dead.
Is that what they told you?
They fed you on lies.
[♪...]
Your mother, your mother stole
your mother, your mother stole
something from me.
Something from me.
Now I'll steal something
now I'll steal something
from her.
From her.
[Breathes heavily]
My disease has no cure.
When I'm finished with you,
when I'm finished with you,
you'll be a child no longer.
You'll be a child no longer.
Look at me!
Noel: Ella?
[Sobbing quietly]
You o.K.?
Camilla's told me about how
you were in a care home.
You were in a care home.
She said that...
She said that bad things
she said that bad things
happened to you there.
Happened to you there.
I want you to know that nothing
i want you to know that nothing
bad will happen while you're
living here.
Living here.
I promise, o.K.?
Her name's not Camilla and
she's not my sister, she's--
my name's Claire.
My name's Claire.
It's Clara,
it's Clara,
she was born Clara.
She was born Clara.
I prefer Claire.
Mmm...
Claire.
[♪...]
[Whispers] Don't.
You lie about me
you lie about me
all the time.
All the time.
If you tell him,
if you tell him,
i will kill him.
I will kill him.
Don't you sometimes crave
don't you sometimes crave
to tell the truth?
To tell the truth?
There is a code that we
there is a code that we
survive by, Eleanor.
Survive by, Eleanor.
Keep it.
[Gulls caw]
...So, in a week say,
...so, in a week say,
how much would your mum make?
How much would your mum make?
Uh, what, high season?
About a thousand.
Oh, we could make that
oh, we could make that
in a night.
In a night.
You could clear all
you could clear all
your debts, noely.
Your debts, noely.
Yeah, but...
I want to save you
i want to save you
from that life.
From that life.
Well, it wouldn't have
well, it wouldn't have
to be me.
To be me.
We could get some girls in.
This is my mother's house.
♪ he's so fair [Kisses]
♪ He's so fair [Kisses]
♪ none can compare [Kisses]
♪ None can compare [Kisses]
♪ oh, but his blood runs Ruby
[♪...]
♪ come, rosy day,
come quick, I pray ♪
Come quick, I pray ♪
♪ let dreams of love
be over... ♪
Be over... ♪
Eleanor: Once upon a time,
there was nothing here.
There was nothing here.
There was no hotel,
there was no hotel,
no promenade.
No promenade.
Just a beach, nets hanging out
just a beach, nets hanging out
to dry, great warships in the
bay and children picking
cockles for their bread.
Cockles for their bread.
My mother was one of those
my mother was one of those
children, barefoot in the sand.
Children, barefoot in the sand.
...Can you hear me?
...can you hear me?
[Woman moans softly]
[♪...]
My mother lives on human blood
my mother lives on human blood
and has done for two centuries.
And has done for two centuries.
But once she was a girl
but once she was a girl
like you.
Like you.
She's never spoken
she's never spoken
of her family.
Of her family.
They're in the store of things
they're in the store of things
she must forget.
She must forget.
So her tale begins with two
so her tale begins with two
officers waiting to be called
to war.
To war.
Are they sweet?
[♪...]
May I try one?
Eleanor: One was
midshipman darvell.
Midshipman darvell.
[♪...]
Mmm.
Here.
Pearl for a pearl.
Eleanor: And the other,
his superior,
was captain ruthven.
Was captain ruthven.
May I offer you a ride?
She's only a child, ruthven.
She knows how to ride,
she knows how to ride,
i dare say.
I dare say.
Don't go with him.
[♪...]
Eleanor: The pearl stays pure
forever while the oyster's flesh
rots around it.
Rots around it.
[♪...]
I have a gift for you.
Captain ruthven!
[Piano playing...]
Here's a treasure
i found on the beach.
I found on the beach.
Welcome, my dear.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Come on.
Let me show you to the captain's
let me show you to the captain's
favorite room.
Favorite room.
You'll find only friends here.
[♪...]
You gave me nothing, sir.
You took.
I've given you
your profession.
Your profession.
Welcome to your adult life...
Eleanor: How many stories
start that way?
Start that way?
[Coin clinks] whore.
[Coin clinks] Whore.
Eleanor: Thousands upon
thousands.
Thousands.
I shall return...
To see what you have learnt.
[♪...]
Come now.
Why do you cry?
I have a gentleman here
i have a gentleman here
who will soon have you
smiling again.
Smiling again.
[Baby cries]
No children in this household.
You know the rule.
Eleanor: Once upon a time,
i was born.
I was born.
[Baby cries]
It is still a fact that the day
it is still a fact that the day
you are born is the day you
are most likely to be murdered.
Are most likely to be murdered.
More human souls are killed
more human souls are killed
by mothers' hands than by
the hands of strangers.
The hands of strangers.
My mother tried to murder me...
But love confounded her.
[♪...]
Her note said, "this is my
daughter, Eleanor webb.
Daughter, Eleanor webb.
I wish her to live
i wish her to live
a clean life.
A clean life.
I shall pay for her upkeep
i shall pay for her upkeep
with gold, which I will leave
every month that she lives.
Every month that she lives.
I wish to spare her a life like
i wish to spare her a life like
my own, which has been
despoiled from the start.
Despoiled from the start.
Please tell her I'm dead."
[Thumping on door]
[Waves crashing]
[♪...]
[Choir singing...]
So I led that clean life.
I sang the orphan's song.
I learned that virtue and
i learned that virtue and
modesty would be my path
to bliss.
To bliss.
Northaven private orphanage
northaven private orphanage
was my abode.
Was my abode.
I wish I could have called
i wish I could have called
it home.
It home.
[♪...]
[Gasps]
[Grunts]
I'm sorry!
Fuck...
Oh, that's gross.
[Grunting]
I've got to get home.
Let me get help.
I've got your bicycle,
don't worry.
Don't worry.
You need stitches.
Were you there to enroll?
What?
Have you joined the college?
I don't know.
Leave the bike there.
[Groans] I hate blood.
Could you get the
could you get the
doorbell, please?
Doorbell, please?
[Rings bell]
Oh, my God, what happened?
He fell.
Oh, my God.
Mark! Mark!
[Echoing] he's bleeding!
[Echoing] He's bleeding!
[Heartbeat thumping, ♪...]
Frank, oh, Frank.
It's o.K., it's o.K.
I got him, I got him.
Get the keys.
[♪...]
Are you his girlfriend?
Where are the keys?
[♪...]
Has he told you?
Oh...
Got the keys?
Yeah.
Keep it up, keep it up, Frank.
Oh, God, Frank!
[♪...]
[Music changes]
Woman: ♪ don't cry...
Pimp: Good girl.
♪ ...Baby, don't cry
♪ ...baby, don't cry
you could do so much better.
You could do so much better.
♪ dry your eyes
[Metal stairs clatter]
♪ let's be sweethearts
again ♪
Again ♪
♪ oh...
♪ Oh...
Pimp: Oi...
Would you like to kiss me?
What the fuck...?
Why?
In celebration of
in celebration of
my wickedness.
My wickedness.
♪ come on,
come on, sweetheart ♪
Come on, sweetheart ♪
♪ and let's try it over again
[Clara humming...]
♪ oh, don't cry
♪ don't cry, baby
♪ don't cry,
don't cry ♪
Don't cry ♪
♪ dry your eyes
and let's be sweethearts again ♪
And let's be sweethearts again ♪
♪ oh...
♪ Oh...
♪ 'cause you know,
you know I didn't mean... ♪
You know I didn't mean... ♪
[Pimp groaning, grunting]
♪ ...To treat you so mean
♪ ...to treat you so mean
♪ come on, come on...
♪ Come on, come on...
[Clara moaning]
♪ let's try it over again
♪ oh, don't cry
♪ don't cry,
don't cry, baby... ♪
Don't cry, baby... ♪
the world'll be more
beautiful without you.
Beautiful without you.
♪ don't cry, don't cry,
don't cry ♪
Don't cry ♪
♪ dry your eyes
♪ let's be sweethearts again
it's all right.
It's all right.
Gotcha.
It's o.K.
I want to die.
No, you don't.
Not today.
If you still want to die
if you still want to die
tomorrow, I'll finish you
off myself. [Chuckles]
[Indistinct conversations...]
[Door creaks]
[Door closes]
[♪...]
[Eleanor breathing heavily]
[Heartbeat thumping]
[♪...]
[Door opens]
Hello?
Oh, hi.
Is it still visiting?
Thanks for bringing him home.
He hasn't told me anything
about you.
About you.
That's boys for you, isn't it?
You been going out for long?
We just met.
Oh, oh.
I'm glad.
What's your name?
Eleanor.
Gabi.
He takes anti-coagulants.
That's why he bled so much,
that's why he bled so much,
that's what you're wondering.
That's what you're wondering.
He's been fighting leukemia
he's been fighting leukemia
for years.
For years.
It's in remission now,
it's in remission now,
so we're hoping it's all over.
So we're hoping it's all over.
So full of life.
Please don't tell him
i was here.
[Door opens and closes]
[♪...]
Woman: Angel...
Peace be with you.
May light shine upon you.
You came for me...
[Breathing with difficulty]
Forgive me for what
forgive me for what
i must do.
I must do.
[♪...]
[Women shriek, laugh]
Woman: Oh, hi.
Woman 2: Hi.
Do you speak? [Women giggle]
Speak English?
You schoolgirl thing?
[Both laugh]
She better pay like she say
she better pay like she say
or I'll say no further.
Or I'll say no further.
Maybe we do lesbian thing.
I don't mind.
That's my little baby sister.
She doesn't drink,
she doesn't drink,
she doesn't join in.
She doesn't join in.
You leave her be,
you leave her be,
do you understand?
Do you understand?
Now, your gentlemen are
now, your gentlemen are
waiting for you.
Waiting for you.
Now, you be professional, o.K.,
now, you be professional, o.K.,
otherwise you're back sucking
cocks on the street-- out!
Cocks on the street-- out!
[Music playing in distance...]
I'll try and keep you out
of this, o.K.?
Of this, o.K.?
In case you shock me?
Look, we need the money.
I'm not complaining.
Well, then wipe that prissy
well, then wipe that prissy
look off your face.
Look off your face.
How can I be prissy when
how can I be prissy when
I've seen it all a thousand
times before?
Times before?
Well, what else are we
well, what else are we
supposed to do?
Supposed to do?
I know I won't get your thanks
i know I won't get your thanks
or your gratitude or
your respect.
Your respect.
You could do so much better.
I put money on the table.
That's what mothers do!
Mothers care about the lives
mothers care about the lives
their children live.
Their children live.
What kind of life is this?
[Music continues in distance...]
Woman: ♪ ...Care for ya
woman: ♪ ...Care for ya
♪ just remember,
i l... l... l... l...
I l... l... l... l...
L... love ya. ♪
[Indistinct conversations]
[♪...]
Man: Humans need to
man: Humans need to
tell stories.
Tell stories.
It's a fundamental and
it's a fundamental and
uniting thing.
Uniting thing.
It's through stories that we
it's through stories that we
come to understand ourselves and
we come to understand the world.
We come to understand the world.
So, close your eyes.
It's our own experience that is
it's our own experience that is
the starting point for all
our creativity.
Our creativity.
Think about your
think about your
early childhood.
Early childhood.
And when I say your name,
and when I say your name,
give me a memory, a, a detail,
a sensation, a feeling...
A sensation, a feeling...
[Voice fading] the first thing
[voice fading] The first thing
that comes into your mind, o.K.?
That comes into your mind, o.K.?
[Girl coughing]
[♪...]
[Whispers] Eleanor.
Teacher: Eleanor.
Mother.
What about her?
She would come to the
she would come to the
skylight at night.
Skylight at night.
I was afraid.
Why?
They told me since infancy
they told me since infancy
that she was dead.
That she was dead.
And then?
[♪...]
Eleanor: The face at the
window had more substance
than a ghost.
Than a ghost.
O.K., thanks.
And yet..Frank.
I knew it could not live.
Frank: Yeah, um, my friend,
David Atkinson.
I'm the only person who can
see him.
See him.
Um... I was probably too much
um... I was probably too much
alone, whatever,
and David Atkinson used to
appear in my room.
Appear in my room.
And we'd play.
And I guess I grew out of him.
He came till I was about
he came till I was about
seven or eight.
Seven or eight.
Yeah.
Thank you.
O.K.
The really funny thing
the really funny thing
is that...
Is that...
Years later, I found out
years later, I found out
that the family before us in
the house were called Atkinson.
The house were called Atkinson.
They lost a baby,
they lost a baby,
like a cot death.
Like a cot death.
And the baby's name...
Was David.
Uh-huh.
Good story.
So, everyone up.
Now, I want you to think about
now, I want you to think about
who you are and next time,
i would like an essay
entitled...
Entitled...
"I am."
And there's only one rule.
It has to be true.
You don't belong here.
This is my mom's hometown.
We came when I got ill.
The healthcare over here is free
the healthcare over here is free
and I was... something of a, um,
drain on our limited resources.
Drain on our limited resources.
My dad commutes.
I don't think he likes it much,
i don't think he likes it much,
but... what are you gonna do?
But... what are you gonna do?
[Dog barks, gulls caw]
My mom said you came to see me
when I was in hospital.
When I was in hospital.
She, um, she thinks...
That you're my girl.
Would that be so bad?
Because I--
because I--
it would be fatal.
It would be fatal.
[♪...]
Look...
I know I'm,
i know I'm,
I'm ill and all, but--
no...
No...
For me.
[Gasps]
If you lived with a secret and
the secret meant that you must
always lie and be alone and
you'd always lived that way
and yet you longed for change,
what would you do?
I'd tell the secret.
[♪...]
[Gasping and sighing]
Tell me.
[♪...]
[Breathing heavily]
[Breathing calms]
[♪...]
Eleanor: My mother did
three things for me.
Three things for me.
One, she spared my life the day
one, she spared my life the day
that I was born.
That I was born.
Two, she paid for my upkeep on
two, she paid for my upkeep on
her knees and on her back.
Her knees and on her back.
And three, she gave me the
and three, she gave me the
story I can never tell.
Story I can never tell.
[Woman coughing]
[♪...]
By the time I was six,
she was dying.
She was dying.
Girls like Clara didn't last.
Her lungs were rotting,
her lungs were rotting,
but she clung steadfastly
to her brutal life.
To her brutal life.
[Clara coughs violently]
[♪...]
[Coughing]
Where have you been?
The captain's been waiting.
[♪...]
Captain ruthven had returnd
captain ruthven had returnd
from the wars.
From the wars.
Make sure you punish
make sure you punish
her, sir.
Her, sir.
Of all the harlots he had
of all the harlots he had
ever made, Clara was
his favorite.
His favorite.
[♪...]
You'll like this one.
She fights.
Then, one winter dawn,
then, one winter dawn,
a stranger came.
A stranger came.
[♪...]
[Man coughs]
[Door creaking]
[Clara coughing]
Are you unwell?
No, sir. [Coughs]
[♪...]
I remember you.
I'm much changed, sir.
And what of me?
Have I changed?
[♪...]
I have.
More than you could imagine.
Open the curtains.
[Groans]
Curse you, whore!
Give me the dark!
[♪...]
Does the light offend you?
[Gasps softly]
Darvell...
My friend.
[Breathes heavily]
But I was with you.
I saw you dead.
And I thank you
and I thank you
for your service.
For your service.
[♪...]
What do you want?
I have not come
to take from you.
To take from you.
I come to give.
I will return at nightfall.
Like you, I prefer the dark.
[♪...]
No!
Bitch!
Eleanor: He answered her
questions with blows.
Questions with blows.
As usual, she endured them.
And she waited for the storm
and she waited for the storm
to pass.
To pass.
[Rings bell]
[♪...]
Frank: What kind of time
do you call this?
Do you call this?
Linear time.
[Chuckles]
...as the relentless day
crept on, the captain told his
tale of events beyond his
understanding.
Understanding.
Ruthven: There was a
ruthven: There was a
rebellion in Ireland.
Rebellion in Ireland.
We were sent to crush it.
Both of us were wounded by the
both of us were wounded by the
beggarly horde.
Beggarly horde.
My wounds were superficial,
my wounds were superficial,
but darvell developed fever.
But darvell developed fever.
It decimated him.
I tried to persuade him
i tried to persuade him
to come home.
To come home.
Clara: That was good of you.
I knew the journey would
quicken his decline.
Quicken his decline.
Darvell was rich and naive.
He had no heir.
I had begun to wish him dead...
[Coughs]
...But before the grave took
...but before the grave took
him, two men entered his life.
Him, two men entered his life.
Scholars, I presumed, of dead
scholars, I presumed, of dead
languages and aged manuscripts.
Languages and aged manuscripts.
As if ancient knowledge might
as if ancient knowledge might
keep his death at bay.
Keep his death at bay.
[♪...]
You have been looking in the
you have been looking in the
wrong place, my son.
Wrong place, my son.
[♪...]
[Darvell gasps]
Here it is.
Thank you.
[♪...]
Ruthven: He told me we must
ruthven: He told me we must
find a shrine, an ancient myth
said it had healing powers.
Said it had healing powers.
It was on an empty island
it was on an empty island
off a barren coast.
Off a barren coast.
I thought it the desperate quest
i thought it the desperate quest
of a dying man.
Of a dying man.
[♪...]
It was a sinister black
thumbnail sticking out of the
ocean, more rock than island.
Ocean, more rock than island.
[♪...]
[Screeching, flapping]
The oarsmen wouldn't set foot
the oarsmen wouldn't set foot
on the place.
On the place.
Said it was cursed.
[♪...]
The way was steep, but darvell
kept on climbing regardless.
Kept on climbing regardless.
I thought-- well, maybe I
i thought-- well, maybe I
hoped-- his heart would
give way.
Give way.
[Darvell coughs]
[♪...]
...is this what you've dragged
us here to find?
Us here to find?
A hermit's hut?
...I hated that place.
So many birds in the sky.
Almost darkened the sun.
They seemed to know something
they seemed to know something
we didn't.
We didn't.
[♪...]
He sent me to fetch water,
he sent me to fetch water,
but that was just a ruse.
But that was just a ruse.
[♪...]
[Darvell gasps]
[Screeching, flapping,
[screeching, flapping,
whooshing]
Whooshing]
[♪...]
I found the corpse.
His breath had gone.
His soul had fled.
[Chuckles]
And I ran.
I've never spoken of it since.
I took his rings...
...Hey!
...hey!
...And when I returned,
...and when I returned,
i took his property.
I took his property.
Everything I own is his.
What will he do?
[Dramatic music on TV...]
Bear in mind, Mr. Kent,
bear in mind, Mr. Kent,
this woman is not your
sister-in-law-- she's dead.
Sister-in-law-- she's dead.
This is a shell and what it
this is a shell and what it
contains is pure evil.
Contains is pure evil.
Oi! Shh!
...You destroy only the evil.
...you destroy only the evil.
[♪...]
[Woman hisses]
[Doorbell rings]
I'll get it.
No, no, no, no.
[♪...]
[Woman on television screams]
[Gate rattles]
[Chuckles] Aren't you a
little young?
Little young?
Eleanor, is she in?
Why, what's it to you?
I read her story.
Can you tell her please?
Well, she's not in.
Go on.
Off you go.
[♪...]
Ella.
Look, I understand what Claire's
look, I understand what Claire's
had to do, right, 'cause there's
money to be made, but--
if you don't like what
Clara's doing, tell her.
You don't like it either,
you don't like it either,
do you, eh?
Do you, eh?
Why she's like that?
Why's she so...
What happened to her, Ella?
She got bitten by a vampire.
Did I?
[Click]
There was a boy for you
there was a boy for you
at the door.
At the door.
I sent him on his way.
He says he's read your story.
[Whispers] What story, Ella?
The one we always tell.
About the care home and how my
about the care home and how my
sister rescued me.
Sister rescued me.
It's homework.
You frighten me sometimes.
Don't.
I won't.
[Gate squeaks]
Fucking brilliant story.
Thank you.
But the assignment asked
but the assignment asked
for truth.
For truth.
I didn't write it
as an assignment.
As an assignment.
I wrote it for you.
I don't want to lie anymore.
Something has to change.
But this?
It's crazy.
I thought...
If I told, all the walls would
if I told, all the walls would
come tumbling down.
Come tumbling down.
Yes.
I think I get that you're using
i think I get that you're using
the story to say that
bad things happened.
Bad things happened.
But... why don't you
but... why don't you
just say the truth?
I am Eleanor webb.
I've given you my secret.
I've told you how I live.
[Piano playing...]
[Woman continues playing...]
Woman, weakly: Hello.
...Would you put the record on?
[Woman sings opera]
It's called "nacht und traume."
[♪...]
Peace be with you.
May light shine upon you.
[Singing continues...]
[Playing piano slowly]
[Stops playing]
I think you should read this.
[Resumes playing]
[Stops]
...I set this every year.
It's a simple autobiography and
it's a simple autobiography and
then I get this amazing piece.
Then I get this amazing piece.
It's as if Edgar Allan poe and
it's as if Edgar Allan poe and
Mary shelley got together and
had a very strange little child.
Had a very strange little child.
"A true account of my making
"a true account of my making
and my life and death from the
year of my birth 1804."
Year of my birth 1804."
Kidding.
If that was a piece of
if that was a piece of
fiction, you'd say it was dark,
passionate, violent, sick,
brilliant bit of writing.
Brilliant bit of writing.
But she's saying,
but she's saying,
"this is who I am."
"This is who I am."
Which makes me think there's
which makes me think there's
something going on with her.
Something going on with her.
She's a very closed-off kid.
Well, she wants to
well, she wants to
communicate, obviously.
Communicate, obviously.
I mean, look at the effort
i mean, look at the effort
she's made.
She's made.
Her handwriting.
Turn of phrase.
Who writes like this these days?
"As darkness fell,
"as darkness fell,
the soucriant returned."
The soucriant returned."
Eleanor: And captain ruthven
prepared for the worst.
Prepared for the worst.
[♪...]
I took these for safekeeping.
Forgive me, my friend.
Forgiveness is a Christian
forgiveness is a Christian
value, ruthven.
Value, ruthven.
My gods are older...
More ruthless.
You died.
How else does one find
how else does one find
life eternal?
Life eternal?
[♪...]
I sent you to fetch water.
And I met the nameless Saint.
[♪...]
[Screeching, flapping,
[screeching, flapping,
whooshing...]
Whooshing...]
[Gasps]
This is what happens.
When?
When you pray for it.
[Screaming]
[♪...]
...I arose and saw
with different eyes.
With different eyes.
[♪...]
Everything I looked on
was a source of wonder.
Was a source of wonder.
But my vision had a price.
My soul was lost.
The price of my existence
the price of my existence
is this sacrifice.
Is this sacrifice.
It flows from...
[Clara coughing]
It flows from blood.
His blood is yours.
Drink, my son.
[Man groans]
Mine is a cruel existence...
But, you do have the qualities
but, you do have the qualities
one needs.
One needs.
You are ever... a survivor.
I would give my soul to be
as you are now.
As you are now.
So be it.
[♪...]
Eternal life will only come to
eternal life will only come to
those prepared to die.
[Gate clatters]
Hello?
You want up?
Thanks.
Have some fun now.
[Gate clatters]
[Music thumping...]
Hello?
Mr. minton.
Hello, Noel, how are you?
What, have I got detention
what, have I got detention
or something?
Or something?
[Chuckles] No.
I'm actually trying to get some
information on one of our
current students-- Eleanor webb.
Current students-- Eleanor webb.
She gave this as her address.
Eleanor?
Is everything o.K.?
We're trying to set up a
we're trying to set up a
meeting with all the parties
interested in her welfare.
Interested in her welfare.
Sure.
Are her parents here?
Um... you need to speak
um... you need to speak
to Claire.
To Claire.
She's Eleanor's big sister.
Claire's her legal guardian.
Is Claire here?
No, she's, um... busy.
[Laughter...]
It's not what you think.
It's Claire's business.
She saves girls from
she saves girls from
the streets.
The streets.
The thing is, Noel,
the thing is, Noel,
Eleanor's written a story and in
her story, she says that she
lives with vampires.
Lives with vampires.
So can you please pass this
so can you please pass this
letter on and tell Claire that
if I don't hear from her today,
then I'll be in touch with
social services and the police.
Social services and the police.
[Gate clatters, elevator whirs]
Shit...
So darvell gave the map and
so darvell gave the map and
passage to your mother?
Passage to your mother?
No, to captain ruthven.
[♪...]
My mother saw her chance
my mother saw her chance
and took it.
And took it.
[Gunshot, ruthven shouts]
Aah!
Bitch!
Eleanor: She stole the map
and rode into the night
towards her unknown future.
Towards her unknown future.
[♪...]
And she made her way to
and she made her way to
where, to this ruin and this...
Where, to this ruin and this...
Soucriant thing took her?
I didn't give you my story.
I've been betrayed into this.
You can leave anytime
you can leave anytime
you like.
So when did Clara come back
for you?
For you?
When I was 16.
And what did she do
and what did she do
in the meantime?
In the meantime?
She's never talked about it.
Really?
She says she can't recall,
she says she can't recall,
but I expect she's lying.
But I expect she's lying.
Lying is a way of life to her.
But I was raised in an orphanage
but I was raised in an orphanage
where I was taught to tell
the truth.
Are there others like you?
I've never met one.
And Clara never speaks of any.
I think we're the only two
i think we're the only two
who still endure.
Who still endure.
How often do you feed?
I'd rather not talk about it.
Thank you.
That's the distasteful part
that's the distasteful part
of being an immortal, isn't it?
Of being an immortal, isn't it?
If you don't believe a word
if you don't believe a word
i say, why this pretense?
I say, why this pretense?
[Clicks tongue] Eleanor, how
[clicks tongue] Eleanor, how
can you be two centuries old?
Can you be two centuries old?
By, by what miracle of science?
You see, that's the tricky
you see, that's the tricky
thing, because it's only over
time that I can prove it.
Time that I can prove it.
30, maybe 40 years from now,
when you're pruning roses from
your wheelchair, I'll stroll by
your garden gate and say,
"hello, morag."
"Hello, morag."
And nothing will have changed.
I am 16 forever.
And you'll realize this and it
and you'll realize this and it
will hurt your heart and I'll
say, "may peace be with you."
Say, "may peace be with you."
And I'll help you with the pain.
Why don't you do it now?
I'm not strong, you could...
Overpower me.
You're not ready.
[♪...]
[Playing fast, complex piece...]
How do you do it?
[Stops playing]
Where are your fangs?
Why don't you die in
why don't you die in
the daylight?
The daylight?
How could you give my story
how could you give my story
to those people?
To those people?
I wrote it for you.
How do you kill?
I never...
People have to consent.
They have to want.
Want death?
It has to be an...
Who the fuck wants death?
Sometimes it releases people.
So you're moral.
No.
I'm ruthless.
Bullshit.
All this "I'm 206, I remember
all this "I'm 206, I remember
everything and it's a burden."
Everything and it's a burden."
It's pathetic.
[Sighs]
My mom's giving me a
my mom's giving me a
birthday party.
Birthday party.
It's not really a party 'cause
it's not really a party 'cause
I'm only inviting you.
Will you come?
Yes.
Good.
[Playing same piece...]
[Door creaks]
[♪...]
[Rings doorbell]
[Breathes deeply]
Frank: Hi.
Happy Birthday.
For you.
Do I have to invite you in?
[♪...]
You'd better come in.
Gabi: Hello again, Ella.
Hello.
[♪...]
Seriously, you can try
if you like.
If you like.
[♪...]
I was hoping to arrange
a more official meeting,
ideally with the school
counselor and with
Eleanor herself.
Well, what's the problem?
'Cause, you know, usually she
'cause, you know, usually she
sails through school.
Sails through school.
Well, um, Eleanor wrote her
well, um, Eleanor wrote her
life story and uh, she's quite
insistent that it's true.
Insistent that it's true.
I don't expect you to be
i don't expect you to be
flattered by this, but in it
she describes you as a
soucriant, which I believe
is a sort of vampire.
Is a sort of vampire.
[Scoffs, laughs] Well, she
[scoffs, laughs] Well, she
has got a great imagination.
Has got a great imagination.
I hope she gets top marks.
Who else has read it?
You have sole care of her,
you have sole care of her,
don't you? That boyfriend,
i bet he's read it.
I bet he's read it.
Lot of responsibility for
lot of responsibility for
somebody so young.
Somebody so young.
I'm doing just fine,
thank you.
So, I shoot the bastard ruthven
and I Nick the map and
then what? Well, it ends.
Then what? Well, it ends.
She doesn't say, does she?
That's 'cause I never
that's 'cause I never
told her.
Told her.
[♪...]
Should we arrange a
should we arrange a
more formal--
I saw that ruthven
wasn't dead.
Wasn't dead.
I should have killed him then,
i should have killed him then,
but I had mercy on the cunt.
But I had mercy on the cunt.
Now, hold that thought because
now, hold that thought because
I'll tell you what he did.
But first, shall I tell you
but first, shall I tell you
what it was like for me?
What it was like for me?
[Nervously] O.K., yeah.
It was wonderful.
I had eyes that cut through
i had eyes that cut through
lies, lungs that breathed
eternity.
Eternity.
I felt I'd lived my whole
i felt I'd lived my whole
wretched life just to prepare me
for that moment.
For that moment.
[♪...]
[Man yells, Clara shouts,
growls, moans]
[Whispers] It was easy.
[♪...]
[Gasps, laughs]
Where's ruthven?
He wasn't worthy of
he wasn't worthy of
your gift.
Your gift.
You stole it?
Are we thieves now?
Do we steal time?
We buy it.
With blood.
We are a brotherhood.
There are no women amongst us.
What is her parentage?
It is low.
And her life before?
She made ends meet.
I was a harlot.
But that is in the past.
Some things are eternal.
You were to find a man of
you were to find a man of
good blood who appreciates this
brotherhood and what we do.
Brotherhood and what we do.
What is it you do?
We are the pointed nails
we are the pointed nails
of justice.
Of justice.
How will you use this gift?
To punish those who prey on
to punish those who prey on
the weak.
The weak.
To curb the power of men.
We should not permit
we should not permit
her to survive.
Her to survive.
We have no choice
we have no choice
unless she breaks our code.
Unless she breaks our code.
You have no part in our order.
Man 2: Truly you're base.
Will you not speak for me?
[♪...]
...they banished me.
I learned that immortality is
i learned that immortality is
unendurable alone.
Unendurable alone.
So I came back.
I watched my daughter grow.
She was my only link with
she was my only link with
everything alive.
Everything alive.
Woman: Back to sleep!
Back to sleep!
You!
Come on.
[♪...]
[Gasps]
...It was because of
...it was because of
Eleanor I broke their code.
How did you do that?
A woman's not permitted
a woman's not permitted
to create.
To create.
I took my darling to the
i took my darling to the
nameless island, I let that
thing save her.
Thing save her.
And for that, they would
and for that, they would
annihilate us both.
Annihilate us both.
You see, I had made a
you see, I had made a
fatal error.
Fatal error.
I'd been merciful.
I'd let ruthven live.
...Eleanor!
[Shudders]
Eleanor!
Give my regards to
give my regards to
your mother. [Eleanor sobbing]
Your mother. [Eleanor sobbing]
Welcome to a slow death.
Eleanor!
[Coins clink on floor]
Welcome...
Whore...
No!
[Ruthven grunting]
[Screaming]
Die! Die! [Sobs]
...Now you know everything.
...now you know everything.
I'm never merciful.
And knowledge is a fatal thing.
[Minton gasping]
[Clara sobbing and sighing]
Eleanor: When I was born,
there were only seven planets.
There were only seven planets.
Neptune hadn't been discovered,
so nobody believed in it.
So nobody believed in it.
Heaven and earth are full of
heaven and earth are full of
things we don't yet understand.
I had a year of chemotherapy.
Spent too much time lying in my
spent too much time lying in my
bed, so I made this.
That's you.
Near the sun.
Where it's warm and bright.
And that's me.
Where light barely penetrates.
And it's cold.
Time moves so slowly.
You're not cold.
[♪...]
Everything outside of time
everything outside of time
is cold.
Is cold.
[♪...]
If you kiss me right now,
would I live forever?
Would I live forever?
[♪...]
[Frank gasps]
[Gasps]
I'm sorry!
Wait!
[♪...]
Stop!
Why do you always run away
why do you always run away
from me?
From me?
If you stay with me,
if you stay with me,
you'll die.
You'll die.
I'm dying anyway.
It isn't life I offer you.
Do you understand that?
You'll take life.
By consent, like you do.
[Tearfully] It's still
[tearfully] It's still
monstrous.
Monstrous.
You'll leave everything behind.
Except you.
[♪...]
The gift I gave you, open it.
Wait until I knock.
[♪...]
Morag: Kevin?
Do you want to come to...
[♪...]
[Gate clatters]
There you are.
I've been worried sick.
Claire's not happy.
I've made changes.
Sent the girls home.
Bought them tickets on
bought them tickets on
the eurostar.
The eurostar.
It's going to be a clean
it's going to be a clean
house now.
House now.
No, I'm leaving.
What are you talking about?
What do you think
what do you think
you're doing?
You're doing?
Telling that fucking school
telling that fucking school
who we are.
Who we are.
I hate the way you speak,
it makes me sick!
It makes me sick!
How dare you put us in
how dare you put us in
such danger!
Such danger!
You told that fucking teacher
you told that fucking teacher
our story!
Our story!
I listened to his crap about
i listened to his crap about
your fantasies of death and all
the while, he was implying
my neglect!
My neglect!
Neglect, Eleanor, of you!
Stop it, Claire!
There is a rule that we live
there is a rule that we live
by and you broke it!
By and you broke it!
What if I broke free?
No!
To tell another is forbidden.
Those with knowledge
those with knowledge
have to die.
Have to die.
You made that rule so you
you made that rule so you
could isolate me.
Could isolate me.
No, I kept you safe!
You stupid fucking cunt,
you stupid fucking cunt,
mother, I hate you!
Mother, I hate you!
[Clara sobs]
No, no, no, leave her!
Just leave her!
Don't leave! Come back, Ella!
Get off!
Eleanor!
Claire!
No, you can't leave!
You're making it worse!
It's not safe, Eleanor!
You can't leave!
Just leave her be!
[Elevator stops]
No! Eleanor: Clara?
You can't leave,
you can't leave,
it's not safe! Clara!
It's not safe! Clara!
She has every right to go!
[Screams] [Gasps] no!
[Screams] [Gasps] No!
[Thud, Eleanor gasps]
[♪...]
Man: Know where she lives?
Yes, I believe it's the hotel
yes, I believe it's the hotel
on the seafront.
On the seafront.
Does she trust you?
Maybe.
I've never lied to her.
Darvell: That's good.
What will happen?
She'll be taken
she'll be taken
somewhere safe.
Somewhere safe.
We just want to talk to her.
You've told your little
you've told your little
boyfriend all about us,
haven't you? No!
Haven't you? No!
You know what happens to
you know what happens to
those with knowledge, Ella!
Those with knowledge, Ella!
No, Clara, don't!
It's like a virus--
it's like a virus--
it's deadly,
it needs to be stamped out.
It needs to be stamped out.
Clara, please, don't!
I know where he lives.
Don't! Clara, don't go!
Clara! Clara!
[Sobbing]
[Gate clatters]
[♪...]
[Cell phone buzzing]
Hello...
Frank.
Where's Eleanor?
She's got a message for you,
she's got a message for you,
can I come in?
Well, you're going to have to
come out here then, aren't you?
Come out here then, aren't you?
[♪...]
[Eleanor breathes raggedly]
I must say, you are
definitely Ella's type.
Definitely Ella's type.
Earnest, clueless, 'bout sexy
earnest, clueless, 'bout sexy
as a pair of shoes.
As a pair of shoes.
I knew you wouldn't let her
go without a fight.
Go without a fight.
Oh... is that what you're
oh... is that what you're
suggesting, Frank?
Suggesting, Frank?
A fight?
[Frank gasps]
Go on.
Finish me.
I still have the advantage.
She's going to leave you anyway.
[Phone ringing]
Eleanor: Frank!
Clara's coming.
Don't answer the door,
don't answer the door,
don't let her in.
Don't let her in.
I'm trapped here.
She caught me.
Just don't let her get you.
It's too late, my love.
I will never forgive,
i will never, ever forgive!
I will never, ever forgive!
Eleanor, what the hell
is going on?
Is going on?
It's Clara, you have to
it's Clara, you have to
stop her! [Gate clatters]
Stop her! [Gate clatters]
These men are looking
these men are looking
for her, where she is?
For her, where she is?
Eleanor: She's here. Ella.
Eleanor, you have to tell us
the truth... something terrible
has happened to Kevin.
Has happened to Kevin.
Clara webb?
Who is this?
You know who we are,
you know who we are,
whore mother.
Whore mother.
I will take care of Eleanor now.
Ella!
[Gasps] Ella!
[♪...]
These men are from the
these men are from the
police, Eleanor.
Police, Eleanor.
They've come to, to help.
[Latch snaps, gate clatters]
We have to get to Frank!
Morag: We will get to Frank,
morag: We will get to Frank,
we need to get you to a doctor,
Eleanor, don't run!
What are you doing?
We need to get to Frank!
Morag: You don't need
morag: You don't need
handcuffs, she's a child!
Handcuffs, she's a child!
Eleanor, I'm coming with you.
Man: Certainly, come.
[Clara breathes raggedly]
[♪...]
I will be with you whatever
happens, there's no need
to be afraid.
To be afraid.
Man: Of course not.
It's a privilege to meet you,
it's a privilege to meet you,
Eleanor.
[♪...]
I thought Clara and I
were the only ones.
Were the only ones.
Surely she told you of
surely she told you of
the brotherhood.
The brotherhood.
Excuse me, what are you
excuse me, what are you
saying to-- darvell.
Saying to-- darvell.
You're just as I imagined.
Help me.
Morag: Where exactly are you
morag: Where exactly are you
taking us, because we've just
gone right past the police
station and the hospital.
Station and the hospital.
Seriously, where are we going?
Eleanor! [Glass cracks]
Ella! [Glass shatters]
Ella! Mother!
They'll destroy you, Ella!
They'll destroy you!
Darvell, let her go!
[Tires screeching...]
Mother! Please!
Now I'm going to show you,
now I'm going to show you,
piece of whore.
Piece of whore.
[Brakes squeal, Clara screams]
Yes! [Tires screech]
Oh, my God, you killed her!
Nothing is that easy.
[Changes gears, morag whimpers]
Mother! Mother!
With this act, I cleanse
with this act, I cleanse
the earth! Mother! No!
The earth! Mother! No!
[Tires screech]
[Morag whimpering]
Be calm, be calm.
Who are you people?
I said be calm!
[Bones crack]
I hate these crying women.
[♪...]
Damn you.
I've followed you
for many years.
For many years.
You take only those who are
you take only those who are
ready... and that has
a certain grace.
A certain grace.
[Metal creaks, bangs underfoot]
You have been condemned from
you have been condemned from
the moment Clara made you.
The moment Clara made you.
Our code does not permit women
our code does not permit women
to create.
To create.
[♪...]
In her stories,
you are wonderful.
You are wonderful.
You had compassion and respect.
You gave her life.
She stole her life.
Please.
Please, stop him.
She killed one of
she killed one of
the brethren.
The brethren.
And that's unforgivable.
Don't go...
[Thud, man grunts]
[Clara shouts]
[Man gasping]
Amazing how two little girls
amazing how two little girls
with no money and learning
slipped through your fingers
for an eternity.
For an eternity.
[Shouting]
[Thud, Clara grunts, screams]
Hold her down. Ella!
Hold her down.
No, no, no...!
No! Eleanor! Ah!
Ella!
Eleanor!
Bring it here.
Bring it here!
Isn't the present everything?
Ella!
This is your last night,
this is your last night,
witch. No...!
Witch. No...!
Last night!
Eleanor! [Sobbing]
[Metal scrapes]
[♪...]
[Eleanor sobbing]
[Clara panting...]
This blade is from Byzantium.
My souvenir of the crusades.
May it send you to eternity.
It was on a beach like this
it was on a beach like this
that we first met.
That we first met.
But I went with ruthven,
but I went with ruthven,
for all my damnation.
For all my damnation.
But it was you,
but it was you,
you were the pearl.
You were the pearl.
See how the bitch uses
see how the bitch uses
her arts to the last.
Her arts to the last.
The honor is yours.
[♪...]
Do what you like with me,
do what you like with me,
but let her go, please!
But let her go, please!
Hold her still.
Please, I beg you, darvell!
Still, I said!
She's going to die anyway!
She can't survive on her own!
Eleanor... [eleanor screams]
My baby!
[Whoosh, squish]
[♪...]
[Head bangs down stairs]
[Sighs]
[Eleanor gasps, sobs]
You truly are a wonder.
[Sniffles, sobs]
[Sobbing]
[Both crying]
Darvell: I've been following
you for years...
You for years...
So assiduously.
Because if I wasn't the one
because if I wasn't the one
to find you, they certainly
would have killed you.
Would have killed you.
What will they do,
what will they do,
the others?
The others?
The brotherhood is strong,
the brotherhood is strong,
unchanging.
Unchanging.
They will come.
With their pointed nails
with their pointed nails
of justice.
Of justice.
[Flames roar, crackle]
[Clara humming...]
Will he travel with us now?
You're not coming with us.
What?
I'm cutting you loose.
You can't stay with your mother
you can't stay with your mother
all your life, can you?
Come on.
[♪...]
Come here.
[Eleanor cries,
Clara stifles sob]
Go on.
Look forward, not back.
Always.
[♪...]
[Sobs, crying...]
Your instinct is to hunt the
your instinct is to hunt the
powerful and protect the weak.
Powerful and protect the weak.
I'd like to try and live
that way.
That way.
Live your life how you
live your life how you
choose, it's no concern of mine.
Choose, it's no concern of mine.
[♪...]
If you could have anything,
if you could have anything,
what would it be?
What would it be?
Your pardon?
In time.
Maybe.
Your company, then?
We have time.
[♪...]
[Gulls cawing...]
[Water rushing...]
[♪...]
Frank: I'm afraid.
Don't be.
[♪...]
I am Eleanor webb.
I throw my story to the wind
i throw my story to the wind
and never will I tell it more.
And never will I tell it more.
Another one begins.
♪