Woman on P.A.:
...terminal A of Boston International Airport.
Transportation
between terminals...
(overlapping voices)
TSA Employee:
Take your laptop out of your bag.
(Overlapping voices
continue)
(phones ringing)
Man on P.A.:
The Boston Police Department requests
that for your safety
and security
and per FAA regulations...
(overlapping chatter)
I'll be home in a few.
Get off in about an hour.
Space cadet, get me a...
Man on TV:
...to go in this quarter.
They need to score
on this drive.
(Overlapping conversations)
Man:
Don't lie to me, okay?
You sound like
one of my kids.
Woman on P.A.:
Gate number 26.
Miss Lauren Goodwin,
please report to gate number 26.
(Buzzer sounds)
Man on TV:
Back to the huddle.
Second down and nine
from their own...
- (phone ringing)
- (woman speaking on P.A.)
Woman:
She's so annoying.
Elizabitch, get your
bony ass over here.
- What is going on?
- Don't hang up on her.
Woman on P.A.:
Your baggage can be claimed at carousel number three.
Please see a gate agent...
Put security cameras
in the whole house.
- Except for the bedroom.
- (Phones ringing)
Christie wouldn't
go for that.
My pool cleaner's
even gone rogue.
No, I'm serious.
Yeah, it's jumping out
of the pool on its own.
Man on P.A.: There is a flight 3598 to Manchester,
New Hampshire.
Your gate number has been
changed to gate A6.
The flight will depart
on time at 4:15 p.m.
Passengers on flight 3598
to Manchester, New Hampshire,
your gate number
has been changed...
(phone ringing)
- Woman: Hello?
- Hey, it's me.
Just got off the plane.
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
I'm picking up Johnny at school.
I'm getting a sitter
from the bus stop.
Going back to the lab because
we got completely slammed.
Sharon, they made an offer.
A big, big offer.
For all the rights
to "Night Traveler."
We're talking about
graphic platforms,
virtual reality,
algorithms,
interface user stuff,
I don't know.
That's amazing, Clay.
Congratulations.
Yeah.
Well, you know,
it's a big deal, yeah.
So are you going out
to celebrate tonight?
Celebrate?
Celebrate, no.
Yeah, this is
a big night for you.
I just assumed you'd want
to celebrate with someone.
Not really.
So you're not
with someone?
No. No.
There's nobody.
Hey, is that Dad?
Can I talk to him?
(Beeps)
- Hi, Dad.
- Hey, buddy.
- How you doing?
- We did the parachute drill today.
- Yeah.
- You put a little parachute on your bat.
I swear, my swing is like
100 times faster.
That's great.
Are you coming home?
Yeah, yeah, soon.
- I just want you to come home.
- Ah, shit.
(Woman speaking over P.A.)
(phones ringing)
(overlapping conversations)
(ringing)
Hi, Shar, it's me.
Yeah, I ran out of juice.
Listen, there's a flight
to Manchester that leaves
in about an hour.
Clay, you've been gone
for over a year.
I love you,
but it's not that simple.
I'd like to see my son.
- Shit.
- Operator: Your time is up.
- I need more money. Hold on.
- Please deposit--
(man screaming)
(groaning)
- (screaming)
- (people shouting)
- (high-pitched whine)
- (men screaming)
- (people screaming)
- What's wrong with you? Stop it!
(Growling)
Get off him!
What are you doing? Get off!
(Groaning)
(growling)
Get off of her!
(Girl screaming)
(screaming)
Stop that!
Woman:
Go! Go! Go!
(Screaming)
Oh, my God, Chloe.
Hey, hey, hey,
don't touch her.
- I'm not gonna touch her.
- She might be contagious.
I need to call 911, though.
- (Dials)
- Hello? Hello?
(Dog whining)
(growling)
(laughing)
(growls)
(screams)
Let me see your goddamn hands!
Get your hands in the air!
(Gunshots)
Why'd you do that?
What, are you gonna shoot everybody?
- What the hell is happening?
- Who the hell knows?
- Quick, let's go.
- Don't use your cell phone.
- Why?
- They did.
(Screams)
(alarm blaring)
- Woman: Help me!
- (Gunshots)
(people screaming)
(gunshots continue)
(panting)
(man screaming)
(jet engine roaring)
(men snarling)
(snarling continues)
(growling)
(people groaning)
No, no, no.
Bro, stop, he's normal.
Hey, hey, hey!
Come on.
Let's go, bro.
Bro, come on.
- (Explosion)
- Don't use your cell phones.
Man: We've been trying,
but we can't get a signal down here.
We need to get out of this airport right
now before it burns to the ground.
Man: Get out of here?
We ain't going nowhere.
Is there a driver
on this train?
- That'd be me.
- Clay: Can we leave?
- No.
- Man: Oh, no.
Central shut down the power,
emergency brakes came up,
and this train can't
move more than 50 feet.
- Shit.
- (Explosions)
- We could walk.
- Woman: Walk?
Man: Walk?
Ain't nobody walking.
- What did you say?
- We could walk.
I got maps of the system
and I got all the maintenance
tunnels with the exits marked.
We can walk
right out of here.
That's a brilliant idea.
You're my new best friend.
- What are you gonna do when the
T starts running again? - Let's go.
You don't want to come,
you don't got to come. I don't care.
You guys are idiots.
We're safe right here.
Only if this lasts less
than 24 hours.
- What do you mean?
- The groundwater.
The sewage workers
pump out the groundwater.
If nobody's manning the pumps,
whole system floods.
All of this
will be underwater.
You'll be forced into the terminal
or back out in the streets.
And if Boston is still burning
or if what he's saying is true...
Man: Don't listen to him.
We're not gonna be down here that long.
- Do you want to stay here or do you want to go?
- It's gonna blow over.
- These things always do.
- Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo. Can I come with you?
- I'm not gonna stop you.
- Yo, awesome. Deuces, man.
- You don't even know him.
- Adios.
Teenager: You think this is
happening everywhere or just here?
Driver: We'll know in a little while.
We lose power,
means it's happening everywhere.
Nobody's manning
the power stations.
Probably running
for their lives like us.
Wonder how many folks were on
those things when it happened.
A lot.
Too many.
Like everybody.
And those that didn't get it the first time got zapped
when they tried to call
911 or their families.
Hmm.
I'm Tom McCourt,
by the way.
Clay Riddell.
Good to know you.
Mike Mattick.
They call me DJ Liquid.
- Keep moving.
- Tom: DJ.
I got to get to Kent Pond.
My family is up there.
I've got a wife and son. You know,
in New Hampshire. Kent Pond?
You got anybody
you need to check on?
- I got my boo.
- Did you say "my boo"?
- Yeah, what you got, huh?
- Come on, come on.
My man, he done left me,
so I ain't got nobody. I live alone.
(Phone chimes)
Yo, I got service.
What does that mean?
I don't know.
Put that thing down.
Are they normal?
- They look normal to you?
- I don't know.
You want to take that chance?
What's abnormal?
(Snarling)
- (groans)
- (screams) Shit!
Shit! Come on!
Come on!
(Snarling)
Come on! Run!
(Grunts)
Come on, man.
Come on.
(Alarm blaring)
(growling)
Come on! Give me your hand.
Give me your hand.
Come on. Come on.
(Growling)
The Dumpster.
I got it.
(Shouting)
Go. Go.
(Alarms ringing)
Hold it.
Clay:
I know her.
- Okay, what floor?
- Two.
Okay, go. Go.
- (Dog barking)
- Shit, hurry up!
Hurry up.
Yeah, dead.
(Cat meows)
Think it's safe to text?
I'm out of juice.
I've got to text my family,
see if they're okay.
Can I borrow
your phone, please?
(Beeps)
(chimes)
It's all jumbled up.
Scrambled.
Why don't you stick
my phone in the freezer?
It makes the battery
last longer.
Probably need it
to check the signal.
If we don't make any calls,
it should last for a few days.
You draw all these?
- (Water running)
- Yeah.
My graphic novel.
Tom: I was thinking about that poor kid
down in the tunnel.
DJ...
Liquid?
God damn.
You know, if we're going to survive this,
whatever it is,
people are gonna
have to put aside
their finer sensibilities.
If they can't,
they're gonna die.
(Pounding on door)
Woman:
Hello?
- She sound normal?
- Hello?
- Please, someone be there.
- Are you normal?
What do you think?
Open the damn door.
(Panting)
- Okay.
- I live upstairs.
Yeah, I've seen you before.
I'm Clay.
- Tom.
- I'm Alice.
I think you guys should close the blinds.
I don't think that's smart.
You guys should
close the blinds.
I don't think it's gonna be good
if somebody sees us in here.
He's gonna close them.
Tom, you close them.
See, he's closing them.
- Are you hurt?
- What do you mean, am I hurt?
Are you physically injured?
Can I help you?
(Crying)
I killed my mom.
I want to get out of this dress because it really smells.
Like blood and sweat
and my mom's perfume.
My girlfriend
might have left some jeans.
I think they'd
just about fit you.
And I have pajamas.
I have plenty of pajamas.
Okay?
Yeah, I'm just tired.
Here, do you want
to maybe...
There's still some hot water
if you want to take a shower.
Uh-huh, okay.
Thank you.
(Thunder rumbles)
(purring)
Clay: Listen, Tom,
I'm gonna head north
to Kent Pond in the morning
as soon as it gets light.
I think you and Alice should
probably come with me.
Clay, I'm really sorry
about your family.
Don't be sorry because there's
nothing to be sorry about yet.
My kid had a cell phone,
but he never made calls.
He just texted, you know?
Liked games.
But my wife,
she had one and I called her right before it happened.
When I met you.
So I don't know if she was on it.
I just want you to know I'm real
glad I ran into you today, Tom.
(Door opens)
You okay?
Oh, um, I found
these in your pocket.
Hope you don't mind.
No, no, no, no.
Here, maybe
drink something.
- No.
- Do you want something to eat?
No.
If you guys go somewhere,
can I come with you?
Hoping you'd say that.
Clay:
Definitely.
Yeah.
I'm gonna try
and get some rest now.
Yeah, we'll be here.
Yeah.
So...
some kind
of terrorist attack
or some shit,
do you think?
I don't know, man.
Well, whoever it was,
us three are like bugs
who had the dumb luck
to avoid the stomp
of the giant's foot.
(Phone ringing)
(ringing stops)
(snarling)
(shouting)
They're like birds.
They're acting like
a flock of birds.
Tom:
Well, I don't like it.
I don't like this flocking
thing at all.
I mean, whatever it is,
I've just got to get to Kent Pond
and find out
about my wife and son.
If you guys don't want to come,
I totally get it.
(Growling)
- (snarling)
- (Alice gasps)
(dog barking)
Hold up.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
- I don't know.
- Should we go back?
- (Tires squeal)
- (roaring)
Woman: Oh,
my God! Help me!
Help me!
- (Man groaning)
- Oh, Jesus.
- (Cracking, tearing)
- (man screaming) Oh, God!
- Should we help them?
- No, no, no, no.
- Nothing we can do.
- We go back or we go right now.
No, go, go, go.
They're not looking.
- They're not looking. Go, go.
- Go.
Tom:
Where they all go?
Clay: Maybe we got lucky and they all dropped off,
you know,
when they lost the signal like at the train station.
Tom. Tom.
Always considered
myself a pacifist,
but I wouldn't mind
having a pistol right now.
Um, guys.
I don't think
that's a good idea.
Clay: I go in with my hands raised
and just say
I want to talk.
Maybe ring the doorbell.
What's the worst that can happen?
I'm a black man
with a crowbar.
I'm not walking
over there.
Okay, how about
that one?
Oh, that makes all the difference in the world.
(Clatters)
Oh, my God.
Oh, my.
Why don't you
take care of Alice?
I'll get what we came for.
(Flies buzzing)
Here, take this.
Uh-uh.
(Cocks gun)
- What?
- Look at you.
Yeah, basic training.
You never forget.
Grab some ammo.
Clay: How do you load these things?
You guys,
there's someone out here.
What?
He's by himself.
Close 'em.
Close the drapes.
(Swing squeaking)
Hey, are you okay?
Hello.
Kid.
- (Barking)
- (snarling)
Clay:
Oh, shit.
(Swing squeaking)
I guess they don't
all travel in flock--
(growling, snarling)
(gunshot)
(panting)
(cracks)
Fuck this.
(Gunshots)
Let's go.
(Clicking, screeching)
(whispers)
What the hell?
Tom: Well,
it looks like when the sun goes down
they're programmed
to pack it in.
It was like they all
did it together.
Like it was an automated
response or something.
You know what I don't get
is how they all knew
exactly where
we were that fast.
I mean, it's not like they
were watching us or anything.
Not with their own
eyes anyway.
Not with their own--
so you're saying when that kid saw us,
they all saw us?
How else do you
explain it?
- So now they're psychic?
- Telepathic.
Like maybe the pulse
flows through them
like they're this big,
organic, you know, network.
Alice:
Like a hive mind.
(Chuckles)
Yeah.
Clay:
You got anything better?
(Geese honking)
Tom: What makes you think they're still there?
I mean, no matter what
or how it went down,
don't you think
they might have bailed?
Clay: If they're safe,
they would have left a message.
Lost most of my money in the great collapse of '08.
And I lost my emotional stability
in the great divorce of '09.
(Chuckles)
You know, at the time,
I thought that was the end of the world.
- Whoa, what is that?
- (Music playing)
- You hear that?
- Yeah.
It's music.
Greetings, gentlemen.
Miss.
Welcome to Gaiten Academy.
If you folks need a place to stay for the night,
we have plenty of rooms.
The boys who didn't have
cell phones have all run off.
The ones
who did have them--
Oh, we know about that.
I'm Jordan.
I'm a scholarship boy.
- I lived in Holloway.
- Good for you, Jordan.
Yes, sir.
That's what the Head said, too.
Charles Ardai.
Headmaster.
Quite a problem these cell phones have caused now,
isn't it?
(Chuckles)
The devil's intercom
is what I used to call them.
Nice.
It's apt.
Clay:
What's with the music?
Did you ever play
musical chairs as a child?
- Yeah.
- Well, as long as the music doesn't stop,
we've got nothing
to worry about.
We'll have a quick peek,
then we'll go over to Cheatham Lodge for dinner.
It's not 200 yards to
Tonney Field, I promise.
(Music continues)
Alice:
Holy shit.
Is the music coming
from their phones?
Charles: Don't worry,
they won't wake up.
Tom: How can you be so sure of that?
Observe.
- What the hell are you doing?
- (Cocks gun)
Charles: No, no,
he's calm. He's calm.
I could put my sword cane
right through his throat
and he wouldn't
try to stop me.
Nor would those around him
spring to his defense.
Of course, if I tried
it in the daylight,
they'd tear me limb
from limb.
The music comes from
their mouths, too.
It's not hardly a whisper,
but you can hear it.
- Come here.
- That's got to be your imagination.
- There's no way that they're actually talking.
- Come listen.
It's like
they don't breathe.
I can hear it.
How is that even possible
without a transmitter?
They are transmitting.
It's a new skill they seem to have picked up.
And they're changing
at an alarming rate.
Alice: Can we please move this conversation inside?
Please.
Charles:
We cannot overestimate
the developmental leaps
we're witnessing here.
They appear
to be eusocial.
Like a colony
of bees or ants.
They act for the good
of the group as a whole.
There's no competitiveness,
no selfishness.
In fact,
they may be the next stage in human evolution.
Every human
on planet Earth
will be part
of one giant organism.
No individuality.
No privacy. Come on.
No war.
No resource depletion.
- No conflict.
- No, thank you.
As to what they're doing at
night as they lie there so still,
open-eyed and listening
to their music,
we think
they're rebooting.
Yeah, I mean,
they might as well have
"software updating,
please stand by" blinking on their foreheads.
You mean they had
their brains wiped?
Yeah, I mean,
what is a brain?
It's just a big
old hard drive.
Organic circuitry.
No one knows
how many bytes.
Like, giga to the power
of googolplex, let's say.
An infinity of bytes.
If your brain were an info strip on a hard drive,
it would say something like
2 % in use, 98 % available.
Holmes, you astound me.
- I love cybernetics.
- Ah.
Cyberpunk fiction, too.
William Gibson.
Clay: Neal Stephenson,
you like him?
Neal Stephenson is a god.
Yeah, he's pretty good.
Right now
the nights are ours.
But what happens if they decide
that they need less sleep?
What happens if they decide to
grow against their digital lullabies?
What happens
when they're not
afraid of the dark?
What are you suggesting?
I think what's happening now is
more than temporary anarchy.
I think it's the start
of a war.
It's going to be a short
but extremely nasty one.
But what does one
do in a war?
One kills one's enemies.
Well, even with
the guns we have,
it'll be slow work.
We have a gasoline pump
in our little motor pool.
Gasoline may serve
to end their lives.
Hold up.
You want to napalm them?
We have a sprayer truck
that we use
to keep our playing
fields very green.
I want to wipe them out.
I agree with him.
I think we should wipe them out.
The ones
on the soccer field.
And I don't want to do it
for the human race.
I want to do it
for my mom.
As many as we can,
as fast as we can.
Before it's too late.
(Music playing)
We sure we want
to do this?
Oh, yeah, for sure.
Let's go.
(Engine starts)
I'm sure.
(Music continues)
(squishing)
Whoa.
Holy cow.
(Groans)
All right.
(Exhales)
Do you like first-person
shooter games?
Yeah.
Pretty freaked out,
huh?
I'm fine.
How about you?
Freak city.
(Truck engine revving)
- Oh.
- (Squishing)
Tom:
We have a problem?
No, no, no.
It's great.
Put it in a lower gear.
Yeah, it's not like I've done this before,
all right?
Just put it
in a lower gear.
Yeah, we were just on somebody's head or something.
All right.
They're coming back.
(Brakes squeal)
No, you've had enough of that to be DUI.
You know that, right?
Yeah.
But it won't
really count
after the mass
murder, you know?
No one knows better than me
that you can't stop progress.
But still, you're never
too old to fight it.
(Howling)
- (music stops)
- Uh-oh.
Holy shit.
Alice: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
(Gunshots)
Shit, the truck.
Get down!
(Grunts)
Alice, you all right?
Yeah, yeah,
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Shit.
Ardai!
(Crying)
No!
Help.
Help him.
Somebody help him.
Tom. Clay.
Help him.
- (Sobbing)
- Okay.
No.
Come on, buddy.
Come on. It's okay.
All right.
(Howling)
- Tom: What is that?
- Yeah, I feel it, too.
It feels like rage.
We got to go right now.
Tom: Do not withhold your mercy from us,
O Lord.
May your love and your truth
always protect us.
For troubles without number
surround us.
Our sins have overrun us
and we cannot see.
Our sins are more than
the hairs of our head
and our hearts
fail within us.
Be pleased to save us,
O Lord.
O Lord, come quickly
to help us.
May those who seek
to take our lives
as this life was taken
be put to shame
and confusion.
May those
who desire ruin
be turned back
in disgrace.
May all those
who say to us,
"Aha.
Aha..."
be appalled
by their own shame.
For here lies the dead.
The dust of the Earth.
(Exhales)
(gasps)
(water dripping)
(man moaning)
(chuckles)
(gasps)
(breathing heavily)
Jordan:
Nightmare?
Clay:
Yeah.
- You, too?
- Yeah.
I thought when you get older,
the nightmares go away.
No, they still happen.
They just grow up, too.
There was this
really creepy,
disgusting guy
in my dream.
He was dirty. Yellow teeth.
He had on a red hoodie.
- What?
- Long hair.
Does he have
a tear on his cheek?
Alice: In my dream,
he was poking my neck with a knitting needle
and calling me insane.
In a red hoodie?
Pushed me in front
of a speeding train.
The guy in my dream,
that's the character
from my graphic novel.
You know, my comic book,
"The Night Traveler."
He's the guy in the drawings on
your wall of your apartment?
Yes. He's a, you know,
prophet of the apocalypse.
So you saw
all this shit coming?
Hey, it was just
a comic book, man.
Unless this is just all
my goddamn dream.
You may have had it first,
but you're definitely not the only one.
It's getting dark.
Let's get out of here.
- Alice: Yeah.
- Yeah, I don't want to sleep no more.
(Phone ringing)
(phone ringing)
(ringing continues)
(ringing)
(crows cawing)
Clay:
"Kashwak equals No-Fo."
"I heart Kashwak."
What does that mean?
Maybe No-Fo means
no phones.
Like a dead zone.
No cell phone towers, so it's safe.
You can't assume that.
It's too early to think we know the rules.
(Knocks)
(music playing inside)
Open up!
We're Americans.
Clay:
Happy hour start yet?
Ooh, company.
You're cute.
You, sir,
are very cute.
Thank you.
And you, my love,
are to die for.
No phoners
come through here.
(Through electrolarynx) Phoners don't like English food.
English people
don't like English food.
- Hey, I do, mister.
- All right, all right.
What the hell is Kashwak?
What do you guys think that is?
Oh, you know Kashwak.
Up in Maine.
It's an unincorporated
area they call TR-90.
Kashwakamak Lake.
Everybody's going there.
Everybody who hasn't been pulsed.
We're going.
We're leaving tomorrow.
Thanks for letting us
come in tonight.
Mmm, we're happy
you're here.
We're really glad you're here.
(Chuckles)
You think Bob Dylan's
a phoner?
(Laughs)
That's a good one.
Tom: There's no-- there's no telephone songs on here.
That would-- that would
be apropos, right?
Like...
¶ Mr. Telephone Man ¶
¶ There's something
wrong with my line ¶
¶ When I call
my baby's number ¶
¶ I get a click every-- ¶
Oh, D2. D2.
(Music playing)
That's like the devil
of ego, right?
The vanity of
super individuality.
But the other one was
this one called Arama.
And he was, like,
a demon of big data.
Of numbers,
of abstraction.
- Right? You know what I'm saying?
- Yeah.
- You with me? You with me, Geoff?
- Hell, yeah.
Tom: When I came home from Vietnam,
you know, I was lost,
drifting and...
somebody reached out
their hand
and they saved my life.
They might be dead now
or even part of the flock
that's trying
to pull me in.
All I know is
that I didn't
survive a war
and all the rest of it
just to get pulled in
by this fucker
or his flock.
You know, the first time
I saw his face,
it wasn't dreams,
it was in his house.
On the wall.
You drew him.
I'm not the first guy to draw a devil on a piece of paper.
- Tom: The devil?
- Yeah.
- How's it end?
- I never finished it.
I mean, it's like
a serial graphic novel.
Didn't really end.
It was just a game and a story.
- Just a game?
- Mm.
Good always
conquers evil.
Now, I believe that.
¶ So long
I've been saving ¶
¶ Tonight was made
for me and you ¶
¶ You can ring my bell ¶
¶ Ring my bell ¶
¶ My bell,
ring my bell ¶
¶ You can ring my bell ¶
¶ Ring my bell ¶
¶ My bell... ¶
You know, and I saw you
with your son once, too.
And I always wanted that.
Anyway, I saw you leave your
apartment with that woman
and I just really
hated that.
- Liz?
- Liz.
Hated that.
Always seemed like
you were pissed at me.
I never knew
what was up with you.
You'd give me
that death stare.
(Chuckles)
Yeah.
I give everyone
the death stare.
But I know you
love your family.
I've seen you
with your son
and I know that shit
happens with couples,
just--
You're gonna
find him, Clay.
You're gonna find him.
You think?
You are.
We were traveling
in the dark
and that was really,
really dark for me.
'Cause I had him.
And I had her.
I had some bullshit job
that I hated
doing graphic design
for some stupid company.
But I hated myself for not having
the balls to do what I wanted
and I hated Sharon for loving me when I hated myself
and all these warped,
convoluted feelings.
Sometimes
I'd get home from work
and I'd change into
my rock and roll T-shirt
and I'd go to the bar and smoke weed
and listen to Norwegian death metal
like some teenager who wanted
to blow up his high school.
It was pathetic.
Then one day I just split
and moved out.
And do you
like being there?
First night I was there,
I knew it was a mistake.
Very first night.
I called Sharon
the day of the Pulse.
I couldn't tell her
I missed her
and that I wanted
to come home.
I said I want
to see my son.
See, I had to prove I was right and
to prove I was special, you know?
I mean,
probably just wanted her to be proud of you.
Well, be great
if that were true.
I think I was
just an asshole.
Here.
That's what you look like.
Human beings are the religion of the angels.
And that is an angel in exile.
What do you think?
(Dog yelping)
(groans)
(yelping continues)
Clay:
Sally?
(Snarling)
(moaning)
Get out of my fucking bar!
(Gunshot)
(whimpers)
(grunting)
Get off!
(Gunshot)
(growling)
Get off!
Clay:
Hold on, Tom!
(Gunshots)
(screaming)
(shrieking)
(gunshot)
(growling)
(shrieking)
(screams)
- (growling)
- (screaming)
(gunshots)
- Alice!
- (Shrieks)
(gunshots)
Alice!
Grab my blanket.
It's okay.
- Keep that over her.
- (Shivering)
It's okay, baby.
Okay.
Grab underneath her.
Come on.
Help me bring her up.
Bring her up.
Okay.
(Birds cawing)
Let it snow.
'Cause then we can
build a fort.
Or a leaf.
Or a bird.
We can build a bird.
We can make
a snowman.
Or we could play
the slinky one.
(Sniffles)
I'm so sorry, buddy.
(Wind blowing)
You know, back in the tavern,
they attacked at night.
The Head said
this would happen.
He also said they'd find new ways
of maintaining their numbers.
You saw what happened
back there, right?
They're not just killing anymore,
they're recruiting.
The pulse is coming
from their mouths now.
They don't need
phones anymore.
(Hooting)
(birds cawing)
Well, well, well.
Man: The President of the Internet
said you'd be coming this way.
And, well, here you are.
- Who are you?
- Why don't you put your shotgun down, my friend?
I'll be happy
to tell you who I am.
I'm Ray Huizenga
from Groveland, Mass.
This young lady here,
Denise Link from Haverhill, neighboring town.
Meetcha.
Ray: But our names don't actually matter anymore.
What matters-- what matters is what we do.
And what we do, hmm?
We kill phone freaks.
Yeah, yeah,
we kill them.
Just like you.
Denise:
The second time in Nashua,
we used dynamite from
a construction site shed.
Ray knew how to rig the dynamite
from when he worked on a road crew.
Ray: That's when we started
seeing those Kashwak No-Fo signs.
Denise: Kashwak.
They're telling people
it's a no-phone zone,
but that's a lie.
The area got an Indian
casino built there last year
and finally put up
a cell phone tower.
The phoners are trying to draw us there in our dreams,
but it's a trap.
Ray: Yeah,
and the dreams started coming after we blasted.
I mean, we blasted.
That first flock, we blasted them.
- You know, powerful dreams. Powerful dreams, like--
- Tom: We've had them.
Ray: Always that phoner.
The phoner in the red hoodie.
- They call him the President of the Internet.
- Yeah.
Got to be taken down.
I mean down.
Like, down, like--
like right there.
We've got to take him
all the way down.
You know what I'm saying?
You take him all the way down.
If you kill him-- you kill him-- you put him in here,
the rest will-- they'll surrender.
They'll quit.
They'll stop.
Just... poof.
But it's not gonna be easy.
Know why?
'Cause they get inside of people's minds.
They get inside
of people's minds.
your mind, Ray?
No, nothing in my mind.
Because I stay up, hmm?
I've been awake, what, four, five,
six-- six days now?
- Clay: That's great.
- Denise: It's true.
She sleeps in there,
I'm out here guarding.
I'll pace all night.
I'll be all over this park.
- Mary had a little lamb. She's my Mary.
- Aw.
- It's not my kid. Not my kid.
- Denise: No.
Ray: But she's my Mary.
I'm looking after her.
That's great.
Sounds like you guys are in a good place.
Oh, yeah.
But you know what?
We can resist as long as we stay awake.
Staying awake is key.
We just stay away from the flocks.
How you plan
on doing that?
Ray: Oh, we got ourselves a canary in a coal mine,
my friend.
Hey, Denise, you want to show them and
I'll finish cooking the burgers with your son?
Denise: My brother's doing more to help me out now
than he ever did
when he was human.
I still hate
to see him like this.
- He's a phoner?
- Yup.
Yeah, he's like
a little calf
that broke off from
the herd and got lost.
On its own, he's nothing.
He just sits here and waits for
them to come back and find it
or else he dies.
God, he hasn't
been eating.
Come on,
don't do this to me.
If a flock passes
within a mile or so,
he starts coming to
and acting up.
The closer they are,
the crazier he gets.
That's why we got
him covered up.
We don't want him showing them where
we are and bringing them down on us.
(Sighs) Come on,
don't do this to me.
(Sighs)
Sometimes I think he can
still recognize my voice.
- You think they can be rehabbed?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Johnny's voice: Are you coming home?
Are you coming home?
- Tom: What the hell's going on?
- Are you coming home?
I have no idea.
He never said anything before.
Are you coming home?
I just want you
to come home.
- That's Johnny's voice.
- No, it's not.
I just want
you to come home.
- Tom: Do not listen to that shit.
- Are you coming home?
You know
that is not your son.
- Clay, no!
- Hi, Dad.
- (Gunshot)
- Denise: No! No! No!
Tom: I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
- He was my brother.
- He saw us, that means they saw us.
He'll lead the rest of them to us.
Come on.
Ray: Hey,
we all need to go now.
- Tom: Come on.
- Ray: Everybody to the truck.
Clay, come on.
(Engine stops)
Why are we
stopping, Ray?
Ray: No, it's too late for me.
It's too late for me because they're in my head.
At first it was in my dreams,
but now I'm seeing stuff when I'm awake.
Things that aren't there.
(Screams)
You haven't slept for a week.
Maybe you were hallucinating.
I'm hallucinating because that asshole in the red hoodie
is putting thoughts
in my mind.
And what the Prez wants,
he's not gonna get
because you're
not gonna let him.
They thought it was me,
but it wasn't me.
It wasn't me, it's you.
He was wrong.
You're the man, my artist.
You are it.
What's that around
your neck, Ray?
I don't like it that you're
holding on to your kid
because your kid is done.
Your kid is done.
You know it in your heart
that your kid is toast.
- Your kid is toast.
- No, I don't.
I don't know that.
(Groans)
Oh!
Here. Here.
I'm passing the torch.
I'm passing it on to you.
When the time comes,
call the number on the slip.
You'll know the time.
I hope you know the time.
- What time is that, Ray?
- The end of the road time.
The end of the road.
Mmm.
No other options.
Ray, what's that
around your neck?
(Sighs)
(groans)
- This, my friend, this is gonna--
- Ray.
This is gonna blow my mind.
You better step away, my friend.
- Okay. Hold on.
- Step away, Clay!
(Sobbing, screams)
- (explosion echoing)
- (birds cawing)
Stay here.
I'll be back.
No, no, no, no.
I'm going with you.
No, no, no.
Just stay with them.
I've got
to do this alone.
Johnny!
Sharon!
(Sighs)
(inhales)
(sniffles)
(breathing heavily)
(creaking)
(rattling)
(door creaks)
(shrieking)
(grunting)
(Clay groaning)
Get off.
(Shrieking)
(Tom choking)
(gasping)
Fucker!
(Coughing)
(gasping)
(breathing heavily)
Is that...?
Yeah.
So what you got there?
That?
Ray gave that to me.
Right before
he blew his head off.
He told me to call the number when the time came.
When the time came?
Uh-huh.
When's that?
Last stop.
End of the line.
That's what he said?
That's what he said.
Hmm.
Seemed like
a reasonable man.
Did you know
there was a bomb in here?
No, or I wouldn't
have ridden in it.
So did Ray tell you
this thing was full of C-4?
There's enough plastique in there
to blow up this whole fucking block.
- Denise: Oh, my God.
- Here, this is Sharon's wagon.
It's in the garage.
I'm going to Kashwak.
Are you out of your mind?
Did you not hear
what Denise said?
It's a trap.
We've been through this.
Maybe.
Come on, man.
If you're going there,
you're not coming out.
It's a suicide mission.
You're gonna die.
I got to find my kid.
I got to know
one way or the other.
Oh, God damn.
Take this.
I want you to spray paint T,
J and D
for Tom, Jordan,
and Denise
on the side of the road
every couple miles.
If you go off-road,
dirt road,
put it up on a tree.
Always on the left-hand
side of the road
'cause that's where
I'll be looking.
Look, don't go.
It's stupid.
You're gonna die.
Hey.
You remember the story
of Orpheus, buddy?
Orpheus traveled
to the underworld
to find his loved one,
bring them back to Earth.
You're not Orpheus.
Take care
of yourself, brother.
Be right behind you.
All right?
Take care of Tom.
You know, you're about
the best friend
anybody could ever have
at the end of the world.
Well, let's hope
it's not quite the end.
Good knowing you,
Clay Riddell.
Good to know you,
Tom McCourt.
- Take care.
- (Scoffs)
Jordan:
You better find us.
Sorry about your wife.
- Kashwak, please!
- Pull over!
- Please help us!
- Please help us! Please!
Take us with you!
(Engine revving)
(static hissing)
(laughs)
(distorted mumbling)
(gunshots)
Johnny's voice: Hi, Dad.
Hi, Dad. Hi, Dad. Hi, Dad.
- Hi, Dad. Hi, Dad.
- Clay: Johnny!
- Johnny!
- Hi, Dad. Hi, Dad. Hi, Dad. Hi, Dad.
Hi, Dad. Hi, Dad.
Are you coming home?
I just want you
to come home.
(Voices overlapping)
Clay:
Johnny! Johnny!
Are you coming home?
(High-pitched warbling)
Johnny!
(Panting)
(phoners howling)
(screeching)
Look, Dad,
there's another.
Mm-hmm.
I'm so glad you get
to meet my friends, Johnny.
Are they gonna be
my friends, too?
You bet.
What's the name
of the place we're going?
Canada.
¶ And don't be afraid ¶
¶ Of the dark ¶
¶ Walk on ¶
¶ Through the wind ¶
¶ Through the rain ¶
¶ Though your dreams ¶
¶ Be tossed ¶
¶ And blown ¶
¶ Walk on ¶
¶ With hope in your heart ¶
¶ And you'll never ¶
¶ Walk alone ¶
¶ You'll never ¶
¶ Walk on ¶
¶ With hope in your heart ¶
¶ And you'll never ¶
¶ Walk alone ¶
¶ You will never ¶
¶ Walk alone. ¶
(Music playing)
(phoners shrieking)