Let's be clear
about this.
Humans were offered
a chance to assimilate
but they refused.
Therefore, they are enemies
of the state and will be
captured and farmed for
blood supply.
It's a disgrace that we
have reduced human
beings to mere vessels
for blood supply.
We should be focusing on
finding a blood substitute...
We always come back to
the magic potion solution.
Where is it?
With little or no population
remaining to sustain industry
other Third World countries
throughout Asia have also...
"Serving 20% blood"
CHIEF HEMATOLOGIST
EDWARD DALTON - APPROVED
All the material in this
meeting is classified
Commissioner?
Death row inmate 4705-B
was a vampire selected
for a month long study
on the effects of
blood deprivation.
What?
A complete lack of human
blood over this period
resulted in a massive
deterioration of the
frontal lobe.
First signs of physical
deformities began with
elongated ears. Mental
functions such as logic,
emotion, most parts of
speech then terminated
much faster than you or
your team originally
speculated, Dr. Dalton.
Out on the streets these
creatures, these subsides,
are becoming a real problem.
Gentlemen, we are starving.
Our latest statistics show
that less than 5% of the
human population remains.
What we're talking
about is the extinction
of the human race.
What we're talking about
is only having enough blood
to sustain our population
until the end of the month.
If a blood substitute
is not found immediately
this will happen to all of us.
Edward?
Enjoy your coffee, Sir.
Did I ever tell you about
my daughter Alison?
In early 2008 I was
diagnosed with Sarcoma.
The shock of finding out
I had cancer was one thing,
but having to tell
my daughter...
She was devastated.
I prayed for a miracle,
but was realistic.
And then the
world changed.
My prayers were answered.
Immortality gave
me my cure.
My daughter and I now
had all the time in the world.
But she saw this
evolution as a disease,
worse than any cancer.
She refused to turn.
I was a monster to her.
She ran, like so many did.
No, we are blessed, Edward.
Blessed.
And you have to stare
death in the face
to truly know that.
We are not ready
yet, Mr. Bromley.
Not a coffee drinker?
Not really.
You pity the humans,
don't you?
Well, me too.
Me too.
These are desperate
times, Edward.
We must start testing
the blood substitute.
It is the only way to
help the human race.
He wants us to move
ahead again, doesn't he?
Yeah.
Okay.
Is there any change?
Hembicillin CBC and a
biochemical panel.
All stable.
The substitute is working.
It's time to move
beyond animal testing.
You know the Vernon
Park Cemetery was
raided by a bunch
of kids last night.
They dug up a dozen
graves thinking
they'd find some
human blood.
It's nuts out there.
Now private, you may
feel a slight increase
in body temperature.
That's just the Hembicillin
entering your system,
it's to be expected.
Yes, Sir.
- How do you feel?
- No change, Sir.
6 degree increase.
Slightly more accelerated
than anticipated but...
you're fine.
68 degrees and holding.
Okay.
- Okay, how do you feel?
- I feel fine, Si...
Shit!
20 cc of Epimone!
Come on!
Violent scenes in London
today, as police clashed
with protesters over
the controversial
new blood rationing schemes.
Demonstrators argue
that the blood allowances
are too strict and that
government bodies are
failing in their promise
to find alternatives.
Similar scenes have been
occurring across Asia
and the Middle East
in recent times.
In local news, blood related
crime is on the rise
with a staggering
1 in 10 people being
confronted by subside
activity in the last month.
Oh, shit!
Fuck.
You alright?
- What are you doing?
- Get back!
- Don't come any closer!
- Shoot him again!
Don't!
- You're human.
- Shoot!
Don't shoot me again!
Listen, I can help you.
Come on! Get in my car.
I'll help you! Come on!
Let me help you!
Get in my car!
Come on. Come on!
Come on, get in.
It's alright.
"Daytime Driving Mode
ACTIVATED"
Daytime protection and
driving mode: Activated.
Car 51 at location.
Shit.
- You okay, Sir?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
Did you get a good
look at them, Sir?
No, not really.
It happened so fast.
They didn't wait around
to see how I was.
We believe they
may be humans, Sir.
Did you see where
they went?
I think they went that way.
You take care, Sir.
Thank you.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
See you around.
Somehow I doubt that.
Happy birthday, Ed.
This is a community health
and safety announcement.
There is now one hour
until sunrise.
10 years after the 2009 outbreak
vampiric wildlife
wandering into sunlight
has become the number
one cause of forest fires
throughout the nation.
The total national
wildlife feeding ban
has not deterred
people from venturing...
Linking homes and businesses
wide across the city
The Sub walk tunnel network
is the safest way to walk
around during daylight.
Sub walk - Protection under sun
Having your car modified
for daytime driving
shouldn't cost you the Earth.
Security alert: Backdoor ajar.
Frankie.
Hey, Ed.
I hardly recognized you.
It's only been a few months.
I got something for you.
What's this?
What the fuck do
you think it is?
Some birthday party, bro.
Yeah. Well, I've turned
thirty-five ten times.
Birthdays are pointless.
Bullshit!
Let's have a drink.
It smells human.
100% pure.
That's one of the perks
of serving your country.
I hear even that
pig shit you drink
is getting hard to find.
I can't.
Fuck that.
You need it.
Yeah, well...
Life is a bitch and...
then you don't die.
Come on.
I don't touch human blood.
You don't touch human blood.
You work for a company that
uses humans like fucking' cattle.
Don't tell me how to live
my life, little brother.
Then don't act all high
and mighty, big brother.
Look Ed, your company
working on some type of
fake blood, that's one thing,
but we all know that
their money comes from
farming humans.
Are we going to pick up from
exactly where we left off?
I don't hunt humans.
That is your job.
I find them. You farm them.
All right. Well...
- Let's just dump this shit.
- Nothing changes, does it?
Does it?
You still don't get
why I joined.
What happens...
when there isn't
a single drop left?
When there isn't
a single human?
-A single anything?
-We will always find more.
A blood substitute means
the end of human hunting.
Fake blood. Doesn't
mean the end of shit.
Well, if I believed that,
let me drive a stake
through my heart
right now.
Shit!
Frankie. Frankie.
Oh, my God!
Frankie.
This is the third home invasion
in this area in the last month.
These things are
in the suburbs now.
So...
it's important that you
update your security.
Subsides. Strong bastards.
The same common traits
as all the others.
The aggression is most
likely brought on by
massive reductions
in Serotonin levels.
We need more patrols
aching these filthy rats.
Ugly son of a bitch.
"Together Forever.
Lillian and Carl".
Carl?
What? You knew him?
Yeah, he was the
local gardener.
I saw him two weeks ago.
He's feeding off
other vamps.
Only takes a couple of weeks
to get this messed up.
Some of these wounds
look self inflected.
He fed on himself?
Perhaps.
And that would speed up
mutation considerably.
Animals.
Security alert: Backdoor ajar.
Hi.
Did you come
to finish me off?
We need your help.
We've been searching for
vampires we can trust.
Trust?
You're a blood doctor.
You can help us.
Help you how?
A blood substitute is a
solution but not a cure.
There's another way.
Take it.
"GORDON CREEK. NOON
WEDNESDAY. ALONE."
Who was that?
It's nothing.
With blood supplies
continuing to dwindle
private investors are pulling
their human stock from the
Bromley Marks harvesting facility.
Many experts believe that
the company will no longer
be able to handle the
national blood demand.
The FDA spokesperson
confirmed yesterday...
How are you feeling, Edward?
The break-in must have
been very traumatic.
I'm fine. Thank you.
Now, these attacks on
everyday citizens are
cause for great concern.
All the more reason to push
forward, wouldn't you say?
I'd just like your guarantee
that a substitute would replace
our need for a human supply, Sir.
Well, it's important
that we allow
the human race
time to repopulate.
That's not exactly
what I asked.
The majority of the
population will be
content with a blood
substitute, yes.
But there will always be
those who are willing to pay
a little extra for the real thing.
Come on, Edward.
We have to be realistic.
If we don't cater
to all markets,
someone else will.
How much do you
think they'd be
willing to pay for
your daughter?
He's waiting for you.
UV Warning.
Trees are the oldest
living things on earth.
Did you know that?
They say, some are over
four thousand years old.
Someday, though...
this tree will die.
And so will you.
Maybe you won't die
of old age like her.
But the thing
you're holding on to,
that last breath
of humanity,
will vanish as soon as
the blood does.
What do you want?
Same thing you do.
A future.
I was like you once.
But not no more.
Lionel Cormack.
My friends call me Elvis.
I isn’t going to bite.
- Elvis?
- Yeah, you know like...
Lord almighty, I feel
my temperature rising.
Higher higher. It's burning
through to my soul.
Feel that?
Hadn't been beating
for nine years.
Seems impossible,
don't it?
It is impossible.
So is walking around
without a pulse.
But here you are.
How did you do it?
Audrey?
- Put the gun down.
- Frankie?
- Put the gun down!
- Frankie, what the...
What the hell
are you doing?
- Move away from him.
- Put the gun down!
Don't make things worse.
- Stop pointing the gun!
- Move away from them!
- Frankie!
- This is serious shit, Ed.
They can put you away
for a long time.
Let's go.
Motherfuckers!
Come on, get
in my car!
Shit!
UV warning.
Got it!
"SIGNAL LOST"
- I can't...!
Move!
Hang on.
Everybody okay?
Yeah.
Motherfuckers.
I loved that car.
You did the right thing.
That was my brother.
Come on.
Never been good
at science, Doc.
Cars have always
been my thing.
Daylight modifications
are my specialty.
Or used to be.
Custom cameras, sun
shields, that kind of thing.
My garage was one of the
first in town to start doing them.
I had a shop right
near your place.
Day time driving' man,
nothing' beats it.
No traffic, no cops.
But if you isn’t careful
you can get yourself
one hell of a sunburn.
You can only go on
so long without blood
before it messes
with your head.
It's amazing how quickly
your whole world can change.
Isn’t it, Doc?
We need to recreate
this. Safely.
That's why we
need you.
The Sun?
You're human because
of the Sun?
Hurt like hell.
Please, have a seat.
Do you know who I am?
My brother's mentioned
you before, Sir.
You did the right thing
reporting his actions.
You want to continue
to do the right thing,
don't you son?
I will do whatever
is asked of me, Sir.
Edward is a valuable
member of our team,
and an essential part
of all our futures.
All we wish, is for him to
continue with his work.
If he returns immediately,
no formal charges will be laid.
I don't know what you
think I can do, Sir.
Do you like being
a vampire, son?
Yes, Sir.
Why?
I mean, your brother
clearly disapproves.
I wonder if it's a common
trait in your family.
I'm good at this.
I was never very good
at being human, Sir.
And I'm not
my brother.
Well...
Good. Frankie.
Every couple of
weeks we head out,
to search for others.
It's getting harder and
harder to find anybody.
I only managed to
pick up three,
when you drove us
off the road.
Stop the car!
When was the last time
you drank human blood?
What's the matter?
I'm fine.
Oh. You... don't...
We need you focused.
- No! No, I'm not...
- She isn’t asking, Doc.
Where we're going...
I can't afford to
worry about you,
around the others.
Well it's about
god damn time.
Stop worrying,
you'll live longer.
Travis, this is Ed.
Ed!
Well isn’t this nothing.
Usually when there's
a vampire around,
I'm the one
shitting my pants.
You better be worth
the risk, man.
Jar's made contact
with the largest
human group we've
found in a long time.
And he's going to
bring them back here.
I set up more cots
in the cellar.
We'll stay in radio contact
and keep you updated.
Good luck.
You too.
Is this place safe?
Being human in a
world full of vampires
is about as safe as
bare backing a 5$ whore.
This is home, Doc.
But none of us are safe.
This vineyard belonged
to my parents.
They always wanted me
to run it someday, but,
at the time I was more
interested in college.
Not long after the
outbreak I came back.
It seemed like a
good place to hide.
I owe that girl my life.
She found me after I
was shacked-n-baked
and brought me here.
I want you to
meet someone.
Ed, this is senator
Wes Turner.
- Hey. You made it.
- Yeah. Barely.
- More damn vampires.
- Back off, Colin.
They're trying to help.
Hey. Being a vampire
and a politician,
it can be hard to
make friends.
Wes knows enough vampires
in office that want this cure.
And more importantly, will
use it for the right reasons.
We want to rebuild
the human race.
But a way back can be
a dangerous thing,
in the wrong hands.
We're an endangered
species, Doc.
It's time we changed
all that.
The escalating global
blood crisis has seen
prices skyrocket over
the past week.
Experts believe that
this will make blood
unobtainable to many citizens
across the country,
and create what could
only be described
as a subside epidemic.
Excuse me.
This is not what
I asked for.
Read the sign, Sir. We're
now only permitted to
serve 5% blood
with every coffee.
I don't care what
the signs says.
Just put some more fucking
blood in my coffee.
I can't.
Move!
We've tested burning
extracted blood under UV light
It always remains infected.
How could yours
possibly be human?
You tell me, Doc.
What did it feel like when
the sun hit your body?
What do you mean
what did it feel like?
I felt like a god-damned
piece of fried chicken.
Can you remember anything
specific about it?
Anything at all.
Well I remember when
the sunlight hit me.
It was like a bolt
of lightning
kick-started my heart.
It was like...
someone let the
air back in the room.
Maybe the only way
to treat the blood
is inside the body.
We need to control
a daylight burn.
- Pickup was successful.
- That's great Jarvis!
Total count is 15.
We'll stay clear of
the interstates,
so it might take us
a while to get back.
Be safe.
You okay?
They may be frightened
of you, but...
none of them doubt
that you can help us.
I can't even remember
what it's like to be human.
Are you afraid to die?
Yeah.
Most of us are too
scared of death to
think of it as
an option.
I guess that's why
so many turned.
How did it
happen to you?
I was betrayed.
My brother...
What are these?
Wine fermentation tanks.
Fermentation.
- That's airtight, right?
- Yeah, that's right.
- What's that?
- It's an extraction fan.
Pulls air out of the tank to
stop the wine from oxidizing.
Okay, perfect. We use that
to put out the fire.
How far is it to the
winery, Jarvis?
It's about two
hours from here.
So, have you been
doing this for long?
Picking up humans,
giving them a home.
Since the beginning.
There's not many
of us left now.
How long have you
been running?
Most of us have been on
the run together for years.
I've never seen
it this bad.
What made you come
all the way out here?
It's safer.
There's lots of sun,
there's not a lot of shade.
Not much food
either, hmm?
Yeah. Thanks.
Oh shit!
Dammed!
Shit!
Tranq dart!
Move! Move!
Oh shit!
Move. Move!
Go go go!
Keep firing.
Fire!
Can anyone hear me?
Hello? Is anyone there?
We hear you,
who is this?
They found us.
They're everywhere.
Where are you?
Got another.
Are you still there?
It's completely secluded.
It should be the safest
place for us to regroup.
How long will it
take to get there?
If we stay off the main
highways and follow
the trails along the
Marshall River
we should reach my
cabin before nightfall.
Okay.
- You be careful.
- You too.
Come on, Ed.
We got to go.
- I can't.
- They'll be here soon.
The sun is about to come up,
we may never get a chance to
set up this experiment
again, I've got to do it.
- That thing could kill you.
- I'm already dead.
Fuck it.
I do love a good BBQ.
You don't need that.
You're safe here,
I promise.
Where are my friends?
Don't hurt them.
Please!
You look so beautiful.
You've grown
up so much.
Dad, please.
I'm so happy to see you.
I never thought I'd see
you again, sweetheart.
You're safe now.
You're safe.
But your friends...
There's nothing I
can do, I'm sorry.
You're not sorry.
Ally, let me help
you, please!
Are you sure you're
ready to do this?
Yeah. What could
go wrong?
You feel so warm.
Ready, Doc?
- Ready.
- Let's do it, Aud.
Okay, on my count.
3-2-1-Now!
Ed?
I'm alright.
He's okay, Aud.
- Let's do it again.
- Again, let's do it again!
3-2-1-Now!
You okay?
Ed?
- Yeah. Again.
- He's fine!
3-2-1-Now!
Ed!
Lord almighty.
Mr. Dalton.
How is the shoulder, son?
It's healing quickly.
How about yourself, Sir?
Oh, I'll survive.
You know...
During the civil war,
General Sherman said:
"I'm tired and sick of war"
"It's glory is all moonshine"
"War is hell."
Less than 50 humans have
been captured the last week.
Some believe hell
may well be coming.
With dedicated soldiers
like yourself,
we can prevent that
from happening.
Frankie...
I need you to do
something for me.
Get away from me!
You don't need to
be scared of me.
Stay away!
Is this what you want?
To live in fear?
See, I can help you.
Make you one of us.
- Free.
- No
You can live forever.
Fuck you.
Welcome back.
"FROM THE ASHES SPRINGS NEW LIFE"
She won't drink
her blood ration, Sir.
Okay.
Ally.
Baby.
Oh, Ally. What are you doing?
That'll poison you.
Is this what you wanted?
- Sweetheart, stop that.
- Is this what you wanted?
No.
You did this.
- You did this.
- No.
No. You did this.
Military forces have been ordered
to most major cities around the country
in a bid to contain what is now being
described as the subside epidemic.
Military leaders have announced
they will take a strict
no tolerance approach
to the crisis.
An order to commence
the immediate round-up
and capture of all Class 4
blood-deprived citizens
has been issued.
Are we close?
The Senator's cabin
should be just up ahead.
It's all gone.
Everything.
We'll start again.
We can't keep running.
I know someone
who can help.
With the current military
round-up in full effect
it's likely we will
continue to see
a decreased subside
presence on our streets.
But the question has been
asked: "Now what?"
Our families are starving.
We can't afford to feed
these creatures, too.
I know it might be
wrong but, these things,
they've got to go.
Die.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I know. I know.
Well, I couldn't have
done it without you.
Shit.
I'll call you back.
You're really human.
-This is unbelievable.
- Hold it.
I'm sorry. Who are you?
We're the folks with
the crossbows.
It's a dangerous
time, Chris.
We can´t be too careful.
Alright? Sit down, please.
Ed, it's me.
After the 6 years we've
spent working together.
You know the sacrifices
I've made.
I've been with you
100% of the way.
- Always.
- I know.
Alright, listen.
We've got something better
than a blood substitute.
We've got a cure.
And I can repeat the procedure,
but I'm going to need your help.
This is a chance to
change everything.
How did you do it?
Are you going to
answer that?
Hello.
No.
Yeah.
Hold on.
Ex-wife.
It's messy. Can you
give me a second?
Yeah.
No. We didn't
agree on that, so...
What are you
talking about?
That's all?
No. I don't remember
agreeing to this...
This is one fucking
ugly house.
Where are you going?
Check on your friend.
Go.
If they find us,
we can't help her.
Put it down.
I don't believe it.
Don't come any closer.
Frankie, I found a cure.
Alright?
I can change you back.
No.
- Put it down, kid.
- No. It's alright.
Frankie, it's alright.
Frankie, it's not
too late.
Do you know why
I turned you, Ed?
You used to say to me
that you'd rather die
than be like the
rest of us.
I didn't turn you because
it was convenient, or
because of some selfish
need for blood.
I turned you because...
you would've died
if I didn't.
I couldn't lose you, Ed.
I'm fucked up bad.
I can get you
out of here.
We're not going anywhere
without Audrey.
- The woman?
- Yes, the woman.
You'll never
get to her.
You want to help us?
Please.
Okay.
God damn it.
Edward.
You've got a tan.
It suits you.
You know, Edward.
Her blood has a scent
that no substitute
could ever replace.
Fear.
I don't want to die.
I can't do this...
being human.
Isn't that what you wanted?
I don't want to be afraid.
I can never be free like
this, I see that now.
Please.
Help me.
What is it that you want?
Turn us both.
Let us leave.
And I'll show you a way to
repopulate your entire human supply.
What the hell are you doing?
And you would give
me this cure?
Yes.
As long as you allow
her to go free, too.
No.
She doesn't sound
that interested
in your proposition,
Edward.
In time she'll come
to understand.
Will she?
Thank you.
You know, I won't deny
that things have gotten
progressively worse
during your absence.
The public, the military;
Everyone seemed starving.
Our blood supplies
are well, gone.
Ed.
I myself was feeling
the effects of deprivation.
But as of yesterday
it's all a thing of the past.
You know, I always
thought it would be you
that would come up
with a stable substitute.
Not Christopher. But,
I guess I was wrong.
Look. We go into mass
production in two days.
It's never been about a cure.
It's about repeat business.
And besides...
what's to cure?
So you see, Edward.
I don't need you anymore.
Of course you couldn't
make it as a human.
You're weak.
The truth is:
You've always been a coward.
What did it feel like to
turn your own daughter?
Oh, you didn't do it, did you?
You couldn't, could you?
You had my brother
do it for you.
So who's the fucking coward?
Your blood.
What have you done to me?
Vampires think they
own this world.
That the humans
have to hide from them.
That isn’t true.
Every day, the sun comes up.
And every day
the vamps have to hide.
Vampires can never survive.
That's the truth.
Elvis Presley once said:
"Truth is like the sun.
you can shut it
out for a time
but it isn’t going away".
Mr. Bromley.
Open up.
Treated vampire blood.
That's the cure.
Welcome back to humanity.
Now you get to die.
Move. Move.
Let's go.
Don't do this.
There's a cure.
Run.
Ed.
They can't be the cure.
I can't let you do it.
I'm sorry.
We have a cure.
We can change you back.
It's not too late.