(Psychedelic music and sounds)
(Country music in the background)
(Southern U.S. accent)
My name's Buck, I'm raring to fuck.
Let's just get it over with.
There ain't no hurry, I...
I paid for a whole hour.
Besides, I sort of thought
we could try something new.
My, my! You're a nice looking filly.
Nice legs...
Those nice big blue lamps.
Nice shoulders...
Hey, why don't you turn over
and get up on your knees, hm?
(Pats the bed) ...for old Buck.
Come on.
I'm going to ride you like
you've never been rode before.
- What do you mean?
- I've got a surprise for you.
No!
- Don't tell me. I'm not gonna to do that!
- Yes, you are. Now come on!
- Stay up on those legs.
- No, I'm not!
- Come on!
- Stop it! No...
Get up on those knees!
Come here!
No! I'm not going to do that,
you stop it!
- Come on now, get those knees up!
- Please, don't!
- Come here!
- No!
There ain't no such word as no,
understand? Now, come here!
- Don't, no, no!
- Come on, now!
- Come on.
- Stop it! Get away!
- Shh!
Listen, all I want to do
is get what I paid for.
So you get back in this bed and you get up
on your knees. You hear me?
Get away!
(Screams) Miss Hattie! Miss Hattie!
No, don't, please don't!
Don't, don't!
(Screams)
What the hell is going on in here?
Miss Hattie, I wasn't doing nothing,
I swear to God, just what I paid for.
- That's all I want.
- I ain't gonna do what he wants.
Not for 20 dollars,
not for nothing!
What you carrying on for like that?
Buck's a good boy.
- He ain't gonna hurt you.
- Yes, ma'am!
I don't know. Maybe I'm just not
cut out to be a whore.
Now, Buck,
I'll tell you what you do.
You get your hat and go on downstairs
and you pick out
two of my very best girls.
- No extra charge.
- Two?
- That's right, two!
- For the price of one?
Exactly. That's a good boy.
Now, you look here.
I didn't ask you to come here.
You came here asking me.
Now, I took you in and I fed you
and I cleaned you up.
You don't want to work?
You just pack your bag
and get the hell out of here.
(Chatter and commotion)
...right now. I got no use for those who
don't work for their keep. Get, get, get.
My bag.
- Ruby! Ruby! Where is that girl?
- Yes, Miss Hattie.
Get this tramp's bag.
I want her out of here right now.
You wait out on the front porch.
Go on! Get!
Get on up there, now. Miss Hattie says
I gets two and I picks you.
(Laughing) We're going to have
so much fun!
Damn fools.
Lord, child! You sure got yourself
in a heap of trouble.
Miss Hattie chased you out.
You've barely been here.
And now Buck.
He'd have made me mad.
Funny business, smart ales,
sassy mouth.
Where are you going to go now, child?
I don't know but I'll be all right.
- Got any money?
- I'll be all right, Ruby.
- You take this.
- No, I can't Ruby, I can't take it.
You take this.
There's a place right down the road.
I think it's called The Starlight.
But just don't go out there
telling them you're from Miss Hattie's.
Now you take this...
Take it!
Thanks! I'll pay you back,
I promise.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
You're no trouble.
No trouble at all.
Some girls just ain't cut out
for things like this.
Now you best be on your way.
You take care, hear?
(Night sounds)
(Country music in the background)
(Water splashing and grunting)
(Psychedelic sounds)
Hello?
Is somebody...?
(Music continues in the background)
Hello?
I'm kind of lost
and I saw your sign.
Are you Open?
Hello?
(Music stops)
(Rings bell)
(Footsteps)
- Uh, what...?
- Do you have a room?
Oh, er... yes.
(Distant hooting and chirping)
Oh, no, no... Over here.
There. Yeah, here.
(Pencil scratching the paper)
(Mumbles)
(Laughs gently) Yeah.
Oh, no ma'am.
Pay in the morning.
(Splashing outside)
Oh, you've seen it, huh?
That ain't no ordinary gator.
That's a croc!
Gators, they can't move fast
unless they're in the water.
Old croc now... not the same.
Outrun a horse.
Oh, upstairs, ma'am.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Yeah. Got out of there one day
and chased down a nigger mule.
Ha-ha! Tore it half in two
before it hit the ground.
Front part still screaming.
Head and legs for 50 yards.
(Laughs loudly)
That old croc made no distinctions.
Not at all. Eats anything. Anything at all.
(Creepy music box melody)
You one of Miss Hattie's girls?
(Sudden strident sound)
Yeah... you're one
of Miss Hattie's girls.
Yeah.
(Creaking)
One of Miss Hattie's girls.
(Shrieks)
Whore!
(Screams) Don't! Stop it!
(Eerie electronic sounds)
(Shouting)
(Panting and moaning)
(Tearing flesh sounds)
(Eerie electronic sounds)
(Hooting)
(Crocodile grunts)
(Splashing)
(Choking)
(Loud splash)
(Night sounds)
(Hooting and tweeting)
(Laughter)
(Radio in the background)
(Hums a tune)
♪ Down, round, tumble down
♪ Standing round in the rain...
♪ Ain't got no ticket
Ain't got no bag
♪ Still waiting on a train ♪
(laughs)
(Hooting and tweeting)
(Splashing and psychedelic sounds)
♪ Down, round, tumble down
♪ Standing round in the rain
♪ Ain't got no ticket
Ain't got no bag
♪ Still I'm waiting on a train ♪
(Hums)
(Hooting and tweeting)
(Ominous sound)
(indistinct quarreiiing)
(Dog barks)
Snoopy!
Come here, Snoopy! Come on!
- I don't know what you expect.
- Does it matter?
We're just going to be here all day.
(Dog barking)
Snoopy!
How do you do, sir?
Oh... Oh, can't complain.
No siree, can't say as I can.
I wonder if I might use
your restroom?
Oh, well, yes, help yourself.
- Snoopy! Come on, Snoopy!
- Where is it?
Right in there.
Go up those stairs there
and you turn to your right.
Snoopy!
- In there, go on.
- Appreciate it.
How do you do, ma'am?
Oh, just fine, thank you.
How far is it to Tyler?
Oh, about an hour, I reckon.
(Car approaching)
Old man!
(Laughing over country music)
Get! Get on out of here!
(Horn blaring)
You got a paying customer here
needs some service!
Get that junk off my property!
Old Buck done work his magic again.
Old Buck goes to work, ain't a woman
alive who stands a chance. Ain't no way!
- You get out of here.
- No way!
- I've got folks here. Real folks!
- In the saddle riding high again!
I've got me some sure enough hot stuff
ripe and ready for the picking.
Yee-haw!
How do, ma'am.
The name's Buck.
I told you I don't want you
coming around here. I told you!
(Piercing sound)
Don't pay him no mind. He gets his
dander a bit... Don't mean nothing.
Look at that. He got
himself all riled up again.
That's it, put it down.
Mark it down, mark it.
Here you go, old man.
Now, you best get out of here,
right now. Go on, get!
Get! Get out of here!
(Laughs) You can count on that.
But I'll be back before long.
Take it to the bank.
(Car engine and radio)
(Grumbles) Won't have it. No... no, sir.
I won't, I won't.
Come and go, come and go,
it's all it is.
Tell it, and I tell it, and I tell it!
- It don't sit right with me.
- Monkey, wake up!
Think I don't know.
Ha! Don't need eyes for that!
No, sir.
Mommy, Mommy!
It's dead, Mommy!
What, sweetheart?
What's the matter?
The little monkey's dead
in its cage. See?
Pitiful little creature.
(Dog barks)
I'm sorry, baby.
Your monkey's dead.
(Grumbles)
(Barking continues)
Well... I reckon that's that.
(Crocodile grunting)
- (Barking and grunting)
- Snoopy!
Snoopy!
- Oh my God!
- Come here!
Angie! Angie, no!
Angie!
(Squealing and screaming)
Folks! In here!
(Angie screams)
Here folks! That old croc,
he'll eat anything. Go in here! In here.
He'll eat anything. Weren't no harm
done. There's nobody hurt.
- Is there a place we can lay her down?
- Upstairs, upstairs.
Ain't nothing no one can do about it.
All according to the instincts.
(Babbling) Make no distinctions.
None at all.
- (indistinct babbling)
- The door!
It's OK, baby. Here we go.
- Would you excuse us, please?
- Oh, yes. Ma'am. Surely, yes sir.
Did you see that thing?
All right, all right.
(Sobbing)
It's OK, baby.
Angie, calm down.
Calm down!
(Creepy music box melody)
Snoopy!
(Sobbing)
(High-pitched sounds)
- (Music box continues)
- (Sniffling)
(Woman) 'Calm down, baby, calm down.'
(Footsteps)
(Distant crying)
Things happen.
All according to instincts.
There ain't none.
There ain't no distinctions.
Distinctions.
None at all.
You've gotta do what...
...what you gotta do.
(Angie whimpers)
It's gonna be OK.
Is she all right, honey?
Snoopy!
What do you expect?
I'm sorry!
I didn't... I'm sorry.
Baby, honey, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry
that this whole thing happened.
(High-pitched noise)
(Anguished wail)
I don't know...
I don't know what you expect.
Nothing.
I don't expect you to do nothing.
(Country music)
(Whimpering in the background)
(Shouting over music)
(Man, quarrelling) 'I'm fine
when I'm alone... when I do my job.'
(Woman, quarrelling)
'You don't even have a job.'
- 'I have a job!'
- 'You did not have a job...'
(Man) 'I have not been laid off...'
(Crying in the background)
(Door slams)
(Country music)
Yes sir, what can I do for you?
We need a couple of rooms,
for my daughter and myself.
Oh, right in here, right in here.
Right here, you've got to sign right here.
Let's see... Rooms three and six,
top of the stairs right there, sir.
(Discordant sound)
No, no. Don't have none
of that here.
You've got to go to the
local prostitution home.
You've seen this girl there?
I've seen them there.
I won't have nothing to do with it at all.
I mean, this girl.
You've actually seen her?
I done said all I've got to say.
Because if you've seen her,
I need to know about it.
All right. At least tell me
how I can find this place.
I'm not looking for trouble.
I just have to locate this girl.
She happens to be my daughter.
Dad, please,
we can see to it later.
All right. You keep it to yourself,
old timer. See where it will get you.
Thank you.
Please, it's just been one
of those days, please excuse us.
Dad? Dad are you all right?
- What are you doing?
- You'll feel better when you get inside
- and lie down.
- I'm not going inside
I'm going to check
this thing out right now.
- Please, it can wait.
- Ma'am, can I help you?
It's the least I can do,
I feel awful bad about it.
- Yeah...
- Coming or staying? I'm going into town.
Thank you. We'll be back later, OK?
Maybe you're right. Got to get
something to eat, anyway.
Why don't you just take that cigarette
and grind it out in my eye?
Was that your eye?
Oh, honey, I thought it was an ashtray!
Oh, did I burn you?
No, you didn't burn me, no,
you just gouged my eye out.
She just gouged my eye out.
No, wait a second...
(Laughs) No, you didn't do that.
No, you didn't.
You did! You did!
There's a hole there.
You did! You gouged my eye out.
Where is it?
Where is it? Where did she put it?
Where did it roll to? Honey?
Honey, where did it roll to?
Let's just take... soon take that eye
and scrunch it up!
Roy? I didn't say anything,
and I didn't mean anything,
and I don't know why
you're being so ridiculous.
Now, you just stop it!
OK, OK, I'll stop it.
I'll just stop it.
(crying)
(Barking noise)
Stop it! Stop it!
(Barking noises)
(Shouting) Roy, stop it!
Stop it!
(Angie whimpers)
Roy, what do you want me to do?
Throw myself to the alligators?
ls that what you want, huh?
Is that what you want me to do?
(Hissing)
(Door slams)
Can't pretend it never happened!
What? Oh, sir, got no call.
Look, it's all according to the
instincts. There was no harm done.
No... Oh, no sir, no sir,
there ain't no call.
No, that ain't no common gator.
He's come all the way from Africa.
They don't come from around here.
Don't come from around here at all.
Frank Buck, Frank Buck,
you know about him?
"Bring 'Em Back Alive" Frank Buck,
they call him.
Come from up at Gainesville.
They've got him a statue
that looks just like him.
Every kind of animal in that zoo.
He's the one! I got it from him.
You know, he told me, he says,
you know, them things, ain't nobody
knows how old... they don't never die.
- Oh, sir! Sir!
- Sir!
That thing is dangerous!
Now, it attacked my child.
I'm going to see to it that I destroy it,
and I would advise you not to interfere.
Oh, just you wait. Get me the uniform.
Give me the uniform.
Tell them to give the signal.
There ain't nobody knows.
Nobody knows.
Most likely never.
Won't never be the way things are...
Creature can't go against himself.
(High-pitched beeping)
- Snoopy!
- Daddy's off to slay the dragon.
(Shouting) Ah!
(Sudden discordant tune)
(Gunshot)
(Laughing)
(Screaming)
(Grunting)
Daddy took care of everything.
Go to sleep, baby.
(Sighs)
(Country music in the background)
Oh, Oh...
(Groaning)
That BC makes me feel
better already.
(Wooden sound)
(laughs)
Roy! Hey! You bring up that suitcase!
Where is he, anyway?
Oh, he'll be up in a minute, ma'am.
In a minute.
(Water running)
(Sighs)
(Country music in the background)
My God! What are you doing in here?
Get out of here!
- I seen it.
- Roy?
(Screams)
(Shouts) Mummy?
(Muffled cries)
(Screams)
Call Daddy!
Daddy!
(Screams)
Mummy! Daddy!
Daddy!
(Screams)
(Clattering)
(Shouts)
Mummy! Mummy!
Angie! Angie!
(Screams)
No! Please!
Please!
(Screams) Angie!
(Screaming) Please, somebody!
Somebody!
Oh, please. Please.
Please?
- Please.
Please.
(Screams)
(Bird cooing)
(Distant hooting)
(Animal-like groaning)
(Sudden piercing sound)
They... done shot up my leg.
Didn't hurt nothing much.
Give me a scare.
Little girl she done run
under my place.
I suspect I gotta go in there
and pull her out.
Well, I... best, I go on.
Oh... I... didn't catch his name.
I never put it down. Yeah.
Put...
Put the letters down...
...put the numbers down...
...and all such as that.
All according to the regulations. Yeah.
Regulations say that
that's the way it's gotta go.
I know the rules...
I know the rules
and I bided by 'em.
(Croaking)
There. Oh, there...
There, now. There.
They come at me,
they come at me.
Give me my uniform,
find me the hat.
Here it is, put it on, get to it!
And by God, that's that.
Come at me.
Think they ain't got to abide
by the rules.
Think I don't know.
Think I don't see.
You don't need eyes for that.
No, sir.
Judd knows...
He knows what he knows.
They laugh, laugh...
Old fool... fool,
and I don't wanna hear it
And by God I ain't going to neither.
They come at me.
I give them the signal.
They know what that means.
That means get and get
or by God you're done for. Done.
- (Strident Sound)
- (Screams)
(Squeaking)
(Screams)
(Typewriter sounds)
(Police radio in the background)
- Are you Sheriff Martin?
- That's right, what can I do for you?
I understand you run
a wide-open town, Martin.
- Dad, please.
- ls that right?
Well, there might be some folks
over there at Huntsville
would be glad to argue that with you.
I'd be mighty surprised to hear it.
- Is that so?
- Well, that's the way I hear it.
Well, I'd like you to tell me.
I'd like to hear it from you.
Just what the hell do you call this bawdy
house thing you've got going down here?
Bawdy house?
You know damn well
what I'm talking about.
Why don't you just simmer down?
You get off that high horse of yours
and maybe we'll get down to something.
Ma'am, how do you do?
Fine, thanks.
Why don't you explain to me
what this is all about?
Well, my sister, she...
She disappeared some time ago.
We've been trying to locate her.
The man from the hotel,
old hotel outside of town,
- the one with the crocodile.
- Old Judd?
- Well, we checked in there.
- Miss...
- Libby... Libby Wood.
- OK, Miss Libby Wood.
Why don't you take your daddy back
to the hotel and get him all calmed down?
We'll look into this
first thing in the morning.
We'll look into it right now.
If my little girl's out there,
I don't want her to spend
another night in that place.
You figure she's over there
at Miss Hattie's?
Damn it! I don't figure!
I gotta know!
All right. I'll take you over there
and put your mind at ease.
And, ma'am, why don't you
go on back to the hotel there.
I'll drop your daddy off at Miss Hattie's,
and... we'll look into it.
I'm going with you.
Miss Hattie's liable to be real surprised
to see you walk in there with us...
Well, if that's the way you want it,
why, OK. Come on, we'll take my car.
(Croaking)
(Country music in the background)
(Night swamp sounds)
(Splashing)
(High-pitched sounds)
(Footsteps)
(Knocking)
Mister Martin! How do you do?
Come on in!
What is it?
Miss Hattie? Mister Martin
and some friends out hereto see you.
Show them on in!
Show them in!
Come in folks.
Martin, is that you? Where the hell
you been keeping yourself?
- How are you, Hattie?
- Just fine. How are you?
I got some friends here
wanna have a little word with you.
How do you do, folks?
Just sit right down.
Make yourselves right at home.
My name is Rebecca.
Folks call me Hattie.
- Where you folks from?
- Houston.
Houston...
Say, would you be interested
in a real good buy?
I got a little piece of property
up at the Heights.
I could sell it to you real cheap.
Course, it needs a little fixing up.
But lots of folks moving in there,
young folks fixing things up.
Hattie?
This is Mr Harvey Wood.
How do you do?
Pleased to meet you.
- And his daughter, Libby.
- Hi.
Now, Mr Woods believes that
you're acquainted with his daughter.
Never saw her before in my life!
Dad, you wanna go now?
Let's get something to eat.
- Where are you folks staying?
- Starlight Hotel.
Judd's! Ha! That old reprobate!
I didn't know he was still
taking folks in. Old goat!
Place about to fall down, ain't it?
Old Judd used to be a regular around
here, but I had to run him off.
The old fool. All he wanted to do
was just look and talk his crazy fool talk.
Scared the girls, too.
Say, you know what he said?
He says that big gator of his
is really a crocodile from Africa.
He says those things don't die.
You've got to kill 'em.
He's the one that tore off old Judd's leg.
That's right, tore it clean off and ate it.
Hattie, these people
have had enough for today.
I'll take them back to the hotel.
Oh yes, well, I suspect you're right,
I get to talking.
Well, you folks come back
if you're ever this way now.
- Thank you. Nice meeting you.
- Yes, indeed.
If you think about that piece
of property now,
you can come up with it.
You'll like it.
It's got a big pecan tree
in the front yard.
- Bye, Hattie.
- Bye there, sweetheart.
Silly fools!
Ooh, little girl. Come on outta there.
Come on. Old Judd,
he ain't gonna hurt you.
No sirree, he won't.
He got something for you.
Look! Look here.
Come on outta there.
Come look at what old Judd
done brought you.
Mm-hm. Yes, ma'am. Look here.
Little girl...
(Squeaking and high-pitched sounds)
Aargh!
(Screams)
(laughs)
Mummy! Daddy!
(Screams)
- (Libby) 'Can I bring you anything?'
- (Harvey) 'No, no, I'm fine.'
(Libby) 'You sure you're not hungry?'
(Harvey) 'You run along. I'm fine.'
(Music box melody)
(Angie whimpers)
(Hooting and chirping)
(Carillon sounds)
(Angie crying in the distance)
'Mummy!'
Who is it?
Who's there?
(Muffled cries)
(Sudden loud cry)
(High-pitched discordant sound)
(Choking)
(Choking and grunting)
Come on and get it.
Come on and get it!
Yes, they will.
They don't wanna hear what
old Judd's gotta tell them.
No, Judd's an old fool.
Yeah, he is.
Set the dogs again, Major.
Shut up! Shut up! Ain't nobody
wanna hear your fool talk!
Think it's easy?
Weren't nobody tell them different.
No, sir, they don't.
No... No, sirree.
I guess we whopped them. 35 zip.
Shit! Them boys
never got inside our set.
Yes, that old colored boy there,
supposed to be so good -
won't go no place tonight.
Coloured, hell!
Goddamn nigger if you ask me.
Showed them old boys
what it's all about.
- Yeah.
- Aw.
- Yeah, we did.
- I'd know where to go.
No need to get no stick after
me either. Not this old boy!
(Country music)
Hey, what you looking at?
What you looking at?
See something you like?
(indistinct)
Stand up man!
(Clapping)
Marlo, I believe you got a shot here.
- Tired, huh?
- Yeah.
Well, I could've saved you this trip.
I reckon I know how it is, though.
If it was my daughter,
I'd probably do the same thing.
- Thank you for being so patient.
- How long's it been?
Your sister...
- Been a while?
- Yeah.
Coffee for two, and the lady
will have something to eat.
Excuse me sir, there's a boy back there
who don't seem to behave himself.
Well, who's that? Buck?
Yeah, but telling him
don't seem to do no good.
Tell him I got my eye on him. I don't
wanna hear another word out of him.
He gives you any trouble,
you come and tell me.
The police turn up anything?
Nothing, huh?
No, nothing.
There's more to it than that.
Dad's very sick...
A very sick man.
It's just a question of time.
What are you having?
I'll have that chicken
fried steak, please.
And you keep the coffee coming.
He can be a hard man.
When she left, Dad said good riddance.
But the things he's been through this past
year have made him a different man.
He's dying and he's obsessed
with finding her.
He's spent a fortune
on private detectives,
chased all over the country himself...
when he's not in hospital.
(Buck) 'Yee-haw.
Shittin' and a gettin'!'
Excuse me just a minute.
Better go have a word with that boy.
Hey, fella. I think it's time
for you to pack it in.
- I ain't doing nothing.
- No.
I suppose that girl
is drinking Coca-Cola.
It ain't hurting nothing.
What's it to you?
Now, you just move on out now.
Take her along with you.
- You understand?
- All right, all right.
All right.
Got a burr up your ass,
don't make a shit to me.
Now, you got a fat mouth, kid.
One more word out of you and I'm gonna
haul your ass in. You understand that?
Yes, sir.
Take off your star, you egg sucker!
- What are you looking at?
- Nothing.
- See something here you like?
- No.
- Something you wanna say?
- I don't wanna say anything.
- Hey, Buck.
- I didn't do anything to you.
- Come on, let's go.
- Watch who you're fooling with, OK?
Come on, Buck.
(High-pitched sounds)
(Metallic banging)
(Muffled sounds)
Hey, old man!
Chicken done come home to roost.
- Get, get!
- Bringing the bacon home!
I told you. I told you,
I don't want you coming around here.
Now get on outta here.
Get off my property.
Get off my property!
Aw, look at that,
done ruffled his feathers.
I'm Lynette. You're cute.
Did anybody ever tell you that?
I said get, get, get!
I won't have none of it.
Now get outta here!
Ain't he cute, Buck.
Oh, don't pay him no mind.
He's jealous. I know about you.
- What?
- Think you scare people but you don't.
They know you're sweet.
You are. I know you are.
You just act mean so people
don't know you're soft-hearted.
See, you know it's true.
I'm full up. I got no room.
Now get outta here.
You took my money, you old fart.
I may have to do what Miss Hattie says.
Take a stick of dynamite and shove it
up that old croc's ass of yours.
Now you pay me some mind.
Come on.
Rutting and rutting.
Do it right there in the dirt,
they got a mind to.
Don't make no difference.
Get it in their heads to do it
and it don't make no difference.
Won't have it.
(Police radio)
Sheriff, I just...
Libby. A lot of kids these days
are running away from home.
She'll turn up.
You just wait and see.
- I hope you're right.
- Tell you what I'll do.
I'll send out
an APB on her right now.
I'd really appreciate it.
You look tired.
Go on back to the hotel.
If you need me,
you get in touch with me.
(Psychedelic sounds)
(Country music in the background)
You gonna get yours, Lynette.
(Giggles)
Hey, stop!
What's the matter, huh?
(High-pitched sounds)
(Giggling)
(Muffled cries)
(Angie whimpers)
(Screams)
(Giggles)
Yee-haw!
- Stop!
- Shit, it's the best way!
(Heavy breathing)
Mummy! Daddy!
What's that?
It's nothing. Come here.
Just don't pay no mind to it.
It's nothing.
(Screams)
(Angie) Help!
(Loud rattling)
What is that?
Judd, turn that God damn radio off!
(Cacophony of various sounds)
What are you doing?
Don't you fret.
I'll be right back. OK?
Buck!
I got some business.
Oh now...
Now, don't.
Don't feel bad, ma'am.
No.
Buck!
- (Loud country music)
- Judd!
(Angie) 'Help!'
Judd!
(High-pitched sounds)
(Whimpering)
I told you to get!
- I said get and get!
- Did you hear that?
I made the signal.
I told you and I told you...
Would you shut up and listen?!
You come in here
and you go in there...
Shh!
Rutting and rutting.
You think I don't know.
(Whimpering)
Aargh!
(Loud splash)
I'll get your ass!
I'll get your ass for this!
Old croc eat anything,
even old Buck!
Aargh!
(Screams)
Buck?
Ah!
(laughs)
Buck!
(Screams)
Oh, God!
Where...? Where?
(Loudly) Where?
Where?
(Latino folk music)
(Metallic sounds)
(Grunting)
Yeah.
(Splashing)
(High-pitched sound)
(Muffled cries)
(Psychedelic sounds)
(Screams)
(Muffled cries)
(Metallic banging)
(Discordant sound)
(Country music in background)
(Knocking)
Oh, my God!
Oh Jesus! Jesus!
God!
(Screams)
(Loud discordant sounds)
Help!
Angie! Angie!
Daddy!
(Music box melody)
(Screams)
(Cacophony of sounds)
(High-pitched sounds)
Angie!
(Splashing)
My baby!
(Cacophony of sounds)
(Sheriff) It's all right.
(Crying) Angie.
It'll be all right.
Angie! My baby.
(Screaming) My baby! Angie!!
(Angie cries and whimpers)