[Narrator]
THIS IS THE ANT.
TREAT IT WITH RESPECT.
FOR IT MAY VERY WELL
BE THE NEXT
DOMINANT LIFE FORM
OF OUR PLANET.
SOUND INCREDIBLE?
IMPOSSIBLE?
HAVE YOU EVER TAKEN
A GOOD, CLOSE LOOK
AT WHAT THE ANT
IS ALL ABOUT?
LIKE THESE
ATTA CEPHALOTES.
ONE OF THE 15,000 DIFFERENT
SPECIES INHABITING OUR PLANET.
THIS ONE CULTIVATES CROPS
OF FUNGUS FOR FOOD.
OTHERS HERD APHIDS,
JUST AS MAN HERDS CATTLE.
AND WHAT ABOUT
THE WARRIORS?
THE BUILDERS OF BRIDGES,
ROADS, TUNNELS?
FRIGHTENING, ISN'T IT, THAT
A CREATURE AS SMALL AS AN ANT
IS ABLE TO HAVE A FAIR CLAIM
TO RANK NEXT TO MAN
IN THE SCALE
OF INTELLIGENCE?
THEY HAVE A SOPHISTICATED
COMMUNICATION SYSTEM.
SPECIFIC MESSAGES
ARE TRANSMITTED
FROM ONE ANT TO ANOTHER
THROUGH THE USE OF
A CHEMICAL SUBSTANCE
CALLED PHEROMONES.
IT CAUSES AN
OBLIGATORY RESPONSE.
DID YOU HEAR THAT?
OBLIGATORY.
PHEROMONES GIVE AN ORDER
THAT CANNOT BE DISOBEYED.
IT'S A MIND-BENDING
SUBSTANCE THAT
FORCES OBEDIENCE.
BUT WE DON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT IT.
THAT'S BUSINESS BETTER
LEFT TO THE ANTS.
[Siren wailing]
GOT IT?
WHAT TOOK
YOU SO LONG?
I STOPPED TO GET
SOME EXTRA LIQUOR.
YOU SHOULD'VE
LET ME KNOW.
I DIDN'T KNOW I WAS
SUPPOSED TO BE ON CALL.
YOU'RE ALWAYS
SORRY, MS. FRYSER.
THAT'S ALL RIGHT,
SWEETHEART.
YOU'RE SO TERRIFIC
IN THE SACK
THAT IT ALMOST JUSTIFIES
THE EXCESSIVE SALARY
THAT I HAVE
TO PAY YOU.
BY THE WAY,
CAPTAIN...
TRY AND GIVE US
THE SMOOTHEST POSSIBLE
TRIP, WILL YOU?
WE DON'T WANT
ANY OF OUR
PROSPECTIVE BUYERS
GETTING SEASICK.
YES, MA'AM.
SICK PEOPLE DO NOT
BUY PROPERTY.
I'LL CUT BETWEEN
THE WAVES.
YOU DO THAT.
I'M SURE
YOU REMEMBER,
BY THE WAY,
THAT I'M PAYING YOU
DAMN GOOD MONEY
TO RENT THIS BOAT,
CAPTAIN.
I'M SURE THAT
IF I FORGET,
YOU'LL REMIND ME.
OH, WELL, IT LOOKS LIKE
OUR GUESTS
ARE FINALLY ARRIVING.
SURE A NICE BOAT,
ISN'T IT?
WE WENT ON A
BIGGER ONE TO
MEXICO THAT TIME.
YEAH, BUT WE PAID
FOR THAT TRIP.
TWO-BIT CRUISE DOWN
THE COAST TO LOOK AT
OVERPRICED SWAMPLAND.
YOU ALWAYS SAID
YOU WANTED A HOME
ON THE OCEAN.
YEAH, I SAID
A LOT OF THINGS.
YOU COMING?
YEAH, YEAH,
ALL RIGHT.
YOU WIN. WE'LL GO
FOR A BOAT RIDE.
HERE'S A $10.
KEEP THE CHANGE.
BUT, LADY,
THE FARE'S $9.80.
DON'T MENTION IT.
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING?
THE LETTER SAID
EVERYTHING WAS FREE.
I'M WRITING DOWN ALL
OUR EXPENSES SO WE
CAN BE REIMBURSED.
UMM...
BEFORE I BOARD
YOUR SHIP, MAY I
ASK YOU A QUESTION?
YES, MA'AM.
I JUST WANT TO
MAKE CERTAIN THAT I'M
UNDER NO OBLIGATION
TO BUY ANY OF YOUR
PROPERTY, IN CASE
I CHANGE MY MIND.
IT'S NOT MY PROPERTY,
LADY.
I JUST GET YOU THERE
AND GET YOU BACK.
THANK YOU.
LET'S GET THIS
CIRCUS ON THE ROAD.
HI. ARE YOU
MS. ELLIS?
YES.
I'M MARILYN FRYSER,
I'M THE PRESIDENT
OF DREAMLAND SHORES.
COME AND MEET SOME PEOPLE.
THIS IS MR. AND MRS. LAWSON.
HELLO.
AND THIS IS
LARRY GRAHAM.
[Marilyn]
I THINK WE HAVE
EVERBODY ONBOARD NOW.
THINK THAT'LL
PLEASE THE BITCH?
EVER SEE
ANYTHING THAT DID?
WHAT A RIP-OFF.
SHE'LL BRING A BOATLOAD
OF SLOBS DOWN HERE
AND CONVINCE THEM
IT'S PARADISE.
IT WOULDN'T BE SO BAD
AROUND HERE IF IT WAS
CLOSE TO SOMETHING.
A ROAD, A TOWN,
ANYTHING.
WHAT ABOUT
DIAMOND SPRINGS?
SURE, THAT'S PRACTICALLY
NEXT DOOR.
ALL YOU DO IS WALK
2 MILES TO THE RIVER
AND SWIM UPSTREAM
ANOTHER 10.
YOU OUGHT TO
READ THE CONTRACT
SHE MAKES THEM SIGN.
THE JERKS THAT BUY
THIS SWAMPLAND
CAN'T EVEN SELL
IT FOR 2 YEARS.
DREAMLAND SHORES WON'T
BE HERE IN 2 YEARS.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
SOME OF THE MEATBALLS
OVER THERE?
THEY ARE
REALLY TASTY.
ARE YOU LADIES
HAVING A GOOD TIME?
LOVELY.
JUST MARVELOUS,
THANK YOU.
IT'D BE WONDERFUL.
EVERYTHING IS SO FRESH.
IT'S
UNBELIEVABLE.
EVERYTHING
ALL RIGHT HERE?
IT'S GREAT.
[Christine]
YOU WON'T BELIEVE
HOW DIFFICULT IT WAS
FOR ME TO CONVINCE LARRY
TO COME THIS WEEKEND.
MR. THOMPSON?
YES.
HAVE YOU TAKEN
SOME GOOD PICTURES?
[Mr. Thompson]
I THINK I HAVE
SOME DANDIES.
EXCUSE ME.
WHERE ARE THOSE 2
GUYS THAT YOU HIRED?
I SUPPOSE THEY FINISHED
THEIR WORK AND THEY LEFT.
LEFT?
WELL, YOU CAN TELL THEM
THAT THEY'RE FIRED.
SPEAKING OF THAT,
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
A LITTLE OF THAT
OLD-WORLD CHARM THAT
YOU'RE SO FAMOUS
FOR ON OUR GUESTS?
I AM NOT RUNNING A
CHARITY ORGANIZATION.
I'VE ALWAYS WANTED
TO LIVE NEAR THE WATER.
IT'S BEAUTIFUL HERE,
ISN'T IT?
YES, IT IS LOVELY.
HOW ARE YOU DOING?
FINE.
CHARLIE, RIGHT?
RIGHT.
GOOD, CHARLIE.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT EVERYBODY'S
DOING HERE?
HERE TO BUY LAND.
WHAT ELSE?
NOT EVERYONE.
OUR AVERAGE IS 1
OUT OF 3 PEOPLE
COME ALONG JUST
FOR THE RIDE.
YOU SHOULD BE MORE
CAREFUL WHO YOU INVITE.
WE SURE WOULD
LIKE TO,
BUT WE GET STUCK
WITH THAT STATISTIC
NO MATTER WHAT.
WHAT ABOUT
THIS GROUP?
THINK YOU CAN FIGURE OUT
WHO'LL BE THE BUYERS
AND WHO AREN'T?
NOT EXACTLY.
BUT I THINK I'VE GOT
YOU FIGURED OUT.
TELL ME.
NOT ONLY COULD YOU
NOT AFFORD A LOT,
BUT I THINK YOU'D HAVE
A HELL OF A TIME
SWINGING FOR
THE BOAT RIDE.
AM I RIGHT?
CHEERS.
EXCUSE ME.
HAVE YOU
HAD ENOUGH?
ENOUGH WHAT?
PARTY BULLSHIT.
I KNOW WHAT
YOU MEAN.
WHY DON'T WE TAKE A
LOOK AROUND? SEE IF
THIS PLACE IS FOR REAL.
I DON'T THINK YOUR
WIFE WOULD LIKE THAT.
UH, WE HAVE
DIFFERENT INTERESTS.
I'M SURE YOU DO.
HOW ABOUT IT?
YES, MR. STRATTON
IS THE VICE PRESIDENT
OF INTERNATIONAL
MANAGEMENT CONSULTANTS.
I'VE WORKED FOR
HIM ABOUT 20 YEARS.
HIS PERSONAL
EXECUTIVE SECRETARY,
YOU UNDERSTAND.
IT'S QUITE A
RESPONSIBILITY.
CHEAP SCOTCH.
I THINK ITS ALL
A COME-ON.
SO WHAT?
IT'S FREE,
ISN'T IT?
THAT'S WHAT VELMA
AND I LIKE THE MOST.
THAT'S A LONG TIME
TO BE WITH ONE COMPANY.
NOT WHEN YOU CONSIDER
ALL THE BENEFITS
THAT CAN ACCRUE--
GIFTS, BONUSES,
RETIREMENT PENSION.
NO WONDER YOU'RE LOOKING
INTO LAND INVESTMENTS.
I WOULDN'T SAY THAT
I'M EXACTLY LOOKING
FOR INVESTMENTS.
NOW, DON'T
YOU WORRY.
NOBODY IS GOING TO
HUSTLE YOU INTO
BUYING ANYTHING.
DREAMLAND SHORES
SELLS ITSELF.
MMPH!
THAT'S NOT WHAT WE
CAME OUT HERE FOR.
COME ON.
I MUST BE CRAZY OR SOMETHING.
I JUST MET YOU AN HOUR AGO
AND HERE I AM
OUT IN THE WOODS
PLAYING HOT FINGERS.
LOOSEN UP.
LET ME GO!
LOOK, I JUST GOT OUT
OF ONE MARRIED MAN.
NOT WITH ME.
IT'LL BE ONE OF THE BIG
DISAPPOINTMENTS IN MY LIFE.
WHERE YOU GOING?
LET GO!
COME ON.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S
ALL ABOUT, BABY.
LET ME GO, YOU
SON OF A BITCH!
RELAX, RELAX.
THAT'S IT.
I JUST WANT TO GET TO
KNOW YOU, THAT'S ALL.
OK.
WE'RE GONNA BE
GOOD FRIENDS. AAH!
SHIT!
OHH! OHH!
EXCUSE ME.
I WAS GOING TO ASK
YOU IF YOU'D LIKE TO
JOIN THE ENTERTAINMENT,
BUT I SEE YOU
FOUND YOUR OWN.
YEAH, WE WERE JUST
LOOKING AROUND.
[High-pitched noise]
IF YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR THE PARTY,
IT'S RIGHT DOWN THERE.
I'M NOT MUCH FOR
PARTIES. BESIDES, I
WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
IT'S DAN, ISN'T IT?
WHAT DO YOU WANT
TO TALK ABOUT?
HERE.
THIS PLACE.
DREAMLAND SHORES.
LOOK, LADY, I
TOLD YOU, I'M JUST
THE BOAT DRIVER.
I GET YOU HERE
AND I GET YOU BACK.
I DON'T SELL THE
LAND, ALL RIGHT?
EXACTLY, SO YOU
SHOULDN'T CARE
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
I DON'T.
I DON'T GIVE A DAMN.
YOU SEE, I WANT TO
OPEN A SMALL BUSINESS.
MAYBE AN AGENCY
FOR DOMESTIC HELP.
BUT IT'S GOING TO TAKE
ALL THE SAVINGS I'VE GOT,
SO I'VE GOT TO
MAKE CERTAIN
THAT I MAKE THE BEST
INVESTMENT POSSIBLE.
I DON'T HAVE ANY
OPINIONS ABOUT THAT.
WELL, BUT YOU'D BE
HONEST WITH ME.
LIKE, THIS LAND
THEY'RE TRYING
TO SELL US,
IS IT A GOOD THING?
OR NOT?
LADY,
IF YOU WANT ADVICE,
WOULD YOU ASK
SOMEBODY ELSE, PLEASE?
I JUST HAD A PRETTY
ROUGH TIME OF IT MYSELF.
AND I GUESS IF
I WEREN'T SO SICK
OF THE WHOLE ROUTINE,
I'D PROBABLY BE
DOING WHAT YOU'RE
DOING RIGHT NOW.
I BEG YOUR PARDON?
ALL THIS SELF-PITY,
"NOBODY-GIVES-A-DAMN"
ATTITUDE.
WHAT?
THE BOOZE.
RIGHT.
YOU KNOW, UMM
WHEN I MET YOU
ON THE BOAT,
I DIDN'T LIKE
YOU VERY MUCH.
THAT'S NOT EXACTLY
A SURPRISE.
I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS I THOUGHT
YOU WERE ONE OF THOSE
MACHO, PHONY TYPES,
THE KIND WHOSE BRAINS
FALL OUT EVERY TIME
HE UNZIPS HIS FLY.
SAY, WHAT IS THIS,
GROUP THERAPY?
MAYBE.
I CAN'T AFFORD TO MAKE
A MISTAKE, THAT'S ALL.
I LIED TO THEM
BACK THERE BEFORE.
I TOLD THEM
I HAD A GOOD JOB,
BEEN WORKING FOR THE
SAME MAN FOR 20 YEARS.
THE TRUTH OF IT IS,
HE FIRED ME.
ALL I'VE GOT
IS SEVERANCE PAY
AND REFERENCES.
I'VE GOT A JOB THAT
PAYS $30,000 A YEAR,
I OWN A 2-BEDROOM
CONDOMINIUM, I'VE GOT
A $10,000 SPORTS CAR,
I'VE GOT A WIFE AND
I GOT A 4-YEAR-OLD KID
WHO THINKS
I'M GOD.
HOW'S THAT?
THAT'S TERRIFIC.
THAT'S FABULOUS.
LOOK, I WAS JUST TRYING
TO TELL YOU THAT
I CHANGED MY MIND
ABOUT NOT LIKING YOU.
THAT'S ALL.
FORGET IT.
I'M A BAD
INVESTMENT.
AND WHY DO
YOU SAY THAT?
BECAUSE THE...
$30,000-A-YEAR
JOB WENT IN THE
TOILET LAST YEAR.
AND THE SPORTS CAR
NEEDS AN OVERHAUL.
AND MY WIFE
IS AN EX-WIFE,
WHO'S SUING ME
FOR BACK SUPPORT.
MY KID WON'T EVEN TALK
TO ME ON THE PHONE.
WHAT ABOUT
YOUR CONDOMINIUM?
PLASTIC,
LIKE EVERYTHING ELSE.
SHALL WE?
OK.
IF IT WAS MY MONEY
AND I WAS GOING TO
BUY THIS LAND,
FIRST, I'D MAKE SURE
THEY STRUCK OIL ON IT,
AND THEN I'D
STILL THINK TWICE.
DOES THAT ANSWER
YOUR QUESTION?
OK.
DAN.
YOU GOT A BUTTON
OFF YOUR SHIRT.
IF YOU GOT TIME,
I ALWAYS CARRY
A NEEDLE AND THREAD.
I DON'T NEED
ANY BUTTONS.
THIS BUILDING HERE IS
GONNA BE TORN DOWN.
AND THE DREAMLAND
SHORES BEACH CLUB
IS GONNA BE
CONSTRUCTED
IN ITS PLACE.
IT'LL BE THE MOST
BEAUTIFUL AND MODERN
CLUB IMAGINABLE,
WITH EVERY POSSIBLE
CONVENIENCE.
IF WE ALL GET INTO
THE TRAM, NOW,
WHERE CHARLIE IS,
WE'LL BE OFF ON
OUR LITTLE TOUR.
HERE WE GO.
[Marilyn]
NOW, DON'T FORGET,
IF YOU HAVE ANY
QUESTIONS ABOUT ANYTHING,
JUST SHOUT THEM OUT.
WE'RE VERY
INFORMAL HERE
AND THIS TOUR IS STRICTLY
FOR YOUR PLEASURE.
I THINK ALL OF YOU BOATING
ENTHUSIASTS WILL BE
INTERESTED IN THESE
PRESENTLY-AVAILABLE LOTS,
WHICH,
AS YOU CAN SEE,
ARE CONVENIENTLY LOCATED
RIGHT NEXT TO THE MARINA.
ALL OF THE HOUSE
LOTS YOU SEE HERE
WILL BE SOLD ON A
FIRST COME,
FIRST SERVED BASIS.
IF YOU SEE A LOT
THAT APPEALS TO YOU,
JUST TELL
CHARLIE OR ME
AND WE'LL GIVE
YOU FIRST REFUSAL.
LARRY,
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
IT'S NOT WHAT I THINK,
IT'S WHAT DADDY
THINKS, ISN'T IT?
HONEY, YOU KNOW MY FATHER
ONLY WANTS TO HELP US--
BOTH OF US.
HE'D HELP US A LOT MORE
IF HE'D LEAVE US ALONE.
THEN MAYBE HE'D BE
SATISFIED WITH WHAT
I COULD GIVE YOU.
YOU WILL NOTICE THAT WE HAVE
CAREFULLY PRESERVED
THE NATURAL BEAUTY OF
DREAMLAND SHORES.
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO TAKE
LONG WALKS INTO THESE
SECLUDED AREAS.
...BIRDS AND BUTTERFLIES
AND FRAGRANT FLOWERS.
FOR THOSE OF YOU
WHO ARE GOLF ENTHUSIASTS,
YOU'LL PROBABLY
WANT TO BE SITUATED
OVERLOOKING THE
18-HOLE GOLF COURSE,
WHICH WILL SOON BE
UNDER CONSTRUCTION.
AFTER WE STOP AT
OUR PICNIC AREA
FOR REFRESHMENTS,
WE'LL GO ON
AND   LOOK   AT SOME
OF THE   INLAND PROPERTIES.
HERE WE ARE.
[Charlie]
BE CAREFUL
GETTING OUT, NOW.
NOW, IF WE'RE
REALLY LUCKY,
WE MAY GET SOME
GLIMPSES OF SOME OF
THE FASCINATING
WILDLIFE THAT'S
IN THIS AREA.
DO YOU KNOW THERE ARE
100 DIFFERENT KINDS
OF BIRDS HERE?
THERE ARE?
YES.
I'VE SEEN
OVER 50 MYSELF.
CHARLIE?
YOU WANT TO HELP ME
WITH THE SANDWICHES,
DARLING?
WOULD YOU LIKE
A PLATE?
THANK YOU.
IT ALMOST LOOKS LIKE
THOSE ROMANTIC PLACES
YOU USED TO SEE
IN OLD MOVIES.
WHAT DOES YOUR
HUSBAND THINK
ABOUT THE IDEA?
HE'S NOT VERY
INTERESTED.
OH, WHAT A SHAME.
BUT YOUR HUSBAND
SEEMS TO BE.
THEN I TOOK ONE
OF THOSE LONG,
SLOW LOOKS.
YOU KNOW THE KIND
YOU TAKE ON A
RAINY WEEKEND
WHEN HE'S HOME PLAYING
GOODY-GOODY FAMILY MAN?
I GOT UP ONE DAY,
GOT DRESSED
AND TOLD THE BASTARD
TO GO BACK TO HIS WIFE.
YOU KNOW SOMETHING?
FROM THEN ON, IT WAS
JUST LIKE A BREATH
OF FRESH AIR.
I CASHED IN MY FUR COAT
AND ALL THE OTHER
LITTLE KNICK-KNACKS
AND DECIDED TO BUY MYSELF
A PIECE OF SOMETHING
REALLY LEGITIMATE--
LIKE A HOUSE.
I COULD GO TO BED
WHEN I WANTED
TO GO TO BED.
THAT'S WHY
I'M HERE.
ALTHOUGH,
YOU KNOW,
I REALLY DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S SO GREAT
ABOUT OWNING A HOUSE.
THOMAS,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
LOOKING,
JUST LOOKING.
YOU'RE TRYING
TO FIND FAULT,
AREN'T YOU?
YOU DON'T
TRUST ANYBODY.
MOST PEOPLE
ARE DISHONEST.
LETS GET BACK
TO THE OTHERS.
IN A MINUTE,
IN A MINUTE.
LOOK AT THIS, MARY!
IT'S A WATER PIPE!
IT ISN'T EVEN CONNECTED!
IT'S A FRAUD,
JUST LIKE I SAID.
THESE PEOPLE
ARE DISHONEST.
THIS IS A FRAUD!
TRUST PEOPLE? I TELL YOU,
YOU CAN'T TRUST ANYBODY, MARY.
YOU CAN'T TRUST
ANYBODY.
I HOPE YOU'VE LEARNED
YOUR LESSON. LOOK!
[High-pitched noise]
WHAT'S THAT SOUND?
WHO CARES?
I FOUND WHAT I
WAS LOOKING FOR.
LISTEN, THOMAS,
IT'S ALL AROUND US.
MARY,
WILL YOU LEAVE--
OH, MY GOD.
RUN, MARY, RUN!
[Screaming]
HELP, MARY, HELP!
HELP, MARY, HELP ME!
[Screaming]
AHH!
OH, MY GOD!
[Screaming]
OVER THERE,
ABOUT 50 YARDS,
WILL BE OUR COMMUNITY
RECREATION CENTER.
IT WILL HAVE A
COMPLETE WORKSHOP
AND HOBBY ROOM.
THERE WILL BE A THEATRE,
A BOWLING ALLEY,
POOL TABLES, SAUNAS,
EVERY CONVENIENCE.
[Mrs. Thompson]
THE LAWSONS.
WHERE ARE THE LAWSONS?
[Coreen]
THEY DUCKED OUT
BACK AT THE PICNIC AREA.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
SAY SOMETHING?
AFTER LISTENING TO
YOU ON THAT BULLHORN
FOR 2 HOURS,
I WAS READY TO
DUCK OUT MYSELF.
KEEP MOVING,
CHARLIE.
THERE'S A LOT MORE
TO SEE, EVERYBODY.
[High-pitched noise]
WHAT'S THAT NOISE?
SEEMS TO BE COMING
FROM OVER THERE.
IT'S NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
IT'S PROBABLY SOME OF
OUR PUMPING EQUIPMENT.
MARILYN, THERE'S NO PUMP.
WE'D BETTER GET
BACK TO THAT BOAT.
SHUT UP.
THERE'S NOTHING TO
WORRY ABOUT, EVERYBODY.
WHEN YOU COMPARE
ALL THE BENEFITS
OF DREAMLAND SHORES
TO OTHER LAND INVESTMENTS
YOU MAY HAVE SEEN,
I'M CERTAIN
YOU WILL REALIZE
WHAT A WONDERFUL
VALUE WE HAVE HERE.
OH, MY GOD!
LOOK!
[Charlie]
THAT'S PETE,
ONE OF OUR WORKERS.
[Mr. Thompson]
MY GOD!
WHAT HAPPENED?
[Charlie]
TAKE IT EASY.
HOLY JESUS.
HEY, WE'D BETTER GO LOOK
FOR THE LAWSONS.
WHO'LL GO WITH ME?
LARRY?
NO, I'M NOT
GOING OUT THERE.
NO, NOT ME.
I'M AN OLD MAN.
WE ONLY CAME
BECAUSE IT WAS FREE.
WE TAKE THESE
TOURS ALL THE TIME.
BUT NOTHING
EVER HAPPENED
LIKE THIS BEFORE.
IT'S OK, HARRY.
JOE, I'LL
GO WITH YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
WE'LL MEET YOU
BACK AT THE BOAT.
MR. LAWSON!
JOE.
OH, MY GOD.
[High-pitched noise]
AHH!
OH, MY GOD.
WHAT THE HELL
ARE THEY?
THAT'S MY BOAT.
DAN!
OH, MY GOD.
LET'S PICK THEM UP
AT THE BEACH!
GET UP!
[Screeching]
AHH!
AAHH!
WE'RE NEVER GONNA
GET OUT OF HERE.
[Larry]
WHY IS THIS
HAPPENING?
[Christine]
LARRY.
I CAN'T
BELIEVE THIS.
GOD.
THEY DON'T LIKE FIRE.
THAT'S FOR SURE.
ALL WE HAVE TO DO
IS KEEP THIS
DAMN FIRE GOING.
[Harry]
THEY JUST COULDN'T BE.
JOE?
ANTS.
WHY DON'T WE GO INTO
THE OLD BEACH HOUSE?
WE'LL BE SAFE
INSIDE THERE.
WITHOUT THAT FIRE, THOSE
THINGS WOULD BE INSIDE
WITH US IN 2 MINUTES.
GODDAMMIT,
WHY DO YOU SHOOT DOWN
EVERYTHING THAT I SAY?
YOU NEVER DID
LIKE WORKING FOR ME
JUST BECAUSE I'M A WOMAN.
THEY'RE WAITING.
THEY'RE OUT THERE
WAITING UNTIL
THE FIRE DIES.
CAN'T YOU HEAR THEM?
[Larry]
WHERE DID THEY
COME FROM?
HOW THE HELL DID
THEY GET THAT SIZE?
WHAT ARE YOU THINKING?
I'M THINKING
OF A WAY OUT.
ALL WE WANTED WAS TO ENJOY
WHAT WAS LEFT OF OUR LIFE.
IS THAT BAD?
HEY, HOW ABOUT
SOME CANDY?
IT'S GOOD.
IT'LL MAKE YOU
FEEL BETTER.
COME ON.
IT'S YOURS IF
YOU WANT IT.
BETTER GET SOME MORE
WOOD FOR THAT FIRE.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA
NEED ANY WOOD.
[Thunder]
[Thunder continues]
CHARLIE?
YEAH?
THE TENT AND
THE WORKERS...
I DIDN'T BRING THEM.
HOW DID THEY GET HERE?
A RIVER NORTH OF
HERE ABOUT 2 MILES.
WE'VE A GOT BOAT
ON THAT RIVER,
A SMALL BOAT!
YOU EXPECT US
TO WALK 2 MILES
THROUGH THAT JUNGLE?
OH NO, WE'RE GONNA
STAY RIGHT HERE
UNTIL HELP COMES!
WHEN THE HELL
IS THAT GONNA
BE, MARILYN?
LOOK, AS SOON AS THEY
KNOW THAT WE'RE MISSING,
THEY'LL SEND
A SEARCH PARTY!
I AM NOT GONNA LEAVE
DREAMLAND SHORES!
YOU CAN STAY HERE
AND BE BURIED
ON DREAMLAND SHORES.
THAT FIRE GOES OUT,
I'M GONNA BE
SOMEPLACE ELSE.
WELL, DO YOU WANT TO TRY
FOR THE RIVER OR NOT?
IT'S UNANIMOUS, JOE.
WE'RE ALL TOO
SCARED TO VOTE.
NO!
NO, THEY'LL
KILL US.!
LARRY, WHY DON'T YOU
JUST WAIT FOR THEM HERE!
CHARLIE,
WE'RE NOT LEAVING!
I'M GONNA STAY HERE
AND YOU'RE GONNA
STAY WITH ME.
WE'LL GO INTO
THE BEACH HOUSE.
YOU'RE CRAZY,
MARILYN!
WE'VE GOTTA GO!
OH! AAH!
AHH!
KEEP GOING!
COME ON.
OH, GOD!
KEEP GOING.
THE BEACH HOUSE
IS FULL OF THEM!
DOZENS OF
GIANT ANTS!
HURRY UP.
COME ON, HURRY UP.
THERE!
[Screaming and shouting]
I CAN'T KEEP UP!
LET'S GO
THIS WAY.
CAREFUL, NOW.
DON'T STUMBLE.
DON'T WORRY, SWEETIE,
WE'LL BE SAFE IN THERE.
LARRY!
AHH!
WHAT?
LARRY, WAIT!
OH!
MY ANKLE!
AGH!
LARRY!
OH, PLEASE,
DON'T LEAVE ME!
LARRY!
[Screaming]
COME ON.
LET'S  GO.
COME ON!
CHARLIE! CHARLIE!
[High-pitched noise]
OH, GOD!
OH, GOD,
NO, PLEASE!
GO!
[Screaming]
[Ant screeching]
THE RAIN
STOPPED.
IT'S A GOOD OMEN.
ALL RIGHT?
THERE IT IS.
THERE'S THE BOAT.
JOE!
WE'RE COMING
THROUGH.
WE LOST THE
OLD COUPLE.
HANG ON.
WHAT ABOUT
CHRISTINE?
NO, SHE DIDN'T
MAKE IT.
COME ON.
I'M NOT GOING
WITH YOU.
GET IN THE BOAT.
CHARLIE'S DEAD.
I WANT TO STAY
WITH HIM.
GET IN THE
GODDAMN BOAT!
OK, JOE, LET'S GO.
GET YOUR FINGERS
OUT OF THE WAY.
MOVE THEM.
YOU'RE WORKING
FOR ME, REMEMBER?
I'M STILL IN
CHARGE HERE.
WOULD YOU
LIKE TO ROW?
VERY FUNNY.
[High-pitched noise]
SEE? I TOLD YOU
WE'D BE SAFE.
THEY'RE GONE NOW.
[High-pitched noise]
[Marilyn]
SO QUIET.
GOD, WHY IS IT
SO QUIET?
[Margaret]
WE GOT AWAY FROM THEM.
WE LEFT THEM ALL BACK THERE.
WE DID, DIDN'T WE?
JOE? DAN?
I DON'T KNOW.
THANK GOD
WE'RE SAFE.
CHARLIE NEVER
GOT AWAY FROM THEM.
WE'LL NEVER GET
AWAY FROM THEM.
THIS HAS TURNED OUT
TO BE ONE HELL OF
A FREE VACATION.
I LOVED CHRISTINE,
YOU KNOW.
I HOPE THAT NICE
OLD COUPLE GOT AWAY.
WHAT WERE
THEIR NAMES?
HARRY AND VELMA.
I WISH I HADN'T SEEN
CHARLIE DIE LIKE THAT.
WHAT WAS I
SUPPOSED TO DO?
SHE RAN OFF.
I TURNED AROUND
AND SHE WAS GONE.
I WENT TO LOOK
FOR HER.
NOBODY'S BLAMING
YOU, LARRY.
WE'RE NOT SAYING
IT'S YOUR FAULT.
YOU THINK I SAW THE ANTS
KILL HER, DON'T YOU?
GO AHEAD AND SAY IT!
GO ON!
WHY WOULD WE
THINK THAT?
MR. STRATTON ALWAYS
LIKED A CUP OF NICE
HOT TEA AT THE END
OF A HARD DAY,
WITH A SLICE OF
ORANGE PEEL.
I TOOK VERY GOOD
CARE OF HIM.
I STARTED THERE
AS A FILE CLERK.
AND AFTER ALL THOSE YEARS,
DO YOU KNOW HOW THEY GAVE ME
MY NOTICE OF
TERMINATION?
IT WAS A LITTLE
PIECE OF PAPER...
A MEMO.
"DEAR MS. ELLIS,
"THIS IS TO INFORM YOU
"THAT YOUR SERVICES
ARE NO LONGER REQUIRED
"AND YOUR EMPLOYMENT
IS HEREBY TERMINATED.
"YOU WILL RECEIVE THE
USUAL SEVERANCE PAY,
"AS IS CUSTOMARY
WITH THIS FIRM."
MR. STRATTON
DIDN'T EVEN SIGN IT.
I'VE NEVER DONE
ANYTHING LIKE THIS,
NEVER TAKEN
ANY CHANCES,
NEVER DONE
ANYTHING DANGEROUS.
IT'S NOT FAIR THAT THIS
SHOULD HAPPEN TO ME.
OH, LARRY,
IF IT'S ANY
CONSOLATION,
NONE OF US ARE
ENJOYING THIS BOAT RIDE
ANYMORE THAN YOU ARE.
MAIN PART OF THE RIVER
LOOKS LIKE IT COMES
FROM THAT WAY.
[Larry]
IT'S TO THE LEFT.
WE SHOULD GO LEFT.
[Marilyn]
I'M GLAD
SOMEBODY'S SURE.
EITHER WAY,
JUST AS LONG AS
WE KEEP MOVING.
IT'S MY LIFE,
GODDAMMIT! GO LEFT!
[High-pitched noise]
[Coreen]
CONGRATULATIONS, LARRY.
YOU'RE ALSO A
DYNAMITE NAVIGATOR.
[Larry]
GO TO HELL.
[Marilyn]
SHUT UP, YOU TWO.
WHY DON'T
YOU ALL SHUT UP?
WE CAN GET AROUND IT.
IF YOU SAY SO, LARRY.
YOU'RE THE NAVIGATOR.
CAN YOU MOVE IT?
[Joe]
WHY DON'T WE
WALK IT AROUND?
[Dan]
I DON'T WANT
TO PORTAGE IT.
[Marilyn]
HOW CAN WE
GET PAST THAT?
DAN! DAN!
[Screaming]
GET THEM AWAY!
DAN!
LARRY, I'M...
I'M SORRY ABOUT
THE NAVIGATOR CRACK,
IF IT MATTERS.
IT DOESN'T.
OK. FORGET IT.
WE'RE ALL ON EDGE.
WE SAY THINGS
WE DON'T MEAN.
YEAH, WELL,
TELL THAT BITCH,
DON'T TELL ME.
LOOK OUT!
[Screaming]
HELP ME!
GOD HELP ME!
WE'LL BE FINE
ALONG THE BEACH.
WATCH THAT TREE!
OK.
OH!
LET'S CONTINUE
UPSTREAM.
WE'LL JUST
FOLLOW THE RIVER.
HOLD IT!
WHAT?
WHAT IS IT?
AHH...
NOTHING.
THOUGHT I HEARD
SOMETHING.
LISTEN!
WAIT A MINUTE.
I TOLD YOU THAT
THIS RIVER DIDN'T
LEAD ANYWHERE.
YOU SHOULD HAVE
LISTENED TO ME,
DAMMIT!
I DON'T CARE WHAT
THE REST OF YOU DO.
I AM GONNA GO IN
THIS DIRECTION!
MARILYN! MARILYN!
[High-pitched noise]
AHH!
[Screaming]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO WE
DO NOW?
OBVIOUSLY, THEY CAN
KILL US ANY TIME
THEY WANT TO.
THEY JUST DON'T SEEM
TO WANT TO RIGHT NOW.
WHY NOT?
CAN'T YOU TELL?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I MEAN, THEY DON'T WANT
US TO GO THAT WAY
AND THEY DON'T WANT US
TO GO BACK THE WAY WE CAME.
THAT ONLY LEAVES
ONE WAY--
UPSTREAM.
OH, MY GOD! THEY'RE
HERDING US LIKE CATTLE!
AHH!
[High-pitched noise]
GOD, WHERE'D
THEY COME FROM?
LET'S GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.
OH, MY GOD!
IT'S CIVILIZATION!
WHERE ARE WE?
IS THERE A TOWN
NEAR HERE?
YOU FOLKS LOOK LIKE
YOU'VE BEEN OUT
IN THAT STORM ALL NIGHT.
IT WASN'T THE STORM
THAT BOTHERED US.
THERE'S A REAL
HORROR SHOW COMING
UPRIVER BEHIND US.
[Joe]
GIANT ANTS,
BIG AS YOU ARE.
[Dan]
THEY'VE ALREADY KILLED
KILLED SOME PEOPLE.
[Man]
PHOEBE WILL CALL
THE SHERIFF.
HAVE YOU SEEN THEM?
PHOEBE!
CALL THE SHERIFF!
PHOEBE'S A
VERY GOOD WIFE.
GIANT ANTS.
THAT'S HARD TO BELIEVE.
NEVER THOUGHT I'D
LIVE TO SEE THE DAY.
WHAT'RE YOU
GONNA DO, SHERIFF?
WELL...
FIRST THING,
I'M GONNA GET YOU
PEOPLE SITUATED.
THEN I'LL GET
SOME DEPUTIES
AND GO BACK TO THE RIVER
AND START SEARCHING.
I TOLD YOU, THOSE THINGS
ARE VICIOUS AS HELL.
A COUPLE OF DEPUTIES
WON'T DO YOU MUCH GOOD.
I GOT A WHOLE TOWN
IF I NEED IT.
I DON'T KNOW HOW MANY
OF THEM ARE OUT THERE.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
ANY ANTS COME THIS WAY,
WE'LL TAKE CARE OF THEM.
THE SUGAR REFINERY.
ON THE WAY BACK,
I BETTER ALERT THEM.
THEY'RE SO CLOSE TO THE RIVER.
YOU FOLKS DON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ANYMORE.
ALL YOU HAVE
TO DO IS REST,
UNWIND AND WE'LL
GET YOU CLEANED UP.
I RADIOED ONE OF MY DEPUTIES
TO MAKE ARRANGEMENTS.
I HOPE THIS PLACE
IS NICE ENOUGH
FOR YOU FOLK.
[Marilyn]
THAT'S VERY KIND
OF YOU, SHERIFF.
SHERIFF, I'D LIKE TO
MAKE A PHONE CALL.
MY FRIEND AT THE
STATE CAPITAL COULD
GET HELP HERE FAST.
SURE, GO AHEAD.
[Coreen]
WHAT I REALLY WANT
TO DO IS GO HOME.
[Sherrif] AS SOON AS WE GET
THE MAIN HIGHWAY OPEN,
YOU CAN ALL BE ON YOUR WAY.
DON'T TELL ME YOUR
PROBLEMS, HARRISON,
AND I WON'T
TELL YOU MINE.
I WANT THAT SHIPMENT
OF SUGAR IN MY TOWN
BY DAY AFTER TOMORROW
OR YOU CAN FORGET IT.
MAYOR, YOU GOT
SOME CUSTOMERS HERE.
BE WITH YOU IN A MINUTE.
LONG-DISTANCE PHONE.
YEAH, I'D LIKE TO PLACE A
PERSON-TO-PERSON CALL
TO MR. JOHN AMSTEAD
IN THE STATE
ATTORNEY'S OFFICE
AT THE CAPITAL.
ANY MORE PROBLEMS,
YOU CALL ME AT ONCE,
YOU HEAR?
ANSON PARKER.
HE OWNS THE MOTEL.
HE'S ALSO OUR MAYOR.
VERY WEALTHY.
DON'T TAKE 3 DAYS
TO DRIVE THOSE RIGS
FROM YOUR PLACE TO MINE.
IT'S A LOUSY
800 MILES.
TELL THE MEN TO
DRIVE ALL NIGHT
IF THEY HAVE TO.
REMEMBER THAT SUGAR
REFINERY WE PASSED
ON OUR WAY HERE?
SOMETHING FUNNY.
FUNNY?
YEAH.
WHEN WE WERE
BACK AT THAT
OLD COUPLE'S HOUSE,
THE WOMAN SAID
SOMETHING TO ME
THAT JUST DIDN'T
MAKE SENSE,
THAT'S ALL.
WHAT DID SHE SAY?
SHE SAID,
"WHATEVER YOU DO,
"DON'T LET THEM
TAKE YOU TO THE
SUGAR REFINERY."
ISN'T THAT CRAZY?
THERE'S NO WAY TO
GET A CALL THROUGH?
DAMMIT, DON'T YOU HAVE
SOME EMERGENCY LINES?
IT'S NONE OF YOUR
BUSINESS WHAT I'M
DOING WITH THE SUGAR.
OUR REFINERY IS
TURNING OUT
ALL IT CAN,
FULL BLAST AND
WE NEED MORE.
OK. FINE.
BYE-BYE.
SORRY.
A LITTLE
BUSINESS PROBLEM.
YOU MUST HAVE COME UP
FROM DREAMLAND SHORES.
HOW DID YOU KNOW
WE CAME FROM
DREAMLAND SHORES?
FIX THESE PEOPLE UP
WITH SOMETHING
REAL NICE, MAYOR.
THE BEST IN
THE HOUSE.
Y'ALL JUST SIGN
THE REGISTER,
PLEASE?
I GUESS I'VE DONE
ALL THAT I CAN.
I'LL GO BACK
TO THE RIVER
AND LOOK FOR...
WHAT YOU WERE
TALKING ABOUT.
A PROBLEM,
SHERIFF?
I'LL TELL YOU LATER
WHEN I'VE MORE TIME.
IF I FIND ANYTHING,
I'M GONNA LET YOU KNOW.
[Dan]
YOU'LL FIND
SOMETHING.
YOU KNOW,
I THINK YOU'RE RIGHT.
IS THERE ANY PLACE
AROUND HERE
I CAN RENT A CAR?
A COUPLE OF BLOCKS
UP THE STREET.
GOOD, WE'RE GONNA
WANT TO GET HOME.
WHY DON'T YOU GUYS
GET SOME REST
FOR A WHILE?
I'LL SLEEP
TO THAT.
ALL I NEED IS
A HOT BATH.
IF YOU FELLOWS
HAVE ANY PROBLEMS,
JUST TELL THEM
TO CALL ME.
YEAH,
WE'LL DO THAT.
THANKS.
FINISH YOUR
PHONE CALL?
NO, ALL THE LINES
ARE DOWN BECAUSE
OF THE STORM.
THAT'S ODD,
THE MAYOR WAS TALKING
LONG-DISTANCE.
HOW DO YOU SUPPOSE
THEY GOT HIS
CALL THROUGH?
[High-pitched noise]
DRIVER'S LICENSE?
YES, WE NEED IT
TO VERIFY THAT YOU'RE
A QUALIFIED DRIVER.
I LOST IT.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
I DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING.
LOOK, MS., THE MAYOR SAID
IF WE HAD ANY TROUBLE,
YOU COULD CALL HIM.
I WILL NEED A NAME,
YOU DIDN'T LOSE
THAT, DID YOU?
JOSEPH MORRISON.
AND YOUR
LOCAL ADDRESS,
MR. MORRISON?
WE DON'T HAVE
A LOCAL ADDRESS,
JUST THE MOTEL
WHERE WE'RE STAYING.
I SEE.
LOOK HONEY, WILL YOU
JUST CALL THE MAYOR
AND GET US A CAR?
WELL, I'M SUPPOSED TO
FOLLOW THE RULES.
COULDN'T YOU BEND
THE RULES A LITTLE BIT?
MAYBE I CAN PROCESS
THE APPLICATION
A DIFFERENT WAY.
RIGHT.
CAN YOU COME
BACK LATER?
[Joe]
HOW MUCH LATER?
TOMORROW.
TOMORROW?
IT'S THE BEST
I CAN DO.
THAT'S THE ONLY CAR
RENTAL AGENCY IN TOWN.
THAT SON OF A BITCH
LIED TO US.
SAID THEY WERE
GOING DOWNRIVER AND
LOOK FOR THE ANTS.
[Engine starting]
[Dan]
LET'S GO.
CAREFUL.
DIDN'T SEE US.
I HOPE THAT'S THE LAST
WE SEE OF THAT PLACE.
WHAT ARE YOU
LOOKING FOR?
I'M LOOKING
FOR A GUN.
NOT THAT WE'D
BE THAT LUCKY.
THIS HIPPIE LIFE
AND MAPS OF FLORIDA
AND SOME
ROAD FLARES.
WELL, AT LEAST WE'RE SET
IF THE CAR BREAKS DOWN.
OH, SHIT.
GOD.
GET DOWN,
EVERYBODY.
[Sirens wailing]
[Screaming]
GET THEM!
DON'T LET THEM
GET AWAY!
[Screaming]
HEY, DON'T SHOOT.
WE'RE PEACEFUL,
HONEST TO GOD.
ALL RIGHT?
GO ON.
ALL RIGHT.
CAN'T YOU GUYS
TAKE A JOKE?
TAKE IT EASY.
RUN!
DAN!
GO! RUN!
NO, DON'T FIRE!
WE HAVE ENOUGH
HERE TO BEGIN WITH.
PICK HIM UP.
[Joe]
WE HAVE A CHANCE IF
WE CAN GET TO THE RIVER
AND FIND A BOAT
AND GET HELP
FOR THE OTHERS.
JUST KEEP MOVING.
[Wheezing]
THERE'S ENOUGH SUGAR
THERE TO FEED AN ARMY
AND THEY TURN OUT
THAT MUCH EVERY DAY.
KEEP MOVING!
OW!
[Whistle blowing]
[Screaming]
AHH!
PLEASE, THERE'S NOTHING
TO FEAR, NOTHING.
COME ALONG.
NOTHING TO FEAR.
PLEASE, COME ON.
[Screeching]
ISN'T SHE BEAUTIFUL?
SHE'S FANTASTIC.
SHE NEEDS US.
THAT'S WHY IT HAS
TO BE THIS WAY,
WHY WE MUST OBEY.
WE HAVE NO CHOICE.
SHE MAKES US DO IT.
AT FIRST, UH,
PEOPLE DON'T
UNDERSTAND.
THEY MUST BE
FORCED INTO
SUBMISSION.
AFTER THEIR INDOCTRINATION,
THEY REALIZE THAT THE ANTS
ONLY WANT US TO TAKE CARE
OF THEM AND TO FEED THEM.
EVERY WEEK, THE PEOPLE
MUST BE BROUGHT
BACK HERE TO BE
INDOCTRINATED AGAIN.
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE
THAT CAN DO IT.
SHE'S THE QUEEN ANT.
YOU SEE HOW
EASY IT IS.
ONCE YOU FEEL HER ENERGY,
THEN YOU'LL UNDERSTAND
THAT WE CAN ALL
WORK TOGETHER.
WE CAN ALL DO WHAT
THE ANTS WANT US TO.
WORK FOR THEM,
FEED THEM.
THAT'S THE WAY
IT SHOULD BE, FOR
THEY ARE SUPERIOR.
SINCE YOU ARE
OUR GUESTS,
WON'T YOU TAKE
THE FRONT OF THE
LINE, PLEASE?
NO!
[High-pitched noise]
[Screaming]
KEEP YOUR HANDS OFF ME,
YOU SON OF A BITCH!
[Screeching]
JOE!
PUT THEM HERE
WITH THE OTHERS.
STOP IT!
QUIET DOWN!
NO! NO! PLEASE!
NO, LET ME GO!
PLEASE!
LET ME OUT OF HERE.
DON'T YOU SEE?
WE MUSTN'T
DISOBEY THEM.
WE MUST TAKE CARE OF THEM
AND WE MUST HELP THEM.
KEEP THE LINE MOVING.
[Screeching]
GET HIM OUT OF THERE!
YOU CAN'T!
TAKE THE WOMEN
DOWN TO THE RIVER!
GO ON!
GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE!
[Ants screeching]
[Screeching]
[Screaming]
UH.
[Sighs]
JOE!
OH, GOD! JOE!
WHERE IS HE?
NO!
GET IN THE BOAT.
GET HER
IN THE BOAT!
JOE!
DAN!