(WHITE NOISE, LOW)
(WHITE NOISE GROWING LOUDER)
(WHITE NOISE ROARING)
(ROARING CONTINUES)
(WHITE NOISE CONTINUES, LOW)
(MACHINERY CLANKING:
RHYTHMIC, MUFFLED)
(CLANKING CONTINUES)
(LEVER CLICKS, CLANKING)
(METAL GROANING)
(GEARS RATCHETING)
(HIGH-PITCHED HUMMING)
(HISSING)
(HISSING GROWS LOUDER)
(HISSING FADES)
(TRAFFIC ROAR, MUFFLED)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
♪♪ (RECORDING: ORCHESTRA, FAINT)
♪♪ (FADES)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(METAL SCRAPES)
- (MACHINERY HUMMING)
- (METALLIC CLANKING)
- (AIR WHOOSHING)
- (MACHINERY POUNDS)
(METALLIC CLANKING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(BUZZER BUZZES)
(MOTOR ENGAGES, WHIRRING)
(ELECTRICITY SPARKING)
(ELEVATOR DOORS RUMBLE SHUT)
(KEY TURNS IN LOCK)
Are you Henry?
Yes.
A girl named Mary called
on the pay phone.
Said she's at her parents'
and you're invited to dinner.
Oh, yeah?
Thank you very much.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(LOW HISSING)
(MECHANICAL CLANKING IN DISTANCE)
♪♪ (PIPE ORGAN: "LENOX AVENUE BLUES")
(RADIATOR HISSING)
(HISSING CONTINUES)
♪♪ (CONTINUES)
(HISSING)
- ♪♪ (STOPS)
- (HISSING GROWS LOUDER)
(HISSING CONTINUES, LOUD)
(MACHINERY POUNDS, MUFFLED)
(HISSING GROWS QUIETER)
(MACHINERY POUNDS, LOUD)
(PHONOGRAPH: NEEDLE RIDING IN GROOVE)
(PAPER RUSTLES)
(MACHINERY CLANKING, RUMBLING)
(DOG BARKING)
- (GLASS SHATTERS)
- (DOGS BARKING)
(STEAM WHOOSHING)
(WHOOSHING)
You're late, Henry.
I didn't know if you
wanted me to come or not.
Where have you been?
You never come around anymore.
Dinner's almost ready.
Come on in.
(SQUEALING, MUFFLED)
Hello there.
Hello.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Sit down.
(SQUEALING CONTINUES)
(PUPPIES SQUEALING, SUCKLING)
It's Henry, isn't it?
Yes.
Mary tells me you're
a very nice fellow.
What do you do?
Oh, I'm on vacation now.
What did you do?
- (MARY WHIMPERING)
- Oh, I'm sorry.
(WHIMPERING, GAGGING)
Well, I-I work at Lapelle's factory.
I'm...
I'm a printer.
Hen-Henry's very clever at printing.
Yes, he sounds very clever.
(DOOR HINGE SQUEAKING)
I thought I heard a stranger.
We've got chicken tonight. Strangest
damn things. They're man-made.
Little damn things... smaller
than my fist. They're new!
I'm Bill.
Hello. I'm Henry.
Henry's at Lapelle's factory.
Oh, printing's your business, huh?
Plumbing's mine. Thirty years.
I've seen this neighborhood change
from pastures to the hellhole it is now.
- (TRAIN RUMBLING, APPROACHING)
- I put every damn pipe in this neighborhood.
- Dad!
- Bill!
- (RUMBLING GROWS LOUDER)
- People think pipes grow in their home.
Well, they sure as hell don't.
Look at my knees!
(DOG BARKING)
- Look at my knees!
- Bill, please.
- Are you hungry?
- Bill.
- (RUMBLING RECEDES)
- (BARKING CONTINUES)
(SQUEALING, SUCKLING CONTINUE)
- (CHIRPING)
- (DOOR SQUEAKING)
The-The girls have heard this
before but 14 years ago...
I had an operation on my arm here.
Doctors said I wouldn't
be able to use it.
"Well, what the hell
do they know?" I said.
And I rubbed it for a
half hour every day...
and I got so as I
could move it a little.
And then I got so as
I could turn a faucet.
And pretty soon,
I had my arm back again.
Now I can't feel a damn
thing in it. All numb.
I-I... I-I'm afraid
to cut it, you know?
Mary usually does the carving, but...
maybe tonight you'll do it, Henry.
All right with you?
Of course.
I'd be happy to.
Do I just, uh...
just cut them up like
regular chickens?
Sure, just cut 'em up
like regular chickens.
(SQUISHING)
(GROANING)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
(GROANING LOUDER)
(SOBBING)
She'll be all right in a minute.
- (SOBBING CONTINUES)
- Excuse me.
(STEAM HISSING IN PIPES)
(HENRY SIGHS)
Well, Henry, what do you know?
Oh, uh...
I don't know much of anything.
(HINGE SQUEAKS)
Henry, may I speak to you a minute?
Over here.
(HINGE SQUEAKS)
(CRYING)
(SNIFFLES)
(ELECTRICITY SPARKING)
Did you and Mary have
sexual intercourse?
Uh...
- Why?
- Did you?
- Why are you asking me this question?
- I have a very good reason.
And now I want you to tell me.
Oh, I-I'm very...
I love Mary.
Henry, I asked you if you and
Mary had sexual intercourse.
Well, I don't... I don't think
that's any of your business.
Henry!
I'm sorry.
You're in very bad trouble
if you won't cooperate.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Well, uh, I...
Mary!
(CRYING) Mother!
Answer me!
I'm too nervous.
There's a baby. It's at the hospital.
Mom!
- And you're the father.
- But that's impossible. It's only been...
Mother, they're still
not sure it is a baby.
It's premature, but there's a baby.
After the two of you are married,
which should be very soon
you can pick the baby up.
(MURMURS)
- (CRYING, WHIMPERING)
- Oh.
Ahh.
- Mom, he's got a nosebleed.
- (HENRY GROANS)
Oh.
(SOBBING)
I'll get ice.
(SNIFFLES)
You don't mind, do you, Henry?
I-I mean about getting married.
(SOBS)
Oh, no.
(CRYING)
(WHIMPERING)
(SNIFFLING)
This dinner's getting mighty cold.
(HINGE SQUEAKING)
(OBJECTS RATTLING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
- (TRAIN RUMBLING IN DISTANCE)
- (DOG WHINING)
- (TRAIN RUMBLING, APPROACHING)
- (WHINING CONTINUES)
(RUMBLING GROWS LOUDER, RECEDES)
- (PHONOGRAPH: NEEDLE RIDING IN GROOVE)
- (BABY FUSSING)
(SPITS)
(MACHINERY POUNDING, MUFFLED)
(FUSSING, GURGLING)
♪♪ ("LENOX AVENUE BLUES")
(FUSSING)
(GAGGING, SPITTING)
(BUZZER BUZZES)
- ♪♪ (CONTINUES)
- (FUSSING, SPITTING)
(COOING)
(FUSSING)
(CRYING)
(MOTOR WHIRRING, STOPS)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
- ♪♪ (CONTINUES)
- (COOING)
(ELEVATOR DOORS RUMBLE)
(NEEDLE RIDING IN GROOVE)
(BABY FUSSING)
(BABY SPITTING)
(FUSSING CONTINUES)
(CLANKING)
(BABY GRUNTING)
(STEAM HISSING)
(HISSING CONTINUES)
(STEAM HISSING IN PIPES)
(HISSING, LOUD)
(HISSING CONTINUES)
(HISSING FADES)
(BABY CRYING)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Was there any mail?
No.
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
- (WIND BLOWING)
- (BABY CRYING)
(CRYING)
- (WIND HOWLING)
- (RAIN FALLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(ELECTRONIC HUMMING)
(HUMMING GROWS LOUDER)
(HUMMING FADES)
(WHIMPERING)
(BABY WHIMPERING, CRYING)
- (THUNDERCLAP)
- (BABY CRYING)
(LOUD CREAKING)
(CRYING)
- (WIND HOWLING)
- (WINDOW RATTLING)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
(CRYING)
- Shut up!
- (CRYING CONTINUES)
Shut up!
(CRYING STOPS)
(CRYING RESUMES)
(CRYING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
I can't stand it! I'm going home!
What are you talking about?
I can't even sleep.
I'm losing my mind.
You're on vacation now.
You can take care of it for a night.
Well, you'll come back tomorrow?
All I need is a decent night's sleep!
Why don't you just stay home?
I'll do what I want to do.
And you better take real good
care of things while I'm gone!
(BED FRAME SQUEAKING)
(SQUEAKING CONTINUES)
(SNIFFLING, CRYING)
- (OBJECT CLATTERS)
- (SOBBING)
(BABY CRYING)
(RAIN CONTINUES FALLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(DRAWER CLATTERING)
(GASPING)
Oh, you are sick.
(GASPING CONTINUES)
- (WIND BLOWING)
- (WINDOW RATTLING)
(LABORED BREATHING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(ELECTRONIC HUMMING)
(HUMMING FADES)
(CRYING)
(WHIMPERING)
(BABY GASPING)
(CRYING)
(GASPING)
(BUBBLING)
(LABORED BREATHING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(RADIATOR HISSING)
(HISSING CONTINUES)
(STEAM HISSING IN PIPES)
(METAL CREAKING)
♪♪ (PIPE ORGAN: "STOMPIN' THE BUG")
♪♪ (PIPE ORGAN CONTINUES)
♪♪ (STOPS)
(SQUISHING)
♪♪ (RESUMES)
♪♪ (STOPS)
- (WIND HOWLING)
- ♪♪ (FADES)
(SNORING)
(QUIET GASPING)
(TEETH CLICKING)
Move over.
(SQUISHING)
(LOUD SQUISHING)
Move... Move over.
(HUSHED) Move over!
(SLAPS AGAINST WALL)
(SQUEAKING)
(SQUEAKING CONTINUES)
(QUIET KNOCKING)
(KNOCKING)
I locked myself out of my apartment.
And it's so late.
(QUIET CRYING)
(MUFFLED CRYING)
Where's your wife?
She must've gone back
to her parents' again.
I'm not sure.
(MUFFLED SQUEALING)
Can I spend the night here?
(BABY CRYING)
(CRYING)
(WIND HOWLING)
♪ In heaven ♪
♪ Everything is fine ♪
♪ You've got your good things ♪
♪ And I've got mine ♪
♪ In heaven ♪
♪ Everything is fine ♪
♪ You've got your good things ♪
♪ And you've got mine ♪
♪ In heaven ♪
♪ Everything ♪
♪ Is ♪
♪ Fine ♪♪
(HIGH-PITCHED HUMMING)
(HUMMING)
(SQUEAKING, RATTLING)
(WAILING)
(HIGH-PITCHED WAILING)
(WAILING CONTINUES)
(WAILING STOPS)
(THUDS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(FOOTSTEPS CONTINUE)
(BUZZER BUZZING)
(BUZZING CONTINUES)
Okay, Paul!
Hiya, sonny. What do you got there?
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
Counter, Paul!
(BEEPS)
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
(DRILL WHIRRING)
(BUZZING, CLICKING)
(WHIRRING)
(BELL DINGING)
It's okay.
(WIND HOWLING)
(CLINKING)
(HOWLING WIND CONTINUES)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(BABY WHEEZING, GAGGING)
(WHEEZING, GAGGING)
♪♪ (PIPE ORGAN, FAINT)
(OBJECT THUDS)
♪♪ (PIPE ORGAN, LOUDER)
(WHEEZING, GAGGING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(ELECTRICITY HUMMING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(ELEVATOR DOORS RUMBLE)
(WIND HOWLING, MUFFLED)
(CHOKING, GASPING)
(GASPS)
(CRIES OUT)
(GASPING)
(WHIMPERING)
(ELECTRICITY SPARKING)
(OBJECT THUDS)
(EXPLOSION)
(ELECTRICITY SPARKING)
(WHITE NOISE ROARING)
♪♪ (PIPE ORGAN: "STOMPIN' THE BUG")
♪♪ (ENDS)