[silence]
[heart beat]
[giggling]
[orchestral music ♪]
♪
[roller coaster chain
clicking]
[birds calling]
[screams]
[laughter]
[whistle tooting]
[roller coaster clattering]
[riders screaming]
[squeals]
[giggling]
♪
[screaming]
What?
I don't understand.
[man on the phone]
Jim, listen to me,
don't let your imagination
run wild.
It's transitional period.
So you're firing me
for no real reason then?
[man on the phone]
Well, there's a little more
to it
than that.
What do you mean?
[man] I can't really discuss
it right now.
[scoffs]
Why not?
What else is goin' on Roger?
[Roger on the phone]
Sorry old boy,
I'm just the messenger.
Do give my best to the
family.
Oh, and don't forget
about Soarin'.
My boys just won't stop
talking about it.
They say you actually feel
like you're flying.
Sounds lovely...
Well...
Hey wait Roger, please!
Best of luck.
[phone cuts out]
[van brakes squeaking]
[melancholy instrumental
music ♪]
♪
No don't! Elliot!
Elliot. Get back here!
Elliot!
Come on,
open the door.
Open the door.
[cell phone vibrates]
[sighs]
Jim?
Where are you?
Hey guys!
Sara, wait up!
Oh my god. She doesn't
even listen to me.
Well she's just excited.
It's this place, you know.
Hey now, you're way too nice
to her.
You have to, like,
not be so nice to them.
Not make me look like
the bad person.
What about him?
Elliot, apologize
to your father.
What?
Did you hear that?
I don't know
what's into him.
He's acting
a little strange today.
He's just a little different,
that's all.
Um, who were you talking to
on the balcony?
What?
Yeah, who were you
talking to?
Nobody, I wasn't talking
to anybody.
So, you're lips were moving?
What are you,
a lip reader now?
Yes I am.
I was just talking to no- Em- I-
- I wanna believe you.
But it was a little weird.
Tell me what's going on.
Honey, it was no one.
Look, I wanna have one final
decent last day here, okay?
That's all I ask, alright?
Okay.
Alright. It's our last day.
Let's go guys.
- Get in honey.
Nice.
Look, the train's about ready
to come.
Look, it's gonna be coming
down those tracks down there.
Can you see it?
- Yeah!
[sneezes]
[coughs]
[announcement] Please
stand clear of the doors.
[announcement in Spanish]
Come on guys.
Here we go.
Everybody in.
Let me sit over here
in the corner.
Okay guys.
[grunts]
Elliot, sit down.
Sit down, Elliot.
Elliot, sit down!
- Sit down honey.
Please sit down, Elliot.
at Disney's Polynesian
Resort.
[giggling]
[singing in French]
[speaking French]
[announcement] Please
hold on to the handrails
and stand clear of the doors
until the monorail
stops completely
and the doors open.
[chatter in French]
Oh, the humidity, my gosh!
Can we go on Buzz
Lightyear?
Ask your father.
Can we Dad?
We'll see, honey.
Depends how long
the line is.
Okay.
[singing in French]
[orchestral music ♪]
♪
Okay, we need to get a
picture
with the castle.
The whole family.
[giggles]
Picture of the castle.
Let's do it.
That will work!
Say Mickey!
[all] Mickey!
And Minnie!
[all] Minnie!
There you go!
Oh, that's beautiful, wow.
That's so cute.
They do have everything.
You wanna go on the,
uh, thing?
Are you scared, sweetie?
I don't like the witch.
Nobody does...
nobody does.
She's afraid.
- No I'm not!
Uh huh.
It's not scary.
I've been on it before.
See, it's different.
They make this
for little tiny kids.
It's not scary. You can hold
daddy's hand really tight.
Honey the line, the line.
- Okay, okay.
[speaking French]
[eerie music ♪]
♪
[door creaks]
Oh no, here she comes.
There she is,
the wicked witch!
[wailing]
She's just pretend, right?
That's right.
Witches aren't real.
No.
[door creaks]
And they lived happily
ever after. Yay!
[whimsical music ♪]
[maniacal laughter]
♪
This is so cute!
[00:09:W:28]
Look at flying Pooh.
- Hey baby, come on.
No, honey, not now, the kids!
- What are you worried
about?
The kids! Not now!
- Come on.
What?
[maniacal laughter]
What!?
No one's around.
Come on.
Not in front of the kids.
Tigger!
No, keep your hands-
honey-
Not here. No.
Not in front of the kids.
No. Stop.
[party sounds]
Come on.
- Jim.
You're such a downer.
You're such a Debbie
Downer.
- No.
[whimsical music ♪]
♪ La la la la lala
lala la ♪
♪ lala lala la
lala la la la la la ♪
♪
[sting]
Sit down Jim.
- Sorry... it's just...
♪ lala la la la la la
lala la la la la la ♪
[growl]
♪
[hiss]
[whimsical music
becomes slow and taunting]
[laughter and hissing]
[moans]
[gurgling]
[hissing]
[moaning]
[echoing] I hate you.
What?
What did she say?
Hate's a bad word.
No, Mommy didn't mean it,
honey.
♪
[growl]
Something's wrong with
Elliot.
Oh, you're not his father.
[laughter]
♪ lala lala la la
la la la ♪
la la ♪
♪
[snorts]
That was fun.
Hey, honey?
Did that...
seem normal to you?
Now can we go on
Buzz Lightyear?
I don't like that ride.
Guys.
- I wanna go on the teacups.
Jim...
What?
Wanna take her?
Yeah...
Uh, no, no actually
you take her
and I'll take him
on Buzz Lightyear.
Yes!
- Alright!
We'll meet you back at the
carousel in an hour.
Okay.
- Have fun!
Okay. Alright.
- Muah muah muah, love
you!
[announcer] Get your astro-
blasters ready, space cadets!
[screaming]
[giggling]
Wooh!
[squeals]
[giggling and funny music]
Wooh!
You know honey,
this might be a while.
Yep.
You sure you don't want to
get a fast pass,
we'll come back later?
That's okay.
We could ride something
else.
Uh-uh.
You really like this ride,
huh?
[fanfare ♪]
♪
[yelling and laughter]
Let's wave to our fans!
Hello!
Hello! Hello!
[laughter]
[chatter and footsteps]
Let's see how long the line is.
[grunts]
You see how long it is?
Whoa, yep.
It's gonna take forever.
Oh man.
[calliope music ♪]
Alright! Wooh!
Giddyup.
[giggling]
[baby wailing]
No we're still in line.
I don't know,
it's not really movin' you?
We're gonna get
something to eat,
because this one looks like
she's about ready to fade.
Okay?
- Alright.
I'll call you if we ever get
out
of here. Alright?
Alright.
[baby screaming]
Bam bam bam bam bam.
I sliced him apart.
[announcement]
Sorry space rangers,
this ride is no longer
in service.
Please proceed to the
nearest exit and have a great
day.
Oh my-- you gotta be
fucking kidding me.
I'm sorry little man.
Looks like someone does not
want us to go on this one.
What happened?
I don't know.
[melancholy music ♪]
♪
You hungry?
- No.
Hey, you wanna
go on Pirates?
No.
Dad?
Yeah...
[speaking French]
[giggling]
[chatter in French]
[go cart engines humming]
[violin music ♪]
♪
[laughter]
[speaking French]
This is fun.
Uh-huh.
Don't slow down
no matter what.
[speaking French
and laughing]
Let's step on the gas!
[laughter and screaming]
[speaking French]
'Moi' is 'me' right?
Oh my- you like a big nose?
[speaking French]
Oh my! Ooh-la-la! Wow.
- Oh-la-la!
[bump]
You alright?
[chatter and giggling]
[squealing]
[giggling]
They like it.
[laughter]
[voices chattering]
[jungle drums and chanting]
[horn music ♪]
Aah!
[giggling]
[whispering and laughing]
[light music ♪]
♪
Come on.
Yes.
- Okay, right here.
[speaking French]
[roller coaster rattling]
[recorded announcement
droning]
Dad?
- Yeah?
Why are we following
those girls?
Girls, what girls?
Bonjour!
Those girls!
Oh... well, um...
I guess they just like
the same rides as we do.
Oh. Dad?
- Yeah?
They're pretty, huh?
Well, yeah, pretty? It
depends on your definition of
pretty.
Do you think they're pretty?
I guess.
Well then, there you go.
That's your definition.
Is Mommy pretty?
You're mother?
Yeah, she's beautiful.
I think so too.
- Yeah.
I mean not in a classical...
sense.
But more in a... Emily
Dickinson.... kind of...
bookish... Tina Fey
kind of thing.
Yeah, but she's beautiful,
yeah.
[children singing ♪]
♪
Hey, hon. We're over here
by the castle.
Just wondering where you
are.
Call me when you get this,
okay?
Where's Daddy?
I don't know!
Let's go find him, okay?
What?
Space Mountain?
What's the matter?
That's a big kids' ride.
You're a big kid, aren't you?
What? Hey...
do you remember when you
were afraid of the teacups?
Same thing.
[cell phone rings]
Hey.
[accordion music ♪]
♪
[vomiting]
Come on. Let's go.
Look!
Elliot?
Oh there's Mommy.
There she is.
What's wrong baby?
What's wrong?
Jim, we've been waiting for
you forever an hour.
I am so sorry, Em--
- Why didn't you answer
your phone?
I'm sorry Em.
Is this vomit?
I threw up.
Oh, sweetie...
What happened?
Dad made me go
on Space Mountain.
I didn't make him go.
You took him
on Space Mountain?!
What's wrong with you?
Did you black out again?
He could barely handle
the tea cups!
You didn't think
Space Mountain
would freak him out?
Thanks. Thanks so much.
Did she eat?
No, she did not.
Well why not?
- I don't know.
Why don't you ask her?
Why didn't you eat, baby?
Come on, let's go.
Wait, wait, Em, what?
You wanna go lie down
with Mommy?
Yeah.
- No, wait!
I don't wanna go, I wanna
stay here with you.
Fine, fine.
Alright fine. I'll stay here
with her.
Okay, fine.
Wait wait wait, Em.... Em.
What?
Alright. Feel better, little
man.
Come on Elliot, let's go.
We're gonna go lie down.
Feel better, honey!
I'll see you back at the
hotel.
You're not hungry?
- No.
At all?
[children singing ♪]
Oh I'm gettin' the train,
honey.
[fake gunshots]
Alright ready?
Here we go.
Bleagh.
[fake gunshot]
That's not funny, is it?
[grunts]
There we go.
C'mon, let's go.
Fun, huh?
Wow, look at this!
Look at this.
[bell rings]
[laughter and chatter
in French]
Hey, hey, come here.
Come on.
I've seen enough of this
tree house. Let's get down.
Do some other fun stuff.
Excuse me.
Wooh. [laughs]
Wow. Here we are
on a new island.
[bell rings]
Come on!
I'm coming, I'm coming.
- I'm coming.
Come on. Here it comes.
Keep goin'!
[bell ringing]
Whoa, Jesus Christ.
I'll be right there, sweetie.
Where are awe going?
Whoa, are we serious?
Can we go down there?
Alright.
This is cool!
Ouch.
I think I'm too fat for this
cave, honey.
I smashed my head.
Sweetie wait, Sara.
Not do fast, not so fast.
Sara?
Honey?
Honey.
Honey, where did you go?
Honey?
Okay, Sara, it's not funny.
Ooh!
- Ugh!
[whimpering]
[children whining]
Sara?
[bell ringing]
It hurts.
Sara!
Sara. Is that your name?
There you are.
He pushed me.
[laughs]
See, they kind of...
bumped into each other.
Tell your kid to watch where
he's going next time.
Come on, honey, let's go.
Are you having lots
and lots of fun?
Uh-huh. I went on Snow White
and wasn't afraid of the witch
'cause... she was just
pretend.
Wow. You're a big girl, huh?
Uh-huh.
There you go.
Good as new.
How's she coin' otherwise?
Good.
No coughing or flu-like
symptoms?
No.
And you?
Me?
I take vitamin C.
Everyone's so worried
about cat flu, now.
Children are most at risk so
we have to be extra careful.
Mommies and daddies, too.
You could be a host
and not even know it.
Lolly?
How 'bout one for Dad?
Um... sure, thanks.
Okay, better get goin'.
Come on, sweetie.
Thanks again.
- Mm-hmm.
Be careful out there.
[crying]
This one's a little hotter,
it's about 2,350.
That's gonna be our base,
I'll show you how fast
this goes.
[chatter]
You think that's good?
Turkey leg?
That's gonna be eight dollars.
- Thank you.
[giggling]
Come back! Stop!
That's not turkey, you know.
Hmm?
What you're eating.
It's not turkey.
No?
Well if it's not turkey,
then what is it?
You really wanna know?
Well...
Now you have to tell me.
Emu.
What?
Emu?
It's a bird.
Well, uh... why don't they just
call it that?
Well, would you really buy it
if they did?
No, I guess not.
Which one's yours?
Oh... over there.
She's beautiful.
Thanks.
No, I mean, she's lovely.
A real princess.
Looks like they're
friends already.
Hmm?
Oh, the boy, he's mine.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Hmm.
- Oh!
I have a little--
- Here.
Thanks.
[squeals]
It's humid today.
I don't really mind it,
though.
[coughs]
Oh, thank you.
You okay?
- Yeah.
Has she met all the
princesses yet?
She has indeed.
[laughs]
Don't you think it's strange?
The princesses?
Pretending to be someone
else, hugging all these kids.
Um... yeah, I guess.
I wonder what age we stop
wanting todo that.
Hug a perfect stranger.
I suppose they aren't really
strangers now, are they?
Everything alright?
What?
Oh, I'm sorry, I...
Oh, your necklace... you're
necklace.
I meant your necklace, sorry.
[laughs]
You like it?
Yeah, it's uh...
It's um...
It's what?
I dunno, there's just....
something about it though...
It's an heirloom
from another time.
Yeah... wow...
Ow.
[moaning]
Fuck me. Feel my vagina.
What the-- wait a minute...
- [moans]
I think you found my hidden
Mickey! Hysterectomy.
Huh?
Sorry, I--
Oh god, here it comes again!
- Oh!
Help!
- Shhh!
You'll wake the kids!
Sara?
Oh here, let me help you.
Oh, you like that, don't you?
Oh!
- [gasps]
[moaning and squealing]
Ooooh! You're incredible!
[giggles]
Can you believe it?
They call this the
presidential suite.
What a joke.
[gasps]
Ooooh.
You're welcome to stay
a while.
My husband won't be back
'til later.
No, I think I better get
going...
Fuck.
You know the princesses?
They're high-priced courtesans.
What?
Rich Asian businessmen
now pay thousands
for one in costume.
You don't believe me?
You're right.
I'm joking.
Well, uh...
It was, um...
It was nice meeting you.
- Yeah.
A real blast, wasn't it?
[music on television ♪]
Come on baby, let's go.
Em?
- Where's Mommy?
I don't know.
[children giggling]
Marco!
- Polo!
[screams]
Marco!
You gotta say Polo!
Hey, you wanna swim over
and surprise 'em?
Okay.
Marco!
- Polo!
[laughter]
Marco!
Hi Mommy!
Oh! My goodness, Sara,
is that you?
Uh-huh!
Elliot, look who it is!
Where's Daddy?
Over there!
Oh! I see!
Did you have a good time?
- Yeah!
Oh, good.
[laughter]
Good.
Hey guys!
Daddy!
- Hi.
Hey.
- How'd you find us?
Oh, it was Sara, actually.
She noticed your suits
were gone.
Oh! So smart!
Yeah, it's crazy here today.
I know, tell me about it.
This place is a mad house!
Yeah, someone's looking
like they're better.
Feeling better, huh?
Yeah! We had a nap,
watched a movie.
How was the park?
It was uh... It was good.
That's it? Just good?
Yeah.
Oh I got you something.
Hold on.
Is this the, uh...
Yeah, it's the one you wanted.
Oh...
Dumbo, Jim?
- What's the matter?
You got me Dumbo?
Isn't that the one you
wanted?
Minnie Mouse, Jim.
I said I wanted-
You know what? Never mind.
Hold it.
- What?
Is she wearing sunscreen?
What's the matter? You
mean from this morning?
No, Jesus, Jim. You have
to reapply the sunblock
before they go swimming.
Sorry... I'm sorry.
Watch Elliot.
What happened to your
knee?
A boy pushed me.
Oh! That's not very nice.
Yeah, he was mean.
- Oh!
How long?
That was super long.
That was super duper long!
[girls singing in French]
[giggling]
[counting in French]
Jim!
What?
You're not even
watching Elliot.
Come on, Em.
Are you crying?
- No.
Ten minutes, then out.
Yeah, if you still wanna go
to
Epcot and see the fireworks.
We gotta change
and get ready.
Why'd you put sunscreen
on her, then?
This is Florida, Jim.
Ten minutes.
[chatter in French]
[whistle blows]
What are you doin'?
I'm fine. What are you doin'?
I was just playin'.
What's going on?
Hey, leave me alone! I'm fine,
I'm fine, I'm fine. I'm alive.
i'm fine.
Just kiddin' around.
Geez.
[piano music ♪]
♪
[birds chirping]
[Sara screaming]
I don't wanna take a bath!
Sara, you come back here!
We've got to wash you up!
Wash the chlorine off you.
C'mon, we're gonna take a
bath and clean you up.
[glass shatters]
Oh shit.
[Sara shouting]
Perfect.
- Splash!
Let's get you clean
sweet pea!
Splash splash!
There you go.
You are so clean now.
This bathroom is gonna be
a mess!
Dry!
Oh wait, there's another
spot right here.
Ah!
Fuck!
Ow, shit.
Let's go find Daddy.
Let's go see what
he's doing. okay?
Does that sound good?
Oh look!
Daddy!
- Hey!
Did you find it?
What?
- The Geosporic!
The Geospor--
Yeah, yeah.
It's right over there I think.
Hold on.
[dramatic classical music ♪]
Wow.
It's a giant testicle.
I don't like Epcot.
I wanna go on
Buzz Lightyear.
- Elliot, look...
If you mention Buzz
Lightyear one more time--
- Jim!
Your father's not feeling
well.
Hey, you don't tell him that.
Well, how about a little
consideration?
I want a balloon.
- She wants a balloon.
Maybe later, sweetie.
[whines]
Okay, fine.
Why don't we all just go back
to the hotel, okay?
Is that what everyone wants?
That sound good?
Hey, hey!
- What?
Over there.
That guy.
That fat guy on the scooter.
His kid pushed down Sara.
What the hell are they
doing here?
I don't know.
They probably just came to
watch the fireworks.
What's the big deal?
- Shit!
Don't swear in front
of the children!
What?
- Why are you acting
so paranoid?
I'm not acting paranoid.
Yes, you are!
You're acting strange!
[accordion music,
whistle blowing]
One!
Two!
Eiffel Tower!
[Sara]
Yay!
Cute!
These are cute!
Okay.
Jim!
Okay, wait!
Hey Sara.
Yabba dabba do.
Come on.
- What?
No, put it back.
Come one.
Look how pretty those are.
They're so big.
Look at the gold one.
I know, that gold one's good.
Look at that one.
That's my favorite one.
[Oom-pah music ♪]
Yeah, thank you!
Thank you, frau!
- No, no.
Don't give him anymore.
Honey.
Enough, enough.
No, no.
Are we gonna fight now?
Eins, zwei, drei!
[audience clapping]
Yeah.
Come on, no!
Jim, Jim, you've had--
No!
- You've had enough!
Just let me have fun!
It's Disney World.
Lighten up!
[burps]
Wunderbar!
Deutschland forever!
Babe, just for the kids.
Just for the kids.
Smile big!
Show me some teeth!
This is for our mantle.
Oh, cool.
Bye!
Did you thank
the princesses?
- Thank you!
Do you wanna take
your picture little boy?
Absolutely.
Hi.
Oh my goodness!
Finally.
Rich Asian businessmen
now pay thousands
for one in costume.
Jim, Jim!
Come on, Jim.
It's time to go.
Jim, come back here.
Lime margarita.
Hey guys!
- It goes over your head.
Hey baby.
- No, not now.
Come on.
- No, no.
What's with your mommy?
- No.
All right, let's go.
Come on.
Mexico!
Meh-hee-co, everybody.
Chop, chop!
- Jim!
[traditional Mexican music ♪]
Sweet!
"Fiesta hoy!"
[distorted laughing]
[scream]
Jim!
Leave me alone.
What's wrong with Daddy?
I don't know, babe.
I don't know.
[throws up]
Oh my gosh.
You guys, look over here.
Look at the city.
Come on, look at Mexico
City.
It's so pretty, all the
lights!
[fireworks exploding]
[throwing up again]
Oh, Jim.
Oh my God.
Look at the fireworks, kids.
Look up at the fireworks.
I'm sorry.
Come on, you guys.
Stay close.
[laugh echoing]
[urinal flushing]
Hey.
Come on, son.
Let's go.
We're not washing hands?
- No.
[air dryer blows]
[motorized scooter revs]
Oh.
What happened?!
Nothing.
Hey!
How is that little darlin'
of yours?
Now, I sure did like her.
Oh!
Oh Lordy!
Jim?
Oh my God!
Elliot, Sara.
Come on, let's go.
Come on, hurry.
Jim, your shirt...it's ripped.
- I know, I know.
Okay, let's go.
Chop, chop.
Come on.
Slow down, Jim.
Excuse us.
- Jim.
Come on, guys.
Comeon.
Slow down.
Jim, slow down!
Wait!
What?!
There's...there's something
going's on here.
Huh?
- It's this place!
What?
I don't understand.
You told Elliot
I look like Emily Dickinson?
I like Emily Dickinson.
- God!
They're a little young, Jim...
...even for you.
Don't you think?
Who?
- Who?!
Who?!
- Yeah, who?
Those Parisian chicks...
or whatever they are!
Okay, just calm down.
- Don't touch me!
People are watching.
Had the sudden urge
to learn French?!
Don't give me that look.
I saw you at the pool.
I'm not a total idiot.
You've probably been
following them
all day, haven't you?
Following who?
Who was on the phone
this morning?
What?!
- Who were you talking to?
I lost my job.
Elliot, Sara!
Come on, we're going.
Emily, wait!
Can I get this?
- No.
No one's getting anything.
Put it back.
Elliot, you too.
Wait, Em.
What about the fireworks?
I've seen enough
for one day.
This vacation's over.
How 'bout just this?
- No.
Elliot, you wanna go on
Spaceship Earth?
Elliot, what's wrong?
- He doesn't trust you.
Not that I blame him.
- That boy has one!
I don't care.
Hey, Sara.
Lemme take Sara.
No, you're drunk.
- No, I'm not.
But I really want it!
- Goddammit Sara!
I said put it back!
No!
God!
Oh my God.
Just...
just take her.
It's okay, honey.
Mommy didn't mean that.
Mommy didn't mean that,
sweetie...it's okay.
Don't cry baby.
It's all right.
Mommy didn't mean that.
It's okay.
She didn't--
She doesn't usually
act like that.
Come on.
[internal dialogue]
Mommy didn't mean to do
that, honey.
She's didn't mean to do that.
She just got angry, okay?
Look at me.
There you go.
[hydraulics whooshing]
[soaring instrumental ♪]
Jim.
Where are you, Jim?
I've been waiting for you.
I have something
to tell you, Jim.
Soon, Jim.
You'll be mine.
You'll be all mine.
[laughing]
[fireworks exploding]
[girls speaking French]
[loud explosion]
[panicked screaming]
Holy crap!
[speaking French]
Come with us.
You speak English?
Please... come.
No.
You won't?
I can't.
Why not?
Well, I'm afraid that if
I come with you...
...something bad
is gonna happen.
But if you don't,
something will.
No, I'm sorry.
You must come.
No, I...
No.
You are sure of this?
Yeah.
Then, I am sorry too.
For what?
[drops hitting face]
[indistinct chatter]
Sara.
Sara?
Sara!
Hey!
Jim White?
Yeah?
What are you doing?
[electricity buzzing]
[beeping]
[automatic doors open
and shutting]
[beeping]
Your father took you here
as a child.
Am I correct?
- Huh?
That must have been right
around the time
this park opened?
Interesting.
Where am I?
Where's Sara?
Consider yourself very
fortunate, Mr. White.
No outsider has ever been
where you are.
That makes you the first.
Yes, and right now you're
under the ride
Spaceship Earth.
What we call Base 21.
I'm still at Epcot?
- But where else?
Oh, I must apologize for
those.
But, you see, I had no idea
what sort of condition you'd
be in.
It's been so long.
Who are you?
[glass clattering]
Consider me a friend.
You work for D[bleep]ny?
No, and fortunately for you,
they are unaware of my
existence.
Unless, of course, the
French take--
Oh, they are
the most dangerous.
You see, I am a servant
of the Siemens Corporation.
What?!
Siemens.
The enterprise which
sponsors this attraction.
[alarm beeping]
Computer, begin the scan.
[screaming]
You've got quite
an imagination!
Just like old W himself.
He died...
...while all this was still
in its early stages.
Epcot's real purpose
remains unfinished.
[voice distorted]
You're inside my head!
Not your head, Jim.
in your imagination.
But we don't want to control
it like they do.
We simply monitor things,
so we can know what they're
up to and keep tabs.
[distorted voice]
Who is that?
That's you.
What?!
Only that's the real you,
in a part of your imagination
you've never sought to use.
Turn it off, please!
Please!
Something's not right.
Didn't your boss relay
the message when
you spoke to him?
My boss?
What are you talking about?
He was instructed to remind
you...
...you were to take the boy.
And Security was to meet
you, after the ride,
at the Land Pavilion.
Do you know how much
depends on this?!
We even had to shut down
the Buzz Lightyear!
Excuse me for a moment.
[doors whooshing]
Geosporic.
[man on monitor]
Oh, yeah, yeah,
it's over there.
[liquid spurting]
[popping sounds]
Jim?
[electricity crackling]
Holy crap!
You're a robot.
[voice distorted]
I was trying to help you...
[alarm blaring]
[grunting and straining]
[cell phone ringing]
Yeah?
- Jim, listen to me.
Don't let your imagination
run wild.
- What did you do with her?!
It's a transitional period.
Just tell me where she is!
I can't really discuss
it right now.
Come on, you son of a bitch!
Sorry old boy.
I'm just a messenger.
Where are you?!
Goddammit you!
Best of luck!
- Wait, no!
[breathing heavily]
[fireworks exploding]
Sorry.
Sara?
[Sara's voice echoing]
Run faster.
Sara, is that you?!
Sweetie, honey,
where are you?
[Sara]
You can't get me.
Sara?
[Sara laughing]
[Sara]
Over here!
Jim!
[Jim yelling incoherently]
Get off my dad!
Someone help!
What's wrong with you Mr?!
You made me...
drop my turkey leg!
It's emu!
- Huh?
Oh Christ.
Sara, thank God.
Huh?
Okay, we're almost ready!
Where is she?
What's going on?
How did you get in here?
Why are you dressed
like that?
- What do you mean?
You took her didn't you?
- Benji, come here!
Sorry, I really have no idea
what you're talking about.
If you even touched her!
Okay, now you're starting
to scare me.
I think you should
leave before...
Before what?
- Before my husband
gets back.
Husband?!
You're not even married,
are you?
- Get out!
What's in the bedroom?
- I'm warning you!
Sara.
Oh, God!
[Sara giggles]
You're okay?
Hi, Daddy.
That was fun!
- Fun?
Un-huh.
Can we do it again?
Again?!
- Sorry, sweetie.
I don't think your dad
would like it too much.
But I'm still thirsty!
Did she give you something?
- Relax, it's just sparkling
apple juice.
It's just pretend.
Are you out of your mind?
You don't just take
someone's kid.
- I always bring them back.
Bring them back?
- Some people don't
even notice.
Jesus Christ.
Wait!
Jim, wait!
Have you even seen
someone decapitated?
What?
- It's not like in the
movies.
That's a pretty dress.
It happens here,
occasionally.
Last time
on Thunder Mountain.
I can't feel my teeth.
People just come here
'cos they wanna feel safe.
They're afraid!
But you can't escape it,
you know.
Bad things
happen everywhere.
Especially here.
You're a witch.
- No!
I'm a princess.
Or at least, I used to be.
Happy day all of you!
I love you!
I'm so happy to be here
with you!
My beautiful princes
and princesses!
Hello, Princess Minnie,
you beautiful angel.
Keep smiling.
Another beautiful princess.
Hello darling.
I used to be one of them
a long time ago.
Back when I was young
and beautiful.
And it was magical.
'til one day I saw
this little girl.
She was so perfect,
like your daughter.
Like Sara?
So I wrapped my arms
around her.
But then something
happened.
When you're a princess,
they teach you to smile.
Be cheery, merry, jovial.
And you can never be sad.
Never ever!
Then something happened.
I couldn't let go.
Help!
I can't breathe!
[neck breaks]
Oh no, princesses must
never cry!
[indistinct]
Hey, what are you doing
to my daughter?!
Let go of her!
- Stop it!
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Let her go!
But you can't be happy all
the time.
It's just not possible.
And you know smiling's not
good...for the wrinkles.
And I hate happy endings.
Hate's a bad word!
[glass shattering]
That's mine!
You're sick, you know that?!
Haven't you ever had a
fantasy, Jim?
Daddy, let's go home.
Thank you for playing with
me, Sara.
You're a very sweet little
girl.
Like a princess?
- Yes, darling... wait!
Your balloon!
You don't want to forget it.
- Look daddy!
Goodbye, Jim!
[announcer on loud speaker]
Welcome you aboard
our highway in the sky.
And hope you've enjoyed
the Magic Kingdom.
We're traveling to Disney's
contemporary resort.
During our travels,
please hold onto
the handrails
and stay clear of the door...
I love you.
You know that?
Uh-huh.
♪ There's a long,
long trail winding ♪
♪ into the land
of my dreams ♪
♪ Where the nightingale
is singing ♪
♪ And the white moon
beams ♪
♪ There's a long,
long night away ♪
♪ until my dreams
all come true ♪
♪ Til the day that I am
walking down ♪
♪ that long, long trail
with you ♪
[grunting]
Aaah!
[breathing heavily]
[groaning]
[toilet flushing]
[heaving]
What?
[coughing]
Everyone's so worried
about cat flu now.
You can be a host
and not even know it.
Cat flu...
[breathing heavily]
Vitamin C...
[grunting]
Ugh.
[door squeaks]
Elliot.
I'm sick.
I need help.
Help.
Elliot.
[ducks quacking]
[melancholy music ♪]
♪
[laughs] You've got
quite an imagination!
Just like old W himself.
He died while all this was
still in its early stages.
Ah. Ah!
How much time?
We're on the floor now.
[crying]
[zapping sounds]
[sobs]
[bell rings]
[intense instrumental music
♪]
♪
[children shouting
and clapping]
Seven... six... five.. four...
three... two.... one!
[cheering]
[crows calling]
[intense music continues ♪]
♪
[engine revs]
Checking in, or...?
That we are.
Allow me to help you
with your luggage.
Thank you.
[children singing ♪]
♪