How do you do?
Mr. Carl Laemmle feels
it would be a little unkind
to present this picture without
just a word of friendly warning.
We are about to unfold
the story of Frankenstein,
a man of science,
who sought to create
a man after his own image
without reckoning upon God.
It is one of
the strangest tales ever told.
It deals with the two great
mysteries of creation,
life and death.
I think it will thrill you.
It may shock you.
It might even horrify you.
So, if any of you feel that you do not care
to subject your nerves to such a strain,
now is your chance to...
Well, we've warned you.
(PRIEST PRAYING IN LATIN)
(BELL TOLLING)
(CRYING)
PRIEST: Amen.
(BELL CONTINUES)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Down! Down, you fool!
(DIRT THUDDING)
Now.
Come on.
Hurry, hurry.
(BELL CONTINUES TOLLING)
(BELL STOPS)
The moon's rising.
We've no time to lose.
(CLATTERING)
Oh, careful!
There we go.
Here he comes!
He's just resting, waiting
for a new life to come.
(WOOD CREAKING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Here we are.
(DOG BARKING)
Look. It's still here.
Climb up and cut the rope.
No!
Go on. It can't hurt you.
Here's the knife.
(BARKING CONTINUES)
(PANTING)
Look out!
Here's the knife.
Here I come.
Is it all right?
The neck's broken.
The brain is useless.
We must find another brain.
That will do,
gentlemen.
(STUDENTS LAUGHING)
And in conclusion,
ladies and gentlemen,
here we have one of the most
perfect specimens of the human brain
that has ever come to my
attention at the university.
And here, the abnormal brain
of the typical criminal.
Observe, ladies and gentlemen, the scarcity
of convolutions on the frontal lobe,
as compared to that of
the normal brain,
and the distinct degeneration
of the middle frontal lobe.
All of these
degenerate characteristics
check amazingly with the case
history of the dead man before us,
whose life was one of brutality,
of violence and murder.
Both of these jars will remain
here for your further inspection.
Thank you, gentlemen.
The class is dismissed.
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(EXCLAIMS FEARFULLY)
(GONG BANGS)
Herr Victor Moritz.
Victor.
I'm so glad
you've come.
What is it, Elizabeth?
Oh, you've heard
from Henry.
Yes. The first word
in four months.
It just came.
Victor, you must help me.
Why, of course
I'll help you.
I'm afraid.
I've read this over and over
again, but they're just words
that I can't understand.
Listen.
"You must have faith in me,
Elizabeth. Wait.
"My work must come first,
even before you.
"At night, the winds howl
in the mountains.
"There is no one here.
"Prying eyes can't peer
into my secret."
What can he mean?
What does he say then?
"I am living in an abandoned,
old watchtower,
"close to the town
of Goldstadt.
"Only my assistant is here to
help me with my experiments."
Oh, his experiments.
Yes, that's what
frightens me.
The very day we announced our
engagement, he told me of his experiments.
He said he was on the verge
of a discovery so terrific
that he doubted
his own sanity.
There was a strange look
in his eyes, some mystery.
His words carried me
right away.
Of course, I've never doubted
him, but still I worry.
I can't help it.
And now this letter.
All this uncertainty
can't go on. I must know.
Victor, have you seen him?
Yes. About three weeks ago.
I met him walking alone
in the woods.
He spoke to me
of his work, too.
I asked him if I might
visit his laboratory.
He just glared at me and said
he would let no one go there.
His manner was very strange.
Oh, what can we do?
Oh, if he should be ill...
Now, don't worry.
I'll go to Dr. Waldman, Henry's
old professor in medical school.
Perhaps he can tell me
more about all this.
Oh, Victor, you're a dear.
You know I'd go to the
ends of the Earth for you.
I shouldn't like that.
I'm far too fond of you.
I wish you were.
Victor.
I'm sorry.
Good night, Victor,
and thank you. Thank you.
Good night.
And don't worry. Promise?
I won't.
Victor?
What is it?
I'm coming with you.
But, Elizabeth,
you can't do that!
I must! I'll be
ready in a minute.
Herr Frankenstein is a
most brilliant young man,
yet so erratic,
he troubles me.
I'm worried about Henry. Why
has he left the university?
He was doing so well, and he
seemed so happy with his work.
Well, you know, his
researches in the field of
chemical galvanism
and electro-biology
were far in advance of our
theories here at the university.
In fact, they had reached
a most advanced stage.
They were
becoming dangerous.
Herr Frankenstein
is greatly changed.
You mean, changed
as a result of his work?
Yes, his work.
His insane ambition
to create life.
How? How?
Please tell us everything,
whatever it is.
The bodies we use in our
dissecting room for lecture purposes
were not perfect enough
for his experiments, he said.
He wished us to supply him
with other bodies,
and we were not to be too particular
as to where and how we got them.
I told him that his
demands were unreasonable,
and so he left the
university to work unhampered.
He found what
he needed elsewhere.
Oh. The bodies of animals.
Well, what are the lives
of a few rabbits and dogs?
You do not quite get
what I mean.
Herr Frankenstein was
interested only in human life.
First to destroy it,
then recreate it.
There you have
his mad dream.
Can we go to him?
You will not be
very welcome.
Oh, what does that matter?
I must see him.
Dr. Waldman, you have
influence with Henry.
Won't you come with us?
I'm sorry, but Herr Frankenstein
is no longer my pupil.
But he respects you.
Won't you help us
to take him away?
Very well, Fräulein.
I've warned you.
But if you wish it,
I will go.
(WIND HOWLING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Fritz!
Hello.
(RATTLING)
Have you finished making
those connections?
Yes, they're done.
Well, come down then and
help with these attachments.
We've lots to do.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
Look out.
(WHIMPERS)
Fool!
If this storm
develops as I hope,
you will have plenty to be
afraid of before the night's over.
Go on.
Fix the electrodes.
(STATIC)
This storm
will be magnificent!
All the electrical
secrets of heaven!
And this time we're ready,
eh, Fritz? Ready.
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
Why, what's the matter?
Look!
Oh.
There's nothing
to fear. Look.
No blood, no decay.
Just a few stitches.
And look,
here's the final touch.
The brain you stole, Fritz. Yes.
Think of it. The brain of a dead man,
waiting to live again in a
body I made with my own hands.
With my own hands.
Let's have one final test.
Throw the switches.
(WHIRRING)
(DRONING)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(CLANKING)
Good.
In 15 minutes, the storm
should be at its height.
Then we'll be ready.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
What's that?
There's someone there.
Quiet.
Send them away.
Nobody must come here.
Here! Cover this.
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
Whoever it is,
don't let them in.
Leave them to me.
Of all times for
anybody to come, now!
Think I'm going to let
these people in? Not much.
I'll show them, messing
about at this time of night.
Got too much to do.
(KNOCKING CONTINUES)
Wait a minute!
All right! All right!
Wait a minute. I'm coming.
It's Dr. Waldman, Fritz.
You can't see him.
Go away.
(KNOCKING)
All right, knock,
but you can't get in.
VICTOR: Henry!
WALDMAN: Frankenstein!
Henry!
Frankenstein!
ELIZABETH: Open the door!
WALDMAN: Let us in!
Who is it? Who is it? What do you
want? You must leave me alone now!
It's Elizabeth.
Open the door!
Henry!
What do you want?
ELIZABETH: Open the door.
WALDMAN: Let us in!
You must leave me alone.
ELIZABETH: Henry, at
least give us shelter!
What's all this nonsense
of locked doors? Henry!
Elizabeth, please.
Won't you go away?
Won't you trust me,
just for tonight?
Oh, you're ill.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I'm quite all right.
Truly, I am.
Oh, can't you see
I mustn't be disturbed?
You'll ruin everything. My
experiment is almost completed.
Wait a moment.
I understand.
I believe in you, but I
cannot leave you tonight.
You've got to leave!
Henry, you're inhuman!
You're crazy!
Crazy, am I?
We'll see whether
I'm crazy or not.
Come on up.
(THUNDER CONTINUES)
Are you quite sure
you want to come in?
Very well.
Forgive me, but I'm forced
to take unusual precautions.
Sit down, please.
Sit down!
You too, Elizabeth.
Please.
A moment ago,
you said I was crazy.
Tomorrow
we'll see about that.
Don't touch that!
I'm sorry, Doctor,
but I insist.
Please.
Dr. Waldman, I learned a great
deal from you at the university
about the violet ray,
the ultraviolet ray,
which you said was the
highest color in the spectrum.
You were wrong.
Here in this machinery,
I have gone beyond that.
I have discovered the great ray that
first brought life into the world.
Oh. And your proof?
Tonight you shall
have your proof.
At first, I experimented
only with dead animals
and then a human heart, which
I kept beating for three weeks.
But now,
I'm going to turn
that ray on that body
and endow it with life.
And you really believe that
you can bring life to the dead?
That body is not dead.
It has never lived.
I created it.
I made it with my own hands from
the bodies I took from graves,
from the gallows, anywhere!
Go and see for yourself.
You, too.
Dead, eh?
Quite a good scene, isn't it?
One man crazy,
three very sane spectators.
(RATTLING)
(THUNDERCLAP)
Is everything ready?
Yes!
Get the batteries.
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(BUZZING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(BUZZING CONTINUES)
(LOUD ELECTRIC BUZZING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
(THUNDER INTENSIFIES)
(BUZZING FADES)
Look. It's moving.
It's alive. It's alive.
It's alive.
It's moving.
Oh, it's alive!
It's alive! It's alive!
It's alive!
Henry,
in the name of God.
In the name of God!
Now I know what
it feels like to be God!
(THUNDER CONTINUES)
Henry is well,
but he's very busy.
He said he would get
in touch with you soon.
Don't worry
about him, Baron.
He'll be home
in a few days.
You two have it all
arranged, haven't you?
You think I'm an idiot,
don't you?
But I'm not.
Anyone can see
with half an eye
that there's
something wrong.
And I have two eyes,
pretty good ones, at that.
Well, what is it?
You're quite
mistaken, Baron.
What's the matter with
my son? What's he doing?
He's completing his
experiments, that's all.
Why does he go messing around
an old, ruined windmill,
when he has a decent
house, a bath,
good food and drink and a darned
pretty girl to come back to?
(SCOFFS)
Will you tell me that?
Oh, Baron,
you don't understand.
I understand
perfectly well.
There's another woman, and
you're afraid to tell me.
Pretty sort of
experiments these must be.
Oh, but you're wrong.
And how do you know?
If you please, Herr
Baron, the Burgomaster.
Well, tell him
to go away.
But he says
it's important.
Nothing the Burgomaster can say
can be of the slightest importance.
Good day,
Herr Baron. Fräulein.
Well, what do you want?
If it's trouble, go away.
I have trouble enough.
Oh, there's
no trouble, sir.
What do you mean, "No trouble"?
There's nothing but trouble.
I brought you
these flowers.
Thank you, Herr Vogel.
Both in my private and official
capacities as Burgomaster...
Yes, yes, yes, yes, we know all
about that, but what do you want?
Well, what I really
want to know is,
when will the wedding be,
if you please?
Unless Henry
comes to his senses,
there'll be
no wedding at all.
But, Herr Baron, the
village is already prepared!
Well, tell them
to unprepare.
Oh, but such
a lovely bride.
Such a fine young man, the
very image of his father.
Heaven forbid.
But, sir,
everything is ready!
I know that. Don't keep
on saying so, you idiot.
There's nothing
to cry about.
Good day, Miss Elizabeth. (COUGHS)
Good day,
Herr Moritz.
Good day, Herr Vogel.
Good day, Herr Baron.
And good riddance
to you.
There you are.
You see how it is.
The whole village
is kept waiting.
The bride is
kept waiting.
And I am kept waiting.
Henry must come home, if
I have to fetch him myself.
No, no, Baron. What
do you mean, "No, no"?
What about his work?
Stuff and nonsense!
What about his wedding?
There is another woman,
and I'm going to find her.
(SIGHS)
Oh, come
and sit down, Doctor.
You must be patient.
Do you expect
perfection at once?
This creature of yours
should be kept under guard!
Mark my words,
he will prove dangerous!
Dangerous?
Poor old Waldman.
Have you never wanted to do
anything that was dangerous?
Where should we be if nobody
tried to find out what lies beyond?
Have you never wanted to look
beyond the clouds and the stars,
or to know what causes
the trees to bud,
and what changes
a darkness into light?
But if you talk like that,
people call you crazy.
Well, if I could discover
just one of these things,
what eternity is, for example,
I wouldn't care if they
did think I was crazy!
You're young, my friend. Your
success has intoxicated you.
Wake up and
look facts in the face.
Here we have a fiend
whose brain...
Whose brain must be
given time to develop.
It's a perfectly
good brain, Doctor.
Well, you ought to know. It
came from your own laboratory.
The brain that was stolen from my
laboratory was a criminal brain.
Oh, well. After all, it's
only a piece of dead tissue.
Only evil can come of it.
Your health will be ruined if
you persist in this madness.
I'm astonishingly
sane, Doctor.
You have created a monster,
and it will destroy you!
Patience, patience.
I believe in this monster,
as you call it,
and if you don't, well,
you must leave me alone.
But think of Elizabeth,
your father.
Elizabeth believes in me.
My father never
believes in anyone.
I've got to
experiment further.
He's only a few days old,
remember.
So far he's been kept
in complete darkness.
Wait till I bring him
into the light.
(SLOW FOOTSTEPS)
Here he comes.
Let's turn out the light.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Come in.
Come in!
Sit down.
Sit down!
You see? It understands.
Watch.
WALDMAN: Take care,
Herr Frankenstein! Take care!
Shut out the light!
Sit down.
Go and sit down.
It understands this time.
It's wonderful.
Frankenstein! Frankenstein!
Where is it? Where is it?
(SCREAMS)
Quiet, you fool!
(MUFFLED SCREAM)
Get away with that torch!
(MUFFLED GROWL)
(SNARLING)
Quick!
Fetch the rope. Quick!
Stop kicking!
Get him to the cellar!
Shoot it!
It's a monster!
(CHAINS RATTLING)
(MONSTER HOWLING)
(GRUNTING)
Quiet. Quiet!
Cooperate!
You'll have the whole
countryside on us!
Come away! He has the
strength of 10 men.
This is madness.
Give me that.
(GROANS)
Oh, come away, Fritz.
Leave it alone.
(GROANING)
(SCREAMING)
Listen. What's that?
Who's there?
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
It's Fritz!
(MONSTER GROWLING)
Come on, Doctor.
Quick. Hurry.
Get back.
(SNARLS)
Quick. Quick!
(SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
(CONTINUES GROWLING)
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
He hated Fritz. Fritz
always tormented him.
Come, come.
Pull yourself together.
What can we do?
Kill it, as you would
any savage animal.
We must overpower him first.
Get me a hypodermic needle.
It's murder.
It's our only chance.
In a few minutes he'll
be through that door.
Come quick. Hurry.
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
(SNARLING)
Got it?
Yes.
Here it is.
It's very strong.
Half-grain solution.
Good. Now, then.
You stand there.
When he goes toward you, I will
make the injection in his back.
Right.
Ready?
Yes.
(DOOR RATTLING)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMING)
Get back. Back!
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
(CONFUSED GRUNTS)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Dr. Waldman?
Dr. Waldman!
Are you hurt?
No, no, I'm all right.
It's nothing.
See who's at the door.
(INCESSANT KNOCKING)
What's happening here?
Elizabeth and your father are
coming up the hill to see you.
You must keep them out.
Too late.
They must not see that.
Here, quick, give me a hand.
Quick.
Down here.
(GRUNTS)
Henry, you better hurry upstairs
and get that blood off your face
before your father
and Elizabeth get here.
All right.
Well, pretty sort of place for
my son to be in, I must say.
Is that the front door?
Yes, this is it.
Why,
I don't like it,
but here goes.
Why, that...
There doesn't seem to be
anybody in the place.
Oh!
(KNOCKING)
God!
(CHUCKLING)
What a forsaken
place here.
You're trying to burn it
down, eh? What's that for, eh?
What's the matter
with you?
You look as though you've
been kicked by a horse.
Where's Henry?
Why...
Well?
He can't be
disturbed just now.
Oh, can't he? (SCOFFS) I'll
soon settle that nonsense.
Victor, where is he?
This place seems to drive
everybody crazy. I...
Good heavens,
what's that?
I beg your pardon.
I am Dr. Waldman.
Oh, are you?
I'm Baron Frankenstein.
Perhaps you know what
all this tommyrot's about.
(COUGHS)
I'll be shot if I do.
I would advise you to take
Henry away from here at once.
What do you suppose
I'm here for, pleasure? Huh?
Where are you, my dear?
Oh, there you are.
Let's go and see
what's up the awful stairs.
I don't know how the deuce
I'm going to get up them.
Just watch me.
Do the trick.
Leave them alone.
No banisters
or anything else.
God bless his soul.
How much further?
HENRY: Come in.
Henry.
Elizabeth.
ELIZABETH: Henry!
Victor, Dr. Waldman,
come quickly!
My dear, what have they
done to you?
Poor, poor, Fritz.
It's all my fault.
Get him on the sofa.
Come on.
Oh. Oh, my boy.
Thank you.
Have you got any brandy?
(MOANING)
I did it. Quick, quick, quick, quick.
Here, I'll do that.
Come on, boy. Now, now,
now, drink. Drink this.
There. There, that's better.
I'm going to take you
home with me, Henry.
No, I can't. My work.
What will happen to the
records of my experiment?
We will preserve them.
And... I will see that it
is painlessly destroyed.
No. Yes, yes. Leave it all to me.
Poor Fritz. All my fault.
There, Henry. You can't do any more now.
You must come home
until you get well again.
You'll soon feel better
when you get out of here.
(GRUNTS)
(CHOKING)
(GROWLS)
It's like heaven,
being with you again.
Heaven wasn't so far away
all the time, you know.
I know,
but I didn't realize it.
My work...
Those horrible
days and nights.
I couldn't think
of anything else.
Henry.
You're not to think of those
things anymore. You promised.
All right.
Let's think about us.
When will our wedding be?
Let's make it soon.
As soon as you like.
(BELLS RINGING)
For three generations,
these orange blossoms have
been worn at our weddings.
Your great-grandfather
wore this, Henry.
Looks as good
as new now, eh?
Thank you.
And here.
Here's one to make the
best man look still better.
Thank you, sir.
Thirty years ago,
I placed this on your
mother's head, Henry.
Today you'll make me very happy
by doing the same for Elizabeth.
And I hope
in 30 years time,
a youngster of yours will
be carrying on the tradition.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
And now, how about a
little drink, eh? Come on.
My grandfather bought
this wine and laid it down.
My grandmother
wouldn't let him drink it.
Oh, bless her heart. Here's
to your very good health.
Well, you all full?
Yes? Come along.
Here's a health to a son
of the house of Frankenstein.
ALL: A son to the house
of Frankenstein.
Here's a jolly good health
to young Frankenstein.
ALL: Young Frankenstein.
Here, Hyde.
Give the servants
some champagne.
This stuff's
wasted on them.
Well, well, well, well.
BARON: Go on, mop it up,
mop it up. It'll do you good.
To the house
of Frankenstein.
ALL: To the house
BARON: Thank you.
Now, then, now be off
about your business.
(PEOPLE WHOOPING)
BARON: Listen.
Listen to them.
The boys and girls
are busy, my dear.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(BAND PLAYING)
It's extraordinary how friendly
you can make a lot of people
on a couple of
bottles of beer.
Tomorrow
they'll all be fighting.
No doubt.
They're calling
for you, Baron.
Eh, oh.
Well, I suppose
I'd better show myself.
WOMAN: Make a little talk.
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN: Quiet!
Thank you all
very much indeed.
I am very pleased
to see you all,
and I hope
there's plenty of beer.
At all events there's lots
more where that came from.
(ALL WHOOPING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
You stay here, Maria. I'll
just take a look at my traps.
Then we'll go to the village
and have a grand time, huh?
You won't be long, Daddy? Oh, no, no.
If Hans comes by, tell
him I'll be back soon? Hmm?
Daddy, won't you stay and
play with me a little while?
I'm too busy, darling. You stay
and play with the kitty, huh?
Bye, Daddy.
Goodbye.
Be a good girl now.
Come on, kitty.
Who are you?
I'm Maria.
Will you play with me?
Would you like
one of my flowers?
Huh.
You have those,
and I'll have these.
I can make a boat.
See how mine floats?
(EXCITED GASPING)
(GRUNTS)
No, you're hurting me! No!
(MARIA GASPING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
WOMAN: They're having a
wonderful time, aren't they?
Henry.
Elizabeth.
Oh, how lovely you look.
But you shouldn't be here.
I must see you
for a minute.
Well, what's the matter?
Could you leave us
for a moment?
Why, of course.
Well, what is it?
Oh, I'm so glad
you're safe.
Safe? Of course I'm safe.
But you look worried.
Is anything wrong?
No.
No, forget my foolishness.
It was just a mood.
There's nothing the matter.
Of course there isn't.
Henry, I'm afraid,
terribly afraid.
Where's Dr. Waldman? Why
is he late for the wedding?
Oh, he's always late.
He'll be here soon.
Something is
going to happen.
I feel it.
I can't get it
out of my mind.
You're just nervous.
All the excitement
and preparation.
No, no, it isn't that.
I felt it all day.
Something is
coming between us.
I know it. I know it!
Sit down and rest.
You look so tired.
If I could just do something
to save us from it.
From what, dear?
From what?
I don't know. If I could
just get it out of my mind.
Oh, I'd die if I had to
lose you now, Henry.
Lose me? Why,
I'll always be with you.
Will you, Henry?
Are you sure?
I love you so.
Sure.
How beautiful you look.
VICTOR: Henry! Henry!
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
What's that? What's that?
Henry! Henry!
Henry! Dr. Waldman! Dr.
Waldman! What about Dr. Waldman?
Henry, don't leave me.
Don't leave me.
No, darling,
you stay here.
Henry. Henry!
Dr. Waldman's been
murdered in the tower.
The monster?
He's been seen in the hills
terrorizing the mountainside.
(LOW GROWL)
He's in the house.
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
He's upstairs!
WOMAN: Oh, God!
(BELLS RINGING)
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(DISTANT GROWL)
It's in the cellars.
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMS)
(MIMICS SCREAM)
(SCREAMING)
(LOUD SCREAMING)
It's Elizabeth. Come on.
Someone open the door!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SCREAMING STOPS)
(GROWLING)
Elizabeth.
WOMAN: Where is it?
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Don't let it come here.
No, no, no, darling.
It's all right.
Don't let it come here.
It's all right, darling.
It's all right.
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
GIRL: Oh, look!
Look, Maria!
(BAND PLAYING)
(MEN WHOOPING)
(BAND STOPS PLAYING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(BELLS CONTINUE TOLLING)
Silence!
Silence. What is it?
What is it?
Maria, she's drowned.
My poor man, why do you
bring her here to me?
But she has been murdered.
(ALL SHOUTING AGGRESSIVELY)
Silence! I'll see that
justice is done!
Who is it?
(ALL SHOUTING)
How is Elizabeth now?
I don't know.
She's still in a daze. Just
looks at me and says nothing.
It's maddening. Easy, old
man. She'll be all right.
Our wedding day.
Steady.
Your wedding will only be
postponed a day at most.
A day? I wonder.
What do you mean?
There can be no wedding while this
horrible creation of mine is still alive.
I made him with these hands, and
with these hands, I'll destroy him.
I must find him.
I'll go with you.
No. You stay here
and look after Elizabeth.
I leave her in your care,
whatever happens.
You understand? In your care.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
Quiet! Quiet!
Quiet!
Ludwig, you will search the
woods. Those are your group.
We'll get him.
Quiet!
Herr Frankenstein, you
will take to the mountains.
Those are your people.
I will lead the third group
by the lake.
Remember, remember,
get him alive if you can,
but get him!
Quiet!
Search every ravine,
every crevice,
but the fiend must be found!
Are you ready?
ALL: Yes!
Then light your
torches and go!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(DOGS BARKING)
(ANGRY SHOUTING)
Stop!
Stop, men.
Frankenstein, mountains.
Ludwig...
Lake party, this way!
MAN: Come on, men!
(ALL SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(DOGS HOWLING)
(DOGS BARKING)
Come on, boys.
Keep together.
Now, you search there.
The rest, come with me.
LUDWIG: Go over there!
Go on.
(GROWLING)
Come on, men!
Come on! Come on!
Herr Frankenstein!
(MOANING)
Come on, men!
Hurry up. This way.
Which way?
Which way did he go?
Hans, which way did he go?
Tell me. Tell me!
Over there.
You stay here
and take care of him.
The rest, follow me.
Come on. Come on, quick!
Come on! Come on!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
No, come back. This way!
Herr Frankenstein!
Where are you?
I think he's up there. Come
on, follow him. Follow him.
Follow him. Quick!
Hello!
There.
Fire. Fire!
(GROWLING)
Help! Help!
Listen!
HENRY: Help!
It's Frankenstein.
That way!
(SNARLS)
This way. Come on.
Hurry. Hurry!
There! Turn
the hounds loose!
(SHOUTING GROWS LOUDER)
Come on! Come on!
Once more.
(GRUNTING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(GROWLING)
(SNARLS)
There he is! The murderer!
(ANGRY SHOUTING)
MAN: Kill him!
(CROWD MURMURING)
Frankenstein?
Bring him down to the village,
and let's take him home.
Burn the mill!
Burn the mill. Burn it.
(SCREAMING)
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Have you got it?
Yeah. Come on. Hurry.
Hurry up.
(WHISPERING)
(GIGGLING)
Quiet, quiet.
Well, go ahead
and knock.
Well, well, well.
What's all this?
What do you want, eh?
What's this?
If you please,
Herr Baron,
we thought that Mr. Henry could do with
a glass of his great-grandmother's wine.
(CHUCKLES) Fine old
lady, my grandmother.
Very foreseeing of her to prevent
my grandfather drinking this.
Mr. Henry
doesn't need this.
Well, as I said before,
I say again.
Here's to a son to the
house of Frankenstein.
ALL: Indeed, sir.
We hope so, sir.