Freddy Krueger:
My children...
From the very beginning...
It was the children
who gave me my power.
The Springwood slasher...
That's what they called me.
[Blades spring out]
[Girl screams]
My reign of terror
was legendary.
Dozens of children
would fall by my blades.
[Laughs]
Then the parents of Springwood
came for me...
Taking justice
into their own hands.
When I was alive, I might
have been a little naughty...
But after they killed me,
I became something much,
much worse--
the stuff nightmares
are made of.
The children
still feared me,
and their fear gave me the power
to invade their dreams.
And that's when the fun
really began!
Aah!
Until they figured out
a way to forget about me!
To erase me completely!
Being dead wasn't a problem.
But being forgotten--
now, that's a bitch!
Aah!
It's only a dream!
Die, motherfucker!
Freddy: I can't come back
if nobody remembers me!
I can't come back...
If nobody's afraid!
I had to search the bowels
of hell...
But I found someone...
Someone
who'll make 'em remember.
He may get the blood,
but I'll get the glory.
And that fear
is my ticket home.
Mike?
Is that you?
All right,
fuck you, then.
I'm heading in.
Mike?
Come on,
it's not funny anymore.
Ohh-aaah-aaah,
aaah!
Aah!
[Whimpering]
[Gasping]
Ohh...Oh...
[Wood creaks]
No!
Jason's mother:
Jason.
I should've been watching
them, not drinking.
Not meeting a boy
at the lake.
I deserve to be punished.
We all deserved
to be punished.
Jason's mother: Jason.
My special, special boy.
Do you know what
your gift is?
No matter what
they do to you,
you cannot die.
You can never die.
You've just been
sleeping, honey.
But now the time
has come to wake up.
Mommy has something
she wants you to do.
I need you to go
to elm street.
The children have been very bad
on elm street.
Rise up, Jason!
Your work isn't finished!
Hear my voice
and live again!
Make them
remember me, Jason.
Make them remember
what fear tastes like.
Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
I've been away from my children
for far too long.
[Freddy cackles]
[Hard rock music playing]
[Thunder]
Marry, fuck, or kill?
Your choices are--
your choices
are the 3 stooges.
Go, Kia.
Oh, God...
Uh, which one had
the super bad toupee hair?
Harry, moe--
no! No, no, no.
It was moe.
Either one,
I'd kill him.
Ok, who'd you fuck then?
This is stupid,
y'all.
Come on. Come on.
Oh, God.
Whatever, look.
I'd fuck the bald guy,
and I'd marry Larry.
Jesus. Is this what
we're doing all night?
'Cause, y'all,
this is really stank.
Hey! Gibb,
what are you doing?
I thought you
were gonna quit?
I only smoke
when I drink now.
But you're
always drinking.
Yeah, well, I'll work
on that next.
Hey, ok.
I got another one.
Fred, Scooby,
or shaggy.
Oh! I'm not
answering that,
and neither is she.
Do you guys think I
should get a nose job?
Oh, my God.
Oh, please, Kia,
what you need
is a lobotomy.
I think I'm gonna
get some candles.
I'm gonna get some beer.
You guys want anything?
Are you sure you
should be driving?
I'm so under
the limit, Lori.
Surprise.
Oh, Trey. You
answered my prayers.
Thank you.
Whoa, babe!
What'd I tell you
about kissing me
after you smoked,
huh?
Lighten up.
They're menthols.
Yeah. I brought Blake.
Where's Linda?
It's Lori.
This is her house,
so don't be
a total cocksmith.
Whatever.
Where are the ladies?
Relax, they'll be here.
I'm relaxed, man.
I'm just wet.
Did you know they
were coming over?
[Softly] Listen,
you gotta be quiet.
Hey, we knew you were be here
all alone this weekend.
[Sighs]
Blake's cute.
[Softly]
He's not my type.
Oh! Who is? No one's
ever gonna live up
to the fuzzy memory
of your first love, Lori.
You were fucking 14,
so get over it.
Yeah, I know
we were young,
but what will and I
had was real.
Well, correct me
if I'm wrong,
but didn't Mr. real
just drop-kick your ass
without so much
as a good-bye handshake?
He ever even call
or maybe even write
to you after he moved?
Send you an e-mail?
No.
You see my point?
It's time to leave
the convent, Lori.
You need to meet a guy.
[Sighs]
Uhh.
[Thunder]
[R&b music playing]
Blake: Hey, Lori,
I, uh, I like the...
Flow of your place.
Got good feng shui.
Yeah.
You know about
feng shui?
Oh, oh!
Oh, you should
see her bedroom!
Hmm?
Great flow in there.
Lori, why don't you
go upstairs
and show Blake
your feng shui.
Shut up!
[Thunder rumbles]
I got a kink
in my neck.
Come on. You can
massage it out for me.
I think I need
a few more drinks
before there'll be
any massaging.
What do you
see in him?
[Whispering] I don't know,
but he has a cute ass.
Babe, don't make me
ask you twice, ok?
So, Lori...
Am I gonna get that
grand tour or what?
Yeah.
You know, why don't you
start in the kitchen,
and get us some beers.
Cool.
Oh, my God, Kia,
he is a total idiot.
Get him out of here.
Oh, Lori, come on,
give him a chance.
I don't like him.
You know what?
You don't like anybody.
I mean, Lori, you've
barely gone out since--
since what?
Since my mom died?
Yeah, well, you know what?
My dad needs me.
So I can't just go out
with guys all the time,
and if I did, it would not be
with somebody like Blake.
[Wind howling]
[Floorboards creaking]
[Gibb breathing heavily]
Trey: Yeah,
fuck me, baby!
Aah!
Your back door
was open.
I closed it.
Mm.
Babe, you know
I don't like
to be touched
after, ok?
Fine. I'll go have
a shower then.
Good.
Your hair smells like
menthols, anyway.
Asshole.
Ahh.
[Shower running]
Ohh!
Aah!
Unh! Aah! Ack!
Trey!
What the hell
are you doing?
Aah!
[All screaming]
Help us!
Oh, my God!
Over here!
Please help us!
Help us!
You kids need
some assistance?
What the fuck
do you think?!
We need to lock this
down now.
Keep it contained,
you hear me?
Killed in bed.
Jesus.
It's even
the same damn house.
1428 elm.
It's gotta be him,
right?
It's gotta be
Freddy Krueger.
Hey! Don't even say
that son of a bitch's
name out loud.
Let's just keep it
together.
We've been
through too much
to let this thing
spread now.
Take all the kids
down to the station.
Keep them separate.
Do it now.
Yes, sir.
We'll be in touch.
Thank you.
Let's go home.
[Huffs]
So?
She doesn't know
anything.
None of them do.
I'm pretty sure
we're good.
Pretty sure? You better
make damn sure
none of those kids
knows anything,
or I'll send your ass up
to westin hills with them.
Knows what? What
do you mean?
Good work there
tonight, Stubbs.
Right place,
right time.
But we'll take it
from here, all right?
Your father's
on his way.
Do they know
who did this?
No, not yet.
But I thought I heard
one of the officers
mention a name.
You know, to tell
you the truth, Lori,
I--I just moved here
about a month ago,
but if they have
a suspect,
I'd be the first
to know.
But they asked me all these
really weird questions,
like about my dreams--
[knock on glass]
What was the name?
Freddy.
[Child sobbing]
Hello?
[Sobbing]
Are you ok?
Ohh!
[Various voices]
His name is Freddy Krueger.
And he loves children,
especially little girls.
Freddy's coming back.
Soon he'll be strong enough.
It's ok to be afraid.
We were all afraid.
Warn your friends.
Warn everyone.
Aah!
Aah! Ohh!
Children:  1, 2,
Freddy's coming for you
3, 4, better
lock the door
5, 6, grab a crucifix
7, 8,
try to stay up late
9, 10, never sleep again
1, 2, Freddy's coming
for you
aah! Ohh!
Ohh.
Blake, we have to talk.
What the hell were you
doing over there?
You were supposed to be
watching your sister.
Were you drinking?
My best friend was
just killed, dad!
So how about
giving me
some fucking space.
You watch yourself, boy.
I'm gonna get him
for you, Trey.
Cop let it slip.
It was somebody
named Freddy.
I'm gonna take him out
myself, Trey.
I swear to God.
[Bushes rustling]
Who is that?
Someone there?
[Baa]
Ohh!
Jesus.
[Baa]
Ha ha ha ha ha!
I'm ok.
I'm all right.
Not strong enough yet.
Well, I will be
soon enough.
Until then...
Heh heh heh!
I'll let Jason
have some fun.
Dad?
Aah! Aah!
Aah!
Hypnocil. What does
this shit do, anyway?
How come we all
have to take it?
It keeps you
nice and docile
while I kick
your little ass.
I'm fine with that.
Announcer on TV:
We interrupt this program
for a special report.
After tonight's murder
in this neighborhood
of Springwood,
the sheriff's department
has confirmed
that there is
one victim...
Hey, turn that
up, man.
Remain sketchy,
but the sheriff--
sorry, will.
You know the rules.
Turn that back on.
I know somebody
that lives
in that house.
Come on, turn it
back on, man!
I never ask
for anything.
Just turn on the
fucking TV, please!
Fuck you, man!
What the fuck is
your problem?!
What are you
doing, man?
You want 10cc's
of that pink
tranquilizer
in your ass?
That was
Lori's house.
They said something
about a murder.
I gotta--
I gotta go to her.
I gotta see
if she's ok.
Back to Springwood?
Do you want me to start
having nightmares again?
Don't start with that
dream demon shit again.
Ok? You know that's all
just in your head.
Yeah, yeah,
and who are you,
the poster boy
for sanity?
You're the one
that told the cops
Lori's dad killed
his wife.
Yeah, right, and now it
looks like someone else
got killed
in the same house.
You think that's
a coincidence?
2 murders
in one house?
Kurt, how many times
do I have to tell you, man?
I don't do checkers.
I'm an uno guy,
all right?
So go grab the
fucking uno deck
and we'll play, ok?
Please. Thank you.
Look at us, will.
Look around you, man.
We're institutionalized.
We're stuck here.
We're not going anywhere.
Mark: I do miss
my family, man.
I mean,
it's been 4 years
since I've seen 'em,
you know.
All these years,
and you're still convinced
you saw her father
do that?
I know
what I saw, mark.
Fuck what
the doctors try
to get me
to believe.
I need to know
if she's ok.
[Howling like monkey]
[Farts]
You want to play?
Uhh.
Sweet dreams,
monkey boy.
What the hell
was that for, man?
Heh heh heh!
You're a fucking
lunatic, you know that?
I know you are,
but what am I?
Are you sure
you didn't see anyone?
No, dad,
none of us did.
I already went over this
with the police.
It's just...
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
You're all
I have left.
Dad, I'm not going
anywhere.
I promise.
Look at you.
You're exhausted.
Freddy: Lori.
We need to
get you to bed!
Ohh! Oh! Um...
I don't want to
go to sleep, dad.
I just want to
see my friends.
I don't think
it's a good idea
for you to go
to school today.
You've
just been through
a very traumatic
experience.
Dad, please...
I just need to get
out of the house, ok?
I'll be fine.
I promise.
Well, at least drink
your juice.
Will rollins
and the Davis boy
escaped from westin
hills last night.
Oh, Jesus.
It's all
coming apart again.
Don't worry.
We'll find them.
Keep this thing
contained.
Kia: Lori!
Oh, my God! God, you guys,
I'm so glad you're here.
Uh, Blake's dead,
too.
What?
Yeah, he--
he was stabbed
to death late last night.
Um, same with his dad.
What?
Shit, shit!
This is bullshit!
The police
are blaming
everything on Blake
like its some kind
of columbine thing
or something.
They're saying
he went crazy.
Killed Trey,
killed his dad,
and then took
his own life?
This is so
fucking messed up.
This is messed up.
[Bell rings]
Excuse me. Sorry.
Uh, Lori?
What is it, Linderman?
Um, well, I heard
what happened,
and I just wanted to
express how, um--
well, to tell you
how sorry I was.
Thank you.
That's sweet.
Right. You know,
actually,
if you need anybody
to talk to or--
whoa, Linderman, let
me give you a tip.
Place your hormones
back in the box
and quit while
you're ahead, ok?
We don't have time
for date-a-dork
right now. Thanks.
Right. Uh, sorry.
I swear, every day
it's the same thing.
He's like one of those
fucking frou-frou dogs
that keeps humping
your leg.
Give a couple
to some ladies.
Thanks, man.
I see what
you're saying, Gibb,
but that's exactly
why you should go.
I mean,
be amongst friends
where it's safe.
There's gonna be
a whole lot of
loving there for you
and my boy Trey,
all right?
Yeah. Yeah, you're
right. I should go.
I could use
a few dozen drinks.
That a girl.
Let your
freak flag fly.
See you there.
You want to go?
No, I don't think so.
I--I didn't get much
sleep last night,
and when I did sleep,
I had the most
terrible nightmares.
Lori, you had to sleep
at a police station.
I'd have nightmares, too.
No, no, no,
it wasn't like that.
I mean, this was
really real.
I mean,
there was this man,
but he more like
a monster really,
and they kept
calling him Freddy,
and he was so real.
Shh!
What did he
look like?
He--he had this...
Dark brown hat, and...
His skin was
terribly burnt,
and on this right hand
he had this like these
razor fingers, and--
Kia: You must
be tripping.
No, no, no!
And then there were
these little girls...
It's ok. It was
a bad dream.
They were singing like
this--this song like--
1, 2, Freddy's
coming for you
you know why
they sing that?
Because that's when
he comes for you...
In your dreams.
You're lucky
to be alive.
Who is he?
He's a child murderer
that some parents
from around here
burned alive,
but then he came back.
Back for revenge
in our nightmares.
Funny no one ever
told us about him, huh?
Ok, thank you!
No!
Want some free advice?
Coffee.
Make friends with it.
Will: Mark!
That's enough.
You're scaring her.
Will?
Hey.
Uh...
I thought you might
be in trouble, so we--
Lori!
Oh, my God!
Lori, honey,
wake up!
Someone get help,
please!
Someone get
some help, please!
The principal! Will,
let's go, let's go!
Please, somebody
help her. Lori?
How much longer
is it gonna take?
Is she ok or what?
Shh.
Tsk!
For nose jobs,
what kind of anesthesia
do the doctors use?
They put you
all the way under,
right?
Ohh!
Got your nose!
Aah!
Ohh!
Strong work, man.
I came to make sure
she's ok
and you put her
in the infirmary.
What were you
thinking about,
telling her
all that stuff, man?
I mean,
we're not in group.
Because I'm thinking
for the first time
in my life that
maybe I'm not crazy,
that my brother
wasn't crazy.
She had the same
dream, will.
Officer: Will rollins!
Mark Davis!
[Bell rings]
Mark: This doesn't make
any sense.
There's nothing
on Krueger.
Not his arrest,
his death,
not even
a birth certificate.
Whole sections of
the records are gone.
Look at all these
blacked-out obituaries.
January 18th.
That's the day
my brother
committed suicide.
Why isn't that
in here?
I don't know!
But I'm sure there's
a good reason.
I mean, remember in group
when they told us
not to jump
to conclusions.
Listen to yourself.
You're holding onto
that psychobabble
bullshit
like it's some kind of
security blanket, man.
Let it go. They covered
him up, will.
They never told us
about Freddy
because that's how they
decided to beat him.
They treated him like he
was a fucking disease,
and they locked up
all the kids
who had made
contact with him
so they wouldn't
infect the others.
That's crazy?
Is it?
How come
we were never allowed
to call any of
our friends, man?
How come none of our
friends ever called us?
We were in a fucking
quarantine, man.
That's what
westin hills was for.
Will: Well, even if all
you're saying is true,
then why didn't
Freddy kill Lori?
Maybe he's not
strong enough yet.
My brother said
it's our fear
that gives him
his power.
Yeah, well,
you sure as hell
spread enough fear
today at school.
Holy shit.
You're right.
They wanted
to forget Freddy
so they wouldn't
fear him--
what if I screwed up
the town's plan?
No.
Fuck! This fucker's
gonna spread
like the plague, man.
Kids are gonna start
falling asleep,
it's gonna--
let's leave, man,
let's leave right now.
No, I can't leave.
Why not?
I gotta go talk to Lori.
I gotta see if she's ok.
Well, is she worth
dying for?
Because if you
fall asleep,
you ain't waking up.
Yeah, well,
if that's the case,
how come
you're not dead?
Or any of the freaks
at westin, huh?
When's the last time
you even had a nightmare?
I don't know.
I can't remember
my dreams anymore.
Look, just give me
one night, ok?
Just let me find Lori,
and then we're out of here.
I swear.
All right. If your
ass isn't back here
by dawn, I'm gone.
We clear on that?
This baby's
my brother's
pride and joy,
so be careful.
[Techno music playing]
Oh, shit.
Linderman!
Uh, shack,
I don't drink.
[All laughing]
Hi, Lori. Didn't think
I'd see you here.
Uh, can I get you
something to drink?
Smooth opening,
but, you know,
we're already
taken care of.
What happened
to your clothes?
Oh, this. Uh...
I was playing
a drinking game
with some of the, uh,
lower primates,
and I guess I'm penalized
for my ability
to read above
a fourth grade level.
Linderman, you know,
I always pictured you
as a straight up
bed wetter.
You know what, Kia?
I used to think
you hated me
because you thought I wasn't
good enough for Lori,
but that's not it.
You see, you tear me down
to make yourself
feel better
because you really
hate yourself,
which is kind of pathetic
when you actually
stop and think about it,
assuming, of course,
you can think
with all that make-up
weighing down
your head.
The cops said Blake
committed suicide.
Apparently, it was
grief over Trey.
No, man,
that's bullshit.
I heard
some guy Krueger
killed them both.
Said his name
to my parents,
they almost shit
themselves.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, man,
and I heard
that Freddy freak,
he used to live here.
Fucking gutted Trey like
a goddamn Turkey, man.
Like I heard
his intestines and shit
was on the floor--
oh, shit. I'm sorry.
Oh, my God.
Look who's here.
Look who's here!
Kia: What are you
looking at?
Come on, come on,
let's dance.
Come on, Linderman,
let's go.
Where have
you been, will?
Didn't you get
my letters?
What letters?
They must've never
even mailed them. Heh!
Who?
The...Doctors at
westin hills.
I've been in
a psychiatric hospital.
Uh, mark was
with me there.
Some other kids, too.
I don't understand.
Well, I saw on the news
the other night,
I mean, that kid that was
killed at your house.
I mean, I needed to know
that you were safe.
What happened?
I don't know.
Nobody knows. Nobody
saw what happened,
and the police
have been acting
really weird, like
they know something,
and I heard them
mention some name.
Some...
Freddy.
Freddy Krueger.
Where was your dad?
Out of town.
Are you sure?
What is
going on, will?
Well, look, 4 years ago,
I thought I--
Kia: Enough with
this bullshit talk.
Let's go
shake our ass
on the dance
floor. Come on!
Trey: I'm dead one day
and you're already out
getting shit-faced?
Same old Gibb!
Trey, I--
I can't believe it--
come on, let's go.
Babe, don't make me
ask you twice, ok?
Now!
Gibb: Trey?
Trey?
[Softly]
Oh.
[Water trickling]
Trey?
Trey!
Ohh!
Aah! No!
Open the door!
Please, the door--
aah!
[Moans]
[Whimpering]
[Hiss]
Ohh!
Aah!
Ha ha ha ha
ha ha ha!
No! No!
Aah!
[Clanking]
[Blades scratching metal]
You're the one
that killed Trey!
Oh, don't worry about
my little errand boy.
The only to fear
is fear himself!
Aah!
Uhh!
Oh.
[Groaning]
[Creaking]
Aah! Aah!
[Gasping]
Aah!
No!
She's mine.
Mine!
This everclear is
kicking my ass.
This--ha ha ha!
Check out this
fucking guy.
Well, hey, Jethro!
This is a rave,
not a Halloween party.
Why don't you
go find yourself
a pig to fuck?
Yeah!
Invite only,
cornpoke.
And you
weren't invite--
son of a bitch.
Uhh!
Yeah!
Burn, mother fucker!
Ohh!
[Whimpering]
No!
Uhh!
[Crowd screaming]
Run, man, run!
[Car engines starting]
Aah!
Freak!
You killed my brother!
Whoa!
Gibb!
Oh, my God!
Oh, Gibb! No!
Let's go!
Let's go, come on!
Was that him?
The guy you were
talking about?
Freddy Krueger?
No, that wasn't
the guy in my dream.
That was
somebody else!
Who cares about some
fucking dream guy, ok?
That psycho in
the hockey mask was real.
Dude, that goalie was
pissed about something.
We need to find
the police.
No, no!
Fuck the police!
Just take me home, will.
Gibb, I--
I can't believe she...
I know.
[Softly]
Look, call me later, ok?
Please?
Just to check in.
Ok.
[Sniffles]
Bye, will.
Be careful.
[Thunder]
Will, I'm gonna
go inside now.
No, I think that's
the last thing
you should do
right now.
Oh, will, please.
After everything
that's happened,
I just want
to go to--
there's more
to it than that.
Look, I tried to tell
you this earlier.
The reason
I was sent to westin
is because I saw
your dad kill your mom.
Will, my mom died
in a car accident.
No, that's what he
wanted you to believe,
but I was there, Lori.
I was sneaking
up to your room
like I used to do.
Only you weren't there.
I saw him kill her.
[Knocking]
Dad!
Get out of the van.
Get out of the van!
Where were you?
What are you doing?
I've been looking
all over for you!
Get away from her!
You're in a helluva
lot of trouble,
you know that?
Yeah, like I give
a shit anymore.
Get in the house!
You! I'm taking you
back to westin.
No! No way!
You can't trust him, Lori.
Whatever you do,
don't go home with him!
No, listen to me!
Lori, he was the one
who had me committed!
See, you didn't
understand.
You still don't.
You were confused!
Stop it!
Both of you,
stop it!
Damn it, will!
I am not gonna
let you endanger
my daughter again!
Not after everything
that's happened!
Stop it!
Stop it! Fuck!
Lori!
[Coughs]
I--I--
did mom die
in a car accident?
Yes.
Of course she did.
Prove it.
Show me
a death certificate.
an autopsy report.
Lori, I don't think now
is the right time--
really, dad?
Because I think
it's a perfect time!
Why didn't you tell me
about westin hills?
Do you work there?
Because I thought
you were a fucking
general practitioner!
Yes, I...
I do some consulting
there now, but...
It's--it isn't
what you think.
Oh, my God.
So you knew about will
this whole time.
Lori, listen to me.
You're upset.
We both are.
Now I think
what you need now
more than anything
is to get some rest.
Why don't I give you
some pills,
and that'll
help you sleep,
and then we talk
about it in the morning?
I don't want
to sleep, dad!
I want to know why
you've been lying to me!
We'll talk about it
in the morning!
Now do what I say!
Lori! Lori!
Lori!
Open this door.
Open this door!
Go away!
Dr. Campbell:
Damn it, Lori!
Let me in !
Lori!
Goddamn it!
Aah!
It's ok, it's me.
It's me, shh! Shh!
You ok?
Are you ok?
It's me, all right?
Will: I don't know
how your father's
connected to all this,
but I think
mark was right.
There's some kind
of cover-up
going on here
with Krueger.
We can't trust
the police.
any of the adults.
So what do we do?
We gotta get
to mark.
He's the expert
in all of this.
He'll know
what's going on.
[Stereo playing]
You always looked out
for me, bro.
Man, ghostly:
Hey, mark.
[Water running]
[Whispering]
Just stay awake.
[Sighs]
Shit!
Hey, mark.
You didn't forget
about me, did you?
Oh, God.
[Freddy's voice]
Oh, that's right!
Everyone forgot!
That's why they weren't
afraid anymore!
That's why I needed Jason
to kill for me
to get them to remember.
But now he
just won't stop,
that hockey puck!
Aah!
Freddy: Ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
This isn't...Real.
[Hissing]
Somebody, please,
wake me up!
Please!
[Tires screeching]
Mark!
Mark, wake up!
I need you to send
a little message for me.
That's all,
just a little message.
Mark: I'm not
gonna do it.
I won't do it!
No?!
I won't do it.
[Sniffles]
I'll have to pass
that message myself.
Won't I, hmm?
Aah!
Uhh!
Lori: Aah!
Ha ha ha!
Aah!
Let go of me!
Help...Me.
Mark!
Ohh!
Aah!
Freddy: Pass on a little
message for me, will ya?
[Sighs]
Uh, sheriff,
I've been compiling info
based on eyewitness reports
of the hockey mask killer.
We already know
who did this.
Sheriff, we closed
down the school
and set up a curfew
for anyone under 18.
Good.
Now I want 24 hour
roadblocks set up.
Nobody leaves town,
nobody gets in.
We're gonna contain
this son of a bitch
before he spreads
any further.
Yes, sir.
Sir, shouldn't we have
the FBI come in and--
no outsiders, Stubbs.
We can handle this.
We've stopped him before.
Ok, I'm a little
lost here.
Stopped who before?
We don't say
his name out loud.
You're not
from around here.
I don't expect you
to understand.
With all due resect,
sheriff,
I think
we have a copycat
of the old
Jason Voorhess
crystal lake killer
on our hands--
you listen to me.
We do things around here
a certain way
for a reason.
And that's given us
4 years of peace.
So you either do your job
and keep your mouth shut
or, so help me God,
I will lock you up!
Do you understand me?!
Do you understand?!
Yes, sir.
[Crow caws]
Charlie: Why don't
we all just leave?
No, even if we leave,
Freddy can still get us.
We all know about him,
we're all afraid of him.
It was our fear that
gave him his power.
We're marked now.
Man,
screw that clown.
I mean, what kind
of a pussy comes
after you in
your dreams anyway?
Now that big ass
mother fucker
back at the cornfield,
all right, that's who
we should be afraid of.
Tell me who
the fuck that was.
His name was
Jason Voorhess.
Uh, shit, man...
Um...
How'd you know
we were here?
Nothing personal,
but the Scooby van out back
wasn't exactly subtle.
And never keep
your keys in the door.
Great, so now we're
completely fucked.
No, you're not.
I'm here to help you.
Now, this Jason Voorhess
supposedly drowned
at camp crystal lake
back in 1957
when he was
11 years old.
The counselors weren't
watching him,
then they made the mistake
of killing his mother.
The legend has it
that Jason kept returning
from his grave to punish
whoever returned
to the camp.
I think we're dealing
with a copycat here.
No. No. No, no, no.
He's not a copycat.
I've seen what he can do.
He's the real Jason.
That's impossible, Linderman.
Jason is dead.
Yeah. Well, you'd better
start thinking outside
your little box, dude.
'Cause somebody's
definitely breaking
the fucking
reality rules, ok?
Will: It makes
sense in a way.
I mean, what if Freddy
brought Jason back
because he was too weak
to go after us on his own,
so he used Jason.
I mean, he knew that
we'd think it was him,
that we'd spread
the fear again.
And now that it's working,
it's like he can't
shut Jason back down.
Wait a minute.
Freddy died by fire,
Jason by water.
How can we use that?
I think we should
concentrate on Jason first.
But I thought we decided
that Freddy was the one
pulling the strings.
Shouldn't we go
after him first?
I don't know, maybe
what we need to do is
to offer Freddy
a sacrifice.
Yeah, yeah, totally.
Like a virgin, right?
Someone pure.
Dude, don't look at me.
Even if you pay for it,
it still counts.
Oh, come on.
Look, we all know who
the real virgin is here.
Kia!
Come on, Lori.
I know you never
made it with will.
Why would
he want to
when he can fuck
somebody like me?
[Chuckles]
[Giggles]
Let's tie the bitch up.
What?
Don't worry, angel.
You've still got me.
Come on,
give daddy a kiss.
Aah!
Your eyes say no-no,
but my mouth
says yes-yes.
Aah!
Aaaaah!
Lori, are you
all right?
You fell asleep.
[Gasping]
Ohh!
Oh, shit!
I pulled that
out of my dream.
How is that possible?
Anything is
possible now!
God, you just
don't get it!
Oh, God, y'all,
2 killers?
We're not safe
awake or asleep.
It's not the sleep
that's killing us,
it's our dreams.
At westin, mark and I
never had dreams.
Were you on any drugs?
Yeah, but there's
something called hypnocil.
They never told us
what it was for,
but everyone there
was taking it.
Hypnocil.
Experimental drug...
Not even approved yet
by the fda.
Will: Oh, shit.
Used for...
Suppression
of dreams.
We need those pills.
Enough for all of us.
Can you get us
back to westin hills?
[Buzzes]
[Monitor beeping]
All right,
this isn't it, guys.
Come on, let's go.
[Whispering]
Hey, dude.
Let's take a little
j-break, huh?
No, man.
He's a cop.
Oh, come on.
What's he gonna do,
arrest me?
Hold up.
Hang on a second.
Fuck.
Oh, that's better.
[Pounding on door]
[Gunshot]
Where's freeburg?
Come on.
Come on!
[Door alarm beeps]
This is d-wing.
Will: These are the ones
who wouldn't stop dreaming.
Are they dead?
They're in a coma.
It says they were given
too much hypnocil.
Who would do
this to people?
Your dad's name
is at the bottom
of both
of these charts.
[Coughing]
Cool...Yeah.
What the fuck?
[Growling]
[Laughs]
Nice.
Oh, yeah.
[Coughs]
Hold up, man.
What?
[Patients whispering]
What do you want?
No, I don't know where
the hypnocil is, ok?
I can't pour these
down the drain.
We need this stuff.
[Gasps]
Uhh!
Freeburg!
Freeburg,
what are you doing?
Charlie:
We need those drugs!
Dude, no!
Dude--
aah!
Go on!
Get out of here!
Go!
Ohh!
Aah!
What was that?
[Electric crackling]
Let's go check it out.
Let's go.
Get back!
Shit! Hell!
Fucker!
Help me!
Shit!
They're all empty!
We gotta keep looking.
Maybe there's
some down here.
Damn, it's gotta
be here somewhere.
Aah!
Freeburg, come on!
Come on!
Kia: What are you
waiting for, come on!
Freeburg,
time to go.
We gotta go!
Now, come on!
[Freddy's voice]
Let me handle this, bitch.
What?
Come on, come on!
Ok, let's go!
Will: Let's go.
No, wait, wait!
Look.
Come to Freddy.
These are
my children, Jason.
Go back where
you belong!
Ohh!
Fuck you!
Linderman...
Freddy: These are
my children, Jason.
Go back where you belong.
[Freddy laughing]
Jason's mother:
Jason...Jason...
My special, special boy.
I'm disappointed
in you, Jason.
You disobeyed me.
You were supposed
to come back home,
just kill a few of them!
But I blame myself.
I should've known
you wouldn't be able
to stop killing!
You are like
a big, stupid dog
who can't stop eating,
even though your master
said you've had enough!
Ha ha ha.
Now it's time to put
this bad dog to sleep...
For good!
Haaa!
Aah! Aah!
Freddy: Not my arm!
Aah!
Ha!
[Chuckles]
Welcome to my nightmare.
Penny for your thoughts,
chief!
Uhh! Oh, scary.
Ha ha ha ha ha! Uhh!
Ha!
Ah ha ha ha ha!
Ah ha!
Ha ha ha!
[Pinball bells dinging]
[Alarm buzzes]
Ha! Ohh...
Tilt.
Ahh!
Ah ha ha ha ha!
Why won't you die?!
Aah!
Argh!
Aah! Uhh!
Come on.
Come on!
Ahh.
So you are afraid
of something
after all, huh?
Ah ha ha ha ha!
How in the fuck
did I let y'all
talk me into this?
Why don't we just
try and do it here?
Why go all the way
to crystal lake?
Lori: Best-case
scenario: Jason wins.
He'll already be home,
back where he belongs.
I mean,
why follow us anymore?
And if Freddy wins?
At least Jason
has home-field advantage.
[Scoffs]
Ahh.
[Whimpering]
[Chuckles]
Aww...How sweet.
[Shrieks]
You ugly little shit.
Now there's a face...
Only a mother could love!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Yeah!
Now we're
getting somewhere.
Let's see
what really scares you.
Ohh.
[Whimpering]
And dig a little deeper.
Freddy: I'm dying to see
what skeletons
are hidden in your closet.
[Door creaks]
Ok, we're seriously running
out of tranq here, guys. Ok?
I got maybe one dose,
plus enough for Lori.
Well, we're almost there.
Then I better
get going.
No, no, just...
I don't want you to go.
I'm coming back.
Just give me 15 minutes,
then wake me up.
I'll bring that bastard
Freddy back through.
Just make sure
Jason's waiting for him.
Lori: Now I lay me
down to sleep.
[Oldies song playing
on car radio]
[Children shouting]
Children, chanting:
Freak show! Freak show!
Boy: Bull's-eye!
Children: Freak show!
Freak show! Freak show!
Try this on!
Ohh!
Children: Freak show!
Freak show! Freak show!
Stupid!
Ohh! Ohh!
Aren't you gonna
help the kid?!
Can't you see
I'm busy here?
You mean
you're not coming?
It's not my fault this bitch
is dead on her feet.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Aah!
It's been 5 minutes.
Well, that was the last
of the tranq, ok? We're out.
Calm down! Ok?
Just relax!
[Children shouting]
Heeeeelp!
Wait! Give me
your hand!
Give me your hand!
Aah!
Help!
Jason? Aah!
Jason vorhees!
Aah!
[Freddy laughing]
Kia:
Y'all...Y'all...
Y'all,
something's wrong.
It's like he's drowning
or something.
Freddy must be
killing him.
We need him alive!
Dude, what do you
want me to do?
Like, give him
mouth-to-mouth or something?
[Jason gurgling]
Um...
Hell no.
Why are you--
no! No, I'm not
gonna do that. No!
Kia, look, I would
do it myself,
but I've had asthma
since I was 6, ok?
I don't
have the lung power.
No.
Kia, he has asthma!
Ooh! Ooh...
Look, you can
do this, ok?
You can do this.
You just--
shut up!
You're not the one
that has to do this.
I know, but I--
shut up!
Aah!
Oh, my God.
Ohh, God!
Oh, man.
Oh, shit.
[Gags]
[Whimpering]
Aah!
[Tires screech]
[Kia screams]
You!
Aah!
[Blades clink]
[Watch beeping]
What's wrong, Lori?
Miss your wake-up call?
Aah!
Hunh!
Wake me up!
I got him! I got him!
No!
Lori, come on!
Wake up!
Lori, wake up, please!
Look!
Guys, look.
We're almost there.
Help me. Come on.
We gotta get her up.
Come on. Start running.
Start running.
Wake me up!
Daddy, don't!
[Whimpering]
[Gasps]
Daddy!
No, daddy, don't!
Freddy! It was you!
[Gasps]
I've always had a thing
for the whores
that live in this house.
Aah!
[Screaming]
Lori, wake up!
Oh, shit.
It's him. He's here.
Lori, come on!
You gotta wake up!
Uhh! Uhh...
Ha ha ha!
Oh, yes.
[Whimpering]
Aah!
My God!
Ohh.
Come on,
Lori, wake up!
Lori, please.
Wake up!
Aah!
Go! Go, go, go!
Ohh!
Lori!
Oh, you fuckin'
asshole!
Goddamn it!
Aah!
Welcome
to my world, bitch.
I should warn you,
princess,
the first time tends
to get a little...
[Blades clink]
Messy.
[Chuckles]
[Whimpering]
Yah!
Get away from her!
Gah!
Uhh!
Linderman.
Unh!
Oh! Oh, no!
Aah!
Ahh!
[Gasps]
Die, you little bitch.
Ha ha ha ha!
Uhh!
Ohh!
Aah!
Jesus, Linderman. You--
you're really hurt.
No. No, no, no.
Don't worry about me.
Just a scratch.
Just go get help, ok?
What?
You don't think--
look, I'm just gonna
rest here a minute.
Linderman--
I'm fine, Kia.
Really.
Now get out of here.
Go get help.
But you--
just go.
Ok, ok, but...
I'm gonna be back
as soon as I can.
[Both coughing]
Lori!
Think you're so smart,
huh, bitch?
Freddy!
How sweet...
Dark meat.
No! Kia!
Let's go!
Nooo!
So you're the one
everyone's afraid of?
Tell me something.
What kind of faggot
runs around
in a Christmas sweater?
[Hisses]
I mean, come on.
Get real.
You're not even
scary.
And let's talk about
the butter knives.
What is with
the butter knives?
You trying to compensate
for something?
Maybe coming up
a little short there
between the legs,
Mr. Krueger?
Hmm.
I mean, you got
these teensy-weensy
little things,
and Jason has got
this big ol' thing
that's like...
Ohh.
Lori: Kia!
No! No!
Come on!
Come on, Lori.
Let's go.
We can't help her
anymore.
No! I'm staying!
Are you crazy?
You got what you wanted.
You pulled Freddy out,
and now he's
fighting Jason.
Come on!
What more do you want?
He killed
my mother, Will!
It was Freddy.
My dad covered it up
to protect me.
He didn't do it.
Look, he has taken
everything from us!
He has ruined
both of our pasts--
and I am not leaving
until I see him die!
Uhh! Unh! Uhh!
Aah!
Freddy: Man the torpedoes.
Hey, asshole!
Up here!
Aha!
Ahh!
Yeah.
Ah, give me a break.
Uhh!
Ohh! Ahh! Aah!
Ohh! Ohh!
Aah! Aah! Aah! Aah! Ohh!
Oh, no.
Ohh, noooo!
Ahh!
[Chuckles]
[Groaning]
Oh! Aah!
Ohh!
Lori, get the tanks!
Give it up!
Freddy!
Go to hell!
Ohh!
Gah!
Ohh...
Uhh!
[Gagging]
Argh!
Ahh!
[Spluttering]
[Choking]
It's ok. It's ok.
Aah!
You...Ohh!
Aah! Aah!
[Whimpering]
Ohh!
Welcome to my world, bitch!
[Freddy laughing]
[Hard rock music playing]