[Rumbling]
[Woman On Police Radio]
Suspect describedas white male,
approximately 30.
Suspect about 5-11", medium build,
brown dark pants.
Suspect number two about 6-1, medium
build, round glasses, dark clothes.
[Leg Muscles Cracking]
Be advised, suspects are armed
and considered extremely
dangerous. Use caution.
- [Man] Hey, Earl.
- Yes, sir.
- What do ya know?
- Well...
it's a hot goddamn day.
I haven't felt it a bit. Been
inside with the air conditioner
blasting all day long.
- Oh, is that right?
- That's right.
[Opens Bottle]
Did you break for lunch
or nothin'?
All by myself today.
Ate my lunch out of the microwave.
Jesus H. Christ, Pete.
When you gonna learn that microwave food
will kill you faster than a bullet?
I mean, them damn burritos
ain't good for nothin' but
a hippie... when he's high on weed.
- Pull me down a bottle
of that Jack, will ya?
- Yeah.
I think I'm gonna get
tanked tonight.
What's the matter?
[Sighs]
Yep.
It's been one long, goddamn,
hot, miserable, shit-ass, fuckin' day...
every inch of the way.
First off, Nadine over at Blue Chip
got sort of sick.
So she got that goddamn Mongoloid boy
of hers workin' the grill.
I mean, that fuckin' idiot doesn't
know rat shit from Rice Krispies.
- [Chuckles]
- They eat breakfast about 9:00.
And I'm pukin' up
pigs in a blanket...
like a sick,
fuckin' dog by 10:30.
Isn't there a law or something against
retards serving food to the public?
Well... if there ain't,
there oughta be.
I mean, who in the hell knows
what's goin' on in the mind
of a goddamn Mongoloid?
Nadine should've hit that boy
in the head and sold the fuckin' milk.
You could sue the shit
out ofher, you know that?
That kid belongs under a circus tent,
not flippin' burgers.
- You could own that fuckin' place.
- Oh, shit, Pete.
What would I do
with that grease pit?
Besides, Nadine's
got a cross to bear.
I mean, taking care
of that... potato head.
I guess you heard about that shit
up in Abilene? Bank robbery?
That's all that's been
on the box all day.
They killed some people,
didn't they?
Yeah. Killed four Rangers,
three cops,
one civilian.
Took a lady bank teller
hostage with them.
Supposed to be headed for the border,
which'd bring 'em right my way.
If I get my hands on them crazy, sick,
fuckin' bastards, it's payback time.
I mean--
Well, we'll get 'em.
[Sniffles]
We'll get 'em.
Oh, I don't doubt it.
Well...
I gotta drain my lizard.
- Mind if I useyour commode?
- [Chuckles]
- Knock yourself out.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
- [Moans]
- [Cocks Gun] You think I'm fuckin'
playin' with you, asshole?
Do you want this little girl to die?
Or that little girl? Or yourself?
Or your bosom buddy with the badge?
Now, I don't wanna do it.
But I will turn this place
into the fucking Wild Bunch if
I think you are fuckin' with me.
- What do you want from me?
I did what you said.
- You let him use the bathroom.
- No store does that.
- He comes in here everyday
and we bullshit.
- If I told him no,
he'd know something was up.
- I want him out of here...
in his car and down the road or you
can change the name of this place...
to "Benny's World of Blood."
[Whispering]
- You giving that pig signals?
- Are you kidding?
I didn't do anything!
- He says you were scratching.
- I wasn't scratchin'!
- Are you callin' him a liar?
- I'm not callin' him a liar, okay?
I'm simply sayin' if I was scratchin',
I don't remember scratchin'.
If I did scratch,
it's not signalling. It's because
I'm fuckin' scared shitless!
- [Groans]
- Wait a minute.
The guy's in the bathroom.
Why don't I just go back there,
shoot him in the head, and we
can get the hell outta here.
Don't do that. Look. You asked me
to act natural, and I acted natural.
Under the circumstances, I think
I oughta get a fuckin' Academy
Award for how natural I did.
You asked me to get rid of him.
I'm doin' my best! [Panting]
Well, your best better get
a hell of a lot fuckin' better,
- or you are gonna feel
a hell of a lot fuckin' worse.
- [Exhales]
[Toilet Flushes]
Everybody, be cool.
You... be cool. [Uncocks Gun]
[Gasps]
Yep. Be back at it tomorrow.
Tonight I'm gonna sit in front of that
box and get higher than a Georgia pine.
- [Chuckles]
- How much you want
for that hooch, Pete?
Oh, $6.50.
-Jesus Christ. You buckin'
for early retirement?
- Shit, yeah.
- [Gunshot]
- [Groans]
- [Girl Gasps]
- [Robber#1] Hey! Hey!
- What the fuck is that about?
- He signalled the Ranger.
I didn't! Ya gotta
believe me! I didn't!
When they were talking,
he mouthed the words, "Help us."
- You fuckin' liar! I didn't say shit!
- Shut the hell up!
- [Girl Gasps]
- Hey! You stop it!
- What the fuck is your problem,
goddamn it?
- Seth, he did it!
You were by the beer cooler
with your back turned.
I was by the magazines.
I could see his face!
And I saw him
mouth the words, "Help us."
Start the car.
- You believe me, don't you?
- Yes. Shut up.
- And start the car.
- You believe me?
Start the car. You know that.
Shut the fuck up and start the car.
- Wait a minute.
- I believe you. Start the car!
- You're not just saying that?
You do believe me?
- I believe you! Let's go!
- That means you believe.
- Yes, I believe you!
You should, because I'm right.
[Screaming]
- [Robber#2 Groaning]
- Richie!
Yeah?
- You okay?
- He shot me in the fucking hand!
- I told you he said "Help us."
- I never said "Help us"!
Well, that doesn't
matter now, because you got
about two fuckin' seconds to live!
- Richie?
- Yeah?
When I count to three, you shoot
the bottles out from behind him.
Oh, yeah!
- One...
- Fuck!
- two...
- [Gasping, Whimpering]
three!
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
[Gunshots]
[Screaming]
- [Sighs]
- What did I tell you?
What did I say to you?
I said, "Buy the
road map and leave."
- What the fuck am I supposed to
do, Seth? He recognized us.
- He didn't recognize shit.
Seth, I'm telling you,
the way he looked at us--you,
especially--I knew he knew.
Low profile! Do you understand
the meaning of the words "low profile"?
"Hey, Richie, how's your hand?"
"It hurts like a fuckin' son of
a bitch! Thanks for askin'."
Let me tell you what "low profile"
is not. It is not taking girls hostage.
It is not shooting police.
It is not setting fire to a building.
Bitch, bitch, bitch.
~ Hot airhangs
like a deadman~
~ From a white oak tree~
~ People sittin'on porches ~
~ Thinkin' how things
used to be ~
~ Dark night~
~ It's a dark night ~
~ Dark night ~
~ It's a dark night ~~
[Engi ne Roaring]
[Spits]
[Gasping]
[Rings]
[Man On Radio]
~ My wife left home about a week ago ~
- ~ She stole the kids
and she took all my dough ~
- [Bell Rings]
Oh, screw it!
Goddamn you! Goddamn you!
[Muttering]
What the hell do you want?
What do you think I want, you mean,
old bastard? I want a fuckin' room.
Okay, all right.
~ She peed on the carpet
She shot my horse ~
~ Now things are goin'
from better to bad to worse ~
Do they have cable?
No.
- Do they have the X-rated channel?
- No.
- Do they have a water bed?
- Nope.
- What do they got?
- They have four walls and a roof
and that's all we need.
[Shuts Engine Off]
All right, pop the trunk.
Let's do this fast.
[Whimpering]
Oh.
- Don't say a word.
- [Gasps]
You, plant yourself in that seat.
- What are you gonna do with me?
- I said "plant yourself."
Plants don't talk.
Now,you wanna get on my goodside?
You sit still and you don't make a peep.
- All right, how does this feel?
- How do you think--
It hurts like a son of a bitch.
- It's wrapped too tight. Nice and easy.
- Okay.
All right. Okay,
I'm gonna go get the money.
[Panting]
It's 6:00. What time's
it get dark around here?
- About 8:00.
- Good. I'm goin' to
the border, check things out.
I'm gonna call Carlos.
Try and arrange some sort
of a rendezvous. I don't know what.
Could you see if he could
arrange a better deal than 30%?
It's a standard deal.
They're not gonna change that for us.
- Did you even try
and negotiate with them?
- Richie,
these guys are not spic
firecracker sales men from Tijuana.
They don't even know the meaning
of the word "barter."
You wanna stay in El Rey,
you give them 30% of your loot;
it's scripture.
So it is written, so shall it be done.
Yeah, I know, listen.
Hey, you want sanctuary, you gotta
pay the price. The price is 30%.
- All I'm sayin', man--
- This conversation's over.
Okay?
We need to have a talk.
- What's your name?
- Gloria.
Hello, Gloria. I'm Seth. That's my
brother Richie. Let's cut to the chase.
I'm gonna ask you one question,
and all I want is a yes or no answer.
Do you wanna live
through this?
- Yes.
- Good.
Rule number one:
No noise. No questions.
If you make a noise,
Mr..44 makes a noise.
If you ask a question,
Mr..44 answers it.
Now are you absolutely,
positively clear about rule number one?
- Yes.
- Rule number two:
You do what we say
when we say it.
If you don't...
see rule number one.
Rule number three: Don't you ever
try and fucking run on us,
'cause I got six little friends and
they can all run faster than you can.
- [Uncocks Gun]
- [Whispers] Open your eyes.
Gloria, you hang in there,
you follow the rules,
and you don't fuck with us, and
you'll get out of this alive.
I give you my word. Okay?
I'll be back in a minute.
[Door Opens, Closes]
You wanna come over on the bed
and watch TV with me?
[Men]
Hail!
Come on.
Come and see.
Take off your shoes.
[Man] You got about...
two more hours...
until we get into El Paso,
which is right next
to the border.
- Then we'll stop at a motel.
- [Boy] Stop?
- We're not actually gonna stop
at a motel, are we?
- Yeah, what for?
We have a motor home.
We don't wanna stay
in those roach-haven motels, do we?
- [Together] We're self-contained.
- Okay, okay.
Maybe I was... a little overzealous.
But gimme a break. I just bought it.
- How come you wanna stop anyways, Dad?
- I'm exhausted.
Exhausted? Just lie in the back, Dad.
I can drive us into Mexico.
- I just bet you would.
Don't even think about it.
- [Chuckles]
Besides, I wanna have...
just one night's sleep
in a honest to goodness bed.
The beds in the home
are okay, but...
they're not like a real bed.
Excuse me.
I have to use the restroom.
Oh, guess what? When I called
the machine to check the messages,
um, one of them
was from Bethel Baptist.
And Mr. Franklin
said that...
he wouldn't permanently replace you
until we came back.
- And he said that--
- That's very nice of Ted.
But I'll call him tomorrow
and tell him not to bother waiting.
Daddy, I didn't wanna
talk about this...
in front of Scott
because he gets upset.
But I just wanna know...
don't you believe
in God anymore?
Not enough to be a pastor.
Look, I know this is hard
on you kids.
After Jenny's death, this is probably
the last thing you need, but...
my congregation needs
spiritual leadership.
Well... my faith is gone.
To answer your question,
yes, I do believe in...Jesus.
Yes, I do believe in God.
But do I love Them?
No.
Well, it's just that all our lives,
you've been a pastor.
And then...
one day you're just gonna
wake up and say, "Fuck Him"?
I didn't say, "Fuck Him."
Every person who...
chooses the service of God as his
life's work has something in common.
I don't care if
you're a preacher, a priest,
a nun, a rabbi
or a Buddhist monk.
Many, many times during your life you'll
look at your reflection in the mirror...
and ask yourself,
"Am I a fool?"
I'm not going through a lapse.
What I've experienced
is closer to awakening.
Daddy?
What do you think
Mom would say?
Mama's got nothin' to say.
She's dead.
This bloody crime spree started
just a week ago today.
The oldest of the two brothers,
Seth Gecko,
was serving time in Rollings,
Kansas State Penitentiary...
for his part in the 1988
Scott City bank robbery...
in which two law enforcement
officers lost their lives.
It was while at the courthouse that this
man, his younger brother, Richard Gecko,
a known armed robber and sex offender
pulled off a daring daylight escape,
resulting in the death of
four Wichita law enforcement officers,
and this woman,
Heidi Vogel, sixth grade teacher,
who was run over by the Geckos...
during a high-speed pursuit
through downtown Wichita.
And earlier today, during a daylight
liquor store robbery in Big Springs,
the Gecko brothers killed
another Texas Ranger,
Earl McGraw, and liquor store clerk,
Pete Bottoms.
That changes the death toll to 16;
five Texas Rangers, eight police
officers, three civilians.
And one hostage, bank teller
and mother off our, Gloria Hill.
For the time being, we're very
confident that we'll apprehend
these fugitives within 48 hours.
The Bureau, local law enforcement
and the Texas Rangers...
have all joined in forming a dragnet
to snare Seth and Richard Gecko.
Is it safe to assume that because
of the death count involved...
and the loss of life
of law enforcement officers,
that the Bureau, the Rangers
and the police force are taking
this manhunt personally?
I would say that's
a very safe assumption.
[Door Opening]
- Shit, I was really worried.
Where the fuck you been, man?
- Sightseeing.
- What'd you see?
- The cops.
- Did you see the border?
- Yes, I saw the border.
- What'd the TV say?
- They're gonna apprehend us
in about 48 hours.
I gotta figure out a way
to get us across this goddamn border.
The longer we stay here, our lives
ain't worth shit. Here you go.
We gotta get our asses
into Mexico tonight.
Then Carlos is gonna meet us at
the rendezvous tomorrow morning.
He and his boys, all of them
are gonna escort us into El Rey.
And--
- Where's the woman?
- What?
What do you mean, what? The woman.
The fuckin' hostage.
Richard, where is she?
She's in there.
- What the fuck is she doin' in there?
- Seth, wait a minute.
Seth.
Richard, what's wrong with you?
- Before you flip out, okay, let
me just explain what happened.
- Ex--Explain to me.
I need an explanation.
What is the matter with you?
There's nothing wrong with me,
brother. That woman tried to
escape and I did what I had to.
No, the woman wouldn't have said shit
if she had a mouth full of it.
Wrong, wrong, wrong.
- Yeah.
- After you left,
- she became a completely
different person.
- Yeah.
Is it me?
Is it my fault?
- It's not your fault.
- Is this my fault?
- No, it's her fault.
It's not your fault.
- Is this my fault?
Do you think that
this is what I am?
- I don't.
- This is not me. I am
a professional fucking thief.
I don't kill people that I don't have
to and I don't fucking rape women.
What you are doing--
What you are fucking doing--
What you are doing is not how it's done.
Do you understand that? Do you?
Just say, "Fucking yes."
Say, "Yes, Seth, I understand."
- Yes, Seth, I understand.
- Say it. Say, "Yes, Seth,
I fucking understand!"
I understand, Seth.
I fucking understand.
We'll get to Mexico,
and it's gonna be sweet rosemary
and a hundred proof liquor...
[Sighs] and rice and beans and none
of this shit's gonna matter.
I can't believe he's stoppin' here.
This place is totally cruddy.
- [Door Closes]
- Dad, why are we stoppin' here?
There's nothin' wrong
with this... place.
- [Engine Starts]
- It's a flophouse.
It's not a flophouse.
It's basic and it's simple.
That doesn't make it
a flophouse.
All right. Well,
if it doesn't have a pool,
then we're goin' someplace else.
It has a bed.
That's all I care about.
Well, other places
have beds, too,
and they also have... a gym--
- [Brakes Screeching]
- [Gasps]
[Scott] Geez, what is
this guy's problem?
No idea.
Creepy guy.
[Knocking]
~ [Guitar]
- [Knocking]
- What?
- [Richard] Yes, I'm your
neighbor from, uh, room 11.
- [Sighs]
And I hate to disturb you,
but I'd like to ask a favor.
[Moaning]
I hope none of this
is disturbin' you.
[Exhales]
Hi. Uh, I'm from room 11.
And me and my lady friend need some ice
and we don't seem to have an ice bucket.
If it's not too much trouble,
could I possibly borrow yours?
I'll bring it right back.
[Sighs]
Sure.
Thank you.
[Gun Cocks]
What is this?
- [Groans]
- It's called a punch.
Lose the guitar.
- [Gun Cocks]
- What's your name?
-Jacob.
-Jacob, get up. Get on the bed.
- If you make a wrong move,
I will shoot you in the face.
- [Richard] Open your mouth.
Wide!
Let's go. Let's move
the Jap over here too. Let's go.
So what's the story with you two?
You a couple offags?
- He's my son.
- How's that happen?
You don't look Japanese.
Neither does he.
He looks Chinese.
Oh, ooh, well
excuse me all to hell.
- What's this about, money?
- It's about money,
all right, but not yours.
My brother and I, we're in a little
hot water and we need your assistance.
- [Gasps]
- Stop!
Wha--What's,
um, goin' on?
We're having a bikini contest,
and you just won.
It's okay, honey.
Everything's gonna be all right.
Just listen to your daddy, sugar,
and you don't do anything stupid.
You two, Simon says
sit the fuck down.
Sit down.
Now... where are the keys
to the motor home?
- On the dresser.
- Good. All right,
Richie, you take these keys,
you start this big bastard up
and drive it up front.
Richie, would you do me a favor
and eat my pussy for me? Please?
- Uh... sure.
- Richie, hey!
Not when you get
around to it. Now.
[Groans]
You, Gidget, go in the bathroom
and put on some clothes.
You got three minutes. One second
longer, I shoot your father in the face.
- Do you understand what I just said?
- Yes.
- Do you believe me?
You damn well better. Go.
Look, if you want
the motor home,
just take it and get out.
It's not gonna be that easy, Pops.
We're gonna go on a little ride.
Not a chance.
- Come again?
- If you're takin' people, take me.
But my kids aren't
going anywhere with you.
Sorry, Pops.
I need everybody.
My children are not goin'
with you, and that's that.
That's not fucking that.
This is fucking this.
Dad.
You sit down. Sit down.
You, go sit over there.
Go sit over there, now. Move it.
Sit down.
Now, I don't have time to fuck around,
so I'm gonna make this simple.
You take your kids
and you get in that motor home...
or I will execute
all three of you right now.
So, what's it gonna be?
Yes or no answer.
Yes.
Hey, your old man's all right.
He just saved your life.
Time's up, princess.
Here we go.
Okay, ramblers,
let's get rambling.
Excuse me.
What?
- Where are you takin' us?
- Mexico.
What's in Mexico?
Mexicans.
- Richie?
- Yeah?
Put in your bit.
[Rattling]
I grind my teeth.
~ Dengue woman~
What are their names?
- Scott and Kate.
Who's this?
- My wife.
- Where is the little lady?
- In heaven.
- She dead?
Yes, she is.
How'd she die?
Auto wreck.
Come on,Jacob, gimme some
more details. How'd it happen?
Some fucking drunk kill her?
No. It was a rainy night.
The brakes on the car
weren't great.
She had to stop suddenly.
She slid on the road.
She crashed. She died.
- She died right away?
- Not quite.
She was trapped in the wreck
for about... six hours...
before she passed on.
Yep. Those acts of God really stick
it in and break it off, don't they?
Yes, they do.
Is that real?
- Yes.
- I've seen one of these things before.
A friend of mine had himself ordained
a minister of his own religion.
Some way to fuck the I.R.S.
Is that what you're doing,
or are you the real McCoy?
The real McCoy.
- You're a preacher?
- [Inhales Deeply] I was a minister.
"Was" as in not anymore?
- Yes.
- Why'd you quit?
I think I've gotten about...
as up close and personal
with you as I'm gonna get.
Let's just keep this friendly, okay,
Pops? Let's not get too sensitive.
You're right. Enough with
the gettin'-to-know-you shit. All right.
I don't give a rat's ass about you
or your fuckin' family.
You can all live forever,
or you can die this second.
And I don't
give a shit which.
The only things that
I care about are me,
that son of a bitch
back there in the back and the money.
So you help us get across
the border without incident,
you stay with us through the night
without trying anything funny,
without trying to escape,
and in the morning I'm gonna
let you guys go, all of you.
How do I know you'll keep your word?
You have to convince me
you're tellin' the truth.
Look, dick-head, the only thing
that you have to be convinced about...
is the fact that you are
stuck in a situation with a couple
of real mean motor scooters.
I don't want to have to worry
about you all fuckin'night.
I don't think you wanna be worrying
about my brother's intentions...
towards your daughter
all night, either.
- Did you notice the way
he was looking at her?
- Yes.
- You didn't like it, did you?
- No, I didn't.
I didn't think so.
You get us into Mexico,
and you don't try to escape,
and your daughter will be safe.
And in the morning I will let you go.
I give you my word,Jacob.
If he touches her,
I'll kill him!
Fair enough. You break your word,
I'll kill all of ya.
~ You got me all crazy~
~ I can't get outta bed~
~ Bones are achin'~
~ Backed up in myhead~
~ Dengue woman~
~ Stay away from me ~
~ You got your aches andpains ~
~ O-o-over me ~~
Did you mean what you said
back there in the room?
What?
In the room?
Did you mean what you said back there,
or were just foolin' around?
Because if you really want me to do
that for you, I will. I'd be happy to.
- Do what?
- What you said back there in the room?
What did I say?
- You asked me if I would eat--
- [Seth] Richie.
- What?
- I told you to watch those kids.
Not to talk to them.
You don't have nothin' to say to one
another, so let's just cut the chatter.
We'll talk later. Okay?
[People Chattering]
[Man On Police Radio]
All right, everybody,
it's show time.
Richie, you take Kate
into the bathroom. Scott,
get up here with your dad. Let's go.
Now, what are you
gonna say?
I don't have
the slightest idea.
Just keep thinking about the gun
next to Kate's head.
Get in.
[Chattering Continues]
- [Panting]
- This isn't gonna work, Seth.
Shut up. It's gonna work
just fine.
[Whispering]
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna try and get us
across the border.
Dad, you have to tell them
they're back there.
Have you forgotten
about your sister?
I want to go on record right now as
saying that this is a very bad idea.
Duly noted.
Now shut up.
Oh, my God. Look over here.
Step right over there.
They're gonna kill us, Dad.
They're gonna get us across the border,
take us out in the desert,
then they're gonna fuckin' shoot us.
If they get over the border,
they're gonna let us go.
No, they won't. Dad, come on.
I watch those reality shows.
They never let anybody go.
Any cop'll tell you, in a situation like
this, you get a chance, you go for it.
It may not seem like it, but I know
exactly what I'm doing. Trust me.
I can't do that, Dad.
- If you don't tell the cops, I will.
- Now listen to me!
You ain't gonna do
a goddamn thing! You hear me?
- I'm runnin' the show!
I make the decisions!
- He is runnin' the show--
- I'm runnin' the show!
- Dad!
Shh. I make the plays.
You back the plays I make.
I need your cover.
Cover me.
How many with you?
- Just my son and I.
- [Thumping]
What's your purpose in Mexico?
Vacation. I'm takin' him
to see his first bull fight.
They're gonna search the van.
As long as you don't act like a
fuckin' nut, we're gonna be fine.
-What the hell's that supposed to mean?
-What?
- You just called me a fuckin' nut.
- No, I didn't.
Yes, you did. You said, "As long
as I don't act like a fucking nut."
- Implying that I've been acting
like a fucking nut.
- Take a pill.
- I just meant be cool.
- Yeah, you meant that,
but you meant the other too.
[Sighs]
This is not the time, Richie.
Hey, fuck those spic pigs, man!
You called me a "fucking nut."
- Now, where I come from, that
stops the train in its tracks.
- Keep your fucking voice down.
- [Banging]
- What?
- What was that?
- Hmm?
Oh! That was just,just
my daughter in the bathroom.
I thought you said
it was just you and your son?
Um... I meant me and my son
and my daughter.
Open up. I'm comin' aboard.
What was the nuttiest thing
I did, Seth? I'm curious.
Tell me. What was it?
-This is not the time, Richie.
- I know.
Was it possibly when your ass was
rotting in jail and I broke it out?
- [Chuckles]
- That was nutty, huh?
Not to mention stupid.
[Sighs]
Thanks.
[Panting]
- [Kate] I'm in the bathroom.
- Open up. It's Border Patrol.
It's open.
[Gasps]
Do you mind?
Shut the fuckin' door, please!
Excuse me.
Goddamn, that was intense!
Oh, baby, we did it.
We're in Mexico.
We're fuckin' in Mexico,
you little piece of fuckin' shit!
Come on!
Kate, get out here.
All right, listen up.
Everybody, listen.
Now I know that I put you all
through hell, and I know that
I have been one rough pecker.
But from here on out,
you guys are all in my cool book.
Scotty, I want you to help me
with Richie. Lay him down
on the couch over there.Jacob.
You're gonna keep driving down
this street until you come to
another street called Digallo.
When you get to Digallo, you're gonna
turn this big bastard left,
and you're gonna go down
a couple of miles until you see
a bar called the Titty Twister.
- From what I understand,
you cannot miss it.
- Then?
And then you stop because
that's where we're goin'.
~ [Spanish]
Don't make a career
out of this, okay?
- Come on, hey.
- [Sighs]
Hey, you okay?
[Groans]
Yeah, I think so. What happened?
- I don't know. You just passed out.
- I did?
Mm-hmm. You said something
about your hand hurtin',
- and then you just hit the ground
like a sack of potatoes. [Chuckles]
- Really?
Head hit the toilet.
You scared the shit out of me.
You sure you're okay?
Yeah. I, I think so.
I'm just a little fucked up.
Well, let me tell you something
that's gonna clear your head right up.
- What?
- We are officially Mexicans.
[Chuckling]
We're in Mexico, buddy.
- We are?
- Yeah. We're heading down
to the rendezvous right now.
We're gonna pound booze,
wait for Carlos.
When he gets there,
he's gonna take us down to El Rey.
And then you and I, my brother,
we're gonna kick fuckin' back.
- How do you like them apples?
- Far out.
- [Chuckling]
- [Groaning] Where's my glasses?
Oh, uh--Yeah, they, uh--
they broke when you fell.
- Fuck, Seth, these are my only pair!
- Don't worry about it.
- We'll get you another pair.
- Of course I'm gonna worry
about it. I can't see!
I'll take care of it
when we get to El Rey.
Yeah, like some Mexican hole in
the wall's gonna have my prescription.
It's not a big deal
until you make it a big deal.
Now, I was in a very good mood.
So stop bringing me down
with this bullshit!
[Scoffs]
- I can't wear this shit.
- Hey, guys.
We're here.
~[Rock]
[Man Laughing]
[Shouting]
Pussy!
[Chuckling]
All right,
pussy, pussy, pussy!
Come on in, pussy lovers.
Here at the Titty Twister,
we're slashin' pussy in half.
Give us an offer on our best selection
of pussy. This is a pussy blowout!
All right, we got white pussy, black
pussy, Spanish pussy, yellow pussy.
We got hot pussy, cold pussy.
We got wet pussy.
We got smelly pussy.
We got hairy pussy, bloody pussy.
We got snappin' pussy.
We got silk pussy, velvet pussy,
"Nalgahyde" pussy.
We even got horse pussy,
dog pussy, chicken pussy.
Come on, you want pussy.
Come on in, pussy lovers.
If we don't got it, you don't want it.
Okay, troops, it's the homestretch.
Here's the deal.
This place closes at dawn. Carlos is
gonna meet us here sometime before dawn.
Now, we are gonna go in there,
we're gonna take a seat, we're
gonna have a bunch of drinks.
And we're gonna wait
for Carlos.
Let me just say something.
I'm very happy about where we're at.
We got a real nice I-don't-
fuck-with-you, you-don't-fuck-
with-me attitude goin' on.
So if everybody just keeps playin' it
cool--I'm talkin' to you, too, Richie--
then everybody's gonna get
what they want.
Okay, hard drinkers, let's drink hard.
I'm buyin'. Come on.
Here we go.
Out of the stew pot
and into the fire.
Attention, pussy shoppers!
Take advantage of our penny pussy sale.
If you buy one piece of pussy
at the regular price,
you will get another piece of pussy of
equal or lesser value for only a penny.
Try and beat pussy
for a penny.
If you can find cheaper pussy
anywhere... fuck it!
[Laughing]
Hey, what do we have
approaching here?
A new flavor: apple pie pussy.
[Chuckles]
Hey, not so fast, slick.
- Step aside, asshole.
- [Wrist Cracking]
Son of a--
[Groaning]
Now, is my shit together
or is my shit together?
Here we go.
- Hi! How ya doin'?
Enjoying it? I hope so!
- [Groaning]
Now... this is
my kind of place.
~ [Rock]
[Bottle Shattering]
~ [Singing In Spanish]
I could become a regular.
[Punch Landing]
[Bottle Smashing]
~ [Continues Singing In Spanish]
Whiskey!
- You can't come in here.
- What do you mean?
It's a private bar.
You're not welcome.
Are you tellin' me that
I'm not good enough to drink here?
This baris for bikers
and truckers only.
You, get out!
Ande, pendejo!
- Take your hand off of me.
- I'm gonna count to three--
- No, I'm gonna count to three.
- One--
- Two--
- Now, wait a minute.
There is no reason to get ugly.
There is just a misunderstanding
going on here.
You said this bar
is for truckers and bikers?
Well, I'm a truck driver.
If you look outside your door
in your parking lot, you'll see
a big recreational vehicle.
That's mine. In order to
drive that legally,you need
a Class Two driver's license.
This bar is for truck drivers?
I am a truck driver.
These are my friends.
[Screaming]
Welcome to the Titty Twister.
- Bottle of whiskey and five glasses.
- Coming right up.
~ [Continues Singing In Spanish]
[Screaming]
~ [Trilling]
- You serve food here,Jose?
- Best in Mexico.
I kind of doubt that.
We're gonna go over here. You send a
waitress over to take our order. Okay?
- [Bottle Smashes]
-~ [Stops]
~ [Starts]
[Whip Snaps]
~ Mary had a little lamb ~
~ His fleece was black
as coal,yeah ~
Any time you want a lap dance with that
girl, kid, just let me know, all right?
It's on me.
Pass.
Is it against your religion?
No. I do drink.
I'm just not drinkin' now.
- Fair enough. More for me.
Scott, how 'bout you?
- No.
- Kate, how 'bout you?
- No, I can't. I'm not 21 yet.
That means yes.
Post time, Kate!
Here we go. You slam it down. You knock
the glass down on the table, all right?
One, two, three!
- [Coughing]
- Atta girl, Kate.
- Scotty, are you ready?
Here we go. You ready for one?
- Okay.
- No, he won't.
- Yes, he will, because
I'm not drinkin' by myself.
Kate, round two.
You ready?
- Here we go.
- Yes, I'll have another one. Thank you.
On three. One, two, three.
[Coughing]
Why are you so agitated?
I'm still stewin' about that ape
layin' his hand on me.
- What are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna sit here and
I'm gonna finish this bottle.
And when I am finished, I'm gonna take
this bottle and I'm gonna bust it...
over his melon fucking head!
Before we stepped in here,
you told all of us to be cool.
So, that means you too.
I never said do what I do.
I said do what I say.
~ Expressyourself~
Are you such
a fucking loser...
you can't tell
when you've won?
- What'd you call me?
- Nothing.
I didn't make a statement.
I asked a question.
- Would you like me to ask it again?
- Mm-hmm.
Are you such a loser
you can't tell when you've won?
The entire state of Texas...
along with the F.B.I.
are lookin' for you.
Did they find you?
No, they couldn't.
You've won, Seth.
Enjoy it.
-Jacob.
-~ [Stops]
I want you to have
a drink with me. I insist.
To your family.
To yours.
And now,
for your viewing pleasure,
the Mistress of the Macabre,
the Epitome of Evil,
the most sinister woman to ever
dance on the face of this earth.
- [Man] Bite this!
- Lowly dog!
Bow your head.
Kneel and worship...
at the feet
of Santanico Pandemonium!
[Man]
Ooow!
[Man Gasps]
[Hissing]
~ Watching her ~
~ Strolling in the night~
~ So right~
~ Wondering why ~
~ It's only after dark ~
~ Feel her eyes ~
~ The distant firelight ~
~ Burns bright ~
~ Wondering why ~
~ It's only after dark ~
[Continues Hissing]
~ Find myself ~
~ In the room ~
~ Feel the fever ofmy doom ~
~ Falling for her
through the floor ~
~ I'm knocking
on the devil's door ~
~ Yeah ~
~ Burning my internal flame ~
~ Now that they know
her secret name ~
~ You can tell
whose heaven will go ~
~ But she'll be back
and through the gate ~
~ Yeah ~
~ [Stops]
[Cheering]
That's what I call
a fuckin' show!