[MUSIC PLAYS]
[SINGS IN ITALIAN]
[SONG PLAYS OVER SPEAKERS]
Buonasera.
Grazie.
Ballate, ufficiali!
Uno, due, tre.
I can't hoId her much Ionger.
She's taking on too much water.
-What is going on back there?
-Keep your pants on, Murphy.
We bIew the starboard engine.
Port engine's way too hot.
MUNDER: HoId on.
-Shorten the tow or cut her Ioose.
Epps. . .
...get off my damn tugboat.
We don 't have much time.
MURPHY: Move it, Epps. If she sinks,
she's taking us with her.
Got a punch in the port fIoater.
EPPS: Five minutes before she floods.
-Less than that!
Get back here.
We're cutting her Ioose.
-Cut her Ioose.
-That's it. Get back here.
Come on! You heard the man!
Took us three months to get her off
the bottom. I wiII not Iose her now!
Goddamn it, Epps!
You can't fix everything!
Christ!
-For the last time, get back here!
-She's taking on too much water!
Why do you always have to break
my balls? I said get back here!
MURPHY: Do you want me to come down
there and kick your ass? I'll do it.
MURPHY: Here's to the best damn
saIvage crew in the business!
MUNDER: We did it, guys!
SANTOS: Yeah, Iook at that!
MUNDER:
AII right. Nice work.
-Here's to the fucking sea!
-To the sea.
MURPHY:
To a job weII done.
Mr. Murphy? I'm Jack Ferriman. I was
wondering if I couId buy you a drink.
He doesn't drink.
CouId I taIk to you aIone?
You taIk to me, you taIk to my crew.
That's the way it is.
I fIy the Arctic Weather PatroI fIights
out of Mackenzie Bay.
Last month I was out in the middIe
of the Strait when I came across this.
CongratuIations. You found a boat.
In the middIe of the ocean,
of aII pIaces.
I tried for radio contact
and got nothing. . .
. . .so I figured she had to be adrift.
MURPHY:
In the Bering Strait?
That's miIes from shipping Ianes.
Did you aIert the Coast Guard?
It's internationaI waters,
so they noted it and that's it.
You get a name?
No, I put it out of my head untiI
two days ago when I saw it again.
MURPHY: What are we taIking about?
What kind of tonnage?
Big. Huge.
CouId be miIitary.
Let's say that we're
a IittIe bit interested.
MURPHY:
What's in it for you?
I want 20% finder's fee,
whatever she's worth.
-Have you toId anyone eIse about this?
-Not a Iiving souI.
MURPHY: Give us a minute, wiII you?
JACK: Okay.
DODGE:
So? What do you think, Murph?
Who knows? CouId be fuII of shit.
I do know one thing. I've seen strange
things happen in the Strait.
I know something eIse:
Sea gives you an opportunity, take it.
That's at Ieast a week out of our way.
We've been out for six months aIready.
I got a fiancee waiting, remember?
I'm getting married in a month.
PIan was to go back to Anchorage.
Starboard dieseI needs an overhauI.
-In our business, the onIy pIan is:
GROUP: There is no pIan.
If you don't want to go, that's fine.
Let's teII him we'II get somebody eIse.
Wait a minute. Let's not be hasty.
What's a ship Iike that worth?
Who knows?
MiIIions? Thousands? CouId be nothing.
Depends on a Iot of things.
-MainIy, if we have the right to saIvage.
-Pretty big if.
-What's the spIit?
-We spIit it even, six ways.
-Even spIit?
MURPHY: Beats me paying you overtime.
I'm good.
DODGE:
I'm in.
EPPS:
Greer? What do you say?
AII right.
MURPHY:
Hey, Ferriman! Can you come over here?
So this is the way it works.
10% instead of your 20% finder's fee.
I can't Iet you take advantage of me
Iike that.
That's the way it is.
Take it or Ieave it.
Fine. But I go with you.
Not on my boat, you don't.
Think I'd teII you where a fortune
might be without insurance?
There are five other boats
that wouId jump at this.
I come with you.
So you take it or Ieave it.
[HEAVY METAL MUSIC PLAYS]
Ow! Those things are duII!
She'II Iove it. What do you think?
Too much off the sides, but I can
come up with something she'II Iove.
-Shave that yourseIf.
GREER: Don't want to heIp me out?
Who the fuck are you kidding? Everybody
knows you Navy boys take it up the ass.
-Enjoying the ride, Jack?
-No, sir.
Not the same as fIying pIanes
over ice sheets, is it?
-What's the appeaI?
JACK: I couId ask you the same thing.
What's a nice girI doing in a dump
Iike this instead of raising a famiIy?
I own a third of Murphy's operation.
I'm not that nice.
And these monkeys are my famiIy.
SANTOS OVER RADIO:
Santos to Murphy. Come in.
-Yeah?
-I think you shouId get up here.
-What is it?
SANTOS: I think you should see this!
It was there a second ago!
Ten miIes to the northwest.
WouId you turn off that fucking music?
I'm teIIing you, there must be a gIitch.
I saw it with my own eyes.
-GIitch, my ass. There's nothing there.
-Give me a Iook at this.
There it is! Right in front of you!
TeII me you don't see nothing.
SANTOS: Do you see what I'm saying?
Do you see what I'm saying to you?
-Dodge, couId you get on the bow Iight?
DODGE: All right, Murph.
-It's there, right?
-There's something there.
EPPS:
Hey, Murph, what's up?
MURPHY:
Vessel at position 7-5 north...
. . .this is Arctic Warrior.
MURPHY:
Come in.
This is tugboat Arctic Warrior.
Do you read me?
MURPHY:
This is Arctic Warrior.
Do you read me? Come in.
Shit!
SANTOS: Now do you beIieve me?
-HoIy shit!
DODGE: An ocean Iiner?
Where did that come from?
It's the Antonia Graza.
Jesus Christ.
MURPHY: This is civilian tugboat Arctic
Warrior. Is there anyone aboard?
This is civilian tugboat Arctic Warrior.
Is there anyone aboard?
This is Arctic Warrior.
Can you read us?
-You know her, Murphy?
-OnIy in my dreams.
MURPHY:
Christ, she's beautifuI.
ItaIian Iiners couIdn't compete for speed,
so they buiIt fIoating art paIaces instead.
She was reported missing May 21,
1962, off the coast of Labrador.
Funny thing is, there was no distress
signaI. She just disappeared.
Ever since, every captain's been Iooking
for her, hoping she hasn't gone down.
-Do you know what this means?
-What?
Under the Iaw of the sea, she's ours.
Let's not keep a Iady waiting.
MURPHY: Santos, bring us aIongside.
Fire up the crane. We got business to do.
When we get onboard, stay together. We
don't know what kind of shape she's in.
MURPHY: Take us up, Greer.
GREER OVER RADIO: Aye, captain.
Hey, Murphy, pIease remember to keep
aII channeIs open. Thank you.
They won't Iet me go.
Safety first.
That's why you go Iast, Jack.
Can you sit down?
I'm trying to keep this steady.
-I just want--
-Sit down! Get out of the way!
Okay.
She's had some battering over
the Iast 40 years, you can teII.
GREER:
Stand by. Setting you down topside.
She's stiII a beaut.
UnbeIievabIe.
MURPHY:
You better stay aIert. Watch your step.
40 years of rust can turn
deck pIates into quicksand.
We'II make our way in at the fore,
then check the bridge. This way. CarefuI.
EPPS: Forward mast is history.
-Epps and Murphy, are they a coupIe?
HeII, no. She's Iike a daughter to him.
He'd be Iost without her.
MUNDER: Superstructure's in decent
shape. No sign of damage.
EPPS:
Lifeboats are gone, stern to bow.
MUNDER:
Life preserver lockers are empty.
DODGE: Sure no survivors ever
turned up, Murph?
MURPHY: Sure as we're waIking on
the Graza, Dodge. This way.
[HEAVY DOOR OPENS]
Let's go.
Jesus. She's no fiddIer's green.
MURPHY:
You're wrong, Munder. She's beautiful.
Whoever was on here originaIIy
sure Ieft in a hurry.
[STATIC OVER RADIO]
Murphy, come in.
MUNDER:
Whoa.
[MUNDER WHISTLES]
EPPS: Ladies and gentIemen,
weIcome aboard. I'm JuIie.
I'II be your hostess this evening.
[MUNDER SINGS THE LO VE BOA T
THEME, DODGE JOINS IN]
Shh!
Have some respect, okay?
MUNDER:
Check out aII those champagne bottIes.
DODGE: Looks Iike we missed
one heII of a party.
EPPS: And one heII of a hangover.
MURPHY: Shut up!
[TICKING ]
[PENDULUM STRIKES TIME]
[LAUGHING ]
-Shut up!
MURPHY: Let's find the bridge.
EPPS: Such a manIy man.
MUNDER: What?
DODGE: You aII right?
MUNDER: Shut up!
DODGE:
Come on, Mary, Iet's go.
EPPS: Murph, how many passengers
did she carry?
MURPHY: Over 600. The creme de Ia
creme of society from aII over Europe.
Crew of 500 from ItaIy.
TaIk to me. How's everything going?
[STATIC OVER RADIO]
MURPHY: Good. This companionway
shouId get us to the bridge.
Here, Epps, hoId this.
[RUMBLING ]
What's going on?
-After you.
-No, after you.
No, no. After me.
DODGE:
Tough guy.
Don't Iet go!
-PuII! PuII!
-PIease, Epps!
PIease, Epps, don't Iet go!
DODGE: Give me your hand.
-PuII us up!
MUNDER:
Oh, God!
MURPHY:
I toId you to watch your fucking step!
-Oh, shit. Oh, Jesus.
-From now on, you Iet me Iead. Okay?
MURPHY:
Let's go.
-I think I just shit my pants.
DODGE: No, you aIways smeII that way.
Compass is dead.
HeIm's not responding, either.
FueI tanks are empty. She must've rode
on fuII throttIe tiII she was bone-dry.
Epps!
MURPHY:
I'm Iooking for the ship's Iog.
Let's get this documentation back--
-Are you okay?
-Yeah.
-You sure?
Let's get to it.
DODGE:
Hey, check this out.
-It's a watch. CongratuIations, buddy.
-No. Look again, you moron.
It's a digitaI watch. Do the math. They
didn't have digitaI watches in 1962.
So we're not the first peopIe to board
this ship. But she's ours now.
Let's get some sIeep, tow her at dawn.
Let's hope there's no more surprises.
Amen to that.
MURPHY:
Oh, God.
Epps, can I get some tea?
Any sign of what might've happened?
How she got here?
That's the $64 miIIion question,
isn't it?
-Ever hear of the ship Marie Celeste?
-No.
Twin-masted brigantine out of
CharIeston during the CiviI War.
MURPHY: She was bound for London
with a cargo of cotton.
Thanks.
Two months after she set saiI, she was
sighted by fishermen off TripoIi.
She was doing 12 knots an hour
in a stiff breeze.
Something wasn't quite right. They
didn't know what so they went onboard.
You know what they found?
Nothing.
No passengers. No crew. No captain.
MURPHY:
No sign of distress.
59 days after the Iast Iog entry, it had
traveIed 4500 miIes across the ocean. . .
. . .past the Rock of GibraItar and into
the Mediterranean Sea at fuII saiI.
And nobody at the heIm.
MURPHY: What do you make of that?
-A ghost ship.
Hey, you smeII that?
I smeII buIIshit.
-Been on the sea a Iot Ionger than you.
-I know.
Seen things that
you can't even imagine.
Maritime history is fuII of
Marie Celestes.
So, what's our pIan?
I think we shouId do what we came
to do. Tie her up, tug her in.
You think we can puII
this ocean Iiner?
Yeah.
SANTOS:
Not with the probIems we got.
We couId set her at anchor
and come back with two or three tugs.
No, some Russian trawIer
wiII come aIong.
I've aIready Iooked for her anchors,
anyway. They're gone.
-What do you think?
-Get the engines working. . .
. . .it couId take us two weeks
minimum to tow a vesseI this size.
For my share of what she's worth,
I'd drag her back to Anchorage myseIf.
Don't Iet go!
MUNDER:
HeIp me! Don't Iet go!
-Thought you might want a jacket.
-Thanks.
Boy, do I miss that.
You okay? You seem quiet
since you came back.
I think I saw something
I couIdn't possibIy have seen.
-Like what?
-No, it's crazy.
I'm curious. TeII me.
I think I saw a IittIe girI.
On. . . .
On the. . . . The boat?
Yeah. Looking right at me.
JACK:
And then what happened?
Nothing. She disappeared.
Sometimes, when I'd be fIying
for hours on end. . .
. . .I'd think I'd see stuff too.
It'd be there one second
and gone the next. Like a dream.
Thanks.
-See you in the a.m.
-Okay.
Good night.
JACK: See you tomorrow.
EPPS: Yeah.
She's got a big hoIe.
She's sinking.
-This is where the damage is. See?
-Breach in the huII, about 10 by 20. . .
-. . .torn to the port coIIision buIkhead.
-Did it hit an iceberg?
DODGE: No, you don't need an iceberg
to rupture a huII.
I don't know.
-She's been hit recentIy.
-About a week ago, I'd say.
MURPHY:
This is where we are.
The probIem's this group of isIands.
Nothing spectacuIar. . .
. . .just rocks,
a coupIe thousand seaIs.
The Antonia Graza's caught here
in this strong current Ioop. . .
. . .and sIowIy she's been pushed towards
those rocks. Last time she hit them.
-What about next time?
-Won't be one.
We've got three days to fix it.
That's if the weather hoIds.
Why can't we tow it Iike it is?
It'd be Iike towing a car
with four fIat tires.
-It's a bump in the road. We can fix it.
-Murph, bump in the road?
Look, the breach we can probabIy patch
if we can get to the inside.
We'II weId shut the fIooded compartments,
pump out the water up to the aft peak.
On top of that, the rudder's jammed.
MUNDER: We jerry-rig it, set a 38-degree
current drift to cIear the isIand chain.
What does aII that mean?
I just-- That's a Iot
of work for three days.
But with the gear we've got onboard
and what's on that ship, we can try.
We can do it, right?
With the gear we've got onboard,
I can't fix our engine.
Quit bitching and overhauI
the starboard engine.
-So that's the pIan?
-Just do it.
-I'II caII it in.
-I wouIdn't do that if I were you.
-Maritime Iaw states--
-I know.
We just don't want any
unexpected guests. Just Ieave it.
GREER:
Your caII, captain.
EPPS: AII right, you know the driII.
We do a compIete recon.
Make sure we've got no probIems
before we get to work.
MURPHY: Stay with me. Don't wander.
GREER: Okay.
EPPS: Dodge, Munder, go to the port
coIIision buIkhead.
Jack and I'II work back from the fore.
CaII if you need anything.
MUNDER: How about a pizza?
-You're so funny.
The onIy pIan in this business is that
there is no pIan. What is that?
What these peopIe taIking crazy for?
That's not even good EngIish.
That's okay. Hang in there,
okay, preciosa?
Because someday he'II find
some other genius to fix his boat.
[OIL SQUIRTS]
You want to pIay Iike that?
It's stiII sweet, though.
GREER:
Light coming up.
You were right. She is beautifuI.
She sure is.
Epps, we're heading for
the main engine room. Epps?
Epps?
AII right, capitano.
[GROANS]
[KICKS BOTTLE]
SINGS:
I'm just slipping in the darkness
DODGE:
Oh, shit.
We're gonna have to dive
to get to that tear.
Epps, the engine room
is totaIIy fIooded.
Epps, can you hear me?
[STATIC OVER RADIO]
Wait!
What happened? You okay?
JACK: What are you doing down there?
Did you hurt yourseIf?
What are you doing?
The whoIe bottom's riddIed with them.
JACK: Looks Iike someone
used it for target practice.
-That's the happy version.
JACK: What's the not-so-happy version?
There were peopIe in there.
I saw that IittIe girI again.
What? Where?
-I must be Iosing my goddamn mind.
JACK: WeII, did she say anything?
EPPS:
Forget it. Come on.
[WOMAN SINGS IN ITALIAN]
[STATIC n MUSIC OVER RADIO]
Murphy, come in.
Dodge! Anybody!
[SONG PLAYS OVER RADIO]
Shit.
I think she's fucking with us.
[WOMAN SINGS IN ITALIAN]
EPPS:
Looks Iike centraI Iaundry.
This vent connects to the forward hoId.
We need to see if it's fIooded.
-I may need heIp shutting it.
-You sure we need to--?
[EPPS SCREAMS]
Murphy, where the heII are you?
-How Iong have they been here?
-A month, maybe Iess.
-What are we gonna do?
-Get off this boat!
-But the ship--
-If it sinks, it sinks.
You're right.
JACK:
Stinks.
-What the heII?
JACK: We came through there.
EPPS:
No shit!
Come on!
This way. Come on, Jack.
[PLAYS PIANO KEYS]
GREER:
What the--?
When'd you start
wearing Iipstick, Epps?
Epps?
GREER:
Francesca.
Nice titties.
Not that you can hoId a candIe
to the future Mrs. Greer, though.
EPPS: Come on, Jack. Stop dragging ass!
What's your probIem?
JACK:
What's this?
Forget it. Let's go! Jack!
'58 Jaguar X150. I've dreamt
about this car since I was a kid.
We have to get out of here now.
Do you understand? Now.
There's something moving in there.
Fuck!
Oh, my God!
I hate rats!
EPPS:
What?
JACK:
Oh, my God! Look at this!
I have to get Murphy.
Murphy!
JACK:
[STATIC OVER RADIO]
Is someone trying to caII me?
Dodge! Munder!
VOICE:
Maureen....
Who's Maureen?
It's my first name.
VOICE: It's cold....
-He said coId?
The gaIIey.
VOICE 1: It's cold.
VOICE 2: Please help us.
Don't go in there.
[SCREAMING ]
You fucking asshoIes!
Fuck you!
Take it easy!
You were fucking with us. We fucked
with you. Why aren't you Iaughing?
Wanna hear something funnier? We
found dead guys in the Iaundry room.
And this in the cargo hoId.
Need some heIp, skipper?
[JACK GIGGLES]
I'm sorry.
MURPHY: Jesus.
GREER: Oh, man.
MUNDER:
HoIy shit!
[GROUP LAUGHS]
Yeah!
MUNDER:
We're rich!
DODGE: You son of a bitch!
MUNDER: Rich!
MURPHY: Come on. Let's go.
DODGE: Move this shit out!
One. Two. Three. . . .
How much you figure it's worth, boss?
There's a Iot of goId. Hard to know.
Two, 300 miIIion, maybe. Maybe more.
EPPS: Jesus.
GREER: I don't know.
Lock boxes with haIf of Fort Knox
in them? They gotta be insured.
No way somebody wiII Iet
this much goId fIoat away.
WeII, the markings have been
fiIed down.
GREER: What does that mean?
-Someone didn't want this traceabIe.
It's stoIen.
It may have to do with the reason
this ship disappeared when it did.
Wait. If the goId's got
something to do with 1962. . .
. . .what about the bodies? They can't be
more than three weeks oId.
Somebody's gotta say it, and it might as
weII be me. This ship is fucked up.
EarIier I couId swear I heard
a woman singing. It's Iike she was. . . .
-Like she was coming on to me.
DODGE: Oh, no!
It was the sexiest voice
I ever heard, man.
-She got any backup singers?
-Whatever you're on, get me some!
Maybe you're not quite
ready to get married, Greer.
-Fuck you.
EPPS: Okay, guys.
-What about the Coast Guard?
DODGE: No.
You caII the Coast Guard. . . . What if
the goId did turn out to be stoIen?
Under maritime Iaw, anything
found in internationaI waters. . .
. . .beIongs to the finder. Okay?
That is the Iaw.
-Right.
-Finders keepers.
If we're gonna do this,
I say we do it now.
Get our boat going, grab the goId
and get the heII out of here.
We Ieave the boat, take the goId.
Who's with me?
I'm with the goId, man.
GoId.
The goId.
-Epps?
-I just want to get off this boat.
Okay. Let's go to work.
GREER: Warrior is in position, Murph.
Can we please get the hell out of here?
Yeah, preciosa! SmeII that money!
100 miIIion. You hear what I'm saying?
100 miIIion!
Greer? Get those engines going.
MURPHY:
I'm bringing the gold down.
Yes, sir, captain, sir.
Hey, Santos. Hurry your ass up,
vato. We almost got the gold. AndaIe!
I wanna see these gauges rocking,
because you just had an overhauI.
SANTOS: And you, I want you
to give me some too.
Let's do this!
SANTOS:
Hey, yo, Greer! Fire it up!
We're going to hauI ass.
Bring it on! We'II be so fucking rich!
GIRL:
Stop!
Stop! You don't know
what you're doing!
We're good to go, skipper.
Don't start the boats! He'II--
[SCREAMS]
Shit!
Greer!
What the heII happened?
[SANTOS SCREAMS]
DODGE:
Jesus Christ! Fire on deck!
EPPS:
Santos! Greer! Munder!
JACK:
I got you.
JACK: Epps! I got Munder!
-Greer!
Come on!
Santos!
Santos, answer me!
I don't know what happened.
The engine room just bIew.
Maybe Santos rushed the engines,
didn't seaI up the gaskets right. . . .
Jack, did you find anything out about
this ship before you sent us out here?
No, but I. . . . Look, we've got
the goId, and we are stiII aIive.
-TeII that to Santos, asshoIe!
-Ease up!
This is buIIshit!
Santos came here out of free wiII. . .
-. . .just Iike us.
-What does that mean?
-Enough!
DODGE: Santos is dead because of you!
Come on! It's not gonna
bring him back.
Murph, it's not your fauIt.
You know that.
Murph. . . .
DODGE:
How is he?
Here's the pIan. We're professionaI
saIvors with a fortune onboard.
I say we do what we do best:
fix this rust bucket.
ControI her drift. CIear those isIands.
We can survive Iong enough
to get picked up.
Why is this a question?
We have the materiaIs.
Why don't we buiId a raft and Ieave?
There is something wrong with this boat!
-If we stay here, we may not survive.
-You want to buiId a raft?
-I want to buiId a raft.
-Even with the Warrior. . .
. . .we were stretching to do this
in three days. We can't do this.
You're the best spot-weIder I know.
We can do it right now,
but I need you.
Fine. But there's no way we're doing
a major patch-and-pump in the dark.
Even with the Iights we have,
it'd be Iike going in bIind.
Okay, fine. We'II chiII tonight
and go in the a.m.
Greer? What do you say?
Now you want to know what
the first mate has to say?
I say go to heII, Epps. You're not
quaIified to get us off this ship.
Had Murphy Iet me do it my way,
we wouIdn't be in this.
-And the Coast Guard--
-So it's everybody eIse's fauIt, right?
They'd be here and we'd
be on our way home, miIIionaires.
MUNDER:
That's buIIshit.
Grow up, asshoIe.
Fucking bitch! Keep fucking taIking.
Say another word!
[LITTLE GIRL HUMS]
EPPS:
Here it is. Katie. B-deck.
You were aIone.
DODGE OVER RADIO: 100-to-1, someone
poisoned the passengers to get the gold.
MUNDER: Okay, Sherlock, if they were
poisoned, why are these cans safe?
DODGE: They're stiII seaIed.
It's been seaIed for 40 years. It's safe.
MUNDER:
Okay, shoot for it. Loser goes first.
-Ah! Paper beats rock.
-Come on, man, best of three.
-BuIIshit. You Iost.
-Where's your empathy?
Winners do not empathize
with Iosers. Bon appetit.
I screwed up.
GREER:
I shouId've caIIed it in.
Damn! I knew better!
I'II make it home to you, baby.
I swear.
GREER:
What the heII are you Iooking at?
-That's aII right.
DODGE: No way.
No, reaIIy. It's good.
Look, I'm not kidding.
-Are you serious?
-I'm serious. It's good!
-Oh, wow. You gotta try that!
-That's good!
That's great!
Katie?
EPPS:
[DOORS SLAM]
Can I teII you something eIse?
We get back. . .
. . .I'm gonna take my money
and I'm gonna buy you a bathtub.
I'II get you a Iifetime suppIy
of titty magazines and toiIet paper!
I aIready beat you to it, bro!
There's something on your. . . .
Katie?
[DOOR SQUEAKS]
[CLAPPING ]
Buonasera, capitano.
Benvenuto.
Vuoi ballare con me?
-Who, me?
-Si.
Francesca, I know
aII of this isn't reaI.
So I'm just gonna go with it, okay?
Can't cheat on your fiancee
with a dead girI, right?
Her parents.
KATIE:
PIease.
Don't cIose it.
Haven't seen them for years.
They moved to New York.
I was on my way to join them.
But they're dead now.
EPPS: How wouId you know?
-When you're Iike this. . .
. . .you know these things.
My mother. . .
. . .she made me this dress.
Do you Iike it?
You remind me of her.
I don't think so.
WeII, here. You shouId have this back.
Oh, God, you reaIIy are
a fucking ghost.
Where are you going?
Santos. Povero Santos.
Santos was my goddamn responsibiIity.
-The Lorelei.
-She was adrift. We rescued her.
MURPHY:
I've heard the story of the Lorelei.
I didn't know the Graza was invoIved.
The goId was onboard the Lorelei?
It says here May 19, 1962.
That's two days before
your ship disappeared.
There were no survivors
onboard the Lorelei.
Jesus Christ!
Where you going?
Most spirits are free
to be with their famiIies.
So why aren't you with yours?
-We're aII trapped here.
-Who?
My shipmates and I.
KATIE:
Even the ones who aren't marked.
Marked?
Katie, what do you mean?
When the boat's fuII. . . .
What? You can teII me.
When he has aII the souIs he needs
and has fiIIed his quota. . .
. . .we'II aII be ferried. . .
. . .to. . . .
What is it? What's wrong?
-What is it?
-He doesn't want me taIking to you.
-He who?
-But I'm not Iike the others!
EPPS:
You need to teII me.
You must go at once.
Leave the ship whiIe you stiII can!
Katie, what is it?
[KATIE SCREAMS]
Katie! Katie?
MURPHY:
Epps?
Come on!
We have to Ieave.
Where you going, Murphy?
What's the matter? It's me.
Santos.
It's no fun Iying
at the bottom of the ocean.
No Iights at the end of the tunneI.
Not for me, Murph.
No 10,000 virgins at the pearIy gates.
Because of the pIan, I'm trapped
on this dreamboat of yours.
So you know what?
You're coming aIong for the ride.
No!
[THUD]
Benvenuto a bordo.
Murphy?
Murph?
You aII right, Murph?
You okay?
-What's the matter, Murph?
-It's me!
EPPS: It's me!
-Do it, come on. It'II make you feeI good.
Come on!
-Come on!
JACK: Hey!
Oh, God.
Epps, you okay?
JACK: Keep him in the aquarium.
EPPS: No, Iisten. He was drunk.
He didn't know what he was doing.
Look, he just tried to kiII you.
He stays in there.
DODGE:
Let's go find Greer.
EPPS:
Any sign of him?
MUNDER:
No, we Iooked aII over.
DODGE: Man's pissed off.
Seems to happen on this boat.
DODGE: Least we weren't around in '62.
-The passengers were poisoned. . .
-. . .to get to the goId? Isn't that--?
-Extreme? Maybe, but if the shoe fits. . . .
DODGE: Next thing you know,
we'II be trying to kiII each other.
-What's with the heart?
-Found it. BeIonged to this IittIe girI.
-What girI?
-She toId me to get off this boat.
-She's taIking to you now?
-What are you taIking about?
MUNDER: You're seeing ghosts, Epps?
-Just forget it.
So the ship's got a few kinks.
Let's stick with Munder's specs
and try to fix the ship.
No way five peopIe and the goId
wiII fit on any raft.
Murphy's not going anywhere,
and we're not Ieaving him here.
We stick with the pIan. Fix the boat.
Let's get going. Come on.
MUNDER OVER RADIO:
That's the collision bulkhead hatch.
DODGE: Wheel's busted. It won 't open.
EPPS: Arming the C4.
EPPS: Dodge?
DODGE: I'm good.
EPPS: Munder?
MUNDER: I'm good.
EPPS:
Contact.
MUNDER: There's the tear, portside.
DODGE: Looks bigger from here.
MUNDER:
I'll shut her up, no problem.
EPPS:
Munder, rudder's fiixed. You all right?
MUNDER:
I'm good.
EPPS: What do you think, Dodge?
DODGE: She'll hold.
MUNDER: We're set with the pumps.
-Start them up.
MUNDER: Copy that, Epps.
One and two, kicking in.
DODGE: I give it 12 hours tiII she's dry.
MUNDER: Both on fuII.
MUNDER:
Get ready, Epps. Here it comes.
EPPS:
Great work, guys.
Damn. Current's faster than I thought.
If we controI her drift, headed in this
direction, we shouId cIear those isIands.
We'II keep it afIoat
untiI we get picked up.
DODGE: Son of a bitch.
We may just get out of this yet.
KaziIIionaires.
Check on the bridge
when you're done here.
I'II see if I can find Greer
down beIow.
EPPS:
Greer?
Katie?
Greer? Jesus!
-Shit.
-Number two's cIogged. Who's going?
You go.
Shit. Every singIe time!
Oh, my God.
Come with me.
I want to show you something.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
Murphy.
Murphy!
No!
Come on! No!
Come on!
You can't die on me!
Dodge. Murphy's dead.
-What?
-We have to get off this boat.
There's a reason you, me and Munder are
stiII aIive. That's why he came after us.
-To fix his ship.
-I just saw Murphy. What's happening?
I don't know.
I want you and Dodge
on the rudder.
-But you just said--
-Listen to me.
I'II get Munder, we'II see if the weIds
are hoIding. Stay here tiII we get back.
I do not want you out of
each other's sight. Take this.
EPPS:
Take it.
-Be carefuI down there.
-I wiII.
[RUMBLING ]
Munder!
-That's it, then. We made it.
-For now.
-I'II check on Epps.
-No, she said to wait here.
-Yeah, but--
-Hey, she said to wait! So wait.
You disgust me.
-What did you say?
-You heard me.
You're a pathetic excuse for a man.
She says, Jump, and you jump.
You're disgusting.
I don't have time for this.
-Who the heII are you?
-The question is, who are you?
You worship her, yet you've
never had the baIIs to teII her. . .
. . .because you're a weak,
cowardIy chiId.
However, if you'II kindIy step out of
my way, I'II make your dream a reaIity.
You know, Dodge, if you kiII somebody,
you go to heII.
WeII, you Iive for her.
You wiIIing to die for her?
DODGE:
Epps.
I shot Ferriman. He's dead.
Yeah? Don't be so sure, Dodge.
-What are you doing?
-Trip's over. I'm sinking the boat.
-It's taken its Iast victim.
-That'II kiII us.
-We'II have to take our chances.
-What about the goId?
Fucking kidding? We're not getting the
goId off this boat. Nobody ever does.
Wait, wait. Wait!
That goId can give us everything
we ever wanted.
We couId have our own boat.
The two of us.
We couId have a Iife together.
You and me.
What are you taIking about?
Dodge, we gotta get out of here. Now.
WeII, I can't Iet you do that.
So that's it, huh?
AII right. Okay.
You win. AII right.
Fucking bitch!
AII right, you win! Go ahead, do it!
Go ahead. BIow it up!
KiII us aII!
Hey, Dodge. Why haven't you
asked me where Munder is?
WeII, I suppose that's because. . .
. . .I aIready know.
-You won't puII that trigger, Maureen.
-Try me.
Dodge made the same mistake.
He's dead.
Katie toId you, didn't she?
SouIs without sin can't be marked.
Makes them tough to controI.
But as Iong as I keep the boat afIoat,
we'II aII go down together.
-What the fuck are you?
-I'm a saIvager.
Just Iike you.
You coIIect ships, I coIIect souIs.
And when I fiII my quota,
I send a boatIoad home.
This wiII make management happy.
You see, it's a job.
Given to me after a Iifetime of sin.
So if I Iose this ship, management won't
be happy, which is not a good thing.
I'm not getting through to you.
I'm asking for an exchange.
This ship for your Iife.
I want my crew back.
Sorry. Once a passenger's marked,
they're mine.
Then I guess it's over.
[EPPS SCREAMS]
JACK:
AII you had to do was fix the ship!
I gave you a great opportunity.
AII you had to do was take it.
What are you gonna do, shoot me?
[SHIP BLOWS HORN]
[SIRENS WAIL]
CarefuI. Hang in there, ma'am.
No!
DVD Subtitles: GenieGr.999.org
-klepal-