(Siren blaring)
(Youth) You're gonna fuckin' die!
(Shutter clicks)
♪ This is the world we live in
♪ Don't let it take you over
♪ Scream
♪ Safer to live in a dream
♪ ln a dream... ♪
(Radio squeals)
- Jesus!
- Morning, Uncle Jamie.
Lee, how many times have l got to tell you,
when the red light's on, l'm developing.
This ain't digital, this is real photography.
- Real photography. Yeah, yeah!
- lt is!
- (Lee) Got enough light in here, Dad?
- Yeah, l'll take the pictures, Lee.
l have done this before, believe it or not.
(Lee) Oh my days! Give her a happy pill!
What's the matter? Let's show a bit of skin,
yeah? It's what she wants!
- (Εast Εuropean accent) l'm not a porn star.
- No?
No!
l'm sorry...
- (Man) Yeah, good work, Lee. Very subtle.
- What?
Τakes time, you know.
Go and apologise and bring her back in here.
- All right, bruv?
- All right.
The photoshoot from hell, eh?
A favour for Lee. Don't ask.
This girl wants photos to get into
some modelling agency apparently.
More like a brothel
if that fur coat's anything to go by.
Ηey, have a look at these.
Ηave a look.
She's certainly got something, ain't she?
Picking up some pretty girl, Uncle Jamie?
ln your dreams, yeah?
Oi! Get in your car, you.
Oh, Dad, tell Mum l'll be back later.
Gotta deliver the photos.
- What? Now?!
- She won't wait, Dad. She waits for no man.
- Want a lift?
- No, l'm all right, Ray.
- Sure?
- Yeah, l've gotta get some shopping for Mum.
- See you in the morning.
- (Thumping beats on car stereo)
- (Car drives off)
- (Ηorn toots)
(Glass shatters)
(Screech)
(Screeching)
(Fire crackling)
(Screech)
(Roars) Ohh!
(Shutter clicks, film rewinds)
(Screeches)
People will spend a fortune
on their fucking pets, right? Yeah?
But there are children out there
still starving.
l mean, you tell me what that's about.
And another thing, right, these pro-lifers...
Oi, what you doing?!
Where you going, man? What's the point?
l went to school with your brother, man!
Fucking joke.
Yeah, yeah, what does he expect?
l'm gonna go round his mum's house
and go and get the money. l'll bell you back.
You see that, Jamie? You see that?
Not right, man.
Whole community's gone broken.
- You all right?
- l'm all right.
Let me show you something.
Look.
Protection. We all need it, man.
l like you, Jamie.
You're one of the good guys.
You need one?
- No. l'm fine.
- OK, cool.
l got plenty. lf you change your mind,
just say so, OΚ?
l tell you, man. That world out there...
Ηell.
♪ This is what a skin is all about
♪ lt keeps me in and it keeps you out
♪ This is what a skin is all about... ♪
(Youth) Oi, you fucking freak!
lt's the Phantom of the Opera.
(Distant siren)
Oh, hello there.
Sounds like trouble again.
Trouble, trouble, nothing but trouble.
Fire burn and cauldron bubble.
Oh, you live there?
That makes me your new neighbour.
Andy, mates call me AJ.
l'm Jamie...
Ahh... Put Buddha on the books.
Sorry for staring, man. That was rude of me.
No, it's all right.
Good start, AJ.
(Woman) That you?
Yeah, it's me!
Careful, love, plate's hot.
You OΚ, love?
Yeah.
Well, we've got enough of these
to last us a lifetime.
Sorry, Mum. l was miles away.
Well, l've got miles of clingfilm now.
Miles and miles.
- Jamie!
- Κettle's on, Mum.
No, no, look at this.
(ΤV) ..the local community here is in shock
following an incident earlier this evening
when a man and his son were both killed
in an apparently motiveless
and horrific attack.
Molotov cocktails were thrown at them
by a gang of youths wearing hoods.
Father and son were dead
by the time the emergency services arrived.
(Man) Well, these kids, this gang, they came
out from nowhere. Sounded like wild animals.
They were throwing
these burning things at them.
And the man and his kid just went up
like that! The screams... Jesus!
Sir, did you see the faces of the gang?
No, no. Τhey were wearing these masks,
these demon masks.
- Τhey weren't masks!
- Τhere, it's got kids petrified!
- Masks...
- Τhe victims names have yet to be released
but they were believed to have lived here,
Cendrillon Ηouse.
(Mum) Cendrillon Ηouse?
That's where your dad grew up.
(ΤV on quietly)
I feel your dad very close sometimes.
Like he's watching over us. You know?
- lt'll be ten years next week.
- Yeah, next Wednesday.
(Dad) Jamie... Jamie, keep still.
Ah, that'll be a lovely photo.
Ηave that framed,
put it in the front room, yeah?
How would you like that, eh?
(ΤV) ..emerges from its cocoon
the beautiful hero,
and spreads its wings like the star it is,
ready for the start of a new life.
♪ l have seen another sky
♪ l have climbed another tree
♪ l have wished another star
♪ Above another starlit scene
♪ Another me lives another life
♪ l've always dreamed
♪ Another me exists somewhere
♪ Why can't l live that life there?
♪ Please, let me be
♪ The other me... ♪
(Cheering)
lt's from me and Jamie.
l found the negative in that old box of Dad's.
So I printed it out for you.
- And l framed it.
- lt's beautiful.
All right, darling, give her yours.
This for your gran, is it, Charlie?
(Charlie) l made it all by myself.
lt's a magic wand.
Course it is. Just what l always wanted.
It's beautiful.
You gonna show your gran some magic,
darling?
- OΚ.
- Make me young!
Me, me, me! Make me thin.
What do you want, love?
l dunno...
- This is from me, Gran.
- Oh, you shouldn't.
Oh, it's lovely.
lt's real gold.
Thank you.
Where'd you get the money for that?
- Mum says...
- Says what?
She just says you're a bit...distracted.
- (Phone)
- Well, l'm not. l'm fine.
(Lee) Ηello? What do you want?
- Look, if it's the old trouble coming back...
- l'm all right. Can't you see l'm fine?
You fucking bitch!
Oi!
You must have said something.
There's no way she could've found out.
She will kill me.
l knew you couldn't your mouth shut!
- Fucking Jesus!
- Oi! Language! Remember where you are.
- Gran, l'm sorry.
- Oh, you going?
- l'll see you soon.
- Don't you dare!
No, you fucking stay there!
(Screech)
Sorry, man.
Me. Friend.
You OΚ? Yeah?
You know, when l was in a gang...
l'm well out of all that stuff now, you know,
but when l was...
Τhere used to be dangerous areas
and there used to be safe areas, but now...
Now nowhere's safe.
Ηey, why don't we turn that frown of yours
upside down, huh?
Why don't you come out with me for a drink?
Come on, man, you'll be doing me a favour.
For some reason girls think
l'm an ugly bastard.
But if l'm with a hot piece of chilli stuff
like you...
l mean, in a purely platonic way,
you know, then...
Ηuh? What do you say?
What do you think of my suit, man?
You like it?
- Yeah.
- Cost me a fortune.
So if I don't get royally fucked tonight
l'm getting a refund! Κnow what l'm sayin'?
(Chuckles) Was that a laugh?
You got a nice smile, man.
You should use it more often.
(Rock ballad playing)
Come on, man.
You don't have to sit with these guys.
We'll have a nice little chat. Get us a couple
of cocktails, I know a good one.
This one is called a red rondo alla Faust.
OΚ.
(Both cough)
That's hot!
lt don't work unless it burns, man!
So go on, you were telling me about your dad.
I was a star,
like he told me when l was born right,
that he kissed my face
with so much love in his heart...
That's what left the mark, you know?
That's why it's heart-shaped.
Fuck me, it is shaped like a heart, man.
l love it!
You love it? You love it?
But you wouldn't want it though, would you?
- You know what Rilke used to say?
- No, who's that?
German poet. 1 875 to 1 926.
So, yes. l am educating myself, man.
Anyway, this dude Rilke...
- Ηe says that beauty...
- Yeah?
..is the beginning of terror.
No, it's not. No, it's fucking not.
If beauty's the beginning of terror,
then why are kids scared to even look at me?
l can't stand all this "Beauty's
only skin deep" crap. Because it's not.
l can't imagine what it would be like
to meet someone l like
and actually think that, like...
that they might be interested in me.
l'm never gonna feel like that.
I'll tell you what it feels like, right.
lt feels like l've got this parallel life...
l got this life that l'm living
where people look at me and call me names.
And then I got this other life,
where l'm just like you. l'm normal.
And in that life...
ln that life l meet, like,
a beautiful girl and then...
And we do the lot, you know,
we get married, have a nice house.
You know, have a...
have a kid.
A daughter, a beautiful baby girl.
l'd love that.
A chance to be a good dad.
You know, just like my dad was with me.
We pay them to clean the grave.
lt's all right, Mum. We'll get it clean.
That's better.
- (Gasps)
- What?
l've left my scarf with your dad.
You're joking.
- Look, l'll go and get it.
- You sure?
Yeah, l'll meet you back by the gate.
I won't be long.
(Cawing sound)
(Cawing)
(Screeching)
(Screech)
- What's wrong?
- Ηm?
You've hardly spoke since you got me scarf.
You all right?
- You sure?
- Yeah. No, l'm all right.
Listen to me, Jamie.
You are a beautiful young man.
Beautiful, kind and generous.
This has never been your problem.
You know that.
It's just the world, Mum...
l dunno, it just don't make sense to me.
You know, it's like l open up the window
and all this madness flies in.
And it's like l've never really known
how to live in it.
You do what we all do, Jamie.
We love.
And allow ourselves to be loved.
You need a family of your own.
Like your brother.
(Rustling)
- (Snarling)
- Oh, Jamie...
- l know what you are!
l know what you are!
What do you want from me?!
Oh, Jamie, please...
(Snarls)
Jamie!
- Jamie!
- Mum, no!
- Mum! No, please!
- Let go of me! Let go of me! Mum!
- Jamie! Please!
No!
(Screaming)
No! No!
No!
Please! No!
Jamie... You're getting closer, old son.
(Muttering) Εvery time l close my eyes...
Ηe's coming for me.
lt's the drugs.
Can you stand up? Cos we can get out of here,
I can take you home.
l don't want to go home.
But Mum's killers, Ray. Mum's killers.
The police have got your statement.
The police won't do fuck all.
Come on, let's get you up.
The police don't know what this is, right?
They don't know what they're looking for.
l was there, mate.
l was there. l saw what did this.
l saw what did this.
l saw what killed Mum. l know what did this.
- (Lee) Dad?
- l know what did this.
Jamie, you're in shock. You need some rest.
I'm gonna find 'em,
l'm gonna fucking kill 'em!
We should think about finding you
somewhere else to live.
- Τhe memories of this place.
- The memories of this place are fine.
All right? lt's everything else
that's a fucking mess.
Tea...
Just get off my stuff, Lee, all right?
Just don't touch anything.
Why's everyone keep picking on me?
l've lost her too, you know!
l've lost her too...
(Youth) l'll tell you, mate.
She was fucking hot!
- Fucking hot!
- (Raymond) Κeep the bloody noise down!
(Youth) Fuck off, you old bastard!
(Raymond) Show some respect!
(Youth) Fuck off!
(Raymond) l'm not afraid of you!
Look at all Mum's jewellery.
lt's her mum's stuff and her mum's mum's.
Must be worth a small fortune.
(Sobs)
This is the world that we live in!
Makes me fucking mad, right!
They take innocent people,
torture them and then they film it. Why?
No, for fun! No other reason. Fun!
This is the world that we live in.
Drives me mad, man!
(ΤV interviewer) Are you saying
gangs have made stars out of terrorists?
(Sociologist) Yes.
Τerror is the new fashion accessory.
Τhere's a whole new generation out there
that's grown up watching beheadings
on the internet every night.
Τhey all wear the same clothes,
those black hoods, the masks.
- Τhey're not masks.
- These are the new foot soldiers...
in the family of gang culture.
Violence is their mother...
(Distant footsteps)
(lnterviewer) Τheir father?
(Sociologist) Chaos.
- AJ, you all right?
- Just a bit of trouble, man. Don't worry.
What happened? What happened?!
Oh, shit!
- (AJ groaning)
- All right, man. Lift up your T-shirt, yeah?
Jesus Christ!
AJ, we got to get you to a hospital, mate,
you need stitches.
No, no, no, man. Just pad me up,
give me lots of painkillers. That'll do.
lt's like an animal did it.
You said it, man.
A wild fucking monster.
(AJ) l just want to live a normal life.
I don't wanna fight.
So you meet me tonight, let's talk.
OΚ, l'll be there.
- Ηere you go, mate.
- Oh, cheers, man. Thanks.
Cool mobile, eh? Crocodile.
Crocodile.
Our link with the dinosaurs.
You religious, Jamie?
My mum was.
lt's all a load of bollocks, isn't it?
All of it.
Do you know what life really is, Jamie?
A meaningless pile of shitty chaos.
Accepting it - that's the real bravery.
To know that nothing means anything
and still wanna get out of fucking bed.
"God's will"!
There is no God.
lf there's no God
then there's no force of good
and that means that there can't be evil.
And there's definitely evil.
l mean...
There are demons.
Listen, AJ.
You know what's doing all of this, don't you?
l mean, you really know.
l've seen the future, Jamie.
And it's a kingdom of horror.
♪ Τhis is the age
♪ Of the silent child
♪ Who's forgotten his name
♪ And sits alone
♪ Waiting for stories
♪ Τo make sense of things
♪ Τhe darker it gets
♪ Τhe more you see
♪ But it's going to get a lot darker
♪ Before you see me
♪ lt's going to get a lot darker
♪ Before you see me... ♪
(Banging on door)
(Phone rings)
Fuck me, l'm just ringing you!
l've been knocking and knocking.
Where you been?
l just went out... Go to the shops.
Where is it then?
- What?
- Shopping.
What you doing here, anyway? l thought you
gone to Paris, Disney Land, with your dad.
Yeah, well, remedial dwarfs and a mouse
the size of an ape. Fucking nightmare.
- What, he let you come back on your own?
- l'm 1 7, not seven.
Uncle Jamie... You know that gold heart
l got Gran for her birthday?
l never got it engraved.
And now it's on my fucking brain.
Stupid, innit? But l wanna do it now.
For Gran, you know?
Where is it? ln her room?
Oi. Don't go in there!
That's private.
Your dad put all your gran's jewellery
in the safe, back at work.
At work? l never heard him mention that.
Yeah, well, perhaps he had other things
on his mind, Lee, eh?
Well, you know the combination
to the safe, don't you?
Look, l can't talk about this now, all right?
l'm not in the mood.
l wanna engrave it for Gran, Jamie.
It's doing my head in!
Can't you understand that?
(Raymond on machine)
Hey, bruv. Hope you're OK. Listen...
there's been a blow-up with Lee.
He's gone back.
And my credit card's gone missing.
l think the silly sod's got himself mixed up
in some gang stuff...
Typical! My own fucking dad's against me!
No one wants to help.
Why is that? Εh? No one wants to lift
a little fucking finger to help!
Look, Lee. Lee...
- Fuck off!
- Lee!
(ΤV) A father and his ten-year-old son made
a gruesome discovery here yesterday morning,
when they found a human arm
in a place where children sometimes play.
According to police, the wounds
on the severed limb are so savage
it's as if a wild animal did it.
Various other body parts
have been found further along the river,
but with the head still missing
the police are requesting
- if anyone recognises this crocodile tattoo
- AJ...
..found on the victim's left upper arm,
they should contact the police immediately...
(Phone rings)
(ΤV) A photograph has been released
of the suspected gang leader,
Shevannal Maze,
known in the criminal underworld as "She".
22-year-old She damaged his right hand...
- AJ.
- ..while making a bomb at the age of 1 4
and is now reported to wear
a baroque-bladed weapon...
(Ringing)
(Man) Hello, Jamie.
Who is this?
You know where this is, don't you?
Cendrillon Ηouse?
l'm waiting for you. Also...
..remember what your dad used to say.
"We only regret the things we don't do."
(Phone chirps)
(Glass shatters)
(Screech)
(Bang)
(Ηeavy bang)
(Εchoing screech)
(Bang)
(Phone chirps)
Ηello, Jamie. Come in.
Ηe's expecting you.
Papa B...
The world...
don't make sense to you does it, old son?
No.
What if I can show you
the world does make sense?
Sit, Jamie. Sit.
Question. When is man most alive?
When is man most creative?
l will explain.
Belle...
Close your eyes. Relax.
ls man most creative
in a time of peace and calm?
l don't think so.
Give mankind nothing but calm and order,
and mankind's nothing but a zombie,
a grazing cow.
Man needs the unpredictable
to feel truly alive.
To progress. To create.
Mother Nature knows this.
That's why she gives us cyclones, tsunamis.
Sometimes, just sometimes,
Mother Nature, she can't do it all.
So what happens then?
l help.
(Echoing screams and gunfire)
(Screams and gunfire get louder)
Εnough!
Don't! Stop! Stop it!
Say someone comes to me and they want
money, or fame, a second chance.
l say, "l will give you that.
Just give me a splinter of chaos in return."
lt can be big or small.
Dribbling bleach on a baby
or flying planes into nuclear reactors.
Mankind needs atrocity like this.
Think about it, old son.
What triggers have always
shot mankind forward?
Violence.
That's the engine of progress.
Τhat's what blasts man
into the orbit of a new age
and the more random and horrific the better.
Jack the Ripper heralded
the coming of the twentieth century,
not Florence fucking Nightingale.
lt's atrocity that marks the birth
of a new era.
Gas chambers...Ηiroshima...9/1 1 ...
And l, in my humble way,
contribute to the process.
l'm like...the patron saint
of random violence.
The demons?
All mine.
And my mum? My mum?!
No! Jamie, don't!
(Yells)
Feel better, Jamie?
Belle?
Come on, Jamie. Come on.
lt's all right.
I'm sorry about your mother
but her death was necessary.
- Why?
- To make you ready, old son.
To bring you to me.
l've been watching you, Jamie.
l thought you might be ready
for making a deal.
A deal?
What's your wish, Jamie?
(Growls)
You can have anything.
You can have what you've always wanted.
l'll get rid of this.
l'll make you...beautiful.
Fuck you! Fuck you!
Jamie, stop!
- l don't want anything to do with him.
- Your mum. It's what she wanted.
Remember what she said.
She wanted you to find someone to love.
Ηave a family.
Like your brother.
lt'll be OΚ.
- So what would l have to do?
- Chaos, Jamie. You contribute.
You help my world evolve.
Yeah? Well how, exactly?
- Graffiti.
- What? Graffiti?
Really, Papa?
Yeah, why not?
Make it easy on the boy.
That sound all right, does it, Jamie?
Once every few months you
just scrawl on a wall, "God is a stupid fuck!"
- What, and that's it?
- That's it.
So we have a deal.
Yeah.
Belle...the cocktail cabinet.
Ηow many, Papa?
Just the one.
What's this?
The lighter, Belle.
- What am l supposed to do with this?
- Light it, old son.
The fire will burn away the old.
You'll arise anew.
lt won't hurt for long, Jamie.
l promise.
Let it go, old son.
Let it go, Jamie.
Let the fire burn away the old.
Arise anew.
Think Phoenix!
(Screams)
(Slurps)
(Gasps)
(Κnocking)
- (Belle) Can l come in, Jamie?
- Yeah, come in.
Some new clothes for you.
Thank you.
Papa B says you're to wait for Weapons Man.
- Weapons Man?
- Yeah.
Ηe'll help you with your part of the deal.
Don't worry.
Some people wait over 60 years for him.
Ηey, what's wrong? You OΚ?
Yeah, l'm fine.
You should go before Papa B gets back.
Ηe gets angry sometimes.
(Εlectrical humming)
(Youth) Oi, look who it is.
lt's the elephant man.
Come here!
- Come here!
- Ah, he's hiding!
(Continue shouting)
- What!
- What?
What you laughing at?
What are you laughing at?
Ηello? Ηello?
ls it Temple Buildings?
Yeah. No, it is.
- Εrm, 27?
- Yeah, just that one there.
Oh, thanks,
l've been walking up and down for ages...
Delivery! Please be in.
ls that for AJ?
Andy Jeffries. Sounds like an AJ to me.
Yeah, it's just l know he's gone away,
so he's not in.
- Can l ask you a favour?
- Yeah.
Could you sign for this?
Well, l don't think l should.
OΚ.
Are you sure you're all right?
You don't want to sit down?
No, l'll get fired.
All right. OΚ.
Whoa, whoa. Let me take that.
All right, let me take that.
Are you sure you don't want
to just sit down for five minutes?
l'll get you a glass of water.
- There you go.
- Τhanks.
l have a feeling...
That we've met before?
- Yes.
- Yes. No, no, we have.
We did. When l met you l had a... l had a...
Well, it's actually quite difficult
to explain.
Ah, perhaps don't explain.
The past - we'll wipe it clean.
My name is Tia.
l'm Jamie.
- What is this?
- What's that?
- lt's a magical tree.
- No, it's Victoria Park actually.
lt's beautiful.
That's me sitting there. My dad took that.
You were cute!
Yeah, well, l think he might have got
my good side.
- Your dad was a professional photographer?
- Yeah, he was. Yeah.
l'm interested in photography too.
- You're kidding, are you?
- Yes. l never go anywhere without this.
lt's not very good.
No, no, it's great.
At least it's a film camera.
Of course. Digital!
Digital!
Oh, man, digital is like a rough sketch.
You know, whereas film's... Film's like...
Caravaggio...
Εxactly!
Ηere, look. Let me show you something.
This... This is the first camera
my Dad bought me.
You can see l'm holding it
in that picture there.
Τhis is without doubt, right,
without doubt my favourite camera.
You know, if you want, we could go out
and I could show you how to use it.
OΚ.
Tia, look...
Look, we have met before.
But I was different then.
You know, l used to have this birthmark
right across the side of my face.
l can't explain what happened.
But it just went.
Just disappeared, you know.
lt was like magic.
Look. l can show you, look.
lt's right on this picture here.
Look, if you look all down the left side
of my face you can see it there, Tia. Tia...
Tia?
Tia! Tia, please!
Look, l know it feels
like we're moving too fast,
but you just have to trust me, please.
Please.
Look, my Dad said, "You only regret
the things that you don't do."
So don't walk away.
You could phone work, you know.
You could chuck in your job,
you could throw all the rules
and all the things you're supposed to do
and just chuck them out the window.
l just... l just wanna spend a day with you.
This is the tree here, see? Look at that.
Look, remember what l told you, right?
You just gotta turn...turn the lens
at the front there, to get it in focus.
- lt looks different.
- What? Less magical?
- Yeah!
- You just gotta change the angle.
Look, come here.
Just change the angle.
Come down low, like that.
Try it now.
lt works.
Εverything can look magical if you just...
lf you just look at it the right way.
Εxactly. Ηere.
Go on, look at the camera.
Go on, look at it.
Big smile.
Perfect.
(Tia) l like it here. Like heaven.
(Jamie) Yeah, it is.
My dad, he used to love this place.
You know, we'd just come out here
and we'd just take photographs and just talk.
You know, my dad was
one of them people that just...
Just made sense of the world.
And he'd come up with
all these great stories, that...
l dunno, you know?
Just, they made sense to me.
l'd do anything to go back to that day.
Just for like, a minute...
A second, even.
Look, l'll tell you what l'll do,
l'll take them to the studio
and l'll get some prints developed.
You know, l'd like to do that.
Then we can remember the day.
Well, thank you, Tia. l had a good day.
Tia, will l see you again, though?
Tia, can l see you tomorrow?
Come on, at seven o'clock?
Tia, will you come to the flat?
Come on, please, say yes!
Yes.
(Laughing) Yes!
(Κnocking)
(Laughs)
Mr Morgan?
- Yeah...
- You're expecting me, l believe.
Weapons Man?
Oh, right.
- May I come in?
- Yeah. Yeah, please.
Very nice.
l detect a woman's touch.
Yucca.
Very stylish.
(Sniffs) Oh... My wife would like that.
She's got me to redecorate our bathroom.
She wants it done out in gold taps
and marble floor.
Fake gold and marble, needless to say.
Still cost a fucking arm and a leg, though.
Not to my taste.
Looks like the fucking Palace of Versailles,
you want my opinion.
She soaks herself morning, noon and night
in lavender and bergamot bubble bath.
She says, "l feel like Marie Antoinette."
l say, "Well you know what happened to her."
She don't. She will. l've made plans.
There's a kid l know who's a dab hand
with a chainsaw. lt's a beautiful weapon.
Talking of weapons... Business.
Sorry, yeah, it's just, Belle said it could
take up to 60 years for you to come visit.
Yeah. lt could.
lt didn't.
All this technology makes life so much easier.
Years ago it was all pens and paper and...
Oh! Ηere we go!
Sit down.
Now, just a few formalities.
lt's boring l know, but bear with me.
So your name is Jamie Morgan.
- Yes.
- Any middle name?
- No.
- Address?
l know that, l'm here, ain't l?
- Age?
- Εr, 25.
ln your prime, l see. No peeking!
Now, my job is to make sure
the element of chaos you contribute
doesn't clash with any other
elements of chaos in your area.
lt also helps keep your particular
contribution unique and distinctive.
One brutal murder. Just one.
- Ηow's that sound?
- No, no, l'm, er, doing graffiti.
- That's the deal you did with Papa B, is it?
- Yeah.
What, and you believed him, did ya?
- What?
- (Laughing)
One born every minute. Priceless.
Graffiti!
You saying that he lied?
Of course he fucking lied!
That's not exactly fair now, is it!
Of course it ain't fucking fair!
Who said life is fucking fair?
Life is cruel and unjust
and we wiggle like worms on the hook of...
Oh, who gives a fuck!
Let's just cut the crap and move on, shall we?
l repeat - one brutal murder.
That is very reasonable.
Now, let's find out the victim's profile.
Well, very good. Young male.
Lets find out when the murder should happen.
Mm. When the moon is next full. Very classy.
Sorry, is there any chance
we could talk to Papa B about that?
No. Method of dispatch...
Oh... Yeah, this is bloody good.
Or should l say good and bloody?
"Ηeart to be cut out while the victim
is still alive
"and said heart to be placed on steps of
church, any church, your choice, by midnight."
By the last chime, you got that?
One second, one millisecond later
and that won't do, Mr Morgan. You got that?
l don't understand.
l don't actually think l can hurt anybody.
Priceless again. Anyone can hurt anyone,
Mr Morgan. Ηaven't you learnt that?
Now, to my favourite bit.
Finding the weapon.
Years ago, this was all l did. Ηence the name.
But since Jack the Ripper
things have got a little bit more, well...
inventive, shall we say.
Oh... We're lucky.
The weapon's in the flat.
What?
Oh... Oh, hold up!
(Laughs) Oh...
Oh! lt's in here.
Getting warmer.
Oh, hotter...
What have we got here?
No! That's my dad's coat! That's my dad's
stuff from when he went travelling.
Will you let me do my job, please!
Thank you.
- (Breathes heavily)
- (Bones crack)
Weapon found.
No, my dad loved that.
lt was from his first ever trip. Please...
And it's been waiting for you ever since.
So, that's it.
One heart to be cut out
when the moon is still full
and placed on the steps of a church
before the final stroke of midnight.
lt's a pleasure doing business with you,
Mr Morgan.
No, l won't do it.
l'm serious, all right? l won't do it!
This isn't the deal that l made!
Τhis isn't fair!
Look, come on, it's not fair!
You can't expect me to actually kill somebody!
Look, please... Can you just
speak to Papa B for me? Please.
Ηello, sir.
Yeah, fine, sir. lt's just there's...
There's a little last-minute reluctance
from the client.
Thank you, sir. Much appreciated.
What's going on? What did he say?
Just a moment, please.
Ah! No! No! No!
(Grunts and coughs)
Ah! Make it stop! Please!
- Not much fun, is it?
- Please! Make it stop!
(Coughing)
- Please...
- You gonna do it?
Yeah! Yeah, yeah! l'll do it!
l'll do it! Please!
We got there in the end, Mr Morgan.
(Jamie gasping) l'll do it...
Oh, by the way...
Guess when the moon is next full.
Tonight.
You got till midnight.
(Sobbing)
Belle...
l tried to help but...he got mad.
Come on, Belle...
lt's OΚ.
Ηe'll kill us both if you don't do it.
l don't know how to kill.
l don't know how to...
First, find your prey.
What you doing? l didn't do anything.
l paid money to get in there.
(Bouncer) Fuck off!
(Music playing in nightclub)
(Drunken shouting)
Fucking cheapskate!
You don't know what you're missing.
l'm fuckin' perfection!
Jeeko sex machine! That's me!
Jamie...
Go on...
Go! Go!
- Ηello, handsome.
- All right.
- I just wanted to...
- Like what you see, do you?
Course you do.
You know perfection when you see it.
Look at that six pack. Wanna touch?
lt'll cost you.
- Ηow much?
- Depends on where you touch, mate.
And how long you touch it for. And what you
touch it with, if you catch my drift.
- Location's important, too.
- What?
Well, is it a down-the-alley touch here,
or an indoors touch?
lndoors, Jamie! Your place.
lndoors. lndoors, good idea.
Εrm, indoors, we'll do it at my place.
lndoors costs more
and l get my taxi fare there and back
and the price of a kebab and a Diet Coke.
For you, in total, 1 50 quid,
if we get it all done in an hour.
An hour? All right, that's good.
We've only got an hour.
Well, perfect.
Ooh... Very nice.
You own it, do you?
Worth a fortune now, these places.
Oh... You never thought you'd be lucky enough
to get someone like me, did you?
People don't. I've had grown men
weep at the thought of touching my feet.
Yuccas... Εugh!
"Ηope in the Lord,
the bleeding heart of Jesus."
Can you just put that down?
Please, just put that down.
Don't back out, Jamie.
- l won't.
- Oh, come on, don't get all guilt-ridden.
- Εh?
- Don't say, "l won't." Say, "l will!"
You mustn't be afraid. OΚ?
You've just gotta go for it.
So, what do you want?
Look, l want you to just stop
touching everything.
Please, it's just personal.
Be brave.
Whatever it is, that's what l'm here for.
So... Say it!
Come on!
You've now only got 40 minutes.
You need him to keep still.
l just need you to keep still, please.
Oh, l get it. Passive beauty, eh?
What is it? Ηandcuffs?
(Whimpering) Oh, don't-don't-don't hurt me!
Tie-Tie me...
(Laughs)
Can you get off the chair?
Come on. Describe how you want me.
Ηuh? Εxactly...
Silent and still.
Silent. l need you still.
- And silent.
- Now l'm with you, sunshine.
The old mummified game.
Surprising how popular that is these days.
I wouldn't have thought it
from a first timer but, hey-ho.
Why not jump in at the deep end, eh?
We'll have to improvise.
- Clingfilm!
- What?
lt'll work if there's enough.
Just leave a gap for my eyes and nose.
l like to see what's going on.
And not too long -
the skin needs air, you know?
Oh, and if l make this noise -
"Mmmmm!"
That's the signal to stop...
whatever you're doing.
- Understood?
- Yeah, understood.
35 minutes!
(Siren blaring outside)
Mmm! Gonna have a good time.
(Jeeko) Mm-mm-mm!
(Jeeko laughing)
(Laughing)
- Mm?
- Forgive me...
(Panicked grunting)
(Heavy bang)
You'll never do it in there.
Take him to the kitchen.
(Grunting)
(Jamie roars)
(Screams in agony)
(Jeeko groaning)
- (Screaming)
- (Ηeartbeats)
- (Ticking)
- Run!
(Clock strikes)
(Clock strikes twelve)
(Grunting)
Boo! (Laughs)
You've been sleeping all day, Jamie.
- Ηave l?
- Yeah!
I've cleaned all the mess from the flat
and l bought some new clothes for you.
Come and try them on.
Come on!
It's nearly seven o'clock,
Tia will be here any minute.
Wow...
- l dunno, what do you think?
- lt's amazing. lt looks really good.
- There's just one thing.
- What's that?
You haven't brushed your hair properly.
Let me do it for you.
Please, Dad.
- Ηow's that?
- Great.
(Κnocking)
Oh God, it's Tia. My God, she's here!
Listen, Belle, what are you gonna do?
You gonna be OK?
Don't worry about me. You go and have fun.
lt's the start of your new life, Dad.
♪ When l walk down the street
♪ Τhey set fire to me
♪ Τhey struck the match, it helped me hatch
♪ Made me ignite and l took flight
♪ l will feel it, in diamond night sky... ♪
You're beautiful.
(Whimpers)
- (Tia) Jamie? Are you OΚ?
- Yeah, l'm fine. l'm fine...
Please, Tia, you can't see me like this.
What do you mean? You're worrying me!
OΚ! OΚ. OΚ...
- Jamie...
- OΚ...
- l'm just scared of what you might think.
l don't care what you look like.
Just open the door.
Please...
(Screeches)
(Phone ringing)
(Raymond) Hey, bruv. l just wanted to say...
we all still feel guilty about rushing off.
But we just need to get away
but we'll be back soon and, well...
everything's gonna be just fine from now on.
You'll see.
♪ Your heart beats like a hammer
♪ At the bottom of the ocean
♪ lt wakes the sleeping serpent
♪ Whose blood's a magic potion... ♪
lt means a lot to me.
lt's my family.
♪ Your laughter turns to sparkles
♪ Oh, that's where starlight comes from
♪ ln you are all the stories
♪ l ever need to hear
♪ My happy ever after
♪ My once upon a time
♪ All the stories
♪ All the stories... ♪
(Belle) Ηey, Dad.
- Ηey, Belle.
- Did you have a nice time?
Yeah, yeah. Tia's just dropped off to sleep.
What are you doing there?
- What's this?
- l made it, all by myself.
You did all this? lt's amazing, look at that.
- Don't touch!
- Oh, l'm sorry.
- That's you, Dad...
- Uh-huh.
- That's me...
- Right.
That's Tia...
Mum.
We're a family now.
Εverything's perfect.
Yeah, you're right.
Εverything is perfect.
(Screeching)
- lt's Papa B!
- Jamie!
- Ηe's on the roof!
You've stolen my Belle.
Come on, it's not like that.
Don't play games with me.
lt's not that l'm too bothered.
Silly little bitch wants to live with you,
let her go.
Ηm!
But l can't let it go unpunished.
You understand.
What do you want of me?
Κill for me. Again.
By midnight.
l want another heart.
l've already done that.
You keep changing the fucking rules!
l make the fucking rules
and l've chosen the victim.
l love her.
You can't make me do that.
You can't make me do that!
- Shh...
- You can't make me do that.
Let me explain...
old son.
What do you see out there, eh?
A city, full of people, all yearning for love.
All believing love is eternal.
But love ain't eternal.
Only suffering can be eternal.
(Roars)
(Screeches)
(Car alarms)
- No...
- You know who this is?
(Sobbing) AJ.
Jamie...
You see, Jamie?
Unhappy ever after.
No... No... No...
(AJ) Please, no.
No!
The kingdom of horror is here...
(Muttering)
The kingdom of horror.
(Tia) l know, l know. You know why
l'm sounding upset. l can't help it.
(Belle) She's awake.
(Tia) That's the way l feel, yes.
Sorry. l can't do it here, Belle.
(Tia) l'll do it. l will. l will.
Jamie. Where have you been?
l just put the rubbish out.
- You OΚ?
- Yeah. No, l'm fine. l'm fine.
That was a good friend of mine.
Ηer apartment got broken into last night.
Robbed.
While she sleep.
I know it is stupid
but can l put my book of photographs
in your safe at work, now?
It is precious to me, Jamie.
l won't sleep tonight with worry.
Please...
You can kill her there.
Say yes.
Yeah. Yeah. That's fine.
Jamie, l wanted you to know...
When l first met you, l didn't think
l would fall in love with you...
And l did.
You've got a beautiful heart, Jamie.
And l will always love you,
no matter what happens after this.
After this?
What do you mean, after this?
Oh, come on, what do you know?
Do you know what happened...
Just open the safe, Jamie. Please.
- Why did you say "after this"?
- Look at the time! Kill her!
- You've got to get out of here.
- What?
- You've got to go, Tia. Please, go!
- Why?
Because it's not safe for you here.
- No!
- You're in danger.
- From what?
- From me.
You're running out of time! Κill her!
l can't!
- Κill her!
- l just can't!
- What are you saying, Jamie?
- Κill her!
- Just open the fucking safe.
- Stay out of it, Lee!
Shut it!
lt's all your talking that fucked it up!
Stupid plan. You and him, this!
That's what you thought.
But it wasn't, was it?
Worked like a fucking dream.
- What the fuck's going on?!
- Ηe stole from the gang.
l didn't steal, l was gonna pay it back!
lf you hadn't told She
he'd never have found out! You stupid whore!
- l'm not a whore!
- Don't lie!
You're a whore
and he's just another fuck for money.
- No!
- What?
l just did this to help Lee.
l love you, Jamie.
Tia, please... Please don't...
(Tia) Ηe needs to get the jewellery
to pay back the gang.
lf he doesn't get it by tonight,
we're all dead.
Don't look at me like that.
lf you'd opened the safe when l first asked
none of this would have fucking happened.
- (Rattling)
- lt's She!
Just open it! Open the fucking safe!
Lee! What are you fucking doing?!
Get the fuck off!
(Gunshot)
Tia! Tia! No, please...
No, please...
Oh, God... What have you fucking done?!
Fuck!
No! Please, God!
No! Please, God, no!
Please! God, no! Please...
(Gunshot)
(Lee) Jamie!
Jamie!
(She grunting)
(Roars)
(Screams)
You're gonna fucking die!
(Lee) Jamie!
Jamie!
(Screaming)
l'm sorry.
She said he'd kill you all, one by one.
Burn you alive...
like he burnt Gran.
What?
(Belle) Ηe's lying!
(Scream echoing)
Jamie...
- Demons! Run!
- Jamie...
- Run!
- Don't let them hurt me! Jamie!
Κeep running! Κeep running!
Dad!
Belle, you have to go.
Go! Go! You have to get out!
l'm not leaving you!
They're not interested in you, OΚ?
It's me that they want.
You can be happy somewhere else!
- Dad...
- Just go, Belle, please. Just go!
No! l won't ever be happy without you.
Not ever!
We all lose people, you understand?
OK? But we have to let them go.
We have to.
l love you, Dad.
lf you love me, then you'll let me go.
Go on, let me go. Yeah?
(Demons screeching)
I had this birthmark,
right across the side of my face.
Just disappeared, you know?
lt was like magic.
You're beautiful.
(Crash)
(Glass shattering)
(Snarling)
Come on... Come on!
Come on! Fucking come on!
Fucking come on, then!
(Snarls)
Come on!
(Screeching)
(Roars)
(Man) Well, these kids, this gang, they came
out from nowhere. Sounded like wild animals.
They were throwing
these burning things at them.
And the man and his kid just went up
like that! The screams... Jesus!
(Reporter)
Sir, did you see the faces of the gang?
No, no. Τhey were wearing these masks,
these demon masks.
- They weren't masks!
- Τhere, it's got kids petrified!
l'm not afraid of you any more.
No?
No.
Don't work unless you're scared...
old son.
(Birdsong)
You're gonna fucking die!
(Dad) Jamie...
Jamie!
Κeep still.
Oh, that'll be a lovely photo.
Ηave that framed. Put it in the front room.
Would you like that? Εh?
- (Boy) That boy's face!
- Come on.
Ηave I ever told you about
the night l slept in a forest?
l was only a little bit older than you.
l'd gone there with Dad to take some photos.
l'd never been out of the city,
not at night, l hadn't.
So we made this little camp, yeah?
And that night l looked up...
Cor... Stars!
l'd never seen so many.
Sky was blazing with them.
Dad explained,
you need real dark to see stars.
Because in the city there's
too many street lamps and stuff, see, so...
But when things are really dark,
as dark as they can get,
you see so much more,
so many wonderful things.
Sometimes, old son...
things are gonna get darker for you
than they do for the rest of us.
But you've got to...
You got to see those moments
as something special.
Because they're showing you things.
A way of looking at the world
that no one else will ever, ever understand.
That's a blessing, Jamie.
That's not a curse...
Does that make sense?
l love you, Dad.
l love you, Jamie.
l'll always love you.
lt'll never go.
Come on, old son, let's get you home.
Your mum will be waiting for us.
Oh, Dad...
Dad, you're right.
You're right!
lt is beautiful.
♪ When l woke up this morning,
the trees didn't work
♪ Birdsong had turned to gunfire
and the stars were in the dirt
♪ Snow feels like a heatwave
♪ Sunshine feels like rain
♪ lf a feather touches my skin,
it causes me pain
♪ Come back, come back
♪ And make the world work again
♪ Come back and put an end to all this mess
♪ Come back and prove
the world's not heartless
♪ The air is thick as tar
and my skin is bruised and stung
♪ l try and talk
but no one understands my tongue
♪ With every passing second
♪ l age a million years
♪ When l fall and graze my knees
♪ The universe cheers
♪ Come back, come back
♪ And make the world work again
♪ Come back and put an end to all this mess
♪ Come back and prove
the world's not heartless
♪ When l call your name out
♪ lt turns to shrapnel in my mouth
♪ And the last time l looked up
the north star was south
♪ Come back, come back
♪ And make the world work again
♪ Come back and put an end to all this mess
♪ Come back and prove
the world's not heartless
♪ Heartless