(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN:
What's your pleasure, Mr. Cotton?
The box.
(FLY BUZZING)
Take it, it's yours.
It always was.
(WOOD CREAKING)
(SCREAMING)
- (FLY BUZZING)
- (VOICES WHISPERING)
(GROANING)
(SNARLS)
(RASPY BREATHING)
(KEY RATTLING)
MAN: It's gotta be one of these.
JULIA:
I'm going to freeze to death.
- Okay, okay.
- Well, maybe somebody changed the lock.
Like who?
Who's gonna change this lock?
Well, I don't know.
It was just a suggestion.
Ah. Success.
Voila.
Well, this is it...
the old homestead.
Yuck. It smells damp.
Well, it's... been empty
for a while, hasn't it?
But we'll soon warm it up
and get it feeling like a home.
How long since you were here?
Oh, the better part of 10 years.
I wanted to sell it after
the old lady died,
but I couldn't get Frank to agree.
I guess he needed a
hideout or something.
Would you look at this?
And don't worry,
this stuff means nothing to me.
It all goes.
I thought half of it
was your brother's.
I've never known him to kick
cash out of bed. Besides...
He's probably behind
bars someplace.
You know...
We have to let Kirsty
see this place
before we do a thing to it.
She'll love it.
You really want to move in here?
You don't like it?
I suppose it's better
than Brooklyn.
Oh, don't start, Julia.
- Don't start what?
- Look.
We can make it work here.
Now I've got a terrific job,
you're back on your own turf...
We can be happy.
- All right, all right.
- So what's the argument?
- No argument.
- Oh, Christ!
MAN: Honey...
(WHISPERS) Shit.
(BUGS CHITTERING)
Larry! Larry!
- Where are you?
- In here.
Squatters?
Frank.
- He's here?
- Well, he's been here.
I mean, there's stuff in the
kitchen you wouldn't believe.
He's obviously made one
of his famous getaways.
(PHONE RINGING)
What the hell is that?
- Who is this?
- KIRSTY: Dad.
- Kirsty!
- I got through.
- Barely. Where are you?
- I found a room.
- You what?
- I said, I found a room.
Wait, I thought you
were going to stay
- with us for a while.
- Dad.
Well, you'd like this house.
You'd like my room.
I'd really like you to see
this house. It's something else.
Maybe in the next couple of days.
I gotta find myself a job.
What for, sweetie?
Look, you've already made the
gesture, there's no need...
dad, this isn't a gesture.
This is something I need to do.
Come on and trust
me a little, okay?
- Call me tomorrow.
- I will. I'll see you.
Bye, dad.
So?
Why not?
Great.
We'll move in on Sunday.
LARRY: Listen, look out for the
molding on the way through here.
- LARRY: All right.
- MAN: All right.
- LARRY: Are you all right back there?
- Yeah yeah.
LARRY:
All right, okay. Now just take it
straight up the stairs.
Don't worry, it'll get through.
- All right. What's the matter?
- Hey, you got my arm!
- LARRY: All right, all right.
- Oh, God.
- MAN: Watch it.
- LARRY: Oh.
Let's take five, guys.
How's things in there?
- Looks like a bomb dropped.
- You got any beer?
There's some in the fridge.
Oh, well...
Why don't I get it?
I've got nothing better to do.
Excuse me.
- My lucky day.
- Hi.
- Do you wanna buy a bed?
- Not much.
Dad?
- LARRY: Kirsty!
- Hi.
Hello, sweetie. Come here.
- Here you go.
- MAN: Oh, great.
This is a big house.
- You like?
- Yeah.
Me like.
I'll give you the grand tour if we
ever get this goddamn bed moved.
- Is Julia here?
- She's upstairs.
Look, be gentle with her, okay?
- She hates moving.
- Surprise.
- Kirsty.
- Okay, all right. I'll be nice.
You get on with the grunt work
- and I'll make myself some coffee.
- That's a great idea.
- There's the kitchen.
- Okay.
Bye.
- Is that your daughter?
- Uh-huh.
- Got her mother's looks.
- Her mother's dead.
Oh.
(PIPES RATTLING)
Come on.
Oh, shit.
FRANK: Can I come in?
Can I come in?
- You're Julia, right?
- That's right.
Who are you?
I'm Frank.
I'm brother Frank.
Oh, yes!
I... I came for the wedding.
Well, can I come in or not?
I'm sorry. Of course.
You're very welcome.
Yeah. Well, that's nice to know.
Do you have a towel?
KIRSTY: Have you got a towel?
Kirsty.
There's one in the bathroom.
Oh, by the way, did daddy
tell you I got a room?
It's not that big, but it's okay.
Julia?
- Julia?
- (WOOD CREAKING)
(VOICES WHISPERING)
FRANK: What shall we drink to?
Wedded bliss?
I'm very happy.
I'm sure you are.
You're gonna let me kiss the bride?
JULIA'S VOICE: What about Larry?
Forget him.
(MOANING)
(EERIE VOICE WHISPERING)
Julia Julia Julia...
I need to... take the weight
away from me, my foot's caught.
- You got it?
- I got it.
Now just push it to me as I pull.
(BOTH MOANING)
(YELLS)
It's never enough.
Julia. Jul...
Please.
I'll do anything you want.
(WHISPERS) Anything.
Here.
Oh, is it deep?
I don't know. I haven't looked.
You know me and blood.
- I'm gonna faint.
- You're not going to faint.
Oh, shit!
- L... le... let me see.
- Shit!
Oh, it's going to need stitches.
- I'm gonna throw up.
- You're not going to throw up.
- Just take it easy, just take it easy.
- I'm gonna throw up.
- It's going to be all right.
- (MOANING)
Let's get you to the hospital.
- LARRY: So stupid.
- (HEART BEATING)
What happened?
It was just an accident.
He's all right.
Look, will you drive?
He needs stitches.
- Yeah, sure.
- The keys are in the kitchen.
- So stupid.
- It's all right.
LARRY: So stupid.
(BOARDS CREAKING)
(SQUEAKS)
(SCREAMS)
- (PEOPLE LAUGHING)
- LARRY: No no, I'm not... I am not kidding.
This doctor is poking around
with all the delicacy and
compassion of Josef Mengele,
and I'm warning him, "listen,
I'm gonna pass out."
He says, "oh no, of course you're not
old boy. Of course you're not."
The next thing you know,
I'm on the floor
and he's standing there like
he's the one who needs help.
MAN: He probably is afraid
you're gonna sue him.
I should do it! Bill, I should do it.
You know all about that stuff.
I'll call you tomorrow.
We'll sue his ass.
(ALL LAUGHING)
- Doctors.
- That's right, honey.
LARRY: And what's my
darling daughter drinking?
JULIA: I don't remember.
Listen, Julia,
you want some more bubbly?
Uh no. No more for me, thanks.
Okay. Okay, stop.
- I'm not gonna be able to stand up.
- So lie down.
(MAN LAUGHS)
Would you all excuse me?
I think I'm going to go to bed.
- Are you all right, darling?
- Uh-huh.
I think we ought to
be making a move, too.
LARRY: No... bill!
Absolutely not!
This is the night of
the paper hats here.
We're celebrating
something, so sit down.
Good night.
You'll have to come to us next.
WOMAN: Yeah, real soon.
I'm glad you're back.
Thank you.
- Good night.
- WOMAN: Does it still hurt?
- What?
Oh.
No, only when I drink.
- (ALL LAUGH)
- (WET THUMPING)
(BOARDS CREAKING)
(EERIE WHISPERING)
(WHISPERING STOPS)
(HEART BEATING)
(SQUEAKS)
Oh, God.
Oh! Christ!
(SCREAMING)
Julia.
Oh my God.
Don't look at me.
Who...
who are you?
I said don't look.
Help me!
Tell me who you are.
Frank.
No.
No!
Believe me, it's me.
It's really me.
His blood on the floor,
it brought me back.
Back?
From where?
Just help me, will you?
Please, God, help me!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Somebody...
- Wait.
You can't leave me like this.
You can't.
What do you want me to do?
The blood brought me this far.
I need more.
(WATER FLOWING)
You have to heal me.
Hi.
Are you all right?
MAN:
Kirsty? I thought I'd lost you.
No, I'm here.
Good night.
So why didn't you stay
at Larry's house?
There's plenty of room.
Oh, yeah, there's room,
and there's Julia.
- Ah. I see.
- (WINGS FLAPPING)
She's like you.
She's so damn polite.
Oh, yeah? Meaning what?
Oh, I don't know.
She's uptight and frigid.
I beg your pardon.
See, there you go.
"I beg your pardon."
Hey, we're not all frigid.
- Oh, no?
- Oh, no.
Oh, no?
Oh, no.
That's not what I heard.
Well, you must have been
speaking to all the wrong people.
(TRAIN CHUGGING)
(MUMBLING)
Anything?
Anything.
You'll do it?
Yes...
I will.
(SIGHS)
(WINGS FLAPPING)
(BABY CRYING)
Kirsty? Kirsty?
- Kirsty!
- Ah!
- You all right?
- Yeah.
I-I don't know.
I-I was dreaming.
Daddy!
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
I'm all right, honey.
I just wanted to make
sure you were okay.
Never better.
- Now you sleep well, okay?
- Yeah.
I love you, sweetie.
I love you too, daddy.
Bye.
- JULIA: Who was it?
- She had a bad dream.
- Who?
- Kirsty.
Kirsty.
- Not much fun, is it?
- JULIA: What?
Drinking alone.
Not much.
I thought maybe...
Well...
If we're both on our own, maybe
we could have a drink together.
Why not?
You know, it's not often that I...
You know.
There's a first time
for everything.
That's right, yeah.
I suppose that's right.
Would you... like a drink?
Oh, no no no.
I'm well over my limit.
You know, it's funny,
but I...
I feel like I've known
you for years, you know?
What's the matter?
It's what you brought
me here for, isn't it?
Well, isn't it?
I suppose so, yes.
So what's your problem?
Let's get on with it.
You're not gonna change
your fucking mind, are you?
I'm sorry.
Let's go upstairs.
Okay okay. Sorry, okay? Okay.
- Right.
- (RAT SQUEAKING)
This isn't the bedroom.
No.
So what's going on?
We don't need a bed, do we?
Well, no, I suppose not.
I've always preferred the floor.
Oh. First time for everything, eh?
Why don't you...
Take your jacket off?
Yeah, why don't I?
Why don't you do the same thing?
Maybe I will.
(HEART BEATING)
You're very beautiful.
Am I?
Oh, you know you are.
Loveliest woman... I've ever seen.
Oh, Christ.
What's wrong?
Just one minute.
Too much drink.
Empty the old bladder.
(DOOR RATTLES)
(EERIE WHISPERS)
Did you lock this?
Please! Please!
FRANK: Don't look at me.
(GROWLS)
Jesus Christ.
Ah!
See?
It's making me whole again.
Every drop of blood you spill
puts more flesh on my bones.
And we both want that, don't we?
- Uh...
- Good.
Come here.
Come here, damn you,
I wanna touch you.
Come to daddy.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- LARRY: Julia!
(WHISTLES)
Julia.
Come out, come out,
wherever you are.
(WHISTLING)
Julia,
I was calling for you.
Didn't you hear?
Are you in there?
(DEEP VOICE)
You want a cookie, little girl?
I'm feeling sick.
Oh, babe. Is there
anything I can get you?
Maybe a... a Brandy.
It's coming right up.
I'll be down... in a minute.
Okay.
There's no hurry.
(WATER FLOWING)
(WHISPERING) Frank?
(GROWLS)
- Oh.
- I'm hurting.
Hurting?
My nerves are beginning
to work again.
Good.
One more, maybe two...
- Not again.
- ...To heal me completely.
Then we can be away from here
before they start to follow.
- Who?
- The Cenobites.
It's only a matter of time before
they find I've slipped them.
I must get away from here.
LARRY: Julia?
Are you all right?
Just a moment.
Put on some music. Will you, babe?
LARRY: Yeah, sure.
Poor Larry, obedient as ever.
(WHISPERING)
Keep your voice down.
Don't want "babe" to hear.
You're hurting.
You won't cheat me, will you?
You'll stay with me, help me.
Then we can be together
the way we were before.
We belong to each other now.
For better,
for worse.
Like love...
Only real.
(SCREECHING)
I'm sorry... I'm new here.
You're gonna have to wait.
Could you not do that? Please!
Where's the manager?
That's a problem too, because
he's out to lunch right now.
I want to see somebody in charge.
Then you're gonna have to wait.
- Excuse me.
- Well, excuse me!
What are you doing?
Give those back.
- (CRUNCHING)
- Oh my God.
Get out.
You get out of here.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
- (MONKEY SCREECHES)
- Hi.
Hi.
Just came by to see what
you're doing after work.
What's wrong?
- Something weird.
- What?
(WINGS FLAPPING)
Nothing.
You're sure we're not
gonna be interrupted?
Quite sure.
Only I... uh...
I like to be careful.
(LOUD THUD)
(FRANK HISSES)
I can taste that.
It's a long time since
I tasted anything.
You promised me an explanation.
This is it.
- Let me see.
- No, don't touch it!
It's dangerous. It opens doors.
What kind of doors?
Doors to the pleasures
of heaven or hell.
I didn't care which.
I thought I'd gone to the limits.
I hadn't. The Cenobites gave me
an experience beyond limits.
Pain and pleasure...
Indivisible.
(WIND BLOWING)
(TEETH CHATTERING)
(MOANING)
- (CHAINS CLINKING)
- (GROANING)
(MOANING)
They won't get me back.
I'm going to live and you're
going to help me, yes?
Yes.
They'll never find us,
not in the whole wide world.
ANNOUNCER:
Boom boom has got him now!
Boom boom has got him.
He's knocked down again.
I thought this kind of
stuff made you sick.
-  Moran's getting back up.
- I've seen worse.
Are you all right?
Fine.
- No. No...
- 'Cause we can watch something else.
If you feel like. Get him! Get him!
- (THUNDERING)
- Ah! No! No!
What was that?
I think I left a
window open upstairs.
- I'll go see.
- No.
It was nothing.
Larry!
What's the matter with you anyway?
It's just that I hate the thunder.
I'm here.
You're safe.
You're trembling.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Look.
I really should check it out.
Don't go up there, please.
We'll both go up. Come on.
- Larry, please!
- Don't worry about it. Come on.
- Don't.
- It's okay. It's okay.
(RAT SQUEAKING)
It's probably a rat.
I told you.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Let's go downstairs.
I'll make it better.
No, this is enough light.
(WHISPERING) Let's go, come on.
Let's go inside.
Oh, yes.
(HEART BEATING)
Yes. Yes.
(MOANING)
(HEART BEATING)
(THUNDER BLASTING)
No.
No!
No, please don't. No, please!
I can't bear it, please!
Please, no!
Please!
Please stop!
I can't bear it! Please, no!
I don't understand you.
I mean, one minute...
You're all over me, and the next...
I just don't understand you.
I don't know.
Maybe we shouldn't have come back.
Brooklyn certainly wasn't
any worse than this.
Look.
You love her, so there must
be something worth loving.
I wish it were that simple.
I've got a real
problem here, kiddo.
She doesn't even want
to leave the house.
Really?
It's like she's...
- Waiting for something.
- What?
I don't know.
It's way beyond me.
Look.
Could you... would you...
Uh-oh.
stop by sometime?
Try to make friends?
Sure.
Who knows, maybe all she needs
is somebody to talk to.
- You can't love him.
- JULIA: You know I don't.
- So where's the harm?
- I said no.
Then find me somebody else,
before they come looking.
Now!
(SILENT)
I...
I get lonely sometimes.
(RATS SQUEAKING)
Everybody does.
(HEART BEATING)
Come in.
What is this,
a game?
Jesus Christ!
(SCREAMING)
Oh, Christ! Help me!
Don't!
- Get out of here!
- Please.
- Don't let him kill me.
- (SNARLING)
(DOOR SLAMS)
(SNARLING)
(STAIR CREAKS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Help me.
(CHOKING)
No.
- Kirsty, it's Frank. It's Uncle Frank.
- No!
- You remember.
- Come to daddy.
- Get the fuck off of me!
You've grown. You're beautiful.
Don't...
don't touch me!
Don't touch me or so help me I...
I...
what will you do?
What can you do?
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I bet you make your daddy so proud.
Don't you, beautiful?
- This isn't happening.
- I used to tell myself that.
Used to try and pretend I
was dreaming all the pain.
But don't you kid yourself.
Some things have to be endured,
and that's what makes the
pleasures so sweet.
- (SQUISHES)
- Oh!
(GROWLING)
No!
Give me that!
- No.
- Give it to me!
You want it?
One last time:
Give me that box.
- You want it?
- Give me the box!
You want it? Fucking have it!
No!
- (HEART BEATING)
- (DISTORTED) Kirsty.
(ECHOES) Come to daddy.
(SIRENS BLASTING)
(HEART BEATING)
(DISTORTED)
It's Frank. You remember,
(ECHOES) It's Uncle Frank.
Are you all right?
You're awake.
- Good girl.
- What happened?
- I'll get the doctor.
- Wait a minute. How did I get here?
I won't be a moment.
Please, get back into bed.
I have to call my father.
That's easily arranged,
but first, back into bed.
It's important. It really is...
first things first.
We'll get you a telephone
after we've talked.
What about this? Ring any bells?
You were hanging onto
it like grim death.
I don't remember.
Well, the police will
want to speak to you.
- You know that.
- Oh, Christ.
In the meantime, maybe this
will jog your memory.
Shit.
(BOX CLICKING, PLAYING TUNE)
(WIND BLOWING)
(BABY SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
(SNARLS)
(GROWLING)
(SCREECHING)
Open!
(BANGS)
Oh, come on!
(STATIC)
The box. You opened it,
we came.
It's just a puzzle box!
Oh, no.
It is a means to summon us.
Who are you?
Explorers in the further
regions of experience:
Demons to some, angels to others.
It was a mistake!
I didn't...
I didn't mean to open it!
It was a mistake!
You can all...
Go to hell!
- We can't. Not alone.
- You solved the box,
we came, now you must come with us.
- Taste our pleasures.
- (GURGLES)
Please, go away and leave me alone!
Oh, no tears, please.
It's a waste of good suffering.
Wait! Wait! Wait! Please, wait!
No time for argument.
You've done this before, right?
PINHEAD: Many many times.
To a man called Frank Cotton?
Oh, yes.
He escaped you.
Nobody escapes us.
He did. I've seen him.
I've seen him.
- WOMAN:  Impossible.
- He's alive!
Supposing he had escaped us.
What has that to do with you?
I... I can...
I can lead you to him,
and you can take him
back instead of me.
Perhaps we prefer you.
I want to hear him confess himself,
then maybe...
Maybe.
But if you cheat us...
We'll tear your soul apart.
She'll tell them everything.
I don't think so.
She'll want to warn Larry first.
- (PHONE RINGING)
- That's probably her now...
- Or the police.
- It doesn't make any difference.
Don't you care?
What I care about is a new skin.
Maybe we should just leave.
Like this? Look at me.
We can't just stay here.
My brother will be home soon.
What is it?
I don't know where to begin.
What are you talking about?
It's best you see for yourself.
NURSE:
I left her here safe and sound.
I even locked the door.
STEVE: Well, she's not here now.
I'll start looking for her.
Maybe she's gone back to...
To her father's house.
(BOTH MOANING)
Daddy?
Daddy, it's me,
it's Kirsty! Let me in!
Daddy, let me in!
- Kirsty? It's very late.
- Where is my dad?
- What's the matter?
- I want to see my father!
Of course.
- (HUMMING)
- (DOOR OPENS)
KIRSTY: Where is he?
Where is he?
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Daddy?
Daddy?
- Daddy, you're okay. You're all right.
- Sure I am. I am.
- You're okay!
- It's okay.
I was so afraid that
something happened to you.
I know, I know.
I need to talk to you.
Yeah. Of course.
It's okay, baby,
Julia told me everything.
Oh, no, see...
Your brother Frank is upstairs.
He's upstairs and he's
trying to kill you.
- He's gonna kill you!
- No, wait wait wait.
Whatever Frank did was unspeakable.
Unspeakable.
But believe me,
it's finished with now.
Why is it finished?
He's gone.
What does "gone" mean?
He's dead, Kirsty.
He was insane, baby,
a mad dog. I had to put
him out of his misery.
Jesus, what a scene.
And when I'm feeling better,
I'll go to the police and try
to make them understand.
God knows...
I don't really understand myself.
Did he hurt you, baby?
No, I'm okay.
He's better off dead.
Poor Frank.
I don't believe this.
- I don't believe this.
- Believe it.
I need to see him.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
Yes.
Show her.
(SQUISHING)
(CHATTERER HISSING)
We want the man
who did this.
No.
No, that wasn't the deal.
He's my father and
you can't have him.
No!
Ah! Move.
Kirsty...
Move!
What's the matter?
There's no time.
Wait, no wait. I told you
all that's over with now.
No, it's not!
We've got to get out of here!
No, stay with us.
We can all be happy here.
No.
Come to daddy.
Oh my God!
Come...
To daddy.
- Ah!
- Frank!
(SCREAMS)
Well...
So much for the cat-
and-mouse shit!
No!
Not me!
It's nothing personal, baby.
Where are you, beautiful?
Come out, come out,
wherever you are.
(CRYING)
(THUDS)
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDE)
(CRYING) Oh no.
Oh my God.
Daddy.
No, don't mourn him.
He was dead long before
we ever touched him.
- Bastard!
- Now, hush now.
Everything's all right.
- Frank's here.
- Bastard!
Your dear old Uncle Frank.
- (EERIE WHISPERING)
- (BOX PLAYING MUSIC)
What the hell is that?
(CHAINS CLINKING)
(WET BREATHING)
(MOANING)
Frank.
No!
We had to hear it
from your own lips.
This isn't for your eyes.
You set me up,
bitch!
(BOTH SCREAM)
(SCREAMING)
"Jesus wept."
Not leaving us so soon, are you?
(JULIA GROANS)
Ah!
(GROANING)
We have such sights to show you.
Oh, shit.
- No! Don't do that!
- Go to hell!
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(DOOR KNOCKING)
Kirsty!
(COUGHING)
No.
Steve.
No!
Oh, shit!
Oh, Kirsty! Thank God you're okay.
Let's get the hell out of here!
Now!
Oh, no.
Oh, God. No.
Open!
Steve!
No!
(SHRIEKING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(EERIE WHISPERING)
(CLATTERS)
(WINGS FLAPPING)
(SHRIEKS)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
- What's your pleasure, sir?
- (WINGS FLAPPING)
(EERIE MUSIC PLAYING)