[TV News]...he's definitely got the inside track.
Word is they're having some problems
with injuries.
Really? Are they looking into free agent signing at
the last second or anything like that?
Possibly, I mean they have a strong farm club.
They got some AAA ball players bringing up...
But again, Peter will tell us a little bit
more in the next half hour.
Who do you like?
-- So far, I like what I'm seeing in New York.
They got a strong club as usual.
That is in the American, and..
and the National, I'm still liking Chicago,
with a little bit of twist here for Los Angeles.
- Okay, so we're looking here at New York, Chicago
World Series, possible Los Angeles.
Hey, hold it to him to the
end of the season.
That's gonna do it from the sports desk for right now.
Back to you guys in the studio, thanks Dave.
Thanks for nothing Eddy, thank you guys.
That's not all we're following.
Here's Karen at the health desk.
The world of medicine has seen its share of
miracle cures from the polio vaccine
to heart transplants.
But all past achievements may pale
in comparison to the work of Dr. Alice Krippin.
Thank you so much for joining us this morning.
Dr. Krippin, give it to me in a nutshell.
The premise is quite simple.
Take something designed by nature ...
and reprogram it to make it work for
the body rather than against it.
You're talking about a virus?
- Indeed yes, in this case, the measles.
A virus which has been engineered at a genetic
level to be helpful rather than harmful.
I find the best way to describe it is
if you can imagine your body is a highway....
and you picked the virus as a very fast car, being
driven by a very bad man.
Imagine the damage that car can cause.
But if you replace that man with a cop,
then the picture changes.
And that is essentially what we have done.
-- And how many people have you treated so far?
We have 10,009 clinical trials in humans so far.
-- And how many are cancer free?
-- 10,009.
-- So you have actually cured cancer?
Yes yes, yes we have.
What do you see?
Damn.
Let's go Sam.
Here you go, just the way you like it....
Disgusting.
Excuse me.
Relax.
There you go.
No, eat your vegetables.
Don't just push 'em around, eat them.
I'm not playing.
Eat your vegetables.
Or we'll sit down here all night.
What are you whining about?
Why didn't you just eat your vegetables?
Okay, look, look.
We're gonna eat twice as many vegetables
tomorrow night.
Deal?
That feels good.
Ah Sam.
[Singing]
[Alarm beeping]
Robert, what is happening? I've been trying
to reach you on the cell, I keep getting
the recording.
The network is down.
-- Dad, where are we going?
- I cannot get used to the new rags.
-- We're going to Aunt Sarah's sweetie.
No, why?!
- Just strap yourself in, go.
- We're at 30 minutes Colonel.
- Copy.
- 30 minutes to what?
- They're sealing off the island.
- Seal off the island?  This island?
- But I don't wanna go to Aunt Sarah's.
- Did you bring all the money?  How much?
- 600 dollars, why did you say you're going?
-- That is not enough.
-- Robert, you said "You're going", not "we're going".
- When you get across, I need you to get to the ATM.
Get as much cash as you can.
- It's not even summer yet.
- Take Sarah's car, go upstate.
I'll meet you at the farm, bring
enough food for 2 weeks.
Jesus, Robert. Did it jump?
Is it airborne?
- But we only go to Aunt Sarah's in the summer.
-- Maybe.
It's Christmas. What about my presents?
- He's announcing it.
- Make no mistake my fellow Americans.
- My gifts are still in the closet.
[Radio] - The mutated virus is lethal.
- Hush now Mar.
[Radio] - The survival of not only our nation, but
of every other nation on the planet.
- Mom, look. A butterfly.
- Marley, enough!
So, I announce with great sadness, but
even greater resolve.
that tonight I have signed an executive order,
initiating a military quarantine of New York City.
- God be with us.
- The window is still open, we find something
in a week..or 2 weeks,
...we can reverse the spread.
I can still fix this.
Please, you can do the same work
outside the city.
Ground zero, this is my site.
We talked about this.
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
- I'm not gonna let this happen.
- Let? This isn't up to you, you can't...
How did you sleep?
Now come on, you know better than that.
I'll be back.
Dr. Robert Neville, September 5, 2012.
GA series serum 391.
Animal trials, streaming video.
The results appear typical.
Compounds 1, 3, 4, 6, 8, 9, 10, 11 ...
14, 16 and 18 did not kill the virus.
Compounds 2, 5, 7, 12, 13, 15 and 17 ...
All killed the host.
Hold on a second.
Compound 6 seems to be showing decreased
aggression response.
Partial pigmentation returned.
Slight pupil constriction.
GA series serum 391 compound 6
is the next candidate for human trials.
Hang in there number 6.
Yeah, that's what you want.
Good morning, Marge and Fred.
What are you doing here so early?
Nice sweatshirt there Fred.
Don't fit it down anywhere.
I see you inside.
What's happening brother?
Good morning Hank.
Getting through the G's.
Who's the girl ...
Nevermind, hey I'll see you in the morning.
- What am I supposed to say?
- Hello, wanna see some infected rats.
Okay, tomorrow.
I'm going to say hello tomorrow.
You did so good.
Yes, yes.
Look at that, see that?  Red salmon.
Wow, actual Spam.
No, you'll get some of that later.
Let's go.
I am Robert Neville. I am a survivor
living in New York City.
I am broadcasting on all
AM frequencies.
I will be at the South Street seaport everyday
at midday, when the sun is at its highest
in the sky.
If you are out there...if anyone is out there,
I can provide food, I can provide shelter,
I can provide security.
If there is anybody out there, anybody...
Please, you are not alone.
Keep your eye on this one for me.
I'm getting good.
Call Sam. I gotta call him.
I gotta call him.
Sam, come on. We have to go.
What are you doing?
Sam, we gotta go!
Sam, go now, get out!
You need to pay attention, okay?
- Gotta pay attention.
Listen, I want you to stay here on
this one, okay?
Because you can still get infected and I can't.
Listen, if I am not back by dark...
Just go.
Okay, the subject is female.
Most likely 18-20 years of age.
??? Push effective 6 times the human dose.
Core temperature 106 Fahrenheit, pulse 200 bpm,
..respiration elevated, PAO2 300% of normal.
The pupils are fully dilated.
Now reactive to light.
Extreme reaction to UV exposure...
Symptoms and tissue samples confirm subject
is infected with KV.
Vaccine test series serum 391 compound six.
Commencing human trials.
Respiration is slowing, pulse 190,
Core temperature 105, 104 and decreasing.
We may have something here.
GA series serum 391 compound 6,
ineffective on humans.
Test results linked to this entry,
saved on 6 redundant drives.
Still no cure.
Day 1001: We came in close contact with a Hyve today.
The blood tests confirm that I remain immune....
for both the airborne and contact strains.
Canines remain immune to airborne strain only.
You can't go running into the dark dummy.
Vaccine trials continue.  I am still unable
to transfer my immunity...
...to infected host.  Krippin virus is....
elegant.
It's like fishing in the dark, son.
A behavioral note : Um, an infected male
exposed himself to sunlight today.
Now it's possible that decreased brain function..or...
growing scarcity of food is..
...is causing them to ignore their basic
survival instincts.
Social de-evolution appears complete.
Typical human behavior is now entirely absent.
Why are we stopping?
?????
- You've got less than 10 minutes.
Baby, give me the dog.
-- Let's go baby, let's go.
- Daddy.
Stay in my neighborhood and let nobody stop you by.
-- Mommy, they have guns.
-- It's okay, they're in the army like daddy.
Then, please, back home.
-- Coming through.
If you are not covered by the checkpoint,
then, please, go home.
You're clear. Go ahead.
-- Clear.
Clear...okay, next, let's go.
No good.
Clear -- Okay, go.
-- We are not infected.
-- Please, please take my baby.
You have to move back.
No good.
- What, no!  Robert, Robert!
Whoa, whoa, get your hands off my wife.
I'm lieutenant Robert Neville
Get your hands off me.
-- Scan her again.
-- Stand down!
-- Stand down soldier! Stand down!
-- I am Lieutenant-Colonel Robert Neville.
I order you to scan her again.
Scan her again!
-- Alright, scan her again.
Clear, it's clear, move through.
Dad, why can't we go to our home too?
-- How long?
-- Five minutes, we'll make it.
With Merage, code: 621. We are on site.
I won't take my eyes off them Colonel.
You got my word on it.
Give me a kiss.
Be careful. -- You too.
-- Dear God, please watch over Robert,
keep him strong for the struggle ahead of him Lord.
Please, just bring him home safely, Amen.
Daddy's going to make the monsters go away
baby, okay?
-- Sam, you protect Daddy.
-- No baby, I can't take the dog!
Sir, we have to go.
Dad, look, a butterfly.
-- How'd you sleep?
[TV] -- Dr. Robert Neville will be taking
a closer look
...at the ongoing mutations of Dr. Alice Krippin's
once hailed miracle cure for cancer.
So far, almost 5000 patients treated with a
retrofitted virus, had begun exhibiting symptoms
resembling the early onset of rabies.
25 patients have already died. Dr. Neville
has ordered local hospitals to stockpile
antiviral drugs, and to begin preliminary quarantine
protocol....
--It's my birthday today.
[TV] - We are fully confident Dr. Neville can see us through...
-- Would you like to sing?
My name is Robert Neville, I am a survivor living
in New York City.
I am broadcasting on all AM frequencies.
I will be at the South Street seaport everyday, midday,
when the sun is highest in the sky.
If you are out there....if anyone is out there....
I can provide food, I can provide shelter,
I can provide security.
If there's anybody out there, anybody...
Please, you are not alone.
Listen, if you're planning a party or something,
just tell me now.
Okay, because I don't like surprises, and I swear
I'll act surprised. Okay?
What are you doing out here Fred?
What the hell are you.....no!
-- No! No!
What the hell are you doing out here Fred!?!
How did you get out here?!?
Fred, if you're real, you better tell me
right now!
If you're real, you better tell me right now!
Damn, Fred.
I'm okay.
Come on, Sam.
Come on.
Come on Sam!
No, no, let's go Sam, we gotta go home Sam.
Let's go.
Okay, you're alright.
It's okay. You're alright.
You're alright.
Samantha, Samantha.
Look at me girl. Hey, you're okay.
Samantha, just gotta get you home.
Gotta take you home, take you home.
Alright, come here.
Come here, come here, got you.
It's okay.
I promised my friend.... that I would say hello...
to you today.
Please say hello to me.
Sterf.
Can you hear me?
Stick with me.
Where you live?
I love her. I love him.
Washington and Square.
They don't know where I live.
The night is a big trap.
You must stay in till dawn.
I'm afraid the eggs are powdered, obviously
you know that.  They're yours.
But I did find bacon.  I just found the most
fantastic thing in history.
I found some antibiotics in the bathroom, I put
by your plate because your leg is okay,
but you won't be for very long, if you don't
start a course very soon.
Who are you?
-- I am Anna and this is Ethan.
They're going to get cold.
It's okay.  Go on.
We come from Maryland.
We heard your message heard on the radio.
We were at the pier at noon, we waited all day.
We're going to Vermont.
To the survivor's colony.
In Bethel. It is a safe zone.
There's no survivor's colony, no safe zone.
Nothing's happening the way it was supposed to happen.
Nothing worked the way it was supposed to work.
-- In the mountains, there is a whole colony of
people there who didn't get sick.
The virus couldn't survive the cold, there's a whole...
-- Shut up!
Everybody's dead.
I just need a minute, okay?
Just....
I just, I was saving that bacon.
I was saving it.
I'm gonna go upstairs, alright, just.
I'm gonna go.
Ethan, put that knife down.
[repeating the TV] - Can I say something to you?
You was really really something back there.
are you talking to...me?
Can I tell you that you were great? Those guards.
They thought that they were tough.
And when you came and they were nowhere.
That was fun to see.
That's great. Seriously. -- It is nice to be free.
Why don't you celebrate your freedom
with your own friends?  Hmm?
But I have no friends. And I am not going
out there by myself.
Wait, I have a great idea.
I'll stick with you.
I like Shrek.
You are not as good with people anymore
are you?
Thank you for my leg.
Where have you been?
- I was on a Red Cross evacuation ship
out of Saint Paolo.
- Those boats weren't meant to be permanent.
--No they weren't.
When the Navy fell apart, we set on dock
to get supplies.
Someone picked it up on shore.
5 of us were immune.
You said five. -- The dark seekers got them.
You are the Robert Neville, aren't you?
It's too late today. If we leave tomorrow at dawn,
we can make it to Vermont in a straight shot.
so if we ...
-- I'm not leaving.
This is ground zero. This is my site.
I'm not gonna let this happen.
I can still fix this.
Oh, you scared me.
-- Sorry.
I called down twice.
-- Oh thank you.
That's heavily sedated, don't worry it's safe.
I've never seen one so still.
They're always biting.
Do you think that can cure her?
No, this will almost certainly kill it, but it's
possible by drastically reducing
her body temperature, I can increase the compound's
effectiveness.
Did all of them die?
-- Yes.
My God.
-- God didn't do this Anna.
We did.
Where can Ethan sleep?
He is heavy.
Can you ...
She is beautiful. What's her name?
Her name is Marley
-- It's a beautiful name.
Yeah, we named her after Bob Marley.
Who?
-- The singer.
Damian?
-- His father.
His father.
That is unacceptable.
-- What?
Best album ever made.
You recognize that?
He had this idea, it was kind of a
virologist idea.
He believed that you could cure racism
and hate, literally cure it, by
injecting music and love into
people's lives.
One day, he was scheduled to perform at
a peace rally,
a gunman came to his house and shot him down.
Two days later he walked out on that stage and sang.
Somebody asked him, why.
He said: "The people who are trying to make
this world worse....
...are not taking a day off. How can I?"
Light up the darkness.
Come with us, Neville.
To the colony.
There is not a colony, Anna.
Everything just fell apart, there was no evacuation.
-- Wrong, there is a colony.
I know okay?
-- How do you know, Anna?
I just know.
How, I said how do you know?
-- How could you know?
God told me, he has a plan.
God told you? The God?
-- Yes.
I know how this sounds.
-- It sounds crazy.
But something told me to turn
on the radio.
Something told me to come here.
-- My voice on the radio told you to come here Anna.
You were trying to kill yourself last night, right?
-- Anna.
And I got here just in time to save your life.
-- Do you think it is a coincidence?
Just stop it.
-- He must have sent me here for a reason.
Neville, the world is quieter now.
You just have to listen.
If we listen, we can hear God's plan.
God's plan? Alright, let me tell you
about your God's plan.
We were 6 billion people on earth when the infection hit.
KV had a 90% kill rate, that is 5.4 billion people.
Dead.  Crashed and bled out...dead.
Less than 1% immunity.  That is 12 million healthy people
like you, me, and Ethan.
The other 588 million turned into your dark seekers.
And then they got hungry, and
they killed, and fed on everybody.
Everybody. Every single person that you or I
has ever known...is DEAD!!
Dead!
There is no God.
What is that?
Was it still dark when you brought
us home last night?
You were bleeding, there was light
on the horizon.
Turn the light off.
Turn it off.
They followed us home.
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
-- Yes.
Go to the lab. Downstairs.
Go! To the lab. To the lab.
Get behind them plates.
-- Come on.
Come on. It is okay.
It's working.
Stop.
I can save you. I can help you.
You are sick and I can help you.
I can fix this!
I can save everybody!
I can fix this.
It's working.
Stop.
I can save you. Let me save you.
Dad, look, a butterfly.
What are you doing?
-- The cure is in my blood.
Go, you're going to be safe.
Ethan get in.
Go inside.
Anna, I think this is why you're here.
What are you doing?
-- I'm listening.
Neville, there is room in here, come on.
-- They're not gonna stop.
Stay until dawn.
In 2009, a deadly virus burned through our
civilization.
Pushing humankind to the edge
of extinction.
Dr. Robert Neville dedicated his life
to the discovery of a cure.
And the restoration of humanity.
On September 9, 2012 ...
At approximately 8:49 P.M.,
he discovered that cure.
And at 8:52, he gave his life to defend it.
We are his legacy.
-- This is his legend.
Light up the darkness.