...:::: SiliconChip ::::...
Jessabelle [2014]
(GRUNTS)
Huh? You sure you got that?
Don't strain yourself.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, that's it. Turned in my key.
Yep. No turning back now.
You still think this is a good idea?
What, me driving this thing?
I told you,
I'm more than happy to let you drive.
No, this, moving in with you.
Having this baby.
Jessie, you're the best thing
that ever happened to me.
I've been ready for this for a long time.
I just remembered
the weirdest dream I had last night.
MALE SURGEON: (DISTORTED)
It's the last chance to remove it.
A little more suction, please.
Can't see a thing in there.
It's skull.
It's part of the guy's skull.
(DISTORTION CONTINUES)
lntertrochanteric fracture in your hip.
Your left clavicle and three ribs are shattered.
You've got compound fractures
in your right and left tibia.
Good news is you will walk again
within three or four months of therapy.
(VOICE BREAKING) My baby?
I'm sorry.
(SOBBING)
NURSE: I know
it's been a long haul for you, Jessie.
But we'll still need
to send a physical therapist to you at home.
Can someone come pick you up?
Your mother or father?
Uh, my mom died of cancer
when I was a baby,
and my father gave me to my aunt
to be raised after my mom died.
I haven't seen him in years.
Miss Laurent,
can he come here to pick you up?
(LINE RINGING)
(LINE CLICKS)
(LEON BREATHING HEAVILY)
Dad?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(INSECTS BUZZING)
Thanks for picking me up, Dad.
Hmm. Glad I could help.
Sorry about your boyfriend.
(GRUNTING)
This was your mother's room.
You're gonna have to stay in here.
The other bedrooms are upstairs.
Let's get you in bed.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
When your aunt passed away, they gave me
some things you had there.
Clothes.
You hungry?
I could make you a sandwich or something.
Uh...
No, I'm fine. Just tired is all.
Oh, yeah, the water out of the
tap sometimes comes out bad.
You just let it run a little, it'll clear up.
JESSIE: Preston.
(CHUCKLES)
(INSECTS CHIRPING)
(OWL HOOTING)
(GROANS)
(LIQUID DRIPPING)
(GHOSTLY HUMMING)
(GASPS)
(HUMMING CONTINUES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Dad?
You here?
(TURNS ON RADIO)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(FLY BUZZING)
(STATIC BUZZING ON RADIO)
(TUNING)
(WOMAN CRYING ON RADIO)
(PHONE RINGING)
(RINGING STOPS)
Oh, my word.
Thank you, Mama.
(CHUCKLES)
Ahh!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
BREATHES NERVOUSLY)
Hello, Jessabelle.
Mom.
I went back and forth 100 times
whether or not this was a good idea.
Making these tapes.
But as you can see, here I am.
(CHUCKLES)
It is March 14, and it is 1988,
and I am seven months pregnant with you.
(CHUCKLES)
I love you, Jessabelle. I love you.
(LAUGHS)
If you're watching this,
it means I'm gone.
But I don't want this to be a day of sadness.
I want it to be a day of happiness.
So I'm not even gonna talk about me.
The only thing that's important
is that you know that I love you.
And that I have been
watching over you, always.
Okay. So, enough of that sad shit.
I told your father that I wanted him
to give you this tape on your 18th birthday.
So for you, it is 2006.
Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday, baby!
I thought about having a cake,
but explaining all this to Mrs. Davis
just would have been a little too weird.
Uh, Mrs. Davis is our cook,
and if she's there,
could you tell her I said hi?
She's so sweet. That ought to
freak her out, though. (LAUGHS)
She is scared of ghosts.
Whoo-oo-oo!
(CHUCKLES)
Anyway, um, I wanted to make this tape
because I wanted you to get to know me.
And I wanted to give you a birthday gift,
a birthday reading with my cards.
I am really good at this.
(LAUGHS)
I'm always right.
You can't cut the deck,
so this will have to do.
Here we go.
I still have your bracelet, Mom.
Okay. So this is Death.
But it doesn't mean "death" death.
It means transition.
And this year, your 18th year,
is gonna be a year of transition.
(CHUCKLES)
You know what it says here?
It says that you've never left St. Francis
and that you're never gonna leave.
Baby, you've gotta
get out there and see the world.
There's so much great stuff out there.
Suits of Cups.
That's the water sign, and water is pragmatic.
It goes the way of least resistance.
But this is a lot of water.
Are you a swimmer,
or do you do something with the sea?
I can't even swim.
You're a homebody, just like your mama.
Wrong again. You're terrible at this!
Well, it says here that you're not alone.
That there is a presence
in the house with you.
It's not a bad thing.
There are guardian angels everywhere.
Maybe I'm seeing me.
Uh!
Yes, so she's a she. It's a female.
Um...
She wants you out of the house.
She says it's hers.
(GASPS)
Jesus, Dad!
You scared the shit out of me!
Where did you get that?
I asked you a goddamn question!
I said, "Where did you get that?"
I found it in my room, in Mom's room.
(Y APE SHATTERS)
Don't, Dad! Don't! What are you doing?
Dad, what are you doing?
Oh! No, Dad. Oh, God, Dad.
-(WHIMPERING)
-No more snooping around.
Dad? Dad?
Dad.
Dad!
(DOOR CREAKING)
(KATE HUMMING EERILY)
It's past your bedtime, sweetie.
(CHUCKLES)
(DISTORTED CHANTING)
(KATE SPEAKING DISTORTEDLY ON TV)
That there is a presence
in the house with you.
(CHOKING)
(GASPING)
BREATHES NERVOUSLY)
(SQUEAKING)
(WHIMPERING)
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
Who are you?
(DISTORTED) Jessabelle.
(SCREAMING)
I made breakfast.
Look, I'm sorry about last night.
I was a little drunk.
It's not gonna happen again.
It's all right.
That was your mother's old chair.
It was out in the shed.
Didn't expect to see your mother last night.
That tape, I didn't know she made that tape,
that she actually went through with it.
You just found that one tape?
Uh-huh, just one.
(HORN HONKING)
(CLANGING)
(ENGINE IDLING)
Hello, Jessabelle.
I love you.
I love you too, Mom.
It's been three weeks since our last reading.
There was so much weird stuff in there,
so I asked Moses about it.
Not Ten Commandments Moses,
but my friend Moses
from my church on Jerry's Creek.
Don't tell Dad. He'd kill me.
(LAUGHS)
(couemwe)
Moses taught me how to read cards.
So I showed him your reading,
and he said something interesting.
He said that the two presences in the house,
the two females,
they're both you.
You've been having nightmares, right?
And when you see it, this presence,
it's broken, right?
It's a demon, but it's an inner demon.
You were in some sort of accident
or something,
or maybe somebody you know was.
Now, I want you to listen to me.
It wasn't your fault.
Stop blaming yourself, sweetheart.
It wasn't your fault. Okay?
Now that we know
that's what that last reading meant...
I mean, that's what Moses says.
So, we're gonna get you a new one.
-(CHUCKLES)
- All right.
Death. That means transition.
You really don't have to worry about that.
(BREATHES DEEPLY AND COUGHS)
I see a very horrible death.
(GASPS)
(CLATTERING)
(FAINT CREAKING)
Dad?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(DOOR OPENS)
ROSAURA: Miss Laurent?
I was knocking,
but I know you're in a wheelchair,
so I got in.
Hi. It's just Jessie.
Uh, the hospital told you
I was coming, right?
Uh, no. Um, yes.
Yes.
Oh.
You must be Miss Arlenna.
(CHUCKLES)
Rosaura. You can call me Rosaura.
It's great to meet you.
Let's get started.
Okay. Okay. You feel good?
I'll be back and check on you, okay?
Mmm-hmm.
(BUBBLING SOFTLY)
(HUMMING)
(SHRIEKING)
No, no!
(DOOR RATTLING)
No!
-(SHRIEKING)
-(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERS)
(GASPING)
LEON: What the hell's going on?
(PANTING)
Just calm down. Settle down.
It's nothing. It's nothing.
Where the hell were you? Huh?
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry, Mr. Laurent.
It was only five minutes.
Get out! Now.
- I'm sorry.
-Get out!
What did you mean by "nothing", Dad?
What's nothing?
What are you doing?
It's her goddamn tapes!
She's got you scared out of your mind.
I told her not to do this.
But, Dad, it's Mom. It's all I have of her!
That thing on these tapes is not your mother.
Five weeks into her pregnancy,
we found out she had tumors in her brain.
She wouldn't do chemo.
Nothing to help herself.
It ate her mind, the cancer.
it just wasn't her anymore.
But, Dad, I want to watch them!
Why? So she can scare
the shit out of you some more?
- I'm gonna burn these tapes.
-Dad,no!
No, Dad! Don't, Dad! Dad!
(GRUNTING)
(CLICKING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Dad.
(SCREAMING)
Oh, God!
(GRUNTS)
Dad! Dad!
Jessie!
-(BANGING ON DOOR)
-Jessie!
No! Dad!
Dad!
(SOBBING)
PRIEST: Goodbye, Leon.
May your soul finally find peace. Amen.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Hey, Jessie.
Preston.
How you been?
Uh...
That was a really stupid question.
I heard you were in town last week.
I would have come over,
but I figured I should call first.
I tried you a few times, but no one picked up.
I'm sorry.
My Dad's phone is upstairs,
and it's gonna be a few more weeks
before I can walk upstairs to answer it.
Right. I'm sorry.
It's really good to see you, Preston.
It's good to see you, too.
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
I'm really sorry about your dad.
(DISTORTED) Jessie?
(JESSIE PANTING)
Jessie, you okay?
(DISTORTED TALKING)
(GAS russme)
(GASPING)
(LOUD, HEAVY BREATHING)
(GASPS)
Hey-
Morning.
Good morning.
Uh...
You stayed here all night?
Yeah, well, I figured I'd stick around,
make sure you're okay.
Thanks. You didn't have to.
Well, I guess I should get going home.
But I'd love to see you again, though.
Be okay if I come by some other time?
Yeah. Yeah, I'd like that.
All right. You take care.
Uh, wait, wait.
Please don't go.
What?
If I don't talk to somebody,
I'm gonna go crazy. (CHUCKLES)
Maybe I already am crazy.
Okay. I don't gotta go anywhere.
- I'll stay right here.
- Thank you.
But you think we can
get the hell out of this place?
Kind of gives me the creeps.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
PRESTON: Pretty much everybody's still here.
Rick Fosterjust got back from Afghanistan.
But he's going back, I think.
He's still married to Shawna.
If I was married to Shawna,
I'd be going back, too.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Mary Kimball's been married
and divorced twice.
- Twice?
-She's got three kids.
Lives in that new subdivision
over by the quarry.
(LAUGHS)
The quarry.
(CLEARS THROAT)
So, the quarry's still there, huh?
Yes, well, you know, it is a big, giant hole.
You can't really move a big, giant hole.
Smart ass. Cut me some slack.
Yeah.
Nothing's changed, really.
Marriages and mortgages.
I can see why you couldn't
get out fast enough.
Uh...
Preston, I'm so sorry.
Hey, you don't gotta explain to me.
If I'd gotten into college, I would've left
this town and never looked back.
Never would have given it a second thought.
That's not true.
I thought about this place a lot.
I missed you.
I'm sorry I didn't call more.
I just wanted a clean breakaway, I guess.
But me leaving
never had anything to do with you.
It's okay. I understand.
How have you been?
Married.
Oh, uh...
(CHUCKLES)
Where did she think you were last night?
Oh, I told her the truth.
I told her I was with a Make-A-Wish kid.
- So tell me what's going on.
-Oh...
You seemed so scared back there.
Um, okay.
I've been having nightmares.
I've been having really bad dreams,
and they're so real that I think I'm going crazy.
I dreamed there's this girl.
She looks dead,
and she's trying to get me, kill me.
And there's this man.
It looks like he's been burnt to death,
and he looks at me like I did it.
Like whatever happened to him,
it was my fault.
Well, after everything you've been through,
it would be weird
if you weren't having nightmares, right?
Have you thought about seeing a shrink?
I can't afford it.
I mean, if I had any money at all,
I wouldn't have come home to live with Dad.
I'm flat broke.
And there are these tapes.
Now that we know
that's what that last reading meant...
I mean, that's what Moses says.
So, we're gonna get you a new one.
I really don't think you should
be watching these anymore.
It's no wonder why you're having nightmares.
It's not good for you.
Would you watch them if it was your mom?
Your only chance to get to know her?
Yeah, I would, but I'd wait,
wait until I was recuperated.
Not when I was still
stuck in this house where she died.
I mean, it's just weird.
And besides,
she's wrong more than she's right.
She said you never left town,
you love to swim.
She said Dad was gonna die.
No, she thought you were gonna die.
She said 10 things that were wrong,
and you picked one that was almost right.
Jessie, she didn't predict your dad's death.
She thought she saw your death,
and she was wrong about everything.
Now, look,
I've been thinking about your dreams.
That girl you keep seeing, it's you.
And the guy that burnt in the fire,
you're having a nightmare
about your accident.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Shit, that's my wife.
I'm sorry, but I've gotta go.
Here. That's my work cell.
It's got my home phone number on it.
You call me any time, day or night, all right?
- Promise?
-Okay.
I'm sorry. I gotta go.
Thank you, Preston.
Yeah, of course. Now you take care.
(FLIES BUZZING)
(GASPS)
(CUP SHATTERS)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
This is beautiful South Louisiana.
And here is the belle of South Louisiana.
That's right. Here she is. (LAUGHS)
I'm gonna send this to Mr. Hugh Hefner,
and I'm gonna
make me some money on the side.
The most beautiful woman
in South Louisiana.
Bad.
This is the family portrait.
Wait a minute. Wait.
(enemas)
KATE: I might just
send me some tapes to that Mr. Hugh Hefner.
LEON". These bugs are eating my ass up!
KATE". Let's see those feet. Where'd they go?
- LEON: There it is-
-(CHUCKLING)
- LEON: Oh! There she is.
- Baby!
LEON: Hey, baby,
you can't improve perfection. Look at that.
What are you doing?
LEON". Recording for posterity.
Those who don't remember the past
are doomed to repeat it.
Okay, well, let's go into the future.
Merry Christmas!
LEON". Merry Christmas! Yeah!
Now, listen,
I want to show you how to use it.
You just take it, point it, and shoot it.
You got it?
Okay, you got it? Just hold it.
- Merry Christmas!
-Merry Christmas!
Mrs. Davis,
I think these people are about ready to eat.
They're gonna eat the furniture
if we don't sit them down and feed them.
- I'm gonna do the thing.
-What? Okay.
Let's work with this, okay?
(CLINKING GLASS)
Excuse me. Before you unwrap
the presents and get into some funky music,
I just wanted to take
a little second here to brag about something.
- WOMAN: Oh, yeah, surprise.
- How very unlike you, Leon.
Now wait a minute. Now wait a minute.
It has come to my attention
that my lovely, devoted wife
is With Child.
KATE". I'm pregnant!
(GUESTS CHEERING)
MAN: Raise your glasses
and toast to Leon and Kate!
- Congratulations.
-I can drink.
(KATE SOBBING)
You're already dead, Jessabelle.
(SOBBING)
You're already dead!
(GASPS)
(DIALING)
(LINE RINGING)
Preston? I'm sorry.
I know I said I wouldn't call, but...
SAMANTHA: Who is this?
Uh...
It's Jessie, Jessie Laurent.
Who is this?
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(BEEPS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(FAINT THUDDING)
(RUNNING FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(SCREAMING)
(RU N NING FOOTSTEPS)
FEMALE VOICE: (EERILY)
Come closer.
(WHIMPERS)
Closer.
(SOBBING)
Yes.
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(GROANS)
Hey. You all right?
Sam just told me you called last night.
I'm all right. I'm so sorry.
I just got scared.
Everything okay at home?
Well, "okay" is stretching it a bit, but I'm fine.
Well, I'm glad you're here.
All right.
Well, tell me what happened.
Oh, you see that, too?
Yeah.
PRESTON; What is that?
I don't know.
I think somebody's out there.
There was somebody definitely
out there last night.
You think that old boat still works?
Sure.
What is that?
Mmm. Some kind of voodoo or something.
Half the cemeteries
in this parish are full of that kind of shit.
But why would they put it on our land?
PRESTON: Yeah,
someone's definitely been out here, all right.
That's pretty fresh.
(GASPS)
What?
There's something down there.
What is that?
What are you doing?
This isn't my first time in the bayou.
Hmm. That's weird.
That's my birthday.
Why would someone
want to spook you like this?
Or maybe that's a real gravestone.
Maybe you had a twin sister or something.
I never had a sister.
And why would we both have the same name?
I don't know. I've got cousins with
two Beauregards in their family.
They just like the name.
But who killed that chicken?
And who brings flowers?
Do you think there's something
under that stone?
All right.
I guess we'll go back to your house
and see what kind of tools you've got.
(THUD5)
(GRUNTING)
Uh!
You don't recall any mention
of your parents having another little girl?
Hmm.
Well, you were right to call us.
I suspect it was a stillbirth.
We'll run some tests,
find out if she was a relative of yours
based on your DNA sample.
Of course we have a sample of your
daddy already from his autopsy.
So we'll give you a call
when we find out who this infant was.
Thank you, Sheriff.
We knew we had to call you right away.
Remind me again the nature
of your relationship with Miss Laurent.
We're old friends from high school.
Y'all have a good night, then.
Thank you, Sheriff.
You know you can't stay here, right?
I've got nowhere else to go.
Yeah, you do.
(DOG BARKING)
- You all right?
-Yeah.
(TV PLAYING)
Hey, honey.
(SWITCHES OFF TV)
Hey, Sam, this is Jessie.
Jessie, this is Sam, my wife.
It's almost 1:00 a.m. I gotta work tomorrow.
Yeah, I know.
Um, this is my fault. I'm so sorry.
I'm the one who dragged him all into this.
We don't have an extra room.
Hope the couch is okay for you.
Yeah, it's fine.
I need to get to bed.
Thank...
- I'm sorry about that.
-(DOOR CLOSES)
- Undo these.
-Yeah.
- Okay, now.
-Yeah, thanks.
All right.
Well, just let me know
if you need anything else.
Thank you.
Night.
I'm sorry for getting you in trouble last night.
That's all right.
That's what old friends are for.
You're just lucky you were
asleep when she left for work this morning.
I see.
Yeah. So why do you wanna go to Woodbury?
Well, I think there's somebody who might
know who that baby girl is.
Do you remember Scott Davis from school?
Yeah, I remember him.
His mom, Abbey, used to cook for my mom
and dad back before I was born.
Well, if she's still alive, I'll take you there.
Excuse me, sir.
Abigail Davis live here?
Thank you.
Mrs. Davis?
Hey, Mrs. Davis.
I used to go to school with your son, Scott.
It's Preston. Remember me?
Me and Scott used to play together
when we were little.
You used to yell at us
forjumping off your garage. Remember?
Preston Saunders.
You're gonna break your arm up there,
and I'm gonna laugh my ass off.
(CHUCKLES)
It's good to see you, Mrs. Davis.
It's been a long time.
There's someone else here to see you.
This is Jessie. Jessie Laurent.
You used to cook for her folks.
Jessie Laurent?
Mmm-hmm.
Jessabelle!
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Mrs. Davis.
God, is she all right?
What did she say?
I don't know.
She say, "Rain wet us, Mama.
"Sun dried us, Papa.
"The betrayers are evil.
"Call down Djowou.
Call down Djowou will deal with them."
What's that mean?
It's an old song from Haiti.
They sing it to call the spirits
to possess someone.
Tell Moses Jessabelle
get what's coming to her!
(GASPING)
You Okay?
Goddamn voodoo shit.
I always hated Scott's mom.
Jessie, don't worry.
It's just some crazy old lady.
Probably says shit like that all the time.
What does that mean
"they call the spirits to get possessed"?
O" Purpose?
Well, yeah.
In voodoo, possession ain't a bad thing.
What?
Yeah, it's part of their ceremonies.
You call down the spirits,
and they possess you,
and you dance around. That's what they do.
How do you know that?
You grew up here, too.
There's voodoo all around this place.
They really get possessed?
Well, that depends on who you ask.
I think it's like hypnosis.
You know, like faith-healing,
speaking in tongues.
If you're raised to believe that,
that's what you're gonna think is real.
Plus they've got drums going,
people dancing around.
They rub blood on you.
You think you're possessed.
"Moses". She said, "Tell Moses."
I don't know. Voodoo mixes all kinds
of religions, Catholic, African.
It's all the same to them.
No, my mom knew a Moses.
She said that on the tape.
She learned tarot cards from Moses
at her church.
I think her church
was somewhere out near Jerry's Creek.
God damn it.
Well, I guess you get to see
my patented 175-point turn.
No, wait, wait, wait. What's that?
"Moses Harper. Born December 12th, 1952.
"Died June 12th, 1988."
What the hell is going on?
"Legba, open the gate.
Legba, let Moses back in."
MAN: Get out.
I'm Preston. This here is my friend...
(GUN COCKING)
- Let's go, Preston.
-Look, now, we don't want any trouble.
(ALL GRUNTING)
Hey! Stop it!
Wait!
- Preston, you all right?
-MAN: Go!
(PRESTON GROANING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
You're not coming back here.
Ever. There's no way.
Preston...
You're not gonna stay here.
You go in. Get whatever you need.
You can stay with us again.
Your wife's gonna be thrilled about that.
You could stay at my mom's.
My mom always liked you. You know that.
She's still got our prom pictures up.
That's another reason
why Sam's not so crazy about you.
She knows I still think about you.
And she knows
we're probably gonna move on.
But you didn't do it, Jessie.
Not you showing up right now.
It's just weird timing is all.
All right. I'm gonna get you out of here.
Ready?
Yeah.
Excuse me.
All right, let's get you packed.
Would you grab me that bag?
Yeah.
- Here you go.
-Thank you.
I'll get this over here.
Preston?
All right. Be right back.
You ready? All right.
(GASPS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
Preston?
(BOTH GRUNT)
(SHRIEKING LOUDLY)
(GRUNTING)
(SHRIEKING)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
Preston?
(GASPS) Oh! Preston!
(SIRENS WAILING)
Your boyfriend is in shock,
but his blood pressure is okay.
He should be fine when he comes to,
but they're running
him to the hospital just to be safe.
He's not my boyfriend.
We were just friends from high school.
Miss Laurent, do you mind telling me
what the hell's going on here?
We don't have the results
back on the DNA yet.
But that infant we found,
we do know was a female.
The date on her gravestone
was probably about right.
Well, then was she a stillborn?
No, she wasn't.
She was born alive. They know that.
Then she was murdered.
What?
From the nature of the fractures
and the splintering of the vertebrae,
it seems like somebodyjust picked her up
and snapped her over his knee
like a piece of firewood.
She was murdered.
(SIGHS)
Miss Laurent, I don't know
what the hell is going on around here,
but clearly,
you are one very frightened young woman.
She doesn't want to hurt us.
What?
She needs our help.
- Wh0?
-Uh...
Sheriff, would you mind
calling me when Preston wakes up, please?
All right.
Please call me when you know he's all right.
I know you were murdered.
What are you trying to tell me?
Who were you?
Please, I wanna help you.
Who are you?
FEMALE VOICE: Jessabelle.
What do you want from me?
(CELL PHONE BUZZES)
(GASPS)
Hello? Hello?
(DVSTORTED)
It's Sheriff Pruitt. Your boyfriend's come to.
He seems all right.
I thought you'd wanna know.
Oh, he's all right?
The paramedics said he should rest.
He won't even go to the hospital for an exam.
He wants me to take him
back out to the house
to protect you from something.
Do you know what that is?
Sheriff, I can barely hear you.
Miss Laurent, we also
just got the results back from the DNA test.
That deceased baby girl
that you dug up was black.
What did you say? She was black?
I don't understand.
Does that mean she was my half-sister?
They crossed your DNA
with your father's, with Leon's...
What?
(CRYING)
KATE ON TV: That's you crying.
You're crying 'cause you're scared.
You don't know where you are.
You don't know who you are.
You don't know shit!
(couemwe)
(BABY CONTINUES CRYING)
I'm gonna tell you who you are.
Because that's what good mothers do.
Jessabelle, you're dead.
Your father's dead.
Moses.
(KATE SINGING LULLABY)
No, it's all gonna be all right, isn't it?
I need you, sugar. I need you.
Good girl.
You're gonna come back.
I'm gonna hold the door open for you.
(CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Jessabelle,
you're gonna get what's coming to you!
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPS)
The unwanted presence in the house.
When you see it, it's broken, right?
It wasn't the ghost. It was me.
You were telling someone else's fortune,
weren't you?
You know what it says here?
It says that you've never left St. Francis
and that you're never gonna leave.
Your real daughter, not me.
You gave your life for Jessabelle.
Didn't do chemo.
When the baby was born,
it wasn't Dad's.
(BABY CRYING)
No, no!
He killed her, didn't he?
(SOBBING)
Moses taught me how to read cards.
MOSES: Look at those.
Don't tell Dad. He'd kill me.
(LAUGHS)
-(GUNSHOT)
-(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOT)
So Leon adopted a baby girl
to cover the crime?
A white girl, me.
(KATE CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Your church, Moses' church.
MAN: Get out.
They gave her the grave.
(DRUMS PLAYING)
(PEOPLE VOCALIZING)
(INDISTINCT SINGING)
What do you want from me?
What can I do?
Moses.
What are you doing?
Payback.
What?
(CHANTING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
No! No.
It's not my fault!
Somebody!
(MOSES CONTINUES CHANTING)
Help!
No! What do you want from me?
All Jessabelle wants is what's coming to her.
Somebody! No!
No!
Let me go!
What is... No, no, no!
No!
Please don't.
Where are you taking me?
No, God! Please.
Please!
Jessie!
Please! Help me!
(YELLING INDISTINCTLY)
No! God!
(MUFFLED GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
Oh, my God! Hold on. Hold on.
You all right?
I thought I lost you.
Take me home, my love.
Miss Laurent? Are you all right?
Miss Laurent!
It's Jessabelle.
(VOICES WHISPERING)