(Discordant vocalizing)
(wind whistling)
(sirens wailing)
(tires screeching)
(man panting, wheezing)
131 to dispatch, come in.
(Radio waves squealing)
(man panting, snarling)
Medic:
Hey hey hey hey!
(Men grunting)
Man over radio:
131, this is dispatch. Go ahead.
Man: This is 131.
We have a male, mid-50s,
with burns over 9% to 9.5%
of his body.
Prior to our arrival on scene,
patient apparently doused his head,
neck and face with some sort of
highly-concentrated acid.
The patient's airway is severely
compromised due to fume inhalation.
Vital signs unstable.
Please advise- patient is
a criminal suspect.
We're coming in
with a police escort right now.
(Banging, man snarling)
(respirator hissing)
(knocks)
Hi.
Can I talk to him?
He can't actually talk.
(Sighs)
All right.
Jesus.
Can I just have
a few minutes with him?
(Respirator hissing)
(paper rustling)
(sighs)
We want to know who you are.
We'll find out, you know,
sooner or later.
So just save us some legwork
by communicating with us now.
Are you a Satanist?
Are you involved
in some kind of cult?
'Cause if there's others involved,
we'll get them.
We'll find them, believe me.
- (Heart monitor beeping rapidly)
- What's the matter?
Is that it?
That's it, right?
Is there somebody you want
to tell me about?
(Patient wheezing)
(footsteps)
Woman: I'm sorry,
the nurse at reception
downstairs is on the phone.
She wants to talk to you,
says it's urgent.
Okay.
(Distant TV chatter)
I'll be right back, okay?
(Patient breathing heavily)
President Reagan:
Thank you very much...
Detective: Yeah.
Reagan:
...Reverend Clergy all,
Senator Hawkins...
His daughter?
When was this?
- Is she still here?
- (Monitor beeping rapidly)
Well, did she leave
any information,
a phone number?
What do you mean a little girl?
How little?
(Nurse screaming)
- (woman whimpering)
- Officer: Dispatch, this is Baker 17.
I’m gonna need
a medical backup.
(Wind rushing)
Jesus, Mary, Joseph.
Man: Somebody help!
President Reagan:
There is sin and evil in the world,
and we're enjoined by Scripture
and the Lord Jesus
to oppose it with all our might.
Our nation, too, has a legacy of evil
with which it must deal.
The glory of this land
has been its capacity
for transcending the moral evils
of our past.
Alexis de Tocqueville
put it eloquently
after he had gone on a search
for the secret
of America's greatness
and genius-
when he said: "Not until I went
into the churches of America
and heard her pulpits
aflame with righteousness
did I understand the greatness
and the genius of America."
America is good.
And if America
ever ceases to be good-
Boy: ♪ Eat some now,
save some for later ♪
- (paper rustling)
- ♪ Eat some now, save some for later ♪
♪Now & Later ♪
♪The really tasty ones ♪
(chewing)
♪Now & Later ♪
♪For all-day children's fun ♪
♪Look at all those pieces... ♪
- Woman: Owen!
- ♪ Flavors, oh they're wild ♪
♪Eat some now, save some for later,
eat some now, save some for later... ♪
- Owen!
- What?
Dinnertime, honey.
(Distant dog barking)
(humming a tune)
Bless us O Lord
for these Thy gifts
which we are about to receive.
Please guide and direct us
through all our days
and protect us from evil.
Amen.
So how was school today?
You didn't go and spoil your dinner
on me now, did you, Owen?
No.
- Owen, sweetie-
- No, I didn't.
(Phone ringing)
Eat, please, honey.
Hello.
What?
Look, I’m not gonna
discuss this now, okay?
We're eating dinner.
We had an agreement, John.
I think maybe you'd better
call my lawyer, okay?
Don't talk to me like that!
I will not be spoken to
in that way.
Preacher over radio:
...Judgment to fall.
And if we as a people
turn back to God...
(mother crying)
Preacher:
These are the young people.
The young people are beginning
to turn back to God
Who's waiting on them.
If the Lord calls you,
then the Word comes.
And the Word came
from the Lord...
Hey little girl.
Are you a little girl?
Huh?
Are you scared?
(Woman shouting,
dog barking)
(shouting indistinctly)
(distant pop music playing)
♪Let's dance ♪
♪Put on your red shoes ♪
♪And dance the blues ♪
♪Let's dance ♪
♪To the song they're playin' ♪
♪On the radio ♪
♪Let's sway while color
lights up your face... ♪
(dog barking)
(large vehicle approaches)
(brakes squeal)
(engine stops)
(car door opens and closes)
(children's choir singing)
(keys jingle)
(door opens)
(metal gate opens and closes)
Children:
I pledge allegiance to the flag
of the United States of America
and to the republic
for which it stands,
one nation under God,
indivisible,
with liberty and justice for all.
(Children chattering)
- Stop!
- (Teasing) How's it going?
Stop it. Mr. Zoric.
Okay, Kenny, 10 laps now.
I didn't do anything.
Now!
Or I’ll make it 20.
(Children howling, whooping)
(panting)
Hey little girl.
Ow! Don't.
Are you a little girl?
- Ow.
- (Boys laugh)
That's why he won't
go swimming.
He doesn't want everyone to see
what a little fucking girl he is.
(Boys laugh)
Ow.
(Grunting)
Stop.
- Kenny: Get down. Get his arms.
- Stop.
- Get his arms.
- Ow ow.
Little shit.
(Muffled yells)
Stop.
Ow! Stop! Ow!
Stop, it hurts!
No no no! Shit.
Ow! Stop!
Ow!
Dude, I think he pissed himself.
Oh shit.
(Laughs)
Boy: What the fuck?
He pissed himself.
Jesus Christ, fucking freak.
(Kicks)
(boys laughing)
- Jesus.
- That was awesome.
Boys:
Owen! Owen!
Owen pissed himself!
♪Turning down,
I’m turning in, I’m turning round ♪
♪I’m turning Japanese,
I think I’m turning Japanese ♪
- ♪ I really think so... ♪
- (video games bleeping)
♪Turning Japanese,
I think I’m turning Japanese ♪
♪I really think so... ♪
Cashier:
Is that gonna be it?
♪Turning Japanese,
I think I’m turning Japanese ♪
♪I really think so... ♪
Owen:
Are you scared?
Are you scared, little girl?
Huh?
(Wind whispering)
What are you doing?
Nothing.
You- you guys
just moved in, huh,
upstairs?
How do you know?
I live next door to you.
Right there.
Just so you know,
I can't be your friend.
Why not?
That's just the way it is.
(Distant train whistle blowing)
Well, who said I wanted
to be your friend?
Idiot.
♪Eat some now,
save some for later ♪
♪Eat some now, save some
for later... ♪
(door opens and closes)
(lighter flicking)
(engine starts,
sports playing on radio)
(crossing bells dinging,
train whistle blaring)
(crossing bells dinging)
(bells stop)
(grunting)
(exclaims)
(panting)
(muffled panting,
deep voice shouting)
(distant door slams)
(panting, grunting continues)
(deep voice)
What am I supposed to do?
Am I supposed to go out there
and do it myself?
Huh?
(Pounding)
Answer me!
Maybe I’m getting sloppy.
(Creature panting)
Maybe I want to get caught.
Maybe I’m just tired of this.
(Receding footsteps)
(door slams)
(sighs)
(school bell ringing)
Detective:
Excuse me, everyone.
Let me through here, please.
Policeman over microphone:
As some of you may have heard,
there was an incident
last night
and one of your recent
graduates here was killed.
(Boys snickering, whispering)
I want to assure you that
we're doing everything possible
to find those responsible
for this tragedy.
But in the meantime
we need you all to be on the lookout
for any suspicious activity,
because your safety
is our number-one concern.
(Stomach rumbles quietly)
It's you again, huh?
You know, I really want
to be left alone.
- Me too.
- So leave.
You leave.
I've lived here
longer than you.
What is that?
What, this?
It’s a Rubik's Cube.
You don't know Rubik's Cube?
Is it a puzzle?
Yeah.
Want to try it?
You can give it back tomorrow.
How do you do it?
You gotta get each side
one color.
Like that.
(Stomach rumbles quietly)
You smell kind of funny.
Aren't you cold?
I don't really get cold.
I guess I’ll see you tomorrow.
(Stomach growling)
(pop song playing
through headphones)
♪Let's dance... ♪
(car passes)
♪Let's dance ♪
♪To the song they're playing... ♪
(panting)
Girl: Help me.
Hello?
Girl: Please.
Help me.
Man: Hello?
Hey there.
Are you okay?
What happened?
I fell.
Yeah?
Well,
can't you get up?
No.
How old are you, sweetheart?
Do you live around here?
I live right here.
(Stomach rumbling)
Can you carry me?
Sure. Sure, sweetheart.
Just grab on, honey, okay?
- Got it?
- Thank you.
(Girl snarling,
man screaming)
(girl growling, sucking)
(growling)
(panting)
(bone cracks)
Man: What did you do?
What did you do?!
(Muffled arguing)
Man:
You did it again!
(Arguing continues)
Man:
I have to clean it up!
Bitch! Oh you fucking bitch!
- (Rapid footsteps, door slams)
- (gasps)
(door opens)
(keys jingle)
Fuck this shit.
Fuck!
(Grunting)
(grunts)
(birds chirping)
(school bell ringing)
How did you do it?
I just... twisted it.
Do I smell better now?
What's your name?
Abby. What's yours?
I’m Owen.
How old are you?
12, more or less.
What about you?
12 years, eight months
and nine days.
What do you mean,
more or less?
When's your birthday?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Don't you celebrate
your birthday?
Do you get
birthday presents?
No.
Well, you can have this
if you want.
That's okay.
It’s yours.
I still don't get
how you did this.
Want me to show you?
Yeah.
Romeo:
I must be gone and live,
or stay and die.
Juliet:
Yon light is not daylight.
(Kids giggling)
I know it, I.
Therefore stay yet;
thou need'st not to be gone.
Romeo:
Oh, let me be taken,
let me be put to death;
I am content,
so thou wilt have it so.
I’ll say yon gray is not
the morning's eye...
(urinating)
(boys whispering)
Shh.
- Boy: Shh shh.
- (Banging)
(loud banging)
What were you writing
back there?
What do you mean?
In Cook's class.
Let's see it.
No.
No?
Where is it?
- Ow.
- Show me.
- Jesus Christ, dude.
- What?
You explain that to his mom.
It’s okay.
She's not going to tell her mom
on us, is she?
She fell down on the playground,
that's all.
Right?
Say it, little girl.
Say it!
(School bell ringing)
Come on, man, let's go.
Owen: I fell down
on the playground.
You have to be more careful,
okay, honey?
(Kisses)
I hate to see my baby
get hurt.
Bless us O Lord
for these Thy gifts
which we are about
to receive.
Please guide and direct us for all
our days and protect us from evil.
Okay look, I made one for you
and one for me.
Are you reading this?
Yeah, it's for school. It’s boring.
Come on, look at this.
It’s really cool.
We can talk to each other
through the wall.
Can you hear me
through the wall?
Only sometimes.
Did you hear anything
the other night?
Why was your dad so mad?
Where's your mom?
Are your parents divorced?
My mom's dead.
My mom and dad
are getting a divorce.
What happened there?
Just some kids from school.
Where do you go to school anyway?
I’ve never seen you-
Owen, listen.
What?
You have to hit back.
You have to hit back hard.
I can't.
- There's three of them.
- Then you hit back even harder.
Hit them harder than you dare
and then they'll stop.
What if they hit me back?
You have a knife.
Yeah, and what if that
doesn't stop 'em?
Then I’ll help you.
But you're a girl.
I’m a lot stronger
than you think I am.
I have to get in there.
Move.
(Music playing
through headphones)
♪Dance the blues... ♪
(Owen knocking)
♪Let's dance... ♪
(Abby knocking)
Owen:
Mr. Zoric?
Yes, Owen?
I was just wondering about
the after-school strength training.
Can people still sign up?
Would you like to get strong?
Okay.
4:00 you come-
we make you strong.
Cool.
(Shower running)
(song playing on radio)
♪Do you really want to hurt me? ♪
This is Ms. Pac-Man.
Now I’ll play.
♪Do you really want
to make me cry? ♪
- And...
- (game beeping)
...when you get the big thing,
you can eat them.
- Right there.
- Yeah, let me do it.
♪In my heart the fire's burning... ♪
- God, I hate this game.
- (Abby chuckles)
You want some?
They're really good.
They're my favorite.
They're really really good.
No thanks.
Well, what do you like?
You can have
anything you want.
That's okay.
Oh, okay.
I guess this is it.
Hey.
I guess I could have one.
Really?
Here, it's grape.
I like it.
(Coughing)
(distant train passing)
I’m sorry.
Owen, do you like me?
Yeah.
A lot.
Would you still like me
even if I wasn't a girl?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
I guess.
Why?
No reason.
So where are you guys from?
How come you moved here?
Abby: We...
we move around a lot.
Yeah, but why would you
move here?
Nobody moves here.
I hate it here.
Someday I’m gonna get out
and I’ll never come back.
The people here...
they're-
they're just stupid.
Mother: Owen!
God.
Hang on.
What?
You promised me
you wouldn't leave the courtyard.
Mom, I’ve been here
the whole time.
Well, come up.
It’s time for dinner.
God.
(Distant train whistle blowing)
Good night.
(Door opens and closes)
Are you going out?
Is there a choice?
Please don't see
that boy again.
Okay?
(Engine starts)
Hey, Jett.
Hey.
Jett: Hey, what's up?
Can I get a ride? Keith went over
to see his girlfriend.
Jett:
Yeah, sure. Get in.
(Door opens)
Man: Keith's so fucking
whipped, dude.
I can't even
deal with it anymore.
- Jett: What are you doing?
- I’m trying to move the seat.
It’s in the front.
Man: Hey, thanks for
picking me up, man.
Jett: Yeah man, anytime.
Man: Keith would have left me
stuck there all night.
(Two loud dings)
(brakes squeak,
engine idling)
- Man: Do you need gas?
- Jett: Yeah.
(Door opens,
door alarm dinging)
(door closes,
receding footsteps)
(jingling)
(changing radio stations)
(pop song playing)
♪Home isn't pretty ♪
♪Ain't no home for me ♪
♪Home in the darkness ♪
♪Home on the highway ♪
♪Home isn't my way ♪
♪Home I’ll never be ♪
♪Burn out the day ♪
♪Burn out the night ♪
- ♪ I can't see no reason... ♪
- Fuck! Fuck!
♪To put up a fight... ♪
Help!
Thanks.
(Two dings)
- What's up, Jett?
- Hey guys, what's going on?
♪I’m not the one to tell you ♪
♪What's wrong or what's right... ♪
(screaming)
Help!
♪I’ve seen suns that were freezing
and lies that were true ♪
♪But I’m burnin', I’m burnin' ♪
♪I’m burnin' for you... ♪
(man panting)
♪I’m burnin', I’m burnin' ♪
♪I’m burnin' for you... ♪
(engine starts)
What the fuck?
That's my car! Hey, my car!
Stop the car!
(Men shouting)
Jett: What the fuck?
- (Tires screeching, horn honking)
- (father screaming)
(song continues)
- Argh! Argh! Argh!
- (Horn honks)
(crashing)
(horn honking continuously)
(honking continues)
(moaning)
Jett:
Greg was in there.
- Man: What?
- Jett: He was in the car!
Jett: Hey!
Greg.
Greg!
Abby.
(Flesh hissing)
(screaming)
(muffled radio playing)
(announcer speaking on radio)
An unidentified man
has been arrested in connection
with the recent ritual murder
of a local high school honor student.
The suspect is hospitalized
in critical condition
with severe self-inflicted acid burns
over his face and torso
making it impossible so far for
authorities to determine his identity.
(Jingle playing)
♪Eat some now, save some for later,
eat some now, save some for later ♪
♪Now & Lat- ♪
Man on TV: Ladies and gentlemen,
the President of the United States,
- Ronald Reagan.
- (Applause)
President Reagan:
Thank you.
Abby: Excuse me,
I’m looking for my father.
Is he a patient here?
Yeah, they-
they brought him in.
The police did.
Oh, I see.
Do you know where he is?
Well, he's on the 10th floor,
sweetie, but it's restricted.
Look, why don't we give them
a call and tell them-?
No no, that's okay.
Oh my God, the poor girl.
Sweetie, sweetie!
(Respirator hissing)
(air hisses)
(monitor beeping rapidly)
(wind whistling)
May I come in?
(Wheezing)
(monitor beeping rapidly)
Detective: His daughter?
When was this?
Is she still here?
Well, did she leave
any information,
a phone number?
What do you mean a little girl?
How little?
(Nurse screaming)
(radio chatter,
woman whimpering)
(wind whistling)
Jesus, Mary, Joseph.
Man: Somebody help!
(Wings flutter)
(wind howling)
(knocks)
Owen.
Hmm?
Abby: Can I come in?
No no no, wait wait.
Don't look at me.
But you have to say it-
that I can come in.
You can come in.
Close your eyes.
They're already closed.
(Unzipping)
How did you get up here?
I flew.
Yeah, right.
Hey, you're not
wearing anything.
And you're freezing.
Is that gross?
No.
Abby...
Yeah?
Will you go steady with me?
What do you mean?
Will you be my girlfriend?
Owen,
I’m not a girl.
You're not a girl?
No.
What are you?
I’m nothing.
Oh.
You know, it's okay
if you don't want to be my girlfriend.
You don't have to make stuff up.
Look, can we just keep things
the way they are?
Yeah, sure.
Well, do you have to do anything
special
when you go steady?
No.
So everything's the same?
Yeah.
Okay.
We can go steady.
Really?
Yeah.
(Birds chirping)
"I must be gone and live
or stay and die."
(Children chattering)
Zoric:
Slow down.
Hockey you play
in the center;
Free skating over that side.
Now, everyone,
careful of holes in ice.
Stay away from the holes.
I hope you've been learning
how to swim,
'cause today
you're going in.
Go.
Bring it up
and start passing.
Pass pass pass.
Over here.
What do you think
you're gonna do with that?
I’m gonna hit you with it
if you try anything.
Really?
Wow.
You know what I think?
I don't think you're gonna do
a fucking thing.
I think you're just gonna stand there
like the little girl you are.
And I’m gonna grab that stick
and ram it right up your ass.
And then
you're going swimming.
I want to hear click-click-click-click.
Bully: Shit, dude. Zoric's right
over there checking us out.
Let it go.
We'll beat his little ass later.
Give me the stick.
Argh!
(Kenny screaming)
Jesus Christ,
are you fucking crazy?
Hey!
- (Kenny screaming)
- Hey!
- (Children screaming)
- Boy #2: Hey hey hey!
Okay okay, just move.
Please, just move back.
Move back.
(Saw buzzing)
Woman: Give me one reason
why I shouldn't suspend you, Owen.
Can you think of one?
Don't you know
what could have happened?
You seem like a smart kid.
I just don't want to see you
going down the wrong path.
He's a good boy.
He really is.
- (Doorbell ringing)
- Mother: Hello, is John there?
Excuse me, this is his wife.
Who is this?
Hello, Cindy.
Will you please tell John
that I called?
Detective: Hey there.
Is your mom and dad home?
Yeah.
Mom!
(Mom hangs up phone)
What?
- Oh.
- Sorry to bother you, ma'am.
- What's this about?
- I’m afraid there's been an incident
with one of your neighbors
here in the complex.
So we're just going around, talking to
everybody to see if they know anything.
What kind of incident?
Owen, why don't you
go to your room?
(Indistinct conversation)
(distant police radio chatter)
(distant dog barking)
(knocking)
(doorbell rings)
(pounding on door)
(pounding and ringing
continues)
(floorboard squeaks)
(distant doorbell rings,
knocking)
(distant police radio chatter)
- Boy: Sorry, guys.
- Jeez, could you take any longer?
- I said sorry.
- Come on, let's go play Centipede.
Kenny: Man, why are you even
in that class? It’s so gay, dude.
Boy: Whatever.
Hey! Stop!
- How's the cripple?
- Stop! Hey!
(Boys laugh)
Jesus Christ, dude, watch out.
Man, that kid whaled on your ass.
Can you still hear me, bro?
Stop.
Are you going home?
No, we're going over
to Mark's.
Can I borrow your keys?
I forgot mine.
Please.
Give me the fucking keys.
Thanks.
- See you at home, little girl.
- Hey.
(Boys chuckle)
Kenny: Shut up.
- We didn't say anything.
- Shut up.
Owen: Abby, I did it.
You did what?
They were gonna push me
in the hole in the ice,
so I got a really big stick and I hit
Kenny in the head really hard.
He had to go to the hospital.
I almost got suspended,
but I didn't.
What you said-
I stood up to them.
Owen.
Yeah?
Hey, you want to go somewhere?
Where?
(Children's laughter
and footsteps echoing)
(door squeaks)
(light switch clicks)
(echoing)
It’s pretty cool, huh?
Yeah.
This kid that used to live
in the building-
Tommy-
he would come down here
and drink and smoke
with his high school friends.
And when they weren't here,
he'd play ping-pong with me.
He was really cool.
But then he had to move away.
I kind of like it here.
It’s cool.
And I don't think any of the adults
know about it-
it's just us.
(Turns on stereo)
(pop song playing)
So what did you want to do
down here?
Uh...
I think I have an idea.
Close your eyes.
Keep them closed.
Let's make a pact.
It only hurts for a second.
Here.
(Music sounds distorted)
(exhales)
(growling)
Abby?
(Growling, panting)
(deep voice)
Go away.
- (Dog barking)
- Man: Virginia.
(Abby panting)
Man:
God damn it, Virginia.
- Virginia!
- (Abby growling)
(screaming, dog barking)
- Man: Get-
- (Abby growling)
off!
Man: Hey.
- Hey.
- (Dog barking)
Somebody call 911!
(Police radio chatter)
(people chattering)
Mom?
Mom.
(Phone line ringing)
John over phone:
Hello?
Dad,
can I talk to you?
John: Yeah sure, pal.
What is it?
Do you-
do you think
there's such a thing as evil?
John: What?
What are you talking about, pal?
Can people be evil?
Listen, where are you getting
all this stuff?
Is this from your mother-
- all her religious crap?
- No.
You know what, Owen?
Listen listen,
put your mother on the phone,
okay? I want to talk to her.
She-
she's not here.
All right, she's not-
okay well, please tell her to call.
Just tell her to call me
when she gets back, all right?
Okay?
Dad.
Owen, I want you to get that crap
out of your head, okay?
Your mother- she-
listen, look, she has problems.
And I’m gonna talk to her.
So I don't want to hear
any more of this.
All right?
Yeah.
You have a good night, pal.
I love you.
I’m sorry about the last
couple of months, you know?
But I’ll see you soon-
real soon, okay?
I promise.
Maybe next weekend.
Owen: Mm-hmm.
I love you.
(Clicks, dial tone)
(crying)
(doorbell rings)
Can I come in?
You have to say it.
You can come in.
(Exhales)
Are you a vampire?
I need blood
to live.
But how old are you- really?
12.
But...
I’ve been 12
for a very long time.
(Distant radio chatter)
Where's your dad?
He wasn't my dad.
What's all this stuff?
I like puzzles.
I want to go now.
I want to go.
Are you gonna let me?
What are you gonna do to me?
I told you we couldn't be friends.
(Receding footsteps)
(P.A. chatter)
(knocks)
Hi. Are you Larry?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Sure.
Detective:
I’m sorry to bother you.
How is she doing?
Larry:
It’s been quite a night.
They had to give her
over six pints of blood.
We're just waiting to see
if her body rejects it.
Detective:
Well, I won't keep you long.
I just- I need ask you about
the description you gave
of the little girl.
You said that she had
long blonde hair,
she was 12 years old
and she wasn't wearing
any shoes.
- Right?
- That's right.
Have you ever seen this man?
He's a suspect
in a murder investigation.
Larry: Looks like a guy
from our building.
Did he have a daughter
like the girl you described?
I don't know.
I’ve only seen him a few times.
(Sucking, swallowing sounds)
Why? Do you think this has
something to do with your murder case?
Maybe. We're starting to think
that some of them might be involved
- in some sort of Satanic cult.
- What?
We found another body
a few days ago-
same MO,
victim completely drained of blood.
There were two bite marks,
small ones,
on the victim's neck-
just like a little child's.
Larry: Jesus Christ.
(Sucking)
(sizzling, screaming)
Oh!
- Virginia, Virginia.
- Stay back. Stay back.
(Fire alarm ringing)
(stove beeping)
(switch clicks,
plate sizzling)
Owen: Oh- mm.
(Distant TV playing)
We're told one patient
was killed in the fire
as well as one hospital nurse.
The five-alarm fire started
on the eighth floor of the hospital
and took most of the day
- for crews to contain.
- (Knocking on door)
The official cause is still
under investigation.
- Hey.
You have to invite me in
to your home.
What if I don't?
Why can't you just come in?
Is there something in your way?
(Exhales)
No no no, stop stop.
You can come in.
What was that?
I don't know.
I just know this is what happens
if you don't invite me in.
What if I didn't say anything?
Would you have kept bleeding?
Would you have died?
I knew you wouldn't let me.
(Upbeat song playing)
♪We had broken up for good
just an hour before ♪
♪Oh-oh oh oh-oh-oh
oh-oh ♪
♪And now I’m staring at the bodies
as they're dancing 'cross the floor ♪
♪Oh-oh oh oh-oh-oh
oh-oh... ♪
You can borrow one of my mom's
old dresses if you want.
♪Oh-oh oh oh-oh-oh
oh-oh ♪
♪It was the same old song
with the melancholy sound ♪
♪Oh-oh oh oh-oh-oh
oh-oh ♪
♪They don't write 'em
like that anymore ♪
♪They just don't write 'em
♪We'd been living together
for a million years ♪
♪Oh-oh oh oh-oh-oh
oh-oh... ♪
Mother: Hello?
Owen.
Owen: I’m in here.
I’ll be right there.
(Distant dog barking)
(Abby laughing)
(distant train whistle blowing)
(door squeaks)
Radio DJ:
Los Alamos weather at 6:20 AM.
Calm and cold this morning
with temperatures around 24°,
then picking up this afternoon
bringing snow flurries.
We're expecting 6-12" of snow
in the next 24 hours...
(grunts)
(Owen whispering)
"Hi Owen. Good morning.
I am in the bathroom.
Please do not come in.
Want to hang out with me
again tonight?
I really like you.
Love, Abby."
(Doorbell rings)
(pounding on door)
(knocks)
(floorboard squeaks)
Hello?
Police department.
Open the door.
(Knocks)
Open the door!
Police officer!
(Clicking)
Owen:
No no, stop!
Jesus.
(Abby screaming)
(Abby and policeman screaming)
(screams)
(crunching, detective screaming)
(sucking, slurping sounds)
Owen, I have to go away.
(Wind whispering)
(Owen crying)
(children chattering)
Ah, speak of the devil.
There he is.
Hi.
Today we start in pool, okay?
Okay.
Hey Owen.
Oh, hi.
He's here.
(Boys giggling)
Come on, hurry up.
(Bullies muttering)
Just like we did before,
kick, then in water-
one-two-three breathe,
one-two-three breathe.
Kick kick. Good.
One-two-three breathe.
Yes.
Mark:
Mr. Zoric, there's a fire.
- What?
- Out back.
Owen, I’ll be right back.
- Where?
- At the dumpsters.
Jimmy:
Everybody out of the pool.
Move. Come on, get out.
Out.
I said everybody get out.
- Get out of the pool.
- Kenny: Owen!
(Boys shouting)
Kenny: Owen!
Owen!
What are you gonna do
with that?
No no no no.
Stop!
No no. No! Help!
Stop! Guys, stop!
(Screaming)
No. Stop. Stop.
Stop! Stop!
Oh! Somebody! Ow!
Stop!
Grab his arms.
Get his arms.
No no, stop it.
(Gasping)
We're gonna have
a little contest, okay?
You stay underwater for...
three minutes.
If you can do it,
I’ll just give you a little nick-
on your cheek.
But if you can't,
I’m gonna poke out
one of your eyes.
Got it?
An eye for an ear.
Three minutes.
You'd better take a deep breath.
- Okay, Jimmy.
- Shut up.
- Dude, come on.
- I said shut up!
- (Glass shatters, creature roaring)
- What the f-?
- (Creature roars)
- What the fuck is this? Argh!
Kenny:
Oh my God, Jimmy! Jimmy!
Oh my God, oh my God.
Boy: No no no no!
- (Creature roaring)
- (Owen gasping)
Kenny: No no.
(Screams)
(bones cracking, thuds)
(screaming, roaring continue)
(splashes)
(wings flutter)
(coughs)
(train wheels clacking)
Excuse me,
can I see your ticket?
Is that trunk yours?
(Rhythmic knocks)
♪Eat some now,
save some for later ♪
save some for later. ♪
(Instrumental music playing)
(distant train whistle blowing)
(wind whistling)
(train wheels clacking)
(children laughing)