[Choir]
¶Mater¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ Mater Lacrimarum ¶
[Man, Echoing]
Mater.
¶¶ [Choir Continues]
[Man, Echoing]
Mater.
[Banging]
[Man, Echoing]
Mater.
Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
Easy now.
[Men Gasping]
- You okay?
- Hey, there's something down here!
"Oscar de la Vallé, 1815."
Cut the chains.
[Grunts]
We'll rebury him on the other side
of the cemetery...
later tonight.
And the urn?
Put it in my car.
- Hang on, Monsignor.
- [Creature Roars]
[Monsignor's Voice]
Dear Michael...
we found
something alarming today...
right outside of the cemetery.
I'm sending this urn
over to you...
that you can examine
its contents.
You know more
about the history of magic...
and esoteric sciences
than I do...
and I'm hoping you can deny...
what I fear.
Hey, Sarah.
You seen Michael?
Not for a couple of hours.
- He had to take Paul to the doctor.
- Oh, that's right.
I was wondering why he
wasn't answering his cell.
Come take a look at something.
What?
Here, let me show you.
Come with me.
All right.
- What is it?
- Come. I'll show you.
I know it's late,
but you really need to check this out.
- Really?
- Yeah.
don't keep me hanging.
What is it?
- All right. It's an urn.
- Really?
Yes.
- Where'd it come from?
- Viterbo. A Monsignor Brusca sent it.
They found it with
a coffin buried in 1815.
[Man, Echoing]
Mater.
- Isn't this amazing?
- I've never seen anything like this.
I know.
[Phone Beeping]
Oh. Michael's phone is still off.
[Sighs]
What do you think?
Should we risk opening it without him?
- don't ask me.
- [Laughs] Yeah, right.
You know what? We're just gonna
open it up, and I won't touch the letter.
- deal.
- Okay.
- Let's do it.
- All right.
Do you need help?
No, I think I'm okay.
Ow! damn it!
Are you okay?
What is it?
Aah. I cut myself.
I'll be all right.
- It's okay. Are you ready?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Let's do it.
- Let's go.
- Like this?
Yeah. It's a little tough.
All right. Yeah, there you go.
Careful.
Yeah.
Wow.
Take a careful look at the hilt.
- Tell me what you see.
- The gemstone settings.
It's a medieval technique,
isn't it?
Very good.
Thirteenth century, most likely.
Look. Three statues.
- That's kind of scary.
- Yeah.
- You take it.
- There you go.
Okay. Oh, there's more.
Look at this. Okay.
They're so well-preserved.
- Yeah.
- Look at this writing.
- Hey, there's more.
- Yeah?
This is some kind of talisman.
Can you read the writing?
No, not offhand.
It's some ancient language.
You know what? Go and grab the Aramaic
and Mycenaean dictionaries, will you?
- Yeah.
- He'll want us to move on this right away.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
"Seera Leraji"-
[Creature Growls]
"Sabnack. "
- [Rumbling]
- [Gasps]
[Whimpering]
[Rumbling Stops]
[Sighs]
- [Screeches]
- Huh?
- [Creatures Roaring]
- [Screams] No! No!
- Help me! No!
- [Screeches]
[Screaming]
[Creatures Laughing]
[Gagging]
[Moaning]
- [Flesh Slicing]
- [Groaning]
[Loud Moan]
[Moaning]
[Screeches]
- [Moaning Continues]
- [Creatures Laughing]
[Voice Whispering]
Mater. Mater.
[Voices Moaning]
[Growling]
[Gasping]
[Screeching]
[Screeches]
[Screeching Continues]
- [Growling]
- [Creature Grunts]
[Creature Grunts]
[Panting]
[Grunting]
[Growls, Screeches]
[Woman's Voice]
Go now.
Go now!
[Whimpering]
[Screeching]
Hello. Help!
Please help me!
You saw four people, and they were,
to use your words, "deformed"?
I didn't see their faces, but...
there was something very strange
about the way they moved.
- How so?
- It was like-
God, they tore her to bits.
- The blood, it was-
- Wait.
- How did they move?
- Well, they were sort of hunched over.
But I only saw them
for a few seconds.
- So there were three deformed people.
- Yes, and a monkey.
[Laughs]
- A monkey?
- Yes. It was chasing me.
Okay.
Sarah.
So what exactly do you
do for the institute, Sarah?
I'm studying art restoration
and archaeology.
Mm-hmm.
And did you manage to catalog
these pieces of art...
that were stolen before
they were taken away?
No.
We were just starting
to examine them.
Look, I told you
everything I know.
Can I please
go home now, please?
- Sarah!
- No, it's okay. Let him in.
- Michael. Oh, my God.
- Sarah! Hey, are you okay?
- Michael, it was horrible. And Giselle, she-
- Shh. Shh. It's okay.
It's okay. I'm here now.
It's okay.
Hi, I'm Michael Pierce.
I'm the director of the museum.
I am Enzo Marchi,
the head of this investigation.
Great.
- Look, I'm gonna take her home now, okay?
- Of course. No problem.
- Thank you.
- Are you all right?
I can't believe it.
did you hear that?
She's crazy.
You're some detective, you know?
- Sure.
- Go and keep an eye on her.
[Sighs]
Can I stay at your place tonight?
I really don't feel like being alone.
Of course you can.
It's freezing outside.
- Can I light a fire?
- Yeah, sure. I'm just gonna check on Paul.
All right.
Good. Well, he's still asleep.
Something very strange happened
to me tonight.
And, uh, I feel almost embarrassed
to tell you about it.
What?
Promise me you won't think
I'm crazy.
- I promise.
- All right.
I was trapped in there.
And there was no way I was gonna
get out of there alive.
- And then-
- What?
Nah, never mind.
Come on. Tell me.
And then...
I heard a voice in my head...
telling me to go.
And then- bam-
the doors slammed open!
I mean, they were locked
and they slammed open!
And I-And there was
this woman too-
[Boy]
Dad?
Hey, tiger!
What are you doing up? Huh?
I thought you were asleep.
Ah, come here.
- Hi, Paul.
- Hi, Sarah.
- do you want some hot chocolate?
- Yes. Can I stay up late?
Yes, you can stay up late.
Let's choose one of your books,
and we'll take you to bed.
Which one are you gonna get?
This one? Okay.
I'm gonna come in with the hot chocolate now.
Come on. Back to bed.
Coming in a second, all right?
[Sarah]
I just can't get my head around it.
Why did they have to kill Giselle?
What was so important
about that urn?
Well, from what you told me,
they could be talismans.
Look, I'm gonna go and see
Monsignor Brusca tomorrow morning.
Maybe he can shed
some more light on it.
How do you know him?
Well, he came to London a few years ago
to lecture on spiritualism.
And he's meant to be a leading authority
on mysticism and the occult sciences-
"Sciences"? Come on.
You don't believe in that crap.
- The occult?
- Yeah.
Well, maybe, maybe not.
- Hmph.
- What? [Chuckles]
I was just-
What, you don't think there are forces
out there we don't understand?
Not really, no.
You and I are scientists.
We're supposed to believe in
what we see and what we touch.
[Boiling]
- The chocolate!
- See? Forces.
I keep hearing that voice
echoing in my head.
I think I'm going crazy.
You're not going crazy.
Come here.
[Sighs]
You're not going crazy. You just-
[Kisses Head]
Just need to sleep.
Hmm?
Just try to sleep, hmm?
[Woman]
Chaos. Blood. Tears.
[Men, Women]
Mater! Mater!
[Voices Chattering, Moaning]
[Chattering, Moaning Continues]
[Speaking Ancient Language]
[Coos]
Certo. Certo.
[Crying]
- [Groans]
- [Grunts]
- I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
- [Shouting]
[Crying Continues]
[Doorbell Rings]
- Morning, Father.
- Morning.
I'm here to see
Monsignor Brusca.
Oh, you don't know, do you?
[Father] He had a stroke the day
after we found the coffin.
He was conscious for only a few minutes
before he slipped into a coma.
I'm so sorry.
Look, I... understand
this isn't the best time...
but I really do need to know as much
as I can about the urn.
Look. Look,
I really don't know why...
anyone would want
to take that urn.
The only thing I know is that there was a name
on the coffin: Oscar de la Vallé.
- Oscar de la Vallé?
- Yes.
do you know who he was?
The monsignor thought
it was the same man...
who figures in an old story that's been
popular in Aosta for centuries.
Most people, including me,
consider it nothing but legend.
Brusca didn't. That's why he sent
the items to you for verification.
Well, can you tell me
about the story?
In 1814...
workers renovating
the church curia in Aosta...
discovered an urn.
There were several items inside it...
including a dress that may have been
from pagan times.
[Wolves Growling]
As the legend has it, packs of wolves
came out of the forest...
the night after the urn
was found.
They dug up freshly-buried
bodies in the graveyard...
and tore them to bits.
The local priest decided
to send the urn to the Vatican.
[Horse Neighing]
Oscar de la Vallé
volunteered to deliver it.
He was a knight of noble birth.
Only he was allowed to talk with the pope.
- [Woman Whimpering]
- He had one bad trip.
Wherever he went,
death and destruction followed.
Children died.
Crops burned.
- Whole villages were devastated.
- [People Screaming]
Many towns refused to let
De la Vallé enter.
People were in a panic.
By the time he reached Viterbo,
he was both sick and blind.
The church took him in.
He died six days later.
Maybe it was malarial fever.
His body was buried
in a secret place.
The urn was chained to his coffin
and sealed with crucifixes.
After the urn was found,
the monsignor was a different person.
He began talking nonsense.
[Sighs]
Wait. Wait, wait.
I- Yes-
- He was writing this when he had the stroke.
- Here.
It's a list of what was in the urn.
- "Mater Lacrimarum. "
- Mater Lacrimarum. Yes.
The monsignor thought the urn...
and its contents were magical...
that they belonged
to an evil witch...
named Mater Lacrimarum-
the Mother of Tears.
It's such a shame.
He was a brilliant man- kind...
and a wonderful teacher.
To end his days believing
in this nonsense-
I'm sure he told you the same thing
he told me many times-
that God's plans for us are a mystery
to everyone but him.
Monsignor Brusca wrote this
for a reason.
One we might not understand,
but a reason nonetheless.
Good-bye, Father.
[Dog Barking]
[Engine Starts]
[Thunderclap]
- [Men Panting]
- [Gasps]
[Man]
Hold still. I said hold still!
- No! Help me!
- Open your legs. Open your legs!
No! Help me!
[Opening Drawer]
[Sighs]
[Sniffles]
- [Siren Wailing]
- Stop! Freeze!
- Freeze!
- [Man Groans]
[Tires Screeching]
[Gunshot]
[Keys Jangling]
[Siren Wailing]
Michael?
Hello?
Is there anybody home?
Michael?
Paul?
Michael! What happened?
They took him.
- Who took him?
- The babysitter...
went out for two minutes, she said.
She came back...
and she found... this-
"If you want to see
your son again...
keep the silentium. "
The silentium.
Michael, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, darling.
Those symbols-
they are the same ones I saw on the urn.
I know! It's the same people.
It's some kind of black magic.
Black magic?
- I don't know about black magic-
- What?
What, you think this is all some
sort of coincidence?
- No, I didn't say-
- don't be so bloody naive! Giselle's dead.
Brusca's in a coma.
Now they've taken Paul.
It's - It's all connected with the urn
and-and those talismans.
And they want me to stop looking.
They want me to keep quiet.
About what?
Keep quiet about what?
The darkness... gathering around Rome.
You haven't seen it?
It's happening.
Here, come with me!
- Look. Let me show you. Look.
- I'm coming.
What do you think all this is?
Where is it?
- An epidemic of suicides, 52 in two days!
- Yes.
Look. A wave of violence
spreads through the city-
murders, fires, kidnappings,
church vandalism-
Yes, Michael, you're scaring me.
I- I know all this.
I'm going to Monteleone.
There's a priest there, Father Johannes.
And what on earth could he do
to help this situation?
He's an exorcist-
one of the last confirmed by the Vatican.
He knows more about the occult
than anyone else I know.
And he'll be able to help me get Paul
back in a way they can't detect.
- Look, Michael, why don't we try the police?
- No! No police!
You saw the way they looked at you at the
museum. They thought you were fucking crazy!
Michael, look, I-I love Paul,
okay, as much as you do...
but I don't know if
this is the best way-
He is my son!
Not yours!
- Michael.
- [Door Shuts]
[Women Cheering, Chattering]
Damn it!
Be careful, damn it!
You rot in hell.
[Growls]
[Laughs]
[All Chattering, Squealing]
- Are you ready for the celebration?
- Of course!
- Excuse me.
- [Shrieking]
[Laughs]
Three Furies.
Furies.
Three Fates.
Three Graces.
Diana, the three-headed-
The Triad.
Why are they always three?
[Phone Buzzing]
Sorry. Hello?
- Sarah, hi. It's me. It's Michael.
- Michael?
- Where are you?
- Wait, no, no. Wait, wait, listen.
- I-I really need your help, okay?
- Yeah, of course I'll help you.
Just tell me what to do.
- No, you've got-
- Michael?
Michael!
Hello, are you there?
[Horn Honking]
Help me, Sarah.
Help me.
Michael, are you still there?
Michael? Michael!
[Woman Over P.A. Speaking Italian]
- [Laughing]
- Whoo-hoo!
Hey, sister.
[Laughter Continues]
[Man Laughing]
[Laughter Stops]
Chotomateh!
Simone. Ikeh!
[Laughing]
Okay, please, come on.
Let's find her.
And try not to draw too much
attention to yourselves, okay?
- Okay, I know, I know.
- Okay, you two with me. Come on. This way.
Move! Move!
[Man]
People, we're the police.
No, no, no, you can't go in.
Can't go in.
Lady, you too. Move on, please.
Thank you. Move on.
[Panting]
- [Woman's Voice] Concentrate.
- Huh?
Concentrate!
They won't see you!
Don't worry.
We lost her.
[No Audible dialogue]
Okay.
[Sighs]
[Panting]
[Coughs]
[Shouts]
What?
[Horn Honks]
[Woman Over P.A. Speaking Italian]
Excuse me.
Where's this train going?
- Orte. Leaves in 30 minutes.
- Thank you.
- Michael?
- This is Michael Pierce's voicemail.
- Please leave a message after the tone.
- [Tone Beeps]
Michael, I've run into problems.
I'm going to Monteleone.
Bye.
- Can I help you?
- [Speaking Japanese]
Sorry, I don't understand.
[Japanese]
- [Gagging]
- [Laughs]
[Japanese]
[Laughs]
[Shuddering]
- [Chuckles]
- Get out!
[Woman Over P.A.] The train for Monteleone
now leaving on track nine.
- [Marchi] Where the fuck is she?
- Maybe in there.
- Maybe she's in there!
- [Whistles Blowing]
Well, Sarah Mandy killed
this woman because she saw...
Miss Mandy attacking
da Silva over there.
As simple as this.
Mandy weighs 110 pounds,
at the most?
da Silva, God rest his soul,
was a fucking gorilla.
And he was armed.
No, there's more to this case
than we think.
Can you move them back, please?
[Woman Shouting]
Nafech! Nafech! Nafech!
Nafech! Nafech!
[Woman Continues Shouting]
[Bell Rings]
- Yes?
- Hello?
My name is Sarah Mandy. I'm looking
for a friend of mine, Michael Pierce.
- He came to see Father Johannes.
- No, I'm sorry, he's not here.
What?
Could I see Father Johannes then?
It's very important.
You have to come back tomorrow.
- He can't see you today.
- I'm sorry, but that's not possible.
Please, tell him
I won't take much of his time.
Please.
All right. Come in.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
[Clock Chiming]
You look like you had
a hard trip.
You have it, you know.
Your mother's gaze.
You're Elisa Mandy's daughter,
aren't you?
I'm Marta Colussi.
You really look just like her.
I knew your mother
many years ago in Germany.
She was a wonderful teacher.
I learned so much from her.
She was a great spiritualist-
the best I've ever known.
- My mother was a dancer.
- And a healer.
A white witch, if you will.
And it seems to me
you've inherited some of her gifts.
- Listen, lady-
- It's Marta.
Marta. Whoever you are...
I don't know you and I didn't
come here to talk to you.
Please leave me
alone now, okay?
How did you get away
at the train station?
What the-Who are you?
Elisa was helping you.
Coaching you, wasn't she?
I- I don't know.
I heard- I heard a voice.
- did you really know my mother?
- Quite well.
- You don't know much about her, do you?
- No.
I don't remember much
about my parents.
I was very young
when they died in the accident.
The car crash in Freiburg.
No, honey. I'm sorry.
That's not what happened.
- Your parents were murdered.
- What?
What are you talking about?
Nobody ever told me this.
What are you saying?
Your mother dared to fight
a very powerful black witch:
Mater Suspiriorum,
the Mother of Sighs.
The Mother of Sighs?
[Man Coughing]
Father Johannes.
- How many drops?
- Twenty, please.
You look exhausted.
You need to rest.
With everything that's going on now?
I have to fight.
- I have to fight!
- Stay calm now. Please. Take your drops.
Your weakness is your strength, Father.
I've been expecting you.
- You're Sarah.
- Yes.
Hi.
There's a lot I have to
tell you-about your mother...
about you,
and about a world-
[Laughs]
you hardly know.
More than a thousand years ago...
witchcraft was birthed...
by the shores of the Black Sea
by three sisters.
For years they roamed
the earth...
bringing death and destruction
wherever they went.
Search any art history book
and you'll find images of them.
Eventually, they found homes.
Mater Suspiriorum, the Mother of Sighs,
settled in Freiburg.
The Mother of Pain, Mater Tenebrarum,
went to New York.
Mater Lacrimarum
came to Rome.
She's known as the Mother of Tears.
She's the most cruel
and beautiful of the three.
And she's the only one still alive.
Mater Tenebrarum
and Mater Suspiriorum...
died many years ago.
The Mother of Sighs.
She murdered my parents.
Yes. But not before your mother...
had injured her horribly.
After fighting your mother,
she was reduced to a shell of her former self.
A young dancer
named Suzy Bannion...
finally managed to kill her.
But that's all history.
When that urn Brusca
found was opened...
it restored the Mother of Tears's powers.
How do you know about that?
Your friend, Michael,
told me about it...
when he phoned and spoke
of a magic red tunic...
that would be a great
and powerful talisman.
I've had visions.
Witches are coming...
from all over the world
to celebrate her return.
Yes. They're arriving
in Rome every day.
Every jet, every car...
every train brings more.
They aim to make Rome fall again...
to usher in the Second Age of Witches.
[Groans] I can't take it anymore.
I feel like I'm going crazy.
There's nothing wrong
with your mind, Sarah.
It's the world that's gone crazy.
Have a look.
Look at this.
Usually I have one exorcism request
a month...
but the last few days, I've had more cases
than I've had in my whole life.
Every priest I talk to is faced
with the same challenge.
[All Shouting]
Why is all this happening?
The Mother of Tears
spreads evil wherever she can.
Some she kills,
others she drives mad.
She revels in chaos
and human despair.
[Shouting, Moaning]
We have work to do.
I have a book in my study
that shows us the way.
[Panting]
Valeria! Valeria!
Valeria.
[Moaning]
[Woman Sobbing]
Valeria.
Requiescat!
[Groans]
[Gagging]
[Screaming]
Father Johannes!
[Gasps, Screaming]
[Screaming]
- Mother?
- Marta, come back! Come back!
[Sobbing]
Mother, I obeyed you!
Come on, let's go!
[People Wailing, Screaming]
[Wailing, Screaming Continues]
Let me- Somebody help-
Marta!
Marta, help me!
Oh, my God!
Marta! Marta, let's go!
[Screaming]
- Where's your car?
- It's right there.
They're coming!
Oh, God, run!
It's locked!
Open- Open up!
- Open it!
- I can't find my key!
[Keys Fall To Ground]
Why were they all after me?
- Your mother.
- [Beeping]
- What are you doing?
- I'm calling Michael.
Are you crazy?
They can trace you with it.
You're right.
Fuck it.
Come to my place tonight.
It'll be safer for you.
No, I'd rather go home.
Michael can reach me there.
Mmm.
Here's my phone number
and address.
- Call me anytime. It's no bother.
- Thank you.
You're Elisa's daughter.
That's closer than family.
I don't mean to scare you, but...
they know who you are, Sarah.
Promise me
you won't trust anyone.
I promise.
- [Sirens Wailing]
- [People Shouting]
What's going on here?
[Marta]
They are burning the churches.
It's getting worse.
[Gasping, Groaning]
Mater! Mater!
[Whirring]
- [Whirring Continues]
- [Slam]
[Gasps]
[Gasps Loudly]
[Groaning, Whispering]
[Gasps]
[Groaning,
Whispering Continue]
[Creature Growling]
[Gasping, Panting]
[Sarah]
There was somebody at my apartment!
I saw lights and shadows under the door.
I feel like I'm going crazy!
God! Help. Please help me.
Help me, please.
Take a deep breath.
- Thank you.
- Calm down.
Come in.
- Elga, meet Sarah.
- Hi.
- What is she doing here?
- It's okay.
Marta, you have to help me.
I don't know what's happening to me.
- Come with me.
- You have to explain.
Why is all this happening to me?
Why?
They know who you are.
They can't take any chances.
But I- I-
I don't know anything.
You know more
than you think you do.
How else have you survived
this long with those monsters after you?
Elga, would you please
excuse us for a minute?
Oh, please. Come on.
Please?
You have gifts, Sarah.
You need to accept that
if you want to survive.
[Speaking Ancient Language]
[Continues In Ancient Language]
Watch and learn.
drifting spirits.
They are everywhere,
especially here in Rome.
[Marta]
The old houses are full of ghosts.
Think about it.
The city is 2700 years old...
and we are standing
on five layers of graves.
- How do you do it?
- You can do it too.
With your gifts,
you can see what others can't.
Close your eyes.
Focus all of your energy...
and concentrate on this spot.
- [Gasps]
- Good.
Now just do like I did
and blow.
[Sarah Gasps]
Sarah.
No, it can't be.
Mommy?
Sarah. Ohh.
- Mommy!
- You can't touch her or she'll disappear.
Leave me alone.
Mater Lacrimarum grows stronger.
She grows stronger, Sarah!
Where-Where are you?
Mommy! Mommy!
You're in great danger,
my dear child.
- Learn to fight.
- No!
No! No!
Don't go, Mommy!
Don't leave me! Mommy, please!
Mommy!
[Sobbing]
Please make her come back.
Please!
Mo-
[Sobbing]
Don't leave me.
Don't leave.
She told me to fight.
You have to help me.
I have to fight. Please.
I'm only a psychic.
I can communicate with spirits,
but that's about it.
I don't have your mother's gifts,
or yours.
[Whimpers]
You need someone who can guide you,
point you in the right direction.
Yes.
Tomorrow I'll introduce you
to Guglielmo de Witt.
- He's a great Belgian thinker.
- Okay.
He'll tell you something useful,
if it's not too late.
Thank you.
Oh, thank you.
[Sobbing Continues]
[Moaning]
[Groaning]
No.
[Gasps, Panting]
[Gasps]
[Panting]
[Shrieking]
[Gasps]
[Chittering]
[Chittering Continues]
[Shrieking]
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
- [Line Ringing]
- Pick up the phone.
Come on, Marta,
pick up the phone!
[Ringing Continues]
[Gasps]
[Screaming]
Hello? Hello, Marta?
Marta, you have to get out of there now!
Marta? Hello? Who's there?
Run! It's too late!
Now! Run now!
[Shrieking]
[Shrieking Continues]
[Gasping, Screaming]
- No! She doesn't know anything!
- [Shrieking]
No! don't do it!
don't do it!
[Screaming]
- [Shrieking Continues]
- [Screaming Continues]
[Screaming Stops]
[Shrieking]
[Grunting, Groaning]
[Groaning Continues]
- [Guttural Chuckling]
- [Bones Snapping]
[Gasping, Coughing]
[Screams, Wheezing, Groaning]
Mater! Mater!
Where is Sarah?
[Whimpering]
She isn't here.
Idiot!
- [Shrieking]
- It is you.
It is.
[Wheezing]
[Moaning]
[Laughing]
[Shrieking]
[Cat Yowls]
[Laughing]
Stay strong. Stay strong!
- Mom.
- Stay strong, Sarah!
Yes.
Mom, what did they do
to you and Dad when-
Shh. It's all in the past.
There's nothing you can do.
It was meant to be.
I was so upset,
so angry at you for leaving me.
Plea- Please
don't abandon me again.
Forgive me, little Sarah.
I can't speak anymore.
I belong to another place now.
Use your gifts.
Use them. Use them.
Mommy.
[Gasping]
Okay, guys, listen up.
We're looking for a girl around 28.
Her name is Sarah Mandy.
If you see her, don't approach her.
Michael?
Michael. Mi-
Michael! Michael!
Michael, stop!
Michael?
- [Coughing, Wheezing]
- Michael.
Are you okay?
Michael, you're sick.
Where's Paul?
I thought-
did you-
I think-
I think he's -
I think he's dead.
- Oh, my God.
- They killed him.
- And I can't -
I don't want to talk about that now.
Let's go.
My apartment is not safe.
- Everywhere I go, they-
- We'll go to my place.
They won't look for you there.
[Coughing]
No, no. No lights.
Why?
We don't want them to see us.
[Coughing Continues]
I'm so happy
we found each other.
Are you okay?
- Why don't you just rest, take off your coat-
- No, no, no.
I'm freezing. Sorry.
I'm freezing.
I just haven't spent a-
a single night inside.
- I looked everywhere for him.
- Yeah, what happened?
- Because I went to Monteleone to find you.
- I couldn't get there.
They were following me.
Everything you were trying to tell me
I understand now.
I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
I'm really sorry.
Okay.
Maybe you shouldn't smoke.
- Why don't you-
- [Grunts]
do you want me to fix something?
Tea, maybe?
[Coughs]
No.
No, I'm f- I'm fine.
I'm just-
I'm just pleased
I found you again.
I'm fine.
don't worry. Fine.
[Coughing Continues]
Michael, you're bleeding!
[Gasps]
- It's nothing.
- Michael, you're hurt!
No, it's - it's okay.
It's nothing.
What do you mean, it's nothing?
You're hurt!
I told you it's nothing!
Get off me!
- [Gasping]
- I told you to get the fuck off me!
- [Gagging]
- [Screams]
[Groans]
Do you think they would
spare me and my child?
You're so naive.
You can't escape her.
But they killed your son!
Your mother can't
help you anymore.
We all have one mother now.
The Mother of Tears.
[Screaming]
You bitch!
Oh, you crazy-
you crazy bitch!
[Screaming Continues]
Guglielmo.
The name Marta gave you.
Find him.
[Gasps]
[Groaning]
Mommy!
Sarah!
[Whimpers]
[Sobbing]
[TV: Anchorman]
Welcome back to the morning news.
And now for today's top story.
They're calling it
the second fall of Rome.
Over the past few days the city
has witnessed hundreds of acts of violence.
Detective Marchi,
you say that they are all connected?
Uh, yes...
everything started with events
at the Art Museum of Rome.
The brutal murder of the assistant curator,
Giselle Mares.
But how does that all tie together?
It was the trigger for everything
that's happening now.
We ask everybody to be on the lookout
for this girl, Sarah Mandy...
the only witness
to events at the museum.
- If you see her-
- Is she a suspect?
If you see her,
do not approach her.
Call the police
and ask to speak to Homicide.
Shit!
[Horns Honking]
- [Man ¶1] Fuck you!
- [Man ¶2] Oh, no, fuck you!
- [Man ¶3] Give me my money!
- What are you talking about?
- Give me your car. Give me your car!
- [Woman Screams]
[All Shouting, Screaming]
Sunglasses!
[Screaming]
No! No! No!
Hello?
Yes, can I please have the address
for Mr. Guglielmo De-Witt?
D, e, w, i, double t.
[Dogs Barking]
[Doorbell Rings]
- Yes?
- I need to see Guglielmo De-Witt.
[Scoffs]
And you are?
My name won't mean
anything to him.
All right. Come in.
So, you wanted to see me?
Please sit down.
As you can see, I-
I'm not very mobile.
I'm here because I-
I have to ask you about-
[Groaning]
We alchemists may practice
an ancient art...
but we do watch the news.
do you think I wouldn't know
who you are, Sarah Mandy?
And that the police is looking for you
because you're wanted for murder?
[Whimpering]
Another thing
about us alchemists-
we're not all one
thing or another.
After all, good magic is good,
and black magic is-
[Chuckles]
Well, it's good too.
Some of what we do
is magic, science...
esoterism, theosophy, natural law.
A little of this and a little of that.
This will let me know
who you really are...
and what you've really seen.
[Grunting]
Hmm. Interesting.
I see you have latent powers.
Instinct more than anything else.
Marta Colussi sent you, I see.
So did your mother,
Elisa Mandy.
[Chuckles]
- [Blows]
- [Gasps]
What did you do to me? Huh?
did you expect me to just let you waltz
in here without making sure who you are?
[Chuckles]
Now, why exactly
did you come here?
I need to find
the Mother of Tears.
- Why?
- Look what's happening to the city.
Rome is falling apart.
She has to be stopped.
Mmm. What do you think
you can do? Kill her?
Well, my mother was very powerful...
and I think I might
have the same gifts.
Which you found out about
when? Yesterday?
I don't know.
There's got to be some people that can help,
people like my mother.
Father Johannes said that-
that Mater Lacrimarum is bringing
on the Second Age of Witches.
Mmm.
Father Johannes was right.
Somewhere in the city the celebration
has already begun.
But I'm afraid there is no
army of good witches
out there to come to the rescue.
If you want to stop her,
you have to do it yourself.
So I'm on my own now?
I didn't say I wouldn't help.
I can't give you answers,
but I can share information.
Follow me.
Centuries ago, a great Roman alchemist
named Varelli...
lived for a time in this villa.
He was also a gifted architect.
And near the end of his life, he built
the residences for the Three Mothers.
This may tell you
something you need to know.
[Man Reading]
The Three Mothers.
I don't know
how much it will cost me...
to break what we alchemists
have always called SILENTIUM.
[Man Continues]
I met the three Mothers...
and built three houses
for them:
one in Freiburg,
one in New York...
and one in Rome.
I discovered too late that these houses
hide obscene secrets.
It is from here
that the sisters spread pain...
tears and darkness
throughout the world.
This building should be
the one Varelli built in Rome.
[Sarah]
"What you see...
"does not exist...
and what you cannot
see is truth. "
It's a riddle.
Find where Mater Lacrimarum resides...
and you'll find the answer.
Are you sure
you want to do this?
- do I have a choice?
- [Chuckles]
- [Horns Honking]
- [People Screaming, Grunting]
[Man, Echoing]
Mater.
[Chattering, Laughing]
Stop. Stop right here!
[Chattering,
Laughing Continue]
- [Gasping]
- [Wings Fluttering]
- Hey! Who are you?
- [Gasps]
I, uh- I just saw
some women come in.
- did you see them?
- No.
- You here to interview me?
- Yeah.
Here.
How long you've been living here?
Shh-A long time.
Thirty, forty years.
Since the Nazis escaped
at the end of the war.
And who used to live here
before you?
Oh, I don't know.
A kind of association.
Philosophers. Artists maybe.
I don't remember.
Why did they leave?
Maybe because when the Nazis
occupied the villa...
they tortured and killed
a lot of people down here.
Hey! You won't
report me, will ya?
Shh, shh.
[Whispers]
Easy.
[Door Sliding Closed]
[Footsteps]
- Where did she go?
- I think she's gone.
[Knife Blade Rings]
I'll check upstairs.
- Stay here.
- Yeah.
- She's not there!
- Then she's gone. Everything's okay.
You forgot what we were supposed to do,
didn't you?
- No.
- No?
Inform them every time somebody
comes to look around!
- Understand?
- Yes!
- Yes.
- Move!
[Footsteps Receding]
- Where did they go? They just-
- Shh.
[Sarah]
They're in here. I can feel it.
"What you see does not exist...
and what you cannot see
is truth. "
The secret of the house.
Those are the same symbols
I saw on the urn.
Catacombs.
These are unexplored catacombs.
Oh, my God.
This is the home
of the Mother of Tears...
and her followers.
[Sarah]
Dear God.
Witches.
Witches?
What are you talking about?
You'll see.
Stay behind me.
[Groaning]
The three Graces.
[Gasps]
[Laughing]
What are you doing down here?
I'm an art historian.
I just wanted to see-
Come with us.
I'll let you see something.
[Laughing]
We'll show you! Yeah! We'll show you!
Come on!
[Laughing]
[Laughing, Chattering]
[Gasps]
[Woman Shouting,
Indistinct]
[Whimpering]
[Speaking Ancient Language]
[Ancient Language]
[Whimpering Continues]
[Footsteps]
[Footsteps Continue]
[Whispering
In Ancient Language]
[Ancient Language]
[Gasps, Panting]
[Gasps]
[Panting]
[Moaning, Faint]
[Moaning Continues]
[Woman]
Mother, give us power!
- [Moaning, Chanting]
- Burn it all!
I will! I will!
- [Screaming, Chanting Continue]
- I will!
- Stop please!
- [Groaning, Screaming]
- [Screams]
No! No!
[Groaning]
Mater! Mater!
[Speaking Ancient Language]
- Mater!
Look, Mother!
An intruder!
[Laughing]
- [Groans]
- Wait! [Screams]
Get him!
[Chamber Clicks]
[Screaming, Shouting]
We'll eat you alive!
[Moaning]
Hang him!
Our hour...
is coming!
[Groaning]
- [Screaming Continues]
- [Screeches]
[Sarah Screaming]
- Hello, Sarah.
- [Screeching]
[Screaming, Moaning Quiet]
[Groaning]
Come here.
[Laughing, Chattering]
[Screeching Continues]
[Whispering Chant
In Ancient Language]
[Mater Laughing]
Who wants to eat the girl?
Me.
[Mater]
We have waited for this moment...
for one thousand years!
Our power is here!
[Chanting In Ancient Language]
No one can stop us now!
No one!
[Yelling]
[Gasping]
No!
- [Mater] Damn you!
- [Man] It's an earthquake!
- [All Screaming, Shouting]
- No!
[Screaming, Shouting, Continues]
No!
[Screeches]
[Groans]
[Screaming Continues]
[Groaning]
[Screams]
[Groaning Continues]
[Screaming]
[Screaming Continues]
- Sarah!
- [Screaming Continues]
Shh! Shh! It's me, it's me!
It's me! It's me!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
[Wailing, Sobbing]
Enzo. Enzo!
Go. Go! Go!
[Gasping, Panting]
[Laughing]
[Both Laughing]
[Sarah Continues Laughing]
[Man, Whispering]
Mother.
[Chorus Singing]
¶Mater¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ Mater Lacrimarum ¶
[Man]
¶Hail to the queen of rare delights ¶
¶ Malefic and tragic
are the strings of her magic ¶
¶ Screaming through the night ¶
¶ She is sex and death and more ¶
¶ The scent of evil
in the glittering city ¶
¶ A virgin and a whore ¶
¶ For the horns of blasphemy ¶
[Chorus]
¶Mater¶
[Man]
¶She's our Mother of Tears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ The howling on the wind ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ She's the lover
of all our fears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ Hail to the goddess
of the storm ¶
¶ Dancing on the abyss
in a blaze of light ¶
¶ A darkened star reborn ¶
¶ When the moon hangs in the sky ¶
¶ Sabbatical and fatter
than the blood red sunset ¶
¶ Know the reason why ¶
¶ The heavens burned today ¶
[Chorus]
¶Mater¶
¶ She's our Mother of Tears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ She's our Mother of Tears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ She's our Mother of Tears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ The howling on the wind ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ She's our Mother of Tears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ The more in mortal sin ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ She's our Mother of Tears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ Chaos in the cosmos ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ She's the lover of all our fears ¶
¶ Lacrimarum ¶
¶ Mater¶
¶ Mother¶¶