[loud bang]
[another loud bang]
(male voice, off,
British accent)
The year: 1095 AD.
The once mighty
Byzantine Empire
and the holy land
of Jerusalem
continue to fall
under the wrath
of the soldier Turks.
[sounds of battle]
In retaliation,
Pope Urban II calls
upon all devoted
knights of Europe.
Thousands take up arms.
Thus is the beginning
of the Crusades.
A holy war
that would last
for over 200 years,
giving birth
to the strongest
religious military force
the world had ever known,
the order
of the Knights Templar.
And from their ranks arose
one of their greatest leaders,
Lord Mordest McGirk
Gregoire of Redding.
Many believed his sword
was blessed by God himself.
[sounds of battle]
[shouting]
[groan]
(male voice)
I have counted the gold,
and it is quite a sum.
(male voice No. 2)
Just as you have
made your pact
with the devil.
Truly you and I
have given our lives
to the service
of the king.
There is talk
we captured a wagon
full of gold today.
I am better than you.
This opportunity together.
You will have
none of it.
[voices overlapping]
[overlapping laughter]
Let there be--
I would rather
be eaten by
a pack of wolves.
There's been
a lot of your evil--
You must keep
them divided--
Behind you!!
[overlapping]
I shall enjoy
enough fortune for
ten lifetimes of excess!
(Gregoire)
You've lost
your way.
(male voice)
Nay, brother.
I have found it.
And I will attain it
with the treasure in
yond wagon.
Now Gregoire, it is
time for you to die.
So be it.
You've made your
pact with the devil.
You will have your
ten lifetimes of excess
but then--
I will come for you.
All of you.
[sword stabbing flesh]
[rumble of thunder]
[gasp]
[sword stabbing flesh]
[last breath]
[peal of thunder]
[approaching footsteps]
(male priest)
My brothers,
I must speak to you in
regarding the order
of business
for which we have
gathered here tonight.
Seven hundred
years have passed.
And as prophesied,
the ordained time
will soon be upon us.
It will be your duty
to reunite
their kindred spirits
so that he
may fulfill
his destiny
and as spoken
from his lips
to God's ear,
he will return
for his vengeance
and deliver
the souls of
the accursed
to...hell...
for all eternity.
[modern day rock music]
[engine running]
(Jake)
That's it, I guess.
Wow, it's a castle.
(Cecilia)
Yeah, enjoy
your stay, Jake.
What's your name again?
Cecilia.
That's a pretty name.
Thank you.
Pretty girl,
pretty name.
Small car.
[owl hoots]
Okay.
Hello?
Nobody home.
[church bell ringing]
[ringing continues]
Wow.
[moan]
[moaning]
(Gregoire)
I will come for you.
For all of you.
Hello.
[Italian style music
playing softly]
(male voice)
Continuing warrior position.
Your knee directly
above your ankle.
Your leg comes
directly on
the floor
like a pillar.
The black glove at hand.
You are
a pillar
of strength.
As you settle, relax
your lower back--
[shouting]
[sound of sword
and thunder]
[shout]
Oh, God.
It's getting worse.
What's happening to me?
[approaching footsteps]
(nun)
A package for you,
Father Paul.
What is it?
I don't know.
I found it on the altar,
along with this note.
Well, what does it say?
It just reads
'Father Paul'.
I don't want
to be disturbed.
By anyone.
(shopkeeper)
There you go.
(conversation in
foreign language)
No? Not yours.
[many voices speaking loudly]
Lord Gregoire.
Thank you, Malcolm.
My most valiant warrior.
I know not
what we would do
without your swordsmanship
and that, of
your brother Menas.
Although from a land
quite foreign to us,
Armenia,
we are truly blessed
to have both
the first
and the second
greatest warrior
of all the Mediterranean
fight by our sides.
Thank you, my lord.
But, it is your sword
that guides us.
Stand in my
light, brother.
Fast and righteous.
I am the best.
How does it feel
to be number
two, Menas?
How would it feel
to be dead?
...defending the true
cross, my brothers.
Once more, you have
fought bravely and
with great honor.
(Renault)
As have you, Gregoire.
As have you.
I thank you, Renault,
my fellow knight.
Gregoire--
there is talk we
captured a wagon
full of gold today.
Is this true?
Yes, Renault.
A wagon full of gold.
The grand master
will be very pleased.
And all in the
name of the cause.
As you know,
there are those
who are not able
to make the correct
choice of following God.
They are not free
in mind, body,
or spirit.
Blinded by the
ill forces of evil.
Fortunately, however--
we have blessed
with the charge--
to provide all mankind
with the opportunity to
go their own way.
These heathens, upon whom
we drew swords this day,
made it their trade
to scorn and persecute
defenseless men, women,
and children of pureness.
But, with the strength
of our gallant horses
and the might
of our skillful swords,
these tyrants shall
spread evil no more.
[crowd shouting]
We are the Knights Templar!
Yeah!
[all shouting "Templar"]
Templar!
[Classical Music]
[knocking at door]
Hello?
Oh.
Hi.
Who are you?
I be Shauna the chef.
Shauna? The chef?
They told me
you were a--cook.
Ah, they lied to you.
Evidently.
Who, uh--
who would be
in charge
of me money?
Oh. Hello.
I'm Jake McCallister.
Weekend Coordinator.
- And--?
And me money?
You haven't cooked
anything yet, Shauna.
Huh, perhaps
you're right.
You have pretty eyes.
Ohhh--
you're so nice.
And you're so sweet.
Ohhh--
[barks]
Ah!
[both laughing]
Ooh.
Okay.
[stuffed nose]
(Jake)
Excuse me,
can I help you?
[clears throat]
Do you have my pay?
Pay? Who are you?
[clears throat]
Allow me to
introduce myself.
My name is Benoit,
the butler's for
the weekend.
Oh, you're Benoit
the butler?
Good timing.
I got some grocery bags
at the general store
I gotta pick up.
Do you mind helping me?
No.
(female voice)
Then there is my son.
I told him not
to marry that woman,
but he did.
[crying]
No one is listening
to me anymore.
Everyone is
leaving me behind.
Father Paul?
Well, it's showtime.
(Jake)
Welcome everyone.
Benoit will take your
luggage to your rooms.
Orientation in 15 minutes.
Refreshments are inside.
Excuse me, Miss? Do you
mind identifying
your luggage?
I have nothing else.
(Benoit)
Thank God.
Well?
The bags?
Thank you.
Hey, stud.
Have a light?
Um, I don't smoke.
That's not what I asked.
I win, you lose.
[cough]
Win? I didn't know
we were competing.
What's wrong
with competition?
[clears throat]
Although it looks like
you're not gonna be
much competition.
- Henry, right?
- Yeah.
I read your file,
what you're into.
It's not that
I'm judging you,
the whole animal thing.
Uh, we're cool.
Don't worry, boss,
just competing."
This one right here.
I'm gonna do dirty
shit to that one.
I don't think so, dude.
She's, uh, she's here
for a different reason.
It doesn't matter.
This is my time.
I'll do whatever
the fuck I want.
Dude, I said not her.
Okay? Leave it alone.
- Sorry.
- No, it's cool.
I like it.
We're competing already.
It's good.
If you do that again,
I'm gonna cut your
fuckin' throat.
Alright?
Okay.
Bad boy.
Whatever.
Is somebody missing?
The other one
never showed up.
I hope that doesn't
ruin your plans.
My plans? Why
would it ruin my
plans? Less work.
Well, they're
all yours now.
Yep. Um--
am I supposed
to tip you?
Hm. Tip me?
It was an honor just
being in your presence.
Okay. Uh--
well, thanks pal.
[eerie whispering]
It was a pleasure
serving you.
We wish you
the best of luck.
Godspeed.
Hi, I'm--
I'm Amy.
Hi, Amy.
I'm Jake.
So you're the--
So you're a professional
events coordinator?
Actually, no.
I was doing a play,
and a guy approached
me after the show.
And he just like,
gave me the gig.
He said he was from--
Switzerland, I think.
(Amy)
Oh, you're an actor.
That is so cool,
I love reality TV.
Reality TV?
Hello, everyone.
And welcome to our
individual fantasy
getaway weekend.
My name
is Jake McCallister,
and I'll
be your host
and events coordinator.
My mission is to make
sure everything is
carried out as planned.
That's my task.
I believe that's
why I'm here.
Now, can anyone tell
me the number one rule?
Amy.
We're not supposed
to tell anyone
why we're here
because it will
ruin the surprise
and defeat the challenge.
Excellent. But,
as coordinator,
I will know each
of your personal agendas.
Let's meet up,
Celine--
Henry--
Amy--
and Japoniko, right?
Am I saying
that correctly?
Do you mind if
I talk to you alone?
I read your file
on the plane.
I didn't see
your request
for the weekend.
In order for me
to purvey your
activities, I--
You don't know
why you're here,
do you?
I'm Events Coordinator.
[car horn honking]
We'll talk later.
Okay?
Okay guys, grab a snack,
and I'll be right back.
[honking]
[loud upbeat music]
Let me guess,
you must be Ashley.
- That's me.
- You weren't
supposed to drive,
you were supposed
to be picked up at
the airport
like everybody else.
Those are the rules.
Rules I make
up as I go along.
♪ Talk to my hand
Alrighty then,
Ms. Ashley.
Come on inside,
meet the guests,
and I'll take
care of your luggage.
Great. Uh--store it
in the garage
over there.
[keys hit ground]
and--no scratches.
Hmph.
(Jake)
Hey everybody,
this is Ashley.
- And she's going to be--
- Leaving. I'm outta here.
(Jake)
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
You can't leave.
You just got here.
Besides, you won't get--
I am not
spending one moment
with a bunch
of goddamn low lives.
They're not even
in my social class.
Look at this one.
Her family is low
to middle income,
if lucky.
Look at the cheap
outfit she's wearing.
My mother made
this shirt for me.
"My mother made
this shirt for me."
No fucking class.
You need a milieu
with socialites
like myself.
Jetsetter getaway
weekend, my ass.
Get my luggage, boy.
I'm leaving.
You can't buy class.
What did you say?
I said, you
can't buy class.
And what's that
supposed to mean?
Evidently, you can't
buy intelligence, either.
And who are you
to tell me what
to do?
I'm the events
coordinator.
You call that a job?
Yeah. The ends
justify the means.
That sounds
like something
a fucking unemployed
game show host
would do.
Yeah, kind of
like an actor
doing dinner theater
in Schenectady.
You're a loser.
You're all fucking losers.
Shut up.
I've had enough
of the offending language.
Your leaving now
means absolutely
fucking nothing.
[gasp]
Go. Get your
own luggage.
You'll hear
from my attorney.
[beep]
Oh, darn it.
[grrr]
[meow]
It's all right.
It's okay.
[snarls angrily]
[eerie voice indistinct]
(eerie male voice)
Hear me, Gregoire.
You cannot escape
your destiny.
We must keep
them divided.
I would rather be eaten
by a pack of wolves
than allow your evil venom
to course through
my veins.
[shouts]
[laughing]
[shouting]
[Jake shouting, distant]
[thuds of guitar on floor]
Deceit--betrayal--revenge.
[laughing]
(different male voices)
Forgive me, my lord.
Pretend!
[overlapping voices]
Deceitbetrayalrevenge .
Gregoire.
Deceitbetrayalrevenge.
[shout of pain]
[spear digs in flesh]
Help me, my lord.
It is your time.
It is your place.
(speaking foreign language)
Ugh, he didn't
fucking cover it!
[grunting]
Oh, you are so sued.
[metallic scraping]
[ignition clicking]
Come on.
Come on!
Oh, what the fuck.
He disconnected
my battery cables.
Very funny, asshole.
[pop music playing]
What is this shit?
I hate oldies.
["Magic" playing,
sung by Pilot]
Who the hell are you?
♪ Ho, ho, ho,
It's magic ♪
♪ You know
Who the hell
are you?
What is this,
a masquerade ball?
How come I
wasn't invited?
You can see
through there?
♪ Never believe
It's not so ♪
[shout]
♪ Never been awake
Never seen a day break ♪
♪ Leaning on my pillow
In the morning ♪
[distorted]
♪ Lazy day in bed
♪ Music in my head
♪ Crazy music playing
[distorted]
♪ In the morning light
[gasping]
[choking]
(Henry)
You see the way
he grabbed her throat?
The guy's
a fuckin lunatic.
Seriously, both of you
stay away from him.
I think it's kinda sexy,
the way he takes charge.
Like a tiger.
Yeah? You like that?
You like the rough
stuff, right?
Sometimes I like
it rough. And hard.
What about you?
You like the rough stuff?
No, no one's ever
stuck up for me before.
Whatever.
So a tiger, huh?
I can be a tiger.
Here you go.
Thank you.
What's that?
I don't know.
Somebody left it
here awhile ago.
Where's Japoniko?
Where's the television?
There isn't one.
(Shauna)
Jake, where are
me groceries?
Oh, um, I was
just on the way.
We want our guests
to eat tonight.
Can I tag
along with you?
Um, you
know the rules.
That no one can leave
the property,
I understand.
Right. You
know what?
Okay guys,
until I get back,
Amy is now in charge
of recreation.
- Me?
- You.
But you haven't given
me any formal training.
Listen. Your reason
for coming here this
weekend was what?
To build confidence, right?
So sometimes it's best
to just jump
in the water.
Get a little wet.
You'll be fine.
I hope so. Cause one day
I want to be a good
assistant to someone.
Assistant? That's
kinda odd because
I see you
more as
a leader of men.
You have
unlimited potential.
You think so?
You'd be great.
[door closes]
So. What do you guys
feel like doing?
I guess relax,
grab a snack,
and wait for Mr. Weekend
Coordinator to get back.
I can think
of one or two
things to do.
Or three.
(Amy)
We could play a game.
There's four of us,
we could do teams or--
I didn't come
here to play games.
Okay, silly idea.
We could play
strip poker.
I'm not good
at cards.
Even better.
What is that?
It looks like
an old story book.
What's it about?
The inscription reads,
'Here tells a
tale of passion,
loyalty, deceit,
betrayal, and revenge.'
Sounds good to me.
You read to us.
Okay. Here we go.
(Amy, reading)
An omniscient moon
radiates through
the night.
We find ourselves
in a time when men
(male voice overlapping)
would bravely and honorably
fight and die
in the name
of the true cross.
We see the remains
of a small band
of Templar knights.
Sergeants and stewards,
all of whom were pushed
out of their homelands
quite some time ago.
It is the aftermath
of yet another long
day of battle.
Their coats of mail
vary in color
to distinguish
their rank.
However, all their
uniforms have one
thing in common:
they all proudly
bear the eight
pointed cross,
a symbol of purity
and a reflection
of the crusaders'
vow of chastity.
Gregoire, the leader
of this band
of Templar knights,
takes in
his surroundings
and the results
of the day's events.
He is our hero.
Wait, wait, wait.
What's this hero
guy look like?
(Celine)
It's a storybook.
You make up hero.
He can look like
whatever you want.
Whoever I want?
(Henry)
Lord Gregoire!
(Gregoire)
What do you
have for me?
- An apple, my lord.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, my lord.
- I'll enjoy this.
You stand
in my way, sergeant.
What is your name?
Melkon.
You find
humor in this?
Well, t'is a little
foreign to my ear.
Did I miss something
of importance here?
We fought
victoriously today
under the leadership
of Lord Gregoire.
Lord Gregoire, yes,
I've heard of him.
He's one of the greatest
leaders of our time.
Really?
Catch.
Mm. Delicious.
So this is where
you've been all
day, huh?
Picking apples.
Hm. What can I say?
I love the orchard.
[shouting]
And the blood?
Is it yours?
[grunts and groans]
It is now.
Messy business, huh,
this apple picking.
It is. How are
you, my brother?
I'm ready to go
to battle again on
your command, my lord.
I'm not your lord,
I am your brother.
Yes, my lord.
[horse neighs]
(stunted speech)
We won,
Gregoire, we won!
Yes, again we
were victorious.
When will I be
ready to fight,
my lord?
We've spoken
of this, Koko.
Every day!
Then when?
It is not your time,
little one.
It is not
your place.
You always say--
Koko, is there not
somewhere of more importance
where you should be?
Yes, my lord.
Then get there.
Aha, yes, my lord.
Yes, my lord.
But when you need
me, I am ready.
[laughing]
Get that from him.
He is waiting
for the day
you allow him to
shield and fight.
And he'd be
lost in an instant.
His strength lies
not in sword,
dear Melkon--
but in here--
his heart.
Sergeant?
Vicinity scouted,
my lord. All sound.
Excellent.
Where's Devereux?
Dwyer?
How many did we lose?
Nearly a third, my lord.
Prisoners?
Prisoners?!
None, they would
not surrender,
my lord.
Ah. Such valor.
If only their
beliefs were proper.
Ah then,
scour the acre.
We leave no man behind.
We've already been
around twice, my lord.
Then you need
only scour
once more.
Yes, my lord.
[knocking]
(Father Paul)
Hello? Anybody home?
[door creaks]
Hello, children.
I heard we had
some visitors
in town,
and I wanted to take
the opportunity--
(Shauna)
Who is it?
Oh, hello Father.
Is there something
we can help you
with, Father?
Because if this is
about money donations,
we happen to be short
on money at the moment.
This is not
about money.
It's just that I
wanted to welcome
you to town
and take the opportunity
to invite you to
the house of God.
That's peculiar,
Father, because
well, I'm
from here, and
so is she, and, um--
we've never
seen you before.
You attend Mass?
- No.
Well, that's why
you haven't seen me.
But now we
know each other,
I'll be sure that
I see you again
very, very soon.
And I'm looking
forward to it.
Well, who do
we have here?
I'm really glad
I stopped by.
It's certainly--
a refreshing surprise--
to have you all here.
And it's more than
I had bargained for.
I'll see you in church.
All of you.
Sunday in church.
It's weird, I feel
like I know him.
So do I.
But it's most strange,
he's not the only one
I feel like this about.
(Jake)
Any good?
Oh hey. I didn't
see you come in.
So, any good?
Oh, that? No, just
a hobby I picked up.
Mostly for cardio.
You know, trying to keep
the old midsection flat.
I've tried so many things.
Tennis, swimming.
But, uh-- that
one stuck.
Go figure.
Thank you.
So, what can
I do for you?
Oh, right. I'm at
the Rhein estate
I'm here to pick up an order
for a, uh, chef called Shauna
Irish.
Crossdresser.
That's her--him.
Him.
Coming right up.
Thank you.
Yeah, he comes
in here, uh--
once in a while
with that Benoit guy.
Crafty couple those two.
Couple? They
know each other?
You could say that, yeah.
They're not like, married.
No, just living in sin.
Times have changed.
How much I owe you?
You're all set.
The people that own
that estate, they have
an account here.
Alrighty then--
have yourself
a nice day.
You too.
Say--
do I know you
from someplace?
You ever been
on a reality TV show?
No. Wrong guy.
Ah.
Hey, um--
You need help.
As far as--
The bags, I'll help
getting them into
your car.
Naw, I'm on foot.
Alone?
Yes, alone.
Ha. Well, you've got
yourself a load there
that might
just be too heavy
for you to carry.
Tell you what,
if you need a ride
I can just close
up the store for
ten minutes,
that's all
it'll take.
It's okay.
It's my responsibility.
They're mine.
All of them.
A simple, more
peaceful life.
Well, goodbye
old friend.
[door opens
and closes]
So how does
that sound?
Sounds good,
but the music?
No blues, no jazz.
Are you going out?
Yeah, for a bit.
Down to the pub.
Mickey is hosting
a poker party
for some
out of town patsy.
It's a lock,
should triple this.
So Mickey will have
his hands on the deal then.
Make sure that you
triple this as well.
Mi amor.
[kissing sounds]
Save me a plate, will ya?
[engine starts]
Yeah, what are
you doing here?
- [gushy sound]
- [shout]
- [scream]
[scream echoing]
[birds chirping]
Well, it's
about time.
It was a long walk.
So, uh--where's Benoit?
Who?
Benoit, the butler?
Ah, yes, yes, yes.
I saw him
for only a moment.
He's working hard
on something, I think.
I'm sure.
Well, um--
you're doing a great job.
And--
American, a little bonus.
Ah.
[kiss]
Enjoy it while you can.
[music]
[wolf howls]
(Celine)
I cannot
believe those men.
Taking a lifetime
vow of poverty.
(Henry)
And chastity?
Come on.
I know were not supposed
to speak about why we're here
but I believe you
know my reasons,
what I am.
It's pretty obvious;
you're a prostitute.
And money talks.
Is this a problem?
Nope, not for me.
I'm here for
a sex weekend.
Good. Then it works
for me and for you.
How about
a little sample?
Yes.
[Henry moans]
Oh, you dirty
little whore.
[moaning]
Oh, you dirty
little whore.
[groans]
All better now.
I knew
it was you.
[loud bang]
[panting]
[moaning]
[running faucet]
[closes faucet]
[old fashioned music]
(shop owner)
I need to get the plumber
to work on that thing.
[music continues]
Shauna--
Whoa.
Jesus Christ.
I don't believe this.
Now I have to cook--
and clean.
[sighs]
We should have take-out.
(Amy)
You're all back, great.
I read a little ahead
and the story picks
up the next day
after Gregoire gives
a speech to his men.
[birds crying]
(Renault)
But then again,
Gregoire might not be
so easily persuaded.
We must keep
them divided
and unarmed
if we are to meet
with success.
[wood snaps]
You have a question?
Are we enough?
What if Gregoire resists?
His sword is said
to be blessed by
God himself.
That is why we must
hold to our course.
Catch them--unawares.
And what of Melkon?
He is known to fight
with the strength
of a dozen men.
What say you
to that, brother?
He is your blood.
[unsheathes sword]
I never liked
his shadow.
Some say he is
slightly better.
[shout]
[thuds]
Could not that have
waited until after?
No.
[sound of sword]
You--shall take
his position.
Yes, my lord.
Bury the body
in the brush.
And the head.
Pick it up!
Thank you.
Have I
forgotten something?
You spoke not
of the division.
Yes, my lord.
What is our share?
You shall each
receive a tenth.
A tenth?
Each?
Hmm. More than twenty
fold your greatest harvest.
Milord.
(soldier)
Over there!
Koko!
He spies on us!
(Renault)
Catch him!
[grunting]
Bring the freak here.
Alive.
[Koko, grunting]
Hold him.
Higher!
[grunting]
You're no match
for Gregoire and Melkon.
[slap]
Bind him and gag him.
Hide him close by.
That gold shall be mine--
be he with us
or against us.
[horse neighs]
[galloping horse approaches]
Have you gathered
the volunteers, sergeant?
Renault, Menas and several
others offered before
we need ask.
Interesting.
But all that gold,
my lord?
Will so few men suffice?
A party of too many will
draw suspicion, sergeant.
Have the men meet us
at the abbey
in a day's time.
- Yes, my lord.
- Godspeed, my lord.
(Amy)
I can't believe it.
Gregoire and Melkon are
gonna walk right into
the trap.
Maybe they will be
persuaded by Renault.
If Gregoire is smart,
he will listen
and they will steal
the gold together.
(Amy)
But Gregoir isn't like
that, nor is Melkon.
(Henry)
Then he's in trouble,
so is Melkon.
Because Renault, Menas
definitely want
the gold.
(Japoniko)
Are you blind
or just stupid?
It wasn't about
the money for Menas.
(Henry)
Then what's
the excuse?
One brother's
dick's bigger than
the other brothers?
[chuckles]
Come on.
At least, if
it's about money
then there's
a reason, right?
[chuckles]
I agree.
Money is
a great motivator.
Money isn't everything
and it's not
a reason
to turn
against each other.
Yeah, whatever.
I need a cigarette.
My ass is sore
from sitting,
playing cards, couch.
I think
I soak in tub
before dinner.
Are you coming?
No, I think I'm
gonna stay here
for a second.
Hm!
(male voice)
Do I know you
from some place?
(male voice)
Goodbye, old friend.
[old fashioned music]
[thunder]
I would like
to have bath.
But there
is no towels.
Bring some up to me?
In a moment.
How long before
dinner's ready?
Soon.
I would like
to have you now.
I'm not on
the menu.
Maybe I can change that.
There's no smoking
in the kitchen.
What's your
problem with me?
Are you gay?
Why don't
you want me?
How's this for
a little incentive?
I'm not
a paid up customer.
For you,
I make exception.
[rumble of thunder]
I don't think so.
It's not
why I'm here.
Oh, I will try
to remember this.
But it might
not be so easy.
Especially if you continue
to let me make it so hard.
[gasp]
Or maybe you like
to be the one in charge.
Is that it?
Would you like it
better if you have
to take it--
like an animal,
like an animal?
[panting]
I'd slap
you right now,
but you'd
probably like it.
Do you like
to play rough, Jake?
[hard breathing]
[thunder]
Just with assholes.
Who are you to judge
me for what I do?
[distant thunder]
Prostitution may be
one of the oldest
professions, Celine,
but it doesn't make it
proper in my eyes.
But that's not it.
What I despise most
about you, Celine,
isn't what you do,
but who you are...
deep down inside,
and that over time,
you've done absolutely
nothing to correct it.
Fine, but in the meantime
remember what I am.
Of course, you're
a dirty--little--whore.
[trembling voice]
Yes, a dirty little whore.
It's been very weird.
In all honesty,
you'll get what's
coming to you,
and more--
much, much more.
Now get out
of my kitchen.
Hm.
[thunder]
[loud thunder]
[crashing thunder]
Huh.
[pop music, male
voice sings indistinct]
[rattling]
Hello?
Mr. Jake, is that you?
Did you change your mind?
It's your loss.
Not mine.
Hm.
[turns up volume of music]
♪ I beg you not to go
But you said goodbye ♪
♪ Now you're telling me
All these lies ♪
♪ I hear you knocking
[humming along]
Mirror mirror,
on the wall--
Ah. You know
you want me.
♪ I hear you knocking
Ooh.
[distant music]
Music's kinda loud, huh?
[music becomes distinct]
♪ Ohhh, yeah!
♪ Come on
♪ Oooh Hooo!
On the count
of three.
One, two, three.
[laughing]
What? You want more?
Hm? Hm? Oh!
[giggles]
Oh.
What?
You want more?
What? You can't handle it?
Uh-uh-uh.
No. Not for you, Jake.
[giggles]
♪ I hear you knocking
♪ Go back where you been
♪ I told you
Way back in '52 ♪
♪ That I would
Never go with you ♪
♪ I hear you knocking
♪ But you can't come in
[humming]
♪ I hear you knocking
♪ Go back where you've been
[roaring]
[scream]
[splashing]
[sound of sword
in flesh]
[shouting]
[knocking]
Celine? Do you
mind turning down
the music a little?
[gasping]
♪ You better get back
To your use-to-be ♪
♪ 'Cause your kind
Of love ain't good to me ♪
[gasping]
What's going
on in there?
I didn't get
a radio in  my room.
♪
[volume goes all
the way down]
Thank you!
I speak and
people listen.
[loud gasping]
You're back. Great.
Maybe I can continue
with the story.
Yeah, why don't
you read some
more to us?
[owl hoots]
[wild animal cries]
[horse neighs]
[whinnies]
Claudius--
easy.
[snorts softly]
You seem pensive.
What are your
thoughts, Melkon?
Of no import, my lord.
We have no boundaries.
You may speak to me.
That is it.
Ha.
That is just it.
With you, there
is no jealousy,
no avarice,
no scorn.
But with my
own blood brother--
Melkon.
Ill will betwixt
brothers has ever
been common.
Look at Romulus
and Remus,
Cain and Abel--
My brother is no Cain!
[snorting]
Forgive me, please.
I should not have
raised my voice at you.
It is understandable.
Your brother's contempt
occupies your thoughts.
My worries may
be for naught.
Let us hope.
[patting]
But there is
one thing more.
Speak your heart.
T'is nothing--really.
Malcolm, speak to me.
It is just a thought
that troubles me betimes.
And that is?
Trading my sword
for a simple,
more peaceful life.
Ah. Yes.
But only betimes.
Pray, misunderstand
me not, my lord.
Being the best does
too have its advantages.
Hm, yes.
Worship--
praise, adoration.
- No.
- No?
Then of what advantage
do you speak, brother?
It allows me to be
in your presence,
my lord.
[soft snorting]
[patting]
Let us ride.
Thank you, my lord.
[horse neighing]
I'm not your lord.
I am your
brother, Melkon.
[horse neighs]
My lord,
they are here.
Arm yourselves.
Be not obvious.
On my signal.
[mutters to himself]
My time is now.
(Gregoire)
Easy, Claudius, easy.
[horse snorts softly]
Whoa.
I have counted the gold,
and it is quite a sum.
You have done
well, Gregoire.
We have done well.
The Grandmaster
will be very pleased.
Though wrested from
the hands of evil,
this unforeseen treasure
will serve great purpose.
Many hungry will
be fed tonight.
Many poor will
be clothed.
The villages, restored.
All in the name
of the cause.
You speak naught
but the truth, brothers.
Has anyone
seen Koko?
Ah, he is fetching
water for travel.
Hm.
Might I have a word
with you, Gregoire?
Of course.
(male voice)
Brother--
could you share
with me your, uh--
shielding technique
with the dagger thrust?
Gregoire?
Come, let us
talk, brother.
When thrusting in
with the dagger,
and then over--
We turn to
our weapons, milord.
Will you have us
put a sharp edge
to your dagger and sword?
Indeed.
I thank you.
And yours, my lord?
[snorting]
Be careful
with it, please.
Ah, such magnificence.
I shall give it
a fine edge, my lord.
But gingerly, sergeant,
I need enough steel
to last yet 100
battles more.
Yes, 100 battles more.
Truly you and I have
given our lives
- to the service
of the true cross.
- Oh?
And yet, strange,
is it not,
we have been
granted not for our
years of loyal service.
No tribute for a life
of poverty, chastity
and obedience.
No reward.
Oh, Renault.
Old friend.
You are tired, and
you are weary
from battle.
You mean not
what you say.
But there are
the others.
Knights that are
paid to fight
and they are allowed
to keep their winnings.
Mercenaries? Those who
covet glory and riches?
We are not
warmongers, Renault.
We are of a
different breed.
Aye, and t'is our unity
that gives us strength,
is it not?
By God's divine grace,
we are a glorious force.
Skilled at
confronting the enemy,
luring him in,
catching him unawares.
Victorious time
and time again!
Aye, victorious.
And to the victors
goes the spoils.
Such is the way of
conquering nations,
is it not?
Conquering nation?
I did not
know we'd become
a conquering nation.
I was under the belief
that we're still yet
an order. Hm?
And I say to you it
is time we cease
to worry
about the welfare
of the poor and
the weak!
Let their fate
be in the hands
of God.
How has your heart
become so blackened?
I see it in your eye.
You've lost your way.
Nay, Brother.
I have found it.
And I will attain it
with the treasure in
yond wagon.
Let us seize this
opportunity together, Gregoire.
Truly we would have
none of it if not
for you.
Think of the comforts
such a treasure
would buy.
The pleasures that
we might finally
delight in.
What say you, brother?
I would rather be eaten
by a pack of wolves
than allow your evil venom
to course through my veins.
You are
an honorable man.
Pity.
Melkon! Behind you!
[grunts and groans]
[groan]
(Melkon)
My lord--
my lord--
Shhh.
[groaning]
[stomp]
[neighs wildly]
[Koko, gasping]
I'm sorry, milord.
I am but
small and weak.
[weeps]
I failed you.
Would you forgive me?
You are braver
than any man
I have ever
met in battle.
Was I a good servant?
Servant? No.
I see you more
as a leader
of men.
[distant thunder]
Thank you, my lord.
Thank you.
Brother, how will
you sleep tonight?
Knowing that I'm
no longer number two.
[sword slides]
Oh!
[panting]
Turn. Turn
and look at me
that I
may see your face
as I take your life.
No, I will not give
you that satisfaction.
You have not earned it.
I am better
than you.
Only in cowardice,
my dear brother.
Only in cowardice.
[shout]
[groan]
[thud]
Best of friends,
dear Melkon.
We were--best of friends.
Dear brothers, farewell.
We shall ride again--
backstabbers.
[thump]
[neighs wildly]
(Renault)
The people can fend
for themselves, brother.
In the meantime, I shall
enjoy enough fortune for
ten lifetimes of excess!
[laughing]
And now Gregoire,
it is time for
you to die.
So be it.
But I will avenge
the deaths of my brothers.
You have made your pact
with the devil, Renault.
You will have your
ten lifetimes of excess.
But then--
I will
come for you.
All of you.
[shout]
[gasp]
[loud thunder]
[groan]
[moan]
[thunder]
[weeping]
Whoever wrote
this inscription
wasn't kidding.
Passion, loyalty,
deceit, betrayal--
And revenge.
Right.
[sniffing]
Do you think Gregoire
is going to carry out
his curse?
Yes.
Most definitely.
They have
like 10 lifetimes.
[sniffing]
Say they realize
their mistakes,
that they made--
and they
try to rebuild--
what is it called?
Their spiritual temples.
Do you think that
he would spare them?
(Jake)
Perhaps.
But I believe one
must truly desire
to change.
(Jake)
And even then, ultimately,
it'll be in God's hands.
[thunder]
And if they don't
change their ways?
Then as prophesized--
Lord Gregoire will
kill them all,
without mercy,
and take
their wretched
souls to hell.
It is spoken
from his lips
to God's ears...
it is the inevitable.
What are your thoughts?
I'd say go
for the ten
lifetimes of excess.
I mean, what
the fuck, right?
I don't agree.
But I guess everybody
has a right to their
own opinion.
[coughing]
You're smart.
And you're cute too.
You think I'm cute?
Yep. I noticed you
first time we got
in the car.
I think we should
spend this time
to get to know
each other better.
What are you doing?
I'm just getting
to know you.
What happened
to Celine?
Celine isn't
here right now!
Stop! Stop it!
Stop!
[punch]
[thud]
Fuck! Yo! You said
everyone was free game!
[screaming]
I said not her!
Fine! Fuck it.
Not her then,
my fault.
Shit.
Fuck you.
[weeping]
I should have never
left you alone
with him. Ever.
Look at me.
It won't happen again.
He'll never
touch you again.
Hear me?
I'm sorry, Amy.
Okay?
[sniffing]
Yeah.
[shout]
[groan]
[panting]
[screaming]
Jake!
Jake?
[indistinct eerie voices]
[gasping]
[shout]
[scream]
[sword piercing flesh]
[Amy, reading]
Seven hundred
years have passed,
You will have your
10 lifetimes of excess.
And as prophesized,
the ordained time
will soon be upon us.
Their kindred spirits
will soon be aligned
for the reprisal of he
who was betrayed
so long ago
so that one day
he may fulfill
his destiny.
My mission is to make
sure that everything
is carried out
as planned.
[punching]
That's my task.
Your leaving now
changes nothing.
To deliver the souls
of the accursed
to hell for all eternity.
I believe that's
why I'm here.
I will come for
you, all of you.
And as spoken
from his lips
to God's ear,
he will return
for his vengeance.
[sword sliding]
[Jake's voice, echoing]
It is the inevitable.
Like the threads?
You do wear
it well.
Thank you.
It's befitting
of you and habitual,
once again mimicking
the life of a man of God--
and now a priest.
A great cover,
don't you think?
Free meals.
A cut from
the Sunday basket.
No tax and most of all,
beautiful nuns
and the altar boys.
What could be better?
I tried the Rabbi
thing, but--
too much to learn.
And that Kaballah, oy!
You just love giving
religion a bad name,
don't you?
I aim to please.
Did you get
my calling card?
[screams]
I kill these two over,
and over, and over--
for 700 years,
and each time was
more enjoyable
than the last.
Nobody steals
my fortune. Nobody.
Yours? It was never
yours to begin
with, Renault.
Renault?
Anyway--you know
the old saying,
(speaks foreign language)
Have you considered
any of the turning
the other cheek business?
You know, let
bygones be bygones.
Not today.
Pity. Do you remember
the man you made
the mistake
of calling
the second
greatest swordsman
in all of the
Mediterranean? Menas !
If she's Menas,
then I must
be--Melkon.
Once again.
The advantage of surprise.
Really? Catch.
Hm. Delicious.
I see you've returned
to picking apples.
Occupational hazard.
Any of that
blood yours?
T'is now.
Who the hell is he?
The Shopkeeper
from down the road.
The shopkeeper?
And how in God's name
is he going to help you?
He wasn't always
a shop keeper.
Hello Menas.
It's been a long time.
Yes, it
has been, Melkon.
Melkon? I thought I was--
Melkon? You
must be shitting me.
[indistinct]
(Menas)
As you took
your dying breath,
I did not regret your
death, my brother,
but only the fashion
in which it occurred.
You chose it.
I intended on
killing you honorably.
I robbed myself
of knowing that
I was the best.
And since that night
I've waited in limbo
for 700 years
for this very moment,
to prove that I am
the superior swordsman.
I have no desire
to fight you.
I'm not leaving
you with a choice.
Ah.
My liege.
Looks like we'll have
ourselves a fair
fight this time.
Yes, my lord.
If I've told you once,
I've told you
a thousand times:
I am not your lord,
I am your brother, Melkon.
[chuckles]
Yes, my lord.
Whatever.
[groaning]
I will not live in
your shadow
any longer.
The only shadow
you live in
is the one you
cast for yourself.
I shall cut you ten times.
Once for each
lifetime of excess.
Or perhaps 700, eh?
One for each year of sin.
[laughing]
Come and get it!
Oh, I plan to!
[shout]
[grunting]
You betrayed us.
You swore never
to betray us
and then you did!
So Renault,
as promised--
I'm taking
you to hell.
Ah yeah,
that little thing.
Well, I'm certainly fine
when you're having fun.
Are you sure it's been
already 10 lifetimes?
Because I'm only counting
8 or 9 at the most.
Oh well,
c'est la vie.
C'est la guerre.
Touche.
[groaning]
I just want
to let you know--
each one of my lives
was more decadent
than the last!
I did the unimaginable
to people!
I know.
[punch]
[shout]
I am better than you.
Prove it.
Not with swordsmanship,
but with humility.
No!
You only defend,
attack me!
I will not give you
that satisfaction.
I have waited 700
years for this moment.
Now you pick up your sword
and you fight me.
What are you doing?
Fight me like a man.
Put it in your hand now!
Fighting you will
not make me a man.
Pick it up. Put
it in your hand
and fight me!
Why won't you fight me?
Because--
Because you're a coward.
No.
Because I love you.
Remember as children, how
we played together everyday?
And how our
mother loved us?
And how she made
us promise to her
that when the day came
that she would leave us,
that we would
watch over
each other?
Just like brothers should.
Menas, I would have
died for you then--
and I will now.
If my brother
doesn't love me,
then I have no
wish to live.
[shout]
Your time is up.
Put it down.
Put the sword down!
[panting]
Gregoire, time to die.
I always like to keep
up with the times.
[footsteps]
Jake!
[shout]
[gunshot]
Ahhh.
Ah!
Back off!
We're going to leave.
If you do anything
to stop me--
I am going to
slit her throat.
You understand?
Back off!
I'm sorry,
Jake, I'm sorry.
I failed you.
It's not your fault.
It's just destiny.
Mine and yours.
Back off.
[panting]
It's not your time,
little one.
Just shield and fight.
Back off!
Yes, milord.
[punch]
Ah!
[punching]
Sword!
Not yours, mine.
This has no weight to it.
It's like a butter knife.
It's built for speed.
Look, I've waited 700
years for this moment.
I'm gonna kill him
with my sword,
not yours.
Point taken but--why
do you have to be so
mean about it?
How could you
be so sensitive
and be such
a great fighter?
Ah, that is what makes
me a great fighter.
- And chicks dig it.
- Ah.
[panting]
(Jake)
Now where was I?
- My lord.
- Thank you.
Oh, not you, too.
Well, at least you're
not killing each other.
And now Renault, old friend.
T'is your time to die.
So be it, Gregoire.
Ha.
And now your blood,
shall be mine.
[chuckles]
See you around.
Ahh!
[shouting]
Payback's a bitch.
[shouting continues]
(Amy)
Oh my God,
I think he's in shock!
[heartbeat]
[many voices cheering]
[Amy, distorted]
Jake!
Jake?
Excellent performance,
my lord.
Excellent performance.
Bravo.
A little over the top.
But given the circumstance
and no rehearsal--
How else could
you play it?
But tell me,
my lord,
how can you be such
a great leader
when you're so dramatic?
That is what makes me
such a great leader.
And chicks dig it.
Touche.
Wait. You're
not shot?
No, he missed
me by a mile.
And hey, nice
save by the way.
Aren't you
guys forgetting
about something?
The six hacked up
mutilated bodies?
Six?
Only a couple
are mine.
Four. Four
were yours.
Four.
I'm impressed.
I say we pin
it on the priest.
Nice. See, I told you.
You're a leader of men.
Don't even think
that I'm not
really pissed
at you at you right now.
I just can't have
my new boyfriend
go to jail
on the first night
we start dating.
- Boyfriend?
- Yes.
- Dating?
What are you, nuts?
You're like Koko
and stuff.
Come on!
We're soul mates.
Ow! My nipple, ow!
My nipple!
You're nuts.
I like it.
What a strange day
it's been, huh?
Kapow. Lend me
a hand, shopkeep.
Yeah.
Well old friend,
see you in
the next lifetime.
(shopkeeper)
Yeah, old friends,
old soul mates.
Yes, we are.
♪
[Pilot singing
"Oh ho ho, it's Magic"]
Encoded by VYTO.
Support us by visiting www.P2PDL.com.