(♪♪♪)
(CLICK)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
♪ Here I go
Going down, down, down ♪
♪ My mind is a blank ♪
♪ My head is spinning
Around and around ♪
♪ As I go deep into
the funnel of love ♪
♪ It's such a crazy, crazy feeling ♪
♪ I get weak in the knees ♪
♪ My poor old head is a reelin' ♪
♪ As I go deep into
the funnel of love ♪
♪ I tried and I tried,
to run and hide ♪
♪ I even tried to run away ♪
♪ Ya just can't run
From the funnel of love ♪
♪ It's bound to get ya someday ♪
♪ Deep into the funnel of love ♪
♪ Deep into the funnel of love ♪♪
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(CAR DOOR BEEPING)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
ADAM: Ian.
- IAN: Adam, man, how are you?
- ADAM: Hey.
- Is this the Supro?
- IAN: Yeah.
It's a beautiful one, man.
I hope you're gonna like
it because these Supros,
they're getting harder and
harder to find, you know?
You get one, but the
pickups are messed up.
You get one, the neck is
messed up or something.
Oh, Shit.
Adam, you want me to take off my
shoes? I think I stepped in some mud.
- Ian, I really wouldn't bother.
- All right.
ADAM: The Supro.
IAN: 1959, man.
- Really nice, Ian. Thank you.
- Cool.
All the electronics, everything,
are original, of course.
- I plugged them in, made sure they work.
- Just what the doctor ordered,
as they say.
(STRUMS NOTE)
I shall call him William Lawes.
It's a male?
This one is, yeah.
(PLAYING SOFT MELODY)
Who's William Lawes?
Oh, just some old
17th-century English guy.
Wrote some great funeral music.
Then, during the English Civil War,
he was casually shot dead
by a Parliamentarian.
Oh.
That sucks.
Adam, check this one out, man.
- This one...
- Is a very strange Hagstrom from 1960.
- Swedish.
- Yeah.
- ADAM: Look at this thing.
- Heh, heh.
Look at the back.
- Mother of toilet seat.
- Heh, heh.
Seriously, man.
Wow.
And this one...
Check this out.
ADAM: It's a Silvertone.
From the very early '60s.
With an amp built into
the case. Fantastic.
IAN: Right?
Yeah.
And...
Oh, that's a lovely
Gretsch Chet Atkins.
Mm-hm.
6120, Double Cutaway.
(PLAYS MELODY)
Heh.
I once saw Eddie Cochran
play one of these.
Though he had the front pickup
modified to a Gibson P-90.
Wait. You actually saw
Eddie Cochran play?
Yeah, on YouTube.
Oh, right.
Of course, man.
(♪♪♪)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
MAN: Hey, you.
- I have something special for you.
- Hey. We have what you need.
I know you don't wanna play live,
I know you wanna remain anonymous,
but you being so reclusive
and everything...
is probably only gonna make people
more interested in your music.
ADAM: Yeah.
What a drag.
(GUITAR PLAYING SOFT MELODY)
Listen, Ian. There is
something you can do for me.
Anything. Yeah,
anything. What is it?
I need a bullet.
A very special bullet.
Really? I got you that box of
shells with the .38 last year.
I know, the .38.
I need a .38-caliber
bullet but made of wood.
A wooden bullet? Seriously, man?
And made from the hardest and
most dense wood you can find.
I'd suggest ironwood, lignum vitae.
Maybe snakewood,
Piratinera guianensis.
Or possibly African blackwood,
Dalbergia melanoxylon.
Find someone who can
make it for me?
Yeah, but could you just...?
Could you repeat the last couple?
ADAM: Ironwood, lignum vitae.
Snakewood, Piratinera guianensis
or blackwood, Dalbergia
melanoxylon.
IAN: Dalbergia...
Okay.
Yeah, I mean, I think I know
someone, but what the hell for?
It's for a...
A project.
A secret art project.
Okay, cool, cool.
All right, let me think. Um...
Thank you, Adam.
The shell casing should be brass,
but the bullet has to be wood.
- You just want one?
- Just the one, yeah.
Okay, cool.
Uh, anything else weird or
interesting you might need?
There's a warehouse sale.
This guy's selling all these Sovtek amps,
germanium resistors, Soviet tubes.
I thought I might check
it out, see if you...
No, I'm good. Thank you.
Okay.
Can I use your bathroom
before I head out?
Uh, I'm afraid it's
still out of order.
Still? I'm gonna get someone...
- Don't bother.
- It's really no bother.
No!
Look, Ian, I, uh...
I'm gonna fix it myself. I just
haven't gotten around to it yet.
Please, feel free to
piss in the garden.
(♪♪♪)
(MEN SPEAKING ARABIC)
(ARABIC POP MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
(CHATTERING IN ARABIC)
(DOOR OPENS)
Bilal.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(IN ENGLISH) So...
Tell me, how is he, really?
My teacher is fragile,
but he has a strong spirit.
He's in such good hands.
He's my family.
And I protect...
Protect his secrets.
And yours too.
(COYOTES HOWLING)
(ENGINE WHIRRING)
(♪♪♪)
MAN: Actually, hospital management
no longer considers it overtime.
Yes.
Mistress mine.
EVE: There's only an
hour before sunrise.
I'm well aware of that, my dear.
Is that the really good stuff?
Yes, Eve.
From the French doctor?
Precisely.
So how is the fabulous
Christopher Marlowe tonight?
I told you a thousand times,
never call me that name in public.
Oh.
You nutcase.
I can keep a secret.
You should know that.
But I ask you,
the most outrageously delicious
literary scandal in history...
Dear Eve, that was
four centuries ago.
You've been wearing that
weskit for four centuries.
I was given this in 1586, and
it's one of my favorite garments.
Are you saying that we're never
gonna let the cat out of the bag?
Can't we drop the odd
hint here and there?
It would cause such
thrilling chaos.
I think the world has enough chaos
to keep it going for the minute.
You spoilsport.
Hm.
I see you...
(WATSON MUMBLING)
(MACHINE BLEEPING)
(WATSON CONTINUES MUMBLING)
WATSON: I see you.
Jesus Christ.
You scared the shit out of me.
I've sort of been
expecting you recently
for some reason, uh, doctor...
Uh, Dr. Faust.
ADAM: It's good to see you
again too, Dr. Watson.
(CLEARS THROAT)
You know, uh, this whole setup
is a bit unnerving for me.
Wouldn't you consider meeting
somewhere outside the
hospital sometime
instead of just
appearing unexpectedly
like a phantom?
ADAM:
That would require prearrangement.
Yeah, and it would be safer for me.
ADAM: I like to come to the source.
Besides, the mutual jeopardy
makes me feel safer.
If you'll excuse me.
I don't have any spare time.
Right.
Well, then, let me get
you what you desire,
uh, Dr. Strangelove.
Type O negativo.
Mm-hm.
By the way, that stethoscope
of yours
is for all practical
purposes, an antique.
It's from the 1970s.
Maybe even the '60s.
Is it?
(SIGHS)
Cat gotta be from Cleveland.
(♪♪♪)
(SIGHS)
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah.
Adam.
Eve.
Hey, darling.
- I wanna see you.
- I wanna see you too.
What is that? That you scrabbling
about with all your wires
- and knobs, my little pack rat?
- Yeah, one second. I just...
I just...
Hello.
There you are.
Hello, sweetheart.
- What is it? You look tired.
- Do I?
- Hm.
- I guess I am, a little, yeah.
Any supply problems?
No.
So, what is this, then?
Can you tell your wife
what your problem is?
It's these zombies
and the way they treat the world.
I just feel like all the sand's
at the bottom of the hourglass,
or something.
Time to turn it over, then.
Oh, my liege lord.
We've been here before.
Remember?
You missed all the real fun, like
the Middle Ages, the Tartars,
the Inquisitions.
The floods, the plagues.
Well, how about your music?
I seem to be...
(GUITAR PLAYS NOTE)
Writing a lot of
funeral music. Heh.
Oh, my darling. Why don't you
just come here and kiss me?
You used to love Tangier.
You loved the music.
Oh, fuck.
All right.
I'll come.
But I can't believe you're
doing this to me again.
It's just the traveling
that's such a drag.
Eve...
I love you so much.
I'll take that for the journey.
(KISS)
(SIGHS)
(PLAYING SOFT ROCK MUSIC)
(SOFT ROCK MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
(♪♪♪)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(MUSIC STOPS)
Fucking hell.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(CAR DRIVING AWAY)
(SNIFFING)
(PLAYING CLASSICAL MUSIC)
Yes. And is there a possibility of a
night flight from Tangier to Paris?
Yes, that would work.
And then flying the following night
from Paris to Detroit, is that correct?
Wonderful.
Name of Fibonacci.
(♪♪♪)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(BUZZING)
(DOOR OPENS)
- IAN: Hey, I hope this isn't a bad time.
- Hm.
IAN: I wanted to come right away
because I have that thing for you.
Wooden bullet, .38 caliber.
It's cocobolo.
Dalbergia retusa.
For your art project.
Guy made it for me,
no questions asked.
He said the wood was so dense
that it sinks in water.
And I think they make
guitars out of it too.
Both are true, yeah.
It's perfect.
Thank you, Ian.
No problem, man.
You know, for a zombie,
you're all right.
Thanks.
Please.
Oh, no, man. You already paid
me so much the other time.
- It's okay.
- Ian, please.
You bought my car and everything.
Thank you, Adam.
Uh...
Anything else you might need, man?
Anything you want me to get you?
There were some rock 'n' roll kids
here last night, ringing my doorbell.
- Really?
- Yeah.
How do they know where you live?
No one fucking lives out here.
I don't know, but it's not cool.
We talked about this.
I know. I know we did, man.
It's not cool at all. It's completely
fucked up. How would they...?
All right, I know. Don't worry.
I'm gonna spread some
rumors, very cautiously,
about where you might live and
just throw them way off track.
Whatever you need to
do, please do it.
Just take care of it.
- I'm on it.
- Okay.
Look, I'll see you later.
I've got something I need to do.
(PEOPLE SPEAKING
ARABIC IN DISTANCE)
You know...
I had a dream...
about your infamous
little sister last night.
You had a dream about Ava?
What sort of a dream, Kit?
Kit?
What?
Oh, sorry. I...
- Sorry. I drifted away for a minute.
- Heh, heh.
- You were miles away.
- Italy, actually.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Few hundred years ago.
Was he painfully good-looking?
- What?
- Ha, ha, ha.
Uh...
Look, I know I don't
have to say this to you,
but please be cautious.
I couldn't bear it if...
I couldn't bear it if
something happened to you.
Frankly, I don't understand why
you don't live in the same place
because you can't live
without each other.
Anyway, give my regards to that
suicidally romantic scoundrel.
Do you really think he is?
Scoundrel? Heh, heh. Yes.
Well, let's hope
he's just romantic.
Even so, I mainly blame
Shelley and Byron
and some of those French assholes
he used to hang around with.
Oh, I wish that I had met
him before I wrote Hamlet.
He would have provided the most
perfect role model imaginable.
(♪♪♪)
(IMITATES GUNSHOT)
EVE: Love alters not, with
his brief hours and weeks
But bears it out even
to the edge of doom
If this be error and upon me proved
I never writ, nor no man ever loved
(SIGHS)
Marlowe.
(CAN OPENS)
MAN: Ow. Shit.
Oh, man.
I'm a mess.
Excuse me.
STEWARDESS 1: Oh, la, la. Let
me get you something for that.
MAN: Thank you.
(♪♪♪)
(PA BELL DINGS)
STEWARDESS 2 (ON PA): Ladies and gentlemen, we're
beginning our descent into Detroit Metro Airport.
We thank you for flying
with us on Air Lumiere
and hope to see you again soon.
(FOREIGN LANGUAGE POP
SONG PLAYING OVER RADIO)
(CAR DOOR OPENS)
- I appreciate it.
- No problem.
(TRUNK CLOSES)
Oh.
Mephitis mephitis.
(♪♪♪)
(ADAM BREATHING HEAVILY)
My lady.
May I?
(♪♪♪)
(SOFT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
I love what you've
done with the place.
(ADAM CHUCKLES)
I love your newest music too.
It made me think of when you gave that
string quintet to Schubert. Remember?
- Hm.
- And he presented it as his own.
Yeah, but I asked him to do that.
And I only gave him the adagio.
Just to put something out there.
Is that why you released
this new stuff?
I needed a reflection.
To see if it would
echo back before...
Before what?
Oh, Adam.
You always have the convenience of the
zombies to blame when you get low.
What about all your heroes?
I don't have heroes.
No?
What about your blessed scientists?
The scientists?
Well, look at what
they've done to them.
Pythagoras, slaughtered.
Galileo, imprisoned.
Copernicus, ridiculed.
Poor old Newton, pushed
into secrecy and alchemy.
Tesla, destroyed.
His beautiful possibilities
completely ignored.
And they're still bitching
about Darwin, still.
So much for the scientists.
And now they have
succeeded in contaminating
their own fucking blood,
never mind their water.
Yeah, well, if we're
gonna have a litany
of all the zombie
atrocities of history,
we'll be here till
the sun comes up.
The sun is coming up.
Shall I tell you again about
spooky action at a distance?
Einstein's theory of entanglement.
Yeah. I love the way you tell it.
But not now.
We don't wanna be up all day.
Eve?
Hm?
Can you tell me how
old this guitar is?
I think it's an L2
but I've never been able
to date it exactly.
EVE: Aw.
She's a pretty one.
A Gibson.
1905.
She is old.
Yes, my darling, but you
know your dressing gown
- is at least a century older.
- Is it?
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(♪♪♪)
So this is your wilderness.
Detroit.
ADAM: Everybody left.
- What's that?
- It's the Packard plant
where they once built the most
beautiful cars in the world.
Finished.
EVE:
But this place will rise again.
- Will it?
- Yeah.
There's water here.
And when the cities in
the South are burning,
this place will bloom.
Do you wanna see the Motown Museum?
Although it's not much to
look at from the outside.
I'm more of a Stax girl myself.
Actually, there is something
I could show you.
It's not far.
There.
That's Jack White's house.
EVE: Oh. I love Jack White.
- ADAM: That's where he grew up.
- Oh.
Little Jack White.
Nice.
Do you know he's actually
his mother's seventh son?
(LAUGHS)
That figures.
And this is the famous
Michigan Theater.
They built it back in the 1920s.
A huge sum of money.
It's built, ironically,
on the exact same site
as Henry Ford made his
very first prototype.
They used to be able to seat
over 4000 people in here.
EVE: It's fantastic.
For what? For concerts?
ADAM:
Concerts and as a movie house.
Can you imagine?
Mirrors used to reflect
the chandeliers.
And now a car park.
There goes your queen, playboy.
By the way, your hero, Christopher
Marlowe, sends his love.
I don't have heroes.
And I know what you're doing.
Trying to distract me.
Now, no more talking.
- Did you play chess with Byron?
- Eve, please.
No, I want to know.
You love telling me these
things and I love to hear them.
So, what was he like?
- Frankly, he was a pompous ass.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Why am I not surprised?
And what about Mary?
What was Mary Wollstonecraft like?
Come on, tell me.
What was she like?
- She was delicious.
- Heh, heh.
I'll bet she was.
Talking of delicious,
I have a surprise.
An experiment.
- ADAM: That doesn't work, by the way.
- No, it does. I plugged it in.
- What is that?
- O-negative.
That's delicious.
(SNIFFS)
Blood on a stick.
On a stick.
- That's not bad.
- Very refreshing,
especially when
you're in a hot spot.
Checkmate, my darling.
Eve, you're ruthless.
You're brutal.
I'm a survivor, baby.
It was all the bloody talking.
ADAM: You got to hear this one.
It's Charlie Feathers.
(ROCKABILLY MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
Do you know it?
1956.
"Can't Hardly Stand it."
Yeah.
♪ Runnin' around ♪
♪ I can't hardly stand it ♪♪
(MUSIC STUTTERING AND
RECORD PLAYER POWERS OFF)
ADAM: Shit.
(COYOTE HOWLING)
EVE: Oh.
What a lovely place.
Vitis vinifera, hello.
ADAM:
Look at that. Fucking zombie shit.
The grid. It's so antiquated.
I mean, what century is this?
Tesla had light bulbs you didn't
even have to plug in in 1895.
- But it's not even connected.
- Yeah, I disconnected all that.
(GASPS)
Oh, what a hidden
treasure, my darling.
Did you make that?
Well, I cobbled it together
from bits and pieces.
EVE: It's beautiful.
You're an alchemist.
I just need to check the
charges and the connections.
All right, this might
need recalibration.
Are these the antennae?
ADAM: Yeah.
They're receiving electrical
information from the atmosphere.
- From outer space.
- They get converted into energy
- by this dynamo here.
- Mm.
Hang on. Let me just see this.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
Amanita muscaria.
How odd.
- Adam?
- Yeah?
Have you noticed these?
Yeah.
Fly agaric.
They're behaving rather strangely.
- You know, this is not their season.
- I know.
They kind of appear and then disappear
and then reappear, those caps.
I guess they're receiving information
from the atmosphere like my antennae.
Just goes to show, we don't
know shit about fungi.
Even though life on this planet
couldn't exist without them.
You know, you guys
shouldn't really be here.
Not until the autumn.
(EVE'S HEART BEATING)
Evening.
What's going on, my love?
Are we playing doctors?
I am. I have to go out
for about an hour or so.
- Am I not included?
- Not this time.
1968. Surely you could
do with a newer one.
Have you ever used this on anyone?
Dr. Faust? Right.
What is it, my darling?
I had a dream about your sister.
Not a good one, then.
Well, I suppose it
could've been worse.
But not by much.
- Back in a flash.
- I hope so.
Good luck with the surgery, doctor.
June 23rd, 1868.
Our third wedding.
We look so young.
(CAR DRIVING AWAY)
(♪♪♪)
Marlowe.
Dalbergia retusa.
This has been newly made.
You're looking awfully
pale there, Dr. Caligari.
Maybe you need to get a
little more sunlight.
Vitamin D deficiency can
have serious consequences.
Fresh blood, baby.
What's this about?
Just tell me that you're having trouble with
one of the others. Please tell me that.
I don't see any others.
Ever.
Okay.
Don't ever fuck around like that.
Just playing a part in your story.
It's the zombies I'm sick of.
And their fear of their
own fucking imaginations.
My darling, that's true.
Meanwhile...
just tell me what's so not
frightened about that.
How can you have lived for so
long and still not get it?
This self-obsession,
it's a waste of living...
that could be spent
on surviving things,
appreciating nature,
nurturing kindness and friendship.
And dancing.
You've been pretty
lucky in love, though,
if I may say so.
(SOUL MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ Somebody tell me ♪
♪ What does this man got ♪
♪ He makes me feel ♪
♪ What I don't wanna feel ♪
♪ Somebody tell me ♪
♪ What has this man got ♪
♪ He makes me give ♪
♪ What I don't wanna give ♪
♪ On solid ground ♪
♪ I feel myself sinkin' fast ♪
♪ I grab ahold ♪
♪ But I don't think
it's gonna last ♪
♪ I'm slowly losin' my ground ♪
♪ Slowly sinkin' down ♪
♪ Trapped by this thing
they call love ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ Hooked on this
thing called love ♪
♪ Somebody tell me ♪
♪ What does this man got ♪
♪ He makes me cry ♪
♪ Lord, I don't wanna cry ♪
♪ He calls me up ♪
♪ And I tell 'em to
say that I'm not in ♪
♪ Then I cry all night ♪
♪ If he doesn't call again ♪
♪ I'm slowly losin' my ground ♪
♪ Slowly sinkin' down ♪
♪ Trapped by this thing
they call love ♪
♪ Oh, baby ♪
♪ I'm trapped ♪
♪ I can't help myself ♪
♪ I'm hooked on you baby ♪
♪ I just can't help it ♪
♪ I can never be happy
Loving no one else ♪
♪ Oh, baby
I love you ♪♪
It's a full moon.
Did you know that there's
a diamond up there
the size of a planet?
It's a white dwarf. It's the
compressed heart of a star.
And it's not only a
radiant diamond,
but it also emits the
music of a gigantic gong.
A diamond that emits the music
- of a gigantic gong.
- Gigantic gong.
Where is it?
It's just 50 light-years away
in the constellation Centaurus.
Hm.
I wonder what it sounds like.
(♪♪♪)
EVE: I have to tell you something.
I also had a dream about my sister.
As did Marlowe before
I left Tangier.
I think she's looking for us.
Fuck.
Well, I mean, it's
been quite some time.
Yeah, not long enough.
Shouldn't she be sleeping
in a coffin somewhere?
With a wooden stake shoved in?
- Adam, she's my sister.
- Is she now?
Well, we are related by blood.
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKERS UPSTAIRS)
I didn't leave these lights on.
That's your music.
(MUSIC CONTINUES PLAYING)
EVE: Ava.
What the fuck are you doing here?
Oh, my God, it's so
great to see you.
Mm.
You're still so beautiful.
May I?
My amazing sister, I've missed you.
(MUSIC STOPS)
- Did you get my message?
- I might have. I had a dream.
Oh, how cool. It worked.
There's your spooky
action at a distance.
ADAM:
Yeah, well, spooky action anyway.
AVA:
What are you guys talking about?
You do know that it's very bad luck
to cross a threshold
without being invited?
Are you still afraid of garlic?
I'm not talking about
myths here, Ava.
You know it's also bad luck to listen
to someone's music without invitation?
My God, I love it, Adam.
It's totally brilliant.
- Can I get a download?
- No.
So?
- You just passing through Detroit?
- Yeah.
No, I mean, I came to see you.
I've been living in L.A.
Great.
Zombie central.
Are you alone?
AVA: No.
I'm here with you guys.
(AVA CHUCKLES)
Fuck. Well, you can't stay here.
- Adam.
- No fucking way.
- Not after last time.
- Oh, Adam, it's been 87 years.
What? When?
Are you still upset
about that Paris thing?
Well, are you okay?
Yeah, but I'm...
I'm really, really, really hungry.
Do you maybe have something?
(SIGHS)
Could you smell it all
the way from L.A.?
Come on.
Ava.
I just wanna see where you keep it.
ADAM: No.
(SIGHS)
It is so amazing to see you.
We're gonna have so
much fun together.
She drank a hell of a
lot of our O-negative.
I know.
But she's been traveling,
and that fries you, you know?
It'll be all right.
It's always a bit
weird with family.
Where's she sleeping, though?
I put her in that little
bedroom downstairs.
Which little bedroom?
You know, the little
one down the corridor.
I'll have to put my tapes
in the bloody safe now.
Don't worry. Go to sleep now.
She's out cold, and
it's getting light out.
You can do all that
when we get up tonight.
Just think of that
magical musical diamond
in the sky. It's above us now.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
(DOOR OPENS)
AVA: Eve? Adam?
- EVE: What is it, Ava?
- Can I come in?
ADAM: No.
AVA: Isn't it time to get up?
Darling, can't we sleep
a little longer?
But it's dark out already.
I'm starving.
Go away. We're still sleeping.
In a little while, we'll all get up and
have breakfast together, all right?
Some more of that good stuff?
- Sure.
- Where do you keep it?
You go and get dressed and
we'll bring you some, all right?
Okay.
- Peekaboo.
- Ugh.
I see you.
(POP MUSIC PLAYING ON TELEVISION)
DRACULA (ON TV):
Come in, little girl.
(CHUCKLING)
Let me do it.
Soul Dracula.
(DRACULA LAUGHING)
- ADAM: What the hell is this?
- Heh, heh.
EVE: Oh, this is from
French television, 1975.
(AVA & EVE CHUCKLING)
(TV TURNS OFF)
- Hey.
- You're pressing your luck, Ava.
Why did you turn it off? I love
that. I found it on YouTube.
Of course, you did.
Unh. I don't feel well.
What is it, sweetheart?
You think it's all the traveling?
- Maybe.
- It's probably blood poisoning.
- Don't joke, Adam.
- I'm not.
Are you taking care of your
nutrition? You have to be careful.
- There's a lot of contamination around.
- I try.
Hey, you guys fed without me.
ADAM: Take it easy. Shit.
(♪♪♪)
- My God, that is good. I want more.
- No, you've had more than enough.
This is pure shit.
You're gonna drain our whole
fucking supply, so take it easy.
Fine.
I wanna hear some of your music.
No. I told you, it's private.
Oh, yeah? Well, how come
I heard it in L.A. then?
What? Where'd you hear it?
In, like, an underground
music club.
I don't believe you.
So don't.
- How did you know it was mine, then?
- Oh, come on, I could tell immediately.
I might have been born at night,
but I wasn't born last night.
(AVA STRUMMING GUITAR)
Fine. Then I'm gonna go out.
I wanna hear some music.
- ADAM: Good idea. Go out.
- Oh, but I wanna go with you two.
No.
You're so fucking boring.
Bet he never takes you
out, ever, right?
Well, no, we do go for a drive,
- from time to time.
- AVA: Oh, a drive.
Well, that's exciting.
I mean, go somewhere
where there's music.
Don't you wanna go, Eve?
Well, I wouldn't mind.
We are in Detroit.
- Yeah!
- No.
Adam's gonna take us out.
No, Adam is not going
to take you out.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
♪ All I need ♪
♪ We're all the same ♪♪
(CROWD CHEERING)
IAN: Yeah.
- They're awesome. They're so good.
- They were great.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
IAN: You all have such
awesome gloves, man.
Where, uh...? Where'd you...?
Where'd you get them?
- Hey, Ian.
- Scott.
- SCOTT: How's it going?
- How are you?
- It was the Danny & the Darleans gig.
- I think so, yeah.
- I got something for you. I'll be right back.
- Okay.
Yeah.
- That was great. Awesome.
- So good, yeah.
- So you remember about that 12-inch?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Let me... Let me go grab it.
- Okay, cool.
(♪♪♪)
- Check it out, man. Triple black, man.
- Whoa.
- That's great.
- Yeah.
- 180 gram vinyl?
- 180 gram, man.
- Amazing.
- Yeah. No printing anywhere.
Yeah, that's awesome, man.
So mysterious.
Thanks, man.
IAN: Nice meeting you.
Wow, man, this is... This
is so great, you know?
I couldn't get this guy to just come
out and see some live music, you know?
- Did you like it, Adam?
- Yes.
- Adam, you wanna meet White Hills?
- No.
Cool, man. I read you.
(BAND PLAYING ROCK MUSIC)
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, I'm so sorry.
That's so rude of me.
Could I get you a beer or anything,
Eve? You know, something to drink?
I'm Ava. She's Eve.
I'm so sorry. Eve, can
I get you something?
- A beer?
- No, thank you, nothing.
Ava? Oh, very nice.
You brought your own.
What is that? Jagermeister?
- Where did you get that?
- At home.
- "At home"? You mean at my house?
- Yeah. Want some?
- No.
- I'll have some.
(BAND CONTINUES PLAYING ROCK MUSIC)
Do you think I could
get in on that? Just...
- Sure, Ian.
- Cool.
Whoa, man. Heh.
That was like some
martial-arts-type shit.
Man, this guy is just...
He's amazing, man, you know?
- He's brilliant.
- He is brilliant.
Do you know I can't tell anyone
about him? How weird is that?
Like, I had to sign a confidentiality
agreement and everything.
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS)
That's your music.
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC
CONTINUES PLAYING)
Are you gonna dance
with me, rock star?
- What? Now?
- Yeah.
Eve, we gotta go. Right now.
All right. Just cool it.
Okay? Don't draw attention
to yourself. Just go easy.
- Ava.
- Hm?
(DRUMMING UPBEAT MELODY)
(IAN CHUCKLING)
Ava.
Adam, think we could
hear your new stuff?
ADAM: Now is not a good time.
Seems like a great time.
We're all here, you know?
Yeah, I got you. I'm sorry,
I'm sorry. I'm just getting excited.
Me too.
Adam?
Adam, could I have that
flask back, please?
No, Ava. No more tonight.
- I'm just really thirsty.
- We should all just go to bed.
I mean, it's getting light out,
and I think it's time to retire.
- Well, do you wanna share some of this?
- Hm.
Ian.
I think, um... I think
it's time for you to go.
- Yeah.
- He's gonna go
- as soon as he's finished his little beer.
- Yeah, I should... I should get going.
Yeah, he's gonna go
in just a second.
An excellent idea. Good night, baby.
Good night, Ian. Very nice to meet you.
- I hope to see you again.
- Yeah, I sure hope so.
You're leaving soon, right?
Yeah. No, I'm... I'm going, man.
(IAN CHUCKLES)
(AVA BLOWS AND BOTH CHUCKLING)
Yeah, it's...
- I'm gonna...
- Heh, heh.
I'm gonna get out of here.
Really? Heh.
IAN: Uh...
(COYOTES HOWLING)
Peekaboo. I see you.
Peeka... Peekaboo.
Don't even dare say it.
Hm.
- Is it dark outside?
- Yeah.
(ADAM SIGHS)
What are you doing with this?
I've filled a little
something for Ava.
- Oh, fuck.
- I'm gonna go and check on her.
But you're right, darling.
She's got to go.
- I need you all to myself again.
- Hm.
Good idea.
Before it's too late.
Mm. Well, I guess I'm
getting up, then.
Ava?
(GROANS)
Fuck.
Ow.
- Eve.
- This is the bloody 21st century.
Oh, I didn't mean to.
He was just so cute.
Now I feel sick.
What do you expect? He's
from the music industry.
Oh, just back off.
You drank Ian.
- Adam...
- You drank Ian.
Sorry.
EVE:
We can sort this. Ava is leaving.
Just get off me, Eve.
How many times?
I don't mean to. Ow!
Let go.
What the fuck? That's my stuff.
Get the fuck out of my house.
- Where am I supposed to go?
- Go back and rot in fucking L.A.
You know what you guys are?
You're condescending snobs.
You have no fucking idea.
Fuck you!
Go fuck each other!
EVE: Oh, my love.
He seemed like such
a lovely fellow.
Why couldn't she just
have turned him?
- Can anybody link you two?
- Are you joking?
We were all out
together last night.
So much for that
confidentiality agreement.
Where's his car?
He left it down by
the club. Remember?
Yeah, well, it'll be
gone in a day or two.
Look what she did to my Gibson.
The 1905.
Wow.
How beautifully made it is inside.
Yeah.
(SIGHS)
Have you got a bit of old carpet?
Behind the sofa.
Shall we?
Yeah.
- EVE: Hang on. Hang on.
- Yep. Okay, you got it?
- EVE: Yeah.
- Okay.
- EVE: No, his feet first.
- Feet first. Put his feet in first.
- Just bend the knees.
- Yep.
- Careful with his head.
- Ooh!
All right.
(♪♪♪)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SIREN WAILS)
What are we gonna do with him?
I mean, it's not like in the old
days when we could just chuck them
in the Thames alongside all the
other tubercular floaters.
Any other ideas?
(COYOTE HOWLING)
EVE:
Canis latrans. How lovely.
I think they're clocking you.
Yeah. They're all over Detroit.
Come on, Eve.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Don't even ask.
Ready?
That certainly was visual.
EVE: Hello? Good evening.
I would like to book two flights
from Detroit to Tangier,
traveling at night.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Who is it?
(INDISTINCT DIALOGUE)
ADAM:
Some rock 'n' roll zombie kids.
They're onto me.
Yes, well, be grateful
it's not the police.
Yes, I'm still here.
Thank you. Yes.
Two tickets, first class, leaving
and arriving at night, please.
Yes, I'm sorry.
I know it's complicated.
Connecting through London?
No, no, I'm sorry.
London's no good.
Yeah. Is there another connection?
Madrid. Madrid's fine.
Yes, two travelers. No luggage.
What about all my instruments?
My darling, the world is full
of beautiful instruments.
I'm gonna find you a magical
instrument in Tangier.
Yes, just carry-on.
Can you carry on blood?
Kit has the best stuff.
As soon as we arrive.
Yes, credit card.
Which would you like?
Yes.
The names of Stephan Dedalus
and Daisy Buchanan.
Chet Atkins.
Dates of birth...
(♪♪♪)
(CHATTERING IN ARABIC)
MAN: Do you need something?
(SPEAKING IN FRENCH)
(IN ENGLISH) I have something
very special for you.
Not far to go now.
Come on.
(SIGHS)
Shit, Marlowe, where are you?
Adam.
(ADAM GROANING)
Ow.
Ow. What was that for?
EVE: Come on.
Where are we?
Did you find Marlowe?
No, but we've got to go find him.
You've got to get up. Come on.
If I can even fucking walk.
(GROANS)
(♪♪♪)
Psst. I have something
very special for you.
I have what you need.
Not what I need.
Oh, fuck. Kit.
Bilal.
- Madame Eve.
- Bilal.
(SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Monsieur Adam.
Bilal.
(IN ENGLISH)
Come in. Come in, please. Come in.
Madame Eve,
my teacher is not well.
This is a very, very bad situation.
Very bad.
You... You look not good.
Please. Please.
BILAL: This way.
MARLOWE: Well, well.
Look what the cat dragged in.
You look like shit.
My old darling.
Oh, yeah.
What a piece of work is a man.
What is this quintessence of dust?
EVE: What happened, Kit?
This is the very last
of the good stuff.
No more good French doctor.
I got some bad stuff.
Contaminated.
Avoid the hospital here.
You still been scratching
away, though, Kit.
MARLOWE: Well, you know...
here and there over the centuries.
Bilal.
Bilal...
is an excellent writer in
his own right, you know.
Maybe not yet.
MARLOWE: Humility gets you nowhere.
There's the proof of that.
Heh, heh, heh.
MARLOWE:
Illiterate zombie philistine.
(GRUNTS)
The game paid off, though, Kit.
You still got the work out there.
Never had much choice.
It was all...
so political.
Anyway, I was supposed to be...
dead.
And now...
at last...
I shall be.
(MARLOWE EXHALES)
(SOBBING)
(♪♪♪)
(EVE SOBBING)
Oh, Eve.
Oh, look at that shit.
- What are we gonna do?
Well, I know what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna get you that present.
Give me all your money, baby.
Come on.
Now...
you're gonna stay here. Okay?
And I'm gonna go around the
corner just for a minute.
No funny business.
- Okay.
- Hm.
(BAND PLAYING SOFT MUSIC)
(WOMAN SINGING IN ARABIC)
(MOUTHING LYRICS)
(APPLAUSE)
(SPEAKS ARABIC)
Eve, this bird is fantastic.
EVE: Yasmine. She's Lebanese.
I'm sure she'll be very famous.
God, I hope not.
She's way too good for that.
Come on, baby.
Look at the bowl.
Dalbergia retusa?
Hm.
(STRUMS NOTE)
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
Eighty-two percent of
human blood is water.
Have the water wars started yet?
Or is it still about the oil?
Yes, they're just starting now.
They only figure it out
when it's too late.
How much of the human
body is water?
Fifty-five to 60 percent.
And how much of the
Earth's surface?
Well, 70 percent is ocean and...
then there are lakes and...
And the rivers.
(PLAYING SOFT TUNE)
Oh.
Fuck.
I'm barely still here.
We're finished, aren't we?
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Tell me now about entanglement.
Einstein's spooky
action at a distance.
Is it related to quantum theory?
Mm.
No, I mean, it's not a
theory, it's proven.
How does it go again?
ADAM: When you separate
an entwined particle
and you move both parts
away from the other,
even at opposite ends
of the universe,
if you alter or affect one,
the other will be identically
altered or affected.
Spooky.
Even at opposite ends
of the universe?
Yeah.
EVE: Is that what we're thinking?
Adam, really.
So fucking 15th century.
They are deliciously beautiful,
though, aren't they?
ADAM:
What choice do we have, really?
We're just gonna turn
them, though, right?
How romantic of you.
I get the girl, though.
(♪♪♪)
(SPEAKS FRENCH)