(INHALES SHARPLY)
(CRUNCH)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(THUNDER CRACKING)
(COUGHING)
(WINCES)
(COUGHS)
(GASPS)
Wait! Come back!
Please!
Please help me!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Help me!
(SCREAMING)
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(SPINS REVOLVER CYLINDER)
(WOMAN TALKS INDISTINCTLY)
- WOMAN: We should help him.
- MAN 1: Not until we know what's going on.
WOMAN: Maybe
he has access.
MAN 2: There's a storm out there.
We don't know what's going on.
MAN 1:
He could be dangerous.
He's not the lot of us.
You don't know him.
We know nothing about him.
- WOMAN: Well, he has to eat...
- MAN 1: Yes, he can.
WOMAN: He'll die if we
don't get him out of there.
MAN 1: Not really my main
concern at the moment.
WOMAN: He has no food.
He has no water.
MAN 1: He's not one of us.
We have to take care
of us right now.
WOMAN: Wait...
- Drop your weapon.
- No.
- Drop your gun.
- Both of you, please don't.
He's here to kill us. I'm going
to blow your fucking head off.
Drop your gun.
I won't put it down.
You put yours down.
Do it.
Put your gun down.
Tell him to put his gun down.
- Tell him to put his gun down!
- Lukas, please!
Is this your house? Huh?
Whose house is this?
- You killed those people in the pit?
- Fuck you!
You killed those people.
Who are you?
Uh, I don't remember.
LUKAS: That's bullshit.
Who are you?
I woke up in a pit. Yeah, I
don't remember anything before.
She helped me, okay? This woman helped me.
I need to talk to her.
You let him out?
You stupid...
- Hey...
- Easy!
You know me?
Why'd you let me out?
I need...
(SCREAMING)
- Get you fucking hands off me!
- Sorry!
What's wrong with him?
Help me!
(CRIES IN AGONY)
Just breathe!
- Get your hands off me!
- What's wrong with him?
WOMAN: Just breathe!
Easy!
- Here, here, here.
- Look at me, you will be okay.
It's water.
(GASPING) Easy now.
Okay. Okay. All right.
What the hell is going on?
You people know each other?
(MAN GROANS)
You just need to breathe.
(BOTH GRUNT)
Breathe.
Hey, who are you, man?
I don't remember who I am.
None of us do.
(THUNDER CRASHING)
MICHAEL: Okay, we have
no phone and no computer.
There's no way to
contact the authorities.
All we have to go on is this.
WOMAN: So we know
our names.
I'm Sharon!
I... (STUTTERS) Michael.
You've met Lukas.
So this must be Nathan.
Nathan?
I'm Nathan.
I don't know my name.
I didn't have ID.
We also have keys.
I own a Nissan.
I have a key.
- LUKAS: You have cars?
- No.
There's no cars. I've looked
around outside. There's nothing.
Can you understand
what she's writing?
She's writing over and over again.
Can you read this?
What language is this?
- (STUTTERS) She can't understand you.
- Hey, she helped me, okay?
- Do you know me? Why did you help me?
- I've tried this...
MICHAEL: Stop trying!
You're freaking her out.
You know me, okay?
You helped me out of the pit. Don't
look at these fucking idiots.
MICHAEL: It doesn't matter what you
say to her, she can't understand.
- Hey, shut up!
- She doesn't understand you, okay?
- What, is she deaf?
- No! She's not deaf, all right?
She can hear you. She just
doesn't understand English.
She's mute.
But she acts like she knows us.
We all woke up in this house a
half hour before we found you,
and she was already here.
Anything else?
I'm Catholic, apparently.
And that's it?
Well, you also had a gun.
Yeah, you had a gun, too.
I didn't dig it up out of
a pile of dead people.
We're all in the same boat here.
No! We're not
in the same boat.
We were in the same boat. He was
in the boat with all the corpses!
I don't trust you.
I don't trust any of you.
Have you checked the house?
(CLANGING)
(KEYS JANGLING)
LUKAS: Yes.
We both have this.
Why? What happened?
What happened to us?
I know. What happened?
Hey, where is the girl?
I need to talk to the girl.
Guys, I need to
speak to the girl.
(JOHN TALKS INDISTINCTLY)
I need you to look
at something for me.
Look at this.
Did you do this?
Did you write this?
Yes. You wrote it. Okay.
What does it mean?
- MICHAEL: Hey, guys, come and look at this.
- What... Shit.
(SCOFFS) Well, we have
some ammunition.
Well, I suppose to kill so many
people you need a lot of bullets.
(GUN COCKING)
MICHAEL: What?
Maybe you're a cop.
I say we take some of these and go
and have a look around outside.
No. We load up and protect
ourselves in here.
We'll go in the morning.
Showers work.
We haven't found
any medical supplies.
You can use peroxide on that.
Or you're looking
at a serious infection.
Need me to help?
I'm okay.
Okay.
There's some clothes in the bedroom.
I'll get you some.
You don't need that anymore.
I prefer to hang on to it,
if you don't mind.
Suit yourself.
I'm okay, thanks.
I'm okay.
I am not okay.
(GRUNTS)
Who are you?
What's my name?
The 18th.
Remember.
(RUNNING FOOTSTEPS)
LUKAS:
Guys, the girl ran off.
There she is.
SHARON: Should we
follow her?
Shit!
Okay, gun guy,
you know all those weapons.
(COCKING GUN)
- Yes?
- (STUTTERS) Yes.
Right, stay with him and make
sure we don't lose the house.
Okay.
LUKAS: Where the fuck
is she?
SHARON: I don't know.
Maybe she's
leading us out of here.
Might be a city or something.
We're nowhere near a city.
How do you know?
That.
LUKAS:
What do you mean?
Stars are too bright.
We're miles from anywhere.
After you.
- Go.
- No, please. I insist.
Fuck off. Go.
SHARON: Will you two hurry up?
We're losing her.
(RAGGED BREATHING)
What's that smell?
Oh, my God!
Who would do this?
Someone likes to decorate.
Another one?
(GUN COCKS)
Look at this.
What is it?
It's Latin.
(SCOFFS)
I can read Latin.
Here, let me try.
No, nothing.
(SPEAKS LATIN)
Well, I mean, physically,
I can do stuff.
It's like my hands remember,
my body remembers.
My brain's a complete blank.
Do you know this place?
You know this house?
No.
But I know these books.
They're all medical,
biological reference books.
I mean, from different countries,
different periods in history.
They all relate to human
and animal anatomy.
Wait a second.
What is it?
- Oh, my God.
- What?
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
What?
I can speak French.
(SCOFFS)
I think this is your house.
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
(COCKS GUN)
(SQUELCHING)
LUKAS: Whoa!
(SHARON GASPS)
SHARON:
Oh, my God.
(FLIES BUZZING)
LUKAS: She's feeding
her like a baby.
(CLATTERING)
Fuck me!
(WOMAN SNARLING)
You used me!
LUKAS: Jesus!
She knows you.
I'm telling you, Sharon,
I don't trust him.
(SCREAMING)
I have a daughter!
Someone is watching us.
What?
SHARON: I'm not just
leaving her in there.
JOHN: We have to. She was
tied up for a reason.
SHARON: It is inhumane.
She attacked you! Did you forget this?
She's a crazy woman.
You're unbelievable.
Listen...
(SIGHS) What?
There was a camera in the shack!
We need to find
the monitoring center.
Only building we've seen
so far is the house.
(NATHAN SPEAKING ITALIAN)
It's Italian.
It means, "A man with a lot of
keys has a lot of things to hide."
(SIGHS)
Turns out, I know
a few languages.
- Congratulations.
- Hmm.
Try this...
(BOTH SPEAKING LATIN)
(SIGHS)
That's crazy.
We both know Latin?
You know, I have the strongest
feeling I know you.
Really?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, I feel like
I know Sharon, too.
I mean, not as familiar as I feel
with you, but it's there with her.
I keep thinking
maybe she's my girlfriend.
Or my sister.
She could be my sister, and
that would be pretty gross.
You think she like me?
(STUTTERS) I don't
have time for this, okay?
I got to get this door open.
I gotta try to find some tools,
like a crowbar or something,
get it in there and just
try and pry it open.
You're not going to pry
that open with a crowbar.
How do you know?
You haven't even tried.
No. That's a reinforced
iron door.
You're not going to get it
opened with a crowbar.
What about your keys?
Where'd you get
those keys, John Doe?
I found them.
Where'd you find them?
Downstairs, in the living room,
with all the books
that you can read.
Someone's in here, Nathan?
Listen...
I'm not trying to make
an enemy here, okay?
It's just, uh... We can't
bash the door in now.
Everybody's trying to sleep.
It's been a long night.
I think you should get
a couple hours of rest.
All of your...
(THUMPS ON DOOR)
Locked doors will still
be here when you wake up.
(SNICKERS)
LUKAS: We need to
find the cars.
I think he's got a point.
No, you think he's got a point,
but I wasn't here when you guys had
the meeting that made him boss, okay?
This time, no, or
I'm going with you.
You need me.
Why?
'Cause I'm the best shot.
How do we know?
SHARON:
Jesus Christ, Michael!
NATHAN: What the hell?
How about that?
You know now?
You stay here
and guard the house.
Why won't they listen to me?
Because of what you just did.
(ANIMAL SCREECHING)
JOHN: Is he dead?
LUKAS: I hope so.
(FLIES BUZZING)
This fence must run the
whole way around the house.
Oh, that smell!
I can't handle it.
(RETCHES)
Lukas?
(LUKAS COUGHS)
JOHN: Somebody's put them
up all around the house.
Maybe it's a warning.
JOHN: It's the same
as the last night.
Why won't they listen to me?
You know,
I could've helped them.
It's my job.
(STAMMERS) It's my job.
Why would I have this?
And who are you to me?
You...
My wife? Girlfriend?
If I knew what was going on...
Because, I'm not like the others.
They're all smart!
But I'm... I'm here
to do something.
How do we know one another?
My quiet girl.
This thing between us, it's...
It's important.
I know it.
(DISTANT SCREAM)
Get in the house.
Get inside, now! Now!
Just move! Go!
Go inside.
Okay, now you go in, and you
lock the door. Close it!
Now!
What do you think?
Which way?
(DISTANT SCREAM)
(SCREAMING)
Really?
You're throwing rocks?
(ROCK CLANGING)
(LUKAS COCKS GUN)
Well, we have cars.
(MAN WAILING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
MAN: Please!
Please, help!
Help!
Please!
(GROANS IN AGONY)
(WHIMPERING)
Please...
Please help!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Okay. Okay.
(SHUSHES)
- (SCREAMING) Please help!
- Jesus!
Help.
- Ahhh!
- Okay, okay, okay. Okay? Okay?
(CRYING) Shh...
Easy. We're gonna
work on this.
Please...
(CHUCKLING)
Ahhh!
(LAUGHING)
(GROANING)
Ahhh!
(LAUGHING)
(GROANS)
(YELLING)
(CRYING)
Please. Help me...
(ENGINE SPUTTERING) Come on!
(ENGINE STARTING)
(CHUCKLES)
It's got a quarter tank.
NATHAN: Battery is dead here.
Look if there's fuel inside.
Yeah, it's okay, Nate.
We can push start it.
Nate.
(RADIO STATIC)
(RADIO SQUEALING)
(RADIO STOPS)
What's the matter?
(LUKAS SIGHS)
Headache. Nothing.
Okay, this is low on gas,
but I think we should just try and drive
out of here and see what we can find.
LUKAS: There's no we.
JOHN: What?
You're not with us.
I could be the one
taking the photo?
Guys, we need to get help.
We're not near anything.
We'll end up without fuel in
the middle of fucking nowhere.
Let's get back to the house,
figure out what's going on.
He's got a point.
Sharon...
Guys!
(PANTING) Michael!
SHARON: Jesus.
(COUGHING)
Help me move him!
(SHARON STRAINING)
JOHN: Okay. There we go.
- SHARON: We got to support his head. Jesus!
- JOHN: I got him.
SHARON: (WHISPERING)
Jesus... Oh, my God...
We need to stop the blood.
(SHARON PANTING)
Fuck...
Michael, I need you
to look at me.
Michael. Michael...
- Michael, breathe! Michael!
- JOHN: Sharon...
Come on, Michael.
Michael.
Michael!
Jesus!
(SIGHING) We...
We were in the hospital.
We could have...
- I just need...
- Ahhh!
(MAN GRUNTING)
(MAN PANTING)
JOHN: Leave him here.
Don't touch the body.
- LUKAS: What's wrong with you?
- NATHAN: John!
John, no.
We're going to bury him, right?
I mean...
You're not just gonna
leave him lying there
like the sicko
tying people to trees...
It's Michael.
We're gonna bury him.
JOHN: Look, something is happening
on the 18th. That is tomorrow.
- We don't have time. I'm going to the...
- Wait.
- SHARON: I think we should all stick together.
- JOHN: Yeah.
- To be honest, I'm not sure we're safe.
- LUKAS: Neither am I.
SHARON: Lukas...
Nathan, come on.
- We need to stick together.
- I'd rather take you across.
JOHN: Nathan,
can I have your keys?
I can push start your car.
Can I please have your keys?
Thank you.
- SHARON: I will go.
- LUKAS: What?
SHARON: No-one
should go alone.
Okay, come on.
Come on, please. Come
on, you piece of crap.
JOHN: Come on, now.
Sweat it out there.
Okay, now!
(ENGINE STARTING) Here we go.
Okay, stop. Stop!
(CAR RATTLING)
Hey...
Up there on the left.
JOHN: (ECHOING) Hello.
SHARON: It's too quiet.
(FLIES BUZZING)
JOHN: This is empty.
SHARON:
Yeah. These, too.
- Did you see that?
- No.
What?
- There was a kid.
- Where?
Hello?
Hello!
(ECHOING) Hello.
God damn it.
There's no one.
(THUDDING)
(SOFTLY) Sharon!
What's your name?
Come and open the door.
Do you...
Do you recognize me?
Here. Come here.
Do you recognize this lady?
Go away, Jonah!
They're coming tomorrow!
- No.
- No, no. Come back.
- SHARON: Please... No.
- No. He knows me.
(STUTTERING) He called me Jonah.
NATHAN: All these languages,
and not one of them yours.
(SNIFFLES)
Hey...
You okay?
Hey! Let me help you.
MAN: (GASPING)
Get away from me.
(GRUNTING)
What's wrong?
MAN: No! Please don't!
(SCREAMING) (METAL CLANGING)
(PANTING) My head...
I know you.
Hey, Lukas...
NATHAN: Lukas, stop it. You're...
Lukas, get off her!
Lukas, stop it!
Stop it!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
NATHAN: Okay.
Okay, relax.
(SCREAMS)
NATHAN: Lukas! Stop it!
NATHAN: Are you okay?
(SHUDDERING)
Are you okay now?
LUKAS: I'm okay.
I'm okay.
I can hear him, Sharon.
He's still in there.
(GROWLING)
(BARKING) Fuck!
Hey! Call your dog off!
- It's okay.
- I'm not kidding around now, buddy.
- Call the dog off!
- I'm gonna set my dog on you!
- Get out of here!
- Don't test me! Don't fucking test me!
- Just... Just open the door first.
- JOHN: Okay, that's it!
- BOY: Go away!
- What are you doing?
- Stand back!
- Stop it!
- He knows me!
- Jesus!
BOY: Leave us alone, Jonah.
That is not gonna help!
- You get out of there...
- Stop it!
- You're scaring him!
- Stay out of this!
- Stop it!
- Stay out of it.
- Hey!
For fuck's sake, this isn't helping!
Please!
This is not gonna help!
- Stand back!
- SHARON: Jesus!
(GUNSHOT)
- Come on, open it?
- My dog will kill you!
BOY: Run and hide!
Run and hide!
Please, please. We just
need some answers, okay?
Please, please.
He's so loud.
Fucking stop it!
Out of the way, Sharon.
(CLANKING)
(SHRIEKING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
Stop! What the fuck
are you doing?
I'm going to cut
the fucking door.
It's a child!
He knows me.
He knows my name.
I don't even know my name.
This isn't you, John.
You'll be okay.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
NATHAN: Okay, symptoms...
Headache, nausea...
Hyperventilating...
Delirious...
Violent.
It's... You think that...
Wish I could
speak your language.
(GASPING)
Okay, uh...
There was a woman.
She was tied up.
She was blind in one eye.
She had a bad eye.
The one you were feeding.
They told me about it.
Yeah?
(BREATHING HEAVILY) Hey.
I need your help.
Please help me.
I know this place.
She escaped.
I think there's a path
around the lake.
(SNIFFLES)
(NATHAN PANTING)
Well, I need to know
where it leads.
I'm going.
NATHAN: My name...
Is Nathan. Nathan.
Nathan's my name.
Remember.
(RUSTLING)
Nate.
You can call me Nate.
Tree...
Cracked by lightning.
Two trees,
either side of the path.
And then...
Tree trunk.
(FLIES BUZZING)
(CRUNCHING)
- MAN 1: I'm irresponsible?
- WOMAN: Yes!
MAN: This whole thing
is your fault.
MAN 1: I don't need
a fucking baby sitter.
WOMAN: Okay, stop it,
you two! Stop it!
MAN 1: Oh, it's my fault? It's not
my fucking fault! I didn't do this!
I didn't do any of this.
MAN 2: God, forgive me.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
MAN 1: He's too heavy.
Hold him tight.
Come on, help me, Nathan!
Nathan, tie his legs up.
NATHAN:
They're not animals.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(MAN SCREAMING)
This is inhumane.
You...
(RUNNING FOOTSTEPS)
Don't leave me alone.
Please!
I'm not going to hurt you.
Don't leave me alone.
I know I can trust you.
You can trust me.
(DOOR LATCH CLICKING)
(DOOR RATTLING)
LUKAS: Let me in.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
I remember you smiling at me.
I remember you.
(STAIRS CREAKING)
(DOOR BANGING)
LUKAS: Let me in!
(SOFTLY) I remember you.
LUKAS: I'm not
going to hurt you.
(WOOD CREAKING)
(RUSTLING)
(CLATTERING)
(COMPUTER WHIRRING)
(WOMAN WHIMPERING)
(GASPS)
(WOMAN CRYING)
Helen.
(GROWLS)
Your name is Helen.
NATHAN: I'm sorry
about your daughter.
We wanted to help...
(SHRIEKING)
(MAN SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
WOMAN: Ahhh!
(CAMCORDER BEEPS)
JOHN: Day 96,
this is subject 143,
who I captured in the woods.
He's the first positive
result that I've had,
and, uh, he's responding
to the injection, I believe.
It proves that
I'm onto something.
And then, uh,
one unfortunate side-effect
is a period of unconsciousness
followed by acute memory loss.
(CHUCKLING) But he doesn't
remember anything.
(FAST-FORWARDING)
...two stages that he's going through.
The first stage
is the rest cycle.
He looks calm...
Almost dead.
His heartbeat decreases
to 30 beats per minute.
I don't know why
it's wearing off so quickly.
I just...
I need it to hold.
I need it to hold! Why is he not
responding? It should work!
This should work!
I'm trying everything!
Her blood should be...
(FAST-FORWARDING)
- (SCREAMING) Please! Please stop!
- JOHN: Now you can see...
He looks like he's suffering
from extreme headaches.
He's got extreme strength.
(CAMCORDER BEEPS)
Do you remember your family?
I can't remember my mother.
Who doesn't remember
their own mother?
I know that I know you.
I feel like I know you.
Sometimes, I, uh...
I feel like I might have...
Done some things
that I wasn't proud of...
That I might not like
the man I was, you know?
Watch out!
(CRASHING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(PANTING)
Where the hell
did that come from?
What's that sound?
(TAPPING)
Be careful. I got a bad
feeling about this.
- No, I don't...
- Excuse me!
I don't like it.
(MAN GRUNTS)
- Excuse me!
- No! Shh.
Let's go.
(MAN SCREAMING)
Okay, maybe you were right.
Shit!
(PANTING) Come on!
Sharon!
Come on!
Get in the car!
Go! Go!
Oh, my God, come on!
- John, come on! Come on, let's go.
- JOHN: Fuck!
JOHN: Put it in reverse!
Put it in reverse!
Come on!
(MEN SCREAMING)
They're right on me!
SHARON: What...
What?
(PANTING)
JOHN: They don't like
the smell or something.
(CHUCKLING)
JOHN:
They are deterrents.
Someone hung them up on purpose.
SHARON: They're being
used like scarecrows.
Be careful.
You're a sick fuck.
I knew it was you.
Lukas, put your fucking gun down, man.
You're losing your mind.
What did you do to me?
- Who are you!
- JOHN: What are you talking about, man?
Lukas, what are you doing?
(PANTING) It's him, Sharon.
It's all in here.
I told you you shouldn't
have let him out.
He was doing experiments
on us or something.
LUKAS: He had us
all in prison.
He's a murderer.
John...
What's he talking about?
What's on the tape?
I... I don't know.
I can't remember.
I was trying to tell you
before in the car...
JOHN: I've been having
some memories.
Bad memories of doing
really bad things.
For fuck's sake, Sharon,
can you trust me, please?
I wanted to tell you.
I just didn't know how.
I thought you knew me.
And like I knew you.
- LUKAS: Sharon...
- Please, I was hoping...
Maybe I was somebody
else because I knew you.
- Please...
- LUKAS: You stand back.
(GUN COCKS)
I just... Okay.
You don't fucking move or I'll
shoot you where you're standing
and hang you from
the next fucking tree.
Watch it.
Come on, Sharon, watch it.
Have a look.
(CAMCORDER BEEPS)
(MAN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
JOHN: (ON CAMCORDER) I'm trying everything.
This should work.
What is it, Sharon?
WOMAN: (ON CAMCORDER)
Please. Please, stop.
What's on the tape?
(MAN SCREAMING ON CAMCORDER)
I have needle marks on my arm.
See?
I bet you have them, too.
Was that...
Is that from me?
- Lukas, god damn it!
- You shut the fuck up!
Okay.
I don't remember that.
Did I do that?
Lukas, did I do this to her?
I got to kill him.
I just wanna know what I did, okay?
I'm not sure.
I remember pieces, but I don't...
Lukas, please listen.
JOHN: Okay, I will turn around,
and I wouldn't hurt you.
- No.
- Sharon, please don't let him...
(LUKAS STRAINING)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
You crawl!
Get into the pit with all your
victims, you twisted fuck!
No, not in there, man.
Come on!
Go!
(GUNSHOT)
Okay, okay!
Okay, I'm going.
I'm going. I'm going.
(THUDDING)
(GROANS)
(COUGHS)
Lukas!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Take it yourself.
(SHUDDERING)
LUKAS: Who are you?
Did you get blood in your mouth?
(COUGHING)
(DOOR BANGS)
We trying, okay?
We trying.
We'll pack up and get
fuck out of this place.
(GUN CLICKING)
Your key.
Give me the key.
Give me the keys.
I'll go and get your car.
What about Nathan?
- Does he know?
- Who?
Nathan.
No... No.
The one in the pit
is the one who did this.
It's... It's... John.
(CLATTERING)
Lukas.
You okay?
No, I'm not okay.
I'm all fucked up
because of your Nazi boyfriend
doing experiments on me.
Lukas.
You need to sit down.
You don't look well.
No, no, no.
You're safe with me.
No, you're safe now.
Do you hear me?
You're safe with me. Okay?
I'll take care
of you. Okay?
- Lukas...
- I...
You're scaring me, okay...
I'll take care of you, too.
(WOMEN BREATHING HEAVILY)
You're safe with me.
They tried to take you away
from me, but you're safe now.
Lukas, please.
You're ill.
You're sick.
I'm okay.
- Lukas...
- Don't touch her!
She can't hurt you.
I will protect you!
Remember.
Wait!
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
Look at me!
You must remember me.
You know me.
You know me!
(WHISPERS) Beautiful girl.
Get off her!
(BOTH GASPING)
LUKAS: No!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(THUDDING)
(COUGHING)
(FLIES BUZZING)
Ugh!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MUTTERS)
(GRUNTS)
Tomorrow's the 18th.
There's no time left.
Yeah, the kid knew me.
We need to get back
to that building.
You need to stay away from me.
It may not be safe
to be around me.
(SIGHS) I need the answers.
Get in that house!
Go!
(SHARON GASPING)
Jonah.
Hello? (ECHOING)
JOHN: Please be
careful with this.
This is our last chance.
We only have a couple of days.
"Last chance."
Last chance for what?
(SIGHS) The 18th.
Come on, man, think!
What happens on the 18th?
(SIGHS)
You have to follow
the main road.
(CLATTERING)
They'll meet you there.
Do not stop for any...
Where the fuck were you going?
God damn it!
Who were you meeting?
Come on, man!
You have to follow
the main road.
Fuck!
(WOMAN GROANING)
What the fuck is going on?
(ROARING)
JOHN: Shit!
I'm not gonna hurt you.
I just need to get them.
(SCREAMS)
I...
Fuck.
Just give them to me.
Give it to me, you crazy bitch.
No, no. No.
(SWALLOWING)
You gotta be kidding me.
(ROARS) What the fuck! Get back!
(GUNSHOT)
(WOMAN WAILING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Mamma!
- You!
- Hey.
Do you know me?
'Cause that kid knows me.
You are one of them.
You stay away from my family!
No more needles!
JOHN: Is this
your daughter?
You hurt us all, Jonah!
I'll leave you alive
because I'm not like you.
- Run and hide.
- What?
What do you mean?
Wait. Hang on, hang on!
Listen! Wait, wait, wait!
Listen, please! Just hang on!
I just wanna talk to you!
Please, just tell me!
What did I do?
Please, I just wanna
talk to you!
Where are you going?
JOHN: Overgrown brain.
Possible reason
for the headaches.
White matter decomposing.
The army will meet you there.
They know what to do with it.
The army.
What does the military
have to do to with it?
Jonah Cooke.
Sharon?
Look, it's John! John!
Oh, shit!
(PANTING)
Lukas.
Jesus, Lukas, you're sick.
No!
JONAH: Shh! You should
calm down, man.
This will help you.
I was helping you.
Go away.
Lukas, I was helping you!
I was helping all of you.
(SCREAMS)
Lukas. Lukas.
I'm remembering things.
My name...is...is Jonah.
Do you remember me?
I'm a doctor.
(SCREAMS) You've been infected?
I need to inject you with this.
This can help you.
Look at me.
You remember me?
Look at me. Look at me.
Look at me, buddy.
Give your arm.
I was just trying to help you.
The dose has worn off.
I need to...
No, don't! Come on!
(SCREAMS)
Lukas!
(GRUNTING) Oh, fuck!
Look, Lukas...
(YELLING) Look at me, Lukas!
(GASPING)
Lukas, come on.
Lukas. Lukas.
Look at me. Look at me.
Stay with me.
Stay with me. Come on!
I...
have hell in my head
and I cannot run away from it.
I know you.
Do you know me?
Yeah. Yeah, I know you, too, man.
Come on.
I know you.
Look at me.
LUKAS: I just want to
say thank you, Jonah,
and to all of you
for saving my life.
And also, you gave me
my memory back.
I... I've really
missed them.
Well, most of them.
To memories?
- JONAH: To memories.
- ALL: To memories.
(SCREAMING) MAN: Oh, shit!
Watch out!
(SCREAMING)
(GUNSHOT)
(JONAH PANTING)
How did she get out, Nathan?
Nathan, did you lock up?
(STARTS CAR ENGINE)
Michael, go check
the other cells. Be careful!
They haven't all been treated.
Yeah?
Why am I here, Jonah?
Why am I here?
You're gonna play
big brother now?
(SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
- Stop it!
- It's not my fault?
It's not my fucking fault!
I didn't do this!
I didn't do any of this!
Help me take her into the pit.
Take her yourself.
(SCREAMING IN DISTANCE)
Jonah.
(FLIES BUZZING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
NATHAN: Jonah!
Jonah!
Sharon.
It's me.
(WHISPERS) I remember.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING) Oh, my God.
- SHARON: Nathan!
- NATHAN: I'll lock it up!
Help me block the door!
(SCREAMING)
Come on. Come on, Sharon.
Remember.
MICHAEL: Jesus,
we can't find the woman.
Do you copy?
Do you read?
They're everywhere!
They're out of control!
In the streets.
Do you copy...
JONAH: Michael, gather the group up
in the house and inject yourselves!
SHARON: That's crazy. It's not finished!
We didn't test it!
JOHN: Sharon? Sharon, listen!
There's no time!
You have to inject yourself...
(SCREAMING)
(JOHN SCREAMING)
Oh, shit! (GASPING)
I'm fucking bit!
We're not going to remember.
Oh...
(WEAKLY) My name is Jonah Cooke.
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on, come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on.
Okay. Fuck.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(MAN SCREAMING) Oh, shit!
- Did you see that?
- Yeah.
Okay, okay, okay.
Where are they coming from?
The scarecrows didn't stop them.
Oh, my God.
They're everywhere.
(SPINS REVOLVER CYLINDER)
- They're...
- Something is wrong!
Here we go.
Oh, my God!
(CLICKING) Fuck!
- Shit!
- I have to tell Jonah.
Jesus!
Just in case
he doesn't remember.
Just in case we don't make it.
Okay.
JONAH: We were
here to help.
But we failed.
The plague spread.
Sharon... Sharon, please remember.
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
We need to leave here.
We're out of time.
They're coming.
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
(BULLETS WHIZZING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
The 18th.
Eighteenth.
The rescue party.
They're coming on the 18th,
the dawn of the 18th.
The 18th. We're...
Hey! Hey, don't shoot!
- Wait.
- We're... We're saved!
- Uh, no.
- It's over.
Sharon, it's over. Hey!
We're alive in here!
I'll go get them. I'll go get them.
Hey! Hey! (ECHOING)
Hey, it's okay!
Hey, we're alive in here!
Don't shoot!
Sharon, come on!
Come on!
Hey, we're alive!
Hello?
Sharon?
Hello!
Sharon!
Is there anybody there?
MAN: (ON RADIO)
Standing by for orders.
No survivors.
You were supposed to rescue us.
Please.
No, wait.
(GUNSHOT)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MOUTHING)
Please! Please!
I'm so sorry.
- I'm so sorry.
- I remember.
I remember, Sharon.
That was my brother.
I'm sorry.
(SHUSHING)
(FOOTSTEPS OVERHEAD)
(WOMAN BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WOMAN MUTTERING)
SHARON: Wait. Wait.
We need her. (GRUNTS)
Sharon?
(SCREAMING)
(COCKS GUN)
(SHARON GROANS)
Oh! Oh, God!
You okay?
Did she get you?
Fuck! Come on!
Here, here!
Put this on.
Put this on. All done!
Come on! Come on. The soldiers are coming.
We need to hide.
Come on.
Hurry up. They're coming!
Come on, we gotta hide.
Come on! Come on!
(SCREAMS)
You're okay.
(GRUNTING)
(COUGHING)
Come on! Come on!
Oh, shit! Shit!
Shit! Shit!
Hang on.
Hang on. I have to
stop the bleeding!
Look at me.
They won't find us.
Look at me, okay?
(GROANS)
- Okay. Come on, give me your arm.
- Jonah.
Give me your arm.
Come on.
We're just gonna hide.
And we'll pretend we're dead.
We're gonna wake up, okay?
Oh, Jonah, listen to me...
What's this?
You have to read this, Jonah.
You can't forget. Please.
This time,
you have to do it right.
Please. For me.
You better stay with me.
Listen to me, okay?
You are Jonah.
Don't forget, please.
I love you.
I'll never forget you again.
I love you. You just
get some sleep, okay?
Just go with me.
I'm scared.
- I don't wanna die.
- You won't die.
You won't die. Come on, sweetie.
I won't forget you.
You feel this?
My name is Jonah.
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
SHARON: My love,
I remembered everything.
We were doctors on the
verge of finding a cure
for an awful plague that has
cast the world into darkness.
(ECHOING) Help me!
Please help me!
SHARON: The mute woman
is the answer.
He blood is immune to the virus.
You must protect her.
You will find death
and madness everywhere.
But you'll have to fight
to finish what we started.
We have no time, Jonah.
There are still people
waiting to be saved.
I know your memory
will come back soon.
When it does,
remember I love you.