- I don't know if I wanna do this.
- Relax, Laine, it's fun.
First, the rules.
You can never, ever play alone.
You can never play in a graveyard.
And you always have to say goodbye.
To start, you circle the board
once for each player.
Then we say, "As friends we gather,
hearts are true."
"As friends we gather, hearts are true."
"Spirits near, we call to you."
Is someone here with us?
Debbie, cut it out!
If a ghost is here, you can see them
through the planchette.
It's the eye to the other side.
If someone is here with us,
make yourself known.
(SCREAMS)
What are you guys doing?
Get out of here, Sarah!
Calm down. It's only a game.
(WIND HOWLING)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Goodbye.
(FLAMES CRACKLING)
- (SIGHS)
- (CELL PHONE RINGING)
- (CELL PHONE BEEPS)
- (INHALES)
- Laine, hey.
- LAINE: Deb. Where are you?
I'm here. I've been here.
It's just been a little rough this week.
You've gotta tell me what's been going on.
And don't think you're bailing on me again.
- We're gonna be late for the game.
- Ugh. Oh, yeah.
You know, I don't think I'm coming.
Oh, well. I'm not leaving
until I get to talk to you.
Fine.
I'll be right out, just give me a sec.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
LAINE: What's going on?
- Are you sick?
- No.
- Did you and Pete have a fight?
- No, nothing like that.
Then what is it?
- Nothing.
- Debbie, tell me.
I just don't wanna go out tonight.
No secrets between us, remember?
Remember that game we used to play,
where you ask questions about the future?
- The Ouija board.
- Yeah.
A couple of weeks ago, I played it.
Just messing around and...
(SIGHS)
I don't know. I don't know.
That is just a game.
You know you've always
been like this, right?
- Like what?
- Just a total and complete spaz.
(CHUCKLES)
You're right, I'm being crazy.
Look, I don't even have to go to the
basketball game. We always lose.
- I'm just gonna come in with you...
- No, don't.
I mean, my folks are gonna
be home any minute,
and I'm just being dramatic,
and everything is fine.
Are you sure you don't wanna come?
I have leftovers inside,
I'm gonna rock it out,
but I will see you in the morning,
that's for sure.
- Okay. Do you want me to order for you?
- Mmm-hmm.
- Pancakes with the works?
Okay.
- I miss you.
- I miss you already.
(MICROWAVE BEEPS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(GULPS)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
No.
(GASPS)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
TREVOR: Laine, hey. Sorry I'm late.
I have a surprise for you.
Check this out.
Oh, you have a map. (CHUCKLES)
Yep. This is the place
I was telling you about.
It's up the coast, away from everyone.
- We can make camp right about here.
- Yeah.
Hike down to the beach anytime we want.
It's the first time
I'm hearing it as "we."
I want you to come with.
But I thought this was your
big camping trip with the guys.
I know, but I started thinking about it
and I realized I'd miss you too much.
(SCOFFS)
Okay, so you're surfing all day.
What do I do?
I'm gonna teach you. By the end of
the week, you'll be one with the waves.
- It's gonna be awesome.
- Oh, my God, no.
- I promise. Come on.
- Mmm-mmm.
You can forget about the world
for a while, leave it all behind.
I can't wait to see you
run this past my dad.
I got that covered, too. Tell him
it's the senior trip. Fully chaperoned.
- Good luck with that.
- What? I can be persuasive.
- Really?
- Yeah. I've been told this.
- By who?
- You. Every day.
ISABELLE:
Okay, very cute. Break it up, you two.
- TREVOR: Hello.
- Hey.
Hey, Iz. Little more bean juice.
Uh-huh.
Where's Debbie?
- Oh, I think she's running late.
- Mmm.
So, what time are we hitting
that party tonight?
- I think we're passing.
- Yeah. We might watch a movie or something.
- No, come on, you guys can't.
- Yeah.
Laine's making you bail on me.
You're a big girl, Iz.
There's nothing wrong with flying solo.
Yeah, me showing up alone,
that's not really a good look for me.
(CHUCKLES)
- Not everybody has, you know, this.
- What's this?
Your perfect couple situation.
Look at her acting like
she's not the one
who breaks up with every guy
she goes out with.
- I can't help it, I'm a picky bitch.
- (CHUCKLES)
- LAINE: God!
- (CELL PHONE CHIMES)
What's up?
I gotta go. It's my dad.
Let me guess, your sister?
Yep. Causing chaos wherever she goes.
I'm sorry, guys. Come on.
- What's going on?
- I'm so sorry.
Nona wanted to be here for you.
Laine, sit down. We need to talk.
I don't wanna sit down.
Just tell me what's going on.
Laine, sit down.
I don't wanna sit down!
Someone tell me what's going on!
It's about Debbie.
LAINE: Nona, can I talk to you?
NONA: Uh-huh.
I don't think I can go in.
This doesn't seem real.
(STAMMERING) She should still be here.
She's still here.
She's right here.
Here.
I just don't understand.
None of us can.
She told me that she'd
see us the next morning.
Why would she say
that if she was going to...
We'll never know.
I wish she would have talked to us
about whatever it was.
I know what the police say,
but I can't believe she'd ever...
(SNIFFLES)
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
And that Carol found her like that,
it's just horrible.
They're packed and coming
to stay with me.
Can't be in this house another night.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Pete.
Laine.
- I'm so sorry.
- I'm sorry, too.
(SIGHS)
I brought flowers.
Debbie liked this kind.
They're really pretty. Do you
want me to put them in some water?
No. I'll find her mom.
I should give them to her.
(INHALES DEEPLY)
(SNIFFLES)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CREAKS)
Laine. (SIGHS)
- You were everything to her.
- Mrs. G.
(MUMBLES)
I'm sorry. I just...
I just wanted to be in her room.
- It's okay.
- (SOBBING)
(INHALES SHARPLY)
- The hours you two spent in here.
- (SIGHS)
Hmm.
And by fifth grade,
you'd picked out your college.
(MUMBLES)
(SNIFFLES)
She used to draw pictures of...
of what our dorms would look like.
(CHUCKLING) Everything was purple.
MRS. G: Yeah, I remember that.
Her purple phase.
Thank you for watching
the house while we're gone.
I don't know when we'll be back.
Here.
I put these things together for you.
She'd want you to have them.
Always remember her.
DEBBIE: (ON CAMERA) No, that's it,
that's the one. Look! (LAUGHS)
Let me see your bootyshake!
- See? It's good!
- (KNOCK ON DOOR)
SALESWOMAN: Ladies, I need you
to keep it down in there.
We do have other customers.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
We were a lot cooler than
we're making this seem.
LAINE: Right. Pete says,
"How are you gonna dance?"
- MRS. G: Look at my girls!
- DEBBIE: I'm glad I have it now!
- LAINE: Oh, my God, I need to see you.
- MRS. G: I'm gonna cry!
- Aw, my girls! Look at you!
- Jeez.
- You need to pull that up a little.
- Booty-tooch.
- Oh, I'm sorry.
- Oh, my God!
DEBBIE:
Why are you always pulling up my dress?
Whether or not you have
any sort of affection inside of you
- that you want to give to your boyfriend...
- (GASPS)
- You don't think I have any affection?
- I mean, right now, I don't know.
You're gonna love me for doing that.
- Mmm, why?
- (CAMERA BEEPS)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(HORN HONKING)
(CAR HALTS)
(SIGHS)
Really, Sarah?
After everything that happened today,
you have to do this?
- Do what?
- Sneak out.
Make things so hard, all the time.
Look, I just wanna get out of here
and forget this shitty day, all right?
Oh, I'm sorry,
but you're not going anywhere.
Mom is not around.
She hasn't been for a while.
And you don't need to be her, okay?
It's not your job to
hover over me all the time.
I wish I didn't have to.
Well, then just don't care so much.
It's way easier.
- Okay, Dad, here's your flight confirmation.
- Ah...
Once the permits get approved,
I'll be back.
- It might be a few days, though. Okay?
- Okay.
Nona knows I'm leaving,
so call her if you need anything.
Yeah, I got it covered, Dad.
Don't worry. Bye.
Have a safe trip.
(SIGHS)
I'll text you when I get there.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
We have class in a half hour.
How long is this gonna take?
Um, Mrs. G just wants me to check
a few things. So, two minutes.
Sure.
Oh, and can you go around back
and check the pool cover?
Yeah, I got it.
(GRUNTING)
- (SCRAPING)
- (THUDDING)
Hello?
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(SIGHS)
(GRUNTS)
- Hey.
- (GASPS) Oh, my God.
- It's me. Are you ready to go?
- (CHUCKLES)
I didn't even hear you come up.
TREVOR: What is that?
Just something Debbie and I
used to do ages ago.
- It was a joke, right?
- We pretended it was real.
We asked it questions like,
"Do I have a secret admirer?"
"Will we be friends forever?"
- (SNICKERS)
- Things like that.
And one of you was just pushing it?
LAINE: Yes.
I didn't know she had one.
I have so many questions.
If I had just stayed. I was right here.
If I hadn't have left her, you know...
Laine,
it's not your fault.
You just don't know when it's gonna be
the last time you get to talk to someone.
I never even got to say goodbye.
I know.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Pete.
- Hey.
Can you talk?
Yeah, sure.
Okay.
I haven't gotten a chance
to check in with you yet.
Are you doing okay?
I guess.
I can't bring myself
to erase her voicemails.
I keep listening to them
and it's like she's here, you know?
Leaving me messages, making plans.
- (SIGHS)
- Before Debbie died,
did you notice anything
going on with her?
Like what?
Acting different.
(SIGHS) Yeah, she seemed worried
about something.
Did she ever say what it was?
(SIGHS)
It just kind of started out of nowhere.
I didn't know what was going on.
I'd text her, she'd blow me off.
I thought maybe she wanted to
break up with me or something.
A few days ago, I went to
her house to try to talk to her.
- She didn't even want me to come inside.
- She did the same thing with me.
- Why are you asking me all this?
- I guess I'm just not ready to let her go.
Neither am I.
I don't know. When I'm in the house,
it just feels strange.
- You miss Debbie. We all do.
- No, this is different.
I can't explain it. (STAMMERING)
It's like she's there.
Laine, listen.
Everyone's still in shock, okay?
But those things you were telling me
the other day about feeling guilty,
you don't have to keep
doing this to yourself.
Do you ever feel like even after
someone you love has died,
there's still a way
you can talk to them?
But you can't do that. She's gone.
The board. Isn't that what
you're supposed to do with it?
Yesterday, you said it was just a game.
If we play the game and nothing happens,
then I'll never bring it up again.
But I really wanna try,
so will you guys just do this with me?
Sarah?
- I'm heading out. I'll be an hour.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
Sarah!
- Yeah?
- I'm going out. I'll be back in a bit.
Hour. Yeah, cool. Got it.
- LAINE: Hey! Get out of here!
- (SCOFFS)
(TIRES SQUEAL)
What the hell, Laine?
For a minute there,
I actually had a little faith in you.
- We hang out. What's wrong with that?
- What's wrong with that is that you're a kid
- and that guy is too old for you!
- (SCOFFS)
All right. Since you can't be left alone,
you're coming with me.
- I'm not going anywhere.
- Get your stuff. I'll be in the car.
(GATE CREAKS)
(DOOR CREAKING)
I don't wanna be in this house.
It feels wrong.
Look, this is where Debbie died.
We have to play here.
It's okay.
We're all together.
So, where are we gonna do this?
LAINE: In there.
I'm gonna go and get the board.
(EXHALES)
How are you even supposed to talk
to someone using a board game?
I mean, like, "Yo, can you hear me?
"Signal's real bad.
I only got, like, one bar in here."
Your sister wants to do this.
So, just zip it and go along.
Hmm.
- Oh, my God!
- SARAH: Jesus!
- Pete.
- It's okay.
It's just me. I heard you
come in through the front.
What the hell are you doing, man?
I have a spare key for the back.
I come in that way all the time.
(EXHALES)
- So, let's play.
- LAINE: Wait.
There's a few rules first.
Like, you're never supposed
to play in a graveyard,
never play alone,
and always say goodbye.
Can we just do this? (SIGHS)
(SIGHS)
I don't even think
I believe in these things,
but I still don't wanna touch it.
Come on. They sell them in toy stores.
Circle the board, once for each of us.
And then you say these words.
"As friends we've gathered,
hearts are true.
"Spirits near, we call to you."
If there's a presence here,
please make yourself known.
Is there a presence here among us?
(GASPING)
This is a joke.
Come on, you guys. Who's doing that?
- LAINE: Sarah, cut it out!
- I'm not pushing it.
Is there something you wanna tell us?
PETE: H-I...
It spelled, "Hi, friend."
Hi, friend.
When I was here yesterday, was that you?
Oh.
Who is this?
Debbie.
(EXHALING)
Sarah, if that's you pretending to be Debbie,
then that's really messed up.
- I swear it's not me, all right.
- Okay, this is freaking me out.
- Let's just stop it now.
- I'm sorry. Just put your hand back, please.
Debbie,
was there something I could have done?
Was there some way
we could have helped you?
If there's anything you wanna
tell us about why you did...
If you did this to yourself...
Did you really do this?
(THUDDING)
(SIGHS)
Guys, calm down. It's an old house.
Laine, keep going.
- Debbie, I miss you.
- I miss you, too.
We all do.
If you can hear us, we just...
I don't know, we just wanted
a chance to say goodbye.
- Laine!
- SARAH: Iz.
It's not even real, okay?
It's just a game.
It's all the lights. They're all out.
(EXHALING)
(THUDDING)
So, be honest.
Was it you moving the planchette?
No.
- You?
- No. No way.
(SOFTLY) For all we know, it was Laine.
Maybe it was really
something she needed.
Might not have even known
she was doing it.
Is it Debbie? Did she do this?
- SARAH: Where are you going?
- PETE: Just a second.
(CREAKING)
- Deb, is that you?
- Laine, please stop, okay? It's not her.
What if it is? What if she's
trying to tell me something?
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
Oh, my God!
- What happened? Are you okay?
- What was that?
I saw a reflection in the mirror,
and then someone pushed me from behind.
Can we just get out of here, please?
Come on.
- Why are you bringing that home?
- It was hers. I want it here.
What?
It's just that you need to believe
that was really Debbie.
You were there. It was weird, right?
Yeah, it was weird.
But I don't know if it means anything.
But what if it's her?
What if she wants to tell me something?
You wanted us to play, we did.
And now we can leave it alone.
Laine, you said goodbye to her.
(SIGHS)
I know you'll find the moment
when you're ready, but...
I think you can start to move on.
- Good night.
(BLOWS)
I couldn't sleep last night.
We don't have to talk about it.
I had all these weird dreams.
I keep thinking about being in her house.
Iz, I know you didn't wanna be there.
You did it for me. So, thank you.
I owe you.
Let's just forget the whole deal, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Nona, what are you doing?
You should never touch these things.
You used it, didn't you?
(STUTTERS) It was just once.
Promise me, Laine. Do not go
seeking answers from the dead.
Get rid of the board.
Yeah, I will. Mmm, I promise, Nona.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(GLASS CLINKS)
(SCRATCHING)
(ECHOING) Who is that?
(CLATTERING)
(RUMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
- Good night, Hank. See you tomorrow.
- Uh-huh.
Oh, hey, can you grab the
garbage on your way out?
Thank you.
- (DOOR SLAMS)
- (GASPS)
(KEYS JANGLE)
(GASPS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
Hi, Isabelle.
Where?
No, no, it doesn't sound crazy at all.
I'll pick you up.
I'll be there in a few minutes.
(CELL PHONE BEEPS)
MAN: (ON COMPUTER)
This idea of messages from the board
is nothing more than
our unconscious minds.
It's known as the ideomotor effect.
Involuntary motor muscles kick in
which drive the movement of the planchette.
We're simply telling ourselves
what we wanna believe.
(DOOR OPENS)
Sarah?
- (EXHALING)
- (FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
- Was that you?
- No, I thought it was you.
Dad, you home?
Dad!
Go!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BOTH SCREAM)
(PANTING)
(WHISPERING) Do you have your phone?
- No.
- No?
Shh. It's outside.
Okay, just be quiet, just be quiet.
(BOTH PANTING)
Sarah, stay back, okay?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Isabelle was shaking
when I picked her up last night.
I called this morning to check in.
She doesn't even wanna leave the house.
And I saw it, too.
"Hi friend." Carved right into my desk.
Did we all see it?
Debbie's trying to reach us.
- What could she want?
- If we wanna know, we gotta ask her.
I think we should say
the words together.
ALL: As friends we've gathered,
hearts are true.
Spirits near, we call to you.
If there's a presence here,
make yourself known.
Debbie, we're all here for you.
We all got your messages. We're here.
Can you show us a sign?
Are you here?
(GASPS)
Come on, guys.
You didn't kill yourself, did you?
I knew it. (SIGHS)
Debbie, if you didn't do this, who did?
Did someone hurt you? Did someone...
Who did it? Who hurt you?
Debbie, why won't you answer us?
I have a question.
On our first real date
away from everybody else,
we told everybody we went to the fair,
but where did we really go?
We went to the lookout.
By the point, in the canyon.
Do you remember that?
What I said to you?
This isn't Debbie.
What do you mean?
I never took her there. Not once.
Is this you, Debbie?
Then who the hell is this?
LAINE: "D."
"Z."
Is this who we were
talking to the other night?
Oh, my God.
Were we ever talking to Debbie?
Laine, we can stop.
When Debbie played the Ouija,
did she make contact with you?
D.Z., where are you?
The chair.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
LAINE: I don't see anything.
- Guys, I think we should get out of...
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
"Run"?
- "She's coming."
- (STAMMERING) Who's coming?
SARAH: "Mother."
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
- (GASPS)
- (SCREAMING)
- LAINE: Sarah, wait!
- What happened in there, Laine?
LAINE: It doesn't matter,
because we're not playing anymore.
Okay? We're walking away from
the board, the whole thing.
Debbie played, and now she's dead.
Look, what if we made the same mistake?
What if we broke some sort of rule?
Hey.
Hey. We're finished with this, okay?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Operation Clean House.
I get to clean
the attic!
God.
(SIGHS) All right. Attic done.
I did the best I could. Um...
(SIGHS)
I'm not gonna lie, that was not fun.
However, I did find something.
Along with a lot of old junk
from the previous owners.
Ta-da! It's cool, right? Oh.
- They go together.
- She found it in her house.
Do I like my find?
Oh.
(CHUCKLES)
Yes. Am I cleaning the attic again? No.
(DOOR OPENS)
DEBBIE: Answer my question. I'm waiting.
(CRACKLES)
"R."
SARAH: She played alone?
"H-I-F-R-I-E-N-D." Whoa.
"Hi, friend."
(ENGINE TURNS OFF)
(KEYS JANGLING)
(GROANING)
(MUFFLED STRAINING)
(SCREAMS)
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
As you know, our community has been
devastated the last few weeks.
First with Debbie, and now, Isabelle.
I wanted to talk to
each of you because...
I just wanna make sure
you and your friends are okay.
When you lose someone close to you,
there's always help available.
We care about you.
Now, um...
there's a lot of very,
very helpful information in here
about dealing with loss
and moving forward.
You have no idea
what you're talking about.
- Laine, we're only trying to help you.
- You can't.
I'm not even sure who can.
Trevor.
We need to talk. All of us.
You made us play. Now, Isabelle's dead.
I know, and I'll never forgive myself.
This thing, it's haunting us,
wherever we go,
watching everything we do.
It's coming for all of us.
(SNIFFLES) So, who's next?
Hey.
- Look, back there with Trevor...
- He's right.
Hey, I need you. It's just us now.
What does this spirit wanna do with us?
It's angry. When Debbie played,
she woke something up in her house.
Okay?
Pete, please. I need your help.
(DOOR OPENS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
I think that's where Debbie found it.
(COUGHING)
(STRAINING)
(CLATTERING)
(FLOOR CREAKING)
(GROANS)
(COUGHING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CREAKING)
(THUDDING)
- PETE: Laine, are you all right?
- (GASPS)
- Laine!
- I'm coming!
Pete.
Pete, grab this.
It's heavy. Okay.
(GRUNTS)
(RUMBLING)
(STRAINING)
(SCREAMING)
Laine!
Hey, this is the family.
For some reason,
they're still connected to the house.
From the look of these photos, I'd say
this is the late '40s, the early '50s.
Is there a way to get any records?
I don't know.
Property archives or something?
I can try.
We need to find out who they are.
Laine, you should come look at this.
I found this old article.
Doris Zander.
(STAMMERING) D.Z. This is her.
Pete, listen. Doris Zander.
She used to live in
Debbie's house with her mother.
D.Z. was a missing girl.
They never found her.
They suspected the mother had something
to do with her disappearance.
PETE: So, who is the other girl
in the pictures with them?
Doris had a sister.
And she might still be alive.
(BUZZES)
MAN: (ON INTERCOM) May I help you?
I'm here for visiting hours.
(DOOR BUZZING)
LAINE: Thank you.
They told me my niece was here to visit.
I don't have a niece.
My name is Laine. I'm here to
ask about your sister, Doris.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Doris.
My best friend, Debbie,
lived in your old house.
She's not alive anymore.
And this is gonna sound
really strange but...
but I think I know why.
I believe there's a
presence in that house.
I wouldn't be surprised
if there's more than one.
I found pictures of you and your sister.
You found pictures?
You found my family photos?
Yeah. I can bring them to you,
or send them, if you like.
Please bring them.
I haven't seen my sister's face
in a very long time.
At least not her real face.
I believe I saw her.
Me and my friends. And her lips,
they were stitched shut.
Mother did that to her.
My mother practiced mediumship.
And if practice makes perfect,
let me tell you,
she was pretty damn good,
depending on your point of view.
She conducted séances,
she used spirit boards. Anything.
A bit reckless, actually.
Doris loved my mother.
She wanted to help.
She was fascinated by it all.
And when the séances got bigger
and my mother really made connections,
she needed a vessel.
A vessel to give them a voice.
- Who?
- The spirits.
She used Doris.
And then something
went wrong with Mother.
Chasing the dead and living in all
those shadows, something snapped.
She couldn't turn it off.
She couldn't break the connection.
Mother was consumed by them.
She was insane.
So, she did that to Doris.
To her lips. To stop them from talking.
And then Doris went missing?
Missing.
She never left the house, did she?
No. No, she didn't.
Mother wasn't herself. She killed Doris.
And after that, I did what I
needed to do to stop Mother.
(SNIFFLES)
That's why I'm here.
But that doesn't mean Mother is gone.
(GASPS)
- How did you see her?
- What?
You said you saw her.
You said you saw her lips.
How did you see her?
You wouldn't have been able
to see her. Not unless you...
Look, I just wanna stop whatever it is
that is happening. My friends are dying.
(STAMMERING)
No, you opened up a channel.
You made a connection. With what?
- A spirit board, I bet.
- Yeah.
You played in a graveyard,
and now she's awake again.
Both of them. Mother, too.
And if you could see them...
- Just through the planchette.
- Not for long.
They're getting stronger.
The points of connection. In your case,
it's the body and the board.
The link is between them.
The energy is growing,
and it is hard to stop.
Mother used to have a secret room.
She sealed it up, after Doris,
down in the basement.
Don't go alone.
Mother will try to stop you.
LAINE: What do I have to do?
PAULINA: You need to cut
the stitches from her mouth.
And if it works, you have to pray
that Doris can deal with Mother.
It's supposed to be somewhere here.
Pete, grab this.
TREVOR: This is crazy, Laine.
We should just leave.
We shouldn't be here.
What?
The shadow.
- Trevor!
- (SCREAMING)
PETE: Trevor!
Pete! Trevor! Pete!
(POUNDING ON DOOR)
Laine! Keep going!
(GRUNTING)
LAINE: Sarah, I need your help!
(LAINE STRAINING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
Laine!
Stay there. I found her.
No, no, no, not now.
Come on. Stop. Come on!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(STRIKING MATCH)
Come on.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
No!
(SCREAMING)
(DOOR CREAKING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- Are you guys okay?
- Yeah.
Where's Laine?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
DEBBIE: (ON VIDEO)
Okay, to our future selves,
I hope we look back on this, and, um...
- No, it looks so good.
- My boobs look huge.
Okay, turn around.
What does it look like in the back?
Hold on. Let me see.
MRS. G: You look so beautiful!
- I know.
- Thank you.
- MRS. G: Oh, my babies. Look at my angels.
- (LAUGHS)
I miss you, Debbie. All the time.
(SIGHS)
Debbie?
(SHRIEKING)
(GROANING)
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
Ms. Zander.
Oh. My tenacious little niece.
I did everything you said.
We found the body, I cut the stitches,
she sent Mother away.
But it didn't work. Why didn't it work?
Mother must have come back, because my
friend Pete, another friend, is dead.
(SOFTLY) She's free.
You lied to me.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
(CHUCKLES)
Your mother didn't try to hurt us.
She tried to stop us.
Your mother wasn't
the one that was evil.
- It was...
- I told her that I would help her.
I heard the voices, too.
They tell you the most wonderful,
awful things.
You're gonna hear them, too,
little girl.
You'll hear them soon enough
because she's coming to get you, too.
- I always told her. I told her.
- Ms. Zander.
She's gonna be nice to me.
She knows I was gonna help her
- and now she's gonna be nice to me.
- Calm down. You have to calm down.
She's gonna keep her promises!
No! No!
You have to break the connection
or it will keep coming back for you.
- I'll burn the board.
- That won't be enough.
A spirit this strong
could bring it back.
A connection, once made to a spirit,
is very difficult to break.
The board is just the conduit.
You have to sever the connection
- on both sides.
- How?
Your connection is through the board
and that little girl's body.
The spirit lives through both of them,
so you must destroy them both.
- What? Destroy the body?
- And the board. And you must hurry.
- I'll call Trevor.
- (SOFTLY) Thank you.
- SARAH: Trevor.
- Sarah?
We're back here.
Wait up!
Sarah?
Laine?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- (SHRIEKS)
- (GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
LAINE: Trevor's already here.
Trevor!
Where is he?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WATER DRIPPING)
Trevor?
(BREATH TREMBLING)
- (GASPS) No!
- (MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(BOTH PANTING)
Laine, what do we do?
Laine!
Go get the board.
(CLATTERING)
(CLICKING)
- We need the body, too.
- Let's burn this damn thing...
(SCREAMING)
- Laine!
- Sarah!
Sarah!
Ah!
(BREATH TREMBLING)
Hey!
(SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
As friends we've gathered,
hearts are true.
Spirits near, we call to you.
Doris, I'm playing alone!
You have to play!
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(GRUNTING)
Ow!
(BONE CRACKING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
(SHRIEKING)
(GROWLING)
(LAINE GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(SHRIEKING)
Hey.
- Feeling any better?
- Yeah. Yeah, I guess so.
I just miss them.
All the time.
Yeah, me too.
I guess you never really feel like
you get to say goodbye
and maybe that's okay.
Oh, well... Maybe there are no goodbyes.
Not really.
I keep wondering about that night.
That poor little girl.
All of those dark spirits
that were in her.
Where do you think they went?
(SHRIEKING)
(BEEPS)