[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[WIND HOWLING]
♪ [SINGING IN NATIVE INDIAN]
[SPIRITS HOWLING]
[HOWLING STOPS]
[SPEAKING NATIVE INDIAN]
[THUNDER CRASHING]
[SCREAMING]
[WIND HOWLING]
Taylor!
Tangina.
Over here!
I think we finally
found the core.
We dug under
the swimming pool.
This is directly below
the old graveyard.
There's a presence.
[WATER RIPPLING]
There's something terrible.
Too much power.
I've seen it...
In dreams.
What is it?
Where's the family now?
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
DIANE:
Did you make that?
GRANDMA:
Wait a second.
An inch and a half.
Let me try this up against her arm.
Oh mother, it's too hot
on the kids.
STEVE:
Ok.
Ready.
[STEVE LAUGHING]
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
GRANDMA: You'd be lucky if your
teeth don't fall out from that.
[ALL LAUGHING]
Did you think up
that sandwich all by yourself?
No. Grandma helped.
What a fib!
Grab me the red yarn out of
my basket, will you, honey?
DIANE:
E. Buzz!
CAROL ANNE:
That's disgusting.
Stop!
E. Buzz,
E. Buzz, down!
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
Maybe E. Buzz
wants some mustard.
STEVE: E. Buzz, get down.
Down E. Buzz.
I'll say "down," and then
he'll get down. Down!
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
He really listens to you.
Honey, now could you get me
the yellow yarn?
Oh, Rob, very nice to share
with E. Buzz.
E. Buzz knows how
to share with Robbie.
E. Buzz, get down.
Thank you, angel.
Come on, Guerrero!
Hit it out of the park!
Yeah, hit it!
MAN ON RADIO:
Guerrero has struck out...
[STATIC]
Dad, can't we get a t.V.
Like everybody else?
No, no, we can't
get a t.V.
Great, I'll just have to
grow up retarded.
Come on, Rob,
kids don't grow up retardo
because of
lack of television.
Guerrero drives one...
Atta boy guerrero!
Did you see that Robbie?
No, dad.
I didn't see it.
You got to use
your imagination, son.
Come on. Let's test
this baby out.
God!
[WHIRRING]
How am I gonna
sell this
to innocent housewives,
Robbie?
I don't know, dad.
Whatcha drawing,
honey?
Don't know. Stuff.
You draw very well.
Do you want
to be an artist
when you grow up?
Maybe.
Don't want to grow up much.
How come?
Probably not much fun.
Oh, sure it is.
I've loved every age
I've been.
They all have
their blessings.
When I was your age,
I learned
that I could do things
that other folks couldn't.
Like what
kind of things?
I just knew things.
I didn't know
how I knew, but I did.
Like what?
Once my mother
lost her bracelet
and I knew
where it was:
2 Miles
from our house
in a place
that I'd never been.
Now,
do you ever know things
and can't explain why?
Yes?
Yes.
Well, darling,
that's a very special gift
that you and I have.
It's nothing
to be scared of.
Will it help me
be a ballerina?
Yes, sure it will.
Whatever you dream,
you can be.
They denied
our claim again!
What?
I told you,
we never should have told them
that the house vanished
into thin air.
That's exactly
what I've been talking about.
You tell the truth, and
what do you get? Nada!
They say that if the house
disappeared,
then technically,
it's only missing.
Missing?
What do they think,
this house is going to return
or something?
Now, it's been a full year.
The house is not coming back.
I got a gut feeling, Diane,
I'm positive about that.
I know that, Steven.
You tell them that--
no, no, I'm gonna
fill out the 4th claim.
Ok, what are we going
to claim this time?
Act of God?
Housenapping?
Steven,
we are almost broke.
Ok, we're--we're broke, but
we're not-- we're not starving.
Ok, but I don't
happen to like
having to live off
my mother.
And I think that we deserve a
house of our own again, someday.
Oh, honey, gee, gosh.
See, that's the difference
between you and me, Diane,
I am into
downward mobility.
I'm--I'm not settling for it.
I'm into it.
I like getting out there in the
streets and meeting those...
I like selling vacuums.
I like carrying the pipes
and the apparatus
and my little demo case.
Let's get the kids up,
and we'll paint the car
different colors,
kind of day-glo,
like we used to do when we
were kinda freaky, you know?
The freaky Freelings
on the road again!
You know, the family
whose house disappeared!
Watch them find it, Diane.
I'm not going to get upset
about this,
but I'll tell you something,
I'm writing them back
and when I sign that letter
I'm signing "Mr. president."
[LAUGHING]
You're wacko!
Steven.
Hmm.
Hmm?
Steven, you were
never a hippie.
Huh?
You were never a hippie.
You were always
into making money.
You only reason you painted your Van
Day-Glo colors and grew your hair
was to impress
Cookie Gurnich.
Cookie?
Necki necka wow!
Steven, don't tell me
what cookie can do,
I hated you then.
But I always knew how to
make up to you? Didn't I?
No, I don't remember.
Sure you do.
I do not.
Oh, come on.
I don't. Oh, you'd sing
that stupid song.
♪ If I fell
in love with you ♪
It won't work.
Not in the shadow of cookie.
♪ Would you promise
to be true ♪
Steven, don't even try it.
It's not working.
♪ understand
don't sing that song.
I've never forgiven you
for Cookie Gurnich.
♪ That I've been
in love before ♪
♪ and I found
out love is more ♪
It's-- Steven.
♪ Than just holding hands
♪ if I give my love
Did Cookie
really crumble?
♪ To you
♪ I must be sure
♪ from the very start
[LAUGHING]
♪ That you
BOTH: ♪ Will love me
more than her ♪
♪ 'cause I couldn't
stand the pain ♪
♪ And I
♪ Would be sad
if our new love ♪
Am I interrupting again?
Hi.
Hi, pumpkin.
Mom, I'm going to be
a ballerina.
Great.
Not tonight, honey.
Bedtime.
Say goodnight, mom.
Goodnight, honey.
Let's sleep in our own bed
tonight, shall we?
Ok.
♪ We're dancing down
to my bed ♪
♪ we're dancing
down the hall ♪
♪ we're dancing the tour jete
most of all ♪
♪[ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING
THE STAR-SPANGLED BANNER]
Come on, Dodgers!
Come on, let's go.
Let's go. Come on,
come on.
DIANE:
Robbie?
Mom, I've talked
to the kittens.
They want to come home
with us.
Uh, no, sweetheart,
E. Buzz would get upset.
Robbie, come on.
Why?
Well, he's not used
to having other pets around.
Robert!
How would you like it
if I brought home a new baby?
That's even better
than a kitten.
Mom, I have
a great idea.
No, we are not buying
a television set, Robert.
Mom, a present for dad,
it's a bargain.
Mom!
Mom, where are you?
Mom! Mom!
Robbie!
Mom!
Ah!
Hi.
Are you lost,
sweetheart?
Are you afraid, honey?
Well, why don't you
come with me?
No.
All right.
I'll sing you a song
till your mommy comes back.
♪ God is in
♪ his holy temple
♪ earthly thoughts
♪ be silent now
WOMAN:
I'd like to purchase this.
SALESWOMAN:
Ok, that's $10.26 plus tax.
Where's Carol Anne?
I don't know.
She was just here.
Carol Anne?
Baby!
♪ Is beneath the sk--
Carol Anne.
Honey, what happened?
Did you get lost?
I don't know.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
Such a lovely child.
Oh, thank you so much.
I'm sorry, honey.
We just stopped
into a shop.
I thought you were
right there with us.
Honey, what is it?
Mom,
I want to go home.
They're very unusual.
They're just drawings.
Ugly.
Ah.
You know that she can see
colors with her hands.
Mama, we don't want to hear
that stuff, ok?
And we don't want Carol Anne
to hear, most of all.
There's nothing
to be afraid of.
How do you know what we
should be afraid of?
You weren't there, were you?
Why don't you tell me?
It might help.
I did tell you.
No, not everything.
I don't remember
everything.
Try.
Well,
first the canary died.
And then--then the chairs
went all funny,
and I thought
it was kind of exciting,
you know?
And then...
Carol Anne was gone.
And I--
[PANTING]
Honey, what is it?
Nothing.
I just want to get on with our lives.
It's over.
Diane.
Diane, you've got to go
unafraid into this life.
You don't want to instill
fear into that child
who is truly gifted
and filled with knowledge.
I don't want her
to be gifted!
You don't mean that.
I'm going to bed, mama,
goodnight.
I'll be there
if you need me.
[TOY TELEPHONE RINGING]
Yes?
Yes.
I'll be good.
I love you, too.
Goodnight, grandma.
She knew you loved her
so much.
[CRYING] Oh, if I just
had one more day.
[SNIFFING]
What's wrong?
Honey...
Grandma passed away
last night.
Grandma died?
Come here, baby.
It's all right, mom.
YOUNG DIANE: Let's plant
them over there, ok?
GRANDMA: All right,
now, what do you think?
Do you want it here?
No.
How about here?
I want it there,
right there.
Right there?
Right there.
Absolutely here.
Ok, ok.
You dig a hole.
Dig it very deep.
Ok.
Oh, mom.
You always made me
feel so safe.
I love you so much.
Mom?
Can you put these
on me,
so I can be
a ballerina with wings?
Darling, you can be
anything you want to be.
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
VOICE #1:
Diane.
Mama?
[GASPING]
VOICE #2:
Help me!
Oh!
[DIANE SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[THUNDER BOOMING]
[RAIN POURING]
[TOY TELEPHONE RINGING]
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[RINGING]
[Ringing]
Hi. Grandma?
Do you have wings now?
My ballerina costume does.
Grammy?
Who are you?
No. Uh-uh.
I don't remember.
What?
Hello, little one.
[GASPS]
I am your friend.
We want the angel.
[VOICES CHANTING]
[SCREAMING]
Carol Anne,
what's going on?
what are you doing?
Carol Anne!
Come on! What is it?
[CACKLING]
Diane.
Oh, Jesus!
The kids.
The kids!
Kids!
ROBBIE:
Dad, mom!
We're coming!
Robbie!
Carol Anne!
[GROANING]
Robbie!
Carol Anne!
Where are you?
Robbie!
Carol Anne!
[CLINKING]
[TICKING]
[BUZZING]
They're back.
[BOOMING]
[WOOD CREAKING]
Don't panic!
Go, go, go, go!
[BOOMING]
Jeez!
[ALL SCREAM]
Who the hell are you?
The name's Taylor.
Great. Good name.
Come on, let's go.
Tangina barrons sent me.
Oh, yeah,
say hello to the magic
munchkin for us, will you?
Steve, wait, wait.
Sent you for what?
There's no use running.
It'll find you.
You're better off here.
Let's go.
You stay. We're gone.
Come on, kids.
[TIRES SQUEALING]
You got me up at 4:00 in the
morning to tell me this?
You are a pack
of trouble, girl.
Why are you messing around
with that bum?
WOMAN:
Because I like him.
Dad, are we going to
have to move again?
I don't know,
Robbie.
I'm going to
think about it.
Where can we go?
Disneyland?
Oh, puke!
Don't be such an infant!
Shh, shh, shh.
Ok, what about
dunkin' donuts?
Shut up, jerko.
Hey!
Look. Here.
Take this, go play the,
uh, pinball machine.
And give some
to your brother.
No.
ROBBIE: Come on, I wanna play pinball.
Give the money to me.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know,
I'm--I'm thinking.
Honey, we have
to go somewhere.
We can't just drive around.
Well, mother, just don't you
bring him over to my house.
Waitress, check!
IN GRANDMA'S VOICE:
Listen, children,
you can't run
from this thing.
It has made contact
and will stop at nothing.
You've got to fight it
head on.
Stay together.
Be loving.
Be brave.
Mama?
I'm not your mother, lady.
Elspeth, are you ok?
What happened?
ELSPETH:
WOMAN:
You went funny.
DIANE: But it sounded like her.
I don't understand.
Honey, you can't explain
stuff like that.
It just happens.
I mean, there's no reason for it.
ROBBIE:
What are you talking about?
It doesn't matter,
honey.
What do you want?
She told you the truth.
DIANE:
Who?
You--you mean,
that wo--
ah, man, are you in cahoots
with the lady in there?
I cahoot
with no one.
Then why are you
following us?
I came to help.
Oh, God, I mean,
you don't understand.
See, we don't want
your help.
We don't want
anybody's help.
We want to be
left alone!
Steven.
Why did Tangina send you?
Why didn't she come
herself?
It's my kind of job.
You know,
maybe it's no coincidence.
This guy shows up,
things go kinda screwy.
Get off my car!
Get in the car, Diane.
Get in the car, kids.
Diane, get in the car.
Steven, wait a minute,
let's listen to him.
Fine, you listen to him.
I wanna go home.
Listen, let's be sensible
about this.
Sensible? What is sensible?
Honey, nobody can help us.
Let's just get in the car
and get the hell out of here!
And go where?
It followed us here.
It will follow us wherever we go.
We can't just keep running.
CAROL ANNE:
Where are you from?
From all over.
This is Katrina.
Katrina?
Uh-huh.
Hi, Katrina.
What's that?
It's my
medicine bag.
Charms.
See?
[BARKING]
The house is ok?
You're sure?
E. Buzz agrees.
It's ok for now.
Oh, the dog agrees, huh?
Gee, that's terrific,
isn't it?
Yes.
Your car.
Yeah?
Very angry.
Uh-huh.
I'll fix it.
Make it happy?
[LAUGHS]
Ok.
I've read about these rain dances.
I know.
DIANE:
I understand that.
We don't need rain.
I can't say that Steven
fully trusts him yet.
Well, you can't
blame him, I mean.
Yeah, o--ok, well,
thanks, Tangina. We will.
'Bye.
Honey, she says
he's ok.
I think we should
give him a chance.
Tangina says he's ok?
Yeah.
Oh, that's great.
Keep an open mind,
Steven.
Diane, I mean, really.
This is bizarre.
You know, look, I've got
nothing against these people.
You know, I mean, I read
bury my heart at wounded knee.
I got through
most of the chapters.
I--I got some Indian in me,
I think.
A 16th, my mother
will never admit to it.
But honey, I mean,
what if this guy...
Is, like, an escapee from
the tribal asylum?
ROBBIE:
Mom, come look at this!
[GASPS]
Oh, my God!
I don't believe it!
[LAUGHS]
What are you doing?
Hi mom. I'm going to help
protect the family now.
Let me see.
Come outside, Robbie.
Hey, I'm a big guy now.
I'm still your mother.
Go in the house and wait for me.
Thanks, mom.
He wants to be a man.
Well, there are
a lot of ways to be a man.
I'm not sure wearing claw marks
and war paint is one of them.
How would you know?
What?
You're not a man,
are you?
Ok, I'm not a man.
But you're not
a mother!
It is my job to do everything
I can to make my children
part of a normal world,
a world of school,
and friends, and lovers, and
families of their own, someday.
Well, that's good.
Right, I know.
And I hope that they'll learn
to forget all this soon.
They cannot learn
by forgetting.
Well, what would you
have me do,
I mean, they're just children,
for God's sake.
Children have fought wars.
They've built nations.
They are strong
and have courage.
Don't treat them any less than
that because they're young.
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[CAR BACKFIRING]
[SCREAMS]
STEVE:
Taylor!
Ok, Taylor, ok.
Ok, huh?
Huh? Ok.
You can stay
in the house, ok?
You can have my aura, my spirits,
the ghosts, the whole deal.
The whole cazaba, but keep
your hands off my car!
Ok? Hands off!
It's worse than
it was before.
Car's still angry, huh?
Angry?
That car is pissed!
♪ God is in
♪ his holy temple
♪ earthly thoughts
♪ be silent now
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
♪ While with reverence
♪ we assemble
♪ and before
♪ his presence bow
ROBBIE: Come on, Carol Anne.
It's raining!
Come on!
What's wrong?
♪ He is with us now
Carol Anne, come on!
Let's go.
♪ As we call
♪ upon his name
♪ aiding every
♪ good endeavor
♪ guiding us
toward every aim ♪
DIANE:
Honey, come inside.
You're getting soaked!
Come on, sweetie.
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
Can we help you?
Haven't I've seen you
somewhere before?
That is possible!
I get around.
I love gettin' around.
Love talkin' to people,
even on a rainy day.
[WHIMPERING]
Ha! Dog's sheddin'.
Hi!
Hi.
I saw you
at the shopping mall.
Sure you did,
I remember
your little angel, here.
Allow me
to introduce myself.
Henry Kane.
Mom!
You know, I got to tell
you, we've had, uh,
we had enough of door-to-door
salesmen, if you don't mind.
Reverend Kane!
What I sell is free!
Mind if I come in
and talk to you about it?
Mom, I don't
feel well.
You know,
I got a t-- maybe,
we'll just talk
from here, all right?
DIANE:
Come inside, baby.
I want to take your temperature.
Come on, Robert.
I'm glad we have
this opportunity to talk
with your family
out of the way.
Because I believe
you have a problem here.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
I believe,
there's an Indian
livin' here with you?
Taylor.
[LAUGHS]
So that's what he calls
himself now.
You are in danger!
What do you mean?
I'm with an organization
whose concern
is families like your own,
families in crisis
that are preyed upon
by charlatans
and fake magic
and false solutions!
N-now, I don't expect you
to believe me now,
but let me come in
and talk to you about this.
I don't know.
This is-- this is crazy.
This is nuts.
Please! Open your heart
and your mind
to what I'm saying.
He is dangerous!
[GASPING]
I can see that he has
a strong hold
on this family.
Who do your wife
and children turn to...
With their problems?
They turn to him.
Now, don't they?
They don't trust you...
Anymore.
What you fear...
Is that you're not
man enough
to hold this family
together.
H-h-how do you know?
Because,
I'm smart.
And I'm your friend.
And I know
what you are thinking.
How?
Now,
let me in.
And let's talk about it.
Let me in!
You're my friend?
CAROL ANNE:
Daddy?
Now!
Before it's too late!
[GASPS]
No.
You're gonna die in there!
All of you!
You are gonna die!
Get the hell
out of here!
Sorry to see...
You're still unconvinced.
A pleasure
visiting with you.
♪ As we call
♪ upon his name
♪ aiding every
♪ good endeavor
♪ guiding us
♪ toward every aim
[THUNDER CLAPPING]
[RAIN STOPS]
You did good.
Who was that?
That was him.
Him?
What are you
talking about?
He was testing
your power.
He comes in many forms,
but that was him.
Now you're hooked.
You're on the path
of a warrior.
Hooked? Hey, wait.
What are you
talking about?
Your confrontation with him
was a drain on your power.
We don't have much time.
We must prepare.
Prepare?
Oh, God.
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
[COUGHING]
Tequila.
Ta kill ya!
You want a hit?
No. I used to drink.
I had to give it up.
Bad dreams.
Mmm.
You see something?
No.
What are you doing?
[SIGHING]
Seeking power.
Me, too.
You feel like a leaf at the
mercy of the wind, don't you?
Yep. That's right.
That's me.
Since the day you were born,
one way or another,
someone has been doing
something to you.
No, I don't--
I don't think
that's true.
They've been doing something
to you against your will.
And by now,
you're feeling helpless,
like a leaf in the wind.
Taylor, it would
help me out a lot
if you'd just say
what's on your mind
so I could
understand you.
You understand me...
No matter how much you like
to feel sorry for yourself,
you have to change that.
I'm a warrior.
A warrior would rather
be defeated and die
than act against
his nature.
That is the path
you've chosen to take,
whether you know it
or not.
You should assume
full responsibility.
Responsibility for what?
Responsibility for everything,
everything in your world.
Come on, Robbie.
Robbie, you're supposed
to clean your braces
and come downstairs now.
Shut up, jerko!
I'm doing it, ok?
Don't "ok" me!
You're a pest,
you know that?
[HISSING]
[SCREAMS]
Don't do that.
I didn't do anything.
You're such an infant.
Ready?
Where's Robbie?
He says
he's coming.
Ok.
Kiss Katrina,
too.
Goodnight, girls.
Goodnight.
Rob, come on!
Goodnight, daddy.
Ooh! The telephone.
Hello?
Yes.
Ok.
Dad, it's for you.
Oh.
Oh, maybe it's
the insurance company...
[LAUGHS]
With good news.
Ahem.
Hello?
[DOOR SLAMMING]
VOICE:
Die!
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
Mom!
Oh, God!
Stay here, baby.
Robbie!
[ROBBIE SCREAMING]
We're coming, Robbie!
Rob!
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
Robbie!
Dad, help me!
Taylor!
Help us!
Please!
Help! Taylor!
Taylor!
Hold tight, Robbie!
The plug!
No!
[ELECTRICITY SURGING]
[GASPING]
Get out!
Taylor!
Taylor, where the hell
were you?
We're not safe here anymore, my son
almost dies, and you sit here!
I was protecting
Carol Anne.
It's her he's after,
not Robbie,
not you or Diane.
Carol Anne.
Why the hell
won't you leave us alone?
[CHILDREN SCREAMING]
Dad!
KANE:
You can't keep her!
I am not dead!
[WHIMPERING]
He's still here.
He feels she belongs
to him.
But why?
I'm not sure,
but he's used to getting
what he wants.
Taylor...
Who is he?
What is he?
He's a man
filled with a demon,
lost in a dimension
that surrounds our world.
This entity believes that his
world and ours are the same.
Why doesn't he know
he's dead?
Because he isn't.
How can that be?
Nothing really dies.
Like a caterpillar
becomes a butterfly,
death only transforms us
into another state of being.
This man was evil.
His soul remains evil
because he chooses
not to see the light
and pass on
to a different consciousness.
How are we going
to fight this thing?
Until we learn
how to defeat him,
we do not let him win.
A hell of a plan.
That's a lot of crap.
I suppose you have
a plan of your own.
That's a lot of crap!
Shh.
Listen.
Don't come apart now.
This spirit is very clever.
He knows your strength
is your love,
and he hates you
for that.
He's been tryng to pull
this family apart,
and he will continue to try.
If he succeeds,
he will
possess Carol Anne...
And destroy your spirit.
[EAGLE SCREECHES]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
[GASPS]
[KNOCKING CONTINUES]
[KNOCKING]
Hi!
[GASPING]
Tangina!
Hi, Diane.
What are you
doing here?
Sorry to come unannounced, sweetie,
but I need to speak with you.
Oh, I'm glad
to see you.
Oh, good. 'Cause we're
runnin' out of time.
Mmm-hmm,
below the old cemetery,
what seems to be a tomb
with many bodies in it,
directly below your house.
Who are they?
The researchers don't know
who these people were.
There are no
marked graves.
There are, however,
records of
a religious sect
that mysteriously
disappeared.
What happened?
Their spiritual leader
was a medium
who led his followers
out to California
in the early 1800s
to start a utopian society.
They disappeared
near cuesta Verde
and were believed
massacred by Indians.
This could be them.
[WHISPERING
IN NATIVE INDIAN]
[SNICKERING]
This funny?
Well, no, uh...
I love the health club,
you know.
I'm just wondering when I
get the key to my locker?
[LAUGHS]
Sense of humor is good.
You're going to need it.
[WIND HOWLING]
[RATTLING]
[CHANTING IN NATIVE INDIAN]
The entity has revealed
his essence to you, his enemy.
Now that you've
seen each other,
there'll be no mistakes.
Take this smoke.
Smoke,
make him one with power
and knowledge.
Here is a photo
of those people.
I think you should have
a look at it.
I know this is
hard for you, dear,
but I need your
verification on something.
You see,
I don't really trust
my instincts anymore.
Now, hold this one
and tell me
what you feel.
[GASPING]
Oh, my God,
I've seen him!
I thought so.
Where?
Here! At the mall!
At our house!
Who is he?
Just tell me what you feel.
What do you want me to do?
Who is he?
I've consulted others.
They've told me things,
but they said you know more!
I don't know anything!
Yes, you do!
You traveled
to a dimension
few people have ever
traveled to incarnate!
Your daughter is
highly clairvoyant!
As was your mother,
I suspect.
As you are as well!
Now tell me what you feel!
It is him.
It's the preacher.
They're following him
in death
like they did in life.
They sealed themselves
in the cavern,
because Kane tells them
the end of the world
is coming.
Come with me!
The day he predicts
for the end comes and goes,
but Kane won't
let them leave!
Don't! No, please!
Please don't!
Please, please don't!
[SOBBING]
Please...
Oh, Diane.
Yes, it all
makes sense now.
When you brought Carol Anne
back to this world,
his followers
became restless
because they had tasted
the light of her being,
her life force.
Now he wants
her back.
This person is
no longer human.
He is the beast.
♪ Earthly thoughts
be silent now ♪
♪ while with reverence
you must take
your family back
to cuesta Verde.
What?
The evil spirit
that is stalking you,
it knows who you are,
where you are,
how to find you,
what your weaknesses are.
Your best bet is
to confront him,
surprise him
on his own ground.
But, Taylor, w-what about
Diane and the kids?
They are your power
and you are theirs.
[EAGLE SCREECHING]
[SIGHING]
Uh, are things
desperate, Taylor?
What you see
as desperate,
I see as inevitable.
I've done all I can.
I must be
leaving you now.
I'll take you home.
STEVE:
Um, guys,
you know, there's, uh,
no reason to get depressed.
I mean, Taylor's not here.
That's all right.
We'll just keep on going just like
we've been doing, as a family,
as a unit--
son, you know, I've told you
about the helmet and eating...
I told you,
I'm not hungry.
Miniature golf.
Tomorrow we can play
some miniature golf!
We can get our putters...
How about bowling,
huh?
You like bowling,
sweet pea.
Nature hike, Rob.
Huh? We'll get...
Brisk walk?
I know.
The water slide, huh?
We'll take E. Buzz, we'll put water
wings on him, and shove him down,
and laugh,
won't we? Ha, ha.
So, after Alice fell
down the hole,
why'd she drink
from that bottle?
Because it said,
"drink me" on it.
Oh. Were they going
to capture her?
Take her someplace bad?
Yes, but Alice gets home
all right, remember?
Did she know why they
wanted to hurt her?
I don't think so,
honey.
'Cause I know.
You know what?
Why they're here.
Why, baby?
Why are they here?
Because they don't know
where else to go.
[MOANING]
[SCREAMS]
God! Oh!
[GAGGING]
God!
[SCREAMING]
[PANTING]
♪ God is
in his holy temple ♪
♪ [HUMMING]
Hi, angel!
Are you ok, dad?
Yeah.
I just want to
give my little girl a hug.
Hey, your mom and I
would like to talk alone.
Go put on
your nightie, honey.
What's going on,
Steve?
Nothing. I just
want us to be alone.
Carol Anne's upset.
Does that feel good?
I should dry her hair.
She's all right.
She's safe.
Steven, come on!
Honey!
Is that good?
Don't!
Not now!
Why? When?
What do you mean?
Diane, I have needs, too!
It seems to me, your needs
have been fulfilled
by the bottle tonight!
Oh!
Steven, don't.
Diane, are you accusing me
of being drunk?
I'm not accusing you
of anything.
Yes you are, but that's
what you're thinking.
No, I'm not!
I know you!
That's what you're thinking!
Spare me, Steven.
Diane, you remember,
just the other day
when you were 7
and you were helping
your mommy
plant flowers
in the garden?
You saw it clearly!
How the hell
do you know that?
Because I am smart.
Oh, mommy Jess...
Don't cry.
Oh, shut up.
Don't pout!
You think that all
of our troubles
are because of Carol Anne!
You wish Carol Anne
had never been
given birth to!
You never wanted
Carol Anne!
Shh!
But you thought it!
You thought it!
You thought it,
you thought it, baby!
Shh.
You thought about it!
You thought that?
You thought it! Shh!
You thought it!
Diane's had secrets!
No, don't!
Don't touch me!
Don't, Steven!
I know you!
I feel you!
What is wrong?
What is happening to you?
[SOBBING]
Why are you doing this?
What is happening
to you?
Steven, stop it!
Stop it!
We want the angel!
The sweet pea!
[DIANE SOBBING]
No! Stop it!
I love you!
Damn you!
He is in
his holy temple!
Don't you know that?
I love you!
Believe me,
[GAGGING]
Oh, God,
leave me alone!
What is it?
What's happening
to you?
[GAGGING]
What's going on?
Leave me alone.
What is it?
What's--what's the matter?
Oh, God!
Steven--
God!
Steven, what is it?
What's the matter?
What is it? What is it,
Steven? Oh, God!
What is it?
[SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
Oh, God!
[SCREAMING]
Honey!
Steven!
DIANE:
Wake up! Wake up!
[SCREECHING]
Wake up!
[HOWLING]
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
Robbie!
Carol Anne!
[GASPING]
[CREAKING]
Kids,
where are you?
Stay put!
We'll find you!
[CREAKING]
Babies?
[CRASHING]
[SCREAMING]
[SOBBING]
CAROL ANNE: Daddy, help me!
Help me, please!
Dad!
ROBBIE:
Help me, mom! Dad!
No! No!
Oh, Steven!
No!
Steven!
No! No!
Oh, God!
[SCREAMS]
Oh, honey.
Carol Anne!
Robbie!
I'll check in here.
All right?
Robbie?
Carol Anne?
Oh, babies,
please answer me! Please!
Are you in here?
[THUMPING]
Kids!
Kids, please come!
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
Robbie! Carol Anne!
Kids?
[SCREAMING]
Robbie!
[CREAKING]
Carol Anne!
Please!
[SCREAMS]
Mom!
Oh, baby, baby,
are you all right?
Diane?
[DIANE SCREAMS]
Where's Carol Anne?
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
We can't find her. I don't know.
The garage!
Carol Anne!
Carol Anne,
where are you?
Carol Anne!
Where are you?
Honey?
Oh, God.
Open the door,
sweet pea!
Come on, honey,
open the door!
Lift up the knob,
sweetheart.
Come on honey, open the--
DIANE:
What is it?
Oh, sweet heart, that wasn't
daddy upstairs in the bathroom.
DIANE:
Oh, baby!
Grab it!
Jesus!
Mom!
Dad, watch out!
Ok, Diane,
get in the car!
Go, go, baby, go!
ROBBIE:
Open the door, Carol Anne.
Open the door!
Steven, come on!
Daddy, hurry!
Hurry!
Go! Go!
Get us out!
Go!
Dad, E. Buzz!
E. Buzz, get in!
STEVE:
E. Buzz!
Come on, E. Buzz, now get in!
Be a good boy!
Come on, E. Buzz,
get in.
Come on, E. Buzz!
Get in!
DIANE:
Come on, Robbie!
STEVE:
Close the door!
ROBBIE:
Dad, let's get out of here!
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[WHIRRING]
STEVE:
Come on, move!
Go!
It won't move!
It won't start!
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
STEVE:
Go! Please!
[CAROL ANNE CRYING]
No! No!
Look out!
[ALL SCREAMING]
Move, damn it!
Move!
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Get going, Steven!
Hurry!
Drive the car!
Now, move!
Move!
[SCREAMING]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
Oh, Jesus!
[SOBBING]
Shh, shh.
We're going back to
cuesta Verde, aren't we?
That's right.
But what about
the kids?
Taylor said we go back
as a family.
We go back together--
that's all of us.
Do you believe him, dad?
Honey,
it was real smart of you
to hide in the car
like that.
It wasn't my idea.
Taylor said
it was the only safe place.
Dad, do you
believe him?
I do. I do believe him,
son. Yeah.
I do.
[DIANE SCREAMS]
Oh, God.
Tangina. Thank God.
I knew you'd be here,
so I had to be here too.
We had to come,
Tangina.
I know, but there are
many dangers
you must consider, Steven.
Are you ok,
honey?
Yeah, mom.
I'm ok.
Careful, honey.
Mom!
Honey, honey, if you don't
want to go through with this,
we can leave here
right now, ok?
No, mom,
I do want to go on.
I love you
more than anything.
You always
remember that, ok?
Ok.
Oh, no!
Oh, God,
they're all...
They're all dying here!
Oh, God!
[SOBBING]
They're all reaching out
for help that will never come.
All because
they worship him.
Come with me!
[SCREAMING]
Diane!
Carol Anne!
DIANE:
Steven! Where are you?
CAROL ANNE:
Daddy, where are you?
Help! Please!
Tangina, they are gone!
They have crossed over!
Now we have to get them back,
and you know how. Please!
[TAYLOR CHANTING]
Taylor!
ROBBIE:
Dad!
Taylor!
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
Taylor,
Taylor, where are they?
I see her!
This is the way in.
The entity is with them.
They're in grave danger.
Hold on to each other.
When you find
Diane and Carol Anne,
band together.
That will prevent you from
crossing over into eternity.
I'll try to
bring you all back.
Join together.
The light of the family
can defeat him.
This is the moment you've been
moving towards all your life.
The entrance is
through the flames.
[HOWLING]
Daddy, help!
[CAROL ANNE SCREAMING]
This is an illusion!
The beast lies!
Go through the flames, now!
♪ God is
in his holy temple ♪
♪ earthly thoughts
be silent now ♪
♪ God is
in his holy temple ♪
♪ earthly thoughts
be silent now ♪
[HOWLING]
Take the Lance!
[SCREAMING]
No!
[HOWLING]
[SCREAMING]
No, don't go,
Carol Anne! No!
Baby, don't go!
[CAROL ANNE CRYING]
She's gone.
It's too late.
I've lost.
Dad, look!
Baby.
Oh!
Thank God!
Some battle, huh?
[ALL CHATTERING]
[E. BUZZ BARKING]
TAYLOR:
Uh, your car.
Yeah, well,
it's happy.
Not yet.
How are we going
to make it happy?
It wants to
come home with me.
You asked it?
Yes.
It's sure?
[KEYS JINGLING]
Ok, it's yours.
Take it.
[CAR DOOR OPENS]
[CAR DOOR SHUTS]
[ENGINE STARTING]
We thank you.
It started right up.
Bye, Taylor!
ROBBIE:
Dad, you gave our car away?
STEVE:
Yes.
DIANE: But, Steven, we have
no-- we need a ride home.
Taylor! Whoa!
My car needs me,
CHILDREN:
Taylor!
ALL:
Taylor! Wait for us!
STEVE:
My car likes me!