My name is Alice..
I worked for the Umbrella Corporation..
The largest and most powerful commercial entity in the world.
I was head of security at a secret
high tech facility called the Hive..
A giant underground laboratory
Developing experimental viral weaponry.
There was an incident, the virus escaped...
A lot of people died..
(Screams)
Trouble was.. they didn't stay dead.
The computer that controlled the Hive was a state of the art
artificial intelligence the Red Queen.
The Red Queen responded to the threat
Of the viral outbreak in an extreme way..
She went homicidal
(Red Queen)
You're all going to die down here.
The Red Queen attempted to kill everyone
Whether they were infected or not.
I managed to escape but this was only the beginning.
Viral outbreak spread like wildfire
First across the United States, then the world..
But the T virus didn't just bring the dead back to life..
It mutated them in terrifying ways.
Despite the apocalypse they had created the
Umbrella Corporation continued to experiment with the deadly virus
I was infected but the virus
Bonded with me on the cellular level..
I developed powers..
I became different..
Powerful..  Unstoppable..
As I got stronger the human race became weaker
I tried my best to lead what survivors I could find to safety,
But we were pursued relentlessly.
Even my friend Jill Valentine was
seized and brainwashed by Umbrella
Finally I confronted the head of the
Umbrella Corporation Albert Wesker..
He robbed me of my powers but
I still managed to defeat him.
At last we thought it was over..
We thought we had survived the horror..
But we were wrong.. Once again we found ourselves fighting..
For our lives
(Alice screams)
Rise and shine,
C'mon babe we're late, The alarm didn't go off.
Becky's not up yet, Ms. Anderson is gonna be pissed.
You know how they get when we
drop her off late at the school.
Babe!?  You all right babe?
Yeah...  I'll go get Becky.
I charged your batteries for you.
(Becky Signs "Thank you Dad")
Becky?  You know Ms. Anderson,
She wants you to speak while you sign.
Thank you daddy.
(Whispers) When you come back from school
I have a surprise for you.
I heard that.
The way these batteries are lasting less
and less we'll need to get some new ones.
- OK well I can pick some up on my way home.
- I'm going to be late.. again.
- Ah Shit!
- I'll get you another shirt from the bedroom..
- Someone picked up your dry cleaning yesterday.
- You know you're my little angel don't you?
- You're going to be late remember?
- Oh.. yeah
(Slaps Rear)
I'll get you that shirt.
Get Becky back.. Ahhh!
No!!
Help!! Help Us!!
(Becky Screams)
C'mon!
(Latch Opens, Ladder Extends)
(Zombie Growls)
Go! Go!!
No!!
(People screaming, Gunfire)
(Helicopter overhead, Sirens)
Wait!  Wait!!
What the hell is wrong with you?
C'mon get in the car!
(Zombie Snarls, Alice Screams)
- What's going on?
- Your guess is as good as mine.
- Why are these people doing this?
- Those things are not people..
Not anymo.. (Crash)
(Car Alarms Blaring)
Are you hurt?
Can you move?  OK.
(Alice Grunts)
Oh shit!!
(Alice Grunts and Locks Door)
- Mommy C'mon
- Go!!
(Zombie Snarls in Frustration)
(Mouths) "I Love You"
(Alice Screams)
(Alice Groans)
- Project Alice why did you turn against Umbrella?
- Jill is that you?
- What happened to Chris and Claire?
Where are the others from the ship?
(High Pitched Electrical Whine)
(Alice Screams in Pain)
Project Alice who do you work for?
- Project Alice who do you work for?
- Jill why are you doing this?
(High Pitched Electrical Whine)
(Alice Screams in Pain)
(Computer) Warning! Warning!
Unauthorized Computer Access!
Security System disabled,
central computer reboot in 2 minutes..
central computer reboot in 1 minute 50 seconds..
Security System disabled,
central computer reboot in 1 minute 40 seconds..
central computer reboot in 30 seconds..
Security System disabled,
central computer reboot in 20 seconds..
central computer reboot in 10 seconds..
Central computer rebooting..
(Jill Gasps)
Scramble all security teams and
Sweep the corridor with the laser grid.
(Glass Breaks)
(Computer) Standby.. Standby..
Tokyo sequence initialized
(Zombie Hisses)
(Zombie Snarls)
Oh yeah!
(Alice Gasps)
Don't!
- My name is..
- Ada Wong operative for the Umbrella Corporation..
One of Wesker's top agents..
I know exactly who and what you are..
Now the real question is..
why don't I just cancel your contract right now?
I don't work for Umbrella anymore,
and neither does Albert Wesker.
- I don't care.
- You can kill her if you like but
then you'll never know the truth
- Now be a good girl.
- Wesker!
Put down the knife. (Screen Shatters)
Oh and Alice?
How nice to see you again.
- How did she get out?
- She's obviously getting help..
- We have a traitor in this facility.
- Security Systems were shut down for 2 minutes ma'am.
- What about control?
- We still can't raise them.
(Ada) I executed everyone in this control room,
I enabled Wesker to hack the mainframe..
We shut down the Security Systems,
we let you out of that cell.
(Wesker)
We have to get you out of this facility
- So why do you want to help me?
- We need you, the human race faces extinction..
Our only hope for survival is for us to work together.
I'm not going anywhere until I know where we are
and what the hell is going on here.
- You're in the prime Umbrella testing facility.
- Explain Tokyo?
What you saw was just a detailed recreation,
nothing more
It goes on for a few city blocks that's all.
- I was outside.
- Were you?
- Saw the sky did you?
- It was night.
- Stars? the Moon?
- The testing floor is 300 feet high, the ceiling black..
It's usually night in there,
but isn't that when the monsters come out anyway?
- It was raining.
- Climate control, wind, rain,
They can even make it snow if they want to
Why build such a place?
Simple, the Umbrella Corporation derived
It's primary income from the sale of viral weaponry..
Something that's impossible to test in the real world.
They recreated the center of New York, simulated an outbreak,
showed it to the Russians and sold them the virus..
They simulated an outbreak in Moscow
and sold it to the Americans
- An outbreak in Tokyo.
- Sold it to the Chinese.
- An outbreak in China.
- Sold it to the Japanese.
Exactly!  Everyone had to have it,
The Umbrella Corporation built a new arms race..
Only this time it was biological rather than nuclear.
Highly profitable, and this is where it all happened.
This is Umbrella's greatest creation.
- The belly of the beast.
- So why don't we just get the hell out of here?
Stop!  Sun up is in less than 1 minute,
Why don't you just see for yourself.
This facility is located in the straits of
Kamchatka, Northern Russia
The old Soviet Union built submarine pens here in the 80s
After the Cold War ended the Umbrella Corporation
expanded them and built the testing floor.
No one has ever escaped from this facility.
- Ice!
- You'll need all the help you can get..
So I've arranged for a strike team
to enter from the surface and assist you.
There they are, intake vents for the Umbrella facility.
- Looks abandoned.
- That's what they want you to think.
Let's move!
We have just 2 hours to extract Alice and Ada..
After that we can expect heavy
Umbrella reinforcements.
Running a bypass.
These are the access codes Ada gave us.
- You trust her?
- Just enter the numbers.
- The charges are set.
- We're in!
Let's go do this.
- They're in.
- The strike team has secured an elevator for your escape to the surface.
They will eliminate Umbrella resistance,
Then rendezvous with us and escort us out
- They have a friend of yours with them.. Luther West
- He's Alive?
All right hold on ladies.
Synchronize watches, 2 hours exactly in..3..2..1..Mark!
Leon why don't we just trigger the explosives remotely?
Can't risk them jamming the signal,
Whether we succeed or not this facility has to be destroyed.
- What if we take longer than 2 hours?
- Well then I hope you're really good at holding your breath.
Security Chief Valentine has reached the Tokyo
test environment, she's tracking you.
They're headed this way.
Her orders are to recapture you if possible,
terminate you if necessary.
- Who's giving these orders?
- The Red Queen.
- the computer?
- Yes the same artificial intelligence you encountered in the Hive.
She now controls what remains
of the Umbrella Corporation,
She will stop at nothing to prevent
you escaping to the surface.
I've plotted an escape route for you..
You'll cross the New York environment..
To suburbia where you'll rendezvous
with the strike team..
They'll escort you through the
Moscow environment to the submarine pens..
And take the elevator back to the surface.
The Red Queen has intercepted my signal,
She's about to regain control of the facility..
You must hurry, I can't...
Don't listen to the traitor Wesker,
I am in control now.
Project Alice, Ada Wong stay where you are.
- Let's move
- Project Alice..
- You're all going to die down here!
- I've heard that before.
Defensive formation..
Lock your targets.. Fire at will.
Submarine pens are up ahead.
Barry, you and I take point.
We rendezvous with Alice and Ada in 30 minutes.
(Gunshots)
Clear!
- (Whistles) now that's some hardware!
- Typhoon Class, Biggest nuclear subs the Soviets ever built.
Umbrella used them to secretly
transport Bio weapons all over the globe.
Let's pick up the pace, we have less than 90 minutes.
(Red Queen)
Intruders detected, targeted for termination.
- New York.
- We need to cross two more test environments to escape.
- Let's move!
- Why would Umbrella continue to run these tests?
They want to study the biohazard, learn how to control it.
(Red Queen)
Initialize New York sequence, Activate biohazard.
(Computer) Standby! Standby!
New York sequence initialized!
The Red Queen!
She's activating bio weapons to stop us.
- Let's go!
- Wait!  You hear that?
(Axe Dragging)
- You know what it is?
- I have an idea.
You've got to be kidding me!
(Axemen Growl)
(Windshield Shatters, Ada Gasps)
(Gasoline Sloshes)
Hey boys..
Bad idea!
(Car Alarm Blares)
Let's move!  We're behind schedule.
- What's going on?
- It's the end of the sequence,
They rarely last more than an hour.
C'mon.. Before the Red Queen activates something else
(Red Queen) Target survived,
Security Chief Valentine to intercept.
Intruders entering Moscow test environment,
Activate Los Plagos undead.
- What's going on?
- The Red Queen knows we're here, keep your eyes open.
(Computer) Standby! Standby!
Moscow sequence initialized.
- What?
- Listen!
Right there!
What the hell are those things?
Fall back!  Everyone fall back!
- Clouds?
- They're not real, it's a holographic projection..
When they were running a simulation
Trust me no one was looking at the sky.
This is the rendezvous point,
the strike team is late, where are they?
Someone is in the house behind you..
Upstairs window.
Why would they be in here?
(Alice Huffs)
They're using clones of me.
- Of course! You were one of the 50 basic models.
- (Alice Huffs) Basic Models.
How do you think Umbrella
populates these test scenarios?
Hundreds of people dead
each time they run a simulation..
Umbrella imprints them with basic memories..
Just enough to ensure a correct emotional response
to the threat of the biohazard.
In one life she could be a suburban housewife,
the next a businesswoman in New York..
The next a soldier working for Umbrella.
(Upper Floor Creaks)
(Zombie Screeches)
Mommy! I hid like you told me.
What happened to your clothes
and your hair?
RPG.. Down!!
We're running out of time..
- You have to find as a way out now!
- Almost there!
- None of this is real.
- It is to her.
I know that's the point.
All these feelings she has for you, they were imprinted.
A day ago she was a blank slate,
I could show you a dozen just like her in cold storage.
I'm sorry, but it's true.
- Ready! I was fast wasn't I?
- Yes you were.
- Daddy?
- He's not your father.
(Red Queen)
Capture if possible, terminate if necessary.
- There's a child here.
- Your problem, not ours.
- All heart, you haven't changed a bit.
- I don't know you lady.
Now, surrender or die.
Get down!
Advance, B Team!
You can't stay here,
This will show you the way out..
Go through Moscow to the submarine pens, take this,
The less I have with me the better.
Alpha team forward!
They're coming we have to hurry, Go!
(Leon's Gun Jams)
I got it, this way!
- Hey!
- Wait she helped us, don't you remember?
You two made it..
I thought I was the only one that survived.
What is this place and why is everything in Russian?
And what's with the S&M Getup?
- You know how to use this?
- I campaigned for gun control.
No I don't think you understand,
I marched against the NRA.
Concentrate..
It's just like a camera, point and shoot.
Congratulations you're officially a bad ass!
(Loud Banging)
What the hell's going on here?
I'll explain when I get back,
Right now you have to keep her safe.
- You stay with her.
- You're going? You said you wouldn't leave.
Trust me OK?  What I say is true..
I'll come back for you.
- You promise?
- Trust me.
I love you.
Come on, she'll be back for you.
Gotta find a hiding place.
I met your sister,
She's not very nice.
Let's try hiding down here.
- This way!
- Let's move!
We can work our way around the... (Screams)
Waiting for a written invitation?
(Tires Squeal)
- Sweet ride!
- Well this is Moscow.
I heard gunfire,
Thought you might need some help.
- Where's Ada?
- I don't think she made it, I'm sorry.
- You saw her die?
- No.
She always has a plan.
Boys? You mind?
- Shall we?
- My pleasure.
(Luther Yells)
Let me know when you plan on doing that again.
Heads up!
(Alice Gasps)
Our little friend is back!
Oh Shit!
- Almost there.
- What are you going to do?
(Car Sizzles and Sputters)
- Is everyone OK?
- Yeah.
OK let's go.
Hello? You can come out! I'm back!
Where'd you find these guys?
- Who's this?
- I'm Becky.
- Hi Becky.
- This is my mom.
- Your mom? Oh!
- Long story.
22 minutes left.
- There's no going back the way we came.
- Yeah and we lost our map with Sergei.
I'm on it!
We can take this tunnel at the end there's a service shaft
That leads down to the submarine pens.
Let's go!
(Rubble Moves)
- How'd you end up working for Wesker?
- I don't work for him, things on the surface have changed.
Wesker said you knew of some weapon,
Something I could turn the tide for us
But I don't think I would've risked so much
for one person.
You're probably right.
This way!
The submarine pens are up above us.
C'mon move!
- The elevator platforms are up ahead.
- 11 minutes, we're gonna be OK.
- (Red Queen) Accessing power grid, dispatching biohazard.
Everybody get onboard!
Hold on!
Next stop menswear and sporting goods.
Get down!
- Barry what is it?
- I don't know.
- Where are you going?
- Somebody must have cut the power remotely.
Be strong,
I'm gonna keep you safe.
- Can you get it back online?
- Not without the access codes.
9 minutes..
Looks like we're going with plan B.
- What?
- There's a reason we planted those explosives.
(Squishing)
No!!!
(Neck Cracks)
Mommy!! (Screams) Mommy!!
(Barry Spits)
I feel like shit.
She's dead!
- What are you doing?
- She's alive, I'm going to get her.
- I didn't lose this many friends so you could just walk away.
- I plan on coming back.
Don't do this, you're more important than she is.
- That's where you're wrong.
- This is a mistake.
Get out of my way.
- Don't leave without me OK?
- Are you kidding? I'm going with you.
- Don't move, don't move.
- It's OK, go get her back.
You like that, Huh?
Fall back!
- Fall back to the elevator!
- You go, I'm gonna stay here awhile.
- Barry!
- When the countdown gets to zero you have to be on that elevator.
Someone's gotta stay here Leon..
Besides I'm kind of enjoying myself.
- Go, go!
- C'mon!
(Squishing)
(Paw Slams Down)
(Body Slams)
(Alice Grunts with Effort)
Go!
Bring out the prisoner!
Cease your firing or I'll execute her.
Now, put down your guns and step out.
Step out or she dies.
(Alice Gasps)
Mommy who are they?
Mommy is that you?
(Licker Screeches)
- You're my mommy aren't you?
- I am now!
(Becky Screams)
(Bomb Beeps)
What's going on?
What the hell is that?
- Becky are you hurt?
- No I'm OK.
Told you she'd have a plan.
- Only the two of you?
- It'll be enough.
The Los Plagos parasite.
(Alice Chokes)
(Red Queen)
Terminate Project Alice.
(Extinguisher Hits Evil Rain)
(Luther's Bones Shatter, Heart Stops)
(Alice's Ribs Crack)
Alice!!
- You can't kill me.
- I don't need to.
(Bites Flank)
- I'm coming for you.
- Good luck with that.
(Evil Rain Screams)
Leon..
(Helicopter)
- What is it?
- It's help.
- Glad to have you back.
(Jill Giggles)
(Indistinct Conversations)
Wesker..
I see you've made your self at home.
Well I must say it does have a certain ease to it.
(Alice Yells)
What is this?
What have you done to me?
You were the only one to
successfully bond with the T virus..
To fully realize her powers,
well now I have need of you, the old you..
So I've given you back your gift..
You ARE the weapon.
- I'm gonna kill you.
- Perhaps..
But first you have work to do.
The Red Queen is determined
to destroy all life on earth..
This is the last that remain of us,
Of the human race..
It seems we're bonded against a common foe,
This is why we needed you back,
The ultimate weapon..
This is humanity's last stand, the beginning of the end.
(Captioned by ScorpioM)