[Music]
[ROARS]
[SCREAMS]
[CROWD SCREAMING]
[Music]
WOMAN:
My name is Alice.
I worked for Umbrella Corporation
in a secret laboratory
developing experimental viral weaponry.
There was an incident.
A virus escaped.
Everybody died.
Trouble was...
...they didn't stay dead.
This was the start of an apocalypse
that would sweep the entire world.
The men responsible for this
disaster took refuge underground
and continued to experiment
with the deadly T-Virus.
They felt secure
in their high-tech fortress.
But they were wrong.
[Music]
[GUNSHOT]
[IN JAPANESE]
Biohazard terminated.
Central Shibuya.
Confirm?
[MAN IN JAPANESE OVER RADIO]:
I confirm.
Nice shooting.
And I lead three to one.
TOSHI:
The night is young.
Plenty more fish in the--
[TOSHI SCREAMS]
Toshi, are you okay?
Toshi, where are you?
[SPEAKS IN JAPANESE]
[WHOOSH]
[SOLDIER YELLS]
[Music]
[MAN SPEAKING IN JAPANESE OVER PA]
[IN JAPANESE]
Sentry three respond.
We lost contact with another one.
OFFICER: Chairman Wesker.
WESKER: Report.
Sir, a half-hour ago,
we began to lose contact
with some of our perimeter sentries.
How many have we lost?
All of them.
And you waited 30 minutes to tell me?
We thought it was a communications
problem. I didn't want to disturb you.
Give me the surface gate.
[MAN SPEAKING IN JAPANESE OVER COMPUTER]
This is Chairman Wesker.
[MAN OVER COMPUTER]: Sir.
WESKER:
Report your situation.
Everything is quiet here.
No sign of intruders?
[STATIC BUZZES]
Hotaka.
OFFICER: We have movement.
Multiple targets.
WESKER:
Surface gate, identify targets.
Repeat, identify targets.
[IN ENGLISH]
Sir, Elevator 2 is moving.
I want security at that entrance.
[Music]
[GRUNTING]
[GUNS COCK]
[Music]
[GUNSHOTS]
Hey, boys.
Is that any way to treat a Lady?
[ALARM WAILING]
Tell security to flood the
main entrance with nerve gas.
Sir, our men are still up there.
Any more questions?
Intruders in Sectors 1 through 5,
7 and 8.
Reports of gunfire
in Sectors 10 and 11.
[EXPLOSION]
Stay at your stations.
All security protocols
are now in full effect.
Lock down all elevators.
Seal all internal blast doors.
And I want damage reports.
[Music]
[SOLDIER YELLS]
[SOLDIERS SHOUTING IN JAPANESE]
[Music]
[BEEPING]
ALICE 1:
Come on, move.
ALICE 2: Go, go. Everybody--
ALICE 3: Get out.
COMPUTERIZED VOICE:
Turbulence. Turbulence. Turbulence.
Turbulence. Turbulence.
Turbulence. Turb--
[Music]
Any last words?
[GASPS]
How nice to finally meet the real you.
Hurts, doesn't it?
Well, that's just the start
of the bad news.
All those powers of yours:
Speed, strength, accelerated healing.
Well, you can kiss all those goodbye.
What have you done?
The serum I have injected you with is
neutralizing the T cells within your body.
Put simply...
the Umbrella Corporation
is taking back its property.
You just didn't work out,
so you're being recalled.
[ALICE GRUNTING]
[Music]
I am what you used to be.
Only better.
Please wait.
Last words?
Thank you.
For killing you?
For making me human again.
[ALARM WAILING]
COMPUTERIZED VOICE:
Pull up. Terrain. Terrain.
[COUGHING AND GRUNTING]
MAN: This is Arcadia, broadcasting
on the emergency frequency.
There is no infection.
We offer safety and security,
food and shelter.
This is Arcadia, broadcasting
on the emergency frequency.
There is no infection.
[Music]
ALICE:
While I took revenge on Umbrella,
the last handful of survivors
took a chopper to safety.
They were headed for a town
in Alaska called Arcadia.
We'd received radio transmissions from there.
They offered food and shelter,
safety and security.
A haven, free of infection.
May 3rd, 1600 hours.
A hundred and seventy-seven days
without signs of life.
I am at 58.37 degrees north,
134.58 degrees west.
Closing in on the coordinates for
Arcadia, but no signs of it on any map.
I hope Claire and the others made it.
[Music]
You're not coming?
Take care of the others.
Good luck, K-Mart.
Claire.
[HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
May 3rd.
1930 hours.
Arcadia.
No such place exists.
Just an empty field.
And a beach.
But we all heard the transmissions.
Someone must have sent them.
Someone must have brought
all these people here.
But why?
And where did they go?
Day 177. Signing off.
I don't know
if I can do this much longer.
What if I am the last one?
What if there is no one else?
No one to watch these tapes.
Is this my punishment
for letting all this happen?
[Music]
Hey. Wait.
Wait, please. Stop.
Hello.
Hello?
Answer me.
[CAWING]
[GRUNTING]
ALICE:
Hey, hey.
It's okay.
Sorry about that.
But I had to get this thing off of you.
What is this?
Who did this to you?
Do you even know who I am?
My name is Alice.
We met in the Nevada desert 18 months ago.
Any of this sound familiar?
Mikey, Carlos, L.J.?
K-Mart?
You left in a helicopter
with a group of survivors
headed for Alaska.
Arcadia, remember?
ALICE [ON RECORDING]:
[Music]
ALICE:
May 4th, 0800 hours.
Potting a course for Prince Rupert
in British Columbia.
I will pass Vancouver,
drop down to Seattle.
After that, it's San Francisco and
the rest of the Western seaboard.
[SIGHS]
My passenger is still as talkative as ever.
Whatever that thing was,
it was injecting her
with some sort of drug.
Something that causes memory loss.
I just hope the effects aren't permanent.
CLAIRE:
Your name...
is Alice, right?
ALICE:
She speaks.
Look, I am sorry about back there.
I don't know what happened.
I don't remember anything.
I don't even know my name.
It's Claire.
Claire Redfield.
Claire?
Sound familiar?
Not really.
You will get used to it.
Perhaps you can cut me loose now.
We should get to know each other
a little better first.
[Music]
City of Angels.
May 6th, 1800 hours, Los Angeles.
No signs of life.
Not even the undead.
Some must have burnt with the city.
But what about the rest?
Oh, my God.
CLAIRE:
What?
Look over there.
Damn.
[SIREN WAILING]
BENNETT:
It's a plane.
I knew it.
I told you they would come.
Hey, we're down here. Hello.
[GROWLING AND SNARLING]
No way we're getting in there.
Where is he going?
Why is he flying away?
It's not flying away.
It's circling. Circling?
Damn, he's low.
Down.
What the hell is he doing?
He's going to land.
Get the stuff out of the way.
Land?
Yeah.
Land.
That is one crazy son of a bitch.
[Music]
This may get a little rough.
Then cut me loose.
Thanks.
Just don't do anything crazy, all right?
Nothing as crazy
as what you have in mind.
Come on, Kim, move it.
I am trying.
Well, try.
All right, hold on.
Hurry, he's coming.
Come on.
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[GROWLING]
[YELLS]
Come on, pull it. Come on.
Come on, pull.
LUTHER:
Good. Good.
Good work.
That's it.
Good job.
[Music]
Nice landing.
I think technically it's called crashing.
Luther West.
Alice. That's Claire.
Luther West. A pleasure
to make your acquaintance.
Hi, my name's Crystal.
BENNETT: No, no.
Enough with the introductions.
So you're here to help us, right?
Can you get us out?
You from Arcadia?
What did you say?
Are you from Arcadia?
What do you know about Arcadia?
KIM: They said they'd help.
CRYSTAL: There are survivors.
Civilization and safety.
Infection free.
So they sent you, right?
No.
But there are others out there like you?
It's just us.
There's to be no rescue?
I am sorry.
[SCOFFS]
Sorry.
Look, don't take it so bad.
They had their hopes up and...
Thought you could take them
to the promised land.
Angel Ortiz.
That was some fine flying.
Thanks.
What's the prognosis?
She will live.
Yeah.
You know,
I have the strangest feeling
I know you.
[CHUCKLES]
Yeah, I get that a lot.
You're a sports fan, huh?
Do you like basketball?
Not really.
No? Oh.
Well, maybe just a fan
of fine timepieces.
Yeah.
Luther here is our resident superstar.
So tell me about Arcadia.
What exactly do you know?
Just from their transmissions.
We have been receiving
their broadcast all week.
Food and shelter, safety
and security, no infection.
We thought they sent you.
We have been launching flares
for days to get their attention.
Flares?
LUTHER: Yeah.
Who's going to see flares from Alaska?
Alaska?
Arcadia. I have been there.
It's in Alaska.
It's a town, or so we thought.
A town?
I don't think so.
Take a look.
At what?
ANGEL:
You see?
It's not a town.
It's a ship.
ANGEL:
I recorded this from the shortwave.
MAN [ON RECORDING]: This is
Arcadia, on the emergency frequency.
There is no infection.
We offer safety and security,
food and shelter.
It's the same message we heard.
They must have salled down the
coast, picking up survivors.
This is Arcadia, broadcasting
on the emergency frequency.
[STATIC BUZZES THEN HISSES ON RECORDING]
What is that?
I don't know.
That was the last we heard from them.
Then it just stopped.
That was two days ago.
We have been sending up flares
on the hour.
So when you arrived, of course,
we thought they sent you.
ALICE:
Claire.
That ship over there.
That's Arcadia.
I know.
You remember?
I remember the beach.
People were coming to help us.
What happened?
Why didn't you go with the others?
I don't know.
I can't remember.
ALICE [ON RECORDING]:
We have to get to that ship.
[FLARE HISSING]
[GROWLING AND GRUNTING]
[RUSTLING]
[THUDS]
Welcome to your new home,
cell block B.
Crystal's our cook.
The menu's not extensive,
but she is a master of what she does.
Sorry I didn't bring better news.
Get used to disappointment, right?
That's what my agent used to say.
Were you an actress?
I came to Hollywood,
ended up waiting tables.
Why are we waiting? Excuse
me. I am hungry. Thank you.
Get out of here, man.
BENNETT: Thank you.
I met plenty of creeps
like him in my time.
What's his story?
Back in the world, he was some
kind of big movie producer.
The boy's got a stick up his ass.
Kim Yong used to intern for him. Still
hasn't figured the world has changed.
That plane,
do you think it could still fly?
It can fly, but it only seats two.
So take us to Arcadia one at a time.
Look, I think she was lucky
to land here once.
Five or six times would be suicide.
No offence.
None taken.
There has to be another way out.
We have to get to that ship.
Well, there is the--
[LUTHER CLEARS THROAT]
What?
Nothing.
Look, it would be a waste of your time.
I have time to waste.
LUTHER: When the shit hit the
fan, we took refuge in the prison.
It seemed like it had
the biggest, strongest walls.
The best chance
of keeping those things out.
By the time we got here, the guards
and the inmates were already long gone.
I guess when people
started eating one another,
there wasn't much point
in keeping anybody locked up.
We thought the place was abandoned,
until we made a discovery.
Wendell,
time to take a break.
It's about god-damn time.
I hate being down here.
I am hearing movement in the walls.
So let's check it out.
I will be back in a minute.
Come on.
[Music]
Name's Chris.
You were the one flying that plane.
How do you know that?
Wendell isn't the only one that hears things.
I am glad you made it.
Maybe you can talk some sense
into these people.
What do you mean?
Isn't it obvious?
I am not a prisoner.
I shouldn't be in here.
CHRIS:
I was working with a military unit.
We were using this place as a staging post.
Things were already bad when the order
came through to release all the inmates.
We needed as many people on the streets
as possible to fight those things.
And it was chaos.
We were pulling out and a gang
of the prisoners jumped me.
I guess they thought I was a guard.
I woke up, my unit was gone.
I was in here.
Their idea of a joke.
You don't believe me.
Do the others?
You need to get me out of here.
We're all trapped here.
That's true.
But I can help you.
LUTHER:
Seen enough?
ALICE: You find anything?
No.
CHRIS:
I know a way out of this place.
If you get me out of here,
I will do the same for you.
You're going to need me.
Have you checked
what he's talking about?
His way out?
He's not telling us shit till we let
him out. And I am not letting him out.
The man is a killer.
Really?
I can see it in his eyes.
How can you be so sure?
I know people.
Interesting.
So tell me.
What do you see
when you look into my eyes?
LUTHER:
Whoa.
Holy shit.
Girl's got to be prepared.
What would you possibly want with those?
It's a hobby.
A hobby?
All right.
Well, I will see you in the morning.
[Music]
CLAIRE:
No sign of anyone on deck.
Your friends are out there?
I think so.
You don't remember?
It's coming back.
Slowly.
Nothing that makes any sense.
[TILES CLATTERING]
[SCRAPING IN DISTANCE]
[SCRATCHING]
[THUDS]
[Music]
[GROWLING]
LUTHER:
We still have running water.
ALICE:
That's very civilized.
We do our best.
It's cold.
Our best only goes so far.
These are for you.
Thank you.
I guess I should leave you to it.
I guess you should.
I will be right outside.
Thank you.
[TILE CLATTERS]
Luther?
[CLATTERING]
Take it easy, honey. Move it.
Okay, I am just going to
be on my way now.
Okay, take it easy.
Take it easy.
Get out of my sight.
[Music]
BENNETT:
What is that smell?
Must have burrowed up from the sewers.
LUTHER:
Wendell said he heard things moving.
What? So these things
can just burst out anywhere?
We got to get out of this place.
Arcadia will send help.
No one's coming to get us.
Okay? No one.
We have to help ourselves.
This plane that you have.
Won't hold everybody.
Well, we can draw straws.
ALICE: No.
We all get out of here
and no one gets left behind.
Great.
How are we going to do that?
Walk out of here,
just single file?
BENNETT:
Are you crazy?
They didn't want him getting out.
BENNETT: He's dangerous.
Angel, what do you think?
I think we don't have much of a choice.
This is insane.
Crystal, Crystal, look
at me. What do you think?
I mean, not even you're that dumb.
I guess I am. I agree with Angel.
If this guy thinks he knows
a way out, I want to hear it.
All right.
BENNETT:
Seriously?
This is a mistake.
This is a big mistake.
You better keep your eyes on him.
I was wondering
how long it would take.
Boo.
I--
all right,
let's get the hell out of here.
Claire?
What?
Claire, it's me.
It's Chris.
I don't know you.
CHRIS:
Claire.
I am your brother, remember?
What the hell's happened to you?
It's okay.
Let him go.
Look, she suffered
some sort of memory loss.
If you really are her brother,
it will come back.
All right, this is very touching.
I mean the family reunion.
If we could just get a move on, please,
before we're all eaten the fuck alive.
[Music]
CHRIS: Behind those doors is a
UPV, urban pacification vehicle.
The prison kept it
in case of a serious riot.
Sixteen-wheeler, steel plate,
water cannon. It seats 20.
Ten tons of fun.
We roll on out in style,
drive right over them.
The lock's jammed.
But we can cut through it.
When we hit the coast,
we have to transfer to a boat.
We're going to need more fire-power.
CHRIS: I got you covered.
When I was stationed here,
we used the basement as an armoury.
It's got every weapon you can dream of.
How do you know your unit
didn't take them with them?
Because by the end
there were more guns than
there were people to use them.
[METAL CRASHES]
You go get the guns. Luther.
Oh, my God.
What is this?
They had pumps to keep the
water out of the foundations.
When the electricity failed,
some of the lower levels
started filling up.
There's another two floors down there.
And how far down is the armoury?
All the way.
Luther, come on.
Get back. Get back.
Where do you think you're going?
I was a swim champ back in high school.
Is that right?
Here.
You're going to trust me with a gun?
Yeah. Why not?
Luther, just shoot that mother-fucker.
What the fuck is that thing?
[Music]
all right.
Let's go.
[CRYSTAL SCREAMS]
[Music]
ALICE:
Let's go.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
[UNDEAD GROWLING]
Nice.
[Music]
ANGEL:
Damn.
[UNDEAD POUNDING ON DOOR AND GROWLING]
CHRIS: There must be
hundreds of them out there.
We can't go back that way.
Oh, shit.
What do you mean, "oh, shit"?
What--?
What is this?
What do you think it is?
Don't tell me that thing
fits inside of there.
Can you put this back together?
Maybe, but it could take a week.
What do we do now?
I know.
Bennett,
what have you done?
Luther,
we got to get out of here. Come on.
[ENGINE STARTS]
ALICE:
Did you hear that?
Come on, baby. Come on.
What are we doing?
Getting out.
But the others.
Fuck the others.
Now, get on-board.
LUTHER:
Bennett, what are you doing?
CLAIRE: Hey.
Kim Yong. Don't do this.
Open this door.
Bennett, please.
LUTHER:
Bennett.
Oh, shit.
That's right, bitch. Fuck you.
Yes. Yes.
Son of a bitch.
I am sorry.
I am so sorry.
He's headed for the Arcadia.
[ROARING]
Alice.
[Music]
Come on.
Head for the shower block.
Move.
I will meet you there.
This thing has no power.
We won't need power.
Oh, shit.
Hold on.
LUTHER: Hey, head to
the shower block. Go.
[Music]
Over here.
Are you all right?
I am fine. Thanks.
This is some kind of joke, right?
The tunnels lead to the sewers,
the sewers lead to the storm drain.
This storm drain leads to the sea.
It's our only chance.
I will take point.
LUTHER:
I got your back.
Ladies.
All right, you're next.
I can't do it.
You can.
Let's go.
[Music]
[GUNSHOTS]
[GUN CLICKING]
[Music]
CLAIRE: Aah.
Shh.
[WHISPERING]
Those things are close.
We found a way out just down there.
The tunnels drop into a storm drain.
Go. Be careful.
Where's Kim Yong?
Go. Go.
I knew you'd make it.
Luther.
LUTHER:
Help.
Luther.
You can't help him now.
We have to move on.
[Music]
No welcome party,
huh?
It looks like Bennett made it.
Let's check inside.
Did you find anyone?
Nothing.
CHRIS: I checked the crew
quarters. They're all gone.
Looks like they left in a hurry.
MAN [ON RECORDING]: This is Arcadia,
broadcasting on the emergency frequency.
There is no infection. We offer
safety and security, food and shelter.
Fuel, power,
everything's running normally.
Look at this.
It's the ship's log.
The crew launched
the lifeboats three days ago.
Exactly when the transmissions stopped.
CHRIS: But it says there are
still 2000 survivors on-board.
We have to search
every inch of this ship.
Umbrella.
Of course.
I remember them coming for us.
This whole thing, Arcadia, was a lie.
No, it's worse than that.
It's a trap.
Where is everybody?
I don't understand.
I think I do.
They're underneath our feet.
CLAIRE: They're holding
survivors to experiment on them.
Look.
It's K-Mart. She's here.
ALICE:
Bring them up.
All of them.
[Music]
CLAIRE:
Here she is.
K-Mart.
Get her out.
[K-MART GASPS]
K-Mart, it's okay.
It's okay.
K-Mart, it's all right.
I will get this off her.
Let everyone out.
We're your friends.
Right now, we need your help.
Let me get this off you.
[Music]
[DOOR CLOSES]
Why am I not surprised?
You weren't too hard to find.
Our satellite system is still operational.
And there aren't too many people
flying nowadays.
And besides, I always knew
you'd be drawn to your friends.
Loyalty,
highly overrated.
[SNARLING]
Stop.
Down.
Wouldn't want you harming my pets.
Drop your guns.
Thank you.
Kick them to me.
Good.
You don't look so good, Bennett.
Yeah, I am looking forward
to playing with your pretty face.
What do you want from me?
The T-Virus brought me back.
But it's so strong.
It fights me for control.
I thought if I ingested fresh human DNA,
I could redress the balance.
No wonder your crew abandoned ship.
WESKER:
No matter.
Now I have a new subordinate.
And a new plan.
You were the only one who
successfully bonded with the T-Virus.
Your DNA is stronger than the others.
I ingest you,
I gain control.
That's pretty smart thinking.
There's only one problem with that plan.
Stop right there.
And what is that?
I am not on the menu.
[Music]
[GROWLING]
well, isn't this
one big family reunion?
Chris and Claire Redfield.
You have really become quite
an inconvenience for me.
I told you
I'd be bringing a few friends.
You should have brought more.
[Music]
[GROWLING]
[WESKER GRUNTS]
Claire. Claire.
Chris.
[GASPS]
[ALICE GRUNTING]
[Music]
Don't even think about it.
Who the fuck are you?
[Music]
[GRUNTING]
I don't think so.
[Music]
Don't-- Don't you shut them.
I am a producer.
BENNETT [OVER INTERCOM]:
Open those doors.
You are going to deal with
some serious consequences.
You mother-fuckers.
Open the--
You're going to live to regret this,
all of you.
[SLITHERING]
Oh, God.
I just want to go home.
[BENNETT SCREAMS]
Hey,
it's going to be okay.
[ENGINE WHIRRING]
No.
Chris. Alice.
[Music]
[GUNFIRE]
[GUN CLICKING]
[BONES CRACKING]
Come on.
[DEVICE BEEPING]
[GASPS]
I didn't want you to miss that.
Oh, heh, heh.
[UNDEAD GROWLING]
LUTHER:
That's right.
Star power, bitches.
[Music]
It's a miracle.
I never dreamed there would
be this many of us left alive.
So, what's next?
MAN [ON RECORDING]: This is Arcadia,
broadcasting on the emergency frequency--
[RECORDING CLICKS OFF]
I say...
we live up to the promise.
This is Arcadia, broadcasting
on the emergency frequency.
Location 118.30 degrees west,
34.05 degrees north.
[OVER SPEAKER]
There is no infection.
Repeat, there is no infection.
We offer safety and security,
food and shelter.
If you are out there,
we will help you.
There is hope.
[Music]
What is that?
Trouble.
[A PERFECT CIRCLE'S "THE OUTSIDER
(APOCALYPSE REMIX)" PLAYS]
JILL:
Deployment in T-minus 57 seconds.
When you hit the deck,
you watch your formation.
Take no prisoners and shoot to kill.
Total enemy numbers are unknown
but will include Umbrella fugitives
and prime targets.
Claire Redfield, Chris Redfield
and Project Alice.
So, people,
whatever's waiting for you out there,
just know one thing:
You are going to be in for the fight
of your lives.
[Music]
ALICE:
Hey, boys.
Is that any way to treat a lady?