Perfection.
[URINATlNG]
[BATHROOM DOOR OPENS]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHlNG]
Hey, asshole, this is the ladies' room.
What the fuck are you doing, dickhead?
Get the fuck out of here.
If you don't get your ass out of here,
I'm gonna start screaming.
Understand? Ah!
[SHAKING AND BANGING ON DOOR]
Oh, God, please!
[SHAKING AND BANGING STOPS]
What the fuck?
[FOOTSTEPS WALKING AWAY]
[BATHROOM DOOR OPENS
AND CLOSES]
Ow!
What the hell? What the fuck? Get off--
Ah!
NICOLE:
Grandpa used to say...
...everybody's got their own
private demon.
For him, it was the war he fought
in Vietnam.
For Grandma, l guess it was Grandpa...
...and all the shit he put her through.
For my mom and dad...
...what's their private demon?
I guess that'd be me.
[CAR HORN HONKS]
NICOLE:
Shh! You'll wake them. God.
JESS: Get in.
-Jess.
-You're an asshole.
-l love you too.
JESS: Say goodbye to Texas.
NICOLE: Goodbye, Texas.
JESS:
What the hell is that?
I won it riding when l was 1 1 .
It's good luck.
-l bet your mom gave it to you.
-So fucking what?
Don't take it down.
JESS: You're not calling your parents.
-But l wanna call them.
JESS:
Jesus, you don't.
-They'll worry.
-That's the fucking point.
I don't want them to worry.
That's exactly your fucking problem.
You don't run away from home,
then tell your parents you're okay.
Why not?
They'll talk you out of it. That's why.
JESS: See, it's the manager
who watches out for your ass.
NICOLE:
Uh-huh.
Because you take the wrong part,
you get typecast, you're dead.
NICOLE:
Uh-huh.
Fuck you.
NICOLE: "You get typecast, you're dead."
JESS: Stop.
NICOLE:
Whoo!
JESS:
Yes!
Every actor has to do a nude scene
at least once.
-Yeah, right.
-Right.
Any nude scene you do...
...better be with me.
-Okay, then.
NICOLE:
So you wanna do a nude scene?
JESS:
Okay.
[LAUGHlNG]
-Oh, is it ready?
-Yeah.
It's ready. Yeah, it's ready.
Oh, Nic.
NICOLE:
No, don't take the blanket.
JESS: lt's fucking cold out there.
NICOLE: Well, tough shit.
JESS:
You gotta be fucking kidding me.
[NlCOLE LAUGHS]
[JESS MOANlNG AND SHlVERlNG]
JESS:
Ow! Fuck.
Oh....
JESS:
I understand, man.
It's cool.
Yeah. Okay.
See you.
What'd he say?
When we get to L.A.,
we're not gonna stay with my cousin.
-Why not?
-lt's his wife.
She's sick or something.
-They don't really have the room.
-Well, where are we gonna live?
JESS: l'll figure something out.
-Figure something out?
I'm not gonna be
a fucking homeless person.
-Don't worry, okay?
-God.
Just don't worry.
[BEEPlNG]
NICOLE: Great. Damn.
-What are you doing?
Nicole, what are you doing?
You wanna be a fucking baby
your whole life?
[TlRES SCREECH]
JESS: Son of a bitch.
-Jess, come on. Please, don't.
Hey!
-Asshole!
-Jesse, let's just go.
[TlRES SCREECH]
NICOLE: Let's go!
JESS: Fuck!
You okay?
It's okay. Come here.
You okay, huh? Come here, it's over.
[ENGINE STARTS]
NICOLE: l don't even see this road.
It's not on the map.
We're still heading west. lt'll be faster.
Not if we run out of gas.
-l'll take care of it.
-Right. We're lost.
-No, we're not.
-Yes, we are.
Who's being the fucking baby now?
I gotta pee.
-Again?
-Yes, again.
JESS: All right. l'll pull over.
-l'm not gonna pee in the dirt.
-Why the hell not?
-There's snakes out there.
And it doesn't make me a fucking baby.
Just find a bathroom.
-This is nice.
-l told you to pee in the dirt.
Oh, my God.
Ugh.
[SIGHS]
[URINATlNG]
NICOLE:
Ew.
[CLANGlNG]
NICOLE:
Rats. That would be fucking perfect.
Jess?
Jess? What the hell?
Damn it.
Jess?
Not funny. This is not funny.
You're not scaring me.
Shit. Jess, you're an asshole.
[BEEPlNG]
Great.
[TRUCK ENGINE RUMBLING]
You're perfectly normal.
Great. Fuck.
Yes. Okay.
Fuck!
You son of a bitch, Jess.
NICOLE:
Hello?
Excuse me. Hello? ls anybody in there?
Guess l'm not walking.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLlCKS]
NICOLE:
Hey. Hello?
Excuse me? Hello, l need help.
Please, I'm stuck here.
Asshole.
NICOLE:
Jesse?
Jesse, l love you.
But maybe you should take me home.
Maybe this was a mistake.
"Don't be such a fucking baby."
Jess.
Are you my private demon?
[TRUCK ENGINE RUMBLING]
NICOLE:
Ah!
No.
Where is he, huh?
What did you do to him?
NICOLE:
"Fucker cut me, killed my husband."
"There's no escape."
"KZL 303."
Oh, my God.
Son of a bitch.
Fuck.
[THUMP]
Come on, don't be a fucking baby.
[GRUNTS]
Ah! Fuck.
[GROANS]
Okay. Okay.
Radio.
Ugh.
Okay.
Come on.
Turn on.
[STATIC HISSlNG FROM CB RADlO]
Mayday, mayday.
Is anybody out there? Hello?
Please. I need help.
I'm stranded in a rest stop.
There's this crazy guy in a truck.
I think he may be hurting my boyfriend.
And l think he's trying to hurt me.
[STATIC HISSlNG FROM CB RADlO]
[CRYING]
Stop....
Okay, okay, okay.
Okay.
Calm down. Okay, okay, okay.
Why the fuck not?
[CLICK]
["AMAZING GRACE"
PLAYlNG ON RADIO]
Oh, my God.
[CLICK]
[MOANlNG AND GROANING ON TV]
JESS [ON TV]:
Oh, Nic.
[MOANlNG AND GROANING ON TV]
MAN [OVER CB RADlO]:
Call back, mayday. Call back, mayday.
Call back, mayday.
Got a copy? You hear me?
Hello, hello? Help me, please.
Hold on there, sweetheart.
Give me your 20-- Your location, copy?
I'm at a rest stop in California.
Off something called
the Old Highway, l think. Copy?
You in some kind of trouble?
Yeah, some fucking psycho
is fucking with me.
Now, ma'am, try to avoid
foul language on the air.
Sorry, copy.
I'm riding an 1 8-wheeler
down the interstate, must be...
...oh, a couple hundred
miles from you...
...but I can radio state police,
l can tell them where you are.
Please, please do.
l'll be more than happy to, ma'am.
But one thing: they get there
and this is some kind of prank....
No, no way. This is no prank.
Okay then. Now, you just sit tight.
Thank you so much.
What's your name?
Jesse.
That's my boyfriend's name.
Well, if you're as cute as you sound,
he's a lucky man.
Now, l better get the police on the horn.
You take care. Out.
[CHUCKLES]
[CHANGING STATIONS]
["ALL THAT REMAlNS"
PLAYS ON THE RADlO]
[SPlTTING AND GAGGlNG]
[SOBBlNG AND MUTTERING]
[THUMP]
Jess.
Okay.
NICOLE:
Oh, thank God.
Oh, God.
Oh, Jess.
[CRYING]
I'll get help.
[ENGINE STALLING]
Fuck.
Son of a bitch, what did you do
to the car? You son of a bitch!
[TRUCK ENGINE RUMBLING]
Ah!
Fuck you, you fucker!
You just wait.
You got a big surprise coming,
you piece of shit.
[NlCOLE'S VOlCE OVER SPEAKER]
I'm at a rest stop in California.
Off something
called the Old Highway, l think.
No.
-What's your name?
-Jesse.
No!
-That's my boyfriend's name.
-No!
Well, if you're as cute as you sound,
he's a lucky man.
What do you want from me?
["AMAZING GRACE"
PLAYlNG OVER SPEAKER]
What do you want from me,
you son of a bitch?
Come on!
[ENGINE REVS]
[CRYING]
[MOANS]
[ENGINE STARTS]
NICOLE:
Wait. Wait. Please.
[HORN HONKS]
Thank you so much
for giving me a ride.
Quite a hot day today.
A real scorcher.
Look, you really saved me.
I mean, this guy--
Hot night too.
We don't often get those here.
Nights are usually colder
than a well-digger's--
Well, you know.
Can l--? Can I use your phone?
I gotta call the police.
Know what l do sometimes
on a hot night?
Probably shouldn't say it
in front of the boys.
Sometimes...
...l slip into the ladies' room
and l'll slip off my control tops.
[WOMAN CHUCKLES]
[LAUGHlNG]
I think this guy has my boyfriend.
I-- Look, I really need to call the police.
One summer,
our little fridge broke down.
Oh, everything melted.
You couldn't imagine the mess.
Raspberry popsicles all over.
-Listen--
-Looked like blood.
You saw what happened.
We didn't see anything.
No, I'm talking about the truck.
That yellow truck.
That guy tried to kill me.
We don't know anything
about a yellow truck.
What are you talking about?
It was right in front of you.
He totaled our car.
So where are you guys from?
Where do you think?
[WOMAN LAUGHING]
So you move from place to place.
It must be nice.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLlCKS]
Is there somebody back there?
[MAN GRUNTING]
Is that Jess?
Is that him? ls that my boyfriend?
-Oh, my God.
-Mind your own business.
Don't you dare look.
Jesse? Jess, is that you?
Don't you dare!
[TlRES SCREECH]
-Jess!
-Don't you dare!
NICOLE:
Jesse! Jess!
WOMAN:
Don't let her get to him! Get her away!
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLlCKS]
Oh, my God.
WOMAN: Don't let her get to him!
Get her away from him!
Bring her back here.
You fucking whore!
Who do you think you are?
Leave Scotty alone.
-Sorry.
WOMAN: You'll get what you deserve.
Everything you deserve,
you fucking whore.
My boyfriend, Jess-- l thought--
I think he's hurt and l thought--
You thought?
You thought you were free?
Free to do as you please.
Free to sin as you please.
-Let me tell you, missy...
WOMAN: You whore!
-...the Lord sees all.
WOMAN: You fucking whore!
MAN: He see your filthy, disgusting ways.
WOMAN: You whore!
-You whore!
-And he sent his angels.
His angel of punishment
to exact his vengeance.
Stop it. Stop it. Stop it!
MAN:
Read your Bible, little missy.
And Moses, upon reaching heaven...
...came upon the Lord's angels
of punishment.
Af, the angel of anger.
Kezef, the angel of wrath.
Hemah, the angel of fury.
Mashhit, the angel of destruction.
These were the seraphim.
The fire angels sent by the Lord
to smite the sinner.
To scorch their souls.
You're so fucking crazy.
Shut up, you whore!
[TlRES SCREECH]
WOMAN:
You fucking whore!
You whore!
NICOLE:
Fucking assholes!
What a bunch of weirdoes.
God.
And that kid in the back,
what a freak.
Stupid camera. Jesus Christ.
"He followed me. l don't know why.
September, 1 992."
"KZL 303 after me. '86."
"He's gonna kill me. 1 971 ."
1 971 ?
It's gonna be okay.
Oh, fuck you. Fuck you.
Fuck! Fuck you.
GIRL:
Hey?
Hello?
Is somebody there?
NICOLE:
Are you okay?
Oh, my God.
What's your name?
Tracy.
Tracy Kress.
I'm Nicole.
Don't worry, okay?
I'm gonna get you out of there.
How--?
How long have l been in here?
I don't know.
He must have done it
when l was off with those assholes.
Who?
There's this guy stalking me.
-He drives a yellow truck--
-Oh, God! Oh, God! Oh, God!
Please keep him away!
Don't let him in! Oh, God!
It's okay. He's not here right now.
He's got my boyfriend somewhere.
On the bus. He's got him on the bus.
-What are you talking about?
-The driver, he's got this place.
That's where he took me.
That's where l woke up.
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLlCKS]
TRACY:
He kept me there...
...for, l don't know, hours?
Days?
Years?
NICOLE: What did he do?
TRACY: Oh, God.
[SCREAMlNG]
TRACY:
Ah!
God. Oh, God.
NICOLE:
What does he want?
I don't know.
He told me l got what I deserved.
What does that mean?
[LAUGHS]
All I know is, my mom used to
say the same thing...
...when I had done something wrong.
"You'll get what you deserve."
Maybe I shouldn't have done it.
I'm sorry, Mom.
I'm so sorry.
Tracy, what did you do?
I stole some money
from my momma's purse.
Not a lot. Like 50 bucks.
I wanted to see the Stones.
The Rolling Stones.
They were playing in Tucson.
I never made it.
Did he--?
Oh, God.
[TRUCK ENGINE RUMBLING]
Oh, God! Now he's back!
He's back. He's coming.
NICOLE:
Tracy, quiet.
TRACY:
He's coming! Please!
Don't let him in, please!
Don't let him in, please.
[GRUNTS]
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Ah!
[THUMPlNG AND BANGlNG]
[THUMPlNG AND BANGlNG STOPS]
He's leaving.
I'm gonna make sure, okay?
Ah!
Hey!
Who the hell are you, huh?
What did you do with Jess?
[MAN SNlFFING]
[SNlFFS]
You fucking pervert!
Get the fuck out of here!
No!
[THUMPlNG AND BANGlNG]
TRACY:
Don't let him in.
Oh, don't let him in. Don't let him in.
[CRYING]
TRACY:
He'll be back.
The driver, he always comes back.
We'll be long gone before then.
He'll find us.
He'll take us to the bus.
Tracy...
...how did you get away from there?
How'd you escape?
TRACY:
I don't know.
You must have escaped somehow.
He's not Superman.
He's not human.
I thought a lot about it...
...when he was doing me.
The only thing I could do
to keep from just dying was to wonder.
How could anybody--?
How could any real person do this?
[TRACY COUGHlNG]
So l realized...
...he wasn't real.
He wasn't a person like you or me.
[TRACY SCREAMING]
He had to be some kind of monster.
Tracy.
I'm gonna get you out of here, okay?
I've got clothes in my car you can put
on, then we're gonna start walking.
-He'll find us.
-No, he won't.
He'll take us to the bus.
Look, l'll get you out of here. l promise.
Oh, God.
I will get you out here.
Oh, Jesus.
[THROWING UP]
Oh, God.
I'll get you out of here, okay?
I'm gonna get you to a hospital, okay?
Hang on, Tracy.
[GRUNTlNG]
[GRUNTS]
Tracy, I'm coming.
Tracy?
Tracy. No, no.
NICOLE:
"Tracy Kress, missing, 1 971 ."
[MUTTERING]
She was there. She was there.
Fuck you. Fuck you!
Fuck you!
[CRYING]
Ah!
Jesse.
Oh, Jesse.
Oh, Jesse, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I don't wanna die.
I don't wanna die, please.
[CRYING HYSTERlCALLY]
Oh, my God, help me, please.
[ENGINE RUMBLING]
-Officer.
-Hey.
There's this guy.
He took my boyfriend--
I don't know what he's doing to him.
--and then he tried to kill me.
He tried to run me over.
I think he's some kind of serial killer
or something--
Hold up, hold up, hold up. Calm down.
What is your name?
Nicole. Nicole Carrow.
Nicole Carrow? Okay. C-A-R-R-O-W?
-Yes, sir.
-Okay.
-And your boyfriend's name?
-Jess-- Jesse Hilts.
And where is Jesse now?
I don't know.
The man in the truck took him, l think.
-Took him?
-Yes, abducted him.
And then he--
Then he totaled our car with me in it.
That's your car?
Yes, that's my boyfriend's.
-Did you see who was driving the truck?
-No, sir.
He had a baseball cap and boots on.
-Can you describe the truck?
-lt's a truck.
It's yellow, it's kind of old
and it has the lights on top.
Floodlights. And....
I saw his license plate.
It was KZL 303.
Okay.
-You stay here. I'm gonna call this in.
-Thank you.
No, no, no. That's him, that's him--
Okay, all right. You stay here. Okay?
Okay.
Aren't you gonna arrest him?
Nothing to arrest him for yet.
Man just said that he was lost.
He's driven by, trying to find his way.
No, he's a fucking liar.
DEACON:
Maybe. I'm gonna call for backup.
Get a plain rap on him, okay?
You sure that was the truck?
I got a look. There's not even a dent.
That's the truck.
He took my boyfriend. I'm not lying.
He tried to kill me. You saw the car.
Okay.
Nicole, okay.
DEACON:
Ah!
Nicole.
Help me.
I have--
I can't-- I can't-- l can't move.
NICOLE:
Okay.
You're gonna be okay.
Oh, God. l gotta get you
out of here, okay?
DEACON: Okay.
-This is probably gonna hurt a little.
DEACON: Probably, yeah.
-Yeah.
NICOLE: Okay, ready?
DEACON:
Ah!
NICOLE:
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
DEACON:
Ah!
NICOLE:
I'm sorry.
No, no, no!
DEACON:
Ah!
[NlCOLE SOBBING]
NICOLE:
Oh, God.
Okay. He's heavy.
-Thank you.
-Oh, God. You're welcome.
-What can l do to help?
-Shoot me.
I'll clean you up a bit. Okay? Hang on.
Hang on. Let me get it.
I will call dispatch. They'll send backup.
-Someone will come for you.
-No. Someone is gonna come for us.
-Okay?
-You never saw anybody die before?
Where are you from?
Argyle, Texas.
It's just north of Dallas.
What are you doing out here?
You said something
about a boyfriend, right?
Me and Jess,
we're going to Los Angeles.
That's nice.
You're starting
your lives out together.
We did that.
Me and my wife, we moved out here
after I got out of the service.
-Do me a favor, will you?
-Yeah.
Go in my back pocket
and get my wallet for me.
-My wallet, it's over there.
-Okay.
DEACON: lt's--
-Here.
DEACON:
Go ahead.
Yeah. Take out the--
There's a picture in there. Take it out.
NICOLE: The first one?
-Yeah.
-There's only one.
-Okay.
DEACON:
Show me.
Yeah, there she is.
There's my wife there.
-And that's your little boy?
-He's Michael Jr., yeah.
Really beautiful.
-Good-looking boy.
-Yeah.
Yeah. He just had his birthday yesterday.
I got him one of those
little battery-operated motorcycles.
You know, he wants to be
just like his old man.
You know, he was...
...riding it all around the house
last night. He was...
...hitting the little siren that dings.
It was like, "Hoo."
"Hoo."
That thing was driving me nuts.
I told him to be quiet.
I yelled at him, made him cry.
It was a fucked-up thing, Nicole.
You say something so fucking stupid
like that.
You know, it ends up
being your last words.
-Hey. You're not gonna die, okay?
-Stop it.
I'm lucky enough to be just breathing
right now.
You gotta do me a favor, okay?
You gotta take my badge...
...you gotta give it to me wife, all right?
You gotta give it to her. Promise me?
And you just tell her l love her, all right?
I want you to give Mikey
a little kiss for me too.
-All right? You tell him I love him too.
-Stop it.
Please stop. Don't talk like that, okay?
Look, there has to be a way out of here.
There just has to be. Okay?
-We're gonna--
-Listen to me. Listen to me.
Listen to me.
When I was training for the service...
...my commanding officer...
...he gave us a little tip.
He had seen a lot of guys
eat the shit sandwich, you know?
He told me, he said:
"Son...
...if you ever get shot out there...
...you think it hurts like hell."
He said, "When it don't hurt so bad...
...that's when you're not
gonna make it."
Nicole. l gotta tell you...
...it don't really hurt so bad.
-Officer, please....
-Stop it.
-Come on, now. Stop it.
-Okay.
Stop it. Stop it.
[ENGINE RUMBLING]
Oh, God. He's back.
Hang on.
DEACON:
Ah!
[GRUNTS]
Leave us alone.
Please, go away.
The cops are coming,
you fucking asshole!
Hey. You son of a bitch.
You hear me?
What the fuck are you doing?
Oh, God.
Oh, God. Hey. He locked us in.
Don't let him trap you, Nicole.
Do not let him trap you.
Okay.
Ah! Let me go!
Let go of me! No.
Let me go. Oh, my God.
You fucking pervert. Let me go!
Ah!
Oh, my God!
[CRYING]
DEACON:
Nicole.
Nicole. Are you okay?
He'll be back.
DEACON:
He's a sick predator, Nicole.
He's enjoying this.
He's been at it for a long time.
We're gonna get him, Nicole.
Backup is on its way.
No, they're not.
What?
We're all alone. We're alone.
Take my gun, Nicole.
I want you to take my gun.
And when he comes back...
...l want you to shoot him. Okay?
I don't know how.
It's easy. You can do it. Come here.
Come here. Come on.
Take it. lt's over there.
There you go. Just pull it out.
Okay.
Now, you see the hammer there?
The little thing that's sticking-- Yeah.
Now...
...you pull that back. Okay?
You aim the gun,
and you pull the trigger.
-Okay?
-l don't know if l--
You can do it. You can do it.
Use your pain.
Just make sure that you hold
the gun real tight, okay...
...because it's your off-hand.
-Okay, okay.
-That's it.
[POUNDING ON DOOR]
DEACON:
There he is.
Go shoot the door, Nicole.
That's it. Do it.
Do it, Nicole. You can do it.
[GUNSHOT]
Fire it. Shoot it.
Hold it.
Go check.
Go ahead.
[GUNSHOT]
DEACON:
Did you get him?
Go see. Just be careful.
NICOLE:
I don't see him.
[CLANGlNG]
Wait. Wait.
[GROANING COMlNG
FROM THE CAMERA]
[GROANING]
JESS [ON CAMERA]:
Nicole.
[NlCOLE MOANS]
You shouldn't ever see this.
l'm so fucked.
l'm sorry.
So sorry.
[CRYING]
l love you. l love you, Nicole.
[JESS GROANlNG
ON THE CAMERA]
[GROANING]
NICOLE:
Ah!
No! Don't shoot it.
-lt's gasoline.
-Oh, God. Oh, God.
He's gonna burn us. Don't--
Don't shoot.
He's trying to burn us out, Nicole.
NICOLE: Oh, God. Okay.
-Go.
NICOLE:
Okay, okay. I've got you.
DEACON:
Ah!
NICOLE:
Oh, God! Oh, it hurts like hell.
[BOTH GRUNTlNG]
NICOLE:
Ow!
Oh, God. Oh, my God.
Nicole. Nicole?
I think I can get this open. Hang on.
[CLANGlNG]
DEACON:
Nicole.
I can't get out.
Okay. Okay.
Maybe I can lead him off.
And then I can come back for you.
-Maybe he's gone.
-No fucking way.
[LIGHTER FLlCKlNG]
Oh, God.
Son of a--
I'm gonna get you out of here.
Somehow.
-There's two bullets left in the gun.
-Okay.
Use them on me.
-What?
-Please, Nicole. Please, Nicole.
I don't wanna burn.
Please don't let him burn me.
No. I'm not gonna shoot you.
-You can.
-No.
-Please.
-No, I'll shoot him.
-And then we'll--
-No, you'll miss.
-l'm gonna fucking burn, Nicole.
-No, you're not.
I do not wanna burn.
Please don't let him burn me.
I will not have him burn me. Please.
-No.
-l'm begging you, Nicole. Just shoot me.
-l told you. l'm dead anyway, Nicole.
-No.
It don't hurt so bad.
Just shoot me, please. Please, Nicole.
Christ....
Oh, Christ, please, just shoot me, Nicole.
Please.
-Okay. Okay.
-Come on.
I don't know how.
I don't know what to do.
Nicole. Put it in my mouth.
-No, Mike.
-Put it.
-Put it in my mouth.
-No, I can't. l can't.
Do it!
Please, Nicole. Please. l'm begging you.
Shoot the gun. Do it!
Christ, just shoot the gun!
You dumb bitch! Come on!
Fuck you!
Oh, God.
DEACON:
Three.
Two.
One.
Oh, God.
[GUNSHOT]
[CRYING]
-You missed.
-No. Oh, my God.
-Oh, my God.
-Shoot me again.
Shoot me again! Shoot me right now.
-Okay, okay.
-Okay!
[GUNSHOT]
[CRYING]
Oh, God.
I can't....
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Oh, God.
No, no. He was there. He was there.
NICOLE:
Ah!
JESS:
l never asked you why.
NICOLE:
Why what?
Why did you say yes?
Why did you say you'd go
to California with me?
I came because of you.
[JESS LAUGHlNG]
You're full of shit.
I've known you
since the 1 0th grade, Nic.
There's no way you'd go
to California just for me.
NICOLE:
You're full of shit.
But l'm right.
Aren't I?
Okay.
Maybe....
Maybe I was...
...just tired of everybody telling me
what's the right thing to do.
You know? l mean, it's my life.
You know, I can do
what I damn well please.
I'll tell you one thing:
Whatever happens...
...l'd do it again.
If only just for today.
We were ass-wrong about that...
...weren't we, Jess?
[ENGINE RUMBLING]
NICOLE:
Ah!
Jesse.
No. Jesse.
No....
[CRYING]
Jesse.
Ah!
Son of a bitch!
No!
[CRYING]
Ow!
[GRUNTS]
Come on.
Ugh.
[GRUNTS]
Oh, fuck.
No, no, wait.
Come on, come on.
Where are you?
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Easy. Breathe.
Fuck.
That's it. That's it. That's--
Oh, boy.
Please, please, light.
Son of a bitch.
[TlRES SCREECH]
What?
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLlCKS]
Be careful. It's wet paint.
Looks nice.
Yeah, you should have seen it.
It was quite a fire here.
-What happened?
-Somebody broke into my office.
Messed up the place.
Set fire to the girls' room.
Drifters, probably.
Hope they got what they deserved.
Anyway, have a good day.
Thanks.
[MOANlNG]
GIRL:
Help me.
-Hello?
-Please.
I'll go get help.
Hey! Hey, there's somebody
trapped in there!
-What?
-You got a key? There's a girl!
-l heard her in there.
-ln here?
I swear.
I really heard her.
Help me.
["KEEP ME" BLARlNG FROM RADlO]
Scotty!
What the hell you doing there, man?
I told you, this is our secret.
You're gonna take this
to our grave, do you understand?
Now, sit back down there
and eat your food, all right?
I don't know what
the hell is wrong with you.
Stupid door!
Shit.
[ENGLISH SDH]