Weather Eye One to base...
...we're about to enter the hurricane eye
any second.
Position, center of Bermuda Triangle.
lt's weird how quiet it is
in the eye of a hurricane.
Look!
Dead ahead. What is that?
l don't know. Pilot to base.
This is incredible.
A huge unidentified flying object
coming straight at us, it's--
MAN:
Weather Eye One, continue message.
Weather Eye One, come in.
Weather Eye One.
We've lost all contact.
Dr. Grimsley, what happened?
GRlMSLEY: l'm only a weather scientist,
Captain Harris.
-What do you think?
-l don't know.
But with your permission, sir,
l'd like to fly out there and find out.
[UP-TEMPO MUSlC PLAYlNG ON RADlO]
VELMA: This is the life. Sailing on the
warm waters of the Gulf Stream.
With plenty of good music.
And, like, a teensy-weensy snack
to fight off sea sickness. Ha, ha, ha.
[HUMMlNG]
Huh?
[LAUGHS]
lsn't that delicious?
Oh, boy, oh, boy, oh, boy.
Like l always say,
''First come, first serve.''
Zoinks! Where'd it go?
Huh? Where'd it go?
Cool it, you two.
-The wind's starting to blow pretty hard.
DAPHNE: Wow. look at those dark clouds.
VELMA:
A big storm's coming this way.
Right, Velma. We'd better head in.
MAN [ON RADlO]: We interrupt this
program for a news bulletin in from Miami.
A hurricane hunter plane has
disappeared in the Bermuda Triangle.
-Disappeared?
-Yeah, Scoob.
Ships and plane have been disappearing
in the Bermuda Triangle for years.
Ships and planes?
And the storm is blowing us
right into it.
Hang on, it's getting worse.
-We're ready for anything.
-We are?
DAPHNE:
Look out. A monster wave.
[SCOOBY SCREAMlNG]
Quit clowning, you two.
Get the mainsail down.
Okay.
Help!
[THUNDER CRACKS]
[SHAGG Y SCREAMlNG]
We've lost our mast.
Like, we are doomed.
We're goners, we're fi--
Hey.
-Where did the storm go?
-Yeah.
VELMA: We've drifted into
the hurricane eye where it's calm.
But we're still in trouble.
We could drift like this for days.
[AlRPLANE APPROACHlNG]
Like, we're saved.
lt's a plane. lt's a plane.
DAPHNE:
l see it.
SHAGG Y & SCOOBY:
Help! Help!
Look down here.
lt's no use, Scooby. They don't see us.
We're too far off.
Hey, what's that?
[GULPS]
lt's a flying saucer.
Flying saucer?
VELMA:
lt's heading for the plane.
DAPHNE:
Jeepers, did you see that?
l'll bet that's what happened
to the weather plane.
Any maybe that's what's
gonna happen to us.
-Let's get moving.
-Yeah, moving.
Without a mast?
Like we gotta do something, Scoob.
DAPHNE:
Oh, no, we're back in the storm again.
FRED:
Look, there's an island ahead.
SHAGG Y: Yeah, but like we're gonna--
We're gonna hit that big rock.
[SHAGG Y SCREAMlNG]
Oh, boy, that was close.
[GASPS]
Phew.
DAPHNE:
Oh, thank heavens, we're safe.
You call this safe? She call this safe.
Ha, ha, ha.
Shipwrecked on an island
in the Bermuda Triangle. Ha, ha, ha.
FRED: According to this map
it's called Diablo lsland.
And you can relax, Shaggy.
lt's deserted.
VELMA:
So there's nobody around but us.
DAPHNE:
lt sure gets cold on this island.
FRED:
Yeah, we need more firewood.
Shaggy, Scooby,
see what you can scare up.
Did you have to say ''scare up''?
We are plenty scared all ready.
Come on, fellas,
do it for a Scooby snack.
BOTH:
Like, no way. Uh-uh.
How about two Scooby snacks.
-Oh, okay. Three Scooby snacks?
BOTH: Uh-huh, uh-huh, uh-huh.
-Come on, Scoob, lets go.
-Okay.
[SNlFFlNG]
[SCOOBY GULPS]
-Get off this island.
-Ah!
[SCOOBY RAMBLlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY]
DAPHNE:
What's wrong, Scoob?
SHAGG Y: An old man.
Only one eye. And the beard.
SCOOBY:
Yeah. Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
What did he say, Scoob.
''Get off this island.''
[SHAGG Y & SCOOBY SCREAMlNG]
MAN: Get off or the skeleton men
will get you.
SHAGG Y:
Skeleton men?
MAN:
This island is haunted.
lt's haunted?
SHAGG Y:
l knew it. l knew it.
Get your boat and go...
...while you still can.
DAPHNE: He disappeared.
-Like, you heard what the man said.
Let's get out off this island
while we can.
SCOOBY:
Yeah.
VELMA:
Hold it, you too.
We're not leaving.
FRED:
Velma is right.
Because we could be right on the verge
of solving a great mystery.
The riddle of the Bermuda Triangle.
Zoinks! Heh, heh. Between skeleton man
and flying saucers, l'd rather not know.
VELMA: We'll start by searching
the island for clues.
-Up there? ln the dark?
-Uh-uh.
Look, like, we'll stay here
and keep the fire going. Okay?
FRED: That's a good idea.
-lt is?
Yeah, it'll help us find our way back.
Let's go.
[VELMA PANTlNG]
Next time, we'll go sailing l'll remember
to bring my mountain-climbing shoes.
Hey, look, it levels off,
like some kind of field.
FRED: lt looks like a abandoned airstrip
probably used in World War ll...
...for sub-patrol planes.
VELMA: Good guess.
There's the old airstrip control tower...
...practically falling apart.
[THUMP]
DAPHNE: Hey!
-What happened?
l tripped over something.
FRED: Looks like a smudge pot. And it
hasn't been too long since it was lighted.
VELMA:
Look, two long rows of them.
FRED:
And wheel drags.
Jeepers, maybe this is where
the flying saucer lands.
But why would a UFO
needs old-fashioned smudge pots...
...to light up a landing strip.
Good question.
Let's check out the control tower.
FRED:
This is all modern equipment.
Direction finders, radar.
Everything you need to guide
a plane down on instruments.
VELMA: But why would any plane
want to land here...
...in the middle of nowhere.
Hey, look. Those wheel tracks run
right up to the side of the mountain.
FRED: Hm. We better check this out.
Let's follow those tracks.
Are you get any clams, Scoob?
SCOOBY:
Yeah.
One for Shaggy, two for me.
[SCOOBY WHlMPERlNG]
Boy, oh, boy. Ha, ha.
We're gonna have clam chowder.
[SCOOBY'S TEETH CHATTERlNG]
Clam up, Scoob.
[SCOOBY WHlMPERlNG]
SHAGG Y & SCOOBY:
Skeleton men!
[SKELETON MEN GROWLlNG]
[SHAGG Y & SCOOBY'S
TEETH CHATTERlNG]
BOTH:
Yikes!
-Like, let's hide in this old ventilator.
-Okay.
-Help, Shaggy!
-Zoinks!
[BOTH SCREAMlNG]
[SPLASH]
Like, where are we?
l don't know.
The wheel marks go right to the cliff.
This rusty wheel might be the answer.
[SQUEAKlNG]
Jeepers, the cliff's sliding open.
Except it isn't a cliff.
lt's plaster covering huge doors.
Let's see what's inside.
VELMA: Jinkies, look, the weather planes
that were swallowed by the flying saucer.
But what are they doing here
inside a mountain?
When we find out, we'll be closer to
solving this mystery. Come on.
Like, wow, Scooby, look at that.
SCOOBY:
Submarine?
And a dock, Scoob. Come on.
[CLANKlNG]
Like, stop moving, Scooby.
l'm not.
[CLANKlNG]
[BOTH SCREAM]
-Help!
SHAGG Y:
This way, Scoob, into the raft.
[SKELETON MEN GROWLlNG]
SHAGG Y:
Here they come. Start the engine.
l'm trying. l'm trying.
[ENGlNE SPUTTERlNG]
[WHlMPERlNG]
Come on, Scoob, stop fooling around.
Those guys are almost here.
Zoinks! Like, we forgot to cast off
the mooring lines.
SHAGG Y: Help!
SCOOBY: Help!
Zoinks!
Look out, Scoob.
Hang on, Scooby.
[SCOOBY GASPS]
[THUMP]
VELMA:
See anything unusual?
Nope, not a clue.
l wonder if the radio still works.
Good thinking, Daphne.
This is, Weather Eye One
calling weather base.
FRED: Come in, please.
Weather Eye One calling base.
Weather Eye One?
Yes, sir, with good news.
-Your planes didn't crash.
-What?
They are here on Diablo lslands inside
an underground hangar.
l'll notify the authorities.
Stay put until we get there.
That's funny. lt looks like somebody's
repainting the plane.
Now this mystery
is starting to make sense.
Come on, let's keep looking for clues.
VELMA:
Let's look in here.
A dead end.
lt's filling up with water.
Oh, gosh, we're trapped.
Like, how lucky can we get, Scoob.
We'll be safe from the skeleton men
in this sub.
[SQUAWKS]
[GASPS]
Zoinks, like, what's wrong, Scoob?
Relax, Scoob. Ha, ha, ha.
lt's only a little bird.
A little bird?
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHlNG]
Little bird? Heh, heh, heh.
Ah! The skeleton men!
Zoinks, they're here.
We gotta hide. Come on.
SCOOBY: What's that?
-Like, that's crazy.
A submarine with a skylight.
[SHAGG Y SCREAMlNG]
-Like, quick hide in there.
-Okay.
[SKELETON MEN GROWLlNG]
Zoinks!
SCOOBY:
Help! Help! Help!
Help! Help!
Help, help!
Jeepers, we're doomed.
VELMA:
Somebody dropped us a rope.
FRED:
Quick, let's go.
DAPHNE: But there's no one here.
-Well, the door didn't open by itself.
And what about the ladder?
Somebody saved us.
And l think l know who did.
Look, a submarine.
Come on, let's investigate.
SHAGG Y:
Excuse me.
Like, who are you guys?
[MAN MUMBLlNG]
SHAGG Y:
Come on, speak up. l can't hear you.
[MAN MUMBLlNG]
[SKELETON MEN GROWLlNG]
Yikes, l gotta go.
Nice talking to you.
Zoinks! Ha, ha.
Like, what happened?
[LASER HUMMlNG]
-What's that weird sound?
-Look.
FRED:
The flying saucer.
VELMA: And now it's gone.
-Jeepers, what's that?
-lt's Scooby.
-But where's Shaggy?
There he is.
[GROWLlNG]
[SPLASH]
SHAGG Y:
Help, help! Somebody save me!
SCOOBY:
l'll save you, Shaggy.
Hey, Scoob. Over here.
Give me a hand.
Phew. Like, thanks, Scoob.
Those skeletons almost got me.
l've got an idea.
Like, faster, Scooby, faster.
Those guys are getting on us.
Do something, Scooby.
Hey, Shaggy, Scooby. This way.
-Not bad. Three fish with one hook.
-Over here, Fred.
Yay! We got them.
Quick, the captured men are tied up
in the sub. Like, we gotta get them.
-Come on, Scoob.
-Okay.
[BOTH GASP]
BOTH:
The old seadog!
Help!
Well, you chickens
can stop running now.
Are you kidding?
That old seadog is after us.
We gotta hide.
The old seadog's on our side.
-Like, huh?
-On our side?
You're very smart, miss.
l'm Commander Stern...
...United States Navy lntelligence.
-Navy lntelligence?
-We figured you were the one...
...who saved us from that
flooding dry dock, commander.
Thanks.
And the Navy thanks all of you
for solving this mystery.
Hey, your welcome.
But do you mind
running through it once...
...so Scooby and l
understand what was going on.
FRED: lt was all a plot to take advantage of
the mysterious Bermuda Triangle legend...
...about disappearing
ships and plains.
VELMA:
The saucer was a fake.
A holographic image projected
onto the clouds by the submarine...
...to make everyone think that planes
were being swallowed...
...by an unidentified flying object.
DAPHNE: Then the planes were flown
on remote control to the island airstrip.
VELMA: Where the thieves were
repainting them to sell them overseas.
Let's see who these skeleton men
really are.
STERN: lt's Dr. Grimsley,
the head of the Weather Eye project.
DAPHNE: The one man who always knew
when the planes would be flying.
The Navy is eternally grateful
to what you've done.
Aw, it's nothing.
DAPHNE: Now, this is what l call
traveling home in style...
...on a Navy submarine.
Look, here come the chow hounds.
DAPHNE: What is that?
-Like on a submarine, what else?
A submarine sandwich.
[LAUGHlNG]
Now, that wasn't very nice.
Scoob, we're supposed
to share things between us.
Now what are you gonna give me?
Scooby-Dooby-Doo.