ROSE:
Sharon!
She's not here.
Oh, God. Christopher,
can you see anything?
Sharon!
She's there.
Honey!
Sharon!
Wait for Mommy!
[CAR PASSES OVERHEAD]
Sharon!
Wait.
Sharon! Honey!
[♪]
Oh, my God. Sharon!
Home.
No!
[ROSE GRUNTS]
[TRUCK HORN BLARING]
[YELLING]
Home! Home!
We're going home.
Silent Hill!
Shh. Shh.
CHRISTOPHER: Rose!
Wake up.
Hey.
It's okay, sweetie.
We're here now.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay. We're here.
[GROANING]
ROSE: It's okay, baby.
We're going right home.
What are we gonna do?
We'll get there.
We'll find a way through this.
We'll find a way.
No.
She said it again.
I know.
Come on, baby.
ROSE: Come on, baby. It's okay.
It's okay, baby.
ROSE: We're right here.
CHRISTOPHER:
It's okay.
ROSE:
Shh.
It's okay, baby. Shh.
[♪]
Wanna see?
Sure.
What are you doing there,
pumpkin?
[GASPS PLAYFULLY]
Wow.
[LAUGHS]
This is an amazing lion.
Did you do that all by yourself?
Mm-hm.
I'm so impressed
with you, honey.
[BOTH MEOWING]
[ROSE LAUGHS]
Hey.
You know we're going
on a special trip, don't you?
[MEOWS]
Do you know
where we're going?
No?
Honey, sometimes
when you go to sleep,
you go on a little walk.
And sometimes you talk
about a place...
called Silent Hill.
I don't remember.
Oh, that's okay,
sweetie.
That's why
we're gonna go there,
so you can remember.
[CELL PHONE RINGS]
[BEEPS]
Daddy's not coming?
No, sweetie.
It's gonna be just you and me.
[SIGHS]
[♪]
[WHISPERS]
Hey.
Break's over, sweetie.
You awake?
You wanna go?
[LINE RINGING]
Damn it, Rose!
What's going on?
[RECORDED MESSAGE]
Hi, this is Rose Da Silva.
Please leave a message,
and I'll call you back.
[BEEPS]
[SOFTLY]
Oh, no, Rose.
No.
[♪]
[MOTORCYCLE APPROACHING]
[DOOR OPENS]
[SHARON SIGHING]
Honey, you're awake?
Long drive.
Can I ask you something,
sweetie?
Mm-hm.
Why'd you change
your pictures?
I-- I didn't.
Mommy?
You can't remember?
No.
I-I don't like that, Mommy.
Baby, you--? You can't
remember doing this?
SHARON:
Who did that?
ROSE: Hey, hey, hey, baby,
it's okay.
Mommy, who did that?
It's okay, honey.
Mommy's here.
Can you wait
in the car for me?
Can I sit in front?
Of course you can sit
in the front.
SHARON:
Okay.
WAITRESS: Jimmy, we need a
ham and cheese on white.
ROSE: Hi.
Ma'am.
I just wanna pay for the gas.
And can you tell me the best way
to get to Silent Hill?
I can't seem to find it
on the map.
Why do you wanna go there?
I...I read about it.
Road don't go through no more.
[MACHINE BEEPING]
Your card was declined.
Hey, there.
Is everything all right?
Don't talk to strangers.
Good girl.
ROSE: All right. Well,
thanks for your help.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Why'd you cut off the cards?
That's not gonna stop me
from taking her there.
Listen, honey,
we gotta put Sharon
in a hospital.
She needs constant care,
and she needs that medication.
The medication doesn't work.
She's getting worse
every day.
Honey, the adoption people
said Sharon came
from West Virginia,
and Silent Hill
is in West Virginia.
I'm not giving up on her,
Chris. I'm not.
Have you actually read
the websites, Rose?
Yes, Chris, I read them.
Just trust me on this, please.
Just trust me on this.
Listen, honey,
I love Sharon every bit
as much as I--
Chris, I gotta go.
[LINE CLICKS]
I love you.
Need any help, ma'am?
No, we're--
We're fine, thanks.
We're fine.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[AKIRA YAMAOKA'S "LETTER-FROM
THE LOST DAYS" PLAYS ON RADIO]
♪ Hey there to my future self
♪ If you forget how to smile
♪ I have this to tell you
♪ Remember it once in a while
♪ Ten years ago
Your past self-- ♪
[SIREN WAILING]
Are we there?
Not yet, honey.
Keep your seat belt fastened,
honey.
[TIRES SQUEAL]
Hey!
Mommy! Aah!
[PANTING]
[SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE]
[SIREN WAILING]
[LOUD FEEDBACK]
[WHIMPERS]
[SCREAMING]
It's okay!
It's just the radio!
[SCREAMING]
I'm turning it off!
Mommy!
[FEEDBACK CONTINUES]
[GASPS]
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[GRUNTS]
[ROSE GROANING]
[GROANS]
[GASPS]
Sharon?
Sharon!
Somebody! Help!
Please!
We've had an accident!
Anybody!
[PANTING]
Sharon. Honey.
Ashes.
[♪]
Sharon!
Wait!
[FOOTSTEPS ECHOING]
Sharon?
Honey?
[ALARM BLARING]
[RUMBLING]
[WATER DRIPPING]
What's happening?
[ECHOING CLATTER]
SHARON [WHISPERS]:
Mommy.
Sharon.
[♪]
Sharon?
[WATER DRIPPING]
[CRASHES]
Hello?
[TREMBLING]
[SOFT METAL CLANG]
Hey!
Wait!
Sharon.
[YELPS]
No!
[BREATHING THROUGH MASK]
[GURGLING]
[SCREAMING]
[SHRIEKING]
Help me!
[CREATURES GURGLING]
Help.
Help me. Help me.
Someone! Shit!
[CREATURES GURGLING, SHRIEKING]
Get off me! Get off!
Aaah!
[CREATURES GURGLING, GROANING]
ROSE:
Don't! No!
[ROSE SCREAMING]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
[CREATURES GURGLING]
[GURGLING, SHRIEKING]
[ROSE GRUNTING]
Get away! Get off!
Get off me!
No! No! Get off me!
[SCREAMING]
[CREATURES SHRIEKING]
No!
Get off me! Get off me!
[CREATURES GURGLING]
[SCREAMING]
Get off!
[JOHNNY CASH'S "RING OF FIRE"
PLAYING ON JUKEBOX]
♪ Love is a burning thing
♪ And it makes a fiery ring
♪ Bound by wild desire
♪ I fell into a ring of fire
♪ I fell into a burning
Ring of fire ♪
♪ I went down, down, down
♪ And the flames went higher
♪ And it burns, burns, burns
♪ The ring of fire
♪ The ring of fire...
[ROSE PANTING]
DAHLIA: Only the dark
one opens and closes
the door to Silent Hill.
Please.
I don't know
what's happening.
Do you know what's going on here?
[GASPS]
My daughter.
I'm looking for my daughter.
I'm afraid that she's been hurt.
We've all lost
our children.
Our light.
DAHLIA:
They deceived me.
They're evil.
They're hate.
They hurt my child.
They did terrible things
to her.
Alessa.
This is my daughter, Sharon.
She sleepwalks,
so you have to be careful
but if you see her,
please, tell her
to wait for me.
Yes, she's mine.
No.
It's mine.
It's mine!
DAHLIA:
Get off me!
[YELLS]
Into the fire,
she swallowed their hate.
[♪]
CHRISTOPHER:
Hi there.
Yeah.
Listen, uh, my wife,
she came through here
last night.
Maybe you saw her?
Daughter worked
night shift.
Actually, she was heading
for this place, Silent Hill.
How do I get there?
Heh. You don't.
Town's closed down
'cause of the coal fire
still burnin' underground,
you know?
Breathe enough of them fumes,
oh, bound to kill ya.
Okay.
Where's the turnoff?
[RAPID FOOTSTEPS]
[♪]
Sharon?
[BEEPS]
[WHISPERS]
Come on.
[LINE RINGING]
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[RECORDED MESSAGE] Hi, this is Chris.
Please leave a message.
[BEEPS]
Christopher, it's me.
I'm-- I'm in Silent Hill.
I'm sorry, I made a mistake.
Sharon's lost,
but I think I know where she is,
so I'm going in solo
to look for her.
[SIGHS]
I'm not okay,
all right?
I need your help.
Please, please hurry.
[BEEPS]
[ENGINE SPUTTERS]
Fuck. Come on!
CYBIL: Ma'am, I want you to
put both hands on the wheel.
Put both hands
on the wheel.
Where's the little girl,
ma'am?
Please, my daughter,
she's gone.
I need your help.
Get out of the car.
What?
Move it.
Huh?
Jesus, what are you doing?
You're under arrest.
What? You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say
can be used against you.
I don't think you understand,
there's something weird
going on here.
My daughter, Sharon,
she's in danger.
If you really cared,
you wouldn't have sped off.
Listen to me, she's ill.
She sleepwalks.
Just calm right down.
I'm gonna find the little girl.
[RADIO BEEPS]
Officer Bennett to base,
over?
Base, do you copy, over?
Shit.
You're bleeding.
Cracked my head on the road
pretty good
when my bike went down.
Musta been out
for a while.
You all right
to walk?
Sure.
Then it looks like we'll be
hiking back to Brahams.
What?
You're goin' back
to the station.
Are you kidding?
Nope.
Have you heard
a single word I've said?
Yeah, I heard--
Have you heard
a single word I've said?
I'm sure she's at the school,
we just need to turn around...
ROSE [DISTORTED OVER PHONE]:
Silent Hill-- Sorry--
[STATIC]
--think I know where--
--going--
I'm not okay!
I need your--
Your help--
Hurry!
[CUTS OUT]
Sorry, sir,
this road is closed.
You'll have to turn around.
I'm looking for my wife,
she may have come through here.
Uh, she--
She drives a Jeep Liberty.
Silver, Ohio plates.
[CLICKS]
Sir, this man's wife
was driving the Jeep.
MAN:
Bring him down.
Come on.
You've seen her?
Where is she?
Inspector Thomas Gucci.
Enjoying the weather,
are ya?
For God's sake,
I'm trying to find my wife.
I know, hang on a second.
Now that vehicle you
were talkin' about,
we found it.
Really?
It's at the end of the bridge
here, but it's empty.
Got no indication
anyone's come under any harm.
Good Christ.
Now, you mind telling me
what the hell
your wife's doin' all
the way up here, Mr. uh--?
Da Silva, Chris Da Silva.
My pleasure, Chris--
Look, the faster
we start lookin',
the faster
we're gonna find her.
All right, hold your horses,
hold your horses, Chris.
I've also got
a missing deputy.
And knowing Officer
Cybil Bennett the way I do,
she's probably out there looking
for your wife and your daughter.
Bobby, make sure no one comes
through that barricade.
We're gonna get our asses up
to Silent Hill and take a look.
BOBBY:
Yes, sir.
While Chris here tells me
what's goin' on.
She disappeared yesterday...
Let's go!
CYBIL: Why were you coming up
here in the middle of the night?
ROSE:
I thought it would help her.
CYBIL [SCOFFS]:
You people.
You get off the highway
from whatever big city,
bringin' all your sick problems
with you.
ROSE:
Why aren't you listening to me?
CYBIL: We had a guy come
up here two years ago.
Snatched a little boy
from a rest stop,
dropped him
into a mine vent.
I never wanna see
anything like that again.
Look, I don't know
what you're thinking here,
but you're not helping.
There is no way I would ever
harm my own daughter.
How do I even know
she is your daughter?
Come on.
[♪]
What the hell?
[RUSTLING]
Okay.
Now do you see
what I'm talking about?
Will you take these
handcuffs off me?
No.
Get walking.
There's a fire lookout tower
on the far side of Toluca Lake.
It should have a radio.
Fuck you,
you stupid cop.
This place
is completely cut off.
You got no idea
what's goin' on.
Hey!
Hey, you up there!
I'm a police officer!
[HUMMING]
[CRACKLING]
What's going on?
[CREATURE RETCHING]
CYBIL:
What is that?
Stand back.
[RADIO CRACKLING]
ROSE: Jesus Christ,
shoot it.
[GROWLING]
Stay where you are!
Stop!
[ROARS]
[GRUNTS]
[SCREAMS]
[WHIMPERS]
[♪]
[RADIO CRACKLES]
[PANTING]
[GRUNTING]
[RAPID FOOTSTEPS]
[PANTING]
Sharon!
[DOOR SLAMS]
ALESSA [WHISPERS]:
Rose?
[FLOORBOARDS CREAKING]
GUCCI [OVER SPEAKER]: Mrs. Da
Silva, I am an officer of the law,
and I will take you to safety.
Mrs. Da Silva,
I am an officer of the law,
and I will take you to safety.
Why don't you let me
do that?
Ninety percent of the time,
Chris,
when a wife takes a run,
she takes the daughter
to a place like this,
I'd say she's damn mad
at her husband.
You like hauling skeletons
out of your family closet?
No, not all the time,
but we're drivin' on top
of 'em right now.
Coal fire's
still burning underneath.
See the barbershop
over there?
It used to be my father's.
CHRISTOPHER:
Your father?
Aw, he's dead.
November '74,
when the fire caught.
They tried to evacuate this
place as quick as they could,
but it was hellish, people
were dyin' and disappearing--
Hell, they couldn't even
find half the bodies.
That was the end
of Silent Hill.
These were good people.
Most of 'em.
Some, you might say,
deserved it.
A little bit.
[DISTANT BANG]
[GASPS]
Sharon!
[THUMPING]
[♪]
[CREAKS]
Sharon.
[SOFTLY]
Where are you hiding?
[♪]
ALL:
Burn the witch!
Alessa Gillespie.
ROSE:
Hey!
Wait!
[PANTING]
[GIRL SOBBING]
[GIRL WHIMPERS]
[SOFTLY]
It's okay.
[SOBBING]
It's gonna be okay.
I promise
I'm gonna help you.
[GAGGING]
[PANTING]
[WHISPERS]
Come on.
[GAGS]
[WHISPERS]
Come on.
Oh, God.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
Help me. Oh, God.
[HANDLE TURNING]
Please, please, help me.
Help me.
[THUMPING]
Help me. Help me, God.
Please, help me.
Help me. Help me.
Help me, please. Please.
[GRUNTING]
[CHIRPS]
[FOOTSTEPS RECEDING]
[DOOR SLAMS]
[ALARM BLARING]
It's happening again.
[WALLS PEELING]
[CRASH]
[GASPS]
[GROANING]
[GURGLING]
[GRUNTS]
[YELPS]
[JANITOR SCREAMS]
[SCREAMS]
[RAPID FOOTSTEPS]
MAN:
Help me! Help! Help me!
[SCREAMS]
[YELLS]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
Help me!
Please! Please!
Come on!
[GRUNTING]
[GROANS]
[GASPING]
[THUD]
CHRISTOPHER:
Rose!
Sharon!
[ROSE GROANING]
[WATER DRIPPING]
[COCKROACHES SKITTERING]
[WHIMPERS]
No!
[SCREAMS]
[♪]
Rose!
[PANTING]
[SIGHS]
Rose.
[METAL CREAKING]
[GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
Rose!
GUCCI: Put your mask on.
Rose! Where are you?
[SOBBING]
I felt her.
You what?
Her perfume.
She was here.
Who was?
My wife.
She wasn't here.
Put this mask on.
Perfume.
Breathe, through that mask.
Come on, let's go.
We're gonna go this way.
Chris, come on.
She was here.
No, no,
she wasn't here.
She was here.
I know it.
[SCREAMS]
[CRYING]
Come on.
Let's keep looking.
[CRYING]
[COCKROACHES SKITTERING]
[YELPS]
[SCREAMING]
Get off me! Get off!
Get off!
[ROSE SCREAMS]
[SHRIEKING]
[GRUNTS]
Get me that pipe!
Rose, the pipe!
[GRUNTS]
Okay.
CYBIL:
Hurry!
I got it. I got it.
Quick, come on!
Can we get out of here?
We're trapped.
Last mag.
That's all the bullets you got?
Yeah.
[GUN CLICKS]
Thanks.
[FAINT THUMPING, CREAKING]
You hear that?
[LOUD THUMPING, CREAKING]
That's him.
[BOTH SCREAM]
Stay down! Stay down!
Jesus Christ.
God! Get down! Get down!
[ROSE SCREAMS]
Shit! Oh!
[SCREAMS]
ROSE:
Oh, my God!
[METAL SCRAPING]
[SCREAMING]
[ROSE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[GROANS]
[GASPING]
What?
[CREAKING]
[SOFTLY]
What the fuck?
Oh, what the fuck?
You saw that, right?
That was real?
What the fuck is going on?
All right,
I know this is crazy.
I know.
We gotta calm right down,
because my kid is not here
and I've gotta find her
before this happens again.
Oh, God.
I don't even know
where to start.
I found this.
It's from a hotel.
I don't know where it is,
but she is in this hotel.
Hotel?
Hey.
It's gonna be okay.
We're gonna be okay.
Now, don't be trying anything,
Chris, all right?
We got men up here
all night long.
We're gonna find your wife,
we're gonna find your daughter.
Can't have civilians wandering
around on their own.
You're not telling me
everything.
What really happened
up here?
Just let it rest in peace.
WOMAN [ON PHONE]:
Directory assistance.
Toluca County Archives, please.
One moment.
[LINE RINGS]
WOMAN 2: Archives?
Yeah, listen, um--
Do you have the records there
from Silent Hill?
Uh, which records, sir?
The police records?
Sorry, sir,
those records are confidential.
No, no, I-I can't--
No, listen, I--
Sorry, sir, I can't access
that information.
Listen, goddamn it. I--
Sir, I can't--
This is an emergency.
I can't help you.
[♪]
[ROSE PANTING]
They used to say
this place was haunted.
I think they were right.
ANNA:
Help! No!
Stay away!
ROSE: Come on.
ANNA:
Stay away, sinner.
Get back!
Hey.
Hey, it's here.
DAHLIA: Faith is our destroyer.
Faith has brought us doom.
Get back!
Hey, hey!
Hey, stop!
Think you of they
who cast the first stone.
Lambs without a shepherd,
shepherd without a flock.
It's your sins
which hold you here.
Stop your lies!
Calm down.
Calm down, it's okay.
We're not gonna hurt you.
She's gone.
What's your name?
Anna.
My name is Anna.
What's going on here, Anna?
Who was that?
ROSE:
I've seen her before.
ANNA:
Dahlia was cast out.
Not even the darkness
wants her.
She's lost
her daughter too.
What?
ANNA: Sinners deserve
to lose their spawn.
What are you doing here,
Anna?
Mother needs more food.
You mean there are
other people here?
Christabella keeps us safe.
ROSE:
Anna.
We take refuge
in the church.
ROSE:
Anna, listen to me.
I've lost my daughter.
She's all alone.
ROSE: Can you imagine how
frightened she must feel?
Tell me, have you seen her?
Do you know where she is?
Mm-mm.
If she has faith,
she might survive.
If not...
I'm taking this.
Have you seen this?
I've seen it
at the school.
It's on all of the buildings
the elders of my elders built.
It's a symbol of our unity,
a symbol of our faith.
Rose, look at this.
ROSE:
What is it?
Just like yours.
Where'd you find it?
They're all over the floor.
Rose.
Check this out.
What number
did you take this from?
One-eleven.
We gotta go to room 111.
[TICKING]
[SOFTLY]
Gucci.
WOMAN:
Directory assistance.
Yeah.
Toluca County Orphanage,
please.
One moment, please.
Yes, I have that information--
Yeah.
Can you give me
that address?
[♪]
ANNA: We are wandering
far from refuge here.
Let's keep her with us.
She's all we got.
There's no room 111.
[SOFTLY]
The first burning.
What is it, Anna?
Before the town
had a name.
The elders of my elders
kept us pure.
The founders of this town
were witch hunters.
ANNA: Burning the witch
held back the darkness.
It stopped the apocalypse.
It's here.
ROSE:
There's a room in here.
[CANVAS RIPPING]
Look at this.
Here.
ROSE:
Damn.
[METAL CLINKING]
What is this place?
I don't know.
We're in the next building.
Some factory, maybe.
CYBIL:
Looks like there was a fire.
Hey.
Rose!
[GIRL WHIMPERING]
Who are you?
It's okay.
Don't be scared.
I promise
I'm not gonna hurt you.
[GRUNTS]
Rose?
[METAL CREAKING]
[GIRL WHIMPERING]
Okay. Come on.
Come on.
[SOBBING]
It's okay.
Hey.
[♪]
It's okay.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Oh, my God.
You could be her twin.
Are you Alessa?
Where's my Sharon?
Look at me.
I'm burning.
[GASPS]
CYBIL:
Rose?
Rose? My God.
How'd you get over there?
Where is she?
[MUTTERING]
Grab onto it.
Now swing back around.
Okay.
CYBIL:
Are you all right?
Yeah.
What the hell
were you doing over there?
You're gonna get
yourself killed.
I think I just saw
Dahlia's daughter.
She was the one
that brought us here.
What are you talking about?
She was the one
that made me crash my car.
Alessa.
We don't say her name.
That's the seal,
isn't it, Anna?
The symbol of your faith?
Something terrible
happened here.
We have to leave.
We have to leave!
The darkness is coming!
Let's go.
CYBIL:
Let's go!
ANNA:
The church isn't far.
Run. Run!
Rose, come on!
Rose!
[BIRDS SQUAWKING]
[ALARM BLARING]
Hurry!
Rose.
Come!
CYBIL:
We gotta go.
[ALARM BLARING]
Rose, come on.
I've seen this.
[ALL PANTING]
[♪]
CYBIL:
Rose, let's go!
Cybil!
Rose, come on.
DAHLIA: You run not towards
sanctuary but from your fears.
Do not join the others!
They are deceivers.
They are damned.
We gotta get inside.
No!
They are wolves
in the skin of sheep.
They brought about
their own hell.
They'll take you
with them. Oh!
Filth and lies!
Hey!
CYBIL:
Stop it!
Please.
I've seen your daughter.
I've seen Alessa.
It's coming!
She's dead,
isn't she?
Fire doesn't cleanse.
It blackens.
Listen to me.
Rose, hurry!
She looks exactly like Sharon.
She brought us here,
didn't she?
Why? What does she want?
Evil wakes in vengeance.
Be careful what you choose.
[ALARM FADING]
[CYBIL PANTING]
[♪]
CYBIL:
Rose!
[BELLOWING]
[ANNA SCREAMS]
[GROANING]
[GROWLING]
Oh, God, no.
Witches!
Destroy the witches!
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
No. No. No.
No, we're lost.
[GUNSHOT]
CHRISTABELLA:
This is a sanctuary.
[GUN CLICKS]
[SOBBING] Please, Christabella,
they lured my Anna.
They gave her
to the fiend.
Eleanor, you must remember
that Anna went against our laws.
She went alone outside
into the devil's playground.
She was not the responsibility
of these two strangers.
We'll deal with them later.
Now we must pray.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
[ORGAN PLAYING]
CHRISTABELLA:
And then I saw them
from whose presence
Earth and heaven fled away.
And no home was left to them.
ALL:
And then I saw them
from whose presence
Earth and heaven fled away.
And no home was left to them.
CHRISTABELLA: And I saw the
dead, the great and the small,
and they were judged
according to their deeds.
ALL:
And I saw the dead,
the great and the small,
and they were judged
according to their deeds.
And anyone's name not found
written in the book of life,
they will be thrown
into the lake of fire.
[HIGH-PITCHED SCREAMING]
NUN AND GIRLS:
And now I lay me down to sleep,
I pray the lord my soul to keep.
If I should die before I wake,
I pray the lord my soul to take.
Amen.
All right, girls, into bed.
Quickly now.
No better place to be
on a rainy night.
In you go, Lindsey,
that a girl.
You've got your bear,
that's a girl.
No. No talking
after lights are out.
[INDISTINCT WHISPERS]
Good night, children.
And God bless.
I'm sorry, Sister Margaret,
this really can't wait.
I can't imagine why.
Nine years ago,
a baby was left outside
this orphanage.
My wife and I were the ones
who adopted her.
I'm very happy for you,
Mr. Da Silva,
but I can't give out
information on our children.
Look.
That girl, she looks exactly
like my daughter.
I can't help you, I'm sorry.
It's late.
She must be 40 now.
Where can I find her?
This story isn't hers alone,
but all of ours.
GUCCI:
You got yourself somethin'.
You know what you got now,
Chris?
How 'bout breakin'
and enterin'?
And by the looks of this,
a little assault, as well.
Thank you, Thomas.
This can't go
any farther.
It won't, Sister.
You know,
I have some 12-year-olds
who, uh, cover their tracks
better than you do.
What's this?
Look, Gucci,
do you know her?
Is that my daughter's
birth mother?
Huh?
Look, turn around.
What are you doing?
[HANDCUFFS CLICK]
GUCCI:
I knew that girl.
I did.
I was told she didn't make it
through the night.
The night of the fire.
The night of the big fire
in Silent Hill.
There were these people.
These fanatics.
What they did
to that child was terrible.
That was 30 years ago,
and it's over now.
Not as far as I'm concerned.
What's it gonna be,
city boy?
I-- I can put you in jail,
or you can go home.
And that's your definition
of justice, huh?
There are many different
forms of justice, Chris.
See, you've got man's,
God's,
and even the devil's.
Certain forms
you just can't control.
So I want you to go home now
to your nice warm bed
and let me deal
with this town
and what has happened
over the last 30 years.
Okay? End of story.
CHRISTABELLA:
Tell me first how you got here.
Honestly, I don't know
how I got here.
Right now, I've lost
my little girl, and all I know
is that I'm supposed
to be in this church.
Are you a person
of faith?
I love my daughter.
That's not what I asked.
Who are you to judge?
We judge because the souls
of history hang in the balance.
Because our faith
has never failed us.
Our faith keeps
the darkness of hell at bay.
Then use your faith
to help me find my little girl.
Only the demon knows
where she is.
Then tell me,
where do I find this demon?
No one has ever returned
from the core of the darkness
where the demon
lies in wait.
She's not gonna help us.
Let's just go.
If you wish to face the demon
to find your daughter,
I won't stop you.
Christabella,
they can't go down--
Silence, Adam.
Perhaps your faith
will protect you.
Perhaps not.
[MAN GROANS]
If you don't wanna do this...
I'll understand.
Sharon's adopted,
but I'm her mother.
I knew that from the moment
I first laid eyes on her.
She's lucky to have you.
Mother is God
in the eyes of a child.
[♪]
[DOOR SLAMS]
Quiet.
We're in his domain now.
Look at this map.
Memorize it.
Your memory may save
your life.
Do you see this room?
ROSE:
Yep.
That is where
the darkness lies.
The demon is in the bowels
of this building.
It hides behind the face
of an innocent.
CYBIL:
You mean a child?
Don't believe your eyes.
Your eyes will lie to you.
Faith is the only truth.
I will pray for you, Rose.
But I won't expect you
and your friend to return.
Goodbye.
Adam?
[WHISPERS]
Left.
Right.
Left. Left.
Right. Right. Left...
CHRISTABELLA:
Take them to the lower level.
ADAM: In the basement?
Do it, then return.
ROSE: Left. 3A.
But--
ROSE: Right. 4A.
I said do it.
Left. Left. Right.
CYBIL: Rose? Rose?
Left. Right. Left. Left.
Rose, she's killing you.
Rose!
Let me do this.
I need to do this.
[CREAKS]
MAN:
Take this.
They'll be drawn to the light,
but you won't be able
to see without it.
Thank you.
So this thing
actually works?
It will.
If the demon wants you,
it will.
Forgive me.
We've lived too long
as scavengers.
I believe this is yours.
Witch!
Her child's
the likeness of Alessa.
the next vessel.
Go! Go!
Stop her!
Don't let the witches
go down!
Come on!
Get off her!
Find her.
No! Wait!
Cybil!
Cybil! Open the door!
[METALLIC BANG]
[CREAKING]
[CLICKS]
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
No!
[GASPING]
8A.
7A.
Right.
Right. 6A.
4A.
3A.
Left, left. Right, right.
Left, left.
[GASPS]
[ALL MURMURING]
[WHISPERS]
Okay.
I can do this.
[GASPS]
DARK ALESSA:
Congratulations, Rose.
You're here.
You did it.
Your reward is the truth.
Did you see that Alessa
was a good little girl?
Even though nobody
looked at her that way.
KIDS [CHANTING]:
Burn the witch! Burn the witch!
Their parents told them
she was bad.
She didn't have a father
like they did.
[GRUNTS]
Alessa was alone in the world.
You know what can happen
to little girls
when they're left alone.
[ALESSA SCREAMS]
DAHLIA: It's okay, it's me,
come on.
Even her mother couldn't help.
Even though she loved her baby.
But the rest of the family
didn't love Alessa.
They were just like the others
and made her scared.
We know.
Even the children know it.
Your daughter...
Why you won't
just name the father...
You've brought sin amongst us.
The faithful must gather
in judgment
for we are called
to purify this filth.
What does she mean, Mommy?
You're weak, my dear sister.
You always were.
Trust us, Dahlia.
Have faith in our virtue.
We will restore innocence.
DARK ALESSA: They had met many
times since the town was built
to restore innocence
and purity.
They had a special place
for that.
Do you remember the hotel?
I led you to all these places,
and you were very good
at following my clues.
CHRISTABELLA:
You may leave, Dahlia.
We fight the sin,
not the sinner.
Mommy! Mommy!
Mommy!
You know how that feels,
don't you, Rose?
To lose your little girl?
What have I done?
Oh, God.
CHRISTABELLA:
Weep not for the demon.
ALESSA [SCREAMS]:
No!
Once again we are locked
in mortal battle.
They thought they knew
how to cast out evil.
Praise God for our clarity.
ALL:
Amen.
Praise the innocent
for their sacrifice.
But you should be careful
how you fight evil.
CHRISTABELLA:
Give us back our purity.
ALL:
Purity.
[ALESSA SCREAMS]
And our unity.
ALL:
Unity.
Your weapons
can turn back on you.
[GASPS]
Dahlia [WHISPERS]:
No.
Now you know
why Dahlia is broken.
[GRUNTS]
She tried to get help,
but she went too late.
DAHLIA [SCREAMING]:
No!
GUCCI: Get her out, boys.
Get her out now!
There were good people
in the town.
People like you, Rose.
People who like to help.
Alessa was so lonely
and hurt and scared.
They should have known better
than to hurt her so badly.
[WHEEZING]
When you're hurt
and scared for so long,
your fear and pain
turn to hate,
and the hate starts
to change the world.
Alessa's hate grew and grew,
burning inside her.
[ALESSA WHEEZING]
Her hate got so strong,
she even hurt someone
who was only curious.
That's when I came.
I told her it was their turn.
I promised.
They would all fall
into her darkest dream.
[♪]
Now, Rose, we must talk.
[NURSE WHIMPERING]
[CRYING]
DARK ALESSA:
Don't be afraid.
She won't hurt you.
She needs your help.
Who is she?
She is Alessa.
Then who are you?
I have many names.
Right now,
I'm the dark part of Alessa.
Where's my child?
She's not your child.
She's hers.
The little girl is what's left
of her goodness.
We hid her in safety...
in the world
outside this hell.
[♪]
[BABY CRYING]
Now the dream
of this life must end
and so too must the dreamers
within it.
For over 30 years
they've lied
to their own souls.
For 30 years they've denied
their own fate.
But now is the end of days,
and I am the reaper.
What do you want?
All we ask for is satisfaction.
Satisfaction?
Revenge.
Why me?
You chose.
You chose Sharon.
Christabella will find Sharon.
She plans to purify her.
Oh, God, no.
Their blind conviction
repels me from their church.
I cannot enter
while they deny their fate,
but you can.
Just tell me what I need to do.
Tell them the truth.
[GRUNTING]
[CRYING]
[BANGING]
[GASPS]
DAHLIA:
The girl is mine!
Mine!
She's mine!
The truth is clear
to those who see.
Just as I could see
you hid this child.
GUCCI:
Let's go.
Out of the car.
Turn around.
Just a friendly warning:
I'll be back with people
who know what they're doing.
Before you do that,
Chris,
I wanna tell you
about Officer Bennett.
Few years back, some wacko,
he abducted a kid.
Threw him down a mine vent
up there in Silent Hill.
Cybil Bennett,
she found that boy.
She spent three days
holdin' onto him,
keepin' him alive
until they were rescued.
We know what we're doin'.
I need to do everything I can.
[ENGINE STARTS]
Let's go.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Burn her! Burn the witch!
Burn the witch!
Please.
Christabella, let her live.
Your weakness led
these souls to judgment.
This time you will bear witness.
She is innocent.
Look at her. She's the whelp
of your daughter.
The demon!
The demon fathered
this disgusting abomination
from her child!
No, she's mine!
CYBIL:
Sharon! Sharon, look at me.
Look at me.
Don't be afraid.
It's okay, it's okay.
Your mama's coming.
CHRISTABELLA: Once again we are
called upon to restore innocence.
We burn this witch,
we vanquish evil!
No. You can't, you can't.
Don't let her say this! No!
We burn the child!
We fight the demon!
[CROWD YELLING]
She's just a child!
What the fuck is wrong
with you people?
CYBIL:
Let her go!
Leave her alone!
Those who aid the demon,
they must be cleansed
by the fire
from whence they came.
That's crazy. You're crazy!
CYBIL:
No!
Why are you listening to this?
Why?
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Burn the witch! Burn her!
Burn the witch. Burn her.
Burn the witch.
Sharon.
MAN:
Evil witch!
Suffer.
[CYBIL YELLS]
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Burn the witch!
Burn the witch! Burn her!
Burn her! Burn the witch!
[ALL CHEERING]
MAN:
Back, demon.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Burn the witch! Burn her!
MAN: Demon!
[LAUGHING]
MAN 2: Burn her!
[CHANTING CONTINUES]
You're in your own hell.
[GASPS]
Mama, be with me.
[SCREAMS]
[CHANTING STOPS]
CHRISTABELLA: Here is where
the apocalypse began.
This is where we stop
the annihilation of the world.
We drew a line in the sand
and said:
"Demon, you will not cross!"
But the demon is wicked,
full of treachery.
Yet again he comes to tempt us,
in the guise of an innocent.
To rid the world of this demon
we must burn this child!
[ALL CLAMORING]
ROSE:
That's not gonna happen!
Mommy!
It's okay, baby.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Oh, my God.
MAN: Witch!
What have you people done?
CHRISTABELLA:
You have returned.
Yes, I have.
The witch has returned.
CROWD:
The witch, the witch.
Do not believe her lies.
I come from a world
outside this place.
full of life!
Why don't you tell them
the truth?
Tell them the truth
that you deny even to yourself.
There was no apocalypse!
You burned in the fire
that you started.
And nothing can save you
'cause you're already damned!
SHARON:
Mommy!
Take her! Burn her.
Burn her as a witch.
Burn her! Burn her!
MAN 2:
Demon witch!
Burn me?
Demon witch.
That's your answer?
Burn anything
you're afraid of.
you can't control.
This woman uses your fear
to control you.
She led you
to burn Alessa Gillespie.
She led you to burn
an innocent child.
But you will not deny your guilt
and you cannot deny her pain!
That child was sin incarnate.
No.
It's you who have sinned.
You darkened the heart
of an innocent.
And now you cower in the face
of Alessa's revenge.
Heresy.
Burn her. Burn her!
[CROWD YELLING]
Your faith brings death!
You are alone in this limbo.
And God is not here.
SHARON:
Mommy!
[SHARON CRYING]
She was a blasphemer.
CROWD:
Blasphemer. Blasphemer.
Blasphemer! Blasphemer!
Blasphemer!
[♪]
[GROANING]
[ALL MURMURING]
[SHARON WHIMPERING]
[CREAKING]
[ALL CLAMORING]
[GASPING]
[METAL GRINDING]
What have you done?
You've brought the darkness
in with you.
Do you know
what you've done?
For Sharon.
Mommy.
[♪]
[METAL GRINDING]
[ALL SCREAMING]
[WHIMPERING]
[SCREAMING]
SHARON:
Mommy!
[VICTIMS SCREAMING]
Oh, Lord, give me
the strength to stay pure.
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
[FLESH TEARING]
[SCREAMS]
[GURGLING]
No, no.
[SCREAMING]
Alessa, what have you become?
[SCREAMS]
[SHARON SCREAMS]
Mommy!
Sharon!
Sharon, honey,
it's me, it's mommy.
[SCREAMING]
Down! We're getting down.
Shut your eyes.
Shut your eyes, baby.
It's just a bad dream.
[♪]
Why did she not take me
with the others?
ROSE:
Because you're her mother.
Mother is God
in the eyes of a child.
I love you.
[ENGINE SPUTTERING]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[RINGS]
CHRISTOPHER [ON MACHINE]:
Hi, this is Chris.
ROSE:
And this is Rose.
SHARON:
And I'm Sharon Da Silva.
ALL:
Please leave a message!
[BEEPS]
Christopher, it's me.
I'm with Sharon.
[STATIC HISSES]
Hello? Hello? Rose?
Rose?
And we're coming home.
[BEEPS]
[♪]
[AKIRA YAMAOKA'S
"YOU'RE NOT HERE" PLAYING]
♪ Blue skies to forever
♪ Green grass blows
In the wind, dancing ♪
♪ It would be a much better
Sight with you with me ♪
♪ If you hadn't met me
I'd be fine on my own, baby ♪
♪ Never felt so lonely
Then you came along ♪
♪ So now what should I do
♪ I'm strung out
Addicted to you ♪
♪ My body aches
Now that you're gone ♪
♪ My supply fell through
♪ Gladly gave me everything
You had and more ♪
♪ You craved my happiness
♪ When you made me feel joy
It made you smile ♪
♪ But now I feel your stress
♪ Love was never meant
To be such a crazy affair, no ♪
♪ And who has time for tears
♪ Never thought I'd sit around
And cry for your love ♪
♪ Till now
♪ Uh
♪ Oh, I feel your stress
♪ Uh, uh, oh
Who ♪
♪ Who has time for tears?
♪ Oh, my baby
♪ Yeah, yeah
♪ I never
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah...
[♪]