(operator) "911, What's your emergency?"
(operator) "911, What's your emergency?? Are you there?"
(caller) (sobbing) "There's no people here"
(operator) "OK, Calm down, where are you, what's your address?"
(caller)  "I don't know"
(operator) "Are you in danger?"
(caller) "Yes, ..yes"
(operator) "What's your name?"
(caller)  "Jordan,...Help!"
(operator) "OK, can you tell me what street you're on?"
(caller) "I don't know where we are"
(operator) "Jordan, who are you with?"
(caller)  "We went...We went in the house, we found people..."
(operator) "You found who Jordan?..Who did you find?"
(caller) "There's blood on the walls, ..Help Us!"
(operator) "Jordan, Jordan, calm down"
(caller) "help us, it's everywhere"
(operator) "Jordan, what happened"
(caller) "There's blood everywhere"
(country music playing)
-When did you do all of this?
-Ah, today, with Mike and with the girls..
I thought you'd like it
You can have this room, I'm gonna get set up out there..
(sighing) I don't know about the tub
I didn't know if the roses go in first or after
Yeah, I don't know either
Here, let me...
-Thank you...
-Ok
Mike, it's me, um, we're at the house now,
I ah, I know you're fuckin drunk
Maybe you're asleep now, but,
ahhhh, I'll tell you when I see youbut things,
they didn't work out the way I planned, ..at all
Um, I'm gonna need you to come out here and get me, just when you wake up in the morning.  I'm gonna give her the car
Just call me when you get this, Ok
I know, I know it's a bitch to come all the way out here, but sorry, sucks, OK
Hi
(laughing)
Come outside with me
-I only wanted to dance with you
-We're dancing right now
-Jerk  -You're a
jerk  -You're a jerk
ooh, it's freezing, let's get into the car
-wait a second  -what?  -I
just want to tell you something
What do you want to tell me?
I remember the first time that ever i saw you..
(church bell ringing)
-It's really nice, everything you did, it's beautiful
-Yeah
Here, I can't keep it, I can't take it back.  Please...
Just take it, please
(cork popping)
Here
-The clothes are in the bedroom if you want.
I wanna wear this, I'll only get to wear it tonight
-Makes me feel pretty
-YOu are pretty
I'm so sorry it wasn't the way you though it to be, I'm really sorry
-well What do we do now
-I don't know
-I'm just not ready yet
-OK
-James -Please
-Please, Talk to me
This is embarrassing
(playing country music on record player)
(singing) "...sad and lonely, and I wonder, do you remember me, everyday is sad and lonely...do you ever think of me my darling"....
You're my girl
(Loud knocking on door)
What is it, like 4 in the morning?
(more loud knocking)
-Hi
-Hello
-Is Tamara here
-No, you've got the wrong house
-You sure
-Yeah, I'm sorry
See you later
-That was weird
-Yeah, people get lost out here, should I go get her?
She seems OK, I mean, I think she would've said if she wasn't.
(whispering) It's cold outside
(stranger from door, whispering) "Kill...."
-I'm out of cigarettes
-I'll go get you some more
-No, I didn't mean that, you don't have to, just go to sleep, I'm tired anyway
-I know you want em'
-I'll drive
-It's alright, I want to drive for awhile anyway
Let me light you a fire
-I was thinking when you were taking a bath, I want you to take the car back tomorrow
-What do you mean?
I don't think a roadtrip is such a good idea right now.  I called Mike, he's gonna come out get me in the morning.
Are you sure that's what you want?
Yeah....
Okay, I'll be back, ...if you want, we could talk some more, you don't have to, OK?
-You gonna be OK here?  Yeah, I'll be fine
-Ok  Thanks for lighting me a fire  -Sure
(Loud Single Knock at door)
(piano music in background) "Should we go outside, should we play somewhere?"
(More Loud Knocking)
Hello
(stranger from door) Is Tamara home?
-You already came by here
-Are you sure? (walks away)
(wind chimes blowing outside)
(fire alarm sounding)
(Loud Knock at door)
(Loud Knocking)
Oh, come on-
(more loud knocking)
James, where are you?  That girl came back.  That girl!, I mean, she keeps, she keeps knocking on the door.
What do you mean, I heard her voice
No, I didn't open the door.
I don't know, the battery's dead, I'm charging it right now.
Ok, ok
I just want you to come home ok..
No, I'm fine, just hurry.
How far away are you?
Ok
Will you just stay on the phone with me?
(phone disconnects)
James?
(door closes)
(scared) James?!
(Loud Door Slam)
(Knocking at door)
This isn't happening, this isn't happening
(very loud knocking, wind chimes banging loudly)
(loud screeching noises from outside)
AHHHHHHHHHHHH!
(loud knocking, record skipping) "it's over dead"
(loud knocking and banging, record continues to skip)
GO AWAY!!!!!
(record still skipping) "it's over dead"
(record stops, footsteps towards bedroom)
-Jamie!
-Kristen?
-There's someone out there
-What are you doing
-Don't leave me, Please don't leave me
Stop, stop stop. What happened to your hand?
Stop, stop, come here, come here sit down.  Sit down, sit down, sit down, sit down
-How do you know there's somebody out there?
-I saw a man at the back door, and he's wearing a mask
-What do you mean, like a ski mask?
-a fucking mask, I don't know
Ok, Calm down, calm down
-Jamie, Im so scared
-Ok
-Don't go out there please...don't go
-Please, stop.  I'm right here, stop.
There's no one out here, nobody, come here..
Come here...
It's ok, there's nothing here
-So what do you wanna do
-I don't know
Kristen..
Kristen, what is it
She's watching us
-She looks like a ghost,
-Want me to go talk to her?  -They don't want to talk  -Well, They want something
people don't just stand there staring at us like that, they want something
-Shit..  -what? -I left my phone in the car,
I'm gonna go get it -You can't go out there!
-Why?
-One of them came in here and took my phone.
Kristen, nobody came in here...
She's gone
Fuck...
Shit...
(Loud bangs)
What do you want?
Why don't you get the fuck outta here
-James!?
-Kristen, go back inside
-What's happening?
-Kristen....
Kristen, Go...
-Jesus Christ!..
What?  Sorry, I'm waiting for you
-I want you to get your things, put your shoes on. Did you find your phone?  -No!
I told you they took my phone -I put it in your bag.. -James, it's not in the bag
I plugged it into the wall,
and when I came back, it was gone
I just, I don't understand, I checked the whole house, there's nobody in here.
Let me see your hand..
What are you thinking..?
It's since we've been here, I haven't heard a dog park, not a car pass.  Nothing.
Just us and "them"
-Why are they doing this?
-Listen, I don't want you to think about that OK?
Don't think about it..
It doesn't matter right now.
The only reason is if they'd come through that door..Ok?
-What is it?
-It's my phone, we gotta get out of here..
-Shit!  -Who is
that?  -I don't know
(engine reving)
Get out of the car..!
Oh!
Shit!
Come on!
(engine reving)
(Doors and windows closing, horn blowing outside)
-James, we need a gun
-I'm looking
-Does your dad have a gun?
-Kristen, I'm looking!!  There was one here when as a kid, he always hid it.
(horn continues to blow outside)
Let's go to the bedroom..
Oh my God...
(Gunshots)
-What are you doing?
-Looking for bullets
Got em, got em, I got em
-I don't know how to use this thing..  -What
do you mean?  -I'm not sure even how to load it.
-But you said you used to hunt with your dad..
-No, I never did, it's just something that I said.
I'm gonna open the door, and I just want you to run, OK?
(door breaks!)
-(screaming) AHHHHHHH!
Block the door, Block the door!!
(screaming)
PUSH!!
(Gunshots)
Come on...
We're not going to fucking die here..
We're gonna sit here and wait for the cops to come or whatever, we're not going to fucking die
(footsteps)
(country music playing)
(cell phone dialing)
YO! Jimmy James..
what's up buddy, it's Mike,
Listen man, I'm outside
Ah, I got here early..I just decided to come out and you know,
Just be here for ya as soon as i possibly could
cause you know, you know how I like to wait on you hand and fuckin foot..
What the Fuck!
(country music playing in house)
Hello?
Jimmy?
Kristen?
Hel..--(Gunshot)
Kristen, I shot him...
-He didn't have a mask.. -What?
-why didn't he have a fuckin' mask
What do you mean he didn't have a mask?
James?
-What?!  -Oh,
God -What is it?
-Stay there..  -James,
answer me..  -Oh fuck
-What?  -Stay there.
-Get off of me! Stop it
-It's Mike, it's Mike, Please don't look, it's Mike
-Oh my God
Baby, it's not your fault...
He was my best friend, he was my best friend
What are we going to do?
(Kristen sobbing, coughing)
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go outside,..
I want you to hide somewhere.. -What are you talking about? -There's an old radio
out at the barn, I'm going to try and call for help...I don't know what else to do,
It's ok, I'll come right back for you.
Listen, I want you to go, I want you to hide.
-I'll keep them away and come find you
-James no, I want to come with you.
Kristen, It'll be ok, I promise, I'll be fine.
Be careful...James..
Oh, shit...
(Gunshot)
James?
Oh, Fuck..
(Loud bangs from house)
James?
(Two way radio noise and voices)
Hello? hello?
Hello?
(Radio Static)
Help me....
(Muffled voices from outside)
(Noises and banging from outside)
(Radio transmission)
- "This is 10, 5, 0, read me?  Hello?"
Can you hear me?  Hello?  Please answer me Help Me
(Radio transmission) "Where are you?"
(Piano Playing)
(Footsteps)
(screams) AHHHHHH!  NO!!!
He's gonna kill you..
Why are you doing this to us?
James?
(James coughing)
You're gonna die..
(James) Kristen RUN!
Noooo---Let me out...!
(James) Nooooo!
Baby!!!!
(Kristen Screams)
(Kristen) AHHHHHHH-
Why are you doing this to us?
Cause you were home...
I love you...
Baby?--
No...Please don't..
No...Please, you don't have to do this, please
You can stop now, PLEASE..
You can stop now..
(Kristen Screams)
Look at my face, don't please
Please Please!
Noooo....Nooooo
-Can I have one?
-Are you a sinner?
Sometimes...
It will be easier next time..
(Kristen Screams) Ahhhhhhh--