DISPATCHER: South Hartford 911.
What is your emergency?
(LINE DISCONNECTS)
(DISTORTED)
This is Lieutenant Dreyfus,
badge number 3525, at 174 Willow Lane.
Now entering what appears to be
the living room.
Living conditions are best described as
being in a state of disarray.
Watch your step.
Kitchen also in a state of disarray.
Approaching the stairwell
where first victim was found.
Note the instrument on the floor.
Victim number one is facing north.
Male, approximately 160 pounds.
Sustained injury to the left temple.
Now entering the basement
where victims number two and three
were found.
Entered the basement of the house.
We find victim number two.
Female, approximately 120 pounds.
Facing west.
In the victim's right hand,
we have religious paraphernalia,
apparently is clutching.
Heading south
we find another instrument on the floor.
We find victim number three.
Male, approximately 210 pounds.
We have trauma to the head.
Apparent strangulation with rope,
which is broken or torn away.
We have blood splattering
against the door.
In the center of the room,
we have a chair.
The right armrest of the chair is broken
with apparent claw marks
from a struggle.
Various straps used for restraint.
(THUDDING)
(CRASHING)
ANNOUNCER: WJBP, Channel 11.
A quiet South Hartford community
was leveled by tragedy as
three clergy members were found dead.
At about 11:47 p.m.
on Sunday evening, the 20th,
we received an emergency call
on our 911 line.
REPORTER: At least three bodies
were taken out of this house,
two local priests and a nun.
We checked the location for any
other victims and have not found any.
REPORTER: Apparently,
Maria Rossi was hosting
a church group meeting at her home.
Our homicide detectives
and our lab people
are conducting their investigation.
REPORTER: Mrs. Rossi was found
by police in a crawl space.
We can't speculate as to what
the cause or the motive may have been.
They are not ruling out any possibilities.
However, at this time,
we don't want to speculate
on what may or may not have been
the cause.
My name is Isabella Rossi
and that was my mother.
The thing you have to understand
about my mother
is that she just had a huge heart.
(SINGING) Down came the rain
and washed the spider out
Out came the sun
and dried up all the rain
And there we are.
That was actually on my...
Can you see that?
That was my first birthday party.
And I don't think it was until I was
about six years old that
I actually started to notice, you know,
something was different,
her moods were changing.
Then, she went away for a little bit
and when she came back
they said she was better.
But she wasn't.
We couldn't understand
what was happening.
No one had answers.
MICHAEL SCHAEFER:
So why are you doing this film?
Because I really need to
understand what happened.
What Maria Rossi did,
and her subsequent life,
was incredibly tragic and clouded.
And caught in the middle of it
is a daughter who is just now learning
the circumstances of that tragedy.
MARIA: Isabella,
look at the camera, honey.
If someone had asked me
how is it possible for Mrs. Rossi
to have done what she did,
I would have gone through the list
of things that cause human aggression.
Something like major depression,
or schizophrenia,
or dissociative identity disorder.
It's my understanding
that her current psychiatric diagnosis
has been D.I.D.
But this is her seventh different
diagnosis since 1987.
ISABELLA: You start wondering,
is it in my genes?
You know,
am I going to flip out one day?
Just a matter of time?
Two years after she brutally murdered
three people in her home,
a South Hartford jury
found Maria Rossi not guilty
by reason of insanity.
Rossi was committed
to the South Hartford State Asylum.
ISABELLA: And then in September
of that year,
my mother was transferred
to the Centrino Mental Hospital
for the Criminally Insane in Rome, Italy.
I never really questioned why Italy.
MICHAEL: When did your father tell you
what really happened?
May 23, 2009. I was 25 years old.
He just said it. He said,
"Mom attacked those people
during an exorcism."
An exorcism performed on her.
It's the job of science to try to sort out
what is a reasonable,
plausible explanation.
But science can't explain everything,
such as a person
levitating two feet off the ground
during an exorcism.
I asked my dad if he thought
she was possessed.
He said he didn't know.
That she was gone. It didn't matter.
Not any more.
He died three days later.
I called the church
where the priests had come from.
And they wouldn't talk about it.
They said they don't have
an ordained exorcist and never did.
So we're on our way to see
the Vatican School for Exorcism.
And to see my mother.
MICHAEL: Are you nervous?
Yeah, I'm nervous.
Twenty years is a long time, you know?
So, later, I was contacted
by the Diocese of Rome.
They told me they never authorized
my mother's exorcism.
That's when I knew I had to go to Italy.
I wonder how seriously they take
the exorcism school, you know.
I hope it's not a joke.
(BLOWING WHISTLE)
Oh, wow.
There it is, St. Peter's Square.
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
Something like that.
ISABELLA: This school has drawn
a lot of interest from all over the world.
Maybe it can help me understand
my mother's situation a little better.
FATHER ROBERT GALLO: From
post-traumatic shock to serious injury,
death even.
And not just for the victim.
Also for the family members,
for anyone in the vicinity,
especially the priest.
Sometimes a person
can be tormented
by more than one demon
in what we call
multiple demonic possession.
These cases are extremely
volatile and dangerous,
and they sometimes
lead to transference,
which means
the demon jumps from one person
to another.
The purpose of the class
is to educate priests
and, of course, laypeople,
about the Devil's presence in their lives,
in modern society.
For example, in Italy alone
there are over 800 satanic cults
We had a problem.
We needed more exorcists.
If it is possession,
then first and foremost
we must rule out mental illness.
Schizophrenia. Bipolar disorder.
The course is designed
to explore all these conditions.
(SHOUTING ON TAPE)
(IN ITALIAN)
(MRS. SORLINI SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
(GAGGING)
(SNARLING)
Momma.
(RETCHING)
(LAUGHING IN SQUEAKY VOICE)
(MRS. SORLINI SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
(IN ENGLISH)
(CRASHING)
Okay, anyone, any thoughts on that?
I believe the subject
was clearly possessed.
The subject
spoke in multiple languages.
Come on. Speaking in tongues? Maybe.
Incoherent babbling from
a mentally-disturbed person, certainly.
I'm sorry, Father.
And the subject displayed
abnormal strength
when confronted with holy water,
and while heavily sedated.
The delusional mind
of a paranoid schizophrenic
may actually react to holy water
as if it were,
I don't know, acid, urine.
I'm sorry, I'm gonna have to disagree.
The girl fractured her own femur.
Her strength might have been abnormal,
but not impossible.
It's very well known that
some epileptics do break their bones
during a seizure. It's a fact.
GALLO: As I said, we must be sure
to rule out mental illness.
In the end, this case
could not be proved as possession.
ISABELLA: - The diversity of the class
was comforting.
It wasn't just priests or nuns,
but regular people,
people who are facing
the same things I'm facing.
People like me,
looking to help someone.
ISABELLA: So why are you here?
All this knowledge, you all agree on this,
all this knowledge
is invaluable for us, no?
David, what would you say
drew you to this school?
In particular, to exorcism?
The combination
of science and religion.
I think,
based on my background in medicine,
it gave me a greater sense of purpose.
We all talk so definitively
about God and about the Devil
but we can all agree that there's
no real facts, right? No proofs?
God has never helped me.
What about you?
Sure. Yeah.
So when do you actually witness
an exorcism in class?
This class is all theory.
This is a school of exorcism, is it not?
It's not reality.
Look at the tape we watched today.
That girl fit every criteria for possession
except she wasn't.
It's a mental disorder.
No. When you witness
someone possessed,
you'll know the difference.
You say that like you have.
Have you witnessed a real exorcism,
Father?
Yeah. Right after he saw
the Easter Bunny.
I may have.
Can I ask you something, Isabella?
- Sure.
- I'm curious.
Why are you doing this documentary?
I will be honest. My mom.
When I was about eight years old
she murdered three people.
Members of her church.
I found out that she had committed
these murders during an exorcism.
An exorcism on her.
- See you.
- It was nice meeting you.
Your mother must be at Centrino, right?
- Have you seen her yet?
- Tomorrow.
Okay, well, the class
won't give you the answers you need.
You need to see a real one.
How do you know when it's real?
You know.
Good luck.
Thanks.
(SIGHS)
That was interesting.
- Hey.
MICHAEL: - What are you looking at?
My mother's hospital instruction manual.
Look at this thing, it's huge.
Okay.
So, camera one, two and three.
Which one do I look at?
MICHAEL: You don't have to look
directly at the camera.
Right. I knew that.
MICHAEL: Remember, the cameras
are always running when the car's on.
Let's go.
You know,
my father received a letter from Rome.
I guess because priests were involved.
The Holy Church got involved as well.
And they said that they wanted to
treat my mother at Centrino.
They called it
an "offering of forgiveness."
And I remember thinking that meant
God was forgiving my mother.
I was young.
Okay.
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
- No camera.
MICHAEL: - Show him the media pass.
(THAN KING IN ITALIAN)
ISABELLA: It felt like a prison.
An old prison, really.
But Dr. Costa seemed concerned,
so that was good.
Uh... Follow me.
I only show you this because your
mother has not had a violent outburst
in over 7 years.
(GRUNTING)
She's extraordinarily anti-religious.
We refrain from religious items
and discussion at all times.
They can make her hostile.
But I want to put...
(GROANS)
(LAUGHING MANIACALLY)
(GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT TALKING ON TAPE)
That's enough.
I'm not sure if you knew this, doctor,
but my mother was involved
in an exorcism
while she committed those murders.
Did you know that?
Isabella, your mother's case,
although unique,
is not a matter of demonic possession.
It's a matter of brain function.
So why do you think she was transferred
all the way from the States to Rome?
I don't know.
It was before I arrived here.
DR. COSTA: Unfortunately,
we've had to keep her heavily medicated.
An exhaustive amount of meds,
to be honest.
Anti psychotics.
Sedatives. Anti-anxiety.
It constantly changes.
She is a very, very complex patient.
(PATIENT SINGING)
Miss Rossi, let's keep moving.
She is having a very good day today.
But there still are rules.
Don't talk about faith or God.
And stay passive.
Hostility and aggression are...
Well, they've provoked her in the past.
(DOOR BUZZING)
Just precautions. It will be fine.
In fact, there is a very good chance
she won't even recognize you.
Maria?
You have a visitor.
Come. Come.
Hi, Mom.
I like your drawings.
Maria, I'd like to speak with you
if you'd let me, please.
My name is Isabella.
Isabella Rossi.
I'm your daughter.
I just haven't seen you in a long time.
Connect the cuts.
Connect the cuts. Connect the cuts.
Do you recognize this?
MARIA: Do you know
how to connect the cuts?
I don't know what that means.
Connect the cuts.
Did you do that to yourself?
Please stop.
Maria, I came a very long way
to see you.
Do you want to see my painting?
Yes. I'd like that. I'd love that.
Yes, yes. Maria, he was your husband.
You loved him very much.
Do you remember?
Who are you?
I'm Isabella. I'm your daughter.
- I don't have a daughter.
- Yes, yes, you do.
We just haven't seen each other
in a very long time.
I don't have a daughter.
Do I?
(ISABELLA CRYING)
Why? Why?
Why not?
(GASPS)
Well, thank you for coming.
Please say hello to your family from me.
Have a nice day. Thank you for coming.
I have to go. I have to go.
I have to get ready. I have to get ready.
I have to get ready. Get ready.
Get ready.
You shouldn't have killed.
What did you say?
Maria, please. I don't have a lot of time.
Please, tell me something.
You shouldn't have killed your child.
What?
It's against God's will, you know.
(SCREAMING)
(INDISTINCT)
DR. COSTA: Out, out, out!
MICHAEL: Shit, that was great.
That was great stuff.
Are you all right?
Isabella?
Isabella, I...
(SOBBING)
ISABELLA: What's it like,
losing both parents?
It feels empty.
Like there's no safety net
to fallback on.
And it forces you to be resilient.
Possession and exorcism
have dictated my life.
It took my mom
and it basically killed my dad.
It defines me now.
I mean, here I am
I flew halfway across...
You know, halfway across the world
to see this woman
who I never thought I'd see again.
I don't like that it defines me.
ISABELLA: I contacted
Father Ben Rawlings and David Keane
in hopes that they would review
the footage of my mother.
Luckily, they agreed
and invited me to their loft.
Isabella, hi, welcome.
- How are you?
- Good. Come in.
It's hard to say
why I wanted to be a priest.
Maybe I was drawn to helping people.
I think that duality exists within all of
us and, occasionally, it can take form.
Science can no longer help,
and religion has to take over.
Which can be really difficult
for people to accept.
Isabella, nice to see you again.
How are you? You okay? Okay, great.
- Can I get you a cup of tea or anything?
- Sure.
I'm sorry, I forgot your...
- Michael.
My family were always very religious.
My mother and father,
they were teachers,
but I was closest to my uncle.
He was a priest.
By the time I was 13,
he told me that he was an exorcist.
And, well,
if you can imagine...
It's like, I suppose, you know,
you being told that
your dad is Superman.
That's what it felt like to me.
That he was in direct,
you know, war, I suppose,
with the Devil.
And, I don't know,
it blew me away, really.
And so, he took me along with him
and by the time I was 18,
I'd seen four exorcisms.
I'd even assisted on one.
And it just changes you.
Unfortunately, he passed away
a couple years ago.
Anyway, when I was 23,
I went into the priesthood.
And by the time I was 27,
I was an ordained exorcist.
But I'll tell you this.
After all the years
that I've been in the Church
I've seen the Devil
way more than I've seen God.
That's just not the way
it's supposed to be.
There, what did she say to you there?
Oh, uh...
Yeah, at the end there,
she started remembering things,
specific things,
and she said something to me.
But I'm not sure if she said...
What? What was it?
I terminated a pregnancy
about four years ago.
The doctor said
I couldn't carry it to term, so...
Anyway, she knew about it,
and she said that...
Something about
being against God's will or something.
Hang on. Let's just look at that.
It's against God's will, you know.
ISABELLA:
That means something, right?
DAVID: Possibly. You said you had
a copy of her medical charts?
Wait, wait, wait.
What are those?
ISABELLA: Oh! She cuts herself.
DAVID: Those are crosses, Ben.
Crosses? Wait, wouldn't she
not want crosses if she's possessed?
- Not necessarily.
- Look at them. Look at them.
The way that she's seeing them,
they're upside down.
They're inverted crosses.
They're typically used in Satanic rituals.
I don't have a daughter.
DAVID: Wait, is she speaking
with an accent?
ISABELLA: Yeah,
she did that some. Why?
DAVID: Different accents can be like
speaking in tongues.
The pregnancy,
did you tell her about that at all?
ISABELLA: No.
DAVID: And you're absolutely sure
there's no other way
she could have found out?
I mean, there's no way.
See, there are basically four factors
when it comes to
determining demonic possession.
One, unnatural strength.
You got aversion to holy objects.
Languages or events
that they could not have known.
And preternatural movement,
which is basically
objects moving around the room.
So, strength? No. Languages, no.
Preternatural movement, no.
Aversion to holy objects, maybe.
Yeah, but there are accents
and, Ben, she knew that information.
Yeah, that interests me.
We need to show you something.
Okay. Can I bring the camera?
- Sure.
- All right.
Okay.
- Can I bring this?
- Yeah, of course. Come on through.
MICHAEL: I'm good. I'm right behind you.
Keep going.
ISABELLA: What is all this?
Who are these people?
BEN: These are people
the Church turned down for exorcism.
- And they're all possessed?
BEN: - We believe they are.
These two cases are resolved.
Those two are open
and we're almost done with this one.
This is the girl, Rosa, right?
From the video we saw in Gallo's class?
You both thought she was possessed.
BEN: She is.
We think the Church made a mistake.
So correct me if I'm wrong,
but you guys are performing
these exorcisms yourselves,
without the Church's permission?
That's right. We have to. Otherwise,
these people would continue to suffer.
What is all that?
DAVID: We monitor everything.
Heart rate, blood pressure.
Yeah, go ahead.
That's a camera we use
to determine pupil dilation,
which is very important
in cases of possession.
Nine millimeters
is as large as the average pupil gets.
Maybe 10 or 11
under certain substances
like cocaine, psilocybin,
methamphetamines.
Anything above 11
is considered preternatural.
Why doesn't the Church
help these people?
You see, that's just it.
The Church isn't in the business
of healing people.
The bureaucracy won't allow it.
Their hands are tied. In 1999,
the Church changed the exorcism rites
for the first time in almost 400 years.
Now a priest has to be
absolutely certain
that there's an evil presence
in order to even attempt an exorcism.
And that's a near impossible task,
because a lot of the time
it takes an exorcism
for a demon to reveal itself.
But rather than get distracted
by the Church's hypocrisy,
we're going to
continue to care for these people.
So that means that my mother's case
can actually be something...
DAVID: No, no. Isabella, you...
The Church will never pursue
your mother's case
because the last time someone did,
people died.
What do you suggest?
If you really want to help your mother,
you need a better understanding
of exorcism.
A real understanding.
Okay. So take more classes
and maybe show Gallo the tape?
Isabella, you'll learn more
in five minutes of an exorcism
than you will
in three months in some class.
Plus, you'll get to know
the real difference
between possession and mental illness.
So witness a real exorcism?
With you?
If you want.
So the exorcism rites,
when they were updated,
what exactly changed?
Well, for one, all media coverage
of exorcisms were banned.
Not that they were filmed much anyway.
Exorcisms can take minutes
or they can take years.
No two are the same.
Is this thing we're doing even legal?
No. Not exactly.
You never know what's going to happen.
(CROWS CAWING)
(CHURCH BELLS DINGING)
So do you still get nervous or...
(BARKING)
No, not really.
Demons, like angels, have orders,
or spheres, to be more specific.
A hierarchy, basically.
Now, it's imperative you get the demon
to reveal itself so you can deduce
its rank in that hierarchy.
In our last session
we were able to hone in
on our demon's identity.
His name is Berith.
Look, I know we went over this before.
Keep us between you and her, okay.
I'm not kidding.
MICHAEL: All right, all right.
(BEN SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
- Father.
- How is she?
(IN ITALIAN)
- She's worse? Okay, let me see.
- No, no.
We had to move her downstairs.
To the basement.
The basement?
This is it.
We're actually going to see a person
who is supposedly possessed.
So I guess now we'll see
if it's bullshit or not.
BEN: She's in here.
Michael, come in.
Everyone, bow their heads.
May the Lord bless us and keep us.
May the Lord let His face shine upon us.
May the Lord lift up His countenance
onto us and give us peace.
- Amen.
This really is no place for her,
Mrs. Sorlini.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
We don't know what to do.
Please, please, it's going to be okay.
It's going to be okay.
Rosa?
(MRS. SORLINI SOBBING)
Bless you for your prayers.
You must leave her to us now. All right?
MRS. SORLINI: Yes, Father.
DAVID: This is to help loosen her limbs,
keep her calm.
It's very similar to a muscle relaxant.
(MOANING SOFTLY)
MICHAEL: She's looking right at me.
(MICHAEL SHUDDERING)
(BONES CRACK)
Okay.
Let's get set up.
(RECITING PRAYERS IN LATIN)
(DEVICE POWERING ON)
It's best just to stay close
to Michael, okay?
- A little to the right.
- No, no. It's set.
DAVID: It is Thursday,
December 3, 2009.
Subject, Rosa Sorlini.
Last session, November 13, 2009.
Rosa's appearance has worsened,
skin color and weight.
Temperament appears stable.
Vitals are slightly elevated,
but basically normal.
Her pupils are dilated
to approximately nine millimeters.
BEN: Okay.
Let's begin.
(RECITING PRAYERS IN LATIN)
DAVID: Pupils still normal.
BEN: Rosa, are you in there?
Can you hear me?
I want to know
how you're feeling today, Rosa.
(IN ITALIAN)
BEN: I remember last time, Rosa,
you were strong. You spoke to me.
(IN ITALIAN)
No, no, she's strong.
And getting stronger than...
(IN ITALIAN)
You don't want this one any more.
It's no good for you.
(IN GERMAN)
ISABELLA: She said my name.
She said my name.
- How did she know my name?
- Stay back. Don't listen to her.
(IN ITALIAN)
Five minutes alone with her,
I promise you, her cunt will know me.
BEN: I want you to leave the girl
out of this.
(ROSA SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
I know who you are, demon!
Your name is Berith!
(IN ITALIAN)
Behold the Cross of the Lord.
- Lord, have mercy.
- Christ, have mercy.
God, the Father of
our Lord Jesus Christ,
I appeal to Your Holy Name
that you graciously
grant me help against...
(IN ITALIAN)
(MONITOR BEEP STABILIZING)
- That you graciously grant me help
(SCREAMING)
against this unclean spirit
that's tormenting this creature of Yours!
- Ben, she's hemorrhaging!
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
God, creator and defender
of the human race,
who made man in Your own image,
look down in pity on this, Your servant!
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Help me hold her down, Ben.
Ben, help me hold her down.
Taste it, bitch!
Come taste your mother's sweet milk!
Stay back.
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
Inserting anti-coagulant.
...overwhelms it with fear and panic.
Repel, O Lord, the Devil's power.
(SPEAKING FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
Break asunder his snares.
You can't hide, Berith!
(SCREECHING)
The Mystery of the Cross
commands you!
Blood pressure's way up, 190 over 110!
Come on, hang in there!
Heart rate's up. So is blood pressure.
190 over 110. Hang in there.
(IN ITALIAN)
Blood pressure's going crazy!
It's 220 over 110! Say it, Ben!
St. Barnabas commands you!
- Ben?
- Just keep hold of her!
(IN ITALIAN)
(BEN RECITING PRAYER)
Ben, I can't hold her!
(SNARLING)
(CLANGING)
ISABELLA: Oh, my God! Where is she?
MICHAEL: David! David!
DAVID: I can't see!
I need light! I need light.
(ROSA LAUGHING)
ISABELLA: Do something!
DAVID: Get her back on the bed! Ben!
- Get her legs.
DAVID: - Michael, get away.
(STRUGGLING)
(BEN RECITING PRAYER)
I'll carve out your diseased heart
and eat it!
I have a whole army of angels
and the Lord Almighty by my side!
You want pain? I'll give you pain!
St. Barnabas commands you!
From whose sight you are not hidden!
- St. Barnabas commands you!
(SQUEALING)
St. Barnabas commands you!
You foul, treacherous beast!
Give way to Christ,
in whom you found none of your works!
Bow down before God!
(RASPING)
BEN: Okay, bring her back on her legs.
(PANTING) She's stabilizing.
She's stabilizing.
ISABELLA: Turn that off. Yeah.
(SIGHS HEAVILY)
I don't know what to say.
DAVID: Right there, right there,
you see how her pupil is normal again?
That indicates that she's clean.
Now that you have this,
now you can tell the Church, right,
that you saved her?
BEN: - No.
DAVID: Yeah, it worked. But that
doesn't mean the Church will support it.
That doesn't make any sense. Why not?
Because...
Because the Church would have us
arrested and deported.
What we're doing in the eyes of
the Church is very wrong.
That's why we know it's so right.
(MOBILE RINGING)
BEN: Look, her appearance
is completely normal,
and so quickly after the exorcism.
Hello? This is she. Excuse me.
R-O-S-S-I.
- What's that?
MICHAEL: - I don't know.
I'm her daughter.
I just got here from America.
I think that's a big mistake. We could
go back to the charts, you'll see that...
BEN: This is amazing.
Thank you.
That was the Diocese of Rome.
I asked for a reevaluation of my mother.
MICHAEL: What did they say?
They thanked me for my concerns
and said that any interference would
probably jeopardize her well-being.
Oh! And that God would be watching us
over these trying times.
DAVID: Are you all right?
Fine.
MICHAEL: I can't believe
the Church turned her down.
BEN: Of course
they're gonna turn it down.
...go straight to Dr. Costa
with my own doctor, like David.
The hospital
is outside Vatican City walls,
and I think that means
it's out of their jurisdiction.
MICHAEL: What are you two
talking about?
What's that?
What are you talking about?
- Okay. Okay.
- We need to talk.
- David? Do you have a sec? Okay.
- Yeah.
BEN: We don't know what's wrong
with Isabella's mother.
Nobody does because she hasn't been
evaluated in over 15 years.
She deserves a second opinion.
A second opinion?
It would give us enough time
to determine her condition.
No, you want to give an exorcism
to Isabella's mother.
That's not what we're saying.
We just need time and we need to know
that she's actually possessed.
MICHAEL: Yeah, then she can get
the proper attention.
Look, okay, that's not how this works.
You're here to document,
you're not here to get involved.
- First of all, it's illegal.
- No, it's not illegal.
Yes, Ben, it is!
And in the eyes of the Church...
You know, forget about the Church,
David!
Why does it always come down to that?
What if this works?
What if we find out that it's not D.I.D.?
MICHAEL: Yeah, think about it, David.
This could work.
Michael, I know what you're doing.
I know it would be provocative
for your film, but we will be arrested.
(SIGHS)
How would it even work?
As soon as they found out what we
were doing, they'd shut us down.
The staff won't be allowed with us
in the room.
Yeah, we should have that right
to privacy on her behalf, right?
Yeah, you're right.
David, just...
What if it was your own mother?
I'm really nervous.
I'm an active priest
in good standing with the Holy See.
And regardless of the outcome,
the Church will find out,
and it will put my job in jeopardy.
Father Ben Rawlings.
But at the same time,
there are problems
within this institution.
There are things that I don't agree with.
In the case of Maria Rossi,
I think we should take the time
to actively deduce whether or not
she's being tormented
by an evil presence.
I think.
BEN: What's the Church's stance
on Maria Rossi?
Well, she's faded into the system.
She's pumped full of drugs
and forgotten.
If she becomes too difficult,
there's a panic button on the wall.
- Yeah?
- Yes, I saw that. Thank you.
The bottom line here is that something
horrible happened back in 1989.
And it wasn't Maria Rossi's fault.
You'll be screening her using SCID-D?
Two hours?
DAVID: More or less two hours, yeah.
I'd say so.
I feel the Church needs to change.
We're so eager to just brush things
under the carpet as if they don't exist.
I don't fit in this Church,
in this guise of the Church.
And I have to do what I believe.
DR. COSTA: I'll see you soon, Maria.
ISABELLA: I know it's dangerous,
and it might not even work.
But I can't just sit back and do nothing.
Okay, not a problem.
(MONITOR BEEP STABILIZING)
DAVID: The time is 8:32 a.m.
on Monday, December 7, 2009.
Subject is Maria Rossi. Session one.
Subject appears docile.
Heavily medicated.
Pupils are mildly dilated
due to the medication.
BEN: Okay. Let's wake her up.
When she wakes up,
we'll see if she gets a reaction.
DAVID: Counteracting medication.
Medication should take effect
in 20 seconds.
ISABELLA: So this is
when you provoke her?
BEN: Exactly.
DAVID: Ten seconds.
Five, four, three,
two, time.
Maria?
Maria, do you know what this is?
Maria, is there someone
in there with you?
I don't know.
BEN: Yes, you do, Maria.
Who's in there?
We can help you.
We can free you from it.
EKG is normal.
They'll be angry.
There's more than one?
Maybe she's clean.
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
What was that?
Yeah, we got something.
(BEEP STABILIZING)
Her pupil's still normal.
It's nothing.
ISABELLA: Is she all right?
BEN: Yeah, she...
She's sleeping.
That's the first time
I've seen a possessed person
fall asleep when confronted by
a priest and holy water.
ISABELLA: What does that mean?
(SIGHING) I don't know. I think...
I think we might be wasting our time.
ISABELLA: I came here for her and I'm
going to do everything I can to help her.
This isn't consistent with any form
of possession that I've ever seen.
I'm sorry, Isabella. This...
(SCREAMING)
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
DAVID: Her pupils are
almost fully dilated!
Lord, have mercy! Christ, have mercy!
- What are you doing?
- We're helping her, David!
We need to help her!
- Ben, this is not the time or the place!
- Stay back.
I need you to calm down.
- Christ, have mercy.
- Christ, hear us.
- Christ, please hear us.
- God, the Father in Heaven.
(SCREAMS)
I know you! I know you, little girl!
- God, the Father in Heaven.
(MARIA LAUGHING EVILLY)
DAVID: God, the Father in Heaven,
most merciful.
BEN: God, the Father of
our Lord Jesus Christ,
I appeal to Your Holy Name
against this unclean spirit!
- I know you!
(SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)
(MARIA GRUNTING)
Shove that needle in your fucking eye,
you faggot!
(LAUGHING)
I adjure you, ancient serpent
by the judge of the living
and of the dead.
ISABELLA: - Don't get too close.
- By your Creator...
DAVID: Ben? Ben?
ISABELLA: Michael!
The faith of the holy apostles
and of all the saints commands you,
reveal yourself before the Creator!
ISABELLA: - Watch it!
(GROANS)
David!
BEN: The devout prayers of holy men...
God the Father commands you!
(DISTORTED) Oh, you can't get back
in your God's good graces, priest.
Not after what you did.
- Ben, what are you doing?
DAVID: - Her vitals are going crazy.
(SCREECHING)
BEN: Get back. Get back.
DAVID: Michael, put the camera down
and help!
ISABELLA: I want to help her!
DAVID: Get her leg! Get her leg!
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
Careful. Grab her leg!
I got her. Get her arm.
Isabella, is it locked?
BEN: - Close the bolt!
- Yes! Yes!
(SPEAKING IN GERMAN)
Tell me your name, coward!
Asbeel!
Come that close to me one more time
and I'll use your tongue
to skull fuck the baby killer over there!
(SINGING) The itsy bitsy spider
came down the water spout
(MONITOR BEEP STABILIZING)
BOTH: Down came the rain
and washed the spider out
Out came the sun...
BEN: Isabella, don't listen to it.
It's not your mother.
- Come on, baby.
- Isabella, it's not your mother!
You know the words.
MICHAEL: Isabella, snap out of it!
- Do it!
- Demons!
(IN GERMAN)
You are guilty
before our Lord Jesus Christ
whom you dared to nail upon the cross.
DAVID: Pulse is 284. Rhythm is way off.
(SPEAKING IN SHRILL TONE)
I'm not like the others, demon!
Do you hear me, transgressor?
- I hear you, priest.
- Seducer!
All you fucking do is talk!
(SPITS)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(GUARD SHOUTING IN ITALIAN)
The holy apostles Peter and Paul
and all the saints command you.
Give way to Christ,
in whom you found none of your works!
For it is not He who condemns you,
but rather He
who rules the living and the dead.
Our Father, who art in heaven...
ISABELLA: No, it's gonna kill her!
BEN: Just stay there, Isabella.
No, no, no.
BEN: For thine is the kingdom,
and the power, and the glory,
for ever and ever. Amen.
Let my mother go.
(IN HOARSE VOICE) You'll burn.
You'll burn eternal.
Poor child.
GUARD: - Please, open this door now!
(CONTINUES BANGING ON DOOR)
Pulse is dropping.
Maria? Maria, can you hear us?
DAVID: Starting to regain
consciousness.
Temp is returning to normal.
Over.
BEN: Tell me your name, coward!
MARIA: Asbeel!
I'll be feeling that tomorrow.
See, this is preternatural movement
right here.
I've seen it before,
but I've never captured it on tape.
So, what does that mean?
It means we've got
everything that we need right here.
This is huge, Isabella.
Let's play it again.
BEN: Do you realize how big this is?
With the evidence we've got,
the Holy See has to see us.
They have to.
We can go to the press with this
and in an instant, we'd have
1,000 people standing out there.
DAVID: Our priority right now
should be getting her back to the States.
The endorsement of Dr. Costa is vital.
But after the results that he saw,
there's no way that he can't agree.
Dr. Costa doesn't believe
that she was possessed or anything.
He thinks it was an exercise
that shocked her system.
Anyway, it doesn't matter
what he believes
because his referral's actually gonna
help us get her back to the States.
(DISTORTED) Oh, you can't get back
in your God's good graces, priest.
MICHAEL: What are you doing?
I'm just...
I'm just analyzing Maria's audio.
I'm just trying to work out if there is
more than one voice inside her.
See, there can...
(DISTORTED VOICES
TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
See? See? Right there. You hear that?
- She's speaking in tongues, right?
- No, no.
It's one sentence, spoken in
more than one language, I think.
I'm just trying to isolate how many.
(VOICES DISTORTING)
MARIA: You wanted him to die,
didn't you?
Ben, what is she talking about?
You wanted him to die, didn't you?
Is she talking about your uncle?
I found four voices on the recording.
DAVID: You found four?
ISABELLA: Wait, what does that mean?
It means that the entity
in your mother had disciples.
We call it multiple demonic possession.
You might have heard
Gallo talking about it in class.
ISABELLA: Wait,
so it's a powerful demon.
BEN: Yeah. It's a beast.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
- What?
- You know how lucky we are?
Look, we're gonna deliver all our
findings to the Holy See next Friday.
Yeah, maybe.
He hasn't agreed to see us.
Yeah, well, have you told him that
the press might be interested?
DAVID: That's not very diplomatic.
Can't we just wait a little bit
till my mother's case is resolved?
I mean, the press?
Hang on a minute. Just because
you've got what you want now,
you're expecting us just to keep quiet?
Michael, please, just get...
Stop! Stop! That's not what I meant!
Because there are lot more
people to help
rather than just your mother, okay?
DAVID: Wait, did Father Gallo call you?
ISABELLA: What's your problem?
No. You?
Yeah, he called me twice.
What did he say?
He wants to help us
make the right decision.
He's worried about us.
Especially, he's worried about me.
- You? Why?
- Because of my job, Ben.
David, what are you doing
with the papers? Are you okay?
I'm fine. The conversation's just
giving me a little bit of a headache.
David, he's just trying to scare you.
That's all.
ISABELLA: - Is that blood?
- He's a moral man.
And he's toeing the company line
on this one and you know it.
ISABELLA: Is your nose bleeding?
David, you got something.
Are you okay?
BEN: - Are you okay?
- I'm sorry. I'm fine.
Look.
I'm sorry.
It's probably stress.
- It's a lot of work to do for Friday.
- Yeah.
MICHAEL: Are you all right?
- They won't release her.
- MICHAEL: What?
- Why not?
- I don't know. They won't say.
They can't or won't believe
that she's better.
- Where are my keys?
- I don't...
Where are my fucking keys?
They were right here.
- I don't know. Relax.
- Where are my fucking keys, Michael?
I don't know.
It feels like they'll never release her.
There's no way
the Church can't see this.
I can look them in the eye and tell them
that it was the right thing to do.
(BAGPIPES PLAYING)
This is what they do.
They cover things up, they ignore it,
no matter who it hurts or destroys.
Well, not this time.
Not this fucking time.
This was supposed to be
about my mother. Not anybody else.
Not about Ben's ego, or David's job.
I have a sinking feeling I'm going to be
excommunicated for all this. I think.
- For what we did.
- David's inner coward
is really coming out.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
Ben and David, maybe I get them.
They have their own thing going on,
but Isabella,
we started this together.
Michael just has to stop.
- He just wants to...
(CLATTERING)
They have this group of three
and I'm like
the annoying guy with the camera.
David, what the fuck are you doing?
If it weren't for me
no one would know anything
about what the hell they're doing
in their Church and in their basements.
ISABELLA: Look, I really think
we need to talk about some stuff.
(MUNCHING)
- What's wrong with the camera?
- I don't know. Just...
What's wrong?
- Not then. Before she hit you.
- Michael, did you see anything?
No, I didn't see anything.
BEN: Okay, we'll just try another...
ISABELLA: This is something else.
Yeah, but it's at the exact same time.
It must have been just a power surge
through the hospital.
It's the only thing I can think of.
For all the cameras?
It could be something else.
BEN: - Hey, we're filming.
- I'm sorry.
ISABELLA: - David, you have to see this.
- I have to go.
BEN: - I said we're filming.
- I know. I heard you. I got to go.
BEN: What's the matter?
- The bishop denied our request.
BEN: - What?
It's just a bloody meeting.
What was the reason?
The incident's under investigation.
BEN: Well, of course it is.
ISABELLA: David...
BEN: - David.
- Yeah?
- It's going to be okay. All right?
- I hope so.
MICHAEL: - David, wait, wait.
I'm coming with you, remember?
The baptism?
Come on. Let's go.
- Michael, how long is this going to take?
- Just a second.
- Do we really need this?
- Yep.
- Are you okay with that, David?
- I'm fine. You ready?
DAVID: Baptism, baptism.
Baptism is the transferal of sins,
both original and personal.
Now, for example,
if a baby were to die
after being baptized
it would go to Heaven.
And if before
it would go to Hell.
DAVID: In the name of the Father
and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
(BABY COOING)
ALL: - Amen.
Brethren, our fair Father Christ
in His great loving kindness
hath ordained that His mystic bride,
the Holy Mother of the Church,
to protect her children at every stage
from the cradle to the grave.
And to this end is the Sacrament
of Holy Baptism ordained.
ALL: Amen.
John Thomas,
in the name of Christ our Lord
I anoint thee with oil for thy safekeeping.
John Thomas,
I baptize you
in the name of the Father,
and of the Son
and of the Holy Spirit.
(BABY COUGHING)
MICHAEL: David? What's he doing?
David!
- Father, stop.
- Please stop!
What are you doing, David?
David, stop, stop!
David! For God's sake!
Somebody, stop him!
(ALL CLAMORING)
You know what I'd like to do?
I'd like to take this fucking camera,
turn it around
and stick it in Michael's face.
I'd like to ask him,
"What was it like, Michael?"
"What was it like when"
"your mom fucked
your father's best friend?"
(DOOR OPENING)
(CHUCKLES)
BEN: David?
Hey, David!
(DOOR SHUTS)
Michael, what's wrong with David?
What's happened?
What's going on?
(MICHAEL SIGHS)
The...
The kid almost died.
What?
What happened? What did you say?
The baby he was baptizing,
he almost drowned it.
BEN: - What are you doing?
- Setting up the camera.
BEN: No, wait. Just leave the camera.
ISABELLA: Is the baby okay?
Yeah, I think so.
ISABELLA: You think so? Did you see it?
Were you there or not?
MICHAEL: Do I think the baby's okay?
Yeah.
BEN: Is he in trouble?
I don't know.
They called the police and he just left.
- David!
BEN: - Okay, just come back when you...
Well, he's been acting strange all day.
Did you see it happen?
See it? I filmed it! It
was like he lost it!
He's been under a lot of stress lately,
so maybe that contributed to...
I don't know.
You should have been there.
It was like he was crazy!
Has anything like this
ever happened before?
No, of course not!
(LOUD CRASHING)
ISABELLA: David!
BEN: David?
ISABELLA: What the hell's going on?
BEN: Michael, get the camera.
We need the light.
MICHAEL: Ben?
BEN: David?
(LOUD THUDDING)
(DAVID SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
David?
(DRAGGING BED)
MICHAEL: (WHISPERING)
What's he doing up there?
Watch. Careful.
ISABELLA: What the hell is all this?
BEN: I don't know.
Ben, are those Bible pages?
MICHAEL: Oh, Jesus.
BEN: David!
Come here. What have you done?
Oh, my God, Ben.
He's bleeding all over.
Get his arms up.
Put them up. Put them up.
(SHUSHING)
- No, no, no.
- What is it?
(MUTTERING AND WHEEZING)
ISABELLA: No, no, no.
- What do we do, Ben?
(STUTTERING) - I don't know!
- What do you mean, you don't know?
- I don't know.
I don't know what to do!
Where's...
(ISABELLA SCREAMING)
Go, go, go! Get out! Stay out!
Stay downstairs!
Don't come back upstairs again!
Just stay down there!
- Okay, okay.
BEN: - Look at me. Look in my eyes.
Michael, did you see his eyes?
Did you see his eyes?
(DOOR BANGS OPEN)
- Shit!
Polizia! Polizia!
No, no.
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
Father Keane?
Where is Father David Keane?
MICHAEL: - He's upstairs.
- He's very, very sick.
- Turn on the lights.
- I can't.
MICHAEL: This is the only light we have.
- OFFICER: Are you David Keane?
- No, no.
He's upstairs, he's upstairs,
but it's not safe to go up there!
Stay down here, please!
MICHAEL: Holy shit.
BEN: Do you need the light?
(OFFICER SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
(LOUD THUD)
BEN: - David!
(BOTH STRUGGLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
- BEN: He took your gun?
- Yes, he took my gun!
We need to get out right now.
All of us need to get out. We need to...
David? David?
David?
He's my friend!
David? David, listen to me.
Put down the gun.
- Just put down the gun, yeah?
ISABELLA: - David...
Listen to me. It's Ben, okay?
It's your friend.
ISABELLA: (SHOUTING) - No, no!
- Be quiet, Isabella.
David, listen to me, all right?
This isn't you.
Just listen to my voice, okay?
This is your friend, Ben.
This isn't you.
Something else
has taken control of you.
You know this. You know this.
Okay?
Focus on my voice.
You need to trust me, David. Okay?
Just stay calm.
(SOBBING) I can't stop.
I can't stop it, Ben!
You can, you can fight it.
Just fight it! Fight it, David.
Our Father, who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done on earth...
I forgot it.
- Just give me the gun.
- I forgot it.
He says to say, "Thank you".
(GUNSHOT)
MICHAEL: Jesus!
BEN: (SCREAMING) The light!
(OFFICER SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
Come here, come here. Oh, shit.
(SHUDDERING)
Fuck!
(SCREAMING)
I need an ambulance now!
MICHAEL: What's wrong with her?
She's having a seizure. Come here.
(SIREN WAILING)
You saw his eyes, right?
- Ben!
- I saw his eyes!
- Tell me what's happening, Ben!
- I don't want to...
I got to know what's happening, Ben!
Maybe there's some
transference.
Demonic transference?
Of course I mean demonic transference,
Michael!
- Transference like?
- Just fucking...
- Michael, please just shut the fuck up!
- Don't you fucking yell at me, Ben!
Of course I'm gonna fucking yell at you!
You've been here
the whole fucking time!
Have you not listened to me?
Jesus.
(FACULTY TALKING INDISTINCTLY
IN ITALIAN)
No, no! Please, wait here.
Wait out there! Yes, please.
(ISABELLA SHUDDERING)
MICHAEL: Her name is Isabella Rossi.
Can we see her yet?
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY IN ITALIAN)
I believe there's transference.
- I don't know. Not for certain.
- MICHAEL: Who are you talking to?
More than one. Four, possibly.
Okay, okay. I'll bring her to you
as soon as I can, Father Gallo.
Thank you.
Yeah, I know. It's David's fault.
The doctor asked me to talk to you, yes.
She's doing much better, your friend.
She's stable and she's resting,
so I suggest you go.
When can we see her?
She's gonna be here overnight,
so you can see her tomorrow.
Overnight? That's not possible.
Why is that?
There's something wrong with her.
It's not safe here.
No, this is very safe, I assure you.
Something's wrong with her.
We need to get her
out of here right now.
No, gentlemen, we are extremely...
Do you know
who Father Robert Gallo is?
Father Gallo, yes, I know him,
but I don't understand...
(CLANGING)
(MONITOR BEEPING RAPIDLY)
BEN: Isabella?
(ISABELLA SCREAMING)
Isabella?
(CLANGING)
MICHAEL: What do we do, Ben?
BEN: Isabella, listen to me!
(SCREAMING)
We need to get her out of here now!
(FACULTY CLAMORING IN ITALIAN)
(SPEAKING IN ITALIAN)
Michael!
I've got her now!
We need to get her under control!
(BONES CRACKING)
(SCREECHING) Help me, please!
I know this woman.
She needs to be sedated. Do it, now!
Jesus will bring your plans to nothing.
Christ will have none of your plans.
Let's take this outside.
(ISABELLA SCREAMING)
Michael, put the camera down!
Listen to me. I'm a priest.
Please, go and help those people.
- Keep her here.
- DOCTOR: Thank you, Father.
Okay, let's go, let's go, let's go.
- Come on.
- MICHAEL: She just killed that woman.
BEN: We need to end this.
Grab her legs. Help me grab her legs!
We're going to Father Gallo's.
MICHAEL: What's he going to do?
BEN: I need help with the exorcism.
Get the door. Get the door.
BEN: Oh, my God. What have I done?
You really think Gallo's going to help?
Yeah, I need help.
- I need to fix this.
(GASPING)
Oh, shit. Oh, shit. She's waking up.
She's waking up.
We haven't got much time, Michael.
We haven't got much time.
Stay with me. Don't let it get to you.
When I was 13,
my uncle told me he was an exorcist.
You can't get back
into God's good graces, priest.
(WHISPERING) Not after what you did.
Ben?
(DISTORTED) You wanted him to die,
didn't you?
What is she doing?
(IN MALE VOICE)
He says to say, "Thank you."
Who are you?
You know me. Everyone knows me.
- Lord, have mercy! Christ, have mercy!
(SCREAMING)
Jesus.
God the Father!
(SCREECHING)
Oh, my God!
Oh, shit!
(SCREAMING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
BEN: Your place is in solitude!
Your abode is in the nest of serpents!
Be gone forthwith
from this servant of God!
Get out of her! Get out of her!
(BEN RECITING PRAYERS IN LATIN)
It's working, right?
I have got her under control,
but I don't know for how long.
You've got to hurry up.
(PANTING) It's okay.
It's going to be okay. I'm sorry.
(ALARM BLEEPING)
Just be strong.
- Be strong.
(ENGINE REWING)
Just be strong.
(VEHICLE HONKING)
Michael!
(CRASHING)