[WAVES LAPPING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GRUNTS QUIETLY]
[SURFER SHOUTING ON VIDEO]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
[SURFER WHOOPING]
Oh-oh!
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
[BOY PANTING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Is that you on the beach?
- Oh, no, no, that's my, that's my mom.
- Oh.
Yeah. She came to this beach when
she found out she was pregnant with me.
I've never been, but, uh,
it's kind of our beach.
[QUIET LAUGH]
That's my little sister.
[MAN] Ah.
[LAUGHS]
[MAN SPEAKING SPANISH]
Um, you want to see more photos?
- I can...
- Um...
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
It's only for your eyes.
Real. Authentic.
You're right.
Thank you.
Sorry. I'm American.
[CHUCKLES]
Not too many gringos here.
- Yeah, bummer.
- Gracias a Dios.
[WOMAN LAUGHS]
## ["WALK ON THE WILD SIDE"
IN SPANISH, PLAYS ON RADIO]
[PHONE CHIMES]
She's not coming?
- [SPEAKS SPANISH]
- Uh, my-my friend.
You know, uh, mi Amiga.
You know, the girl we left
back at the hotel?
You know, she smelled like Don Julio...
and bad choices?
She always does this to me, too.
She-she just, she just disappears.
She's like the-the-the fantasmo, no?
You know, you know fantasmo?
- Fantasma, con "A."
- Sí, con "A."
The whole reason I planned
to come on this trip,
con "A," was-was-was
to find the secret beach.
And now she's just stuck back at Las Rocas
with the Irish flu.
[SIGHS]
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Nursing a hangover.
Sí. Major hangover. [CONTINUES IN SPANISH]
You-you don't like it when someone
change your plans, do you?
No, I don't.
No, I don't, it's just, you know.
It's not fair.
Ooh, you know why, though?
It's because I'm reliable.
- You know "reliable"?
- Uh...
"Reliable." [SPEAKING SPANISH] Bossy.
Um, I am re-li-able.
[ELECTRONIC VOICE SPEAKS SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Yes, bossy.
[REPEATS IN SPANISH]
That's me. [SPEAKS SPANISH] Very bossy.
Hey, um...
what is this beach called?
You're not gonna tell me.
Cool.
Cool. Frio.
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
Not possible.
It's too hot here.
No, no, you're cool. You're being cool.
- Oh, never mind, that's good.
- [LAUGHS]
All right, I got it.
## [BRIGHT, JAZZY MUSIC PLAYS OVER RADIO]
Is this the one?
Sí.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GULL SCREECHING]
This is paradise.
Yeah. It's perfect.
Uh...
[SPEAKING SPANISH] This is the island
of the pregnant woman. No?
La Isla?
No.
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Yes.
The nose... the breasts...
and her stomach.
[CHUCKLING] No.
[WOMAN CHUCKLES]
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Yes, it is for me.
Gracias.
Gracias, señor, um...
- No, no, no. Por favor.
- No, please.
Please. Please, I insist.
No, no, we were going the same way.
I live close by, so... don't worry.
Oh, are you sure?
- Yes.
- Okay. Well, thank you.
You're welcome.
I'm Nancy.
- Carlos. Charlie.
- Nice to meet you, Charlie.
Nice to meet you.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Um, you know, have, high school.
You're in school?
No.
I mean, I was in medical school,
but we didn't have
Spanish there, just cadavers.
I'll shut up now. [LAUGHS QUIETLY]
Okay, uh, dark in a few hours, so...
Oh, I never surf at night.
And, uh, how you
getting out from here?
Uber.
Who is Uber?
Never mind. Thank you, Carlos.
Thank you again for taking me here.
It means a lot to me.
- Okay.
- Uh, what did you say
the name of it was again, though?
I just forgot, for some reason.
[SPEAKING SPANISH] Careful.
[SPEAKS SPANISH] Always.
[ENGINE STARTS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[PANTING]
Hey!
You speaking Spanish, guera?
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MAN SPEAKING SPANISH]
I-I don't understand. I'm sorry.
He say that it is hard
to paddle against the current.
Yeah, I wasn't expecting that.
I almost got caught
on the inside coming out.
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
- You American?
- Okay.
Sí. Sí, American.
Yeah!
California?
Uh, close.
Texas.
There's surf in Texas?
Yes, we have surf in Texas.
It's just not like this, though.
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[LAUGHTER]
[CHUCKLES]
Hey, this is a secret break.
How you find it?
Someone told me about it a while ago.
What's it called?
If I tell you,
I would have to kill you!
Well, that would ruin my day.
Anything gnarly out here,
I should know about?
There's some rocks over there!
There's only one tide a day, and when
the tide gets low, it becomes an island.
There's some nasty fire coral.
It stings like a jellyfish.
Okay! Gracias.
Sí... [SPEAKING SPANISH]
Hey, guera...
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Still have no idea what you're saying.
He's saying that you should
come over here.
The wave breaks better.
Oh, I'm okay, I'm okay.
I'm cool here, thank you.
Careful, gringa.
It's rough out here
for a little girl from Texas.
I think I'll be all right.
¡Vámonos! ¡Vámonos!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
# I don't look for trouble,
but trouble looks for me #
# And it's been waiting
around corners since I was 17 #
# They say here comes a hurricane #
# Trouble is her middle name #
# But I don't look for trouble #
# Yeah, trouble looks for me #
# Hey, hey! #
# Hey! #
[WHOOPS]
[LAUGHTER]
[SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
Oh!
[LAUGHS]
[WHOOPS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[NANCY] Yeah!
# Hey! #
# Hey, hey! #
# I don't look for trouble #
# But trouble looks for me #
# Hey, hey! #
# Hey! #
# I don't look for trouble #
# But trouble looks for me #
# Hey, hey! #
# Trouble! #
- # Comes a hurricane #
- # Trouble #
# Is my... #
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SURFERS SHOUTING IN SPANISH]
[PHONE CHIMES]
- Short crop?
- Hey!
- Guess where I am?
- Tijuana.
[LAUGHS]
Oh, my God. No way.
- Mom's beach, right?
- It's just as beautiful as she said it was.
I wish you were here.
I wish she was here.
Does that mean you're alone?
Well, I wasn't gonna come all this way just
to wuss out because I lost my plus one.
That's how you wind up
on Nancy Grace, okay?
Excuse me.
I am supposed to be the boring,
overprotective sister.
You are supposed to be the fun one.
Sis, the surf here, it's insane.
You would not believe
the perfect tube I just caught.
I could shoot tubes just as good as you,
if you would just take me out!
I'll take you. I'll take you out
as soon as I get back.
I love you, sister-mama.
- I love you, too, short crop.
- [MAN] Is that Nancy?
- It's Dad.
- Just tell him it's all fine, okay?
- Love you. Bye.
- Uh, no, it's, it's a friend.
[DAD] Hey, Nance, don't hang up.
Give me the phone. Chloe.
Hey!
Hey, Papa.
Hey, sweet pea.
Where now?
Mexico.
I don't know what to say, Nance.
I'm at a loss. [LAUGHS]
I don't, I don't, I can't understand.
- I don't expect you to.
- Well, help me out, then.
I don't know. What do you, uh,
what do you want me to say?
Oh, say you're coming back.
Say you're not dropping out of med school
after all this time, after all this work.
- You know, just don't quit.
- Okay. Okay, Dad.
That's enough. Can we just
not do this right now, please?
It's what you love. You help people.
Well, not everyone can be helped, Dad.
You-you know that.
Don't do that.
Don't make this about her.
What else would it be about?
If you want to make this
about her, then you stay in it.
She was a fighter.
It's just she fought too hard, Dad.
You know? And for what?
It all ended the same.
Just come back, Nancy.
Please.
I gotta go, okay?
- I'll see you soon.
- When?
- I don't know.
Nance.
I love you. Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[PHONE CHIMES]
[SEABIRDS CALLING]
[SLOW, DEEP BREATHING]
Yeah, girl, it's getting late.
Let's go in.
I'm gonna catch one last one. Thanks.
Okay.
- Nice meeting you guys.
- See you later, guera!
Buenas noches.
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[GASPS]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION IN SPANISH]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[SCREECHING]
[WATER BURBLES]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[GASPING]
[SQUEAKING]
[SQUEAKING, CLICKING]
[LAUGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BIRDS SCREECHING WILDLY]
[GROANS]
[EXHALES]
[GRUNTS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh!
[MUFFLED GRUNT]
[GRUNTS]
[GRUNTING]
[GASPING]
[PANTING]
[GASPS]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
[MUFFLED SCREAM]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[YELLS, GASPS]
[WHIMPERING]
[PANTING]
[GROANS]
[GASPING]
[SCREAMS]
[MUTTERING]
No!
[GROANS]
[GROANS, SOBS]
Oh...
[PANTING]
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
Help!
Hey!
Help me!
Help... me!
I'm here!
Help!
Yes. Yeah.
Here!
Here! Here!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
No!
Help!
[SOBBING] Please, help me!
[GROANS]
[PANTING]
Come back!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
- [RUMBLING]
- Oh, God...
Oh, no, no, no.
Where are you taking me?
[PANTING]
[BIRDS SCREECHING]
[GASPS]
Too far.
[WHIMPERS]
[SCREECHING]
[SCREAMS, GRUNTS]
[GROANS, GASPS]
[PANTING]
[GROANS ECHOING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GROAN ECHOES]
[ECHOING GASPS]
[SCREECHES]
[GASPS]
[CHIRPS]
Okay...
Okay.
[SIGHS DEEPLY]
[GROANS]
[PANTING]
You're not gonna feel a thing, ma'am.
I just put some
Novocain injections to, uh,
numb the area, so...
you're just gonna feel
a little pressure, but...
you're not gonna feel the stitches, okay?
Okay?
[SCREAMING]
[GROANING]
Tie off the suture. Oh, yeah.
That's a nice... That's a nice union.
[GROANING]
One more, and then we'll
send you on your way.
[SIGHING] Okay. Here we go.
[MUFFLED SCREAM]
[GASPS, WHIMPERS]
Oh!
[GASPS, GRUNTS]
[PANTING] Okay.
Okay, ma'am, nice clean wrap.
[GRUNTS]
[GASPING]
[CHIRPING]
Get in line, buddy.
[SIGHS]
Just keep it elevated, ma'am.
Someone's coming.
Okay, okay... you're gonna be fine.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[METALLIC CREAKING]
[CHITTERS]
[SHUDDERING]
- [SEAGULL SQUEALS]
- [NANCY GROANS]
[CHITTERING]
[NANCY GASPS, SHUDDERS]
[WAVES CRASHING IN DISTANCE]
[WHIMPERING]
[GROANS]
[PANTING]
[WHIMPERING]
[GROANS]
[PANTING]
There we go.
[GROANING]
[WHIMPERING]
[BLOWING]
[SIGHS] Gotta get some blood flowing.
Not enough flows
in this tourniquet for you.
[GASPING]
[WHIMPERING]
Come on. Come on.
[GROANING]
There we go.
[GROANING] There we go.
[GRUNTS, THEN SIGHS] Okay.
Okay.
[GROANING]
[SIGHING] Okay, you get
two minutes of blood flow.
Okay... okay...
[GROANS LOUDLY]
Compression bandage.
- [SEAGULL SCREECHES]
- Oh! [GRUNTS]
[GROANS]
[GROANING PAIN]
[SCREAMS]
[GROANS]
[SCREAMING]
[GASPS]
[SHOUTING]
[GROANS]
[SEAGULL SQUAWKING]
[SQUEALS]
[GAGGING]
[SEAGULL CHITTERS]
[CHITTERING]
Ew.
[GULL CHATTERS, SQUAWKS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Are you still out there?
Stay!
Good bird.
[GROANS]
Oh...
[GASPS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SHUDDERS]
[SCREAMING IN PAIN]
[GROANS]
[WHIMPERING]
[GASPING, WHIMPERING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello!
Hey!
[CONTINUES, DISTANTLY]
[PANTING]
[DISTANT] Hello!
[MAN GROANS SOFTLY]
Yeah. Yeah!
Help!
Turn around!
Come on!
NANCY: [DISTANT] Hello! [SHRIEKS]
Hey!
Help!
Help me!
Yeah! Hey! Hey!
Help!
Call for help!
Wait, wait, wait, wait. My backpack.
My backpack! It's over there!
Yes! Yes!
Over there!
¡Teléfono!
Please, go get it!
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
[WINCING]
[DISTANT] Open! Inside!
Inside, the teléfono!
Telephone, please, hurry!
Come on!
[CHUCKLES]
Please. Please.
Hurry!
No.
No, no, no.
No!
No, come back!
Come back, you can have it!
You can have it!
[SOBBING] Come back!
Come back! Please!
Please, help me!
Please!
[SOBBING]
No.
No, there's a shark!
[DISTANT] A shark!
Wait! It's okay!
Just don't go!
No! There's a shark!
Stop!
No!
Shark!
[GASPING]
[SIGHS]
[WHIMPERING]
- [SUDDEN SPLASH]
- [GASPS]
[SOBBING]
[GASPING]
[BIRDS SINGING]
[CHITTERING]
[SCREECHING]
Shut up.
[SCREECHING CONTINUES]
Shut up!
[INDISTINCT CONVERSATION]
[SIGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Stop!
Stop! Get out of the water!
Get out of the water!
Get out!
Stop!
Go back!
Shark!
Don't worry about it!
There's no sharks here!
Stop! Stop!
Get out of the water!
Get out!
Go back! Get help!
[SIGHS QUIETLY]
[SQUAWKS]
[GASPS]
[SCREAMING]
[GRUNTING]
Come on.
Come on!
Come on, come on! Swim!
Come on, come on, swim!
Come on!
Come on! I got you!
I got you! Come on! Come on!
Come on!
[GRUNTING]
[GASPING]
[PANTING]
[SPEAKS SPANISH]
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
Come on!
- [SPEAKS SPANISH]
- I got you!
-[YELLS IN SPANISH]
- I got you! Come on!
- [YELLS IN SPANISH]
[GASPING]
[PANTING SLOWLY]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GULLS SQUAWKING]
[GULL SQUAWKS]
[SHUDDERS]
[CHIRPS, CHITTERS]
[SQUAWKS]
Come on.
[CHIRPS]
[SQUAWKS]
Come on.
[SQUAWKING]
You're okay.
I'm helping you, little buddy.
Let me see you.
I'm not very good at ortho, but...
it just looks like a dislocation.
Like a separated shoulder.
[SIGHS] I think it's the same.
We'll see, huh?
I'm just gonna do this quick, okay?
It's gonna hurt just for a second,
and then you're gonna be okay.
On three. Ready?
One...
two...
- three.
- [CRACK]
- [SQUAWKING]
- I think we did it.
Ah! Ah! Hey, hey, hey!
That's a terrible way to say thank you.
[GULL CHIRPS]
Now you've got a chance, huh?
[SIGHS] And here comes the tide.
Camera.
That's the third time.
I got you.
32 seconds from the whale to the rock.
[SIGHS]
[BEEPS]
[GASPS]
[GASPING]
[GRUNTING]
[MUFFLED GROAN]
[BEEPING]
[GROANS]
[GROANING, PANTING]
[PANTING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GRUNTS]
[GASPING]
[SNARLING]
[NANCY YELLS]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GASPS]
[LAUGHS]
[WHOOPING]
SURFER: [ON VIDEO] Ah, ha, ha! Fuck!
[GARBLED AUDIO AS VIDEO FAST-FORWARDS]
¡Ayuda! ¡Ayuda!
[SURFER YELLS]
NANCY: [ON VIDEO] Come on, I got you!
- [SURFER YELLS]
- I got you!
I got you! I got you!
- Come on!
- [SURFER YELLS]
Hold on!
Oh.
Someone got you.
30, 40 yards.
One-minute swim.
I can make that.
I need a head start.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
This is Nancy Adams.
It's April 26, 2016.
Uh, if you find this,
please send help right away.
I've been attacked by a shark.
He's killed three
other people since I got here.
He's still circling, so...
Uh, he's got this big old whale
over here, but that-that's the problem.
I swam right up onto his feeding ground.
I've been bitten pretty deeply
into my-my gastroc and quad muscles.
I have a-a deep gash running vertically
down my medial thigh, and then
it turns lateral, just above my knee.
And right here, there's one going
across my, my posterior calf.
I'm losing a lot of blood.
Gangrene is setting in.
I feel like I'm losing my strength.
I don't think I have much time.
The-the island I'm on is-is gonna be
taken by the tide in a few minutes.
I'm about 200 yards off the shore.
On this beach.
I never found out what it was called.
So...
Um...
This is useless.
There's a buoy...
Which I'm gonna try to swim to...
About 30 or 40 yards away.
So, yeah.
That's...
that's the plan.
Um...
If you find this, can you just, um...
can you just delete that first part,
and, uh, and send it to, uh,
10231 Oliver Crescent Drive,
Galveston, Texas.
That's my home.
That's-That's where my, uh,
that's where my dad and sister live.
Yeah.
Hey, Pop.
Hey, Chlo.
Um...
I finally got that alone time.
Super overrated.
[CHUCKLES]
Uh...
I mean I'm not, I'm not totally alone.
I got this little dude.
Steven Seagull here, keeping me company.
Show 'em your wing.
I fixed him for you, Chlo.
[STEVEN CHIRPS]
I just don't want you guys to worry,
and I don't want you to feel, um,
you know, bad or anything, 'cause...
[SNIFFS] I love you so much,
and I miss you more than I ever...
I ever even realized I could.
Dad, I gotta get off this rock soon,
um...
but I want you to know I'm gonna fight.
I am.
Just like she taught us.
You were right.
[CHUCKLES]
[CRYING]
I love you.
I love you so much.
Time to go.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
- [SQUAWKING]
- It's okay. It's okay.
You got it. Good job.
You're gonna make it, buddy.
You're okay.
[SIGHING] Okay.
Okay.
[CHIRPS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Shit.
Oh, you're kidding me.
[GASPS]
You didn't like that,
'cause it stings like jellyfish.
This is my head start.
[GASPING]
[INHALES]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
[BELLOWING]
[GASPING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[GASPS]
[METALLIC CREAKING]
[SCREAMS]
[GASPING]
[SIGHING]
[METALLIC CREAKING]
[GULLS SCREECHING]
[GRUNTS, GASPS]
[SHIP'S HORN BLOWS]
[CREAKING]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTING]
Come on...
Come on!
[GROANS]
[GASPS]
Okay...
[GROANING]
[GROANING, GASPING]
[SIGHS]
[METALLIC CREAKING]
No, no, no, come back.
Come back.
Oh... come back.
[GASPS]
Come on.
Come back.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SIGHING]
[GULLS SCREECHING]
[METAL CREAKING, GROANING]
This is Nancy Adams.
It's April 26, 2016.
Uh, if you find this,
please send help right away.
I've been attacked by a shark.
He's killed three other people
since I got here.
I'm losing a lot of blood.
I feel like I'm losing my strength.
[VOICE-OVER] I love you more, short crop.
I'll be home soon.
[CARLOS SPEAKING SPANISH]
[CHLOE] No way. Mom's beach, right?
NANCY: [VOICE-OVER]
Not everyone can be helped.
I don't want you to feel,
you know, bad or anything.
I gotta go, Dad. I'll see you later.
[DAD] Hey, sweet pea.
...she was a fighter.
[CHLOE] I could shoot tubes...
[NANCY] I'm gonna fight,
just like she taught us.
[GRUNTS, GASPS]
Uh-uh.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
- [NANCY GRUNTS]
- [THUD]
[GRUNTS]
Where are you?
Fuck you.
[GASPS]
Oh, shit.
[NANCY WHIMPERS, SHOUTS]
No... no!
No!
[PANTING]
[GASPING, SHUDDERING]
[SCREAMING]
No!
[GASPING]
[GRUNTS]
[THUDDING, CLANKING]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[INHALES DEEPLY]
[ JAWS SNAP ]
[MUFFLED YELL]
[GROWLING]
[PANTING]
CARLOS: ¡Miguel!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[PANTING]
¡Papá! ¡Papá!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
[CARLOS GRUNTING, PANTING]
¡Órale!
[SPEAKING SPANISH]
¡Ándale! ¡Ándale!
[GASPING ANXIOUSLY]
[COUGHING]
Relax. Relax.
Breathe. Breathe!
[CHITTERING]
[SQUAWKING]
[GASPING, SHUDDERING]
[BREATHING WEAKLY]
[SIGHS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm okay.
Ready to get wet, Dr. Adams?
Well, we'll see about that.
Nancy...
Ma would be proud of you.
Both of you.
Thanks, Papa.
Time to go.
# But there's a scream inside... #
Do you think I'll ever be as good as you?
- No.
- [CHLOE LAUGHS]
# I don't wanna die, no,
I don't wanna die #
# I don't wanna die #
# No #
# And I don't care if I sing off-key #
# I find myself in my melodies #
# I sing for love #
# I sing for me #
# I shout it out like a bird set free #
# No, I don't care if I sing off-key #
# I find myself #
# In my melodies #
# I sing for love, I sing for me #
# I'll shout it out like a bird set free #
# Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh... #
# Oh, oh, oh, oh-oh-oh #
# Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh #
# Oh, oh... #
# I'll shout it out #
# Like a bird set free #
# Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh... oh, oh #
# Oh-oh-oh #
# Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh... #
# Oh, oh #
# I'll shout it out like a bird set free #
# Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh... #
# Oh, oh, oh-oh-oh #
# Oh, oh... #
# I'll shout it out like a bird set free #
[SONG ENDS]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[MUSIC ENDS]