MOM: At the end
of high school,
I fell in love with
a substitute English teacher.
It was quite a scandal.
Corin didn't start
out a bad guy, though.
We were together about 10 years
and we had two kids. (CLICKS TONGUE)
And then he fell in love
with someone in a Starbucks,
and moved to Palo Alto,
California.
Kind of severed relations
with the three of us.
My parents, if I were defending them,
which I'm not,
had said, back in the day,
that he had an "impatient eye."
They didn't like him.
(CHUCKLES)
Week I left,
things escalated.
My parents cursed at me,
which was, like, crazy unusual.
And it ended, one afternoon,
very badly. (SMACKS LIPS)
I left at 19, haven't spoken
to my parents in 15 years.
Whatever.
That's just the history.
Recently, my parents
looked me up on the Internet.
Asked to meet
their grandchildren.
Spend a week with them.
I looked my parents up,
they have a counseling website.
(CHUCKLES)
People love them.
Ironically, they counsel people,
which is a hoot.
Whatever. I told the kids.
They said they wanted to go.
I told them I didn't
want them to go.
They said they were gonna
go anyway. (CHUCKLES)
They're brats.
What can I tell you?
And my 15-year-old wants to
make a documentary about this.
BECCA: Wait, wait, wait.
Go back.
Um, describe the events on the day
you left your parents' farm at 19.
I did something
I don't choose to tell you.
If they choose to tell you,
that's their right. Okay?
BECCA: I want to
do this for you.
MOM: Listen,
they're good people.
Ask them.
Can I be done with my part?
I still got to get you guys packed.
TYLER: I'm on the text
with two separate girls.
BECCA: It's important
you put the word "separate" in there,
in case we thought
they were conjoined twins.
MOM: Explain "on the text"?
BECCA: In communication,
nothing more.
TYLER: No, they're on deck.
MOM: You are 13!
There's no deck to be on.
BECCA: I've seen him in the shower.
That's eerily accurate.
TYLER: You don't even
have boobs!
MOM: (CHUCKLES)
Hey, stop, both of you!
(MOM CHUCKLES)
TYLER: I need to text.
MOM: It's one week.
Your phones won't work
all the way out there.
You'll be home Saturday.
BECCA: Are you holding
my camera properly?
TYLER: Swerve, girl. Okay?
Oh.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
(BELL RINGING)
(INAUDIBLE)
BECCA: Our mother,
Loretta Jamison,
is dating an eligible
and rather rakish-looking man
named Miguel Diego Torres.
He's in love with her.
We've decided to promote
this union by giving them time.
They're going on a trip.
Mmm-hmm.
A Royal Caribbean cruise.
Your basic beach cruise.
We're visiting our grandparents,
whom we have never seen.
We don't know their
temperament or their proclivities.
Yeah.
And, we don't even
know what they like.
They, they could be
scrapbookers.
They could think
boy bands are cute.
CONDUCTOR: Ticket?
BECCA: Two for
Masonville, PA.
Our grandparents are meeting us.
You a film prodigy?
You know, I used to be
a pretty good actor.
BECCA: Oh, my camera
light's blinking.
"I am disgraced,
impeached and baffled here."
BECCA: Battery pack is low.
"Pierced to the soul
with slander's venomed spear."
BECCA: Oh, oh, unfortunately,
I'm just going to have to shut the camera off.
Since our father left, my brother's
had a preoccupation with germs.
The psychologist
we saw for a month
said it was his way
of controlling things.
(BEATBOXES)
(RAPPING)
Girl, I'm chilling again
I'm feeling again
I'm like Iron Man and Batman
I'm a hero again
Oh, you think I'm little
but last month
I grew an inch
and a quarter again
You think you're too good for me
But that's really a joke
'Cause, see,
that doesn't bother me
'Cause I'm not
a sensitive bloke
Oh, now, in the end,
you'll be in my bed
We won't be just friends
You'll write inappropriate texts
And hit "Send"
We share
a Starbucks Frappuccino blend
And see, this isn't just philosophy
It's based on science, you see
Mr. Singh, my pediatrician
Just confirmed for me
You tall skanks
I'm going through puberty
Ho!
Ooh!
Whoo!
Pound.
Whoa.
Maybe I can rap at the end of
your documentary.
BECCA: Right, because that's how all
Oscar-winning documentaries end.
With songs of misogyny.
This is where
our mom grew up.
When she left, she thought she was
with the man of her dreams.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
NANA: Hi.
TYLER: Hi. (CHUCKLES)
POP POP: Becca, right? Yeah?
TYLER: Oh! (CHUCKLES)
POP POP: Becca Jamison.
This is Marja Bella Jamison.
Uh, my Nana.
She's a good cook.
And we have the same eyes.
And this is
Fredrick Spencer Jamison.
My Pop Pop.
He's a farmer now,
but they also volunteer as counselors.
BECCA: How do you feel about
your new grandparents, Tyler?
It's all good.
They don't even know
who One Direction is, so...
BECCA: Nana, did you
make these pretzels?
Yes, I did.
(POP POP CHUCKLES)
NANA: Thank you so much.
NANA: Here we are.
(POP POP SIGHS)
BECCA: Tyler, look!
It's Mom's tree swing.
Okay, on camera,
tell us what Mom told you.
She used to wait
out here on this
when her friends
would come over.
BECCA: This is the perfect cinematic
image to open the documentary.
Go near it.
Wait! Wait, don't touch it.
Just let it
organically swing.
We're entering the home
that Mom grew up in.
(POP POP AND NANA
TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
BECCA: Look!
Look, there's the clock
that she told us about.
(CLOCK TICKING)
Do you play sports?
TYLER: I don't like sports.
He used to.
What do you do?
Why are your pants
so low?
I rap.
It's a form of
modern poetry.
If you give him
a topic,
he'll extemporaneously rhyme
on the subject.
His stage nom de plume
is "T-Diamond Stylus."
(CHUCKLES)
Go ahead,
Nana, give him anything.
Is food okay?
I like food.
Yeah. Of course.
How about...
Pineapple upside-down cake?
Yeah. Sure,
why not? Okay.
(CHUCKLES)
Mmm-hmm.
Okay.
Got it. Okay.
(RAPPING)
The girls, they like me
They think
I'm sweet like candy
One girl looked at me
Like I was a Hershey bar
Her name was Angie
And a few tall girls
They just looked at me blankly
So here's the thing
You got to understand about me
I got more rhymes
Than a beehive has bees
So it didn't surprise, confuse
Or make me say "For heaven's sake"
When a Hawaiian girl
With a balance disorder said
"You remind me of
a pineapple upside-down cake"
Ho!
POP POP: Whoa!
(CLAPS)
(LAUGHING)
(POP POP LAUGHING)
Yes, sir!
(LAUGHS) Yeah?
(LAUGHING)
BECCA: Mom's room.
POP POP: It's not fancy.
(GRUNTS) I call the main bed.
BECCA: No pre-calls!
TYLER: No, no,
I got here first!
No, no, no!
BECCA: Rock-paper-scissors?
TYLER: Okay. (CHUCKLES)
BOTH: Rock, paper,
scissors, shoot!
(SIGHS) Do it again.
BOTH: Rock, paper,
scissors, shoot!
Have a nice rest all
the way over there.
You guys are good kids.
This is gonna be
a great week.
By the way, there's mold
in the basement.
We don't want you
guys to get sick.
I got, like, no bars!
None!
BECCA: Just keep unpacking.
No, don't look at the camera.
There we go.
This is so beautiful.
Stop looking at the cam...
Just unpack like you normally would.
But I'm not here, okay?
Just be... Be natural.
Is this natural enough?
(CHUCKLING)
You're such an idiot.
BECCA: These are the people
in Nana and Pop Pop's life.
I have to
burn them a little.
Not too much.
Just a skosh.
So, where are they now?
Outside,
by the chicken coops.
How are they?
Don't answer that,
I don't care.
Are they being nice? Have they said
anything nasty about me?
Don't answer that.
Ah! This is like
a divorce settlement.
They get you for one week
every 15 years, and we try to be civil.
(CHEWING)
Mom, we talked about this.
We made a decision.
You go.
We're having a great time.
Yeah. You should
go, okay?
You won't be so grumpy
when you get back.
(CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLING)
Jacques Cousteau over here
wants to go buy swimsuits.
We're headed for the dock in a few hours!
There you go!
Hey, Miguel.
Morning.
(SIGHS)
I can't believe
I'm doing this!
A Walmart sales
associate's gonna be
on the world's
largest cruise ship!
(SIGHS) I hate you
spoiled brats.
We hate you, too.
We're looking
for visual tension.
Things that pull the frame,
things that force us to imagine
what is beyond the frame.
Record only what is happening
to you as a participant,
and we'll discuss
what "mise-en-scène" is tomorrow.
TYLER: So, I'm, like,
co-director now?
"B Camera Operator"
will be your official title.
This is the first camera that Mom
found in the damaged goods bin.
Just try to be formal, as in classicism.
Moments that are...
(GROANING)
TYLER: (YELLING)
Hi, Pop Pop!
(DOOR CREAKING)
Hi, Pop Pop.
Pop Pop!
What's in the shed, Becca?
(GRUNTS)
Okay.
I've decided to use
female pop singers' names
instead of cursing,
from now on.
(CHUCKLING) Why?
I think it would
sound better.
Like, if I stubbed my toe,
I'd say "Ah, Shakira!"
Ah, you're strange.
(DOOR OPENS)
Is everything okay?
Yeah. We're great, Pop Pop.
I have not seen your Nana
this happy in years.
Becca, T-Diamond Stylus,
we're old people.
Bedtime here
is 9:30. Yeah.
See you in the morning.
9:30?
9:30.
Oh, God.
(CHUCKLING) 9:30.
This is gonna be fun.
(CHUCKLES)
No Wi-Fi at 9:30.
(YAWNS)
BECCA: I want more cookies.
She was right about the burnt walnuts.
So, go get some.
Well, it's past 9:30.
I don't want to wake them.
Oh, just be quiet.
They're old, they won't hear anything.
BECCA: (OVER VIDEO)
I've wanted to spend time
with you for so long, Nana.
TYLER: Seriously,
that makes me want to cry.
You can teach me
all of your cooking secrets.
Are you consciously aware
that that's my intention?
I hate sappy movies.
I find them torturous.
That smells so good, Nana.
TYLER: I think
it looks good.
(MUSIC PLAYING OVER LAPTOP)
I've decided to use
Mom's favorite musical soundtrack.
It's so over the top,
it'll be her presence in the documentary.
Counter-point to
the quiet drama.
This'll be ironic scoring.
TYLER: You're gonna be alone
your whole life, aren't you?
Yeah, like Miss Porter,
the gym teacher.
Oh, and, um...
By the way,
how is this helpful?
(CHUCKLING) Oh, snap!
That's a little
candy for the ladies.
BECCA: I can't sleep.
I need Nana's cookies.
I'm gonna turn
a personal addiction
into a positive
cinematic moment.
Mom, I'm retracing the steps
of how you might
have snuck out
of your room and
stolen Nana's cookies.
(RETCHING SOUND)
(RETCHES)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Tyler?
(MUFFLED RETCHES CONTINUES)
Tyler, wake up.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
T-Diamond, Nana's sick.
TYLER: And that's the camera.
(CHEWING) So, then you put
the videos on the Internet.
So I have four
freestyle videos.
One of them has 347 hits.
You're both so talented.
(CHUCKLES)
Do you know who Tyler,
The Creator is?
No.
Well, I got that
kind of sound.
Mmm.
People say.
Come, Becca, darling. Eat.
(CHUCKLES)
BECCA: Pop Pop.
(POP POP GRUNTING)
Pop Pop?
(BECCA GASPS)
You need me?
Your grandmother's fine.
She had a little bit of
a stomach flu last night.
Must have been
a 24-hour thing.
BECCA: I knew it was
something like that.
(SIGHS)
She's an old lady, Becca.
(CLICKS TONGUE)
She gets sick sometimes.
Yeah, of course.
Tyler!
Pop Pop said he'd take us
into town this afternoon
to shoot some of
Mom's old hangouts.
Tyler?
(TYLER ROARS)
(BECCA SCREAMS)
(SIGHS)
You can play
hide-and-seek down here.
There's, um... There's
lots of visual tension.
Mom's hide-and-seek place.
You better hide,
my ethnically confused friend.
One Mississippi.
Two Mississippi.
Three Mississippi.
Four Mississippi.
Five Mississippi!
Ready or not,
here I come!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
BECCA: I see you,
you little pudge.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(SIGHS) I'll have to
use strategy.
He's faster, but I'm smarter by
at least two standard deviations.
Here I come!
(BECCA SCREAMS)
(PANTING)
TYLER: (CHUCKLES)
Right past me.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Becca?
(GROWLS)
(GASPS)
NANA: Here I come, Tyler!
Here I come!
(TYLER SCREAMING)
(SIGHS)
Tyler?
Tyler!
(YELLING INDISTINCTLY)
(PANTING)
(NANA GIGGLES)
(LAUGHING)
I'm gonna get you!
I'm coming
to get you, Becca!
(GASPS)
(SCREAMS)
(TYLER GRUNTS)
(PANTING)
(GROWLS)
(LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
I'm making chicken pot pie.
TYLER: What the hell was that?
(SIGHS)
BECCA: Can I help you?
Hi, I'm Doctor Sam.
I work at the hospital
where your grandparents counsel.
You must be Becca.
Are you making a movie?
(CHUCKLES)
I used to be an actor
back in my day.
"Life's but a walking shadow,
"a poor player that struts
and frets his hour..."
BECCA: Did you want to talk
to Nana and Pop Pop?
Yes. Are they around?
No, they're taking a walk, I think.
You just missed them.
Okay. Well, tell them
I stopped by.
They were supposed to
volunteer a few days ago.
I tried calling.
I just wanted to make sure
everything was okay.
I think the volunteer stuff
is getting too stressful for them,
although they
won't admit it.
Oh, they're fine.
Well, glad to hear it.
Tell them there's a lot of
excitement down at the hospital.
I can't wait to tell them.
I know they love gossip.
(SIGHS) I'll tell them.
Nice to meet you.
(SIGHS)
12:15 p.m. Tuesday.
Tyler Jamison, known to most ladies
as T-Diamond Stylus,
investigates
what is in the shed.
This is an isolated farm.
People sneaking around.
Is it dead bodies?
I'm gonna go to the shed.
Ugh!
Smells like ass in here.
Um...
I'm moving closer
to the suspicious pile.
(FLIES BUZZING)
Ugh, shit!
(GROANS)
Ah, God damn it!
(GRUNTS)
Ugh, Sarah McLachlan!
(PANTS)
NANA: Tyler.
What the hell, Nana?
Your Pop Pop
has incontinence.
He hides his
accidents in the shed,
and then I think
he burns them out in the field.
He's such a physical man,
he gets ashamed.
You must be disappointed
in your grandparents.
I'm sorry
we ruined things.
We're really trying.
I'll make you
some bread pudding.
Are we okay?
Yeah. Yeah,
I'm good, Nana.
Good.
My mom's a classic
narrative character.
She says things like,
"Things don't work out for me,"
and then makes it happen.
She needs the elixir, or all of
her relationships will fall apart.
NANA: Becca.
Pop Pop, we play this game
where you have to point to a building,
and you have to say who lives there
and what they secretly do.
TYLER: Becca, do that
police station.
BECCA: A police officer
named Jerry works there,
but he never comes in to work,
he never answers the phone,
because all he really wants to do
is be a Latin dancer.
(ALL LAUGH)
TYLER: Ooh, okay, I'll go.
That huge brick building back there
is a sneaker factory,
and a woman named
Sally works there.
POP POP: Oh, that's
Maple Shade, actually.
BECCA: Yeah, Mom said
you guys volunteer there.
Yeah, every
Tuesday and Thursday.
They're good people,
just nobody there to take care of them.
I have to find my Maple Shade badge
and we'll visit.
Join us on a journey
into young Loretta Jamison's past.
This was young
Loretta's high school.
Young Loretta and her friends
used to hang out at this sign.
We will now go
around to the back,
to catch
a glimpse of young,
mischievous Loretta's locker
through a window.
BECCA: Pop Pop,
was Mom a good student?
We have to go.
That fellow keeps staring at us.
BECCA: (STUTTERS)
He's not, Pop Pop.
Damn it,
he keeps stopping.
BECCA: Pop Pop?
Pretending like he's not watching.
What are you doing?
Pop Pop, stop!
Hey.
Hey! Stop following me.
He's following me!
MAN: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
I'm not following you, man!
I don't know you!
Stop following me!
You cross-eyed bastard!
BECCA: Pop Pop!
You're hurting him!
MAN: Get off me!
Hey.
What's your problem?
BECCA: Tyler...
He doesn't
know you, Pop Pop.
POP POP: Oh, man.
Yeah, my mistake.
I'm fine, I'm...
I'm sorry.
TYLER: That was crazy!
He's as strong as a wrestler!
BECCA: He's old.
They get confused.
Don't freak out.
Old people get paranoid.
And he's a country guy.
All he does is chop wood.
TYLER: Hey, you still
don't want to talk about it?
(CREAKING SOUND)
What is that?
Okay, we think there's
someone outside the door.
It's 10:47.
Open the door, Becca.
No way.
TYLER: Okay,
keep recording this.
Come on,
let's see what's out there.
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
BECCA: No, something's wrong.
I'm opening the door, Becca.
I'm opening
the door now, Becca.
I don't think you should.
Here I go.
I'm gonna open the door.
Open it, then!
Why do you keep talking about it?
Close the door,
close the door!
Ugh!
Jesus, Becca, I'm blind!
Pop Pop?
I gotta tell you the truth.
She has a diagnosed disorder.
Apparently, many
elderly people have it.
Why was she
throwing up like that?
Well, sometimes she gets it in
her head that she ate something,
and it's inside her.
(SIGHS)
And trying to crawl out.
It's called Sundowning.
It's a kind of dementia.
It's triggered by nightfall.
BECCA: This is real?
It's like somebody talking in their
sleep is how I was explained it.
It's probably best that
we just call it a rule
that you two shouldn't come
out of your room after 9:30 p.m.
Deal?
Is that a deal?
Yeah, yeah. It's fine.
I'm sorry about this.
You must not be
happy now.
It's okay, Pop Pop.
I'm okay. We're just here till Saturday.
Are you going somewhere?
Yeah, I've got to catch the
train to go to the costume party.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Pop Pop, I think you're
mixing up something.
Huh?
Oh, man.
Oh, man. What a...
What a bunch of
confused old fools
your grandparents
turned out to be.
That's all right.
It's okay.
(SIGHS)
Don't worry about it.
Yeah.
Okay?
(SNIFFS) Okay. Yeah.
It's okay.
Right. Yeah.
NANA: Good morning,
Cecil B. DeMille.
He was a great director.
I made you
cheddar biscuits, dear.
Was the old coot getting ready for
the costume party again?
BECCA: Yeah, he was.
He's crazy.
I'm just doing some chores in the barn.
I'll be in in a minute.
Something happened
to your computer.
I spilled some
biscuit batter on it.
I tried to clean it
with cleaner.
I'm sorry.
TYLER: She's weird
during the day,
and then gets even
weirder at night?
I'm telling you it's okay.
I downloaded the definition
of "Sundowning."
You wouldn't
understand half the words
I'm reading.
The word "YOLO" isn't in it.
It's got to do with
neurological reactions
to sunshine and moonlight.
It's literally
a chemical reaction.
"Sundown Syndrome: a term
for disorientation, agitation,
"a general worsening
of mental symptoms,
"classically described
in the elderly at dusk or nightfall."
It's normal
old-age problems.
People are scared
of old people for no reason.
What about the computer?
The only thing messed up
is the computer camera.
There's something else
going on.
She used oven cleaner,
and now the tiny camera
on the screen doesn't see anything.
You don't find
that odd at all?
She made a mistake.
Just come to accept they're old people
and things won't be as weird.
MOM: We're on the upper deck.
Miguel has entered
a hairy chest competition.
He's getting oiled.
(CHUCKLES)
It's so weird
I can't see you.
(SIGHS) I think
I can clean it off.
Tyler, why are you quiet?
Nana and Pop Pop
are acting strange. Ow!
What kind of strange?
Becca, did you hit Tyler?
No.
Kids?
Pop Pop wears diapers
and he keeps them in an outhouse,
and Nana walks around
at night without her clothes,
and Pop Pop thinks
strangers are following him.
(EXHALES) I knew we were gonna have this call.
They're old, Tyler.
I've discussed this with him.
Old people have trouble
with their bodies sometimes.
They also aren't very self-aware.
They can get paranoid, too.
Becca, how strange
are they acting?
They haven't been
mean one second.
Nana crawled after us
under the house.
Playing hide-and-seek.
You guys played hide-and-seek
under the house? I used to love that!
Carrie Underwood.
T, just bear with it
for a couple of days.
My parents were strange back then.
Mom was a hippie.
She used to sunbathe in the
back yard without warning back then.
I'm already partially blind.
I used to get so embarrassed.
They're just weird people, honey.
What level of
problem is this?
One.
See?
I miss you guys.
(PEOPLE CHEERING OVER LAPTOP)
Oh!
The hairy chest competition
is about to begin.
I can hear
the cougars clapping.
I got to go.
I wish I could see your faces clearer.
Hi, honey.
(WATER RUNNING)
Nana, could I ask you
about Mom?
Maybe you'd be okay
to talk for a minute in an interview?
(FAUCET CLOSED)
Would you mind getting
inside the oven to clean it?
I'm sorry? (SIGHS)
I'm too big.
I can't reach back there.
The kitchen's
got to be clean.
The oven's off.
Yeah, sure.
Get farther in there.
All the way in.
Okay, I'll star
in your movie.
BECCA: If you could be any animal,
what would you be?
Is there a right answer?
No, these questions are
intended to get you loosened up.
Oh.
A grizzly bear.
(BOTH LAUGH)
I think we're warm.
Mom told me that you and Pop Pop
were very much in love.
Where did you
first meet Pop Pop?
In a garden.
And what did you
think of him?
Oh, he was handsome.
He has a very
strong personality.
This is great.
We'll come back to that.
Right now,
I want to talk about something else.
I know it happened
a long time ago,
but what happened
on the day Mom left?
She won't tell me.
Did she do something?
Nana? Nana?
(WHIMPERING)
Nana, don't answer
that question.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
No more questions
about Loretta Jamison.
Maybe I can ask about...
I don't wanna
star in your movie.
Okay. It's Wednesday night.
Three nights left.
T-Diamond Stylus is gonna find out
what exactly is going on.
What are you doing?
I'm putting the camera
out tonight. Okay?
It's like we're living
with a werewolf.
You can't record her.
Swerve.
Look, I know you
won't understand this
because your brain
isn't fully developed yet,
but you can't do this.
Why?
It's exploitative.
I have cinematic standards.
(LAUGHING) No. No one gives a crap about
cinematic standards, okay?
It's not the 1800s.
Have you seen reality TV?
Housekeepers of Houston
has, like, a billion viewers.
If one of us isn't
participating in the event,
we can't record it.
It's just what's ethical.
No offense to Ryan
Seacrest or whoever
came up with
the Housekeepers of Houston.
You think you're
so great, don't you?
I hope things
don't get weirder.
'Cause I'm at my limit.
TYLER: Show the clock.
Show the clock.
This is what Pop Pop
was talking about.
The werewolf is real.
BECCA: Wait!
She's Sundowning.
We're participating in this.
You're not being Housekeepers of Houston.
Wait. If you're gonna open the door,
just open it for a little bit.
(CREAKING)
(GROWLS)
(BECCA GASPS)
She's supposed to do that?
BECCA: It's just like
someone talking in their sleep.
You used to talk in your sleep
till you were seven.
Dad used to come in
and quiet you down.
Hey, Becca.
Who am I?
BECCA: T. T.
There's a family of foxes.
You're going to miss it.
We're coming!
BECCA: We're coming!
BECCA: Just stop.
TYLER: Why is Nana
staring into the well?
Come on, let's go.
Come on, enough of that.
BECCA: I don't know.
POP POP: Come on.
Mise-en-scène.
BECCA: You know,
you're not as dumb as your performance
on standardized tests
would indicate.
Oh. Oh!
I forgot I had
something for you.
When you think of Dad now,
in California, do you still like him?
I don't know.
Stuff happens.
No, but Dad is hilarious.
Dad's funny.
He sent the funny card
of the fat lady on the boardwalk. (LAUGHS)
Do you remember that?
What do you mean
"stuff happens"?
People leave.
Because they find something
they like better.
So you don't feel bad?
No.
You're not being truthful.
Well, you can believe what you want,
but this is how I feel.
Make me believe you.
So, I'm on the Titans pee wee
football team and it was third down.
It was at the end
and we were leading.
So if we stop them,
we probably win the game.
Give me context.
How old are you?
I'm eight.
So, I'm free safety.
Which means that
I'm supposed to tackle the guy
if he makes it past
the people on the line.
So, their running
back punches the hole... Okay.
Am I supposed to be
following these terms?
Are these phrases supposed
to mean something to me?
Just listen.
So their running back,
who's big, makes it past the line,
and I'm the only one
left to tackle him.
All I got to do
is tackle him,
put my hands around him
and tackle him, but...
I just stand there.
They call it "freezing"
and I could hear everyone yelling.
Coach Daugherty, Dad.
All my teammates, and...
He gets the first down
and runs and runs,
and the other team is celebrating,
and I'm still standing there.
Same place.
Then the assistant coach
came and got me,
and Dad patted me on the shoulder
and then went to the car,
and he never told me
he was angry or anything.
You think Dad didn't
say anything and left
because you didn't tackle another
eight-year-old in a game
five years ago?
When you say it like that,
it sounds stupid.
(CLANKING)
BECCA: Why are we here?
TYLER: She was
staring at something.
So, what did you find?
It's only water.
So, I just
read these in order?
"If you could be any animal,
what would it be?"
I feel like a douche, Becca.
Shut up.
I would be a dolphin.
It's an intuitive and highly
intelligent creature
with great power
and poetry in its movements.
How come you like
the pizza delivery guy,
even though he has
all that ratchet acne?
Please answer the question.
He's kind.
He has kind eyes.
How come you don't look
at yourself in the mirror?
Okay, fine.
What's this now?
Besides when you're editing,
you don't like looking at yourself.
You never look at
yourself in the mirror.
You comb your hair
with your back to the mirror.
And I see you
brush your teeth.
You look down
the whole time.
Your sweater's inside out.
Did you know that?
Did you see that in
the mirror this morning?
Is that correct?
It doesn't feel
so good, does it?
Are you changing
the focal length of the lens?
No, I don't even
know what that is.
Are you zooming?
No.
So do you admit that
you don't look at yourself,
or are you gonna
keep lying?
When do you think
I started doing that?
You know when.
That's not true, asshole.
You think you're worthless.
Admit it.
(SOBBING)
He gave me
a card when he left.
A card.
Old footage of us as kids.
I was thinking of
using it in the doc.
I refuse to use anything
that has my dad in it.
That would mean
I forgive him.
TYLER: Nana?
Nana?
Becca's blind.
I know I'm right.
That there is
something going on here.
Maybe there's something
down in the basement.
They don't want us to go down there.
They're throwing shade.
Speak English.
They could be hiding
something down there.
There's mold down there.
That's why they don't want us to go down.
Just stop, okay?
Just let me put
the camera out.
Hi, I'm Stacey. Is
Mr. and Mrs. Jamison around?
BECCA: No, they just stepped out.
It's just me and my brother here.
Mr. and Mrs. Jamison
were counselors at Meadowbrook.
I was in
the rehab program there.
They used to sit by my bed
when I wasn't in good shape.
All night sometimes.
Anyway, this is
a blueberry cobbler for them.
They were supposed to stop by on
Saturday but they never showed.
I know Mrs. Jamison
hadn't been feeling herself,
so I thought
I'd just stop by and check in on them.
They hear all that
scuttlebutt down at Maple Shade?
Uh, I don't think so.
Stacey, it's okay.
Just be natural.
I'm just getting
portraits of everybody.
Just be natural.
Uh, okay, never mind.
Pop Pop?
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(SIGHS)
We're even.
(BECCA CHUCKLES)
I've been editing
montages with music,
but I need some everyday footage
of our grandparents,
so I've decided to spend
Thursday afternoon following them around.
(NANA LAUGHING)
Hear that?
She's laughing as she's watching TV.
Maybe Mom and her
watch the same shows.
(MUSIC PLAYING OVER TV)
(CHAIR CREAKING)
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
BECCA: Nana?
Nana, are you okay?
Good afternoon.
I heard you laughing.
I have the deep darkies.
Nana? Nana!
Nana, Nana, Nana, stop!
Nana, stop!
Nana, what's happening?
You have to laugh to keep
the deep darkies in a cave.
(BECCA BREATHING HEAVILY)
Pop Pop?
Pop Pop, I think Nana's...
I was just cleaning it.
What is that?
You want something?
I was just
cleaning it, really.
I think Nana's
not feeling well.
Thank you, Becca.
I'll check on her.
(BECCA BREATHES HEAVILY)
BECCA: We're putting
the camera out tonight.
(WHISPERS) What do you think?
Whoo-hoo! Ladies!
MIGUEL: That's right.
I'm bad, I'm bad.
She seems like
she's better off without us.
We're doing this
so Mom can have a life, dummy.
MALE HIP-HOP INSTRUCTOR:
Give me some real
Doug E. Fresh now, people.
From the top. Here we go.
Good night!
Is everything okay?
BECCA: We're fine.
You sure?
You both seem to
be acting funny.
We're terrific, just terrific.
Thanks for asking.
Okay.
BECCA: Good night.
Good night.
What am I gonna do?
What happened?
There aren't any tissues
left in the bathroom
and I had to touch
the toilet handle.
There's something on my hand though.
Okay. Let me see.
You can't see it
but I can feel it!
(SHUSHING)
Tyler, Tyler.
It's disgusting. Nothing's...
Nothing's coming off!
Let me have a look.
I can feel it. There's
no tissues left, Becca.
Tyler, there are tissues
underneath the sink.
Where? What?
It's okay.
It's too late.
No, it's not gonna come off.
I think it is.
Rubbing it isn't
gonna make it come off!
(SHUSHING)
It's okay.
It's all right.
I can feel it though.
I'm definitely
getting at it. Look.
It's definitely coming off.
You sure?
There.
See?
Yeah.
Just look next time,
all right?
I didn't know they were there.
It's okay.
(SIGHS)
(APPROACHING FOOTSTEPS)
(ROARS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BANGING SOUND)
TYLER: Becca?
BECCA: (WHISPERS) Stay in bed.
(LOUD BANG)
(SIGHS)
Mom will be home
late this afternoon.
We're ending
this trip tonight.
We stay away from
them unless I say.
Pack your bags.
I still need them to
give Mom the elixir.
TYLER: Becca,
what's the elixir?
BECCA: Just pretend
like you're playing.
Is everything all right?
We're just playing.
Uh, do you wanna
do the interview?
TYLER: What?
What are you doing?
I thought we were
staying away from them, Becca.
You're gonna interview him?
Mom told me you worked
in the coal industry for a long time.
I did work in a factory.
I know.
Worked at night.
Saw a white thing
running around.
A white thing?
Yeah, it used to run around
the factory at night.
Only I saw it.
I started to tell people about it
and they didn't believe me.
Had yellow eyes.
Then they fired me.
And nobody talked to me.
Mom didn't tell me that.
Oh, she doesn't know.
Happened after she left.
Pop Pop, you seem down.
Well, it's just, uh...
The end of your trip.
I know it's all
coming to an end.
Why don't you just ask
Mom if you can visit?
Are you really still angry?
(SIGHS)
She can't get over this.
She still thinks you're mad at her.
TYLER: That whole "white thing" story,
the hairs on my arm stood up.
It's definitely some sort of
late onset schizophrenia.
They're both
in bad shape.
Great. Our Pop Pop
has schizophrenia,
and our Nana becomes Michael Myers
when the sun goes down.
BECCA: That's Stacey.
...ride in my car.
Okay, stop.
What did you do...
TYLER: What?
Why is she angry?
She must be telling them
that they need to get help.
I don't...
Just come
to the back here.
I don't want you
to touch me.
Come to the back.
Okay.
I got it all off.
TYLER: I didn't see
Stacey leave.
Did you?
Nana said okay.
BECCA: Thanks for doing this.
We're leaving soon, Nana.
I'm sad it's all over.
This is the last time
I'll get to ask you questions.
It's like
the big end to my film,
and like you said,
you're the star.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Tell me anything.
Whatever you want to talk about.
I know a story.
It's about water.
Great.
There is a pond
that has little creatures in it.
These creatures are from another
planet but no one realizes it.
These creatures
spit into the water all day long.
Their spit can make
you sleep, but not die.
When people go
underwater in the pond,
they go into
a deep sleep.
A really beautiful sleep.
The creatures from
another planet have
many people at
the bottom of the pond,
storing them up.
They are going to
take them back
to their planet of
Sinmorfitellia one day.
That's just
a made-up story.
It's not real.
Wow, that's some story.
And the creatures
have antennas,
but they are
invisible antennas.
(CHUCKLES)
Can we talk about Mom?
You don't ever
want to see her?
No.
Never.
On the day she left,
she must have done something.
(SOBS)
Okay, okay.
Let's pretend we're
telling another story.
And the story
concerns a young girl
who thinks she's in love
with an older man,
and they decide to
run off together.
Now, the parents of the girl
warn her that this won't work.
And they refuse
to let her go.
And then one day,
the girl gets into a horrible fight
with them
and leaves forever.
(NANA SNIFFLES)
Now, the parents in
this story don't know it,
but she misses them a lot.
And she suffers greatly.
And then
the worst thing happens.
The man, he breaks the girl's heart
and leaves forever.
And leave their two
small children behind.
(SNIFFLES) So, Nana,
Nana, in this story,
what do you hope will happen to the girl?
In this story,
is she very sad?
She's inconsolable at times.
She tries everything to be happy.
Medications and goes
to therapy for four years
but still remains
a little sad.
I don't like this story.
Nana, what do you think
the parents in this story should do
if they saw the girl again?
Nana, pretend you
were in this story
and she was your daughter,
and she left.
What would you say
when you finally
saw her again?
I would tell her,
"I forgive you,
little girl."
(SNIFFLES)
(SOBBING)
NANA: (OVER VIDEO)
"I forgive you, little girl."
BECCA: That's the elixir.
What are you doing?
This is how
children play, okay?
Hey, Mom should be home.
Let's go and Skype with her
while they're in the back.
Right.
This will be the denouement.
(DIAL TONE RINGING)
MOM: Hey, kiddos!
Did you get my videos?
I know, I look like an apple.
Trip was great.
Miguel and I had
a little fight this morning.
He wanted to get
short stack pancakes,
I told him he was gaining
a little weight.
Can you believe it?
Things don't work out for me.
Mom?
Yeah?
Mom, you need to come
and get us right now.
What? What happened?
Mom, get in the car
and come right now.
Do you know how long
that would take by car, Rebecca?
(SIGHS) Mom, trust me, there is something
wrong with Nana and Pop Pop.
I'm telling you, you need to come
and pick us up tonight.
Becca, you're scaring me.
My heart is in my throat.
We're okay now.
Just come.
Where are they now?
Uh, they're outside
by the chicken coops.
They won't see you.
Becca...
BECCA: They've been acting so strange, Mom.
We've been recording them.
Becca...
Yeah, I kept telling Becca
something was wrong, didn't I?
Becca, Tyler...
And Nana walks around
at night with a knife.
And Pop Pop had a gun in his mouth.
Rebecca, Tyler...
I think he was
trying to hurt himself.
Becca, Tyler, babies,
I need you to listen to me very carefully.
Becca, Tyler,
just listen to me.
We are.
Those aren't your grandparents.
What are you
talking about, Mom?
Where are Nana and Pop Pop?
You've been staying
with those people the whole time?
(SHUDDERING EXHALE)
Masonville Police Department.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(SIGHS) Come on, come on.
(GASPS)
What are you guys doing?
We'll be right in,
sweethearts.
VOICEMAIL:
This is the Masonville
County Police Department.
Our officer, Jerry,
is currently out on dispatch.
Please leave a message...
Police aren't answering.
Damn it! Stupid hick town.
Okay. I'm gonna keep calling
from the car, I promise.
Get you and your brother out.
(WHISPERS) Okay.
Try to get
to a neighbor.
Just stay calm, T.
I'm coming.
(WHISPERS) We're in a house with...
(DOOR OPENS)
After we clear up,
I have a fantastic idea.
We should play a board game!
Families play board games.
It's our
last night together.
NANA: Becca?
You'll help me
clean up, right?
You can record it
with your camera.
BECCA: Okay.
Yeah! (LAUGHS)
(SNIFFS)
Maybe we should
go outside and film
some evening
shots of the house.
Okay, sounds good, sister.
Could you clean
the oven for me, Becca?
(CHUCKLES)
Get all the way inside.
TYLER: Mmm, Becca?
She's done it before.
We really should
film something outside.
Do this first.
I'll be quick.
Oh, this will just
take a second. (GRUNTS)
BECCA: (MUFFLED) Nana? Nana?
I can clean those.
BECCA: Nana,
please open the door.
NANA: Oh, that's okay.
Please open it.
There she is.
So, what was
the big fuss?
Let's make it...
(DICE RATTLING)
...a perfect family night.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh!
(LAUGHS)
Your Pop Pop is very competitive
with board games.
Be warned.
POP POP: If you want
to move that over here, that's fine.
NANA: If we use this table,
there's not room for the cookies.
T-Diamond Stylus
and I are gonna do
one last interview
outside and be right back.
NANA: You can
sit over there.
Figure out
what the teams are.
BECCA: Go, go, go. Hurry.
TYLER: Brought a coat. I'm coming.
Okay, open it.
BECCA: (GASPS)
What is that?
(GASPS)
Picked teams.
It's young versus old.
POP POP: Stop rolling all
the dice on every roll!
You're losing
the game for us!
NANA: No, I'm not.
(CHUCKLING) We don't
have to keep score.
I'm a Yahtzee master.
Doesn't everyone in the cafeteria call me
the Yahtzee master?
(MUSIC PLAYING OVER RADIO)
What cafeteria?
You wanna win at Yahtzee,
listen to me.
You're not a Yahtzee master.
That takes 10 years.
See? He's using strategy!
A Milton Bradley-approved strategy.
I don't know
what I'm doing.
This game is made
by Hasbro, Pop Pop.
That's a lie.
It used to be made
by Milton Bradley.
Who cares, Becca?
Finally!
I'm having so much fun.
(LAUGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(SIGHS)
Wow, my battery's running low.
I'll be right back.
You keep playing
with them, T.
Just keep playing.
I'll be right back.
(SPITS)
(GRUMBLING)
(MUNCHING)
Becca?
(WHISPERS) Katy Perry.
What time is it, Nana?
Isn't it getting late?
(SCREAMING) Yahtzee!
(YELLS) Becca!
(BECCA BREATHING HEAVILY)
I'm going down
into the basement.
I think they have
my grandparents here.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Pop Pop?
Nana? Are you down here?
Things are not
working out tonight.
It's half past nine.
I have to get your Nana to her room.
You wait here.
(BECCA BREATHING HEAVILY)
BECCA: (WHISPERING) Nana?
Pop Pop?
"Maple Shade
Psychiatric Hospital"?
(GASPS)
Should the three of us
finish the game?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHIMPERS)
(GASPS)
(YELLS)
My name is Becca Jamison.
If you find this footage...
(SCREAMS)
My name is Mitchel.
They kept telling us
you were so great.
How you're gonna visit,
how you're gonna be a family.
That was a bad thing
they did.
They knew Claire
had put her two children
in those suitcases
in the pond.
She deserved this week
as a grandma.
Claire's kids are
on Sinmorfitellia.
You're gonna join them!
(BECCA SCREAMS)
(POP POP GRUNTS)
(BECCA YELLS)
(SCREAMS)
BECCA: Stop!
POP POP: The only way to Sinmorfitellia
from here is through the well.
BECCA: Stop!
(SIGHS)
Wasn't it a perfect week?
(WHIMPERS)
I promised her
it would be.
The white thing with
yellow eyes is real.
It waits for us.
I saw it out in the field.
It was laughing at us.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
BECCA:
They're murderers, Tyler!
Becca!
Get out of here, dummy! Run!
(GROANS)
TYLER: Becca!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
POP POP: We're all
dying today, Becca.
BECCA: No...
(DOOR BANGS)
(BECCA GRUNTING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(WHIMPERING)
(GROANS)
(BREATHES RAGGEDLY)
(SCREAMS)
You have
a magic spell on you.
(WHIMPERING)
(WATER RUNNING)
(YELLING) Help!
Help!
(GRUNTS)
(SHUDDERING)
POP POP: (WHISPERS)
I never liked you.
(TYLER WHIMPERS)
(NANA MOANING)
BECCA: Claire?
I'll tell you a story.
(BECCA BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
(CLATTERING)
(YELPS)
I have to go to the train
to go to the costume party.
It's a company party.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GASPS)
That's not now.
I know that!
(NANA GIGGLES)
(BECCA YELPS)
(SNARLS)
(GROWLS)
(WHIMPERS)
(TYLER WHIMPERING)
You have a problem
with germs, don't you?
(WHIMPERS)
(BECCA WHIMPERS)
(NANA LAUGHS)
(SNARLING LOUDLY)
(SNIFFS)
(GROWLS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
NANA: I don't like you.
(BECCA GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(BECCA GROANING)
(SCREAMS, CHOKING)
(RETCHES)
(SCREAMING)
You are blind.
I am the exposer.
I am a seer.
I see the veiny...
...deformed...
...face of the world.
(BREATHING SHAKILY)
(GRUNTING)
(KNOB CLATTERS)
We can all be saved tonight.
(SHUDDERING)
Your magic spell
will be lifted.
(BECCA SCREAMS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Becca!
(BECCA YELPS)
Have you been
watching me?
BECCA: (SOBBING)
Run, Tyler, run!
(TYLER GROANS)
(POP POP GRUNTS)
Eyes on the runner!
Watch his hips!
(SCREAMING)
Stay low!
Wrap the arms!
BECCA: (SOBBING) Tyler?
(GROANING ANGRILY)
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
Tyler! (CRYING)
TYLER: (YELLS) No!
Any other crazy bitch-ass
fucking people here?
Come on out!
(GROANS ANGRILY)
(TYLER COUGHS)
(BECCA CRYING)
(TYLER CRYING)
MOM: Becca, Tyler!
POLICE OFFICER: Stand by.
I've arrived on site.
MOM: Babies!
(BOTH CRYING)
Oh, my God!
I'm here. I'm here.
I'm here.
OFFICER: Is this everybody?
Come over here.
Oh, my God!
Let's go! Move, come on.
We need an ambulance!
Hurry up! Over here.
Yo, Jimmy, watch that front door.
Go around the back.
Come here,
come here, come here.
BECCA: Mom, honestly,
you know you don't have to do this.
I want to
do this for you.
(SIGHS)
I used to sing.
My mother used to say
that she wasn't listening,
but I know she was hiding behind this
big clock down the hall,
the kitchen towel over
her mouth to hide her smile.
She thought I had a better voice than
Olivia Newton-John.
Olivia Newton-John
was like, her Elvis.
My father was
a gentle man.
We'd take these long walks together,
we'd never say a word.
I used to wake up early when
I was a child. Work on some project.
(SNIFFS)
My father thought that meant
I was gonna do great things.
Anyway, as I said before,
the day I...
(SMACKS LIPS)
The day I left
turned really badly.
My parents cursed at me.
I moved to the door to leave and
my mom stepped in front of me.
I hit my mother.
And then my dad hit me,
and then we kind of stood there in shock,
and then I left.
They reached out
to me soon after.
I refused to
take their calls.
I know you were trying
to get me forgiveness, Becca.
You didn't have
to do that, honey.
It was there
whenever I wanted it.
(SNIFFLES)
(SIGHS)
Please...
Don't hold
onto anger, Becca.
Hear me?
(CRYING)
(SINGING)
Happy birthday to you
Blow them out!
Okay, okay!
(BLOWS)
Yay!
(RAPPING) I may be 13,
may not live in the hood
May not carry no chrome,
may not be allowed a cell phone at dinner
But I'm young and can do
18 pushups and I speak the truth
My sister tried to make a film about
old people feeling dismay
But it didn't
turn out that way
She had to scream and kill
and got vomit in her face
Chunks in her hair
from a stew
But she washed them out with
Herbal Essence Body Envy Shampoo
So here's a few things T-Diamond
learned from visiting elders
Adult diapers
come in many a name
There's Attends and Depends
and Medline and Prevail
But they all the same
They keep your mess from spilling out
and they keep it contained
So here's the truth
I got messed up with a killer
who's truly insane
I will try not to refrain
Try to overcome my pain 'cause
one day it will get me my fame
Like 50 Cent getting shot
and being lame, you see
I got a diaper shoved in
my face for half an hour
I thought it was over
I thought I'd be under the ground
growing four-leaf clovers
Some dude going
over me with a mower
But that's not what happened
you see, 'cause I went all mental
I was like Mel Gibson
at the end of a Lethal Weapon rental
I'm straight now,
I'm not gonna lie
For three weeks that diaper
left me like a basket case
I had to use two whole
Dove bars on my face
And one last thing
and I don't mean to sicken
But the truth is
shit doesn't taste like chicken
Oh, Shania Twain, bitches!