♪
[♪ B.I.G. E.G.O - Wise Blood
plays ♪]
[music skips]
[music cuts off]
[birds chirping]
[birds chirping loudly]
[bag unzips]
[rustling]
[plastic bag rustles]
[snap]
[cd player snaps shut]
[music resumes in headphones]
Go! Go! Go!!
[snarling]
[gunshot echoes]
[♪ There Ain't No Grave (Gonna
Hold My Body Down) - "Brother"
Claude Ely ♪]
[♪ Voodoo You - Sun Hotel
playing in headphones ♪]
[boot unzips loudly]
[groans]
[boot unzips]
[music continues loudly
in headphones]
[crunching loudly]
Hey. Hey.
A thousand bucks.
I won a thousand bucks.
Yeah?
Heads up.
[spits, can opens]
A thousand bucks, man.
[fly buzzes]
[rips lottery card off]
[chews loudly]
Did you keep that?
I saw you keep that.
[chuckles]
That lottery ticket's about
as useful as your fuckin'
hair gel Mickey.
[bag rustles]
Hey man, let's have a catch.
- Nah. I don't feel like it.
- [spits] Aw, come on.
Let's work on that
curveball, huh?
Yeah and what's a
curveball useful for?
Uh, it's fun man.
It's baseball. We love
baseball, remember?
[bird chirps]
Yeah.
[sighs] Okay no uh...
no shorties, I'm not wearing
a cup.
None of this 57-foot slider
bullshit.
You know, in Latin America,
they don't let
kids throw curveballs.
They teach them the changeup.
It's a lot easier on the
shoulder, but just as effective.
Was that your changeup?
You don't have
a changeup either.
You're a one pitch bitch,
Mickey.
[imitating baseball announcer]
'One Pitch Bitch Mickey!'
Hell of a pitch, though.
[♪ lightly mysterious music ]
♪
[music ends]
[footsteps]
[gun clicks]
[birds chirping, ducks quacking]
[line reeling]
Hey Mick.
Wanna fish for a while?
What?
Do you wanna fish for a while?
No.
Okay.
Might be a nice trick to learn.
Think I could figure it out.
Oh you do?
You know, it's not
so easy Mickey.
There's a subtlety to it.
A finesse.
Yeah, you're subtle.
You're Mr. Finesse.
You're about as subtle as a
fucking sledgehammer.
Anyway, look.
Fish, fish, fish, more fish.
[sigs]
Point taken.
Why don't you start a fire.
[wind whistling softly]
[brook babbling nearby]
What are they doing out here?
You said they wouldn't
come in the woods.
No, I never said that.
- Yes! You said that...
- What I said, Mickey...
was that there would be less of
them in the woods.
Same as there will be
less of them on the moon.
Relax.
It's done.
[flies buzzing]
Why don't you go put some
coffee on or something?
[♪ mysterious, tense music ]
[footsteps]
[moaning, labored breathing]
[zombie growl]
Oh my God!
Stinks?
Ugh!
Oh!
[car dings]
[car starts, engine revs]
[♪ wayward instrumental
music ♪]
[thunder]
Hey Benny, look,
there's a sun roof.
Yeah well it's a fucking
rain roof right now!
Close the thing, Jesus Christ.
[radio static]
[static continues]
Well, it's better than the shit
that used to be on.
You remember that girl I was
seeing up in Pittsfield?
[thunder, rain falling]
Ummm, no...
[silence]
[♪ The Wind - We are Jeneric
plays in headphones♪ ]
[music gets louder]
Hey.
[snaps]
Check this out.
Right?
Look at this.
It's huge!
We could lay some
pillows down, blankets...
it's like a bachelor pad.
Sure.
Alright, then.
Let's go steal some of your dead
girlfriend's blankets.
[crickets chirping]
I know what you're
thinking Mickey.
And the answer is
no fucking way.
What?
You wanna stay.
Just for a little while.
No fuckin' way.
Why not?
Do I really have to
answer that question?
But we just go and go, man.
Where are we going?
We're not goin' anywhere.
Mickey, that's the point.
We're like sharks.
Sharks are the
ultimate survivor, Mickey.
They've been around four hundred
million fucking years,
you know why?
'Cause they keep moving.
They stop, they die,
it's the same as us.
It's not the same.
That was a house,
up in Pittsfield,
that we were stuck in.
For three fuckin' months,
- Remember?
- I remember.
Your mother, your brother
- They were in a house.
- I know.
We ate dog food.
- I know, Benny!
- And then we ate the dog!
We ate the fuckin' dog, Mickey!
I had to kill the dog
so we could eat the dog.
I'm not gonna
have this discussion.
I'm not gonna trap myself
in a big dumb-ass
stupid fuckin' house again!
No thank you.
No we came,
we checked it out,
you're girl's not here.
I'm sorry about that.
But we got some cool shit!
And as of now we're not
completely surrounded
by fucking monsters.
So I don't think we should
press our luck.
Can't we just stay...
Ahhhhhhhhh!
Ahhh!
[♪ Darlin' You're Sweet - Wise
Blood playing in headphones ♪]
Mickey.
Hey.
What?
Pile's hot.
[♪ The Time of Dragonflies -
The Parlor ♪]
[♪ music plays
in headphones ♪]
Mickey!
Wanna throw me some?
Mick?
[breathing raspily]
[zombie growl]
[snarling]
Jesus! What the fuck, man?!
Don't do that shit!
Those things are gonna
get you killed, man.
And maybe me too.
Turn 'em down, will ya?
- Alright.
- I'm serious
I heard you, alright.
Okay.
Now...
- Here.
- Come pitch me some...
Check this out.
[walkie-talkie beeps]
Come on, get out there.
Testing, testing,
What do you think the
range is on these things?
I don't know, five,
ten miles maybe.
Well, they work.
They do work.
Alright, you can come back in.
Nah, actually I think
I'm gonna go take a shit.
[farting in radio]
[man on walkie]
Annie, this is Orchard.
Come back.
[walkie static]
This is Annie, go head.
Yeah, listen. I got an addition
to your shopping list here,
courtesy of Miss Carter.
[Annie] Go head.
Well, apparently she
told Jason uh,
he could pick the
movie this week,
on account of the
birthday thing.
What do we do?
[man] She told him,
"Any movie you want."
[Annie] What'd he pick?
[man] "Tremors"
[Annie] Say again?
"Tremors"
It's the giant killer worm movie
with uh... Kevin Bacon.
[Annie] I'm familiar
with "Tremors" over.
[man] Well, she promised
the kid we'd find it.
Been on my ass all day about it,
like I got time for this shit.
What kind of a goddammed movie
is that to pick anyway?
Over.
[Annie] Well if they got it,
I'll get it, Frank.
[Frank] Yeah, well don't
bust your ass over it.
We got more pressing concerns.
Go head, man.
Hello?
Hello, over.
Annie.
Frank?
The Orchard.
Anyone, over.
[walkie static]
[Frank] Who is this?
Uh, hi. This is uh, Mickey.
I'm here with Ben.
Benjamin McBride. We're...
We're uh, ballplayers.
We were playing baseball
up in Pittsfield, when...
Well...
Anyway, we've been
walking forever, and...
We just found a car.
We're in Connecticut. Over.
[walkie static]
[Frank] You stay off
this channel.
What?
Wait.
Wait, what?
Hello.
Please, we're...
we'e just looking
for a place to stay.
We're really hard workers.
We can...
fish, and cook...
and I think that we could
help each other out, over.
[Frank] We got hard
workers, kid.
What we ain't got is room.
We got no vacancy.
You understand?
Now that's that.
And don't try to find us.
You're not welcome.
Annie, come back.
[Annie] Go head.
[Frank] I don't want you
talking to these kids,
you understand?
You know the rules.
Just stay off the waves and
get back in, you copy?
[Annie] 10-4 and out.
No. No, no, no, no.
Hello!
Hello, please!
Please!
We're gonna die out here.
Hello.
Annie.
Annie, please.
Hello?
You believe that?
I don't know.
What do we do?
[laughing] I don't know.
You don't know?
What don't you know?
I know.
You know, I know that
these are the first people
that we've heard from in months.
Months!!
They've got their
shit together, man.
Communications...
birthdays...
fucking movies!
Fucking "Tremors"!!!
Yeah, and we're clearly not
invited to the party, Mick.
I don't care.
I don't wanna live out here
like this anymore, man.
Sleeping on rooftops.
Living out of a car.
With you.
You're like a fucking caveman.
And you stink.
And you don't seem to care.
You know, you like living this
hunter-gather lifestyle,
but I don't!
You know, I don't like waking up
every day wondering if
today's the day I'm gonna die.
Wondering if today's the
day that a fucking
walking dead person
eats my head!
[chuckling]
It's not funny man!
- No it's not funny
- It's not fucking funny!
- It's the way you said...
- I'm serious!
Okay, I know, okay,
you're fucking serious, man.
I get it.
You wanna find 'em,
go find 'em.
They don't wanna be found, man.
How you gonna find 'em?
[walkie static]
Annie, come back, over.
They're not gonna
answer you, Mickey.
It's been days, man.
That shit was just
a whisper in the wind.
Annie.
Come back, please.
Wait a minute,
wait, wait, wait, wait, wait...
What?
You got a thing for her,
don't ya?
Annie!
Oh my God!
You're so fucking funny, man.
You're so weird!
You're not asking for,
for Frank.
You're not asking for
The Orchard.
Shut up.
Just... Annie.
Annie, come back!
Annie, please come back!
Save me!
- Shut up.
- Please, Annie!
You know what?
You wanna know the difference
between you and me?
What, I'm not an asshole?
It's that...
we both know...
that there's a girl out there,
right?
Driving around...
doing some highly
organized scavenging...
some recon missions...
who knows,
it could be a couple
fuckin' weirdos
on the radio but...
let's say she's out there.
She's probably coming from
someplace fortified...
big walls, like you said.
But these are logical
deductions, yes?
- What's your point?
- Well...
My point is...
in your mind,
she's like this
post-apocalyptic pixie girl.
With like, a gun on her hip.
And like, a garter.
And maybe like, a scar
that's so well placed that it
shows how tough she is
but doesn't fuck up
her pretty face, right?
And in my mind?
She's like a 46-year-old
softball coach.
With a mullet.
And fuckin' calves like
canned hams, man.
Right?
I mean, if they're gonna
send a woman,
that's who they're gonna send.
A trucker. A bull dyke.
Not fuckin' Frank's
barely legal niece.
[scoffs]
But...
you're a romantic.
and I'm a realist,
that's okay.
Probably gonna get you
killed, though.
Just like those fuckin'
headphones.
You know, you're the
only person I know
that could walk
all the way across New England
and gain weight.
I'm the only person
you know, Mickey.
Period.
Plus...
I'm a catcher,
I'm allowed to be fat.
Well then you pull it off.
Fuck you, sir.
Fuck you to death.
[wind whistling, birds and
crickets chirping]
I think you're over thinking
this one, Mickey.
- Yeah?
- Yep.
I think you're grasping
a little bit.
Who says that?
"No Vacancy"?
Uh, people say it man.
It's a saying, it means...
No room, no space,
don't uh...
don't come here.
we cannot accommodate you.
- Please don't come to...
- Oh shit!
[zombie growling]
God dammit.
I told you this was
gonna happen.
[zombies wheezing]
Get in the car.
Get in the god damn car.
Can we go now, are we done?
Can we cross this place
off the list?
You know, I don't know why you
feel like you have to
kill every fucking one of them.
Because I do!
Because we do, it's our duty.
[talking over Ben] No you don't!
You're gonna get yourself
killed because you have to
confront every single one.
Pay attention! Watch out!
If you'll just stop fucking
distracting me
while I'm trying to do this!
Just do it and
get back in the car!
You know, why don't you
get out here and do it?
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Are we gonna do this again?
- Yeah, no, I think it's time.
Get out here and fucking do it.
I mean, aren't you just
a little bit angry?
Aren't you just
a little bit angry, Mickey?
Shut up.
This one over here?
She killed your brother.
- Fuck you.
- This motherfucker here?
- He ate your mom!
- You're an asshole!
- He ate her right up!!!
[grunts]
[breathing heavily]
[squeaking against windshield]
You're gonna have to
do it sometime, man.
Yeah.
But I don't have to do it today.
And neither do you.
[squeaking on windshield]
Fuck you!
Fuck!
[splatters]
[sighs] Here hold this
for me, will ya?
Get that outta my fucking face.
[slam]
[birds chirping, forest sounds]
[river running]
Ah!
Aya whoohooo!
Whoooo!
Wooo!
Ah ha haaa!
Ahhh!
Haaaa! ho hoooo
Haaaaaa!
Ha!
Ohhh!
Hahahahahah!
[wheezing]
[growling]
Ah!
No! No, no, no!
No, no, no, no!!
Ah, shit!!
Ah, sh- shit!
Shut up!!
Oh, God!
[growling]
Ben!!
Oh!
[grunts]
[panting]
[moaning]
[breathing raspily]
[gasping wheezily]
[rustling,
belt buckling jingling]
[breathing heavily]
[growling, snarling]
[panting]
[straining]
[grunts]
[gunshot]
The fuck!?
[laughs]
Oh my fucking...
[laughs hysterically]
I'm sorry, Mickey!
I'm sorry, man!
Oh shit, are you finished?
[laughing]
I can't even fucking,
I can't breathe!
[laughing]
[giggling breathlessly]
Fuck, I gotta go.
I'll come back,
you finish up!
Aw, Jesus!
[still laughing]
[♪ emotional instrumental
guitar music ♪]
♪
[music fades]
[floor creaking]
We're fucking staying the night.
Okay?
We're in the middle of nowhere!
There's nothing around for miles
and the only reason
we got stuck in that
house in Massachusetts,
is because we didn't know what
the fuck was going on!
I want to sleep in a house.
In a bed!
Like a real human.
So we're fucking
staying the night!
Okay.
Guess we're staying the night.
[bag unzipping, rustling]
[♪ We've Got A Lot To Be Glad
For - Rock Plaza Central plays
in headphones ♪]
Hey Ben?
Have you seen my...
What's up?
What are you doing?
I'm trying to put this...
fucking bow together.
I can see that.
So you wanna borrow those...?
Oh yeah.
Yeah, yeah, these?
You can have 'em back tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Yeah.
I'll give them back
when we leave.
You'll give them back?
They're my headphones.
You're the one who
wants to stay the night.
So that's what this is about?
Yeah, it is.
You wanna have
a fuckin' sleepover...
in a big box with no wheels.
And I don't want
you to be distracted.
I want you to be able to hear
a fucking squirrel
take a shit out there.
That's the only way
I'm gonna feel
remotely safe sleeping in
this house.
What?
You think I don't like music?
I fuckin' love music, man.
But I always have to
be present and aware,
because you don't
wanna deal with shit.
You're always hiding
in these things, Mickey.
You're burning
through batteries,
you're blowing
out your eardrums,
and you're putting
my life at risk.
How am I putting
your life at risk?
Because we're a
fucking team, man!
A battery!
Remember?
Whether you like it or not
and you know what,
maybe I'm just tired of
watching both of our
fucking backs all the time.
It's for your own good man.
You need to wake up and realize
that this is how it is
out here now.
Nobody's gonna flip
this switch back on.
Flip the switch back on?
What's that, I'm sorry,
I can't hear you.
Can't hear you
through the beautiful...
music.
It's so loud.
It's so loud and glorious.
I'm gonna fucking shoot you.
[music continues
in headphones]
Did you see that?
Hey Mick!
Come and look
at this fuckin' mural, man.
It's insane.
There's like a beautiful woman.
Perky little titties.
Long legs.
She 's sitting in
the middle of the woods.
Surrounded by a bunch of
animals. There's like...
a gazelle, a fucking red fox.
A huge stork.
Some kind of bird of prey.
And she 's like,
leaning on a lion.
It looks like...
You know what it looks like?
It looks like one of those...
Jehovah's Witness
pamphlets.
You know, where all
of God 's creatures...
are united and peaceful
in the Kingdom on Heaven
or some shit.
Come here. Come look at it.
What? No? Okay.
I want to go there.
[crickets chirping]
[walkie beeps on]
Annie, you...
you there?
Anyone?
I don't know how much
longer I can do this.
[sighs]
[walkie static]
[Annie] They'd put me
over the fence
if they knew I was
talking to you.
Hello?
[Annie] You've gotta
let this go.
You understand?
Please.
I can't
[Annie] This place...
it's not what you think it is.
What is it?
[Annie] That's exactly
the sort of thing
they'd put me
over the fence for saying.
I bet it's not...
sleeping on a roof.
Or a tree.
Or in a car.
Like a rat in a cage.
Is it?
[Annie] No, it isn't.
Then don't tell me to let it go.
I don't have anything else.
[Annie] What about
your friend?
Ben?
Ben... I...
We were ballplayers, I...
He was the starting catcher.
I was out in the bullpen.
We never hung out
in the same circles.
I hardly even know him.
[Annie] Listen, I didn't
push this button
to gab like schoolgirls.
For your own good,
change the fucking
channel, Mickey.
[♪ singing along to Anthem for
the Already Defeated by Rock
Plaza Central ♪]
♪ They can take our bones
and bury them ♪
♪ deep under the river,
but we'll still be together ♪
♪ and we cannot be defeated.
♪ They can take our trombones
♪ and pack them
down there with us. ♪
♪ But no matter how
long it takes us ♪
♪ we will not be defeated.
♪ When we dance,
we dance together. ♪
♪ Under the moon,
and under the weather. ♪
♪ We will all rise forever,
and at night. ♪
[music continues]
[continues singing along]
[music stops]
[screaming]
[music resumes]
[music stops]
[wheezy breathing]
[snarling]
Good morning.
[grunting]
Come on.
Shhh.
[whispering] Shut up.
Shut up, shut up.
Shut up!
Mickey wake up!!
What the fuck!?!!
Come on, Mick!
- You gotta do it!
- What are you doing?!
- Come on, Mickey!
- Let me out!!!
I left the bat in there!
I've seen you swing it!
Swing the fucking bat, Mickey!
- Nooooo! No!
- Come on, Mick!
- Noo!
- Mickey!
God! Please!
[screaming turning to laughter]
- Come on man!
- Stop! Get off! Get off!
Mickey!!!
[screaming turns to
heavy crying]
Man?
[crying, gasping]
Mickey?
[heavy panting]
Well?
You made a fucking mess,
but you got the job done.
[screaming]
What the fuck, Mickey!
What the fuck are you...?
Get off me!
What the fuck!
[grunting]
You motherfuck...
Get off me!
Fucker.
[laughing]
Oh, fuck!
Aw, Mickey. Mickey!
Come back, man.
You're on the board, Mick!
We gotta celebrate!
[whimpering]
Mickey!
[thunder]
Where you goin', Mick?
[breathing unsteadily]
Mickey.
What are you doin'?
I talked to her.
Who?
Annie?
[gulps]
She said they'd kick her out
if she talked to me.
[sobs] She told me to let it go.
Aw shit man.
[sobbing]
You know, you look like
a fuckin' lunatic right now.
Why don't you uh...
come get cleaned up.
Get some clothes on.
Get outta this fucking rain.
Come on.
Cheer up, Mickey.
Mickey.
Cheer up!
It was just a girl on the radio.
There's other girls
out there, brother.
Somewhere.
We'll find you a nice one.
This is the saddest game
of catch I've ever had.
Do you want me to do a...
Do you want me to do a dance?
A funky dance?
[singing funkily]
Doo-dat-dooo-dat-doo
doo-dee-doo-dee-doo
dooodle-doo-dat-doo!
Cheer up, Mickey!
Alright, let's get you
an assist.
You want an assist?
Here we go.
He's gonna come around second.
He's gonna head for home.
You're gonna
throw him out, alright?
I want a rope.
Come on, Mick.
[Music\é]
He's comin' around!
Comin' around third!
Get it in, get it in!
Whoooo!
He's out!!
[♪ Mammoth - El Cantador ]
♪
[laughing]
[music continues]
[music fades]
Ben.
What?
It's hot.
I think there's someone here.
Hello!
Anybody there?
Just keep an eye out.
We'll be gone in a second.
Ben.
- It's fucking...
- Benny!
bone dry!
There's not a dr-- hey!
Whoa, what the fuck!?
Stop right there.
Just gimme the keys,
and I'll let him go.
Just calm down, okay?
Gimme the fucking keys!
Can we talk about this?
Let's talk.
I don't have time
to fucking talk.
Why not, what's the rush, man?
Where you going?
Please, we can help you.
We can take you
anywhere you want.
Yeah, I need to go
to fucking Arizona.
Are you gonna take me
to fucking Arizona?!
No, I didn't think so.
Now put down the gun,
and toss over the keys.
I don't have the keys.
God dammit I am not
fucking around here!
I will open this
motherfucker up!
No you won't.
What did you say?
I said you won't do it.
Then you have no leverage.
If they find me
I'm a dead man anyway.
Who?
Who finds you?
I'm done talking to you,
asshole.
Hey tell me,
what's in Arizona, huh?
You got three seconds.
What do you got, a wife?
Shut your fucking mouth!
Couple of kids?
Tell me.
Are they gonna be happy about
the way you got home?
Stealing from innocent people?
Don't you think we got
enough to worry about?
Without having to worry
about each other?
Tell me your name, man.
What's your name?
Jerry, my name's Jerry.
Jerry.
My name's Ben.
- That's Mickey.
- Stop trying to talk me down!
- Sir please!
- Shut up!
They told me they
were gonna take me.
They said if I stuck it out,
and worked through
the winter they'd...
come spring they'd
give me a truck.
And a gun, and enough food and
gas to make it home.
But they fucking lied!
Who, who lied?
If you don't
put down that gun...
and give me
the keys to that car...
I will take his fucking eye.
No Ben! Benny!
Please!
Give him the fucking keys!
How's that for leverage?
I told you, Jerry.
I don't have the keys.
They're in the car!
They're in the car.
In the ignition.
Okay?
Okay.
[thunder]
You know,
if it was my kid, Jerry...
I would have walked across
this whole fucking country
by now.
Fuck you!
You don't know me, motherfucker!
Open the door.
Okay okay!
Okay, Jerry?
You win, Jerry.
You win.
Here's what's going to happen.
I'm gonna throw the gun away.
You're gonna let Mickey go.
And you get in
and drive away, okay?
Okay.
Give me the gun.
No I'm not gonna
give you the gun.
This is not a negotiation.
Alright, I'd rather
shoot you both and
take everything.
You're not taking
the car and the gun.
I am gonna throw the gun away,
you're gonna let Mickey go,
and be on your way.
Okay.
Throw it away.
Let him go, Jerry.
[keys jingle]
You fucking motherfucker!
Fucker!
[gunshot]
[rolling thunder]
[gunshot echoes]
[heavy thunder]
That was a person, Benny.
Yeah it was.
A real asshole, too.
He just wanted
to see his family.
Yeah.
I wanna see
my family too, Mickey.
But A: they're far away.
And B: they're probably
fucking dead.
And I'm not gonna take someone
else's livelihood to do it.
I mean,
I don't understand you, man.
That guy had a fucking
knife to your throat.
I don't understand
people anymore, I tell ya I'm...
starting to prefer
the dead ones.
Ben!
Look!
[car approaching]
Hey, hey, hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
[female voice]
We friends or what?
I don't know, are we?
Well that's our car right there.
We come to get it
and be on our way,
that alright with you?
Well it's got no gas in it.
We got gas.
So...
we friends?
Or what?
I guess so.
Great.
Thought you said
we were friends.
What about
the shadow back there?
Oh that's Egghead.
Not because he's smart, either.
Because he's got
a big ol' egg for a head.
Put it away Eggs, get the can.
Who are you guys?
[sniffs] Survivors, same as you.
You uh, happened to see the guy
who was driving this?
Yeah, we saw him.
Where'd he go?
He was bit.
I had to finish him off, he's in
the field right there.
He uh, say anything
to you before?
Bout what?
Anything?
No, uh... just...
panicky, yammering on
about family back West.
He say where he got the car?
No.
Only that it was owed to him.
And that you were probably
gonna come and get it.
Half true.
He tried to take ours, too.
Well he was a thief.
Weird dude,
you did the right thing.
You wanna see him?
No.
We got what we came for.
Keep on keepin' on, boys.
Wait, wait a minute.
Annie?
Beg your pardon?
It's you isn't it?
Annie?
It's me, Mickey.
Jesus Christ!
What are you doing?
I told you to let it go.
[Benny] Aw, God!
I- I did! We did!
[Benny] Oh!
What the fuck!
How were we supposed to know
you were gonna be here?
[yelps in pain]
You fucking bitch!
I already shot you once,
Beardy-face I will do it again.
I'm sorry, I told you.
The Orchard is not
what you think it is.
I can't have you following us.
Where are your keys?
- Ben, give her the keys.
- Aw, come on Mickey!
Ben, give her
the fucking keys, man!
Alright, alright! Here!
Here you motherfucker!
I'm sorry.
Way to go, Mick!
There she goes!
The girl that
kept you up nights!
Was she worth it?!
Huh?!
You watching?
You wait till we're gone
before you go after 'em.
If I see you again,
I'll kill you both.
They gotta, they gotta be
right around there, Mickey.
I watched them fall.
Yeah I know, but...
I don't know.
Yeah, okay.
Alright, just come on in.
We'll find 'em in the morning.
[sighs]
I'll give you one thing, Mick.
She wasn't no bull dyke.
You were right about that.
[grunts]
[whispering] Benny.
Benny.
What, what?
What, Mickey, what?
[whispering] Did you hear that?
What?
[thud]
Oh shit!
Oh shit, oh shit!
Where's the light?
Where's the flashlight?
Mickey calm down!
Calm down, man.
Turn the- hit the headlights.
Oh!
- Oh no!
- Oh my God!
We gotta go.
We gotta go no, come on!
Ben, come on!
I can't Mickey,
my fucking leg, man!
Just go!
Go!
[grunting]
Aghhh!
Oh, they're everywhere!
Mickey turn off the lights!
[groaning, banging on car]
[groaning,
thuds on car continue]
See if I can get
any of these motherfuckers.
ahhh!
[gunshots]
Ah, shit.
Jesus!
We, ugh!
We have to try to hot wire it!
What, hot wire the car?
We've only tried to do it
a dozen God damn times, Mickey.
There's gotta be a way.
It's just...
twisting wires.
Oh, yeah, in the movies.
In the fucking movies
it's twisting wires
Mickey you're gonna
get in there,
start stripping wires,
and you're gonna fuck
everything up!
It's already fucked up!
Everything is fucked up!
- They keys are gone!
- Yeah. And why is that?
Why is that?
What?
Why are they keys gone?
You told me to
get them tomorrow morning.
No, no why are they
in the fucking field, Mickey?
Why did I get shot?
So you're blaming this on me?
I'm saying...
they told us that
we weren't welcome
and you couldn't let it go.
I told you not to
sugarcoat this girl.
That it was gonna bite ya, and
now look where we are.
Maybe if we just lay low,
and shut up,
they'll go away.
They don't go away, Mickey.
You know that.
But shut up anyway.
[♪ Loud Mouths - Wise Blood
plays in headphones ♪]
[volume increases]
[groaning]
[grunts]
Hey.
How much water you think
a person's supposed to
have everyday.
I have no idea.
How many days you think that is?
Hey.
- Hey.
- What's up? What?
What about what
we did up in Pittsfield?
What about it?
Do you think it would work?
No.
I don't see how.
I mean, that was
a two story house, Mickey.
There was a little bit
more wiggle room,
don't you think?
This sound is driving me crazy.
It's kinda nice, I think.
Soothing.
Like rain on a tin roof.
[heartbeat]
[heartbeat speeding up]
[♪ Seasonality - Sun Hotel
playing in headphones ♪]
[stapling]
You done?
Can't look at their
fucking faces anymore.
Let's see, what do you want,
you want uh,
tuna?
Luncheon loaf?
Chicken I think.
Umm, chicken I guess.
Okay, you wanna split
a can of peas, too?
Sure.
Oh wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, don't...
don't eat that.
Lemme get that...
Oh, come on. That's disgusting.
Yeah.
Wait till we have to
start saving our piss.
Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
Shut the fuck up!
"Like rain on a tin roof."
Shut up.
I have an idea.
Let's get shitfaced.
That's not an idea.
It's a great idea.
How's that gonna help?
I think we should celebrate.
What? What are you
talking about?
Celebrate what?
I don't know.
Last night on earth, maybe?
That's depressing.
[chuckles]
[laughing] okay!
[mockingly] It's the source
of infection!
[laughing crazily]
We figured it out!
We fucking figured it out!
Oh my God!
No, no! Don't do the other one!
Don't!
This one's really bad!
It's really bad!
I'm taking the socks off too!
- Not the socks!
- Ahhhh!
- Come on! No!!! No! No!
- [giggling drunkenly]
Oh come on!
- Ewww
- It's not that bad.
It's not that bad! [giggling]
Just say it man.
- Say what?
- Say it!
Say it! Say it!
Say the "Z" word!
No.
- No way.
- Why not?
Because they're not real.
Oh they're fucking real.
They're pretty fucking real.
Come on, you know what I mean.
Let's do "Ro Shambo" you gotta
drink if you lose, alright?
- Oh! Come on!
- Fuck you.
I'm trapped in a fucking car.
And I wish I had...
air conditioning.
[laughing]
Okay, I wanna win one.
Fuck!
Let's switch it up.
Say they got fangs,
and they're sucking
fucking blood
and they're
burning up in the sun.
and you have a crucifix,
and they can't eat garlic...
- What do you call 'em?
- Fuck you!
Yeah, exactly.
I'm just saying...
if it walks like a duck,
quacks like a duck...
it's probably a fucking zombie!
[both laughing]
[both] Ohhhh!!!
Trapped in a fucking car,
I wish I had air conditioning,
balloons, cheese...
and dynamite.
I'm trapped in fucking car...
and I wish I had
air conditioning,
balloons,
cheese,
dynamite,
and every Beatles album.
Yeah.
[at same time]
- Yeeeesssssss!
- Nooooooooo!
- Drink for beating me!
- Okay.
...And then you just jump
over 'em and you get the keys!
But I couldn't
find the keys when...
when there weren't
fifty fucking zombies,
- How am I supposed to...
- [laughing]
- Wait a minute, wait.
- What?
What did you just say?
Say it again.
- Ohhhh...
- Say it again.
What did you say?
Say the word.
- Fifty...
- Say it.
- Zombies!
- Zombies! Ha ha haaa!
Alright. Okay, okay, okay.
[ambient sounds]
[♪ singing "Show Me the
Way to Go Home" ♪]
♪ I'm tired and I wanna
go to bed. ♪
♪ I had me a drink
about an hour ago ♪
♪ and it went straight
to my head. ♪
♪ Wherever I may roam,
♪ by land, or sea, or foam,
♪ you can always hear me
singing this song. ♪
♪ Show me the way to go home.
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow we die.
Okay.
[both laughing]
[banging, zombies growling]
Mickey, you can do this, man.
You can do it.
You say low.
And go hard.
You'll be fine.
Mickey?
If you don't find the keys,
don't come back.
I'm not leaving you here.
Ben.
I can do this.
[moaning and groaning
gets louder]
[metal pots banging]
[groaning continues]
[loud bang]
[louder bang]
[mutters] Come on Mickey.
[groaning continues
monotonously]
[thud on car]
Come on, Mickey, man.
Fuck, fuck.
[muttering] Come on, Mickey.
Come on, come on.
Come on, Mickey.
[muffled] Benny!!
[thudding on car]
Oh my God!
Mickey! Mickey!
[screaming, laughing]
Come on, buddy!
Come on!
[panting heavily]
Did you get 'em?
Mickey!
Did you get 'em?!
Mick?
Mickey.
Mickey, did you get the keys?
Mick?
Mick, what's wrong?
Mickey, Mickey were you bit?
Oh my God!!
Mickey, are you bit?!
Oh fuck!! Mickey!!!
- Oh Jesus!!!
- No Ben!!
Mickey!
- Please Ben!
- Mickey!
Oh fuck!
Ohh!
- Oh God!
- [Mickey crying]
- What do I do?!
What do I do?!
Ben, please!
Ben! What do I do, please!
Oh God dammit!
- Don't shut down...
- God dammit!!
Please! Tell me what do I do?!
I'm scared!
[crying]
Ben!
Ben, please don't
shut down on me!
- Mickey!
- No!
Ben, no!
Put the gun away!
You gotta get outta the car.
No, you can't!
You gotta get
outta the car, man...
- I can't!
- Get outta the fucking car!!!
[shouting]
Mickey get out!!!
- You can't do this!
- I have to, Mickey!
You know it!
God dammit!!!
Please let me stay!
Get outta the
fucking car, Mickey!
- Please!
- Oh, God!
- Ben!
- Ohh!
- Oh my God!
[crying]
[gunshot]
[panting]
[screams]
[silence]
[♪ menacing instrumental guitar
music ♪]
Is anybody out there?
You know, me and Mickey we were
trapped in a house
for three months
when it all started.
Had to board up the windows.
Block out the sunlight.
You ever been inside,
in one place...
for that long?
Listening to the same sound,
all day.
Every day.
It does something to you.
Annie.
Are you listening?
I bet you are.
Oh I bet you are.
Mickey didn't make it.
Because of you.
You hear me?
It's funny.
How we finally got
outta that house.
We just opened the door.
They all tried to pile
in one side, and we just...
went out the other.
All that time.
And it was that easy.
Just...
let 'em in.
I think I'm gonna try it again.
If it doesn't work this time...
I'm just gonna put
a bullet in my head.
But if it does...
I'm gonna come
and put one in yours.
I'll see you soon.
[♪ We've Got A Lot To Be
Glad For - Rock Plaza
Central ♪]