This is Rudy Behlmer speaking.
For the next 71 minutes,
I'll be talking about
the background and making of
the 1933 film version of HG Wells's
novel The Invisible Man,
a film that still plays remarkably well.
Various outlines, treatments and scripts
were submitted by 12 writers,
before RC Sherriffs approach was
accepted by all involved,
including author HG Wells.
Four different directors were slated at
various times to handle the production,
before James Whale was set.
Boris Karloff was definitely
the studio's choice for the title role
until late in preproduction.
The amazing special effects
of 1933 by John Fulton
are still amazing in this day of
seemingly boundless effects technology,
but details on all this and much more
will follow as we go along.
No, the music you are hearing
is not Tchaikovsky's Swan Lake,
which was used under the main title
for four Universal horror films,
beginning with Dracula in 1931,
but this is an original score
by Heinz Roemheld.
It's a sparse score, to say the least.
After the opening,
you won't hear any more of it
until the last seven minutes of the film.
The film and HG Wells' novel
open in the exact same way.
I quote from the beginning
of chapter one in the book:
"The stranger came early
in February one wintry day,
through a biting wind and a driving snow,
the last snowfall of the year,
over the down, walking as it seemed
from Bramblehurst railway station."
"He was wrapped up from head to foot,
and the brim of his soft felt hat
hid every inch of his face
but the shiny tip of his nose;
the snow had piled itself
against his shoulders and chest,
and added a white crest
to the burden he carried."
Wells's story took place in the West
Sussex village of lping in England,
but British director James Whale
drew upon his memories
of growing up in the town of Dudley,
in the West Midlands of England,
in order to cast
and direct character types.
Whale said "I do not doubt that
when Dudley people see this film,
they will recognise some of these types."
The village inn,
in the film called "The Lion's Head",
has a cross section of types
engaging in characteristic activity.
Typical inn and pub. Conversation,
laughter, a few pints of ale, and darts.
Enter the mysterious stranger.
He is dramatically pointed up by a series
of three successively closer shots,
similar to Whale's introduction
of Frankenstein's monster,
played by Boris Karloff in
the 1931 production of Frankenstein.
But the voice you're going
to hear is certainly not Karloffs.
Rather, the unmistakable and unique
vocal delivery of Claude Rains,
who was making his first sound film.
What happened regarding the planned
casting of Boris Karloff in the title role?
After his success in Frankenstein,
and to a lesser extent,
The Mask of Fu Manchu, on loan to MGM,
and The Mummy,
back at his home studio,
Universal regarded him
as a full-fledged star,
and all along had planned
for him to do The Invisible Man.
But the Great Depression
had taken its toll on Universal,
as well as most of the other studios,
and they were in dire straits.
In May 1933,
when Karloff returned from England,
where he had been on loan
to Gaumont-British for The Ghoul,
he was still set
for the starring role in The Invisible Man.
Then, in June, he encountered
contract problems with Universal.
As the trade paper Variety reported,
"Universal is continuing its policy
of dumping contract players
as soon as
they reach the big-money class,
and substituting them
with new people at less money."
"The latest Universal star
to go off the list is Boris Karloff."
"At the studio 18 months,
Karloff had been drawing $750 per week
and was scheduled to get $1250
on his coming option jump."
"The sum represented a jump of $500,
or $250 each for two option periods."
"Karloff waived
the previous option increase,
which would have boosted
his salary to $1000,
on condition that he would get
the full amount on the next option."
"Universal refused to meet
the figure, which came due Thursday,
and Karloff walked."
Whale offered the role
to fellow Britisher Colin Clive,
who had been the director's leading man
in both the stage and screen versions
of the well-received Journey's End,
and who played the leading role of Dr
Frankenstein, who creates the monster,
in Whale's 1931 film of Frankenstein.
But Clive, who had
a marvellous voice and delivery,
had just completed two additional
film roles in Hollywood,
and wanted to get back to England,
although the part did appeal to him.
In the British magazine Picturegoer,
in July 1933:
"Colin Clive gets a kick out of playing
parts like his grim role in Frankenstein."
"He certainly does not see himself
as a leading man or romantic lover."
"He wants the strong stuff."
Now what?
Whale remembered Claude Rains,
and discovered that he had made
a screen test for RKO Radio Pictures
for the leading male role
in A Bill of Divorcement in 1932.
Apparently it was not good.
In fact, it was, in the actor's own words,
"the worst screen test
in the history of movie-making".
He said that when Whale saw it,
he howled with laughter.
Incidentally,
the part in A Bill of Divorcement
went to luminary John Barrymore.
But Whale wanted Rains
and his special presence.
A test was made, and Rains, who had
been appearing in Broadway plays,
was signed at virtually the last moment.
Unless one had seen him on the stage
in his native England, or in New York,
the unique and commanding
texture of his vocal delivery
would be a new experience
for movie-goers at that time.
That's why Whale wanted him,
for his voice.
Whale knew Rains and his work and he
knew the voice had to be a distinctive one
because of the unusual nature of the role.
He also wanted a highly-trained
and consummate actor,
who would be able to give extra
dimensions to what might be regarded
as merely a highly-charged,
melodramatic role.
Rains had played a vast range of roles
in his many years in the theatre,
and was never typecast.
So far, the film has been following
the HG Wells novel very closely,
but RC Sherriff quite rightly felt that some
changes in Wells's novel were necessary
in order to present a more unified
structure for a 70-minute film
and to give the mysterious stranger
certain sympathetic qualities for contrast.
Sherriffs modifications
were thoughtful and not capricious.
A change of scene.
We are introduced in this sequence
to two characters not in the novel at all,
but very much a strong presence
in the screenplay.
Dr Cranley, played by Henry Travers,
is obviously a scientist or medical man,
and we shortly find out that
the mysterious man at the inn
is probably Jack Griffin,
a scientist employed by Dr Cranley
who has been gone for a month,
working on a private experiment.
But his whereabouts are unknown.
Flora, played by Gloria Stuart,
is Dr Cranley's distressed daughter,
who, we can tell, is very much in love
with Jack Griffin, the stranger at the inn.
To get maximum mileage from this
character introduction and exposition,
we learn a bit about
Griffin's secretive experiments,
which, combined with what we've seen
of his actions previously at the inn,
and the film's title, The Invisible Man,
leaves little doubt
about what he's been up to.
The gradual revealment
is a necessary dramatic setup
for the events that will follow.
This exposition
of character relationships is expanded
by the introduction of Dr Kemp, played by
William Harrigan, a character in the novel
whose role is greatly enlarged
for dramatic purposes in the film.
He obviously is
in the employ of Flora's father,
as is Jack Griffin, the Rains character.
It's necessary to get
Flora and Kemp to another area,
via Whale's use
of the lateral camera move,
which, as in the theatre, breaks away
walls and leads us to another room.
Now Kemp is able to have
a more intimate discussion with Flora.
He's presented here
as a romantic rival for Flora,
and as a not particularly charming suitor.
While under contract
to Universal Pictures for four years,
Gloria Stuart, who plays Flora, did
two other films for director James Whale:
The Old Dark House in 1932
and The Kiss Before the Mirror in 1933.
Stuart has said that Whale was
an exceptionally well prepared
and enthusiastic director.
On his script, he had each
camera setup for the day's shooting
noted in his own handwriting
opposite the dialogue.
Many other performers and technicians
have noted Whale's meticulous approach.
William Harrigan had been an actor
on the stage since the age of five.
In 1929, he went to Hollywood
with the advent of talking pictures,
and the mass exodus
of many Broadway players.
Now, Dr Kemp is declaring,
quite emphatically, his feelings for Flora,
who, not too subtly, is surrounded by
flowers in the photographic compositions.
Flora, flowers.
Anyway, Flora amply
demonstrates a definitive example
of the attraction/repulsion theory
by her reaction
to Kemp's romantic overture.
In this instance,
repulsion wins hands down.
Meanwhile, back at the inn,
the mysterious stranger
is trying desperately
to find a solution to an aspect
of his experiment, one of many,
that we're not too clear about as yet.
We wonder about his intense frustration.
Una O'Connor,
whose real name was Agnes McGlade,
was born in Belfast, Ireland in 1880.
She attended convent school,
and joined the school
of the Abbey Players in Dublin.
She made her official debut in 1911.
Una acted with the Abbey Players,
the Irish Repertory Company,
and the Irish Literary Theatre,
in plays by Shakespeare, O'Casey,
Yeats, lbsen, Shaw and Galsworthy.
In 1913, she made
her London debut at Court Theatre,
and she acted in various London plays.
In 1931,
there was that great success Cavalcade,
which featured Una
as the cockney charwoman.
When Fox planned
to film the Noël Coward play,
they sent for Una, and Merle Tottenham,
who had played the maid of Cavalcade,
and reprises that role in this film.
In 1933, James Whale, who had
known Una from the London stage,
invited her and Merle
to act in his Invisible Man.
For many years, she appeared in
many memorable Hollywood films,
including James Whale's
sequel to Frankenstein,
the 1935 Bride of Frankenstein.
Some of her other supporting roles
include The Barretts of Wimpole Street,
David Copperfield, The Informer,
The Adventures of Robin Hood,
The Sea Hawk, How Green Was
my Valley, Random Harvest,
The Bells of St Mary's,
and Adventures of Don Juan.
There are many British players
in this film,
most from theatre,
both in England and America,
and some who arrived in Hollywood
after the introduction of sound.
Whale had worked with or knew them,
and naturally felt comfortable when
he personally cast them in the film.
This gentleman is Forrester Harvey,
who was born in
County Cork, Ireland, in 1884.
He moved to London at a very young age,
and before coming to America in 1924
Harvey had been featured in
English film comedies for ten years.
He then appeared in New York plays.
Returning to London,
he accepted the role of Lieutenant Trotter
in the Whale-directed
hit play Journey's End,
and then again came to America,
this time to stay.
His film roles include
Tarzan the Ape Man, Red Dust,
Tarzan and his Mate, Captain Blood,
Rebecca, The Invisible Man Returns,
the 1941 Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde,
The Wolf Man, Mrs Miniver
and many others.
We now see that the stranger
is capable of a furious outburst,
and we'll see extreme violence,
a portent of his obviously
unstable and dangerous state.
Una O'Connor
is capable of bursting forth
with an incredible volley of
high-decibel cackles, screams, shrieks
that seem rather over the top,
to say the least.
There's another scene a little later where
she reprises her full complement of these.
Fair warning. Obviously, director
James Whale didn't think it was too rich.
In fact, two years later, he had her going
through her screech repertoire again
for Bride of Frankenstein.
But interestingly, you don't hear her
going anywhere near that level
in her many other fine characterisations
through the decades.
HG Wells's novel The Invisible Man
was first serialised in England
in Pearson's Weekly, in 1897,
and then published
in book form that same year.
Universal had a synopsis
in the late 1920s,
when Wells's agent
was offering motion picture rights.
MGM apparently turned it down in 1931
because of potential technical obstacles.
But Universal, by late 1931,
was seriously considering the title
as one of the follow-ups
to their Dracula and Frankenstein.
The studio executives
turned to John Fulton,
the head of what was then referred to
as the "trick department",
to see if it was possible to create and
execute acceptable effects for the subject.
Fulton said yes,
so Universal bought the story rights
on September 22nd 1931 for $10,000,
with author HG Wells granted
script approval as part of the deal.
The studio also bought,
about that same time,
a new 1931 novel by Philip Wylie
called The Murderer Invisible.
But more about that anon.
John Fulton, nicknamed "The Doctor"
around the lot,
knew that the travelling-matte technique
would be the way to approach
the most dazzling of the effects.
Before coming to work at Universal,
Fulton worked for the
Frank Williams Laboratory in Hollywood.
Where the travelling-matte system
had evolved.
Fulton wrote an article on
The Invisible Man for the June 1934 issue
of American Cinematographer,
and I quote:
"Pulling off a nose.
This scene was made by using a dummy,
an exact replica of the player's make-up."
"And then the unwrapping action
was handled in the same fashion
as the other half-clad scenes,
that is, by multiple printing
with travelling mattes."
"We had considerable trouble in getting
the actor to move naturally,
yet without ever passing
his hands in front of himself."
This is only a warm-up, of course,
for the multiplicity of effects that follow.
We are now about
17 minutes into the film,
and the build-up
to this moment has been just right.
We were allowed one brief profile shot
of an invisible mouth, chin and jaw
several minutes ago,
and now with the unwrapping shots
we wait with fascinating anticipation
to see what lengths the invisibility
presentation will take us next.
For the undressing scenes, RC Sherriff
wrote a note in his screenplay...
Wait a minute. I guess the invisible man
doesn't wear underwear.
Anyway, his note says:
"I suggest that trick photography
be employed here, as far as possible,
with the aid of invisible wire frames
manipulated by the marionette method."
But, as Fulton explained,
"the wire technique could not be used,
for the clothes would look empty
and would hardly move naturally".
"So we had recourse
to multiple printing with variations."
"Most of these scenes involve
other, normal characters,
so we shot these scenes
in the normal manner
but without any trace
of the invisible man."
"All of the action, of course,
had to be carefully timed,
as in any sort of double-exposure work."
"The negative was then developed
in the normal manner."
"The scenes in which he is totally
invisible are, of course, very simple."
"Anything he may move about, such
as furniture, books, a bicycle and so on,
could be moved by fine wires
invisible to the camera,
and thereby give exactly the right effect."
Actor EE Clive,
playing the police constable,
made his film debut in The Invisible Man.
Incidentally, his first name was Edward.
Born in Wales, Clive was a master of
the various dialects of the British Isles,
and toured extensively in the provinces
after taking up a stage career
at the age of 22.
He moved to the United States in 1912.
He only spent seven years in Hollywood
films before dying from a heart attack,
but in that short span,
racked up over 80 movies.
We've now moved from melodrama
into knockabout comedy,
with the invisible man
leading us through a parade
of Whale's expertly
choreographed physical wire effects,
all carefully rigged and executed
by Al Johnson and Bob Laslow.
Of course, the actors had
to move and react convincingly
to make these quick cuts work.
A bicycle riding away by itself
is on a concealed track,
and wires above kept the bike upright.
The invisible man's patter during
this collage was not in the script,
but was probably post-recorded by Rains.
Much of Rains' dialogue throughout
the film was either pre- or post-recorded.
Most of the exteriors made
were shot on the back lot at Universal.
EE Clive worked for director James Whale
in five additional films.
One More River, Bride of Frankenstein,
Remember Last Night?
Show Boat, and The Great Garrick.
Some of his other credits include
A Tale of Two Cities, Captain Blood,
Libeled Lady, Camille,
The Charge of the Light Brigade,
The Hound of the Baskervilles,
The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes,
and his last film, Hitchcock's
Foreign Correspondent in 1940.
Not only a change of scene,
but a total change in mood.
More developments regarding
Jack Griffin's experiments,
and one major discovery coming up,
regarding a dangerous drug.
We are so accustomed to the wonderful
character actor Henry Travers
being cast as a whimsical, bemused
benign person, often slightly eccentric,
that it's curious here to see him
playing seemingly straight and sombre.
This was only his fourth film.
Although born of Irish parents in England
on the Scottish border in 1874,
he had been in America since
the beginning of the 20th century,
and appeared for years
on Broadway in major works,
including seven plays
by George Bernard Shaw,
in addition to Liliom, Volpone
and Reunion in Vienna, et cetera.
He made his film debut
in the latter in 1933.
Travers, whose real name
was Travers Heagerty,
had appeared in two plays
with Claude Rains,
Camel Through the Needle's Eye in 1929
and the stage version
of The Good Earth in 1932.
Dr Cranley tells Kemp
about the drug monocane.
The doctor has discovered
this on a list of chemicals
which had been left behind by Griffin.
Cranley refers to monocane
as "a terrible drug"
that "draws colour
from everything it touches".
He also says that the drug
gradually induces madness.
The fictional monocane was
an invention by screenwriter RC Sherriff.
In the book, Griffin, a university student,
has damaged his mind with strychnine.
But by having monocane
be part of the invisibility formula
as well as a mind-altering drug,
which presumably was not known by
Griffin, per the dialogue in this scene,
gives an acceptable motive
for his various acts in the film,
versus the book's one-note monomania.
In the 1940 Universal sequel
The Invisible Man Returns,
the name of the drug
is changed to duocane,
presumably marketed underground as
"New, improved and double-strength".
A few of Henry Travers' 52 films
include Ball of Fire, High Sierra,
Mrs Miniver, Random Harvest,
Hitchcock's Shadow of a Doubt,
and that hardy perennial, Frank Capra's
It's a Wonderful Life in 1946
as the memorable Clarence, the angel.
He died in 1965.
A quiet evening at home,
reading and listening to the radio.
A sidebar, if I may:
The tune being played on the radio
is that apotheosis of maudlin
sentimentality "Hearts and Flowers",
performed in an old-fashioned manner
even for 1933,
on what sounds like an upright piano
with all the frills and trills.
Presumably, this is an inside joke,
put in by a music editor some years later,
to replace the music used
for the initial release of the film.
That music was "La Rosita",
a 1923 composition
that became a semi-standard.
The substitution probably stemmed
from a music clearance situation.
The invisible man has decided
to pay a visit to his old colleague.
The radio announcer
begins the news with a report
about an invisible man
in the village of lping.
Kemp is interested. Then the radio, of
course, is turned off by you know who.
Both writer RC Sherriff
and director Whale did not want
to rely on just the invisible man's voice
to indicate his presence
during scenes when he's totally invisible,
as in this situation.
They wanted the audience
to be drawn to the character,
so everything was set up,
staged and photographed to this end.
Whale told Film Weekly "It was all very
well to film the scenes without the actor,
but I knew that I had in some way
to let the audience know clearly
that the actor was there all the time,
although he was invisible."
"Therefore, in nearly every one
of the 'invisible' scenes,
I had to devise bits of business so
the audience should know where he was,
what he was doing and so on."
"In one scene,
I made him sit in a rocking chair,
so by the movements of the chair,
the audience would realise he was there,
although there was
no sign of his presence."
"He's sitting in a chair
talking to another person."
"I showed the seat of the chair
sagging slightly as he sat down."
"Then, when his voice
became more confidential,
I had the chair moved
a few inches toward the other person,
as though the invisible man had drawn it
closer for more intimate conversation."
Although we have been seeing
strictly wire effects here,
Sherriff and Whale mix it with intriguing
travelling-matte work you've just seen,
for the cigarette lighter, the handling
of the cigarette and smoking effect.
William Harrigan, the actor playing Kemp,
was a last-minute substitute
for Chester Morris,
who had been scheduled for the role.
Morris was a leading player, who had
come from the theatre to Hollywood.
He had starred in
The Big House, The Bat Whispers
and The Red-Headed Woman
opposite Jean Harlow,
just before being slated
for The Invisible Man.
But, when newcomer
to American films Claude Rains
was signed and given top billing,
Morris, who already was unhappy with
his unsympathetic and colourless role,
after finally reading the script,
bowed out around mid-June,
shortly before the start of filming.
Harrigan and Claude Rains
had recently appeared
in the well-received Theatre
Guild production on Broadway
of the Irish drama,
The Moon in the Yellow River.
It's possible that Rains recommended him
to Whale after Morris pulled out.
Harrigan had become a leading man on
the Broadway stage by his 21st birthday.
His family was one
of the oldest in theatre history,
having been on the stage
uninterruptedly since 1660.
Some of Harrigan's films include
'G' Men with James Cagney,
The Farmer's Daughter, with Loretta
Young, Desert Fury with Burt Lancaster
and Flying Leathernecks
with John Wayne.
He created the role of the Captain
in the stage production
of the extremely popular
Mister Roberts in 1948,
and stayed with it
during its original three-year run.
His sister was film
and stage actress Nedda Harrigan.
The actor died in 1966 at age 79.
I would like to talk about the person who
wrote The Invisible Man novel in 1897,
HG Wells.
Herbert George Wells.
An English novelist and journalist,
who was known for his science fiction,
his satirical novels and
his popular books on history and science.
He was a vigorous advocate
of socialism, feminism,
evolutionism, nationalism
and the advancement of science.
Often called the first
great writer of science fiction,
Wells wrote The Time Machine, The
Island of Dr Moreau, The Invisible Man,
The War of the Worlds, The First
Men in the Moon, among many others.
They were all published at the end of the
19th century and beginning of the 20th.
Wells was not the first to write
about a person becoming invisible.
In 1833, James Dalton composed
an ambitious cautionary tale
in a three-decker novel
called The Invisible Gentleman.
Later, Edward Page Mitchell
dealt with the subject
in a story called The Crystal Man in 1881.
And CH Hinton wrote a tale of invisibility
titled Stella in 1895.
These are just a few examples.
In The Invisible Man novel,
Wells writes about Griffin's experiments
that involve a fourth dimension,
in this case, light.
Refraction, reflection.
He goes into pigment research
and optical density, which determines
the degree of visibility of things.
There is a two-phase process
using a drug and a mechanical device.
By an ingenious use of scientific patter
it all seems perfectly logical and feasible,
especially since Wells wrote
in a very straightforward style.
Of course, his books contain
highly imaginative ideas
that have been the basis for
many films over the past 100 years.
In the film, the invisibility
experiments are reduced to
Griffin talking about trying "a thousand
experiments, a thousand failures",
and mentioning "a mixture of drugs".
Add to this Dr Cranley discussing
monocane in an earlier scene,
and that takes care of what
the audience is allowed to know.
The scene between Griffin and Kemp
was used for Claude Rains' test.
He had been appearing in the play Peace
Palace in New York in early June 1933,
so the test probably was made in New
York and was not directed by Whale.
Also, Rains was not done up
in bandages and goggles for the test.
The actor said that
he had never read the novel,
and he had no idea that his face
would not be seen during the film.
Rains said
"For five years - five years, mind -
I was prating to the Theatre Guild about
my artistic integrity. My artistic integrity!"
"Then, the first day at the studio,
James brought over some bandages."
"I asked about them and he said I was to
be bandaged during most of the picture."
"And I had been fighting with the Theatre
Guild about my artistic integrity!"
"It served me right."
Rains recalled also that "James kept
talking about this and that in pictures,
about actors of whom I'd never heard."
"When he learned
I'd only seen six films or so in my life,
he told me
to go right out and see pictures,
to see three a day
until I knew something about them."
Now, listen to Griffin's plan.
I... You mean...?
I must have a partner, Kemp,
a visible partner,
to help me in the little things.
You're my partner, Kemp.
We'll begin with a reign of terror.
A few murders here and there.
Murders of great men
and murders of little men,
just to show we make no distinction.
We might even wreck a train or two.
Just these fingers round
a signalman's throat, that's all.
We think of Claude Rains' very distinctive
and dramatically appealing voice,
but it was not always thus.
William Claude Rains was born in 1889
in London. The family was poor.
Hating school and teased by classmates
because of a serious speech impediment,
he ran away at a very young age.
After appearing in a crowd scene on
the stage of London's Haymarket Theatre,
Rains, at age 10 in 1900,
made the monumental decision
to devote his life to the theatre.
But in addition to a broad cockney accent
and a stutter,
Rains had other speech problems.
Over 50 years later, when Rains received
the Medal for Good Speech on the Stage,
in New York, he recalled:
"Almost my first occupation
in the theatre was a callboy."
"I had to summon actors from
their dressing rooms to the stage."
"It was difficult to be taken seriously
because I had a speech impediment."
"I had no Rs. If anyone asked my name,
my answer came out as 'Willy Wains'."
I had ideas that someday
I would become an actor,
so the all-important thing
was to get rid of the impediment."
"I discovered I had a 'lazy tongue',
the muscle of which
had never properly been used,
because my mother
thought I talked 'pwettily'."
But Rains worked hard
to overcome his problem.
He took elocution lessons,
did voice and speech exercises,
and worked on them with great intensity.
He also listened, and observed everything
in the theatrical atmosphere around him.
He made his adult acting debut
as Claude Rains in 1911,
again at the Haymarket Theatre,
his voice
and speech problems conquered.
Walter Brennan, before
he became a major character actor.
In the British Army
in France during World War I,
Rains was subjected to heavy
artillery bombardment and poison gas.
As a result, while in the infirmary
he discovered that his vocal chords
had been paralysed,
and that his right eye
was almost completely blind.
Eventually he was able to speak again,
and Rains later would say that
the unique, husky quality of his voice
was due to the effects of the poison gas.
But his near-blindness
in his right eye was another matter.
Only his family and some
very close friends were aware of it.
That lasted through the rest of his life.
Rains had a distinguished career
on the London stage,
playing in
some very important productions,
including a series
of George Bernard Shaw plays.
He also became an acting teacher at the
famous Royal Academy of Dramatic Art,
where he worked with such
students and later luminaries
as Laurence Olivier and John Gielgud.
In late 1926,
he moved to the Broadway stage
in American touring
companies of hit plays.
Rains went on to become,
in the late 1920s,
the Theatre Guild's
outstanding character actor.
Now we're going to see more physical
effects - mostly wire effects - coming up
to get material out of his room
and down to the street.
None of this involved travelling mattes,
but it involved heavy-wire work
that you couldn't see
because of the thinness of the wires.
The actor playing Inspector Bird
is Britisher Harry Stubbs,
who had been
in American films since 1929.
Horror film buffs will recognise him from
later appearances in Werewolf of London,
The Invisible Man Returns,
The Mummy's Hand, The Wolf Man
and Frankenstein Meets the Wolf Man.
For those who wanted yet another round
of Una's shrieks, this is the moment.
It is also her grand finale for this film.
In 1954, Una was
a very frail and weak 74 years old,
but she couldn't resist taking
the part of the deaf Scottish maid
whose testimony provides comic relief
in Agatha Christie's play
Witness for the Prosecution.
A major hit,
it ran for 645 performances in New York.
Una's portrayal delighted audiences.
Billy Wilder directed the film version,
starring Tyrone Power, Charles Laughton
and Marlene Dietrich in 1957,
and Una went to Hollywood for her last
screen appearance, recreating her role.
She died in 1959 at the age of 78.
Two years earlier, James Whale, when
he died, had left a bequest to the actress.
Now the invisible man has started to
put into practice his "reign of terror".
Remember that speech about beginning
with a few murders, here and there?
Inspector Bird was his first murder victim,
but we know there are more to come,
perhaps on a big scale.
Here's actor John Carradine,
then known as John Peter Richmond,
when he was playing
small roles around Hollywood.
Coming up very soon is one of
the most ingenious but complicated
travelling-matte shots in the film.
Special-effects technician John Fulton
will explain in his own words
his working methods for the matte shots.
As stated earlier, the scenes involving
the invisible man partially clothed
or totally invisible but with props
such as cigarettes or lighters visible,
along with other characters on the set,
were photographed as normal,
but without any evidence of the
invisible man and/or the handled props.
The negative was then developed. After
the entire film was finished shooting,
Fulton and his crew,
along with director James Whale,
began the special process work.
Said Fulton "We used a completely black
set, walled and floored with black velvet,
to be as nearly
non-reflective as possible."
"Our actor was garbed from head to foot
in black velvet tights,
with black gloves and a black headpiece
rather like a diver's helmet."
"Over this, he wore
whatever clothes might be required."
"This gave us a picture of unsupported
clothes moving on a dead black field."
From this negative, we made
a print and a duplicate negative,
which we intensified
to serve as mattes for printing."
"Then, with an ordinary printer,
we made our composite."
Now here's that scene I was talking about.
John Fulton says
"This shot had to show
the man himself from the rear,
and his reflection in the mirror."
"Ordinarily this would be simple enough,
but when you add the difficulties
of showing the unwrapping
of an invisible head,
you have some complicated
problems to solve."
"This required the making
of four separate takes,
combined by the travelling-matte
printing system into one picture."
"First, there was the shot
of the wall and the mirror,
with the mirror itself
masked out by black velvet."
"Next, a separate shot of the opposite wall
of the room, as reflected in the mirror."
"Thirdly, the shot of the invisible man
from the rear, unwrapping his bandages,
and lastly, the reflection of him
from the front doing the same act."
"All of these had to be
perfectly coordinated,
matched in viewpoint, perspective
and action to a fraction of an inch."
"Several of the negatives
required hand retouching."
"And last, but far from least,
the action had to be figured out
so that the hands of the actor did not
pass between himself and the camera
or between
the reflection and the camera."
"It was as difficult
a shot as I have ever made."
In some scenes it was possible
to leave small eyeholes
in the black headpiece the person
in the all-black outfit had on.
But for other shots, such as
the close shots of the head unwrapping,
this was not possible,
and the actor had to work blind.
Sometimes the actor was Claude Rains,
but often it was a double.
Air was supplied through tubes,
as in a diving suit.
The tubes were mostly concealed,
running up a trouser leg.
Fulton recalled
that on at least one occasion
either the air supply developed a problem,
or the summer heat
along with the units lighting the set...
In any case, something. The double
was overcome and he fainted mid-scene.
Fulton recalled "In nearly all of these
scenes, though they were made silent,
it was difficult, sometimes impossible,
to direct the actor."
"The helmet muffled
the sound from outside,
and the air tubes made
a roaring rumble in his ears,
which drowned out any sounds which
might filter through the padding."
"When I used a large megaphone,
and shouted at the top of my voice,
he could just barely hear a faint murmur."
"Accordingly, we had to rehearse, and
rehearse, and then make many takes."
"As a rule, by take 20 of any such scene,
we felt ourselves merely well started
toward getting our shot."
Also, care had to be taken
to get the actor to move naturally,
yet in a way that did not present,
for example,
an open sleeve-end to the camera,
which would destroy the illusion.
Also, the actor couldn't pass
his hands in front of himself.
Of course, there were small imperfections
that were not detected until those
involved
viewed the developed
and printed film the next day.
Fixing these slight problem areas
was accomplished
by individuals who carefully
retouched the film, frame by frame,
with a very small brush and opaque dye.
According to Fulton, approximately
64,000 frames were retouched in this way.
Until Universal's
The Invisible Man Returns in 1940,
there was no attempt to deal with such
spectacular invisibility effects in films.
But, on a somewhat
less spectacular level,
in 1937 producer Hal Roach made
his first of three Topper features.
The story related the humorous
adventures of two ghosts,
husband and wife, played by
Cary Grant and Constance Bennett.
They sometimes appeared
in a transparent mode,
other times they were invisible, and they
often appeared to be completely visible.
Roy Seawright's effects weren't as
elaborate as those in The Invisible Man,
but they were well done.
One of the challenges for John Fulton,
when he was doing his special invisible
shots against a black velvet background,
was matching the lighting
on the visible part of the shots
with the general lighting used by
the cinematographer, Arthur Edeson,
on the normal parts of the production.
The Invisible Man was
the last of five pictures
Arthur Edeson
photographed with James Whale.
The two apparently got along well.
There were never any
arguments or disagreements.
Whale learned a lot from Edeson,
beginning with their first film together,
Waterloo Bridge in 1931,
and then Frankenstein that same year.
But Edeson moved elsewhere
after The Invisible Man.
One of his major productions soon after
was the 1935
Mutiny on the Bounty at MGM.
Then there was the classic 1941
Maltese Falcon with Humphrey Bogart,
and he just happened to photograph
a picture called Casablanca in 1942.
Here's John Carradine again.
He was born Richmond Reed Carradine,
but his name was changed
to John Carradine
when he went under contract
to Twentieth Century Fox in 1935.
Arthur Edeson went way back as
a cinematographer, way back to 1914.
He shot some of Douglas Fairbanks
Senior's big productions in the 1920s,
including Robin Hood
and The Thief of Bagdad.
He did the first version
of The Lost World in 1925.
Edeson and director Lewis Milestone for
All Quiet on the Western Front, in 1930,
liberated the camera
from the cumbersome booths
that had been used to muffle noise when
sound was introduced in the late 1920s.
Believe it or not, there were motion
pictures dealing with invisibility
as far back as 1904.
A little number called The Invisible Siva,
a Georges Mélics French production.
Mélics was famous for doing trick films
with the magic executed in the camera.
Another French production,
The Invisible Thief, was done in 1905.
The Invisible Fluid in 1908
bestowed temporary invisibility
on men and inanimate objects.
Then came the British
Invisible Dog in 1910.
The Light Unseen in 1914
featured an invisible scientist.
A 1923 feature picture directed by
Roland West called The Unknown Purple
has an inventor,
played by Henry B Walthall,
discovering a purple light
that renders the user invisible.
He utilises the light to revenge himself
against those who framed him for theft.
And in 1933, the same year
The Invisible Man was made,
there was a German film called The
Invisible Man Goes Through the City.
Even animated cartoons
tried the invisible man theme.
One example is a 1939
Warner Brothers Looney Tunes
called Porky's Movie Mystery,
featuring Porky Pig as Mr Motto.
No, not Mr Moto. He's a detective
trying to track down the invisible man,
who is creating problems
at the film studio.
Finally, the character becomes visible,
and is revealed to be
the caricatured image
of Warner comedian of the time,
Hugh Herbert.
The above rundown of films
constitutes only some examples,
not a definitive and complete listing.
Before and after
the 1933 Invisible Man film,
there were various features,
serials, TV versions, even commercials.
Whale's biographer, James Curtis,
many years ago interviewed Ted Kent, the
film editor on nine of the director's films,
including The Invisible Man.
Recalling Whale's working methods,
Kent talked about
Whale wanting to maintain control
over all aspects of the productions.
In scripts, for example, he would point
out where close-ups were to be used.
Then at the back of his scripts
he would make suggested illustrations
for the art and costume departments.
Apparently, in creative areas,
it was difficult for Whale to delegate.
This is the first
of only two scenes in the entire film
between the invisible man
and his beloved Flora.
In part, it is a very poignant scene.
Griffin displays genuine tenderness
toward his inamorata.
You have the feeling that his love for Flora
has temporarily held in check
his maniacal behaviour
from the effects of the monocane drug.
Griffin's vocal delivery
reflects his momentary change
back to what was surely his personality
prior to the nefarious experiment.
After some devoted, touching
comments by Griffin, Flora asks:
- Why did you do this?
- For you, Flora.
- For me?
- Yes, for you, my darling.
I wanted to do something tremendous,
to achieve what men of science
have dreamt of since the world began,
to gain wealth and fame and honour,
to write my name above
the greatest scientists of all time.
I was so pitifully poor.
I had nothing to offer you, Flora.
I was just a poor, struggling chemist.
I shall come back to you,
Flora, very soon now.
The secret of invisibility
lies there in my books.
I shall work in Kemp's laboratory
till I find the way back.
There is a way back, Flora.
And then I shall come to you.
I shall offer my secret to the world,
with all its terrible power!
The nations of the world will bid for it -
thousands, millions.
The nation that wins my secret can
sweep the world with invisible armies!
Obviously the monocane
is fighting to regain its power,
and it succeeds.
Gloria Stuart has given many interviews
regarding her reactions
to playing scenes
in this film with Claude Rains.
She found him rather distant,
self-absorbed
and prone to upstaging her
in front of the camera.
But Whale intervened.
All in all, she did not find working with
Claude to be an enjoyable experience.
Actor Peter Lorre told an amusing story
about a joke played on Claude
that took place
when they were filming Casablanca.
"Claude was constantly studying, making
sure he had each line letter-perfect."
"One day we wrote a scene which
had nothing to do with the script,
and asked all the actors to memorise it,
except Claude, of course."
"When he came in the next day and saw
us rehearsing the scene, he was frantic."
"He called me aside and said 'Peter,
something terrible has happened to me."'
"'I can't remember a single line.' We all
broke up, and he wasn't even mad,
just relieved that
his memory wasn't failing."
Gloria Stuart was playing in The Seagull
at the Pasadena Playhouse in 1932
when Phil Friedman,
then Universal's casting director,
saw her and asked her to make a test.
A contract followed.
In addition to her films at Universal,
including three with James Whale,
she was loaned for various pictures,
including Here Comes the Navy
with James Cagney and Pat O'Brien,
and Gold Diggers of 1935
with Dick Powell.
One day Universal's production chief,
Carl Laemmle Junior, asked to see her.
Gloria recalled
"Junior was sitting behind his desk."
"'Sit down, Gloria.
We have a wonderful idea for you."'
"'We're going
to make you a female Tarzan!"'
"I guess it was a count of one, two,
three, then I really started screaming!"
She then went under contract
to Twentieth Century Fox,
and was featured in such films
as The Prisoner of Shark Island,
and two films with Shirley Temple,
Poor Little Rich Girl
and Rebecca of Sunnybrook Farm.
When she tried to make the move from
screen to Broadway in the 1940s,
"I never made it. It was years
and years of disappointment."
Her second husband, screenwriter Arthur
Sheekman, convinced her to stop trying.
In 1983 she learned printing
from Ward Ritchie,
a master printer and book designer
she had met back in 1930.
Both were widowed. Soon she was
creating artists' books in limited editions.
Ritchie was her companion
until his death in 1996.
When director James Cameron
selected the 86-year-old Gloria
for a leading role in Titanic in 1996,
yet another phase of her careers began.
Since Titanic, she has appeared in other
films and is still going strong aged 90.
Clearly, RC Sherriffs screenplay stayed
reasonably close to HG Wells' novel.
But what about those various treatments
and 11 scripts prepared by 12 different
writers that preceded Sherriffs version?
Garrett Fort, who had worked on the
scripts for both Dracula and Frankenstein,
started the parade with
a screenplay dated April 9, 1932.
He worked with Robert Florey,
who at that time
was slated to direct The Invisible Man.
But the script
was not based on Wells's book,
but rather on Philip Wylie's 1931 novel,
The Murderer Invisible,
that Universal had recently purchased.
Wylie's novel was set in contemporary
times in New York and New Jersey.
It dealt with a research scientist,
prior to disappearing himself,
experimenting and making an octopus
invisible in his laboratory tank.
With his own invisibility
comes megalomania.
He wreaks havoc on New York City
by blowing up Grand Central station,
among other major acts.
His plans are thwarted as he is about
to place invisible cholera bacteria
into New York's water supply that
no microscope would be able to detect.
Then the heroine crashes
a bottle of ink on his skull.
The bottle breaks,
and the ink deluges him,
making him visible and
an easy target for the police.
The early scripts were
quite faithful to Wylie's novel,
except that Garrett Fort modified
the invisible cholera
to invisible rats carrying bubonic plague.
But the invisible one is killed,
along with the rats,
by the police showering
his refuge with chlorine gas.
John I Balderston,
who had worked on the play versions
of Dracula and Frankenstein,
as well as the screenplay
of Universal's The Mummy,
wrote several drafts of the script
based on Garrett Fort's adaptation
of The Murderer Invisible.
A later draft of Balderston's was done
with the collaboration of Cyril Gardner,
who for a while
was going to direct the film.
Through the long gestation period,
various directors were announced
by Universal to do The Invisible Man.
In addition to Gardner and Florey,
James Whale was to be
on the project at different times.
Even EA Dupont, the German director.
Since HG Wells
supposedly had script approval,
it seems unlikely that Universal would
send versions based on another novel
but still titled The Invisible Man,
not The Murderer Invisible.
Perhaps these were considered
experimental drafts and not sent to Wells.
A puzzlement.
The train setting is a miniature
on a three-quarter-inch scale,
created for this film by Charlie Baker
and his miniature unit at Universal.
John Fulton and Baker
worked as a team at the studio.
The crash coming up
is very well executed in all respects.
Universal got a lot of mileage
out of this scene,
as it was recycled
for other features and serials,
one example being the 1942 feature
Sherlock Holmes and the Voice of Terror,
with Basil Rathbone and Nigel Bruce.
Philip Wylie, author of
The Murderer Invisible novel,
was a prolific writer
who worked in various genres.
Science fiction buffs know
such books as his When Worlds Collide
and After Worlds Collide,
among many others.
At the time The Invisible Man
was being prepared and filmed,
Wylie was at Paramount working on
the screenplay of another HG Wells book,
The Island of Dr Moreau.
The title was changed
to The Island of Lost Souls.
In addition, he contributed
to the scripts of Murders in the Zoo
and King of the Jungle
at Paramount during 1933.
The reporter asking the questions
is played by Dwight Frye.
We think of such characterisations
as the crazed Renfield in Dracula,
as the hunchback Fritz, Frankenstein's
loony assistant in the 1931 Frankenstein
and a similar role
in Bride of Frankenstein.
But here, his brief appearance
is one of complete normality.
Before coming to Hollywood in 1930, he
had an impressive career in the theatre.
Frye was in six of James Whale's films.
Moving on with the saga of
the evolving Invisible Man screenplays...
New approaches included
a treatment by Richard Schayer,
which has a scientist render
his mutilated assistant invisible
and later stand trial for a murder
committed by the assistant.
Preston Sturges contributed a script
that had a doctor treating his maniacal
assistant with an invisibility drug,
following which the two journey to Russia
to avenge the killing of the scientist's
relatives during the revolution.
James Whale decided to do
a six-page treatment of his own.
The approach presents
the invisible man as a scientist
who was able to make himself invisible
to obliterate a ghastly disfigurement.
But he too has a mind alteration
afterwards and goes on a killing spree.
Gouverneur Morris wrote a screenplay
based on Whale's six-page treatment.
For this version, Philip Wylie's invisible
octopus had a return engagement.
Apparently, Laird Doyle did a script
and John Weld, we are told,
wrote a treatment and screenplay that
were actually based on HG Wells' novel.
He was replaced by
British playwright RC Sherriff,
whose very successful
play Journey's End
had been directed by James Whale
on the stage and screen.
The actor playing
the chief of detectives is Dudley Digges,
another Irish-born actor
who made his stage debut
with the Abbey Theatre Players in Dublin,
and first performed
in the US in New York in 1904.
In 1911, he became stage manager
for the distinguished actor
George Arliss, for seven years.
And from 1919 to 1930, Digges appeared
in many Theatre Guild productions,
and staged or produced several plays.
In 1923 he produced George Bernard
Shaw's The Doctor's Dilemma,
which featured Claude Rains.
Later, Rains relieved Digges the actor in
two plays with extended runs and tours.
Digges, starting in 1929,
appeared in many films,
including the first version
of The Maltese Falcon in 1931,
as Casper Gutman, Sydney Greenstreet's
role in the 1941 Bogart version.
Other notable screen credits include
the 1935 Clark Gable, Charles Laughton
Mutiny on the Bounty,
The General Died at Dawn, The Light
That Failed, Son of Fury, et cetera.
He died in 1947.
RC Sherriff, in his 1968 autobiography,
described some of
the rejected adaptations he had read
prior to starting his own.
He mentioned that one turned
the invisible man "into a man from Mars,
who threatened to flood the world
with invisible Martians".
That particular approach
has not shown up as of now.
Perhaps this was
the elusive John Huston treatment,
written in the summer of 1932
when he was under contract
to Universal as a writer.
Or, perhaps Sherriff, in retrospect,
was confusing this with a project
that he and Whale were working on
at the time for Universal
called A Trip to Mars,
which was never made.
Sherriff reread HG Wells'
novel after many years,
and wondered why so many
writers of the previous scripts
had chosen to ignore
what Universal had purchased.
With Whale in agreement, Sherriff
did a dramatically sound adaptation.
Said Sherriff in his autobiography
"To give reality
to a fantastic story, HG Wells knew
it had to be told through the eyes
of ordinary, plain-spoken people."
"A screenplay, to my way of thinking,
lay about halfway
between a stage play and a novel."
"You were free from
the narrow boundaries of the stage,
but you had to keep from wandering
down the bylanes open to the novelist."
"I had to add ingredients here
and there to tighten up the drama."
Historian Paul Jensen was
the first to research and write
an in-depth study
of The Invisible Man, many years ago.
He pointed out that
some of the changes Sherriff made,
such as adding Flora and her father,
expanding Kemp's role,
and making him a romantic rival,
presented an interesting parallel.
Jensen wrote "The model for these added
aspects was probably Frankenstein."
"The two films share the situation
of a passionate young scientist
who has disappeared
in order to experiment alone,
leaving behind a worried fiancée,
a fatherly associate -
Dr Cranley here becomes Dr Waldman,
and Baron Frankenstein -
and a friend who is fond of the fiancée."
"By increasing Kemp's importance,
Sherriff and Whale provide Griffin
with a specific antagonist,
thereby creating a more precise conflict
than exists in the novel."
"Such a conflict is dramatically necessary
in The Invisible Man,
because there is no overt struggle
between the scientist and a monster,
as in Frankenstein."
"Here, the scientist himself
becomes the monster."
RC Sherriff, Robert Cedric Sherriff,
was born in Kingston-upon-Thames,
Surrey, England, in 1896.
He worked with Whale
on two other films at Universal,
One More River and The Road Back.
He also wrote the unproduced version
of Dracula's Daughter
that Whale was originally set to direct.
In 1939 he wrote the excellent script
for Korda's Technicolor production
of The Four Feathers.
Other credits include
the Robert Donat Goodbye, Mr Chips,
That Hamilton Woman with
Laurence Olivier and Vivien Leigh,
and Odd Man Out with James Mason.
He died in 1975.
Kemp's car going over the cliff
was another of Charlie Baker's,
and his Universal
miniature department's efforts.
As usual, a first-rate one.
This scene was also reprised
in other Universal films,
including Jungle Woman in 1944
and a 1945 Sherlock Holmes entry,
The House of Fear.
The British actor playing
the chief of police is Holmes Herbert.
This policeman is played
by Monte Montague, an American,
who speaks here with a British accent.
He was an actor
and stunt man for decades.
After a long absence,
since the main title, actually,
music returns as underscoring
for the last seven minutes of the film.
Composer Heinz Roemheld
also did original scores
for two other Universal
horror films at the time,
The Black Cat in 1934
and Dracula's Daughter in 1936.
In case the score
sounds somewhat familiar,
but you can't quite
place where else you heard it,
how about trying Universal's 1930s
Flash Gordon and Buck Rogers serials
with Buster Crabbe?
The music you're hearing
provided a perfect accompaniment
to the intrepid interplanetary adventures
of Flash, Dale and Dr Zarkov.
And The Invisible Man main title music
was put into service
whenever a rocket ship
in those serials raced here and there.
The farmer is Robert Browner,
who goes back to 1909 as a film actor.
Although The Invisible Man was always
thought to be Claude Rains' first film,
it was confirmed recently
that he had a supporting role
in a silent British feature production
of 1920 called Build Thy House,
which apparently is a lost film.
But based on items in the files
of the British Film Institute
Rains was eighth billed
and played a drunken loafer who,
while applying for a job,
gives some revealing and dramatic
information about the leading character.
After his success in The Invisible Man,
Rains did two more pictures for Universal:
The Man Who Reclaimed his Head,
which he had done earlier on the stage,
and The Mystery of Edwin Drood, based
on Charles Dickens's unfinished novel.
And Whale thought of him for the role
of Dr Pretorius in Bride of Frankenstein,
but we know
that Ernest Thesiger played that part.
In 1936 he signed with Warner Brothers.
It was unusual in that he was paid
only when actually working on a picture.
When Rains finished shooting,
he would head immediately
for his beloved farm in Pennsylvania.
Also, his deal was non-exclusive.
He played the villainous Prince John
in 1938's The Adventures of Robin Hood,
photographed in Technicolor.
He was nominated for
an Academy Award for his performance
as the suave but corrupt senator in Frank
Capra's Mr Smith Goes to Washington.
Then he returned to Universal
to be top billed in The Wolf Man.
No, he wasn't the wolf man, but his father.
Rains played the title role in Universal's
opulent 1943 Technicolor remake
of The Phantom of the Opera.
There followed Now, Voyager,
Casablanca, for which he won his second
best supporting actor nomination,
and Mr Skeffington,
yet another Oscar nomination.
Rains gave one of his finest performances
in Alfred Hitchcock's Notorious,
for which he was
Academy-nominated for the fourth time.
The eminent George Bernard Shaw
personally chose him
to star opposite Vivien Leigh
in the British production of Shaw's
Caesar and Cleopatra, released in 1946.
He also did another HG Wells story,
The Passionate Friends,
released in America as
One Woman's Story in 1949.
It was directed by David Lean.
John Fulton described how the footprints
in the snow coming up were done.
"We dug a trench along the line
where we wanted the footprints,
and covered the trench with a board
in which the footprints had been cut."
"The footprint openings
were filled with wooden outlines,
which had been cut
to make the footprints."
"These were supported by pegs
extended to the bottom of the trench,
and a rope was looped around the pegs
so that pulling upon it
would pull out the pegs,
causing the snow to drop down through
the holes, giving us perfect footprints."
Those footprints look like
shoe prints to me,
but if he had shoes on, the shoes,
of course, would be visible.
What do you think? Dramatic licence?
The doctor here
is British actor Jameson Thomas.
Film buffs may recall his role
as Claudette Colbert's fiancé,
until she ran off with Clark Gable,
in It Happened One Night.
During the late 1950s and early 1960s,
Claude Rains appeared
in many prestige TV productions,
including several Alfred Hitchcock shows.
He had a role in the epic big-screen
Lawrence of Arabia in 1962,
and his final film was
The Greatest Story Ever Told in 1965.
Rains died in 1967 at the age of 77.
In all, Universal made seven films
in which an invisible man
or woman appeared.
Invisibility-effects highlights
from the group
appear as part of the video documentary
included on this special-edition DVD.
Check your menu.
Once again, John Fulton describes
how he accomplished
the gradual revealment
of Jack Griffin in peace in death.
"This was done directly in the camera."
"The pillow, the indentation and all,
was made of plaster,
and the blankets
and sheets of papier-mâché."
"A long, slow lap dissolve revealed
the skeleton" - a real one, by the way.
"Another lap dissolve replaced the
skeleton with a roughly-sculpted dummy,
which suggested
the contours of the actor."
"A further series of dissolves, each time
using a slightly more finished dummy,
brought us to the real actor himself."
Audiences finally get to see
what Claude Rains looks like.
In marketing, Universal decided to
emphasise the novelty aspect of the film,
rather than sell it as a horror film.
The studio also stressed what was
called at the time "feminine interest".
My favourite catch line is
"Though he was invisible, she loved him."
The Invisible Man was a big success,
critically and commercially,
and a major factor in putting Universal
in the black for the first time in two years.
Remember, this was the worst of times
for the Great Depression.
This is Rudy Behlmer speaking.