[CROWD CHATTERlNG]
What am I working on?
I'm working on something
that'll change the world...
...and human life as we know it.
Change it a lot or just a bit?
You'll have to be more specific.
You want me to be specific
here in this room...
...with half the scientific community
of North America eavesdropping?
Is there another way?
You could come back to my lab.
Listen, l'll make cappuccino.
I have a Faema of my own.
Know what that is?
It's not the dilettante's
plastic kitchen model.
It's a real restaurant espresso machine
with an eagle on top.
Somehow l get the feeling
you don't get out much.
-You can tell that?
-Yeah.
You're making a mistake.
I think you really wanna talk to me.
Sorry. l have three other interviews
before this party's over.
But they're not working on something
that'll change the world.
They say they are.
Yeah, but they're lying.
I'm not.
Are you sick?
No-- Sure.
You're not a very accomplished drunk.
No, I'm always like this. lt's the...
...motion sickness. When I was a kid,
I puked on my tricycle.
I hate vehicles.
Should I drive more slowly?
No, no, no. Just turn left.
We're almost there.
This is it?
It's cleaner on the inside.
Please.
Listen. Maybe this is a bad idea.
It's too late.
You've already seen them.
Can't let you leave here alive.
I haven't seen anything.
Those.
Designer phone booths.
Very cute.
Hey, I bet you have a really neat
jukebox in here too someplace, huh?
Over there maybe?
No.
No. This is the...
...prototype of those.
It's the first one I had made.
It works, but it's clunky.
I call them telepods.
They're controlled by this.
Thank God for that.
So, what do they do,
the phone booths?
Telepods.
Okay, l need an object.
Say, do you have something on you
that is...
...personal that l could use?
Something uniquely you?
An item of clothing or jewelry?
What, are you kidding?
No, I'm serious.
Okay. Here it goes.
Mm-hm.
-l don't wear jewelry.
-Mm-hm.
It's nice.
Brundle, Seth.
BRUNDLE'S VOICE [ON COMPUTER]:
[BRUNDLE WHISPERS]
Keep your eye on the stocking.
Well?
Great.
The world's largest microwave oven.
I'm glad I didn't give you my Rolex.
If l had a Rolex.
No, you're missing the point. Look.
Teleportation?
Please.
Oh....
Wait a minute.
Is that a hologram?
-Where's my stocking?
-That's it, the real one.
Go ahead, pick it up.
I don't think l get it.
What happened?
You get it all right,
you just can't handle it.
Your stocking has just
been teleported...
...from one pod to another.
Disintegrated there
and reintegrated there.
Sort of.
It'll change the world
as we know it, right?
Oh. Oh.
This is-- This is incredible.
I mean, it's not possible, is it?
How have you managed
to keep this quiet?
Please sit down.
How could you do this alone?
Well, l don't work alone.
There's stuff in there I don't
understand. l'm really...
...a systems manager. l farm...
...bits and pieces out to guys
who are more brilliant than l. I say:
"Build me a laser, design me
a molecular analyzer" and they do.
I just stick them together.
But none of them knows
what the project really is. So....
Wow. And the money?
Bartok Science lndustries financed this?
Mm-hm. But they leave me alone
because l'm not expensive.
And they know they'll end up
owning it all, whatever it is.
-You haven't told them?
-When l'm ready.
[TAPE RECORDER BEEPS]
Wait a second.
What's that?
-You want me to get the quotes right.
-Quotes? No, no.
I thought this was personal.
You can't write about it.
What are you talking about?
I'm a journalist.
-Oh, no, no, no.
-You knew that.
I'm sorry, I made a mistake. I shouldn't
have shown you this. l'm very sorry.
Listen. Particle Magazine sent me
to that party to get a story.
And this is the most exciting thing
I've ever seen.
No. Absolutely not.
I'm gonna have to ask for that tape.
-Please.
-You can't do that.
Don't you dare write a story.
I'd never have told
this stuff to a journalist.
-But you did tell it to a journalist.
-ln a way, l suppose l did but--
-Sure did.
-Now wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait. Come here.
What about your stocking?
Keep it for good luck.
BRUNDLE [ON TAPE]:
l farm bits and pieces out to guys...
...who are more brilliant than I. I say:
"Build me a laser, design me
a molecular analyzer" and they do.
l just stick them together.
But none of them knows
what the project really is. So....
VERONlCA: Wow. And the money?
Bartok Science lndustries financed this?
BRUNDLE: But they leave me alone
because l'm not expensive.
And they know they'll end up
owning it all, whatever it is.
Well, that's it.
What do you think?
It's a joke.
-What?
-He's conning you.
It's an old nightclub routine.
The two cabinets.
[PHONE RlNGING]
-And you fell for it.
-Wait a minute.
-That was no night--
-Are we having lunch?
Listen. That was no nightclub routine.
I was there. l saw it.
Yup?
Sure.
Send him in.
You must have made an impression.
What do you mean?
Your magician has followed you here.
[KNOCKlNG]
I'm Stathis Borans.
I'm the editor of Particle Magazine.
-Seth Brundle.
-l know who you are.
Listen, why don't you two use
my office? I've gotta run.
If you plan to make anything
disappear, please let me know.
I've got an assistant editor
who's outlived his usefulness.
You didn't waste any time.
I'm not getting any younger.
He wasn't impressed by your tape?
He thinks you're a con man.
-Excellent.
-Yeah?
Well, let's see what the people
at Omni think about it.
No, no. Listen, Veronica....
I've come here
to say one magic word to you.
Yeah?
Cheeseburger.
I've been working alone too long.
I have a strong urge
to talk about what l'm doing.
But if this gets out now...
...Veronica, it'll kill me.
The Bartok people
and my colleagues will kill me.
It's not ready yet.
It seems to work okay.
No, something important's missing.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Which is?
I can only teleport inanimate objects.
What happens when you
try to teleport living things?
Not while we're eating.
Can't be worse than this.
Listen, you're not doing a very good job
of convincing me.
I think the world should know about it now.
I think I should be the one to tell it.
You should tell it...
...but not yet.
Look, what do you got so far?
Enough to make you nervous.
Why not get more?
Let me become your major project.
I'm talking about a book,
not a magazine article.
Follow me and my work day by day
in as much detail as you can stand.
I don't have a life, so there's
nothing for you to interfere with.
Research the background.
Cover the process.
"The complete record of the most
earth-shattering invention ever.
The one that ended
all concepts of transport...
...of borders and frontiers,
of time and space."
And the book'll end with me...
...transporting myself 1 5 feet through
space from one telepod to another.
That's what's really missing.
Wait for me that long?
[SHOWER RUNNING]
What are you doing in my apartment?
Just happened to be in the neighborhood.
Felt a bit scummy.
Rough day.
[FLUSHES TOlLET]
[STATHlS YELLS]
How did you get in?
I have a key, remember?
You gave it to me.
I knew l should've changed the lock.
I knew you wouldn't.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
That's because unconsciously...
...you still want me to come back,
move in again.
No.
That's because, very consciously,
I'm lazy and disorganized.
Your new playmate's an interesting guy.
What playmate?
The nightclub act.
Brundle.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Yeah, l was wrong.
He's really quite brilliant.
He was the leader of the F32 team.
Remember that?
An inch away from the
Nobel Prize for physics.
He was only 20 at the time.
I don't even think l'll do Brundle. l'm
still considering the Psychology Today gig.
That's not like you.
Are you getting out or am l?
I'll go. I have to put this issue to bed.
Want me to come back and tuck you in?
No. Key.
I'll keep it...
...for old time's sake.
You're a petty schmuck.
Initiate in five seconds.
[SQUEALING]
I've gotta do this, Seth.
Talk to the tape. Get in the habit.
The world will wanna know
what you're thinking.
"Fuck" is what I'm thinking!
Good.
The world will wanna know that.
What else? Why didn't it work?
I think it turned the baboon
inside out.
Why?
Can't deal with the flesh.
It only works with inanimate objects...
...nothing that's living.
It must be my fault.
Why?
Computers are dumb.
They only know what you tell them.
I must not know enough about
the flesh myself. I'm gonna have to learn.
I don't wanna talk now.
Do you ever change your clothes?
What?
The clothes. You're always
wearing the same clothes.
No, these are clean.
I change my clothes every day.
Five sets of exactly the same clothes?
Learned it from Einstein.
This way l don't have to...
...expend any thought on what l'll wear.
I just grab the next set on the rack.
I bought some steaks.
Can l make you one?
We could go out.
Cheeseburger?
No, we don't have to go there.
You're very cute. You know that?
Am l?
[KISSlNG]
Oh, ow!
-What happened?
-On my back. Ow.
Oh. Oh, God.
Something's stuck to your back.
Well, pull it off.
VERONlCA: Oh, ew.
BRUNDLE: Ow.
Ow.
Sorry.
Oh, huh.
I wondered what happened to this.
-Do you have any disinfectant?
-No, it's okay.
I'm gonna kiss it for you.
Thank you.
Ow, ow, ow.
Sorry. l just wanna eat you up.
You know, that's why old ladies
pinch babies' cheeks.
It's the flesh. lt just makes you crazy.
Ronnie. Ronnie.
You wanna try an experiment?
Sure.
BRUNDLE:
Okay.
Eat this.
I need an objective opinion.
-Yes?
-Well....
It could use some finesse,
but it tastes like a steak.
BRUNDLE:
Okay....
Now try this teleported half.
-A monkey just came apart in there.
-Baboon. Eat.
-Oh--
-What?
That tastes funny.
-Funny how?
-lt tastes...
...synthetic.
Mm-hm.
So, what have we proved?
The computer is giving us
its interpretation...
...of a steak. It's translating it for us,
it's rethinking it...
...rather than reproducing it.
And something's getting lost
in the translation.
Me. l'm lost.
The flesh.
It should make the computer crazy.
Like those old ladies pinching babies.
But it doesn't, not yet.
I haven't taught the computer
to be made crazy by the flesh.
The poetry of the steak.
So l'm gonna start teaching it now.
I should've known it.
What are you doing here?
I followed you.
Psychology Today, my ass.
You stayed with Brundle all night.
Why didn't l believe you, l wonder.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, l think he'd look great in this.
Don't you?
For your TIME magazine cover,
you've gotta look good, right?
Don't you get it? l am finally
onto something that's big.
-Huge.
-Yeah? What? His cock?
Crude, Stathis. Very crude.
You're too perfect to believe.
You're a goddess.
Thank you for making my
most paranoid fantasies come true.
I don't have to report to you,
you creep!
Ronnie? You've got to talk to me.
I don't have to.
We're finished, remember?
I'll spend the night
anywhere l damn well please.
Sorry. l'll take this too.
[BABOON CHATTERlNG]
I think it's time for champagne.
VERONlCA:
Oh, God, Seth.
It's really happened. You did it.
-You'll never have to get carsick again.
-Or airsick or seasick.
I know. Or tricycle-sick.
What's next?
We'll send the baboon out for tests,
see if he's really okay.
How long will that take?
Could be weeks.
Really?
Yeah, why?
Well, l was thinking that
we could take a holiday.
We could?
Yeah. You know,
like an old married couple.
The old man's got
a couple weeks off, so...
...they go to Florida, someplace warm.
Just you and me?
Yeah. ls there someone else
you're thinking of bringing along?
No, no, I just....
Is this a romance we're having?
Is that what it is?
Yeah. Could be a romance.
Come here.
I have a great idea.
You like Chinese food?
Yes.
We're gonna have
a romantic dinner right here.
Hey, what's this?
From your editor.
Somebody slipped it under the door.
Hello, Victor?
Yeah, it's Seth Brundle.
-Yeah, I'll wait.
-Oh, no.
BRUNDLE:
What? What's that?
[VERONlCA SIGHS]
Nothing. It's just personal bullshit.
Old married couples
share their personal bullshit.
That's how they
stay old and married.
-Listen, Seth, don't rush it.
-What are you talking about?
-Look, I have to go out for a few hours.
-Now?
No, Ronnie, spicy eggplant, champagne.
Just for a few hours.
I still have the residue of another life.
I have to scrape it off my shoe
and get rid of it once and for all.
Hi.
[DOOR CLOSES]
VERONlCA:
What's this supposed to mean?
It means that l'm your editor and
I'm shaping your material into a story.
You told me there was no story.
You said Brundle was a con man.
I've decided to trust
your journalistic instincts.
Thanks very much.
But this is not your story.
It's mine.
Says who?
I sent you to the Bartok party
to see what you could find.
Your discovery is my discovery.
I have a lot of background on Brundle.
He's been working on this for six years.
There's material to find
if you dig deep.
-l dug.
-Stathis....
Everything that has to do with
transportation will become obsolete.
And l am right there in the middle of it.
-The only inside recorder of the event.
-Okay.
Okay.
Look, just keep me informed.
All right?
As a friend?
As a professional confidante?
That's all?
I don't want you
to disappear from my life.
Okay.
What about sex?
I'm not saying love or affection.
Just stress-relieving sex.
You and me.
You're disgusting.
As always.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Wouldn't wanna disappoint you.
Residue means her old boyfriend,
doesn't it?
Stathis Borans is her old boyfriend.
"From the desk of Stathis Borans."
How about, "Under the desk
of Stathis Borans"?
She's working for her old boyfriend.
Now she runs out late at night to see him.
What is this, the Ronnie game?
I'm catching on. l'm catching on.
I didn't mean to kill your brother,
but he didn't die in vain...
...if that's of any comfort.
As the general said, l wouldn't ask you
to do anything that I wouldn't do myself.
[FLY BUZZING]
Hey, you're all right.
I'm looking at you.
I can tell you're okay.
What are we waiting for? Let's do it.
[CHATTERS]
[FLY BUZZING]
How you doing?
Now, you tell me.
Am l different somehow?
"Is it live or is it Memorex?"
It's too bad Ronnie missed it.
I missed you last night.
It's still night. I came back.
You had to celebrate without me.
I'm sorry.
I went through last night.
You went through?
Without testing the baboon?
I was drunk. I was a bit upset.
You could've killed yourself.
Are you sleeping with Stathis Borans?
What are you talking about?
I don't know.
I just get that feeling.
That's why you were upset?
I got jealous.
Oh, God. Seth, you don't
have to be jealous.
He's an old boyfriend.
He was teaching at college.
I was a science major.
He got me started in journalism.
Is he still in love with you?
How could he not be?
Hey. Oh, what about our deal?
You went through and I wasn't there.
Don't worry, l taped it for you.
You did?
[FLY BUZZING]
[BUZZlNG STOPS]
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
BRUNDLE: So I asked the computer if it had
improved me, and it didn't understand.
That's made me think about what
I've been feeling and why. l'm thinking...
...that the sheer process of being taken
apart atom by atom and reassembled--
It's like filtering coffee. It's a purifying
process. lt's purified and cleansed me.
I'll tell you, I think
it's gonna allow me to realize...
...the personal potential l've been
neglecting all these years...
...that l've been obsessively pursuing
goal after goal.
-Do you take coffee with your sugar?
-What?
You know, I just don't think
I've ever given me a chance to be me.
But, of course interestingly,
when l achieved...
...what will probably prove
to be my life's work...
...that's when l started
being the real me, finally.
So, listen...
...not to wax Messianic...
...but the synchronicity of those two
events may blur the individual effect.
But it is, nevertheless, also certainly true.
I will say now, however subjectively,
human teleportation...
...molecular breakdown and reformation
is inherently purging.
It makes a man a king. Since l walked out
of the pod, I felt like a million bucks.
I think I am gonna have a cannoli
after all. Waiter!
I mean, what an accomplishment.
But what have I really done?
All I've done is say to the world:
"Let's go. Move.
Catch me if you can." Waiter.
Jesus Christ!
[MOANlNG]
VERONlCA:
Oh, God. Wait.
Oh, God.
BRUNDLE:
What?
VERONlCA:
How can you keep going?
You can't have any fluid left
in your body.
We've been doing this for hours.
I'm not ready to quit yet. Come on.
Come on.
Hey. What's this?
BRUNDLE:
It's an attempt to distract me.
No, really, what is it? lt's like...
-...hairs or something.
-l don't know, it's....
It happens when you get older,
weird hair.
They're really coarse.
I've never really been hairy enough.
Know what l mean? Always too boyish.
I'm looking forward to a hairy body.
It's one of the compensations
of old age. Where are you going?
Hey, hey, hey!
Not my new hairs. What are you doing?
Relax, Brundle.
I don't really think you want
a body covered with these.
God! They're really tough!
Listen.
I want you to go through.
I wanna teleport you right now.
You'll feel incredible. l hardly
need to sleep and l feel wonderful.
It's like a drug
but a pure, benign drug.
The power l feel surging inside me--!
We'll be the perfect couple.
The dynamic duo. Come on.
-Right now.
-Hey, wait.
Don't give me that born-again
teleportation rap. l'm scared to do it.
What do I have to say?
I'm not gonna do it!
You're a fucking drag, you know?
Something went wrong. When you
went through, something went wrong.
No? Not you?
If you're too chickenshit to be
in the dynamic duo club...
...l'll find somebody else
who can keep up with me.
Seth, listen to me--
You're afraid to dive
in the plasma pool, aren't you?
You're afraid to be destroyed
and re-created.
Think you woke me up about the flesh?
You only know society's
straight line about the flesh.
You can't penetrate society's
sick gray fear of the flesh.
Drink deep, or taste not the plasma
spring. See what l'm saying?
This is not just sex and penetration,
but penetration...
...beyond the veil of the flesh.
A deep, penetrating dive
into the plasma pool.
I'll have a Scotch.
Who's winning?
I don't know.
I hope it's Marky.
-How come?
-Because.
I like Marky tonight.
Well, l like you tonight.
Maybe I'd better get involved.
Hey, pal, you're disturbing us.
$1 00 says l can beat either of you.
-Take a hike, asshole.
-Here.
Here's my hundred.
I get to take the lady home
for the night if I win.
Says who?
Do I look like a hooker?
Tawny, it's an easy hundred.
Come on, let's get it over with.
-Watch out. He eats chocolate bars.
-Yeah, so l noticed.
[SCREAMlNG]
TAWNY:
Are you a bodybuilder?
BRUNDLE: Yeah, l build bodies. I take
them apart and put them back together.
TAWNY:
Well, you sure took Marky apart.
-Let's go back to my place.
-Your place?
Yeah, well, okay.
I live with my mother anyway.
But could we go to
maybe a few more bars first?
-lt's a little too early to quit.
-Sure, a few more bars.
Great place.
Hey!
There's no elevator.
-l can't make it.
-There's an elevator.
There, don't you feel elevated?
TAWNY:
Whoa.
Wow.
Are you some sort of magician?
Yes.
So are we going to breakfast or not?
It's your turn.
-To do what?
-l want you to go through.
No. I don't wanna try that.
Why not? It'll make you feel sexy.
But l already feel sexy.
How about...
...a nice...
-...alcohol rub?
-Don't do that! lt hurts.
Sorry, hon.
I didn't know you had
the skin of a princess.
-You're real sensitive, huh?
-Okay!
That's it. You're going to like it.
-l don't want to. I'm afraid.
-Don't be afraid.
VERONlCA:
No.
Be afraid. Be very afraid.
Who's this?
I forgot to tell you.
I live with my mother too.
Mom, meet Tawny.
I gotta go.
Thanks for a wonderful time.
Why'd you scare her off? Jealous?
You're changing, Seth.
Everything about you is changing.
You look bad.
You smell bad.
I've never been much of a bather.
Those weird hairs that grew out
of your back, l took them to a lab.
I had them analyzed.
The hairs?
Oh, yeah.
That's a strange thing to do.
Not as strange as the results.
The guy at the lab
had trouble identifying them.
He finally concluded that they
were definitely not human.
Oh.
-Very good.
-Not human, Seth.
In fact, very likely insect hairs.
That's silly. That's ridiculous.
Look.
Now there's more. Look at your face.
Something happened
when you went through.
You've got to get some help.
I think you must be sick.
You're jealous!
I've become free. I've been released,
and you can't stand it.
You'll do anything to bring me down.
Does this look like a sick man to you?
No, stop it!
Know any sick men who do that?
Come here.
The deal is off.
I don't need you anymore.
No, wait.
Seth, please, wait. Seth!
Don't come back.
Oh, God.
[CRYING]
Oh, no.
What's happening to me? Am I dying?
Is this how it starts? Am l dying?
Brundle, Seth.
Give me a disc.
I need the first
teleportation: S. Brundle.
Run sequence.
[PHONE RlNGS]
Hello.
[HEAVY BREATHlNG]
Seth.
Seth, I've been trying to reach you.
Where are you?
BRUNDLE: For the last four weeks,
l've been afraid to see you.
Now I'm afraid not to.
Where are you?
Are you at home?
You don't know how right you were.
l've gotten...
...much, much worse.
Please come see me.
Please come now.
Seth?
I'm here.
BRUNDLE:
Stop!
Seth.
You were right.
I'm diseased...
...and it might be contagious somehow.
I wouldn't want to infect you.
And it's been accelerating.
It's unrelenting.
Every day there are changes.
Every time l look in the mirror,
I'm someone different, someone repulsive.
What happened?
[SINGlNG]
Seth, please.
I was not pure. The teleporter
insists on purity. I was not pure.
I don't know what you mean.
A fly...
...got into the transmitter pod with me
that first time when l was alone.
The computer got confused.
There weren't supposed
to be two separate genetic patterns.
And it decided to splice us together.
It mated us, me and the fly.
We hadn't even been properly introduced.
My teleporter turned
into a gene splicer.
A very good one.
Now I'm not Seth Brundle anymore.
I'm the offspring
of Brundle and a housefly.
Oh, God. Oh, God, Seth!
You look so pretty.
What will happen?
I think it's showing itself
as a bizarre form of cancer.
General cellular chaos and revolution.
I'm just gonna disintegrate.
In a novel way, no doubt.
Then l'll die.
-And then it will be over.
-No, no, no. I don't accept that.
There must be something we can do,
someone to go to, tests that can be done.
No! I won't be
just another tumorous bore...
...talking endlessly about his hair
falling out and his lost lymph nodes.
What do you want me to do?
Why did you call me?
Oh....
That's disgusting.
My...
...ear. No!
I'm scared.
Help me.
Please. Please, help me.
-Don't go back to him.
-That's it?
That's your advice?
He's right. It could be contagious.
It could turn into an epidemic.
I have to go back to him.
-l don't believe this.
-lf you saw him, Stathis....
If you saw how scared and angry
and desperate he is--
I'm sure Typhoid Mary was nice too
when you saw her socially.
-l do not want--
-l don't care what you want.
All right, fine, okay.
Do I have permission to claim
your body when this is over?
Oh, God.
Look, how about this?
You say, if only l saw him.
Show me.
Tape him. Show me.
Let me think about it.
I'll come up with something.
Seth?
-Seth?
BRUNDLE: No, no, no. Up here.
Oh!
I've gotten pretty good at it, haven't l?
Yeah, it's almost second nature.
I stopped biting my nails.
Look at this. What's this?
I don't know.
I seem to be stricken by a disease
with a purpose, wouldn't you say?
Maybe not such a bad disease
after all.
I can't stay.
No, no, no.
Why not? Why can't you?
I can't take it. It's too much.
What's there to take?
The disease has revealed its purpose.
We don't have to worry about contagion.
I know what the disease wants.
What does the disease want?
It wants to turn me into something else.
That's not terrible. Most people would
give anything to be something else.
Turned into what?
What do you think, a fly?
Am l becoming a 1 85-pound fly?
No, I'm becoming something
that never existed before.
I'm becoming "Brundlefly."
Don't you think
that's worth a Nobel Prize?
Here.
I want to give a demonstration...
...that l think you'll want
to record for posterity.
I think you must chronicle...
...the life and times of Brundlefly,
don't you?
At the very least, it should make
a fabulous children's book.
You seem tired.
You got me there?
How does Brundlefly eat?
He found out the hard way that
he eats very much the way a fly eats.
His teeth are now useless.
Because although he can chew up
solid food, he can't digest it.
Solid food hurts. So, like a fly...
...Brundlefly breaks down solids
with a corrosive enzyme...
...playfully called "vomit drop."
He regurgitates on his food.
lt liquefies.
And then he sucks it back up.
Ready for a demonstration, kids?
Here it goes.
[BRUNDLE REGURGlTATES]
Oh, my God.
My God!
[DOOR OPENS]
Hey, Ronnie.
Ronnie!
What is it?
I'm pregnant.
Oh, no.
I'm pregnant with Seth's baby.
What do you wanna do?
I don't know.
I just....
-Stathis, I'm scared.
-lt's going to be all right, Ronnie.
It's going to be fine.
I don't think l want to lose it.
Is there something wrong?
Why am l losing it?
It's better this way, Ronnie.
You'll see.
It's the best thing that could happen.
GYNECOLOGlST:
Okay, she's expelling it.
It's coming out.
I don't think we'll have to go in.
NURSE: lt's gonna be easy.
Don't worry, honey.
No. Please, no.
GYNECOLOGlST:
It'll be over soon. Here we go. Okay.
A little suction here.
A little suction.
Suction.
Hold it. Hold on a minute.
There's more in there.
VERONlCA:
There's more?
GYNECOLOGlST:
Yeah, l mean a lot more. Okay.
You're gonna have to help us.
Come on. Push.
Push it out. Come on, push.
-That's it. Come on, push.
-No, wait.
GYNECOLOGlST: Give us a push.
You can push it out. Come on. That's it.
-No, wait, wait. No.
-You can do it.
Wait.
No!
[VERONlCA SCREAMING]
I want a disc.
Give me preliminary integration.
BRUNDLE'S VOICE [ON COMPUTER]: I want
a disc. Give me preliminary integration.
You're relics. Yes, you are.
You can't deny it.
Vestigial, archaeological, redundant.
Artifacts of a bygone era.
Of historical interest only.
You've missed some good moments.
Is that why you're here? To catch up?
I wanted....
My teeth have begun to fall out.
The medicine cabinet's now
the Brundle Museum of Natural History.
-Want to see what else is in it?
-No.
Then...
...what do you want?
I came to tell you....
I just....
I wanted to see you...
...before....
You have to leave now...
...and never come back here.
Have you ever heard of insect politics?
Neither have l.
Insects don't have politics.
They're very brutal.
No compassion.
No compromise.
We can't trust the insect.
I'd like to become...
...the first insect politician.
I'd like to...
...but l'm afraid....
I don't know
what you're trying to say.
I'm saying....
I'm saying l'm an insect...
...who dreamt he was a man
and loved it.
But now the dream is over...
...and the insect is awake.
No, Seth.
I'm saying...
...l'll hurt you if you stay.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[GROANING]
Let's go. Let's do it now.
Now? Wait.
Wait a minute. What did he say?
I couldn't tell him. Let's go, damn it.
No! I think we should
wait a few days.
-You're not in the right state of mind.
-No, now.
I want it out of my body now.
You should have seen him.
There could be anything in here,
in me, in my body.
I don't know if l can
arrange it right now, tonight.
Why do we have to--?
I don't want it in my body. Understand?
I don't want it in my body!
Well, okay, what's the story?
She's pregnant and
she wants to have an abortion.
In the middle of the night?
We have good reason to think that...
...this child will be deformed.
-Yeah, but in the middle of the night?
-Look, Brent.
Please.
Is it your child?
No. It's the--
It's the child of a man
who is deformed.
CHEEVERS:
I don't mean to interfere...
...but l detect a certain
uncertainty here.
There are tests we can do
to determine whether--
I don't want tests.
Tests can't guarantee anything.
The baby could start off normal,
then become....
I want an abortion.
I'll do it myself if l have to.
Okay. lf you'll just slip into that,
we'll be on our way in no time.
No. No.
Wait, Seth, no.
Why did you wanna kill Brundle?
The baby might be all that's left
of the real me.
Please don't kill me.
I can't have it. l'm afraid.
Please, have the baby.
I can't.
Too bad.
[SCREECHES]
Jeez!
[SCREAMlNG]
VERONlCA:
No, don't. Don't, please.
Please.
Help me.
Help me be human.
How?
Well....
I go there...
...and you go there.
We come apart...
...and then we come together there.
You, me and the baby.
Together.
No.
We'll be the ultimate family.
A family of three,
joined together in one body.
More human than l am alone.
No!
[CHOKING]
VERONlCA:
Oh, please. Oh, God. Please!
No!
Oh, God, please don't!
No! No. No.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
VERONlCA:
Let me out. Oh, God.
[VERONlCA GASPlNG]
[SCREAMS]
No. No, l can't.
I can't. No.
[GROANING]