Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
(panting)
Oh, God, help me! Somebody help! Help me!
(gasps)
(woman speaking Japanese on PA)
(chattering in Japanese)
WOMAN (on PA): Attention, please.
Japan Airlines Flight
3400 from Honolulu...
- (woman on PA continues)
- (line ringing)
WOMAN (on phone): Konnichiwa.
It's Jess. Leave a message.
- (beeps)
- FEMALE VOICE: The mailbox is full
and cannot accept any
messages at this time.
Good-bye.
(beeping)
WOMAN: Hello?
MAN (on phone): Is this Sara Price?
I am with the Yamanashi Police.
The school where
your sister teaches,
they've filed a missing
persons report with us.
Look, Jess has done this
before. I'm sure she's okay.
The last time I talked
to her she sounded... off.
Hey. You know Jess.
Everything's great. Then it's terrible.
No, it wasn't just a bad mood.
Okay, look, let's forget about dinner.
- I'll take them to a restaurant.
- No.
It's your boss. We're going to
impress her. I'll be fine. I promise.
(all laughing)
WOMAN: Sara, it is nice
to finally meet you.
Baby, are you okay?
- (beeping)
- (line clicks)
SARA: I don't understand.
If you know she went there, why
aren't you already looking for her?
JAPANESE POLICE OFFICER: Your sister
was last seen in Aokigahara Forest.
I'm sorry to say this, but it is a
place where some people commit suicide.
What?
She was seen leaving the path
to go into the forest alone.
When we see this,
it means the person does
not want to be found.
JAPANESE POLICE OFFICER:
Miss? Are you there?
I'm here.
After 48 hours
we have to assume a person has gone
through with their suicide plan.
No, she's alive.
What's going on?
I'm going to Japan. The
police think Jess is dead.
MAN: What?
Apparently, they have a forest in
Japan where people go to kill themselves
and Jess went into it.
Sounds like exactly the kind of place
your sister would go hiking for fun.
Rob, she's my twin,
she's in trouble and she needs me.
She always needs you.
She makes a bad decision
and you clean up her mess.
SARA: I don't know, Rob. It
feels different this time.
ROB: It's your call.
Why don't you just sleep on it, okay?
If she doesn't call you
by morning, reassess.
If you still want to go, you can go. Okay?
- Okay.
- Okay. All right.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
It's gonna be all right.
Everything's gonna be fine.
(laughing)
(sighs)
- ♪♪ (speakers: upbeat pop)
- (people chattering, laughing)
- ♪♪ (fades)
- (chattering continues)
(speaks Japanese)
- You wouldn't happen to have a dead one, would you?
- (Japanese)
- Okay.
- (women laughing, chattering in Japanese)
SARA: ♪ Happy birthday to us ♪
Stop... Stop messing around. Smile.
♪ Happy birthday to us ♪
(blows)
CHILD'S VOICE (faint,
singsongy): Sara.
- (latch clicks)
- (hinge creaking)
CHILD'S VOICE (faint,
singsongy): Sara.
(gasps)
(shrieks)
(alarm beeping)
- WOMAN: On a longboat.
- STUDENTS: I went on a longboat.
WOMAN: I am going on a longboat.
STUDENTS: I am going on a longboat.
WOMAN: I will go on a longboat.
STUDENTS: I will go on a longboat.
WOMAN: He went to London.
STUDENTS: He went to London.
He is going to London.
- (all gasping)
- (screaming)
(speaks Japanese)
(speaking Japanese)
She thought you were Miss Jess.
- She's ashamed.
- We're twins.
I am... sorry.
It's okay.
But why were you scared?
(translating into Japanese)
(Japanese)
She knows your sister went into Aokigahara.
She thought you were a
yurei. A ghost.
Aokigahara. Th-The suicide forest?
In old times it was a
place for ubasute.
When there was not enough food,
families would bring elderly women,
the blind or sick to the forest
and leave them to die.
That's awful. I don't understand.
Why would the school
take a class trip there?
Mount Fuji is very beautiful
and important to history.
Aokigahara is simply part of the mountain.
(speaking Japanese)
People say spirits cannot rest there.
They come back.
(Japanese)
Angry.
They come back angry.
- (Japanese)
- Hai.
Hai.
Can I see Jess's room before I go?
Normally I would respect privacy,
but because you're family...
Thank you.
(door opens)
Jess, do you have the packing tape?
- Hey. Those could be worth something.
- They're from the Stone Age.
Didn't Grandma say they
were collectors items?
She also said Rob was gay 'cause
he parted his hair to the right.
Point taken.
Be careful with that jar.
- Why? She keep her stash in it?
- She kept Grandpa in it.
(both laughing)
SARA: You're terrible.
JESS: So, when was the
last time you saw Grandma?
Six months ago.
I feel bad.
We just abandoned her, went
off to do our own thing.
She understood. We
needed to start our lives.
I'm about to start mine all over again.
I'm sure it'll be great,
Jess. I'm proud of you.
Tokyo isn't exactly the next town over.
It'll be good for you.
Plus, it'll give me an excuse to
get on a plane every once in a while.
You'd better.
(man on PA speaking Japanese)
(station bell clanging)
- Konnichiwa.
- Hi.
I'm, uh...
I'm looking for my sister.
She came here on a trip with
her school and disappeared.
- Have you seen her?
- Yes. We find.
You... You found Jess?
Oh, my... Wh-Where is she?
She here. I take you.
Sakura. (Japanese)
- (chattering in Japanese)
- I...
What is this?
Basement.
You come?
Keep the bodies here when we find.
- Keep them cold.
- The bodies?
Someone stay with them at all time.
If bodies alone, the
spirit scream all night.
(lock clanking)
(woman speaking Japanese, muffled)
Sorry. Two second.
You wait.
♪♪ (headphones: pop)
(conversation in Japanese, muffled, faint)
(inhales)
(speaking Japanese)
- It's not her.
- No?
- Good. Good news.
Is there someone who could
help me search the forest?
The forest is very dangerous.
Do not leave the path.
- Can get lost.
- I understand.
- What if I want to hire a guide?
- No guide. Come back.
- Maybe more bodies.
- No.
She's lost. She's not dead.
Do not leave the path.
Shit.
Hey. It's mountain.
Lots of metal. Cell
phone do not work up here.
Do you know the forest?
Could you take me in? I'd pay you.
The forest has yurei.
Everybody know that.
Yurei.
You mean ghosts?
Different from ghost.
The forest use them to trick you.
Do you know why "do not leave the path"?
Because if you get lost
and you have sadness in your heart,
they will use it against you.
Yurei come find you
and make you see things
and make you want to die.
And you do it yourself.
Okay.
Thanks for that.
If the yurei are looking
for me, I'll be at my hotel.
(rustling)
(girls giggling)
(people chattering)
- (chattering continues)
- ♪♪ (speakers: dance pop)
- (Japanese)
- Thanks.
You look familiar. Have we met?
Here? Four days ago?
Uh, hey, sorry.
I don't know you. I was
just a line to start a chat.
"Have you ever been to Greece? Did you go
to Camp Minnehaha in the Rocky Mountains?"
- That kind of thing.
- Right.
I thought you might
have met my sister, Jess.
She came here... and disappeared.
Do you know about the forest?
Yeah.
Is that a possibility with your sister?
We're identical twins. If she
were dead, I would just know.
What do you think she's up
to then, if she's out there?
I think she's struggling with her demons.
Yeah, it happens.
Some people go in. They do sort
of a walkabout, think it over.
Sometimes they come back out again.
I'm Aiden, by the way.
Oh. Sara.
Sara. Pleasure to meet you.
You too.
That's her, a couple of years ago.
- Same, right?
- Identical.
Uh... (Japanese)
- Sisters.
- (Japanese)
- No.
- No, he's never seen her.
Are you fluent?
Yeah. I live in Tokyo. I write for
a travel magazine out of Australia.
- So, did you?
- Huh?
Go to Camp Minnehaha
in the Rocky Mountains?
(laughs) No.
No, I was lucky. I... I went to space camp.
- Oh, space camp.
- Yeah. Lots of fun.
(both laughing)
- All alone?
- Yeah.
- What?
- (laughing) No.
- No, you'll get lost.
- (mutters)
- Trust me.
Trust me. You will. I've been
in the forest a hundred times.
I don't go in alone.
I can't let you do that.
Well, good thing I don't need
your permission, guy I just met.
I have clearance to go with the park
nature guard tomorrow for my article.
He goes on rounds every few
days, kinda like a suicide watch.
He knows the park better than
anyone. I could ask if you could come.
- That would be great.
- One thing though. A favor, if you wouldn't mind.
Yeah?
Your search for your sister,
it's gripping, it's human.
- I mean, it's an article.
- Oh.
- I'd like your permission to write about it.
- Right.
Will I be a celebrity in Australia?
- Do you want to be a celebrity in Australia?
- Nope.
Are you sure? You might
like it. You never know.
Is it all right if I record you for the
story? For my own notes, for accuracy?
- Uh-huh.
- You have to say "yes" out loud.
"Yes out loud."
Thank you.
So you and Jess were
raised by your grandmother.
And you believe she's okay because you
have this kind of mystical twin connection.
It's not mystical.
It's just when something happens to
one of us, the other one can tell.
I mean, usually it's something happening
to her and me coming to bail her out, but...
Yeah. I've got a little brother myself.
He's a good kid. Just, he can't
seem to stay out of trouble.
Jess is the same. She never learns.
When we were little, no
one could tell us apart.
It was like we were the same person.
Do you mind if I ask what
happened to your parents?
No, it's totally fine.
It was a car accident. We were six.
They had gone to a movie. Grandma
was over. She was watching us.
MAN (shouting, muffled):
What is wrong with you?
WOMAN (muffled): Put that
down. You're scaring me!
They were supposed to be back any
minute. We heard this crash outside.
(gunshot)
(shotgun cocks, fires)
Grandma rushed outside. We followed her.
It was a drunk driver.
He'd been doing 60 in a
residential neighborhood.
Hit them right as they
turned into the driveway.
Jess was in front of me. She saw it first.
(Grandma gasps)
Jess told me later their bodies
were right there on the lawn.
Close your eyes!
Don't look! Don't look!
(audio drops out)
I kept my eyes closed, but she saw it all.
Jesus.
- Did they ever catch the guy?
- What guy?
- The... The drunk driver?
- Oh, no. No.
Hey. I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to dredge all that stuff up.
Oh, it's fine. Long time ago.
- Mmm. Cheers.
- Cheers.
Hi. This is Rob. Sorry I
can't get to the phone.
- Please leave a message.
- (beeps)
Fine.
(electrical buzzing)
(switch clicks)
- (rattling)
- (switch clicks)
- (switch clicking)
- (rattling continues)
(switch clicking)
(buzzing continues)
(rattling continues)
- (screams)
- (gasping)
(speaking Japanese)
- Sorry.
- (old woman moaning)
She's elderly.
- (speaking Japanese)
- (gasping, panting)
(phone buzzes)
- (beeps)
- (line ringing)
ROB: Hey, babe. I got your message.
It's nice to finally hear
your voice. I miss you.
But you going into this forest
alone, it sounds really dangerous.
If I don't hear back from you
soon, I am hopping on a plane.
So just come home. Please.
(speaking Japanese)
- Morning.
- AIDEN: Morning.
Michi, this is Sara.
Hello. Thanks for this.
Michi does these suicide
watch hikes off the books.
That's very good of you.
What?
You must understand,
after this long
most people who go into the
forest to die are already dead.
She's not dead.
Do you have family?
- I have children.
- Okay.
If this was your child,
if you knew she was lost and in pain,
you'd do anything to help, wouldn't you?
I can't prove to you that I'm right.
All I can do is ask you to
understand where I'm coming from.
- I still think you should not go.
- Why?
Because you're sad.
- Okay?
- Let's go.
Jukai means "sea of trees."
If you look down from Mount Fuji,
the forest looks like an ocean.
There's ice caves beneath the forest.
There's whole sections that
have never been explored.
Some people believe it's a
gateway to the other side.
(faint screeching, echoing)
AIDEN: Sara!
Take a look at this.
Okay, that's weird. Why is that happening?
Iron deposits in the
mountain. It's crazy, huh?
- Yeah.
- Look.
People sometimes see things in the forest.
Important to remember.
If you see anything bad, anything strange,
it is not real.
Okay? It's not there.
It's here.
- Watch out.
- I got it.
(animal bellowing, faint)
(bellowing continues)
(insect buzzing)
MICHI: Let's head this way.
What's that?
If you bring a tent, you're not sure.
Stay here.
(Michi speaking Japanese)
(Japanese)
What will you do if we
don't find your sister today?
Try again tomorrow.
What if we don't find her tomorrow?
(Japanese continues)
How does it feel to be in the
forest where she disappeared?
It feels...
necessary.
Jess ever tried suicide before?
She was living in Florida a few years ago
and one night she wasn't
picking up the phone.
I just knew something was wrong.
I got 911 to check on her.
They found her unconscious.
She'd taken some sleeping pills.
That was the second time.
First time was back in college.
- Pills then too?
- Mm-hmm.
I mean, knowing Jess, she probably
just thought it was romantic,
following in the footsteps
of her favorite poet.
"Not one would mind, neither bird nor tree,
if mankind perished utterly.
And Spring herself..."
"When she woke at dawn, would
scarcely know that we were gone."
Now, what's a guy like you
memorize Sara Teasdale for?
(laughs)
Meet a lot of girls on
their junior year abroad?
Whatever works.
Hey, Michi, what happened?
He will be okay, I think.
MICHI: Let's go.
What's that?
AIDEN: People use tape or rope like this
if they think they might want
to find their way back out.
Or they hope somebody will follow the rope
to remove their body
from the forest one day.
MICHI: This one looks recent.
AIDEN: Doesn't look like anyone's
here. Maybe they changed their mind.
(gasps)
I must cut him down.
- I'll make a note of where he is.
- AIDEN: Why?
So the rangers can retrieve the body.
(Michi speaking Japanese)
(screeching, faint)
Michi. (Japanese)
- (Japanese)
- Take a break.
(loud screech in distance)
(woman, faint) Help me.
Can we go this way?
I mean, if we're just picking a direction.
(scoffs)
Come.
SARA: Jess!
Jess!
We must turn back soon.
What, already?
We're several hours from the trail.
We do not stay in the forest after dark.
In the day, easy to get lost.
At night, you're blind and
temperature drops quickly.
Jess!
Do you see something?
Oh, my God, that's her tent.
Jess! Jess!
I knew it! Jess!
It's her! It is! It's her! Oh, my God.
Michi, you said if they bring a
tent, it means they're not sure.
Oh, my God, she's close. She's so close.
- Jess! Jess!
- Jess!
Jess!
Jess? Hello!
Hello?
Since she's not here, we'll
come back tomorrow morning.
- We must go now.
- We've got to stay.
We must go now. You can
leave a note for her.
Leave a note? Are you crazy? I'm
staying. I'm staying till she comes back.
Aiden, tell him.
No, he's right.
- We can come back tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
No, tomorrow is gonna be too late.
She left the tent. She's gonna come back
to sleep. Her clothes are on the line.
Sleeping here is foolish.
We'll not stop looking
for Jess... in the daytime.
Now we must go.
I understand.
You two go. Go.
It's all right. I understand. You go.
You cannot stay!
At night in the jukai,
people see bad things.
Sometimes do bad
things. Very bad things.
The forest draws out
your fear, your sadness.
You believe in yurei, Michi? You
sound like the girl from the visitor center.
I came 6,000 miles to find my sister.
She's here in these woods.
I'm not leaving without her.
Thanks for your help.
I'm so grateful. Really.
But I'm staying.
Sara, you're making a big mistake.
(sighs)
- What are you doing?
- I'm gonna stay here with you.
- Don't be foolish, Aiden.
- It's fine.
We'll stay here. We'll stay the
night. We'll watch after each other.
- (Japanese)
- Hey.
- We'll be fine.
- I'll come back tomorrow.
Do not move from here. Okay?
You don't have to do this.
It's my sister, not yours.
Yeah, well, if it was my
brother, I'd stick around too.
Thanks.
I changed my mind. Let's
come back in the morning.
Yeah. Very funny.
Here. Give me a hand with this fire.
No, not like that. Here. Like this.
Like you're the expert.
You went to space camp.
I know you're not supposed to pile it
up like that. You gotta let it breathe.
Okay. You mean up, like this?
- Yeah. There you go.
- Okay.
I salute your caveman skills.
- Want one?
- What's this?
A Power Bar. Japanese version.
They're pretty good.
It's not bad.
You take the tent when you get tired.
I'll stay out here by the fire.
Avoid any awkwardness.
A caveman and a gentleman.
(insects chirping)
(loud screech in distance)
- What's that?
- I don't know.
But I promise you they
have centipedes in Australia
more dangerous than anything out here.
Jess must be lost.
She's close.
And alive.
Explain that to me.
It's like a sound.
It's too low to hear, but I can just...
feel it...
running through me.
And that night I was telling
you about, when she almost died,
the sound dropped away.
Where Jess had been,
there was just...
silence.
You know, when we were kids,
my brother would start fights.
And I never stepped in.
Figured he needed to learn not
to start them in the first place.
One day he got beat up so bad
that it left him deaf in his left ear.
And I remember seeing him,
and that feeling... just guilt.
So now whenever he's in
trouble, I come running.
- I feel guilty too.
- What do you mean?
My parents' bodies.
I closed my eyes, but she looked.
It's always been the difference between us.
She looks at the dark
stuff and I turn away.
What she saw,
she carried that all by herself.
I should have shared it with her.
That's why I come running.
I'm going to try and get some sleep.
Yeah.
(rustling)
(footsteps)
Aiden?
Aiden, say something.
(footsteps)
(running footsteps)
(screams)
(loud screech in distance)
(shrieks)
(rustling)
Hello?
Jess, is that you?
Hey, wait.
Wait.
Please!
Hi.
Do you speak English?
Little.
Hoshiko.
Hoshiko, are you alone?
You're cold. Let me help you.
You Sara?
Yeah. How do you know my name?
No trust him.
Who?
Miss Jess know him.
Jess? Is Jess your teacher?
I find her here.
She say, "Need your help."
- Where is she?
- No trust him.
AIDEN: Sara!
No, no, no, no! Wait!
(gasps)
Goddamn it.
(groans)
I lost her. I lost her.
- Jesus. Look at your hand.
- Oh, God.
Who? Who'd you lose? Jess?
No, it was...
It was a teenage girl. She said...
She said what?
Something in Japanese.
Oh, man.
Well, we're not gonna find her
if she doesn't wanna be found.
We'll tell Michi.
Okay, let's get back before
we get turned around. Come on.
(groans)
Come on.
(thunder rumbling)
All right, kiddo. There's
enough light for us now.
Let's get you out of here.
- But Michi said noon.
- Seven hours from now?
No. Look at your hand. You need stitches.
Let me worry about my hand.
Jess might still come back.
Sara.
You just saw a child out in the woods
presumably contemplating suicide,
considering that she ran from you.
We tell them that, they'll
send a search party quick.
Maybe that search party
finds your sister. Make sense?
In the meantime,
in case your sister does
come back while we're gone,
you do what you should've done yesterday.
- (backpack zips)
- Leave a note.
This is the way we came.
We keep walking in this direction,
we'll come to the path before too long.
- We didn't pass the river coming in.
- Yeah, I know.
But at least we can follow it down.
It may take a little longer,
but it'll lead us back to
civilization just the same.
Sara. Hey. Careful. Hey.
Hey, get back from there. Come on.
- SARA: Do you see that?
- Jesus.
Hey, come on.
Get away from there. Come on.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
We were walking that way.
- No, we weren't.
- Yes, we were.
Two minutes ago, we were walking that way,
and now you're leading
me back the way we came.
No. Sara, we're following
the river down. Remember?
We're not climbing the mountain.
Down.
Water flows down.
See?
SARA (on recording):
I feel guilty too.
AIDEN (on recording):
What do you mean?
SARA: My parents' bodies.
I closed my eyes, but she looked.
- Hello!
- That's always been the difference between us.
- Oh, shit.
- She looks at the dark stuff and I turn away.
- What she saw...
- You recorded that?
You gave me permission, the other day.
- That's why you questioned me so much last night.
- Yeah, I'm doing a story.
That's why you stayed at the
campsite... for your story.
In part.
Also because I was concerned
about you... and your sister,
and I liked you.
- Do you even have a brother?
- Of course I do.
What's his name?
Mikey.
- Which ear is he deaf in?
- His... His...
Okay, yes, I wanted to get
closer to you for the story.
Yes, but also mainly to get
closer to a pretty girl in the bar.
- Who are you?
- Everything else I told you is true.
- When did you meet Jess?
- I've never met her.
- Yes, you did.
- Why do you keep saying that? It was just a line in a bar.
- Give me your phone.
- Why?
- Why not?
- Because it's my phone.
You're hiding something?
You're getting just a little too
agitated. It's making me uncomfortable.
I'm lost in the woods with a
strange man who's been lying to me,
and I do not give a shit if it
makes you feel uncomfortable.
- Now, give me your phone!
- All right, calm down.
I'll give you the phone.
- Don't mess with it first.
- I'm unlocking it!
- What are you doing?
- I'm deleting all the recordings.
If you even are a journalist,
then permission is revoked.
You cannot use my story.
How do you...
How do you what?
Oh, my God.
What?
You met me on purpose, didn't you?
I don't know what you think...
or what you're talking about.
- What did you do to her?
- Who, Jess?
- Yeah.
- I've never met her.
There are photos right here on this phone.
- Give me the phone.
- Stay back.
- Give me the damn phone!
- No!
Give me it!
(phone hits ground)
Sara!
Hey, you're gonna get lost!
Come back!
Sara!
No.
Aiden?
Sara!
FEMALE VOICE: Turn around, Sara.
No. (sniffles)
No.
Turn around, Sara.
- (sobs)
- Turn around, Sara.
You're not real!
Turn around, Sara.
(gasps)
(speaking Japanese)
- Michi?
- Rob. Hey.
We'll find her. Don't worry.
(groaning)
(gasping)
(coughing)
(groans)
(screaming)
(howling)
(loud shriek)
(clattering)
GIRL'S VOICE (singsongy): Sara.
Sara.
It's me, Hoshiko.
- What are you doing down here?
- Come.
- Come where?
- You come.
Miss Jess want to see you.
Jess?
- I take you.
- Down here?
- (screeching in distance)
- What's making that noise?
- Animal.
- That doesn't sound like an animal.
Why is Jess down here?
Tell me!
(shrieks)
Help!
Can you hear me?
- AIDEN: Sara?
- Aiden?
- Sara.
- Aiden!
- You gotta get me out of here.
- Hold on.
I'm gonna find something
to throw down for you.
Aiden, don't leave me, please! No!
No.
If you see something bad, it's
not real. It's just in your head.
not real. It's in your head.
If you see something bad, it's
It's in your head.
(insect buzzing)
(gasps)
No.
(screams)
No! (screaming)
- AIDEN: Sara!
- Aiden.
Sara, hang on.
(sobbing) Aiden, get me out of here.
Okay. All right, grab that.
I gotcha.
Okay.
- Pull.
- (grunts)
Hey.
Sara, you okay?
Michi was right.
The forest does make you see things.
Look.
I found a place.
It might have a radio. It's a
ranger station. It's not that far.
You just stumbled across it right now?
(backpack unzips)
Here.
Take the knife.
Why am I taking the knife?
So you trust me more.
We're in this together, right?
Right.
Just let me wash off first.
AIDEN: Sara.
- You all right?
- (gasps)
I'm fine!
Well, if there's no radio, at
least we got a place to sleep.
Hello?
Come on, baby. Come on. Work.
(clicking)
Hey, Sara, give me the knife.
What?
The knife... let me have it.
- Why?
- So I can open this thing up.
Or I can smash it on the damn
table! Just give me the knife!
(rattling)
(clicking)
Why do you think they locked the basement?
What makes you think it's a basement?
What else would it be?
I don't know. A closet?
- JESS: Sara?
- Jess?
- Shh.
Oh!
Okay.
- Okay.
- God, please be real.
AIDEN: Hey, do you wanna chow down
before it gets too dark to see?
Huh?
Sara, what are you doing?
Here, it's the last one. You can have it.
Come on. Take it.
I don't know if the
forest made you a psycho
or if you were crazy anyways.
But if you don't let my
sister out of that basement,
I will kill you.
Sara.
Wake up.
Your sister is dead.
- She's been in here for five days.
- Give me the key.
Okay. All right. All right.
I'll let her out, okay?
Just let me get the key.
- Where is it?
- It's in my boot.
Let me get it.
Yeah.
(groans)
(gasps)
(coughing)
(gasping, coughing)
(door opens)
- (hinge creaking)
- Jess?
She...
She's not here.
(gasping)
Jess.
Jess?
Jess, no. Stop. Don't look. Don't look.
Don't look.
Don't look. (gasps)
Oh, God.
Daddy, why?
- Oh, Daddy.
- (gasps)
Oh, God.
Go!
Go, go, go.
Daddy. Daddy, no. Let me go!
Let me... go!
(screaming)
(officer speaking Japanese)
MICHI: We should go.
(speaks Japanese)
(screaming)
JESS: Oh, God, help!
- Jess?
- Please, somebody help! Help me!
Oh, God, Jess.
Jess!
Wait!
(speaking Japanese)
(whimpering)
- Oh, God, help me.
- Sara?
Sara. Hey. Hey.
(whimpering) Don't touch me!
Jess. Jess.
It's me. It's Rob.
Rob?
- Is that you?
- Yeah.
Oh, God!
I've been lost for days.
I didn't think I'd make it.
- Hey, hey. Have you seen Sara?
- What?
- Have you seen Sara?
- She's not with you?
No.
Please, let me go.
Let me go!
No! No!
No! (screaming)
She came for me.
She knew you were still alive.
We go back in first thing, all right?
- We have to go back right now.
- ROB: No, no, no.
- Right now.
- Jess. Hey.
What?
Nothing.
That's the...
It's silent.
Okay.
Oh, Sara.
(engine starts)
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
♪♪ (children
singing in Japanese)
♪♪ (continues)
♪♪ (stops)
♪♪ (children resume singing)
♪♪ (continues)
♪♪ (stops)
♪♪ (singing resumes)
♪♪ (continues)
♪♪ (ends)