Mr. Dobson,
it's time for us to do what
the Good Lord would refer to
as a "cleansing of the wicked,"
and what my brother George,
God rest his soul,
used to call
"100% Alabama ass kickin'."
So you think we're gonna
die here today?
Dying's not an option.
Now, you stick that back
in that gray matter of yours
and you make that stick,
'cause any other thought's
gonna get you cold-slabbed,
toe-tagged and mailed home to your
mom in a plastic bag. Are we crystal?
- Crystal, sir.
- Gentlemen!
Let's do what
God made us to do.
This is Sheriff John Quincey Wydell...
of the Ruggsville County
Sheriffs Department.
You're completely surrounded!
You have no chance of escape!
Now would be the time
to vacate the premises peacefully.
There's a million
fucking cops!
Come on.
Otis, the fucking pigs
are everywhere!
- Tell me something I don't know!
- We've gotta do something!
You're completely surrounded.
You have no chance of escape.
Can't take the car,
about 25 pigs.
I know, I know!
Shit fuck shit fuck!
Shit.
Where the fuck is Tiny?
- I ain't seen Tiny.
- Tiny!
- I think he went out last night.
- Everybody shut up!
Mama, what's the matter?
I keep thinking
about... old times...
Iike when you was
a fuckin' baby.
- You looked like an angel.
- I know, Mama.
- You told me that a million times.
- Yeah.
Gentlemen!
On the count of three!
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- One!
- I love you, Mama.
- I love you, Baby.
- Two!
Let's go.
Three!
Fucking pigs!
Stupid motherfucker!
Die, you fuckers!
- You okay?!
- Yeah, are you?
Fuck!
- Ready?
- Yeah yeah yeah, go go!
Wydell:
Man down!
- Hold your fire!
Dobson! Get some tear-gas
in that house!
Sir!
Mama!
Let's go! Let's go!
Do not fucking move!
I advise you
to lower that weapon.
I'm sorry, Sheriff,
but you ain't gettin' me.
Looks like you ain't
gettin' off that easy,
huh, bitch?
All right, everybody listen up.
I want this place gone over
with a fine-tooth comb.
Wherever these fuckers are,
- they gotta be close.
- I am standing outside the perimeter
of what is turning out to be
the most horrific crime scene
since Jack the Ripper
stalked the streets of London.
What police have uncovered
reads like this--
words can't describe it--
"Human skulls
used as ornaments,
body parts stuffed
in refrigerators. "
And I can't believe
what it says here:
"A mass grave
of decomposing bodies
dumped under the crawlspace
of the house."
Hey, Chief, you might wanna
check this out.
- What?
- I don't know.
Jesus H Christ.
Motherfucker.
What, you recognize the clown?
Yeah, his name is Spaulding,
Captain fucking Spaulding.
Oh, yeah! Ooh, yes!
Gimme-- give it to me!
- Yeah.
- Yeah yeah.
Yeah, ride the horse, baby!
Ride it!
Ride it! Yeah yeah yeah.
God! Oh, yeah, honey.
Oh-ho!
- Give it to me.
- Oh, yeah. Yeah! Oh, yeah!
- You're the captain.
- Come on, baby.
- Yeah yeah yeah...
Oh, ride me, baby.
Ride it, ride it.
Ride it!
Feels so good!
Yeah! Yes, give it!
Give it up! Give it!
Give it, give it!
Yeah! Oh!
Come on, baby, ride it home!
Yeah yeah yeah...
- Yes! Yeah!
- Yeah, oh!
Ah! Oh, honey!
You gettin'
a good ride tonight.
Next time, you gonna
have to pay me.
Did you just call me
a fucking whore?
Well, I calls 'em
like I sees 'em.
Really?
You think I'm
a fucking whore?
I don't think it,
I know it.
- Whore this, fucker.
- Hey hey hey hey!
Come on now, baby,
hold on.
I'm just messing with ya.
You know us clowns,
we like to just fool around
a bunch, you know? Come on.
- Yeah.
- Laugh.
Clown... Iaugh!
Poopy.
What's the matter,
bad dream?
Yeah, 50-50.
You want to fool
around some more?
Oh, Jesus Christ, woman,
I gotta take a piss.
- No.
- Didn't you get enough ass-banging
Iast night?
God damn it, my dick is still sore.
- Oh, come on, I'm horny.
- No.
Most guys like
that quality in a girl.
Yeah, except you acting like some
kinda spastic mongoloid in heat.
- Fuckin' bitch.
- Hurry!
Spaulding: Ah...
Where is it?
Just calm down,
it'll be on in a minute.
Ah! Ha ha!
There it is!
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
- Yeah.
- You look so sexy.
Captain Spaulding again. I'm here to
tell you about a brand-new attraction.
Mary... the monkey.
Oh yeah, that's right.
- Ha! That fuckin' monkey.
- This here little monkey
... is half real human, half monkey...
- I love that monkey.
...I brought all the way
from the wilds of Borneo.
When y'all come in, make sure you bring
little Johnny and Suzie with you.
She'll scare
the holy guacamole out of 'em.
Ha ha! And remember
while you're down here,
pick up a "Captain Spaulding
for president" T-shirt
all shapes and--
Hey, what the fuck is this?
I paid good money for
this goddamn commercial!
Sheriff, "News Update,"
what is the situation now?
The situation?
Now what?
God damn it!
- What are you--
- Yeah, what?
- Daddy, you gotta get outta there.
- Why?
- The pigs hit us this morning real bad.
- Shut the fuck up!
- They're gonna be coming for you too.
- All right, just calm down.
I'll meet you at the Kahiki Palms Motel
just like we always planned.
- Yeah, okay.
- I'll be there as soon as I can.
All right,
just go now.
Poopy!
What do you need a gun for?
Where are we going?
- You ain't going nowhere, bitch.
- Oh, Poopy!
Get outta my fuckin' way!
If you're out there listening to this,
I got a message for ya.
I'm coming to get ya.
You can't run forever.
You're gonna have to stop
somewhere, sometime, and when you do
I'm gonna be there to put the wrath
of the Lord up your ass.
Poopy, don't go!
God damn it,
stop calling me Poopy!
- But, Poopy--
- Leave me alone, woman!
- I want my Poopy! Poopy, no!
- Leave me alone!
In an attempt to help the Ruggsville
Police Department,
we here at "News Update"
would like to show you
these mug shots of the suspects
known to have escaped
during the raid earlier this morning.
100. 150.
175.
184 bucks?
What?!
- Candy!
- What?
Candy, come on down here!
Come on, cut that out.
Turn it off.
Candy, come down here!
- Come on down here!
- All right. Shit.
What?
This is bullshit, baby!
What is this?
What do you want me to say?
It's a slow fuckin' night, boss.
All them farmers want is
a quickie hand job and boom!
10 dolla!
Get back on their tractors,
save the real fucking for the sheep.
Jesus, Candy, you gotta figure
a way to hook 'em in.
You gotta hustle
that pussy.
Find a new angle and you might
attract a higher clientele.
Yeah, well, I've been
thinking about that.
I was thinking about something spacey
like that "Star Wars" shit.
You know, them losers wanna
fuck Princess Leia, right?
I'd fuck her.
Thank you.
I don't know, you start messing
with that spacey shit,
and you'll really bring out
some sick bitches.
They all wanting
to pretend they're robots.
Last thing I need is horny robots
running around, tripping over shit.
Droids... boss,
they call 'em droids.
Whatever.
I still say it's risky.
Wong's Hong Kong Gardens,
this is Mr. Wong speaking.
Cut the shit, Charlie.
It's me, Cutter.
I got a serious meltdown
going on down here
and I need a place to cool out,
so I'm coming down.
Fuck, man, I don't think it's such
a great idea, you coming around here.
I am coming down... now.
- Whoa, ho-- hold it!
- Fuck.
Hold it!
Fuck!
Man, I don't see him.
Shit, where the fuck is he?
Jesus! Can we get
over this already?
I mean, I just don't
find it funny anymore.
I don't know,
it's still pretty funny.
- I'd say so.
- I hate to be the one
- to tell you I told you so--
- Then don't.
--but ridin' a mechanical bull
is not as easy as it looks.
Technically, she had
a pretty good ride...
until tragedy struck.
Hey, the lesson here is
that tube tops are not the proper attire
for bull riding, Glory.
I agree with you.
You gonna have to put a harness
on them little suckers, honey.
Her "tig bitties"
were flappin' around--
My titties don't flap!
They looked like two raccoons
in a gunnysack fighting to get out.
- Oh, Adam, shut up.
- When her top fell down,
I was gonna pee myself!
"l was gonna pee myself!"
You're just jealous
'cause you don't have any titties.
Oh, Gloria, come on,
no reason to get mean.
Come on, baby.
You had one titty going this way
and one titty going that way.
It was pretty amazing.
Chances are high you made
a few fans that night.
Oh, shut up, dipshit.
Well, I told Johnny Cash,
and he said--
did you know I shook hands
with Johnny Cash once?
Roy, how about you go
find me the ice machine?
I need a drink.
I'll get you the ice, but you gotta
promise us an encore tomorrow.
Roy!
You wish, honey.
Don't you wish.
The babes are
going into seclusion.
Man over radio:
The leader of this group who is
a local celebrity goes by the name
of Captain Spaulding
along with two other
suspects known as Otis--
Aw, shit fuck
shit fuck!
God, calm down.
Get rid of the car.
Don't worry,
I'll get us a room.
- Well, hurry the fuck up!
- Fuck you!
Fuck you!
Police revealed today
that they believe
most of the victims were drugged,
kidnapped and sexually assaulted.
God damn it! Fuck!
Hey, Roy, I was doing some research
on that thing I was telling you about.
- What thing?
- Rodeo clowning.
Rodeo...
A rodeo clown?
You been smoking dope.
Yeah-- I mean no,
not right now.
Let me tell you
something.
You spend one second in that pen
and that bulI'd have his horn
up your ass
and sticking out your pecker.
That's exactly what
I thought you'd say.
You know, you can never be supportive
of anything I wanna do.
What do you
want me to say?
That you're dressed for the part
and headed in the right direction?
Well, Adam was saying...
I've always been
good with animals.
I mean, dogs love me.
And isn't a horse
kinda like a big dog?
I don't know.
No, you're not
clown material.
Forget it. I'm gonna walk
on over to the gas station.
- You want anything?
- No-- yes.
Get me some
of that beef jerky.
Thanks for talking.
I could've been on that pit crew
down in North Carolina.
Yeah.
Baby:
Meow! Meow.
Hey, pussycat.
Hey, got a light?
No, uh, I don't smoke.
My doctor says I got lungs
like a professional athlete.
Ah, I get it.
You wanna live forever.
Yeah yeah, well...
So what, are you on vacation
all by yourself or something?
Yeah-- no. I'm actually out here
with my singing group.
I do the lead singing for it.
It's called
"Banjo and Sullivan."
I used to sing with Johnny Cash.
He shook my hand.
I love famous people. They're so much
better than the real thing.
Well, yeah,
I suppose they are.
I bet all the girls
wanna fuck you.
- Would you say that again?
- I bet all the girls wanna fuck you.
( both laughing )
Do you kiss your mama
with that mouth?
Trust me, fella, that ain't
the only thing I do with this mouth.
Don't tell me that!
What? Say that again.
That I ain't the only thing
I do with this mouth.
It's so depressing.
Let's talk about some of the symbols
of these groups
Iike the inverted cross
or the pentagram
or the number 666
left at the scene of the crime.
What do you
think about that?
This is not
an isolated incident.
Well, members of these cults
realize they have no chance
of attacking God directly.
- So the next best thing...
- Adam, could you switch this?
- I can't stand to hear about this.
- What do I look like, Roy?
I'm Sullivan,
Roy Sullivan.
Well... Roy Sullivan.
You gonna take me
back to your room and play with me?
My wife's in that room.
Or is my brother
gonna have to shoot
your fucking teeth
out of your head?
Okay, let's go, Hoss.
Move it.
Just makes me sick
to my stomach to think
that we live in a world
where there are Satanic cults.
Come on, Gloria,
it's a bunch of crap.
- I don't know.
- Look at these two idiots.
They're just exaggerating all this shit
to try and kick up ratings.
They wanna get people scared
so they stay at home,
buy TV dinners.
Fuck me running.
I don't know about that.
That business down in Ruggsville...
Ruggsville?
Ruggsville can kiss my ass.
Ain't nothing but a bunch
of local cousinfuckers
corn-holing the livestock.
Could you just switch it
for me anyway, please?
Jesus Christ, I don't know
how Roy puts up with your shit.
What is taking Roy
so long, anyway?
- Hey!
- On the bed now!
- Get on the bed!
- Let me check my-- all right.
- Easy!
- What's going on here, Roy?
Shut up! Did I tell you
to fucking speak?
- Hey! Hey! Quiet! Quiet!
- Did I tell you you could talk?
Roy, what the hell is this?
- God damn it, look at that jacket.
- What?
On TV.
- Well, fuck the TV.
- Fuck the TV? Fuck you!
Will you keep your head
on the business at hand?
- Who's in the shower?
- That's my wife!
- God damn it!
- Don't fuck with.22.
What are you gonna do, man?
What the fuck are you gonna do?
I wanna know what the fuck
are you gonna do?
Wendy!
Get the fuck out of here!
Don't hurt her, please.
Is this everyone?
Hey, Roy. Open up.
I got some of that Dr. Corndog's
hickory-smoked jerky.
Who the fuck is that?
That's Jimmy.
He's our roadie.
I forgot all about him.
Baby, you all right?
Now I know
I can't trust you!
I'll get him.
- Hey.
- I'm sorry. I got the wrong room.
I'm looking for
room number two.
No, you got the right room.
Come on in.
- Is Roy in there?
- Roy's in here, all right. Come on in.
Get your ass in here!
On your knees!
Roy, help--
Shut up!
We're at the scene
of a horrific multiple murder.
- No telling how many--
- God damn it!
Fuck!
... in the process
of recovering the corpses
which are in varying states
of decomposition.
It's currently being treated
as a sign of a mass homicide.
- If initial figures prove--
- ( radio shuts off )
Come on, honey.
Mommy has to get to work.
If I'm late one more time,
Mr. McDonnell is gonna can my ass.
I am hurrying!
I dropped something.
Will you get in the car?!
Okay, come on, let's go get in.
- Mom, a clown.
- Yeah yeah, a clown.
Oh-- hi.
Hi. I'm gonna have to
be taking your car today.
See, I have some
top-secret clown business
that supersedes any plans that you
might have for this here vehicle.
What's that about clown business?
Do I stutter, bitch?
Jamie, get in the car.
Lock the door.
Where the hell you going?
Damn it.
Don't you never turn your back
on a fucking clown
- when he's talking to you!
- Get your fucking hands off of me!
What's the matter, kid?
Don't you like clowns?
Why? Don't we
make you laugh?
Aren't we fucking funny?
You best come up with an answer
'cause I'm gonna come back here
and check on you and your mama.
If you ain't got a reason
why you hate clowns,
I'm gonna kill your
whole fucking family.
All right, now get
your fucking ass out the car!
Go on!
Yeah yeah yeah yeah!
Shit! Woo!
Chinese, Japanese,
dirty knees, look at these.
Hoss, are you staring
at my sister thinking bad thoughts?
No.
Why not? You a faggot?
Well, what are you?
I mean, you got this hot piece of ass
shaking her shit right
in front of you
and you're not getting any ideas?
What do you call that?
I'm a married man.
A married fucking man.
Hey, that's just great!
Let's give him a big round
of applause, folks, for the married man!
Come on!
Woo! Married man!
All right. Wow.
Okay, Mama,
front and center, on your feet.
Don't hurt her.
Get on your feet.
Come on.
Let's go.
Please, mister,
this is insane.
Boy... the next word
that comes outta your mouth
better be some brilliant
fucking Mark Twain shit,
'cause it's definitely getting
chiseled on your tombstone.
Okay, come on, Mama.
Take that shit off,
Iet's see what's been holding Hoss's
balls at attention all these years.
What?
What? Take off your clothes,
or one of these assholes
is going to die.
Come on, come on.
Shit, way to go, Roy!
She ain't too bad.
She got a tight
little ass on her!
And she got some
child-rearing hips.
Huh, yeah, hey.
Please don't hurt me.
Here, ooh, Jeez.
Roy, beginning to see what you mean.
Whoa.
Please don't hurt me.
You like this, don't ya?
Say "Yes, I do."
You like that, don't ya?
Yes, I do.
Yes, l-- I do.
Okay.
Okay, now.
Give me some sugar.
Make it sweet.
Don't want me to tense
up my trigger finger.
- My finger's getting tense...
I want you to say,
"You're the almighty devil,
and I want you to make me
my filthy whore."
Come on, say it.
I know it.
I know you're
feeling it. Say it.
You're... the...
almighty... devil
and I want you...
to make me your... fucking whore.
You make me sick.
Woo-hoo!
I feel like we're all really getting
to know each other now.
All right, ladies.
Me and the boys have an errand to run.
We'll be back
in a little while.
Come on, Hoss,
move it.
Come on, shit stain!
Gotta go!
Come on!
God damn it!
Authorities struggle to
comprehend the grizzly remains found
in what is now being called the most
heinous crime in American history.
The group responsible
for these murders
is now being referred to as "The Devil's
Rejects" by the local media.
A woman known only
as "Mother Firefly"
was taken into
police custody today
after a violent
gun battle with police
that left four officers
dead and seven wounded.
I'm Derek Sanderson
bringing the world
to your doorstep.
Open the gate.
Ma'am...
my name is Sheriff
John Quincey Wydell.
Let's see
who we got here.
Miss Gloria T easdale,
alias Eve Wilson,
alias Southern Betty Woods...
Betsy Woods.
And of course,
alias Mother Firefly.
You can read.
Congratulations.
Four counts,
grand theft auto.
Five counts,
armed robbery.
What's this?
Looks like your specialty...
17 counts, solicitation
and prostitution.
You've been one busy whore.
I bet them old farmboys love you.
Everyone loves me.
Don't you pretend...
you don't fancy me.
Oh, yes, ma'am.
I find you quite irresistible.
- Dobson.
- Yes, sir.
- Put them books over there.
- Got it.
Ma'am, you recognize
these books, here?
Yeah.
Oh! Ain't she an angel?
Well, she gonna be one dead angel
when I catch up to her--
you, your whole clan,
you dead already.
You're just ghosts,
just waiting to expire.
The way I figure it,
only choice you got
is to cooperate
and tell me where they are.
That way your little
angel over there
don't have to die like no dog
in the streets when I catch her.
- Are you done trying to scare me?
- No, ma'am.
With God as my witness...
I have only just begun.
Oh... Sheriff...
can I show you something?
I'll need this book here.
I did never...
get around to putting these
in the book proper.
And I thought...
you might enjoy them.
Oh... you know...
he was a real sweetie pie.
Tall...
big moustache...
bald head...
You know,
I feel contrite
about blowing
his brains out,
'cause he seemed
like such a nice man.
I think...
he said... his name
was also Wydell.
Was he kin to you?
Listen to me,
you gonna listen to me good.
I'm going to kill every
member of your family.
I am gonna hunt them down
like animals and skin 'em alive.
They are gonna feel the pain
and suffering of every last victim.
They're gonna crawl on their hands
and knees and beg me for mercy,
but all I'm gonna
have for 'em is pain.
- You're dead!
You go get 'em, Sheriff!
Go get your ghost!
Them ghosts is gonna
crawl right up
in your h-e-e-e-ead!
You found yourself into something
you ain't never getting out of!
We'll get ya!
We'll... get ya!
You're dead, Sheriff!
You're dead!
I'll see you
in fucking hell!
Hey, Hoss,
you like this song?
Do you like this song?
I don't know.
Yeah, I guess so.
Oh, really?
- Which way?
- Take a right.
You like that T op 40 shit?
I thought you
were like some kinda
true-blue-balls-earnest-kill-'em
country fucker.
You're nothing but a city faggot
with a cowboy hat.
Stop here.
Okay, get out.
This way.
Follow the yellow brick road.
Otis:
That's right.
Go on.
You know, Hoss,
if I'm not mistaken,
I think I can smell your wife's
pussy-stink on my gun.
Hope it doesn't rust the barrel.
Oh, man.
You know, the stress
of the day is really setting in on me.
You guys happen to know how a guy
like me could relieve some tension?
Ah, maybe-- I think
your wife Wendy, boy,
Iooks like she could
relieve some tension.
- Mister, where we going?
- Those little titties--
we're going down
the road here.
Those little titties,
she's got a tight little ass.
Does she like it
when you puke?
Is that part of your deal?
Where you taking us?
Well, I guess, it wouldn't
do no harm to tell you none.
We're gonna go dig up some guns
I buried out here a couple years ago.
- Then what?
- Well, there ain't no "what."
That's the end of the road.
What?
- You're not gonna kill us, are you?
- Killing sounds so permanent.
Adam: We did everything
you want, mister, just let us go.
We did what you said.
First of all,
I didn't say anything.
And second of all,
I'm calling the shots!
Consider me fucking
Willy fucking Wonka!
This is my fucking chocolate factory!
You got it?!
My factory--
Get him, Roy!
Get the gun, Roy!
Roy!
Please, mister, stop.
Please.
- Stop.
- Stop?
Bitch, I have just started.
You know, I was gonna take
it easy on you, boy,
but you brought this
down on yourself.
You had to come
all fucking-big-stick- walking-tall
Iike a big, fucking hero!
You got yourself to blame.
Look at you now, hero!
You're gonna fucking bleed to death.
Fuck you!
That's what they all say,
"Fuck you!"
Well, it ain't gonna save ya.
It don't scare me none
and don't make you a hero!
Wanna see what happens
to heroes, boy?
You wanna see bad-ass, motherfucker?
I'll show you bad-ass!
Roy!
Hoss, I want you
to pray to your God.
I want you to pray that
He comes and saves you.
I want lightning to come down
and crash upon my fucking head!
- I pray... Jesus...
- Louder!
Bless the bunnies,
bless the little birds--
- I don't feel anything.
---bless the springtime morning.
I feel it!
Oh, Great God Almighty,
I repent, I repent!
I feel the love
of the God-God-God Almighty!
Oh, the Holy Spirit
is in my body!
I am the devil, and I am here
to do the devil's work.
Roy! Roy!
You fucking motherfucker!
Son of a bitch!
I've got other
plans for you... hero.
Shut the fuck up!
Can I go to the bathroom, please?
I'm about to piss myself.
Excuse me...
Can she go to
the bathroom? Please?
What?! I heard you the first time.
I was just thinking.
What are you
gonna do for me?
- What?
- Go piss yourself for all I care.
If you want special favors, you gotta
give me something in return.
What do you want?
I want you
to hit her in the face.
- What?
- I know you heard me.
Go ahead.
Go on.
Make it hurt,
no love taps.
I want to hear it.
Harder, she ain't gonna break.
You better make this
next one fucking count!
- Ah!
Good, very nice.
Now you come here.
Right here.
Kneel down.
Give me a kiss and say, "Thank you,
Baby, I'm having a great time."
Thanks, Baby,
I had a really good time.
Now make it fast, bitch!
Don't try anything cute!
Shit!
Now, what do you
want to do?
Damn it, I knew that cunt
would do something stupid.
Shut up!
Open the fucking door!
- Open the goddamn door!
- Okay! Hold it!
Somebody help me!
What are you
gonna do, shoot me?
What did I ever
really do to you?
I swear I'll do it.
I'll kill you.
Why would you
want to kill me?
I'm you're only hope,
my brother's fucking crazy.
- Please!
- Wendy, it's all right!
Come on out--
Go ahead, shoot me.
Shoot me right in the ass!
Stupid cunt!
Ain't no bullets in this thing.
It's all fucking mind power.