[train horn]
[intercom] Due to a computer error,
the food stamp program
has been suspended
until further notice.
Please do not apply at this time.
All applicants' report wages
will now report to window P.
Thank you.
Last place of employment?
Denver, Colorado.
Worked there for ten years.
Then things just seemed to dry up.
They lost fourteen banks in one week.
So, well...
There's nothing available
for you right now.
[man] They use
their tongues to deceive.
The venom of snakes is
under their lips.
Their mouths are full
of bitterness and curses.
And in their paths,
nothing but ruin and misery.
And the fear of God is not
before their eyes.
They have taken the hearts
and minds of our leaders.
They have recruited
the rich and the powerful.
And they have blinded us to the truth.
Our human spirit is corrupted.
Why do we worship greed?
Because outside
the limit of our sight,
feeding off us,
perched on top of us
from birth to death
are our owners-- our owners!
They have us!
They control us!
They are our masters!
Wake up, they're all about you.
All around you.
[woman] Sometimes, when I watch TV,
I stop being myself.
I'm a star of a series or a--
or I have my own talk show
or I'm on the news
getting out of a limo
going some place important.
All I ever have to do is be famous.
People watch me and they love me.
And I never, never grow old.
And I never die.
Excuse me.
You need anybody?
Maybe.
I got my own tools.
Well, this is a union job.
So, then may I please speak
with the shop steward?
Sir?
Hey, there's no sleeping
on this site.
So you park your ass
someplace else tonight.
Excuse me.
Then when do I get paid?
Thursday.
You need a place to stay?
Justiceville's over on Fourth Street.
They got hot food and showers.
I'm going that way
if you want me to show you.
I don't like nobody following me
'less I know why.
Well, I don't join up with anybody
until I see where he's going.
They're serving the food up soon.
Good, I'm starving.
Whoa.
Hey, throw the ball.
Hey, Frank, how's it going?
Now you get a chance to meet
some of the folk.
This here's Gilbert.
Anything you need,
he knows where to find it.
Hi.
Howdy.
What do you got in that pack, tools?
Yes, sir.
Well, if you can use them
we can use you.
Shower's caving in over there.
Let's get something to eat.
There you go.
- Howdy.
- Want some peas?
- Yeah, please.
- Thanks.
- Some more?
Yes.
Peas?
I got a wife and two kids
back in Detroit.
Haven't seen them in six months.
Steel mills were
laying people off left and right.
They finally went under.
We gave the steel companies
a break when they needed it.
Know what they gave themselves?
Raises.
The golden rule--
He who has the gold makes the rules.
They close one more factory,
we should take a sledge to one
of their fancy, fucking foreign cars.
You know, you ought to have
a little more patience with life.
Yeah, well I'm all out.
The whole deal is like
some kind of crazy game.
They put you at the starting line,
the name of the game is,
"Make it through life."
Only, everyone's out for themselves
and looking to do you in
at the same time.
Okay, man, here we are.
Here we are--
now, you do what you can.
But remember,
I'm going to do my best
to blow your ass away.
So, how you going to make it?
I deliver a hard day's work
for my money.
I just want the chance,
it'll come.
I believe in America.
I follow the rules.
Everybody's got their own
hard times these days.
[blues harmonica]
You've always thought
you couldn't wear
press-on nails because of all
the active things you do?
Well, if you're ready for beautiful,
natural looking, easy to apply nails,
three colors in seven luscious hues,
just-- [static]
Our impulses are being redirected.
We are living in an artificially
induced state of consciousness
that resembles sleep.
Goddamn hacker, that's the second time
tonight that asshole's cut in.
The movement was begun
eight months ago
by a small group of scientists
who discovered quite by accident
these signals being sent through--
[static]
Thing's giving me a headache.
Yeah, tell me about it.
Must took the hacker's months
to figure out how to do this.
The poor and the underclass
are growing.
Racial justice and human rights
are non-existent.
They have created
a repressive society
and we are their unwitting accomplices.
Their intention to rule rests
with the annihilation
of consciousness.
We have been lulled into a trance.
They have made us
indifferent to ourselves, to others.
We are focused only on our own gain.
We ha--
Please understand, they are safe
as long as they are not discovered.
That is their primary
method of survival.
Keep us asleep, keep us selfish,
keep us sedated.
...they're pulling the water
out of the sand like sponges.
Blow it out your ass.
Choir practice went
a little late last night, didn't it?
Oh, the church lets us use
their kitchen.
Until four in the morning?
Hey, we're taking care
of a lot of people here.
They are dismantling
the sleeping middle class.
More and more people are becoming poor.
We are their cattle.
We are being bred for slavery.
The revo--
Not again.
We cannot break their signal.
Our transmitter is not powerful enough.
The signal must be shut off
at the source.
We have--
Danny, I have a headache.
Me too, honey.
Can somebody please explain to me
what the hell that's all about?
Just that idiot licking his nuts again.
[choir singing "Rock of Ages"]
[singing continues]
I just checked the connection
and there's nothing wrong with it.
[choir louder, continues]
We have to face facts.
Only a few seconds got on the air.
It's time to forget about breaking in
on top of their signal.
They're only going to jam us out
again and again.
Then we have to send
the shipment out on the street.
No, no, no, that's not
going to work that way.
We've been all through this.
We have no other choice.
Robbing banks,
manufacturing Hoffman lenses
until we're blue in the face.
We're just not going to reach
enough people!
We've got to find new people,
strong people-- people to work with us.
That's my baby.
Just leaving--
you know, your door was open.
Just wanted to close it--
didn't want no one breaking in.
Neighborhood watch.
Yeah, well, let me touch your face.
- Mmm, it's good.
- That's fine.
Now your hands.
- Good.
- Eh, you're a working man.
- Yes, sir.
Here, it's the revolution.
Let me show you.
I got to be going right now.
Maybe some other time, huh?
Huh?
This world may have blinded me,
but the Lord has let me see.
You'll be back.
You'll be back!
I've been hearing something
on the streets
the last couple of weeks.
Weird stuff.
Some sort of epidemic of violence
what they've been saying.
I was talking to one old boy,
he's from San Anselmo.
He told me they got
some sort of cult up there.
End of the world kind of stuff.
Well, what are they doing?
You know, shooting people,
robbing banks.
Same old thing as always.
Whole lot of people gone crazy
over some nutty dream they just had.
You want to know the truth?
This kind of shit happens
the end of every century.
It does-- it's just people
afraid to face the future.
It's all it is.
Hey, what's happening?
I was inside there a while.
All kinds of cardboard boxes,
some kind of lab set.
What do you mean?
There's no singing.
It's a tape recorder.
Leave it alone, man.
It ain't none of my business,
ain't none of yours.
Yeah, but our boy, Gilbert's
in there helping them.
Look, I got a job now.
And I plan on keeping it.
I'm walking a white line all the time.
I don't bother nobody,
nobody bothers me.
You better start doing the same.
White line's in the middle of the road.
It's the worst place to drive.
I'll see you later.
Step down.
Watch it.
Easy, easy, this way.
All right, now we're going
to cross the road.
It's dirt here.
[sirens blare]
Quickly, quickly!
- Go, go!
- Come on, this way-- this way.
Frank!
We know who you are.
Leave us alone!
We know you!
Don't hurt him either.
God help me!
Though I walk through the valley
of the shadow of death,
I will fear no evil.
Thy rod and Thy staff will--
Jesus! Jesus!
[groaning]
Come on!
Come on in and join the party, man.
You go with them.
[helicopter blades whir]
[sirens]
Somebody start World War III?
Oman's collection puts passion
before fashion.
Dash and trash are back.
Out goes glitter
and in comes divine excess.
The fall collection revels
in freedom of expression.
Gay abandon rushes to meet
the roaring '90s.
What's your problem?
I said, what's your problem?
How are you today, sir?
- Okay, how's it going?
- Fine, thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Here you are, sir.
Thank you.
Hey, buddy,
you going to pay for that or what?
Look, buddy,
I don't want no hassle today.
Either pay for it or put it back.
Huh.
[male voice]
Sleep, sleep, sleep...
Can you believe it?
She didn't even go to Lamaze class.
I told her,
for yourself and for the baby,
go!
Did Bob make you go
to John and Mary Ellen's last night?
I was shocked,
she served blue corn tortillas.
It's so dated.
[both laugh]
So depressed,
I don't know what to do.
Hey, go for it, man.
It's easy for you to say,
you got the promotion.
Look, it'll come, all right?
Just don't worry about it.
The feeling is definitely there.
It's a new morning in America--
fresh, vital.
The old cynicism is gone.
We have faith in our leaders.
We're optimistic
as to what becomes of it all.
It really boils down
to our ability to accept.
We don't need pessimism.
There are no limits.
It figures it would be
something like this.
Uh.
Excuse me.
You know, you look like your head
fell in the cheese dip
back in 1957.
You, you're okay.
This one, real fucking ugly.
Oh.
You see, I take these glasses off,
she looks like a regular person,
doesn't she, huh?
Put them back on, formaldehyde face--
That's what we got.
That's enough out of you.
Get out or I call the cops.
Call the cops,
you know what you need?
You need a Brazilian
plastic surgeon, that--
I've got one that can see.
[mumbling into their watches]
He's a tall Caucasian male,
doesn't appear armed,
wearing sunglasses.
I don't like this one bit.
Not one bit.
[car honking]
That's like pouring perfume on a pig.
All right, suppose we settle down?
That's far enough.
Where'd you get those glasses?
Tooth fairy.
I'll bet.
We got him.
Nick yourself shaving this morning?
You look as shitty to us
as we do to you.
Impossible.
It would be easier if we don't have
to splatter your brains.
Just take it easy.
Now, you stumbled onto something here.
Maybe we can all benefit
from this slight misunderstanding.
Now, let's go someplace quiet
so we can talk this over.
So you bastards die
just like we do.
[siren wails]
[gasps]
I have come here
to chew bubble gum
and kick ass.
And I'm all out of bubble gum.
Near the entrance.
Has a shotgun.
White male, 30s, long hair.
Mama don't like tattletales.
Wearing sunglasses.
And who are you, little fella?
Come to show them where I am.
Not nice.
Drop it!
I said drop it!
Beat your feet.
[tires screech]
Take it easy.
Just want a little ride out of here.
Close the door.
Drive.
Not too fast.
They're gone.
Just keep driving.
Where am I going?
You married?
Yes.
Please don't lie to me.
No.
Live alone?
[sighs]
Your place.
I'd rather not do that.
I'm afraid I must insist.
[dog barks]
Hi, Holly.
Hmph.
Look, I don't know what you want.
Oh, just quiet.
Whoo.
It's like a drug.
Wearing these glasses makes you high,
but, oh, you come down hard.
Now look, things turned out
a little sour for me today.
You're not the only one.
Yeah, well, I'm sorry.
But I needed you to get away.
No, you have two guns.
You're not sorry.
You're in charge.
Look lady, we're in trouble.
The whole world's in trouble.
They're all around us
and we never knew it.
You can only see them
with these special glasses.
I swear to you we're being controlled
by these things!
I don't know what they are
or where they came from,
but we got to stop them!
- All right.
I'll do whatever you want
whenever you want.
Just don't hurt me, please.
Listen to what I'm saying to you.
Okay.
You're fighting the forces of evil
that none of us can see
without sunglasses.
Take a look.
If you want me to look
through your sunglasses,
I'll look through your sunglasses.
If I don't see what you see,
I'm going to see it anyway.
Yeah, you have it your way, huh?
It's not my way.
It's your way.
Don't fuck with me.
I'm thirsty.
Go ahead.
Look, uh,
I'm sorry I have to be here, huh?
[pours wine]
So, your name's Holly, right?
Holly Thompson.
It's a pretty name.
So what do you do?
Assistant program director,
Cable 54.
A TV station?
Yes.
They're sending some kind
of signals out of TV sets.
No, no.
I'm all right.
Holly Thompson,
8634 Circleview Drive.
Yes, I'll hold.
[sirens approach]
Frank, we're ready when you are.
Frank.
Don't let nobody see you.
I've had a rough couple of days.
I don't want nothing to do with you.
How many people did you kill?
Not people.
You crazy son of a bitch!
- I got to show you something.
- No, you ain't showing me nothing!
I got a wife and kids.
So, leave me alone.
Get out of here.
[trash men argue]
Watch this.
Oh, no.
Yo.
One week's pay.
It's the best I could do.
Wait!
Hey, you better find yourself
someplace to hide
and keep praying
nobody ever finds you.
Try these on.
Look, you crazy mother,
- Put these on.
- Hey, stay away from me!
I'm telling you,
you dumb son of a bitch--
I'm trying to save you
and your family's life.
You couldn't even save your own.
I'm giving you a choice.
Either put on these glasses
or start eating that trash can.
Not this year.
Okay.
All right.
- Okay.
- Come on.
Come on.
I don't want to fight you.
- Come on!
- I don't want to fight you.
- Stop it!
- No!
Fuck!
Shit!
Put on the glasses.
Man, I told you,
I didn't want to be in--
You dirty motherfucker.
Take a look.
Put 'em on.
No!
Shit.
Oh, man, I'm sorry, man.
You f--
Fuck!
Put the glasses on!
Put 'em on!
Fuck you.
Look.
Look at them, they're everywhere.
Maybe they can see.
Alley Fifth and Spring.
Now hold on.
You ain't the first son of a bitch
to wake up out of their dream.
[rumble]
What's that?
Brother, life's a bitch.
And she's back in heat.
[police siren]
I want a room.
Ain't love grand?
Don't wear them glasses too long.
Starts to feel like a knife
turning in your skull.
How long have they been there?
Who knows.
What are they,
where do they come from?
Well, they ain't from Cleveland.
Look, man, I don't need
that kind of shit!
What are we going to do?
We're going to wait.
Wait wait for what?
You know, that really answers
my fucking question.
Well, when you get
some kind of master plan
you let me know, huh?
We can't be the only
ones who can see.
We got to find the people
who made these.
Yeah, if any of them are still alive.
A long time ago
things were different, man.
My own daddy
took me down to the river,
kicked my ass, told me
about the power and the glory.
I was saved.
He changed when I was little.
Turned mean.
Started tearing at me.
So I ran away when I was 13.
Tried to cut me, once.
Big old razor blade.
Held it up against my throat.
I said, "Daddy, please."
Just kept moving back and forth.
Like he was sawing down a little tree.
Maybe they've always been with us.
Those things out there.
Maybe they love it.
Seeing us hate each other.
Watching us kill each other off.
Feeding on our own
cold fucking hearts.
I got news for 'em.
Going to be hell to pay.
Because I ain't
Daddy's little boy no more.
Frank?
There's a meeting tonight.
Be at this address at 11 o'clock.
Watch out no one follows you.
[spins and clicks gun cylinder]
World needs a wake-up call.
We're going to phone it in.
Hey, brothers.
There's something new going down.
They're using candy floss packages.
It's like building a park
for a toxic waste dump.
They colorized it.
Here's a list of safe houses.
You're going to memorize it
and then destroy the paper.
What's a safe house?
What kind of gun is that?
Hey, Frank.
- Hey.
- Hey, glad you made it.
Oh, you can take your sunglasses off.
We're all human in here.
Memorize these safe houses.
Brand new.
Got the first shipment today.
They won't hurt.
There's less interference.
Go ahead.
There is a signal broadcast
every second of every day
through our television sets.
Even when the set is turned off.
- The brain receives the input...
- Hey.
- Hi.
- You have any trouble getting here?
No, we made it fine.
Good, the city's crawling with cops
looking for us.
And most of the cops are human.
They've been told that we're commies
trying to bring down the government.
And some of them are being recruited.
Creatures are trading wealth, power.
You mean people
are joining up with them?
Most of us just sell out right away.
Then all of a sudden we get promoted.
Our bank accounts get bigger.
We start buying new houses, cars.
Perfect, isn't it?
We'll do anything to be rich.
Look around the environment we live in.
Carbon dioxide, fluorocarbons,
and methane
have increased since 1958.
Earth is being acclimatized.
They are turning our atmosphere
into their atmosphere.
What do these things want
and why are they here?
It's in our best interests.
They're free enterprisers.
The Earth is just another
developing planet.
Their third world.
We are like a natural resource
to them--
deplete the planet,
move on to another.
They want benign indifference.
They want us drugged.
We could be pets.
We could be food.
But all we really are is livestock.
Now, we need an assault unit.
Someone to hit them hard
when the time comes.
You've got it.
Ever see their disappearing act?
Once.
What's that?
They all wear these expensive watches.
Turns out they're really
two-way radios.
You can listen to their broadcast.
There's something else.
Some kind of secret code
or hidden control.
They push a button
and then all of a sudden-- bang!
They're gone.
I've been trying to figure it out.
All right, now everybody listen up.
Now, we're obviously not getting
to enough people
because look at our numbers tonight.
There should be twice
as many of us here.
We're getting too sloppy,
that's all there is to it.
Now, their detection
is becoming more effective.
So we have to be more careful.
Stay aware of keeping up appearances.
Go to work, punch your time clocks.
Do what's expected of you.
We've gotten reckless.
And the movement's suffering for it.
Time to stop talking about it
trying to figure out how it happened.
Now we start spilling some blood!
[group clamors]
Wait a minute, it's not working!
We don't stand a chance
with a few guns and grenades.
So what are we supposed to do?
We bide our time.
We seek out and locate their signal
and shut it off!
Wake people up!
Now, Dave here works at KRDA.
He claims that the signal
may be coming from one place.
KRDA is clear.
The transmission is going out clean.
The signal is coming
from somewhere else.
How does she know?
[crowd grumbles]
All right, this is the point.
It's important to find out exactly
where this signal's coming from.
And the only way we can do--
I got to go talk to someone.
If you're approached by anyone
to work for these creatures,
by all means accept.
Gain their trust.
Make them believe
they can buy you off.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
I thought I'd killed you.
I thought so too.
I didn't know.
I'm so sorry.
Look, I just want to--
Can we just--
Get out!
[continuous gun fire]
[siren wails]
- They're killing everybody.
- I got to find her.
- Wait a minute, man, are you crazy?
- I got to see if she's all right.
Just stay back!
There's nothing you can do out there.
If I can get this thing working,
we can listen in.
- Frank,
- What?
- What!
- Get set to shoot.
- Oh, shit!
[loud rumble]
- What was that?
- I don't know.
[woman's voice] Attention,
your wristwatch has malfunctioned.
This entryway is temporary
and will disappear in ten seconds.
- Get in there.
- What?
- Move.
- I don't know what's down there.
- Now!
- Oh, shit.
[woman's voice]
Seven seconds.
Six seconds.
Five seconds.
Four seconds.
Three seconds.
Two seconds.
One second.
[intercom] If you need assistance
in finding your destination,
bilingual instructions are posted
at the end of each corridor.
What language is that?
I don't know.
Where the hell are we?
I think we're under the city.
Maybe some kind
of underground base or something.
There got to be a way out.
I just hope that nobody
saw us dropping in.
[radio] Operation Steel Fist
has been a complete success.
All security stations stand down
to operational--
Right.
- We have eliminated the terrorists.
- Okay.
We got 'em, we wiped them out!
It's a win, man.
They got to meet the A-team.
[distant applause]
I'm hearing something.
[applause closer]
Our projections show
that by the year 2025,
not only America,
but the entire planet
will be under the protection
and the dominion
of this power alliance.
The gains have been substantial,
both for ourselves and for you,
the human power elite.
You have given us entrée
to the resources we need
in our ongoing quest for
multidimensional expansion.
And in return, the per capita income
of each of you here tonight
has grown, in this year alone,
by an average 39o/o.
And I've just received word that
our forces have won a major victory.
The underground terrorist network
has been destroyed
here on the West Coast.
We are off crisis alert.
The situation is normal again.
[crowd applause and cheers]
How you doing boys?
I didn't know you'd been recruited.
Welcome aboard.
You know you boys really
should have dressed for the party
now you can afford it.
I got to tell you,
I sure am proud to be here.
You seen the whole place?
I haven't had a chance to yet.
Come on, I'll show you around.
You know, I knew me and you
had a lot in common
first time we met.
[speaker] Money isn't
the nicest thing in life,
- Hey, waiter,
- [speaker] the only thing.
Thank you, buddy.
Excuse me,
where the hell are we?
Back stage at the show, boys.
I'll admit it is a little funky,
but it serves its purpose.
How did you get here,
use one of these little portable jobs?
I know we ain't supposed to use 'em
except in cases of emergency,
but they're so much fun.
Now, you think that's something?
Take a look at this.
Go on, take a closer look.
[intercom] Attention commuters,
flight Alpha 7 to Andromeda
is now ready for boarding.
Please step in
to the transmission platform.
That's where they come from.
All carry-on luggage
must be held securely.
Thank you for waiting and we hope
you have a pleasant trip.
I don't know how it works exactly,
but it has to do with some sort
of gravitational lens deal--
bending the light or some damn thing.
But you can move from place to place,
world to world if you want to.
You see, the whole thing works
like one big airport.
Boys, let me tell you,
they got their act together.
Believe you me.
Evening, boys.
Looking sharp.
Wait until you see what
I'm going to show you now.
And here we got the brains
of the whole operation.
That's where the signal goes out
from here to the satellite.
We bump it out all over the world.
Pretty fancy, huh?
Not too familiar with it myself.
Well, boys, as far as we go.
A technique called
multispectral analysis.
This would allow space sensors
to penetrate natural barriers
and camouflage--
Can you get us inside?
I've never seen the inside
of a TV studio before.
You look like the gentleman to ask.
Well, I guess it wouldn't be
that much problem.
You see them boys over there?
Friends of mine.
Hey, fellas, I got a couple
of my buddies here.
Thought I'd give them the grand tour.
Think we can go inside?
Be serious.
You have your authorization cards?
Right here.
Watch the door.
[knocks on glass]
Soundproof.
- Where's that signal?
- It's up on the roof, I think.
Holly works in there.
If she made it,
maybe we can find her.
Then we can go to the roof
and break that signal, man.
Wait boys, wait
you're making a big mistake.
You made the mistake.
No, no, you got to listen to me.
I thought you boys understood.
It's business, that's all it is.
You still don't get it, do you boys?
There ain't no countries anymore.
No more good guys.
They're running the whole show.
They own everything--
the whole goddamn planet.
They can do whatever they want.
What's wrong with having it good,
for a change.
And they're going to let us
have it good if we just help 'em.
They're going to leave us alone.
Let us make some money.
You can have a little taste
of that good life too.
Now I know you want it--
hell, everybody does.
You do it to your own kind.
What's the threat?
We all sell out every day.
Might as well be on the winning team.
See you, boys.
Let's go!
Is this the two minute break
or the thirty second break?
I think it's the thirty second break.
They dropped 12,
I guess we must be running long.
I think so.
We are experiencing
a technical difficulty.
What the hell's going on?
Come on.
[people clamoring]
Get down!
[whispers] Now what?
Find out where the hell we are.
Excuse me.
- Come on, man.
- Wait a second.
Do you know Holly Thompson?
Come on, man, I mean it.
Holly Thompson, assistant program
something-or-other.
- Where is she?
- I, I...
[intercom] Security alert--
sections delta and x-ray
report to the fourth floor immediately.
Who's Holly?
[scream]
Oh, shit.
Well, I hate to interrupt you folks,
but could someone please guide me
how to get to the roof.
Security.
How do I get to the roof?
There's an elevator through there.
Turn to your left,
it's at the end of the hall.
Thank you very much.
Well?
Well, there's got to be more than
one way to get up there.
Security 9-5-0.
Lock the elevators down.
They're on the move.
[screams]
[beeping]
I hear them on the 19th floor
above me.
We got you.
We're on the 21st
we'll be waiting for 'em.
Go, up.
Holly!
[alarm beeps]
- Come on, come on!
[intercom]
Security alert.
Intruders are here--
head for the roof.
Repeat.
Intruders--
Let's go!
[gunshot]
Frank,
you and Holly clear?
[woman]
I'm clear.
Are you?
Don't do it.
Don't interfere,
you can't win.
Drop your weapon.
Stand away from the dish
or we will open fire.
Come inside with me.
You have ten seconds.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven.
Six.
Fuck it.
The Oscar winners gave
a press conference
and "How to Buy a Sailboat" as--
[man]
Gloria, you look like shit.
[man] I'm out of here.
[woman] What happened?
What's wrong?
All the sex and violence on the screen
has gone too far for me.
I'm fed up with it.
Filmmakers like George Romero
and John Carpenter
have to show some restraint.
They're simply--
You're filled with lightning
when you hit the road.
You're feeling that V6 power
as you take control.
Nothing can stop you now.
You're moving on.
Hey, what's wrong, baby?