[ Cows Mooing ]
Ahh.
[ Snoring ]
Good morning, Mr. Basset.
This is your wake-up call.
Please move your ass.
Stampede ! Stampede, Earl !
Get outta the way !
You dumbshit.
[ Laughing ]
I was in a stampede once.
- Three hundred head
goin' hellbent for the horizon.
- Hellbent for the horizon.
Exactly how many cows
are required for a stampede, Earl ?
Is it like three or more ?
ls there a minimum speed ?
I wish a stampede up your ass.
No breakfast ?
I did it yesterday.
It was bologna and beans.
No.
It was eggs.
I did eggs... over easy.
The hell you did !
Bologna and beans.
It's your turn.
Well, I guess when I'm your age,
I'll forget what I eat too.
Ow ! Goddamn it !
I ask you, is this a job
for intelligent men ?
Show me one. I'll ask him.
If we were real serious about money,
we'd quit being hired hands.
Handymen, Earl.
We are handymen.
Yeah, yeah.
We should quit this job...
and find ourselves
some real employment.
Are you gonna give up
all this personal freedom ?
I don't know.
[ Younger Man Laughing ] Freeway !
What's on the agenda for today ?
- It's garbage day.
- Oh, man ! Already ?
What's Nestor payin' us ?
Fifty bucks. And that's
forty-seven bucks more than we got.
Burt and Heather's place
is closer.
Let's do their linoleum today
and do the garbage tomorrow.
Nestor's not home tomorrow.
Look, we don't dig today,
we don't get paid today.
Damn it, Valentine,
you never plan ahead.
You never take the long view.
Here it is Monday, and I'm
already thinking of Wednesday.
It is Monday, right ?
Hey, who the hell's that ? That's not
what's-his-name, the grad student ?
Nah. He graduated.
Must be the new one.
The new one ?
That's supposed to be a girl.
Yah-hoo !
You will have
long, blonde hair,
big green eyes,
world-class breasts,
ass that won't quit
and legs that go all the way up !
Hi ! I'm Rhonda. Rhonda LeBeck.
I'm up here for the semester.
- Yeah, geography.
- Geology.
Yeah, well, actually seismology.
Earthquakes.
You two must be
Val and Earl.
- I've heard all about you.
- We deny everything.
I've got a question for you.
Do you know if anybody's
doing any drilling or blasting...
- or anything like that ?
- [ Laughing ]
Around here ?
No, ma'am.
Well, I'm supposed
to monitor the seismographs.
- You know, they measure vibrations.
- Vibrations in the ground.
Yeah.
Well, I've been getting
some really strange readings.
The school's had machines here
for three years, and we've never
recorded anything like this.
We'll ask around. You know,
see if anyone's heard anything.
Thanks.
God, I hope they're not broken.
I might have to bag the whole semester.
Anyway, sorry to bother you.
No problem.
Nice meetin' you.
Hope you get it all sorted out.
If you wanted,
we could take a look at those, uh,
seismographs for her,
if you want.
What the hell do we know
about seismographs ?
Nothing. But it sure might be
a slick way to get to know her.
Why ?
Damn it, Valentine.
You don't go for any girl unless she
fits that stupid list of yours.
Well, sure.
Yeah, and it's dumber
than my hind end.
I mean,
like that Bobby Lynn Dexter.
Tammy Lynn Baxter.
It don't matter.
They're all the same... dead weight.
"Ooh ! I broke a nail !"
[ Sighs ]
Makes my skin crawl.
Well, I'm a victim
of circumstance.
I thought you call it
your pecker.
Hey, pizza face !
Melvin ? Melvin, you touch
that truck and die.
Oh, man, I'm really shakin'.
Thanks, Walter.
These are hollow points, but they're not
Hydro-shock hollow points.
- I thought bullets were bullets.
- Hi, guys. What you been doin' ?
We ran into
that new college student, that Rona.
Rhonda. She's having trouble
with her, uh...
uh, uh... things.
You know, those college kids turn up
oil or uranium or something out there,
next thing the Feds
will be at our door.
- "Sorry. Time to move. Eminent domain."
- Down, honey, down.
Yeah, Burt.
The way you worry,
you'll have a heart attack...
before you get a chance
to survive World War Ill.
We'll see.
[ Shrill Squeaking Noise ]
Hey, guys, listen.
Bearing going out. What do you think ?
- Could be.
- Catch you later, Chang.
We got a schedule to keep.
Oh, yeah.
See, we plan ahead.
That way we don't do anything right now.
Earl explained it to me.
[ Rumbling Noise ]
- Cocktail ?
- You bet.
[ Fly Buzzing ]
Well, I'll tell ya. Nobody
handles garbage better than we do.
Yep.
Come on, Earl.
This is low.
We have got to set our sights
a little bit higher.
** [ Rock And Roll On The Radio ]
Melvin, why don't you
give us a hand ?
Most of this shit
is yours anyway.
Listen, run to the store and
pick me up a six-pack. I'll pay for it.
Son, beer is for adults.
You know, not having a plan
is what keeps us doing jobs like this.
Just doin' jobs like this
is you draggin' your feet.
Are you gonna stand there
and tell me in broad daylight...
that I'm the reason
we're still in Perfection ?
You know how close I am
to leavin' this place right now ?
I'll call that little bluff.
How close ?
Ah, shit ! Goddamn !
- [ Laughing ]
- Jesus Christ ! Goddamn !
Don't forget the TV.
- What're you bringin'
that vacuum cleaner for ?
- I like this vacuum cleaner.
- Hell, you never use it.
- It's good for parts.
And, besides, maybe we'll hire a maid.
Had you thought about that ?
Get in the truck.
Guys !
Hey, guys, wait !
Hi.
Sorry, Nancy. We're not
delivering firewood anymore.
- We're headin' for Bixby permanent.
- Oh, sure. Oh, my God !
- You really are !
- [ Pogo Stick Hopping ]
Hey, Mindy,
what's the count ?
[ Mindy ]
Six hundred and forty.
Guys, I don't need firewood.
I have this big order and
have to build my pottery kiln.
Come on. It'll be
at least a month's work.
I'll throw in lunches.
And beer !
[ Valentine ]
Ah-wa-wa-wa-woo !
I can't believe we said no
to free beer !
We did it ! We faced temptation
and did not bend !
Goddamn !
Praise the Lord !
Now there's nothin', and I mean nothin',
between us and Bixby but nothin' !
- Yeah ! [ Laughing ]
- Yeah !
Hey, look at that guy !
[ Earl ] That's one job I'd never do.
Working around electricity.
Hey ! Hold up.
- That's Edgar Deems.
- [ Chuckles ] Come on.
He only wears
that one damn jacket.
That's him, I'm tellin' ya.
Man, oh, man.
He sure must've been drunk this time.
Edgar, get your butt
down from there !
[ Sighs ]
[ Valentine ]
Well, shit.
- We can't leave him up there.
- [ Chuckling ]
Thank you, Edgar.
You owe me on this one,
you damned ol' boozehound.
One of these days, you're gonna have to
get your ass on a wagon and stay there.
It's not like I don't have
better things to do than climb towers...
and drag your hairy ass down.
Jesus !
[ Valentine ]
Was it a heart attack, Doctor ?
No.
He died of dehydration.
Thirst.
That doesn't make any sense. That takes
a couple of days, doesn't it ?
Maybe even three or four.
You mean he sat up there
three or four days ?
[ Earl ] He sat up there
and just died of thirst ?
[ Sheep Bleating ]
Hmph.
[ Screaming ]
You reckon he hated
Perfection more than us ?
Do you suppose
he wanted to kill himself ?
Come on ! Somebody must've
chased him up there.
You mean someone that ain't scared
of a Winchester rifle ?
Then what'd they do ? Camp out
down below and wait for him to die ?
[ Earl ]
What the hell ?
[ Brakes Squealing ]
Whew ! What the shit ?
Hey, Fred !
Hey, there, Old Fred !
[ Knocking ]
Hey, Fred !
Fred ? Fred ?
- [ Earl ] This is weird.
- This is real weird.
- Oh, Jesus !
- What the hell's goin' on ?
I mean, what the hell
is goin' on ?
[ Horn Honking ]
Get the hell outta here !
- There's a killer on the loose !
- What ?
A murderer, man ! A real psycho !
He's cuttin' people's heads off.
I'm not kiddin' !
They're pullin' our chain.
Yeah.
[ Screeching ]
What ?
Shit.
[ Yelling ]
Howard !
[ Screaming ]
- Carmine ?
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming ]
Who could be doing it ?
I'm not accusing anybody.
Just some cattle are missing.
Are you serious ?
Old Fred's dead ?
You're bullshittin' me.
What happened to Fred ?
- No worse than Edgar.
- What happened to Edgar ?
- You won't believe it.
- I need one of those candy bars.
I don't believe this. The phone is dead.
Walter, your phone is dead !
- I didn't do it.
- Nestor, what's happening ?
- Somebody killed Old Fred.
- What's going on ?
Val, you gotta get to Bixby,
and you gotta get the police
up here. And step on it.
Consider it stepped on.
[ Valentine ]
Man !
We decided to leave this place
one damn day too late, you know ?
Yeah. Well, there's sure as hell
nothing to stop us now.
Everybody we know
between here and Bixby is already dead.
[ Earl ]
Look out !
Is there some higher force
at work here ?
I mean, are we askin'
too much of life ?
Where the hell
are these guys ?
What are they doin' ?
Blastin' ?
Hey ! Where are you guys ?
It's not like there's
another road, assholes !
Val ? Val !
[ Flies Buzzing ]
- Jesus ! I don't believe this !
- You're hung up.
- I am not !
- [ Engine Revving ]
You're hung up,
I tell ya !
You're gonna burn the clutch !
- You could break an axle like that.
- Could you shut up ?
Hey ! I don't need
to spend the night out here.
Crybaby.
- [ Heather ]
Could it have been coyotes ?
- [ Burt ] No way.
Hey ! It's Val and Earl.
They shouldn't be here already.
- Thought you two were in Bixby by now.
- You're never gonna believe this.
- Mom !
- Oh, my God !
- [ Heather ] Burt, be careful.
- [ Melvin ] Eew, unreal.
- Where'd you get it ?
- I didn't know we had it.
- It's disgusting.
- Some kind of snake ?
- It's more like an eel to me.
- Eels live in the water.
- Big mother slug, maybe.
- Don't touch !
Relax. It's dead.
Hey, it must've grabbed us !
That's why the truck stalled out.
- The next time I tell you
I'm not hung up--
- This stalled out your truck ?
It'd have to be
one strong son of a bitch.
Whew ! Stinks too.
I'll give you boys $5 for this.
Twenty.
- Okay, ten !
- Fifteen.
- Okay, fifteen.
- Damn right, fifteen.
I don't believe you guys.
Could be a snake !
Some kind of mutation.
Yeah.
Whatever it is,
just one of these couldn't eat up Fred
and his whole flock of sheep.
So you think there are
more of 'em out there ?
I'm dead. Let's put this stuff up
in the morning.
Uh-uh.
We have to go to Bixby
in the morning.
- The cinder blocks are in.
- Oh, the cinder blo-- Oh, my God !
Just keep lookin'
at that beautiful sky.
That's the sky that's gonna be over
our roof every night when we're done.
[ Man ]
What if we don't finish the roof ?
- Then we can look at the sky
all the time.
- [ Chuckling ]
- [ Generator Motor Sputtering ]
- Oh, that damn thing.
Maybe it's time we buy
a new generator, huh ?
It's gone !
What do you mean,
"It's gone" ?
You sure this
is where it was ?
It was right here !
There's the cord.
Hold this.
Maybe the ground caved in. There's
a lot of mines and stuff around here.
Well, don't then.
You don't wanna fall in.
- Let's go.
- God, what is that stink ?
- [ Rumbling Noise ]
- You hear that ?
[ Woman ]
Come on.
Come on. Let's just go.
Let's go back to town
or something. Please, Jim !
Maybe it's a geological thing
like natural gas.
Or a geyser.
They stink like that.
Remember in Yellowstone ?
- Jim !
- [ Yelling ] Something's got me !
- No, Jim, no !
- Something's got me down here !
[ Screaming ]
Oh, Jim !
Oh, God, oh ! Get something.
Get me out of here !
[ Screaming ]
Oh, oh ! Jim !
Oh, God,
something's got me.
- Please get me out !
- Jim !
[ Screaming ]
Help me !
Jim !
[ Roaring ]
[ Screaming ]
** [ Country-Western Music
Plays On The Radio ]
Oh, my God.
** [ Country-Western Continues ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Rumbling Noise ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
- Mindy, smile.
- Honey, don't look so afraid.
- It's not gonna hurt you.
- Mindy, look up. Smile.
- Come on.
- Hold it.
Melvin, get outta there !
- Ol' Chang, slick as snot,
and I ain't lyin'.
- Fifteen lousy bucks.
A man who plans ahead.
Look, we arm ourselves,
we set perimeters, we stand guard.
Any of those snake things
show up here, we make 'em extinct.
- All right !
- Burt, get serious.
Yeah !
You make it sound like a war.
- What do you people got
against being prepared ?
- Rambo.
Walter's got a C.B. radio.
Why aren't you calling somebody
in Bixby ? The police--
We can't reach outside the valley
because of the mountains.
Melvin, you're next.
Sit down. Look scared.
The phone's out.
The road's out. We're on our own.
You two are just loving it,
aren't you ?
Nancy, don't get personal about this !
We gotta do something.
Hell, yes !
We are completely cut off.
We got the cliffs to the north,
mountains to the east and the west.
That's why Heather and me
settled here in the first place.
Geographic isolation.
- There's gotta be some way
we can get help.
- This isn't the moon !
What are you gonna do,
walk the 38 miles to Bixby ?
Hey, there's Walter's
saddle horses.
That's it.
You're welcome to them.
Somebody could ride to Bixby.
That's not bad.
Who's best on a horse ?
Walter, they better be fast.
We don't wanna be stuck
on a couple of canners.
Those snake things
couldn't travel that fast.
Shit, for all you know
they could fly.
What do you want ?
This Colt or Edgar's old rifle ?
Rifle.
- Earl, here's some Swiss cheese
and some bullets.
- Thanks, Walter.
- You guys all set ?
- Ready as we'll ever be.
Gonna see if we can find
that college girl, tell her
to get her ass back into town.
Good idea. We'll swing
by the doctor's place and see
if they went into Bixby.
Wait a minute, guys.
Y'all have to take somethin' that packs
more of a punch than that 30-30.
Why don't you take
one of our Browning autos ?
Or better than that.
Why don't you take my Model 70 ?
It's .375 H&H Mag.
Thanks, Heather.
Well, I hope we don't need to use it.
[ Screaming ]
It's got me !
- [ Laughing ]
- Melvin !
Damn it, Melvin !
[ Nancy ]
He's only kidding.
You came that close.
Too close.
No more games.
Melvin, one of these days
somebody's gonna kick your ass.
** [ Country-Western Music
Playing On The Radio ]
Doctor ?
Man, I hate this shit.
Wait a minute.
The car's gone.
We just missed 'em, that's all.
Where the hell's the goddamn
golden oldie comin' from ?
** [ Music Continues On Radio ]
** [ Music Grows Louder ]
- What the hell's this ?
- You got me.
Here's the plan. We don't even stop.
We ride like hell.
Tonight we'll keep right on goin'.
We'll walk the horses.
That is the plan. Goddamn,
what the hell are those things ?
- How could they bury
a whole station wagon ?
- Why would they do it ?
[ Whinnying ]
Come on, git, git !
Walter wouldn't know a decent horse
if it bit him in the ass.
Wait a minute. They got wind
of something they don't like.
Git.
Something's goin' on here.
[ Valentine ]
I don't see anything anywhere !
[ Whinnying ]
Hey !
- Are you okay ?
- Yeah. What about my hor--
[ Whinnying ]
What in the name of--
That's how they get you.
They're under the goddamn ground.
- What the hell are they ?
- Sons of bitches !
Must be a million of 'em !
[ Screeching ]
Nope. Just one.
[ Screeching, Roaring ]
Come on.
[ Gunshots ]
He's gaining on us !
Look !
We can make it !
Stupid son of a bitch.
It knocked itself cold.
Cold, my ass !
He's dead.
We killed it.
We killed it !
Fuck you !
[ Laughing ]
Hey, guys.
What's goin' on ?
Did you notice anything weird
a minute ago ? I mean, it just happen--
What's that ?
[ Earl ] All right, together.
One, two, three.
[ Gasps ]
Jesus Christ !
Does it smell like that
'cause it's dead ?
[ Flies Buzzing ]
I don't see any eyes.
Must be totally subterranean.
And those tentacles.
Yeah.
You know, I think they shoot
right out of its mouth,
and they hook ya
and pull you right in.
Good thing we stopped it
before it killed anybody else.
Look, this is important,
you know.
This is like--
Well, let's just say it.
This is probably the biggest
zoological discovery of the century.
[ Valentine ]
Hey ! Hey, check this out.
I found the ass end.
Jesus, we really
caught something here.
- Wow !
- Man !
That's one big mother.
This must be the old boy
had your seismos working overtime.
Yeah.
It must push itself along
with these.
All of them pushing at once.
That's why it moved so fast.
This thing had sensors tripping
all over the place. No--
Rhonda, you ever heard
of anything like this before ?
Everybody knows about 'em.
We just didn't tell you.
Hell, man, no one ever saw
anything like this !
We're really onto something.
I'll tell you, ol' Chang don't
get his slick mitts on this
for no measly fifteen bucks.
You got that right.
- All right, here's the plan.
We need a flatbed.
- Right, with a winch.
- Five-ton, maybe.
- No, don't want a winch.
It'd tear it all up.
- A crane.
- Yeah, a crane with liftin' straps.
Hey, shut up. The way I figure it,
there are three more of these things.
- What ?
- Three more ?
I've got seismographs
all over this valley.
If you compare the readings,
here's one at 2:00 yesterday,
but here's one three miles away
at the exact same time.
- That's two. But here--
- We'll take your word for it.
- Where's your truck ?
- Just beyond that hill.
- [ Screaming ]
- What ? What ?
- Damn prairie dog burrow.
- Little sons of bitches.
Psst.
This way !
Up on that rock !
[ Screeching, Roaring ]
Looks like the one
that grabbed our truck.
- Where the hell's your truck ?
- Right over there.
Oh, man, I don't think
we can make that.
At least he can't climb.
Whew. Oh, man !
Live ones smell worse
than the dead ones.
[ Valentine ]
I got it, I got it.
They're mutations
caused by radiation.
No, no, no. The government built 'em.
Big surprise for the Russians.
There's nothing like them
in the fossil record. I'm sure.
Okay, so they predate
the fossil record.
That would make 'em
a couple billion years old.
And we've just never seen one
'til now. Right.
I vote for outer space.
No way these are local boys.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, haven't seen a sign
for hours.
Must be long gone.
Yeah, must be. Hey, why don't you
take a little stroll and find out ?
[ Sighs ]
We gotta do something.
"We gotta do something."
I don't know why "we" always
has to be "me" every damn time.
We, we, we. What do I look like ?
An expert on worms ?
Watch it, Valentine,
it's got a good six-foot reach.
Thank you, Earl.
Son of a bitch !
Son of a goddamn bitch !
Pardon my French.
Shit ! It's been waitin' here all this
time ? How's it know we're still here ?
It's got no eyes, right ?
Sure as hell can't smell us underground.
I say it's been listenin'.
Of course !
It senses seismic vibration.
It can hear every move we make,
especially on this rock.
It's a perfect conductor !
That means we're stuck.
That pisses me off !
[ Earl ] I hate to be crude,
but I gotta take care of business.
- [ Valentine ] Me too.
- [ Rhonda ] Same here.
[ Earl ]
Ahh.
Thanks.
Oh. No problem.
Anytime.
Well, what's the plan ?
The first thing we gotta do
is see if ol' Stumpy's still out there.
- Can I borrow that shovel ?
- Yeah.
[ Roaring ]
Doesn't he have a home
to go to ?
- That's why Edgar never got
down off that damn tower.
- I think I have an idea.
We're gonna have to come up
with some sort of plan or
he's gonna wait us to death.
- I was thinking--
- Why don't we make a run for it ?
We outran him yesterday.
Run for it ?
Running's not a plan.
Running's what you do when a plan fails.
You're not tryin' to think.
[ Valentine ] It ain't like we got
a hell of a lot of options.
There's always options.
We just gotta think of them, that's all.
Well, why don't you
start thinkin' ?
Why in the hell do I always
have to do all the thinking ?
- Who died and made you Einstein ?
- You know how to pole vault ?
We just stay where
he can't get us,
on these residual boulders.
My truck's parked
right next to one.
Stay on those
residual boulders !
That Tammy Lynn Baxter,
she do much pole vaulting ?
Shit !
That's pretty good.
That slimebag ain't gonna give us
much time once we hit that truck.
- I say we all jump together.
- Right.
Wait, wait, wait.
Okay, ready.
One, two, three !
Go, go, go, go !
Watch it, Val !
Move ! Move !
- [ Laughing ]
- Uh, can somebody, perhaps, help me ?
[ Valentine ]
No, no !
The snake things are just
their tongues or something.
These animals are huge !
I'm sorry. I'm... having
a real difficult time with this.
- [ Walter ] Come on, you guys. Answer.
- Hey, Walter.
- Where's Burt and Heather ?
- I can't reach 'em.
I guess they're still
driving around somewhere.
Rhonda, what's the name you call those
things ? Where do they come from ?
- I don't know.
- You're a scientist, aren't you ?
Aren't you supposed
to have a theory ?
Look, these creatures
are absolutely unprecedented.
- Yeah. But where do they come from ?
- Yeah !
It doesn't matter
where they come from.
No name. Hmph !
We discovered them.
We should name them !
Walter, forget the damn name !
Now me and Earl think we better
get the hell out of this valley.
Hang on, Val.
Let's not go off half-cocked.
Yeah ! Somebody's bound
to come check on us...
once they see the road is out
and the lines are down.
Yeah, that's how it works.
[ Flies Buzzing ]
- Or "suckoids."
- "Oids." Oids.
I like "snakeoids."
One of 'em comes near me, and I'll just
hit him with a five-pound pickax.
You don't understand, Nestor.
They come up from underneath
the ground and grab you.
They sense the slightest vibration
through the ground.
Even footsteps.
That's how they hunt.
Hey, so like
we don't vibrate, right ?
Maybe they won't even
come through here.
Maybe they'll leave us alone !
- [ Nestor ] Chain saw.
That's what I'll use.
- Hey, hey, hey, wake up !
Now, look !
You see,
they're headed right for us.
Look, they trapped Edgar here.
Grabbed Old Fred right here.
Nailed those two
poor suckers on the road,
and the doctor's place is here !
This valley is just
one long smorgasbord.
We have got to get out.
- I'm gonna go get Mindy.
- She's okay. I saw her
playing down the street.
That's what I like... "graboids" !
That's it, graboids !
Jesus, Walter.
We're gonna be sorry
if we don't give it a name.
Okay, Val, you say let's get outta here.
Where are we supposed to go ?
Well, Rhonda's got an idea
about that.
Yeah. See, they move very easily
through the Pleistocene alluvials.
The dirt. The loose soil
that covers the valley floor.
But they can't move
through rock.
- So we should
head west to the mountains.
- Up the old Jeep trail.
If those mountains are solid granite,
we'd be safe there.
- And we could hike
along them to Bixby if we--
- [ Scream ]
[ Melvin Laughing ]
I scared you, didn't I ?
You little ass wipe.
You don't knock it off, you're gonna be
shitting this basketball.
Pardon my French.
Mindy ?
Mindy !
[ Valentine ] It's gonna take us days
to get back with help.
- [ Earl ]
Nestor, we're not gonna leave you alone.
- [ Roaring ]
[ Melvin Screaming ]
- Damn it ! I'm gonna kick his ass !
- I'm gonna help you.
Melvin !
Where is
that little shit stain ?
[ Whimpering ]
Melvin, get your--
Get inside !
- Run ! Come on !
- Come on. Get in !
Jesus Christ, Walter,
you got a gun ?
- No ! What are we gonna do ?
- Be quiet, quiet !
- Where is he ?
- [ Rumbling Noise ]
[ Rhonda Whispering ]
Now remember,
no noise, no vibrations.
[ Pogo Stick Hopping ]
- Oh, no, Mindy.
- Stop, stop.
[ Miguel ]
Mindy, get off the pogo stick.
[ Boards Creaking ]
- Get her, Val !
- Mindy, come back !
[ Gasps ]
[ Mindy Screams ]
- Mindy--
- Shh, be quiet. Don't move.
- [ Gasps ]
- Mindy, get back.
- [ Screams ]
- Run ! Get in the house !
We gotta get him off.
It'll suck that truck down.
Go back for chrissake !
Jesus, here comes another one !
Run ! Come on !
Come on !
[ Screams ]
Get out of your pants !
Look out !
Run, run !
Run !
[ Earl ]
Don't look back. Come on !
- [ Rhonda ] Ow.
- [ Whispering ] Sorry.
- [ Whispering ] Rhonda, here.
- Thank you.
[ Whispering ]
So, what are we gonna do ?
You know,
how long 'til they go away ?
They got the patience of Job.
They sit and goddamn wait until they
hear something that sounds like lunch.
- We gotta have a plan.
- I got a plan.
You and Val
drive the truck to the mountain,
walk to Bixby, get some help.
Walter, those scumsuckers
ate our radials.
You can take my truck.
Nah, we need a major four-wheel drive
just to get up that Jeep trail.
Ahh, that trail's
all messed up.
[ Shrill Squeaking Noise ]
- [ Shrill Squeaking Noise ]
- Turn it off. Turn it off.
Pull it back.
I got it.
[ Roaring ]
Here, give me your hand !
[ Screaming ]
- Ohh !
- Son of a bitch.
Son of a bitch !
Come on. Let's go !
The roof !
Come on !
- [ Earl ] Jump ! You can do it !
- I can't !
Rhonda, don't stop.
Keep moving !
Oh, my God.
Hey !
You okay ?
[ Melvin ] Hey, what's goin' on ?
Where are you guys ?
What's up, man ?
What the hell are you doing up there ?
[ Whispering ]
Melvin, shut the hell up.
- Get up on your roof.
- No way !
[ Rumbling Noise ]
[ Screeching, Roaring ]
[ Gasping, Panting ]
Nestor.
Nestor !
Nancy, get up on your roofs.
Up on your roofs !
They come through the floor.
Oh, I don't know.
I can't believe it.
No tracks.
No sign. No spoor.
You'd think after eatin' all those sheep
they'd have to take a dump someplace.
Yeah. I don't understand it.
[ Burt On C.B. ]
Yo, Walter. This is Burt. Come back.
Walter ? Anybody copy ?
I'm waitin'.
- Walter, you there ? Come back !
- Okay, I got it.
Yo ! Who's mindin' the store,
for God sakes ?
Burt, listen. We found out
what's been killin' people.
- Say "over."
- Over.
Negative copy on that, Walter.
Check your frequency.
I'm on 22. Come back.
[ Valentine ]
Burt, can you hear me now ? Over.
Val, is that you ?
What're you doin' back already ?
Somethin' real weird's
goin' on over there.
They're up on top
of the roof.
Hey, I think
they're going for Burt.
[ Miguel ]
Oh, man ! They're going !
Burt, get out of your basement.
Take your radio.
You and Heather get up on your roof.
We'll talk later. Over.
- Up on the roof ?
What are you talking about ?
- Damn it, Burt.
- Listen to him. Something's wrong.
- Burt, Jesus Christ !
Get up on your roof !
The things !
They're under the ground.
They're bigger than we thought.
They're huge. They're coming after
you guys. They're comin' right now !
We don't see anything. What the hell
are you talking about ? Over.
Burt, they're under the ground.
They're under the ground.
They can dig like a son of a bitch.
Big monsters !
Underground !
Now get out ! Hurry !
[ Rumbling, Growling ]
[ Growling Continues ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Burt ]
Jesus Chri--
[ Rifle Shots ]
[ Yelling ]
Burt, come on.
- Magazine !
- Yeah !
Here !
[ Roaring Continues ]
[ Panting ] Broke into
the wrong goddamn rec room,
didn't you, you bastard ?
[ Burt ] We killed it !
You got that ? We killed
that motherhumper ! Come back.
[ Laughing ]
Uh, roger that, Burt.
And congratulations.
Be advised, however, there are two more.
Repeat, two more motherhumpers.
Burt got one !
He killed one !
- Way to go, dude !
- All right !
Yes ! Yes !
- I guess we don't get to make fun
of Burt's lifestyle anymore, huh ?
- Say, Burt.
- Any chance you can get
the other two ? Come back.
- Yeah.
One second, pal.
You didn't get penetration
even with the elephant gun.
Shit !
Good Lord !
[ Sighing ]
Val,
we can't get 'em.
I never figured on
having to shoot through dirt.
The best goddamn bullet stop
there is. Come back.
Let me see that.
Burt, listen. Forget shooting them.
Can you get to your truck ?
- No problem.
- Good. You have the only truck
that can get up that Jeep trail.
Listen.
Here's the plan.
You and Heather go for help.
You get to the mountains and--
- You guys ! You guys !
- [ Growling ]
- Come over.
- Hang on a sec.
He's up to something.
[ Valentine ] Well, if it isn't
our old pal Stumpy.
Bastard.
Rhonda, what do you think
it's trying to do now ?
Why do you keep asking me ?
What the--
Gee. Wow !
What the hell was that ?
[ Burt ] Breaker there, Earl.
What did you want us to do ?
Come back.
Hang on, Burt.
This bastard's trying something new.
- [ Rumbling ]
- Over.
[ Rumbling Continues ]
Oh.
They wasn't making no noise.
Why is he bothering them ?
It's like it's studying the buildings,
trying to figure them out.
They can feel our vibrations,
but they can't find us.
Looks to me like
they're coming up with a plan.
[ Valentine ]
Watch it, Nestor !
Jesus !
Shit ! Enough !
Aaah !
[ Valentine ]
Get off the ground, Nestor !
Get movin' ! Get outta there !
[ Earl ] Get off the ground !
Move it ! Move it !
[ Valentine ] No, Nestor !
That's no good. You gotta get higher.
Aaah !
[ Screaming ]
No way !
No way, man !
[ Melvin ] No ! No !
You guys gotta do somethin' !
You gotta do somethin' !
[ Valentine ]
Burt, Heather ?
You got us, Val.
Come on back. Over.
We're in deep shit over here.
We'll have to change that plan.
- Burt, cut it out !
- I think I scared 'im.
No use goin' for help. We'd be dead
long before you'd ever get back.
Val, we're with you.
Tell us what you wanna do.
This one's gonna tear this town
out from under us.
We're all gonna have to get out
of here together... now.
Okay, Val. We're comin' after everybody.
Just hang tight. Over.
Yo.
[ Car Alarm Wailing,
Horn Honking ]
[ Wailing And Honking
Continue ]
[ Heather ] Val, you're gonna
have to forget about the truck.
Yeah, we gotcha, Heather.
Look, the situation
hasn't changed.
We still have to make it to solid rock.
There's gotta be some way.
Like what ? There's nothing left
that can make it to those mountains.
Val, quiet, man.
- It doesn't matter now.
They know we're here.
- Ah, shit !
We need a helicopter is what we need.
Or a goddamn tank !
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute ! The Cat !
- Could we take the Cat ?
- Ah, Jesus. It's slower than hell.
But it weighs better than 30 tons.
There's no way they could lift 30 tons.
- Could they ? I mean--
- But we can't all fit on the bulldozer.
No. No, but we could, uh,
drag something, though.
We, we could pull a car
behind it. I don't know.
Hell, that old semitrailer.
Its tires are flat.
Doesn't matter.
That Cat can pull anything.
Well, all right.
We just roll on outta here.
We've got a plan !
'Course...
that's a hell of a long walk.
Listen, they only respond
to vibration, right ?
Couldn't we
distract them somehow ?
Yeah. Good.
Something to keep 'em busy.
Like a, like a decoy.
Hey, Melvin,
you wanna make a buck ?
Ahh, eat it !
How about the tractor ?
Walter's little tractor ? Start him up.
Let those things
follow him all over...
if they like that noise.
Not bad.
What do you think ?
[ Yelling ]
Ground's gettin' closer, Earl.
I say we go with Miguel's plan.
[ Growling, Rumbling ]
- Whew.
- Hold on, Nancy !
- I'm makin' the run for the Cat.
- Like hell you are.
- Get real. I'm faster than you.
- But I'm best at drivin' the Cat.
- Not while I'm around.
- Damn it, listen to me.
I'm older and wiser.
Yeah, well, you're half right.
Damn ! I lost.
Guess I'll have to do it.
Uh-uh. I won.
I pick who does it.
Ready when you are, Miguel.
[ Engine Revving ]
[ Growling ]
There he is.
There he goes !
He's chasing it.
He's chasing it !
It's going.
This one's going too !
- Good luck, shithead.
- Don't worry about me, jerk-off.
Shit !
[ Sighs ]
You suicidal...
son of a bitch.
Damn !
Keep goin' !
[ Growling ]
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God ! Oh, my God !
Come on, come on !
They're gonna get him !
Val, stop !
They're coming ! Be quiet !
Don't move !
It worked.
They can't find him.
We gotta, uh--
We gotta make some noise.
A lot of noise !
Hey, you sorry sons of bitches.
Come and get my ass !
Over here, you slime bucket !
Come get me !
Hey, come on !
Come on !
[ Men Shouting ]
Come on. What are you, scared ?
[ Shouting Continues ]
Hey. What's she doin' ?
Agh ! Agh !
That did it, girl !
Goddamn good thinking.
[ Engine Revs ]
Yah-hoo !
Ha, ha, ha, ha !
- You okay ?
- Yeah.
Here goes.
- Yea !
- Yes ! Yes ! Ha, ha ! Yeah !
- Here.
- Yeah.
Goddamn !
Armored transport.
- Burt, Heather ! Let's get going !
- Let's move it, Burt. Heather !
Come on. Let's go, you two.
We're headed for the mountains.
If that's how we're doin' it,
we're goin' prepared.
We can't hold still long. These things
are getting smarter by the minute.
That's fine. We've got
some new things to teach 'em.
You see that ?
They're doin' it again. They try it
every time we stop ! Come on !
Jesus Christ !
We're only goin' nine miles.
Well those things are gonna be on
our ass every foot of the way, right ?
[ Rhonda ] Hurry !
What are you doing up there ?
Get in the trailer !
What do you think ?
Max firepower or this ?
I go for penetration. The .458,
shootin' solids. Less ammo to carry.
Come on, Burt !
Move it !
Watch these ammo boxes !
- Come on, Burt !
- Heather, hurry !
- Tell 'em to come on !
- Okay, now !
Now ! Come on !
Come on !
Gimme a gun.
I'll take one.
I wouldn't give you a gun
if it was World War Ill.
Food... for five years.
A thousand gallons of gas,
air filtration, water filtration.
Geiger counter,
bomb shelter.
[ Sighs ]
Underground.
Goddamn monsters !
Yo, there we go !
Fallen Rock ! Yeah !
[ All Cheering ]
Any sign of 'em ?
Maybe they just gave up, you know ?
Hey, what's that ?
Damn it !
What the hell are they doin' ?
I don't care what they're doin' as long
as they're doin' it way over there.
Wait, wait !
Look out !
- Mommy ! Mommy !
- Everybody stay here.
- Burt, you okay ?
- I'm okay.
[ Mindy ] Are they gonna get us ?
What happened ?
- Burt, you sure you're okay ?
- Yeah.
[ Nancy ]
What happened ?
They dug a trap.
I can't believe this.
- All right.
- Here.
[ Gunfire Continues ]
Let me have my gun.
Hungry ? Eat this !
Everybody down !
[ Monster Screeching ]
God ! Ooh !
There they are !
- [ Melvin ] Did you get one ?
- [ Burt ] I don't know.
No ! There's still
two of them. Look !
- There are two different dust trails.
- Made 'em think twice though.
What the hell's
in those things ?
A few household chemicals
in the proper proportion.
They're coming back !
We'll have to make a run
for those rocks.
- I don't know.
That's a hell of a long way.
- They'll get us !
They're sure as hell
gonna get us if we stay here.
- You have any more of those bombs ?
- We've got you covered.
What if we throw one that way,
the way we wanna go ?
If it drives them away,
we run like goddamn bastards.
Pardon my French.
- [ All Yelling ]
- What if they don't get scared ?
What if they don't run ?
I don't think it does scare them.
It hurts them.
- They're so sensitive to sound,
they've gotta run.
- Hell, she's got my vote !
That's it !
We're making a run for it !
- We're goin' for the rocks.
- I don't know, man. They're too fast.
- You can't outrun 'em. No way !
- Yo, Melvin. This'll
make 'em think twice.
- Everybody ready to run ?
- [ Together ] Let's get outta here !
[ Monsters Snorting, Growling ]
Heads down !
[ Screeching ]
Oh. Whoa.
[ Rhonda ]
It worked ! There they go !
All right, let's go !
Here.
Come on, Burt.
Aah ! [ Gun Clicks ]
Oh, Burt ! You asshole !
Agh ! Mommy !
- Get up.
- I've got her.
[ Heather ]
Come on, Burt. Hurry !
- Get up here !
- I'm with ya, honey.
Go, go, go !
Burt, you asshole !
There's no bullets in this gun.
Gotcha movin', didn't it ?
[ Screaming ]
So now what ?
Could we make it to the mountains,
use Burt's explosives ?
No way.
We'd need 50 of those bombs.
That's it.
We're not gettin' off this rock.
Well, we're not
gonna pole vault outta here.
That's for damn sure.
Wait a minute.
What're y'all talkin' about ?
It's like you're givin' up
or somethin'.
[ Rhonda ] They'll just wait out there
'til we're dead.
That's exactly
what they do.
W-Wait. Wait !
For chrissakes, we could've made a stand
at our place. We had food, water--
You can't fight 'em like that.
So you two screw-ups hauled us
way the hell out here ?
Hey. Hey. Why don't you
just back off, string bean ?
- We could've left
your worthless ass on the roof !
- I wish you had, fearless leader.
- Who the hell put you two in charge ?
- Don't goddamn push me !
- If them graboids
don't kill 'im, I will.
- What ?
They'd've torn your place
out from under you in half an hour.
Come on. Just let it go.
Forget about it.
- [ Mumbling ]
- I know he does.
He thinks he knows everything.
[ Sighing ]
If it comes to starvation,
I know what I'm doin'.
Take one of these,
walk right out there with the fuse lit
and let 'em take me down.
Boom.
Good Lord, honey.
- Now that's not a bad idea.
- [ Chuckling ]
No, no. It gives me an idea.
Goin' fishing like.
There's one...
straight out in front.
Let's see if we can keep him
right there.
- How much we need ?
- I don't know. They're pretty quick.
Fifteen seconds at least.
- Which kind of fuse is that ?
- Cannon fuse.
- What the hell you use if for ?
- My cannon.
You guys watch yourselves.
Right about there,
about 30--
Oh, man. You're not gonna do
your lasso thing ?
Just 'cause you're no good
with a rope--
All right, get back !
Come on, baby.
Take it.
Take the bait !
Yeah ! All right !
- Look at 'im !
- Yeah !
Whoo ! Whoo !
Yeah ! Yeah !
[ Laughing ]
All right !
Yeah !
[ Rhonda ]
Okay, one to go.
Damn !
Where the hell is he ?
Hope he didn't wise up.
[ Rhonda ]
Nope. There.
Look who it is.
Give me that thing.
This son of a bitch is mine.
- There it goes !
- All right, get back !
- I got it.
- Come on. Come on.
Come on, lunchtime, hothead.
- Yeah !
- Hey !
All right, get down !
Oh, shit !
Oh, my God !
It's com--
Get back ! Get back !
Run ! Run !
Get up, come on !
What're you doing out there ?
[ Roaring ]
Let's make some noise.
Try to distract them.
Come on, everybody.
[ Shouting, Whistling ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
- [ Growling ]
- Fresh meat !
[ Whispering ]
Wait, wait, wait.
[ Quiet Growling ]
This one's not falling for it.
This one ain't dumb.
He's trying to trick us.
- Use your bomb.
- It's our last one.
Huh. What else
you gonna use it for ?
So what if we make it
to the rocks.
We'll be dead
in three days anyway.
Well, I wanna live
for the three days.
[ Burt Yelling ]
What the hell ? What's the matter ?
Use the bomb,
for God sakes !
[ Melvin ] Throw that bomb, man !
Scare 'em away !
[ Whispering ]
Throw the bomb !
This bastard
ain't smarter than us.
For chrissakes, Val !
- I'm gonna go for it.
- Go for what ?
- What are you doing ?
- I got a goddamn plan !
Where the hell is it ?
I've got it !
[ Earl ] This better be
one hell of a great plan !
Get ready !
- Light it, man !
- Not yet. Not yet !
What are you waiting for ?
Go !
Come on, come on !
Come on !
Too far !
You threw it behind him.
Run, Val ! Run !
Yeah !
Can you fly, you sucker ?
Can you fly ?
Well, it just...
suddenly hit me, you know.
- Stampede.
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Cheering ]
- Way to go, Val ! Yeah !
Now...
the second we hit Bixby,
we start making some phone calls.
We could make
some real money on this thing.
We could get
in People magazine.
People ? Hell !
National Geographic.
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Smile.
Hey.
Burt loaned me his camera.
Yeah.
He gave us these tires too.
It's all pretty exciting, huh ?
There's gonna be major research,
and I'm gonna be in on it.
Hmm.
The first thing to do is take pictures
of that one we dug up.
Yeah. Yeah. Pictures...
seem like a good idea.
Well, thanks for everything,
saving my life and stuff.
Yeah. Well, uh...
you're welcome.
- Maybe I'll see you sometime ?
- Uh-huh.
Well... see ya.
I know. I know !
I'm working up to it.
What am I doin' ?
I mean, what's a woman like her
want with a guy like me ?
She's going for her damn Ph.D.
- Rhonda ?
- Yeah ?
I-l-l just...
wanted to--
* Well, pardon me
but you've had my attention *
* Ever since you strolled
into the room *
* Believe me
that it's not my intention *
* lf I appear
to come on too soon *
* It's not like me
to make such advances *
* But this time, baby
I could not resist *
* So if you're up for taking
a chance on love *
* I can't see
a better time than this *
* So, baby, why not tonight *
* This could be the start
of something right *
* Hey, we can take it easy *
* We can take it slow *
* We can take it anywhere
that you'd like to go *
* So, baby, why not tonight *
* Well, the stars are out
and I'm sure they'll agree *
* Whoa, it's a perfect night
for fallin' in love *
* So why not fall in love
with me *
* Whoa, maybe we could go out
for some dinner *
* And later on now
we could do the town *
* You know I'd consider
myself a winner *
* Just to have
a boy like you around *
* And if you're up
for doin' some dancin' *
* Hey, I know a place
they dance until the dawn *
* You know, anything you'd like
Well, it'll be all right *
* So why not take a chance
and come along *
* So, baby, why not tonight *
* Uh, this could be the start
of something right *
* Oh, we could take it easy
We could take it slow *
* We could take it anywhere
that you'd like to go *
* So, baby, why not tonight *
* Hey, the stars are out
and I'm sure they'll agree *
* Now it's a perfect night
for fallin' in love *
* So why not take a chance
and come along *
* So, baby, why not tonight *
* Uh, this could be the start
of something right *
* So, baby, why not tonight *
* Hey, the stars are out
and I'm sure they'll agree *
* Now it's a perfect night
for fallin' in love *
* So why not fall in love *
* Why not fall in love *
* Why not fall in love with me *
* Yeah **