[Static]
O/o/ [Electronic]
[Announcer]
Civic TV,
the one you take to bed
with you.
Max, it's that time again:
Time to slowly, painfully
ease yourself back into consciousness.
No, I'm not a dream,
although I've been told
I'm a vision of loveliness.
- [Chuckles]
- [Man Chuckles] Who told you that?
I'm nothing less than your
faithful girl Friday, Bridey James,
here with your wake-up call of today,
which is Wednesday the 23rd.
You got that?
Wednesday the 23rd.
And I have a message.
Remember your meeting
this morning at 6:30...
with Shinji Kuraki
of Hiroshima Video.
This meeting is to take place
at the Classic Hotel,
suite 17.
And needless to say,
it's your first of the day.
Don't you know anyone
who works 9:00 to 5:00?
Over and out, Commander.
[Announcer] Civic TV,
the one you take to bed with you.
[Ticking]
[Tape Player Clicks]
[Sighs]
[Moans]
[Munching]
- [Man]
Cindy, open the door, will ya?
- [Woman] Go away.
Come on.
You know I love ya.
- Get outta here!
- Will you open the door?
For fuck's sake, open the door!
- [Baby Crying]
- I want you out of this place!
For fuck's sake,
open the door!
[Man And Woman Arguing]
You just gotta open
the fucking door!
Well, I looked over
the stills.
I am interested
a little bit.
- How many shows you got?
- Thirteen,
with a possibility of
another six if the sales go well.
- You got cassettes?
- Of course.
[Both Laughing]
No, hold it.
Uh, show me the last one.
- [Speaking Japanese]
- Number 13.
But you won't understand anything.
Everything is set up in the first two.
My audience ain't gonna see the first
two shows. Show me the last one.
What do ya think?
Can we get away with it?
Do we wanna get away with it?
I think Oriental sex
is a natural.
I think it'll get us an audience
we've never had before.
I don't like it.
Not tacky enough.
- Not tacky enough for what?
- Tacky enough to turn me on.
Too much class
is bad for sex.
Maybe.
I don't know.
[Exhales]
It's soft.
Something too...
soft about it.
I'm lookin' for something
that'll break through, ya know?
Something... tough.
[Motor Hums]
Hey, Harlan, uh...
Huh?
Oh. Okay.
Here we go.
[Clicking Switches]
Now, it'll
come through on that.
Now, we only got about 53 seconds,
so keep your eyes open.
They've got an unscrambler scrambler,
if you know what I mean.
It sensed that we
were unscrambling...
and, uh, automatically
changed its code on us.
What satellite
is it coming from?
- Snooker, I think.
- Country of origin?
Uh, let me see. Uh... Assuming 53
seconds represents the period of delay,
I'd say somewhere, uh,
in Malaysia?
- [Hums]
- Okay, here we go.
This is it.
[Woman Moaning]
[Moaning Continues]
What is that wall behind her?
What is that, clay?
- Yeah. White clay.
- [Sobbing, Moaning]
I think it's electrified.
[Moaning Continues,
Static Crackling]
[Woman Moans, Screams]
[Moaning Continues]
[Static Crackling Loudly]
- [Tape Ejects]
- That's it?
That's it.
- [Sighs]
- Grotesque, as promised.
Okay. Can you hang a search
on it next time it...
Already workin' on it.
I was pretty insulted when it just
shrugged us off in less than a minute.
Well, patron, interested?
Yeah. Harlan, can you do something
about these labels?
I mean, uh, this is supposed
to be a clandestine operation,
you know what I mean?
Si, patron.
I always find myself
getting nervous,
even if you've been doing it
all your life, don't you think?
[Woman]
Oh, yeah. Oh, for sure.
- 'Course, that's part
of the excitement of it.
- Mm-hmm.
Want a smoke?
- No, thanks.
- [Max] Mmm.
- Max, just relax.
- Okay.
[Announcer] And now here it is:
The Rena King Show.
And this afternoon,
Rena's guests are Max Renn,
controversial president of Channel 83,
radio personality Nicki Brand...
and media prophet
Professor Brian O'Blivion.
Take it away, Rena.
- [Max Exhales]
- Max Renn,
your television station
offers its viewers...
everything
from soft-core pornography...
to hard-core violence.
- Why?
- Well, it's a matter
of economics, Rena.
We're, uh, small. In order to survive,
we have to give people...
something they can't
get anywhere else,
and, uh...
and we do that.
But don't you feel
such shows contribute...
to a social climate of violence
and sexual malaise?
- And do you care?
- Certainly, I care. [Chuckles]
I care enough, in fact,
to give my viewers a...
a harmless outlet for their fantasies
and their frustrations.
As far as I'm concerned,
that's a socially positive act.
What about it, Nicki?
Is it socially positive?
Well, I think we live
in overstimulated times.
We crave stimulation
for its own sake.
We gorge ourselves on it.
We always want more,
whether it's tactile,
emotional or sexual,
and I think that's bad.
Then why did you
wear that dress?
- Sorry?
- That dress.
[Chuckles] It's very stimulating,
and... and it's red.
You know what Freud would
have said about that dress.
And he would've been right.
I admit it.
I live in a highly excited
state of overstimulation.
Listen, I'd really like
to take you out to dinner tonight.
- You're beautiful in that dress.
What do you think?
- Professor O'Blivion,
do you think erotic TV shows
and violent TV shows...
lead to desensitization,
to dehumanization?
[Max Murmuring]
The television screen has become
the retina of the mind's eye.
[Murmuring
Continues]
- Yes.
- That's why I refuse
to appear on television,
except on television.
Of course, O'Blivion is not
the name I was born with.
That's my television name.
Soon all of us will have
special names,
names designed to cause
the cathode ray tube to resonate.
- [Max] Yes, I am, actually.
- Yes.
- I am very interested.
- Nicki, is Max Renn
a menace to society?
I'm not sure.
He's certainly
a menace to me.
- [Screaming]
- [Static]
[Max] When does the plot, uh,
start to unravel here?
I mean, who is this black guy?
Is he a political prisoner?
- There's no plot.
- [Man Moaning]
It just goes on
like that for an hour.
- Goes on like what?
- Like that.
- Torture, murder...
- [Air Hisses]
Mutilation.
- We never leave that room.
- Nope.
- It's a real sicko.
- Brilliant.
- For perverts only.
- It's absolutely brilliant.
I mean, look, there's almost
no production costs.
You can't take your eyes off it.
It's incredibly realistic.
Where do they get actors
who can do this?
- Oh, help me. I think he wants it.
- Come on.
It's worth checking out.
Did you have any trouble
locking onto it this time?
Not after I realized
the Malaysia delay was a plant.
It's not coming
from Malaysia?
You cannot fool the Prince
of Pirates for long.
Har... Harlan,
where is it coming from?
- Pittsburgh.
- [Screaming Continues]
That's in the U.S.A.
Pittsburgh.
- [Screaming Continues]
- Pittsburgh.
- Get professional help.
- [Woman Caller] But it's not me.
- It's my sister.
- It's not your sister.
It's you, lover.
Can't ya tell? Isn't that
why you called me?
You want help.
You need help.
You're going insane. I can hear you
disintegrating while you talk to me.
- I've got your number, haven't I?
- [Woman Sobbing]
I hate my sister.
[Sobbing]
I don't want to.
It's ripping me up inside.
[Sniffs]
But I do. I do.
- [Sniffles]
- Will you call our Distress Center?
Will you call
the CRAM Distress Center?
They'll tell you where
to get help, lover,
and you need it.
- You need it now.
- [Sobbing] I will. I will.
Oh, thank you, Nicki.
[Hangs Up]
[Announcer]
We'll return to Nicki Brand...
and the Emotional Rescue show
in just a moment.
This is CRAM in Toronto,
and we've got the weather for you.
- Got any porno?
- You serious?
Yeah.
Gets me in the mood.
What's this?
"Videodrome."
- Torture, murder.
- [Chuckles]
Sounds great.
Ain't exactly sex.
Says who?
[Water Splashing]
[Screaming]
- God, I can't believe it.
- I'll turn it off.
No, no, no. It's okay.
I can take it.
[Flogging Continues,
Woman Sobbing]
Can you get it any clearer?
It's a pirate tape.
They scrambled it.
[Moaning Continues]
I like it.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, it turns me on.
Take out your Swiss Army knife
and cut me here...
just...
just a little.
Looks like somebody's
beat me to it.
[Woman Grunting,
Screaming]
I wonder how you get to be
a contestant on this show.
I don't know. Nobody ever seems
to come back next week.
What did you say happened
to your shoulder?
A friend. I think
he'd like Videodrome.
You let somebody cut you?
- Uh-huh.
- [Moaning, Screaming Continue]
What do ya think?
Well, I-I don't know.
You wanna try a few things?
[Nicki Exhales, Hisses]
[Nicki Sighing]
Oh.
[Moaning]
[Sighs]
[Chuckles]
[Nicki Moaning]
[Max Moaning]
[Chattering On TVs
In Various Languages]
Max, thank God. Masha Borowczyk
has been in your office for an hour.
- Masha.
- What were you doing last night?
Didn't you get my message?
- I don't think I'm ready for this.
- Coffee.
- Cigarette. Office. Masha. Go.
- All right. Masha.
- She's hot to trot.
- [Chattering On TVs Continues]
[Masha]
I call it...
Apollo and Dionysus.
[Max]
Masha, does it ever get good?
It's all good.
- Darling, I am looking
for something a lot more...
- [Woman Giggling]
Contemporary.
I want something that's gonna
show people what's really
goin' on under the sheets.
This stuff is too...
It's too naive.
It's too sweet,
like you, darling.
Well, it's your market.
Do you know a show
called Videodrome?
- Video-what?
- D-R-O-M-E.
Videodrome,
like video circus, video arena.
- You know it?
- No.
It's just torture
and murder.
No plot, no characters.
Very, very realistic.
I think it's what's next.
Then God help us.
- [Knocking At Door]
- Better on TV than on the street.
Arnold on line three.
You interested in, uh,
tracking it down for me?
I'll see that you get
the agent's commission.
I'm interested.
Let me try.
Max,
did you ever think...
of producing
your own show?
Right here?
I could be your agent,
worldwide.
I could sell subterranean
for you everywhere.
- No, I don't have the temperament.
- But if you did,
what kind of show
would you do?
I mean,
for the subterranean market.
Would you do...
Videodrome?
[Nicki]
Max.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm goin' away tomorrow
for two weeks...
on assignment.
Guess where?
L.A.
- Pittsburgh.
- [Chuckles] Fabulous.
- Don't stay in the sun too long.
I hear it's bad for the skin.
- Oh, come on.
Isn't that where
they make Videodrome?
Yeah. Why?
I'm gonna audition.
I was made for that show.
Nobody on Earth
was made for that show.
Hey. Listen to me.
- Listen to me.
- What?
I want you to stay
away from it.
Those mondo weirdo video guys,
they've got unsavory connections.
They play rough, rougher than
even Nicki Brand wants to play.
Do you understand me?
Sounds like a challenge.
Got a cigarette?
It's not a challenge.
I swear. You know, in Brazil,
Central America, those kinds of places,
making underground video
is considered a subversive act.
They execute people for it.
In Pittsburgh, who knows?
[Liquor Pouring]
Max.
Nicki, don't!
Nicki, don't.
Don't.
O/o/ [Drums]
- Do you have a hangover?
- No. Stayed up late watching TV.
Did you get in touch
with our friends in Pittsburgh?
In a way.
At a distance.
- Subterranean grapevine.
- And?
Max,
Videodrome is something
for you to leave alone.
It is definitely not
for public consumption.
[Chuckles] Channel 83 is a little
small to be considered public.
It is still too public.
Do you understand me?
No.
What's the punch line?
I think
it's dangerous, Max.
- Videodrome.
- Why? It's Mafia? They do business.
No, no. It's more, um...
How can I say?
More political
than that.
Come on, Masha.
What are we talkin' about?
Videodrome.
What you see
on that show,
it's for real.
It's not acting.
It's... snuff TV.
I don't believe it.
- o/o/ [Stops]
- [Whistling]
So... don't believe.
Why do it for real?
It's easier and safer to fake it.
Because it has something...
that you don't have,
Max.
It has a philosophy, and that
is what makes it dangerous.
Whose philosophy?
There must be a name.
Give me a name I can talk to.
Masha, Masha, you know me.
I stay away
from the scary stuff.
Max,
you are going to have to
be nice to me for this.
We can take a shower together,
anytime you say.
[Chuckling]
I'm sure you would be
very beautiful,
but, uh, you're a little
older than I prefer.
Thank you...
so much.
Sell me a name,
and I'll make Apollo and Dionysus
part of the package.
[Sighs]
That hurts me, Max.
Hey, the world's
a shithole, ain't it?
Yes, Max.
It is.
Brian O'Blivion.
That is the only name
I have to give.
Professor Brian O'Blivion.
[Woman] Wait, where you goin'?
Come back here.
Hey. Hey, buddy.
Got a fag?
- [Man] Are they goin' in now?
- Got a cigarette?
[Indistinct Muttering]
- Gotta have a smoke
and a cup of coffee.
- [Woman] Wait a minute.
They don't serve coffee there.
They just serve piss water.
- [Muttering Continues]
- I don't need to put up with
this shit. I'm a young woman.
Take a good look at me.
I'm a good-lookin' woman.
I got nice tits.
[Man]
Let's go.
[Muttering Continues]
[TV Noise,
Indistinct]
[Woman Greeter]
Hello. Move along.
[Greeter Continues,
Indistinct]
[Female Derelict]
Move out of my way!
Hello. Straight down
the hallway.
Keep on.
Straight down the hallway.
Keep going,
keep going.
Come on. Step along.
- Bianca O'Blivion?
- Yes.
I'm Max Renn. I, uh...
I run Civic TV.
I did a panel show
with Prof. O'Blivion.
The Rena King Show.
Oh, yes. You said some
very superficial things.
Violence, sex,
imagination, catharsis.
- My exact words.
- What do you want?
I wanna talk
with your father...
about a new twist in video
that he may not be aware of.
I love the view.
You look like them,
like one of Father's derelicts.
[Chuckles] Think it's a style
that's coming back.
In their case, Mr. Renn,
it's not a style.
It's a disease forced on them by their
lack of access to the cathode ray tube.
You think a few doses of TV
are gonna help them?
Watching TV will help patch them back
into the world's mixing board.
Absolutely.
And I guess you encourage Father's
derelicts to make home movies?
The world's mixing board?
Prof. O'Blivion sends video letters
all over the world.
- Is the Professor here?
- I am my father's screen.
Once you've told me what this
visit is all about, he may
choose to send you a cassette.
If he does, which format
would you like?
If he does, it's gonna make
conversation a little difficult.
My father has not engaged
in conversation for at least 20 years.
The monologue is his preferred mode
of discourse.
Format.
Videodrome.
Is that a Japanese
configuration?
- You've never heard of it?
- No.
Then there have been
serious gaps in your education.
- Videodrome.
- o/o/ [Clock Chiming]
Mention it to your father.
He may want to have a conversation.
[Chuckling]
I love the view.
[Door Closes]
[Harlan]
Torture, murder, mutilation.
[Masha]
Videodrome.
What you see
on that show,
it's for real.
[Nicki]
I'm gonna audition.
I was made for that show.
[Masha] It has something
that you don't have, Max.
It has a philosophy,
and that is what makes it dangerous.
[Knocking At Door]
Hi. This is
your wake-up cassette,
and this came to the office
for you by courier.
- What did they say at CRAM?
- They said that Nicki Brand...
is definitely not
on assignment for them.
- She had a month off coming
and decided to take it.
- Don't touch that!
[Grunts]
Jesus, Max, you scared me.
What the hell's
wrong with you?
I don't know, man. I think
I'm gettin', like, a rash or somethin'.
- Uh...
- What?
Are you all right?
Bridey, I didn't mean to hit you.
Hit me?
You didn't hit me.
No? No. No, I know I didn't hit you.
I meant...
- [Exhales]
- Do you want me to stay here?
- Uh...
- You look awful.
- Can I get you something?
- Uh, no, uh...
No, I'm just, uh...
Uh, I'm...
[Exhales] I'm exhausted. I was
in a deep sleep when you knocked,
and I guess I'm
still not out of it.
And I guess I'm
I'll remember to set the timer.
Don't worry.
- You're sure? Are you sure?
- I'm sure. Yeah.
Thanks, Bridey.
Tomorrow.
Max, that other cassette is from
the office of Brian O'Blivion.
I promised I'd hand-deliver it
directly to you.
Will you call me
if you need me?
- [Sighs]
- [Gasps]
[Tape Loads, Clicks]
The battle for the mind
of North America...
will be fought
in the video arena:
The Videodrome.
The television screen
is the retina of the mind's eye.
Therefore, the television screen is part
of the physical structure of the brain.
Therefore, whatever appears
on the television screen...
emerges as raw experience
for those who watch it.
Therefore,
television is reality,
and reality is less
than television.
- [Chuckles]
- Max.
I'm so glad
you came to me.
I've been through it all
myself, you see.
Your reality is already
half video hallucination.
If you're not careful,
it will become total hallucination.
You'll have to learn to live
in a very strange new world.
I had a brain tumor,
and I had visions.
I believed the visions
caused the tumor...
and not the reverse.
I could feel the visions
coalesce and become flesh.
Uncontrollable flesh.
But when they removed
the tumor,
it was called Videodrome.
I was the...
[Choking]
L... I...
was Videodrome's...
first victim.
But who is behind it?
What do they want?
I want you, Max.
You.
Come to me.
Come to Nicki.
Come on.
Don't make me wait.
Please.
[Breathing]
[Nicki Moaning]
[Breathing Deeply]
[Nicki Moans]
I want you, Max.
You.
Come on.
- Come on.
- [Breathing Continues]
Come to me now.
Come to Nicki.
- [Breathing Continues]
- Don't keep me waiting.
Please.
[Siren Wails]
[Announcer] Today Lady Luck
may smile on these four players...
and start them on the road
to $12,000...
We have a new group
of people coming in this afternoon,
so tell the staff
about that.
- All right. Good.
- [Audience On TV Cheering]
[TV Noise Continues]
Exciting. Very lively.
Careful. It bites.
- You watched the cassette?
- Yeah.
- It changed my life.
- I'm not surprised.
It's dangerous, you know.
Because your father admits
he's somehow involved with Videodrome?
More than that. It bites.
Isn't that what you said?
What kind of teeth
do you think it has?
It triggered off a series
of hallucinations.
I woke up with a headache.
- First time ever?
- No, I-I've been
hallucinating for a while,
- ever since...
- What?
Since I first saw
Videodrome.
How did you come
to be exposed to it?
Pirate satellite dish.
A-An accident.
I made some tapes.
This is part of my own
Videodrome collection.
But that tape is just your father
sitting at his desk.
The tone of the hallucinations
is determined by the tone
of the tape's imagery.
But the Videodrome signal,
the one that does the damage,
it can be delivered
under a test pattern, anything.
Mmm.
Damage?
The signal induces
a brain tumor in the viewer.
It's the tumor that creates
the hallucinations.
You let me watch it?
I expect them to come to me
eventually to hurt me.
I thought it might be you.
Now I realize you're
just another victim...
like Father was.
Where is your father?
I think I'd better talk to him.
He's in there.
O/o/ [Clock Chiming]
I'm afraid
he'll disappoint you.
This is him.
- This is all that's left.
- What are you talking about?
Brian O'Blivion died quietly
on an operating table 11 months ago.
- The brain problem?
- The Videodrome problem.
- You have it too.
- But he was on that panel show with me.
On tape. He made
thousands of them.
Sometimes
three or four a day.
I keep him alive
as best I can.
He had so much to offer.
My father helped
to create Videodrome.
He saw it as the next phase
in the evolution of man
as a technological animal.
When he realized what his partners
were going to use it for,
he tried to take it
away from them.
And they killed him.
Quietly.
At the end, he was convinced
that public life on television...
was more real than
private life in the flesh.
He wasn't afraid
to let his body die.
[Sighs]
Tell me about
my Videodrome problem.
My father knows much more
about it than I do.
Listen to him.
Where's Harlan?
He's not in the lab.
- I think he's up in V.T.R. Max...
- Not now.
- Harlan.
- Si, patron.
Have you been
hallucinating lately?
No.
- Should I be?
- Yes.
You should be.
I believe...
that the growth in my head...
this head,
this one right here...
I think that it is not
really a tumor,
not an uncontrolled, undirected
little bubbling pot of flesh,
but that it is in fact...
a new organ,
a new part of the brain.
I think that massive doses
of Videodrome signal...
will ultimately create
a new outgrowth...
of the human brain,
which will produce...
and control hallucination...
to the point that it will
change human reality.
After all,
there is nothing real...
outside our perception
of reality,
is there?
[Chuckling]
You can see that, can't you?
[Phone Rings]
[Rings]
- [Man] Max Renn?
- Yes.
- Who is this?
- Barry Convex would like to talk
to you about Videodrome.
I've got a car waiting
downstairs for you, sir.
Please direct your attention
to the television set
in front of you, Mr. Renn.
Mr. Convex has recorded
a little introduction for you.
[Tape Clicks]
O/o/ [Electronic]
Hi, I'm Barry Convex,
Chief of Special Programs,
and I'd like to invite you
into the world of Spectacular Optical,
an enthusiastic
global corporate citizen.
We make inexpensive glasses
for the Third World...
and missile guidance systems
for NATO.
We also make
Videodrome, Max,
and as I'm sure you know,
when it's ready for
the marketplace, things will
never be quite the same again.
It can be a giant hallucination machine
and much, much more.
But it's not ready. Those were
test transmissions you picked up.
We thought nobody
could tap into them.
He's good, that Harlan.
Good pirate.
Well, now that you have,
I think we oughta have
a little talk, don't you?
I thought maybe...
my place?
- [Chuckles]
- [Convex] I hope you realize
you're playing with dynamite.
That's our spring line.
Top secret stuff.
I brought it with me for a trade show
here in town later this week.
Max Renn, I'm Barry Convex.
L...
I think that machinery
you're wearing is...
too much for the shape
of your face.
Overwhelms you.
T-Try something more, uh,
spidery,
more delicate.
Here she is.
This is our prototype.
This is the little number
that started it all.
Max,
I would like you
to try this on for size.
I would like to use this machine to
record one of your hallucinations now.
Then I would like to take that tape
back with me to home base for analysis.
Do I get to
keep the copyright?
I mean, I'd hate to see it
show up as a Movie of the Week
and not get paid for it.
Max, I'm trying
to help you.
What makes you think
I need help, Barry?
None of our test subjects
has returned to... normality.
They're all in need
of intensive psychiatric care.
Now, you seem to be
functioning reasonably well...
so far.
I'd like to find out why,
and I think an analysis
of one of your hallucinations...
would be the right
place to start.
Will it hurt?
It won't hurt you.
You might catch yourself
sliding in and out...
of a hallucinatory state
after this is all over.
If you do, just relax and enjoy it.
It'll soon go away.
But for now, I think that you'll
find a little S-and-M...
will be necessary to trigger off a good,
healthy series of hallucinations.
- [Beeping]
- That's why our Videodrome show
is so strange.
Something to do with the effects
of exposure to violence
on the nervous system.
It opens up receptors
in the brain and the spine,
and that allows the Videodrome
signal to sink in.
- You mean I'm gonna have
to hurt you, Barry?
- [Chuckling]
'Fraid not. You don't have
to actually hurt anybody.
You just have to think
about it.
[Humming]
[Humming Loudly]
Wha-a-a... That's too bright!
I can't take it!
- Yes! I forgot! Sorry!
How's that?
- Shit.
- [Humming]
- [Max] Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, that's fine.
Okay, we're rolling.
The taping mechanism
is all self-contained.
You don't have to do
anything now but hallucinate.
Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
I'll come back for you
later.
You'll forgive me if I don't
stay around to watch.
I just can't cope
with the freaky stuff.
[Max]
Nicki?
- Nicki.
- Well, here we are at last,
right where we oughta be:
On Videodrome.
What are you
waiting for, lover?
Let's perform.
Let's open
those neural floodgates.
[Breathing Heavily,
Moaning]
[Nicki Gasps]
Aah!
[Shouts]
[Moaning]
Aah!
[Gasping]
- Aah!
- [Panting]
What's going on, Prof. Oblivion?
[Chuckles]
I mean, really.
Oh.
[Gasps]
Oh, Masha.
[Exhales]
Harlan,
it's Max.
Can you come over to
my apartment? Right away.
Yeah, I'm serious.
Come on in.
Well, here I am, patron.
Camera. Flashgun. What's up?
Ya wanna be a centerfold?
I want you to go
into my bedroom,
and I want you to take a look
at what's in my bed.
Uncover it. Don't be shy.
I want pictures.
- Pictures of what's in your bed?
- Yeah. Do it.
Sure. Okay.
Oh, God.
[Exhales]
Well?
Max.
I don't see anything.
You didn't just want me to shoot
your bed, pillows, sheets,
did you?
- It's disa...
- Max, are you in some kind
of drug warp?
I've got friends
who can help.
Bridey said she came by
a couple of days ago. You were...
Did you tape Videodrome
last night?
If it was transmitted,
the machine would've caught it.
I'll meet you in the lab in one hour.
I wanna see it.
- Jeez, it's not even 7:00 a.m.
- I'm not fucking around!
Do you understand me?
Well, fuck you. I'm not some fucking
servomechanism you can switch on.
You want me to run around like an
asshole, tell me what I'm doing it for.
- Otherwise, I'll see you
during office hours.
- Harlan.
You're right.
It's momentum. I'm runnin'
like an express train here.
I don't know how to stop.
Look, I'll meet you
in the lab in one hour.
Okay? And then we'll see if we
pulled in any Videodrome last night...
and I'll tell you
what's going on.
Everything. I promise.
Okay?
Okay. I'm sorry
if I freaked out on you.
- I don't work with you for the money.
- I know that.
With pirates, it's never
just for the money, is it?
You want a cup of cof... No, look.
I'll meet you in the lab in an hour.
Come on in.
- [Door Closes]
- Did you look at the tape?
- Did you see me on Videodrome?
- There was no tape.
- There was no Videodrome
transmission last night?
- Not last night.
- Aw, fuck!
- Not ever.
What... What are you
talking about?
[Knocking At Door]
I'm out of my depth now,
patron.
I had to bring in
the reinforcements.
Max.
An intriguing combination.
Very interesting.
- Don't let me interrupt.
- I think I was saying something like,
"What are you talking about?"
I was playing you
tapes, Max.
Prerecorded cassettes.
Videodrome has never been transmitted
on an open broadcast circuit.
- Not yet.
- I guess Barry sent you here,
what, two years ago?
It has been... two years,
hasn't it, Harlan?
Two. Two wonderful years.
Why?
[Exhales]
To get you involved.
To expose you
to the Videodrome signal.
It didn't affect you because
you never watched it!
You knew what was there.
You didn't have to see it.
[Chuckles] It really does work
on just about anybody.
Anybody who watches it, Max.
But why would
anybody watch it?
Why would anybody watch
a scum show like Videodrome?
Why did you watch it, Max?
Business reasons.
Sure. Sure.
What about
the other reasons?
Why deny you get your kicks
out of watching torture and murder?
You murdered Brian O'Blivion,
didn't you, you freak?
Did you enjoy that?
North America's
getting soft, patron.
And the rest of the world
is getting tough.
Very, very tough.
We're entering savage
new times,
and we're going
to have to be pure...
and direct...
and strong...
if we're gonna
survive them.
Now, you and this, uh,
cesspool you call
a television station...
and, uh, your people
who wallow around in it...
and, uh, your viewers...
who watch you do it...
you're rotting us away
from the inside.
We intend
to stop that rot.
We're gonna start
with Channel 83, Max.
We're gonna use it for our first
authentic transmissions of Videodrome.
I have a hunch it's gonna be
very popular... for a while.
I've gotta be hallucinating now, right?
I mean...
[Chuckles] you two can't
possibly be for real.
Ah, we did record
your hallucinations, Max,
as I said we would.
And we did analyze them.
You're ready
for something new.
That's terrific.
[Breathing]
What do you, uh...
What do you want from me?
I want you to open up, Max.
Open up to me.
[Breathing Continues]
I've got something
I want to play for you.
[Breathing Continues]
Oh, my God!
[Coughs]
[Convex]
We want Channel 83, Max.
- [Grunting]
- Give it to us.
Give us Channel 83.
Kill your partners.
Kill them.
Kill your partners
and give us Channel 83.
[Grunts, Exhales]
[Grunting]
Aah.
[Squishing]
[Gasps]
[Convex]
Give us Channel 83.
Kill your partners.
Kill them.
Kill your partners
and give us Channel 83.
[TV Noise]
Hello, Max.
[Office Workers
Chattering]
[Man]
How ya doin', Max?
Where's Moses?
He's in a meeting with Rafe.
I'll tell him you want him.
Don't.
[TV Noise Continues]
[Phone Rings]
[Man] We dub in a funny track.
Gentle comedy.
Mm-hmm. And you'd be
the one to write it.
Yeah. Yeah, I would. I used to write
in high school, then I lost it.
Hi, Max.
You're just in time to throw some light
on an interesting problem.
Don't.
Max.
What the fuck?
[Man]
Jesus!
[Man #2]
It was from the boardroom!
Max, what happened?
Are you hurt?
- They killed... They...
- [Gasps] What happened?
- They killed us!
- What happened?
- Jesus! Look out!
- [Woman Screams]
[Woman]
Help!
In here! In here!
Get out!
Just clear outta here!
Come... Get out!
Let me see.
[Office Workers
Shouting, Screaming]
Max!
Max.
[Convex]
Kill Bianca O'Blivion.
She knows too much.
She can hurt us.
Don't let her hurt us,
Max.
Kill her.
Kill Bianca O'Blivion.
[Airplane Passes
Overhead]
[Lock Unlatches]
- o/o/ [Clock Chiming]
- [Door Closes]
[Footsteps]
Bianca O'Blivion.
I run Civic TV.
I was on a talk show
with your father.
So it was to be you
after all.
You've come to kill me.
No. No, I'm Max Renn.
I run Civic TV. I don't...
I don't kill people.
Oh, but you do.
You're an assassin now
for Videodrome.
They can program you.
They can play you
like a videotape recorder.
They can make you do
what they want,
and they want you to destroy
whatever is left of Brian O'Blivion.
They want you
to destroy me.
Destroy you?
[Tape Cassette Loads,
Player Clicking]
[Bianca] They killed her, Max.
They killed Nicki Brand.
She died on Videodrome.
They used her image to seduce you,
but she was already dead.
Don't back away.
I stole it from them
just for you to see.
[Tape Player Clicking]
Videodrome is death.
[Gunshots]
That's better.
So much better.
It's always painful
to remove the cassette,
to change the program.
But now that we have,
you'll see that you've become something
quite different from what you were.
You've become
the video word made flesh.
[Exhales]
I am the video word made flesh.
And now that you are
the video word made flesh,
you know what
you have to do.
You turn
against Videodrome.
You use the weapons
they've given you to destroy them.
Death to Videodrome.
Long live the new flesh.
[TV Reporter] It was only 26 hours ago
in the building you see behind me...
that a bizarre, apparently
motiveless shooting occurred...
which has triggered off
an intensive manhunt by Metro Police.
Thirty-four-year-old Max Renn,
president of the Civic TV Corporation,
is being sought in connection
with the shooting deaths of
two executives at Channel 83...
You wanna see the monkey dance,
you pay the piper.
See what I'm sayin', Teddy?
You know how much my monkey's
batteries cost?
They don't last in the cold.
The cold knocks 'em right out.
I can't dance.
I would if I could.
But, uh, I can't, so...
You got some change, Teddy?
You got somethin'.
Half a buck. Teddy, yeah.
A quarter.
You got somethin', Teddy.
[Bus Rumbling]
Can't ya put somethin' in,
Teddy?
Well, hello, sport.
They call me Brolley.
How can I help you, sir?
- Just looking.
- [Chuckles] Yeah, man.
Well, that's a good one.
There ain't much to see here, but take
your time and have a good look anyway.
Ah, what this?
Yeah, this is one hell
of a scrip you got here.
Very tricky grind.
Can't imagine you'd see things
too clear without them, you know.
Well, don't worry at all. I'm gonna
get you fixed up in no time flat.
[Tape Unpeeling]
[Exhales]
Where's Convex?
Oh, setting up
his trade show.
- Oh.
- Gotta introduce the spring line.
- What's in the box?
- Your head.
- [Chuckling]
- [Chuckles]
- Got your head in this box.
- [Both Laughing]
- Ah.
- Been busy, Max.
- Been readin' about you in the papers.
- Hmm.
Have you been
to see Bianca O'Blivion?
- I saw her.
- And she give you any trouble?
No.
Well, that's good.
Maybe you'd like to visit
somebody else now.
- Is that why you're here?
- Maybe.
You've been very useful
to us, Max.
- We'd like to keep using you
until you're all gone.
- [Tape Breathing]
Open up to me.
[Breathing Continues]
Got something
I wanna play for you.
[Breathing Continues]
- [Gasps]
- [Squishing]
- [Screams]
- [Ticking]
[Shuddering]
[Whimpering]
- [Ticking]
- [Screaming]
See ya in Pittsburgh.
[Screams]
[Dog Barking]
[Child]
Mommy, look what he did to the wall!
Tracey,
come back here!
- Stay with Mommy.
- I want... I wanna see it.
You come with me.
Come on.
We're going home now.
[Crowd Chattering]
[Chattering Continues]
- o/o/ [Stops]
- [Applause]
[Applause Continues]
Well, you know me.
- [Man] Yeah, we know you.
- And I sure know you.
- Every one of you!
- [Applause]
We're here to celebrate
the arrival of our spring collection,
the Medici line,
and our theme for this year
is based on two quotes...
from the famous Renaissance statesman
and patron of the arts...
Lorenzo de Medici.
"Love comes in at the eye,"
and " The eye
is the window of the soul."
Now, I think that even Pete...
oughta be able to sell the hell
out of a classy campaign like that.
[Applause]
[Gasps]
[Panting]
Oh, God!
- [Crowd Chattering]
- [Gasping] No!
- [Gunshots]
- [Grunting]
- [Woman Screams]
- [Gunshot]
- [Audience Screaming]
- [Gagging, Choking]
Death to Videodrome!
Long live the new flesh!
- [Feedback]
- [Gagging Continues]
[Feedback Continues]
[P. A:
Convex Gagging]
[Convex Gagging,
Grunting]
[Water Dripping]
I was hoping you'd be back.
I'm here to guide you, Max.
I've learned a lot
since I last saw you.
I've learned that death
is not the end.
I can help you.
I don't know
where I am now.
I'm having trouble...
finding my way around.
That's because you've gone
just about as far as you can
with the way things are.
Videodrome still exists.
It's very big, very complex.
You've hurt them, but you
haven't destroyed them.
To do that, you have to
go on to the next phase.
What phase is that?
Your body has already
done a lot of changing,
but that's
only the beginning,
the beginning
of the new flesh.
You have to go all the way now.
Total transformation.
Do you think you're ready?
I guess I am.
How do we do it?
To become the new flesh,
you first have to kill the old flesh.
But don't be afraid.
Don't be afraid
to let your body die.
Just come to me, Max.
Come to Nicki.
Watch. I'll show you how.
It's easy.
Long live the new flesh.
[Jacket Unzips]
[Gunshot]