[ Whispering sound ]
[ Whispering continues ]
[ Seagull cawing ]
[ Whooshing soun]
[ Whooshing continues,
whispering sound ]
whispering continues ]
[ Whispering continu,
faint ]
Did you hear that?
What?
[ Moans ]
Say, barbara?
[ Whispering sound,
faint ]
Did you--
did you hear that?
Could've sworn
I heard whispering.
You were
reading my mind,
that's all.
My thoughts
sound like whispers.
Oh, yeah?
And what were you
thinking?
Mmm, I love you, doc.
[ Giggles ]
You sure make it fun
to wake up before dawn,
I'll tell you that.
[ Whispering sound
continues ]
[ Whooshing sound,
whispering continues]
Frank?
Hey, frank?
[ Spits ]
Hey, frank.
Did you finish
last night?
No.
Oh, honey.
It's a quarter
to 6:00.
It's important.
Okay. Okay.
Thanks.
Okay.
That's everything.
[ Gasps ]
Helium for the balloons!
I'm picking up a tank
at harold's right after
I drop you off,
per your instructions.
Did I think of that?
Cool.
I must be
starting to get this
delegating authority stuff.
Well, Mrs. Magoo,
I guess that's why
they made you principal.
Honey, don't smo.
Hey, come on, come on.
You're gonna make me crash.
Look, I'll quit smokin'
when you decide to get
pregnant, all right?
Ahh--
[ Giggles ]
[ People chattering ]
Hey, guys!
[ Chattering
continues ]
Hey!
Hi. Hi.
[ Talking, indistinct ]
[ Grunts ]
Be careful.
Here I come.
Watch it.
Watch your step.
Ooh!
Thanks. Okay.
[ Chattering continues,
indistinct ]
You all right?
[ Woman ]
Hey, jill!
[ Jill]
Hey!
Hi.
Great.
Who's the chef?
Oliver.
Oh, great.
I love burnt hot dogs.
Thanks. So when's
ben coming home?
Six weeks,
four days and...
Nine hours.
[ Laughs ]
Okay, now, watch the edges.
Don't spill it.
I got it.
Let's take it
over here.
Hey, callie. How are ya?
Frank.
Good. Good to see you.
Hey,
where's my helium?
Say you love me, baby.
Not until you get me
my helium.
[ Falsetto voice ]
Righty-o. I'll get
right on it, dear.
See ya.
Oh, you go here.
Okay.
There's jill.
I've got those receipts here.
Hey, how ya doin'?
Hey, man,
how the hell are ya?
All right, bye.
Bye.
See you later.
Barbara!
Hey, frank!
Good morning, sam.
And you must be cindy.
It's nice to finally meet you.
How are you today?
Shall we go in
and take a look around?
You're both
gonna love this place.
Harold.
Morning, doc.
Hey, frank.
Doc,
how the hell are ya?
Headin' over
to the school fair?
I gotta go to butler county
today, make my rounds
at the hospital.
You gotta try out this muscle
machine I made, show everybody
how strong you are.
I should probably just sit
in the shade and watch
you young guys do it.
[ Doc laughs ]
[ Doc ]
See ya, tough guy.
Right.
[ Chattering,
applause, laughing ]
[ Man ]
Okay, thanks, ji.
We need finger paints.
Okay,
uh, I'll get 'em.
[ Chirping ]
[ Belches ]
[ Sighs ]
Finger paints. Okay.
[ Chirping continues]
[ Whooshing sound ]
Yikes.
[ Whooshing continues,
whispering sound ]
whispering continues ]
♪ [ Wind Chime ]
[ Engine idling ]
[ Birds chirping ]
♪ [ RADIO: Country ]
[ Chirping continues ]
♪ [ RADIO:
Continues ]
♪ [ Humming Along ]
♪ [ Continues ]
Whoa!
[ Static crackling
on radio ]
[ Man ]
Well, a civilian pilot
spots the smoke,
and then I get here
and find two of my offics
passed out like babies.
Everything on that side
of the white line is out cold.
So somebody starts talkin'
about chemical weapons,
somebody hits
the panic button.
And then you peoe
are callin'.
There you go.
Look, there is
no research la;
there is
no chemical plant;
there is no toxic waste dump;
there is no nuclear plant.
There's no nothin'
around here.
Okay.
[ Officers,
people talking ]
Nothing on the news channels,
nothing on the news services;
nobody's got it yet.
Good.
I'm just gonna
take myself in there
and get a look-see.
Hey, ed.
Hey.
That's frank mcgowan's
truck, right?
What's left of it.
Lucky you wasn't
in town today, doc.
What's going on here?
Nobody knows nothin',
not even that fed doctor
down there.
She brought this
whole circus with her,
and they ain't got a clue.
[ Dispatcher on radi]
10-4, west end,
all emergency vehicles
en route, code three.
[ Police radio continues,
indistinct ]
Go on out there and see what
the hell's goin' on. Be careful.
Okay.
[ Man #1 ] stay here?
[ Man #2 ]
Yeah, we're just waitin'.
All right, goo.
- [ Sighing sharply ]
- oh, no!
- hey!
Pull him back!
Get him outta there!
[ Officers,
men yelling ]
- get him do!
- stay back!
- excuse me!
Hits 'em like a hammer, doc;
that's all we know.
Some kind of chemical, gas?
[ Woman ]
No, it can't b.
The edges
of the affected area are
well-defined, stationary.
[ Officer ]
Doc, this is Dr. Susan-
verner.
Like turner, with a "v."
Epidemiologist,
national science foundation.
Alan chaffee.
M.d.?
Yeah.
He's breathing; good pulse.
I think he just fainted.
Is midwich
affected by this?
My hunch would be yes.
My wife's in midwich.
We tried to get through for
the last six hours. Nobody
picks up or calls out.
Could somebody please
get me some blood
and urine samples?
Y-yeah.
[ Man #1 ]
What's the cal?
[ Moos ]
[ Man #2 ]
Ninety-eight.
[ Man #1 ]
You goin'?
Okay, all righ.
[ Mooing continues ]
Just take it easy.
Somebody get him a blank.
[ Groaning ]
[ Both groaning ]
[ Bird chirps ]
[ Chirps ]
[ Man ]
What happene?
[ People groaning
quietly ]
[ Whines ]
[ People talking quietly ]
[ Woman ]
Ohh.
[ Talking continues ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Sizzling ]
[ Sirens wailing ]
Barbara?
Barbara. Thank god.
Are you all right?
Sweetheart,
are you okay?
I'm cold.
All right, come on.
Let's go home.
[ Quiet rustling ]
[ Quiet clicking ]
[ Screams ]
[ Geiger counter
clicking ]
[ Police rad,
indistinct ]
[ Amplified breathing ]
[ Geiger counter
clicking continues]
[ Breathing continue]
Oh, no.
[ Reverend ]
Heavenly father,
we mourn these lives,
cut short without warning
or apparent purpose.
We search for a reason
and find none.
We have become accustomed
to the power of science,
so when we were struck down,
we turned to science
and asked, "why?"
But it
could not answer.
So now we turn our es
toward heaven...
And seek our comfort
in god's infinite merc.
Let us pray.
Our father,
who art in heaven,
[ Mourners praying along ]
Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done,
on earth
as it is in heav.
Give us this day
our daily bread...
And forgive us
our trespasses...
As we forgive those
who trespass against u;
and lead us not
into temptatio,
For thine is the kingdom
and the power and the gly
forever and ever.
Amen.
Did you ever hear
of charles fort?
Mm-mmm.
He wrote
the book of the damn;
about things nobody's
been able to explain,
like frogs
falling from the sky,
blue snow, red rain.
Are you suggesting
I read him?
No, no.
It's just that...
Sometimes mysteries
don't get solved.
I mean, what if something
like this happens again?
I don't know.
What do I do?
Can I call you?
Well, of course
you can call me.
Oh, and by the way,
I suggest you read
sir arthur conan doyle.
As sherlock holmes
once said,
when you've eliminated
the impossible,
whatever remains,
however improbable,
must be the truth.
Ohh.
Ooh.
[ Sighs ]
It's not possible.
You made a mistake.
Do it again.
Well, I mean,
I don't have a problem...
Running the tests again,
callie, but--
I have felt like this
before in the morning.
It is just some kind of bug.
[ Woman weeping ]
Melanie?
Melanie.
What's the matter?
Maybe I can help.
No. You can't.
[ People chattering,
laughing ]
[ Man ]
There they are!
Hey, you guys!
[ Woman ]
We're empty!
We need some more he!
Hi, how are you?
Oh, it's good to see you.
Hi.
[ Chattering
continues ]
Wow.
Whoa!
Hey, ben,
this is fantastic.
[ Laughing,
chattering continues]
[ Jill ]
Callie, look up and smile.
So, ben,
after a year in japan,
did you ever think
you'd have to get used
to being a dad?
[ Gasps ]
Hello, doc.
I said, hello.
[ Chuckles ]
How long you been
standing there?
Oh, ages.
Liar.
[ Sighs ]
Hey, big guy.
Mmm.
[ Chuckles ]
Mmm!
Hey, why are you
kissing me like that?
I wanted to know first,
so I used
a home pregnancy kit.
Well, honey, you know those--
those are unreliable.
And that's why I went to see
Dr. Cornright to make sure.
Gonna open it?
[ Paper tearing ]
Alan?
[ Knock at door ]
Hi.
You got a minute?
Sure.
Well, everything's positive.
Yare pregnant.
[ Sighs ]
We'd been trying,
you know.
Look, um,
I wanted to tell you
something before you hear it
from somebody else.
There's a lot
of pregnancies.
I mean, a lot.
Much more than would
normally be expected.
Wh-what do you mean?
Well, um--
is something wrong
with my baby?
No, it's nothing to
indicate that. You're a
normal, healthy young woman--
alan, don't talk to me
like a doctor.
Okay.
All the pregnancies...
Seem to date from
the day of the blackout.
Oh, no!
[ People talking ]
[ Jill ]
Dr. Susan vernr
has flown in--
this is all 'cause of
that blackout, ain't it?
[ All shouting ]
- just come out
and say something!
- they don't know for sure!
They are all
gonna be deformed!
Why won't everyone
say it?
[ Shouting continues ]
W-w-wait a minute.
That's not true!
That's n-- excuse me!
That's not true.
There's no reason
to believe that.
Barbara and I are pregnant.
We know how you feel.
We know what
a lot of you are thinking,
so let me say right now...
The same thing
I've told a lot of you
INDIVIDUALLY:
The standard tests
have not revealed
one abnormality.
Anywhere. Not one.
All right?
[ Crowd murmuring ]
Let's listen
to Dr. Verner, please.
She's come to talk to us.
Dr. Susan verner,
ladies and gentlemen.
I wanna start off by saying
we are all very concerned
about your well-being.
[ Crowd murmuring ]
But ultimately
it will come down
to individual decision.
And I understand
that these decisions...
Will be probably the most
intimate, personal,
difficult decisions...
That you ever make
in your life.
However,
because your pregnancies.
Have attracted intense
scientific interest,
including the nationl
institutes of health.
And national
science foundati,
those of you who decide
to have your child...
Will have all
prenatal expenses paid.
You'll also receive $3,000
monthly as an allowance.
[ Murmuring continues ]
If you allow your child to
be examined and tested on
some sort of regular bas.
Is that $3,000 a family?
What if your wife
and your daughter
both have kids?
Then you would receive
$6,000.
[ People whispering ]
[ Woman ]
$6,000?
!
[ Talking resumes ]
Look, I-i don't want you to
interpret this allowance...
As some sort of a pressure.
It isn't.
It's your decision.
And if you decide
to terminate,
then of course you have
the right to do that.
You can do it privately,
or if financially unable
a medical team will be
brought in next week.
The choice
is yours.
That's killing babies.
[ Talking resumes ]
[ Jill ]
Callie?
Are you okay?
Ben's moving out.
Oh, callie.
He won't believe me.
What are you gonna do?
I can't keep it.
I mean,
it can't be ben's.
I just don't--
I just don't
understand.
Something very strange
is happening...
To all of us, callie.
You know, they say the--
the roberts girl
is a virgin.
What are you
going to do?
I don't know.
[ Rumbling,
loud whispering sound ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Whispering continu,
quieter ]
[ Whispering continues]
[ Baby cryin]
[ Rumbling continues ]
Hey.
You all right?
Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
Yeah, uh--
it was just a dream.
Okay. Okay.
Let's go back
to sleep, huh?
Yeah.
[ Moans ]
[ Phone ring]
What's going on,
doctor?
Nothing.
They have
apparently decided
to keep their babies.
All of them?
Why?
That's a very good
question.
[ Women groaning,
panting loudly ]
Nurse!
[ Groaning,
panting continue]
Keep pushing!
Push!
All right, mom!
Okay, here we go.
Here we go. Almost.
[ Groaning loudly ]
Almost done!
Good, mom.
That's good.
Push, push, push.
[ Woman screaming,
groaning continues ]
[ Woman screaming ]
Hurry!
Oh, god!
[ Panting ]
[ Reverend ]
That's it. That's it.
[ Screaming continues ]
Ohh! Ohh!
You're doing great!
Take a deep breath and-
deep breath and push!
Push, push, push!
Come with that.
Push a little more.
Push, barbara, push.
A little more.
Oh, it hurts.
[ Panting ]
Push. I know. Push. Push.
[ Screaming,
panting continue]
Help me. Help me!
Help me, help me, help me!
We've got a problem!
[ Screaming, crying ]
Icu, now!
[ Shallow,
rapid breathing ]
[ Women, men shoutin]
[ Woman screams ]
Ohh!
[ Midwife ] good gir!
Push, push, push!
[ Alan]
Come o!
Yeah!
There we g!
Good, barbara! Ohh!
And there we g.
[ Baby cryin]
Aw, beauty!
Lookin' great, sweetie.
[ Crying, panting ]
Good job.
[ Baby continus
crying ]
It's a girl, hon.
Is it all right?
It's a girl?
She's fine.
Push!
Ohh! Ohhh!
There we are. Clamp this.
Look, here's your ba.
Here's your baby.
Ohh!
[ Panting heavily ]
[ Baby cryin]
Oh, god. Oh.
[ Whispering ]
Look at him. Look at him.
[ Crying continues ]
He's beautiful.
[ Babies' cryig
continues ]
[ Baby cooing ]
Oh, ben.
[ Susan ]
Come on, just breathe once.
Oxygen. Oxygen.
[ Man ] watch the BP.
[ Woman ] just relax.
You're hyperventilatin.
Come on, sweetie,
you can do it. Push.
Doctor, get your ass
over here and help me!
Yes, Doctor vern.
Bear down on her!
Push!
All right, here we go!
Come on, push!
Give me one big push!
[ Groaning ]
Come on, here we g!
Come on!
Come on.
[ Squishing soun]
I'm sorry.
It's stillborn.
[ Groaning, crying ]
Get some fluid in her.
Yes, Dr. Verner.
We need another clam.
Hold it. Then we'll put it
in the E.DI. Unit.
Hey, how we doin'?
Everything all right?
We lost
the roberts baby.
Oh, god. How?
Respiratory failure.
Umbilical asphyxia.
[ Doctor ]
You held up pretty wel.
[ Woman chuckles ]
Where did you take the baby?
I saw you take
melanie's baby outside.
I took the baby
for an autopsy.
I didn't want
the other mothers to see.
I baptize thee...
In the name
of the father...
And the son...
And the holy spirit.
Amen.
[ Whispering ]
I got you. I got you.
[ Cries ]
Oh, yes.
[ Crying continues ]
[ Reverend]
Let us pra.
Heavenly fathe,
we thank you...
That by the water
of the holy spirit...
You have bestowed upon
these, your servants,
the forgiveness of sin...
And have raised them
to the new life of grace.
Sustain them, o lord,
in your holy spirit.
Give them an inquiring
and discerning heart,
the courage to wl
and to persevere,
the spirit to know
and to love you...
And the gift
of wonder and joy
in all your work. Am.
[ All ]
Amen.
[ Baby cooing ]
Good girl.
[ Baby cough]
That's a good girl.
Yeah.
Note how the section of hair
is flat on one side
then arced on the other,
like a capital "d."
Right.
The texture is, I don't know--
it's unusually soft.
What did you think
when you looked
at her nails?
Narrower than normal.
Any results yet
from the dna testing?
Common genetic
characteristics.
Almost as if they're siblings
from the same parent.
But, uh, it's way too early
to have anything conclusive.
Hey, baby.
What ya doin'?
David.
You can spell your name.
[ Chuckles quietly ]
How can you
spell your name?
Huh?
How can mommy's...
Smart little boy...
Spell his name?
[ Soup boiling ]
[ Cries ]
Sweetie,
was the soup too hot?
Okay, baby.
We're gonna go see
our friend mara.
Yeah.
[ Shivers ]
[ Boiling
continues ]
Okay.
[ Babbling ]
Yeah.
[ Screams ]
Barbara?
[ Screaming continue]
Oh, god!
[ Screamg
continue]
Barbara!
Stop that!
[ Screaming continues ]
No! Are you crazy?
How could you-- stop it!
Barbara! Barbara! Oh!
[ Barbara screamin,
crying ]
[ Screaming continue]
[ Jill screaming]
Oh, god!
Barbara.
Honey, can't you tell me
what happened?
[ Seagulls cawin]
[ Alan ]
Barbara?
Barbara!
Barbara! Don't!
No! God, no!
Barbara!
[ Man ] I understand
there are some recent
developments at midwic.
Yes.
The children are beginning
to interact more
with the general community.
There have been
a few casualties--
I should say accidents,
suicides--
that might be related to
contact with the children,
but no direct physical
violence was involved.
I have also been trying--
unsuccessfully--
to get Dr. Chaffee
back on the program.
His daughter's the leader,
isn't she? He's probably
got his hands full.
Personal considerations
aren't important,
are they?
I think that the opportunity
to study these children...
Should take precedent
over any considerations.
Let's cut
to the chase here.
It is now of interest
to national security...
That we continue
to carefully monitor
their developing powers.
I ask for
another year's grant.
Good afternoon,
children.
Mara.
Why do you smile?
- you're trying to hide
your thoughts from us.
- oh.
Just how deeply
do you see?
Everything active
in your mind.
But the process that leads
to the spoken words
eludes us.
Why do you
speak some thoughts
and not others?
Wouldn't it be a noisy world
if we said everything
we thought?
Okay, I'm gonna put a drop
of this in your eyes.
It won't hurt.
[ Screaming ]
[ Crying,
screaming continues ]
I'm sorry. Calm down!
[ Crying, screaming
continues ]
I'm gonna wash your eye out!
Shh!
Okay, open your eyes!
It's all right!
Shh! It's okay!
It's okay! Shh.
[ Crying subsides ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming echo,
fades ]
[ Siren wailing ]
How's the doctor?
Corneal scarring.
Most likely
permanent blindness.
How did it happen?
Doesn't remember much.
It'll be listed
as an accident.
It was the children.
There's no proof
of that.
What I want to know is,
are the people
in this town safe?
What are they gonna do
to us?
[ Woman ] alan.
Hi.
This has got to stop.
They don't belong
in regular classes.
It's getting dangerous.
The other children
can't learn.
I was thinking
maybe you could teach them.
They seem
to respect you.
Respect? No.
They don't even know
the meaning of that word.
Why bother?
It doesn't make
any difference what we do.
Alan, we need you.
What am I
gonna teach them?
What am I possibly
going to teach them?
Humanity.
[ Whispers ]
Hello... Sweetheart.
Come on.
There's no need for you
to become emotional.
I'm old enough
to do things by myself.
Hey, david?
You wanna talk
about what happened
at the clinic today?
Why should I be experiencing
emotion at this moment?
Wh-what is that word
you're thinking?
What is "empathy"?
So if I have felt pain,
I should be able
to identify with others...
Who feel pain.
Yeah. Yes.
Good night, david.
What's the matter?
Ya want some?
I'm sorry.
I just can't hack it.
[ Gunsho]
[ Reverend ]
"God said,
let us make man...
"In our image,
after our likeness"
But "image" does nt
mean outer image,
or every statue
or photograph would be m.
It means the inner image,
the spirit, the soul.
So we gather here today...
To remember the inner beauty...
Of one who lost her hold.
Melanie roberts somehow
lost that image of herself...
As a creature made
in god's bountiful spiri.
But what of those
in our midst...
Who do not have
individual souls...
Or spirits?
They have one mind...
That they she
between them,
one spir.
And they have
the look of ma,
but not the nature
of mankind.
David?
What are you
doing here?
Looking for the baby.
The one who was born with us,
the one who died.
How do you know
about that?
The baby's not here.
She was taken away.
Where?
I don't know.
Do you have a memory
of the baby?
But it bothers you.
It hurts. It hurts
to lose a loved one.
She was to be with me.
We were to be together.
How do you know that?
You've lost someone too.
[ Alan ]
Listen. I think
I can teach them.
Well, anyway, I'll t.
[ Sighs ]
I never told david
about the roberts baby.
Right.
And then h-he said,
"she was to be with me"?
What did that mean?
[ Exhales ]
I don't know.
Are they paired up,
like a mate?
Well, what can I teach
such bright young students?
What about
human physiology?
That's at least something
I know a little bit about.
For example,
does anybody here
know how the eye works?
Do you mean
how do we see, or--
well, what else
can the eye do?
- the eyes are--
- the eyes are the windows
of the soul.
Yes. That's right, mara.
I see that you've been
reading proverbs.
I was speaking to robert.
The eyes are
the windows of the soul.
Right.
All right, if you'd rather
talk about philosophy...
Instead of physiology, let's--
let's talk about the soul.
[ Jill on intercom]
Alan. Sorry.
Can you come to my office
for a minute, please?
Um, yes.
I'll be right there.
While I'm away
for just a moment,
why don't you each
take out a volume
of the encyclopedia and--
and try to learn a little
something about our culture.
I know your game.
I know what you're up to.
Ever since you got here,
I been watchin',
watchin' people
leave this town,
watchin' things die.
Ya ain't right.
None of ya.
And one of these days,
somebody's gonna do
somethin' 'bout it.
I don't like the way
you're lookin' at me, boy.
[ Chuckling ]
I got a gun too,
and I ain't the only one.
One day somebody's gonna
get up on a rooftop...
And they're gonna start picking
you little bastards off,
one by one by one.
Well? Ain't ya
gonna do somethin'?
Ain't ya gonna bawl
like all the other
little pissants?
Well, do somethin',
damn it!
[ Grunts ]
[ Softly ]
God.
There are going to be changes.
[ Softly ]
God.
God help us.
The children did it.
I know they did it.
And my daughter
was involved.
Now, who are they?
I'd originally thought
they were some form of mutation,
some abrupt
evolutionary jump.
It was their
communal consciousness,
but I couldn't explain
the blackout...
Or the mass pregnancies.
Midwich isn't the only colony
of such children.
In a township in
northern australia, 30 infants
were born in a single day.
They all died within
ten hours of birth.
In an inuit community
outside of anchorage,
a group of ten children
were born.
There were 20 births
in a small village near
the turkish-iranian border.
Each location was remote,
isolated,
and each had a blackout
the same as midwich.
And how long have you
known about this?
The way I see it,
there's three possibilities.
Number ONE: Parthenogenesis,
the development
of a fetus
without fertilization.
I know. I don't
buy that, either.
Number TWO: We do know
the C.IA. Slipped
large doses of lsd to men...
Without them knowing it
in order to study the effects of
psychotropes on gene structure.
So maybe the government
engineered the blackout,
then artificially
inseminated your women
with super sperm.
First they knocked 'em out,
then they knocked 'em up.
And what's
the third possibility?
Xenogenesis. Implantation.
The production of an offspring
unlike that of the parent.
Or should I say host?
[ Water dripping ]
Come back
to the project, alan.
Not just a matter
of protecting your daughter.
As you can see,
it goes far, far beyond that.
Put this in the back
of your mind.
Don't even think about it
when you're
around the children.
Don't ever let them know
that you know.
Why didn't you tell us?
I mean,
why didn't you warn us?
Because I couldn't.
Well, I couldn't, alan.
If anybody else knew,
the children would know.
Look, I have spent
years of my life building
a wall around this,
hiding it
so they couldn't read
what was in my mind.
But as their powers grow
stronger, they just keep
looking deeper and deeper.
I need your help.
Alan, would you
please just...
Come back to the project?
[ Door slams,
engine starts ]
[ Door close]
We've made our decision.
Discussion will not
change our plans.
We will live
in the abandoned barn
outside of town.
You will bring us suppli.
You can't stop u,
you know.
Don't try.
You've been discussing us
with Dr. Verner.
What did she tell you?
You are hiding something.
I'm not letting you go.
You haven't been given
an option.
Have you?
You know, you don't
always have to do
everything they tell you.
We are the same.
No. You're not.
You're david.
You're different.
I've come to get julie.
Have you seen her?
Is she at the barn?
Fine.
[ Tires screech ]
Are you all right?
I'm sorry.
You're okay, aren't ya?
Julie doesn't want
to come with you.
Well, damn it, I don't
care what julie wants.
Her mother's frantic.
I'm bringin' her home.
[ Engine starts ]
[ Sirens wailing ]
[ Sirens continu]
Some kind
of big accident, doc,
out by the barn.
Alan, wa!
Alan,
I was just informed...
That the other towns
with blackout children
have been destroyed.
What? All of them?
And everyone in them,
the adults and the children.
They couldn't evacuate
without the children
knowing what was happening.
The governments
gave no warning.
God. What about midwich?
I've been told
to pack and get out.
I'm leaving tonight, alan.
Do the same.
Get out while you can.
Another man is dead.
Why do you hate us
so much, mara?
It isn't a matter of hate.
It is a biological obligation.
You are thinking of
what happened to the others.
We have to survive
no matter what the cost.
We are the only ones left now.
I don't see
why we can't reach
an understanding.
Why can't we just
live together?
If we coexist,
we shall dominate you.
That is inevitable.
Eventually you will
try to eliminate us.
We are all creatures
of the life-force.
Now it has set us at one another
to see who will survive.
That's a cruel sport.
Life is cruelty.
We all feed on each other,
exploit each other
in some way to survive.
I don't agree with you.
I think that adaptation
is the key to survival.
Cooperation
and symbiosis...
And compassion.
Why do you think
your own survival depends
upon emotion from us?
Should we pity you?
Empathize with your plight?
You should feel!
You should
feel something!
Without feelings,
you're nothing.
You're just second-rate
mimics of a higher organism.
That's right,
a higher organism.
We're your superiors
in our capacity to love.
Without compassion,
you're a doomed species.
Emotion is irrelevant.
It is not our nature.
Well, I'm not so sure
you're right about that, mara.
Still, you are aware
of the other colonies,
so you must be,
in some basic sense,
aware of who--
whwe are.
Yes.
So the question become,
"should you be
allowed to live?"
You're suddenly
thinking of an ocean.
You're blocking your thoughts
rather effectively
with this image.
We must leave here,
spread out, disperse.
Soon we will have reached
a stage where we can
form new colonies.
You will arrange a method
of getting us away from here.
What if I refuse you?
You are a prisoner
of your values,
and you won't be able
to deceive us.
You know that, don't you?
Father?
Yes. Yes.
- yes, I know that, mara.
- make your arrangements.
We must leave tonight.
You're thinking
of the one who died.
She was
to be my partner.
Yes, it's true.
Without a mate, you are
of less importance to us.
And your development
of emotions is disturbing.
We can't leave you behind,
david.
It is time we resolved this.
[ Gunsho]
Hurry up!
[ Shouting woman ]
Begone, everyone who is proud,
and bring him low,
and tread down the wicked
where they stand!
This is the last of .
All right, get going.
Bind their faces
in the world bel.
Then will I also
acknowledge to you...
That your own right hand
can give you victory!
Yeah!
[ Shouting, chattering ]
[ Gasps ]
I-i'm glad you're here.
I wanted to talk to you.
I really think
that I can help you.
[ Shouting continues ]
[ Woman ] get 'em!
[ Man ] send 'em back
to hell where they belong!
[ Shouting continues ]
[ Jill ]
Please! Please!
You've got to stop!
Please stop!
You gotta stop!
Sarah, please!
Hast thou eyes of flesh?
Dost thou see
as man sees?
[ Slicing ]
[ Slicing continues ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Sirens wailig
in distance ]
[ Sirens continue ]
[ Officer on PA. ] a state
of emergency has been declared.
Please return to your homes...
And remain there
until further notice.
[ Sirens continu]
[ Woman ] come her!
Grab my hand, quic!
[ Man ] come on!
[ Officer on PA. ]
People will be arrested.
Authorized vehicles--
[ Officer #2 on PA. ]
This is a state of emergency.
[ Sirens continu]
Oh.
Oh, please be home.
Alan! The children
murdered sarah.
Susan verner too. I just
found her at the clinic.
The state police are
on their way out to the barn.
They're going
after the children.
We've gotta stop them.
No, no, no.
You can't go out there.
You'll just get hurt.
We've gotta try!
No. The state police can't do
anything to stop the children.
It'll be a bloodbath.
We gotta try.
No, jill! Jill!
Now, listen to me.
Listen to me.
There's another way.
Now, look, something
happened today.
I was able to block mara
from reading my thoughts.
How?
I suddenly thought
of the ocean.
I suddenly saw the view
in front of our house.
You know how
barbara and I used to
dream our dreams there?
We used to stand
on the cliff side,
and right in front of us
was something so much more
powerful than we'll ever be.
Well, that image came to me.
That image came to me,
and they couldn't see past it.
I know I can do that again.
I can build a wall.
I can build a wall
and deceive them.
What are you gonna do?
The only thing
that we can do.
[ Softly ]
Oh, no.
No! No! Not david!
He's not one of them!
No!
[ Sirens wailing
in distance ]
[ Sirens continue ]
[ Dispatcher on radio ]
Possible 417. All units
respond and echo your 10.
[ Dispatcher ]
Multiple suspects.
Possible 417.
All units respond
and echo your 10.
41-A.
41-A, do you copy?
Echo, 41-a. Do you cop?
Okay, we're in position.
Send 'em in.
Roger, this is 2-a. I co.
241 in progress. Stand b.
[ Dispatcher, faint ]
[ Dispatcher ]
Emergency vehicles on standby.
What are you waitin' for?
You got your orders.
[ Tires screech ]
[ Officers shouting ]
[ Cop ]
Get ou!
[ Tires screeching ]
[ Groans ]
[ Automatic weapon firing,
gunshots ]
[ Gunshots continue ]
[ Panting ]
[ Softly ]
Oh, god.
- more death.
- survival.
Tell us what arrangements
you have made for us.
Well, I haven't
had much time.
It is 11:22.
What are you anxious about?
The arrangements.
Um... Oh, yes.
Actually, I, uh--
I left my notebook
out in the car.
I wonder if somebody could
go out and, uh, get my notebook
from the front seat of my car.
David?
No.
I am unable to see
what you're thinking.
Well, I'm just--
just wondering
who's gonna go out and get
the notebook from my car.
- david.
- no.
You are successfully
blocking your thoughts.
You are thinking...
Of a brick wall.
Why do you keep
looking at the clock?
David.
Come on.
We're going now.
Mother, no.
Take your place.
Stop it! Leave her alone!
Jill! Take him!
Take him!
Go now! Go!
[ Groaning ]
[ Alan groaning ]
Don't worry, david.
We'll go someplace
where nobody knows who we are.