[ Gasps, Coughing ]
[ Panting ]
[Pulls Plug]
[ Stops ]
[ Scoffs, Sighs ]
- [ Shrieks ]
- [Dryer Restarts]
Good morning, beauty.
Let's go, or we'll
never leave on time.
I'm totally ready.
[ Laughs ]
Come on. I'll make
you some waffles.
- Mother!
- Caitlin.
Blueberries!
Hey, Cooper.
You want some breakfast too?
Huh? You want some waffles?
Good boy.
[Door Opens]
[Indistinct Arguing]
Oh.
They're at it again.
[Man]
Oh, Christ, that's twice in--
When did they move in?
- Three weeks.
- Mmm, three weeks, yeah.
What's their name?
Feur, I think.
Psych department.
Figures. They're all nuts.
[ Laughs, Moans ]
[ Laughs, Whispers ]
She's awake.
We'll be quiet.
Quick and quiet.
I don't wanna be either.
Hmm. When's she out of here?
Norman Spencer.
All right.
I can't stand the rejection.
I'm going for a run.
- Hey. You okay?
- Hmm?
Yeah.
Come on, Pooper, let's go.
We're gonna have to leave by 11:00
if we want to beat the traffic.
Eleven o'clock.
You know, you can
call me whenever you want.
Sweetheart, I've known this day
was coming for a long time.
I have Norman and the garden
and the new house.
You really
don't have to worry.
- I'm just saying if you--
- Really.
'Kay.
Mom.
Mother.
- Come on.
- I have to go.
* [Indistinct Rock]
Come on, let's go home.
If I don't get you outta here,
they're gonna make you enroll.
- I'll call you.
- Okay.
- Bye.
- Come home often.
- All right.
- Call your mom.
- Okay.
- Beatrice, it was nice to meet you.
- Bye.
- You guys take good care
of each other, okay?
- I won't go to a bar without her.
- I'm just kidding.
- Come on.
Bye.
* [Continues]
[ Sobbing ]
Well, I almost made it.
What you reading?
Genetic Repair Mechanisms
in Eukaryotic Organisms.
Eukaryotic.
How is it?
Excellent.
Ooh, a couple
of Swedish sailor cells...
just gang-divided
a virginal cheerleader cell.
Almost there.
[ Moaning ]
If you have to work--
No, no, just
let me get this.
Okay, almost--
I'm there.
- How's it going?
- Great. I think we cracked it.
The prenatal thing?
Yeah, the targeted repair.
You are so brilliant.
- Yep.
- Madame Curie, Jonas Salk,
Norman Spencer.
- Yes!
- [ Chuckles ]
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- Yeah?
- I am, yeah, really.
It's okay if you're
not, you know.
To tell you the truth,
I'm... excited.
- Really?
- Yeah, yeah.
Get my life back.
Have some time for myself.
Some time for us.
We did a great job.
She's a good kid.
We did.
It's just us now.
[ Sighing ]
I know.
Tired?
Nope.
Wanna fool around?
Yep.
[ Moaning ]
[Loud Moaning, Grunting]
Jesus.
[ Laughing ]
What is he doing to her?
I guess they're making up.
Wait.
Leave it open.
- Think we can take 'em?
- It's worth a try.
[Moaning Continues]
[ Moaning ]
Do the brilliant Norman
stuff some more.
[ Laughing ]
And speak up.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckling ]
[ Sniffling ]
[ Sighs ]
Oh.
[ Exhaling ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
[Woman Sobbing]
[Sobbing Continues]
Hello?
Ouch! Ow!
Mrs. Feur?
H-Hello?
Are you all right?
- [ Gasps ]
- He's so-- It's too much.
[ Sobbing ]
I c-can't. I can't breathe.
And I'm afraid.
What?
What are you afraid of?
That one day
I'll just, just disappear.
Is-- Is there something
I can do?
Can I--
- I've never even met you.
- I know. I'm-I'm sorry.
I've been concerned.
[ Sobbing Continues ]
This... fence, it's so--
I'm sorry. Listen,
would you like to come over
for a cup of coffee or--
Oh, God, he's back!
I'm sorry.
Please forget what I said.
I don't even know what I'm saying.
She sounded terrified.
- Of what?
- Of him, I think.
- Did she say that?
- Oh, more or less.
I-- I want to go over there.
Let's just walk over there.
- Why?
- Well, I just-- I just want
to see if she's all right.
We're not gonna go marching
over to our new neighbors
and accuse them of--
- Honey, that's not
what I'm suggesting.
- Especially since they're...
probably gonna be
keeping us up all night
with their sexual Olympics.
Norman, what if something
were to happen to her?
- Nothing's gonna happen.
- I'd never be able to forgive--
Honey, people argue.
People fight.
It's not our business.
- I've gotta work tonight.
- I know.
This conference is the first
big preview of my paper,
and I've just gotta stay focused
a little while longer.
This is what
I've been working for.
I just wish you could've
heard her, that's all.
Look, I'll tell you
what I'll do.
I'll call Harvey Tomes tomorrow
in the psych department,
[ Sighs ]
and I'll see what I can find out
about the guy, okay?
- Promise?
- Yeah, I promise.
[ Knocking ]
Hey, lady!
What are you doing?
Looking for you.
[ Scoffs ]
What are you doing?
Just trying to drop off
this welcome thing
for the new neighbors.
- Oh, not home?
- Guess not.
You are so good at this.
If I were, I'd
have done it weeks ago.
I give my neighbors some wine
that somebody left at my house.
- Are you staying?
- No, I just stopped by
to see how you're holding up.
Um, good. I'm good.
Are you?
[ Chuckles ]
Why does everyone
find that so surprising?
'Cause your only daughter
just went away to college,
who you're extremely close with,
and, I don't know,
I'd be trippin'.
- Oh, right.
- Well, you had
a hell of a year too.
The move, the new house,
the garden.
- The car.
- A minor setback.
- Was that a year ago?
- This week.
Hmm, wow, now Caitlin.
Big stress stuff.
Okay, I'm a little tender.
[ Chuckles ]
Good. You're human.
And so far this week,
my big task...
is to take pictures of my roses
for the garden club.
Ooh, got here just in time,
didn't I? Brought you something.
- Oh, what is that?
- It's kambucha mushroom tea.
It soothes heartache
and promotes psychic wellness.
Floriana suggested I bring it.
Oh, great, so you're discussing
me with your psychic now?
No, no, and she's not really
a psychic. She's just
a very enlightened spirit.
- Like me.
- That's worse.
You're gossiping about me.
[ Scoffs, Clears Throat ]
Notice anything different?
Oh, my God!
You bought it!
- [ Laughs ] Yep.
- Nice.
Yes, it's a beautiful
thing, a limony.
You lose a husband,
get a car.
- Think it'll help me pick up dudes?
- Absolutely.
Cool. Well, I have to run.
You take care.
- Thanks for the tea.
[ Sighs ]
- Mm-hmm.
[Thunder Rumbling]
[Thunder Continues]
Norman.
- Norman. Norman!
- [ Gasps ]
- Come here. You have to see this.
- Wha--
- What's the matter?
- Look.
- What, Claire?
- [Thunderclap]
I th-- I thought I saw--
- I--
- What?
- I thought I saw something.
- Oh, Jesus. Great.
[ Groaning ]
Ow!
[ Sighs ]
[Turning Doorknob]
[Claire]
Hi. Is Caitlin there?
Any idea when she'll be back?
You'll be sure to tell her
I called? Thanks, Beatrice.
[ Phone Beeps ]
Well, that's a first.
- [ Growling ]
- Cooper, come on. Get your ball!
What's the matter with you?
[ Growling Continues ]
Cooper, it's your favorite ball.
[ Scoffs ]
[ Grunts ]
- [Phone Rings]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Cooper Growls ]
- Hello?
[ Norman On Phone ]
Hi. I'm stuck here for another
couple of hours. Sorry.
- Oh.
- Unless you want me to come home.
No. Uh, no, it's fine.
You sure?
Claire?
Huh? Oh, absolutely.
Take your time.
- See you soon. Love you.
- Love you. Bye.
[ Phone Beeps ]
Cooper!
Fine. Have it your way.
[Radio Turns On, Noisy Static]
[ Turns Off]
[Man]
We use different kinds,
but now we're using halothane.
Halothane?
Is that a sedative?
It's a dissociative agent.
It paralyzes motor functions,
but leaves her conscious.
She can't move,
but knows what's going on.
- Hi, Mrs. Spencer.
- Hi, Teddy.
- How long does that last?
- About five minutes or so.
Sometimes three.
- Can it be used on all mammals?
- Oh, yeah.
Any kind of procedure where
you want to get the patient
immobile, pain free.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hi, honey.
What's going on? Are you okay?
- I-- I heard noises.
- What kind of noises? Where?
- I didn't want
to disturb you, but--
- What noises? Where?
At the house. I was scared.
- Did you call the police?
- No.
I'm gonna have the police
check on the house while I'm gone.
Oh, great. "Could you check in
on my wife? She's hearing voices. "
Yeah, wait till that gets around.
Honey, I'm gonna be
in New Haven for the conference.
I want you to feel safe.
I do. I do. I'm--
I'm sure it was just...
nothing.
Did you call about the Feurs?
Oh, yeah.
Harvey says the guy's harmless.
Wouldn't hurt a flea.
Warren. Warren Feur.
What abou ther?
[ Groans, Whispering ]
I know he told me. Um--
Oh, I met Schumway today.
Oh, who wrote
that book you love.
We were doing some spiel
for the chemistry department,
so Bob Shine introduces us.
You're gonna love this.
The guy looks right at me...
and congratulates me
on Spencer's Theorem.
He didn't know
your father was dead?
He knew.
Oh, Norman.
[ Laughing ]
- [ Sighs ]
- What?
You're so sensitive about that.
- No, I'm not.
- No, you are.
You always overreact.
Well, I'll have to
watch that, won't I ?
Was it Mary? Uh, Mrs. Feur.
Warren and Mary?
Yeah, Mary, that's it.
Gotta do some work.
[Glass Shattering]
Hello? Mrs. Feur?
[Car Approaching]
[ Gasps ]
Can I help you?
Um, um, yes.
I-- Hi.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm-I'm Claire Spencer
from next door.
Nice to meet you.
I... wanted to stop by and
welcome you to the neighborhood.
- I'm--
- Thank you, but this
really isn't a good time.
- I'm running late.
- Oh. Is your wife home?
No, she isn't.
When, uh--
When will she be back?
I have to go.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It was nice to meet you.
[Jody On Phone]
What's he doing?
[Claire]
Eating dinner, alone.
- TV dinner.
- Oh, that's bad.
- [Doorbell Rings]
- [Jody] That's my shiatsu guy.
Listen, call me back if he starts
in on some serial killer dessert...
like lady fingers.
- You got it.
- Bye.
Where'd you go?
[ Scoffs ]
Shit.
[Dog Barking]
[Barking Continues]
Oh.
- [ Screams ]
- Jesus, Claire.
- [ Stammering ]
- What the hell are you doing?
- I was looking--
- Spying.
- Spying on Mr. Feur.
- How come you're not dressed?
- Dressed?
- Dinner with Stan.
- Tonight?
- Tonight.
- We're gonna be--
- Fashionably five minutes late.
What are you saying?
That he murdered his wife?
Is that so ridiculous?
She was terrified.
Now she doesn't answer
the door, but her car is
sitting in the garage.
Maybe she was out
or in bed with the flu.
- Maybe she was abducted by aliens.
- [Phone Touch Tones]
- Who are you calling?
- Restaurant. Let 'em know
we're running late.
You can't get service till
we're at the center of the bridge.
I know we're not
at the center of the bridge.
- [ Phone Dialing ]
- There. See?
Well, that's a relief.
- Hi, Stan.
- Hey, Claire.
- Norman.
- Hey, Stan. Sorry we're late.
- It's my fault.
- No, we just got here.
- Where's the new squeeze?
- Here I am.
- This is--
- Elena?
Oh, my God, Claire!
I don't believe it!
- [ Laughs ]
- Oh, this is--
- We know each other.
- I mean, can you belie--
- Norman.
- Hello, Norman. How do you do?
- Oh!
- Claire, look at you.
You look beautiful!
There was this brilliant
conductor...
in purple bikini briefs,
with no bangs.
Shhh. That's--
Cursing his ass off in Finnish.
Oh, Claire.
- Oh, God.
- I made an honest woman out of her.
- So how long have you
been up here in Vermont?
- Somebody had to do it.
- Ah, what a job.
- Oh, well, Norman grew up here--
- Do you remember Beau Flynn,
the head of cardio?
- His father worked here.
- How's Caitlin?
- They just sacked him.
- I just dropped her off at college.
- For what?
- Some stalking incident
with an intern, some girl.
- Oh, God, Claire.
- Oh, we're getting so old.
- My God.
- They don't screw around
with that shit anymore.
- Sure don't.
- When was the last time
that we got together?
- It was New York.
- Oh, of course, 'cause
it was right after--
- Right after Michael died.
- Yeah.
- Michael who?
- Marlov.
- Claire's first husband.
- Oh, the musician.
- Yeah, mm-hmm.
You know, we all
toured together, and--
Have you heard her play?
- No.
- Ah!
[ Chuckles ]
No, I, I would sit on stage...
- [ Exhales ]
- during Claire's solo,
and, truly, I had tears
streaming down my face.
I mean, she's fabulous.
So, why'd you stop?
Oh...
[ Chuckles ]
well, one night,
um, after a concert,
I met a dashing, handsome,
genius scientist,
and three months later
I was married.
Ohh. Now, is that--
is that when you guys
moved up to Vermont?
- No, we were living in Boston...
- No, we were in Boston.
when Norman was, um,
offered a position.
- A position?
- Uh-huh.
DuPont Chair in genetics.
Oh, I see, of course.
So now you're teaching
at your father's school.
Uh, well, I actually
don't do much teaching anymore.
I run a research project.
Oh.
Um, Norman's father
had this old stuff--
uh, stately place on a lake.
- Which we're renovating.
- Practically gutted.
- No, we didn't.
[ Laughing ]
- Yes, we did.
[Stan]
Wait till you see this
place. It's beautiful.
- It is beautiful. You'll see it.
- Oh, I bet.
It's haunted.
[Elena]
No? Is it really?
Claire's hearing things.
- What? What are you hearing?
- What?
[ Laughs ]
I, um-- I don't know.
I heard, uh, voices, whispering.
A picture fell.
You know, I completely
believe in all that.
- You do?
- I do.
Wait a minute.
Who do you think it is?
I know exactly who it is.
It's my old man.
He's pissed about us
dicking around with the house.
[ Laughing ]
[ Chuckles ]
Ow! Tsk.
Hmm.
[ Screaming ]
What is it? Jesus.
- What's the matter?
- [ Panting ]
Calm down, Claire. It's okay.
[Claire Continues Panting]
Whose idea was it?
Mine. His.
We both thought--
I didn't want to come here.
- Then why did you?
- Because he was worried about me.
- Your husband?
- Yes. I'm sure he's hoping...
you'll pack me full
of Prozac or lithium or something...
- [ Laughing ]
- so he can live out his life
in peace.
- Do you really think so?
- No.
- And are you on medication?
- No. Well, Valium.
- For sleeping.
- Having trouble sleeping?
Sometimes, um,
when I get anxious.
Do you get anxious only at night?
No, I only take
Valium at night.
For sleeping?
Why do you get anxious?
I don't know.
Why do you think your husband
is worried about you?
Because-- I don't know.
Because ever since
Caitlin left--
Well, ever since
my daughter left for school,
There have been--
I-I've been--
Oh, why is it so hard?
Here, have a fireball.
[ Chuckles ]
Thank you.
It's hard... because
I'm a complete stranger,
and we're talking about things
that are incredibly personal.
Besides, most people when they
come here for the first time,
part of them is wondering
if I think they're crazy.
- [ Sighs ]
- Don't worry.
I am required to have at least
three sessions before I can commit.
- That was a joke.
- [ Chuckles ]
These are good.
They're hot.
There's a ghost in my house.
I saw her in the water,
beside me, in the bathtub.
What does she look like?
She looked like... me.
Oh, only she had green eyes.
Any idea who she is?
Maybe, but I'd rather
not say just yet.
Fine.
So what do you think
I should do?
Try to contact her,
communicate with her somehow.
Find out what she wants.
[ Chuckles ]
What do you want me to do,
go buy a Ouija board?
Ahhh.
Are we hoping the ghost
is gonna have to use the potty?
This where she was.
This is where I saw her.
Oh, that makes sense.
Where'd you finally find one?
Kmart.
You know, I think we're
supposed to sit in a protective
circle or something, aren't we?
- What's that for?
Where'd you get it?
- Never mind.
You stole
the dead woman's shoe.
You have to have something
of the dead woman's.
Says who?
Is that blood on it?
I don't know.
Just place your fingers
on the message indicator.
Okay.
[ Exhales, Shudders ]
We wish to commune
with the spirit--
[ Laughing ]
- What?
- "I wish to commune."
- Oh, forget it.
- What?
- No, this whole thing is insane.
- I'm sorry.
What-What's her first name?
Mary... Feur.
Mary Feur. Mary Feur.
Mary Feur.
[ Sighs ]
We wish to communicate...
with the spirit of Mary Feur.
- Not much happening.
- Shhh.
[ Stifled Laughing ]
What was that?
It was flickering.
Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
Wha-- Did you see that?
Yeah.
[Creaking]
[ Both Screaming ]
Cooper!
Listen,
about our little seance--
Norman doesn't need to know.
I won't tell if you won't tell.
It's-It's just that
ever since the accident,
he, he treats me like
I'm this fragile, loopy--
Well, I am seeing ghosts
in the bathtub, aren't I?
You did wrap your car
around a tree, doing, like, 80.
He was pretty shaken up.
We all were.
It was an accident.
A year ago. I'm fine.
Right?
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
Of course you are.
You're just not much
of a medium, however.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Get some rest.
Did you pick up
any dudes yet?
I have one in the trunk.
[ Laughs ]
Bye.
[Car Drives Off]
- [Indistinct Voice]
- [ Gasps ]
Wha-- What do you want?
[ Panting ]
- She's dead.
- Who's dead?
- You know damn well who's dead.
- This is this Feur thing.
Listen to me. He killed her,
and I'm not crazy!
- Jody and I had a seance
in the bathroom--
- Who did?
Jody and I! Nothing happened.
But when I went back there,
she was there. She was.
- [ Sobbing ]
- Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
You-You had a seance?
Are you angry with me?
What?
- Maybe you resent
how busy I've been.
- No.
You know what I've got
at stake with this paper.
- You know how important
this is to me.
- Yeah.
I can't help but feel
that somehow you're
trying to sabotage me.
- You're trying
to hurt me somehow.
- Norman, this isn't about you.
Something is happening to me,
and it's not to get even or--
and it's not some warped
bid for attention.
Something is happening in our house,
whether you like it or not!
[ Sniffling ]
Claire.
Claire, stop.
You're overreacting.
Don't tell me how to react.
- Will you keep your voice down?
- I will not!
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I am losing my mind.
But what if I'm not?
What if she died some--
- Can we--
- some horrible death?
Can we please not do this here?
- Oh, wow.
- [ Indistinct Chattering ]
You. You think
you're smart, don't you?
You think you got away with it.
Well, I know you killed her,
you murdering son of a bitch!
- Who?
- Don't give me that shit.
Your wife!
- [ Panting ]
- I'm sorry. She's very upset.
- Forgive us, please.
- Honey.
I didn't kill my wife.
Are you all right?
[ Whispering ]
Come on, honey. Okay?
- [ Pants ]
- Come on, baby.
Let's go. I'm sorry.
- Hmm?
- Are you all right?
Oh, yeah. I'm-I'm fine.
What happened, just now?
Oh, I-I just saw Norman's face.
Oh, he was
so frightened for me.
How's your marriage?
Good. Really good.
We've had our moments, I guess,
but he's a wonderful
husband and father.
I mean, sure, he can be
obsessed with his work,
and sometimes it's like,
um, that he doesn't see me.
Or, you know, like I'm--
that there's something
wrong... with me.
That can't feel good.
[ Chuckles ]
No.
Okay, okay, I-I-I see where
you're going with this.
But my marriage is fine.
Now, I have had some kind
of empty nest episode...
where I-I saw...
some things
that weren't there.
Let's deal with that.
I'm-I'm willing to deal with that.
[ Sniffs ]
"Thought you might need this.
Love, Jody."
[ Chuckles ]
Uh-oh.
Mrs. Spencer--
[ Sighs ]
I wanted to apologize...
for scaring you like I did.
When I thought about what
that must have seemed like--
Please, let-let's just--
[ Sighs ]
- Claire Spencer.
- Mary Feur.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
Very much.
That day at the fence,
you seemed terrified.
I-I don't think I imagined that.
No.
What were you so afraid of?
Have you ever felt so completely
consumed by a feeling for someone,
that you couldn't breathe?
Thought that your time together
was so passionate and consuming...
that you felt physical pain
when they would leave?
Um, sure.
I couldn't catch my breath,
and I panicked.
I never dreamed
anyone would hear me.
I tried to leave him.
I went to my mother's
in Providence.
But he brought my things up
in the middle of the night
during a rainstorm...
and pleaded with me
to come home.
- [ Sighs ]
- You must think that I'm pathetic.
No. No. I, I don't.
I'll make this quick.
I've just gotta talk to Sidon,
get him to okay my budget
before he goes to Europe.
What is Templeton's
wife's name again?
- Lois, honey.
Phil and Lois Templeton.
- Lois, that's right.
Don't let her corner you.
She'll chew your ear off.
- Evening, Phil.
- There they are.
- How do you do?
- Hi.
- How nice to see you again, Lois.
- * [Classical]
- [ Chattering ]
- Oh, hi.
- Hi.
- Oh, stop it.
- [ Laughs ]
Hi, Claire.
[ Chattering Continues ]
White wine, please.
- Thank you.
- How are you holding up?
- Just fine. It's a lovely party.
- Oh.
Norman was telling me
the house is finally finished.
- Almost.
- Wonderful.
It's good to see you doing so well.
- Thank you.
- Well, I was worried.
I don't think I've seen you since
Norman's reception here last year.
You were worried?
I swear, I've become...
that nosey old lady I used to run
away from at Amherst.
No, no, I'm just
not sure what you mean.
You, you got so upset.
Oh, at the party.
For the DuPont Chair.
You remember?
Yeah, I remember
the party, but I--
Oh, God.
I had completely forgotten.
I, I broke your crystal.
Oh, my dear.
Cheap wine glass from the caterers.
But you went
completely pale.
You couldn't get
your breath.
It was as if you
had seen a ghost.
- [Glass Shatters]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Gasps, Sighs ]
"Missing girl."
"Madison Elizabeth."
M.E.
"Fank."
"Madison Elizabeth Fank."
M.E.F.
Claire?
Hey, good morning.
- You been up all night?
- Mm-hmm.
You okay?
Do you remember this?
Uh, uh-huh. This is the girl
that disappeared last year.
- Did you know her?
- No.
Claire, I'm afraid to ask.
[ Sighs ]
Where's all this going?
It's her.
- The woman I saw in the bathtub.
- The ghost.
Yes, the ghost. I thought
it was Mrs. Feur, but it's not.
- Stop it, Claire.
Claire, stop it!
- I'm positive this time.
Stop it!
Look, I know you're
going through something
that I don't understand.
And I have tried to be here
for you, but this is enough, Claire.
Enough!
Do you want to go
see somebody together?
I'll call Dr. Drayton.
Then what, Claire?
What?
Tell me what to do.
It's her.
So let me ask you this,
Mr. McCain or--
- McCann.
- Uh, s-- nothing
was ever found, no car--
- No, nothing.
Listen, uh, this girl's
a real live wire.
She drives around in a souped-up
Mustang convertible.
Most people around here think
she's off tooling around Mexico
somewhere with her fiends.
Police downgraded it to a runaway.
Um, her mother lives
out here in Addison County.
- Mrs. Fank?
- Yeah.
I'm Claire. Um--
I wanted to talk to you
about Madison.
Just plain coffee.
None of that mocha nonsense.
[Claire]
Fine.
You look a little old
for a student.
Oh, I'm not a student.
Uh, we met at a party.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, well, that sounds about right.
I never understood how
a girl that wild got all A's.
She liked to read a lot, though.
Sometimes she'd lock herself up
in her room for days, just reading.
They wanted to put her in
a special school for the gifted
when she was young.
[ Chuckles ]
Maddie wouldn't hear about it.
I don't know where she got it.
She didn't get it from me.
She probably got it from
her father's side of the family.
She never really
mentioned her father.
Yeah, well, she wouldn't.
She was 12 when he left.
Never spoke about him after that.
[ Sighs ]
You don't even need the sound.
You can pretty much tell
what's happening by the faces.
I turn it up sometimes, though.
Feels like there's someone here.
Why are you here?
I don't know.
Do you want to see her room?
[Door Opens]
Full scholarship. Princeton too.
She wanted to stay
on the east coast.
You must be so proud.
[ Chuckles ]
These are the last pictures
taken of her.
The police used this one.
- [Phone Ringing]
- Let me get that. Excuse me.
- [Mrs. Fank]
- Hello?
[Continues, Indistinct]
[Door Opens]
[Norman]
Claire?
[Door Closes]
[ Smacks Lips, Sighs ]
Hello, Dr. Spencer.
Mrs. Spencer.
[ Chuckles ]
Forbidden fruit.
You got a problem with that?
I guess this means you're
not mad at me anymore, huh?
I wouldn't go that far.
Oh.
[ Laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Grunts ]
Hey.
Take it easy, huh?
What's got into you?
Mmm. Ow!
- What's the matter?
- It's too rough.
Since when?
[ Grunts ]
You--
- Jesus Christ,
it's a brand-new shirt.
- Shhh.
- Claire, listen to me.
- Why don't you shut up, Professor?
Why don't you just...
shut up... and...
[ Indistinct Whispering ]
I think she's starting
to suspect something.
Who?
- Your wife.
- [ Gasps ]
Stop it!
[Gasps, Groaning]
- You know.
- What the hell are you doing?
I know.
[ Exhales ]
I was there.
Just before the accident.
Oh, I remember now.
What?
I came to the door.
There was whispering.
I saw you in the mirror...
lying there... with her...
in our house.
- Claire, listen to me.
- Oh, oh.
She was at the DuPont party,
staring at me.
- It was her.
- Honey.
That's why I couldn't breathe.
That's why l--
- That's why I dropped the glass.
- Honey, that was last year.
- We were having troubles.
- So you slept
with a fucking student?
- That's not what I'm saying.
- Don't touch me.
Get away from me.
[ Sobbing ]
Get out!
I said get out!
Fine.
Claire, please, please--
I gave up everything.
Claire, please don't--
- [ Sobbing] My life, my music!
- I never asked you to quit.
Oh, there was never
any other choice!
You had to-- to be perfect daddy.
That meant perfect wife,
perfect family!
That's not fair.
You were a single mother
touring with a baby.
You were happy to give it up.
And when you did, you hated me
so you gave it all to her!
- Who?
- Caitlin!
- You leave her out of this.
- And then, out of nowhere,
- some bright young woman
finds me attractive--
- Stop it!
- And I slipped.
God help me, I slipped.
- I'm not gonna listen.
- Claire, I tried to break it off.
- You should've tried harder.
I was in Adamant.
In Adamant?
That artsy little hippie village
a couple hours away down on 7.
I stopped at this little cafe, and
I see Norman sitting in the back,
but he wasn't alone.
It was a young blonde woman.
I didn't see her face.
And I didn't think
anything of it at first.
I was walking over to say hello.
And they started arguing
in such a way...
that it stopped me.
And then a few days later,
you were in the accident,
and I get a bizarre call from
Stan working at the hospital,
asking me was I with you
that day, if you were upset.
He made it sound like
you had deliberately
driven your car into a tree,
and I thought, "Oh, my God,
Claire's found out. "
And when I went to the hospital,
I see Norman...
and he was so desperate
at the thought...
of losing you.
I couldn't say anything.
Please...
don't hate me, Claire.
I don't hate you.
[Phone Ringing]
[ Answering Machine ]
Hello, this is Miss Jody.
Can't get to the phone.
Leave your name and number,
and maybe I'll call you back.
[ Machine Beeps ]
Jody, it's Norman.
I'm looking for Claire.
Will you please--
Ask her to call home, please.
[Machine Beeps]
I can't talk to him.
Will you call him and tell him
I'll be home in the morning?
I have to ask him something.
[Thunder Rumbling]
Norman?
[Water Running]
Norman!
No-- Oh, God.
- [Stan] How's his blood pressure?
- [Woman] 140 over80.
- And how about his rhythm?
- Rhythm is normal. Normal sinus.
- No sign of arrhythmia.
- Good.
Pulse ox is normal.
His pupils are equal and reactive.
- I'd still like
to take you down, sir.
- I'm fine, really.
- Dr. Powell, I'd recommend
a cardiac workup.
- Oh, please.
- I'll take care of that.
- Okay, he just needs to sign
the release form, then.
- Okay, thanks, guys.
- Sure.
Norman, they can take you
for a CAT scan tomorrow
if you start feeling dizzy.
I'm not going to the hospital...
unless they have a miracle drug
for clumsiness.
Honey, I'm so sorry.
I'm glad you came home.
- Thank you.
- Oh, you're welcome.
You know, if that breaker
hadn't popped, he--
- I know.
- Yeah.
Don't worry, Claire.
You just keep him quiet
tonight, okay?
- Okay.
- Oh, in the future,
you might want to think
twice about keeping anything
electrical next to the tub.
- Oh, thank you.
[ Laughing ]
- Thank you.
- Bye-bye. Call me, okay?
- Bye. Okay.
- Oh.
- Bye-bye.
I called you last night.
I left a message on Jody's machine.
I want you to answer
one question.
Did you have anything to do
with her disappearance?
Yes.
I had an affair with her.
And when I tried to break it off,
she became unstable.
She came out here to the house.
She threatened to kill herself...
or you.
I didn't think she'd
go through with any of it.
But then she--
she disappeared.
It was her, Norman.
She tried to kill you.
- Claire.
- You said it yourself.
She wanted you dead.
Are you saying
I was attacked by a ghost?
You had an affair with a girl
who threatened to kill herself,
and now there's a presence
in our house
a young, blonde girl.
Don't you get it?
She did it, Norman.
She's dead, and now
she's trying to hurt you...
or both of us.
- We don't know that she's dead.
- Of course we do!
It's the only thing
that makes sen--
Oh, God.
Oh, it's my-- it's my fault.
I-- I opened the door.
- What are you talking about?
- Madison. I-I-I--
- I stole a braid of her hair, and--
- from where?
- And it gave her power.
- Claire, nothing attacked me.
There are no ghosts.
It was an accident. I'm fine.
It's not your fault.
Are you listening to me?
- Yes.
- Claire, say it. Say it.
"It was an accident.
It's not my fault."
Say it, Claire.
I need to go lie down.
I didn't sleep last night,
and I need to lie down.
I want to be alone for a while.
[Norman]
Hey, Teddy, it's me. Right, yeah.
What's the name of that friend
of yours at Duke,
the "who you gonna call" guy,
the guy that does the,
the paranormal psych stuff?
- Holodnik.
- Holodnik, yeah.
Um, could you contact him
and ask him to give me a call here?
- I'd really, uh, like
to talk to him today.
- Sure, no problem.
[Phone Ringing]
Hello?
Yes, this is he.
Thanks for calling back.
Uh, no, sir.
That, that was my father.
Yeah, he passed away
a couple of years ago.
Yes, he was. Thank you.
Look, the reason
I'm calling is I--
I'm a little out of my depth
here, but, uh...
someone who's very close to me,
um, uh, believes herself to be,
or seems to be in, uh,
contact with some kind of...
entity or spirit, and--
No. No, there's no, um,
history of delusional behavior.
But, well, I guess
what I'm asking is...
is it possible that she could be...
causing these manifestations
through some,
some kind of unconscious
or telekinetic--
Uh-huh.
Well, is there anything else
that it could be?
Uh-huh. And this
has been documented?
Oh. Really?
Um, listen, I'm sorry,
but could I ask you to--
Can I call you back
or have you call me back?
Please. Yes, that'd be great.
Thank you, sir.
Claire!
[ Gasps ]
God.
- [ Coughing ]
- You all right, Claire?
- The braid.
- What?
The br--
Wh-Where's the braid?
- What braid? What
are you talking about?
- [ Stammering, Coughing ]
- Honey, what are you
talking about? This?
- [ Gasping ]
- Is that what
you're talking about?
- Yes.
- What is this?
Where'd you get this?
- I took it from Madison's house.
[ Gasps, Coughs ]
This is hers?
- This is Madison Fank's hair?
- Yes.
What do you think?
I really don't know.
Norman.
Yes... I believe you.
Hey, Coop.
* [Cello]
*
You're playing.
She's gone.
- How do you know?
- I can feel it.
I picked up the book
you ordered at the bookstore.
Claire, I don't know
how to apologize to you
for what I've done.
But if you give me
another chance...
I promise you I'll spend
the rest of my life making
you glad that you did.
Please.
Last sail of the year.
Beautiful, isn't it?
- Mm-hmm.
- We oughta take a drive
before the leaves all disappear.
- Stay at some little
bed and breakfast.
- Look for antiques.
Yeah, we haven't
done that for a while.
Adamant.
Adamant?
Yeah, an artsy
little village down 7.
It's supposed to be charming.
Do you know it?
No.
Maybe we'll stop there for lunch.
What's that for?
Nothing.
[ Moaning ]
Hmm.
[ Panting ]
[ Gasps, Panting ]
Oh, God.
You don't understand
what that is.
Don't I, Norman?
It's Madison's... necklace.
You killed her, didn't you?
I did not.
I didn't kill anyone.
Jesus, Claire, listen to me.
When I got here,
she was already dead.
She killed herself here
in our house to destroy me.
Do you think
that I'm stupid?
She left that for you
in the garden with a letter.
I burned the letter,
and I threw the box in the lake.
A week before...
sh-she showed up
at the DuPont party.
I was terrified.
She insisted,
so I agreed to meet her here.
When I got here,
she'd taken pills.
I, I tried to revive her,
but... she was gone.
There was nothing
I could do.
So-- So I put her
in her car, and l--
I drove
to the boat ramp...
and I rolled it
out into the lake.
I made a terrible mistake.
I know that.
But tell me, Claire, tell me,
what should I have done?
Should I sacrifice everything?
Our marriage?
My work, which I've
spent my whole life on?
Tell me, Claire.
Tell me, please.
'Cause we can
put this behind us.
Our life can go on.
It's not too late.
What are you asking me to do?
I'm asking you to forgive me.
That girl must be brought up.
[ Phone Beeps, Dial Tone ]
[ Touch Tones ]
Hello. This is
Dr. Norman Spencer.
I have some information
about a missing person.
Madison Fank, yes.
Would you send an officer
out to the house, please?
It's, um,
15 Willoughby Lane.
It's about a mile
from the bridge.
Okay. Thank you.
[Phone Beeps]
I'm gonna go get dressed.
[Water Running]
[ Phone Beeps, Dials ]
[ Man On Phone ]
Information. What city?
[ Screaming ]
[ Claire Grunting ]
Don't.
[ Muffled Screaming ]
Stop it!
[ Grunts, Gasping ]
- Ow!
- [ Panting ]
[ Phone Beeping ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Screams, Groaning ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Grunting, Panting ]
[ Sighs, Pants ]
I begged you, Claire.
I pleaded with you.
But you wouldn't let it go.
[ Sighing ]
Oh, Claire...
I never wanted
any of this to happen.
All I ever wanted
was for you to love me,
be proud of me,
to be happy.
[ Sighs ]
She was going to go to the dean.
She would have ruined us.
Did she think I was just gonna
sit there and watch it happen?
You have no idea
what it was like...
to hold her underwater...
watch her life slip away.
But she gave me no choice.
And neither have you.
I can't figure out how
you put it all together.
At first, I thought you knew,
that you created
the whole ghost thing as
some kind of elaborate trap.
Then I realized you believed it.
It's a passive-aggressive
masterpiece.
First time I met you...
all I ever wanted was to spend
the rest of my life with you.
Not gonna happen now.
Ooh, too cold, huh?
I almost froze to death
laying here...
wet, naked,
pretending to be electrocuted.
- Hey, Coop.
- [ Whimpering ]
Howya doin'?
Howya doin', boy?
Let's go get your ball.
Come on. Come on!
[ Cooper Whimpering ]
[Door Opens]
Jody, it's Norman.
If you're there, pick up, please.
It's Norman. Uh, uh, uh--
[Sighs]
Listen, Claire and I had a--
a terrible brawl.
Could you do me a favor?
I'm gonna go sleep at the lab.
Could you check on her
in the morning?
I'm terribly worried about her.
Okay, thanks.
[ Phone Beeps ]
[ Sighs ]
Halothane's starting to wear off.
I'm sure, in some tragic way,
your suicide is gonna help bring
Caitlin and I closer together.
And every time I look at her,
I'll see you.
- Oh, God.
- [ Sighs ]
What's this?
- [ Groans ]
- [ Screams ]
[ Grunts, Groans ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunting Continues ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Whimpering ]
[Water Draining]
[ Gasping ]
[Panting]
[ Coughing ]
[ Panting Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
[Claire Panting]
[ Grunts ]
[ Busy Signal ]
[ Groans ]
[Hangs Up Phone]
[Door Creaking]
[Creaking Continues]
[ Screaming ]
[ Whimpering ]
[Shuddering]
[Phone: Busy Signal]
[ Busy Signal Continues ]
[ Whimpering Continues ]
[ Screams ]
[ Panting ]
[ Panting Continues ]
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Cell Phone Beeps ]
[Phone Beeps]
Oh, sh-- shit.
[ Panting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
- I'm on the bridge!
- [Norman Grunting] Claire.
- Stop!
- Somebody help me!
I'm on the bridge!
[ Grunts ]
[ Gasps, Screams ]
[ Engine Sputters, Stalls ]
No.
[ Shrieks ]
No!
No! No!
[ Gasping ]
[ Gasping, Screaming ]
No!
[Screaming Continues]
[ Grunts, Screams ]
[Whimpering]
[ Screams ]
[ Gasps, Panting ]
Norman... I beg you.
Think of Caitlin.
Please don't, please.
Shhh.
[ Whimpers ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Coughing ]