[Crickets Chirping]
[Dog Barking]
I made the reservations
for 8:15. We're gonna be late!
[Doorbell Rings]
Dr. "Minakis"?
Mandrakis. It's okay.
Everyone gets it wrong
the first time.
- You're Jill. Come on in.
- Hi, Jill.
I'm Mrs. Mandrakis.
Honey, could you get this
for me, please? Thank you.
Oh, I wrote the number
of the restaurant
on the notepad by the phone.
Now, if we're not home
in two hours, that means we've
decided to go on to a movie...
and won't be back until after
midnight... Is that okay?
- Sure.
I've told my service
to pick up any calls coming in
on my office phone, so...
Oh, the children are asleep
upstairs, first door on your
left at the top of the landing.
Now, they're both just
getting over really bad colds,
and I had a terrible time
getting them to sleep,
so please try not to wake them.
- Okay.
- Do you have any questions?
- No.
Okay, great. We're late.
Let's go, honey.
- Okay.
Make yourself at home.
The refrigerator's loaded.
- Okay. Bye.
Oh, we even have some
low-fat yogurt in there.
- Honey, come on, will you?
[Girl Over Phone]
Are you over at Dr. Mandrakis's?
- Yeah, I've been here for about an hour already.
- Isn't it a neat house?
- I guess. I haven't looked around much.
- Did you see his kids?
- They were asleep
when I got here.
They're really cute.
So, what's goin' on?
You think you're
gonna be talkin' to him
sometime tonight?
- Who?
- Bobby.
Probably.
You know,
Bobby asked me
to go out with him
this weekend,
and I was really,
really tempted,
'cause I like Bobby a lot...
as much as you do.
But I told him I couldn't
'cause I didn't think
it was right,
because you were my friend.
- You are my friend.
Yeah, I guess so.
Listen. Do me a favor.
Just give Bobby
the number here, okay?
Don't tell him
I told you to.
- Okay. I gotta go now.
- Okay.
Bye, Nance,
and thank you.
Yeah. Bye.
Bye.
[Phone Rings]
Hello?
[Click, Dial Tone]
[Phone Rings]
Bobby?
[Man, British Accent]
Have you checked the children?
- What?
[Click, Dial Tone]
[Mutters]
[Phone Rings]
- Hello?
- Have you checked the children?
Dr. Mandrakis?
[Click, Dial Tone]
Oh, yeah, sure.
Dr. Mandrakis.
[Rattling]
[Phone Rings]
[Continues Ringing]
Have you checked
the children?
Robert, I don't think
this is very funny.
Bobby.
Who is this?
[Click, Dial Tone]
[Dial Tone Continues]
[Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
[Line Ringing]
[Man]
Golden Bull.
- Hello. Uh...
Is Dr. Mandrakis there?
This is his baby-sitter.
- Hold on a minute.
[Man Over Phone]
Hello?
- Hello? Yes?
- Dr. Mandrakis left the restaurant
about 40 minutes ago.
[Sighing]
- Forty minutes ago?
- That's right.
[Click, Dial Tone]
Okay.
[Line Ringing]
- Operator.
- Hello. Could you
get me the police?
- Is this an emergency?
- Yes.
- Well, no, not really.
- The number's 555-9431.
- Would you like me
to connect you?
- Yes.
[Line Ringing]
- Seventh Precinct,
Sergeant Sacker.
- Hello. Uh,
I've been getting phone calls
about every 15 minutes.
It's a man. I think
he's trying to scare me.
- An anonymous caller, ma'am?
- That's right.
- Has he threatened you?
- No.
- Has he been using
obscene language?
- No.
Sometimes he doesn't
say anything.
He just keeps calling.
Well, there's really nothing
we can do about it down here.
- Is the phone listed in your name?
- No, I'm just a baby-sitter.
It's probably
just some weirdo.
The city's full of 'em.
Believe it or not,
we get reports like this
every night.
- It's nothin' to worry about.
- Oh.
- Hey, have you tried whistling?
- What?
Well, if you can find
a good loud whistle
somewhere in the house,
blow it into the phone,
hard, next time he calls.
Probably break his eardrum.
He won't bother you after that.
No, I...
You're probably right.
It's nothing to worry about.
♪♪ [Jill Humming]
♪♪ [Continues Humming]
[Phone Rings]
Hello?
Why haven't you
checked the children?
[Dog Barking]
[Phone Rings]
[Ringing Continues]
[Ringing Continues,
Stops]
[Line Ringing]
Seventh Precinct,
Sergeant Sacker.
I called you before...
about the man
who keeps calling me?
- Oh, yeah.
- He called me again.
Did you try whistling?
- No. He's out there.
- Out where?
In the neighborhood.
He's watching me
through the windows.
- Did you see him?
- No, but I know he's there.
- Is the house locked up?
- Yes.
Well, then you're safe.
If he wanted to break in,
he wouldn't be calling you.
Please, can't you help me?
I'm all alone here.
Okay. Now, take it easy.
I'll tell you what.
- If this guy calls you again...
- He will call again.
I know he will.
All right. Now, calm down.
Look, I can alert the phone company...
[Whimpering]
So that if he calls again
we can try to trace the call.
- What's your number there?
- Uh, 555-2368.
- And the address?
- Uh...
Uh, 3317 Oakridge.
Oh yeah, I know where that is.
Okay, now, if the guy calls again,
you try to keep him on the line
for at least a minute
so we can trace the call.
I can't do that.
He doesn't stay on for more
than a couple seconds.
Well, uh,
that's the only way
we can help you.
[Sobs]
Uh, by the way,
what's your name?
- Jill Johnson.
- Jill,
the important thing is
for you to relax.
Now, you're safe where you are.
We've got patrolmen cruising
that area all night long.
Just stay calm.
Will you do that for me?
- Yes.
- Okay. In the meantime,
we'll be watching your line.
All right, Jill?
- Yes.
- You call again
if there's any problem.
[Sighs]
Okay.
Good night.
[Click, Dial Tone]
[Phone Rings]
[Ringing Continues]
Hello?
[Man]
It's me.
I know.
Who are you?
[Clears Throat]
I'm not gonna be here
much longer.
Dr. Mandrakis and
his wife are coming home.
I know.
Can you see me?
Yes.
Sorry I turned
the lights down.
I'll turn 'em back up
if you like.
Hmm-mm. Don't.
"Don't"?
You've really scared me,
if that's what you wanted.
Is that what you wanted?
No.
What do you want?
Your blood...
all over me.
You don't know who I am...
or-or where I live.
And Dr. Mandrakis will
take me home,
or maybe even the police.
You've called the police?
I wanna... I wanna
talk to you.
[Click, Dial Tone]
- [Ringing]
- Leave me alone!
Jill, this is Sergeant Sacker.
Listen to me.
We've traced the call.
It's coming from
inside the house.
A squad car's going
over there right now.
Just get out of that house.
Jill? Jill?
[Jill Screams]
[Woman Over Police Radio]
1000 Chestnut, a 918-X.
Are the parents here yet?
[Man]
Yeah, they arrived
about ten minutes ago.
[Sighing]
Christ.
What a homecoming.
What happened, Charlie?
We were less than a block away
when the call came through.
When we got here,
the guy was still upstairs
in the kids' bedroom.
- He was covered with blood.
- Blood?
- Not his own.
- The children had been dead
for several hours.
Oh, Jesus.
He'd been using some old phone
the parents never had disconnected.
Who is he?
Well, we found this
merchant seaman's card on him.
He's English,
entered this country
less than a week ago.
[Sobbing]
How 'bout
the baby-sitter?
She'll be all right.
[Siren Blares]
Dr. And Mrs. Mandrakis, I'm
Lieutenant Clifford. I'm
very sorry about this. I'll try...
[Thunder Rumbles]
[Doorbell Rings]
[Knocking]
[Man]
Sit down.
- Thank you.
So,
you're in business
for yourself now.
- Yes, sir, for the past
three and a half years.
- That's good.
And you'd heard about
Curt Duncan's escape?
Oh, yes.
Do you think
the police will find him?
I know they haven't assigned
anyone to it specifically.
It's an old case.
An old case.
[Rain Falling]
[Sighs]
Can you find him?
Yes.
Maybe not tomorrow,
maybe not this week,
but I'll find him.
- He could be anywhere by now.
- I don't think so.
Because he's a foreigner,
he'll come back to the city.
After six years in confinement,
that's the only place
that's familiar to him.
It's important.
A man murders two children
in cold blood.
Ajury declares him insane.
How could such a person
not be?
He's sent to
a state mental institution...
where the security is
less than perfect,
and he escapes.
It isn't fair.
[Thunder Rumbles]
A thing like that...
should never be allowed
to happen again.
I couldn't
agree with you more.
Go ahead then.
My accountant will
contact you.
Thank you.
[Footsteps Recede]
[Phone Ringing]
[Woman]
State Hospital.
[Buzzing]
[Woman]
Curt Duncan isn't going to run
out and kill more children.
I'm not worried about that.
We had him in here for six years
under continuous therapy,
some of it rather forceful...
drugs, tranquilizers,
depressants, lithium.
Eventually, anyone will
respond to the treatment here.
- You gave him
electric shock?
- Yes, some.
It says here 38.
38 times?
It's a fairly standard
procedure.
Uh, what will happen
to him now without the,
uh, drugs he was on?
Well, there'll be
some deterioration.
That's inevitable.
We can't say how much.
During the time
that you had him here,
did you discover any
particular habits of his...
peculiarities, quirks...
anything that might
help me find him?
Well, yes, of course.
It's all in the folder,
Mr. Clifford.
[Phone Rings]
[Sighs]
Any mail from, uh,
people back in England...
family?
That, too, is in the folder.
[Phone Rings]
Let's get somethin'
straight here, Doctor.
I've been 33 years in
the business of trackin' people
down and puttin' 'em away.
I spent almost a year
on Curt Duncan alone,
with the trial...
and the testimonies and
the background investigations.
Now, I didn't come here
today to look in your
goddamned folders.
In fact,
I wouldn't be here at all
if you'd done your job right.
This is a hospital,
Mr. Clifford,
not a penitentiary.
Everything appertaining to one
of our patients is meticulously recorded
in that patient's folder...
whether you can
make sense of it or not.
Do you want to know
how much we really understand
of the human mind?
Listen.
This is Curt Duncan,
shortly after he was
admitted here six years ago.
[Dr. Monk On Tape]
...is to give you medication
that will calm you down.
We're not putting anything
in your food either.
[Duncan] No?
I don't eat the food.
It doesn't taste right!
- That's Duncan.
- Curt, why are you fidgeting?
- Can't you get comfortable?
- No!
I'm not comfortable!
Don't you touch...
Don't you talk to me.
Don't you touch... me.
Stay away.
- Curt, I'm only
trying to help you.
- Stay away.
[Multiple Voices Shouting]
[Duncan Gagging]
[Pool Balls Clicking]
Hello.
- Whatcha been up to?
- My own business.
Look,
thanks for the light.
Okay?
Next round's on me.
Look, I've got
my own money,
so if you don't mind...
After what I've been through,
I don't mind anything.
See,
that's the whole point:
My mind,
your mind...
where do they fit in?
Do you see what I mean?
[Bartender]
Okay, pal.
[Cash Register Rings]
Do you live 'round here?
Get off of me!
Oh, listen, I...
I didn't mean anything.
You see,
I don't live around...
[Man] Hey!
I think the lady wants
to be left alone.
I think an apology's
in order.
- [Scoffs]
- Is that the best you can do?
- I think you better
move along, pal.
- Bill, it's okay, really. He...
No! I want him
outta here, man!
Hey, are you deaf?
Go on, beat it!
Hey, I'm not gonna
say it again, mister.
- [Grunting]
Get... out!
- [Blows Landing]
- [Bartender]
Hey, Billy. Bill!
- [Groaning]
This is Torchy's.
I want to report a fight.
Who you callin'?
[Moaning]
Hey...
I don't know why I keep
coming back to this dump.
[Groaning,
Trash Cans Rattling]
[Guests Chattering]
[Man]
For a cop, that Charlie Garber
really throws a party.
Charlie?
[Drunkenly]
Hey! Hey, Cliff.
- Hey, let me fix you a drink, man.
- No, I want to talk to you.
- You want some of this?
- No, no, thank you.
- What's goin' on?
- Let me talk to you in private.
Sorry.
- You know these people here?
- Yes, I do. Excuse me.
- What can I do for you?
What's goin' on here?
- I want to talk to you privately.
Ah. Ohh, hey,
come on, Cliff.
I can't take any more
surprises tonight, huh?
[Slurring,
Unintelligible]
Come on, I want to
tell you something.
Let's go upstairs for a minute.
All right, now,
what's goin' on?
Come on, tell Papa.
- Hey, you gettin' married?
- No.
I got a job this week
tracking someone.
Fantastic, Cliff.
Fantastic.
I knew you could do it.
Keep up the good work.
It's Curt Duncan.
Wha...
You didn't know
he escaped?
[Baby Cooing]
- Shh-shh-shh.
- I need your cooperation
on this one.
Yeah, sure,
anything you want...
anything.
♪♪ [Humming]
[Coughing]
Oh, it's you.
- What do you want?
- I came to apologize.
Listen, I'm... I'm the one
who should be sorry.
I didn't mean
for that to happen.
I'm new in town.
I don't know anybody.
Where you from?
[Phone Ringing]
Excuse me.
[Ringing Continues]
Hello?
[Laughing]
No, I just got in.
I don't know if I can.
Listen, I can't talk right now.
Can I call you back?
[Chuckling]
All right. Bye.
Uh, I'm, uh...
I'm from New York,
actually.
[Laughing]
Look, you can't
come in here.
Oh.
Well, I... I thought perhaps
we might get some coffee.
No, I don't think so.
- Somewhere nearby?
- Not tonight.
You'd better go.
I got no place to go.
Well, you can't stay here.
Just a coffee,
please?
[Sighs]
Well, maybe tomorrow.
Okay, tomorrow.
When?
I said maybe.
I don't know.
Look, I'm sorry about
what happened this afternoon,
I really am.
All right?
Mmm.
That was my boyfriend
on the phone.
He's coming over,
so please leave...
now.
- I like you.
- Look, do you want me
to call the cops?
No, it's okay.
It-It-It's okay.
I'll see you sometime...
later.
I still want
to buy you that drink.
[Elevator Clattering]
[Faint Knocking]
[Knocking Continues]
[Rattling]
[Charlie]
How long will you be here?
[Clifford]
Depends on how lucky I get.
I want to look through
the old files on him...
and check every recent report
of assault, vagrancy,
things like that.
Just want to ask you
a question, Mr. Trumble.
- Alright, what do you want to know?
- What was stolen?
[Man]
Wake up! Hey, God bless it,
get outta here! Out!
All right, all right!
Damn it, all right!
All right.
[Chuckles]
What do you say,
partner?
Mmm.
Hey, looky here...
I'm dry as a bone, man.
You got any money?
[Clifford]
Well, keep the picture.
If you think you see him, I'd appreciate a call.
- About four blocks.
- Oh, yeah? Down by the park, huh?
- Foreigner... has a British accent.
- No, I haven't.
He's about my height,
light complexion.
I was just with that guy.
Looked bad.
- Where?
- Ah, hell, partner, I can't remember.
Probably see him again, though.
I tell you what.
You leave that money with me,
and I'll see that he gets it,
as...
as a favor to you.
- I gotta talk to him.
- What's a matter? Don't you
trust me, hmm?
We can work together.
Yeah, sure.
Now, you keep the bottle,
huh?
I'll be back.
- Bar downtown?
- Yeah, I got the name
and the address if you want it.
Appreciate it.
[Knocking]
[Pounding]
[Dog Yapping]
Oh, shit!
[Pounding Continues]
Who is it?
My name is John Clifford.
I'm a private investigator.
You're a what?
A private detective.
[Yapping Continues]
What do you want with me?
I thought maybe we could talk,
ask a few questions.
I don't know nothin'
about anything or anybody.
[Muttering]
Shit.
Listen, lady,
I can be back in 30 minutes
with a search warrant
and a handful of cops,
and I could probably have you
arrested, whether or not
the charges would stick.
Now, you wanna
let me in and talk?
[Pounding Resumes]
- Have you got a badge?
- I'll show you a badge when
you open the goddamned door!
[Pounding]
I don't have a badge.
I'm issued a license...
a piece of paper...
and I left it at home.
You're Tracy Fuller?
Will you sit down?
You recognize this man?
Why?
He's escaped
from the insane asylum.
Seven years ago,
he murdered two children...
broke into the house and
found them asleep in bed.
It was a little boy,
four and a half, and his
little three-year-old sister.
After the coroner's
investigation, the bodies
were taken to the mortuary...
...where the undertaker took one look
at them and said their bodies
couldn't be reconstructed...
for the burial without
six days of steady work.
Then he asked what had been
the murder weapon, because,
looking at the mess in front of him,
he couldn't imagine
what had been used.
The coroner told him there
had been no murder weapon.
The killer had used
only his hands.
He's been here.
Think he'll try
to see you again?
I don't know.
He... He said he had
no place to go.
Well, let's play it safe.
Let's assume he will.
Will you work with me?
You found him?
- I think so.
- Where?
From here on,
I go it alone.
[Scoffs]
Why take a chance on it,
Cliff?
- We'll let you have the credit.
- No.
I'm gonna kill him, Charlie.
The closer I get
to this guy, the more...
he gets to me...
I don't know.
- Look, you better go on home,
Cliff. You're fallin' in.
- No.
Not this time.
This is the case that makes up
for a whole career.
Now, if you don't understand that
now, you will in a few years.
Who hired you to do this?
[Sighs]
So, now you're a hit man.
Jesus Christ, he killed
two kids in cold blood!
You were there too!
What are you going to use?
Lock needles.
You are straining
our friendship, Cliff.
If you blow this thing
at all...
You'll never
hear from me again.
[Sighs]
All right.
Take your time,
and do it good.
[Coughing]
You okay?
All right.
Keep it, honey.
My treat.
[Muttering, Indistinct]
No luck.
Did you see him?
He still could
be out there though.
Oh, God.
Are you okay?
Okay.
I'm gonna hang around
outside for a while.
I'll be back
on and off again
all night.
- You sure you're all right?
- I'm fine.
Okay. Bolt your door,
and don't let anybody in,
no matter what.
Okay.
I'll be seein' ya.
Listen. Thanks.
Sure.
[Rustling,
Clanking]
♪♪ [Humming]
♪♪ [Continues Humming]
[Gasping]
I... I must talk to you.
[Whimpering]
I want you
to be my friend.
[Gasping,
Breathing Heavily]
Please?
Okay?
No! No!
No!
[Tracy Screams]
- Tracy! Tracy!
- [Tracy]
No!
Tracy?
Tracy!
[Metal Clanking,
Clattering]
[Cat Howling]
[Panting]
[Coughing]
[Man]
Hey, what's happening,
old buddy?
[Chattering]
♪♪ [Piano, Distant]
Hey!
Hey! Crazy Curt!
Hey, old fella, well met
and all that jazz.
Looky here.
This is our lucky day.
Friend of yours has got
some money for ya,
and we got to get on
back down to the park
now and meet him.
Hey, come on, now. Come...
Wait. Listen. He gonna be
comin' for you, Crazy Curt.
He's got some M-O-N-E-Y.
We can get us
a little joy juice, partner.
Come on, now.
Come...
Hey. Come on, man.
What's the matter with you?
You really are crazy.
[Jackhammer Pounding,
Distant]
[Vehicle Engine Motoring]
[No audio]
[Panting]
[Gasping]
[Sobbing]
♪♪ [Clock Chiming]
[Grunting]
Hey!
Hey there, partner!
♪♪ [Chiming Continues]
[Man Coughing]
[Man Sniffs]
[Groans]
[Coughs]
[Feet Shuffling]
[Man Grumbling]
[Door Opening]
Duncan?
It's over now.
Come on out.
My name's John Clifford.
I'm a private detective.
I was hired
by Alexander Mandrakis
to take you back.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
There'll be no more pain.
You're safe now.
Take it easy, Duncan.
You're all right.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
Just come with me.
It's all right, Duncan.
Duncan!
[Duncan Yells]
[Grunts]
Duncan!
[Duncan Yells]
[Yelling]
[Yells]
- Duncan!
- [Yelling]
[Clifford] Grab him!
Stop that guy! Hold him!
[Yelling]
Duncan!
Come on.
Get out of the way.
Let me through here!
Come on!
[Panting]
Nobody can see me anymore.
Nobody can hear me.
No one touches me.
I'm not here.
I don't exist.
I was never born.
No one can see me anymore.
No one can hear me.
No one touches me.
No one can hear.
I don't exist.
I wasn't born.
Come on.
[Both]
Hi, Mommy.
- Hi, you guys.
- Look what the wind blew in.
You been playin' hard?
- Yeah.
- Yeah? You hungry?
- What do you want
for dinner?
- Hamburgers.
Hamburgers? I never knew
he liked hamburgers, did you?
[Phone Ringing]
- Can you get that?
- Okay.
Maybe that's Daddy, huh?
Hello?
[Man] Hey. How's my little tiger?
- Okay. When you coming home?
- Real soon.
- Why don't you let me
talk to Mommy, okay?
- Okay. Bye, Daddy.
- Thank you. Hello.
- Hi, babe. How's my girl?
Fine. You wanna go with Stevie?
[Stevie] Come on.
[Girl] I'm comin'.
- You know that dress I got you
for your birthday?
- Yeah?
- Well, now's your chance
to wear it,
'cause I'm taking you
out to dinner tonight.
[Jill] What's goin' on?
- A little surprise.
Look, I'm leaving here now.
I'll be home in half an hour.
- Okay. Bye-bye.
Bye, babe.
[Receiver Hanging Up]
[Stevie]
...pray the Lord
my soul to keep.
If I should die
before I wake,
I pray the Lord
my soul to take.
God bless
Mommy and Daddy...
And me.
Grandma, Aunt Lucy,
Uncle George...
- And me.
- And her.
- Now will you read us a story?
- No, I will not read you a story.
- You try and go to sleep, okay?
- Okay.
- Good night, Mommy.
- Good night. And Sharon will
be here while we're gone.
- Okay.
- Okay. Good night.
Mommy, will you
come here a minute?
I wanna tell you something.
What is it?
- Come closer.
- Hmm? What is it?
- I love you.
- I love you too, Beebell.
- Good night.
Sleep good.
Good night.
- Hi, Sharon.
- Hello, Mrs. Lockhart.
I saw your picture in the paper
the other day. Congratulations.
- Eww. Wasn't that
a terrible picture?
- I thought it was nice.
- The kids asleep?
- No, but they will be.
I give about 20 minutes,
then go up and take a peek.
But I warn you:
If Stephen sees you, you're
gonna have to read him a story.
- Okay. Let's go.
Okay, now, I have the number
of the restaurant here,
and you know the number
for police and emergencies
is 9-1-1?
- You know that, right?
- Honey, in ten seconds, I'm
gonna eat this staircase.
Yes, lord and master.
I'm not
wearing that thing.
- Have a good time.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Good-bye, Sharon.
- Bye-bye.
- Good-bye.
You got everything,
right?
♪♪ [Clock Chiming]
♪♪ [Classical]
- [Man Laughs]
- I don't believe it...
district sales manager.
It's about time.
It's about time
they recognized you
for what you really are.
You know, I'm going
to be the youngest
district sales manager...
in the company's history.
- Does this mean a raise?
- It sure does.
- How much?
- A lot.
Well, how much?
[Inaudible]
- You are kidding?
- No.
- And a car? Do you get... Yes?
- And a car. And a car.
I'm so proud of you.
- What's the matter?
Don't you want your food?
- Excuse me.
- Mr. And Mrs. Lockhart?
- Yes?
- There's a phone call for you.
- No. I'll get it. I'll get it.
It's just Sharon, I'm sure.
Eat your dinner.
This way.
Thank you. Hello?
Hello?
[Duncan, Voice Echoing]
Have you checked the children?
[Jill Screams]
[Woman]
Someone help us!
- [Confused Chattering]
- Please. Jill?
- What's happened? What's wrong?
- The phone! That man!
- He's on the phone!
He's got my babies!
- Wait. What?
- Curt Duncan. He's back.
He has my babies.
- He's on the phone?
- My babies. Please.
[Sobbing]
[Clicking Receiver]
[Line Ringing]
It's okay. It's okay.
- It's okay, honey.
- [Sharon]
Hello?
Hello? Sharon?
This is Mr. Lockhart.
What's going on over there?
[Sharon]
Nothing's going on.
- Is everything all right?
[Sharon]
Yes. There's nothing going on.
Everything's fine.
- Why? What's the matter?
- Sharon, listen to me
very carefully.
Look. If there is a man in the house... if there's
any reason why you can't talk to me right now...
just answer "yes"
over the phone.
If there's any danger
of any kind, just say "yes."
[Sharon] I don't understand.
What man in the house?
Sharon?
Please do me a favor.
Just tell me truthfully:
When was the last time
you checked my children?
About 45 minutes ago.
Everything's fine.
They were fast asleep.
- Wh...
[Gasping]
Sharon, I'm sorry
about the hysterics.
We're leaving the restaurant
now, and I'll explain everything
as soon as we get back.
Before we hang up,
would you do one more thing
for me?
[Sharon] What?
- Would you go upstairs
and check the children?
No!
Honey!
[Sharon] Sure. Hold on.
[Man]
Excuse me. Excuse me, please.
Excuse me.
What's the problem, sir?
Officer, I'm Stephen Lockhart.
Just a second.
I'll explain everything.
Sharon?
[Woman]
Why doesn't he hurry up,
get her to the hospital?
Sharon?
[Dial Tone]
Sharon!
Sharon? Sharon?
Sharon? Jill!
[Sharon] Hello?
[Stephen] Sharon?
[Sharon] Mr. Lockhart,
what's the matter?
[Stephen] What's going on?
[Sharon] Nothing's going on.
[Stephen] Are you all right?
What about the phone?
[Sharon] What phone?
[Stephen] When we called you
from the restaurant.
Mommy?
[Sharon] When I got back
to the phone, the line was
dead.
[Sharon Continues, Indistinct]
Go back to sleep.
[Stephen] Was
anybody else here tonight?
[Sharon Responds, Indistinct]
[Stephen] Is it okay if
the police take you home? I
don't want to leave Jill alone.
[Sharon]
Have I done something wrong?
[Stephen] No. No.
Don't worry about it.
[Stephen]
Jill, I'm here.
We're both here.
We're safe now.
Okay. Look.
If it'll make you
feel any better...
Hmm?
I'll keep it
right here beside me
all night long, hmm?
You know I'm a light sleeper
and a damn good shot.
Satisfied?
- I'm sorry to be
putting you through all this.
- Oh, come on. Hey.
Hey, Bert.
This report just came in
on that guy, Curt Duncan.
It seems he broke
out of the nuthouse
about three weeks ago.
[Officer #2]
Oh, yeah? You gonna
put this in our report?
[Cardplayer]
Diamonds, Charlie.
Diamonds was led.
Yeah, yeah, I think we should put it in the report.
Maybe this gal tonight really did get a call from him.
Who knows?
[Cardplayer]
Your lead, Charlie.
What the hell you doin'?
That's a trump.
A card lead
is a card played.
Yeah. You're right.
We'd better leave this on
Ruznik's desk in the morning.
Sorry, fellas.
Give 'em all to me.
I've got 'em all.
[Cardplayer]
Jesus Christ.
- I can't help that.
[All Muttering]
- Say, Omar, can I see this a minute?
- Yeah.
- You guys have a stakeout
on this house?
- Yeah.
Bernstein and Waller
are checking in about
every 20 minutes or so.
[Line Ringing]
[Clifford]
Hello?
Cliff, I think
I got something for you.
[Gasps]
[Line Beeping
Rapidly]
- Stephen? Stephen?
- Wh... Yes?
- Honey, where'd you get this?
- [Sighs]
The candy.
Where'd you get the candy?
[Groans]
[Creaking]
[Line Beeping Rapidly]
- Operator, what does that mean?
- I'm sorry, sir.
That line seems
to be disconnected.
- Then why don't I get a recording?
- I don't know, sir. Maybe the number...
was just recently disconnected,
or maybe there's a temporary
malfunction in the wiring.
Could you try it again
in the morning?
Yeah. Okay.
Thanks.
[No Dial Tone]
[Man Mumbling]
[Sighs]
[Duncan's Voice]
You can't see me...
but I had to come back.
- Stephen.
- Don't you know why?
[Hangers Rattling]
Stephen! Stephen!
- [Snarling]
- [Screaming]
[Growling]
[Screams]
[Continues Growling]
[Gunshots]
[Gunshot]
[Grunts]
[Man Groaning]
[Jill] Stephen.
[Jill Whimpers]
[Groans]
[Wailing]
Shh, shh, shh.
Your husband's okay.