FEMALE RADIO ANNOUNCER 1:
This is J. T.L. Morning News.
This is Holly Chadwick.
FEMALE RADIO ANNOUNCER 2:
Thanks for joining us.
We have a great show
in store for you this morning.
MALE RADIO ANNOUNCER: Well, it's
a great morning to be in the studio.
BRITISH NEWSMAN 1: Authorities have
confirmed an avian flu outbreak.
WEATHERMAN:
Forecast, cloudy skies...
NEWSMAN 2: Good morning.
Reporting from Brighton.
MALE EPIDEMIOLOGIST:
This will be a different scenario
if the virus changes in a way that allows
transmission between humans.
- So, let's get started.
-
FEMALE REPORTER 1: Yet again today,
another group of dolphins
became stranded.
CO2 emissions have
dramatically increased in...
TV ANCHORMAN: Are there any
real threats that you know of?
Not at all.
SOUTH AFRICAN NEWSWOMAN:
Environmentalists are trying
to determine the cause of death.
FEMALE REPORTER 2:
At alert level six,
W.H.O. guidelines for governments...
Your socks are so cute! I like them.
Police say they've seen
similar cases recently
of people behaving strangely.
TV ANCHORWOMAN:
The U.N. health agency is not likely
to recommend official travel restrictions.
OLDER BRITISH MAN:
It's a little bit unsettling.
MICHIO KAKU: They're not physicists.
They're not engineers.
They think it's just gonna go away.
They live in a fantasy parallel universe.
FEMALE CALLER: Right on top
of the man, beating him.
The man is bleeding.
BRITISH NEWSMAN:
Twenty-one confirmed cases.
All the talk
about a doomsday is a big hoax.
MALE REPORTER:
The subject growled at him
and continued to maul the victim.
NEWSWOMAN: The best estimate
is about 15,000 in the U. K.
EPIDEMIOLOGIST:
We don't know if this is spreading.
BRITISH NEWSMAN:
Rhythms of change...
EPIDEMIOLOGIST:
So far there's no manifestation.
MAN 1: Monitors have arrived,
even carrying them...
MAN 2: With that much
public at risk, we cannot...
MAN 3: They're trying to move us on,
trying to tell the journalists to get out.
CONNIE: Wake up!
- Oh, creatures in our bed...
-
- No sleeping!
Oh, you're getting very big.
- What do you want to eat?
- GIRLS: Pancakes!
We got a lot more sunshine today.
You have to only say one word.
GERRY: Hey, by the way,
what do you want for your birthday?
say a puppy-
A PUPPY-
GERRY: You mean
a stuffed animal puppy?
Because that we can do.
Scusi.
KARIN: Good morning.
That looks yummy.
RACHEL: She gets the bigger one?
CONNIE: Yeah, sorry.
KARIN: She's tiny.
Did you pack your, um, inhaler?
Bathroom sink.
- In a minute?
- Scootch! Go.
MALE REPORTER: The government
has declared martial law.
Daddy, what's martial law?
Uh...
Martial law is like house rules,
but for everybody.
Were you ever
in places like that with your old job?
GERRY: Mmm-hmm.
But I quit my old job
so I could be with you.
Do you miss it?
GERRY: No, I like my new job.
All you do is make pancakes
in the morning!
Yeah, but I'm really good at it.
- Look who I found!
- Oh!
STUFFED ANIMAL:
Here comes the number 12 train!
GERRY: It's not Subway Sam, is it?
You want more pancakes?
Good.
Go, go, go. Come on, scootch!
CONNIE: At least...
KARIN: Move it on out.
Hey! Plates in the sink!
CONNIE: Later!
KARIN: Do that when we get back!
Uh... Does it live in the jungle?
Oooh.
No.
Do you eat it on Sundays?
Does it live
on the Great Plains of Africa?
- Yeah.
- Oh, well, I guess, yeah.
Do people keep it in pens all its
life and harvest it for meat?
- That's really gross!
- RACHEL: Gross!
Dad!
Is it an animal you'd have for a pet?
- Yes.
- Is it a cat?
- RACHEL: Yes.
- Ha ha ha.
- Okay, now we have another one.
- Do another one.
-
- You totally got one!
Why are there so many?
It's like, three in the last five minutes.
-
- What is going on?
RADIO ANCHORMAN: The World
Health Organization has been
tracking the recent outbreak of rabies
that began in Taiwan and has now been
reported in over 12 countries.
Responding to allegations he hasn't
done enough to prevent the spread...
Can we try BBC?
You're not British anymore, baby.
You lost your accent a long time ago.
Except after two bottles of wine.
Am I British?
Yeah, your grandma is.
- Hey!
- Yo!
He's just gonna keep going, Daddy?
Hold on, guys.
RACHEL: Daddy, be careful on the road.
GERRY: It's okay, baby.
ANCHORMAN: Can be
transmitted between species
commonly from a bite
from an infected animal.
Our best recommendation is to stay
away from densely populated areas.
Hey, yo! You all right?
Yeah, I'm okay. Thanks.
- You need anything?
- No. You know what's going on?
No, man, I don't know anything.
It's crazy.
-
Gerry?
Get back in your car right now!
Remain with your ve...
-
What are we doing?
GERRY: That's our way out of here.
I want my blanket!
Baby, it's packed right now.
Snuggle with Subway Sam, okay?
My blanket!
Rach?
Rachel, baby, you've got
to get back in your seat.
- Baby, we need you in your seat.
- GERRY: Put your belt on!
KARIN: Rachel, right now!
- Gerry?
- Rach, get your belt back on!
- You okay?
- GERRY: You okay?
- Rachel, sweetheart?
- Rachel, you hurt?
- KARIN: Connie?
- Are you okay? It's okay.
We should get out.
Everybody out of the car.
GERRY: We've got to get out of the city.
Her door won't open!
Rachel, go out that side.
Okay, you have to climb over, honey.
OFFICER: Out of the way!
Move it!
Come on, honey. Come on.
Sweetheart, are you okay?
Let's go. Let's get off the street.
What is that, Gerry? What is that?
I don't know!
Get to the RV.
Subway Sam!
Here comes the number 12 train! One.
Two.
- What's happening?
- SUBWAY SAM: Three.
Four.
-
- Five.
Six.
Seven.
-
-Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
Eleven.
Twelve.
Train's in the station!
Gerry!
- KARIN: Watch out!
-
POLICEMAN:
We're pulling back on Fifth Street!
COMMAND OFFICER:
Containment is a fail.
- KARIN: Try to relax.
-
Give yourself air.
In and out.
- Come on, baby, try to relax.
-
Gerry? We left my purse in the car.
Where's her spare?
I'm gonna go check
your backpack, all right?
Do you want to be with her?
GERRY: Rach, you'll be all right.
You're gonna be all right.
Hey, hey, you breathe
through your nose.
Rach, Rach, look at me. Look at me.
You're gonna be all right.
You've done this a hundred times.
Look at me. Look at me.
Breathe in through your nose,
out through your mouth.
Okay, we're gonna go to a pharmacy.
We got to move.
Okay.
-
- GERRY: Good. Good. Look.
Look at me, look at me.
Rach, breathe through your nose.
KARIN:  No, no, no, no...
You're gonna be all right.
- Look at me.
- Daddy, what are those things?
Honey, find us some water.
Okay? Something to drink.
It's Thierry.
Where are you?
THIERRY: Airborne.
Lower East Side to Turtle Bay.
It's all gone. We barely made it out.
- Tell him to go south.
- No, no, we need visual confirmation.
-
- No,no,no,no,no,no,no.
What is this?
We don't know. How close were you?
Face to face.
Good, honey, good.
Daddy.
Connie, give me that.
Give me that. Oh, thank you, honey.
THIERRY: Where are you?
GERRY: 95, heading north.
-
- Okay. Okay.
THIERRY: All right.
We'll try to get a helicopter to you.
I'll call you back with an extraction point.
Can you hold out for another hour?
Do we have a choice?
This is not
for old time's sake, my friend.
I'll need you.
I need you back.
Don't forget about us.
What do you mean, we've lost Boston?
All right. Good luck, Gerry.
Okay.
Good, honey. Keep it going.
It's gonna be all right.
- Come here. Stay close.
- Super close.
Take my hand.
Get her medicine,
I'll get us something to eat.
I'll meet you back here.
Stay close, honey.
What do you need?
Albuterol.
They outgrow the asthma supposedly.
And this shit, too. It's magic for my kid.
GERRY: Thank you.
CONNIE: Daddy!
GERRY: Connie?
Daddy!
- Connie?
- CONNIE: Daddy!
- Where's Mommy?
- KARIN: Gerry!
Gerry!
Karin?
- Karin?
- KARIN: Gerry! Gerry!
Get off of me!
Get off of me! That's all I have.
- Gerry!
- Hey!
- Gerry.
OFFICER:
Multiple 11-99s at Washington Park.
Please, send units.
We're falling back on Reed Street.
FEMALE DISPATCH:
Two Robert 12, units need backup.
Mobile ops is down. Please respond.
Two Robert 12, are you there? Copy.
- GERRY: Girls!
- Responders, Code 3, Code 3.
KARIN: Rachel, quick, come on.
{DISPATCH CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY}
No.
No!
We got to get out of here.
We got to get off the street.
Gerry.
Apartments?
Hey. Yeah.
- Gerry?
-We're in Newark.
We're stranded.
Apartment buildings, 23rd.
If we can get to the roof,
can you get someone to us?
- Not tonight.
-When?
The earliest would be sunrise.
Sunrise.
Tell him I got flares.
GERRY: We'll be on the roof with flares.
Listen, Gerry, I will move
mountains to get you out here.
-
- Come here, baby.
Go! Go! Go!
KARIN: Baby, in here!
GERRY: Come on. Quick!
Gerry!
Inside, girls!
By the stairs. Inside, inside!
GERRY: Wait!
Wait.
KARIN: Up, up. It's okay, baby.
-
Run! Run! Go, Rachel!
KARIN: Go!
GERRY: Go!
Keep running, baby.
KARIN: It's all right.
GERRY: To the top.
GO! Go!
Go!
Run!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
I need a new flare!
This asshole's about to get through!
KARIN: Where's Connie? Connie?
GERRY: Connie?
KARIN: Connie!
CONNIE: Let me in!
- Baby?
-It's not her. It's not her.
- Let me in!
- Connie!
Let me in!
In, in, in! In!
Thank you so much.
- I'm Tomas.
- GERRY: Hey, Tomas.
TOMAS: My mom's cooking everything
before it starts to stink.
GERRY: That's smart.
You guys all right?
It's all right.
It's okay.
Are you guys hungry'?
Yes, thank you.
- TOMAS: Here you go.
- Thank you.
-
KARIN: You want some juice?
ROBOTIC MALE VOICE:
The following message
is transmitted at the request of the
New Jersey State Police Department.
Authorities recommend
that the following actions
should be taken
by all the members of the public.
Stay indoors if at all possible.
Have enough food
and water supplies for sheltering
for one to two weeks.
The following message
is transmitted at the request
of the New Jersey State
Police Department.
An unidentified virus strain is rapidly
spreading across
the state of New Jersey.
-
She was crying.
GERRY: Hmm.
Thanks, Tommy.
I used to work in dangerous places
and people who moved survived,
and those who didn't...
Movement is life.
You have a better chance
if you come with us.
You need anything else
before you leave?
GERRY:
Okay. Come on. Come on.
We should have left with them.
There is nowhere to go.
What's going to happen
when the food is gone?
-
Okay, come on.
I'm scared.
Connie, there's a helicopter
waiting for us on the roof.
Keep your eyes
on Mommy and Daddy, okay?
Be ninja quiet.
Just a walk in the park.
How do we know they're coming?
They're coming.
Ready?
- GERRY: Okay, come on, guys.
-
Come on! Come on!
KARIN: UP, UP, UP-
GERRY: Come on, baby.
Go, go, go!
- Come on, baby!
- KARIN: Go, go!
Go, girls! Gerry!
Come on. Gerry!
Girls, get back!
Watch out!
- Go!
- Go, go, go!
Come on, faster, girls!
PILOT: Lieutenant, I've got no contact.
I say again, no contact.
-
- GERRY: Let's go, let's go!
Karin!
- Karin!
- Yeah.
Go through the door!
Gerry?
PILOT: There they are!
Ace, we have positive contact.
That's our target! Get us down!
Daddy!
- Daddy!
- Baby, get back.
CONNIE: Daddy!
Gerry?
- Gerry, what?
- Stay back!
Baby! No!
One thousand seven.
One thousand eight.
CONNIE: Daddy, get off the edge!
- KARIN: Gerry, please?
- One thousand ten.
One thousand eleven.
I got it in my mouth.
You're okay. You're okay.
-
- Go! Go!
Come on. Come on.
SOLDIER: Let's go! Let's go!
Come on, let's go! We got to go!
KARIN: You got her?
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
CONTROLLER:
Traffic en route, altitude 5-7 thousand.
Heading 250. Turn right,
heading 075, once clear.
Remain below 4,000.
Clear to land,
heading 040, wind 060 at five.
Follow L.S.O. directions.
Prep for immediate dust off.
THIERRY: Gerry.
GERRY: Thank you.
THIERRY: Good to see you, my friend.
CONTROLLER:
Tango five, this is Argus command.
Cleared for take-off.
PILOT: Tango five. Wilco.
THIERRY: Karin, to the right.
This is good, right?
GERRY: Bunk beds!
Your bunk beds
are number two, three and six.
Please make yourself at home.
You want to get up here?
- There you go, sweetheart.
- KARIN: That's good.
THIERRY:
We're not dropping anchor again.
You're safe.
It's not me I'm worried about.
They're safe.
KARIN: Baby.
It's bigger than
our old apartment on 72nd.
Need anything, Karin?
Water.
I'll organize.
Is this worldwide?
Is anyone doing better than we are?
Baby. Go talk somewhere else.
Okay.
The President is dead.
Four of six Joint Chiefs. V.P. missing.
Reports of gun battles
in the streets of the capital.
Your parties are panicking.
The bigger cities are the worst off.
The airlines
were the perfect delivery system.
Carnival cruise vessel Dream
has been given permission to join.
Twenty seven knots south and closing.
How soon are they showing
symptoms after contact?
TECHNICIAN 1: The provisional
government currently considers
northern Minnesota
to be a potential safe zone.
TECHNICIAN 2: Have you recorded
any instance where a person
was bitten but not infected?
How the hell do I know
if Russia's fallen?
Sir, I cannot action that order.
Colonel, I'm sorry,
but we cannot facilitate
an evacuation for you or your men.
Sir, there is nowhere to evacuate you to.
Malnutrition. Dirty water.
No gas for the winter or transportation.
No bullets to fight.
And it has spread
to all corners of the globe.
MICHAEL: The question
that we have got to address
is what the hell is it?
About 5% of the population
aren't affected immediately.
It is viral. It has to be viral.
There is no plausible alternative.
And like any virus, once we find its
origin, we can develop a vaccine.
- We find it, contain it...
- That's Dr. Fassbach.
Virologist from Harvard.
The analogy I keep coming back to
is Spanish Flu.
Spanish Flu?
It didn't exist in 1918, but by 1920,
it killed 3% of the world.
He's our best bet
at figuring out what this thing is.
You all read the same email I did,
-and it said "zombies."
-
Are you completely out of your mind?
So, the earliest mention
of the word "zombie"
was in a memo
from Camp Humphreys in South Korea.
We haven't had contact with them since.
But this could lead us to the origin.
If we knew where this thing started,
then we'd have a chance
of developing a vaccine to stop it.
So we send in Dr. Fassbach
there to look for the source.
He's just a kid.
You're right.
SERGEANT: Attention on deck!
At ease!
Mr. Under-Secretary.
The Under-Secretary
here says you were
his best investigator
when you were at the U.N.
I want to send you in. With a team.
Help Dr. Fassbach
find whatever it is he needs.
You brought...
I wanted for the circumstances
to speak for themselves.
No.
Captain, I'm not your guy.
You were on the ground
during the Liberian Civil War.
Investigated Chechen war crimes.
Sri Lanka in '07.
Places you and I both know
Dr. Fassbach wouldn't last a night in.
Gerry, a handful of SEALS
will go with you as security force.
No.
My guys will get you in,
you assist the doctor,
pursue any leads,
my guys will get you out.
We do the heavy lifting.
I can't help you. I can't leave my family.
Take a look around here, Mr. Lane.
Each and every one of these people are
here because they serve a purpose.
There's no room here
for non-essential personnel.
There's a long line of people
waiting for one of those bunks.
You want to help your family,
let's figure out how we stop this.
It's your choice, Mr. Lane.
Simple.
KARIN:
You don't work for them anymore.
- Karin...
- You might not remember
what this job did to you, but I do.
So do not ask me to say yes to this.
I have to go.
They're going to kick us off the ship.
What?
If I go, you, the girls, Tommy,
have a place to stay.
If I don't, we're back in Philly tonight.
What about Thierry?
Can't he do anything?
Men like Thierry
aren't in charge of anything anymore.
You keep this with you.
I'll call in once a day.
As long as I make that call,
everything's gonna be okay.
I'm coming back.
Okay?
We're going to make the best of it.
As we do.
Like we do.
Okay, baby doll,
Daddy's got to go to work.
I'm not a baby.
Okay.
Tall, beautiful, tiny adult.
I'll be back soon.
Yeah?
All right, tough guy...
Take care of the ladies for me?
Yeah.
Deal.
You're awesome.
Daddy's coming back.
This way, sir.
GERRY: Look.
We don't know what we're walking into.
So we do what they say. Okay.
If they move, we move.
If they stop, we stop.
If things were to get crazy,
just focus on their boots,
focus on their voices,
and we'll be all right.
- FASSBACH: Mmm-hmm.
- These guys are hammers.
And to hammers,
everything looks like nails.
I heard that.
You were meant to.
So, you see something that's important,
you call it out and we'll make it happen.
Okay.
You think we're gonna find anything?
Yeah.
Yeah, we're gonna find something.
Mother Nature is a serial killer.
No one's better.
More creative.
But like all serial killers,
she can't help the urge
to want to get caught.
What good are all those brilliant crimes
if no one takes the credit?
So she leaves crumbs.
Now, the hard part,
why you spend a decade in school,
is seeing the crumbs
for the clues they are.
Sometimes the thing you thought
was the most brutal aspect of the virus,
turns out to be the chink in its armour.
And she loves disguising
her weaknesses as strengths.
She's a bitch.
NAVY TECHNICIAN: Attention.
D.C. has gone dark. I repeat,
D.C. has gone dark.
The Capitol evacuation
has been suspended.
All available resources should be
directed to Naval Station Norfolk.
WARRANT OFFICER:
All non-essential personnel
given F-6 status
and in groups A through E
need to report
to the flight deck for relocation.
Groups A and B relocating to Orlando
should be on the stern
clear of the landing zone.
I say again, all non-essential
personnel given F-6 status
need to report to the flight deck.
Choppers are inbound
for immediate relocation.
Mommy, is this dinner?
Yes, sweetheart.
Water here tastes funny.
It's jet fuel, young lady.
He's joking.
I wish. Desal has trouble filtering it out.
Probably because
there's too many people on this ship.
PILOT: Everybody wake up.
We're on approach
to Camp Humphreys.
Most of the base is dark,
and no one is manning the tower.
We're running on fumes,
so there's really no choice,
I've got to put us down.
So buckle up.
GERRY: Hold up.
Keep your finger off the trigger.
Okay.
-
Fassbach! Wait!
GERRY: Damn it.
SEAL COMMANDER: Move back!
SPEKE: Friendly! Friendly!
Keep it down. Keep it down.
What is this? What happened to him?
He slipped. He's dead.
Come on! Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
SPEKE: Okay, I'm good!
- Who was it? Who fell?
- LINCOLN: Skilken.
- Hold! Clear.
- Hold.
SPEKE: I want an ammo count,
then you reload your mags!
RANGER: Yes, sir!
My boy who just died out there was 23.
He was 23.
You want to tell me why?
Because the guy who just shot
himself, he's a doctor, a virologist.
What are you talking about?
GERRY: He was supposed
to be our best hope.
Well, he's not our best hope anymore.
Hey.
That guy volunteered to come here.
He didn't have to, you know.
None of them did.
We're still trying to figure out
what the hell this thing is.
Well, shit happens.
The doctor would have
strongly agreed with you.
How do we go about refuelling?
When I say so. And very carefully.
The noise, are they drawn to it?
Yeah. Sound draws them.
Body shots only seem
to slow them down.
Head shots do the trick,
but just to be safe
we tend to burn them when we can.
- You fought any Zeke yet?
- GERRY: Yeah.
- SPEKE: Where?
- Philly. Newark.
Bad?
- What about Houston?
- St. Louis?
- Baltimore?
- MALE RANGER: Atlanta?
FEMALE RANGER: Detroit?
Guys, I'll be honest with you,
I don't know of any place back
home that's doing very well.
All right...
If the other guy was a virologist,
what do you do?
There was a memo
sent from this installation 11 days ago.
It had the word "zombie" in it.
Do you know anything about it?
Yeah.
It was an email, not a memo.
Pretty obvious
nobody back home bothered to read it.
Now, there's 15, 16 guys in this room.
Most of them guards.
But all of them were bitten
trying to get this man
handcuffed to the cot.
Now, our colonel
said he was the first one.
This colonel, is he around?
Oh, yeah. He's right here.
The guy who's shackled, do you know
who bit him, what bit him?
SPEKE: He was the base doctor.
He'd just returned from the field.
He'd been sent out
to verify the death of a soldier
who had just gone AWOL
the week before.
Some villagers had found this guy
foaming at the mouth,
oozing some kind of black tar.
Then he tried to bite one of them.
They shot him, tied him up,
threw him in a barn.
-
That's all we know, except the doctor
comes back here
and begins attacking his patients.
GERRY: This soldier,
do you know where he came from?
No.
GERRY: Anyone he might
have come in contact with?
No.
There's got to be records.
SPEKE: You are welcome
to take a look if you want.
GERRY: Then the origin could
have come from anywhere.
It's a shame you had to fly
all the way out here to figure that out.
How did you all escape this?
The expenditure of ammunition.
Is that how you tweaked your leg?
No, shit's been bugging me a while.
This prick stands right in the mix,
while seven or eight of them
turn Zeke all at the same time.
But they got no time
for Ol' Dirty Bastard here.
Biting everything like fat kids love Twix.
Got no time for his lucky ass.
Ain't it obvious I'm charmed?
The ones I saw bitten
turned in 12 seconds. Same here?
Five or 10 minutes.
Yeah, Davidson went
and he turned in 10 minutes.
"Stevie?
"Captain Spekes! Oh, my God!
My God! My God! Are they eating me?"
Who's that?
Waste no time on that freak.
SPEKE: He's C.I.A.
Got caught selling guns to North Korea.
Davidson,
he turned in 10 minutes.
That doesn't sound viral
to me at all, sports fans!
You're with the C.I.A.?
But they're not with me.
And who are you?
U.N.
Oh, my God!
Captain, put on the World Music!
The day
is saved!
Why'd you sell guns to the North?
Why not?
GERRY: Are they surviving this?
Indeed they are.
Using your guns.
Guns are half-measures.
How then?
All right.
They took away
the Zekes' exponential power.
They pulled the teeth of all 23 million
in less than 24 hours.
The greatest feat
of social engineering in history.
It's brilliant.
No teeth,
no bite.
No great spread.
Bullshit.
BURT: More books,
fewer receptions, Boutros Boutros.
Now, why do you have to burn them
to ashes to get them to finally stop?
Why do they move like a plague?
Why is Israel winning?
How is Israel winning?
They sealed off their entire country
days before the undead attacked man.
First to know,
first to act.
GERRY: People have been
building walls there for two millennia.
Mmm. Right. Yeah, but,
finish all those
thousands of years of work a week ago?
Impeccable timing is all.
You want answers?
Jurgen Warmbrunn.
That's the man
in Jerusalem you want to see.
You ever seen anything like that?
Hell, no.
We're going to Jerusalem.
I'm your co-pilot.
Oh, hang on.
Hang on. Hang on a minute.
- Hello?
-
Gerry?
- Honey?
-Gerry, can you hear me?
Karin?
Hello?
- God damn it!
-
SPEKE: Give me your hand.
No way. No.
My mother. Dallas.
Probably pacing a hole
in the floor right now if she's still there.
Better chance of you seeing
her before me, that's all.
It's a big plane. We got a lot of room.
Better the devil you know
than the one you don't.
You'll be all right.
Just pedal your ass off.
Make sure Maverick here keeps
the nose of that plane
pointed towards the sun.
Just remember, don't lock
the bowser's fuel line to the inlet.
Tell me 10 more times.
- You good?
- SEAL COMMANDER: Right here.
All right. Don't rush.
We've got one chance
to fuel their plane, so let's do it right.
If you ain't a crack shot,
don't aim for the head,
just get Zeke on the ground.
Remember, "Spine's divine,
those knees they work just fine!"
Let's go, lights out!
ALPHA TEAM LEADER:
Alpha in position.
BRAVO TEAM LEADER:
Bravo moving out.
SPEKE: Remember, these things
are drawn to sound.
So I need you close to target
before I bring you the truck.
Now there's only one way
we're getting you on that plane,
and that's quietly.
-
- Shit!
SEAL COMMANDER: God damn it!
Shut that thing off!
-
ELLIS: Looks like we just woke the dead.
SPEKE: Out of respect for others,
please turn off all pagers
and cell phones.
-
We got to move.
We've got to get out of here, let's move!
Go, go, go!
SPEKE: Whoo!
I'm gonna clear a path through Zeke!
You pedal like hell!
Come on, boys,
I need head shots! Tap 'em out!
I want to see some Zeke on the ground!
SPEKE: You're kidding me.
I'm a God damn Zeke.
I got you, Captain. Just say the word.
SPEKE: It's all right, boys. I got this one.
- God damn it.
- PILOT: We got enough!
We need to detach the fuel line!
Israel better pay off.
All right, I have instrument,
but only on single prop.
You'll have to talk me through it.
Okay, we're clear.
Okay. Give me all the lights.
Switch on the anti-icing.
- Where?
- The red knob.
- Got it, got it.
- Set up our heading 020 for departure.
- We got to move!
- Set flaps 15 degrees.
Flaps 15.
All right, we are all set.
Let's get out of here!
GERRY: Make it steep.
- Gerry?
-Hi, baby.
Hi. Hi.
KARIN: I tried to call you.
I know, I was...
It was bad timing, I was running around.
Are you okay?
Yeah, everything's okay. I'm okay.
That's the spirit.
Yeah.
Listen,
Korea didn't work out.
Now it looks like
we're gonna have to go to Israel.
Try to get some rest on the flight.
How are the kids?
Um...
I think...
They're really... They're good.
I got Connie right here.
Baby?
TRAFFIC CONTROLLER:
Attention, unidentified aircraft.
You are in a restricted airspace
and not clear for landing.
Jerusalem tower, Reach 394.
Pan, pan, pan.
Request immediate landing.
Contact Mossad,
office of Jurgen Warmbrunn.
Special Envoy, United Nations.
Stay with the plane. Be ready to bug out.
I'll be back before dark.
{RADIO CHATTER CONTINUES
IN HEBREW}
JURGEN: The problem
with most people is that
they don't believe
something can happen
until it already has.
It's not stupidity or weakness.
It's just human nature.
How did you know?
Gerald Lane.
Wrote a self-defeating Jeremiad
about his employer,
the U.N., back in 2010.
Caused a few ripples.
Sidelined your career.
Thought you'd have parlayed
those ripples into a self-righteous book.
No nose for profit.
How did Israel know?
We intercepted a communique
from an Indian general
saying they were
fighting the Rakshasha.
Translation, zombies.
Technically undead.
Jurgen Warmbrunn.
High-ranking official in the Mossad.
Described as sober, efficient,
not terribly imaginative.
And yet you build a wall
because you read a communique
that mentions the word "zombie"?
Well, when put like that,
I'd be sceptical as well.
In the '30s, Jews refused to believe
they could be sent
to concentration camps.
In '72, we refused to fathom
we'd be massacred in the Olympics.
In the month before October 1973,
we saw Arab troop movements,
and we unanimously agreed
they didn't pose a threat.
Well, a month later, the Arab attack
almost drove us into the sea.
So we decided to make a change.
A change?
The Tenth Man.
If nine of us
look at the same information
and arrive at the exact same conclusion,
it's the duty of the tenth man
to disagree.
No matter how improbable it may seem,
the tenth man has to start digging
on the assumption
that the other nine are wrong.
And you were that tenth man.
Precisely.
Since everyone assumed that this talk of
zombies was cover for something else,
I began my investigation
on the assumption
that when they said "zombies,"
they meant zombies.
Was patient zero from India?
That's the problem.
There's so many
potential sources in play
that no one knows where it began.
The organ trade in Germany.
Strange examples of violent behaviour
across the Asian peninsulas.
Meanwhile, the zombie plague keeps
spreading, and we do what we can.
These are
the Jerusalem Salvation Gates.
Two of 10 portals
through the security perimeter
into fortified Israel.
You're letting people in.
Every human being we save
is one less zombie to fight.
It's okay.
If I could get into India, where
would I start? Who would I speak with?
India's a black hole.
Forget about patient zero.
I can't do that.
It's too late for me to build a wall.
I'm running out of time. I need specifics.
- I need answers...
- I don't have answers.
All you can do is find a way to hide.
Get troops down there.
It's too loud! It's too loud!
They're coming over the top!
- Shit!
-
Command, we have a breach
at Salvation Gate.
They're coming over the wall!
{MAN SPEAKING HEBREW
OVER RADIO}
-
Get him to Jaffa Gate.
She'll get you out of here,
she'll get you to your plane!
Stay low!
Wrong way! Wrong way!
Go to landing point B.
Roger, we are inbound
to landing point B.
Hawk 5, almost there.
E.T.A. one minute.
DISPATCHER: Hawk 5. Hawk 5,
you're patched in. Over.
This is Hawk 5. Listen carefully.
The city is breached,
and they're heading towards the airport.
- GERRY: One thousand one.
-
One thousand two.
One thousand three. One thousand four.
-
- One thousand five.
One thousand six.
One thousand seven.
One thousand eight.
We got to move.
You'll be all right.
You're not gonna turn.
You're not gonna turn!
We got to move.
-
- We got to move!
5 going down.
DISPATCHER: Chopper 5 is down.
I say again, chopper 5 is down.
L.Z. is overrun.
Tower, Reach 394.
Requesting immediate departure.
MALE DISPATCHER: Tower to 394.
Proceed to runway four.
Good luck out there.
No!
There! That one!
Stop. Stop.
GO! Go!
Get them out of here!
STEWARD: Stay calm, please.
Stay calm.
Come on. Go, go, go.
What's your destination?
I don't know. We were headed here,
but I don't know.
I'm Gerry, by the way.
Segen.
GERRY: Segen.
First or last?
Just Segen.
So, what we're doing,
we've got to change this bandage
and we're gonna clean it.
Okay?
You okay? Okay?
Okay.
Come on, gut up. Gut up.
Here we go.
We're almost there.
Okay. Big breaths.
Let's get this over fast. Big breaths.
Here we go.
Come on. Good.
Last step. Last step.
Big breath.
Good job. There it is. Okay.
Mmm-hmm.
Okay. Okay, I think you've earned this.
Very good. Okay.
You a doctor?
No.
I've had some training in the field.
SEGEN: How did you know?
Cutting it off...
How did you know it would work?
I didn't.
Now I'm just a liability.
SPEKE: This prick
stands right in the mix,
while seven or eight of them
turn Zeke all at the same time.
GERRY: Is that how
you tweaked your leg?
No, shit's been bugging me a while.
SPEKE: Got no time for his lucky ass.
FASSBACH: Now, the hard part
is seeing the crumbs
for the clues they are.
And sometimes the thing you thought
was the most brutal aspect of the virus
turns out to be the chink in its armour.
JURGEN: I don't have answers.
All you can do is find a way to hide.
Gerry?
Are you okay? Where are you, baby?
What's happening?
I love you. I'm sorry.
But you've got to get Thierry now.
I'll find him.
- Thierry! Thierry.
- Excuse me. Karin.
KARIN: Gerry needs you. I love you.
Gerry? Where are you?
On the last flight out.
Listen, my phone is dying
and I need some quick Intel.
You got to locate the closest
medical research facility.
A C.D.C., a W.H.O.,
something that makes vaccines.
- And the closest airport to it.
- I don't understand.
No time to explain.
Just make it happen, man.
Okay, okay.
But, Gerry,
I still don't know where you are.
Well, go and find out what he needs.
You're gonna want to take this.
Take it.
Your battery is dead.
We made contact
with Cardiff Airport, Wales.
Your people directed us.
There is W.H.O.
research facility nearby,
but they are not sure
it's still operational.
This is location.
Can we make it?
PILOT: Ladies and gentlemen,
this is your Captain.
I'm glad to report that
we are on our final approach
to Cardiff Airport in Wales.
All European airports
are under lockdown.
But we have been given
priority status and cleared for landing.
We will be allowed to disembark.
We are very, very lucky.
Hey. Who do you belong to?
What's there?
-
- What is it?
You... Bags.
We need trolley and bags.
Mayday, mayday, mayday!
Bravo 160 heavy.
Emergency descent!
Prepare for impact.
Got to move.
Come on, come on.
Give me something good.
TECHNICIAN: Sir, Cardiff Airport
lost contact with the plane.
Lane is M.I.A. I'm sorry, sir.
{INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENTS
OVER PA}
WARRANT OFFICER: Chopper inbound
for immediate relocation.
I say again.
All non-essential personnel
given F-6 status
need to report for immediate relocation.
Ma'am?
Thierry would like a word with you.
Captain, it's only been 48 hours.
He's a resourceful man. There's every
chance he could have survived.
Sir, I gave him my word
we would look after his family.
Yes, sir. I understand.
SOLDIER: Okay. Let's go. We're good.
{ECHOES OF SNARLING
AND GASPING}
CONNIE: Daddy!
Daddy!
BRIT: You're a tough bastard.
And a lucky one.
Who are you?
I came here with a... With a woman.
Is she still...
BRIT: Who are you?
Why have you come here?
Why do you keep looking at him?
'Cause he's the one in charge.
You know what this place is?
Of course I do. That's why I'm here.
BRIT: Then you understand
how this must look to us.
JAVIER: This
is important to you?
- How long have I been out?
- BRIT: Three days.
Give me the phone.
Just give me the phone.
Give me the God damn phone!
Give me the phone!
As soon as you answer my question.
Call it.
Call the number,
they'll tell you who I am. Call it.
THIERRY: Gerry?
- Yeah, I'm here. I'm here.
- My God.
We thought you were dead.
Gerry, where are you?
Thierry, I'm with
a couple of nervous gentlemen.
They need some bona fides
before I can speak with you.
Of course.
This is Thierry Umutoni.
Deputy Secretary-General.
United Nations.
To whom am I speaking?
Where's Karin?
Thierry, why didn't Karin answer?
I'm sorry, Gerry.
I did what I could.
GERRY: What does that mean?
You've got to calm down.
No, stop! Stop.
You're going to hurt yourself.
You're okay.
His family has been sent
to a refugee camp in Nova Scotia.
I'm sure they'll be safe.
Are you? Thierry told you
who I am and what I used to do, right?
Yeah.
Then trust me when
I tell you they're not safe.
I understand how you feel.
- Do you? Yes?
- Yes.
Do you have a family?
- No.
Then you couldn't possibly understand,
could you?
I lost my son and wife in Rome.
Rather, I lost my son to
something that had once been my wife.
We have all lost someone, Mr. Lane.
In your case, there is hope at least.
I'm sorry.
Now,
why did you come here?
What do you need from us?
Your worst disease.
DR. KELLY: He wants a what?
Deadly pathogen.
With a high mortality rate.
- But curable.
- Okay, well...
You'd want a bacteria
rather than a virus,
I would think. Typhus?
Meningitis. Scarlet Fever.
DR. KELLY: Rocky Mountain Fever.
Anyway, excuse me, what's this for?
Mr. Lane believes we can use
such a disease against the undead.
I would give you points
for originality, Mr. Lane,
if we hadn't already tried that, first thing.
One of the many things a virus or
bacteria needs to thrive is a live host.
A functioning circulatory system.
I'm afraid it boils down
to one simple fact...
You can't make a dead person sick.
It's not for them.
It's for us.
I believe these things have a weakness.
And that weakness is weakness.
- Our weakness.
-
I have witnessed them
literally bypass people.
Walk right around them like
a river around a rock. Why?
I think, because those people were sick.
I think they were terminal.
And these things could sense it.
I think they're spreading a pathogen,
and they need a healthy host.
But even if you're right, I mean,
infecting the populace
with a lethal illness is not exactly a cure.
It's not a cure. It's camouflage.
It's camouflage.
There's a natural precedent.
Hungry predators
will avoid diseased bodies.
Equipped with the right pathogen,
our troops
would be essentially
invisible to the enemy.
You understand the only way
to prove this theory of yours is
for some idiot to infect themselves
with a lethal pathogen and then...
...meet with her, face to face.
Yes.
Do we have what we need to try it?
DR. KELLY: We have all he could want.
Typhus, H1N1, SARS.
The problem is,
they're all stored in B-Wing.
What's the matter with B-Wing?
BRIT: Dr. Spellman.
Our chief vaccinologist.
Within hours of the outbreak,
he'd been sent blood samples
to try and isolate the pathogenic cause.
Unfortunately...
This is B-Wing now.
God damn it.
How many?
How many are there?
There were 80 people working there.
I've never seen them move like that.
BRIT: They're dormant.
They're awaiting stimulus.
Now, this
is vault 139.
That's where your samples would be.
This is the skybridge.
That connects B-Wing
to the main building here.
And this, is the only thing
standing between us and the skybridge.
So,
what do you propose, Mr. Lane?
DR. KELLY: You are not serious.
B-Wing's a maze.
They'll never make it back alone.
We don't even know
if his theory is correct.
JAVIER: Well, I know I'm not asking
one of you to take him there.
Each has its merits.
- Last resort.
- It's too loud.
Let's go.
Try not to kill one.
It only makes
the rest of them more aggressive.
Yeah.
You sure you want to do this?
Of course I'm not. Let's go.
BRIT: Good luck.
See you all shortly.
Good luck.
If anything comes down this hall before
we do, you seal these doors for good.
- Understood?
- Okay.
DR. KELLY: There they are.
Go, go.
Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up.
Come on!
They're fine. They're fine.
DR. KELLY: Shit.
JAVIER:
The vault we need is in 139.
Go!
Oh, my God.
Left, left, left!
What are you doing?
She'll get you to the vault.
That's the vault.
- We can make it.
- No, we can't.
We can't make it. Let's go!
They're not gonna make it.
You heard what Javi said,
we cannot open it.
They're not alone, we can't open it!
They are coming back!
We can't leave them there.
Come on!
Open the door!
BRIT: Run!
DR. RYAN: Run!
Run! Faster, come on!
Run!
In, in, in!
Come on!
Now where is Gerry?
Where is he, where is he, where is he?
Come on, come on, where are you?
DR. KELLY: 5-6-9-6-4.
5-6-9-6-4.
What happened to Gerry?
Not that one. Not that one.
Oh, shit!
Shit!
BRIT: Jesus.
He's going to inject himself.
We have no idea
which one's going to work.
We don't know if any of them will work.
DR. RYAN: If he uses anything
he took from that left case,
he's dead anyway.
What's he doing?
How long does he have to wait?
Before he's infected? Not long, but,
that's not the question
we're really asking, is it?
-
Look at them.
He just walked right past him!
He walked right past him!
-
- Like it was nobody!
Okay.
GERRY: This isn't the end.
Not even close.
WOMAN:
Hi, there. This is...
This is Amy. Is anyone out there?
INDIAN MAN: Hello. I'm trying
to get in contact with anyone.
AMY: We've had some luck
finding people with this transmission.
GERRY". We've lost entire cities.
NEWSWOMAN: When there's
no more people left to infect,
they go dormant. Whole cities are lost.
NEWSMAN:
The World Health Organization
reports today that help may soon...
NEWSMAN 2:
...a hybridized meningitis strain
with components of smallpox and H1N1.
GERRY: We still don't
know how it started.
NEWSMAN 3: The World Health
Organization has created
a vaccine that works
as a kind of camouflage,
making people who receive it
invisible to the infected.
GERRY: We bought
ourselves some time.
NEWSWOMAN: Volunteer forces
are delivering the vaccine
to areas that have been cordoned off.
MAN: Distribution efforts
began in earnest on April 10th...
NEWSWOMAN: The importance
of getting the information
out to those still alive
within the quarantine...
GERRY: But it's given us a chance.
MILITARY OFFICIAL:
If you can get to a colder area,
to higher ground,
they move slower on the ground.
RUSSIAN NEWSMAN:
The Battle of Moscow is still raging.
FRENCH NEWSMAN:
Initial tests on the so-called camouflage
have been largely successful.
-
GERRY: Others have found
a way to push back.
SQUAD LEADER: Move, move!
All right, juice 'em up!
PILOT: Approaching target.
Permission to engage.
COMMAND OFFICER:
Permission granted.
PILOT: All clear.
Light 'em up. Light 'em up.
TELEVANGELIST: It's permanent!
It's settled, it's settled! It's over with!
There's no forgiveness in hell!
Whatever goes to hell, stays in hell!
WOMAN:
This is Station 7 in Nebraska,
broadcasting on the shortwave band.
GERRY: If you can fight, fight.
NEBRASKA WOMAN:
Head north if you can.
AMERICAN WOMAN: Hello?
Is there anyone out there hearing this?
GERRY: Help each other.
NEWSMAN: Mexico City has been
declared a complete loss.
GERRY: Be prepared for anything.
Our war has just begun.