NORA: Reverend?
- How are you? Come in, come in.
Oh, thank you.
I didn't see your car out front.
Oh, it's in the shop.
My son dropped me off.
Uh, please.
How can I help you, Nora?
My wedding anniversary
is coming up.
Mine too. Yeah, this Saturday.
Annie and I
have been married 19 years.
That's nice.
We would've been married 25 years.
Oh. I'm so sorry. I--
I did-- I completely forgot.
Forgive me.
NORA:
It's okay.
It's been three years
since James was murdered.
The boy who killed my husband
is in a juvenile detention facility.
He's a juvenile, and he plead guilty,
so I never got to see him in court.
I want to see him.
I want to talk with him.
I-- I've written him a letter every week
for three years now.
He's never responded,
and he doesn't wanna see me.
Okay, so?
I've tried everyone,
from his social worker
all the way up to the governor, and...
And no one can convince him.
- And do you think I can?
NORA: I don't know.
But I don't know where else to turn.
What's his name?
I've written it all down for you.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
- I'll do my best.
- Thank you, Reverend.
I'll be in touch.
Oh, Reverend? I hope you and your
wife have a very nice anniversary.
[MOUTHING]
Thank you.
I really mean that.
[DIALLING NUMBER]
[PHONE RINGING]
ANNIE:
Upstairs.
Hello.
Hey, I'm glad you're home.
Don't go anywhere.
- Hmm.
- What's up?
I'm not sure. That was your dad.
- What'd he say?
- He told me not to go anywhere.
Hmm.
SIMON: Here, put these away
and then go down to the kitchen.
- Something's up with Dad.
- What?
I don't know, but he's
on his way home right now. Hurry.
- Get off.
- Um, could you hold on one second?
Get out.
I'm talking to Heather's mom.
Dad's on his way home,
and something's up, something big.
Um, okay, so just, uh, tell Heather
I'll see her around 7.
LUCY: What's going on?
SIMON: I don't know, something big.
ERIC:
Annie!
Oh, good.
Will you marry me?
I don't know how to put together
a wedding over a couple of days.
We spent months
planning the first one.
Yeah, and the first one fell apart.
Hey, don't worry.
I'm gonna take care of it all.
I'll call and invite anybody you want,
and I'll get flowers
from the church florist,
and I'll get a cake,
and, hey, I got the church.
All you have to do is be there.
Mm. And get dresses for the girls.
They can wear whatever they wore
at the last wedding they were in.
Okay. Oh, and tuxes for the boys.
I've given Ted Shields
so much business,
I'm sure he'll let us have them
for nothing.
And, hey, you can wear
that kind of hippie-dippy wedding dress
you wore the first time.
- I love that dress.
- Well, I still have it.
But I doubt that I can still get in it.
Sure you can. What?
I wanted to wear
my mother's wedding dress
the first time we got married.
Oh, right, and my mom
wanted you to wear her dress.
That was round one
of the Camdens vs. the Jacksons.
You think your dad
still has your mom's dress?
Well, it might still be in his attic,
but, ah, he's leaving tomorrow.
He won't have the time.
Besides,
that "hippie-dippy" dress will do.
Hey, Mom?
- Mom?
- Can't you see she's busy?
What is it, Simon?
I was just wondering,
with this whole wedding thing and all,
you still gonna have time
to finish the attic?
Would it hurt if you moved
into your new bedroom a week later?
Dad, school starts next week.
Junior high.
I can't go to junior high
and still be sharing the same room
with my little sister.
Word would get around.
It's okay, Simon.
I assure you, I will finish on schedule.
I don't know, Mom.
I'm afraid either my room
or your wedding will suffer.
ERIC:
Mm.
I need to talk to Mom and Dad alone,
please.
What do you think I was doing?
Please, tell me the wait
is almost over.
Go.
I just want you to know,
I may not make it to the wedding.
- Oh.
- Why not?
Because no one else wants to go,
so I may not have a ride.
Why don't your brothers and sisters
wanna go?
Because it's the last weekend
of the summer,
and they've
kind of got a lot of stuff to do.
Besides, you're already married.
Well, I hope
they'll all change their minds,
because since none of you were there
for the first wedding,
we'd really like you to be there
for this one.
- So we have to go?
- Yes, you all have to go.
Oh, man.
I don't know.
Are we just being crazy here?
Are we just doing this
because Nora stopped in
to see you today?
Yes, we're crazy.
And yes, I decided
to do this after seeing Nora.
It was kind of a reminder
that life is short
and we shouldn't put things off
we've always wanted to do.
Do you think you can get in
to see that kid who killed her husband?
Please, me? I can do anything.
[SIGHS]
Found out from his social worker
that the thing he misses most
from the outside
is a real fast-food burger,
fries and shake, so...
He might not see Nora for that,
but I have a feeling
he'll give me a shot.
You have no qualms
about bribing him?
The kid killed someone,
it's not like I'm gonna corrupt him.
Okay, it's a small sin
for a good cause.
[CHATTERING]
Thanks.
Um, you know I wanna
be with you every minute
before you leave for school
on Sunday.
Well, my parents
have kind of screwed that up for us.
You see, they've decided
to get, um, married this weekend.
They're not married?
Oh, no, no, no, they're--
They're married.
They, uh...
They're getting married again.
See, uh, they never got to have
a big wedding,
so they're gonna have one
on their anniversary this Saturday
and I've gotta be the best man.
So our last date together before I leave
will be a wedding?
- Cool.
- If you say so.
- So, what do you wanna do tonight?
- Stare at your face.
You wanna tell me
why you're in such a bad mood?
I'm not in a bad mood.
Look, I know what's bothering you,
so why can't we just talk about it?
You don't know anything.
I gotta go inside.
You know, if you won't talk to me,
you need to talk to somebody.
You've gotta stop acting so mature.
Don't I get a kiss?
Good night.
WILSON:
Careful.
Good night.
[DIALLING PHONE]
[PHONE RINGS]
JIMMY [ON MACHINE]:
I'm not home right now.
You can leave a message
or try me at Ashley's.
[MACHINE BEEPS]
[DOOR CLOSES]
LUCY:
Excuse me, I'm sleeping here.
MARY: It's 10:00.
You're not sleeping. You're crying.
All you've done
all summer long is cry.
LUCY:
So?
I haven't had anything else to do.
Not one single guy has called me
since I broke up with Jimmy.
And why are you
in such a bad mood anyway?
I'm not.
It's just that Jimmy broke up with you
three months ago, so get over it.
I can't get over it.
And once school starts,
it's gonna be even worse
because I'm gonna have to see
him and Ashley together.
It's gonna be a nightmare.
It'll only be a nightmare
because you're making it a nightmare.
Things like this happen.
That is what life is all about,
disappointment and failure,
so get used to it.
And you're not in a bad mood?
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS
ON WALKMAN]
You know, I think
I'm gonna put the bed over here
once we take down the bunk beds.
- Fine. I want the top bunk.
ANNIE: Guys, come on.
It's time for you two to go to bed.
It's late.
SIMON: Yeah, that's one
of the advantages of getting this place.
I won't have the same bedtime
as a 6-year-old.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, Simon, tomorrow
I want you to go with Matt to get a tux.
Mom,
why do I have to wear a tuxedo?
Because I've always dreamed
of having a wedding like this,
and seeing my two sons waiting for me
with my husband
at the end of the aisle.
Mom, do you hear
how weird that sounds?
- Do I get a tuxedo too?
ANNIE: Oh.
Ha-ha. No, honey, I'm going
to make you a beautiful dress,
and you can be the flower girl
and throw rose petals down the aisle.
Why can't I throw flowers
in a tuxedo?
[SCOFFS]
Well, I'll think about it. Off to bed.
What does a tuxedo look like
anyway?
[ANNIE GRUNTS]
Grandpa? It's Eric.
Eric Camden.
Your son-in-law.
Did I wake you? I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Well, I tried to call you earlier, but then
I thought you might be at Ginger's,
and I didn't wanna leave a message
because I'm trying to surprise Annie.
Yes, that Eric.
Hold on a sec. Yeah.
[WHISPERING]
Who's that you're talking to?
I just wanna get started
on some of the wedding plans.
- Well, isn't it a little late?
- Well, yeah,
but I wanna stay on top of things.
- Hey, Annie? Honey?
- Yeah?
You know you put two paintbrushes
in the freezer?
You can freeze brushes
instead of cleaning them
when you're gonna be painting again
the next day. It's an old painter's trick.
Grandpa, you still there?
I don't want you
to go back to school.
[THUDDING]
- Hi.
- Hey, Luce. What's up?
Nothing. Just this stupid wedding.
What are you doing here?
Well, I thought we were going
to the pool to work out the knee a little.
- What wedding?
- It's nothing.
My parents
are getting married again.
It's their anniversary or something
this Saturday.
I didn't say
I was going to the pool.
You know,
school is starting next week,
and you made it your goal
to be off crutches by then. I didn't.
- Yeah, so what?
- So I think you're ready.
- You can do it.
- You don't know that.
You don't know anything,
and you don't know how I feel.
So tell me how you feel.
I'm right here, I'm listening.
Can we please
talk about something else?
Okay. Uh, tell me
about this wedding. Am I invited?
You can come if you want.
Yeah, I wanna come,
but I wanna be invited.
- You don't want me to go?
- I don't even wanna go, and I'm in it.
Tell you what.
You seem like you need a little space,
so I think I'm gonna
spend the day with Billy.
- You still wanna go out tonight?
- Not really.
[DOOR OPENS THEN CLOSES]
You know, I say we leave her here,
have Dad pick her up later.
MATT: He can't.
He's on his way to see that murderer.
Hey, Ruthie.
- Hurry up, we don't have all day.
- So where's Heather?
Oh, uh, a friend of hers
from school's staying at her house.
- They're riding back together.
- A guy friend or a girl friend?
- What difference does it make?
- It's a guy, huh?
- Yeah.
- So, what's the story?
You know, I just assumed
it was a girl friend, that's all.
- Oh, yeah.
MATT: He kind of took me by surprise.
You know, he's from Canada,
so he drove down.
He's staying with Heather and her mom
until they take off for school.
I hate to say it, but this is trouble.
You know that, don't you?
Oh, Ruthie, that is stunning.
Much better than the gold one.
Oh, yeah, yeah, stunning.
Can we go already?
What do you think?
Oh, it's, uh...
It's great. I think this one's it.
How about something in white?
White.
Uh...
You know, the only thing
that's keeping me sane here
is that I'm getting my own room.
[GROANS]
Ruthie, can I come in?
May I.
May I. Okay.
This isn't about the tux, is it?
Why are you taking so long?
- Because.
- Because why?
Because Simon's moving out
because he doesn't like me,
and I'll never see him
anymore either.
Hey, Curly,
just because Simon's moving out,
doesn't mean he doesn't like you.
It just means he's growing up
and he wants to be on his own.
I have a room of my own.
Yeah, well, since you're alone
and I'm going to be alone,
maybe we could move in together.
Come on, give it a shot.
You might like a room by yourself.
No, I won't. I love living with Simon.
Okay, I'll make you a deal.
If you take any of the tuxes
you've tried on and we can leave now,
I'll fix it so Simon doesn't leave.
At least, not in the near future.
- How?
- Don't worry.
I know how to get to him.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
- Mom, do you have a second?
- Yeah, I might have a couple.
Okay, here it goes.
I know how important
this wedding is to you and Dad.
But to me, it's the universe's way
of pointing a big fat finger and saying:
"Lucy Camden,
you're alone and have no one."
Honey, tell me why the universe
can't be pointing a finger at you, saying:
"Lucy Camden, someday you're gonna
fall in love with a wonderful man
and have a wedding all your own."
I'm thinking about calling Jimmy
and asking him
to come to the wedding.
For old times' sake.
You know, like friends.
Is that what you really want?
Just to be Jimmy's friend?
It's better than nothing.
[SIGHS]
If you need me, Reverend,
nothing would give me more pleasure
than dragging this guy
out of here for you.
ERIC:
Thanks.
Well, I'm Eric Camden.
Thanks for meeting with me.
- Well, I take it you're Martin.
- You were expecting someone else?
I take it you're here
to talk to me about my junk mail.
[PAPER RUSTLING]
My friend would like to talk to you.
She needs some closure
in her life.
I gave her the ultimate closure, man.
[WHISPERING]
I killed her husband.
And I suppose you're gonna
try to tell me that doesn't bother you?
You don't feel you owe her
five minutes of your time?
Hey. I don't owe her
or anybody else anything.
I'm paying my debt to society
right here.
But, um,
maybe I'll, uh, pay her a visit
when I get out.
Disappointed?
Well, I'm a big disappointment
to everyone.
But what can I say?
I had a bad life.
I had a bad mother, no father,
and only a TV to raise me.
And all I learned from the TV
was how to kill people.
I'm sorry you had a bad life.
And I am sorry you had a mother
that wasn't good enough for you,
and I'm sorry
you didn't have a father.
But regardless of what you saw on TV
or in the movies,
don't you try to tell me
that you don't know the difference
between right and wrong
and life and death,
because I know you do.
You never even opened them?
- Just the first one.
- And you won't see her?
Yeah, fine.
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
MARY: Look, we have to try on
these stupid dresses.
- Who you calling?
- No one.
[PHONE RINGS]
LUCY:
No, don't!
- Hello.
- Hello, Mary? Jimmy Moon.
Did Lucy just call me?
I have call return.
Uh, no, I was calling
my boyfriend, Wilson,
and I dialled your number
by mistake.
- I know it was her. Is she there?
- Do you wanna talk to him?
I told you not to pick up.
Yeah, well, you shouldn't have
called him and then hung up.
JIMMY: Hello?
- Hello.
I know you called. That boyfriend story
Mary made up was lame.
LUCY:
Well, she happens to have a boyfriend.
- Okay, I called.
- What do you want?
Um, well, my parents
are getting married
on their anniversary
this Saturday,
and I thought
that maybe you'd like to come.
You know, since you
used to practically be part of the family.
- But I'm with Ashley now.
- Yeah, I know.
So you mean
you want both of us to come?
Yeah, of course.
That's incredibly mature of you.
Yeah, well,
I matured a lot over the summer.
Okay, well, I'll ask Ashley
if she wants to go. Thanks.
- Hmm, hmm.
- What did you just do?
I don't know,
but it's all your fault and I hate you.
Well, fine, I hate you too,
but we still
have to try on these dresses.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Hi. Do you, uh, read lips, Zack?
How do you know to--?
When someone rings the bell?
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Right.
- Come in.
- Well, I-- I thought we were going out.
I don't wanna leave Zack alone.
Well, we've got tonight
and tomorrow night, and that's it.
I don't wanna be with Zack.
I wanna be with you.
Okay. All right.
So, what I'm thinking is,
I'm gonna hang
all my superhero posters
all over the walls.
And then I'm gonna string my entire
superhero collection of action figures
across the ceiling.
What do you think?
Good idea.
Superheroes everywhere.
- You'll probably need them.
- What do you mean need?
Everybody knows
ghosts hang out in the attic,
especially in this house.
Why in this house?
Because the lady who died
and left the house to the church...
- Yeah?
- She died in this attic.
- Where'd you hear that?
- Matt told me.
That's why no one
ever slept up here before.
[WHIMPERING]
These will be just fine
once I let them out a little bit
here and there.
Besides, you're both so pretty,
it doesn't matter what you wear.
Hey, sorry I'm late.
I stopped by the flower shop.
They're gonna deliver
Sunday's flowers a day early,
plus throw in a bouquet
and some rose petals for Ruthie.
Mrs. Bink can't come. She's gonna
make a gift of the wedding cake.
And the ladies' circle is gonna arrange
a potluck dinner. Is that okay?
Oh, it's more than okay. Oh.
How are you? How was your day?
How was your meeting?
Uh... Didn't go all that well,
actually, but, uh,
I'm not gonna let this kid
get to me.
- I'll tell you about it later.
- Okay.
So, Mary,
is Wilson coming to the wedding?
No. He's crazy about her,
but what does she care?
- Shut up.
ANNIE: Mary.
Why isn't Wilson
coming to the wedding?
I don't want him there, okay?
But yet you forced me
into asking Jimmy and Ashley.
- How did she do that?
- I didn't.
- If you weren't on those crutches--
- You'd what?
Hey. What's going on?
This is a wedding.
It's supposed to be fun.
Well, I hope you two are having fun,
because nobody else is.
Did we fare any better
with the tuxedo team?
Oh, yes, they are fitted,
pressed and quite handsome.
See, it's Matt's new look.
The short hair, much better for a tux.
- I don't know, I liked it better longer.
- Yeah? Do me a favour?
- Hmm?
- Don't tell him.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
Oh, hi, Wilson, come on in.
- Mary?
MARY: I don't wanna see him.
- Come on in, I'll see what I can do.
- No, I should've called.
I was just on my way home
from a friend's house.
She's just in a bad mood.
It's okay, really. Good night.
I still think I'll see what I can do.
- You've had a hard day, I'll get this.
- What's with those two?
They're in a self-pity contest.
And I'm about to declare them
both losers.
That's what's going on with them.
- So it's not just the ugly dresses?
- No.
You don't know how lucky you are
to have a boyfriend.
Yeah, you don't know
how lucky you are you can walk.
Uh, sorry about that.
I'll pay for it.
Yes, you will.
Uh, Mary will be right down.
- Don't go anywhere.
- Okay.
Go.
If you don't want
Wilson around anymore,
then you tell him.
But don't just ignore him
or be rude to him
when all he's done all summer
is try to be supportive and helpful.
[SIGHS]
It's about time
someone said something to her.
I said something to you too.
You have got to stop
feeling so sorry for yourself
and start thinking about
getting over Jimmy Moon.
How am I supposed to do that
when he and Ashley
are coming to the wedding?
Uninvite them. Blame it on me.
[RINGS]
JIMMY:
Hi, I'm not home right now.
You can leave a message
or try me at Ashley's.
[BEEPS]
Um, hi. It's me, Lucy.
I just wanted to tell you that,
actually, I'm not that mature
and I changed my mind
about you and Ashley
coming to the wedding.
So I guess I'm sort of uninviting you.
Unless, of course,
you wanna come by yourself.
Listen, I got ten minutes to get home,
so I'm gonna make this quick.
I'm crazy about you.
And if I've been too pushy
about the sticks, I apologise.
And I wanna go
to your parents' wedding with you.
- No, don't.
- Why not? You're crying.
Help me out.
I'm a little lost here.
What is it? Is it the wedding?
I'm just tired of using crutches,
but I'm afraid if I don't, I might fall.
Yeah, you might.
But if you do, you'll get right back up,
and that's the worst that can happen.
You know,
you really are no help at all.
Yeah, but I'm trying.
- How's it going?
- Eh, not so good. How about you?
- Not so good.
- Heather?
- Yeah. Mary?
- Yeah.
- Good night.
[ERIC TYPING]
Hey, what's up?
Oh, uh,
I'm confused about Heather.
You know, uh, I thought
we had everything planned, you know?
How we'd handle being apart.
She'd come home for Thanksgiving
and Christmas.
Then I could fly out
for Valentine's weekend,
and then she'd come back
spring break.
Sounds like there's a lot of holes
in that plan.
Like, uh, who are you gonna take
to the homecoming game?
Or, uh, senior prom?
Or graduation?
All that great stuff
that's reserved for seniors.
Well, I just figured I wouldn't go.
I mean, except for graduation.
I don't have to have a date for that.
What about Heather?
She has a friend, Zack,
that I didn't even know about,
that she does
all that stuff with.
Ah. And Heather having someone
to, uh, do things with
that she would otherwise miss out on
is a problem for you?
Well, yeah. I don't have some girl
I'm hanging out with
- who's just a friend.
- Well, all I can say is, son,
uh, if I were in your shoes,
I wouldn't let any man in the world
change the way I feel
about the woman I love.
I wouldn't wanna let someone else
have that kind of control over me.
Uh, I think I'm a little
too late for that.
Well, think again, will you?
Yeah.
[SIGHS]
[DOOR CREAKING]
It's not so bad.
Just a little bit more light
and it'll be fine, huh?
[THUDS]
Oh.
[WIND WHISTLING]
[GASPS]
[BOTH YELL]
[SIGHS]
- Mom, you scared me.
- You scared me.
I heard a noise.
I didn't know you were up here.
- Are you okay, honey?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
What are you doing
up here so late?
Well, I was just checking to see
if the ghost of the lady
who lived in this house
was lurking around.
She died up here, you know.
- Who told you that?
- Ruthie.
- And who told Ruthie?
- Matt.
Well, Matt's wrong.
The lady who left this house
to the church died in Florida.
That's where she moved
when she retired.
Look...I hate to say it, Simon,
but I think maybe your sister
and brother
have a little conspiracy going
to keep you in the room.
You may be ready to leave,
but I don't think
Ruthie's anxious to have you go.
You're right.
And as her older brother,
I'd be willing to stay in the room
a little longer.
But to tell you the truth,
now that you've done all this work,
I feel a little obligated to move in.
Well, don't.
Doing something for your sister
out of love
is far more important
than doing something for me
out of guilt.
If you ever wanna take that back,
I'll understand.
[LAUGHING]
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello.
Yeah, this is Reverend Camden.
Oh, right, sure,
you're Martin's social worker.
Tomorrow?
My wife and I
are getting married tomorrow.
Well, it's a long story, but--
Yeah. Well, if he's willing to see Nora,
I'll be there.
Okay. Uh-huh.
Great, thanks.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
- Yes.
- How are you, Reverend?
Sign right here.
You don't know
how happy this makes me.
Well, if you're happy, I'm happy.
- Have a nice day.
- You too.
ANNIE: What is this?
- Oh. Uh, it's a wedding present.
I thought the wedding
was the present.
You shouldn't have done this, Eric.
I didn't get anything for you.
It's not from me, it's from your dad.
"Annie,
I should never have let
19 years go by without...
...apologising for everything we did
to make you call off the first wedding.
Congratulations on your anniversary.
Love, Dad."
[CHUCKLING]
I'm sorry I let you stay up
fixing the other one,
but I didn't know if this would come
or if it would fit or--
- I gotta go. I gotta pick up Nora.
- We won't start without you, okay?
No matter if everybody gets tired.
- I'll be there.
- Okay.
I'll wait for you at the altar
with the rest of the family.
- I won't be late, I promise.
- Okay. Oh.
Oh.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
- You look beautiful.
- Thanks. You too.
- It's for your mom and dad.
- Oh.
Thanks.
Oh, um...
Don't you wanna come
to the wedding?
Come on,
I'd really like you to come.
I have to do my, uh, best-man gig,
and you can keep Heather company.
Are you sure?
It's our last night together.
Yeah, yeah. And after the wedding,
we can, uh, drop Zack off
and we can have
some time together alone.
I promise.
[MOUTHING]
Do you have five minutes?
Five minutes.
Oh, uh, I actually got that one.
[CHUCKLES]
I'm sorry I've been such a jerk.
I just don't wanna lose you.
I was going to wait
until after the wedding,
but I might as well tell you now.
- Tell me what?
- Well, I've decided not to move.
I'm gonna give it another six months,
to give you some time
to get more used to the idea.
Oh.
So do I still get the top bunk?
No. As long as it's the top bunk,
it's all mine.
When is six months gonna be up?
- Are you sure you wanna do this?
- I have to do this.
[DOOR OPENS]
Here you go, Reverend.
Good luck, ma'am.
Nora, this is Martin.
Hello, Martin.
Thank you for seeing me.
I was hoping that I could find out
something about my husband's death.
How James died.
Maybe...why he died.
Look, I had a knife.
The guy got in my way.
He shouldn't have.
I see.
Was he in your way
when he was running out of the store?
No, he got in between me
and the manager guy.
You intended to kill
the store manager?
I didn't intend to kill nobody,
but like I said,
your husband...got in my way.
His choice.
NORA:
Well...
[SIGHS]
At least I know
he was protecting someone
when he died. That's something.
Do you have any idea
how you've changed my life?
My husband
meant everything to me.
Because of him,
everything had meaning.
I still have the same job,
but now there's no one
to buy things for,
no one to help pay the rent
or save with for holidays or vacations.
There's no one
when I come home at night.
There's no one in the morning
when I make breakfast.
And it's been like that now
for three years.
[SIGHS]
But now it's time to move on.
But I just couldn't until I saw you.
Thank you.
This has all been very helpful.
And it's somewhat comforting to know
that my husband died a hero.
I never knew that.
And just one more thing.
I want you to know, Martin...
...that I forgive you.
Hey. I didn't ask you to forgive me.
Who needs your forgiveness?
You hear me?
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
She didn't forgive you for you,
she did it for herself.
Otherwise
she'd go on being your victim,
and I think she's been
your victim long enough.
- Wait.
- I can't.
I'm getting married this afternoon.
Before you go,
just tell me one thing, Reverend.
Do you, uh...?
- Do you think God will forgive me?
- You'd better pray he does.
But I gotta tell you...
...I'm not sure I ever will.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[SIGHS]
I shouldn't have told Jimmy
that he couldn't bring Ashley.
Next time I see them,
I'm gonna feel really stupid.
Yeah, well, it's too late now,
isn't it?
Look, Miss Pathetic,
you're feeling sorry for yourself.
Doesn't mean
you need to take it out on me.
Me? If anyone's feeling sorry
for themselves, it's you.
Yeah, well, I think I have good reason
to feel sorry for myself.
I just lost the man of my dreams.
Oh, please. Jimmy Moon
is the man of your dreams?
What's wrong with Jimmy Moon?
He's just as good-looking as Wilson
and a lot smarter.
First of all, it's not nice to judge guys
by the way they look.
And secondly, if I remember correctly,
and I do, I had to tutor Jimmy
because he was failing science,
so how smart can he be?
Smart enough
not to become a teen father.
Okay, that does it.
Oh, right, I am really worried.
I could take you in like two seconds.
Oh, yeah? You want a piece of me?
Come on, I'm calling your bluff.
- Throw your crutches, Crutches Girl.
- I'm not gonna throw them down.
I can knock the stuffing out of you
just like this.
[ORGAN MUSIC PLAYING]
Come on. Come on, huh?
LUCY: Let go of those things.
MARY: You let go.
MARY: Let go. Ow!
LUCY: Let go of me.
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
LUCY:
Off. Get off! Ow!
Ow! Help.
MATT: Hey. Wait.
- No.
[MARY AND LUCY GRUNTING
AND YELLING]
[ORGAN MUSIC STOPS]
MATT:
Uh...
All right, Dad just got here. Let's go.
Listen, um, go get
your rose petals, okay? Okay.
Feel better now?
["THE WEDDING MARCH"
PLAYING ON ORGAN]
[CROWD MURMURING]
I guess Jimmy decided
not to come.
- He has no idea what he lost.
- Thanks.
LUCY: Are you gonna be okay
without the crutches?
MARY:
Yeah, just don't let go of me.
You missed a great chick fight.
[CROWD MURMURING]
WOMAN:
Beautiful.
[MOUTHING]
I love you.