Previously on 90210:
Come on,beverly hills is going
to be great r far ou Mily.
we got the weather,we got the
palm trees with themore palm trees.
- more palm trees.
- More palm trees.
You had,like,a million friends.
Back home.
And they all knew about
the whole adoption story.
Ethan,this is annie,the
new principal's daughter.
Annie,my boyfriend,ethan.
Yeah,well,actually,yeah,we-we
know each other.
We met,like,two summers ago?
- Hey,ty.
- Yeah. You want to grab dinner tonight after rehearsal?
- ya
- You can spence anybody.
- Annie!
- Ty.
I wanted to bring you these.
If you guys want to grab
some food,I can watch sammy.
You just got here.
Don't worry,I'll be here for a while.
I went to dad's office last night,and
I saw him there kissing another woman.
I'm gonna take you home,okay?
Okay. It's okay.
In eighth grade,my dad had an affair.
I had to tell someone,so I
told my best friend,naomi.
She promised me that
she wouldn't tell anyone.
So she told everyone.
Well,I got some bad news.
I just got off the phone
with your drama teacher.
Got a family emergency in atlanta and she
is taking an indefinite leave of absence.
So what does that mean?
You're not canceling
the musical,are you?
Well,if I can't find somebody Ise
I don't know that I have a choice.
Dad,no!
We've been rehearsing for
weeks and the show is amazing.
Can't you just find
someone to supervise us?
Harry,how hard could it be to
find an acting coach in L.A.?
I mean,I could throw a rock
out the window and hit an actor.
Fine. I'll do it.
- What?
I'll direct the musical.
Uh,but... but,grandma,uh...
you're so busy writing your memoir.
Sweetheart,when the theater is
in pain,I come to mend the wound.
O... okay.
Tabitha,that is a very nice offer.
Annie,you are very lucky.
I'm so excited.
I'm excited,too.
I have to remember some of those
breathing exercises I used to do.
I had a director who'd say,
if you're not breathing from your
ass and reaching to the skies,
the back row won't hear you.
I slept with him.
now I know you don't love
it,but it's great,and,hon.
Mom,okay,stop?
I think that your
foundation's a little dark.
It's the same one I
use every single day.
Merry early christmas,everybody.
Both my girls look beautiful.
Why are we shooting the
christmas photo without jen?
We're gonna photoshop it in.
What?That's the dumbest
thing I've ever heard.
Can we just shoot this,please?
All right,everyone get in real close.
Linda and bob are
gonna start renovating.
So I was gonna offer
them the beach house.
I've already offeredfor the same reason.
Charles,would you mind
turning towards tracy?
There's a big space right
here between you two.
I wish I could live at the beach house.
- What does that mean?
- Tracy,you're looking a little stiff.
Charles,can you put your arms
around both ladies,please?
Naomi,can I get a smile?
And,tracy and charles,can I get
a little kiss between you two?
could you hurry up,please?It's
really hot out here.
It's an out-of-town
emergency. Give me a second.
why do we even bother?
Naomi
- it'll be just a second.
- Okay.
Dixon,your mom is driving me to school.
You can take my car.
Sweet.
You call the realtor this morning?
Only one couple looked
at the house this month.
Not surprising.
Tough market.
What's going on?
We're having trouble
selling the house in kansas.
Is that a bad thing?
It's not a good thing.
We're paying a mortgage on
a house we're not living in.
It's not like we're paying rent here.
Yeah,but we still got expenses.
We got moving expenses,gas priceshey,
hey,don't worry about it.
We're fine.
hi,mom.
Where are we going for dinner tonight?
I made reservations at craft.
Is dad coming?
He has a meeting.
Is that code for "sleeping
with his girlfriend"?
- Naomi...
- mom,how can you live like this?
How can you just accept that
dad's with another woman?
How is that okay?Can you explain
that to me?'Cause I just don't get it.
It's just a casual fling,that's all.
She doesn't even live here.
So what,mom?
He's still cheating on you.
This is between me and your dad.
Stay out of it.
I'm not discussing this with you again.
Do you understand?
Perfectly.
I wish we could've done
breakfast at the peach pit.
I hate early morning meetings.
Don't worry about it.
I'm getting a kick out of being here.
I can almost still hear the chanting.
- Donna martin graduates.
"That's crazy.
Oh,thank you very much. Now that's
gonna be stuck in my head all day.
Speaking of,have you seen donna?
Yes. And,oh,my god,her baby
is so cute,I can't stand it.
I know. How's the play?
It's good. I mean,the taper
just went through a renovation
so it's a really nice house to perform
in. You're gonna come see me,right?
Of course. I wouldn't miss it.
- So... dirt.
- What?
- Ryan.
- Ryan. Okay.
Um... he's nice.
I like him.
We work together,so it's awkward.
And he's ten years younger
than me,which makes it bizarre.
I asked him where he was when kurt cobain
died and he said he was watching cartoons.
Does he know about ryan?
Why would he need to know?
It's none of his business.
Well,it may be his business if
things get more serious with ryan.
You know,because of sammy.
Well,let me worry about that.
Fair enough.
Ethan,I'm a mess.
I'm freaking out.
My family is so fake.
I mean,my sister's being photoshopped
into the christmas card from paris.
My dad is kissing my mom
while having an affair.
Look,I don'T... I'm sorry
you're going through this.
Thank you.
- But,look,naomi...
- I know.
We're not together anymore.
But it's really good to talk to you.
oh,damn.
why were trying to fit that
tank into a compact space?
Uh... I thought I had room.
Do you know how much
parts cost on german cars?
A lot?
Just give me your insurance info.
Um... listen,uh... do you think there's
any way we can handle this between us?
Oh,you don't have insurance.
No,no,my dad does,but i
don't want him to find out.
You know,he won't let
me drive the car anymore.
I can get you the cash.
I'm good for it,I swear.
It's not like you don't
know what school I go to,man.
It's not like I'm gonna
disappear or anything.
Just please do me this solid,man,please.
My dad's away on business
for a couple weeks.
I just need the cash
before he gets back.
Hey,kelly.
Um,so about saturday.
There's a new pizza place in silverlake. And
apparently it's good,like new york good.
Oh,saturday,I can't do it because silver's
not going to be around to help me with sammy.
How about brenda?
She has a show that night.
Sammy's dad,does he ever take him?
What?
Sammy's dad. Did I... did
I say something wrong?
No. No,it's fine.
Um... he just... he doesn't live here.
Where does he live?
All over kind of.
Yeah,he's,uh,he's a do-gooder.
He's actually halfway across the
world right now doing charity work.
- Impressive.
- Yeah.
- Well,maybe we can do sunday,okay?
- Okay.
I'll see what I can do.
- Great.
Hey,annie,I haven't seen you around.
I've been around.
Busy with the play.
So how's naomi?
Uh,just a lot of really intense
stuff going on with her family.
Yeah. Yeah,it seemed like it.
So are you guys like...?
No,no,no. No,uh...
she was just flipping out and
I know how to deal with her.
- Right.
- What about you and ty?
What's up with that whole...?
Ah... nothing really.
Well,I had a lot of fun hanging
out with you the other night.
Me,too.
Well,good. Do you want
to maybe do that again?
Like thursday?
Uh,thursday night I
have nothing going on.
uh,cool.
Well,I'm with my brother
all afternoon,so you want
to just meet at the peach
pit like around 6:00?
Yeah. Cool. See you then.
Awesome.
- =www. ydy. com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
Sync: YTET- 邦德猪
Season 1Episode 04
So,the other night,I left
without saying good-bye.
I'm sorry about that.
Oh,no,it's no big deal.
Well,I think it's a big deal 'cause
I didn't get to hang out with you.
Anyway.
vampire weekend's playing
this secret show at
the avalon and my cousin
got me vip tickets.
It's thursday.
You want to go?
Oh,I can'T.
I have plans.
Okay.
Uh,is it like a group hang?
'Cause I don't have to go to the show.
My cousin's in the music biz
and hooks me up all the time.
Um,it's-it's not really a group hang.
It's more of a
one-on-one kind of thing.
Got it.
I'll see you around.
Silver... hey,hey,silver.
Can I talk to you?
Headphones.
You have a nanosecond.
Please don't blog about my dad's affair.
You thought my family
problems were gossip.
Why shouldn't I treat
yours the same way?
Look,I've said it before,but
I'll say it again- I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry,okay?
Because I get it now.
I know what you were going through.
What I did was really messed up.
Yeah,it was really messed up.
no,stop.
My ears are bleeding.
You have no passion,girls.
You got to sing like
your privates are on fire.
For god's sake.
Just because you're a bunch of rich
brats doesn't mean you can't have angst.
Channel it.
This is a song about your mother.
She's been lying to you about
sex,and it pisses you off.
You're all teenagers,so I
know you hate your mothers.
I hated mine.
Use the anger.
I will show you how it's done.
- Grandma,maybe I...
- annie,I'm not your grandmother here.
I'm the director.
Everyone..
（这老太太的歌喉... orz！）
you've got to move from the
hips and claim the stage!
Dad,you know how very much I love
grandma,and it was a nice idea.
But you have to,have to find
a new director for the musical.
I cannot replace her.
You have to,okay?
Yes,you can. She...
she makes me do these crazy heavy
breathing exercises all the way to school.
And she's so embarrassing.
Sweetheart,just one more week.
There you are,harry.
Excuse me,darling.
When you have a moment,I need to
go over the theater budget with you.
The lights need new gels and
the costumes are not up to par.
Is that coffee on your tie?
What?
Great.
You're seriously arguing with me?
Uh,hello.
- My mother...
- saw the whole thing.
Hey,now you know how annie
feels having you here.
You know people in the
entertainmed inustry,right?
Anybody who might be
able to direct a musical?
I think I might know someone uh,here.
Thanks.
You caddied at a country club in
wichita,cut grass,shoveled snow...
And this would be your first real job?
Yes,sir.
- You go to west beverly?
- Yes,sir.
I once hired a kid from west beverly.
A long time ago.
He was a good,good egg.
Tell you what,I'll try you out.
You don't mess up,you got the job.
Thank you,sir.
Stop calling me sir. " The name is nat. "
Thanks,nat.
Mom?
Like to introduce you to somebody.
This is brenda walsh,a west beverly
alum and a very big fan of yours.
Really?
Well,it's nice to meet you.
It's an honor to meet you.
I've seen every one of your films.
Not every film.
There were some real
stinkers in the '80s.
Well,you were wonderful in all of them.
Also I saw your hedda
gabler at the ahmanson.
That's the greatest part
ever written for a woman.
I got to play her.
Not as well as you,of course.
Oh,you're an actor.
Yes.
Mom,opening night is around the corner.
There's a lot of work left.
So I thought you could use some
help,and brenda offered to assist.
I thought I was handling
this all rather well.
Oh,well,I've seen the original
production of spring awakening.
And I always think it helps
to have an extra pair of eyes.
Wonderful.
Fine.
Great.
all right,explain to me,why
didn't you say yes to ty?
I mean,it's vampire weekend.
It's a secret show.
It's ty collins.
Ethan asked me out.
No.
No ethan.
What is wrong with you. He's off limits.
Ethan and naomi are over.
They are never over.
Let me explain something to you.
Naomi and ethan have this thing,right?
It's like they're in this
bubble- this impenetrable bubble.
- A bubble?
- And no matter how hard you try
you can't get in and
you don't want to get in.
Trust me,I stand beside
the bubble and I'm scared.
Well,the bubble has popped.
No,no,you see,you just think it has.
Silver,I am going out with ethan
and you cannot talk me out of it.
And I'm not scared.
I'm going to buy you a box of tissues.
So... what can I get you ladies?
Wait,you're working here?
Yeah.
Are you trying to make me
look bad with mom and dad?
No,I'm trying to make me look good.
I've been messing up since
I got here,so,you know,
I'm trying to do something
a little more responsible.
kiss ass.
Hey,you shouldn't be talking.
So can I get you anything?
The digital proof is in.
Naomi!
Come take a look at this.
I think I'm going to order 500 more.
At least. I think you look beautiful.
Thank you.
Gross. I look terrible.
Well,you've been outvoted,kiddo,'cause
jen likes that one,too.
I think you look great,honey.
Great?I look high.
No,you don'T.Were you high?
oh,that's the office calling.
Give me a second. Yeah,I'll
be there at 8:00.
Outside's in control... that's funny.
You're home late.
Uh,yeah,I got a job at the peach pit.
What?W-when did that happen?
Just today.
They said they needed help.
And,dad,you know girls in beverly hills.
They like expensive stuff
and expensive places.
Yes,they do.
I want to roll in style.
Maybe one day get a nicer car.
No... no offense.
None taken. It is a piece of crap.
yeah.
Dixon... having a job,good thing,but I wish
you would've discussed it with us first.
You guys don't want me to take it?
No,you can. You can.
Uh,but I don't want it to interfere with
your schoolwork or lacrosse practice.
It won'T.
Mom,I'll be right down. I'm
just saying good-bye to dad.
Bon ami beverly hills,this is gail.
How can I help you?
Hello?Hello?
*********
again All right,all right,focus.
All right. Okay.
Which organ produces bile?
the pancreas.
Liver.
All right,name the three
classes of digestive enzymes.
I know this one. I know this one,um...
lipases,uh,amylases and... and,um...
and?
And I'll study again after work.
those dimples are not going
to get you into harvard.
I think mrs. Schwartz is
going to give us a pop quiz.
I'm gonna study after work.
I promise. I promise. I'm sorry.
Ethan,I'm freaking out.
Naomi,now is not a good time,okay?
Why?What's going on?
It's steven.
I told my mom that I'm
watching him so she could have
some time to herself and
he's just having a bad day.
That's all right. Let me help you.
We have a new cleaning
service and I forgot
to tell him not to touch the furniture.
He's been rearranging it all afternoon.
I've tried everything that usually works
to get him to change
his focus but nothing,
and I really need him to
stop before my mom gets home.
Hey,it's all right. I'm
here. Okay?I'll help.
Hey,steven.
Hey,man. Naomi came to see
you. How cool is that,huh?
The couch is in the wrong place.
Oh,I can see that. You
want me to help you out?
No.
- I got it.
- Okay.
Well,you know what?I
was actually hoping maybe
we could pop some
popcorn and watch a movie.
What do you think about that?
I came all the way from
my house just for you.
Oh,it sounds
good,right?You love popcorn.
I like popcorn,with butter.
A stick of butter,two teaspoons
of salt and a pinch of pepper.
That's perfect.
That's exactly how I
like mine,but we need
the couch to sit on to
watch the movie,okay?
So why don't you come with
me and we'll get some popcorn.
Hold my hand. Here we go. Okay.
annie,your posture is horrid!
Pull your shoulders back.
you're singing from the throat.
Annie,what is wrong with you today?
- Okay,guys,how about we take five?
- thank you
Hey,dixon.
Hey,what's up,man?
Uh,so look,my dad's trip
got cut short,which means,
I need the money by the end of
next week,and I got the estimate.
It's $500.
Are you serious?
We can still go through
insurance,if you want.
No,no,no,no,no,no.
Um... I'll get you the money,man.
I'll just pick up some
extra shifts,you know?
Okay.
Yeah,yeah. All right,cool,man.
Annie!
You're singing from the throat.
I need diaphragm.
Annie,what is wrong with you today?
I always learn a lot watching
my rehearsals on tape.
Helps me tweak things.
Like did you notice that jill
was off-key in the second verse?
And adriana,she needs some refocusing.
You know,brenda,that...
was very helpful.
Eye-opening.
I'm gonna go talk to
her. I know where she works.
You really want to do that?
It's my family. I can't just
sit back and do nothing.
I just think there
might be a better way.
And what way is that?
Did you like when your
parents got divorced?
You would have stopped it if
you could have,wouldn't you?
I mean,look what happened to silver and
her mom- their whole lives fell apart.
What are you gonna say to her?
I'm gonna tell the bitch to stop sleeping
with my dad and back the hell off.
My dad's obviously going through a mid-life
crisis and she's probably just some slut.
If I can get her to leave him,then
everything will go back to the way it was.
But I need your help.
Will you please go with me?
yeah. I'll go.
well. That's your fourth dr. Pepper.
How late is ethan?
Half an hour.
Did you call him?
Not answering.
Maybe he forgot.
That really doesn't make me feel better.
oh,crap.
Hey,dixon,can I grab
a coffee to go,please?
- Yeah,yeah. Yeah,yeah.
- Thanks,man.
So... these were your plans?
I'm waiting for someone.
Right.
I wellhope you have a good time.
- coffee?
- Thanks,man.
Thank you.
I am such a ginormous idiot.
Yes,you are.
He's a pretty good tipper.
Ty is cool and sweet and
he really likes me and
I'm sitting here waiting
for a guy I might not get.
A guy in a bubble.
An impenetrable bubble.
Look,annie,you're holding on to a crush
you had on ethan,what,like
two years ago.
You need to go for the guy who treats
you good,not the one who gives you grief.
Yo,willie!Burgers for
table five,man. Come on.
can't make it,so sorry explain later
yeah.
Lots of grief.
thanks for helping.
The kids can play it,but
they can't arrange.
Sure,sure. I would add a little
percussion to the bridge here.
That sounds great.
So... do you want to play with the band?
I was hoping for a fuller sound.
Yeah,I don't think so.
um... by the way,kelly asked me if I could
babysit on sunday and I don't think I can.
I have a lot of catch-up
work to do with this.
All right. No worries.
Do you know sammy's dad?
I do.
He sounds like a cool guy.
Traveling the world
and,uh... helping people.
You know,I don't really feel comfortable
talking about kelly's personal life.
If you have questions,you
should just ask her.
Yeah. No,you're... you're right.
Should I have questions?
There's just a long history there.
you want me to go in there with you?
no.
Just wait here.
I'll be here.
we're closing in ten minutes.
are you gail?
hi,naomi.
You know who I am.
Of course.
Why are you here?You're
supposed to be in denver.
Why aren't you in denver?
I just moved here.
- Naomi,I...
- you know what,stop. Just stop.
Leave us alone.
Leave my dad alone,leave
our family alone.
Go away- my dad
doesn't love you.
You're just a fling.
I'm gonna lock the door for a minute.
Do you want some water or something?
No,I don't want any water,and I don't
want to be locked in here with you.
I want you out of our lives.
Why don't you go after
someone who's single?Try that.
I've asked myself that
same question so many times.
There are some things that don't
make sense just because they don'T.
I guess somehow it's worth it to me.
Oh,really?
Why might that be?
Because I love him.
Oh,my god,I've heard enough!
That's the address to my beach house.
Your break's over in five minutes,dixon.
I don't care about the same stuff
kids in beverly hills care about.
Hip nightclubs.
Trendy purses.
I just like doing my own thing.
So,you're trying not to fit in?
I just like being different.
It's how I'm made,you know what I mean?
Do i know what you mean?
I'm a black kid living
with a white family.
Doesn't get more different than that.
Right.
Is that weird?
You know,they're my
family,and I love them.
They don't care that I'm black.
I don't care that they're white.
But,you know,sometimes,like,when
we're eating dinner
or if we're talking about
something or even laughing,
then just for a split second...
I feel like I don't fit in.
Then,just like that,the
feeling goes away,
- but...
- somehow,it's still there.
Yeah.
So,when are you gonna ask me out?
maybe I don't want to ask you out.
Yeah,you do.
Oh,you're so sure?
Uh-huh... I bet you that you do.
Wait... that means if I do ask
you out,then I'll lose the bet.
Oh,there's no losers here.
all right,I like the way you think.
Dad said you're quitting the play.
Oh,well,I couldn't work under
those conditions anymore.
The acoustics in that
auditorium are atrocious.
And the stage is literally falling apart
well... thank you so
much for all your help.
You're welcome,darling.
You're in good hands with brenda.
Annie?
You are doing a wonderful
job in the musical.
You are very talented.
Thank you,grandma.
Mom.
I went to see gail.
I talked to her.
Why would you do that?
Because I want her out of our lives.
You have no business getting involved.
Mom,it's not just a casual
fling with her and dad.
He's moving her into the beach house.
Dad lied.
What?
- Mom...
- no.
I'm sorry.
Oh,god.
No.
hey,teach.
you look tired.
up all night thinking about me?
Uh... yeah,I wish.
No,I was... up studying bio.
All right,everybody,let's
focus. We got tests coming out.
- Test?
- Yeah.
Bio's tomorrow.
Flannery o'connor short stories today.
no no no
Annie.
Hey,annie,listen,I am so
sorry about standing you up.
- This whole thing with my brother...
- don't worry about it.
It's not like it was a
date or anything,right?
I got to go.
So,do you think you could score some tickets
for the sea wolf concert this weekend?
I heard they're playing spaceland.
- Yeah,I have tickets for that show.
- Cool.
I'm already going with someone else.
later.
So,I can't do pizza on sunday.
I just can't get a
sitter- everybody's busy.
Okay.
What's the matter?
look,I don't know what the story
is with you and sammy's dad.
It just feels like there's
unfinished business.
And what would give you that idea?
Well,I was talking to brenda,and...
wait,wait- you were
talking to brenda about me?
I'm just trying to get to know you.
Look,kelly,I just want you to
feel like you can talk me,you know,
like you can tell me anything,and if there
is something going on with you and your ex,
then... I'm a big
boy... I can handle it.
there's nothing going
on with me and my ex.
Brenda.
Uh,what did you say to ryan?
- About what?
- About me.
Not much.
You shouldn't have said anything.
Okay,kelly,any guy that dates you
is gonna have questions about him.
You should just get your story straight.
My story is straight.
You know,you get really emotional
when you talk about this.
I wonder why that is.
What are you saying?
I'm saying that you still
have feelings for him.
Of course I still have feelings
for him- he's my son's father.
Kelly,come on,you know
there's more to it than that.
No,there isn'T.Because it can't be;
because he's not here,and I deserve
to be with somebody and be happy.
Oh,give me a break.
You are never gonna be
happy with somebody else,
because you're still in love
with dylan,and you know it.
dad,what are you doing here?
Hear they have great coffee.
Well,you came to the right spot.
Mr. Matthews told me that you got an
incomplete on the test you took today.
I'll make it up.
Look,dixon,I like
that you have this job,
b5ut I told you I didn't want it
to interfere with your schoolwork.
Dad,look,I-I need this
job right now,you know?
After next week,you know,I'll
cut down on a few shifts,but...
why next week?
Um... because I,uh...
accidentally knocked
off someone's side mirror
when I was parking the van and
wanted to pay for it myself.
You should've come to me.
But,dad...
your insurance would've went up,right?
And I heard you and mom
talking about money problems.
So I wanted to take care of this myself.
I don't know many other kids
who would've gotten a job.
I mean,hell,I never did.
You're already ahead of me.
Look,uh,I'll-I'll pay for it
now,and you can pay me back in time.
- How's that sound?
- Thanks,dad.
Leave a tip.
I got your tip: Don't
get any more bad grades.
Do you like it?
Oh,I love it.
I think I'm gonna wear it to school.
Oh,you would not. I dare you.
Come on,get into the video.
All right,all right,all right.
you look pretty good with
a monkey on your head.
Oh,yeah?Well,you look good
with a tiger on your head.
Thank you,thank you.
This is the best day ever.
I love you,ethan ward.
I love you.
You're not cotton candy.
yo,dix.
Here.
Thanks for helping me out,man.
No worries.
So,listen,my dad has a
hookup with the lakers.
We got courtside tickets,but
my buddy bailed on me.
So you interested?
- For real?
- Yeah.
Kobe?
Hell,yeah,I want to see the lakers,man!
you hit that guy's car,almost got him in
trouble,and then he asks you to a game?
It's nothing.
I've seen guys fistfight,and then
five minutes later,they're hanging out.
that's crazy.
Yeah,you know,guys aren't like girls.
We don't hold grudges.
Life is way too short.
Look...
I'm not gonna post anything
on my blog about you.
Okay.
Thank you.
Just thought you should know.
Okay.
So see you around?
Yeah. See you.
all right,man,so I'll
just catch you later.
What's this?
Snickerdoodles. They're apology cookies.
When I do something screwed up,I bake.
Uh,you know,just forget about it.
I can't forget about it.
I'm an idiot,ty.
I like you. I want to hang out with you.
Well,you really haven't
been acting like it.
I know. I know I messed up.
And-and I am so hoping that
I'm not too late to fix it.
Am I too late?
Look,I-I spent the whole
night making you these cookies.
So eat a snickerdoodle;
they're really good.
I really don't think
cookies are gonna do it.
You haven't tasted one yet.
Annie,I don't have to. I just...
That's way better than cookies.
I'm sorry. Really.
You know,if you weren't
so freakin' adorable,
I wouldn't even be having
this conversation right now.
- Can we start over?
- Okay Yeah.
So you want to go out this weekend?
Yes,I would.
I remember that hat.
L.A. Zoo.
Still cute.
How you doing?
I'm all right.
I realized,can't always get what I want.
no matter how bad I want it.
Can't fix my parents' marriage.
Can't make my dad love my mom.
I'm sorry.
You've been wonderful
through all this craziness.
Thank you.
Think we can start over?
What do you mean?
all I know is I miss those
two people who went to the zoo
and ate cotton candy and
were silly and happy together.
so you saying... you
want to get back together?
I'm saying take it day
by day,see what happens.
I can do that.
Come here.
- so cute.
- Yeah?Still cute?
Still cute.
- =www. ydy. com/bbs=-
Proudly Presents
Sync: YTET- 邦德猪