Is this madness?
How...How could it be?
In that cave...
Free me.
How could I have
seen myself...
..when I was not yet myself?
The Sons of Mithras have been
entwined with your destiny
since long before
you were born, Leonardo.
Time is a river,
and there are members of our
fraternity who have learned
to navigate it - both upstream
and downstream.
You may think
that you're not yet yourself
but, in every moment, you are
both the child you once were
and the sage
you will some day be.
- That's not an answer.
- I never promised you answers.
For those, you will need
to find the Book of Leaves.
Answers to questions
that haunt all men.
Questions that haunt you.
- The fate of my mother.
- And more.
I speak of your destiny.
Much as I enjoy
the entertainment, signor,
we came to talk to the Duke
about hiring his mercenaries,
not to watch them
beat each other senseless.
Some mead,
fine sirs?
Thank you.
Yes, indeed.
We mull it with
a little honey.
The pride of
the Duchy of Urbino.
- A little honey?
- Just fucking drink it.
Brilliant! Bravo!
- Medici!
- Urbino!
You know you fight like a man who's
not seen battle for far too long.
- It's been too many years.
- Yes.
Federico da Montefeltro,
Duke of Urbino.
Leonardo Da Vinci.
Reading? My!
This primer was given to me
by Gentile Becchi.
You mourn him still.
How may I serve you,
sister-in-law?
We are due to hold a pageant for
Martedi Grasso, some days hence.
I hoped you might
escort me.
Even if Lorenzo returns
from his diplomatic forays,
he usually finds pressing
business when the revels begin.
At least he pays for
the revels.
But what is a lady
to do for a partner?
I can only thank heaven
Lorenzo has a brother
who knows his way around
a dance floor.
Mm. You must forgive me,
but I have a plot to unravel.
Becchi charged me with ferreting
out the spy within our midst.
But the evidence against Becchi
was overwhelming.
Testament to
the ability of our spy.
He is a kind of genius.
I will soldier on at the revels
without you, then.
I'm touched at
your dedication.
The fact that, for all
your opportunities...
..you're so intent on doing
the right thing.
Maybe your most
attractive quality.
My lady, it is time.
My personal torturer
has arrived.
- You know we have no choice.
- Mm.
Twice a day,
I must down this potion
if I'm to produce a boy,
after my earlier failures.
Oh, Moses, tell Giuliano
what's in this.
I cannot bring myself
to say the words.
Asses' milk,
powdered goats' antlers,
bull's testicles...
Giuliano, you could spare me
this liquid atrocity
if you would father
a son yourself.
If we do not produce
a male heir soon,
somewhere in our line,
the house of Medici
will start
to look like
an unstable investment.
We each have our duty, I see.
Salut.
It's there.
Logic dictates
that land lies due west.
You think the identification of
a simple cardinal direction
is all you need
to find your goal?
It's all I need
to get started.
You could spend a hundred
lifetimes traveling west,
could you not?
The map Avraham ben Yosef
brought to Florence
is not an original,
but a reproduction,
riddled with notations that
only one man can decipher.
The cartographer
who copied it.
- Another Son of Mithras?
- His name is Solomon Ogbai.
We call him
the Abyssinian.
Lucky for you,
he is not dead.
Not yet.
You have yet to save him.
His retinue was
brutally intercepted
while he was traveling under the
employ of the Ottoman Sultan.
A most savage warlord
holds him captive.
The Abyssinian cannot be freed by
simple diplomacy, or even ransom.
It will take guile and inventiveness
- which only you possess.
These are delicate times.
I have commitments to Florence.
Your destiny lies elsewhere,
Leonardo.
Save the Abyssinian
while he still breathes.
I have to think it over,
I can't...
You've already
thought it over.
In truth, your journey
has already begun.
Time...is a river.
You have already made
the decision.
You make it every time.
He's done the coin thing,
has he?
You're the map maker.
I thought
you needed rescuing?
- I will.
- In the future?
The sooner you move beyond words
like present and future,
the sooner you become
the man we need you to be.
Are all the Sons of Mithras
unable to speak plainly?
I admit, on occasion, we can be
inscrutable, but so can you.
I wanted to meet
the storied Da Vinci
in the bright of day.
We're different men,
once Hell breaks loose.
And when's that happen?
Hell happens when
the evil of this world
exceeds our belief
that we can conquer it.
You ask me when
you'll reach that point.
I cannot say.
Depends on you.
Whatever befalls us,
do not shirk from the task.
I have a knack of rising
to the occasion,
if I might only be told
what the occasion is...
I venture to say it's true
what the Sons of Mithras
have seen you in you,
and you are closer
every day, artista.
- Closer to what?
- Wake up.
Where are you leading me?
L-leading you? Maestro,
you're the one leading us.
What?
You woke us in the night, gave
us one of your shopping lists.
Buy more magnesium,
obtain obscure alcoholic
beverages from the East,
acquire three horses...
You had some plan.
Do you not remember?
I do, I do. I remember it.
- How long have we...
- Days.
You've been a sullen fuck
the entire trip,
all for some foreign halfwit
who got himself abducted.
- The Abyssinian.
- It's like...
It's like
I'm just waking up.
I lost part of myself
on the journey.
- Journey where?
- It's not where...
..it's when.
The evils of this world.
There's something odd
around the castle.
- What's this?
- You'll see what it does.
Whose kingdom is this?
The locals call him Tepes.
That's the man
we've come to confront?
The one who has your captive
is the fucking Impaler?
I lost my right eye in battle.
Removed the bridge of my nose,
so I'd still have peripheral vision.
There.
Clever, eh?
That is quite...gleaming.
And so we should explain
our reason for being here.
- Piero?
- May I?
The two Papal states flank
your land and mine
and while we can watch
Rome with one eye...
..we must always keep
another...eye,
always on the Pope's property,
to the north.
Unless...
..the northern realm
became our property.
And how would that happen?
Well,
if we allied ourselves -
Florence and Urbino -
it'd make sense if we could carve up the
northern Papal territory between us.
I can annexe the city of Bologna
and its environs.
You could double your port
capacity on the Adriatic.
A bold stroke, but why don't I
conquer it myself?
I have the army.
What do you offer up?
Money, of course,
from the largest banking concern
in all of Europe.
From each of us,
as he is...
..blessed.
Scared you,
didn't I?
That'll be fine, Medici.
I shouldn't provoke
my own godson,
but I like to test
a man.
You've grown to be
a worthy ally.
And it's been too long since
I led my men into combat.
Our proposal is timely, indeed.
I knew you had something
juicy in mind,
when you showed up on
my doorstep.
There's no way you'd caravan
all this distance
just to watch me take a shit.
Their turbans are nailed
to their skulls.
All Turkish. Clearly this
warlord has an issue with the Ottomans.
His bravery against the
Turks won him 13 years in prison.
But, seeing as none of us
are Turks ourselves,
we should have
nothing to fear.
You don't think,
with my blood,
someone could take me
for a Turk?
How do I know this warlord's
eyes aren't failing?
Because I spotted you
from miles away.
Though I were blind,
I could hear the clattering
and nattering of your Tartar
tongue from further yet.
- I'm not a Tartar.
- What are you, then?
- Unique.
- Unique?
Dung beetles think
they're unique.
Your mongrel half-breed lineage
speaks louder than your words.
You see God, well, has many
punishments for mankind:
earthquakes, volcanoes,
plagues and cancers.
Worse than these, he sent
the Turks and the Tartars
and the mongrels,
like you.
Ave,
Vladislaus Dracul Filius,
vaivoda partium
Transalpinarum.
Prince of Transylvania
and Wallachia,
son of Vlad II known as Vlad
Dracul, or Vlad the Dragon,
which makes you Vlad III,
Son of the Dragon.
Or as it is known in
your language: Dracula.
Impressive,
your command of my titles,
but tell me who you are
and what you want here.
My name is Maestro Leonardo.
These are my companions,
Nico, Zoroaster.
We were sent by the
Magnificent Lorenzo de Medici
of the Republic of Florence.
All of Italy wonders at your
victories against the Ottomans,
and my lord extends
his friendship
and seeks military counsel
for the greater glory
of Florence
and Wallachia.
You must know this land
has been bedeviled by war,
and worse than war.
We shall talk more...
..at dinner.
As long as
the dinner's not us.
So we're selling tickets to
the Papal baths now, are we?
An urgent matter has arisen.
Urgent enough that you sully
this chamber with her presence?
I know where to find
whores if I want them.
We thought it best you hear this
news directly from her lips.
I've come from Florence,
Your Holiness.
And does your absence
from the city...
..create no suspicion?
My aunt in Siena is
providing me with an alibi.
No-one of import will
miss me in Florence.
Certainly your husband doesn't
fall into the category of import.
What of
Lorenzo's war engineer,
in whom the Count seems
so fascinated?
Da Vinci has set out
from the city.
No man knows where.
Nor woman?
Nor I.
Lorenzo himself
has left Florence.
As we speak,
he makes an embassy to
the Duke of Urbino,
fresh with the credit
of his dealings
with Ferdinand and Isabella.
He seeks to create
a new military alliance.
The calculating rogue.
Far from reeling at our attempts
to weaken his rule,
Lorenzo courts the most
accomplished mercenaries
on the peninsula.
I know what
the naval do with them.
He and Urbino
will march north.
Together, they'll sack our lands
surrounding Bologna
and divide them up.
How do you know, Holy Father?
Because it's exactly what
I'd do, you fucking coward.
Look at the lot of you.
Too scared to bring me
this news yourselves.
Hiding behind
this Florentine slit.
How can I wonder Lorenzo
resists me so well,
when I see
the quality of my allies?
We only tried
to serve your glory.
We had not the benefit
of your divine guidance.
Guidance? You want guidance?
Do you remember what proved
I was chosen by God?
So... So many things,
Your Holiness.
The way I survived
drowning as a child.
Let's see how you do.
Holy Father, surely...
a loving God shows mercy.
You dare question me?
The rock upon which
God's word stands.
Kiss this ring.
My bath is ruined.
I don't care how,
end the house of Medici,
before I end you.
Dinner awaits.
How are we supposed to free the
captive from a place like this?
If I knew that,
I'd be Da Vinci.
You've dropped some change.
Of course, you'll have
noticed the money.
The Sultanis -
a base currency...
..for the heathen ruler
of the east.
You see, this is how
I allow my soldiers
to prove
their loyalty to me.
I toss these Sultanis on
the ground before them.
And, do you know, the coins are
never, ever touched?
It's just they've fallen
quite randomly,
you'd really notice
if one was gone?
I miss nothing.
Please, now.
A little Tuscan wine,
just to make you feel
at home, no?
Thank you. Thank you.
I must say, I'm impressed with
your hospitality,
so soon after your escape
from captivity.
I am, sadly, at home
in dungeons.
As a child, my father sent
my brother and me
to be hostages held by
the Turkish Sultan.
The prisons converted
my damnable brother
to the cause of the Turks,
but not me.
I learned to trust nobody.
To survive any pain,
the dogs, the dungeons,
even a lightning strike,
which has left me with
this...web of scars.
Now I spend every waking hour
in resistance to my brother...
..and the fucking Turks.
Well your victories against them
have been recognized,
even by the Pope.
If we're going to raise
a toast,
let's lift a glass to the one who
helped me out of the prison this time,
to the Bringer
of Light himself.
Who, my lord?
Lucifer,
the Bringer of Light.
Most beautiful
of all the angels.
And how did Lucifer
help you?
Like me, Lucifer rose
against a tyrant.
Like me, he was abandoned and
betrayed by the God he loved.
I made a pact with Lucifer
to win my freedom
and ascend to my throne
one last time.
And, do you know...?
I don't find it hard
to live without a soul.
Lucifer.
And how fortuitous for
Da Vinci.
The clever devil leaves just as
I arrive with questions.
You don't find
that curious?
Trust me, signor, that's the
least curious thing about him.
What is your relationship
with him?
We had our day...
..but that's all it was,
a day.
And, anyway,
his eye is set on another.
- How do you know?
- I'm a woman.
No, of course
we're friends.
He saved my life and, for that,
I deeply admire him.
That hasn't become illegal,
has it?
It has if it hurts Florence.
All I want is
your help in guarding her.
I don't know where he's gone.
You keep
his confidences well.
I'd like to lie
to anyone else, Excellency,
but not you.
Although, if you tried
to force it out of me,
I'd be helpless
to stop you.
Perhaps we should discuss
this somewhere else.
- Somewhere more quiet?
- Mm.
Until we make it less so.
The city gates are closed.
Two minutes to curfew,
scoundrel.
Either you get your arses home
or spend the night here.
Persons caught roaming the streets after
curfew get put in my little book.
Being put in my little book means you
explain your transgressions to the judge.
Signor Medici,
forgive me.
I hadn't seen you with
a bar wench.
- Your little book?
- My ledger, full of pigs, mostly.
You record every curfew
violation?
Since the day
it was declared.
If one were to study these,
one might see who was out,
when they shouldn't
have been?
Yes, if one were
a glutton for punishment.
Take me to them.
One could speak weeks paging
through these records.
Then we're in luck. According to my
brother, I'm great at wasting time.
Your secret, sir?
Oh, it's a matter of knowing
which elements to blend.
Magnesium here,
iron filings there, so on.
I think it's ingenious.
Does it have
a military application?
Not yet.
Well, then,
we must talk further.
Since I've renounced
your Christian gods,
I've only my wits and
ferocity to protect me
from the forces
of Sultan Mehmed II.
Perhaps the ingenuity you bring
to Lorenzo's court
could benefit me as well.
Now...
..since you've shown me
your little party piece,
I will respond in kind with
a little diversion of my own.
You see, without a
soul weighing me down,
I can see in the dark.
I cannot be killed.
I can enjoy certain
entertainments
that may have made me
blanch years ago.
This is the last of the retinue
of a Turkish ambassador
who was foolish enough to
approach me.
I miss no opportunity in
reminding the Turks
of the childhood
they provided.
Is it the one
we're looking for?
Unshackle him.
Now...prove stronger
than your friends.
Defeat these dogs
and you will go free.
And please don't think
me so inhuman
that I wouldn't give you
a fighting chance.
Here's a butter knife.
Please! Don't!
This...
This is justice.
So...shall we send
for the main course?
I can't eat.
My tastes are not universally
shared, it's true.
- Let us retire.
- Before we do...
You have honored us with the
traditional wine of our homeland,
and so do we honor you, with the
traditional liquor of Wallachia.
- You've brought Tuica?
- Mm-hm.
Well, our master in Florence
would spare no expense
to demonstrate his admiration
for you, my lord.
To Vlad III.
When have I ever known you to
hesitate about a drink, my friend?
To Vlad III.
Good.
And some for your maid?
Your men?
- Yes.
- Yes? Good.
There you go.
Some for you...
Some for you.
Show the friends to a room.
- Some for you.
- Once my guards have toasted our guests,
the artisan and I
will parley further.
How about your dogs, who entertained
us so well, this evening?
There's some for you, for you,
the last little drop.
Please don't be unsettled
by the vermin.
I welcome them.
Often, in prison,
they were my only friends.
Well, I know what it is
to be thrown into a cell.
Without the companionship
of the bats,
I would not
have survived.
You see.
- We understand each other.
- Hmm.
Come.
Beautiful, is it not?
You see, this is why I wanted to
return to Castle Poenari so badly.
From the heights...
..I can almost forget
the decades the Turks
have been living
underneath the earth.
It's a shame, then,
that was the last of them.
Oh, there is one more.
Their master, Solomon Ogbai.
The name Ogbai,
in Amharic, it means:
don't take him away.
Yeah?
Indeed.
For stooping to serve them,
I take my time with
the Abyssinian.
I keep him ready for
my personal whims.
I invent new ways to torture,
just for him.
There is a window,
near where I keep him.
He cannot see the view.
So I said I would recreate
the scenery for him...
..if he would only
provide me with
the raw material
for a suitable miniature.
These are the crenulations of
the towers outside my window...
..carved in
the Abyssinian's own flesh.
There is one frontier he shall
never stop exploring.
Agony.
May I share a confession
with you?
Yeah, yes...
..if it pleases, my lord.
I know...
..that I'm mad.
Indeed?
But will you tell me how
I could be otherwise?
A father rips a child
from his home,
from everything he knows
and tosses him into the claws
of his worst enemy.
Well, we are...
We are too often
what our fathers make us.
Whether we like it or not,
better or for worse.
Oh, yes.
In my case,
definitely for worse.
You see, my father,
he taught me
that cruelty is the only true
currency of the universe,
and now I am the richest man
in all of Christendom.
Ha!
- My God, it is true.
- Yes?
Servants told me you were carrying
books upon books into your quarters.
I wondered if they'd been
raiding the wine cellar.
- I'm easy to tease.
- Only sometimes.
Well, at least you have
a hobby you love.
And what is your new hobby?
The Florentine obsession with
record keeping is paying off.
These are the records to every guard
at every station in the city.
Anyone who breaks curfew
will be put down here.
Including, I suppose,
the true spy,
whom you believe
framed Becchi.
You smirk, but there are
mysteries to be solved here.
For example, why do these symbols
from the zodiac keep coming up?
This. That's the sign for
Capricorn, I think.
And this, that's Aquarius, yes?
With certain sensitive
subjects of Florence,
their names are indicated
with symbols,
rather than list them clearly as
violators of the curfew.
Ah. This date I recall.
After a long night of carousing,
I was questioned on my way home,
so is this the symbol for me?
Athletic champion
that you are,
Sagittarius is
a natural code name for you.
Tell us the identity behind each
of these symbols, then.
I'm not privy to
that knowledge.
- That's in Captain Dragonetti's office.
- Obtain it for me.
Becchi would be proud of you.
The man we're here to save must
be dead by now.
No. No, not yet.
But...but we must move
to save him now.
You two can go on.
I feel like I could sleep
for the next week.
As could I.
That's because
we've all been poisoned.
What?
Drink some antidote.
That bastard.
- He slipped something in our drinks.
- No.
I did.
There's nothing you won't do to
us in your bloody quest.
I... I adulterated the Tuica
before we arrived.
That we'd all have to drink it, in
order to convince him it was safe.
And now...
..everyone, including the dogs,
should be passing out.
Ready?
How do you know where
we're going?
It's a simple
architectural assessment.
The Abyssinian pointed it
out to me himself, in a way.
Do we wanna know
what you mean?
No, actually, you don't.
It's here.
Are you sure about this,
Maestro?
No.
What does that say?
Don't take me away.
Now, this, this is justice.
To Vlad III.
Farewell greetings from
a half-breed mongrel.
Nico...
..go get the horses.
I'll meet you outside.
Ah. That one.
Careful. Careful. Careful.
It's that one, then that one.
Not too fast,
he'll be cut even deeper.
It's all over. It's OK.
It's over.
It's not. It's not.
It's not him.
It's not Vlad.
Shit.
Fuck me.
You're an arrogant
little fool, aren't you?
I've endured every drug
and poison known to man.
I fought off
the Ottoman empire.
Do you really think that
I would die at the hands
of a fucking Florentine?
Shit.
Or a mongrel?
How's that for
a military application?
Zo, wake up!
Wake up! Zo!
Life...
Life is a trap,
don't you think?
Well, now,
I'm going to set you free.
Curious.
You cannot kill
a man without a soul.
You must go.
Do not shirk from the task.
Stay out of Florence
for the next few days.
Oh, and don't speak with
Lorenzo, or anyone in the city.
I suppose
I could go to Siena...
..and create a story to explain
my extended absence, but why?
You've seen what happens,
when people question the plans
of the Vatican, haven't you?
I have.
Speak to nobody
along the road.
And make sure
no-one speaks with you.
That shouldn't
be a problem.
I have a strategy.
- Have some men follow her.
- Of course.
Then discreetly
have her killed.
Her value to us
has been exhausted.
She's...
..compromised by
her affections for Da Vinci.
Did His Holiness
order this?
Do it outside
the walls of Florence.
Leave no ties to Rome.
Make it look like
bandits did it.
Oh, and er...have them drive
stakes through her eyes.
She's seen too much.
The guards, the dogs,
they're gonna rouse soon.
Where did you get that wound?
There are more urgent
things to explain.
- Did you know this would happen?
- I knew it might.
I had to take that chance,
for the Book of Leaves.
Sword.
Maestro, shall we see to
his injuries?
They're beyond seeing to and I
cannot meet my end here.
In other words,
fuck this place.
I want to spit on
Vlad's body.
Yeah. Well, you could if
we knew where it was.
Where the fuck is he?
Just come on! Let's go!
Maybe some creature
dragged him off.
Let's not find out. Come on.
You really must try this,
Camilla.
Surely you have a sweeter
tooth than your brother.
You certainly have
a sweeter smile.
Some honey.
The pride
of the Duchy of Urbino.
Oh, I've made arrangements
with their Duke.
With brawn like his, I pity those
who wish harm upon Florence.
You'll have your hands
full with that one.
Federico da Montefeltro's
a...colorful character indeed.
Did you invite us here to show
off your new alliance?
Bernardo!
I don't recall inviting you at
all, Signor Baroncelli.
Perhaps you fail to understand
why I went to Urbino.
You think Rome will
look after the Pazzis
but, when all is said
and done,
Rome only looks after Rome.
And you - both of you -
are loyal sons of Florence.
Don't you think the time has come
for union in our republic...
..not further divisions?
My brother Giuliano has
a stubborn mind,
but a good heart.
At one point, we hoped to
see him in a Cardinal's hat,
but our current relations with
the church have precluded that.
And yet, a young man like
Giuliano, needs a future.
He would make a fine husband
for Camilla...
..would he not?
Honey, anyone?
Farewell.
Arrivederci.
Whether or not the Pazzis agree
to this union, I have to ask,
did you consult your
brother about this?
Giuliano's interests are
the interests of Florence.
I'll have breakable objects removed from
the room before I broach the topic.
She is the child of
our enemy, signor.
Some might argue he is being
thrown to the wolves.
You underestimate
my brother, Piero.
We are not feeding
these wolves.
We are taming them.
Did you know he was
going to propose this?
I had an inkling...
..seeing as it was my idea.
- You've had your elixir?
- Relax.
They say children conceived in
frustration are born bitter.
You'll understand I'm agitated by
this league of devils around us.
After our ploy with
the Pazzis,
you're not ready for
another master stroke.
Our doctor said this position is more
likely to conceive us a male heir.
Men would prefer a position
where a woman's face
is rammed down so far
she can't even speak.
I'm sorry, what was that, dear?
Please.
Wooo!
It was the cage.
The words written on the side:
don't take him away.
It wasn't a taunt,
it was a warning.
Vlad built the device to eviscerate
you if you were freed...
..to rip
an unstanchable wound.
I should've realized.
- I'm sorry.
- Never mind.
I must tell you
of the key you seek.
The other key that opens
the Vault of Heaven?
Yes, tell me.
It's waiting in Rome,
there for your taking.
And, when you have
both keys...
..your mother,
Caterina
she is alive.
She carries
the Book of Leaves for us,
beneath the post of the sun
in a town made of stone...
..in a land on my map.
Why...I need you
to decode the map.
Then you may take
what you need.
Here.
Here is the secret
to deciphering the map.
I will not survive
to come with you.
You must cut my flesh loose
and take it with you...
..once I die.
The Turk said that
I would save you.
And so you will...
..someday...
..but not today.
But there are so many things
you must learn first.
Yes? Yes?
You must learn
that anything is possible...
..including defeat.
- You must...learn...
- What? What?
What?
- Maestro...
- I must - must learn what?
- Maestro, he's gone.
- Maestro.
- I must learn what?
I must learn...
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck.
I've been here before.
- No, this isn't the path we came in on.
- No. No.
This is where the Abyssinian
and I first met.
He warned me...
I thought
I could solve things...
..like I always do.
Hell happens...
..when the evil of the world
exceeds our belief
that we can conquer it.
= sync, corrected by elderman =