- Tell me the worst, Billy.
BILLY: Mr Rogers beat you
- by three and a half seconds.
- Take it like a man, Henry.
Can I help it if I'm your superior?
Heh. Do you want a drink?
Why not?
See you there. Thanks, Billy.
- Well, this is very nice.
- What is?
Mary's beau, Henry Talbot,
has invited us all to watch him drive
- at Brooklands next week.
- He’s just sucking up.
Mama won't ever let you go.
ROBERT: I don't see why not.
- You're convalescing.
I only want to watch the race,
not drive in it.
It's a long way when it won't last
more than 10 minutes.
He told me he's inviting Bertie Pelham.
- Oh.
- What about you, Mary?
I think I’ve talked myself into it,
although I'm sure I'll be sorry.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
It's finished and open for business.
- You are the owner of a hotel.
- What were you having done'?
I turned a bedroom into a bathroom
and I've installed an inside privy.
Leaves me two bedrooms
and one for my niece to run it.
- Yours when the time comes.
- Hmm, when the time comes.
All you need now are clients.
And that'll happen soon enough.
- How's life with the newlyweds?
- Fine,
only Mr Carson wants to dine
at the cottage again.
No need to sound gloomy.
I can rustle up something.
Whatever you do rustle up,
I won't cook it right
or the plates will be cold,
or the dressing will be wrong.
- Does he appreciate all you do?
- Does any man?
Oh, Daisy. Mr Dawes has been
given a date by the examining board.
- Blimey. When is it?
- The 20th.
Ohm; Gad.
Do not take the name
of the Lord in vain.
I hope it's not in vain.
I need all the help I can get.
VIOLET: Do you enjoy weddings?
- Yes, but I'm not going to that one.
I'd feel like the wicked fairy
at the christening of Sleeping Beauty.
Why would Larry Grey
want you to be there?
- You of all people.
- I'm sure he doesn't.
- Dickie must have persuaded them.
- I doubt that.
He wouldn't want to subject you
to more insults.
Well, who then?
I'd say this is the work
of Miss Cruikshank.
She's the one always making
a show of friendship.
Why don't I pay a call on her
and see if I can winkle out the truth?
- I'm sorry I showed it to you now.
- Oh, don't be. Don't be.
Are things going well
in my former kingdom?
Cora is settling in.
I know it must feel awkward.
Oh, no. I am yesterday,
she is tomorrow. That's the way it is.
You must be feeling very hurt.
Well, yes, the fact is,
I must be very honest,
- I am angry at the way I've been treated.
- I don't blame you.
While angry I say things some people
find hard to forgive.
So I have decided to go away.
I'd rather vent my rage
on the desert air
and return when I've regained control
of my tongue.
Your self-knowledge
is an example to us all.
- You don't think I'm wrong.
- The last thing you need,
at this stage in your life,
is to quarrel with your son
- and daughter-in-law.
- Precisely.
But don't fear, I'll call on
Miss Cruikshank before I leave.
I suspect she's quite a tough nut.
And I’m quite a tough nutcracker.
How's Mr Mason?
I’m ready if he needs any help.
I'm going there,
I’ll tell him you said so.
I am trying to find a position,
Mr Carson. Honestly.
I don't say you're not,
but it doesn't seem quite fair
on his lordship, to string it out.
Does that mean I'm sacked?
It means I shall be pleased
when we learn the identity
of your next employer,
Mr Barrow.
[CHATTERING]
We'd stay with Rosamund,
drive to the track,
have lunch, see some racing
and come home the following day.
It's so unnecessary in your state.
But I'm not in a state.
- Unless it's a state of boredom.
- Heh.
- Please let me.
- It's not my decision.
If you mean that, then we're going.
- Edith?
- I'm in if Bertie's coming.
It's a long way for him.
Maybe there's something else for him
to do in London.
Isn't it enough that it's a chance
to see you?
Would it annoy you if it were?
[DOOR OPENS]
I’m sorry if Mr Carson
spoke harshly.
He doesn't mean to be unkind but it
worries him when a plan is delayed.
The plan being my departure.
You just haven't found
the right person yet, Mr Barrow,
but I’m sure there are friends out there
waiting for you,
and a new job in a new house
may help you to find them.
But you see, Mrs Hughes,
this is the first place I found
where I've laid down some roots.
I'm terribly sorry, Lady Grantham.
No one told me you were coming,
and Lord Merton is out.
- It's you I've come to see.
- How flattering.
- May I offer you anything?
- Only your attention.
Shall I sit here?
Now, Mrs Crawley
tells me you paid her a visit
when you first came.
That you were amazingly friendly.
Well, I hope I'm always friendly.
Nobody's always friendly.
And now you have invited her
to your wedding,
which has taken her by surprise.
You mean Larry and Mrs Crawley
have not seen eye to eye in the past.
Larry Grey has spoken to Mrs Crawley
in a manner,
that in any other century,
would have resulted in him
being called out and shot.
Heh. I can't believe
it was as bad as that.
You are misinformed.
But I want to know this:
Why encourage Mrs Crawley
when your fiancé detests
the mere idea of her?
I still dispute that,
but I would say
that Larry had perhaps not quite
thought matters through.
- Meaning?
- Only that his father is old
and alone
- and in need of...
- In need of care?
Which you are not prepared to give.
I would have said a companion.
Which you are not prepared to be.
And what of this house?
Will you surrender it to be free of him?
She won't want to live at Cavenham
after Lord Merton's death.
- It would be lonely for a woman like her.
- But by heaven,
I bet it won't be too lonely
for a woman like you.
I expect they'll have to drag you out
as you break your finger nails,
catching at the door case.
So there we have it.
You want a free nurse
to take a tiresome old man
off your hands.
You're a cool little miss, aren't you?
I'd feel sorry for Larry
if I didn't dislike him so much.
I shall forget you said that
but you should go now.
Much more and we may feel awkward
when we meet,
- which we are bound to do.
- I think not, Miss Cruikshank.
Not if I see you first.
Uh, as you may have gathered,
the family will be away for three days
next week.
So if any of you feel
you're owed some time off,
perhaps you could take it then,
uh, but clear it with me first.
I’ve put in the advertisement.
It'll be out in the morning.
- Now you just have to be patient.
CARSON: What's this?
Mrs Patmore is ready for her
first visitors to the guest house.
- That was quick.
- Yeah, just what I said.
- I’ve got butterflies. Heh.
- Don't be silly.
I'll go over to check it
when they're in London.
I’ll come with you if you like.
Everyone has something to do
on the free days.
- Except me.
- We know what you've got to do.
Yes, Mr Carson.
[DOOR OPENS]
Well, if that doesn't just take
the biscuit.
Are you gonna tell me or not?
She's only decided
to up sticks and set sail
- for the South of France.
- When?
The family are in London next week,
for the racing.
She wants to leave while they're away.
- She can't do that.
- No?
Well, perhaps you'd pop up
and tell her.
- Save me packing.
- What happens to you?
What do you think? I go with her.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, I don't know.
Strolling along the Croisette,
dining in Saint Juan les Pins.
- It's a burden I can bear.
- And what about me?
You stay here. Sticking in stamps.
So she's going to sneak off,
while they're away from home?
My lady doesn't sneak,
thank you very much.
If there's any sneaking,
I'll leave it to you.
[BELL RINGS]
Ah, must go. So much to do.
It's a nuisance but I can't help it.
Two dinners, neither very grand,
- and clothes for Brooklands.
- Very good, milady.
I'm sorry if you're not keen. lam.
I worry about getting
Mr Talbot's hopes up.
I’m curious about the fellow.
Listen, I like him a lot,
but I don't believe a professional driver
will make her happy.
Sybil, maybe.
- But not Mary.
- But that's the whole point.
What's he got that fascinates Mary
when poor old Tony's rolling acres
and glistening coronet didn't?
You'll say sex appeal,
but isn't Mary too sensible?
We have a contrary daughter.
Anyway, I’ve never been motor racing.
Mr Talbot will fix it.
You can help with the picnic.
Take the train.
There won't be any room in the cars.
- Mr Bates is looking forward to it.
- I wish I was.
- You don't have to go, you know.
- I think I do.
It's part of him
and I must get used to it.
That sounds serious.
I suppose you don't approve.
It's not for me to say.
But do you approve?
Mr Talbot seems a nice gentleman,
I'm just not sure his life
and your life fit together.
- I don'! mean to offend you, milady.
- I'm not offended.
I’m troubled, because I understand
what you mean.
They do say that opposites attract.
Yes, they attract.
But do the}; live happily ever after?
[SIGHS]
I think I'll go up in a minute.
How do you revise if he's testing
your general knowledge?
Surely you'll know it or you won't.
- I feel I have to do something.
- ls it so important?
It's important I don't feel a fool.
- You're not a fool. I’m the fool.
- Why do you say that'?
Because I still can't decide
what to do about Coyle.
I don't know why not.
Maybe if I'd given evidence in court,
but that never happened,
and as her ladyship said,
- the story feels unfinished.
- You sound as if you're going.
I need to be sure he has no power
over me anymore.
Will you tell me when you decide?
When Daisy said you'd like to help,
I wondered if you could bring
the books up to date a bit.
Or tackle some heavy stuff?
There's nothing I can't do
until we separate the piglets.
But I've got to get on top of the figures.
When can you come?
I’m busy just now, as it happens.
Well, let me know
when you can get away.
[CHUCKLES]
You're leaving now? Today?
I’ll spend tonight in London,
then I'll sail on the S. S. Paris
from Southampton tomorrow.
We'll cruise round the Mediterranean,
then I'm staying with the Broughams
in Cannes. They keep asking me.
Surrounded by foreigners.
My reason for travelling
is to make myself eager to come home.
A month among the French
should manage it.
- Won't Robert be hurt?
- Ha.
Not as hurt as he would be
if he knew why I was going.
Now, can you give this to him
when they get home?
What if they want to contact you?
Well, I’ve-- I've written to Tom
and told him how to reach me.
He's the most sensible.
Oh, by the way,
I called on Miss Cruikshank.
And was she behind
that odd invitation?
The fact is,
she wants you to take Dickie
off her hands and out of her hair.
I'd say your choice is harder now
than before.
When we talked, you didn't want to come
between a father and his sons.
Well, what's changed?
Well, now you must decide
whether to abandon him
to his selfish and greedy children.
I mean, is that kind? Or right?
It's a tug of war
I have no wish to be part of.
My guess is when you take delivery
from Miss Amelia,
you'll be lucky if you see
a Christmas card.
- Can you be ready by tomorrow night?
- It's just one couple.
Well, the house has been
beautifully finished.
Heh, no doubt about that.
But there's a lot to think about.
You don't offer dinner, do you?
No. If they need dinner,
they can go to the pub,
but I would like to make a thing
of my breakfasts.
- I want a reputation for them.
- You'll manage that easily enough.
I’m here again tomorrow, but should I
come back on Thursday morning?
The family will be in London and Daisy
could do the servants' hall breakfast.
I've no objection.
Now, uh, dinner with Mr Carson.
Why not tomorrow night
when they're away?
I suppose we could eat
at a normal time for once.
Ah, well, you could and you couldn't.
Because I’ve had an idea.
- Hello, stranger.
- I'm not really here.
I'm racing at Brooklands tomorrow and
I thought I'd pop in and see what's new.
Not much. Oh, although...
We have had an offer today and
I was going to ask what you thought.
Uh, her name
is Miss Cassandra Jones,
she thinks we ought
to have an advice column.
- With her dispensing it?
- Yes, but, I must say
her samples are quite funny.
"Your husband is losing interest?
Well, here's step one.
Take a look in the mirror." Heh.
- What are you proposing?
- We'll invent some problems,
she can write the answers.
Then we'll see how the public likes it.
There's nothing new
in an agony column of course,
but they're very popular in America,
which means they're due a revival here.
Should we interview her?
No, let's leave it until we decide.
I think it's worth a try.
I've never seen motor racing
close up.
My sister's new boyfriend drives.
Why net come?
I’m not sure I should.
I'm your employer, so if I think
it's all right, then it must be.
You can meet my family,
if you're strong enough.
[ALL CHUCKLING]
Looking round, I wonder if we ought
to have opened Grantham House.
- I feel guilty.
- Don't. I know what a palaver it is.
More so now there's no real staff.
Almost everyone we know
is selling their London house,
but that's not for me to say.
I went past the site of
Devonshire House on my way home.
There's something vast
going up in its place.
[DOORBELL RINGS]
- Flats, offices and salerooms.
- People don't want palaces any more,
- even if they can afford them.
- They were fun.
In my youth, all great hostesses used
to have luncheon laid for 20 every day.
If you turned up in time,
you sat down to a lovely feed.
[ALL CHUCKLE THEN DOOR OPENS]
Sorry, Lady Rosamund.
I thought dinner would be finished.
And so it should be.
We'll go through.
Unless the boys prefer to stay
and talk racing cars.
- I think I'd rather join the ladies.
- Like Lord Byron.
Mm, heh.
Well done, Tom, for rounding them
all up. I'm very grateful.
Don't be. I’m as keen as you are.
MARY:
It's a bit obvious,
- dropping in, uninvited, after dinner.
- I hope it is obvious.
Obvious that I want to be part
of this family.
Don't I have a say in the matter?
I want to surround you
with people murmuring,
"Isn't he divine?"
or, uh, "You'd be mad to let him go."
Suppose they say,
"I shouldn't have thought a
racing driver was your sort of thing."
They don't have to say that,
you've already said it.
[CHUCKLES]
I'm afraid there's a list as long as your
arm of people who are coming tomorrow.
Hmm, just give me the list
and I'll sort it out.
Did you mind my inviting your family?
I’m here, aren't I?
Let's get some coffee.
Are you prepared for your exams?
- I've done as much as I'm able.
- No one can say more.
I confess I wasn't always sure about it.
But now you've got there, well done.
- I wish you good fortune.
- I wonder where she'll go from here.
Doesn't Gwen's visit show us that in
the new century anything is possible?
What about you, Mr Molesley?
Are you ready?
I think so, hmm.
Ready as I'll ever be, heh.
I’ll walk down some lunch for you
and Daisy and Mr Dawes.
- You don't have to.
- Oh, I'd like to.
- I'll give you a hand.
- Mr Barrow?
What are you doing
with your free time?
Scanning the jobs column,
Mrs Hughes.
What else?
[ENGINES REVVING]
[CHATTERING]
There. That's got it.
I think you're all set.
- It's a good car.
- We need you on the team, Tom.
- Don't tempt me Henry. Ha, ha.
- Ha, ha.
TOM: Who's this?
- Laura Edmunds. My editor.
This is Tom Branson, my brother-in-law
and the man of the hour, Henry Talbot.
HENRY: Hello.
- My sister, Mary, these are my parents.
Sort them out in your own time.
- Nice to meet you at last.
- Lord Grantham. Lady Grantham.
This is Charlie Rogers.
He drives on Henry's team.
Henry's team, is it? When I beat him
into a cocked hat every time?
He's just showing off.
I’m faster, younger and better.
- But not at driving.
- Heh.
I wish there was something more
I could do to be useful.
Oh, just cheer, Tom.
I don't have to be asked. Ha, ha.
I don't know why I am doing this.
I can't swallow.
- Not a bit what we're used to.
- No?
Normally it's an oil-stained sandwich
and bottle of pop.
I’m glad to think we've wrought
an improvement.
Hmm. Thank you.
My train sat in a tunnel
for an hour.
Anyway, I'm here now.
Come and meet Miss Edmunds.
Is it hard to be a woman editor'?
Fleet Street sounds so very tough.
It's hard to be a woman anything
if it isn't domestic, but I do my best.
- I think it's courageous and good.
CORA: Heavens.
Papa's conversion to the modern
world is almost complete.
EDITH:
Don't be deceived.
He'd still like to see us happy
wives and mothers.
That's not fair. Even leopards
can change their spots.
Quite. Now, there's still some food.
No one seems unhappy that
Lady Edith hired a woman, heh.
You're a big improvement
on the last editor, that's for sure.
You're not the only one around here
who has broken a few barriers.
I started my life at Downton Abbey
as the chauffeur.
[MAN SPEAKING OVER PA]
I think we're being summoned.
The cars are in place. We should go.
- Right behind you.
- You'll stay there if I have my way.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
I can't begin to tell you what it means
to me that you came today.
I hope so, my digestive system
has packed up completely.
I’m going to be fine. Mary,
you must credit me with some skill.
Now, when I pass you,
I expect to see you cheer and wave.
Does praying count?
CHARLIE: Henry!
- Coming!
Now, that should keep my spirits up.
I'll see you in a minute.
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
OVER PA]
[CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
MAN [OVER PA]:
The drivers are ready to start.
We're just waiting for the last chap
to get into position at the moment.
Here he comes, it's Henry Talbot
driving car number 14.
Good luck, Charlie.
Good luck, old boy.
And now, at any moment, the flag
will fall and the race will begin.
[AUDIENCE CHEERING
AND APPLAUDING]
Just listen to the roar of those engines,
ladies and gentlemen. And they're off!
There they go,
tearing down the straight...
[ANNOUNCER CONTINUES
SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY OVER PA]
Come on, Charlie!
Here they come.
Come on, Talbot!
You can't shout that.
Isn't Talbot the name of a car?
I can't shout, "Henry!"
They might all be Henry.
- Oh, my God. Here they are.
WOMAN: Come on!
- When will it be over?
- Not soon. They go round and round.
MAN:
Yes! Come on!
Come on! God bless you!
Come on!
What's the point? What do they get?
What do you think? Speed!
This is kind of you, Mrs Patmore.
Oh, I meant to bring lemonade
but I left it on the kitchen table.
- I could kick myself.
BARROW: ls this what you mean'?
Oh, that was kind of you,
Mr Barrow. Thank you.
How were the exams?
Did you do well?
We can't know the answer,
can we, Mr Dawes? Heh.
You'll find out soon,
but Daisy will have to wait a while.
I'm not finished yet.
I’ve got more papers.
Was it harder than you thought?
See for yourself.
What about number two?
It knocked me for a loop.
[ALL CHUCKLE]
What does it say? Read it out, Andy.
- I'll read it.
- Whatever's the matter?
"Tsar
Nic-holas
- c--"
- Here. Give it here.
"Nicholas the 1st called
Turkey The Sick Man of Europe.
What were the causes
of Turkey's illness
and what measure was the Russian
Tsar prescribing for its recovery?"
I can't read, Mr Molesley.
Mr Barrow has been trying
to teach me to read,
but I'm too stupid to learn.
- Don't say that.
- So there we have it.
I am a fool who knows nothing.
lam nothing.
MAN [OVER PA]: The race is going
harder now because the lead car,
car number six,
driven by Sir Patrick Axioms',
has withdrawn
with what looks like radiator trouble.
Oh, dear. it Rooks like Sir Patrick
has blown a gasket too.
Here they come again.
But don't you envy them?
- Heh, no, I don't.
- Nor me.
Clearly we're going to have
to keep an eye on Tom.
[CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
But there is something gallant
and daring in it.
Even I can see that.
Andy.
Maybe I can help, if you'd like me to?
That's very kind.
What do you say, Andy?
I’ve tried and tried with Mr Barrow,
and I'm not able to break through.
- I'm too stupid.
- Will you stop saying that?
You're not stupid. And I promise you,
I can soon have you reading
for pleasure
if you'll come two or three times
a week after school closes.
- Could you manage?
- Best time for me.
- It won't take long.
- We can go on with--
Actually, Mr Barrow,
it might be better if you step back.
You've been generous,
but I wouldn't want to confuse Andy
- with different methods.
- No. Of course not.
Well, I hate to out this short,
but Daisy's got work to do
and she better get started.
- Do you need help?
- I can manage, heh.
- Well. Good luck, Daisy.
- Yes, good luck.
Funny when the house is empty,
above decks and below.
All the more reason for us
to be vigilant.
- Let's sit down.
- Um, I don't know.
Oh, just for a moment.
There. That's nice, isn't it'?
They don't live badly.
You have to concede.
They live as they are supposed to live.
It has its burdens and its benefits.
Better than a life of just burden.
I hope you're ready for tonight.
For once, we can eat when civilised
people eat, so don't be late back.
Are you sure you know
how to cook it?
Don't you worry.
I’ve been through every detail
with Mrs Patmore.
Hello?
What have we here?
Can anyone join in?
No, Mr Barrow. They cannot.
MAN [OVER PA]: It's shaping up to be a tight battle.
But what's this?
Corvell's Bentley is slowing dam.
It's pulled into the side. Looks like
steering trouble. There goes Rogers.
Charlie Rogers has taken the lead
and now look,
Henry Talbot is going to
try to snatch that lead away.
He's already overturned a Viper,
here he comes!
Talbot attacking,
challenging for the lead.
I don't think Rogers' machine
can fight him OK. Goodness me!
I think he's upped his gear change.
Look, Rogers is caning hack at him.
He's going to take back the lead!
What a stunning piece of driving
by Charles Rogers!
Here they come again,
it's the two Bentley's,
and they fight, neck and neck
past the grandstand, some on'.!
[CHEERING AND APPLAUDING]
Come on!
Chin up. It won't be long now.
Really? It feels as if we're trapped
in some witch's curse for all eternity.
[TYRES SCREECHING
AND CARS CRASHING]
ANNOUNCER: Oh, my God.
This is terrible! This is awful!
- Stay here. Bertie, come with me.
- Of course.
[CHATTERING]
No. It's no good. I can't stay.
You're not going anywhere.
- I must go.
- No, no, Anna.
- Not in your condition.
- I have to go.
- Can you follow her, please?
- Of course.
MAN 1:
Get him out of there!
- Charlie!
MAN 2: Come on!
MAN 3:
Can anyone see him?
Get him out! Charlie!
BERTIE: It's too late!
Henry, get back!
BERTIE: Get back!
TOM: Henry! Henry!
HENRY: Charlie!
- He's gone, Henry!
HENRY:
No! Charlie!
TOM:
It's too late.
HENRY:
Charlie!
TOM:
He's gone.
HENRY:
We have to help him. Charlie!
- Charlie!
MARY: Let me pass!
I know him! Let me pass!
You can't say that.
We don't know ifs him.
- Oh, my God!
- I need help here!
Who is it? Can we find out who it is'?
Tom! Bertie! Who is it'?
[PANTING]
I’m afraid it's Charlie Rogers.
He was my friend.
My best friend, really,
if that phrase didn't sound like
something from a Rider Haggard novel.
I keep asking myself if I
- encouraged him.
- Of course you encouraged him,
- and he encouraged you.
- Yes, but I was so stupid.
I needled him and I teased him,
I pushed him.
And he did the same.
If you died instead of him,
he'd be here asking
the same questions.
Yes, but I didn't die and he did.
Sorry.
We're going now.
Aunt Rosamund doesn't want
to cancel dinner tonight.
She thinks we should all be together
on a day like today.
I can't. I have to deal
with Charlie's family.
Of course. I wasn't thinking.
Tell her thank you.
- And, Mary--
- No.
Let's not do any of that stuff now.
Go on, then. Put us out of our misery.
Did he pass or not?
Mr Molesley.
I'd be very glad if you would join
the teaching staff at the village school.
I’ll be...
Good of you to come up tonight
to tell me.
- Does that mean you'll be a teacher'?
DAISY: When will you leave?
Give him a moment.
There's a lot to be settled.
- Of course there is.
- I'm impressed, Mr Molesley.
There are Oxford and Cambridge
graduates who know less than you do.
You should be proud.
Good night.
Mr Dawes.
Thank you very much.
Well done, Mr Molesley.
- It'll be you next.
- I doubt it, but thanks.
We should celebrate.
Come into the kitchen.
There's a bottle of wine there
and Mr Carson wouldn't mind.
Is that the end of service for you?
Service is ending for most of us, Daisy.
- I've just got a head start.
- Will you miss it?
Oh, let's face it,
I’m never going to make butler.
Well, not in a proper house
like this one.
There's gonna be more
and more people
chasing fewer and fewer jobs.
So it's probably time, and this seemed
like a good way to go.
- Well, I'm glad. You deserve it.
- Ha, ha.
I never think I deserve anything.
Perhaps I've been wrong all along.
- Are you coming, Mr Barrow?
- In a minute. You go ahead.
[CHATTERING]
PATMORE: You like red wine?
Well, here you are, take it.
Andy, want one?
Have a glass of wine.
WOMAN:
Congratulations.
But how did you do it?
I must have stumbled and fallen over
in the wrong way.
Mrs Patmore put on a bandage.
I'll go to the doctor if it's no better.
- But how are you going to cook?
- I can't cook.
I can't lift.
It's not difficult.
I'll talk you through it. Don't worry.
You mean,
I’m going to cook?
It's very straightforward.
Now, get the chicken in the oven
right away.
Peel the potatoes,
prepare the cauliflower.
Oh, and put a kettle on, to boil.
You should find bread and an onion
for the bread sauce.
Butter and milk are
in the meat safe outside.
I assume that none of us
are going to eat anything else?
One talks of risk and danger
and it sounds like fun,
but of course the reality behind it is,
sudden death.
Sudden, stupid, wasteful death.
It was a bloody awful business.
A bloody, bloody awful business.
- English language never lets you down.
- Oh, shut up.
Shall we go through?
- You're going to bed.
- Me too.
[PHONE RINGING]
The rest of you can talk
into the small hours.
Should I say goodbye?
Not yet.
Come into the drawing room
for a drink.
Henry's on the telephone.
Tell him to ring tomorrow.
I think you should speak to him.
MARY [OVER PHONE]:
You should try to sleep.
I found that I had to
hear your voice first.
We truth is,
I won't sleep until I know
where we're headed.
Henry, please,
let's not do this now.
Think of Charlie, not us.
Hear me out. Charlie would have.
Because his death has made me realise
we don't have a minute to waste,
you and I. This is my Carpe Diem,
and that I, I must seize the day--
No.
- What do you mean?
- Sorry, I wouldn't have said this now,
but today has made me
realise something too.
We're not meant
to be together, Henry.
- We're not right.
- I can--
Don't start saying you'll give up racing.
I don't want you to give up anything.
- Except me.
- I can't give you up.
Please, I wish you nothing but good.
I want you to have along
and happy life.
- Just not with me.
- Mary, please don't do this.
I must.
Good night, Henry.
I wish you wouldn't.
[WHIMPERING]
Do you know the worst thing?
When they said it was Charlie
and not Henry who was dead, I was glad.
Think of that. I was glad.
You're not seeing straight.
Today brought up Matthews death.
You're in a black mist--
- It's not what I want.
- You're frightened of being hurt again,
but let me tell you this,
you will be hurt again and so will I,
because being hurt
is part of being alive.
But that is no reason to give up
on the man who's right for you.
I’m sorry I'm a bit behind.
- The potatoes may have caught.
- Never mind.
- Uh, how's the cauliflower'?
- Ugh. Oh, my God.
- Ah!
- Oh, while you're there,
put in the apple crumble.
Bottom oven.
I think it's been a good day.
The funny thing is,
I quite enjoyed it in the end.
I’m glad it's turned out well
for Mr Molesley.
- And Andy. I think that'll turn out well.
- I suppose so.
Even if he only wants to read to learn
more about farming from Mr Mason.
And if he does? You must share, Daisy.
Love isn't finite.
If Mr Mason makes new friends,
it doesn't mean he has
any less love for you.
Doesn't it?
I’ve never had much
that was my own, you know.
Well, you've found
the love of a father there,
and you can count on him,
just as you can count on me.
Now, run along and I'll finish this.
Mm. This crumble's good.
My mother's was always a bit soggy.
Oh, crumble. Oh.
Is that it, now? Are we done?
Put the things in to soak.
Cover the pots with water.
You don't have to wash
until tomorrow if you don't want to.
- You won't be better by the morning?
- Oh, not for that.
We could ask Billy to come over,
but he's got his own work to do.
You don't mind, do you?
Ugh, no.
I don't mind.
I expect you're glad to get to bed.
I know I am.
What is it?
I just wondered if I was right,
that you're to be congratulated.
It's a bit early to shout about it,
but yes.
I’m happy for you.
It's good to think of a new life coming.
Especially on a day like this.
- Well, good night.
- Heh.
Look at you, stretched out like a Pasha.
A creature of leisure.
Early night for me. He went to bed
when he left the dining room.
- Not for me. She's very shaken.
- By the crash?
Because of the crash,
and she's broken up with Mr Talbot.
It wasn't the right night
to make that decision.
Mm, she says she's sure.
- Do you think she's right?
- I don't know.
Probably.
Then there's no more to be said.
[SIGHs]
I’m afraid I’ve got to go.
You've been such a help.
It's odd, isn't it?
We witnessed a tragedy today,
but sitting here,
with your arm around me,
I can't remember
feeling so comfortable.
Heh. When you say things like that,
you make me so happy.
If it isn't wrong to feel happy,
on a day like this.
I don't believe it's ever wrong
to feel happy and confident
- in someone else's company.
- Do I make you feel those things?
It's not a trap.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Today has been sad and wretched,
and having you here
has helped me face it. That's all.
The thing is, I'd like to be trapped and,
well, I'd better just say it.
- I want to marry you.
- Oh.
- You're not offended?
- Offended?
Why would I be offended? I’m thrilled.
I'm delighted.
I’m just rather surprised.
Why? You know I'm mad about you.
I don't ever think I'm the sort of girl
men are mad about.
Then you're wrong. Because I am.
I know I've not got much to offer,
and your father is probably hoping
for more than a penniless land agent,
but if love is allowed to weigh
in the balance, I've got plenty of that.
I must ask you something.
Would you let me bring Marigold
with me?
Marigold?
Your family's ward?
You see, I'm much fonder of her
than anyone else,
and I'd hate to leave her behind.
If she means that much to you.
I hope we'll have children of our own
before close of play.
Oh, absolutely. I'd like that loo.
Does that mean you accept?
Not quite.
I’ll have to think about it.
I'm sorry to be a kill-joy, but I must.
Be my guest. I’m not going
to marry anyone else.
Not until after you've
broken my heart, anyway.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
I’ll go.
Kiss me first.
And I promise I won't keep you
waiting too long.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Let's see what you make of that, heh.
I must be off, but my niece, Lucy, is in
the kitchen. She'll see to everything.
- Thank you.
ROBERT:
Hello, Carson.
Mrs Crawley is in the library, my lord.
- She's been here for some time.
- Why?
She didn't say, but she seems eager
to see you all.
Also, uh, Mr Spratt rang to ask
when you'd be arriving from London.
- Mr Spratt?
- The Dowager Countess's butler.
Oh, that Mr Spratt.
What did he want?
Again, no explanation was proffered.
Curiouser and curiouser.
Isobel, I hope we haven't kept you
waiting for hours.
Not at all. It's entirely my fault,
I got here far too early.
- How was it?
- Terrible, as it happens,
- but let's not go into that now.
ISOBEL: I am sorry.
And, to be quite honest,
- I feel rather awkward.
- Why? What is it?
I’ve a letter from Cousin Violet.
- Why didn't she bring it?
- Because she's gone away.
Gone away? Where?
She is on board to the Paris,
headed for the Mediterranean.
This is me, isn’t it? I've done it.
Shes furious with me.
I don't see the point
of bringing that up now.
- What does it say in the letter?
- Nothing much.
She needs a change of air and Spratt
is bringing a present by way of goodbye.
That's why he rang.
- Mr Spratt has arrived, my lord.
- Show him in.
Well, that is, he's in the servants' hall
with a, uh, present for your lordship
and he doesn't want to bring it here.
- What is going on?
- He may be right, my lord.
- Let's go and see.
ROBERT: If you wish.
But it all seems very rum to me.
What is it? What's the surprise?
You'll soon see, mi'lord,
but I think it's a good one.
- Good day, mi'lord.
- Spratt.
What is this secret
you're to reveal?
Her Ladyship chose her herself,
mi'lord.
She was most particular.
Ah! Hello, little one. Oh!
[CHUCKLING]
Now, what are we going
to call you?
CORA: Oh, hello.
- Oh, I know, Teo.
I thought we always had names
from Ancient Egypt.
Teo was a wife of Amenhotep the 2nd
and the mother of Tuthmosis the 4th.
- Don't you know?
SPRATT: She's not exactly trained yet.
We decided against bringing her up.
Oh, I don't care about that.
You're coming upstairs with me.
- He does love his dogs.
- Mm.
How were your guests this morning?
- Was everything satisfactory?
- Oh, very.
He was a doctor, Mrs Hughes.
Imagine that.
So I don't think I could have
started better.
Even if I worked harder
on their breakfast
than anything I've done
since Lady Rose got married.
Oh, talking of which,
has Mr Carson survived his ordeal
from last night?
Put it this way,
he has discovered a new respect
for the role of cook and bottle-washer,
so I think he'll be giving less trouble
in the future.
[BOTH LAUGHING]
What's so funny?
Just life, Mr Carson.
Just life.