( Theme music playing )
♪ Game of Thrones 1x06 ♪
A Golden Crow
Original Air Date on May 22, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
( Gulls cawing )
Your pardon, Your Grace.
I would rise, but...
Cersei: Do you know what
your wife has done?
She did nothing
I did not command.
Who'd have thought
she had it in her?
By what right dare you lay
hands on my blood?
I am the King's Hand, charged
with keeping the peace...
You were the King's Hand.
You shall now be held
accountable.
Oh, will both of you
shut your mouths?!
Catelyn will release Tyrion and
you'll make your peace with Jaime.
He butchered my men--
Lord Stark was
returning drunk
from a brothel
when his men attacked Jaime.
- Quiet, woman.
- Jaime has fled the city.
Give me leave to bring him
back to justice.
I took you for a King.
- Hold your tongue.
- He's attacked
one of my brothers
and abducted the other.
I should wear the armor
and you the gown.
I shall wear this
like a badge of honor.
Wear it in silence
or I'll honor you again.
( Door slams )
See what she does to me?
My loving wife.
I should not have
hit her.
That was not...
That was not Kingly.
If we don't act,
there will be a war.
So tell your wife to return
that little shit of an Imp
to King's Landing.
She's had her fun,
now put an end to it.
You hear me?
Send a raven and put an end to it.
And what about
Jaime Lannister?
- What about Jaime?
- I'm half a Kingdom in debt
to his bloody father.
I don't know what happened between
you and those yellow-haired shits.
I don't want to know.
This is what matters--
I can't rule the Kingdoms
if the Starks and the Lannisters
are at each other's throats.
So enough.
As you command,
Your Grace.
With your leave,
I will return to Winterfell
and set matters straight.
Piss on that.
Send a raven.
I want you to stay.
I'm the King.
I get what I want.
I never loved my brothers.
A sad thing for a man
to admit, but it's true.
You were the brother
I chose.
We'll talk when I return
from the hunt.
The hunt?
Killing things
clears my head.
You'll have to sit on the
throne while I'm away.
( Chuckles )
You'll hate it more than I do.
The Targaryen girl--
seven hells,
don't start with her again.
The girl will die
and I'll hear no more of it.
Put on the badge.
And if you ever take it off again,
I swear to the mother I'll pin the
damned thing on Jaime Lannister.
( Door slams )
( Distant horse whinnies )
Khaleesi?
Oh, Khaleesi!
You're hurt.
( Raven squawks )
( Squawks )
( Pounding footsteps,
door slams )
( Bran yelling joyously )
- Not too fast.
- Come on, Dancer.
When are you gonna
tell him?
Not now.
- Blood for blood.
- Bran: Come on!
You need to make the Lannisters
pay for Jory and the others.
- Robb: You're talking about war.
- I'm talking about justice.
- ( Bran cheers )
- Only the Lord of Winterfell
can call in the bannermen
and raise an army.
A Lannister put his spear
through your father's leg.
The Kingslayer rides for Casterly Rock
where no one can touch him--
you want me to march
on Casterly Rock?
- You're not a boy anymore.
- Bran: Come on.
They attacked your father.
They've already started the war.
It's your duty to represent your
House when your father can't.
And it's not your duty,
because it's not your House.
( Birds chirping )
Where's Bran?
I don't know.
It's not my House.
( Horse nickering )
( Whinnies )
Robb?
All alone in the deep,
dark woods.
I'm not alone.
My brother is with me.
I don't see him.
Got him hidden
under your cloak?
Ooh, that's a pretty pin.
- Silver.
- We'll take the pin
and the horse.
Get down.
Be quick about it.
I can't.
The saddle--
the straps.
What's wrong with you?
You some kind of cripple?
I'm Brandon Stark
of Winterfell.
If you don't let me be,
I'll have you all killed!
Cut his little cock off
and stuff it in his mouth.
The boy's
worth nothing dead.
Benjen Stark's
own blood?
Think what Mance
would give us.
Piss on Mance Rayder
and piss on the North.
We're going as far South
as South goes.
There ain't no White Walkers
down in Dorne.
Robb:
Drop the knife!
- Let him go and I'll let you live.
- ( Hisses )
( Yells )
( Grunting )
Robb.
- Robb.
- Shut up.
Drop the blade!
- No, don't.
- Do it.
( Arrow thunks )
Are you all right?
Yes.
It doesn't hurt.
Tough little lad.
In the Iron Islands, you're not a man
until you've killed your first enemy.
Well done.
Have you lost your mind?
What if you'd missed?
He would have killed you
and cut Bran's throat.
- You don't have the right--
- To what, to save your brother's life?
It was the only thing
to do, so I did it.
What about her?
( Gasping ) Give me my life,
My Lord, and I'm yours.
We'll keep her alive.
( Sigh of relief )
( Wind blowing )
Mord!
Turnkey!
( Jangling )
Dwarf man
making noise!
How would you like
to be rich?
Dwarf man still
making noise.
My family is rich.
We have gold,
lots of gold.
I'm prepared to give you
lots of gold in--
No gold!
Well, I don't
have it here.
No gold.
( Grunts )
Fuck off.
( Door slams )
I don't want
to practice today.
No?
They killed Jory.
My father is hurt.
I don't care about
stupid wooden swords.
You are troubled.
- Yes.
- Good!
Trouble is the perfect
time for training.
When you are dancing in the meadow
with your dolls and kittens,
this is not
when fighting happens.
I don't like
dolls and k--
You're not here.
You're with
your trouble.
If you are with your trouble
when fighting happens--
( gasps )
--More trouble for you.
( Tisks )
Just so.
How can you be
quick as a snake...
...Or as quiet
as a shadow...
...When you are
somewhere else?
You are fearing
for your father, hmm?
That is right.
- Do you pray to the gods?
- The old and the new.
There is only one God
and his name is Death.
And there is only one thing
we say to Death:
"Not today."
( Dothraki chanting )
Rakh! Rakh! Rakh haj!
- Priestess: Khalakka Dothrae!
- Rakh! Rakh! Rakh haj!
- Khalakka Dothrae!
( Chanting continues )
She has to eat
the whole heart?
I hope that wasn't
my horse.
She's doing well.
She'll never
keep it down.
( Chanting continues )
Rakh! Rakh! Rakh haj!
Khalakka Dothrae!
Tell me what she's saying.
"The prince is riding.
I have heard the thunder
of his hooves.
Swift as the wind he rides.
His enemies
will cower before him...
And their wives will
weep tears of blood."
She's going
to have a boy.
He won't be
a real Targaryen.
a true Dragon.
( Gags )
- ( Chanting stops )
- ( Daenerys sobs )
( Sobs )
( Gulps )
Vezh fin saja
rhaesheseres!
"The stallion
who mounts the world."
The stallion is
the Khal of Khals.
He shall unite the people
into a single Khalasar.
All the people of the world
will be his herd.
...Rhaesheseres!
Rhaesheseres!
( Speaking Dothraki )
( Chanting )
Rhaego! Rhaego!
Rhaego!
Rhaego...
They love her.
Rhaego! Rhaego!
Rhaego!
Rhaego...
She truly is
a queen today.
( Sighs )
Don't let them see you
carrying a sword in Vaes Dothrak.
You know the law.
It's not my law.
They don't belong to you.
Whatever is hers
is also mine.
Once, perhaps.
If I sell one egg,
I'll have enough to buy a ship.
Two eggs-- a ship
and an army.
- And you have all three.
- I need a large army.
I'm the last hope
of a dynasty, Mormont.
The greatest dynasty
this world has ever seen
on my shoulders since
I was five years old--
and no one has ever given me
what they gave to her in that tent.
Never.
Not a piece of it.
How can I carry
what I need to carry without it?
Hmm?
Who can rule without wealth
or fear or love?
Oh, you stand there,
all nobility and honor.
You don't think I see you looking
at my little sister, hmm?
Don't think I know
what you want?
I don't care.
You can have her.
She can be Queen
of the savages and dine
on the finest
bloody horseparts,
and you can dine on whichever
parts of her you like.
But let me go.
You can go.
You can't have the eggs.
You swore
an oath to me.
Does loyalty
mean nothing to you?
It means everything to me.
And yet here you stand.
And yet here I stand.
- ( Wind roaring )
- Mord!
Mord!
Mord.
Noise again!
- About the gold...
- No gold!
- No gold.
- Listen to me!
Listen to me.
Sometimes possession
is an abstract concept--
( groans )
When they captured me,
they took my purse,
but the gold
is still mine.
Where?
I don't know where,
but when they free me--
You want free?
Go be free.
Have you ever
heard the phrase
"rich as a Lannister"?
Of course you have!
You're a smart man.
You know who
the Lannisters are.
I am a Lannister.
Tyrion, son of Tywin!
And of course,
you have also heard the phrase,
"a Lannister always
pays his debts."
If you deliver
a message from me...
to Lady Arryn,
I will be in your debt.
I will owe you gold.
If you deliver
the message
and I live, which I very much
intend to do.
What message?
Tell her I wish
to confess my crimes.
( Metal tapping,
courtiers murmuring )
You wish to confess
your crimes?
Yes, My Lady.
I do, My Lady.
The sky cells
always break them.
Speak, Imp.
Meet your gods
as an honest man.
Where do I begin,
my lords and ladies?
I'm a vile man,
I confess it.
My crimes and sins
are beyond counting.
I have lied
and cheated...
gambled and whored.
I'm not particularly
good at violence,
but I'm good at convincing
others to do violence for me.
You want specifics,
I suppose.
When I was seven
I saw a servant girl
bathing in the river.
I stole her robe.
She was forced to return
to the castle
naked and in tears.
If I close my eyes,
- I can still see her tits bouncing.
- ( Gasps )
When I was 10 I stuffed
my Uncle's boots with goatshit.
When confronted
with my crime,
I blamed a squire.
Poor boy was flogged
and I escaped justice.
When I was 12
I milked my eel
into a pot of turtle stew.
- ( Gasps )
- I flogged the one-eyed snake.
I skinned my sausage.
I made the bald man cry
into the turtle stew,
which I do believe
my sister ate.
At least I hope she did.
Once I brought a jackass
and a honeycomb
- into a brothel--
- Silence!
What happened next?
What do you think
you're doing?
Confessing my crimes.
Lord Tyrion,
you are accused
of hiring a man to slay
my son Bran in his bed,
and of conspiring to murder
my sister's husband
Lord Jon Arryn,
the Hand of the King.
Oh, I'm very sorry.
I don't know anything
about all that.
You've had
your little joke.
I trust you enjoyed it.
Mord, take him back
to the dungeon.
But this time find
a smaller cell...
With a steeper floor.
Is this how justice
is done in the Vale?
You accuse me
of crimes,
I deny them,
so you throw me into a cell
to freeze and starve?
Where is
the King's Justice?
I am accused
and demand a trial!
( Courtiers murmuring )
If you're tried
and found guilty,
then by the King's own laws
you will pay with your life.
I understand the law.
We have no executioner
in the Eyrie.
Life is more elegant here.
Open the moon door.
( Robin giggling )
Lysa: You want a trial,
My Lord Lannister.
Very well.
My son will listen
to whatever you have to say,
and you will hear
his judgment.
Then you will leave...
By one door
or the other.
No need to bother
Lord Robin.
- I demand a trial by combat.
- ( Laughter )
You have that right.
My Lady, I beg the honor.
Let me be your champion.
The honor should be mine.
For the love I bore
your Lord husband,
let me avenge his death.
- I'll fight for you, My Lady.
- It'll be my honor.
- The honor should be mine.
- Make the bad man fly!
Ser Vardis...
You're quiet.
Don't you want
to avenge my husband?
With all my heart,
My Lady.
But the Imp
is half my size.
It would be shameful to slaughter
such a man and call it justice.
Agreed.
You demanded
a trial by combat.
Now I demand a champion.
I have that right, same as you.
My Lady,
I will gladly fight
the Imp's champion for you.
I wouldn't be
too glad, Ser.
I name my brother
Jaime Lannister.
- ( Whispering )
- Lysa: The Kingslayer
is hundreds of miles
from here.
Send a raven for him.
I'm happy to wait.
The trial will be today.
Do I have a volunteer?
( Laughter )
- Anyone?
- ( Giggling )
Anyone?
I think we can assume
that no one is willing--
I'll stand
for the dwarf.
Lancel:
More wine, Your Grace?
- What was I saying?
- Renly: Simpler time.
It was! It was.
You're too young to remember.
Wasn't it simpler, Selmy?
- It was, Your Grace.
- The enemy was right  in the open,
vicious as you like, all but
sending you a bloody invitation.
Nothing like today.
- It sounds exhilarating.
- Exhilarating, yes.
Not as exhilarating
as those balls
and masquerades
you like to throw.
( Laughing )
You ever fuck
a Riverlands girl?
Once.
I think.
You think?
I think you'd remember.
Back in our day,
you weren't a real man
until you'd fucked one girl
from each of the Seven Kingdoms
and the Riverlands.
- We used to call it "making the eight."
- Those were some lucky girls.
You ever make
the eight, Barristan?
I don't believe so,
Your Grace.
( Laughs )
Those were the days.
Which days, exactly?
The ones where half of Westeros
fought the other half and millions died?
Or before that, when the Mad King
slaughtered women and babies
because the voices in his head
told him they deserved it?
Or way before that, when dragons
burned whole cities to the ground?
Easy, boy.
You might be my brother,
but you're speaking to the King.
I suppose it was all
rather heroic...
If you were drunk enough
and had some poor Riverlands whore
to shove your prick inside
and make the eight.
More wine, Your Grace?
Man: They burned most everything
in the Riverlands:
Our fields;
Our granaries;
our homes.
They took our women,
then they took 'em again.
When they was done,
they butchered them
as if they was animals.
They covered our children
in pitch
and lit them on fire.
Brigands, most likely.
They weren't thieves.
They didn't steal
nothing.
They even left something behind,
Your Grace.
It's the King's Hand
you're addressing, not the King.
The King is hunting.
( Squelches )
( Groans )
Fish.
The Sigil of House Tully.
( Whispers )
Isn't that your wife's house--
Tully, My Lord Hand?
These men,
were they flying a Sigil?
- A banner?
- None, your--
Hand.
The one who was
leading them...
Taller by a foot
than any man I've ever met,
saw him cut
the blacksmith in two,
saw him take the head
off a horse
with a single swing
of his sword.
That sounds like
someone we know.
The Mountain.
You're describing
Ser Gregor Clegane.
Why should Ser Gregor
turn brigand?
The man is
an anointed knight.
I've heard him called
Tywin Lannister's mad dog.
I'm sure you have
as well.
Can you think
of any reason
the Lannisters
might possibly have
for being angry
with your wife?
Maester Pycelle:
If the Lannisters
were to order attacks
on villages
under the King's
protection,
- it would be--
- That would be almost as brazen
as attacking the Hand of the King
in the streets of the capital.
Well...
I cannot give you
back your homes
or restore
your dead to life,
but perhaps I can
give you justice
in the name of our King,
Robert.
Lord Beric Dondarrion.
You shall have the command.
Assemble 100 men
- and ride to Ser Gregor's keep.
- As you command.
In the name of Robert
of the House Baratheon,
the first of his name,
King of the Andals and the first men,
Lord of the Seven Kingdoms
and protector of the realm,
I charge you to bring
the King's Justice
to the false knight
Gregor Clegane
and all those
who shared in his crimes.
I denounce him
- and attaint him.
- ( Murmuring )
I strip him of all
ranks and titles,
of all lands and holdings,
- and sentence him to death.
- My Lord...
This-- this is
a drastic action.
It would be better to wait
for King Robert's return.
- Grand Maester Pycelle.
- My Lord.
Send a raven
to Casterly Rock.
Inform Tywin Lannister that
he has been summoned to court
to answer for the crimes
of his bannermen.
He will arrive within the fortnight
or be branded an enemy of the crown
and a traitor
to the realm.
( Softly )
A bold move, My Lord,
and admirable.
But is it wise
to yank the lion's tail?
Tywin Lannister is the richest man
in all the Seven Kingdoms.
Gold wins wars,
not soldiers.
Then how come
Robert is King
and not Tywin Lannister?
( Clanking )
( Wind fight! )
- ( Crowd shouting )
- Man: Hold!
- Attack attack!
- Come on, Ser Vardis!
- Attack!
- ( Roaring )
Lysa:
Stand and fight, coward!
( Giggling )
- ( Gasps )
- Yes!
- ( Panting )
- Enough, Ser Vardis! Finish him.
( Yells )
Woman: What are you doing?
Get up!
Get up, get up,
get up!
Raise your sword.
Raise it!
( Roars )
Get up, man!
- On your feet!
- Get up!
Get up and fight,
Ser Vardis!
( Crowd shouting )
Woman:
No! Have mercy!
( Groans and gasps )
Is it over?
You don't fight
with honor!
No.
He did.
( Crowd muttering )
Can I make
the little man fly now?
Not this little man.
This little man
is going home.
I believe you have
something of mine.
( Coins jingle )
A Lannister always
pays his debts.
You wear your hair like
a real southern lady now.
Well, why shouldn't I?
We're in the South.
It's important to remember where
you come from.
I'm not sure your mother would
like these new styles.
My mother isn't
from the North.
I'm aware of that.
Why do you care?
Do you even have hair
under there?
Yes.
I have hair.
I've never seen it.
Would you like to?
No.
Where are you from anyway?
The North or the South?
I come from a very
small village in--
Oh, wait.
I just realized
I don't care.
- Sansa--
- Septa.
- ( Door closes )
- Now you are being rude.
Septa:
My prince.
My Lady.
I fear I have
behaved monstrously
the past few weeks.
With your permission?
It's beautiful,
like the one
your mother wears.
You'll be queen someday.
It's only fitting
you should look the part.
Will you forgive me
for my rudeness?
There's nothing to forgive.
You're My Lady.
One day we'll be married
in the throne room.
Lords and ladies from all over
the Seven Kingdoms will come,
from the last hearth
in the North
to the Salt Shore
in the South,
and you will be Queen
over all of them.
I'll never
disrespect you again.
I'll never be cruel
to you again.
Do you understand me?
You're My Lady now,
from this day
until my last day.
Stop.
- Stop!
- Whoa.
- What are you doing?
- Going to King's Landing.
In a turnip cart?
I'll find a ship heading
south in White Harbor.
And you can afford that?
Some of my friends are more
generous than others.
There's a thousand
girls like you in King's Landing.
So I'll have
lots of company.
Yes, you'll be
very popular...
Until some fat lord
comes to visit
with a big belly
and a little prick
and he can't get it up
so he knocks all your teeth out.
( Chuckles )
And what will happen
to me if I stay here?
Will I become
Lady Greyjoy,
- mistress of the Iron Islands?
- Don't be a fool.
I hear Jaime Lannister
attacked Lord Stark
in the streets
of King's Landing.
Every man for a hundred miles will be
marching off to war soon
and most of them
will never come back.
There's nothing left
for me here.
Let's go, Stefon.
Giddyup.
Let me see it
one more time!
See what?
( Coin clinks )
( Laughs )
I'm going to miss you.
I know.
I'm sending you both
back to Winterfell.
- What?!
- Listen--
- What about Joffrey?
- Are you dying because of your leg?
Is that why
you're sending us home?
What? No.
Please, father.
Please don't.
You can't.
I've got my lessons with Syrio.
I'm finally
getting good.
This isn't
a punishment.
I want you back in Winterfell
for your own safety.
Can we take Syrio
back with us?
Who cares about your
stupid dancing teacher?
I can't go.
I'm supposed to marry
Prince Joffrey.
I love him and I'm meant
to be his Queen
- and have his babies.
- Seven hells.
When you're old enough,
I'll make you a match
with someone who's worthy of you,
someone who's brave
and gentle and strong--
I don't want someone brave
and gentle and strong. I want him!
He'll be the greatest
King that ever was, a golden lion,
and I'll give him
sons with beautiful blond hair.
Arya: The lion'sot
s Sigil, idiot.
He's a stag,
like his father.
He is not.
He's nothing like that old drunk King.
Go on, girls. Get your Septa and start
packing your things.
- Wait!
- Come on.
But it's not fair!
( Door slams )
"Lord Orys Baratheon,
black of hair."
"Axel Baratheon,
"Lyonel Baratheon,
black of hair."
"Steffon Baratheon,
"Robert Baratheon,
black of hair."
"Joffrey Baratheon...
Golden-haired."
( Drums playing,
laughter )
Daenerys!
( Drunkenly )
Where's my sister?
Stop him.
( High-pitched )
Where is she?
Hmm?
I'm here for the feast.
- The whore's feast?
- Come.
Get your hands off me!
No one touches
the Dragon!
Khal rhae mhar!
- Me ifa!
- ( Laughing )
Khal Drogo!
I'm here for the feast.
Nevakhi vekha ha maan.
Khal Drogo says
there is a place for you.
Back there.
That is no place
for a King.
You are no King.
- Keep away from me!
- ( Drums stop )
Viserys, please.
( Dothraki hissing )
There she is.
Put the sword down.
They'll kill us all.
They can't kill us.
( Chuckles )
They can't shed blood
in their sacred city.
( Gasps )
But I can.
I want what I came for.
I want the crown
he promised me.
- He bought you.
- ( Irri translating )
But he never
paid for you.
Tell him I want what was bargained
for or I'm taking you back.
He can keep the baby.
I'll cut it out
and leave it for him.
Anha vazhak maan
rek me zala.
firikhnharen hoshora
ma mahrazhi aqovi
affin mori atihi mae!
What's he saying?
He says yes.
You shall have
a golden crown...
That men shall tremble
to behold.
That was all I wanted.
What-what was promised.
( Chuckles )
Qora mae.
- ( Bone cracks )
- ( Screams ) No!
No!
You cannot touch me.
I am the Dragon.
I am the Dragon!
I want my crown!
Ahh!
- ( Screaming )
- Ammeni haz jolin!
- Look away, Khaleesi.
- No.
Viserys:
No, dany.
Dany, tell them.
Make them!
Dany, make them...
No, you can't!
Just-- please!
Dany, please!
A crown for a King.
( Screaming )
( Thunks )
Khaleesi?
He was no Dragon.
Fire cannot kill a Dragon.
( Theme music playing )
== sync, corrected by elderman ==