Game of Thrones 1x07
The Pointy End
Original Air Date on June 5, 2011
Yah!
Left high, left low.
Right low, lunge right.
You break anything,
the Septa will have my head.
What is...
Your sister knew perfectly
well we were to leave today.
- How she could forget...
- She didn't forget.
She's with her dancing master.
She's with him every morning.
She always comes back with scrapes
and bruises. She's so clumsy.
Hush!
Go back to your room.
Bar the doors
and do not open them for anyone
you do not know.
- What is it? What's happening?
- Do as I told you.
Run!
This way!
Left, right.
Rah!
Now you are dead.
You said right,
but you went left.
And now you are a dead girl.
Only 'cause you lied.
My tongue lied.
My eyes
shouted the truth.
You were not seeing.
I was so.
I watched, but you...
Watching is not seeing,
dead girl.
The seeing, the true seeing,
that is the heart of swordplay.
Arya Stark, come with us.
Your father wants to see you.
And why is it
that Lord Eddard is
sending Lannister men
in place of his own?
I am wondering.
Mind your place,
dancing master.
This is no concern of yours.
My father wouldn't send you.
And I don't have to go
with you if I don't want.
Take her.
Are you men or snakes, that you
would threaten a child?
Get out of my way, little man.
I am Syrio Forel...
Foreign bastard.
...And you will be speaking
to me with more respect.
Kill the Braavosi.
Bring the girl.
Arya child, we are done
with dancing for the day.
Run to your father.
Bloody oafs.
Be gone now, Arya.
Come with me.
Run.
The First Sword of Braavos
does not run.
What do we say
to the God of Death?
Not today.
Go.
Stay away from me.
I'll tell my father.
I'll... I'll tell the Queen.
Who do you think sent me?
Needle.
There she is.
- What do you want?
- I want you, wolf girl.
- Come here.
- Leave me be.
My father's a lord.
He'll reward you.
She'll reward me...
the Queen!
Stay away!
Lord Stark,
you must be thirsty.
Varys.
I promise you
it isn't poisoned.
Why is it no one ever
trusts the eunuch?
Not so much, My Lord.
I would save the rest,
if I were you.
Hide it. Men have been known to die
of thirst in these cells.
What about my daughters?
The younger one seems
to have escaped the castle.
Even my little birds
cannot find her.
- And Sansa?
- Still engaged to Joffrey.
Cersei will keep her close. The rest
of your household though...
all dead, it grieves me to say.
I do so hate
the sight of blood.
You watched my men being
slaughtered and did nothing.
And would again, My Lord.
I was unarmed, unarmored and
surrounded by Lannister swords.
When you look at me
do you see a hero?
What madness led you
to tell the Queen
you had learned the truth
about Joffrey's birth?
The madness of mercy.
That she might
save her children.
Ah, the children.
It is always
the innocents who suffer.
It wasn't the wine that killed Robert,
nor the boar.
The wine slowed him down
and the boar ripped him open,
but it was your mercy
that killed the King.
I trust you know you are
a dead man, Lord Eddard?
The Queen can't kill me.
Cat holds her brother.
The wrong brother sadly.
And lost to her.
Your wife has let the Imp
slip through her fingers.
If that's true,
then slit my throat
and be done with it.
Not today, My Lord.
Tell me something, Varys.
Who do you truly serve?
The Realm, My Lord.
Someone must.
It's Othor, without a doubt.
The other one is
Jafer Flowers, My Lord,
less the hand
the wolf tore off.
Any sign of Benjen
or the rest of his party?
Just these two, My Lord.
Been dead awhile, I'd say.
- Mmm.
- The smell.
What smell?
There is none.
If they'd be dead for a long time,
wouldn't there be rot?
We should burn them.
Snow's not wrong, My Lord.
Fire will do for them.
The wildling way.
I want Maester Aemon
to examine them first.
You may be a coward, Tarly,
but you're not stupid.
- Get them inside.
- You heard him.
Lord Commander,
Maester Aemon awaits you
in his chambers...
A raven from King's Landing.
Come on, move 'em out.
Bring me a horn of ale, Snow,
and pour one for yourself.
The King is dead.
Is there any word of my father?
Sit.
Lord Stark has been
charged with treason.
They say he conspired
with Robert's brothers
to deny the throne
to Prince Joffrey.
I hope you're not thinking
of doing anything stupid.
Your duty lies here now.
My sisters were
in King's Landing too.
I'm sure they'll be
treated gently.
Your father has proved to be
an awful traitor, dear.
King Robert's body
was still warm
when Lord Eddard began plotting
to steal Joffrey's rightful throne.
He wouldn't do that.
He knows how much I love Joffrey.
He wouldn't.
Please, Your Grace,
there's been a mistake.
Send for my father. He'll tell you...
the King was his friend.
Sansa sweetling, you are innocent of
any wrong. We know that.
Yet you are the daughter
of a traitor.
How can I allow you
to marry my son?
A child born
of a traitor's seed
is no fit consort for our King.
She is a sweet thing now,
Your Grace,
but in 10 years who knows
what treasons she may hatch?
No, I'm not. I'll be a good wife
to him, you'll see.
I'll be a Queen just like you,
I promise. I won't hatch anything.
The girl is innocent,
Your Grace.
She should be given a chance
to prove her loyalty.
Little dove, you must
write to Lady Catelyn
and your brother,
the eldest, what's his name?
Robb.
Word of your father's arrest
will reach him soon, no doubt.
Best it comes from you.
If you would help your father,
urge your brother
to keep the King's peace.
Tell him to come to King's Landing
and swear his fealty to Joffrey.
If... if I could see my father,
talk to him about...
You disappoint me, child.
We have told you
of your father's treason.
Why would you want
to speak to a traitor?
I only meant that...
What will happen to him?
- That depends.
- On... on what?
On your brother.
And on you.
Treason?
Sansa wrote this?
It is your sister's hand,
but the Queen's words.
You are summoned to King's Landing
to swear fealty to the new king.
Joffrey puts my father in chains,
now he wants his ass kissed?
This is a royal
command, My Lord.
- If you should refuse to obey...
- I won't refuse.
His Grace summons me
to King's Landing,
I'll go to King's Landing.
But not alone.
Call the banners.
All of them, My Lord?
They've all sworn to defend
my father, have they not?
They have.
Now we see what
their words are worth.
Yeah.
Are you afraid?
I must be.
Good.
Why is that good?
It means you're not stupid.
You've had this since dawn?
He sent it to me, not you.
I've only shown it
to you as a courtesy.
A courtesy?!
My husband has been
taken prisoner.
My son intends to declare war.
A war?
Your son against
the Lannisters?
You should go to him.
Teach him patience.
Ned rots in a dungeon
and you speak of patience?
He is your brother by law!
Does family mean
nothing to you?
Family means everything to me.
And I will not
risk Robin's life
to get caught up in another
of your husband's wars.
- I'm hungry.
- Hush now, darling.
You just ate.
You will not support us then?
Do I understand you correctly?
- But I'm hungry!
- Soon, love, soon.
You're always
welcome here, sister.
But if you're asking me to send men
from the Vale to fight...
That is what I ask.
Go on, sweet.
Time for your bath.
I'll feed you after.
If you fear for the safety
of your son...
Of course I fear
for the safety of my son!
Are you an idiot?
They killed my husband.
You say they shoved
your boy from a window.
These people will do anything.
And that is why
we have to stop them.
The knights of the Vale
will stay in the Vale
where they belong,
to protect their Lord.
Will you shut up?
There's hill tribes
all around here.
If I'm going to die,
it may as well be
with a song in my heart.
I should just take your food
and leave you here.
Eh? What would
you do then?
Starve, most likely.
You don't think
I'd do it, do you?
What do you want, Bronn?
Gold? Women?
Golden women?
Stick with me
and you'll have them all,
for as long as I'm around
and not for a moment longer.
But you knew that.
That is why you so valiantly took
up arms to defend my honor.
Fair enough.
But don't go looking
for me to bend the knee
and "My Lord" you
every time you take a shit.
I'm not your toady
and I'm not your friend.
Though I would treasure
your friendship,
I'm mainly interested
in your facility with murder.
And if the day ever comes when
you're tempted to sell me out,
remember this:
Whatever their price,
I'll beat it.
I like living.
Tyrion.
Come, share our fire.
Help yourselves to our goat.
When you meet your Gods,
you tell them
Shagga Son of Dolf
of the Stone Crows sent you.
I am Tyrion son of Tywin
of Clan Lannister.
How would you like to die,
Tyrion son of Tywin?
In my own bed, at the age of 80
with a bellyful of wine and
a girl's mouth around my cock.
Take the half man.
He can dance for the children.
Kill the other one.
No no no no no!
My... my House is rich
and powerful.
If you see us
through these mountains,
my father will
shower you with gold.
We have no use
for a half man's promises.
Half a man maybe, but at least I have
the courage to face my enemies.
What do the Stone Crows do?
Hide behind rocks and shiver
when the knights
of the Vale ride by?
Are those the best weapons
you could steal?
Good enough for killing sheep,
if the sheep don't fight back.
Lannister smiths
shit better steel.
You think you can win us over
with your trinkets?
That trinket is worth more than
everything your tribe owns.
But if you help us,
Shagga Son of Dolf,
I will not give you trinkets.
I will give you this.
What is "this"?
The Vale of Arryn.
The Lords of the Vale have always
spat upon the hill tribes.
The Lords of the Vale
want me dead.
I believe it is time
for new Lords of the Vale.
Now there's a rare sight...
not only a bastard,
but a traitor's bastard.
- Jon, no!
- Jon, stop, put it down!
Blood will always tell.
You'll hang for this, bastard.
I told you not to do
anything stupid.
You're confined
to quarters. Go.
Ghost, what's wrong?
Is something out there?
Commander?
Stay.
Hello?
Who's there?
Lord Commander?
Snow?
Commander!
Move move!
What did they do?
I thought the Dothraki
didn't believe in money.
Gold to hire ships, Princess,
ships to sail to Westeros.
Jorah, make them stop.
- Khaleesi?
- You heard me.
These men have shed blood for their Khal.
Now they claim their rewards.
Princess, you have
a gentle heart,
but this is how
it's always been.
I do not have a gentle heart, Ser.
Kash qoy qoyi thira disse.
Me qorasokh anni!
- Come.
- Anha afichak mae m'arakhoon!
What do you want
done with them?
Bring her to me.
And those women there.
You cannot claim
them all, Princess.
I can,
and I will.
Me fati!
Khaleesi vazha
anhaan qorasokh anni,
ch'anha afichak
mae m'arakhoon anni!
Me vastoe hatif anni;
ahhazaan yer nemo vacchaki.
Ohos.
Thank you, silver lady.
Who are you?
I am named Mirri Maz Duur.
I was the godswife of this temple.
My mother was godswife
here before me.
She taught me how to make
healing smokes and ointments.
All men are of one flock,
so my people believe.
The Great Shepherd sent me
to Earth to heal his...
Lamb or lion,
his wound must be
washed and sewn
or it will fester.
For 30 years
I've been making corpses
out of men, boy.
I'm the man you want
leading the vanguard.
Galbart Glover
will lead the van.
The bloody Wall will melt
before an Umber marches
behind a Glover.
I will lead the van
or I will take my men
and march them home.
You are welcome
to do so, Lord Umber.
And when I am done
with the Lannisters
I will march back north,
root you out of your keep
and hang you
for an oathbreaker.
Oathbreaker, is it?!
I'll not sit here
and swallow insults
from a boy so green
he pisses grass.
My Lord father taught me
it was death to bare steel
against your liege lord.
But doubtless the Greatjon only meant
to cut my meat for me.
Your meat...
is bloody tough.
- What is it? What's happened?
- Shh, it's all right.
- Where are you going?
- South. For father.
But it's the middle
of the night.
The Lannisters have
spies everywhere.
I don't want them
to know we're coming.
They have more men than we do.
Aye, they do.
Can't I come with you?
I can ride now.
You've seen me riding.
And I won't get
in the way, I...
There must always be
a Stark at Winterfell.
Until I return
that will be you.
You are not to leave the castle walls
while we are gone. Do you understand?
Listen to Maester Luwin.
Look after your little brother.
I will.
I'll send letters
whenever I can,
but if you don't hear from me,
don't be scared.
Until I return.
How long have you been
hiding out there?
Robb will be looking for you
to say goodbye.
They've all gone away.
They'll be back soon.
Robb will free father
and they'll come back
with mother.
No, they won't.
Please watch
over Robb.
And watch over all the
other men from Winterfell.
And Theon too, I suppose.
You hear them, boy?
The Old Gods are answering you.
What are you doing here?
They're my Gods too.
Beyond the Wall,
they're the only Gods.
Even slaves
are allowed to pray.
You're not a slave.
Well, your friend did
put a knife to my throat.
I'm not complaining,
little lord,
just telling truths.
What did you mean
about hearing the Gods?
You asked them,
they're answering you.
Shh.
Open your ears.
It's only the wind.
Who do you think sends the wind
if not the Gods?
They see you, boy.
They hear you.
Your brother will get no help
from them where he's going.
The Old Gods have
no power in the South.
The weirwoods there were
all cut down a long time ago.
How can they watch
when they have no eyes?
Well, there's a big man.
He has giants' blood
in him or I'm the Queen.
Go back and find
your clothes, Hodor.
Go dress.
Hodor.
Are there really giants
beyond the Wall?
Giants and worse than giants.
I tried telling your brother,
he's marching the wrong way.
All these swords,
they should be going north, boy.
North, not south!
The cold winds are rising.
They were touched
by White Walkers.
That's why they came back.
That's why their eyes
turned blue.
Only fire will stop them.
How do you know that?
I read about it
in a book...
a very old book
in Maester Aemon's library.
What else did the book say?
The White Walkers
sleep beneath the ice
for thousands of years.
And when they wake up...
And when they wake up, what?
I hope the Wall is high enough.
Summer snows, My Lady.
Robb's brought
the North with him.
The river lords
are falling back
with Jaime Lannister
at their heels.
And Lord Tywin is bringing around a
second Lannister army from the south.
Our scouts confirm it's even larger
than the Kingslayer's.
One army or two,
the Kings in the North
threw back hosts
10 times as large.
Mother!
You look well.
Lady Catelyn, you're a welcome
sight in these troubled times.
We had not thought
to meet you here, My Lady.
I had not thought to be here.
I would speak
with my son alone.
I know you will
forgive me, My Lords.
You heard her!
Move your asses!
Come on, out.
You too, Greyjoy.
Are you bloody deaf?
Have no fear, My Lady.
We'll shove our swords
up Tywin Lannister's bunghole
and then it's on to the Red Keep
to free Ned.
- You old devil, Rodrik.
- Jon.
You're not
wasting away, are you?
I remember the day
you came into this world
red-faced and squalling.
And now I find you
leading a host to war.
- There was no one else.
- No one?
Who were those men I saw here?
- None of them are Starks.
- All of them are seasoned in battle.
If you think you can send me back
to Winterfell...
Oh, would that I could.
There was...
a letter.
From Sansa.
From the Queen, you mean.
- There's no mention of Arya.
- No.
How many men do you have?
18,000.
If I go to King's Landing
and bend my knee to Joffrey...
You would never be allowed to leave.
No.
Our best hope...
our only hope...
is that you can defeat
them in the field.
And if I lose?
Do you know what happened
to the Targaryen children
- when the Mad King fell?
- They were butchered in their sleep.
On the orders
of Tywin Lannister.
And the years have
not made him kinder.
If you lose,
your father dies,
your sisters die,
we die.
Well, that makes it
simple then.
I suppose it does.
From here it might be best if
Bronn and I continue alone.
Best for Tyrion son of Tywin.
Not best for me.
If the half man betrays us,
Shagga Son of Dolf
will cut off his manhood...
And feed it to the goats, yes.
All right then.
Time to meet my father.
- Tyrion.
- Uncle.
Father.
The rumors of your demise
were unfounded.
Sorry to disappoint you.
And who are these...
companions of yours?
This is Shagga, son of Dolf,
Chieftain of the Stone Crows.
Timett Son of Timett,
ruler of the Burned Men.
This fair maid is
Chella daughter of Cheyk,
leader of the Black Ears.
And here we have
Bronn son of...
You wouldn't know him.
May I present my lord father,
Tywin son of Tytos
of House Lannister,
Lord of Casterly Rock
and Warden of the West?
Kind of you
to go to war for me.
You left us no choice.
The honor of the House
was at stake.
Your brother would never have
submitted to capture so meekly.
We have our differences,
Jaime and I.
He's braver.
I'm better looking.
He's been covering himself
in glory.
Jaime smashed the river lords
at the Golden Tooth,
and now lays siege to Riverrun,
Catelyn Stark's homeland.
And the Starks?
Lord Eddard?
...Is our hostage. He will lead
no armies from his dungeon cell.
How did my sweet sister
persuade the King
to imprison
his dear friend Ned?
Robert Baratheon is dead.
Joffrey rules in King's Landing.
My sister rules, you mean.
Stark's son has
called his banners.
- He moves south with a strong host.
- A green boy.
One taste of battle
and he'll run
back to Winterfell
with his tail between his legs.
Maybe.
Though the boy does have
a certain belligerence.
You'd like him.
While we're on
the subject of war,
I made promises
to my friends here
and a Lannister
always pays his debts.
We shall require
3,000 helms and shields,
plus swords, pikes,
gorgets, maces...
If it please My Lord,
Ser Addam bids me report
that the Northmen
have crossed the Neck.
The wolf rushes
into the lion's jaws.
So be it. Kevan, command the
drummers beat assembly.
And send word to Jaime that
I am moving against Robb Stark.
At once, My Lord.
It is said that the men of the
mountain clans are great warriors.
Ride with me against my enemies
and you shall have all
my son promised you and more.
Only if the half man
fights with us.
Until we hold the steel
he pledged us,
the little lion's life is ours.
The scouts report
Lord Tywin moves north.
We need to get him
on broken ground,
put his knights
at a disadvantage.
No, we need to get around him
and break Jaime Lannister's
siege of Riverrun.
Do that and the river lords
will join us.
To do either we need to cross
the river
and the only crossing
is at the Twins.
Lord Frey controls
that bridge.
Your father's bannerman.
"The late Lord Frey"
my father calls him.
At the Trident, he didn't appear
until the battle was done.
Some men takes their oaths
more seriously than others.
Robb's right.
We need that bridge.
So what's it going to be?
Do we move against
Jaime or Lord Tywin?
Your pardon, my lords.
We've captured
a Lannister scout.
Don't worry, lad. He won't be
leaving this tent with his head.
Where did you find him?
In the brush above
the encampment.
He looked to be counting.
How high did you get?
20,000.
Maybe more.
You don't have
to do this yourself.
Your father
would understand...
My father understands mercy,
when there is room for it.
And he understands honor...
and courage.
Let him go.
Robb.
Tell Lord Tywin
Winter is coming for him.
20,000 northerners marching south
to find out if he really does shit gold.
Yes, My Lord.
Thank you, My Lord.
Are you touched, boy?!
Letting him go?
You call me boy again.
Go on.
Oi.
It is also the wish
of His Grace
that his loyal servant
Janos Slynt,
- Commander of the City Watch...
- Ser Aron.
...Be at once raised
to the rank of Lord...
- Lord Gyles.
- And granted the ancient seat of Harrenhal,
and that his sons and grandsons
shall hold this honor
after him
until the end of time.
In the place of the traitor
Eddard Stark,
it is the wish of His Grace
that Tywin Lannister,
Lord of Casterly Rock
and Warden of the West,
be appointed Hand of the King.
Lastly,
in these times
of treason and turmoil,
it is the view of the Council
that the life and safety
of King Joffrey
be of paramount importance.
Ser Barristan Selmy.
Your Grace, I am
yours to command.
Rise, Ser Barristan.
You may remove your helm.
You have served the Realm
long and faithfully.
Every man and woman in the
Seven Kingdoms owes you thanks.
But it is time to put aside
your armor and your sword.
It is time to rest
and look back with pride
on your many years of service.
Your Grace, the Kingsguard
is a sworn brotherhood.
Our vows are taken for life.
Only death relieves us
of our sacred trust.
Whose death, Ser Barristan?
Yours or your King's?
You let my father die.
You're too old
to protect anybody.
- Your Grace...
- The Council has determined
that Ser Jaime Lannister
will take your place
as Lord Commander
of the Kingsguard.
The man who profaned his blade
with the blood of the King
he had sworn to defend!
Careful, Ser.
We have nothing but gratitude
for your long service,
good Ser.
You shall be given
a stout keep beside the sea,
with servants
to look after your every need.
A hall to die in
and men to bury me.
I am a knight.
I shall die a knight.
A naked knight, apparently.
Even now I could cut through
the five of you like carving a cake!
Here, boy!
Melt it down and add it
to the others.
If any man in this hall
has other matters
to set before His Grace,
let him speak now
or go forth and hold
his silence.
Your Grace.
Come forward, My Lady.
The Lady Sansa
of House Stark.
Do you have some business for
the King and the Council, Sansa?
I do.
As it please Your Grace,
I ask mercy for my father,
Lord Eddard Stark,
who was Hand of the King.
Treason is a noxious weed.
- It should be torn out, root...
- Let her speak.
I want to hear what she says.
Thank you, Your Grace.
Do you deny
your father's crime?
No, My Lords.
I know he must be punished.
All I ask is mercy.
I know My Lord father
must regret what he did.
He was King Robert's friend
and he loved him.
You all know he loved him.
He never wanted to be Hand
until the King asked him.
They must have lied to him...
Lord Renly or Lord Stannis
or somebody.
They must have lied!
He said I wasn't the King.
Why did he say that?
He was badly hurt.
Maester Pycelle was giving
him milk of the poppy.
He wasn't himself. Otherwise he
never would have said it.
A child's faith...
Such sweet innocence.
And yet they say
wisdom oft comes
from the mouths of babes.
Treason is treason!
Anything else?
If you still have any affection
in your heart for me,
please do me
this kindness, Your Grace.
Your sweet words have moved me.
But your father has to confess.
He has to confess
and say that I'm the King...
Or there'll be
no mercy for him.
He will.
== Sync by elderman ==
Corrected by honeybunny