So I guess now you know why I
don't talk to you about things.
Thanks for coming with me.
You wanna talk about it?
I don't see what's so wrong
about wanting my life
To go back to normal. What needs
to get back to normal is you.
I'll be waiting at the top
of the empire state building.
At 7:01, I'm closing my heart to
you forever. Well, I won't be there.
Sync for 720p by Baqinardo
Transcrypt by www.addic7ed.com
You reap what you sow.
What goes around comes around.
No matter how far you run,
You can never truly escape.
♪ I don't like you ♪
Everything catches up to you
in the end,
And when it does,
It usually kicks your ass.
♪...Always thinking of you ♪
Jenny?
Rufus, teenage girls
are a nightmare.
As soon as they realize
That you'll love 'em
no matter what they do,
You lose all of your power.
You just have to wait
till they finish college.
Or in the case of serena, rebel
and not go.
Just talk to her.
Is she in her room?
No. I sent her to the loft
to stay with dan
So I could consider
the best course of action.
Well, grounding her again
probably won't work.
Short of sending her away,
I don't know nything else
that will.
Well, I think
that would be a mistake.
And I would hate to separate her
and eric. They need each other.
Don't worry about me. After what
I witnessed yesterday,
You can do whatever you want with
jenny what are you talking about?
She's your sister. No, not by
choice. She said so herself.
So go ahead
and send her crazy ass away.
Although if I were you, I'd do
it sooner rather than later,
Before she hurts anybody else.
♪
Oh. Finally.
jenny. Hey.
You're still here.
Gee, thanks. As if it wasn't
humiliating enough
When you fell asleep
in the middle of my sentence.
Don't you mean monolou?
Seriously, though, thanks-
Thanks for listening to me
last night.
Yeah, no problem
You know I'm here for you,
whatever you need. But...
I just-I don't want you
to get the wrong impression.
don't worry
I get it.
You and I are friends.
You love serena.
Although it loos like
Love's a bit of a one-way street
right now. Did she call?
She's mad, but she'll cool off.
Morning, sunshines.
Hey, uh...
Jenny's on her way out,
actually.
She just crashed the night.
Ah, save it. I know
nothing untoward happened.
Tat was clear by the sound
of you snoring at 2:00 a.M.
And "new moon"
on the pay-per-view bill.
Although I was hoping
to catch you two
In the midst of something more
than a heart-to-heart.
Okay, I'm gonna
go get dressed.
Be careful, nathaniel.
You and serena are on thince.
All it taes is someone to
tap their foot and that cracks.
Oh, what do you know
about relationships?
A lo in fact,
I'm about to save mine.
I suggest you do the same
if you can.
I'm sorry.
I- I cannot reach table.
Just this once, dorota.
But if that baby
does not arrive soon...
We're going to have to look
into getting you help.
Believe me, I want this baby
to come out as much as you do.
Now as soo
as that moment comes,
Your mother and I are heading
straight back to paris.
So are you coming with us?
What are your plans? Nothing,
Beyond having a secon date
with cameron this afternoon
D staying as far away
as possible
From the empire state building. What's the
empire state building have to do with anything?
"an affair to remember"
was on tcm last night.
It gave me nightmares.
Blair loves
the empire state building,
Even though she doesn't want to,
and she should just admit I
And make all our life easier.
Miss blair loves othing
Except for shoes, clothes
and anything harry winston.
Now, dorota, would you please
gt me some steamed milk?
'cause this is ice cold.
Actually, no.
I will help you.
Since it appears
you have taken an interest
In the deadline
a certain bass-hat set for me,
I'm calling you into service.
But I already
ironed your sheets
And alphabetized shoes
by designer, like you ask.
What more is there to do?
I'm ordering you to chaperone
my date with cameron.
I need to make sure
that no matter what happens,
I don't go anywhere near
that stupid art deco landmark.
Miss blair, I defrind mr. Chuck
in facebook and in life.
But... This is pretty romantic
thing he's doing.
If not going means never having
chuck in your life again,
Are you prepared
to live like that?
Yes. But even if I'm not,
If you let me go
anywhere near 34th street,
There won't be a miracle
but a massacre.
Now...
put on your walking shoes.
We're going on a date.
Georgina sparks?
Is that you?
Da. Nice hotel, by the way...
For the upper west side.
I hope you're not here
to hurt me.
"operation ditc the bitch
in belarus" was blair's idea.
I don't want revenge.
I need help. I'm scared. Even if
I believed you, I wouldn't care.
This isn't like
the other times, chuck.
The russians
don't mess around.
It's really cold there,
and there's, like,
Barely any designer jeans,
and the average citizen
Drinks about 3nts
of pure alcohol a year.
Unless a one-way ticket
on the "siberian express"
Is what you're looking for,
I'm out.
So if you wouldn't mind, I have
some business to attend to.
Maybe I could just wait here
until you get back?
Or I could see you out now.
It's either me or security.
What time is it?
uh, it's later than either of us
wants it to be.
by that, I mean morning.
Oh, my god.
Wow. That's not usually
the reaction I hope for
When waking up next to a woman.
It's not that and you know it.
oh!
Last night-
don't even finish those words,
Unless-unless they end
with "was a mistake."
I mean, right?
Right. Right.
My thoughts exactly.
I mean, we're...
We're both in relationships.
Yeah. Yeah, it was-
it was totally meaningless.
I mean, we just fell asleep. Yeah,
after an entire bottle of wine
And-and a whole lot
of talking.
And one kiss.
Did that even happen?
I'm not sure-I'm not sure
that happened.
You know, all I remember is-
is you falling sleep on my arm,
And then my not being able
to move it.
In fact, I don't even know if
I still can. Like...
I- I was just upset,
and you were there for me.
It was just
a couple of old friends
Falling into a comfortable
pattern for a minute... Or ten.
And I love nate.
I love vanessa.
W- do we have to tell anyone?
Not on your life. No.
I mean, there's no reason
to explode our whole world
Just for some... Meaningless
kiss between old friends.
Whatever this was,
it's just between us. So...
It's not like we can't
keep that safe.
Yeah.
Call me if you need anything.
Okay. All right. Bye.
Bye.
That was a mistake.
It was completely random.
It was gravity.
Okay. Bye.
You were going for the hug.
I- I went for the...
♪ all dressed up w♪
Spotted-a family reunion only
faulkner would approve of.
♪ all dressed up
with nowhere to go ♪
I used to think
that s. And lonely boy
Were the most boring couple
on the upper east side.
But what makes them
actually great together?
Is when they're supposed to be
with other people.
76th and 5th, please.
Actuallyke that
the empire hotel, and quick.
Good luck talking your way
out of this one, s.
I hope you're on your way
to see nate.
You saw the blast? Yes, and
although I'm inclined to say
That gossip girl doesn't know
what she's talking about,
Since she also posted
some blurry photo
Of a russian mail-order bride
and said it was georgina,
That really did look like
you and humphrey.
I mean,
isn't that a little '08,
Like maxi dresses and
miley cyrus? Blair.
We all try on old clothes
from time to time,
And sur, we may even be
surprised when they still fit,
But that doesn't mean we should
wear them again, ever.
Nothing happened
and as for the photo,
It was obviously the work
of jenny humphrey.
I knew she hated me,
But apparently
she hates dan, too.
I just wish she would
hole up in brooklyn
And leave the rest of us alone.
Brooklyn. Is that where she is right now?
I guess so.
Look, I-I gotta go call dan
And make sure he knows
what's going on.
Bye.
We have to
get off this island.
Cameron, would you mind
if we made a little detour?
How little?
hey.
So now that our morning
Seems to have made t all over
manhattan... Yeah, I saw that.
I just wanna make sure
we're still on the same page.
Uh, absolutely.
I don't wanna jeopardze
my friendship with nate
Or my relationship
with vanessa
Just as much as you don't want
to jeopardize
Your relationship with nate
or your friendship with vanessa.
Are you friends with vanessa?
Friendly enough
To not want her to get upset
over a meaningless kiss.
I mean, it was meaningless,
right? dan, is that you?
Uh, you know, I gotta go.
Good luck.
Hey, was that my lincoln hawk
t- shirt serena was wearing?
You saw "gossip girl"?
I just kinda glanced
over eric's shoulder.
Have you seen jenny?
I need to find her.
I need to talk to her about why she took
that picture. I thought she was with you.
No, she-she wasn't there when
I wok up and she wasn't there
When I went to sleep either,
which wasn't until, like, 4:00.
I wish I didn't have to
say this, dad,
But she's out of control.
I mean, yesterday,
it was your marriage,
And today it's nate and serena,
vanessa and me.
She-she's gotta be stopped.
We should go wait for her.
She's bound to show up there
sooner than here.
Hey, have you seen nate?
I have no idea where he is,
Though I do have a good idea
where you've been.
Chuck... Look, before you go and
use whatever line youve prepared,
Think hrd.
Nate knows who he loves
and what he wants.
So unless you can
say the same,
Look him in the eye and tll him
that or stop playing games.
Courage, ma soeur.
Please.
Hey.
Hi.
I mean, I wish I could say
I was happy to see you.
Nothg happened with dan.
We just fell asleep talking.
Oh, really? Nate, you
and I both screwed up.
I only turned to dan
because I was mad at you
For calling the cops
on my father.
And what your dad did
was really wrong, serena.
That was not
for you to decide.
Nate...
I love you.
I just wanna
make things work again.
Nothing happened?
Nothing happened.
I just wanna go back
to being us.
I know that it'll be hard,
but I do wanna try.
Blair.
What are you doing here?
Someone has to give you
the smackdown
You so richly deserve.
That's it me who gets to do it
is just the cherry on top.
Bring it on.
I knew when I sent the blast
there'd be fallout.
When are you gonna get it?
For three years, you've tried to
worm your way into our world,
But you will never be
a part of it
No matter what you do.
This isn't copycat dressing
at constance
Or dumping dairy on you
best friend to prove a point.
Nate and serena?
That's mythic.
You don't mess with that
and survive.
You're hurting people I love.
You're hurting people you love.
I wasn't trying to-
Nate loves serena,
Dan loves vanessa-
god knows why-
And chuck loves me.
But, you, jenny?
No one loves you,
except your daddy.
And after what you pulled
yesterday,
Who knows
if that's even true anymore?
Well...
I guess you'll find out now.
that's so beautiful. I can't
believe it. Are you okay?
the miracle of life
growing inside of you.
I'm in luck! Two smackdowns
for the price of none.
What the hell are you doing?
Don't screw up nate and serena.
Nothing happened.
So said serena,
But I'm thinking she left
a little something out.
All right.
Blair...
Say life is givng you signs,
and you're ignoring them because
You're afraid of the thing
they're signaling you to do.
But-but then-
but then you think,
What if these signs
are here for a reason
And-and ignoring them just makes me
a coward? Sgns are for the religious,
The superstitious
and the lower class.
I don't believe in them
and neither should you.
Damn you, chuck bass.
Damn you to hell.
Why-when did we start talking
about chuck bass?
Spotted atop the empire...
State building, that is-
A boy bllionaire,
flowers in hand.
Oh, chuck.
If you could only see
to brooklyn,
You might turn that frown
upside down.
Okay, dorota.
we got a deadline to make.
Uh... Ooh.
My water re.
Oh, my god. Holy... O-okay. All
right, slowly. Slowly. Slowly.
Come on. This way.
A little faster.
Then again, maybe you
should guard your heart. Ahh.
Lennox hilspital
right now.
Dorota's water might not be
The only thing breaking
tonight.
I spoke to your mother
this morning,
And we decided that you should
spend the summer in hudson
And finish high school
there next year. What?
I thought you'd be happy.
It's a fresh start-
somewhere wthout mean girls
And drug dealing boyfriends
and "gossip girl."
Dad...
The city's all I have.
If I leave,
I have nothing.
I'm sorry.
That's the way it's gonna be.
It's done.
Dorota!
Dorota, did I miss it?
Of course not.
Now, you know,
you have at your service
One of the best lamaze coaches
in the world.
I've been present at the labor
of many of my clients.
One of them didn't even know
she was pregnant. Hello, dear.
Hi.
You must go now, miss blair.
If-if you don't arrive before
7:00, he will be gone forever.
No, I-I can't leave you.
I have plenty help. Please.
You have my blessing.
We both get what we want now.
Go.
Okay. I'll be back.
W- where's she going?
What's that about?
Aah!
Hey, nate's getting-
I'm sorry! I can't talk! I have
to go! I hope I'm not too late!
♪
Hey.
I've been feelinguilty
all day.
Yeah, I-I know.
I got your text.
Um, I'm not sure riht now
is the right time to tell nate.
I mean, there are babies being
born and-and watr is breaking,
And I don't even know what
we would say to him anyway.
U, you don't have to
say anything.
I think I already know.
(eastern conference champions'
"don't think twice,
it's all right" playing)
Blair. Stop.
Georgina?
Where are you doing here?
I followed your mom and cyrus
from your apartment.
I need to talk to you.
I'm in trouble. Big trouble.
And while it warms my heart
hearing that, I'm late.
Good-bye, georgina.
May god save your soul... Again.
No, a kiss is not nothing.
People don't just kiss
because they're upset.
People kiss because they have
feelings for each other.
So do you?
Nate, that's ridiculous.
I'm with you, and-and he's with vanessa.
Oh, yeah, what about vanessa, huh?
I mean. I seriously doubt she's
reading "gossip girl" in haiti.
But just in case she is,
or even if she's not,
Maybe you should give her
a call, bring her up to speed.
Don't threaten him. Serena,
please. I can stand up for myself.
Really? Because you're being awfully quiet
right now. Yeah, it's because he knows I'm right.
It's time!
The baby is coming!
♪ when your rooster crows
at the break of dawn ♪
Come on, dorota! Push!
♪ look out your window
and I'll be gone ♪
Not enough! Not enough!
♪ you're the reason
I'm traveling on ♪
♪ but don't think twice ♪
♪ it's all right ♪
♪ and it ain't no use
in turnin' on your light, babe ♪
♪ I'm on the dark side
of the road ♪
♪ still, I wish there was
something you would do or say ♪
Oh!
oh!
It's a girl!
She's beautiful.
♪...Talkin' anyway ♪
♪ but don't think twice,
it's all right ♪
Hi. I'm meeting
a young man here-
Probably in a bow tie,
possibly carrying peonies.
♪ I can't hear you anymore ♪
♪ I'm a5thinkin'
and a-wonderin' ♪
♪ walking down the road ♪
♪ I once loved a woman-
a child, I'm told ♪
♪ I gave her my heart
but she wanted my soul ♪
Nate?
♪ but don't think twice ♪
♪ it's all right ♪
Chuck, what are you doing?
Trying to forget.
I did the most romantic thing
I could think of,
And it didn't work.
It was never going to.
I'm sorry.
Well, um,
I guess if nate's not here,
I'll go.
Not that I really have
anywhere to go.
You can stay here
if you want.
It's not like you haven't
done it before.
Well, yea, but that was
always with nate,
Playing video games
o watching movies or whatever.
Well, I don't play video games,
so if you wanna hang with me,
You do what I do.
I'm trying to forget
some things, too.
Mostly how happy
I thought I'd be
Once I made it
in this world.
The world you're looking for
only exists from the outside.
The only reason
I survive in it...
Is because I always knew
it was empty.
Yeah. And now I know, too.
I found out the hard way.
The hard way
Is the only way.
If you want to leave,
Now would be the time.
I don't want to be alone.
Neither do I.
I didn't expect to find you here
staring at babies.
Turns out I'm a big fan
of babies.
Everything for them
is-is so simple.
They start out
with a clean slate.
They have no idea
how complicated
Everything is gonna
get for them. Yeah.
That baby right there-
He's gonna grow up to be smarter
than the rest of 'em,
Which will make him
feel like an outsider,
Give im a bit of a chip on
his shoulder. Oh, really?
Well, uh, you-you see
that baby there?
She's gonna grow up
to have fabulous hair
And a great smile,
but her daddy issues
Are gonna make it real hard
for her to trust people.
Wanna take a walk?
Yeah.
And this baby's
gonna do some things
To make all the other babies
hate her.
Anastasia.
It's a beautiful name.
Can I hold her?
I know-I know it's soon,
But she's so pink and perfect,
and, oh...
who knew babies
could be so astonishing?
Miss eleanor.
Oh.
In fact, uh...
Yes, dorota and I
were talking...
Miss eleanor,
Mr. Cyrus,
Would you be ana's godparents?
Would we?
Paris, schmaris.
I am never letting go
Of this precious creature.
Ah!
I feel terrible about nate.
Oh, god, I know.
I know-which part, exactl
Was it the kissing me part
or the him finding out part?
Or wait, was it the part
Where he asked us if we had
feelings for one another?
All of the above. I need to tell vanessa. She
- she's gotta hear this from me.
You guys really are happy,
aren't you?
Yeah, we, uh,
yeah, we are, definitely.
But I-you know, I can't lie.
Knowing someone so well,
you think it's gonna be esier.
But in a lo of ways, it just-
it makes it harder.
Maybe ignorance
really is bliss.
Hmm. Is that why
it was so easy with us?
You mean because?
Yeah. Sure.
Everything is a discovery-
This unknown person
who can do or think anything.
Well, that was
perfectly timed.
Very.
It's vanessa.
Good news is, she does not get
"gossip girl" blasts in haiti,
But she does get nate's texts,
and he sent her that photo.
How could he do that?
How could he not?
Are you okay?
You're welcome
to stay the night.
You're not kicking me out
into the street?
Lucky me.
Hey. Some people
don't get the offer.
Nate?
chuck?
Chuck!
blair.
What are you doing here?
What are you doing? Is there
someone in there? No, nobody.
Excuse my confusion.
I... Didn't expect
to see you tonight...
Or ever again.
You went.
Sorry I was so late.
I- I waited.
Dorota went into labor.
She had her baby.
I wasn't going to show up.
I was resolved not to.
Every bone in my body
tried to slow me.
Every voice in my head
screamed, "don't!"
But...
But I didn't listen.
I followed my heart
because I love you.
I can't deny that our path
has been complicated,
But in the end,
love makes everything simple.
Why don't I make you
a drik?
How about some music?
My ipod's in my room.
We don't need music.
I want everything
to be perfect.
Jenny.
go away.
No. We may get mad
at ach other sometimes,
But if you're really hurting,
I'm here for you.
You say that now.
But I'll do something
to let you down.
Then you'll turn your back
like everybody else.
My dad.
Dan.
Nate. Serena.
Blair.
Everybody hates me, even...
Even chuck.
Chuck?
What did you do to chuck?
it was such a mistake.
Mistake? Chuck?
♪...To call so we wait for ♪
♪ morning to wak you ♪
Jenny, why would you-
why would yo that?
I was sad. He was sad.
I don't-I don't know.
♪ and to know me ♪
it's not the worst thing.
I mean, it's not worse
than that time with damien-
I didn't do it with damien.
What?
I wanted you to think it.
I didn't, and...
I wanted to wait. I...
I wanted it
to be special, and..
♪ and I'll be redy ♪
Don't touch me.
Don't tell anyone?
♪ at every occasion, once more ♪
♪ it's called the funeral ♪
♪ at every occasion,
oh, I'm ready ♪
♪ for the funeral ♪
Nate, we need to alk.
I was just gonna say
te same thing.
Excuse me.
Hey.
Hey. Have you seen
my dad and lily?
They're supposed
to be here with food.
No. No, I haven't seen them,
but, um, jenny's here. Uh...
She needs help. You're just
now realizing this? You-
Dan. Okay.
What-what-what happened?
You need to ask her.
She's in the chapel.
I don't know, I guess I thought
when my dad came back,
That I would start making
different choices
And-an stop making
the same mistakes.
Well,
at least that's honest.
Yeah, I think I need
to be alone for a while.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Wait.
I find it in my heart
To forgive you
for kissing another guy,
And you're gonna break up with me? It's not
breaking up. It's-it's just taking a break.
It's not you
- oh, "it's not you. It's me." right?
Yes, serena, it is you.
You know, I think it's great
That you want
to work on yourself,
But I'm not gonna wait around
to see how things go.
So if you're out,
you're out.
That's fair.
Nate, I love you.
I really do.
But if we're ever gonna have
a real chance,
This is the only way.
Despite the false start
earlier,
This night is perfect.
Well, there is one thingthat wo.
I am so sorry for the pain
I've caused you.
And I know
I can't take it back,
But I wanna try
and make it up to you,
Even if it takes me
the rest of my life.
Blair, will you-
humphrey!
Have you lost your mind?!
What the hell are you doing?!
You, tell her.
Tell me what?
What's going on?
You didn'.
Blair.
you did.
You.
Get out of here now.
And not just
out of this hospital,
But off this island.
Go and never come back,
Because if you ever set foot in
manhattan again, I will know...
And I wll destroy you.
blair, I'm sobry.
You have no reason to be sorry.
This begins and ends with chuck.
hey!
Who's hungry?
I got enough bagel chips
to feed an...
What'd I just walk into?
Dad.
Rufus. Hey, come here.
Come here. Let's go st.
Are you okay?
Hey, let me walk you home.
blair, I-
I thought you didn't
love me anymore.
I didn't care
if I lived or died.
Jenny humhrey was ust-
no, don't say her name!
Or anything else to me
ever again.
This whole night
didn't happen.
are you sure
you wanna do this?
Yeah.
It's my idea this time
Dad!
come here, kiddo.
No tears!
Oh, don't worry. I'm
done crying. I meant me.
I'm gonna miss you so much.
Yeah. Your mother's thrilled
to have you,
But you can come home
anytime.
You are my daughter,
jenny,
And I love you forever
and always, come whatever.
I love you, too.
There's nothing here for me
anymore, though.
I'm here.
Eric.
Please don't go.
You may be a total bitch
sometimes,
But you're still
my best friend.
What am I gonna do next year
at school without you?
Who's gonna dump yogurt
on my head?
I'll skype you every day.
All right, dan, jenny.
Humphrey hug.
Aah!
Eric and lily,
get in here, too.
aah!
All right, I gotta go.
No, no, no. A little longer.
A little longer.
but I love you. Bye, guys.
See you.
I'm actually excited
to have an entire summer
With nothing to do
but figure things out.
Um, first of all, s.,
You didn't go to school
this year
And you haven't
had a real job in months,
So life is kind of like summer
for you. Oh, okay. Thanks.
Kick a girl when she's down.
I really am gonna change.
Why? All the drama-
it's who you are,
Just like I'm someone who's not
gonna stop looking for love
Just because I've lost it...
Which is why I'm going
Directly into the bell
of the beast-paris-
And why you're coming
with me.
Uh, I was gonna
do a cleanse and yoga.
And maybe keeping
a dream journal.
Haven't you heard
of retail therapy?
And everyone goes to paris
to write their memoirs-
Not thatyou'll,
What with all the riding around
on vespas in cute outfits.
We have never been single together...
Or traveled to a foreign land!
La première on air France
has turndown service,
And the chef has
three michelin stars.
Come on.
Shopping at palais royale,
People watching at café de flore?
Oh, lingerie and pierre hermé?
Mm-hmm. Ooh! Thank you! I
really think I need this.
Me, too.
It's gonna be okay, b.
As long as we have each other,
we're both gonna be okay.
paris! Aah!
Hey, man,
thanks for calling.
Um... You gonna apologize
or you waiting for me?
'cause I don't-I don't mind
going first. No, I'll go.
Look, I'm sorry
for what happened with vanessa.
I mean, you fired a shot at me.
I fired a shot at you.
But it was a dick move.
And I don't blame you for what
happened between me and serena.
Uh, well, thanks,
but I didn't exactly help.
So, uh, I'm sorry for that.
As for vanessa, I mean,
maybe if I told her the truth,
That photo wouldn't have
hit her so hard.
That bad, huh?
What'd she say?
Nothing, since she's not
currently returning my calls.
But I'm-I'm about
to write her
The world's longest and most plaintive
e- mail. You trying to get her back?
I'm just trying to explain
what happened,
To her and-and to myself,
you know? Let me know
If you wanna take a break
from the little soul searching.
When he took off for prague,
Chuck left me
his little black book.
Oh, I-I didn't realize you
and serena were actually over.
Yeah, well, I'm not gonna
spend the entire summer
Waiting for her to figure things out.
Righ yeah, that, uh, that makes sense.
Listen, I'm gonna have to pass
on the little black book thing.
But, uh, you enjoy yourself. All
right, man? Oh, I'm sure gonna try.
hey, dan. I mean, bonjour!
No, you mean, au revoir.
Good-bye, humphrey!
We're leaving! Is that
blair? Where you guys going?
Paris.
Paris? Oh, wow.
Um... Well, have-have fun.
thank you.
You called me. What's up?
Oh, yeah. Um, you know,
Just calling to talk about-
about things.
Uh, but obviously,
now's not a good time.
So just call me when you get
back. Okay. I'll miss you!
I'll miss you, too, humphrey!
Bon vacance!
I'll see you in September,
okay? Okay, sounds good.
Okay, bye.
No, it doesn't.
Uh, come in! It's open!
Hi, dan.
Georgina, what are you-what are
you doing back in town?
Looking for you, actually.
I, um, I have something
of yours.
What? I don't-I don't remember
giving you anything.
Well...
You gave me this.
What?!
Congratulations, daddy.
He looks just like you
♪ pressure ♪
And all in an instant,
everything changes.
♪ under pssure ♪
We leave the past behind
and speed toward the unknown-
Our future.
We set out for far-off places
and try to find ourselves...
♪ people on the streets ♪
♪ it's the terror of knowing ♪
Or try to lose ourselves
Exploring pleasures
closer to home.
♪ pray tomorrow,
gets me higher ♪
♪ people on the stret ♪
The problems start when
we refuse to let change happen
And cling to old habits.
Dekuji, ladies.
A velvet revolution indeed.
Hey. Look, you don't-
you don't need to get rough.
Okay, I've got lots of money.
I'm chuck bass.
Hey. Hey! Hey!
Come on. Come on
not that. Not that.
just let me keep the box.
Take me to a bank.
I will give you the money.
Just let me keep the box!
But if we hold on
to the past too tight,
The future may never come.
Till death do us part.
X.O.X.O., gossip girl.
Sync for 720p by Baqinardo
Transcrypt by www.addic7ed.com