[SCREAMING]
You invent a time machine
and can't do anything
useful with it?!
I can use it
to get away from you.
David Clinton,
inventor of the chrono suit,
at your disposal.
You tried to steal
Batman's utility belt.
Don't hurt anyone. We could
accidentally change history.
We've been
expecting you.
Static, what's going on?
Dad?
We need to get out of here.
Leaving
so soon?
You didn't even take
any party favors.
Incoming!
That's not
gonna hold.
Where do you think
you're going, sugar?
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMS]
Look, Dee Dee,
another Green Lantern.
He's much cuter than
the last one we killed,
don't you think, Dee Dee?
[SCREAMS]
[BOTH GRUNT]
How'd you...?
[GRUNTING]
Ow.
[CACKLING]
Hold still so I can pound you.
Yeah, that's what I'll do.
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
Hey! What's
the big idea?
[GRUNTING]
You shouldn't ought to
have done that.
We're getting
out of here now.
Not a chance.
Hold the line.
He's right.
We're the Justice League.
We don't run from a fight.
[GRUNTS]
I don't remember
putting this up for a vote.
GREEN LANTERN:
Keep your head in the game.
There's always
a way.
Virgil!
I need some cover.
They're gone,
Dee Dee.
Bet I know which way
they went, Dee Dee.
After 'em!
I think we've lost them.
Where are we headed?
The watchtower?
Not exactly.
[SQUEAKS]
This is Justice League
headquarters?
For now.
We're all that's left
of the League.
You've traveled
about 50 years into your future.
Last time I saw you,
you were too young to drive.
You look good
for a man your age.
The miracles
of modern medicine.
65 is the new 30.
And the watchtower?
It's gone.
We lost a lot
of good people that day.
You mean, Superman,
J'onn, all the others?
MAN:
Yeah.
You too.
And the bat cave?
MAN:
This is all we have left now.
Deal with it.
Surprised to see me?
A little.
I'm more surprised
that I lived so long.
Batman, Bruce Wayne.
Bruce Wayne, Batman.
Or have you met?
Not now.
Great. What did
they used to call it?
Stereo?
This is a little weird
for everybody.
I'm War Hawk.
Rex Stewart.
Your mother.
Who is she?
Kind of obvious,
don't you think?
Even if it isn't,
leave it be.
You don't wanna know
too much about your future.
Trust me,
you really don't.
Shayera was one
cranky pregnant lady.
Although, to be fair,
if I'd laid an egg that size...
He's kidding, Dad.
Not that I understand
why you think this is
anything to joke about.
Because we already won.
Think about it.
If old Bruce
is here,
that means he already
lived through this as Batman.
Flawless logic.
Except that I have no memory
of ever going to the future
and meeting my older self,
or of anything else
that's happening today.
Those historical buildings
we saw on the street.
The time line's
been polluted.
So polluted that history itself
is becoming fluid.
We'd better
compare notes.
Enid, I have to say
that I'm vexed.
Yes, vexed is precisely
the word for it.
You shouldn't let yourself
get upset, David.
You're right, dear.
But here we are.
Now, look at it
from my point of view.
I go to the trouble
of taking over the whole city
so I have a nice place
to keep my collection.
And it's a beautiful
collection, David.
I was gonna say
the same thing, boss.
For instance,
this is a really nice boat.
Big.
Don't patronize me,
Chucko,
and especially,
don't interrupt me.
I'm sorry.
Sorry what?
Everybody?
ALL:
Sorry, Lord Chronos.
It doesn't seem right.
I go to
the future.
I get
the technology
that gives you all
your new super-powers.
I let you run amuck
in my town
in return for
the occasional security job.
And what do you do
in return?
Um...
Rhetorical.
My point is,
I give you an easy job:
take care of Batman,
Wonder Woman and Green Lantern.
It should have been
10 minutes work.
But the JLU showed up.
They got in our way.
Yes, they did.
And the question arises:
Who told them where and when
our targets would arrive?
I mean, I told you.
And I only know, because
I'm the undisputed master
of space and time.
I'll look into it, boss.
I'll find out
where the leak was.
No, don't trouble
yourself, Chucko.
No, don't bother.
[WHISPERS]
I already know.
Somebody's getting a payoff.
Yes, he is.
Chucko, Chucko, Chucko.
You've been
a very bad clown.
[WHIMPERS]
Enjoy your stay.
[ROARING]
You think I'm scared?
I'll be running this dump
in a few y...
Oh, phooey.
[RUMBLING]
Do you know
what killed the dinosaurs?
Uh, no, sir.
Well, Chucko does.
And unless you wanna
find out firsthand,
you'll go finish off
the Justice League.
Skedaddle.
Time is money.
Actually, time is
the nonspatial continuum
in which events
occur linearly,
usually in the direction
of increased entropy.
But the clowns seem to
relate better
to the money thing.
[ENID GASPS]
Oh, Enid, look at
what I've done.
And you always said
I wouldn't amount to anything.
I guess I showed you.
[LAUGHS]
[LAUGHS UNCOMFORTABLY]
Now I've taken over Gotham,
which gives me plenty of space
to store my antiques.
Did you notice I took that stuff
out of the garage?
You can park there now
if you want to.
Thank you, David. Heh.
David, uh, didn't you tell me
it was dangerous
to take important things
from the past?
That it could
damage time somehow?
Don't you think
I can handle it?
O- of course I do.
Dear?
Hmm?
Do you know what
would make me happy?
If you let my mother
out of the thing,
like you promised.
We'll see.
Rub my neck.
It's just that...
it seems cruel to
keep her there so long.
Your mother was
the one who always said
I'd never amount
to anything.
And you agreed with her.
Whatever I do,
whatever I accomplish,
it'll never be enough
for you, will it?
I just wanted you to love me!
I'm sick of this!
I'm sick of you!
Wait, baby, please.
Isn't there anything I can do
to make things right?
I sincerely doubt it.
We still don't know
much about him.
Obviously, he's
a time-traveling warlord.
He's littered the streets
with buildings he's stolen
from other
time periods.
He's not
a warlord.
At least,
he wasn't at first.
When we chased him
to the Old West,
all he was stealing was
historical trinkets.
He's causing severe damage
to the space/time continuum.
The degradation
is increasing exponentially.
BATMAN:
I've got something.
When we were
in the Old West,
I got a good look
at his time belt.
[BEEPS]
I've written a program
that should disable it.
If we can get close enough
to upload it.
WONDER WOMAN: If we can
get our hands on the belt,
maybe we can stop this from
happening in the first place.
[VOICE FADING] We could even
undo the death of your friends...
Diana!
She... never
left the island.
Or she was never born.
Time is
running out.
Literally.
We need to
find Chronos.
How? He could be
anywhere.
Sometimes the old
ways are best.
It's not
gonna work.
You don't know
your way around.
A lot of things
have changed.
Are criminals still
superstitious and cowardly?
Yep.
Good enough for me.
You're supposed to be
the real Batman, right?
I mean, the first one.
I've seen history cubes
about you.
Hard to believe somebody
stupid as you
ever beat the Joker.
Maybe I'm smarter
than I look.
[SCREAMS]
[GROANS]
Oh, terrific.
You've got some
information we need, Ghoul.
You won't find me
the talkative sort.
Hey!
[GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS, SCREAMS]
Where's Chronos?
My arm's getting tired.
I can't believe
I was ever that green.
[WHIMPERING]
[SCREAMS, GRUNTS]
This is how
you interrogate someone.
And we've got
9,453 active jokers
organized into about
200 smaller groups.
I don't know where Chronos is.
He contacts us.
Spends every night
in a different one
of those old buildings.
There's no way
of knowing ahead of time
where he's gonna be.
And that's everything I know.
Everything?
I wet my bed
until I was 14.
Losing
my patience.
I can't control
my friend here much longer.
You better give us
something we can use.
His wife. I know
where his wife is.
Wow. Batman playing
good cop.
Everything's
relative.
[LOUNGE MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
Get me another box
of bonbons.
[BANGING,
PUNCHING]
Will you hold it down
out there?!
You guys are always fighting!
Enid Clinton.
We've got business
with your husband.
What?
John?
Hal Jordan.
Another time shift.
I'm up to speed.
Carry on.
Okay. I'm starting
to get a migraine.
We'd better
get used to it.
This is going to get worse
before it gets better.
Any one of us could change
or even cease to exist.
That's why you have to tell us
where to find David.
We just wanna undo
the harm he's caused.
You have my word.
We'll do everything
to keep from hurting him.
Between you and me,
I wouldn't mind one bit
if he got roughed up
along the way.
WAR HAWK:
Then where is he tonight?
The Parthenon?
The Great Sphinx?
He just wants people
to think he moves around.
He always sleeps
in the same place.
No booby traps.
At least none
that my ring can detect.
Make up your mind,
would you?
Anyway,
it's safe to go in.
If we don't beat this guy,
it's the end of everything.
We've been there before.
Not like this.
What are you
supposed to do
when you have the weight of
the world on your shoulders?
Plant your feet.
GREEN LANTERN:
I don't understand.
With all of the places
he could be,
why sleep here?
Because a loser
with a kingdom
is still just a loser.
See for yourself.
Huh... Uh...
Enid?
Nice on the stealth
thing, lady.
Get the belt.
Nothing else matters.
[GRUNTING]
[GASPS]
[GRUNTS]
A real gentleman,
isn't he, Dee Dee?
They're practically
extinct, Dee Dee.
[SCREAMS]
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS]
It happened again.
Look out!
Monsters!
Fire at will!
[GRUNTING]
Batman's not paying us
any attention, Dee Dee.
He should be punished,
Dee Dee.
[SCREAMING]
Terry!
Terry.
[GRUNTING]
How could you
betray me, Enid?
Everything I've done,
I've done for you.
Don't blame this on me.
I just wanted you
to assert yourself,
not destroy the universe.
[GRUNTING]
[ROARING]
[GROWLING]
Get away from my kid!
[GRUNTS]
Chronos!
You are good.
Isn't he good?
Look at what's
happening around you.
Look at the sky.
Pretty.
GREEN LANTERN:
Stay with us, man.
We've got
a problem here.
Right.
You're right.
This calls
for another approach.
You'll love me
next time.
Where's he going?
There's nothing left.
Yes, there is.
The beginning of time.
He can reset everything.
Make himself into a god.
Only if
he gets there first.
[GASPS]
The Green Lanterns
have a legend:
No one can see
the beginning of time.
It's a universal law.
Write him a ticket.
No!
[WHIMPERING]
Uploading
the program.
Make it fast.
Having a little trouble
with the brakes.
That all
really happened?
Think so.
Then we won.
Everything's back to normal?
That's a nasty cut, John.
You don't remember going on
a mission with us today, do you?
I just got here.
The time line's
restored to equilibrium.
We're the only two people
who remember what happened.
That complicates
things.
What happened
to Chronos?
I reprogrammed the belt
to make sure that Chronos
would never come to exist.
ENID: You worthless, good for nothing,
wretched waste of space.
[SCREAMING]
You invent a time machine
and can't think of
anything useful to do with it?
I can think of one thing.
Worthless, good-for-nothing,
wretched waste of space.
You invent a time machine
and can't think of
anything useful to do with it?!
I can think of one thing.
ENID: Worthless, good-for-nothing,
wretched waste of space...