"Melissa and Joey" is recorded in
front of a live studio audience.
Charlotte, I really
appreciate your honesty.
You're a good friend.
Honest. Okay, talk later.
Bye.
Well, I'm never seeing that bitch again.
You just said you appreciated her honesty.
Obviously I was lying.
How I feel and what I
say isn't always related.
That's good to know.
I just called to confirm
our dinner for this weekend
and she said, get this...
That she's not sure
they're going to be hungry that night.
Okay, if she's going to blow us off,
she'd better put a little
more effort into it than that.
No kidding. Finally she told me the truth.
They don't want to hang out with us anymore
because we argue too much.
- We do not argue too much.
- Yes, we do!
No, we don't. What we do
is we disagree with volume.
And hand gestures.
Well, Charlotte said that
nobody can relax around us
because of all of the loud disagreeing.
Nobody can relax around us?!
That's ridic... I am insanely relaxing.
I'm like Xanax in human form.
Well, you are a pill.
Look, I think it's time we face the fact
- that we have a problem.
- We do not have a problem, honey.
The only problem is that
you think we have a problem.
So you admit we have a problem.
Wow, you guys started early today.
Started what?
Arguing. I could hear you
over Ryder's bathroom noises.
See?
Okay, fine, so we argue occasionally.
That doesn't mean we have a problem.
Lennox, you can handle this for us.
You think your aunt and I argue too much?
Yes.
- She's totally right.
- She's obviously wrong.
(Theme music playing)
- ♪ It's all good
- ♪ all good
- ♪ it's okay
- ♪ okay
- ♪ it's all right
- ♪ all right
♪ as far as I can see
- ♪ it's all good
- ♪ all good
- ♪ it's okay
- ♪ okay
- ♪ it's all right
- ♪ all right
♪ I guess you're stuck
♪ with me.
Sync & Corrections by Darcade
- Addicted.com -
(Whirring loudly)
(Whirring ceases)
Hey, great news.
The air-conditioning repairman
is coming on Thursday.
- Why?
- To fix the air-conditioning.
Honey, it's not broken. You
just don't know how to set it.
- Yes, I do.
- No, you don't. No, no.
You can't use a hammer
to set the temperature.
Joe, look, it needs some work.
And so do we.
Oh, jeez.
Is this about the whole
arguing thing again...
Which, by the way, we really do not do.
We can't go more than three sentences
without contradicting each other.
That's...
But...
That's a new dress, isn't it?
No. Look, all of my girlfriends
that are in healthy relationships
go to couples' counseling.
I think we should give it a try.
Oh, my God.
You want us to go to therapy?
Like I gotta cry and stuff?
Everyone can benefit from counseling.
You don't only go to the
dentist when you have a cavity.
You go for prevention.
My dentist is a sadist.
Okay, bad example.
Couples' therapy is something
you should do for better health.
Like getting a colonoscopy.
You really know how to
sell this, don't you?
So you don't think we should
bother improving our relationship?
I didn't say that. I just
don't think couples' therapy
is a worthwhile investment for us, okay?
Honey, you don't bring in a third party
to help a couple out with their problems.
Three does not equal two. It's just math.
Math is never wrong.
You know what I think?
I think you're resistant to therapy
because you are not open to new ideas.
That's not true. I'm
just closed to bad ideas.
Okay, fine. I'm sure you
have lots of interesting ideas
about how to improve our relationship.
- I would love to hear them.
- I would love to share them with you.
- Great, go ahead.
- Okay, first off...
(Whirs loudly, ceases)
Okay, as I was saying, I don't...
- What I was trying to say was I don't...
- (Whirs loudly, ceases)
You're going to keep doing that until
I agree to go to therapy, aren't you?
- Oh, is this frustrating you?
- Little bit, yep.
Well, maybe you could
talk about that frustration
in our first session.
Fine, I'll go.
- Yay!
- But not because you're right, okay?
- It's because I'm just trying to...
- (Whirs loudly)
- I...
- (Continues whirring)
And then, at the 10-second mark,
Cassandra's superpowers kick in.
She's reading "Romeo and Juliet" and...
And Juliet leaps off the page.
Well, with my animation, it'll
be less of a graceful leap.
More of a choppy bounce.
And then, Cassandra says to Juliet,
"listen, girl, I know he has
cute floppy hair and all..."
"But he is so not worth it."
"Totally."
You know, Zander, even though
you're halfway across the country,
it feels like you're right here in my room.
Just with a four-second delay.
Yeah, I totally know...
What...
I was just messing with you.
Hey, babe. Ryder said
you were on the phone.
Hey, Emerson. (Clears throat)
Yeah, I am just finishing
up a session with Zander.
He's my... He's my creative partner.
Oh, the ex.
Dude, what's up?
Hey, I know this could be awkward.
New boyfriend, old boyfriend.
But listen... I'm not jealous.
Lennox told me it's strictly professional
between you two now.
Ah, that's interesting.
Lennox told me absolutely
nothing about a new boyfriend.
(Chuckles) Yeah.
You know, I meant to tell you.
I was just waiting for the right time.
Apparently out of
nowhere is the right time.
- Zander...
- No, no. It's fine.
I get it, you know. You're in college now.
It's good that you're
meeting all the new freshmen.
Actually, I'm her philosophy T.A.
Oh, wow.
You know, dating a teaching assistant
is really not allowed at my school.
But, hey, that's probably
a rule that was created
for no reason whatsoever.
(Chuckles)
Listen, we should really get going.
Okay, well, have fun you two lovebirds.
Or should I say one
sweet, innocent lovebird
and one much older predator.
Good-bye!
Okay, this is not a
judgment about the therapist,
but I just want to point out
that all the magazines here suck.
Joe, you promised you'd have an open mind.
- Right.
- And when we go in there,
- you'll participate, right?
- Yep.
And you'll use more than one syllable?
Done.
Look, Dr. Kathryn Miller is
the best therapist in the city.
She even saved my friend
Rebecca and Phil's marriage
and that was after Phil became felicity.
I'm just going to throw this out there.
That's not going to be our issue, okay?
Thanks for pointing that out, though.
And you can stop with the
sales pitch, Mel. I'm here.
Don't I get a sticker or
something for just showing up?
Yeah, Joe, that's why we're here.
For the stickers.
Oh, you must be...
Joe?
Katie?
Actually, I go by Kathryn here.
Oh, you guys know each other?
(Chuckles)
It's a funny story, actually, honey.
- We...
- Dated.
Briefly. Years ago.
She beat me to it.
If this is a problem,
I'm happy to waive my
24-hour cancellation fee.
No, don't, you're the
best therapist in the city
and it was tough to get
certain people down here.
Well, if neither of you have an issue,
I'm comfortable putting the past aside.
I mean, what happened between Joe and me
was so long ago.
- Years ago, actually.
- It's insignificant now.
Yeah, it was a blip. It was a blip, really.
Not even a blip, actually, more like a...
You know, a... blip!
Then we're good. This is not a big deal.
I can't tell you the amount
of times we've run into someone
I've hooked up with... I
mean, happens all the time.
Like, all the time.
Okay. Okay, Mel... Mel, thank you.
Let's save something for
the session, shall we?
So we were in the parking structure
and I suggested going up a level
but Joe refused, and I park
in that structure every day.
I mean, every day.
You know, I'm noticing a pattern here.
What I'm hearing is that Joe is, by nature,
very strong-willed and
not open to new ideas.
What do you think about that, Joe?
You really hit the nail on the head, Katie.
I mean, you are an
amazingly perceptive person.
So you agree this is
something you need to work on?
Absolutely. Absolutely.
100%. And thank you.
Thank you so much for
pointing that out to me.
I don't know why no one else
has ever said that to me before.
Are you kidding me?
I said that. I said that yesterday.
I think I would have remembered
if she had said something that insightful.
Clearly not.
Perhaps you're both right.
Sometimes it's difficult for
couples to really hear each other.
Wow, that is another great point, Katie.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Miller. (Laughs)
You know, this has been such an
eye-opening experience for me.
I mean, I guess sometimes
it really does take
a third person to come in and help
two people out with their problems.
I mean, you know, three
is greater than two.
It's really... It's really just math.
Right?
Yeah.
You know, Mel, one syllable responses
are not always the most helpful.
She's good.
- Zander.
- Surprise.
What are you doing here?
I was really hoping for,
"hey, have you been working out?"
'Cause I have.
Wait... what... you
have class in 10 minutes.
In Vermont.
You know, I think you're going to miss it.
I actually came into town
for my aunt's funeral.
Oh. Oh, my God.
I am so sorry. Come in.
Thanks. I appreciate it.
Actually, it was my aunt's
cat's funeral, but...
You know, now that he's gone,
it's really just a matter of time
before the old lady lets go too.
Anyways, point is, I'm here.
What about your midterms?
They let you make 'em up. I think.
You know what... I'll
just tell the Dean that
I was sad.
Gets you out of anything at art school.
Uh-huh...
Right, okay. So listen, len.
The untimely passing of my aunt's cat
has got me thinking.
Should you really be dating
your teaching assistant?
I mean, should anybody?
Really? 'Cause... ugh.
Oh, gee.
You know, the death of a cat affects us all
in different ways.
And some that are none
of your business, Zander.
Yeah, yeah, uh-huh. Understood.
So aren't you just like
a little bit concerned
that he'll treat you differently
than the other students?
Because, you know, you
treat him differently.
What, you think he'll
give me an automatic "A"
because I'm his girlfriend?
Not automatic. I mean, I'm
sure you'll have to work for it.
Excuse me?
No. No. Mm-mm.
No, see, the... What I meant was...
Is that he's... He's older, you know.
And he might abuse his power.
I'm 18 and he's 23, okay?
There is nothing wrong with that.
Mel: Lennox.
Oh, what did Mel and Joe say
when you told them you
were dating your T.A.?
Shh! They'll hear you.
Oh! You haven't told them yet
because you know what
you're doing is wrong... ha!
Oh, Zander.
I didn't know you were in town.
So what exactly is Lennox doing wrong?
Well, Mel, I hate to rat Lennox out.
But she's been...
Smuggling food out of the dining hall.
Oh, that's not wrong.
In politics, we define wrong
as "will anyone really notice?"
You know, speaking of which,
at the budget meeting today
I yelled out, "dibs on the bagels!"
Here you go. All right. Save me one.
Hey, Joe, we need to talk
about this morning's therapy session.
Happy to. Can't wait for the next session.
Yeah, well, that will be Tuesday
the 14th of never.
What was that little "teacher's
pet" routine of yours?
What are you talking about?
Come on! You spent the whole time
bending over backwards
trying to kiss her butt.
It was like watching the
Cirque du Soleil of ass-kissing.
Whoa, wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Hold up, hold up. Are you jealous?
Of a tall, beautiful,
highly-educated professional woman
you used to date?
Please.
Oh, come on. It was a long time ago.
It meant nothing, you know, and
after a short period of time,
- I broke up with her.
- You broke up with her?
Yeah, she wasn't what I was
looking for, so I ended it.
You broke up with her.
Yes, I broke up with her, all right?
It didn't matter to her
and it didn't matter to me.
And I thought it didn't matter to you,
but apparently I was wrong.
Wait, so if this wasn't about Kathryn,
then... okay. I get it.
You were trying to beat me at therapy.
Honey, please. It's not a competition.
Okay? (Laughs)
But if it was, probably
would have been a shutout.
You know, therapy is not
about who wins and loses.
It's about doing what's
best for the relationship.
But if it was a competition,
I would smoke you like a Cuban cigar.
Yeah, well, we'll just have
to see next time, won't we?
Mm-hmm.
Clearly we need help.
Yeah.
Oh, hi, Mel. Have you been here long?
Oh, don't worry, I didn't
hear anything you said
to your last patient.
Just the "wah, wah, nobody loves me" part.
Actually, I was in there by myself.
Kidding!
You know, Mel, I am impressed
that you're continuing
to see me even though
you know I dated Joe.
A lot of people wouldn't
be able to handle that.
It shows a lot of maturity.
Well, I'm impressed that you're okay
hearing about me and
Joe after he dumped you.
I have to say I am not on the best of terms
with a lot of the guys that
gave me the old heave-ho.
That's what Joe told you, is it?
- What do you mean?
- Oh, nothing.
Your face didn't really
look like, "oh, nothing."
Well, not to dredge up the past,
but I was definitely
the one who broke it off.
Not Joe.
Oh, okay. Well, I guess, you know,
Joe probably shaded the truth out of pride.
The therapeutic term for that is "lying."
Okay, but it's not that
big of a deal, right?
'Cause Joe promised he's
gonna work on himself.
Yes, but what if he's lying?
Since apparently he has no problem lying.
But you said in our last session
that Joe was making real progress.
Yes, but that's before
I knew about the lying.
Okay, could you stop
saying lying for a sec?
Listen, Mel,
I'm not saying this as your therapist,
but woman to woman,
I'd say that Joe's revisionist history
about who broke up with who
is just, well, very telling.
Telling like telling a fun story, or...
Telling of a larger issue.
I'm just glad I spotted
the warning signs early
and got out when I did.
Look, I know things didn't
work out with you and him,
but Joe and I have a great relationship.
And that's why you came
to see a therapist...
To talk about how great
your relationship is?
Our relationship is solid.
We just came in for a little tune-up.
Listen, Mel, if I could give you
a piece of advice about Joe...
Run! Run while you still can.
But, well, Joe loves me.
And if he can't be honest with you now,
what's gonna happen in the future?
(Door opening)
Hey! I'm here, I'm here.
I'm so sorry I'm late. What did I miss?
Nothing. We haven't started yet.
Oh, good.
(Stammers) I just
remembered... I have a thing.
You have a thing? What thing?
A big thing. A thing we can't miss.
And we have to go right
now and never come back.
But wait, what?!
I can't believe I forgot
about it until just now. Bye!
But I... I... I just paid for parking.
It was like eight dollars.
Oh, my goodness. Check out this drivel
your fellow student wrote
on the hegelian dialectic.
"Mr. Hegel's cool ideas
never truly go out of style."
Uh, you know what, babe?
I really don't think you
should read that to me.
You're right.
Just hearing it could
kill brain cells. "D."
Oh, wait.
No, his parents are alumni.
(Winces) "C."
Ooh.
Here's an interesting
test by Lennox Scanlon.
Oh, you know what?
I... I can leave the
room while you grade it.
No, no, no. You don't have to do that.
Your smokin' hot presence won't sway me.
Okay, well, just don't tell me my grade.
Shh, shh, shh. I'm reading something.
Something very intelligent
that bears out my choice in girlfriends.
Uh-oh!
What's uh-oh?
You didn't answer the question
on the back of the page.
(Gasps) There was a question on the back?
Lennox, relax... I know you know
the supposed contradictions
between being and not being.
We talked about this. Right?
Yeah, but...
Check. "A."
What are you doing?
I'm just giving you the
grade you deserve, babe.
Um, okay.
And just act all surprised
when I hand back the tests.
Like it's your birthday.
Hmm...
So, then... what do you
want to do, Ms. Burke?
Well, you know, I thought
I knew until this afternoon.
Oh, you mean about the air-conditioning?
Um, I... I don't know.
What do you think, Wayne?
I say dump it.
You know I've always told you the truth.
You're better off replacing
it with a new system
that doesn't have so many issues.
But I like this one.
I mean, even though it
can be loud and annoying
and sometimes I want to smack it...
Huh?
I mean, I'm comfortable
with this one, you know?
I mean, the current air-conditioning unit.
I don't know. You stick with this one,
it's just gonna cause you a world of pain.
But what if this system is the one?
You know, for my house.
I mean, I don't appreciate
people telling me
I should get rid of something
I've lived with for so long
and can see spending
the rest of my life with.
This isn't really about
the air conditioner, is it?
How 'bout I come back in a week or two
after you've had a chance
to collect your thoughts...
On air-conditioning.
(Sobbing)
Yeah?
Hi. I have something for you.
Oh, is it unsolicited advice
on how to live my life?
'Cause I'm all stocked up.
No, no. It's just some new
artwork for our web series.
Shouldn't you be getting back to school?
Yeah. I've got my meeting
with the Dean tomorrow,
so I'm working on my look
of despair. How's this?
Stick out your lower lip a little bit.
Yeah, there you go.
Come in.
But hey, you know, while I'm here,
I just want to say
I'm really sorry about yesterday.
When I implied that you're
getting special treatment
by dating your T.A. I was way off base.
'Cause you're like the most
principled person I know.
Don't say that, please.
No, it's true. And I just say that
because I really care about you.
As a friend. Not as a girlfriend.
'Cause, you know, that's
where we're at right now,
because you're... because
you're with someone else. Right?
Yes, I am.
I should be getting back to Vermont.
Right.
So, bye.
I gotta go.
Hey, Mel. I got a guy in the garage
waiting for a training session,
but I saw your car in the driveway
so I just wanted to come say hi.
Oh, hello.
Hey, um... are you okay?
'Cause you seemed a little...
Upset this afternoon.
Oh, I was. But, you know, I'm okay now.
This helped.
All right.
(Sighing)
Hey, Joe, can I ask you a quick question?
Sure. What's up?
Are we gonna make it?
Of course.
What are we talking about?
Be honest. Do you think
we have a future together?
As a couple?
Where's this coming from, Mel?
Well, uh... when I talked to Kathryn today
she told me something very interesting.
She said that she broke up with you.
Is that true?
You know what? Now that I think about it
that... That is what happened.
So then why did you tell me you dumped her?
Man, it's hot in here.
The A.C. guy ever come over today or what?
Don't change the subject.
Look, Mel, um... there's
a perfectly good explanation
for all this, okay? And once you hear it,
it will answer all of your questions.
I lied.
How could you do that?
Do you want a relationship built on lies?
Wait a minute, now. It's
not lies. It was a lie.
And you wouldn't have even known
about it if I hadn't told you.
You didn't tell me.
Point taken.
Why would you lie to me?
It's not what you think, all right?
I... I lied to, um...
To what, Joe?
I lied because I didn't want you to think
you were dating somebody's cast-off.
That's why you did it?
Yes, yes. Okay?
Because you deserve the
best and I'm not always that.
And you know, I... I guess I thought
that if you knew that she dumped me
that you'd think less of me,
and, you know, I kind of...
I... I want to be seen
as perfect in your eyes.
Oh, Joe. I'll never see you that way.
Thanks a lot.
No, it's just that, you know,
I guess I'm not done
trying to impress you yet.
Oh, and I hope you never are.
Hey, you know, I don't think
it's so bad that we argue.
We don't argue. Who says we argue?
Okay! We disagree with volume
and drive each other insane.
But you know, we get it all out.
We don't hold anything back.
Yeah? I'm actually kinda
holding something back right now.
It's got nothing to do
with arguing, though.
(Laughs)
Don't you have a client to train?
Yeah, I told him to warm up
for ten minutes on the stairmaster.
That means we got nine whole minutes, baby.
Come on.
Hey Wayne.
I'm sorry to bother you, Ms. Burke.
Yeah, wayne, I thought we weren't
going to talk for a couple of weeks.
- This couldn't wait.
- What is it?
Your air conditionner is perfectly fine.
That's why I'm here.
But you told me to dump it.
You said it was outmoded and would
cause me nothing but pain and heartache.
I lied.
I've been getting a lot of pressure
from the suits to sell the new systems.
That's where all the profit is, but,
then I felt terrible, because, well,
our relationship
is more important than
moving some new condenser.
But the air conditioner's
not working properly.
Nah...
you just don't know how to set it.
I can show you.
Wait, wait, wait, so you're saying
my system is fine and wonderful?
Yeah.
This could be the last system you ever buy.
It should last a lifetime.
Bless you!
Sync & Corrections by Darcade
- Addicted.com -