At this very moment
in the town of Couer d'Couers
Young Ned was 9 years, 27 weeks,
6 days and 3 minutes old.
His dog Digby was 3 years, 2 weeks,
6 days, 5 hours, and 9 minutes old.
And not a minute older.
This was the moment young Ned realized
he wasn't like the other children.
Nor was he like anyone
else for that matter.
Young Ned could touch dead things
and bring them back to life.
Transcript
www.All-About-Subs.fr
A.a.S. Team
This touch was a gift given to him,
but not by anyone in particular.
There was no box, no instructions,
no manufactures warantee.
It just was.
The terms of use weren't
immediately clear,
Nor were they of immediate concerned.
Yound Ned was in love...
Her name was Chuck.
At this very moment she was 8 years
42 weeks 3 hours and 2 minutes old.
Young Ned did not think of her as being
born or hatched or conceived in anyway
Chuck came ready-made
from the Play-Doh fun factory of life.
In their imaginations, yound Ned and the
girl named Chuck conquered the world.
Long after their play date was over,
young Ned remained under Chuck spell.
Until a blood vessel in his mother's
brain burst, killing her instantly.
Must have slipped.
Clumsy. Did the timer go off?
Young Ned's random gift that was,
came with a caveator too.
It was a gift that not only gave...
...but took.
Young Ned discovered he could
only bring the dead back to life
for one minute without consequences.
Any longer and someone else had to die.
In the grand universal scheme of things,
young Ned traded his mother's life
for Chuck's father.
Come on big Neddy, go to bed
But there was one more thing
about touching
dead things that young Ned didn't know.
And he learned it
in the most unfortunate way.
First touch : life.
Second touch : dead again, forever.
He maketh me to lie down
in green pastures.
After a brief mourning period,
Young Ned's father would
hustle him off to boarding school.
Never to be seen again.
Chuck would be fostered
by aunts Lily and Vivian,
A renowned synchronized swimming duo
They shared matching personality
disorders and a love for fine cheese.
At their respective parent's funerals
Dizzy with grief, curiosity and hormons
Young Ned and the girl named Chuck,
had their first and only kiss.
After his mother's death,
Ned avoided social attachments,
fearing what he'd do if someone
else he loved died.
And he became obsessed with pies.
It's 19 years 34 weeks
1 day and 59 minutes later,
Hereto for known as now.
Young Ned has become the pie-maker.
And this is where he makes his pies.
The peaches never brown,
the dead fruit in his hand becomes ripe
with everlasting flavor
as long as he only touches it once.
Every day I come in, I pick a pie,
I concentrate all my love on that pie,
if I love it, someone else is gonna
love it, and you know what?
By the end of the day,
I've sold more of those pies
than any other pie in the bakery.
- Yeah? What pie do you love today?
- Rhubarb.
I'll stick with three plum, a la mode.
Emerson Cod was the sole keeper
of the pie-maker's secret
And this ishow he came to be the sole
keeper of the pie-maker's secret
A private investigator,
Mr. Cod met the pie-maker
when his Pie Hole was
on the verge of financial ruin.
Mr. Cod proposed a partnership.
Murders are much easier to solve when
you can ask the victim who killed them.
The pie-maker reluctantly agreed.
I asked you not to use the word zombie,
it's disrespectful
Gamboling around, squawking for brain,
that's not how they do.
And undead, nobody
wants to be un-anything,
Why begin to stick with the negative?
It's like saying : I don't disagree,
just to say you agree.
Are you confortable with living dead?
You're either living or you're dead
When you're living your life when
you're dead,
that's what you are but when you're dead
and then you're not, you're alive again.
Can't we say alive again?
Didn't that sound nice?
It sounds like you are narcoleptic.
I suffer from sudden
uncontrolable attacks of deep sleep.
- What's the other?
- Necrophiliac?
Well, all these sounds are
mixed up in my head.
Me too. I used to think
masturbation meant chewing your food.
I don't think that anymore.
Can you lock the door behind you?
So you want in on
this opportunity or not?
A dog is involved.
- What kind of dog?
- He's gonna be a dead dog.
A dead dog named Cantaloupe.
They put her down in allegedly
killed her owner.
- When you say allegedly...
- Cantaloupe was framed.
Someone put a part of the victim
in her mouth.
Docile as a kitten, says the family.
Despite of being a Chow, the breed
most likely to turn on its owner.
That's racial profiling, look at you.
If the dog is innocent,
then it's murder.
And if it's murder,
then there's a reward.
The facts were these :
one Leonard Gaswint
39 years, 42 weeks, 5 days,
3 hours and 26 minutes old,
was found mauled to death
in his own office.
His dog Cantaloupe was the sole witness
and only suspect in the murder.
Convinced of her innocence,
the Gaswint family
afford a significant reward
to find the real killer.
You're the dog expert?
Already had a dog expert.
I'm the other one.
Fine, but my threshold's pretty high,
so you have to takewhat I say
with a grain of salt.
That ain't a grain of salt.
that's what them blokes
they give cows to lick.
He can't help how he is.
That don't make any less dramatic.
- For who?
- Me.
And I'm sure him, but mainly me.
I'm gonna wait outside.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Sorry to disturb you Mr. Gaswint
or Leonard,
- do you prefer--
- Leo!
Your current condition...
Do I have something right here?
There's nothing right there.
- Damn dog.
- Cantaloupe?
No, Cantaloupe is docile as a kitten.
It's that Rottweiler,
my secretary sicked her dog on me.
She's been upset
since last year's Christmas party.
You know, it's a funny story...
Was it the Chow?
The secretary... with her Rottweiler.
Her good name cleared
and her execution stayed,
Cantaloupe was freed.
And the secretary
and her Rottweiler were hold to justice.
An anonymous tip led
to solving the murder
of a Michigan entrepreneur thought
to be mauled to death by a family pet.
The truth however is much more sinister.
Olive Snook enjoyed
her time with Digby.
He was a surrogate
for the human connection
she wanted with the pie-maker.
Her desperate attempts to connect
to someone
so disconnected terrified him.
But that didn't stop her from trying.
How was your convention?
Conventional.
How is Digby?
Neurotic. He's a very nutty dog.
Do you pet him?
Maybe if you pet him once in a while,
he wouldn't be so neurotic.
I pet him, I'm allergic so I can't
actually touch him but I pet him.
With a stick? How do you pet him?
A stick is involved but it's more like
a handle to a... handing device.
A dog needs to be touched.
We all need to be touched.
You touch him. Other people touch him.
He's your dog.
Do you...
... touch anything?
Of course, I...
I touch lots of things.
With affection.
When was the last time
someone touched you with affection?
I get touched...
Can you get Digby's leash now?
You don't mind
that I don't touch you, do you?
And then came the event
that changed everything.
... the body of a young woman
allegedly murdered
aboard a cruise ship
has been recovered from the sea.
The victim's identity
is being withheld...
The pie-maker listened
intently to the news,
unaware that he stopped breathing.
He was haunted by the name of this woman
who met her end on the high seas.
Oh, my... here's your leash.
But he didn't know why...
Her name is still withheld,
very little is known of the victim
who was reportedly traveling alone
when murdered aboard
a passenger ship that was returning
from a tropical cruise sailing between
the United States and Tahiti.
The ship's captain initially
dismissed the death as an accident,
suggesting the victim likely
returned from a late night out...
Been watching the news lately?
Doesn't seem like much going on in
the world besides a dead girl on a boat.
I'd going on with that dead girl.
Is that so?
50 000 $ with the dead so...
- You're interested in a conversation?
- Yeah, I could be persuaded.
Well, you better be persuaded quick
as the dead girl's about
to go into ground.
They just put her out of the water.
Jewish.
Christians leave them laying around,
Jews got to get them buried.
- Where’re we going?
- Couer d' Couers.
- You ever been there?
- I grew up there. Sort of...
This dead girl from Couer d' Couers,
does she have a name?
Charlotte Charles...
Chuck...
The pie-maker
never returned to Couer d'Couers
after being sent away to school.
But he thought of Chuck everyday.
- You know this girl?
- I know of her.
Know of her in the biblical sense?
I haven't thought of her since I was 10.
Think of her a lot when you were 10?
Don't remember anything when I was 10.
The pie-maker remembers everything.
The facts were these...
Charlotte Charles, 28 years, 24 weeks,
3 days, 11 hours and 51 minutes old
was found floating in the ocean moments
after her body was discarded there.
Discarded by whom
seemed to be a question
only Charlotte Charles could answer.
The funeral director,
always eager to supplement his income,
Gentlemen.
was more than happy to grant
the deceased an audience.
I just wanna... I wanna...
Can I do this one alone?
On account of... you know...
the whole historical context of...
You have something
personal you need to say?
No...
OK, maybe. But I've nothing
to gain but a small amount of closure
What do you got so
open that needs closure?
Just wanna say I'm sorry for something,
one of those stupid things kids do,
they don't know they're doing.
Yeah, well,
you ask who killed her first.
- OK.
- You only got a minute.
- I know.
- 60 seconds.
- All right.
Only Prince Charming could know
how the pie-maker
felt upon looking at her.
Great thought was taken
as to where to touch her.
The lip's too forward
The cheek...
The cheek.
- Chuck, wait!
- Who are you?
You remember the little boy who lived
next door to you when your dad died?
Ned? Oh, my God! Hey, how are you?
Good, you look great.
You know what's happening right now?
I had the strangest dream, I was being
strangled to death with a plastic sack.
You were strangled to death
with a plastic sack.
That's probably an odd thing to hear but
I wasn't quite sure how to sugar-code it
You only have a minute... less.
What can I do in less than a minute?
You could tell me who killed you,
so... you know, justice can be served.
Well, that's really sweet
but I don't know who killed me.
I went to go to get ice
and I dropped my room key
in the icemaker, as I was thinking,
... "That was dumb".
- She was thinking, "That was dumb",
Chuck was strangled
to death with a plastic sack.
And then you touched my cheek.
- What's going on?
- Just a second!
- Is my time up?
- I'm sorry.
Well... thanks for calling me Chuck.
Do you know, nobody's
called me Chuck since...
... since you.
And I used to,
when I lived next door to you...
I had a cr... I was in...
You were my first kiss.
Yeah?
You were my first kiss too.
You wanna be my last kiss?
First and last? Is that weird?
That's not weird.
It's magical.
Chuck's minute of life was nearly over.
The pie-maker's lips went
as far as they would go.
He couldn't will them to go any further.
And as a consequence...
... the funeral director
would go no further.
Hey, if you don't wanna kiss me,
it's OK. I just thought it may be...
No, I want to, I do, I...
What if you didn't have to... be dead.
Well, that would be preferable.
Nobody can know.
Hop in !
I got to think of a way
to get you out of here.
Can you lie really still,
until I get back?
Doesn't know. Didn't know.
So somebody just threw
her carcass over boat
- Why're you sweating?
- I'm... It's warm in there. What?
- Your eye's twitching.
- My eye?
You eye is twitching.
When people aren't being honest,
their eye twitches.
Right there. Like yours did just now.
It's nerves.
Aggravated by a stomach thing.
It's like acid reflux but in my eye.
I think I'm gonna stay for the service.
Is that so?
Just feeling nostalgic. Do you remember
how get back to the station?
It's down the... I'll catch you
later boss.
Lying in the dark, Chuck considered
how she came to be lying in the dark.
She considered the life
that was with aunts Lily and Vivian.
That personality disorders blossomed
into incapacitating social phobia.
Which made it difficult
for them to leave the house.
Which in turn made it difficult
for Chuck to leave them.
She served her community
by harvesting honey for the homeless.
She never strayed far from home.
She read about people
she could never be,
and adventures she would never have.
Life was good enough,
until one day, it wasn't.
Chuck wanted more.
But at Boutique Travel Travel Boutique,
she got more than she bargained for.
Hey, I think somebody's truck's on fire.
Oh Jesus!
Sorry I'm late.
Only Sleeping Beauty could know
how she felt at this moment.
I can't even hug you,
what if you need a hug?
A hug can turn your day around.
I'm not a fan of hug.
Then you haven't been hug properly,
it's like an emotional Heimlich
someone puts their arms around you
and they give you a squeeze and...
All your fear and anxiety
come shooting out of your mouth
and a big white light and
you can breath again.
That's fine for someone else to do
if I'm chocking on something other
than emotion but
you can't touch me.
So a kiss is out of the question?
I've lost my train of thought.
How long have you been thinking
about this?
Like thinking thinking?
That was unpremeditaded,
I wasn't lining in wait,
more like I was musing on the idea
not you know,
dwelling,
there was time I did dwell on you
about you, a little.
But I was't seriously considering
till the exact moment I did it
or didn't do it...
I was wondering if you'd come back.
I guess you came back
when I needed you most.
Well that would have been
before I was killed,
but this worked out.
You understand you can't go back, right?
You can't see your aunts.
they'll go off their rockers
without me besides
they're shut-in,
it's not like they talk to anybody.
People are used to this sort of thing.
Issues of morality,
how come she's not dead anymore.
It'd be a disaster.
I suppose dying is as good an excuse
as any to start living.
This is Digby.
Wasn't your old dog named Digby?
This is him.
Did you...?
And now is here?
Yeah.
You seem to do that a lot.
Why do you do that a lot?
It's just the two of you.
I hate to be a bad host
but I'm sort of exhausted
- from chasing your coffin.
- Oh yeah, of course.
I'm gonna sleep here,
you take the bed, I insist.
My eyes are rolling back into my head.
I'm lying down now.
I'd kiss you but it would kill me.
28 year-old lonely tourist
Charlotte Charles
was laid to rest earlier today.
She is survived by her aunts,
Vivian and Lili Charles,
In a strange bed,
watching her own funeral
on the evening news,
Chuck was strucked
by the undignified nature of celibrity.
No one wants to be famous
for the way they died.
Boutique Travel Travel Boutique
has offered a $50,000 reward
in the murder of Charlotte Charles.
Ned?
Would I be alive right now
if I knew who killed me?
Of course, don't be silly,
that's something in the news
about the reward.
You said you wanted to know who killed
me so that justice can be served.
And I don't think
justice was on the menu,
maybe is a side dish,
but not as an entree.
It's most definitely an entree.
It was a special of the day.
Can we drop the metaphore?
I wouldn't have known you had died
if it weren't for the reward.
When were you gonna tell me?
In the morning, or when it came up
which ever didn't come first.
$50,000, that makes a lot of pie.
25,000, I have a business partner.
- What? It's a business?
- Not in the traditionnal sense.
You touch murdered victims,
you ask who killed them,
you touch them again,
they go back to being dead,
and then you...
collect the reward ?
That's it in a nutshell.
So you're after my reward?
I'm not mad at you,
I just want to know...
I'll be mad at you
if you lie to me though.
I don't want your reward.
I'll be so mad if you're lying,
you have me scratching the drapes.
I'm not lying.
Please don't attack
the window treatments.
Okay, go back to sleep.
I'm a friend of Ned's.
Does he touch you?
-  So how was the service?
- You know, I just paid my respects.
You are not going to get paid.
Might see a dead woman
speaking to you in confidence
as an opportunity to make
a whole lot of money by you lonesome.
- Regardless our prior arrangements.
- There's no opportunity here.
Are you the business partner?.
- Yes, M'am.
- Found her upstairs.
Doesn't she look a lot
like that dead girl?
She looks exactly like that dead girl.
You should take that as a compliment,
she was pretty.
Pie time.
Pie time?
I've been ruminating and by ruminating;
I mean pondering not chewing cud.
How about we solve my murder
and collect the reward?
wouldn't that be poetic?
Certainly an anecdote.
She's supposed to be in the ground.
I thought you didn't want the reward.
No, I wanted you not to want
the reward. $50,000 is a lot of money.
Three way split.
30 - 30 - 40 ?
It's only fair I get more;
I did die for it.
I'm not a detective, I make pies.
You can't just touch somebody's life
and be done with it.
Yes I can, that's how I roll.
I could do 30 - 30 - 40.
She's supposed to be dead.
You're supposed to be dead.
- This is pushing your luck.
- Yeah, well,
luck pushed me first.
It's just so shockingly stupid,
I have a hard time believing you did it.
You just agreed to be her partner.
I did the profit from your stupidity.
Are you in love with her?
Cause if it's that level of stupid...
I admit to be confused,
it's a very confusing time
and childhood issues,
digging in the dirt, it's all coming up.
You know what?
We all have childhood issues, okay?
Believe me,
I got the full subscription, okay?
- Horror stories.
- I kinda kill her dad when I was 10.
Maybe not horror stories.
She doesn't know.
But I wanted to make it better
or different in what it was because
what it was was her dead and
I didn't that to be my fault too.
But who died instead?
It's a random proximity thing.
- Bitch! I was in proximity.
- I wasn't thinking.
I wonder what happened to him.
He was a very very bad man.
He stole stuff off dead people
and sold it on the internet.
- It's all on the obituary.
- That's nice.
The fact
that he was a very very bad man
makes you feel better
about what you did?
Yes, immensely.
I would've felt horrible if it was...
you for example.
I'm not proud.
You know what? I'm glad you did it.
Makes the worst thing I ever did
seem insignificant.
Listen to you, all judgy judge.
Judgy judge?
Look.
You don't know anything about this girl
except she got herself killed.
I'm not who you think I am.
Who does he think you are?
The small town girl
who never saw the world,
only to have her first time out
be her last.
Well, that is who I am but
I was hoisted by my own petard.
What's the petard?
In my case,
the petard is that Tahitian getaway
was a devil's bargain.
- Who's the devil?
- Deedee Dafield.
Manager Boutique Travel Travel Boutique.
She offered me a high seas adventure
at no cost.
What I had to do was pick up a package.
- Are you a drug mule?
- No.
I'm a monkey mule.
And these are the
monkeys on the question.
You died for a pair of plaster monkeys.
Deedee said they weren't worth much,
their only value was sentimental.
Those must have been
some emotional monkeys.
You should ask Deedee about all of this,
I'm very curious as what she has to say.
Boutique Travel Travel Boutique
manager Deedee Dafield
hoped the $50,000 reward
would catch her killer
before her killer caught her.
The reward failed short
of achieving its desired goal.
I guess I can't be too mad at her.
Is that how they found me?
It's humiliating.
How long she's been here?
Touch the poor bitch and ask her.
I'm sort of embarrassed to do it
in front of you.
Hey, Charlotte.
Hey, Deedee.
How'd I know you'd be the first person
I'd see when I got to...
Is this...
Which one is this?
This is neither.
Well, maybe it's both,
but listen, this is the deal.
You get to talk for like a minute,
we're gonna catch up
and then you're not talking anymore.
Does everyone get to do this?
Cause, girl, we got to break it down.
Did you know I was gonna get killed?
I thought there might
be the possibility,
yes, I'm really sorry about that,
I probably should've said something.
But to be honest, and...
really why not at this point?
If it was safe,
I would've done it myself.
God, this is fantastic.
Being honest is fun.
Ask her who killed her and you
and what's with the monkeys.
Who are those peaople?
That's Emerson,
I don't really know him,
and this is Ned.
He was my first kiss.
You're adorable.
Look at...
You couldn't have...
Scooted back a little.
I didn't know she was gonna
touch my cheek, who does that?
Actually, she does that a lot.
All right, but why would
whoever killed you kill her
when he already got his monkeys?
I dropped my key in the icemaker,
he couldn't get into my room.
For christ's sake.
This is a nightmare.
He doesn't have the monkeys.
When you get murdered on a boat,
where do they send your things?
Your next of kin.
You stay here.
I just want to look in the window.
You can't. You could have your pie
but you can't eat it,
that's the way it works.
- You're making me hungry.
I was supposed to keep them
sane and I left.
I'd just die if anything
happened to them,
I mean I'd die... again.
We'll make sure your aunts are safe
and then we'll call the police.
I wish I could give you
an emotional Heimlich
'cause you could cough up that
all your fear and anxiety but I can't.
Give her a hug.
That was from me.
Aunt Vivian and Aunt Lily were
all Chuck had
and before Chuck
all they had was each other.
While still in their teens they made
a name for themselves as the
"Darling Mermaid Darlings".
Many, many, many years later
still holding on to their fading
glory as underwater artists
their lifes were changed forever,
when Lily, while cleaning the litterbox,
got dirty cat sand in her eye.
Not only did she lose her eye
but the "Darling Mermaid Darlings"
lost their careers.
They retreated behind a fence
and made sure the world
stayed on the other side.
Hello?
Hi, my name is Ned.
I lived next door 20 years ago.
I am... was a friend of Chuck's.
Charlotte's, rather.
Please, come in.
Please.
Charlotte was a firecracker, always
trying to get us out of the house,
threatening to bake antidepressants
into our food.
It got to the point I was scared
to eat anything she cooked.
She was a good cook and a nice girl.
Do you like girls?
Yes, M'am.
Didn't want to assume...
Charlotte was a nice girl.
With the exception of puberty...
Which was unfortunately when Lily
was going through a change of life.
Impolite to discuss a person's menopause
in mixed company.
It nearly killed me
Horrible, the way Charlotte died.
On a cruise...
Lasts days spent surrounded
by middle-aged overweight women
who wear sweatshirts with things
sewed to them.
Usually kittens made a felt too.
Food is perfectly atrocious.
Unless she enjoyed
vomiting and diarrhea,
I can't imagine
she had a good last meal.
Good last meal van go a long way.
Our penal systems makes a point of it.
It's nice she had a little glimpse
of the world before she died.
Nah, the world isn't that great.
Well, at least she had the good sense
not to fly.
Airplanes fall out of
the sky every day.
Cheese. I would recommend
the pure goat with blue ash...
it has a grassy flavor.
It does, I have a grassy flavor.
It's delicious with Charlotte's honey.
You haven't lived
until you've tasted her honey.
The homeless love it.
Not to change the subjects but,
has the cruiseline returned
her belongings?
Specifically a stainless
steel briefcase.
Chuck couldn't remember why she was
so desperate to leave this life behind.
She missed her aunts,
she missed her bees.
She missed everything she was.
Hello?
Smuggling monkeys put
an end to her life.
Chuck didn't want to be remembered
as the lonely tourist.
She wanted to be remembered
as something sweeter.
Unaware of Lily's fate upstairs,
the pie-maker did his best
to comfort Vivian.
Charlotte always wanted to get away.
She got away further
than any of us thought.
In a rare moment of sensitivity,
he reached out and touched her.
Not realizing she didn't like
being touched.
I go see if she needs
any help bringing it down.
Didn't I kill you?
I can hold my breath for a long time.
The jig appeared to be up.
Aunt Lily was looking
directly at her niece.
Her niece who wasn't supposed
to be alive.
And if she possessed
two good eyes...
She would have seen her.
A rush of warmth
washed over the pie-maker.
He would later describe
this feeling as "delight".
The girl he rescued from death
had returned the favor.
Former "Darling Mermaid Darlings"
Vivian and Lily Charles
defeated a deadly home invader
who may have some connection
to the smuggling-related murder
of their niece
lonely tourist
Charlotte Charles.
When asked about a
"Darling Mermaid Darlings" reunion,
the sisters mentioned
a benefit performance to support
"Honey for the Homeless"
was in the works.
Was this really an act of kindness?
Me, here...
Were you really trying
to do something good
for no other reason than to help me?
I was being selfish.
I'd love to tell myself
I was being unselfish
but I know deep down in
my premier sweet spot
I was being unselfish
for selfish reasons.
I just thought, my world would be
a better place if you were in it.
Is there anything else I should know?
The pie-maker wanted to tell Chuck
about that fateful afternoon
when he inadvertently
killed her father, but instead he said:
No.
Well I figure since they cost me my
life, I should get to keep at least one.
And seeing that I wouldn't be alive
if it wasn't for you...
I want you to have the other one.
It's like those
little half-heart pendants...
except with monkeys.
Thank you for bringing me back to life.
You're welcome.
Oh, these are heavy...
The monkeys value was significantly
more than sentimental...
They were golden.
The man who killed Chuck
was killed by Aunt Lily.
After collecting the $50,000 reward,
Vivian and Lily had
a renewed interest in the world
on the other side of their fence.
They retreated
from their retreat...
and took the plunge.
Emerson Cod was plunged
into something else altogether...
A three-way split.
You know this whole thing is sorta like
reincarnation but more immediate.
Sorta.
Do you believe in reincarnation?
Hell no.
The planet's falling appart.
Right now, it's the children's problem.
We reincarnate, it's our problem.
- Afternoon.
- You're the toxicologist?
Yes.
Aren't you the dog expert?
No.
The facts were these:
One Matthew Miltonburger, 37 years,
6 hours and 45 minutes old,
was found stabbed to death
in a public restroom.
Before Mr. Miltonburger could get
into the specifics of his demise...
Chuck thought it would be nice to ask:
- Hi
Do you have any last words
or thoughts or requests?
- What?
- Just something I never thought to ask.
As he stared at her, he reached
around his back and held his own hand,
pretending he was holding hers.
And at that very moment,
she was pretending to be holding his.
Transcript & synchro
Trystero, Babybello, Toupack & Shadow
With help of Jesslataree,
LucasCorso, Teewee, The Lovers
www.All-About-Subs.fr
A.a.S. Team