ONE, TWO, THREE, FOUR...
ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR, FIVE, SIX.
SHAKE IT, DUDE.
[ ?????? ]
Men:
[ Shouting/cheering ]
[ ?????? ]
FROM HIGH SCHOOL
SENIOR TO GO-GO BOY
IN LESS THAN A YEAR.
IT'S GOT TO
BE A RECORD.
Ted:
ANOTHER SUCCESS
STORY FROM
FATHER KINNEY'S
HOME FOR
RUNAWAY BOYS.
AND TO THINK SOME
PEOPLE SAY HE
DOESN'T MAKE A
GOOD ROLE MODEL.
IF I WERE BRIAN,
I'D GO CRAZY
SEEING ALL
THOSE GUYS PAWING
MY BOYFRIEND.
YOU KNOW, IT
MUST BE TRUE
WHAT THEY SAY
ABOUT DEAFENING
MUSIC DAMAGING
YOUR EARDRUMS.
I COULD SWEAR
I HEARD YOU SAY
IF YOU WERE ME...
COME ON, IT'S GOT TO
BOTHER YOU A LITTLE BIT.
I MEAN, EVERY-
BODY KNOWS
THE ONLY WAY YOU GET
TO DANCE ON THE BAR
IS IF YOU LET THE
BOSS BLOW YOU.
IT'S BUSINESS.
Emmett:
GETTING HEAD
TO GET AHEAD?
HE'S EARNING AN
HONEST LIVING,
NOT TAKING ANY HANDOUTS.
CHECK OUT HOW MUCH
MONEY I'M MAKING.
THAT'S ENOUGH
TO PUT A CHILD
THROUGH SCHOOL.
SHOULDN'T THE
CHILD BE AT
HOME, IN BED?
THAT'S A
GOOD IDEA.
I CAN'T. I HAVE
TO WORK TILL 2:00.
BUT, SWEETIE,
YOU ALREADY
LOOK EXHAUSTED.
HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO KEEP IT UP?
ESPECIALLY AT HOME.
Justin:
DON'T WORRY.
I'M NOT PAYING YOU
TO MAKE OUT WITH
YOUR BOYFRIEND.
I'M ON A BREAK.
BREAK'S OVER.
RELAX, SAP. HE'S KEEPING
YOUR CUSTOMERS HAPPY.
IT'S SAPPERSTEIN,
KINNEY.
AND THEY'RE MY
CUSTOMERS, NOT YOURS.
COME ON, YOU'RE
MINE FOR THE
NEXT FOUR HOURS.
WHAT AN ASSHOLE.
[ ?????? ]
UM, DID I EVER
MENTION THAT
I... I HAVE
AN IRRATIONAL,
BUT NEVERTHELESS
QUITE INTENSE
FEAR OF ANY
PHYSICAL ACTIVITY
THAT DOESN'T TAKE
PLACE IN BED?
COME ON, IT'S JUST
HORSEBACK RIDING.
DON'T BE
SUCH A SISSY.
ANY OTHER
IMPOSSIBLE REQUESTS?
COME ON. WHERE'S
YOUR SENSE OF
ADVENTURE?
UH, RIGHT BACK
IN THE COZY,
WARM BED THAT I
CRAWLED OUT OF
TO FREEZE MY
PRECIOUS BUNS
OFF OUT HERE
WITH YOU.
WELL, IT'S TIME
YOU TRIED SOME-
THING DARING, HUH?
SOMETHING NEW.
YEAH, I'M
PERFECTLY HAPPY
WITH MY BORING
LITTLE LIFE RIGHT
HERE IN PITTSBURGH.
HAVEN'T YOU
EVER WANTED
TO TRAVEL?
HUH? GO AROUND
THE WORLD?
I BELIEVE WE DID
THAT LAST NIGHT.
I MEAN FOR REAL.
[ Chuckle ]
COME ON, EMMETT,
WHEN YOU WERE
A LITTLE BOY
GROWING UP
IN HAZELHURST,
WHAT DID YOU
DREAM OF?
GETTING OUT.
WHAT ELSE?
WHERE DID YOU
DREAM OF GOING?
BILOXI.
IT WAS THE
NEAREST AIRPORT.
AH. AND
AFTER THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
NEW YORK,
PARIS, ROME.
ANY PLACE
AUDREY HEPBURN
EVER MADE A MOVIE.
[ Chuckling ]
AND WHERE THERE
WEREN'T GUYS
IN SHIT-KICKERS,
KICKING THE
SHIT OUT OF ME.
BUT I ONLY GOT AS
FAR AS PITTSBURGH.
WELL, NOW YOU
CAN GO ANYWHERE
YOU WANT.
THE WORLD
IS YOURS.
IT'S YOURS
AND MINE.
SO JUST SAY
THE WORD.
THE WORLD
IS, UH...
MINE.
[ Chuckling ]
Michael:
AROUND THE WORLD?
THE ENTIRE WORLD?
Emmett:
YEAH. BORA-BORA,
THE HIMALAYAS,
THE SERENGETI...
[ Chuckling ]
GEORGE SAYS WE
COULD BE GONE SIX
MONTHS, A YEAR.
WOW! I MEAN, A TRIP
LIKE THAT ISN'T
JUST A VACATION.
THAT'S A LIFE
EXPERIENCE.
HMM.
THERE'S SO
MANY PLACES
I WANT TO GO.
LIKE WHERE?
OH, CHINA,
JAPAN,
TIBET
TO MEDITATE.
I WANT TO
GO TO BERLIN,
AMSTERDAM,
PRAGUE.
GREAT ART,
GREAT HISTORY.
GREAT MEN.
[ Chuckling ]
YOU DON'T HAVE TO LEAVE
LIBERTY AVENUE TO GET
INTERNATIONAL CUISINE.
FRENCH TOAST,
BELGIAN WAFFLE
AND A SPANISH OMELETTE FOR
OUR OWN LITTLE JET-SETTER.
[ Chuckling ]
OH, D-DEBBIE?
YES, BEN?
UH, I'M SORRY.
WH-WHAT ABOUT
MY BREAKFAST?
WORKING ON IT. I HAVE
JUST SO MANY HANDS.
THAT IS SUCH CRAP. YOU
ALWAYS GET SERVED LAST.
AND WHEN IT
ARRIVES, IT'S COLD.
YEAH, WELL, I DID
ORDER WHEATIES.
MA.
YES, SWEETIE?
WHAT'S GOING
ON, MA?
WITH WHAT?
THE WAY
YOU'RE BEHAVING
TOWARDS BEN.
WHY? 'CAUSE I
DIDN'T HOP TO
WHEN HE WANTED
HIS CEREAL?
IT'S MORE THAN
THAT. YOU... YOU
NEVER SAY HELLO.
YOU BARELY SPEAK
TO HIM UNLESS
YOU HAVE TO.
WELL, FORGIVE
ME IF I'M NOT
SITTING DOWN
AND CHATTING WITH
HIM ABOUT CURRENT
EVENTS OVER A
CUP OF TEA.
I HAPPEN TO BE
BUSY. OR HAVEN'T
YOU NOTICED?
NOW, EXCUSE ME.
I'VE GOT TO GET
SOMEBODY HIS BREAK-
FAST OF CHAMPIONS.
[ Ringing of bell ]
WHEATIES.
[ Beeping of alarm clock ]
OH-H...
GOOD MORNING...
SUNSHINE.
I THOUGHT YOU
HAD A CLASS.
I DITCHED IT.
HOW ARE YOU
SUPPOSED
TO DO YOUR BEST WORK
WHEN YOU'RE UP ALL
NIGHT FUCKING AROUND?
I'M TAKING
LESSONS FROM YOU.
AND I'M NOT FUCKING
AROUND. I'M WORKING.
YEAH, I SAW HOW YOU WORK.
STICKING THAT...
FUNNY WHITE POWDER
THE SAP GAVE YOU
UP YOUR
CUTE, LITTLE
BUTTON NOSE.
YOU'RE SUPPOSED TO
BE PUTTING YOURSELF
THROUGH SCHOOL,
NOT GETTING SO
HAMMERED YOU CAN'T
MAKE IT TO CLASS.
$410 IN
ONE NIGHT.
FOR YOUR TUITION,
WHICH YOU WON'T HAVE
TO WORRY ABOUT
WHEN THEY KICK YOU OUT.
YOU SOUND LIKE MY FATHER.
FUCK OFF.
[ Beeping of alarm clock ]
BREAK IN THE CASE?
NAW. NOTHING YET.
SO, WHAT ARE
YOU DOING HERE?
IT'S A DINER,
ISN'T IT?
IT'S LUNCH TIME,
IT'S A LITTLE
EARLY, ISN'T IT?
BUT WHAT'LL
IT BE?
UM, MEAT LOAF
SANDWICH,
SIDE OF FRIES.
AND HOW ABOUT YOU
AND ME GOING OUT
TOMORROW NIGHT?
YEAH, THAT
LAST ITEM ISN'T
ON THE MENU.
I THOUGHT WE COULD
GET ONE OF THOSE FANCY
COFFEES, YOU KNOW,
UH... MOCHA...
FRAPPE LATTE, WHATEVER
THE HELL THEY'RE CALLED.
YEAH, WELL,
CONSIDERING HOW
MUCH OF THAT
STUFF I POUR,
IT'D BE A
BUSMAN'S HOLIDAY.
HOW ABOUT DINNER
THEN? SOMEBODY
CAN WAIT ON YOU
FOR A CHANGE.
NO, THANKS.
IS THAT "NO THANKS,
NOT TOMORROW"
OR "NO THANKS, NOT EVER"?
JUST... NO THANKS.
HEY, HORVATH?
YOU WANT A LEMON
BAR FOR THE ROAD?
HUH. NO, THANKS.
[ ?????? ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Groans of climax ]
[ Applause/cheering ]
AH, YES!
OH.
TO FETCH DIXON,
A BIG...
BIGSTAR.
YOU'RE A HARD
ACT TO FOLLOW.
[ Applause ]
OH-H...
DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO SAY...
GOOD. THEN, LET'S
HAVE SOME CAKE.
[ Laughter ]
HOWEVER...
EVEN THOUGH I'M RETIRING
FROM THE BIZ,
I WILL ALWAYS BE GRATEFUL
FOR MY EXPERIENCE HERE,
AND, UH, AND... AND
FOR FETCH DIXON.
WITHOUT HIM, I NEVER
WOULD'VE MET MY HONEY.
YOU'RE AN
INSPIRATION
TO US ALL.
AH. AN INSPIRATION?
NO, I'M...
JUST... LUCKY.
UM, I MEAN, THE
SAME THING COULD
HAPPEN TO YOU.
YOU NEVER WHO'S OUT
THERE, WATCHING.
SO, NEVER GIVE UP HOPE.
ONE DAY YOUR
PRINCE WILL COME.
Brian:
WHEN HE DOES,
TED WILL BE MAKING
$19.95 FOR THE
FIRST 10 MINUTES.
[ Laughter ]
Emmett:
OOH!
PRESENTS.
YEAH.
Various:
[ Chuckling ]
Emmett:
ALL RIGHT...
WORKING TONIGHT?
HMM. 9:00 TO 2:00.
YOU CAN
HARDLY KEEP
YOUR HEAD UP.
I'LL BE
ALL RIGHT.
THE SAP WILL
SEE TO THAT.
DERAMINE.
IT'S FOR MOTION SICKNESS.
WELL, THAT
SHOULD TAKE
CARE OF THE SEX.
YOU DON'T WANT ME TO
GIVE YOU THE MONEY,
I'LL LOAN IT TO YOU.
I DON'T NEED
YOUR HANDOUTS.
IT'S NOT
A HANDOUT.
WHEN YOU GRADUATE
AND GET A REAL JOB,
YOU CAN PAY ME
BACK WITH INTEREST.
NO, THANKS.
WHY ARE YOU BEING
SUCH A TWAT?
I'M NOT
BEING A TWAT.
I'M TRYING TO
LOOK AFTER MY-
SELF FOR ONCE,
INSTEAD OF
ALWAYS LETTING
YOU DO IT FOR ME.
Emmett:
DICTIONARY OF
FOREIGN PHRASES.
Ted:
NOW YOU CAN SAY
"FUCK ME FASTER"
IN FARSI.
LOOK, YOU ONCE
TOLD ME THAT YOU
WANTED TO MAKE ME
THE BEST HOMOSEXUAL
IT WAS POSSIBLE
FOR ME TO BE.
DOESN'T THAT INCLUDE
BEING A MAN?
SOMETIMES A
MAN KNOWS WHEN
TO ACCEPT HELP.
HERE'S SOME SEXY UNDER-
WEAR FOR YOUR TRIP.
IT'S EMPTY.
[ Laughter ]
EXACTLY.
[ Laughter/whooping ]
"WINE, MEN AND SONG,
LATE 40s, EPICUREAN,
LOOKING FOR
FELLOW GOURMAND.
PEEL ME A
GRAPE AND I'LL
PEEL YOU ONE."
SOUNDS PERFECT.
HIV-NEGATIVE
ONLY NEED APPLY.
OH. YOU'LL
FIND THE RIGHT
GUY SOME DAY.
AT MY AGE, IT BETTER
BE SOME DAY SOON.
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR THAT
CRAP ABOUT "AT YOUR AGE".
EMMETT FELL FOR
GEORGE, RIGHT?
WHICH ONLY PROVES
THAT LOVE IS POSSIBLE
NO MATTER HOW
OLD YOU ARE.
SO WHAT'S YOUR EXCUSE?
I DON'T HAVE
AN EXCUSE.
NOR DO I
NEED ONE,
'CAUSE SOMEONE
ASKED ME
OUT TODAY.
YOU?
YES, ME.
HUH, I MEAN, WHAT I MEAN
IS, YOU LIVE WITH FAGS,
YOU WORK WITH FAGS.
YOU HAVEN'T SEEN A
STRAIGHT MAN IN YEARS.
WELL, WHAT DO YOU
CALL THAT DETECTIVE?
THE ONE INVESTIGATING
THE MURDER.
HE ASKED YOU.
NONE OTHER.
HOLY SHIT!
SO, WHEN ARE
YOU GOING?
I'M NOT.
YOU TURNED
HIM DOWN?
HE'S NOT MY TYPE.
HE'S ALIVE AND
HE'S GOT A DICK.
WHAT MORE
DO YOU NEED?
SOMEONE WHO'S
NOT A HOMOPHOBE.
BECAUSE HE MADE A
COUPLE OF CRACKS?
THAT DOESN'T MEAN
HE'S A FAG-HATER.
IT JUST MEANS
HE NEEDS...
ENLIGHTENING.
SO YOU GO
OUT WITH HIM.
YOU'RE MORE
HIS TYPE.
HOW LONG HAS IT
BEEN SINCE YOU
WENT ON A DATE?
HOW THE FUCK
DO I KNOW?
1992.
MUST BE SO
RUSTY IT SQUEAKS.
I'VE BEEN BUSY.
DOING WHAT?
TAKING CARE
OF YOU.
SO WHAT'S YOUR
EXCUSE NOW?
I ALREADY
TURNED HIM DOWN.
BUT... YOU'RE
A WOMAN.
SOMEWHAT OUT OF
PRACTICE, BUT
NONETHELESS...
YOU'RE ALLOWED TO
CHANGE YOUR MIND.
WELL, GO ON.
JUST SAY YES.
COME ON.
Emmett:
HARDER!
Michael:
PUSH.
YES.
YES!
[ Groaning ]
WHEW! DIDN'T
THINK I'D GET
ALL THAT IN THERE.
[ Chuckling ]
WELL, THAT'S THAT.
YEAH. AND NOW
THAT I AM GONE,
YOU AND BEN WILL
HAVE THE PLACE ALL
TO YOURSELVES,
SO YOU CAN...
HUMP AND BUMP
AND MAKE MAD
PASSIONATE LOVE
AT THE TOP OF
YOUR LUNGS,
WITHOUT ME
LISTENING THROUGH
THE WALLS.
[ Chuckling ]
ON SECOND THOUGHT,
MAYBE I'LL STAY.
[ Honking of car horn ]
TOO LATE, THAT'S
THE LIMO.
COME ON UP,
GEORGIE.
[ Giggling ]
GOD, I GOT TO
REMEMBER NOT TO ACT
LIKE A SHOPGIRL.
DON'T WANT TO
EMBARRASS HIM
WORLDWIDE.
WHY WOULD YOU
EMBARRASS HIM?
WELL, BACK
IN HAZELHURST,
GEORGE IS
WHAT WE USED
TO CALL REFINED.
AND I AM WHAT WE
USED TO CALL A
PIECE OF THRASH.
SOMEONE LIKE
HIM WOULD NEVER
ASSOCIATE WITH
THE LIKES OF ME.
WELL, YOU'RE NOT
IN HAZELHURST
ANY MORE,
AND GEORGE DOESN'T
FEEL THAT WAY.
I KNOW.
IT'S JUST...
MORE THAN I
EVER DREAMED.
YOU DESERVE A
FABULOUS LIFE, EM.
AS FABULOUS AS YOU.
HMMM. OOP.
WELL, HELLO,
DREAM-DATE.
YOU ALL PACKED?
YEAH.
OH, WOW! LET ME
REPHRASE THAT.
IS THERE ANYTHING
YOU HAVEN'T PACKED?
[ Chuckling ]
HAVE A GREAT TRIP.
AH, THANKS, MICHAEL.
Chauffeur:
I'LL TAKE
THAT, SIR.
WELL, I GUESS...
THIS IS IT.
UM, MAKE SURE YOU
TELL THE ASSHOLE
SUPER TO FIX
THE RADIATOR.
LAST WINTER WE
HAD TO GO TO THE
BATHROOM IN PARKAS.
OH AND, UH, MAKE
SURE HE REPAINTS
IN THE SPRING.
ALTHOUGH HE'S ONLY
BEEN PROMISING
FOR, LIKE...
TWO YEARS.
OKAY.
MMM, I'M, UH...
REALLY GOING
TO MISS YOU.
YOU KNOW, I,
UH, HATE TO
INTERRUPT THIS,
BUT, UH, WE GOT
A PLANE TO CATCH.
I'LL, UH, I'LL
SEND YOU POSTCARDS,
FROM RIO AND...
POSITANO AND, UH,
OH! AH, BEIJING.
OH.
[ Chuckling ]
OKAY, BYE.
BYE.
IT'S JUST FOR THE WEEKEND
SO THAT I CAN
FINISH A PROJECT.
MAYBE YOU DON'T
UNDERSTAND SOMETHING.
THIS ISN'T A PARTY.
THIS IS A BUSINESS.
I NEED TO BE ABLE TO
DEPEND ON MY EMPLOYEES
TO SHOW UP ON TIME,
DO THEIR JOB...
IF I DON'T,
MY PROFESSOR
SAID HE'S GOING
TO FAIL ME.
I FEEL FOR
YOU, KIDDO,
I REALLY DO.
RIGHT.
I'LL TELL
YOU WHAT.
JUST THIS ONCE,
I'LL LET YOU OFF.
OH, THANKS, SAP.
UH, GARY.
BUT...
I WANT YOU TO DO
ME A LITTLE FAVOUR.
[ ?????? ]
THAT'S NOT BAD.
THANKS.
MAYBE WE'LL
EVEN HANG IT.
REALLY?
THEN YOU CAN
TELL EVERYBODY
YOU'RE HUNG.
I ALREADY DO.
SO HOW DID
YOU GET THE
NIGHT OFF?
[ Clearing of throat ]
I TOLD THE BOSS I HAD
TO FINISH A PROJECT.
THAT WAS EASY.
MM-HMM.
I TOLD YOU I
COULD HANDLE IT.
OW.
SMART ASS.
IN FACT, HE SAID I
COULD HAVE THE WHOLE
WEEKEND IF I JUST WENT
TO SOME
AFTER-HOURS
PARTY AT
HIS HOUSE.
FOR WHAT?
HE WANTS SOME PRETTY BOYS
THERE FOR DECORATION.
WHO ELSE IS GOING
TO BE THERE?
HOW SHOULD
I KNOW?
HIS FRIENDS.
I CAN IMAGINE
WHAT KIND OF
FRIENDS HE HAS.
AND I CAN GUESS
WHAT KIND OF
PARTY HE'S HAVING.
THAT GUY'S A
FUCKING SLEAZE.
YOU DON'T KNOW HIM.
[ Scoffing ]
I KNOW HOW YOU
GOT TO DANCE
ON THE BAR.
I LET HIM BLOW ME.
BIG DEAL.
I'LL GIVE YOU $5,000.
WHAT FOR?
THAT DRAWING.
IT'S NOT FOR SALE.
NO. JUST YOU.
Melanie:
WE'RE ALMOST
THERE.
DON'T OPEN YOUR
EYES. I'M STILL
PUTTING ON
YOUR MASCARA.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT
ALL THE FUSS IS ABOUT.
HORVATH KNOWS
WHAT I LOOK LIKE.
IT'S NOT
FOR HORVATH.
IT'S FOR YOU.
WELL, I KNOW
WHAT I LOOK
LIKE TOO.
OKAY, READY?
OPEN UP.
HOLY SHIT.
I LOOK NICE.
NICER THAN NICE.
YOU LOOK LIKE
A PRINCESS.
WELL, IT'S BETTER
THAN LOOKING LIKE
THE QUEEN MOTHER.
All:
[ Laughing ]
[ Chiming of doorbell ]
AH.
OH, CHRIST.
IT MUST BE HIM.
DON'T BE
NERVOUS.
I'M NOT NERVOUS.
I'VE GOT EVERYTHING
UNDER CONTROL.
OH, HEY, THE...
THE... THE FRONT
DOOR IS THAT WAY.
OH, YEAH. OKAY.
HI.
YOU LOOK, UH...
ARE THE WORDS
YOU'RE SEARCHING FOR,
"LIKE A PRINCESS"?
I WAS GOING TO
SAY "NOT BAD".
THAT'LL DO. HUH.
OH, COME ON IN.
THANKS.
UM, THIS
IS LINDSAY
AND MELANIE.
HI.
THEY'RE LESBIANS.
THAT'S NICE.
AND THIS IS
DETECTIVE...
HORVATH.
CARL.
HEY, CARL. NICE
TO MEET YOU.
WELL, WE'LL BE
ON OUR WAY. HUH.
HAVE FUN.
YEAH, HAVE A
NICE NIGHT, UH,
EVENING.
BYE.
YEAH, BEN'S
STILL WORKING
ON HIS BOOK,
SO I FIGURED I'D
COME DOWN HERE,
HAVE DINNER WITH
YOU AND MOM,
TRY A LITTLE
DIPLOMACY.
WELL, IF YOU MEAN
ABOUT YOU AND
HIM, FORGET IT.
SHE'S DUG
HER HIGH HEELS
IN AND SHE'S
NOT BUDGING.
IT'S STILL
WORTH A TRY.
NOT TONIGHT.
SHE'S GOT
A DATE.
[ Chuckling ]
WITH A MAN?
OF COURSE
WITH A MAN.
WHY SHOULD SHE
BE ANY DIFFERENT
FROM US?
WAIT, IS THAT HIM?
THAT DETECTIVE?
Vic:
I ALWAYS THOUGHT
DETECTIVES
WERE SEXY.
HERCULE POIROT
WITH THAT
LITTLE MUSTACHE.
COLUMBO IN
THAT RUMPLED
TRENCH COAT.
I THOUGHT SHE
SAID HE WAS A
REAL HOMOPHOBE.
Debbie:
HI, SWEETHEART.
CARL, YOU
REMEMBER MY
SON MICHAEL
SURE.
AND MY
BROTHER VIC.
VIC.
HI.
MIKE, HOW'RE
YOU DOING?
FINE.
WELL, WE'RE OFF.
Carl:
ALLOW ME.
THANK YOU.
Carl:
THERE YOU GO.
[ Ignition of engine ]
I'LL HAVE SOME
OF THE BRIE...
PLEASE, AND, UH,
OH, THE... THE
TARTE AU CHOCOLAT,
AND... AND, UH, AND
THECREME BRULEE.
[ Giggling ]
AND, UH, AND
DON'T BE STINGY
WITH THE CHAMPAGNE.
George:
[ Chuckling ]
YOU'VE BEEN EATING
SINCE WE TOOK OFF.
WELL, IT'S
MY FIRST TIME
IN FIRST CLASS.
I, UH, I WANT TO
MAKE SURE I GET
YOUR MONEY'S WORTH.
Both:
[ Laughing ]
LISTEN.
WHAT?
IF YOU'RE
VERY QUIET,
YOU CAN ALMOST
HEAR THEM MOO.
WHO?
THE CATTLE
IN COACH.
OH.
[ Chuckling ]
I KNOW. I
USED TO BE ONE
OF THE HERD.
BUT NOW I AM
FINALLY ON THE
OTHER SIDE OF
THE CURTAIN,
AND IT'S A
WHOLE NEW WORLD.
WELL FROM NOW ON,
I HOPE THE WORLD
WILL BE A WHOLE
NEW WORLD.
HMMM.
IT WILL BE...
'CAUSE I'M
WITH YOU.
WOULD YOU FIND IT
TERRIBLY TEDIOUS
IF I TOLD YOU HOW
MARVELLOUS YOU ARE?
HOW MUCH YOU
MEAN TO ME?
I WILL TRY
TO ENDURE IT.
I TELL YOU,
EMMETT, NO ONE'S
EVER GIVEN ME
SUCH PLEASURE.
I CAN HARDLY
WAIT TO MAKE
LOVE AT EVERY
DESTINATION.
HMM.
[ Giggling ]
YEAH, AT
MACHU PICCHU.
IN A GONDOLA
IN VENICE.
ON THE GREAT WALL
OF CHINA.
I WONDER IF THERE'S
A 3000-YEAR-OLD
GLORY HOLE?
I WISH WE COULD
DO IT RIGHT NOW.
WHY NOT?
HAVEN'T YOU EVER
HEARD OF THE
MILE HIGH CLUB?
HONEY, IT'S WHY
WILBUR AND ORVILLE
INVENTED AVIATION.
YOU GO IN THE
LITTLE BOYS'
ROOM FIRST.
THEN WHEN NO
ONE'S LOOKING,
I'LL SLIP IN
AND, UH...
[ Whispering
inaudibly ]
OKAY.
MM-HMM.
[ Clearing of throat ]
[ Clicking of lock ]
Debbie:
I DIDN'T KNOW
YOU HAD CHILDREN.
Carl:
YEAH, TWO.
MY SON,
CARL JUNIOR,
HE'S IN THE
AIR FORCE,
STATIONED
IN GERMANY.
HE'S GOT A COUPLE
OF LITTLE ONES.
VERY NICE.
MY, UH,
DAUGHTER VICKI.
MMM.
NAMED AFTER
HER MOM, GOD
REST HER SOUL.
SHE'S IN
SALT LAKE.
SHE'S A MUSIC TEACHER.
MARRIED?
UH-HUH. TO
A BLACK GUY.
OH.
UH...
DON'T GET THE
WRONG IDEA.
DID YOU HEAR
ME SAY A WORD?
HE'S NICE ENOUGH.
HE'S A LAWYER.
SUCCESSFUL.
BUT YOU DON'T
LIKE IT.
WELL, I'M
WORKING ON IT.
BIG OF YOU.
YOU GOT
ENOUGH THERE?
MM-HMM.
PLENTY.
[ Sigh ]
I JUST DON'T
GET WHY SHE'D...
WANT TO GO
MAKE HER LIFE
MORE DIFFICULT.
[ Sigh ]
I TRIED TALKING
TO HER BUT...
YEAH, WELL, YOU
CAN'T DICTATE
TO YOUR KIDS
ABOUT HOW TO
LIVE THEIR LIFE
OR WHO TO LOVE.
AND THE MORE
YOU DO, THE
WORSE IT GETS.
SOUNDS LIKE
WE'RE, UH...
TALKING FROM PERSONAL
EXPERIENCE HERE.
MY SON'S SEEING
SOMEBODY WHO'S
HIV-POSITIVE.
HOLY SHIT.
THAT'S WHAT
I SAID.
BUT TRY TALKING
TO HIM AND HE'LL
BITE YOUR HEAD OFF.
WELL, I GUESS IT'S
LIKE YOU SAY...
IT'S NONE OF
OUR BUSINESS.
WE'RE JUST THE
POOR SUCKERS
WHO BROUGHT THEM
INTO THE WORLD.
I WORRY FOR HER
THOUGH, YOU KNOW.
FOR THE KIDS
THEY MIGHT HAVE.
HMMM.
I WORRY TOO...
FOR MY KID'S LIFE.
SO I'M AN OGRE.
A DAMN PRETTY ONE.
DON'T TRY TO
SWEET-TALK ME.
WHAT? CAN'T YOU
TAKE A COMPLIMENT?
IT'S BEEN SO LONG
SINCE I'VE HAD ONE,
I WOULDN'T KNOW
WHAT TO DO WITH IT.
YOU SAVOUR IT,
LIKE THIS.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Panting ]
AH, IT'S PRETTY
TIGHT IN HERE.
THANK YOU.
[ Chiming of P.A. ]
Steward: [ On P.A. ]
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE'RE EXPERIENCING
A LITTLE TURBULENCE.
THEM TOO?
THE CAPTAIN HAS TURNED ON
THE OVERHEAD SEAT BELT SIGN
AND REQUESTS THAT YOU
PLEASE RETURN TO YOUR SEAT.
SORRY, MY
SEAT'S TAKEN.
[ Groaning ]
SH-SH-SH-SH.
WE DON'T WANT THE
STEWARD HEARING
AND BURSTING IN,
ALTHOUGH HE WAS
KIND OF CUTE.
[ Groaning ]
[ Panting ]
THAT SOUNDED
LIKE A GOOD ONE.
YOU ALL RIGHT,
GEORGE?
OH, MY GOD. GEOR...
[ Panting ]
OH, MY GOD.
GEOR... GEORGE,
A-ARE YOU...
OH MY GOD.
[ Muttering ]
SOMEBODY HELP US.
[ Whimpering ]
GEORGE... GOD.
SOMEBODY...
[ Banging on door ]
SOMEBODY!
SOMEBODY
HELP US, PLEASE!
GOD...
WELL, WHAT
DO YOU KNOW?
YOU WAITING UP FOR ME?
IT'S AFTER MIDNIGHT.
GONNA TO GROUND ME?
[ Chuckling ]
YOU'RE DRUNK.
I'VE HAD
A COUPLE OF
GLASSES OF WINE
AND A VERY NICE
TIME, IN CASE
YOU'RE INTERESTED.
WITH THAT
HOMOPHOBIC PRICK?
HE'S NOT A
HOMOPHOBIC PRICK.
OKAY, SO NOW
WHAT IS HE?
HE'S A 55-YEAR-OLD
STRAIGHT GUY
WITH 55-YEAR-OLD
STRAIGHT GUY ATTITUDES
WHO NEEDS HIS EYES OPENED.
HE'S NOT
THE ONLY ONE.
FOR A FREE MEAL
AND A LITTLE
ATTENTION,
YOU'RE WILLING TO
OVERLOOK EVERYTHING
YOU BELIEVE IN?
YOU DON'T KNOW
HIM, MICHAEL.
NEITHER DO YOU.
WELL, I'D
LIKE TO.
AND IF YOU DON'T APPROVE,
THEN I SUGGEST YOU
FOLLOW YOUR OWN ADVICE
WHEN I SAID I DIDN'T
WANT YOU SEEING BEN,
AND MIND YOUR OWN
FUCKING BUSINESS.
YOU KNOW, YOU MIGHT
TRY REMEMBERING
ALL THE YEARS
THAT I RAISED YOU
AND LOOKED AFTER
YOUR UNCLE VIC,
WITHOUT EVER TAKING
A MINUTE FOR MYSELF.
AND NOW, FOR
THE FIRST TIME,
A-A GUY ASKS
ME OUT IN...
I CAN'T EVEN
REMEMBER HOW LONG,
AND YOU HAVE A PROBLEM
INSTEAD OF BEING
HAPPY FOR ME.
WHAT, HAPPY
YOU'RE SO FUCKING
DESPERATE
YOU'LL GO OUT
WITH ANYONE?
[ ?????? ]
Man:
HEY, SAVE SOME
FOR OTHERS...
[ ?????? ]
Man:
HI, GUY.
[ ?????? ]
COOL PLACE, HUH?
YEAH.
COOL.
[ ?????? ]
HUH.
WANT SOME?
NO, THANKS.
COME ON,
LOOSEN UP,
RELAX.
[ ?????? ]
WHY DON'T YOU TAKE
YOUR SHIRT OFF?
WHAT FOR?
IT'S WHY YOU'RE
HERE, REMEMBER?
DECORATION.
THAT WAS THE DEAL.
[ ?????? ]
THAT'S BETTER.
[ Chuckle ]
Man:
OUR LITTLE
FRIEND HERE
LOOKS LIKE
HE COULD USE
A DRINK.
WHY DON'T WE,
UH, OFFER HIM
SOMETHING?
LATER.
[ Chuckle ]
[ Deep
inhalation ]
GO AHEAD. IT'S
GREAT SHIT.
[ ?????? ]
Man:
OH, WHAT'S
THE MATTER,
TOO STRONG?
WHAT HAVE
WE HERE?
YEAH.
[ ?????? ]
I MEAN, MICHAEL'S
GOT BEN...
YOU'VE GOT JUSTIN.
Brian:
[ Snort ]
EVEN EMMETT
HAS GEORGE, FOR
CHRIST'S SAKE.
HOW COME EVERY-
BODY'S GOT SOMEONE
EXCEPT ME?
THE REASON YOU DON'T
HAVE A BOYFRIEND
IS BECAUSE...
YOU DON'T WANT ONE.
I DON'T?
IF YOU HAD ONE,
IT WOULD CHALLENGE
THE WELL-ESTABLISHED
OPINION YOU
HAVE OF YOURSELF
AS A WORTHLESS
SACK OF SHIT
THAT NOBODY WANTS.
THEREFORE, YOU GO
AFTER GUYS YOU KNOW
WILL REJECT YOU,
THEN YOU STAND
AROUND HERE AND
BITCH LIKE A
HIGH SCHOOL GIRL,
WHEN IN FACT YOU'VE
GOTTEN EXACTLY
WHAT YOU WANT,
MAINLY...
NOTHING.
[ Sniff ]
WELL, THANK
YOU, DR. KINNEY.
YOU'VE SAVED ME
YEARS OF THERAPY
NOT TO MENTION
SEVERAL THOUSAND
DOLLARS.
SHE HIT ME. MY MOTHER
FUCKING HIT ME.
SHE'S ALWAYS
HITTING YOU.
THAT'S HOW SHE
SHOWS HER AFFECTION.
I MEAN FOR REAL.
WELL, WHAT DID MIKEY DO?
I DON'T WANT TO
TALK ABOUT IT.
I TOLD HER SHE WAS
PATHETIC FOR DATING
THAT FAG-HATING COP.
YOU KNOW, IF SHE
KEEPS THIS UP,
WE'RE GOING TO HAVE
TO TAKE HER HONORARY
QUEER BUTTON AWAY.
WHERE ARE
HER VALUES?
HER PRINCIPLES?
YOU KNOW HOW
IT IS WHEN
YOU WANT COCK.
THEY'RE THE FIRST
THINGS TO GO.
COME ON, LET'S
GET OUT OF HERE.
LITTLE MIKEY'S
JEALOUS.
WOULD YOU SHUT
THE FUCK UP?
WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
DO YOU THINK
THEY DID IT?
DO YOU THINK HE SLIPPED
HER THE BIG GREASER?
HOW ABOUT SOME MUSIC?
Brian:
IT'S JUST YOUR
GARDEN-VARIETY
OEDIPAL THING.
ALL YOUR LIFE YOU'VE
BEEN HER LITTLE MAN,
AND ALL OF THE
SUDDEN SOME BIG
OLD DICK POPS UP,
THREATENS TO
TAKE HER AWAY.
AND YOU'RE HURT.
YOU'RE ANGRY. YOU'RE
MAD ENOUGH TO KILL.
OKAY, ONE MORE WORD OUT
OF YOU AND I'M THROWING
YOU OUT OF THE CAR. OKAY?
EVEN IF IT IS YOURS.
[ Wailing of siren ]
SHIT.
WHAT NOW?
WE'RE BEING PULLED
OVER. FUCK!
[ Blasts of siren ]
YOU HAVE ANY-
THING ON YOU?
YEAH, 16 POUNDS OF COCAINE
AND 24 OUNCES OF HEROIN.
THIS IS NO TIME
TO BE FUNNY.
WHO'S BEING FUNNY?
LICENSE AND
REGISTRATION, SIR.
ARE YOU THE OWNER
OF THE VEHICLE?
NO. HE IS.
IT'S A WONDERFUL
EVENING, ISN'T
IT, OFFICER?
ARE YOU AWARE
YOU WERE SPEEDING?
OH, THAT MUST BE
WHY IT FELT LIKE WE
WERE GOING SO FAST.
MICHAEL.
YOU WERE DOING 60
IN A 35-MILE ZONE.
WOW, WHAT DO
YOU KNOW? MATH.
GIVE THE OFFICER
A JELLY DOUGHNUT.
EXCUSE ME, SIR?
LOOK, DON'T YOU
HAVE ANYTHING
USEFUL TO DO,
LIKE... ARREST
A MURDERER?
JESUS, WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING?
DO YOU HAVE A
PROBLEM WITH POLICE
OFFICERS, SIR?
ONLY ONES THAT ARE
BOFFING HIS MOTHER.
SHUT UP,
ASSHOLE.
JUST GIVE ME THE
GODDAMN TICKET.
OH, NOW HE'S DONE IT.
GET OUT OF
THE CAR, SIR.
NOW WE'RE
GOING TO GET
ARRESTED.
WHAT NOW? SO
YOU CAN WORK
ME OVER?
OH, NOW WE'RE
GOING TO JAIL.
YOU TOO.
PUT YOUR HANDS
ON THE CAR.
WHAT DID WE DO?
I SAID OUT.
AW!
OFFICER, I'D BE
MORE THAN HAPPY
TO DRIVE THESE
TWO GENTLEMEN HOME.
?? ...THEY LOVE YOU WHEN
YOU'RE ON ALL THE COVERS ??
?? WHEN YOU'RE NOT THEN
THEY LOVE ANOTHER... ??
IT'S SHOW TIME.
?? ...ARE MADE
IN CALIFORNIA ??
?? WE LOVE YOUR FACE ??
?? WE'D REALLY
LIKE TO SELL YOU ??
?? THE COPS AND QUEERS ??
?? MAKE GOOD-LOOKING MODELS ??
?? I HATE TODAY ??
?? WHO WILL I WAKE UP
WITH TOMRROW? ??
?? THERE'S LOTS OF
PRETTY, PRETTY ONES ??
?? THAT WANT TO
GET YOU HIGH... ??
HMM.
YOU LOOK KIND
OF THIRSTY.
HUH.
HAVE A SIP.
THANKS.
YOU HAVEN'T
SEEN MY PLACE.
COME ON, I'LL
SHOW YOU AROUND.
[ ?????? ]
?? THEY LOVE YOU WHEN
YOU'RE ON ALL THE COVERS ??
?? WHEN YOU'RE NOT
THEN THEY LOVE ANOTHER ??
?? THEY LOVE YOU WHEN YOU'RE
ON ALL THE COVERS... ??
HE LOOKS LIKE
HE'S HAVING
A GOOD TIME.
[ ?????? ]
YOU EVER BEEN
IN A SLING?
OH, YOU'D
LOVE IT.
COME ON, WHY
DON'T YOU GIVE
IT A TRY?
I DON'T... I
DON'T WANT TO.
I DON'T WANT TO.
[ Groan ]
COME ON,
IT'S JUST...
I SAID THAT
I DON'T TO!
[ Groaning ]
[ Mixed shouts ]
SHIT!
YOU BROKE ONE
OF MY CAPS.
I BETTER GO. I...
FUCKER.
DO YOU KNOW
HOW MUCH
THESE COST ME?
I GOTTA GO.
YOU'RE GODDAMN
RIGHT. AND
DON'T BOTHER
COMING BACK TO WORK.
GOD...
Man:
YOU OKAY, GARY?
[ Groaning ]
[ Murmurs of concern ]
[ Sighing ]
IT, UH...
IT APPEARS
THE GENTLEMAN
SUFFERED A
MASSIVE MYOCARDIAL
INFARCTION,
A HEART ATTACK,
UH... BROUGHT
ON BY, UH...
OVEREXERTION.
WELL... THANK
YOU, DOCTOR.
LUCKY TO HAVE A
HEART SPECIALIST
ON BOARD.
UH... ACTUALLY,
UM, I'M A DOCTOR
OF ECONOMICS.
BUT, UH, THE SAME
THING HAPPENED
TO MY UNCLE.
WHAT A
WAY TO GO.
IS THERE ANYTHING
I CAN GET YOU?
A DRINK.
I COULD REALLY
USE A DRINK.
OVER ICE?
WON'T BE NECESSARY.
THANKS.
[ Sniffling ]
UM, DO YOU, UH...
DO YOU MIND IF
I STAY UP HERE?
I DON'T WANT TO
LEAVE HIM ALONE.
MAKE YOURSELF
COMFORTABLE.
IF YOU NEED
ANYTHING, JUST
HOLLER. I'LL...
FETCH IT FOR YOU.
HEAR THAT, GEORGE?
HE RECOGNIZED ME.
I GUESS, UH...
I GUESS STARDOM SOMETIMES
HAS ITS ADVANTAGES.
SO, HERE WE
ARE, HONEY.
FLYING AROUND
SOMEWHERE BETWEEN...
HEAVEN AND EARTH...
[ Sniffling ]
LOST IN THE STARS.
Various:
[ Snoring ]
I'M SO DISAPPOINTED.
I KNOW, I
FUCKED UP.
I DON'T
MEAN THAT.
ALL THE PORNO FLICKS
I'VE SEEN THAT TAKE
PLACE IN PRISON
ALWAYS SHOW THESE HOT
CRIMINAL TYPES IN HEAVY
MAN-ON-MAN ACTION.
NOTHING LIKE THIS.
YOU'RE NOT EXACTLY WHAT
I WAS HOPING FOR EITHER.
[ Clearing of throat ]
I WONDER WHO I HAVE
TO BLOW AROUND HERE
TO GET A TRIPLE
NON-FAT LATTE?
[ Buzzing of door ]
HMM, IF YOU SAY SO.
Carl:
OKAY, GENTLEMEN.
FREE TO GO.
THANK YOU, SIR.
THANK YOU.
YOU KNOW, YOUR
HOUSEKEEPING STAFF
DESERVES A THRASHING.
A WORD?
IF YOU GOT A
PROBLEM, TALK
TO ME ABOUT IT
INSTEAD OF TAKING IT
OUT ON THE OFFICER
WHO PULLED YOU OVER.
YOU'RE A HOMOPHOBIC BIGOT
AND I WANT YOU TO STAY
AWAY FROM MY MOTHER.
THANKS FOR BEING
FORTHRIGHT.
MAY I BE
THE SAME?
I DON'T
HATE GAYS.
I JUST DON'T
GET IT.
BUT THEN YOU
COULD SAY THE
SAME THING
ABOUT ME,
SO WE'RE EVEN.
AS FOR YOUR
MOTHER...
SHE'S A VERY
NICE LADY.
BIG HEART,
BIG PERSONALITY,
BIG MOUTH.
CALL ME CRAZY,
BUT I LIKE THAT.
AND SHE SURE AS
HELL LOVES YOU.
GO PAY YOUR
SPEEDING TICKET
AT THE FRONT DESK.
THERE'LL BE NO
RECORD OF YOUR
NIGHT IN THE SLAMMER
FOR YOU OR
YOUR FRIENDS.
THANKS.
MOTHER? MOM?
YES?
CAN WE ORDER,
PLEASE?
YOU LOOK LIKE SHIT.
THANK YOU.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
TWO EGGS OVER
EASY, BACON,
RAISIN TOAST
AND TO SAY
I'M SORRY.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
UH, WHEATIES.
MOM, DID YOU
HEAR WHAT I SAID?
TWO EGGS OVER EASY,
BACON, RAISIN TOAST.
I MEANT THE
SORRY PART. I
SAID I'M SORRY.
LIKE YOU WERE ORDERING
SOMETHING OFF A MENU.
AND YOU EXPECT ME
TO SERVE YOU UP A
NICE PLATE OF...
FORGIVENESS.
JUST LIKE THAT.
I THINK I SHOULD
LEAVE AND LET YOU
TWO WORK THIS OUT.
STAY.
I HAD NO
RIGHT TO JUDGE
DETECTIVE HORVATH
WITHOUT KNOWING HIM.
AND I HAD NO
RIGHT SAYING
THE THINGS TO
YOU THAT I SAID.
YOU'RE ENTITLED
TO DATE WHOEVER
YOU WANT.
YOU'RE GODDAMN
RIGHT I AM.
RIGHT.
BUT THEN,
SO AM I.
YOUR CEREAL'S COMING
RIGHT UP, BEN.
THANK YOU.
[ Arrival of elevator ]
[ Sliding of door ]
WHAT HAPPENED TO
YOU LAST NIGHT?
DON'T ASK.
WE HAVE AN
ARRANGEMENT.
HOME BY 3:00,
OR MY BALLS TURN
INTO PUMPKINS.
HMM.
BELIEVE ME,
YOU DIDN'T
MISS A THING.
HOW WAS
THE PARTY?
OH, INCREDIBLY
TEDIOUS.
I LEFT EARLY.
BET THE SAP
DIDN'T LIKE THAT.
FUCK THE SAP.
ANYWAY...
I QUIT.
I DECIDED
THAT...
WORKING ALL NIGHT
AND GOING TO SCHOOL
DURING THE DAY
WAS COUNTERPRODUCTIVE
TO MY GOALS.
I NEED TO
PRIORITIZE,
CONCENTRATE
ON MY ART.
SO...
I'D LIKE TO TAKE YOU
UP ON YOUR OFFER...
IF IT STILL STANDS.
IT STILL STANDS.
WE'LL NEED TO
DISCUSS THE TERMS
OF THE LOAN...
INTEREST,
REPAYMENT
SCHEDULE.
AND WE SHOULD
HAVE SOMETHING
IN WRITING.
OF COURSE.
MM-HMM.
SO, WHAT MADE
YOU CHANGE
YOUR MIND?
A MAN NEEDS TO
KNOW WHEN TO
ASK FOR HELP.
[ ?????? ]
?? HEAVEN ??
?? TAKE ME TO HEAVEN ??
[ ?????? ]
?? TAKE ME ??
?? TAKE ME TAKE ME TAKE ME
TAKE ME TAKE ME TAKE ME ??
?? TAKE ME TO HEAVEN ??
[ ?????? ]
?? WE'LL GET HIGHER ??
?? OH YEAH ??
?? ALL I WANT TO KNOW ??
?? IS DO YOU WANT
TO ROCK ME? ??
?? THE LIGHTS ARE LOW
AND YOU KNOW WHERE TO GO ??
?? SO BABY,
LET'S HIT THE FLOOR ??
?? ALL I WANT TO SAY ??
?? IS IF YOU LIKE TO FUNK ??
?? THE LOOK IS RIGHT
THE MOOD IS RIGHT ??
?? SO BABY, LET'S BE ??
?? ALL I WANT TO SAY ??
?? IS DO YOU
LIKE TO JUMP? ??
?? THE TIME IS RIGHT
THE MOOD IS RIGHT ??
?? SO BABY,
LET'S TRIP OUT ??
?? WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE ME TO HEAVEN? ??
?? TAKE ME TO HEAVEN ??
?? OH, TAKE ME TO HEAVEN ??
?? WE'LL GET HIGHER ??
?? OH YES WHOA ??
?? OH WHY DON'T YOU
TAKE ME TO HEAVEN? ??
?? WHY DON'T YOU
?? TAKE ME TO HEAVEN ??
?? WE'LL GET HIGHER ??
?? HIGHER ??
[ ?????? ]
MOO!