Apologies.
lt appeared abandoned.
l stand proof it is not.
Return to where you came.
A slave is so treated.
l have owned them.
lf that be offense enough,
have my life.
Wine's gone anyway.
Good Mercato
assures me grand spectacle
to be spoken of for years
throughout the Republic.
l have invoked the god Hymenaeus
to sanction the union.
His blessing is affirmed.
The gods bestow gift
beyond measure.
He appears well pleased.
until life leaves from body.
A simple task.
You have a way of making a man
invisible as well.
Great spectacle is being made
of the games tomorrow.
llithyia's slaves attend her.
Most of Glaber's men
provide welcome security
to calm nervous city.
lt should not be hard
for a man of your talents
to avoid the remainder.