[MUSIC]
DONNA, HAVE YOU NOTICED THAT
EVERY TIME WE DO THE... AHEM,
WHAT WE JUST DID...
IT IS ALWAYS FUN?
[NERVOUS GIGGLE]
ERIC, YOU'RE SO CUTE.
OW! OW!
DONNA, I THINK BY "CUTE"
YOU MEAN...
RUGGEDLY HANDSOME.
YOU READ MY MIND, ERIC.
OH, YEAH.
THAT'S THE OTHER THING.
AFTER WE DO... THE THING,
I DON'T REALLY FEEL
LIKE AN "ERIC."
REALLY?
UH, YEAH. I THINK
I FEEL MORE LIKE A STAN.
OR... A CHUCK.
OR A...
A MAVERICK.
SO DO YOU WANT TO GO TO
A MOVIE TOMORROW, MAVERICK?
OH, UH, I TOLD KELSO AND FEZ
I'D HANG OUT WITH THEM.
REALLY? OH.
HEY, BUT, UH, YOU CAN COME,
TOO, IF YOU WANT.
NO. IT'S OKAY.
UH, REALLY, YOU SHOULD COME.
NO. YOU GO.
HAVE FUN.
ARE YOU SURE?
SURE. IT'S NO BIG DEAL.
OKAY, COOL.
♪ HANGIN' OUT ♪
♪ DOWN THE STREET ♪
♪ THE SAME OLD THING ♪
♪ WE DID LAST WEEK ♪
♪ NOT A THING TO DO ♪
♪ BUT TALK TO YOU ♪
♪ WE'RE ALL ALL RIGHT ♪
HELLO, WISCONSIN!
[MUSIC]
SWEDISH PANCAKES?
WHAT'S THE CATCH?
OH, NO CATCH. EAT 'EM WHILE
THEY'RE HOT. THERE'S PLENTY.
WELL, THIS IS A REAL
TREAT, MRS. FORMAN.
PSST. CAREFUL, STEVEN.
THERE'S ALWAYS A STRING
ATTACHED TO SWEDISH PANCAKES.
TRUST ME.
MOM, YOU ONLY MAKE
SWEDISH PANCAKES
WHEN SOMETHING HORRIBLE'S
ABOUT TO HAPPEN.
DOES SOMEONE HAVE CANCER?
NO, NO, NO. NO ONE
HAS HORRIBLE CANCER.
HA HA HA HA!
NOW, LET'S JUST
SIT DOWN AS A FAMILY
AND ENJOY OUR SPECIAL PANCAKES.
GOTCHA! HA HA HA HA.
WE'RE ALL GOING TO THE NURSING
HOME TO VISIT AUNT PEARL.
OH... AW...
ISN'T SHE DEAD YET?
LAURIE!
WELL, I MEAN SHE IS OLD...
SO... MAYBE WE
SHOULD CALL AHEAD.
RED, CAN YOU BELIEVE
THIS FAMILY?
WELL, THE BUCKS ARE
PLAYING THE CELTICS.
OH, COME ON!
ALL I'M ASKING IS
FOR A QUICK VISIT.
REAL QUICK. QUICK, QUICK, QUICK.
SAY, KIDS, HOW ABOUT A NICE
TRIP TO OLD AUNT PEARL'S?
OHH... OHH...
HEY!
THANK YOU, RED.
I DON'T HAVE TO GO, DO I?
I'VE ALREADY BEEN TO SEE
HER 3 TIMES THIS YEAR.
OH, YEAH. AND I'M A VIRGIN.
GOD, I MISS JACKIE.
I CAN'T SLEEP.
I CAN'T THINK.
I CAN STILL EAT, BUT...
I MEAN, MY LIFE HAS NO MEANING.
I'M DEAD INSIDE.
OH, SO THAT'S WHAT SMELLS.
YEAH, MR. BROKEN HEART.
WHEN WAS THE LAST TIME
YOU TOOK A BATH, MAN?
WHEW, YOU'RE GETTING GAMY.
MAN, I AM SO GLAD
DONNA'S NOT JACKIE.
BUT I'LL TELL YOU WHAT.
I'M EVEN MORE GLAD I'M NOT YOU.
NO OFFENSE.
I GOTTA WIN JACKIE BACK.
I GOT IT! I'LL WRITE HER A SONG!
MAYBE THE BEST WAY
TO GET JACKIE BACK
IS TO LET HER DATE OTHER PEOPLE,
FOREIGN EXCHANGE PEOPLE.
NO, MAN. I THINK A SONG
IS A REALLY GREAT IDEA.
HOW ABOUT THIS ONE?
♪ YOU DON'T LOVE ME ANYMORE ♪
♪ YOU CAUGHT ME CHEATIN'
WITH A WHORE ♪
SEE? 'CAUSE LAURIE'S THE WHORE.
YOU GET IT?
YEAH. MY SISTER IS SUCH A WHORE.
[SNIFFLE]
YEAH, I'M GONNA WRITE
JACKIE A SONG.
I GOTTA WIN HER BACK BECAUSE
I CAN'T STOP THE TEARS, MAN!
[SOBBING LOUDLY]
KELSO?
WE'VE BEEN OVER THIS.
THERE'S NO CRYING IN THE CIRCLE.
AND THEN ERIC SAYS, "YOU
CAN COME... IF YOU WANT."
IF YOU WANT?!
OUCH!
RIGHT?!
I DON'T KNOW, I THINK HE'S
SORT OF TAKING ME FOR GRANTED.
EYAH, I DON'T KNOW.
MAYBE I'M JUST OVERREACTING.
NO, DONNA. YOU'RE UNDERREACTING.
ALL MEN TAKE ALL WOMEN
FOR GRANTED...
ALL THE TIME.
JACKIE...
SAVE YOURSELF
THE HEARTACHE, DONNA.
BREAK UP WITH ERIC NOW
BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE.
THEN WE CAN BE
SINGLE GIRLS TOGETHER.
OOH! WE COULD TAKE A CRUISE!
I DON'T KNOW. I'M JUST WORRIED.
I MEAN, IF HE'S ACTING
LIKE THIS NOW,
IMAGINE WHAT IT'LL BE LIKE
IF WE GOT, LIKE...
MARRIED OR SOMETHING.
GLORIA, I JUST LOOKED AT HER!
SHE WAS GIVING ME CHANGE!
NO, MICHAEL! IT WASN'T A LOOK.
IT WAS A LOOK.
OH, MY!
PLEASE DON'T FIGHT.
YOUR FATHER WILL BE HOME
ANY MINUTE.
WOW, MA! YOU'RE ALL DRESSED UP!
OH, YEAH. YOUR FATHER'S
TAKING ME OUT TONIGHT.
GOOD FOR YOU, MA.
YOU DESERVE A NIGHT OUT.
WELL, HO, HO, HO AND
WHOOP-DI-DOO. I'M HOME.
OH, HI, ARCHIE.
AH, JEEZ, EDITH, NO TIME
FOR THE KISSES THERE.
THE FIGHT'S ABOUT TO START.
BUT, DADDY, YOU TOLD MA YOU
WERE TAKING HER OUT TONIGHT.
THAT'S TRUE, ARCH.
SHUT UP, YOU MEATHEAD, YOU!
WELL, IF YOU ASK MY OPINION,
MAYBE YOU JUST FORGOT.
AH, JEEZ, EDITH, I DIDN'T
FORGET NOTHIN' THERE,
SO GET ME A BEER
AND STIFLE THERE, HUH?
OH, MY...
OH, MY GOD, JACKIE.
WHAT AM I GONNA DO?
I DON'T KNOW, DONNA.
I JUST DON'T KNOW.
OH, HI, MR. FORMAN.
GO TALK ON YOUR OWN DAMN PORCH.
SO... YOU'VE BEEN PLAYING
MUCH BINGO, PEARL?
OH, FOR GOD'S SAKES, KITTY,
I ATE YOUR DAMN PUDDING.
SO GO!
LAURIE, SAY SOMETHING NICE.
FINE. SOMETHING NICE.
THAT'S MY MAGAZINE.
NOBODY NEEDS TO SEE THAT.
Aunt Pearl: GET OUT!
YOU KNOW, IT'S WEIRD.
BUT I THOUGHT AFTER ME
AND MICHAEL BROKE UP,
I WOULDN'T WANT TO
HANG OUT HERE ANYMORE.
YEP. THAT'S WHAT WE WERE HOPING.
BUT I THINK IF I LEFT,
YOU'D REALLY MISS ME.
RIGHT?
AHEM.
I, UH, I SUPPOSE...
THAT, UM, YOU KNOW,
IT'S IMPORTANT
WHEN YOU HAVE A BAD BREAKUP
THAT YOU FIND FRIENDS TO, UH...
UH, SYMPATHETIC...
UH, STUFF...
UM, SUPPORT AND, UH...
I DON'T KNOW.
RIGHT.
SO LET'S GO TO THE MALL.
NO. I MEANT FRIENDS
LIKE DONNA OR... NOT ME.
BUT I NOTICED
YOU'RE ALONE A LOT,
AND I'M ALONE A LOT,
SO LET'S BE ALONE TOGETHER.
LOOK, WE'RE ALONE RIGHT NOW.
THAT'S NOT REALLY A VERY
GOOD REASON FOR US TO...
WAIT.
LET'S GO TO SIZZLER.
THEY'VE GOT A SALAD BAR.
IT'S ALL YOU CAN EAT.
PLUS 5 DIFFERENT COLORS
OF JELL-O.
I'LL BUY.
YOU'VE BEEN THROUGH
A ROUGH TIME.
LET'S GO, KID.
A SONG FOR JACKIE.
BY MICHAEL KELSO.
♪ YOU MAY THINK
THIS SONG IS STUPID ♪
♪ SO I MADE A CALL TO CUPID ♪
♪ AND HE TOLD ME TO PUT
MY HEART OUT ON MY SLEEVE ♪
♪ SO WE CAN RETRIEVE
OUR LOVE FROM THE TRASH ♪
♪ TRASH, TRASH ♪
SO WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WELL, I THINK THAT...
YOU SHOULD DRAW HER A PICTURE.
HEY, PAL...
YOU THINK YOU'RE FUNNY?
WELL, JUST WAIT,
'CAUSE SOMEDAY DONNA'S
GONNA CRUSH YOUR
STUPID LITTLE HEART, TOO.
YEAH. AHEM.
SEE, I DON'T THINK SO
BECAUSE I'VE TAKEN SPECIAL
PRECAUTIONS TO PREVENT
THAT VERY THING FROM HAPPENING.
UH, LIKE, FOR INSTANCE,
I... DON'T SLEEP
WITH OTHER WOMEN.
YEAH?
WELL... IT'S ONLY
'CAUSE YOU'RE CHICKEN.
HEY.
HEY, BABY.
WHAT SAY YOU GRAB PAPA
A ROOT BEER, HUH?
OH, MY GOD. I CANNOT LOOK.
LISTEN, YOU WORM,
I AM NOT YOUR SLAVE
OR A WAITRESS OR YOUR DAMN MAID!
AND DON'T GET ALL
ARCHIE BUNKER-Y ON ME,
OR I WILL KICK YOUR ASS
TO THE MOON!
HEY, ERIC, WHAT RHYMES
WITH DONNA?
♪ I DIDN'T MEAN TO CHEAT,
BUT SHE FORCED ME ♪
♪ SHE DOWNRIGHT COERCED ME ♪
HEY, THAT'S KINDA GOOD.
MAN, I JUST ASKED HER
FOR A ROOT BEER.
YOU TRIED TO CONTROL HER, ERIC.
AND THE WOMAN ALWAYS
CONTROLS THE MAN.
THAT'S TRUE.
DONNA DOES NOT CONTROL ME!
OH, ERIC, YOU HAVE SO MUCH
TO LEARN, MY FRIEND.
YEAH. I WISH JACKIE
WAS STILL CONTROLLING ME.
I LOVE BEING ON A SHORT LEASH.
♪ PUT THE SHORT LEASH
BACK ON ME ♪
KELSO, LET ME SEE THAT
FOR A SECOND.
YEAH.
YOU KNOW, THAT'S KINDA FUNNY.
THAT WAS YOUR GUITAR.
BURN!
HYDE, THOSE BOOTS
LOOK REALLY NICE ON YOU.
YOU KNOW, JACKIE, YOU BUYING
ME BOOTS IS JUST WRONG.
YOU SHOULD'VE LET ME
SHOPLIFT THEM.
NO, HYDE. I WANT YOU
TO HAVE THEM.
BESIDES, I'M SAVING A FORTUNE
NOW THAT I DON'T HAVE TO FEED
AND CLOTHE MICHAEL.
WELL, IF YOU INSIST.
I DO.
SO I WAS THINKING
TOMORROW NIGHT,
WE SHOULD, YOU KNOW...
WHOA, OKAY. ALL RIGHT NOW,
COME ON, JACKIE.
THIS WAS A ONE TIME ONLY
THING, ALL RIGHT?
IF YOU'RE TRYING TO BRIBE
ME WITH THESE BOOTS, MAN,
YOU CAN JUST TAKE THEM BACK.
I SEE.
OH, WHAT ARE YOU
GONNA DO NOW, CRY?
OH, MAN, YOU'RE CRYING.
HEY, JACKIE...
COME ON, MAN.
IT'S GONNA BE FINE, OKAY?
YOU'RE GONNA BE FINE.
THIS WHOLE THING IS
GONNA BE FINE, ALL RIGHT?
NO. NO!
BAD JACKIE!
BUT, HYDE, I THOUGHT WE AGREED
THAT YOU WERE ALONE
AND I WAS ALONE...
JACKIE, I'M TRYING TO HELP YOU
OUT HERE, ALL RIGHT?
SO JUST LISTEN TO ME.
YOU GOTTA REALIZE THAT YOU
CAN DO BETTER THAN KELSO.
BUT WHAT IF I NEVER FIND
ANYBODY ELSE?
OH, YOU WILL, MAN.
YOU'LL FIND SOMEBODY GREAT.
YOU SEE, I, MYSELF,
DON'T LIKE YOU.
I FIND YOU ABRASIVE.
BUT IF I DIDN'T KNOW YOU
AND I HAD NEVER TALKED TO YOU,
I'D THINK YOU WERE TOTALLY HOT.
THANK YOU, HYDE.
ANYTHING FOR YOU, DOLL.
PEARL, HONEY, PLEASE COME OUT.
OH! LAURIE, SHE KINDA LIKES
YOU. DO SOMETHING.
AUNT PEARL!
WHY DON'T YOU COME OUT,
AND YOU CAN SHOW ME
YOUR DAMN SCRAPBOOKS AGAIN?
EVERY TIME YOU PEOPLE COME,
I GOTTA GET DRESSED
AND PUT MY TEETH IN.
AND YOU'RE NOT WORTH IT,
SO GET LOST!
NOW CAN WE GO?
NO. AHEM.
OKAY, FINE. YOU KNOW WHAT?
I GIVE UP.
LET'S JUST GO.
I JUST HOPE WHEN I GET OLD,
SOMEONE COMES TO VISIT ME.
DON'T BE RIDICULOUS, MOM.
ERIC WILL COME.
WELL, I'M GONNA GO WARM
THE CAR UP.
NO, LAURIE.
THIS IS IMPORTANT
TO YOUR MOTHER.
SO SIT DOWN.
COME ON, PEARL.
THERE'S A BUCKS GAME ON.
THE BUCKS, HUH?!
OH-HO!
WELL, YOU KNOW, SEE?
THIS IS NICE.
THE ONLY THING
THAT KEEPS ME ALIVE
IS WATCHING THE BUCKS LOSE.
PFFT!
GO BUCKS.
MICHAEL, NO. I DON'T
WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
NO. YOU'RE RIGHT.
OKAY? BECAUSE WORDS DON'T DO IT.
THAT'S WHY I WROTE THIS SONG.
OH, GOD.
♪ JACKIE, PLEASE
TAKE ME BACKIE ♪
♪ I'LL GET THE KNACK, SEE ♪
OKAY, MICHAEL, STOP.
MICHAEL, STOP.
YES, PLEASE, KELSO, STOP.
I CANNOT TAKE THIS ANYMORE.
THIS IS HOW YOU SERENADE
A WOMAN.
♪ BESAME ♪
♪ BESAME MUCHO ♪
♪ COMO SI FUERA ESTA NOCHE ♪
♪ LA ULTIMAVEZ ♪
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YEAH. WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
UM, THIS IS MY SCHOOL SONG
FROM BACK HOME.
I DON'T LOVE YOU.
HEY, WHAT'S GOING ON?
NOTHING.
NOTHING AT ALL.
THANK YOU, HYDE, FOR TONIGHT.
IT WAS VERY SPECIAL.
OHH! AIEE.
ISN'T SHE NICE?
HEY, FELLAS, YOU
LIKE MY NEW BOOTS?
SO, THEN ERIC SAYS TO DONNA,
"I CANNOT GO OUT WITH YOU,
BECAUSE I'M GOING OUT
WITH THE GUYS."
OH, JEEZ.
WHAT? I DON'T THINK
THAT'S THE PROBLEM.
NO. WHAT'S HIS NAME'S RIGHT.
LOOK, I DON'T THINK
I DID ANYTHING WRONG.
I'M NOT GOING TO
APOLOGIZE TO DONNA.
OH, YEAH?
WHAT? WHY?
HERE'S THE THING.
YOU'RE ASSUMING THAT YOU'RE
GOOD ENOUGH FOR DONNA.
AND YOU'RE NOT.
YES, I AM.
NO, YOU'RE NOT.
JUST LIKE I'M NOT
GOOD ENOUGH FOR YOUR MOTHER.
OKAY, WELL...
YEAH, THAT'S TRUE.
HEY, WATCH IT. I'M TRYING TO
HELP YOU OUT HERE.
I'M SORRY. YES, SIR.
LOOK, DO YOU REALLY
THINK I WANTED TO SPEND
THE WHOLE DAMN DAY
SITTING IN A ROOM
WITH A WOMAN WHO HATES THE
BUCKS AND SMELLS LIKE CABBAGE?
WELL, I DIDN'T.
BUT THAT'S THE PRICE
YOU PAY, SON.
NOW, YOU GO CALL DONNA
BEFORE SHE REALIZES
HOW MUCH BETTER OFF
SHE IS WITHOUT YOU.
GO ON NOW. GO!
GO! YOU HEARD HIM, GO!
BUT WHAT ABOUT...
BLAH, BLAH, BLAH.
MAKE THE CALL, LITTLE MAN.
LISTEN, DONNA...
NO. WAIT.
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT...
YOU KNOW...
WHAT HAPPENED.
AND I REALIZE
I MAY HAVE OVERREACTED.
IT'S JUST THAT I'M
A LITTLE VULNERABLE NOW
THAT OUR RELATIONSHIP
IS... MATURED.
DONNA, NO APOLOGY NECESSARY.
I WELCOME YOUR INSANE
BEHAVIOR AND CRITICISM.
DON'T BE A JERK, ERIC.
NO. NO. UH, AHEM, I'M
ACTUALLY... I'M BEING SERIOUS.
I'M WILLING TO DO...
WHATEVER IT TAKES
FOR US TO BE TOGETHER.
WHATEVER IT TAKES.
IT'S WORTH IT.
WELL... THANK YOU.
SO, UH, FOR FUTURE REFERENCE,
DO I HAVE TO ASK YOU,
UH, BEFORE I GO OUT
WITH MY FRIENDS?
NO.
UH... YES.
SOMETIMES.
SO, UH, HOW WILL I
KNOW WHICH TIMES?
WELL, YOU'LL KNOW AFTERWARDS
WHEN I GET MAD.
OKAY. YEAH.
UH, IS THERE, YOU KNOW,
MAYBE A BETTER SYSTEM THAN THAT?
NO. I REALLY CAN'T
THINK OF ONE. NO.
OKAY, FAIR ENOUGH.
I'M REALLY SORRY.
ME, TOO.
SO, UH, I BLEW OFF
THE GUYS TONIGHT
TO HANG OUT WITH YOU.
SO MY CALENDAR IS WIDE OPEN.
I'M... I'M HERE FOR YOU, DONNA.
OH, THAT'S TOO BAD.
I'M HANGING OUT WITH JACKIE.
YOU COULD COME IF YOU WANT.
THAT'S REALLY NOT FUNNY.
SO, AUNT PE...
SHH!
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY CARSEY-WERNER
PRODUCTIONS AND FOX BROADCASTING COMPANY
I WAS WONDERING...
SHH! OKAY.