Previously on
The Secret Circle...
Aah!
Cassie.
I'm sorry
about your mom.
Thanks.
Have you seen her yet?
She got in yesterday.
It's ok, Cassie.
We're different.
You're different.
You're a witch. You're
a full blooded, 100% witch.
There's no such thing
as witches and magic.
Are you doing this?
We are.
With her here, we
have real power now.
Each family
has a book,
a journal that lays down each
family line.
A complete circle is 6.
You complete
the circle.
Now we're whole.
You are seriously
messed up.
She's got the gift.
Are you sure you can get
Cassie to do what we need?
The circle will take care of that
without even knowing it.
My sweet Cassie,
I didn't want you
to have this life,
but destiny's not
easy to run from.
You have incredible power
inside you.
People will come for it.
They will come for you.
I hoped that keeping this secret
would keep you safe,
but all I've done
is left you unprotected.
I know how alone
you must feel,
but be careful
who you trust,
even people who
call themselves friends.
Your power is the only thing
that can keep you safe.
Give me light.
Ok.
* The Secret Circle 01x02 *
Bound
Original Air Date on September 22, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
You got to go.
Come on, my aunt's
a Jesus freak.
Fine.
Did things work out
with Cassie and you girls?
Us girls?
You're a part of this, too.
No. We think Faye's monsoon
scared the crap out of her.
So are we binding
the circle or not?
I guess not.
I mean, Faye says
it's a bad idea anyway.
Do you always listen
to Faye?
No. Otherwise
I wouldn't be here.
And, you know what,
can you keep this quiet, ok?
I don't want anyone knowing we
hooked up, so don't go bragging.
I'm gonna brag
about you?
You're an ass.
Please.
Do you own a shirt?
Ok, curtains,
you can close now.
Close, now!
Hey, want some
breakfast?
No, I'm late.
Everything ok?
Uh, yeah, I'm fine.
I'm just frazzled.
Cassie, I know
this isn't easy.
Losing your mother,
moving away from home.
But I'm here
if you want
to talk about anything.
I really am late.
What's the racket
outside?
Sea fair.
It's this weekend.
They're setting up.
We're out of steelhead
and mussels.
No, we're not.
I already called them in.
So what's going on
between you and Diana's dad?
Hmm?
You two almost
went to blows.
Charles Meade's a punk.
He's always been a punk.
Well, that punk is also a lawyer
on the town council, Dad.
So it's probably not
the best idea to piss him off.
And he's Diana's father.
So, please just try
and make an effort, ok?
Faye, we're late.
You don't have to shout.
Is that what
you're wearing?
Do you love it?
It's new.
Exactly how I don't
want you to dress.
You could stand
to lose a button.
I'm the principal.
I have to be buttoned.
Well, then live vicariously
through me.
Granddaddy!
Hey, there, kitten.
What are you
doing here?
It's lonely up at the lake
all by myself.
Dawn.
Henry.
How long
you staying?
I'm not sure yet.
I have some business
to take care of.
You're retired.
And I wanted to see
my granddaughter
and daughter-in-law.
Well, I'm happy
to see you.
So long.
Is everything ok?
If it's not,
I'll let you know.
Well, you're welcome
to stay as long as you'd like.
That's gracious of you,
being it's my home.
Hi, there.
I'm Sally Matthews, class President.
Oh, hi. Cassie.
The new girl.
I just wanted
to welcome you
and see if you
needed anything.
Anything...social,
extracurricular, I'm your girl.
And if you're not
doing anything tomorrow,
you should come
to the fair.
I'm in charge of
the school raffle,
and we really need
new band uniforms.
I could really use
the help.
It's a great way
to meet people.
- Ok, sure.
- Ok.
She's been here
for 5 minutes,
don't torture
the girl yet.
We're talking, Faye.
And I'm
interrupting, Sally.
That Sally Matthews
talks more than I can listen.
Look, I want
to apologize
for what happened
on the dock with the storm.
Things got a little
out of hand.
I wanted to thank
you for stopping it.
With you here,
our powers are magnified,
and it's awesome, but
we have to practice a little.
Has Diana gotten to you yet
about binding the circle?
- Not yet.
- Just say no.
It is exactly what
we don't want to do.
Why not?
It links us together,
all 6 of us.
We won't have
individual power.
It'll become a factious circle with
control freak Diana as dictator.
And I don't want someone telling me
what to eat for lunch,
much less what parade
I can rain on, you know.
No, I don't.
I don't know you,
I don't want to know you,
and I don't want any part of this,
so you need
to leave me alone.
Understand?
Charles Meade.
- Why is Henry in town?
- I don't know.
He's your father-in-law,
not mine.
Could he be onto us?
I doubt that.
We were very careful.
We covered our tracks.
I don't like him here.
I don't trust him at all.
You just don't like him.
'Cause he doesn't like me.
He blames me for Tom's death,
like it was my fault.
We all have to blame
someone.
Keep your eyes open.
So I have two big rules
in my classroom.
Rule number one...
do not breathe in the vapors
of these chemicals.
Rule number two...
always wear goggles.
Ok, let's get it started.
Got a big day today.
First and foremost,
safety goggles on, please.
Afterwards, I want you to pour
300 milliliters of solution "A"
and two drops of solution "B"
into your beakers, please.
Now, take in mind that many of
these carbonates are very toxic,
which, for those you
who don't know,
that means dangerous.
Now, remember that
the point of this experiment
is to compare the reactivity
of these different metal carbonates...
Fire without flame
bring me heat.
- What are you doing?
- Experimenting. Try it.
Fire without flame...
Bring me heat.
- Fire without flame...
- Bring me heat.
Ohh.
As you can see, it's a white salt
soluble in water,
and it's found in bleach,
and it's used as well in the
production of soap and glass.
It's also the primary
component of potash...
Ohh!
Is anyone hurt?
Cassie. Cassie,
wait a minute.
I did that.
I got mad and that's
what happened.
I didn't mean to.
Why is this happening?
How do I stop it?
That's the thing,
you can't.
But if you let me,
I can help.
Why do you guys
come here?
Because
no one else does.
Condemned buildings
are like that.
Well, it's important
that no one find out about us.
Especially our families.
How did you discover...
we're witches?
Diana found her mom's
Book of Shadows.
That's how we know
about all of us.
She's the only one
with a book?
Technically each family
has a book,
but hers is the only one
we have access to.
Why?
Because witchcraft
is forbidden.
It was abolished.
Because of what happened
years ago.
It's when my mom died.
And Diana's mom.
Faye's dad.
Melissa's mom.
Nick lost both
of his parents.
And my dad.
I don't know much
about him.
Just that there was
some big accident.
Well, the official story
was some teens were
partying on an old boat
and there was a fire.
Some didn't get out.
A fire.
Diana thinks it's because
they didn't bind the circle.
I don't understand.
Every witch is born
into a circle.
Ours is made up of
our 6 families.
The circle has more power
than any one person can handle.
Binding it is the only way
we can utilize the power,
but keep it controlled.
Faye says that it will
link us together.
Yes. It will limit
our individual abilities,
but strengthen us
as a group.
That way no one
can have too much power.
It's like living
in a Harry Potter movie.
He has a wand.
It is not all bad.
Just let me show you.
He used a Signa spell.
I nearly drown on
the floor of my own bar.
You were drunk.
I could tell when
you called me last night.
I'd been drinking.
I wasn't drunk.
He used magic.
He tried to threaten me,
Henry.
It's impossible.
Everyone in your circle
was stripped of their power.
I know.
Believe me, I know.
But he's figured out
a way around that.
Why would he be
threatening you?
I was talking to
Cassie Blake about her mother.
He was worried I would
say something stupid.
Did you?
No.
Of course not.
Hey.
Diana,
what happened?
Adam took
the blame.
He said he mixed
the chemicals
and miscalculated
the chloride.
And Mr. Herman
believed him?
He couldn't explain
it any better.
Faye, we got lucky.
No one was hurt.
Now, when are you
gonna get it through your head,
we have to bind
the circle.
Have fun.
Can't you talk
to her?
Maybe we should bind it.
I don't like all this stray energy
floating around.
No.
Not if it means
we'll be linked.
I don't want you to have
a say in what I do.
I don't want you
to control me.
But we'll have
more strength as a group
and can use it
better.
For what, world peace?
Are we gonna save the turtles?
Why can't we just
enjoy it?
Because it's selfish
and dangerous.
Yes, and I'm good
with that.
In fact,
I'm great with it.
Ok, what's this?
Some spells in Diana's book
requires certain herbs
and roots.
We've been experimenting.
Are you crazy?
It's grounded.
I'm holding it right now.
Trust me.
Take my hand.
Heh.
Energy is flowing
from the battery,
through you, to me,
to this.
Heh.
Try it by yourself.
Just concentrate
on the energy.
Feel the flow
inside you.
Focus.
Ok. Breathe...
Slow, deep breaths.
Look at me.
This is a bad idea.
- I'm...I'm sorry.
- No. It's my fault.
I shouldn't have come.
* I'm-a gonna let go *
* I'm-a gonna waste some time *
* oh, my, my, my, oh *
* you-a gonna say so... *
Oh, uh,
there's Sally.
Are you gonna be ok
without me?
Of course. Have fun.
I'll see you at home.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I didn't think
you'd come.
I figured
Faye turned you against me.
Faye turned me
against Faye.
Well, we just became friends
in this moment.
So what do I need to do?
It's super easy.
You just have to sell tickets.
Ok. Great.
Easy's exactly
what I need today.
* Burned, burned,
burned, oh *
* on and on and on *
* the lights goes
off and on *
* on and on and on *
* dare you to,
but don't you dare *
* when you come down,
I'll be there *
* when I come down,
we'll play fair *
* I'm not cold,
I'm just a-shakin'... *
Boo.
I win.
He broke
my concentration.
Ok, I'm bored.
Let's turn it up
a notch.
Follow me, ladies.
* On and on and on *
* the light goes off
and on *
- Hey, Cassie.
- Oh. Hee hee.
How did you get
roped into volunteering?
I'm here for
the distraction.
Adam told me
you guys practiced last night.
I'm happy to help
some time if you want.
The thing is,
we need you.
We can't be a circle
without you.
I'm sorry. You're gonna have
to find someone else.
There is
no one else.
You're one of
the 6 families.
I thought you
understood that.
No, I don't understand
any of this.
What you're asking
is ludicrous.
I can't just blindly
agree to it.
I know it's a lot
to accept.
It's too much.
I can't.
You're scared.
Of course I'm scared.
Who wouldn't be?
Look, I...
I have a feeling,
and then things explode.
Which is why we need
to bind the circle.
Our energies are flying
everywhere all at once
with no rhyme
or reason.
We have to contain it before
someone gets really hurt.
I'm sorry. I don't think that
I can help you.
Please note that no
black cauldron was used in
the making of this potion.
Open up.
Mmm.
What's in it?
All natural herbs
and spices.
Just boiled down to liquid.
I tasted them.
And...
And you got this
from Diana's book?
Will it work?
Are you gonna
try it?
No, I'm good.
Thanks.
So what do I tell
Diana, huh?
She won't stop with
the binding ritual crap.
You tell her to shove her ritual
up her hoo-ha.
Everything's been out of whack
since Cassie got here.
You know she busted my window,
completely shattered it.
You know, I think
we should listen to Diana.
She's the one with
the rule book.
We just need
to practice more.
More power requires
more practice.
You started a monsoon
and couldn't stop it.
Oh. Could we all
just let that go?
Mmm.
Enjoying yourself,
Henry?
Ethan Conant said Charles Meade
threatened him with magic.
He said Charles used
the signa on him
when he overheard him talking to
Cassie Blake about her mother.
I don't believe it.
Ethan isn't exactly
a reliable source.
He's an alcoholic.
And Charles, he doesn't
have any power.
None of us do.
Your circle took care
of that.
I'd be inclined
to agree with you,
except I've witnessed it.
Henry, nobody
is practicing.
Those days are over.
The children.
I saw them today.
Your own daughter
is one of them.
Faye?
With the Blake girl
back in town,
they have a complete circle.
They can awaken
to their full potential.
We have to stop them.
They don't know
anything.
We've kept this
from them.
I'm gonna take care of it.
I swore I would never let what
happened to your circle
ever happen again.
Henry, stop.
Look, I know we've
had our differences,
but I lost my husband.
I'm not about to let something
happen to Faye.
Let me help you.
Tell me what I can do.
What were you thinking?
That he wouldn't
say anything?
Use your head.
I may have gone
too far,
but we can't have Ethan running
his mouth off about Amelia.
He could blow it for us.
No, you've already
taken care of that.
What are we gonna do
about Henry?
You're not gonna do anything
except give me that crystal.
That is all the power
we have.
If we use it up,
we have nothing.
We can't waste it.
Ok.
You made your point.
Look, I get it.
It feels good
to do magic again.
It's seductive.
But we have to be
smart, Charles.
Just think of
the bigger picture.
Hey, Cassie.
Hey.
How you doing?
Um, the other night you were
telling me about my mom.
You caught me drinking.
I'm sorry if I said
anything inappropriate.
You said our
families are aligned.
What did you mean?
There's this old legend
about our families.
Some astrological lore
about the two of us
on some collision course
of destiny.
It's silly.
I've never really believed
in astrology.
Me either.
To be honest,
I just know that whenever
I was around your mother
I'd get this feeling.
This attraction to her
that was impossible to ignore.
All she had to do
was look at me
and smile just right,
and I'd light up inside.
No one else could do that.
Like I said...
It's silly.
Uh, no.
Not at all.
* I can't believe
I can't let it go *
* difference made... *
Hey.
So I've been asked to come
over here and convince you
to bind the circle.
Yeah. She kind of
struck out.
Yeah.
Yeah, so I heard.
What did you tell
Diana about last night?
That I showed you how to focus
and harness your energy.
She's ok with that.
Does it always feel
like last night?
There's always some
physical reaction.
You know what I mean.
Ok, so if we bind
the circle,
then we'll be able
to control it better?
Yes.
No more exploding
light bulbs or floating water?
I don't think so.
Look at them.
They're like little
goldfish stuck together.
Shut up, Faye.
Seriously, Diana, you are two
minutes away from losing him.
I want to bind
the circle tonight.
I'm busy.
Faye, use your head.
You know we have to.
Oh, I'd prioritize
if I were you.
You've got a bigger problem.
Stop groping.
It's not gonna happen.
Why are you fighting?
Just go with it.
Do you honestly think that
I would get with you?
Ha ha.
Would you hit that?
I'd have to leave
my self-esteem at the door.
Hey, Cassie.
What you doing?
I'm looking
for Sally.
She's a bore.
Hey, what do you say
you and me do a little magic?
I don't think so.
Like start another storm.
This time you start it
and I'll stop it.
That's not funny.
You could have killed somebody
with that storm.
Fine, we'll do
something else then.
You pick.
Think big.
Get away from me.
You did that.
You're a little fire cracker,
aren't you, Cassie?
I don't want to
start this with you.
Faye, please, don't.
Come on, it's a total rush
and you know it.
- It's too risky.
- Then stop me.
Stop it.
Stop it!
Excuse me,
little miss telekinesis.
Hey, what's going on?
Not now, Sally.
Yes, now, Faye.
I am so sick of your
superiority complex.
Ok, Sally, why
don't we just...
Get off, Faye.
No. You go away.
Faye, what did you do?
She's not breathing!
Somebody call
an ambulance.
I called already.
They're on their way.
Step back.
Ok, ok.
It's ok. It's ok.
No, no, no. Don't move.
You used
the crystal.
I thought we weren't
gonna waste it.
We don't kill
innocent children.
You have a very interesting
set of rules there, Dawn.
You'll have to
explain them to me sometime.
It was Faye's fault.
She's my daughter.
That kind of guilt
would have destroyed her.
What would you have done
if it were Diana?
The paramedic said
she's gonna be ok.
I didn't mean for
anyone to get hurt.
I really didn't.
With you here,
we can do more.
I just have to will
things and they happen.
We can't let our feelings
control us like this.
But I like...
I don't want this
to go away.
We don't have a choice.
It's too dangerous.
If we can't control
what we feel or what we think,
we're just gonna keep
hurting people.
I don't want to be
connected to you
anymore than you
want to be to me.
But no one else
can get hurt.
It's wrong.
Diana's right.
We have to bind the circle.
We'll be at
the beach at midnight.
It was Charles
that threw me.
At first I thought he pushed
the children to form a circle
and then used their power
to somehow reestablish his.
But then I realized
Charles Meade is many things,
clever is not
one of them.
And then I saw you.
You couldn't have saved that
girl tonight without a crystal.
Where'd you get it?
They were all destroyed.
It's wrong of you
to strip us of our power.
There was a time
for witchcraft.
Time is long gone.
There's no place for it
in this world anymore.
You've forgotten
what it feels like.
How long has it been
since you practiced, 15 years?
This circle
is different.
You know what can be unleashed
if they bind together.
I'm going to
the elders tomorrow
and tell them what's
going on here.
Give me the crystal.
You know, Henry,
I've got a better idea.
I think you should go back
to the lake and take it easy.
It'd be awful if you had
another heart attack.
You might not
survive it this time.
You should know...
I loved your son.
* I'm still wondering *
* After all this time *
* turning over leaves *
* that everything falls off,
oh, so easy.. *
I'll get the book,
you drive Cassie to the beach.
Ok.
Well, you did it.
You convinced her
to bind the circle with us.
I don't know what to do expect.
Do you?
No, not really.
So how do we know
it'll work?
I don't know, Adam.
I just found
the stupid book.
I didn't go looking for it.
I don't know anymore than you
or anyone else.
What's going on?
Nothing.
I don't know
what I'm doing.
I pretend like I do,
but...
Do I have anything to worry
about with you and Cassie?
Why would you
ask that?
Because I'm insecure.
And I love you.
Come here.
I love you, too.
You're home.
Your grandfather drove back to
the lake tonight.
He said to tell you
good-bye.
What happened
tonight?
Were you drinking?
Things got a little
out of hand.
I'm the high school
principal in this town.
It's how people see me.
What do you think runs
through their minds
after something
like tonight?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to embarrass you.
You embarrassed
yourself.
Come here.
That girl could have
been you tonight.
Everything's gonna
be ok, mom.
Get in.
I'll take you there.
I'm good.
Seriously,
I want to walk.
I like it.
It's a nice night.
Come on,
we're friends now.
Sure. Friends bound
for eternity.
Totally normal.
It's the right thing
to do, you know.
For all of us.
I hope so.
So, ok, friend thing
settled.
Get in already.
The beach
is 2 miles away,
and I promised Diana
I'd bring you.
["Victory Dance" by
My Morning Jacket playing]
* Should I lift the dirt
and plant the seed *
* even though
I've never grown *
* should I wet the ground
with the sweat from my brow *
* and believe in
my good work *
* my good work *
* my good work... *
Fire, earth, metal, air, water,
and blood.
By these elements,
we bind the circle
and follow in the footsteps
of our ancestors
who pledged
themselves to fight
against the forces
of darkness.
When evil assails us,
when fear weakens us,
when descent
threatens us,
in the circle we will
find out power.
We come to this place
alone, but leave bound as one.
With this oath,
our journey begins together.
Do you accept the circle?
I accept.
== sync, corrected by Ownsin ==