It's hard to believe it,
but spring is here.
Yep, this year's
just flying by.
Yeah, and you know, I got to say,
this year, not as good as last.
You think?
I do. I mean, look. We all tried
some new things, and that was fun.
Uh, yard guys, illegitimate daughters,
less fighting, more live music.
Well, maybe you remember last year
as better, 'cause it was all new.
So you think I've sentimentalized
the past all out of proportion?
Yeah, come on, I mean, we
can't keep living in last year.
Sure we can. And check this out, man.
Things are already going
back to the way they were.
I'm back together with Summer.
You're single again.
-I think I know where this is going.
-I'll tell you where it's going.
It's going to the Harbor
School Pep Rally Bonfire.
Come on.
You could rally a little
pep, couldn't you?
-Especially if you invited...
-Don't say it.
Aw, it would be
so last year though.
-There's nothing going on with me and Marissa.
-Really?
So, there's just no feelings there whatsoever?
You couldn't care less.
It's not about that.
Besides, she's...clearly already taken.
I don't know. I don't
see any chemistry there.
Maybe we should ask them to kiss...real slow-like.
Couldn't help but notice
the, uh, bonfire banner.
Oh, don't talk to me about it.
It's been so stressful.
I can't even find someone
to design the bonfire.
-But you guys are coming, right?
-I don't know, it's a pep rally.
Yeah,
a bonfire pep rally.
-You bet we are.
-Okay, cool. Well,
I'm gonna be late.
Okay. Hey, Ryan, you're going
the way of lockers and classrooms.
Why don't you walk her?
That'd be a nice gesture.
-Okay. Thanks.
-No problem.
-Live in the now, Seth.
-I'm sorry. I'm afraid. I can't do that.
Don't even think
about it, Cohen.
We have lived through enough
of their pain and suffering.
-Yeah, and it was awesome.
-Do not meddle with Ryan and Marissa.
-They're like combustible.
-Yeah, Summer, and what better place for said combustion,
than the Harbor School
Pep Rally Bonfire?
-You're kind of creeping me out.
-I'm okay wi th that.
Wait. Summer.
All right, nice and easy.
Now, start that shoulder turn.
Keep your eye on that ball.
Maintain the spine angle.
Come on, turn those shoulders.
Finish that turn,feel that weight shift!
You feel the...
All right, I'm just gonna stand here,
nice and quietly.
But supportively.
All right.
That was good. Your feet were a little busy.
Maybe quiet your feet down.
-Come on, try it again.
-No more tries.
I hate golf.
I suck at golf.
I no longer want
to play golf.
Honey, you could
only get better.
I'll have to take
your word for it.
Come on. We could
play together.
And you look so
cute in that visor.
I do?
I got to go. We're putting together our
first issue of "Newport Living,"
and we're trying to figure out
what photo of Julie to use on the cover.
Talk about Sophie's Choice.
So who'd you finally get to edit the "Medusa Monthly?"
Carter Buckley. He's really great.
He wants to take it beyond
gossip and dish, focus on culture,
the local art scene. So it's really
more of a pamphlet than a magazine.
Carter Buckley.
Now, what's he done before?
Oh, a bunch of stuff. A magazine,
called The Ugly American,
National Geographic, GQ,
and he self-published
a magazine called Revolution.
You gotta be kidding.
-You know it?
-That was the magazine of Berkeley's left wing.
Portraits of the misunderstood,
the marginalized, the crackpots.
-An entire magazine about losers.
-Oh, but lovable ones.
I read it religiously.
I'm impressed.
-You know, I'd love to meet him.
-Well...
I'll, uh, I'll set something up.
-You found your wedding ring.
-Uh...yeah, behind some cushions.
Thanks for the lesson.
-Hello, Marissa.
-Hey, Cohen.
You seem stressed,
a little distracted.
Yeah, well, it's this bonfire. It'd be
really great if we had, you know, a bonfire.
Well, Coop,
I think I got what ails ya.
First of all,
only Summer calls me Coop.
Yeah, but I figured,
we're back together now,
and you know, if A=C and B=C then A=B,
you know what I'm saying?
No.
I really don't.
So what's your plan?
Who's your social chair savior?
Ryan.
Mr. Water Polo?
I don't think so.
Yeah, but think about this.
That guy worked in-- no, no, no--
he toiled in an actual
construction job.
Also, he enjoys architecture
and burning stuff down.
He did torch Caleb's model home.
But I don't know, I mean,
do you think he'd say yes?
To you? How
could he resist?
Especially now that Lindsay's gone,
the kid's kind of blue.
Might be good for him.
Distract him. And it would be fun.
Although I personally
don't see the appeal, yes.
All right, that's
a good idea. Thanks.
Don't mention it.
Seriously, don't,
especially to Summer.
Hello, Mother.
No, I'm not coming home, okay?
Please, do not...
She's such a little me.
Okay, like you're not creepy enough?
You're just appearing in doorways now?
-Trouble at home?
-Like I'd open up to you.
-Well, here if you need me.
-I'll keep that in mind.
-What do you want?
-I want my money.
Again, good to know.
How'd you get past security?
Charm and good looks. Now, I know
you got this magazine ready to launch.
-Get out, Lance.
-This is not the moment when you want
your somehow perfect reputation undone
by one bad decision, and some not so flattering lighting.
You got three days
to get my money,
or everyone in Newport's
gonna see a lot more than your face.
Traffic was terrible.
Is Carter here yet?
Mr. Buckley left a voice mail
at around 3:30 a.m., said don't expect him today.
He say why?
No, but I couldn't understand
everything on the message.
-He was...slurring.
-You're kidding.
Well, I guess Julie and I
will proceed without him.
-Oh, hey, Keeks, can't make the meeting.
-Something up?
Just a critical personal
emergency, but nothing important.
Well, I guess
the meeting's canceled.
I can try Mr. Buckley,
see if he's changed his mind.
Uh, no, I'll-I'll,
I'll take care of it.
So how are you and Alex?
Hmm? You know, really great.
Really great?
Or really great?
Really great.
Thanks for clearing
that up for me, Coop.
Oh, hey, can you tell Seth
never to call me Coop again?
'Cause he kind of
ruined the nickname.
Cohen called you Coop?
-When?
-Earlier.
-Hey, hope I'm not interrupting.
-No, actually, I was hoping I'd run into you.
-Oh, yeah? You were?
-You were?
I was. I need someone
to build the bonfire for us,
and I figured, who else has worked
in construction, likes architecture...
-And has burned down a house?
-Yeah. Exactly.
And I thought it would be fun...
working together.
-Oh, you did.
-You did?
Yeah. Besides, if you don't do it,
then the water polo team's not going to have a pep rally.
Yeah, well, we can't
have that happen. Um...
-Sure, yeah, okay.
-You'll do it? That's great.
-Isn't that great?
-It's great!
-What's great?
-Ryan's going to build the bonfire for us.
Hey, great idea, you two.
I love that,
making it happen
on behalf of the school.
Yeah, you know, the idea
is just inspired.
Well, I've got a big test
to study for,
so it looks like
I'll be eating in the library
So long.
Oh, come on! Do you have to go?
You know, will you two
excuse me?
Um, so, thanks again.
I'll see you after school?
-Yeah, sure. My place?
-Your place with Alex?
-Yeah. Is that a problem?
-No.
Okay.
No problem at all.
I looked in the box.
This computer does not have an access key.
Look, look, look, all I want
to do is check my E-mail.
No!
Do not transfer me.
You must have been
talking to Marissa.
Julie, you scared me...
more than usual.
-Always a pleasure, Sanford.
-Only Caleb gets to call me Sanford because he won't not.
-What are you doing here?
-Official business.
And as a new client,
I'm not impressed.
If this is a marital issue, I'm going
to have to decline. Caleb's got me on retainer.
Caleb and I are just fine,
thanks, and well, I'm trying to keep it that way.
I think this is
the first time in my life I'm actually speechless.
It was the '80s.
I was young,
I had no money and...
it was the '80s.
Well, that explains everything.
I'm not going to give you my whole sob story.
Needless to say,
I never thought that it would resurface.
-So where did this come from?
-The auteur behind this masterpiece, his name is Lance Baldwin.
-He's an ex.
-So you started with a porn producer and you ended up with Caleb.
See, I'd consider
that a lateral move.
He wants half a million or he goes public
on the eve of Newport Living's launch.
-You've got to go to the cops.
-No, Sandy, no cops.
And before you even suggest it,
no Caleb.
-I am so not the guy for this.
-Sandy, please.
I'm begging you.
Forget the company
or my marriage.
If Marissa ever
found out about this...
I mean, she's already moved out on me.
She won't take my calls.
She would never
speak to me again.
Oh, it's all right, Julie.
You deal with Marissa
and I'll...
I'll deal with the Colonel.
It's a Boogie Nights reference.
Expect a lot of them.
Fine, don't worry about
it, I wasn't reading.
What the hell
is your problem, Cohen?!
You're interrupting
very studious people.
Like me.
-Now no one can hear you scream.
-What is your problem, woman?
You are. What did I tell you
about messing with Ryan and Marissa?
I was concerned that the water polo team
was gonna be without a pep rally this year,
so I suggested it for the good of the school.
Cohen.
-They belong together.
-No, they don't.
Yes, they do. It is me and you
and it is Ryan and Marissa.
And that's the way
it's supposed to be.
Listen up, Ass Hat.
Ryan and Marissa separate,
both great people that I love.
Together, disaster.
So stay away from
them, all right?
Or otherwise more than the
bonfire is going up in flames.
I can make no promises.
Hey, what's up?
Nothing. I just wanted to see
what you were up to after school.
I feel like we haven't had
a lot of time to hang.
I know, I just, I have
this project to work on after school with Ryan.
With Ryan?
What thing?
-This bonfire pep rally.
-You never mentioned a pep rally.
Yeah, well, I kind of have a handle
on your sense of school spirit.
Yeah, good point. so I guess
I'll just see you at home?
-Hello?
-Yeah, sorry. I'll see you later.
Hello?!
Anyone here?!
Kirsten. Sorry, private party.
We had a meeting.
You want to explain what happened?
Oh, it was just a little thing
I like to call...
-my wedding anniversary.
-You're divorced.
No wonder this party sucks.
I see you found your ring.
Must mean you're still married.
Thanks for stopping by.
Look, I'm sorry
I just stopped by.
But you could at least apologize
for blowing off the meeting.
Right. Yeah. I'm sorry.
And I'm sorry for all the...
future meetings I'm gonna miss.
You see?
Now you don't have to feel bad
about firing me.
Maybe you're not in the best frame
of mind to be having this discussion.
And I'm going to be
less self-loathing if I'm sober?
Come on, I work for a rag
about Julie Cooper... Nichol.
No, it's about culture,
it's about art.
Oh, come on, Kirsten,
this magazine is just a photo opportunity
for 55-year-old women with 25-year-old breasts.
But this is a chance to turn
this community upside down.
Be subversive,
irreverent.
I'd rather be drunk.
You see, Oats, it was even
the same for The Valley.
Last year was just better.
You and Captain Oats
catching up?
Yeah. Does he seem grumpy
to you these days?
I know how he feels. This bonfire
thing, it's a disaster.
you and Marissa working on the
bonfire together. That's pretty cool, huh?
Not so far.
Did a bunch of designs, but they all suck.
Yeah, well, I'm sure whatever you
come with, Marissa will love you.
It.
Dude, there's nothing going on
with me and Marissa.
-Oh, it's none of my business.
-Hey. You guys cool fending for yourselves for dinner?
Sure.
Your mother's at work and I've got to run.
But I'm leaving you some money for pizza.
Thanks.
You two all right?
Yeah. Just a
school project.
Ryan's working with Marissa.
Oh, you and Marissa. That's nice, just like last year.
You and Mom have been
kind of working a lot lately.
-Is everything all right?
-Yeah, yeah. Everything's fine, just busy.
I feel like there's maybe been
some kind of tension recently.
Well, listen, you're married to someone for 20 years,
you're bound to hit a few speed bumps.
It takes work.
But it doesn't mean we don't love each other.
-Good.
-Okay, I'll see ya.
-All right.
-Bye.
You hear that, Ryan?
Love takes work.
-Are you referring to me and Marissa?
-No. I'm staying out of that.
You go work on
your cool bonfire.
-Me and Oats are gonna order in.
-Hey, can I borrow Captain Oats?
Sure. But he's a poor
substitute for a broken heart.
Oats, if he touches you
anywhere weird,
and by weird I mean...
I want you to neigh
as loud as you can.
See, you're punching people.
That's very last year.
It's cool, though.
What?
It's nice to see you,
too, sweetie.
Whoa, hello?
I haven't been vaccinated.
-What do you want?
-Well, I thought that we could talk face-to-face.
-May I come in?
-No.
Don't you think you're
taking this a little too far?
You enjoy living in squalor?
Well, you and Caleb don't live here,
so it can't be that disgusting.
-I could make you come home.
-What are you gonna do, call the cops?
I'd love to tell them
all about you.
-I could take away your credit cards.
-I'll get a job.
-You? Doing what?
-Or maybe I'll just steal. You know I'm really good at that.
Marissa.
Come home, please.
Don't throw away your future
just because you hate me.
We've all done things in life that we regret,
but it is never too late.
-The door is always open.
-Not this one.
Hey, you're in my room.
Which never happened
when we were dating.
I hope I'm not interrupting.
What, are you trying on
new clothes or something?
No, actually,
I've been trying on clothes from last year.
Come in.
Hi. What's going on?
I know this is weird,
but, I need your advice.
It's about Marissa.
Well, I'm a little fuzzy
on your guys' relationship,
so perhaps you have some photos
or a video or things you...
I was just trying to be
thorough.
It's not about me and Marissa.
This is about Marissa and Ryan.
I just...
I have a sense about them.
-Yeah, I have a lot of...
-Oh, so there is something going on?
Hey, if you were this sensitive and neurotic when
we were dating, things might have really worked out.
I just... I really, really
have fallen hard for this girl.
Please, will you just tell me
if I am fighting for a lost cause here?
Are they just one of those couples
that will always be a couple?
Is this about the other night
at the mall?
What, no.
I know all about the mall, why?
Okay, so then, big deal.
They slept in a tent together.
A lot of friends would do that.
I'm sorry,
did you just say "tent"?
Does that...
did you think I said that?
No, no,
'cause I said...
what did you think?
No, 'cause I was saying
-that they repented for lent.
-Marissa forgot to mention that part.
-Probably because it wasn't a big deal.
-Well, thank you, you've been very helpful.
Wait, I wasn't even trying
to meddle. I was saying...
Summer's gonna kill me.
-Oh, come in.
-Great. Thanks.
Sorry about the mess.
We're between maids.
Ah, how do you survive?
So where's...where's Alex?
-working.
-Got it.
Just us.
-Yeah, go ahead.
-Okay.
Let's see.
Da-da-dum!
-Captain Oats?
-Yeah, Seth let us borrow him for the bonfire.
Oh, we're not gonna burn
him, though, are we?
No, no. He's our inspiration.
I figure we'll build a scale model so we'll
know how much wood to use for the real thing.
-Oh, a Trojan horse.
-Exactly. So, what do you think?
I think it's perfect.
Yeah, it's not bad.
So let's get started.
How are you with
Popsicle sticks?
Really good.
-You got a warrant?
-You're not suspicious, are you.
I'm Sandy Cohen.
I'm Julie Cooper's attorney.
And I'm a huge
fan of your work.
-You got my money?
-I'm here to negotiate.
Is this gonna be a three-way?
'Cause my rate doubles.
Why don't you grab some
more smokes at the store.
We got business.
You know the offer. 500 grand
makes this thing go away.
Oh, well, that's no offer, that's extortion.
She's willing to pay you $50,000, which could
finance a handful of your masterpieces.
You need to add another zero
to that offer.
Otherwise this thing is streaming live
on the Internet in 72 hours.
-Do you really think anyone's gonna care?
-Oh, I think Julie will.
Enough to save her magazine, her marriage.
-Well... you'll be hearing from me.
-It's been a pleasure.
-This is gonna be great.
-Ah, glad you liked it.
Yeah, and I'm glad Seth
suggested you for the job.
-Seth suggested me?
-Yeah. Why?
No, he's, kind of stuck in the past.
He thinks that now that
he's back with Summer, that...
you know.
-Yeah. Crazy.
-Totally.
Yeah.
-Good night.
-Yeah, good night.
You almost hit me.
I'm sorry, I'll try again.
-What do you think you're doing?
-Let me try to put it in a way you'll understand.
Stay away from her.
-Alex, there's nothing going on.
-What're you talking about?
Studying late together?
Sharing a sleeping bag?
Yeah, there's nothing
going on at all, Ryan.
Hey! Hey! Listen to me...
No, no, no. You listen to me.
Don't go near my
girlfriend again.
You understand me now?
-Walk away.
-I'm gone.
-Ah, I'm sorry I missed you last night.
-I'm sorry I missed you, too.
The all-consuming magazine.
-And you were...?
-Also at work.
On a new case.
Another Newport calamity?
No. This is one
I've never seen before.
I hope to never see it again.
Hey, how about you and I log
a little quality time today?
-I'd love to, but I have to work.
-Ah, with Carter Buckley?
Actually, without.
It turns out that Newport Living
wasn't for him after all.
When he didn't show up for work yesterday,
I went by his place, and I found him
drowning in self-pity and tequila.
Only a couple weeks in Newport
and already his spirit is crushed.
I never would've thought that'd be possible.
Here's a guy who built a whole magazine
around people who fought the system, no matter the cost.
The guy was
an inspiration to me.
You know, that magazine of his
that you loved in college?
Do you happen to have a copy?
Revolution?
Yeah, I probably do.
Probably in the office
Or the garage.
Hey, man. How'd it go
last night with Marissa?
Things with Marissa
went great.
Good.
Things with Alex,
not so much.
-Alex was there?
-Yeah.
She threw a beer
can at my head.
-What?!
-And shoved me a couple times, yeah.
-Pretty hard, actually.
-That is one angry lesbian.
Okay,
here's the thing.
I may have accidentally let a
little something slip about, you know...
-A tent?
-No, I didn't. Yeah, okay, maybe. Yes, I did,
-but I don't understand why she's making
-such a big deal out of it.
Like there's something dirty about camping.
And before Alex and I had
our friendly little chat,
Marissa mentioned that it was your idea
that we work on the bonfire together.
I might have been
the one to mention it,
-but I don't think I should hog all the credit.
-Stay out of it!
Just 'cause you're back with Summer
doesn't mean me and Marissa...
I know.
-You were just a lot happier back then, okay, so...
-Well, that was then.
All right.
Hey, I'm not gonna
be able to make it tonight.
But, uh, the wood's ordered, and
you have the plans, so everything should be fine.
Have fun.
-Who was that?
-My mom.
More empty threats.
You were asleep last night when I got home.
Yeah. Yeah,
I was really tired.
You should try sleeping
in a tent with Ryan.
Oh, but you already did that.
Look, I'm sorry.
I was going to tell you that.
It's just, I didn't want
to make it a big deal.
-Well, it wasn't until you lied.
-I didn't lie.
-I just...
-Lied?
No big deal.
Please tell me
you have some good news.
Well, unfortunately, Lance is
as sleazy as he looks...
but not as dumb.
He owns the rights to the movie
in perpetuity,
and you were a consenting adult when it was shot,
so if he wants to make money off it, it's his prerogative.
Sandy, there's got to be
some way to stop him.
Yeah, we could charge him with
extortion and get an injunction,
but that would involve
the authorities.
Even if I paid him off, there's nothing
to stop him from leaking it anyway.
Look, I'll figure
something out.
You worry about Marissa;
I'll handle the rest.
I can worry all I want,
doesn't seem to help anything.
Why is it that the one person who knows what's best
for their childis the last person that child wants to hear from?
Yeah, we had a similar situation
with Seth last summer, and...
all I can say is that sometimes
it's not the message, it's the messenger.
I don't know, Coop, it sounds
like a pretty bad fight.
-I mean, maybe you should just move home.
-I can't
Because you love Alex and
wherever she is, that's your home?
Because it'll make
my mom too happy.
What was I thinking?
Well... you can't go to the
bonfire with Ryan, then go home to Alex.
You can't ride two horses
with one ass.
It's a proverb.
Okay, well, Ryan is not
going to the bonfire.
What? Why? I thought
it was, like, his idea.
He didn't say,
but I know it's because of Alex.
Wait, I'm confused--
I thought Alex wasn't going.
She's not, but Ryan and I were working late
at the apartment the other night,
and, well, somehow she found
out about the mall and the tent, and...
well, I hadn't exactly
told her about it.
Well, if you didn't tell her,
then who did?
Oh, I am going to kick his ass
back to last year!
Whoa. Hello? Summer?
Whose ass?
Not now, Seth. I'm busy.
sorry to interrupt you
doing... whatever it is you were doing.
Brooding, is it?
Yeah, and right now I'm in the middle
of a major session, so if you could just...
What's going on?
Well, actually, I'm very glad that
I caught you before you go to the bonfire.
-I'm not going to the bonfire.
-Oh, but you have to go.
What, are you and Seth
working on the same team now?
No, I'm on my own mission:
I need help... with Marissa.
For whatever reason that I don't
quite understand, she listens to you.
She needs help.
Maybe she's happy
where she is.
Do you honestly think that
Marissa knows what she wants right now?
She is in so far over her head
with this relationship.
She's skipping school,
she's staying out all hours,
risking everything that's
important to her just to prove a point.
-Okay. So what do you want me to do about it?
-Well, I know that she wants to come home,
but if she does it for me, it's like she's letting me win.
But if she does it for you...
No, I'm not getting in the
middle of Marissa's life.
All right? Not again. And especially
her relationship with Alex.
This is not about Alex. It's about Marissa and her
future, which we can both see is slipping away from her.
Ryan, please help me.
Convince her to come home.
You know that's
what's for the best.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Looking for Marissa.
-This is you staying away?
-It's not about me. I'm here 'cause of her mom.
What, are you and Julie Cooper a team now?
-Yeah. Where is she?
-She's at her little bonfire.
All right.
No, no, you remember what I told you last night.
-You stay away from her.
-Or what?
-You want to find out?
-Sure.
You go down there, it's on.
Great.
You know, this sort of thing
used to be my specialty.
Oh. Little word of advice. If you got to try
this hard, it's not working.
Is this part for the hind legs or the front?
It's just labeled "leg."
Um, front, I think.
-Right or left?
-Guess. The odds are fifty-fifty.
Marissa,the horse's head
seems to only fit the hindquarters.
What do we do?
We're running out of time.
I don't know, okay?
I picked the font for the banner.
I color-coordinated the balloons.
This is not my area of expertise.
Maybe I can help.
-I thought you weren't coming.
-Yeah, well, Captain Oats was concerned that he'd be well-represented.
He's very self-conscious.
He is... Seth's horse.
-So you gonna stick it out?
-Uh, yeah, if I'm needed.
Oh, yeah. Hang on!
Hey, everybody?
This is Ryan.
He's gonna answer any and all of your questions.
All right! Great. That horse is gonna
have its head up its ass if we're not careful.
We need to rotate the neck
over to the other side.
You guys in back. You guys take care of that.
I need you ladies,
right over there, you need to hoe that area.
Hoe that thing down. We need to, uh, we need
to set the tiki torches over here.
Hey! You with the gasoline!
Away from the fire!
What are you doing, man?
All right!
Sun's gonna be down in about an hour.
We can make this happen, okay, people?
Let's go, let's go!
Well, that was a dirty trick.
Haunting me with my past.
I was trying to inspire you.
You know, looking this thing over,
it feels like a lifetime ago.
What was I thinking, making
a magazine all about losers?
Well, at least
they were lovable ones.
Where'd you find this?
Oh, a crusading idealist who remembers every word
of that magazine like it was yesterday--
my husband.
Well, I'll have to meet him.
So, what do you think?
You in?
You say subversive and irreverent,
I say Julie Cooper Nichol.
-Where's that leave us?
-Pretty much lost.
That's pretty much
my favorite place to start.
I've got an idea. Okay, it's not really my idea.
One of the other people from the magazine thought it up, but...
Summer.
Hey, how are you?
I hope you have some Motrin in the house,
'cause you are about to feel some pain!
-I just wanted everyone to be happy!
-Yeah, well, nice going 'cause now everybody is miserable!
You need to start apologizing,
starting with Ryan!
Okay!
Go!
Ryan? You around?
I'm here to apologize.
-He's not here.
-Yeah, I know, I can see that.
Well, where is he?
-You think he went to the bonfire?
-If so, we have a four-alarm emergency on our hands.
Break out your hose, Cohen!
-It's a metaphor.
-I know.
-You got me my money?
-I got this.
You're starting
your own film company.
What better star to hitch
my wagon to than Julie Cooper.
-So you're buying the film from me.
-The master, the film and the negatives.
We're gonna meet
your offer.
-A hundred bucks?
-Consider it a good-faith deposit.
I need two weeks
to raise the rest.
I sign this, I get
half a mil in two weeks?
That's right.
And Lance, just so you know,
if one frame of this
leaks onto the Internet--
I'm not saying that would happen
because you seem like a stand-up guy--
we're coming after you for
ten times the amount, all right?
For copyright infringement and piracy
and... you could go to jail.
I got some good news and some not-so-good news.
-Good news first, always.
-You don't have to worry about the movie surfacing
as long as we pay him,
which is the bad news.
And where am I gonna get
this money?
You're going to have
to talk to Caleb,
-and hopefully he'll understand.
-Oh, yeah, sure he will.
-I am so screwed.
-I know, I saw the footage.
-This is going great.
-Yeah.
-Not for long.
-Hey! What are you doing here?
-Are these your friends?
-Yeah. They're here to see Ryan.
You gotta be kidding me.
Why?
Do you think it's funny?
Hey, guys! Stop it!
Guys, seriously, stop it, okay? Cut it out!
Oh, no, not you guys.
You guys are great!
Go, Harbor!
This is between you and me.
Fine, then let's talk,
you and me.
-Fine.
-You've got wrist cuffs.
-You want to tell me what the hell is going on?
-I just want to talk.
You want to talk? Why don't you tell me why you
brought two skeezy ex-cons to my school bonfire?
I am sorry if I interrupted your bonfire!
It just seems like that's all you ever do lately!
Well, I didn't realize moving in
with you meant giving up my life.
I didn't ask you to give up your life!
All I ever wanted was to be a part of it!
Well, this
is my life, okay?
That's it.
So what do you think?
I think...
this is your life
and I don't fit in.
Pep rallies,
cheerleaders... boys.
Nothing happened with Ryan.
Yeah, not yet, but what do
you give it, a week? A month?
I really wanted this
to work between us.
Look, I'm sorry if I hurt you.
I'm sorry that I brought two
skeezy ex-cons to your bonfire.
Actually, only one of them
ever really served time, but...
-So what happens now?
-Who knows?
I think I might go back home,
save some money, go back to school.
-Actually looks kind of fun.
-Yeah, from really far away.
Come on. We're gonna miss the human pyramid.
Pretty good, huh?
Not a school spirit thing, that's cool.
I'm sorry.
It wasn't about you.
That's okay.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
Now all that's left
is lighting the bonfire.
I don't hear any screaming.
I don't see any ambulances.
Maybe we're here just in time.
Or maybe someone was right all along.
Thanks.
You know what?
This honor's yours.
We built it together,
let's burn it together.
I think Captain Oats
would be very proud...
or deeply disturbed
by this visual.
You guys, it's so good.
Thanks, Seth,
for making it all happen.
Oh, see that? They're
thanking me. That's nice.
So what do you guys
want to do now?
Feel like going home?