(Jack): Previously on
The Pillars of the Earth:
Stephen's army
has us surrounded.
We've been besieged for weeks.
I'm Tom Builder.
We'd like to repair your church.
We'll quarry this stone
to build our new cathedral.
When my chisel
hits the rock,
it's a song of what will be.
Kingsbridge gets
the rents, the tolls.
It gets the taxes,
the business.
As of next month,
the market moves to Shiring.
Pray with me.
That boy with red hair,
I want him dead by morning.
(Grunting)
He can't be dead.
(Roaring, horse neighing)
They've captured the king.
I claim you as my prisoner.
- Your brother's been taken.
- Oh God!
Your king lies in a dungeon
to be hanged tomorrow.
Why shouldn't you hang
with him?
All you have to say is
that you betrayed Bartholomew.
(Screaming)
Yes! Yes!
See that he's hanged.
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
That's it.
Forgive me God,
for I have sinned.
I am king.
You have made me king.
(Man groaning in distance)
...forgiveness
for your sins?
(Muttering in Latin)
Do you ask God's forgiveness
for all your sins?
(Muttering in Latin)
Do you ask God's forgiveness
for all your sins?
Dear God!
Philip.
(Bell tolling)
(Woman crying)
If you wish Maud to make
your son Earl of Shiring,
I need to successfully trade
Stephen with Gloucester.
I'll contribute to the ransom
fee, if that's your concern.
No, my concern is Stephen.
If he is redeemed,
will the war continue?
Undoubtedly.
Therefore Queen Maud
may not rule for long,
and then, whose side are we on?
We need to play both sides.
Oh, I intend to
do that as negotiator,
but your position
is not as flexible.
Are you with Maud
or are you against her?
That's what Stephen will think.
And as of this moment,
you are most decidedly with.
Well then, if he wins,
you will have to
intercede for us.
You presume our position
is that of equals,
I need you to serve me,
not command me.
Dear Lady, you mistake
my meaning entirely.
Well, then, what would
Your Eminence have me do?
Whatever your wish,
I am happy to obey.
I wish to be made
Archbishop of Canterbury
once Stephen
regains his throne.
The current one will have
to be removed, of course.
(Man coughing)
Drink this, brother.
How did I come here?
I told the executioner that,
as the Queen's secretary,
I would answer for
your innocence.
But I thought
you supported Stephen?
Shhh!
He's as self-serving
as his predecessor.
I've become a
politician, Philip.
I serve who best serves me.
(Chuckles)
And I hear you
have a cathedral?
Not yet. I need a
few miracles first.
Then let us
give thanks, brother.
This is a day for miracles.
I found you,
Maud is now in power.
And the dead have
returned to life.
They found him crawling
from a mass grave.
You're a new man, Jack.
A Lazarus.
I'm sure I stink like Lazarus.
(Chuckling)
You must have died too,
from the look of you.
Nearly.
God has further plans for me.
For you too, I suspect.
What plans?
What do you remember
of the last 3 days?
Did you pray?
I was laying with the dead.
(Chuckling)
I suppose I don't remember.
I dreamt, though.
I remember that.
What of?
(Man shouting in distance)
Of Aliena.
(Frog croaking)
(Gasps)
Lovely evening.
What are you doing here?
I just came out
to look at the moon.
No. No, wait!
Aliena, don't go.
I can't swim very well!
Help!
Aliena! Help!
Alfred?
(Gasps)
(Gasping)
Don't come near me again.
What?
But I love you!
I love you!
(Crickets chirping)
- The Empress's terms
are non-negotiable.
Stephen must sign a document
acknowledging her sovereignty
and leave the country forever.
In addition, you will pay Maud
1,000 pounds in gold
and hand over Robert of
Gloucester in good health.
Interesting.
We were gonna ask
1,000 pounds from you.
Why not cancel the ransom fees
and proceed from there?
Your Eminence,
may I have a word?
(Grunts)
(Quietly):
We need the fee
in order to bankrupt them.
Otherwise, what guarantee
do we have
that Stephen won't ignore
anything that he signs
and begin a war again?
We need a guarantee.
If we ignore the ransom fees,
we need to hold
Stephen's son, Eustace,
until his father
has left the country
and peace has been kept
for 5 years.
King Stephen will never agree.
It's not his decision.
Think about it overnight...
dear Richard.
No one at Maud's court
knows what Eustace
looks like, do they?
(People murmuring)
And what's your name?
Elizabeth.
That's a pretty name.
How old are you, Elizabeth?
I'm 12.
You're a very pretty girl...
with very pretty lips.
Has anyone ever told you that?
(Chuckles)
Good day, Bishop.
I thought you were for Stephen.
Do you see these people
before us, Henry?
Yes, Mama.
They've come to ask us favors.
Do you know why?
You're the Queen.
I'm the Empress.
I rechristened myself
this morning.
And one day,
you will be Emperor,
and people will come
to ask you favors.
So I want you to listen.
Francis, you may speak first.
And who is this handsome man?
This is my brother,
Philip, Empress,
the Prior of Kingsbridge.
Handsome, I pray,
before God, Empress,
but, uh, very plain to others.
Humility and humor,
a rare combination.
You ask us to grant you
a license to hold a market?
The income from which
will be used
to finish building a cathedral.
Finish? How did you pay
to start it?
We had a license, Empress,
but it was lost.
King Steph...
Uh, the usurper Stephen refused
to grant us an other.
Why is that?
He kept his reasons to himself.
May I speak, My Empress?
The market at Kingsbridge
was closed,
because it took money
from the one at Shiring.
The rule is that markets must
be at least 14 miles apart.
Kingsbridge and Shiring are 20.
Stephen nevertheless decided...
What Stephen decided
is of no interest to us.
You also ask the right to take
stone from the Shiring quarry.
We have had those rights
for years until William...
I closed the quarry
in retaliation
for his illegal market.
Who owns the quarry?
We do, My Empress,
It was the usurper Stephen
that allowed Kingsbridge
to take the stones.
A foolish bequest, giving
quarry rights to one party,
yet letting another mine it.
We quite agree.
The quarry and all its mining
rights shall belong to Shiring.
Thank you, My Empress.
On the condition that you
successfully negotiate
the release of
our brother Gloucester
from the enemy.
Kingsbridge, however,
shall have similar market rights
to Shiring.
The same condition applies.
(Francis):
Thank you, Empress.
In addition, Henry here would
like a toy from each of you.
(People chuckling)
And I'd like a toy, too.
100 pounds or your requests
will be denied.
Next.
Can you borrow it?
Money lenders charge
exorbitant interest.
I could never pay it back.
No one else?
A merchant who benefits
from the market?
He might find it
to his advantage.
- She.
- What?
She.
I did her a favor once.
We've just received the word!
What? Martha,
what is it?
Jack's alive!
- What? Martha,
- Jack, Jack, Jack! is it?
Hey, Jack!
Jack!
(Giggling)
(Cuthbert):
Brother, welcome home.
Welcome home!
(Man 1):
Welcome back, Jack!
(Man 2):
Good to see you, man!
Prior Philip is back.
(♪ Flute and drums ♪)
100 pounds?
I'd lend it to you gladly,
but I need it to buy
next's year's wool.
When would you
need it returned?
Early spring.
Can you manage it?
No.
No, not unless...
Why can't I sell you
next year's wool?
- You haven't got it yet.
- I will in the spring.
You'd sell it in advance?
Pay me now and I give you
the first shearing.
I never heard of
it done like that.
Why shouldn't it be?
I'd have to offer you
a lower price for it
than you'd get by waiting.
The price for wool
goes up in the spring.
I could keep building in winter
and everybody
would be employed.
So I give you 100 pounds,
you give it to Maud
and you get a license?
The same as Shiring.
In addition to
the Sunday market,
Shiring has the
annual fleece fair.
That's where I make
most of my money.
I... I don't follow.
Why don't we have one here?
If the license is
the same as Shiring's,
why can't you host a fair next
year to compete with Shiring?
It would save me
transportation.
I could lure
the Flemish buyers here.
You would make
more money in a week
than you would in
a year of Sunday markets
and it would break
the Hamleighs' back.
Ha! Brilliant!
William would be
as mad as a bull!
Yes, and there's nothing
he can do about it.
(♪ Flutes ♪)
♪ ♪ ♪
Welcome back.
Thank you.
(Both laughing)
(Laughing)
I knew you weren't dead.
You shouldn't be here.
They'll see you.
No. Even Waleran
can't keep me from my son.
Come on!
What are you doing?
(Laughing)
I'm trying to be helpful!
(Both laughing)
Ow!
Walter will take the boy.
Who is that boy you gave them?
Your son Eustace, Sire.
That wasn't Eustace.
Well, they don't know that.
Brother.
My dear Maud.
So, war begins again.
And chaos is king.
I don't see how
that benefits us.
Oh, when chaos
reigns, dear Lady,
Satan often forgets about
God's humble servants,
and we may carry on with our
holy work without interference.
(Man): Attack!
(Grunting)
Yah! Yah!
(Roaring)
(Neighing)
We are betrayed!
Stephen has attacked
us once again!
Does he honestly think
we'll spare his son?
Empress, I fear,
sadly, the boy is...
is not his.
He says his name is Charlie
and he's missing his pigs.
Richard of Kingsbridge
substituted a farmer's child
for Eustace.
He resembles the
usurper's son near enough.
He even fooled me, Empress.
Kill him anyway.
Stephen will learn
that we, at least,
keep our promises
and we are not to be crossed!
(Groaning)
(Exhaling)
(Richard): Dear sister,
once again we're at war.
Advance is slow but sure.
And we hope by spring
to defeat Maud and Gloucester.
Of course, since I fight
for Stephen, if Maud wins,
I might never regain Shiring
and Father's title.
William and is mother have
taken Maud's side,
for the time being,
but their loyalty is
as dependable as snow
and goes wherever
the winds of power blow it.
Their ally, Bishop Waleran,
has already laid the groundwork
for siding again with Stephen
if he were to win.
You must forgive my despair.
Winter slows the war and gives
me too much time to brood.
It has stopped
cathedral work too, I imagine.
(Honking)
But come spring,
Hope may blossom,
the war may end,
the church walls
may rise ever higher,
and I will once again
return to your dear self.
Until then,
I remain your
loving brother, Richard.
(Man):
One, two, three!
You started work late today.
(Mooing)
Late?
Well, there's not much we can do
without a stock of stones.
Nevertheless, I thought it
would be further along by now.
We can't work
in the winter, Prior.
And when we get more stones...
And if we don't?
You should've conserved
their use, Tom.
Jack's been using too many,
carving gargoyles.
Well, we can purchase
some more soon.
You paid your debt to Maud,
She's given you
a license for a market.
Maud is losing battle
after battle.
What happens to my fee
if she's deposed?
They'll be no more stones
and the coffers will be empty.
(Man 1):
Get off there. Get off!
(Man 2): Steady hands!
Keep it level.
Da, look!
If I can do this,
I can build a stone vault.
How many times
do I have to tell you?
A stone vault is too heavy.
It can't be supported.
Why don't you listen?
How many of these
have you made?
Sixteen, so far.
It's a little bit of fun
in God's house.
What a waste.
♪ ♪ ♪
Philip's in a sour mood.
All employers get like this
at some point.
See, the work starts
to slow down,
it costs more than
they ever imagined,
and all they can think
to do is complain.
They can't see the future,
which, as a builder, I have to.
As a cathedral
builder especially.
No pessimists allowed.
(Laughing)
But realists, yes.
I won't see
this church completed.
Da?
Nor will you, Alfred.
Nor you, Jack, most likely.
I may see it roofed.
You might see the interior
well on its way.
But it might be 50 years
before it's finished,
which is why I teach you.
That's why you must
never stop learning...
even after I'm gone.
Learn from who?
From your pupils.
Your younger masters, they might
find new ways to perfection.
Do you know what this is?
That's glass.
What if I were
to tell you that one day,
this is what cathedrals
will be built from?
Ha! Never.
"Never" is a word
you must never use.
Now, this is all I have,
right here,
to pass on to my successor.
You're both my sons,
Now, I'd like to be able
to share ownership
between the two of you,
but I know that
sometimes you work
at cross purposes.
I'd really like it if you could
try your best to be friends.
And if not,
the one that gets this
will be the one that best
embodies my vision, my knowledge
and my belief in the future.
Do you understand that?
Bastard!
Jack, you bastard,
you are not my brother!
(Roaring)
(Roaring continues)
(Panting)
Marry me.
(Chuckles)
(Laughing)
No.
(Grunting)
(♪ All chanting ♪)
(Bell tolling)
(Bird squawking)
(Birds chirping)
- Morning.
- Oh!
(Chuckling)
Oh God!
Don't ever sneak up on me.
I didn't.
I made a lot of noise.
You were just so engrossed in
that, that you didn't hear me.
I've never heard of
a woman with such a library.
Which one is this?
(Chuckles)
The Song of Roland.
It's about this knight
who has a big horn.
He blows it so hard...
(Both):
That his head bursts.
You know it?
My mother told it to me
when I was a boy.
But she didn't call him Roland.
She changed the name
to Foolish Jack.
How would she heard of it?
My father told it to her.
"The French seduction"
is how she described it.
He was French?
He was a story teller.
In fact, apparently she laughed
so hard at that one,
that he got very angry.
(Chuckles)
Did she know any others?
Yeah, a few.
But the best were
the ones that I told her.
You?
Yeah, I made them up, you know.
There once...
There once was
a very brave knight.
Who...
Who went into battle
and received a mortal wound.
And as he lay there, dying,
his soul...
Flew to the house
where there lived a woman...
That he loved.
Yes.
And his...
His soul ate with her
and slept with her
and was so filled
with longing for her...
He flew back to his master
and brought him back to life.
In hope that one day...
(Screaming): No!
All right?
Don't touch me there.
Don't you ever touch me again!
Jack! Jack!
Come quick!
It's Alfred! He smashed
all of your statues.
What?
He smashed them all.
(Groaning)
(Both grunting)
(Men shouting, indistinct)
(Man): Come on, boys!
Help me!
There's fighting.
(Grunting)
(Man): The scaffolding is
not made for that violence!
(Screaming)
(Man shouting, indistinct)
It's not the first time, Tom.
But Philip, what bro...
No! No excuses.
If 2 of your workers
continually fight,
destroy property,
tear down work that you
spent months building up,
what do you do?
(Sighing)
I will not have Jack and
Alfred working together.
Look...
One of them must go.
He's an apprentice!
I'm a master stonemason,
Send him away, Da, not me.
I'm your real son!
If Ma was alive, this wouldn't
even be a choice!
We were a team once, remember?
I was supposed to
be your successor.
Alfred, you'll have to pay
a fine for the damage caused.
One month's wages.
A month?
Doubt the prior
would accept any less.
Leave us for a moment.
Da!
Go... before
I double it.
(Sighing)
(Man):
That one over here?
I'm sorry, Jack.
Why me?
I pleaded with Philip,
but he wouldn't soften.
This is my life.
He's my son.
I'm your son too.
You said it.
You're the one
that Philip will miss.
You know, Alfred...
he's competent.
But you're brilliant.
Now, in a week or a month,
the Prior will see his mistake.
And if he doesn't?
You wouldn't even have a job
if it weren't for me.
That's enough.
Do you hear what I'm saying?
I burned it down.
I burned the old cathedral
so that you would have work.
God forgive you then.
Get out.
Get out!
Can I climb it?
(Donkey braying)
What do you wanna climb all
the way up there for, Jonathan?
Brother Jonathan.
So I can see Jack.
He's gone away and
he hasn't said good-bye.
(Men talking in distance)
Sit down.
(Cow mooing)
Jack went away because
he'd done something bad.
He hurt Alfred.
Like Cain hurt Abel?
No, not as bad as that,
but anyway. Jack and Alfred
are not really brothers.
Isn't Jack your son?
Well, I'm raising...
was raising... Jack
as a favor to Ellen,
like Johnny Eightpence
raises you.
He isn't my mother,
but he likes to think he is.
I know.
My mother's dead.
I know that.
(Man): That's all of them.
Take them away now.
Do you know who my father is?
Who?
God.
He's everybody's father.
Of course he is.
Where will you go?
Wherever they're
building cathedrals,
I'll go to Jerusalem
if I have to.
Philip is wrong.
He will understand that
he made a mistake.
Philip's stubborn, you push
against him and he pushes back.
It would take witchcraft
to change his mind.
(Bird hooting)
(Knocking)
Come in, Tom.
(Door opening)
What are you doing here?
You saved my life, once.
I know you're a man of mercy.
How did you get inside?
Not all of the brothers
fear me as you do.
- Ma.
- Let me speak, Jack.
I don't fear you.
I oppose what you stand for,
which is hatred of God,
and church and morality.
I love God.
Although I don't worship Her
quite the same way as you do.
My church hasn't
as many rules as yours
and is a lot more forgiving.
And as for morality,
I use love as my compass,
which Christ seemed
to approve of,
even if you don't.
Ma, you promised to be civil.
Come in.
Close the door.
I spend too much time making
decisions on the building.
I need an assistant
who can answer queries
on construction,
who can keep track of
the money and raw materials,
who can handle payments to
suppliers, who can pay wages.
You wouldn't be carving stone,
but you would be supervising
the entire design on my behalf.
Really?
Prior, that's fantastic.
In your spare time,
if you had any,
you'd learn speak
and read Latin.
You'd serve me during Mass...
Why would he need to do that?
Because my assistant
must be a monk.
Your church is not
having my son.
That's Jack's
decision, not yours.
It burned his father.
It tried to burn me.
Ma!
If I found the time,
could I do some carving?
Yes, of course.
And I'll have free reign
to walk the grounds,
speak with whomever I wish?
You may speak to men,
on business, yes.
God wants you, Jack.
Of that I'm certain.
He saved your life.
He speaks to you
through your art
as clearly as he spoke
to Augustine, Gregory,
all His artist-saints.
The question is this:
Do you want God?
It's a simple choice...
not an easy one.
(Bell tolling)
Rise.
(Speaking Latin)
Put your hood on.
(Bird squawking)
Kingsbridge is planning
a fleece fair
and Shiring shall become
a village of ghosts!
Who told you this?
Two of the Flemish traders who
normally do business with us.
It's planned for
the last Sunday in June.
That's 2 weeks from now.
How can we stop it?
That is a lovely stone.
No.
This belonged to my father.
It's all I've got left of him.
Queen Maud, as you well know,
is fleeing back to France.
Stephen thinks you are
both traitors.
How else will I
convince him you're not?
He loves a gift.
Get him to stop the fair.
Dear Lady, the fair
will begin, as planned,
but it will not end as planned,
will it, William?
Don't be nervous, My Lord.
Take your lesson
from their cathedral:
Some take it as a work of art,
a reason for living.
Well, I say destruction
is a work of art...
(Both grunting)
...and requires
significant talent.
You have a gift, Lord William.
Let's make your mother proud.
(♪ Flutes ♪)
♪ ♪ ♪
You couldn't ask for
a better crowd,
could you, Father?
Or better weather.
God's been good to us, today.
(Children giggling)
Entrance.
Entrance fee.
Hello, brother dear.
Kate!
Ah, Kate!
Have you...
Have you come to be shriven?
Oh sweet Jesus!
I've prayed for this every day.
I came to sell
my wares, Cuthbert.
Any of your monks
interested in buying?
(Laughing)
(Woman 1): Oh, that place.
In the shade.
(Woman 2): OK.
In the tree.
Did I, uh...
did I see Ellen here?
Yes, she came to see her son.
Not me.
She's still angry with me
for going along with your idea.
She's a good woman, Prior.
You should accept her as she is.
You're not gonna be able
to convert everyone.
But I can bring her son to God.
He's doing wonderful work.
You should tell her that.
If the Good Lord Himself came
down from heaven to praise him,
I don't think that would
make her happy.
40,000 sheep sold me
their winter coats.
Would you believe it?
It's cost me 200 pounds,
but I'll make 3.
Even I lose my breath
when I think about it.
If you need help,
I will gladly stick around
after I see Jack.
Ellen, I know how hard
it must've been for you.
I'm perfectly fine. It's Jack
you should worry about.
He seems happy.
Good. That's all
a mother asks for.
What is?
Oh I don't look that bad, do I?
You've lost weight.
They're starving you.
They feed me too well, Ma.
You look exhausted.
How many minutes of sleep
do they allow you
between prayers?
Oh I skip most of
the services, so...
Do the monks try
to sleep with you?
Ma...
No, I have no interest
along those lines
and even if I did,
it's forbidden.
Do you have interest
along other lines?
- What?
- Do you pleasure yourself?
Ma!
I... No!
I don't, no.
That's unnatural.
I want to make
a confession, Father.
Mmm...
(Women laughing)
(Laughing)
You're Kate, aren't you?
Brother Cuthbert's
little sister.
I remember you well.
What's it to you?
You're everything to him.
He prays for you daily.
You are a knife in his heart.
(Scoffs)
See the dogs spite the bear!
(Growling)
I got... I got 6
on the brown dog.
Who wants a piece of it?
(Growling)
(Barking)
(Man):
Winner takes the pot!
(Men shouting)
(Bear growling)
What are they gonna
do with him?
They're gonna fight him.
Do they kill him?
In the end, yeah.
That's sad.
(Growling)
Oh, not so much, not for him.
He gets to die bravely,
fighting for what he longs for.
What's that?
Honor, really.
And he gets to go
to bear heaven,
wander around, eat as
much fish as he likes.
(Dogs barking)
Come with me.
I got a surprise for you.
Up you climb, then.
You really mean it?
Go on, I'm right with you.
That way.
There you are.
Don't get too close.
I can see everywhere!
I can see London.
And the ocean.
(Wind whistling)
I can see heaven!
Hey, Jonathan...
I mean, Brother Jonathan,
I'm sorry.
There's something
I wanna tell you.
I think I can see an angel.
Listen to me. You know how
you and I are friends, yes?
Well suppose I was to tell you
we were something
closer than friends?
And when Jack went away,
for me that was sort of
like losing a son.
But...
What's that?
(Neighing)
Yah!
Ellen, get inside the priory!
William Hamleigh's attacking!
Get inside the priory!
(Children screaming)
(All roaring)
We've got to get
away from here.
I've got 6 pence on the...
Never mind that now!
Get inside everyone!
(Attackers roaring)
(Screaming)
Run away!
(Roaring)
(Groaning)
(Screaming)
(Man): Everybody!
No!
Come, Aliena!
We need to go.
I can't!
No, it's all I have!
Leave it, Aliena!
(Crying)
(Woman screaming)
Stay here.
Stay here, Aliena.
Shut these doors.
These doors need shutting.
You stay here!
Stay!
(All shouting)
(Screaming)
It's locked!
Go to the cathedral.
Follow me.
(Man 1):
Open the door!
(Man 2): For the love
of God, let us in!
(Man 3): Tell him
to get the keys!
(Shouting and pounding)
Remigius, what is it?
What's happening?
Prior Philip,
there's a riot or something!
Someone's attacking the fair!
- Open! Let them in!
- Don't be a fool!
Get out of my way! Out!
(Screaming)
(Horse neighing)
Dear God!
Dear God, why? Why?
Let me through!
I can open it.
It's locked!
Ease back, let me through.
Don't worry.
Don't worry, I can open it.
Quickly, please.
Open it!
(Screaming)
(Man): Burn it! Come on!
(Grunting)
Burn everything.
Burn the wool!
All of it!
(Gasps)
Aliena!
Yah! Yah!
(Grunts)
Burn, witch.
(Screaming):
No! No! No!
No! No!
(Screaming)
No!
Aaah!
(Gasping)
(Whinnying)
(Panting)
Yah!
(Grunts)
(Groans)
Tom!
Don't meddle, monk!
It was all for nothing,
Tom Builder.
Yah! Yah!
(Crying)
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com