Previously on "The Secret Life
of the American Teenager"...
I'm... pregnant?
Amy, you can't be pregnant.
Maybe we should think
about adoption.
If I did end up having the baby,
do you think I could get married?
Married?
Yeah.
Ben said he would marry me.
What's the matter with my girl?
She's pregnant, George.
I don't think it would be too smart
if Amy actually had your baby, do you?
What? What baby?
You mean she's having an abortion?
This is not your problem.
This is my problem.
If your decision is not to have the baby,
you really should talk to your parents.
Who's this Ritchie character, anyway?
Ricky. He's in the band.
You've seen him.
He's that drummer
that's always showing off.
This girl I don't even know and care
nothing about is gonna ruin my life.
You think Amy wanted this to happen?
Grace, I regret what I did,
and I apologize.
I take full responsibility for my actions.
That's more than Ricky's
ever gonna do for Amy.
Things are what they are, and we're
gonna have to figure them out.
Do you think I made
the right decision?
I think that you made
the right decision for you.
I'm gonna drop your sister off
at school and hit the road.
You're sure you're OK
talking to your dad alone?
Yeah. I don't mind
talking to him alone.
I just mind him
looking at me.
You look fine. You don't
even look that different.
No, Mom. Look at me. I'm huge,
and I'm gonna get more huge.
It's OK, Amy.
Your dad loves you, and so
do I, and so does your sister.
You don't have to go away.
I don't mind asking your grandmother
if you can stay with her.
I don't even mind telling her
why you want to stay with her,
but you don't have to stay with her.
You can stay here.
Mom... let me go.
You said I could go.
You promised me.
I know, Amy, but I can't imagine
not seeing you every day,
being with you through all this.
I don't want you
to see me like this.
I don't want anyone
I just....I wanna do this all alone.
But you're not alone.
We're alone.
Finally.
Mom's been waiting for you.
You're gonna be late for school.
Yeah, well, at least I'm not
gonna be late for my period.
Ashley, apologize.
Fine. I apologize.
But you know she's pregnant. I don't
see why some good can't come of it.
Why can't you make Dad come
home and have him help?
I'm not even gonna be here, Ashley.
I thought you two
were getting along.
I thought you and Dad
We're talking about Amy.
That's all we ever do
is talk about Amy.
Can't we talk about Dad for once?
Your dad is the one
who decided to leave.
Dad decided to leave.
Amy decided to leave.
Maybe I'll decide to leave.
Can I go live with him?
May I go live with him?
Let's go.
So... that isn't a no.
www.1000fr.com presents
Capture:FRM@Evelyn~zx
Sync:FRS@greenBB VinE
The Secret Life of the American Teenager S01E07
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
Why can't you mother
clean out the coffeemaker?
No. Dad... I meant...
No. Sweetie, don't do that, all right?
You been crying for weeks.
Come on.
It's OK.
OK, it's not OK, but... I just
don't know how this happened.
I mean how'd it happen, Amy?
How is this possible?
Sex?
I guess I should've talked to
you more about personal stuff.
Guys.
Where babies come from.
But... you really think you wanna go
away and live with your grandmother?
I mean, you think
that's the best thing?
Yeah.
Was that your idea
or your mom's idea?
I don't wanna stay here, Dad.
I don't wanna face everybody.
What about Ben?
I still wanna marry him, but...
but Mom still thinks it's a bad idea.
What do you think?
Do you have any new
thoughts on that?
Maybe later... when you're 30.
Yeah.
When the baby's my age - 15.
Honey, everything's gonna be OK.
These things happen.
Mainly when guys talk young girls
into doing things they shouldn't.
It's not all his fault.
I just let it happen.
No, it's his fault.
He knew what he was doing.
And this Ricky guy -
he knows about this?
Yeah, he knows.
But you haven't talked
to him face to face.
No.
I don't want anything
to do with that guy.
Little late for that.
After yo u have the, um...
child, then what?
I don't know.
I can't think about that
right now, Daddy.
You haven't called me that
in so long, baby.
Aw, Amy...
Oh.
Maybe it really is time
for me to come home.
So, what are you gonna do?
I'm not gonna do anything.
Have you talked to her?
No, I haven't talked to her.
Well, talk to her.
I don't wanna talk to her.
I don't want anything to do with her.
You've already had something
to do with her, son.
You are not my dad.
You're right, I'm not, but I've tried
to be a good father to you,
and now you're gonna be a father, so...
what kind of father
are you gonna be?
It's time to have a conversation.
Go talk to her, today, this
morning before you go to school.
I'm already late,
and don't you think
if she wanted to talk to me,
she'd come talk to me?
She knows where to find me.
We have band together.
So is she gonna stay in school?
How would I know?
Wait, how could she stay in school?
She does have that option.
She's not gonna come to school
when she's having a baby.
Can't you do something about that?
What would you want me to do?
Aren't you a social worker?
Yes.
And I encourage teenage mothers
to stay in school.
Are you kidding me?
No, I am not
kidding you, Ricky.
I encourage you
to take responsibility
for whatever happens
to this baby.
Not exactly the responsible type
and neither is she, thus the baby.
Any word yet?
We're running out of time.
We gotta get you to school.
I haven't heard anything yet.
All I know she wants to leave town.
It's not that far away
to grandmother house.
We can drive up
on the weekends and see Ames.
She doesn't want us to see her.
Or at least she doesn't
want me to see her.
Is that crazy, or what?
She's scared, Ben.
I mean she's scared and she's
angry and she's overwhelmed.
Do her and yourself a favor and go
along with the plan, whatever it is.
Of course, whatever it is is
probably gonna change
over and over and over again.
It's just not easy, that's all.
What in life is easy?
Not much, that's what.
Certainly not
the sausage business.
Come on,
we better get going.
Dad...
I know, you wanna stay home.
I'm pretty sure your mother
would want you to go to school.
I don't think she would.
All right, stay home,
as long as it's for one day.
You don't wanna stay home
and hang out with me?
No. Can't do, I'd rather stay busy.
And besides...
I'm pretty sure you
don't have any intention
of hanging around
the house all day.
Am I wrong?
No.
Call her, text her, do something.
Let me know what happens.
Hello.
I love you.
Me too.
Is he still there?
No, he's gone.
Then what's the decision?
Decision?
Are you goin'?
Yeah.
I'm going to my grandmother's.
I thought maybe your dad
would say no.
I think that's kinda up to me
to decide, don't you?
Ben, you can't decide for me.
I have to go. I can't stay.
Stay with me, at my house.
I mean just say you're going to
your grandmother's,
and live with me and my dad.
I can't do that. I don't
want you to see me, either.
I have to see you.
I'll die if I don't see you.
OK, please don't say that.
We both know you're not gonna die.
It makes me feel like
you're threatening to kill yourself.
OK, one - "I'll feel really bad if I don't
see you" doesn't express my true feelings,
and two - I think you're aware
that when you lose a parent,
it makes you value your own life,
so I have no intention of offing myself.
I totally just forgot about your mom.
Say something, please?
You really think going to your
grandmother's is the only solution?
No, I don't think
there is any solution,
but I do think
it'll make things easier.
Ben, this isn't easy.
What is?
Not much, that's what.
What?
Nothing.
Why is it going to be easier for people
to see you after you've had the baby?
Either way, they know.
Just don't care if they know.
Don't care.
You can decide that, you know,
to not care what people think.
Who doesn't care
what people think?
Me. I don't care.
Come on, Amy. At least consider
going back to school.
I'll be right there with you,
holding your hand.
I already told you I can't.
They're a bunch
of high school students.
Ben, I'm going to my grandmother's.
You can come over tonight
and say goodbye if you want.
I'll probably leave
in the morning.
No.
Thanks for asking, but, no,
I don't wanna say goodbye,
because I don't want you
to leave.
Who is it?
It's me.
What are you doing here?
Come on,
let's stay home today.
I can't.
Why?
'Cause I don't want to.
All right. Can I stay here?
I'm not in the mood
to go to school today.
You can't stay here.
Is your mom home?
You know she's not.
Come on, Adrian. I can't
go to school today.
I can't.
Sedlack will kill you
if you don't make practice.
I'm already missing practice,
and I don't care about band.
Can I come in?
I need you.
Oh, come on.
My life is falling apart.
I need you.
Really. Just take a day off.
Call in sick, stay in bed.
Mnh-mnh. I have to turn in
my English Lit paper.
Turn it in tomorrow.
No. I worked really hard on it.
I'm not gonna
get points taken off
just 'cause I didn't
turn it in on time.
OK, I'll come back at lunch,
after English Lit.
You can stay,
but I have to go.
What are you doing home?
Come on, you didn't think
I was actually going to school.
We're parent-free.
So, how'd it go with Dad?
I don't know. He cried,
and I cried...
Yeah, and?
And he wants to come home.
Thank you. Finally.
Just because he says that
does not mean she'll let him.
And aren't you concerned you're gonna
get in trouble for ditching school?
Yeah.
Guess I kinda
lowered that bar.
Thank you for that, too.
Don't you think you're taking this
whole thing a little too seriously?
It's not like you're dying.
You're just having a baby.
Just? Just having a baby?
Ashley, I'm 15.
I don't wanna have a baby.
I just wanna be normal
like everyone else.
I wanna go to a normal school
and be in the band
and go to high school dances
and fall in love and get married
and then maybe have a baby.
Then why did you have sex?
I don't know.
I didn't... think about it.
I didn't have a good reason.
I just did it.
Ashley, promise me that you won't
have sex until marriage.
Please. Not one of your fake
promises to Mom and Dad.
A real promise.
I don't want you to make
the same mistake I did.
Are you kidding?
I have condoms.
I'm not an idiot.
You have condoms at 13?
Where did you get condoms?
The grocery store.
You are not using condoms.
Now there's some really bad advice.
OK, you know what I mean, Ashley.
You don't need condoms.
Just say no.
That doesn't work, obviously.
I didn't say no.
I didn't say anything.
I just let this happen.
I cannot believe
I let this happen to me.
Ashley, just listen to me.
You do not wanna have a baby.
Not at 13. That's why
I have the condoms.
When did you even
get condoms?
I dunno. Right after
I found out you were pregnant.
It's not like they're illegal.
Anyone can buy 'em.
Why are you in such a bad mood
this morning?
I thought it was
because Dad was coming over,
but that's obviously not it.
I'm not in a bad mood.
Yeah, you're right.
You're in an angry mood.
What, are you angry at that guy Ricky?
No. I'm just angry
with myself.
No, that's not it.
What, is it Ben?
God, how can you be angry
with a guy who loves you
despite the fact that
you're pregnant by another guy?
I just can, OK?
Well, it's a step up
from feeling sorry for yourself.
Change your mind?
Who are you?
A friend of Adrian's.
I didn't break in
or anything, honest.
Are you breaking in?
I got a key. What's your name?
I recognize you.
Ricky Underwood.
Oh, yeah, I know you.
And you are?
I'm Amy's dad.
Don't you hit me. If you hit me,
I'll hit ya back, I swear.
Why would I hit you?
Oh, no. I know.
I know, all right.
And I'd like to hit you,
but if I started hitting you,
I don't think I could stop.
'Cause I wanna kill you.
But for one - I don't feel like going to
prison for killing the likes of you,
not that I couldn't get away with it,
because believe me,
people would understand.
And two - I don't wanna lose
any business for killing the likes of you.
Because you know I'm the one who would
end up paying for whatever happens here.
Which brings me to three -
I wanna talk to you.
So you listen up.
I don't want you involved in
anything that my daughter decides.
Is that clear? You have no part
in the decision-making process whatsoever.
And whatever decision Amy
and her mother and I make,
that's it. That's the decision.
Not yours.
You have nothing to say.
No, of course not.
It's her baby.
Don't be an idiot.
It's your baby, too.
But you're not gonna have
anything to do with it, ever.
If she wants to put it up for adoption,
you're gonna sign when you have to sign.
OK.
And if she ends up
keeping it...
and she doesn't
want you around,
you're not around.
But believe me, you're gonna pay for
that baby for the rest of his or her life.
You, not me. You.
And that money doesn't
entitle you to a thing.
You give up all rights
to anything and everything
when you take advantage
of an innocent 15-year-old girl.
I understand,
and I'm OK with all that.
Band camp.
That's what people do nowadays
at band camp, they have sex?
It just happened.
Sex doesn't just happen.
I'm a man.
I know how hard it is
to get a woman to have sex.
Why do you have a key
to Adrian's condo?
It's not her condo,
it's her mother's condo.
I'm... putting some new
furniture in for her mother.
I came by to measure a room,
not that it's any of your business.
No, but I notice you feel comfortable here.
You opened a new jar of mayonnaise.
Are you seeing Adrian's mother?
You're the boyfriend?
Let's just stick
with the furniture story.
What, you got a problem
telling a little white lie,
but you don't mind ruining
my daughter's life?
'Cause you ruined her life.
You realize that, don't you?
You ruined her life,
her sister's life,
her mother's life, and my life,
not to mention the life
of an innocent child.
I don't think I've ruined
anybody's life.
Why aren't you at school?
'Cause I don't feel like having
people stare at me all day.
So, what, you gonna
drop out of school, then?
No, I'm not dropping out.
I can't just drop out of school.
I'd like to, but I can't.
Why not? Why can't you drop
out or go to another school?
Amy's gonna have to go
to another school.
Why shouldn't you?
Oh, that's right.
Because people can see
that she's having a baby,
but you, you just get to walk around
like the worthless
piece of trash that you are.
You stay away from my daughter
and you keep your mouth shut
about me and Adrian's mom.
No one knows about that
but me, her and Adrian.
And now you.
I'm not a worthless
piece of trash!
*The feelings all roll back
As I flip another page*
*It's funny how back then I'd dream
of better days, but when it all...*
Hi, Adrian.
Did you say something?
Hi.
Hi what?
I wanted to apologize for the way
I talked to you at that clinic.
I was in a panic.
You were on a mission.
I was.
I still believe what I believe, but maybe
I could've handled the whole thing better.
We can have a difference
of opinion and be friends.
That little skirmish at the clinic
and a difference of opinion...
that's what you think is
keeping us from being friends?
How about we're not friends because...
your boyfriend and I hooked up?
I've forgiven him.
What?
I don't know if we'll date again,
but regardless of that, I've forgiven him.
And... I forgive you.
Who are you to forgive me?
You're exactly right,
who am I to forgive you?
Forgiveness belongs to God,
so I'm forgetting what happened
between you and Jack.
I have the power to do that,
to forget, to just... let it go.
It still happened.
What happened?
I hooked up with Jack.
You did? I forgot.
You haven't forgotten.
You can't.
I don't think you can forget
I think it would've been a good idea
if Amy decided
not to have a baby.
Maybe if we were friends,
we could talk about that sometime.
Or even if we can't be friends,
maybe we can at least speak
in the hallway
without it being a big deal
like it is now.
I don't see any reason why we have
to have hard feelings between us.
OK, what is it?
You think that if you're
friends with me,
you could still hang out
with Ricky, is that it?
I can hang out with Ricky,
anyway, if I want to.
Your Christian parents are gonna
let you hang out with a guy
that got a 15-year-old girl
pregnant?
I guess.
A guy like that needs friends now,
don't you think?
No, I don't think.
The only friend he needs is me.
OK.
But don't you need a friend?
You're the girlfriend of a guy
who got a 15-year-old girl pregnant.
The whole situation is so sad, I think.
Must be so tough on both of them,
having a baby so young.
He's not having a baby.
She's having a baby.
And I hear she's
leaving town to do it,
so she's not gonna
be around anymore.
It's over for her and Ricky.
You don't think at some point
Ricky's gonna wanna see his own baby
or be involved with his child
as he or she grows up?
Nope.
I can't imagine Ricky would
never wanna see his own child.
That's 'cause you live with
two parents.
Most families
aren't like that.
Every child has two parents.
I don't.
Bye.
Call me sometime.
We'll talk.
Or just drop by.
You don't have to call.
I'm not nothin'.
He has no right
to talk to me like that.
I'm a human being.
I'm as good as he is.
I could've punched
that guy.
But you came here instead
to talk it out,
so you didn't punch him.
That doesn't mean I won't.
-I think it does.
-No, it doesn't.
The next time he or anyone else
tells me I'm trash, I'm gonna punch 'em.
No, you're not.
Didn't I just say I was?
I'm not gonna let anyone
talk to me like that ever again.
Because you're not trash.
You're a man. You're somebody.
What are you sayin'? I'm pourin' my
guts out, and you're mocking me?
I'm not mocking you at all.
I'm agreeing.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Half the time I'm here, I don't know what
you're talking about or who you're talking to.
That's because up until now,
you didn't know who you are.
-Who am I?
-You're a man.
As good as Amy's dad,
as good as anyone else.
You're a human being.
No matter how you've been
treated before in this life,
you are a human being,
and human beings make mistakes.
How can I be a man
who's as good as everyone else
when I made the mistake
of getting a girl pregnant?
A 15-year-old girl is pregnant
because of me,
and I don't care
about her or the baby.
All I care about is that
her father called me trash,
and I'm not trash.
-Because?
-Because I'm not.
That is as good an
answer as any.
You're the doorway
to self-respect.
Open it, Ricky.
Open it and go on in.
I don't know how.
I think you do.
Hello.
Anyone home?
Came home from school for this?
-Yeah, it's me. What do you want?
-Where are you?
Leave a message, not that
I'll call you back.
So I came home.
Where are you?
Adrian?
What are you doing here?
-What are you doing here?
-I live here.
Why aren't you
at the furniture store?
I brought you something.
-It's all set, boss.
-Thanks, fellas.
-You brought me something?
-Yeah.
Something for you
and your mom.
-I don't want anything from you.
-Fine. I'll take it back.
At least take a look
at it first.
Why would you get me a desk?
What am I gonna do with a desk?
I see you studying at the kitchen
counter, on the couch, all over the place.
Thought you might like a desk.
What do you want?
-Nothin'.
-No, you want something.
-You all want something.
-All?
Oh, OK, I get it.
You don't want me
to say anything to Amy.
Of course I don't want you
I don't want you to say
anything to anyone.
But this isn't a bribe,
it's a gift.
So...
did you get my mother
a new desk, too?
No, an armoire.
Oh...
Top-of-the-line armoire.
It was made in India.
Goodbye, George.
Goodbye?
You're breaking up with her,
aren't you?
What are you talking about?
All the last guy gave us
was a box of steaks.
I knew you were smart.
That's why I got you the desk.
Just leave.
Just so you know,
Ricky was here earlier.
I came by to get some things,
and he was here.
Be careful.OK?
Or what? I'll end up pregnant?
-Everyone knows.
-All right.
Is that why you're
going home?
That's none of your business.
Guys would like you anyway,
you know that, right?
What do you mean, anyway?
Even if you don't have sex
with 'em.
And that's
none of your business.
You're welcome for the desk.
Hey, jerk.
I'm sorry.
My day took a weird turn.
Yeah, so did mine.
You coming over or not?
Nah. Something I have to do.
Amy's father
said he talked to you.
He's not trying to force you
to marry her, is he?
No. Pretty much the opposite.
Look, I can't ignore the fact
that I'm the father of a baby.
Sure you can.
Lots of guys do.
Lots of guys? Like who?
Like my father.
I didn't know.
You do what you have to do.
I don't care.
Yeah, ya do care, and I know
you were counting on me to come over,
and I'm sorry.
I'm gonna start being
more responsible.
I just have to
take care of something.
Look, I don't need you
to come over.
I have friends.
No, you don't.
Call her back?
Yeah, called her back.
Good.
That's a start. What's next?
Hi.
Hi. I didn't know you guys
were stopping by
during school hours,
uninvited.
Your dad called.
He thought maybe
you needed some company.
No, that's fine.
Thank you, though.
Did you hear from Amy?
-Is she...
-Leaving?
I guess so.
Are you going over to her house
to say goodbye?
No.
I can't.
You have to say goodbye.
Doesn't matter.
She'll be back.
Yeah, eventually.
She doesn't want me to see her,
either, when she gets...
bigger.
Like that would matter to me.
All right, you guys
make yourselves at home.
Want some company?
No. I got my dad's driver
for company, but thanks.
Sweet.
We can't just stay here
when Ben's not here.
Yeah, we can.
We're his best friends.
Yeah, which is why he left us his
room for the first time ever.
Have we ever
been in here alone?
Is this a set-up?
-No, I swear.
-I'm not having sex.
Is that why you wanted me
to come here, to have sex?
It's pretty much why I do
everything - to have sex.
But we don't have sex.
But we could if we wanted.
I have a condom.
You think because we're in high school,
we're supposed to have sex?
I don't know about supposed to,
but I'd really like to,
and you said you wanted to
take the next step, right,
before, when you decided,
so now I decided.
By next step, I didn't mean
actual intercourse.
I meant next step.
Yeah, and I think we took
that next step.
Please, Alice.
Maybe on your birthday,
if you don't beg. I hate begging.
My 16th birthday?
Oh, no.
I don't know why
I said that. No, probably not.
-But maybe.
-No.
-Come on, say maybe.
-I already said I hate begging.
-OK, I hear ya.
I can live with no.
You'll have to.
When we get older and we do get
married and we do have sex,
I bet it's going to be
really good sex.
Most people
don't have good sex.
52% of Americans 16 and older
are not fully satisfied with their sex lives.
But we're not like most people.
How can you look at me
and still wanna have sex?
How can I look at you
and not wanna have sex?
But I'm a man, and I can
take no for an answer.
Good, because
you'll have to,
at least for a few more birthdays
or until I decide otherwise.
Amy, it's me.
-Oh, no.
-Who's me?
It's Ricky.
Can I talk to you?
No, no, no.
Uh, is Amy home?
I'm her friend Ricky.
Could we talk?
I don't know.
I talked to your dad earlier,
or he talked to me.
My dad?
Look, Ricky, I'm not sure
I really wanna talk to you now.
I'm not sure I wanna talk
to you, but we have to talk.
No, we don't have to talk.
Are your parents home?
Why?
If they're not, I'll come back and talk to you
when one of them is here,
either your mom, your dad,
or both.
I think it's best if we have a chaperone,
parent-type chaperone,
maybe not in the same room,
but in the house, anyway.
What do you even
wanna talk about?
She knows.
I know everything,
and I have condoms.
I'll come back.
Considering our situation, I'd like to have
one of your parents here.
I'd like to talk
before you leave town.
Are you leaving?
That's the rumor around school.
Maybe.
Did you say you actually
talked to my dad earlier?
Yeah, and I made some promises to him
I don't think I can keep.
Like?
Like I think I do wanna
be involved.
Seriously?
Involved?
I'm the father of this child,
and I think I should have
some say in what happens here.
Just call me when I can come over
and talk to you, OK?
OK, now I see how it happened.
She's beautiful,
don't you think?
I know we're a little young,
and... she's
a little pregnant...
...but I'm really in love,
and I don't think
she understands that.
If she did, I don't think she'd
be running off
to her grandmother's house.
This is the woman I wanna spend
the rest of my life with.
She says she feels
the same way about me, but...
I don't know.
Of course, it's complicated,
but life is complicated.
Heh. I sound like Dad,
don't I?
Except Dad would add,
"Sausage is complicated."
Probably.
That's not her,
you know.
It's her.
Nah, that's the container that holds
the container that used to be her.
Is this the first time you've come to see her
since we said goodbye to her?
It is, yeah.
I don't like coming here.
But I didn't come for her,
I came for you.
Why do you come here every year
on the anniversary of her death?
Why do you do this
to yourself every year?
'Cause every day
would be too often.
Life is for the living, son.
You can talk to the deceased
but not the living?
Join the living.
If Amy's leaving
and going to her grandma's,
then that's what's happening.
Do you won't be together
for the rest of your lives.
It means she's going away
for a while.
For a while. Get it?
She's not leaving forever.
She's choosing to go.
Mom, she didn't have a choice,
but Amy is...
You can't have your way
on this one, Benjamin.
Jue I couldn't
have my way on that one.
Live with it.
I'm really happy
you stopped by.
And surprised.
Yes, we're very happy.
We're very happy.
We've heard so much about you.
From me. That's why
we are surprised.
Yeah.
I remember the other time
I was surprised to see you.
Why don't we just
let that go, Tom? Let it go.
Really. We're really happy
you stopped by.
I didn't have your number.
I don't usually just
stop by anywhere.
I don't even know why
I did this.
Maybe it's because I asked
if you wanted to be friends.
I'd really like to be friends.
Really?
Yeah, Grace is friends
with lots of people, Tom.
Lots of people.
She's very friendly.
Um, are you hungry?
Have you had dinner?
I'm not hungry. I don't
usually eat this early.
We don't either, but my wife
had a function at church,
lots of leftovers,
so I can fix you a plate.
I'll get you something.
No, I'm really
not hungry.
Is it me?
Sometimes
I make people nervous.
Oh, no.I like you.
You seem to be pretty honest.
Yeah, I am.
-Well, not that many people are honest.
-Yeah.
-True.
I know. You thought Ricky
is here.
Oh, no. I know where he is.
Is he at Amy's?
-And you would know that how?
-I was guessing.
I told you at school
I thought maybe Ricky
was capable of taking some
responsibility for what happened.
Not that I know him
better than you.
I'm just an optimistic person.
Just being optimistic,
hoping for the best.
And in this situation,
what do you think is the best?
Ahem. Why don't you let me
take this one, all right?
Um, in this situation, I think the very
best possible choice for Amy and Ricky
would be to find a loving family
to adopt the baby.
That way,
when the baby grows up,
he or she can be thankful
to both of them
for providing a loving family
that has two adults
that can actually
take care of him or her.
Yeah. That's good.
Tell you what - Tom,
why don't we give the girls
a little private time
to talk? What do you say?
Good night.
Really nice to meet you.
You too.
I don't wanna talk
about this anymore.
about Ricky or the baby.
I thought I did,
but I don't.
I don't know, I didn't want him
to be my only option tonight.
I should go.
No, please, stay.
When you drop by, you're
supposed to stay a while.
There are rules?
No, but hang out.
We'll talk about something else.
Anything else.
Like?
Like... I don't know.
I don't have any girlfriends
that I do this with, either,
so...
I'm not really any better
at this than you.
So what's new in your life?
Oh, I got a new desk.
A desk? That's great.
I'd love
to come see it sometime.
OK.
Where did you get it, online?
I got a great desk online
one time.
Uh, no.Actually, it was a gift
from my mother's boyfriend.
Yeah.
How'd you get home from school?
Taxi.
You don't have
that kind of cash.
I took the bus.
You don't even know
where the bus is.
I walked.
All the way home
from school?
Do people at school know?
Know what?
About your sister?
The whole world knows.
How do they know?
How does everyone know?
Well, the people at school
have brothers and sisters
who go to school with Amy.
Welcome home, Dad.
Hello, princess.
I saw we had company,
so I came around the side.
Whose car is that?
Can he stay?
Why don't you let
your father and I talk?
Can't the three of us talk?
It is about the three of us,
especially if Amy's
going off to Mimsy's.
OK.
Why don't we start with how
you got home from school today?
Right. I guess you have, um,
more important things
to talk about than me.
She hitched a ride with the bagboy
from the grocery store.
The college kid?
He saw her walking home
and picked her up.
The cashier we like told me when I
stopped in the market on the way home.
She skipped school,
George.
You know, maybe it
really is time I come home.
Or not.
We got one daughter
who's pregnant
and another one
who's skipping school.
Your point being?
Point being is you
need me around here
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but weren't you living here
when Amy got pregnant?
And I'm pretty sure you were here this
morning when Ashley skipped school.
Come on. I know
we have problems,
but we're not gonna fix our marriage
with me outta the house.
It took me a few weeks to realize it,
but, hey, at least I realized it.
I'm not so sure I wanna fix
our marriage.
Did you tell Mimsy you and I are living apart?
Does your mother know?
She doesn't need
to know that.
I can't imagine
she'd be too happy about it.
She likes me...
better than you, even.
Yeah, she likes everyone
better than me.
So... Amy?
She can stay there. I got
a referral for a doctor,
and I met her,
she seems very nice.
She's getting Amy into a group
with other teen mothers.
I don't want my daughter
associating with girls like that.
Come on, I wanna come home.
Where are you staying now?
You know, here and there.
I checked our credit-card account,
and there aren't any hotel bills on there.
You're not staying
at the store, are you?
Well, I'm...
Yeah, I didn't think so.
So why don't you slither
on back down the driveway,
back to wherever it is
that you are staying?
Where's Amy?
She's talking to Ricky.
-I told him to leave her alone.
-I told her to talk to him.
We'll see who's right
about this.
Call me when you need my help,
'cause you're gonna need my help.
-Good night, George.
-Good night, Anne.
This is my house, too,you know.
Yeah, I know.
I'm not saying
I'm against adoption.
I'm saying I'd like to know
who's adopting, where they live,
and if I can see my own kid.
I really don't see why you
should have any say in this.
You and your dad
would like to ignore I even exist.
You know what? I don't know
what my father said to you,
but I am perfectly capable
of speaking for myself!
Since when?
Since I got pregnant!
That's when.
Since I discovered I'm going
to have to take charge
of another human being's life.
I might as well start
with my own.
OK, OK.
But I'd like to know where you are
and what's going on,
if you don't mind.
Maybe I do mind.
I'll think about what you said,
and I'll call you.
When? When are you
gonna call me?
When I feel like it.
OK, I'll take that.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Now go home.
Do you wanna exchange
phone numbers?
No. I'm pretty sure I can find your number
if and when I want to call you.
Good night.
What?
I was hiding in the bushes.
I hope you don't mind.
I was coming up the walk,
and I saw your dad pull up,
and I knew Ricky was inside,
so... I got stuck.
I don't mind.
I don't mind at all.
No, no, no. Stay.
That bump - that's not me.
It's the baby.
Yeah, I thought so.
The baby.
Don't shut me out, Amy.
Please don't shut me out.
welcome to  www.1000fr.com