The Tudors - Season 1 Episode 1
For www.forom.com
Ducal Palace
Urbino, Italy
Signore Ambassador.
It's really most
humiliating Signore Bedoli.
My lord, Prego, excellency, Prego.
What could possibly be so important
that you dragged me
from my bed before 7 o'clock
in the morning?
The duke has called an early meeting
of the council he wanted you to attend.
Tôt le matin.
Monsieur.
Why are the French here?
That is what his grace
wants to talk to you about.
Excellence.
French bastards!
Whiteball Palace
London
Mr. Pace.
Mr. More.
His Majesty wants council
this afternoon to be brief.
- He doesn't want a lot of speeches.
- Where is the king?
He's in seclusion and
not to be disturbed.
How is he?
With regards to...?
With regard to Italy!
What the French are doing in Italy.
What other regard is there?
His Majesty is counselling patience.
Yes, but you're his secretary.
You see him everyday.
In private he's mad with grief.
Almost inconsolable.
I think you ought to remember
it was his uncle they murdered.
The King!
My Lords.
We meet to consider
questions of great moment.
The King of France has demonstrated
to the world his aggressive policies.
He has already overrun 5
or 6 city states in Italy.
He's a threat to every Christian
nation in Europe,
yet he bullies the Pope into
declaring him defender of the faith.
On top of that, to prove that
nobody can touch him
he has our ambassador
in Urbino...
and my uncle...
murdered.
In cold blood.
My Lords...
I believe these are
all just causes for war!
Your Majesty is certainly right.
You have every reason
to prosecute a war.
Indeed, I warned you a year
ago about French ambitions,
though has taken this personal tragedy
for Your Majesty to accept my word.
Norfolk.
I agree with my Lord Buckingham.
The King of England has
an ancient and historic right
to the French throne, which
the Valois have usurped.
It is high time we kick them out.
We should attack France
with all our might.
Yes.
What say you, Wolsey?
I concur with Your Majesty.
These are indeed, just causes.
Good!
Then it is settled.
We are to war with France.
Yes!
Your Eminence will make
all the arrangements.
Now!
I can go play.
Do you really think
we should go to war?
I think we should try to do
what the king wants us to do.
What if the king doesn't know
what's in his best interests?
Then, you should help him decide.
How is your husband?
My husband?
He's extremely jealous.
He's threatening to make a scandal.
Says he'll put me in a nunnery.
Oh!
That would be such a waste.
Hampton Court
Surrey
His Excellency the French
Ambassador and Bishop Bonnivet.
Gentlemen, welcome.
Your Excellency...
what happened in Urbino, the
butchering of our ambassador was
most unfortunate. Especially for me.
Your Excellency is well aware of
my sentiments towards your country.
I have laboured long ad
consistently in French interests.
But how to explain this?
The matter of my king's uncle.
Frankly, it was not done
on my master's orders.
And those that committed
the crime have been punished.
Now, now, you must understand,
we are well beyond that.
King henry is a young man.
He has an appetite for war
and on this occasion
he will not be easy to appease.
Then, by all means
let us have war.
With the greatest respect,
you don't mean that.
Well, I believe that everything
humanly possible
should be done to avoid
a war between our 2 countries.
It would do England no good
to get involved in our
European squabbles.
Far better she stands above them.
I'm sure Your Eminence has ways
of pacifying the young lion.
Play on!
15-love.
- 30-love.
- Yeah!
Good shot.
Our game, I think, Anthony.
Your Majesty knows
we're just lettin' you win.
Actually, I was playing as hard as I can.
Now there is someone I have to try.
See, middle gallery, blue dress,
that exquisite virginal face.
Who is she?
40-love. Game.
She's Buckingham's daughter.
A hundred crowns, you don't succeed.
Done.
How is our daughter?
She's well.
You know her tutors say
she has exceptional talents.
Especially in music.
You should be proud.
I am.
You know I am, Katherine.
Mary is the pearl of my world.
You have not answered
my nephew's letters.
Just because your
nephew's the king of Spain.
Does he think I have
nothing better to do?
You know he advises you to
sign a treaty with the emperor,
recognizing France
as our mutual enemy.
He also advises you not to
heed everything Wolsey tells you
because Wolsey is so
biased with the French.
Since when are you a diplomat?
I am my father's daughter.
You are my wife.
You are not my minister.
You are not my chancellor.
But my wife.
I should like to be
your wife in every way.
Henry, will you not visit
my bed chamber as you used to?
Eat.
Gown.
Your Majesty.
Where is the Queen Katherine?
Her Majesty is still
at prayer, Your Majesty.
Tell her Majesty...
I came to offer my love and
devotion as her true husband.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Holy Mary, Mother of God, pray for
us now and at the hour of our death.
Amen.
Hail Mary, Mother of Grace,
our Lord is with thee blessed
art thou amongst women and blessed
is the fruit of thy womb. Jesus.
Jane.
Your Majesty...
Do you consent?
Yes, Your Majesty.
3 points!
Earl of Portland!
Mr. Charles Brandon has
now entered the list.
Your Majesties.
My Lady Buckingham,
would you do me the honour of
letting me wear your favours today?
Lord Hallam challenges.
A plaisance!
A terre!
Two points.
Mr. Charles Brandon.
His Grace the Duke of Buckingham
will now joust a plaisance
with the Earl of Newcastle.
A terre!
Another 3 points for His Grace.
Does Your Eminence have a plan?
A way to avoid war?
This is the outline
of a new peace treaty.
Uniting the English with the French.
May I?
No.
I want you to take it away
and read it very carefully.
I believe it represents something
new in the world of diplomacy.
If your King accepts it in principle
he can sign it without any loss of face.
Indeed, he can rejoice.
My master can rejoice.
We can all rejoice.
In which case, what does
Your Eminence want in return?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Nothing from you.
What I want, Your Grace.
Only you can give me.
The Duke of Buckingham
has re-entered the lists.
He's won 10 courses already.
What is he trying to prove?
- I'm gonna take him.
- No, I'll do it.
I'd love to damage
Buckingham's pride.
My Lords, the king
has entered the list.
His Majesty makes the challenge?
A la guerre.
Here we go again.
Claim or no claim.
Buckingham's not the king.
Not all of the court is
as loyal as you Charles.
My Lady.
A terre!
His Majesty wins the day.
The King.
And easy!
Present oars!
- Thomas.
- Your Majesty.
This is my family.
Your Majesty.
My wife Alice.
Alice, won't you kiss the king?
Mistress Alice.
Your Majesty.
Shall we walk by the river, Thomas?
I like walking.
Why won't you come
and live at court?
You know perfectly well
why; I don't like it.
My legal practice
and my life are here.
The court is for more ambitious men.
You didn't say much
in council last month.
About what?
Going to war with France.
As a humanist I have
an abhorrence of war.
It's an activity fit only
for beasts yet practiced
by no kind of beast
so constantly as by man.
As a humanist I share your opinion.
As a king I am forced to disagree.
Spoken like a lawyer.
- You should know. You taught me.
- Not well enough, it seems.
- Are you finished?
- Yes!
Harry!
I must urge you
that instead of spending ruinous
amounts of money going to war,
you should spend it rather, on
the welfare of your people.
Thomas, I swear to you...
I intend to be a just ruler.
But tell me this:
why is Henry V remembered?
Because he endowed universities
and built alm's houses
for the destitute?
No.
He is remembered because he
won the Battle of Agincourt.
3000 English bowmen
against 60 000 French.
The flower of French
chivalry destroyed in 4 hours.
That victory made him famous,
Thomas.
It made him immortal.
He has no right to any of this.
His father seized the
crown on the battlefield;
he had no real claim to it, only
through a bastard on his mother's side.
Your Grace's family is more ancient.
I'm a direct descendant of
Edward II. This is my crown
and this is my court.
Not his crown or his court.
That's treason, Your Grace.
It's the truth.
And one day...
we shall make it come true.
Your Grace.
What's this?
Brandon!
It's what it looks like.
Your Grace.
You violated my daughter.
No.
No, she begged.
You've taken her honour.
I swear to Your Grace, someone
else was there before me.
You son of a whore.
Yes, that is true, Your Grace.
I should kill you for this.
Get out.
Eminence, Lady Blount is here.
Very well.
Your Eminence.
What can I do for you, Lady Blount?
I am...
with child, Your Eminence.
Yes...
it is His Majesty's child.
- You are certain?
- Yes.
- Have you told the king?
- No.
Good.
I will inform His Majesty
in due time.
In the mean time you will say
nothing to anybody on pain of death.
Do you understand?
When you are no longer able to
hide your condition, you will be...
removed to a private
place for your lying-in.
There you can give
birth to your bastard.
Thank you, Your Eminence.
Will you bless my sick child?
Your Eminence, please
draw me an audience...
Oh My Lords and Masters, make
way for His Lord's Grace.
Your Eminence.
Ah, Mr. Pace.
I trust you are keeping a
good eye on my interests?
Of course, Your Eminence.
Like an eagle.
I don't want an eagle, Mr. Pace.
They can soar too high.
- Be a pigeon, shit on everything!
- Yes, Eminence.
Where is the king?
Out hunting.
Good. It keeps him in good humour.
- Send word when he returns.
- Yes, Eminence.
Who are you?
What is it you want?
I have letters of introduction sir.
But these are from the Dean
of Canterbury Cathedral!
Yes, sir.
Why did you not present yourself?
- Thomas Tallis.
- Yes, sir.
And you can play, it says,
the organ and the flute
and can sing more
than moderately well.
Anything else?
Yes, sir.
I compose a little.
Indeed.
Well...
if the dean commends your talents...
we shall have to see, won't we?
Thomas.
I trust Your Majesty
enjoyed hunting today.
How are the preparations going?
Very well.
Both your army and
fleet are assembling.
Stores and provisions
are being laid in.
You could go to war
in a matter of weeks.
Excellent.
- I knew I could depend on you.
- I am grateful to Your Majesty.
What is it?
Your Majesty, wars are expensive.
To pay for them
you have to raise taxes.
That is not always popular.
What if Your Majesty could gain
more power and prestige
- by other means?
- Other means?
Peaceful means.
What!
No battles?
No glory?
I think Your Majesty
should hear him out.
In the past few weeks,
I have conducted,
on Your Majesty's behalf,
an intense round of diplomatic talks.
Not just with the French ambassador
but also with
representatives of the emperor,
with envoys from
- Denmark, Portugal, the Italian states--
- What for?
To make a treaty.
What kind of treaty?
A treaty of universal
and perpetual peace.
- How is it to be effected?
- In several stages.
In the first place
there would be
a summit meeting between
the kings of France and England.
At the summit, Your Majesty's
daughter would be betrothed
formely to the French dauphin.
And at the end of the summit,
you would both sign the treaty.
The treaty is entirely new
in the history of Europe,
committing all its signatories
to the principles of
collective security
and universal peace.
How would it be enforced?
Should any of the signatory
countries suffer aggression,
all the others would immediately
demand that the aggressor withdraws.
If he refuses, within 1 month the
rest would declare against him...
and continue until peace is restored.
The treaty also envisages the
creation of pan-european institutions.
In some ways I like it.
I recognize it...
So do you, Thomas.
Indeed.
It's the application of humanist
principles to international affairs.
Your Eminence is
to be congratulated.
I don't seek praise.
Your Majesty would be known as the
architect of a new and modern world.
That would be reward enough.
Always, be assured of our love.
Goodnight gentlemen.
What is it?
Your Majesty, the Duke of Buckingham
insists upon an audience.
Your Grace.
Your Majesty ought to be made
aware that I have discovered
Mr. Charles Brandon in flagrante
delicto with my daughter.
Mr. Brandon has brought
shame to my family.
I demand that Your Majesty
banish him from court
with whatever other punishment
Your Majesty sees fit.
There will be no punishment!
Unless your daughter
accuses Mr. Brandon of rape.
Does she so claim?
Does your daughter claim
Mr. Brandon raped her?!
She doesn't need to.
The offence is against
me and against my family!
As far as I know, there
has been no offence.
So there is no need
for any punishment.
Your Majesty.
Your Grace.
Be careful of Buckingham, Harry.
He may well be stupid, but
he's richer than you are,
and he can call upon
a private army.
Not even your father crossed him.
I'm very happy that the King
of France has agreed
to sign the treaty and
to host the summit.
His Majesty is delighted
there will be no war.
As we all are.
What about the other
matter we discussed?
Which other matter, Your Eminence?
I saved your master's arse.
Now I want my reward.
And you can arrange it.
Do you understand?
Poor you.
Now, where were we when we
were so rudely interrupted?
Charles...
we shouldn't.
My father will kill you.
Then I shall die a happy man.
Now...
Have you all finished
your reading?
Yes, father.
Yes.
Very well.
May god and his angels bless you
and keep you this night and always.
Goodnight.
Goodnight children.
Stop.
The letter to King Francis,
Your Majesty.
My dearest Royal Cousin...
No.
Make that my beloved cousin.
We send you our love.
We love you so much it would be
impossible to love you better.
Make all the necessary arrangements
so we may meet face to face.
Nothing is now closer or more
dear to my heart
than this treaty of universal peace.
As a token of my good will,
my commitment to this treaty, and
my love for Your Majesty,
I have decided...
Yes, Majesty.
I have decided I will not
shave again until we meet.
My beard will be a token
of universal friendship,
of the love between us.
- Your Eminence.
- Your Grace.
I have some news
for Your Eminence.
His Holiness, Pope Alexander,
is desperately ill.
It cannot be long before he
is summoned to God's house.
In view of Your Eminence's
well-known Piety,
as well as your great
learning and diplomatic skills
I can assure Your Eminence of the
support of the French cardinals
at the conclave
to elect a successor.
With the votes of your own cardinals
and if it is pleasing to
god you will be elected Pope,
Bishop of Rome
ur new Holy Father.
Thank you, Your Grace.
You make me feel...
truly humble.
Are you ill, Lady Blount?
No, Your Majesty.
Please, stay.
Thank you.
Goodnight.
I have not talked to
anyone for a long time.
Cardinal Wolsey dismissed
my Spanish confessor
and most of my Spanish ladies
in case they were spies.
And I cannot trust
my English confessor.
But I can trust you though,
can I not, Lady Blount?
Yes, madam.
What is my sadness?
It is that I...
I cannot give the King a living son.
I gave birth to a baby boy once.
A sweet boy...
but he died...
in my arms...
after just 4 weeks of life.
The king blames me. I know.
He thinks it all my fault!
He does not know how much
I suffer, how much I pray.
I've been thinking
about my brother.
Arthur.
When he died it was decided
that I should marry Katherine.
I think my father didn't
want to lose her dowry.
Or the prestige...
of a Spanish marriage.
In any case...
Katherine swore the marriage
was never consummated.
That's why a Papal
dispensation was granted.
And so I married her.
And since then we have
had 5 still-born children.
A boy...
who lived for 26 days...
And a single living daughter.
What if their marriage
was consummated?
She has sworn before God
that it was not.
What does it say in the gospels?
If a man should marry
his brother's wife?
Tell me.
In the Leviticus...
it says: "If a man
marries his brother's wife,
they will die childless".
But you have a child.
But not a son!
I have no son.
Thomas Boleyn, Your Grace.
Sir Thomas.
I hope you didn't find my
invitation presumptuous.
I heard you had been
recalled from France.
I'm here for a short while,
Your Grace.
Come.
They tell me you are
an excellent ambassador.
Then, whoever they are,
they are very kind.
You come from an old family.
Though not as ancient, nor
as grand, as Your Grace's.
The King chooses to surround
himself with commoners,
men of no distinction, new men,
without pedigree or titles.
How does that help the
prestige of his crown?
- Your Grace, I...
- His father only acquired the crown
- by force not by right!
- Your Grace,
no one wants to return to
the evil days of civil war.
What is done is done.
The King is the King.
Wolsey.
A man of the cloth with a
mistress and two children.
How do you like this fellow?
Not at all.
We shall talk again.
Tell me about King Francis,
Sir Thomas.
- He is 23 years old.
- Is he tall?
Yes.
But ill-proportioned.
What about his legs?
Are his calves strong, like mine?
Majesty, no one has calves like yours.
Is he handsome?
Some people might think so.
- He certainly thinks so himself.
- He's vain?
Your Majesty, he's French!
What about his court?
It has a reputation for loose
morals and licentiousness,
which the king, by his own
behaviour, does nothing to dispel.
You have two daughters, Sir Thomas.
- How do you protect them?
- I keep a watchful eye on them.
But I also trust in
their goodness and vertue.
You will return immediately to Paris.
I am entrusting you with all the
diplomatic negotiations for the summit.
Checkmate.
Your Majesty...
Mary!
Papa.
Aren't you beautiful?
Aren't you the most
beautiful girl in the world?
- I don't know.
- Yes you are. How do you feel?
- Well.
- Well?
Papa's busy.
Be good.
Do everything you are told.
May we speak?
Continue.
My Lady.
Majesty.
- I do not like it.
- What don't you like?
Your beard.
- Not what it represents.
- Katherine.
You are giving my daughter away
to the Dauphin and to France.
You did not even consult me.
The Valois are the sworn
enemies of my family.
She is mine to do with as I see fit.
It's a great marriage.
I see Wolsey's hand behind this.
Though I love Your Majesty,
and am loyal to you
in every way,
I cannot disguise my
distress and unhappiness.
Well you're going to have to.
Paris, France
Bonjour Monsieur l'Ambassadeur.
Il y a des messages pour vous.
Et demain vous avez une
audience avec le Roi.
Très bien. Merci Pierre.
Where are my daughters?
I have some exciting news.
There is to be a summit between King
Francis and King Henry near Calais.
I am to arrange it.
That means you will both
have the opportunity
to meet the King of England!
Mary.
And Anne. Boleyn.
To your futures!
His Eminence Cardinal Wolsey.
I want your opinion.
Do you like this cloth?
I think it suits Your Majesty very well.
Perhaps, if I might suggest...
with these.
Do you think Francis will
have anything as fine as these?
Only if he steals them.
Come.
Let's eat together.
We can talk.
Hold.
Your Grace will apologize.
I said...
You will apologize.
I apologize if I have offended
Your Majesty.
Your Grace may leave us.
Boy, fetch the chancellor
a new pair of shoes!
Hopkins!
Your Grace.
It's time.
Speak to me.
Yes, well...
everything is prepared
for the summit.
It will take place in the Pale
of Calais, English territory.
In a valley known as the
Val d'Or, the Valley of Gold.
A thousand labourers have constructed
a palace for Your Majesty.
It's known as the Palace of Illusions.
Some say it's the
8th wonder of the world!
You are to purchase as much cloth
of gold and silver as you can find.
It is a better thing to
bribe the guards with.
Yes, Your Grace.
Then I want you to proceed to our
estates and do as we discussed,
just making some noise that we're
only raising men to defend ourselves.
Yes, Your Grace.
Lady Blount is with child.
Lady Blount?
If you want to keep the child,
I will arrange for her
to be moved to
the house at Jericho.
I will also deal with her husband.
My father...
once told me how he had planned
to assassinate Richard III.
He would come before him with a
knife secreted about his person.
Your Majesty!
I can't wait for this summit!
It'll change the world forever.
That is my dearest
hope, and my ultimate belief.
Nothing will ever be
the same, Your Eminence.
You and I will be immortal.
Transcript : YDY Team
Adaptation/Resynchro : Tagne
www.forom.com