( I'd Iike to get you )
( On a sIow boat to China )
( AII to myseIf )
( AIone )
( Get you and keep you )
( In my arms evermore )
( Leave aII your Iovers )
( Weeping on a faraway shore... )
We agreed to
discharge your debts,
in return for your Japanese assets.
ReaI estate?
- No!
- Insurance companies?
- GambIing parIors?
No! No! No!
( Out on the briny )
( With the moon big and shiny... )
He said that the gambIing
parIors beIonged to his mother
and that she wouId be
very angry to see them soId.
Then I think
you have a choice.
PIease your mother,
or face criminaI charges.
WeII, to a man of honor,
that is no choice.
Then he may go to jaiI.
PIease sign here.
( MeIting your heart )
( Of stone... )
That was physicaI! I haven't had
a physicaI confrontation Iike that
since I was your age, Storey.
His mother is very angry.
WeII, his mother
packs a powerfuI punch.
( I'd Iove to get you )
( On a sIow boat to China... )
It's a contract with--
with bIood on it. My bIood.
- Let me get a new copy.
- No, no, no. I Iike the drama,
and I sort of respect
the gesture.
I hope you wouId
punch a foreigner
who bought your mother's
property, Storey.
Perhaps I wouId check
if he wouId punch me back.
( AII to myseIf )
( AIone... )
WeII, the spiIt bIood might heIp
to remove his shame.
You shouId now make
the three monkeys.
What?
You shouId invoke the three monkeys
every time you make a deaI.
Hmm.
The Pachinko ParIors
are not smaII change.
They are big business.
And you deepIy offended
his honor.
- You were rude.
- I wasn't rude.
And whose side are you on?
- You shouId seII them quickIy.
- No. If they can arouse such passion--
keep them.
l do not think, Mr. Storey,
that that is wise.
And I have your
best interests at heart.
They're not mine,
but they have my blood on them.
WeII...
we'II keep them for a year.
Fresh assessment next ApriI.
Though you must
manage them, Storey.
Maybe by next year
they'll have your blood on them.
Ear, chin, time one,
time two, prick, foot, hand,
and God.
Sic fatur Iacrimans
immitit-que.
The Iuck of a man
without a woman.
"The quick brown fox
jumps over the Iazy dog."
Simato.
The Iuck of a woman
with a man.
Hello, Storey, it's me.
What are you doing in Geneva?
You're supposed to be here tomorrow.
Dad, are you stiII there?
Do you want me
to caII you back?
- lt's your mother.
- Oh, how is she? Put her on.
She's not well.
- What's the matter?
- She's very ill.
ln fact, she's so ill
she's not moving anymore.
What are you taIking about?
She's not breathing anymore.
She's not living anymore.
ln fact...
she's dead.
What?
l-- l can't talk anymore just now.
Hey, wait, Dad?
When you've thought
about it, Storey, ring me.
10 minutes, five minutes.
l won't go away.
Ear, chin, heart--
heart,
prick, foot,
and God.
Benedictus,
benedicap...
benedancien...
Christian dominum
nostrum...
ad infinitum.
I Iived most of my Iife
with my wife in this bed.
You make it sound as though
you never got up.
I Iike sIeeping.
You were conceived
in this bed.
You weren't asIeep then.
No, but I've a feeIing
your mother was.
Read to me.
Your mother did.
What shaII I read?
Something grand and...
significant.
The Constitution of America?
No.
Your mother wasn't
an American,
and she never needed it.
The Lord's Prayer?
No. I never needed that, either.
Something in Latin?
You don't understand Latin.
Benedictus benedicap
benedancien,
Christian dominum
nostrum, amen.
You see? MangIed rubbish.
I Iove Latin.
But for some reason,
I was very bad at it.
ShamefuIIy and bIushingIy
bad at it.
- You were bad at maths.
- WeII, that was different.
In moments of stress
the embarrassment
of how bad I was at Latin
reaIIy hit me.
Like being Iaughed at by somebody
you desperateIy Ioved.
Where are you going?
Maybe I want to see
that maid,
CIothiIde, again
with a coffee pot.
Or maybe I wish
I wanted to see her.
How come that she
can be aIive
pouring coffee
and not your mother!?
You aren't--
gay, are you?
No.
WeII, I Iike my own
cock weII enough,
but I've never been abIe
to work up much enthusiasm
for anyone eIse's.
You've had aII this
re-decorated.
It was your mother's idea.
She was spring cIeaning.
Don't change the subject.
How come you haven't
got pIans to marry?
Perhaps because I'm too much
in Iove with my own prick
to share it permanentIy.
It's probabIy your fauIt.
My fauIt?
Ever since I was eight,
and you put that fuII-Iength mirror
in my wardrobe door,
and I wanted to be doubIe-jointed
so I couId kiss my cock good night
before I went to sIeep.
AII this narcissism's
rather boring, isn't it?
Find yourseIf a woman.
Get someone eIse to kiss
your cock for you.
Let's go to a hoteI.
No.
It's too far away from her
and she might want me.
How's that possibIe?
I might want her.
You've never sIept
with a corpse, I take it?
( I'd Iike to get you )
( On a sIow boat to China )
( AII to myseIf )
( AIone )
( Get you and keep you )
( In my arms )
( Evermore )
( Leave aII your Iovers )
( Weeping on a faraway shore. )
When I was young
I hated my body,
because it was so thin.
Now I try not
to Iook at it too much
because it's...
...so oId.
Perhaps there was just
six months when I feIt
comfortabIe with it.
When I discovered aIcohoI
for the first time,
and I'd Iearned to drive,
and was fattening up
when I just met your mother.
What was that noise?
lt's an owl.
Sounds Iike your mother
singing in the Ioo.
She sang to Iet you know
she was in there.
It's a funny thing to do,
don't you think?
If you were oversensitive
about bodiIy functions,
you'd have thought
she'd have kept
very quiet about it,
wouIdn't you?
It's no good.
This is too uncomfortabIe,
and you make me feeI guiIty.
Why?
You shouId have had
brothers and sisters.
Then you couId have
discussed sex with them.
But you're my father.
Why can't I discuss
sex with you?
Your interest in sex
got me here.
Why do you keep
saying things Iike that?
I'm bonding.
Did you ever do it
in the back of a roIIs?
Shut up.
I'm too miserabIe
to think about sex.
Look at aII these
wasted empty bedrooms,
aII set up with beds
and bathrooms.
It Iooks Iike a hoteI
without peopIe.
There used to be peopIe here
enough in the summer
when I was a chiId.
You shouId fiII
the rooms up again.
What the heII with--
concubines?
Let's go take a Iook
at your room.
You know...
you're my nearest
surviving reIative.
l'll always be nearer you
than your wife.
Shh!!
She'II hear us.
She didn't Iike
to be discussed.
So, this is the infamous mirror
that saw so much of
my son's nakedness?
You're a great deaI fIeshier than me
when I was your age.
Where do you get it from?
CertainIy not your mother.
You've a nice backside.
- I can sit on it.
- You couId say that.
You Iook a stranger
to me, naked.
It works both ways.
Get out of bed.
I want to see what I'II Iook Iike
when I'm 57.
55. And there's a corpse
in the house.
She's not a corpse.
She's my mother.
WeII, I don't know
what to say, reaIIy,
except you Iook immortaI
and I Iook bereft.
That's not true.
There's onIy one pair.
You can have the trousers.
Oh my God.
My God, my God, Storey.
Who is ever gonna
hoId me cIoseIy again?
You're a rich man--
I couId think of hundreds.
Money? That's no good.
That's no good at aII.
How can you say that?
Who is gonna hoId me
and Iove me...
...for me?
For my body as it is now?
For me as I am now,
Iike she did?
I thought you said
she was very passive in bed.
Did I?
You've got too many
cIothes on.
I've never sIept naked.
I hate pajamas.
I didn't know
you couId do this.
You can do anything.
Besides, you're my father.
And you're very,
very, very unhappy.
Lift your arm
and Iie on your back.
- I'm unhappy, too.
- Mmm?
Sort of.
But not as unhappy
as you are, of course.
- We'II just have to sort it aII out.
- Mmm.
Be patient.
Grieve properIy.
Remember,
I'm your nearest reIative.
And besides
we couIdn't make babies
even if we tried.
I want to wear white
to EmiIia's funeraI.
- She didn't Iike bIack.
- You can't. They won't Iike it.
It's a reputabIe cemetery.
I have been contributing
to this town for 35 years.
I am a respectabIe
Genevan citizen.
They can honor
my wife through me
with this IittIe request!
Okay, okay, okay.
So--
Iet's do this properIy.
ObviousIy, the underwear
must go, too!
If you insist on bIack,
Iet's bIoody weII
go through with it!
So-- who's wearing
bIack underwear?
Hmm? Hmm?
Do I go to my wife's
funeraI naked?
She never once,
in her whoIe Iifetime
saw me compIeteIy naked.
WeII, now's her chance, eh?
Father, don't be
so bIoody stupid.
Nobody's going to see
your underwear.
Everybody's probabIy wearing
white underwear anyway.
But, you idiot,
that is just the point.
Just to show you how
bIoody stupid
aII this etiquette is.
You want me in bIack?
Okay, okay, okay.
So I'II wear bIack.
Don't make such a fuss, PhiIip.
- I'm wearing a bIack T-shirt.
- Okay, get it off.
I've got bIack underwear on.
Is that usuaI
for a man in your age?
It Iooks Iike swimming trunks.
I can go swimming
in the Iake afterwards.
What was EmiIia to you?
An excuse for a quick dip?
CharIie, Iend me your suit.
Go and sit in the car.
Come on, hurry up!
CIean on this morning.
Oh, don't worry.
You'II get 'em back
And they'II be washed
and pressed.
- 60 francs for your shirt.
- What?
- 80 francs?
- No.
100 francs.
No, it's new.
Okay, 150 francs?
God! Whoever paid that
for a bIack shirt?
- It's a coIIector's item.
- BIoody is, now.
Benedictus, benedicap,
benedancien,
Christian dominum
nostrum, Amen.
You know,
to make his rigid, tedious,
boring painting seem
at least a little human,
the Mondrian enthusiasts
keep insisting that Mondrian
was a great tango dancer.
Art is supposed to heIp
in times of crisis.
I'm sure that food, aIcohoI, and sex
are a better distraction.
Food onIy makes me retch.
AIcohoI onIy makes
me scared.
And sex?
Your mother's dead.
And with her everything
that's compatibIe with my prick.
What an extraordinary
thing to say.
Why? It's true.
I know I'm a prude,
but I'm aIso a good dancer.
( I saw a man who danced
with his wife )
( In Chicago )
( Chicago is my home town. )
Or I used to be.
I used to have a wife.
I'm taking you to the cinema.
- I never go to the cinema.
- A great escapist medium.
I can't stand sitting
in the dark with strangers.
HarmIess.
AII of us obIiged to share
the same emotionaI experiences.
- It's too intimate.
- Two hours of forgetfuIness.
I Iike to be emotionaI
in private.
I haven't noticed.
You know, Storey, I haven't
been truthfuI with you.
When I was a young man--
this is going to shock you--
I, too, often wanted
to sIeep with my father.
Is that strange?
The other night--
it was, on my part,
an unpremeditated act.
I was hoping to consoIe you.
And I thought I did.
At Ieast I distracted you.
WeII, you've heard
of young men
wishing to sIeep
with their mothers,
but not with their fathers, sureIy?
I mean, there's a name
for sIeeping with your mother
- but not with your father.
- Shut up, Father. Not now.
Don't caII me Father.
He was Iike a Iarge piIIow--
my father.
He took me swimming
in the Iake
practicaIIy every day
in the summer.
I watched him cIoseIy.
A Iarge man with a Iarge cock.
Big, purpIe, rubbery.
My mother must have been deIighted,
she'd had two husbands aIready.
AII the servants
came down to watch.
I was pIeased that they Iooked,
because after aII,
that's where I came from.
You see? You too,
are interested in sexuaI continuity.
Remember, I was onIy 10,
perhaps...
13.
Now, contempIating
my father's prick,
I often think that that's what got me
interested in engineering.
What?
Watching his EiffeI Tower,
his Empire State BuiIding...
perhaps made me a good engineer.
Shut up, Father,
and watch the fiIm.
The penis, if you think about it,
is the most enterprising
engineering feat imaginabIe.
HydrauIics, compression,
propuIsion, heat sensitive.
PracticaIIy every
engineering characteristic.
Towers, drawbridges,
rocket ships.
No man-made engineering
structure to match it.
My father's invoIuntary anatomy
instructed my career prospects.
Do I have that much
infIuence on your career?
What's the matter?
You must excuse me.
I was disturbed
by your frankness.
You are obviousIy
on a voyage of discovery.
Oh, dear, oh, dear.
TaIking sex again.
What eIse is there to taIk about?
Give me another subject.
Death?
That is not a decent
subject matter to discuss.
Watch the fiIm.
- Money?
- Money's not interesting.
Too easy to get hoId of.
Too many stupid
peopIe have it.
Money can easiIy
be buried in the other two.
Buried.
I don't want to taIk
about buriaIs.
Why do you think
FeIIini kept inventing
aII these exciting women?
Do you think
he Ioved them aII?
Did he sIeep with them aII?
Did he sIeep with any of them?
Or did he get Mastroianni
to do it for him?
Dad, I have to go back
to Kyoto.
Oh, stay another week.
I need you here.
Why don't you come with me?
A change of pIace
wiII do you good.
I'II see.
How many fiIm directors
make fiIms to satisfy their...
sexuaI fantasies?
I wouId imagine most of them.
If you don't come
to Kyoto this week,
come for your birthday.
Those women.
AII nationaIities.
Every shape and size,
every age.
He was just an oId ItaIian pimp.
We know how Iecherous
the ItaIians are supposed to be.
But it's probabIy
an undeserved reputation.
What's going on?
This woman has been
caught stealing.
Then call the police.
The father won't do it.
He says it is a famiIy matter.
You run a temptation shop.
He's very angry.
She's soId his car
and mortgaged his house,
- to pIay your machines.
- How couId she have done that?
- She forged his signature.
- Whose signature?
The brother's and the father's
and now the fiance's.
This pIace is a trap
for weak-minded women
with nothing better to do.
They want to beat her--
And they want you to pay them.
She's very simple-minded.
Ask her why on earth she does it.
She's stupid.
What did l tell you?
- TeII her she's beautifuI.
- You are beautifuI.
- She says you must give her credit.
- No.
You'II end up in jaiI, and they
don't have these machines in jaiI.
- They do.
- They do?
The jailers take credit for sex.
Then maybe I shouId do the same.
Ask her if she'll sleep with me,
then I'II give her credit.
- She agrees.
- You didn't ask her.
She'll accept.
WouIdn't that disgrace her
more than steaIing?
Not necessariIy.
- You see, her family suggested it.
- They what?
What about her fiance?
Buy him a car,
and he'll forget her.
What am I getting into here?
You make it sound aII sewn up.
She says she's staying the night,
unless you want to hear
she's been beaten.
And your pachinko parlor
will be held responsible.
You might Iose your Iicense,
and it might affect
your other premises.
- Where's she going?
- I toId her you Iive upstairs.
Jesus!
That's an unrecognizabIe
bIasphemy in Japan.
Do you need an interpreter
in the bedroom?
No, thank you.
UnIess you'd Iike to participate.
- If it heIps to get rid of her.
- God, l always thought the Japanese
had an overdeveIoped
sense of shame.
OnIy from our point of view,
not yours.
And you are a foreigner,
so, in this case,
shame doesn't enter into it,
unIess we want it to.
Kito, what is she saying?
She says, she doesn't
use contraceptives.
Send her away.
She's a Iesbian.
- What? You speak?
- l am not a lesbian.
Of course, I speak EngIish.
But you whispered.
It's an oId routine.
I've known her too Iong.
She's aIways been a misery.
Kiss me.
I can't beIieve she's femaIe.
She is a man.
She couIdn't hide it.
At Ieast--
how wouId she know where--
Training, observation,
fuIfiIIing aII the femaIe
stereotypes invented by men.
You're too cynicaI.
Can she-- he, be married?
PossibIy.
Though you'd never see his wife.
He wouIdn't much either--
Work and rehearsal,
dedication.
Are you aII right?
What did she say?
- She says, impossibIe.
- What's impossibIe?
She says she wants to be
a female impersonator.
Whatever for?
She wants to be
more femaIe than she is.
Strange ambition.
lsn't she female enough?
He has to act. She is.
TeII her she's beautifuI.
TeII her.
Is that aIways the way
you start a courtship?
It's the truth.
Kito said you are
interested in her body.
Watch out, Kito.
What are we paying you?
Watch out, Storey,
I am jeaIous.
You have no right
to be jealous of a woman
who wants to be
more of a woman
by watching a man
dressed up as a woman.
CompIicated, eh?
What we need now
is an earthquake to cIear the air.
- My God!
- How the hell did you do that?
- Coincidence.
- Oh, you bring bad Iuck.
Call up an earthquake
and he will follow you
aII the days of your Iife.
Teach me... aII about kabuki...
and I-- we...
wiII heIp you become
more Iike him.
Her.
To be more female
than you think you are.
Watch out, kabuki lover,
you are in for some
sexuaI experiment.
Shut up, Simato!
What are we watching
but sexual experiment!
My feet ache.
I'm not used
to so much waIking.
Do I have to waIk anymore?
What are you doing?
Doing? l'm not doing anything.
l'm watering my coffee.
I can't make it taste
any worse than it does.
You can't sit there
being miserabIe.
l can't walk any more.
I've seen too many shrines,
and they're no comfort
- 'cause they're not my reIigion.
- Oh God, Father.
Why don't you go and Iie down?
You're using the word God
an awfuI Iot these days.
ls it significant for you?
l hoped it was gonna be
significant for me, but alas no,
for me it is onIy
etymoIogicaIIy interesting
as dog backwards.
Dad, stop being petuIant.
Come, Mr. EmmenthaI,
watch TV with us.
TV?
I don't watch it in Europe,
why shouId I want
to watch it here?
I didn't know you couId
do it Iike that.
But outside of noveIs
and Swedish cinema--
Dad, where have you been
aII these years?
With your mother.
She was passionate
enough, but...
l can see now,
perhaps a little unadventurous.
I bet it was your fauIt.
You were probabIy very Iazy.
Come to think of it
perhaps with your mother
I was too easiIy satisfied.
I need some heIp.
Do you think some re-training?
Is that what you're doing?
Is that the Japanese
Do you have to be Japane--
excuse me, Simato.
How on earth couId you
beIieve that?
l gave it a great
deal of thought.
It sort of excited me,
but anatomicaIIy, I was worried.
WeII I think we're
gonna have to put you
out of your racist misery.
Is she reaIIy Japanese?
And there are some
100 miIIion Japanese woman
who are no Ionger Japanese.
because--
I don't want your mother's
prejudices broadcast around.
But l am delighted to find
that your mother was wro--
Oh God, I'm gonna be sick.
That's not very complimentary.
I show you my girIfriend's private parts
and you rush off to be sick.
I'm sorry, I was suddenIy fiIIed
with such intense
and desperate Ionging
that aII my insides heaved.
Do you know,
l am amazed, in a way,
to think that you can
get sick with grief.
Perhaps it was too much
in-fIight aIcohoI.
That was four days ago.
SIow stomach.
Oh my God! What's happening!?
It's an earthquake.
The third-- third for me.
It's the best yet.
Asa nisi masa!
Good God,
there's no one about.
The street's empty.
Can't see much damage.
"All day long, the noise of battle
rolled amongst the mountains
down to the winter sea."
"Lucy in the sky with diamonds."
"Nebuchadnezzar ate grass
"SmeIIs Iike teen spirit!"
"Oh, yellow 'catchie'
come and have a go
if you think you're
hard enough!"
Get into bed.
We must ceIebrate
my third earthquake success.
Success?
I've survived
my third earthquake.
What makes you think
they're yours excIusiveIy?
You, Father,
have a Iot to Iearn.
We must make the earth shake
and quake for you.
- Have you shaved?
- I don't need to shave.
Her skin is very deIicate.
My beard has hardIy grown
since your mother died.
Okay, we'II show you
what to do.
What do you mean?
CouId I have a Iight
Iess bright,
do you think?
- Let's Iose those sIippery sheets.
- No, Iet's not!
Suppose there's another earthquake?
We'd be exposed.
With the experiences
you're about to have,
you're not supposed
to know the difference.
- How can we do it again?
- Find your own woman.
It was a speciaI
earthquake anniversary.
I got carried away.
Simato got carried away.
Don't earthquakes make you feeI
very excited, indeed?
No-- emphaticaIIy not.
The uItimate chance event.
In this country,
you know they are coming.
But nobody,
absoIuteIy nobody--
no expert, no geoIogist,
no pubIic reIations men,
no poIitician-- knows when.
No predictions,
no givabIe odds.
Amazing.
And besides,
what about mother?
Yes.
WeII, that's a very brief
answer for you.
Just what are you doing, Storey?
You said you wanted to educate me.
You keep giving me
the most delightful presents,
and then you take them away.
Think of aII those empty bedrooms
you've got in Geneva--
and you once careIessIy
mentioned concubines.
I suspect there are
quite a few Japanese Iadies
who wouId Iike
to come to Europe.
But what wouId your
mother think?
Don't teII her.
Look out for me.
I want somebody warm--
with a good body temperature.
Did you know that
maIe temperatures are higher
than femaIe temperatures?
No coId feet.
LiteraIIy, or metaphoricaIIy.
There's a woman in the Ocean
Fire Insurance Office Company
I've aIways been intrigued about.
Wears a great deaI of pIaid,
though I'm certain she's not Scottish.
I'm sure she's Norwegian.
Do you know any Norse?
Most Scandinavians
speak very good EngIish.
Norse probabIy disappeared
over a thousand years ago.
Look.
We're under surveillance.
Do I Iook guiIty of anything?
This Norwegian,
Scottish woman
was under surveiIIance
for embezzIement.
Theresa's her name.
Or GriseIda.
If it wasn't GriseIda
it ought to have been.
She was good.
Fine fingers.
One day she put
a poultice on my forehead
and my feet in a basin
of cold water with salt.
I wasn't feeIing at aII weII.
Then she made me a compIicated drink
that sent me to sIeep at my desk.
Was this mereIy soIicitous,
do you think?
Or was she trying
to get to the safe?
She was charged--
and I think, indicted.
I must see what I can do.
You must help me there,
Mr. Expert.
Do you think l'll ever get
to see an in-flight Fellini movie?
l would be curious
about one of those
Jane Austen women,
you know?
Long suffering, dutifuI,
but aII right in the end.
A pIump 19th Century type--
5'4",
ringIets, brown eyes,
Iong fingers.
Raw sex is the Iast thing
you're gonna encounter
- in a Jane Austen woman.
- Rubbish. AbsoIute rubbish.
A Iong white dress,
that starts under the breasts
and traveIs on
interminabIy down
so the Iegs are
entireIy mysterious.
She couId have one Ieg
or two inside that dress.
A Jane Austen woman
couId be incredibIy passionate
inside that dress.
And you wouId never know
if she had feet.
Which you couId not say
about Mio.
Mio,
this could be your room.
You have a view
of the garden and the moat.
You will feel very comfortable.
The rising sun shines directIy
through the window.
Dickens.
God, no.
A Dickens heroine wouId never
Iet you see her sitting on the Ioo.
I think a Jane Austen
heroine just might.
She couId end up
Iike a Thomas Hardy woman.
Victims-- start bad,
finish much worse.
Lots of tears.
CIothiIde?
Can you go to room four
and ask Mio to get undressed,
and take a bath?
I don't speak the Ianguage,
Mr. EmmenthaI.
Neither do we.
- I must get Kito to come over.
- No, we mustn't.
She'II have us aII audited.
Thomas Hardy was interested
in seIIing women.
That's auditing for you.
The uItimate audit.
Sell your wife.
l found out her name.
Georgette.
Such a modern name.
lt sounds Romanian.
Sounds like someone
who's had a sex change.
- She's a retired nun.
- Retired?
How on earth
can she be retired?
She's bound to enjoy scrubbing.
Look at her hands.
She's must be allowed
to scrub a great deal.
She's like all those
nun paintings.
The starched Iinen,
pIucked brows,
sharp pins in the pink flesh,
and the wet eyes,
the devotional glance.
And modesty that
conceals the body
that still has breasts
and pubic hair.
The contrast is so exciting.
She's certainly a bed maker.
Clean sheets flying
in the air in the sunlight.
She'd be an angel,
making her bed forever.
She owes the bank
140,000 pounds.
How do you know?
Come on. How does
a bank manager know secrets?
Let's tempt her.
Offer her a loan--
high interest.
See how she reacts,
and then more.
Make sure she doubIes the debt
and then offer her a way out.
Whiter, much whiter.
Like miIk.
Or snow.
And make her Iips
very, very smaII.
So small, l couldn't get
my little finger between them.
Are we doing this correctIy,
do you think?
ShouId we paint her
entire body white, do you think?
Let's do it anyway.
No, CIothiIde.
Not here.
It's most out of pIace.
I teII you what,
take it to bedroom one--
no, six.
In preparation.
A token.
We must find
somewhere to fit it.
Stand it at the end of the bed
And surround it in flowers.
Poppies-- Renoir fIowers.
- Are poppies in season?
- No, Mr. EmmenthaI.
What are Renoir's fiIms Iike?
He was the director who said,
"Every man has his reasons."
Do we have reasons?
No-- you just have Iust.
Oh, beautifuI.
It smeIIs of canaries.
Lapsang souchong.
The smeII of my watch strap
after a game of squash.
- Mice.
- Horsehair cushions.
Brown sugar just unwrapped
out of a damp paper bag.
Burnt eggs.
No orgies,
Don't want to get sexual indigestion.
l can't stand more than one
naked woman at a time.
lt reminds me of a pig farm
or a cattle market,
or one of those terrible
concentration camp films.
Good Lord, Iook at that.
WouId you beIieve it--
in the 1990s?
What's her name?
- Caspar.
- Caspar?
Oh, no, sorry.
That's the name of the horse.
Is he... aII right?
What is the name
of your horse doing
on your hospitaI charge sheet?
He's not my horse.
- He's not your horse?
- Then whose horse is it?
I stoIe him.
You stole him?
Hey...
why don't you come
and convaIesce with us?
We couId provide you
with a new horse.
A physiotherapist.
You could do therapy
in our pool.
The horse couId do
therapy in our pooI.
Where are you going?
- To buy some fIowers.
- FIowers aren't gonna heIp.
Yes, they are.
CIothiIde says
fIowers aIways heIp.
Good evening.
BeautifuI.
Excuse me?
You are Iooking so beautifuI.
Thank you.
Pregnancy makes you beautifuI.
Don't you think?
You know?
Wake up-- having babies?
This is the sixth.
The sixth?
You must have
an understanding husband.
Tsk, tsk... no husband.
Oh!
ArtificiaI insemination?
No, too impersonaI.
Are you offering?
No.
I mean-- weII, I couId.
I-- I'd Iike to.
Can I?
And the chiIdren?
Three adopted.
Two with their fathers.
You could think about it.
Nice hair.
Do you stiII go to church?
No.
Do you stiII say
your prayers?
No.
Do you stiII beIieve in heII?
Depends what you mean by still.
l've never believed in hell.
Then you beIieve
you wiII not pay for your sins?
Not in hell, only on Earth.
However, I've aIways
beIieved in heaven.
Heaven on Earth.
And you, GriseIda,
are a piece of heaven.
- But--
- But what?
Now, don't take this
reIigion too seriousIy.
- lt's a pose.
- No, it is not.
It is a way of Iife.
Come in.
GriseIda's becoming
a nun in her heart
as weII as her body.
Then I'm aIready
jeaIous of God.
JeaIousy?
It'II destroy you.
- "OtheIIo."
- CompIimentary tickets.
I'm the financiaI secretary
of the friends of the Genevan opera.
ObIigations to attend.
You bored us aII
in Kyoto, Storey,
by taking us to the kabuki.
It's my turn to bore you.
We go to the opera.
The whoIe firm wiII go.
Dress up.
The fuII compIement.
Now, pIease Ieave us.
Devout, inestimabIe GriseIda
has a higher caIIing to make.
- I'm taking CIothiIde.
- Oh, whatever for?
It's obvious she wouId
want to come.
I understand the
thoroughbred was worth nearIy
haIf a miIIion doIIars.
Owned by a Saudi Arabian.
Now, there are some peopIe
who prize their horses
above their women.
Punishments in Saudi Arabia
can be harsh.
- An eye for an eye.
- A horse for a horse.
A horse for a woman?
No, l don't think,
we need go quite that far.
And as it happens,
we were abIe to return it.
- Caspar.
There were questions asked.
And the owners have
a pretty shrewd idea
who stole their horse.
lt seems you've done it before.
They did not understand
what a sensitive horse they had.
They had no idea.
He needed affection.
Perhaps.
- Are they downstairs?
- Good Lord, no. I don't think so.
- At Ieast not yet.
- Not yet?
Who are those peopIe?
I am accused
of unethicaI practices.
And what may they be?
WeII, I Iike having babies.
So I've noticed.
There are many peopIe
in the worId
who want to have babies
and can't have them.
So, you perform an unusuaI
phiIanthropic service?
I'm good at having babies.
Is it so bad to make a Iiving
at what you're good at?
I see.
This time there is a way out.
I can see it coming.
You can be my husband.
Am I to be responsibIe
for aII six?
No. You can be the father
of just this one.
I have a proposition.
Quite frankIy, Mr. EmmenthaI,
I am a modern woman.
I do not want to be
deported to Saudi Arabia.
And as Iong as horses
are invoIved,
I think I am prepared
for aII eventuaIities.
However, I have one
important responsibiIity
I cannot reIinquish.
- I have a pig.
- A pig?
Horses and pigs
aIways get on weII together.
They are inteIIigent animaIs
and Iike one another's company.
Can you--
can you ride a pig?
Hortense is far too dignified
to be ridden.
However, Hortense and I
have a reIationship--
which you might find unusuaI--
beyond mere affection.
I have no intention
of breaking this reIationship.
- I see.
- Neither does Hortense.
WeII...
as Iong as I don't
get too jeaIous,
and you both
take a bath afterwards,
l can't see that l need
to be difficult.
Kiss me.
That was a husband's kiss,
I suppose.
You couId show
a IittIe more passion.
WeII--
weII, I suppose you better
make you an offer.
We-- I, wiII pay for you
to have babies.
No artificiaI insemination.
And you have come
to coIIect this chiId.
When it's ready, of course.
I'm having no interferences.
Of course not.
In that case,
couId you have me moved
into a nicer room?
I think...
bIue waIIs.
I'm sure it's going to be
a boy this time.
And I think I charge
$25,000 for a boy.
It's time now.
Are you enjoying
the music, Clothilde?
I am enjoying
Mr. EmmenthaI's smiIe.
He was so heartbroken
at the death of his wife.
WeII, you couId aIways
enjoy his smiIe at home.
She was good to me.
I wouId Iike to repay
her kindness
trying to make
her widower
and his son happy.
I couId never take
EmiIia's pIace entireIy,
but I wouId be honored
to take it in part.
Which part?
Whichever part he wishes.
I wouId Iike to ask
if I couId be aIIowed to--
no, l can't say this--
Go on, say it.
to wear her hats.
My mother's hats?
That's aII?
Just her hats?
In bed.
Nothing eIse.
I know you, don't I?
At Ieast I know
your father, PhiIip.
These aII your girIfriends?
OrientaI speciaIities?
Best of luck.
You're very restIess.
You weren't taking them
to the gents for a fuck, were you?
That one's crying
her eyes out.
What have you done to her?
It's her birthday.
WeII, that expIains everything.
She's sentimentaI.
Likes horses.
And especiaIIy pigs,
apparentIy.
Go and get us something to drink.
I have a desperate thirst.
I reaIIy did know your father
three years ago.
I heId his hand
at a passing-out ceremony
on a very big stage.
I toId him where to stand.
He was very awkward.
I aIways Iiked the way
he swung his Iegs.
Always thought
he'd do himself an injury.
I asked him
to sIeep with me.
I Iaid it aII on for him.
I brought my toothbrush
and a cIean pair of knickers
round to his
hoteI room in Utrecht.
Or was it Berlin?
However, he turned me down.
AII manner of
ridicuIous excuses,
Iike, he was
happiIy married.
Wasted a golden opportunity.
However, never say die.
I've Iooked forward
to French kissing him ever since.
( Des--demona )
Meet Simon--
the singing cockereI.
Simon has no shame.
He says I wiII aIways be
the favorite white woman
he Ioves to undress.
And he does it
as often as he can,
which is often,
and everywhere.
And in the most
unIikeIy pIaces.
OnIy he goes
on tour,
and he has a wife.
Don't you, Simon?
And he makes me wait
for the services of his big bIack cock,
and the deIights of his
magnificent singing voice.
Or is it the other
way around?
So...
how is your father?
Why don't you come and see?
- But he's not bIack.
- That's true.
- And he can't sing.
- Not that I remember.
We couId aIways cork his face
and pinch his backside,
and he might give you a dark stare
and a IittIe scream.
He used to stroke
his IittIe round beIIy
with a circuIar motion.
I'd Iike to do the same.
TeII him.
What wouId you say
if I'd Iike to share the attentions?
Perhaps.
Are you his naturaI heir?
I am his heir.
NaturaIIy and unnaturaIIy.
- FinanciaIIy?
- FinanciaIIy.
What have you got
that I've never seen before?
You're free to go, PaImira.
You are free to go.
l'll be your number four private whore--
for one year,
for 75,000 US dollars.
No possible demands
denied.
lmpossible ones
considered.
l have a high pain
tolerance,
but don't abuse it.
The greater your invention,
the greater mine.
I'II Iook after
the contraception.
Never trust an oId man.
UnreasonabIe?
If I'm sharing your prick,
I want medicaI checks
every week
with a quaIified doctor.
And I want my privacy,
when I need it.
And I want to sIeep Iate.
Very Iate.
And I want to traveI.
So, PhiIip,
I want to see what
I missed three years ago.
You can have me on approvaI.
Open the window,
I need fresh air.
Out you go,
Storey EmmenthaI.
Let's see what tune
your father sings,
and how he's gonna
sing it with me.
lt's okay, it's on expenses.
Whose goddamn expenses?
Tax deductibIe.
From Kensai,
or from Geneva airport?
From Paris.
But that's hours away
by heIicopter.
- I bought, ah--
- Put her in room six.
We'II fix somewhere
for her Iater.
Giaconda?
My God! What have
you done with the baby?
What baby?
God, who are you?
Oh God, Kito.
- But you're in Kyoto.
- Oh, stop that.
- Stop what?
- l'm too tired for that.
And you're drunk.
You're not supposed to be in here.
This is Giaconda's room.
l'm only staying a few nights.
l arrived from the sky.
l'll stay a few moments,
just to warm you up.
l'll wait a little bit just in case
Giaconda comes back.
She's probably gone
for a pee.
Pregnant women spend
half the night going to the loo.
Did you know that?
Yes, l did know that.
And with a little help
from you...
l might be able
to experience it, too.
Kito.
Oh, Kito.
You have always
surprised me.
Poor thing.
They say she's onIy
haIf a person.
A midget.
I've heard worse.
Much worse.
That she's a mongreI.
A mongreI?
What do you mean?
How come?
If there ever was
a good case for abortion...
- I don't understand.
- Have you been in that room?
No.
There's no number
on the door.
They haven't even
given her a proper name.
They sometimes
call her Giuletta,
after a fiIm
about a waif and stray,
a simpIeton
who pIays a trumpet.
You don't think for a moment
that it's a chiId?
God, no.
She sounds Korean.
How wouId you know that?
Kito says she was born
in a Pachinko parIor,
and deaf because
of aII the noise.
Kito Ioves Storey
to distraction.
I wouId never beIieve
anything she says.
Perhaps she's Vietnamese?
A boat person?
What? Who arrived one morning
on the Iake from Hong Kong?
I don't think it's a woman at aII.
I'II bet it's a man.
A transsexuaI.
And the haIf refers
to a haIf-man, haIf-woman.
Francois says they
conceived it together--
- The father and son.
- CeIeste!
For God's sake,
puII the other one.
Through the backside.
RidicuIous.
Who was the father, then?
WeII he was, of course--
the oIder.
There's more spunk in him
than a cage of chimpanzees.
How do you know that?
I know.
I wanted to be a candidate once,
you know?
Clothilde made it.
But I aIways suspect
she had an uIterior motive,
being EmiIia's favorite
when she was aIive.
I went for an audition.
They tried me out,
but they weren't too excited.
I was too wiIIing.
l liked the prison life
too much.
And I loved the cIothes.
I even Iiked the humiIiations,
you know?
No...
I don't know.
Hot drinking chocoIate,
foIIowed by the ice cubes.
You know the stuff.
Picking up handkerchiefs
off the floor
with your teeth when you're naked.
Gallons of hot water,
string vests,
and wet t-shirts,
and nippIe cIips.
Shaved beIIy.
AII the cIiches.
You've seen them in the cinema,
and read about them in the newspapers.
Standing on your head--
miIk bathing--
putting on excess weight.
Sounds Iike athIetic
nouveIIe cuisine.
WeII, it couId be--
in a way.
Goodnight, sleep tight,
Make sure the bugs don't bite.
Goodnight, sIeep tight,
make sure the bugs don't bite.
make sure the bugs don't bite!
There's no wiIdIife
in this house that's not Iicensed.
And stop banging the doors!
I have to kiss everyone
on the backside before I go to sIeep.
It's an acknowIedgement
of possession.
IncIuding the pig?
Hortense has a nice backside,
but it is reserved for BeryI.
Simato, GriseIda, BeryI,
Giaconda, PaImira, Mio,
Kito, GiuIetta, CIothiIde.
Eight and a haIf women.
I bet you never kiss
PaImira on the backside.
Oh, I'd Iike to.
My God, I'd Iike to.
Can't you put a word in for me?
Oh, pIease?
And she's taken to partiaIIy
shaving her beIIy,
showing evidence
of the most deIightfuI kind.
Did you ask her to do that?
My God.
Why does she have to waIk around
the house naked Iike that?
And in the garden.
Simato, Griselda, Beryl,
Giaconda, Mio, GiuIetta,
Kito, CIothiIde, and PaImira.
Divorced, beheaded, died.
Divorced, beheaded, survived.
Those are Henry VIII's wives.
Catherine of Aragon,
Anne BoIeyn, Jane Seymour,
Anne of CIeves,
Catherine-- something,
- and Catherine Parr.
- Go to sIeep.
You know those great passions?
Those unbeIievabIe sexuaI passions?
Like Anthony and CIeopatra,
or Henry VIII and Anne BoIeyn?
Oh, my God.
PaImira, PaImira,
PaImira, PaImira, PaImira.
Oh, PaImira, PaImira...
I think you can say with safety
that nowadays,
women have finaIIy
acknowIedged their position
of not Iiking men.
We couId say that women
don't Iike men.
They acknowledge that
they prefer the company...
of their own kind.
I think that we can aIso say
that most men
don't Iike other men.
Most men prefer to like women.
So, women are the most Iiked
by the most peopIe.
Men Iove women,
women Iove chiIdren,
and chiIdren Iove hamsters.
It's a one-way sIide.
There's IittIe going back the other way.
Simato and Mio insist
on speaking Japanese.
WeII, that's an improvement.
Mio normaIIy doesn't taIk at aII.
We'II have to get Kito
to stay here permanentIy.
The very threat
might make them taIk.
Mr. EmmenthaI,
I am offering a refuge
to these Iadies in need.
This is Sister Mary.
This is Sister Sophie.
This is Sister Iphigenia.
And this is Sister Fatima.
They are here to pray for the house
and aII who Iive in it.
- God!
- The father of Christ.
GriseIda,
this is becoming an obsession.
- You started it.
- But my fantasy has no God in it,
just naked nuns.
The fascination of the wimpIe
and the fIesh.
God is everywhere,
Mr. EmmanueI.
It's EmmenthaI--
Jesus Christ!
The son of God.
Excuse me, sisters.
I am bound at this moment to pay
certain duties to these gentIemen,
my benefactors who rescued me
from perfidy,
and danger and temptation.
Clothilde has left
the servant's quarters
and taken to sleeping
in room seven.
All your mother's hats
have been taken.
lt's a signal that she's ready.
Watch out for Clothilde,
there's something creepy about her.
Far too subservient.
It's unnaturaI.
You were the one
who was so eager to incIude her.
I think we shouId
inaugurate a chapeI.
I have pIans for where
the 12 stations of the cross shouId go
in the garden,
and aIong the drive.
I think we couId weII create
a reIigious community.
I couId be an exampIe
to others.
An object of suffering.
She's pregnant again.
And this time she isn't certain
who the father is, me, or you.
She wants to abort at once.
Simato's compIaining again.
She's sitting on the top step,
demanding attention.
CompIaining that I
don't wash my prick.
Says she's frightened
of cervicaI cancer.
Where did she get
that idea from?
PaImira?
Good God.
My prick gets more washing
Than a dishcIoth in a Iaundry.
Ask GriseIda.
She fills her mouth
every morning with soap.
Okay, l've heard enough.
Never used to be
so crude, Father.
I'd Iike to borrow 800 francs
to buy Mr. EmmenthaI a present.
Anything Iess wouId not
be worthy of him.
What are you gonna buy him?
He has everything.
I don't think he has happiness.
Goodness, who on earth has that?
l do.
You do?
AII right,
for someone that rich,
you can have
a thousand francs,
At 4.5% interest
over three months.
That woman's insides must be
Iike a traffic accident.
l've never understood Beryl.
Beryl?
Which one's Beryl?
Number five's old room.
The one you knocked off her horse.
Why do you keep
changing their names?
I don't.
Isn't her name BeryI?
This is very good, CIothiIde.
Thank you, Mr. EmmenthaI.
Don't be so patronizing.
- She's very soIicitous.
- Patronizing?
I was paying her
a compIiment.
Do you think CIothiIde
couId be trying to poison me?
You're fantasizing.
lf she kills you
it will be with overfeeding.
Did you notice Kito
counting her money?
I've aIways noticed
her spending ours.
There's a suitcase under her bed
full of us bonds and large Swiss notes.
She's become a moneyIender.
Charges interest.
They're moving out of
EmmenthaI debt into Kito debt.
Miss?
Miss Kito, we've come
to ask for a Ioan.
Then she says,
"How do you want to do it?
From the front?
From behind?"
And l say,
"A little from the front,
and a Iot from behind."
"Do you want to do it
in the garden,
or by the pooI?
Or do you want me to Iie
on the grass?" she says.
I say, "Yes."
"Or do you want me perhaps
to stand?" she says.
"Yes", I say.
"Or do you want me to sit
with my heeIs in the air?"
"Yes", I say.
"Yes to what?" she says.
"Yes to everything." I say.
"Then I wiII", she says.
And she does, just Iike that.
My God!
Can she swim?
Can money swim?
Value?
Depends how you look at it.
Metal balls--
no value at all.
To a Pachinko parlor player--
60,000 US dollars,
400,000 French francs,
or nearIy eight miIIion
Japanese yen.
- I'm gonna shout.
- Don't.
- You'II Iose the stake.
- She's bIuffing.
Simato!
Keeping me here, Storey,
is Iosing your money--
hands over foot.
Oh, for God's sakes,
it's "hand over fist."
What on earth are you doing?
Oh, bIoody heII.
Can't you guess?
I'm trying to Iook Iike
that boyfriend of hers.
For Christ's sake,
you're ridicuIous.
I know.
I'm desperate.
She wiII Iaugh you to derision.
I know.
She mustn't Ieave me.
- I'd be destitute.
- You couIdn't compete.
He's her age, has sexuaI charisma
Iike a house on fire,
And no doubt,
a 12 inch cock.
Wash that stuff off at once,
And be in my bed
in six and a half minutes flat.
l want my bottom
smacked tonight--
real hard...
with a tennis racket.
Mio wants you to dress up
as a female impersonator.
And then, she says,
she could possibly
love you with enthusiasm.
Good God.
Why all the charade?
If you want Iife out of her,
do it!
She says you are a man.
WeII, of course I'm a man.
But she wanted you
to be a woman.
CompIicated, eh?
You dress as a woman.
You've been asked to act,
However badIy,
as a woman.
- But you are a cheat.
- Of course I'm a cheat.
That's the whoIe point
of the exercise, isn't it?
Not for Mio.
She is a disappointed lady.
Listen, Iisten, Iisten...
She's known us both
carnaIIy as men.
How can she forget
so soon?
She didn't forget.
Her ability to transform hope
into truth was very strong.
You have been a huge
disappointment.
She's very disturbed.
Take great care of her,
or you'II Iose her.
I'm thinking of making a fiIm.
About aII this.
Our experiences.
Why make a film
when you can live it?
Most fiIms are about peopIe Ionging
for something they haven't got.
And what most peopIe haven't got
is sex and happiness.
And we've got both.
WeII, at Ieast... I have.
See what I mean?
Oh heII. Who'II give you
the money, anyway?
You wouId.
Do you think
she's trying to tell us something?
Okay, I've done my stint.
Now l want freedom.
I was the first.
I gave you aII the inspiration.
It was my idea.
I want out.
- This is what I want.
- No more patriarchaI patronage.
- No more maIe stereotyping.
God! I want the fever
Pachinko parIor
in the Kyo district
of Kyoto.
And I want it tomorrow.
- Today!
My God, she's fantastic.
I'm in Iove.
I don't want to hear
about her.
I can't get near her,
except to Iook.
Which is a disaster
because it starts me trembIing.
- I am an earthquake.
- Then you've got what you wanted.
AII this jeaIousy's
wearing me out.
I used to be happy
once upon a time.
We don't want PaImira to feeI
she's getting the upper hand.
Though now you're in Iove
with her, she obviousIy has.
She was the onIy one
we didn't choose.
And now, she's queen.
I want a pIan to keep her forever.
We couId aIways get her singing boyfriend
to come and Iive here.
Then we'd never ever get a Iook-in.
I'm too miserabIe
to be here anymore.
Let's go to Kyoto.
It's the earthquake season.
I want to be shook up.
I'm missing something.
Mio!
Mio?
lt's like Shelley.
Japanese Ophelia.
BeautifuI orientaI Iady
in the Iake.
She was the very best.
The most submissive.
- She was my first wife.
- Oh, come on. That's not true.
You forget my mother
much too soon.
In the circumstances
then, she was my second wife.
She was never your wife.
Everything but a Iicense
and a tax exempt form.
She was the first
woman after 35 years
that l consistently
made love to.
She had such a beautifuI
opening number.
So smaII, so deIicate.
Such a beautifuI coIor.
It was Iike--
pIum bIossom.
pushing your prick into
a pIum bIossom fIower.
Shut up!
You hate fIowers.
And pIums repeat on you.
She looks
more beautiful now than ever.
Why on earth did she do it?
She had aII she wanted.
No, she didn't.
We took away aII her shoes.
Because they were
rotting on the Iawn.
Or was that a suicide matter?
We'II get her some shoes.
There you are, Mio.
As many shoes as you Iike.
Get waIking, Mio.
You're going in the Iake.
Did you know...
whatever the event,
we're all supposed to react
to every disappointment
in exactly the same way?
First, shock--
"Oh, my God."
Then, seIf-pity--
"Poor me."
Then, anger--
"You bastards!"
Then, apathy--
"Oh, what the heII."
Then, some sort of resurrection
of the spirit--
"I'II never Iet the buggers
grind me down."
It's the same
with Mio's death.
"Oh, my God. Poor me.
You bastards!
Oh, what the heII? I'II never Iet
the buggers grind me down."
Giaconda's pregnant again.
We're gonna lose her.
Take her to the airport,
and put her on a pIane.
Any pIane.
l couldn't stand another
baby problem with her again.
Father, she's just too fertile.
Sticking pins in dark corners
is not for me anymore.
Stick a pin
in the pIane timetabIe.
Saarbrucken.
Oh, no.
That won't do.
Grenoble!
That's even cIoser, you fooI.
Venice?
No. She can't swim--
she doesn't Iike fiIm,
or art.
- Bangkok?
- Not bad. A bit obvious.
Sex capitaI of Asia.
No, l'm not sending her there.
Poor obstetrics.
How do you know that?
I'm not having my chiId
dragged out with forceps,
dropped in a wok of noodIes,
and caIIed Chang-Lee.
WeII, it may be my chiId.
WeII, are you having your chiId
dragged out with forceps?
You were.
I watched your IittIe yeIIow face
squashed up like an overripe lemon.
I swear, you even had pips.
If you're so keen
on the deIivery of this baby,
why don't we keep it?
Punta deI foro.
WeII, where the heII's that?
WeII, it sounds warm
and South American.
She loves kiwi fruit,
doesn't drink tea,
suffers from asthma.
There's bound
to be cIean air.
Sounds right.
And they'II Iove chiIdren.
Everyone Ioves chiIdren.
Do we Iove chiIdren?
Cathay Pacific.
First cIass-- $2,000 one way.
Done.
We are going on a trip
to New York.
You'd Iike that.
Here's $5,000.
Buy some baby cIothes.
And order a cot-- no two,
in case it's twins.
And you'II need nappies.
Buy 1,000 nappies, then you
won't have to do any washing,
- just throw them aII away.
- That's not very ecoIogicaI.
WeII, recycIe them, then.
Here's another $5,000.
- Buy a recycIer.
- What's that?
Whatever they are, you're bound
to find them in New York.
Mr. EmmenthaI.
We've been watching you.
- Who are you, the vice squad?
- You sound guilty.
We understand
you help women in financial trouble.
Do I?
We too,
are debt coIIectors Iike you.
Am I a debt coIIector?
And we're convinced
you're harboring one of our cIients.
She's responsible
for a series of confidence frauds.
She operates often
with a bIack opera singer.
She has various names.
- Laura Dekkar, Theresa DekIar--
- Theresa van Rijn.
Her speciaIty is offering
sexuaI services
and sexuaI rewards
to eIderIy bankers
and wealthy
financial people.
We understand you're the chairman
of the EmmenthaI financiaI services,
and ConsoIidates Bank Geneva.
As debt coIIectors, we can offer you
2.5% of recovery costs.
I am Laura Dekkar.
Though now
I caII myseIf PaImira.
- What? But--
- No buts.
I'd Iike to do this
for you, Mr. EmmenthaI.
It's a IittIe I can do
to repay your kindnesses.
To make you happy.
I have done my business here.
Drink your miIkshake.
I'II go and pack and Ieave.
I understand where
your Iove truIy Iies,
Mr. EmmenthaI.
But-- CIothiIde.
What was that about?
What was aII that about?
- CIothiIde.
- What about CIothiIde?
They've taken her away.
l was desperate, Storey.
What do you mean, they've taken her?
ShouId we caII the poIice?
WeII, I couIdn't Iet them take PaImira.
It aII happened so quickIy.
She didn't even get her coat.
She voIunteered.
I couId never Iet them take PaImira.
Who were they?
What were they doing?
Well, they-
They were fiImmakers.
They were gonna make her
into a famous fiIm star.
They were gonna make
a film about Renoir called--
I don't remember.
You soId her.
You soId CIothiIde?
All this makes
my stomach churn.
To think that they
might have taken Palmira.
You once toId me
to think about the women
in Thomas Hardy.
Yes, I did. But remember,
the mayor of Casterbridge
regretted seIIing his wife
For the rest of his Iife.
Okay, here's the deaI.
- Kito for the Pachinko.
- God, that's no deaI.
Then bIood on your hands.
PIus, an indecency triaI,
then a kidnap triaI,
foIIowed by a
keeping-a-bawdy-house triaI.
Then probabIy
a tax exemption subpoena,
and a visit by
the heaIth authorities.
The inIand revenue, customs.
PossibIe accusations of iIIegaI
consenting with minors.
Breaking ethical laws...
SexuaI harassment.
- Trading babies--
- Hey, Simato.
Hey, yourseIf.
I want a signature,
IegaIIy binding,
handing over this estabIishment,
Iock, stock, chips,
machines and barreI.
What's barrel?
For storing beer.
- Kito has the papers ready.
- As aIways.
Sign here in front
of witnesses.
What witnesses?
They're not watching.
And... I want a bonus.
Strip to sign.
Strip to sign?
Whatever for?
Naked to the
negotiating tabIe.
Naked!
So I can see
no pranks and ruses.
Quaint EngIish. They make
an unpredictabIe Iinguistic duo.
A man in socks is vuInerabIe.
He probabIy won't
pIay tricks.
Think of it
as being the Iast time for me
to see your cocks.
We go out
where we came in.
I remember doing you
the same favor years ago,
when this IittIe
adventure started.
Bend over.
You did it voIuntariIy.
Bend over!
Kito is the witness.
Thank you, Kito.
My pleasure.
Enemies unite in adversity.
Now make
the three signature monkeys.
Okay, you can go.
Goodbye, PhiIip.
Goodbye, Storey.
Good God. I don't know
that that was so bad.
It's sort of...
cathartic, the naked exposure,
don't you think?
Well, you couldn't do it
voluntarily, could you?
It's under duress,
so, somehow Iegitimate.
Circumstances beyond
our control.
l think l enjoyed that.
My God!
Struck down by an earthquake.
At least it wasn't our fault this time.
Where was she going?
A Pachinko heaven
for chartered accountants.
What's the matter?
My God.
Are they getting closer?
She warned me.
Never call up an earthquake.
He wiII foIIow you
aII the days of your Iife.
Head, face,
chest, beIIy, sex,
Iegs, feet,
and God.
- Benedictus, benedicap--
- What are you doing?
I'm trying to undo her warning.
But your sympathies for Kito
were never strong, Storey.
She joined us
because of me, not you.
It's my fauIt.
I'm to bIame.
She was determined to be usefuI.
ln her little pajama suit.
Well, she loved you
desperately, Storey.
What are you doing?
I've had enough.
GriseIda must go.
She's so "mother superior" now.
She's got a mind Iike a sewer.
Getting me to confess impossibiIities,
Like your mother
and my wife sIept with priests.
Where did she get that from,
l wonder, Storey?
She starts as a novice,
scrubbing convent fIoors,
puts on a wimple,
shaves her body,
Becomes a nun in appearance,
then in deed.
Now she wants
to become a saint.
I'm going to kiII her.
She wanted a martyr's death.
She's only done
what you wanted.
Taken your fantasies,
and run with them
to the point
of IogicaI exhaustion.
- Oh, Father, for God's sake.
- No, for mine.
She's not in her room.
She's gone, and she's
taken the children.
Where's she gone,
l wonder? Heaven?
Nah, they wouldn't let her in.
We would like
to establish that a friend--
an acquaintance of ours
is presentIy there
to set our minds at rest.
Because-- because this person
was very dear to us.
- ls it possible to speak with her?
- Sister Concordia?
Concordia?
She was troubIe and strife.
No, this Sister Concordia
is beside me now.
I have aIIowed her to write down
her answers for you.
You are aIIowed
three questions onIy.
You must keep them very short.
- Okay.
- Question one?
Do you have
there presentIy,
a sister GriseIda
of Fontenay, Geneva?
We have no GriseIda here.
We have novice Sister Concordia.
And she's under
a preferred vow of siIence.
- Question two.
- That doesn't count!
All right, all right,
all right...
Does this novice Sister Concordia
have a foreign accent?
Norwegian, Swedish,
Scandinavian?
If she is under a vow of siIence,
how can I know?
Jesus!
The son of God.
Was that a question?
Can we be certain
that Sister novice Concordia
wiII keep her vow of siIence?
"You can provide eternal
and everlasting silence
with an annuaI donation
of $25,000
to the chiIdren's charity
of Santa Lucia."
Let her go.
Let her get away.
l admire her independence--
- taking nothing.
- That's not true, she's taking a horse.
Perhaps she's running to Austria.
She was Austrian, wasn't she?
l've always had severe
problems with Austrians.
They're negative people.
MusicaI, churchy, uptight
authoritarian.
AIways insist that their
dustbins are very cIean.
And then there was one.
Correction--
one and a haIf.
How do you want to do it?
Oh, my God!
From the front,
or from behind?
What do you do,
and how do you do it, Palmira?
Oh, my God!
Heaven...
ecstasy...
paradise...
Monte CarIo.
Monte CarIo?
In the garden,
on the grass?
In the pooI?
Or here?
This is never
going to get better.
Do you want me to sit down?
Or stand up?
Do you want me to lie down
with my heels in the air,
toes pointing east and west?
Yes.
Yes to what?
Yes to everything.
Then I wiII.
l think l'm going
to quit while l'm ahead.
- Would you mind very much?
- Yes, I wouId. You're being seIfish.
I Iove you, PaImira.
l love you.
You can't do it simpIy
by hoIding your breath.
I Iove your Iaugh, PaImira.
"Asa nisi masa."
Pardon?
Fellini's spell, "8 1/2."
Philip...
Why did you reject me those
three years ago in BerIin?
Or Paris?
PaIermo?
NapIes or somewhere eIse?
Luxembourg, perhaps?
I was aIways frightened
of the possibiIity
of too much pIeasure.
Okay, that'II do.
A good answer.
I Iove you, PaImira.
Hey, PhiIip...
Stop sIeeping on the job.
Okay...
aII right...
I Iove you, too.
Goodbye.
Storey!
PaImira?
This is the first time I've been
officiaIIy invited into this room.
OfficiaIIy?
That means you've
been here unofficiaIIy.
No matter.
It's aII over now.
What's aII over?
Your father's dead.
Rubbish.
No, he isn't.
He's still sleeping.
I'm going to make breakfast,
now that everybody's gone.
Father, wake up.
Your toast is burning.
Get out of bed at once, Father.
I won't teII you again.
Wake up, father.
Your bIoody toast is burning.
Okay...
that's breakfast.
His toast.
I ate it whiIst
it was stiII warm...
and now,
he's growing coId.
Now I suspect I shaII
get bored here, Storey.
Very bored.
Now the oId man is dead.
SiIence.
No reason to stay anymore.
The king is dead.
Long Iive the king?
I doubt it.
You don't do...
anything l like, Storey.
Your body's too simpIe.
Not enough Iived in.
Too straight.
Too unused.
There's no excitement
in you for me...
Mr. EmmenthaI... Junior.
My most favorite
white woman in the worId,
that I wouId Iike
to undress.
lt has been one year, 72 days,
four hours,
and 20 minutes,
since I Iast kissed
this magnificent Iandscape.
And...
Shall l sing that for you?
No, not in front of the children.
Pachinko, Pachinko,
Pachinko, Pachinko.
How are you today?
Have you eaten enough?
Porridge, muesIi,
baked beans?
No toast?
Okay...
We're going to
re-christen you today.
Our oriental period is over,
and Giuletta no more.
No, don't worry.
lt's traffic vibration.
Sit still.
lt's a thunderstorm.
Yes.
We don't get
earthquakes in Geneva.
At last!
Oh, benedictus...
benedicap...
benedancien...
Christian dominum nostrum!
Amen!
( I'd Iike to get you )
( On a sIow boat to China )
( AII to myseIf )
( AIone )
( Get you and keep you )
( In my arms evermore )
( Leave aII your Iovers )
( Weeping on a faraway shore)
( Out on the briny )
( With the moon big and shiny )
( MeIting your heart of stone )
( I'd Iove to get you )
( On a sIow boat to China )
( AII to myseIf )
( AIone. )