Your Majesty.
Papa,
we've made you breakfast.
Only Francoise is too little
to carry the tray,
so we have
Philippe to help.
Yes, Uncle.
I am the strongest.
I could carry it.
My queen.
Good morning, Majesty.
Be it known
that we intend to hold court
at the Palace of Versailles
within the coming month of May.
Clap.
Do you see how important it is to
elicit the appropriate response?
Yes.
To this auspicious end,
the finest examples of humanity
shall embody
the true glory of France
in a palace of eternal
and resounding splendor.
Take note.
Your eloquence they must love,
your demeanor they must fear.
I have further commanded
that the greatest masters of
France will realize this vision
unparalleled in
the history of the world
in gardens of exquisite
and matchless beauty.
Heaven
shall be here.
The light is fading, master.
Torches!
Madame?
Is it?
A week tomorrow at 11:00.
Don't forget about the length.
If you stand on the hem,
you'll rip it at the waist.
It's pinching me here.
Thank you.
Master Le Notre,
I am delighted to
make your acquaintance.
I've long been
an admirer of your work.
Le Notre?
Too clever by half,
if you ask me.
And riding
on his father's name.
The strategy I employ
is to imitate.
They cannot resist flattery.
'Tis all vanity
to these bigwigs.
Of course, once you're in,
you must have the talent.
Speaking of vanity,
there's a hat,
now, gentlemen.
Who is this person?
That's  Madame de Barra.
I'm astounded by that.
Monsieur Mauve's plans.
How many more candidates,
Claude?
Three more,
monsieur, after this one,
but the end is in sight.
Dullness or disrespect,
that is my apparent choice.
If the king's demands
were not so vast,
I would build
the gardens myself.
Indeed, master.
And in the meantime...
Monsieur Mauve.
Madame de Barra.
Monsieur Duras.
That a new coat?
The wife's idea.
Be covered in mud
by Tuesday,
but by then she thinks
we'll have this job,
so the coat will have been
a worthwhile extravagance.
Sound reasoning.
Gentlemen,
I've not had the pleasure.
Jean Risse
and Daniel Le Vielle,
Madame Sabine de Barra.
You're all here
for the interview?
We are, and you?
The same.
Been in Paris long,  madame?
Two years.
And you've worked
for someone before that?
I know all the contractors
in the provinces.
All the gentlemen, that is.
There is no gentleman,
monsieur.
I work for myself.
We all to be interviewed
at this time?
We're here early
to spy out
the other candidates.
I've been in already.
Oh, how did you fare?
Spent upwards
of an hour with him.
Very detailed examination
of the work, so, you know,
we shall see.
You must have impressed him.
I worked for his father.
I'm not disheartened.
He seems not disheartened, too.
Madame de Barra.
Well, gentlemen.
Best of fates to you.
Claude Moulin,  madame.
Secretary to Master Le Notre.
Have you met
the master before?
I have not.
Madame.
Sir.
I'm delighted to
make your acquaintance.
I have long been
an admirer of your work.
I am so pleased to attend...
These are your plans,
madame?
Yes. Some are to be
seen around the country.
Others are still in progress,
not yet completed.
However, as required,
there are two sets of plans
to your instructions.
The fifth and sixth,
I believe.
Perhaps at the bottom...
I have examined them.
Ah. So...
May I ask you a question,
madame?
By all means, master.
Are you a believer in order?
Order?
Order over landscape?
Well, I admire it.
Looking at these plans,
there seems to be no trace.
I would not agree.
I think there is
pattern enough
in number six
to suggest absolutely...
Do you believe
in order over landscape?
Order seems to demand
that we look back to
Rome or to the Renaissance.
What I'm saying is,
surely,
isn't there something
uniquely French
as yet not celebrated
by us?
Which needs the rules
of order to attain it.
All of my work
is based on a principle
you choose to deny.
I wonder that
you tender yourself
for a position with
someone you believe
to be outdated.
Sir, I...
I have nothing
but admiration
for the scale of your work.
You were the first
to use such techniques.
I must apologize
for any insult that
I may have unwittingly
offered you.
Perhaps,  madame,
when you have been
in the public eye
and available for ridicule
for as long
as my family has,
you will think again
about this conversation.
Good day to you.
Three minutes,
would you say?
How was the interview?
Well?
Not so well.
You have a preferred
candidate, master?
The king wants to
improve on perfection
and reach for the impossible.
I'm surrounded by barbarians.
No doubt it's death
if I fail him.
Prison, more like.
Get your hands dirty,
see what grows.
That's what your father
would have done.
You once said,
"No man, however grand,
"knows what he wants
until you give it to him."
True.
A gentleman wishes to see you.
Monsieur Le Notre.
Here?
Don't worry, I'll stay.
Come on.
Oh!
Here.
Go on.
Madame will be
with you presently.
My father taught me gardening.
He encouraged me
to see beauty
and re-create it,
not as an exercise,
more as an act of faith.
He told me that
God put us first
into a garden,
and when we lost Eden,
we were fated to search
and reinvent it again,
but only some of us
have the gift
of knowing this.
Only some of us
have that gift.
I spied on you today
before you attended
the interview.
You moved one of my pots.
I did.
I was curious.
I will not take up
too much of your time.
I have been looking
again at your plans.
You did not care for them.
I am none the less for it.
In plain truth,
I am used to it.
I did not say
I did not care
for your plans.
I said I could find
no order in them.
This abundance of chaos,
this is your Eden?
My search for it.
I spoke today of the pressure
of being in the public eye.
I will spare you
any repetition,
but,  madame, in my world,
even anarchy is
by royal command,
and chaos must
adhere to budget.
Good evening.
Later,  messieurs.
Gentlemen.
Welcome to Versailles.
You found your way here
without too much effort,
I hope.
The map you sent
was wonderfully accurate.
I shall need it to
get back out again.
We shall be
traveling about a bit.
Madame de Barra,
Monsieur Sualem
and De Ville.
They are building
the Marly waterworks
and an aqueduct from
there to Versailles,
which we hope
will alleviate the severe
water shortage here.
Madame.
Gentlemen.
Madame de Barra
will be constructing
the Rockwork Grove
here at Versailles.
Water, or rather
the lack of it,
will be a pressing concern.
Master, the king's
ambitions are already...
Are vast and ever changing,
and our task is to meet them.
With respect,
no man can meet
infinite demand.
The king's commands
are not infinite, De Ville.
They are the king's commands.
Well, quite so,
but the aqueduct
can only do so much.
When we began construction,
I was under
the impression that...
The past is history.
Our task is to suppress
nature to our will,
according to the present plans.
But,  monsieur,
the money being spent.
The aqueduct will
carry sufficient water
to the gardens
of Versailles
because it must.
That is your brief.
Madame?
It is essentially your plan,
number six in your
submission, I believe.
This part is entirely
original to myself.
You see?
It fits onto this
end of your plan.
Now you can see
the extent
of the enterprise.
Yes.
It's a large, flat area.
An arena with tiered sides.
Indeed.
The orchestra
will be up here.
Orchestra?
A ballroom.
It's an outdoor ballroom.
There is a pool of builders.
Select whatever
supplies you care to.
Commission
whatever embellishments
you think appropriate.
Time is not unlimited.
Here's the budget.
Try not to exceed it.
Master?
Why me?
These gardens
should be large enough
to embrace voices
other than my own.
Mama!
I'm coming.
Madame de Barra.
Monsieur, forgive me
for disturbing you at home,
but I've been
reworking the plans.
If... If we fill
a reservoir
at the top of the hill,
we would have enough water
to run the fountains
and the building works.
We don't need water
continually if we just
recycle it.
Pressure will force it
back up to the start again.
And there's a river,
here, underground.
May I?
Of course.
Well, thank you,  madame.
I will examine
these in more detail.
I must apologize
if this adds to the turmoil.
I am trained to it.
Like a good plant, I submit.
We waited
an hour for a gaming table.
Montespan and Lauzun
had monopolized them.
Anyway, then came the news
her house was on fire.
We felt sure this would
end her winning streak.
Apparently not.
The marquise played on.
Her children were safe,
what could she do?
She showed wonderful spirit
and was clapped for it.
How does this dress
look on me, Andre?
Andre, are you listening?
You look very well in it.
What are you studying
that's so important?
Some plans.
Versailles.
Are these the drawings
that woman
brought to the house?
They are.
I see.
Button these
gloves for me, Andre.
Blunt instruments.
Perhaps that's what
makes us a good match.
You're creative,
but unable for the more
delicate maneuvers.
Don't forget that, Andre.
I'm the expert.
You're merely the gardener,
however grand.
Without me to promote
your interests, well,
use your famous imagination.
That's more than
enough for one day.
What...
Where are you...
Where are you going?
Luc?
The sight of you, madame.
What time were you up
this morning?
Did you not sleep again?
I don't remember.
You must take more care.
You'll never last
at this rate.
Then what will become of us?
I always
think of something.
Hmm.
Came today.
What does it say?
Anyone you know?
Monsieur Duras.
Need to know your way
around the crews.
Otherwise, you end up
with the wasters.
The lot you had before,
they're cooling their
heels on another site.
Won't bother us again.
Same with
the timber suppliers.
One of your friends
at the interview
recommended them.
Perhaps he hadn't
thought it through.
And you have?
If you fail, we all fail.
Not pretty, I'll grant,
but it's true.
So...
So, I learned
after some inquiries
who had the commissions,
and everybody
had good laborers
coming out their ears
except you.
Thanks to your friends
at the interview.
Some men take
losing harder than others.
I, on the other hand,
have a leviathan for a wife
and am very used to being
on the losing end.
She issued very
precise instructions
which, as I say,
I would never
dare go against.
Instructions?
"Ask her for work."
Well, a man snaps
like a carrot exposed
to the leviathan.
Besides, I have little ones.
They make me proud,
even if I am
humbled elsewhere.
Can I take this off now?
I've been issued
an invitation to the Louvre.
Gracious me.
Supper, too, I expect.
Very nice.
Will there be others there?
Versailles shall be
the heart of our kingdom,
inhabited by
the finest examples
of humanity,
fit for the gods
of old to behold
and finding
their echo in gardens
where each new turn
brings another excitement.
Fountains whose gentle flow
is balm enough
to ease a ringing ear.
Scented groves
of orange blossom
blown by temperate winds.
What light,
what beauty, what hope.
Versailles, Versailles,
Versailles.
Oh, pardon me.
I believe this is
the way forward,  madame.
Some cool night air is,
I think,
in order,  madame,
do you not?
Oh.
Thank you.
Your first time
at court,  madame?
Is... Is that where I am?
Where did you imagine
yourself to be?
Well, I don't know.
A reception for
the gardeners of Versailles.
A sort of shed affair?
How exquisite.
A tiara amongst the weeds.
I think I...
I have
underestimated the event
on some level,  monsieur.
Antoine Nompar
de Caumont,
Marquis de Puyguilhem,
Duc de Lauzun.
Antoine.
Sabine de Barra.
Charmed.
Now, let me give you
the grand tour.
What do you
know of us,  madame,
we mice in a trap?
Not a thing,
I'm sorry to say.
Winter, summer,
autumn, spring,
we are here.
We may not leave
without permission
of the king.
Yes, mice in a trap.
A small community,
there's only
about 2,000 of us.
Everybody knows everybody else.
Everybody has worked
their way through the group.
"Worked their way through"?
Fought with,
had an affair with,
that kind of thing.
Marquise de Montespan.
Late, as usual.
She's the king's mistress.
Has at least four
of his children,
but his attention has wandered.
Now there is
a new star rising.
Oh?
Madame de Maintenon.
And she is here?
Devoted to God.
Never attends anything
as frivolous as a party,
unlike some people.
Don't look.
They're talking about us.
Madame de Barra.
You are...
Am I... Am I late?
No.
Early?
What, then?
Here.
One of your gardeners?
Perfect.
I must accompany
the marquise to supper.
I could surrender
my new friend
into your care?
Of course.
Guard her well,  monsieur.
The vultures are circling.
It has been my pleasure.
Madame?
It seems
an extraordinary life.
But you may come and go?
Oh, yes.
I'm out and about.
And now they're all
moving to Versailles.
To a village.
Will you not join them?
I would go slowly mad.
Oh.
Do they think of you
as a vegetable grower
or something?
You show no consideration
for my vanity,  madame.
I'm quite sure
you possess none.
What of you,
Madame Sabine de Barra?
Are you prone?
You remember my hat?
It would be
impossible to forget.
It was
a considerable expense.
And entirely unnecessary.
Nolly!
My dear old cabbage!
Monsieur.
Give me a kiss instantly
or I shall take
grave offense.
What a splendid hat.
Do you think so?
I'm trying it out,
I never wear a hat.
No.
Fear of squashing my wig.
But who's this?
Dear lady,
you are prostrate.
Allow me.
May I present
His Royal Highness Philippe,
Duke of Orleans?
Your Highness,
this is  Madame
Sabine de Barra.
Delighted,  madame.
How is it that
a woman of such
exquisite taste
falls in with a clay
kicker like Andre here?
I must confess to being
a clay kicker myself,
Your Highness.
I am working for
the master at Versailles.
I am unable to picture it.
Do tell us
how it is that you are.
Oh. May I present
Marquis du Vasse?
Master Le Notre,
Madame de Barra.
Delighted.
But the mystery
remains,  madame.
What is a woman of such
restrained sophistication
doing with Nolly here?
I speak
from the opposite end
of the fashion scale.
I don't apologize for it,
I like it about myself.
Answer,  madame.
Stop me talking.
It was the only thing
I knew how to do,
for money.
And you enjoy
your profession?
It stimulates you?
It has seen me
through some very hard times
and allowed me
to be independent.
Dearest!
I simply do as I am told.
Even down to marrying
large German women.
Though, I confess,
I like her better
than my last wife,
who is dead as
a doornail now,
thank God.
Do kiss me, husband.
I am in need of affection.
It is wonderful to have
access to one's spouse.
My dear,
we're being very rude.
Princess Palatine,
Duchess of Orleans,
may I present
Madame de Barra, who...
Nolly, what is
Madame de Barra
engaged to do?
Hold for this, my dear,
it will interest you.
She is to build
a water cascade
at Versailles.
Nothing like it will
exist in the gardens.
How fascinating.
I am a great admirer
of engineering.
Madame, you must promise
to show us.
Perhaps Your Highnesses
would care to take lunch
at the Louveciennes aqueduct?
Is it in the country?
I always disappear
in the country.
But now that we are to move
out to Versailles,
I shall become
a human jellyfish.
A miserable, formless being.
We should love to come,
Master Le Notre.
Everybody should
really attend, I imagine.
Come,  Madame de Barra.
Take a turnabout with me
and tell me of your scheme.
With pleasure, Your Highness.
Well, Nolly,
Madame de Barra has certainly
thrilled my dearest.
Has she thrilled you also?
She's very diverting
and extremely clever
at what she does, I think.
Do you indeed?
I am glad.
Good man.
Macaroon?
Thank you, sire.
My speech went
down well, I thought.
It did.
"The finest
examples of humanity"
certainly enjoyed it.
We may be building with stone,
but I can tell
you it's a feather
compared to the weight
of the state.
My brother tells me
you're inviting
new ideas
into the gardens. Why?
I've been persuaded
to expand my horizons.
Have they been tested?
They are, in my opinion,
appropriate.
Appropriate?
Last year, we had the Nymphs
and Shepherds costume party,
and it was not a bit funny,
all those haggard
faces under flaxen wigs.
We looked ancient.
I want a window
to perfection
so that people can see
the very best of themselves.
We've grown too old
for jokes.
The work will be
original but balanced.
The responsibility
will be mine.
Yes.
It will.
Andre.
I did not see you
there in the gloom.
Did you enjoy your evening?
As much, I imagine,
as you did yours.
You were with that woman.
Clear!
You are reckless,  madame.
Do you know that my husband
and the marquis are lovers?
It has not stopped
us having children,
and he loved them dearly.
In battle,
he's immensely brave.
And he has a good heart.
I am happy with my choice.
Another thing about the country
is the muck.
One encounters it everywhere.
Or beasts making muck.
The country is full of muck.
I sometimes feel
entirely defeated
by life's extremities.
When I come to
a place like this,
gradually, a small
courage takes hold of me
and I feel fitter for things.
Do you feel
that way often?
More so with time.
Your wife does not
accompany you ever?
That is, she does not
come out with you,
other times, besides now?
You're very direct,  madame.
We have an arrangement.
I feel disloyal in
discussing such matters.
You are also married?
No.
My husband died.
I'm sorry.
Today you said
I was reckless,
but to be reckless
is to abandon safety,
but I think
maybe it is safety
that has abandoned me.
What is it?
Nothing.
It...
I would like to walk on.
Of course.
Come.
There's something
you should see.
It's a shrine.
The queen is dead.
So kind.
So quick.
Did you have fun
on your picnic, Andre?
I take it,  madame,
you are unaware of events?
Events?
What do you mean, events?
The queen is dead,  madame.
The queen?
Is dead.
The king could marry again?
But no longer
to your friend,
the marquise, I think.
I feel sorry for Montespan.
Tread carefully,  madame.
More on the wagon!
No, the other one.
I want the seasoned wood.
Seasoned.
Here, pass it here.
Madame de Barra.
Master.
You've made
some progress here.
I have a new foreman.
Monsieur Duras.
We've had to drain the soil
below the fountain.
The ground is waterlogged.
It's a problem
common to the gardens.
Thank you.
Do you sometimes
forget to eat?
This is pâté from
Madame de la Tour.
She feeds the ducks
on seaweed.
It was all she could afford.
Virtue from necessity.
What amuses you?
There was an Irish woman
who died,
and her husband
put on her tombstone,
"Here lies Eleanor Fitzgerald.
"Her virtues
exceeded her failings."
How noble of him.
You think
he showed her that
before she died?
I'd have stuck
an arrow in his eye.
Perhaps he was being truthful.
How is the king?
Shocked, I believe.
Poor little Spanish woman.
Has her head chopped off
and her organs
laid out neatly.
And all her friends,
her maids, everyone,
must gather around the table.
Why would they
chop her head off?
To see what she died of.
You must
attend the funeral,
I suppose?
Well, I should go.
It is I, King  Monsieur.
May I?
Come, then, brother.
If the king does not eat,
France does not eat.
I shall feed France,
and you must put up with it.
I'm not hungry.
I have rose jellies.
Have you lemon?
I wish to go to Marly.
And I wish to be alone.
Try not to bend the tops.
My beauties.
Monsieur de la Quintinie?
Madame Sabine de Barra.
I'm very happy to meet you.
I am directed by the Office
of Buildings of Versailles
to order shrubs,
such as I require,
from your good self.
I have brought with me
a selection of perennials
I thought we might exchange.
Is this the Four Seasons?
Yes, I believe so.
Mmm.
Divine.
Good color, too.
You say you have
a selection of plants?
I had them unloaded
into a little cart,
intending to have
them conveyed here,
but there seems to be
no one about.
I wished to be alone,
I had them sent away.
If you wish to be alone,
I could come back.
No, no, no.
I find you are
the very company
I need today.
Nothing would suit
me better than for me,
the king's gardener,
to take some advice
on perennials.
Allow me,  madame, to assist you.
Hmm.
Most kind,  monsieur.
You are a devoted
pear man, master.
I quite like them,
not overly.
Oh...
I think the master is
playing a trick on me.
A trick?
Well, yes, I do know
of your book on pears.
My book on pears?
Oh, yes, I have written
a book on pears.
I believe I said
I liked them a lot
in my book.
I believe you did.
And perennials.
You like flowers, master?
Madame de Barra,
I love all flowers
passionately.
However, I am banished
from using as many
as I would like
at Versailles by
the Master Le Notre.
He indulges me in
a few small parterres.
I'd hoped to be able
to convert him
when we took up residence.
However...
Oh!
You're wise to me now,  madame.
May we ignore all that
and continue as before?
Today, I am
Monsieur de la Quintinie.
Indeed.
And you are.
You are
the better for the move
to Versailles, sire?
Very much.
It's good for the children
to be away from the city.
I know it's a crush
for everybody.
I felt, though,
that I should never
get the builders out
unless I moved in.
You are familiar
with builders,
Madame de Barra?
At present, I am
building in your gardens
at Versailles.
Which construction
would that be?
The Rockwork Grove.
I am familiar with it.
I cannot claim it
entirely as my own.
Master Le Notre took
a simple sketch of mine
and made it outstanding, so...
You see my reluctance.
You admire the master,
madame?
He is the most
complete person I know.
You make me lonely
for someone to
describe me thus.
These are your flowers?
My wife died recently.
Did you hear?
I did, sire.
I remember the day
of your marriage.
I hope so,
it cost enough.
Though her father paid
for a large portion.
Astray in his wits,
bless him.
A long bloodline,
never a good thing.
She was an innocent, really.
But she was nice.
And devoted to me.
I found this after she died.
It's just an account
of our lives.
The writing's like a child's.
You see here?
"Today I saved a flower
from His Majesty."
And then the time
and the place.
This little woman's
secret life.
I feel the loss of it.
I should like to
marry again.
This time someone I choose,
not the state.
Has Your Majesty
someone in mind?
I have,
but the lady's very pious.
Most evenings
I stroll over to her rooms,
and we just sit and talk.
But it is
the ease of it I like.
The ease.
Unfortunately,
she is of no birth,
so, you see,
I am at a little impasse.
If you were to be
married to
the lady of your choosing,
would it be necessary
for everyone to know?
If the ceremony
were private,
between the couple,
who would be in a position
to argue the outcome?
They would be foolish
to do so afterwards,
when it was done.
Mmm.
Yes.
So much to contend.
And what of you,
Madame de Barra?
What pulse drives you?
There is someone you love?
I cannot say.
Why?
Because...
Because of something private.
What is so private that it
cannot be shared in love?
The time has come,  madame,
for us both
to face down our past
and live in the present.
I shall write a letter
from one gardener to another,
shall we say,
in return for seeds sown.
It will bring you
to the court,
where my eye
will always be on you.
I shall not forget
our day in the garden,
Madame de Barra.
Are you still fiddling
with your bits, Andre?
It helps me think.
For you.
It has the fleur-de-lis.
Is it from the king,
I wonder?
Is it an invitation?
There is something
you need,  madame?
Andre? So secret?
I must inform you,
since you ask,
that I leave
for Fontainebleau
at the end of the week.
Fontainebleau?
I was not aware
there were activities.
The marquise
must have forgotten.
I will travel there alone.
Plainly,  madame,
that is the position.
If you will excuse me.
Madame de Barra.
Is she an aspect
of your life
I must now include?
Andre, a builder?
I'm a builder,  madame.
You are funded
by that profession.
Very amusing.
Perhaps that is the fantasy
between you and she.
So be it.
However, I must request that
you keep it
separate from our lives.
If this liaison
became common knowledge,
it would make me
a laughingstock.
It makes my flesh crawl.
I remind you,  madame,
that it was you who
embarked on this path.
You and only you
dictated how we live now,
and you did it,  madame,
when I needed you most.
Andre.
I feel us at the edge
of something here.
I'm trying to pull us back.
You knew the damage
you inflicted,
but you have been free
to live your life
as you wished
without embarrassment from me.
I ask you now
to extend me
the same courtesy.
Andre, you must make
the sensible choice here.
Do not exclude me,
I beg you.
I begged you once.
Do you remember?
Allow me to give you
the same advice
you gave me then.
You said,
"It is a matter
of feeling special.
"If we are unable,
one, to make
the other feel special,
"we must just accept it,
"seek comfort elsewhere
"with others.
"It is an honest contract,
my dear.
"You'll grow used to it."
That is what you said.
What's the root ball like?
It's a bit dry.
Soak them overnight.
You may not need to.
Just secure them, then.
We should cover these tiers.
I need more rope.
I need more food.
In the warm.
You go on, I'll follow.
Madame de Barra.
My name is Le Notre.
Madame.
Did you ever see someone
and know that they were to
play a role in your life?
You're a widow, I believe.
How lonely that must be.
I've known for some time
that Andre had
some secret happiness,
but my husband's ambitions
are married only to mine.
You're not
the first diversion,
and I believe at the moment,
not the only one.
You will come
and you will go.
Understand me,  madame.
It suits my
husband and I this way.
Pretty thing.
We found
the sluice gate that connects
the reservoir to the fountain.
If we fill it,
the pressure in
the pipes will build,
and we can flood the grove.
Do it.
Later.
Use the wood
to hold it down!
The sluice gate
must be open!
We need more hands!
Then pray.
To hell with that.
Thank you.
Will it mend?
It will mend.
The tiers were too weak.
The gate was left open.
You cannot be blamed
for that, or the storm.
What should I do?
Adapt.
Like a well-trained plant?
Like a well-trained plant.
Am I part
of an amusement for you?
Not at all.
I'm unused to all this.
Is it honest?
Are you?
No.
I have not been honest
since I watched you
in my garden.
Your heart beats fiercely.
Mine just ticks.
I have not gifts
to offer such a wonder.
If you are hungry,
I'll feed you.
If I am mad,
you will tell me.
You are not mad.
You don't know all of me yet.
Are you hungry?
Starving.
Are you not happy?
Yes.
That's what is making me cry.
I can't.
Don't ask me.
- What am I to say?
- "It is original"?
"Continue indefinitely"?
Do you expect that of us?
You've been working
with  Madame de Barra.
Are you committed
to this design?
If I may say,
Your Majesty,
I was just
as skeptical as you are
in the beginning, like.
But now?
I'm a convert,
so to speak,
Your Majesty.
Even now, the setbacks
were due to nature, sire.
Perfection does
not bow to nature.
What on earth
are those things?
Well, sire,
I'm glad you asked me that,
because that, really,
is what  Madame de Barra is.
Odd, sire.
May I show Your Majesty?
You will recall what I said
about Nymphs and Shepherds.
As we age,
we see things more clearly.
This project,
is it worthy of us?
There's no precedent
for  Madame de Barra's vision.
Trust is all we can give
to those who reach
into the new, sire.
But when beauty
can be described
with such imagination,
then her art,
above all I know,
is worthy of the king.
I see only mud.
Your words
we will weigh later.
For now,
inform  Madame de Barra
that I shall see her
at Fontainebleau.
I do not know
what story this tells
or what harm it is part of.
This is a bad end
for both of us,
and I am sorry for it.
Welcome to Fontainebleau.
Antoine.
How beautiful you look.
I believe it is compulsory.
Indeed.
However, some of the ladies
find it more of a challenge.
I am bound to say,
I see no trace of
that challenge in you.
Do not talk to me
about it,  madame.
I am ruined by the expense,
and worse,
it is interfering
with my gaming.
I must confess that
escorting you down
is something of a coup.
How so?
There are several parties
who are anxious to meet you.
I am no one.
What could the interest be?
Madame, you answer yourself.
You see how they
look at you?
You are no one
where everybody
is someone,
and yet you are here.
That makes you
more the someone.
Especially if you
have conversation.
Words just tumble.
You see?
People are looking
our way with interest,
because of my mirth.
But the hordes may
not have you yet.
I am under strict instruction
to convey you to one
person in particular.
The Marquise de Montespan.
Heavens, the lengths
I've had to go to,  madame.
I have had to bribe, lie
and use every form of
deception to meet you.
How much did you pay
the maître d'hôtel?
Five gold louis.
Was that too much?
Money well spent.
Lauzun, I love you dearly.
Kiss me now and leave me
to explore my prize.
I shall enjoy you later.
Madame.
Good fortune
at the tables.
I feel lucky tonight.
My dearest friend
and a most divine lover.
What can I say,  madame?
Events overtook us before
I had the king's interest.
Is this your first time
at Fontainebleau?
It is.
Have you no birth?
Not a drop.
No blood whatsoever.
You are here entirely
on your own merits.
I know a famous man.
Ah, I see.
I was going to
offer you Lauzun,
but you're
ahead of the game.
Athenais.
Palatine.
And  Madame de Barra.
I'm so happy
to see you again.
Princess.
Oh, please, call me  madame.
It's affectionate,
and everybody does.
Come. My secret space.
Do you dig earth?
Yes.
Yet you're not
blackened by the sun.
Perhaps a little.
And never had the smallpox.
Your skin is clear.
Show us your breasts.
Are they pretty?
Would you like to see mine?
Mine are the most beautiful.
Yes, they are,
apart from Suzanne,
who's 70.
Oh, yes, hers are perfect.
You see, here, touch.
Oh!
Your eyes
are the color of the sea.
This gown is cut differently.
I like it at the waist.
Are you married?
Widowed.
Did you like
your husband?
- Yes.
- Children?
Dead?
A girl.
How old?
Six.
Palatine has
lost her son, too.
He was four.
So little and beautiful.
Charles was one.
I lost Joan and Ann together.
Smallpox.
I lost my husband
and my son
on the battlefield.
They died in
each other's arms.
I'm barely here.
How did they die?
Do you find it
hard to speak of it?
That can happen.
I put everything in a trunk.
All their clothes, shoes,
her toys.
I haven't had the courage
to go in there since.
When you are
strong enough,
my dear,
when you are strong enough.
We're not
allowed to speak of death
at court.
The king does not like it,
but we speak about it
amongst ourselves.
Nobody may ban a child
from its mother's heart.
I commended all my children
into Maintenon's care.
How she has turned on me now.
Saintly old bitch.
It is an amazement
to me a convent
has not claimed her.
Costume's not as lavish.
Oh. The king comes.
Have you been presented before?
No.
Your Majesty,
it is my pleasure
to present Madame de Barra.
Madame.
Your Majesty.
Is it a Four Seasons?
It is, sire.
For the most famous
gardener in the world.
Allow me,
Your Majesty.
A light, honest scent.
Natural and unforced.
Some of the roses seem faded
and overblown.
That fate awaits
all roses, sire.
Continue,  madame.
All roses are open
to the elements,
Your Majesty.
They bud, bloom and fade.
Is that so,  madame?
The rose grows entirely unaware,
changing naturally
from one state to another,
and although the elements
may treat her cruelly,
she knows nothing of it
and continues to her end
without judgment on her beauty.
Alas,
'tis not the same for us.
If such a rose could speak,
what would she say?
Yes, I am here
and gave service
under nature's eye,
and after me,
my children will be.
Is there any
greater contribution
or more graceful end?
A wise rose.
And what protection
can the gardener
afford this rose
from the harsh
elements of change?
Patience, care
and a little warmth
from the sun
are our best hope,
Your Majesty.
I'm obliged to you,  madame,
for that sweet reminder.
Now walk with me.
And tell me of
your progress in our garden.
Her kindness,
unbribed.
That was very brave tonight.
I hoped he might listen.
Enough humility.
There you are.
Philippe.
You're dressed.
I'm off on business to Chartres.
Thought I would
take Marie-Claire.
There's a good puppet
stand and a pie shop.
Marie-Claire!
Are you there?
Papa! Did you find her?
Here is Belle Boobie
asleep with Mama.
Hello, Marie-Claire.
You naughty doll!
Come here and I
shall punish you.
Oh, my goodness.
Is she all right?
Don't be silly.
She's made of cloth.
Sabine, I have
something to tell you.
How long?
We've not been close of late.
And most men take
mistresses in due course
in such circumstances.
Such circumstances?
What's her name?
Diane.
Where does she live?
Berry.
Oh.
Not too far.
There's the coach now.
We'll talk again
on this matter.
When will you be back?
This evening,  madame.
Do not  "madame" me, Philippe.
Marie-Claire, tie your laces.
You'll fall over them.
I can't, Mama.
Wait there.
Master, look at this.
Marie-Claire.
Jean, the wheel.
I told the master.
He said it would
do until Berry.
Berry?
Marie-Claire!
I did not kiss Mama.
Stop! Stop!
No, no!
No! No!
Sabine!
She was the most
beautiful thing I ever made,
and I killed her.
Did you intend them to die?
Is that what you planned?
It was...
It was your husband's choice.
He took away the child.
No, it was my fault.
It was my fault.
I let him take her away.
What if no one
person is to blame?
And what use is blame?
It is enough to
have it happen to you.
It is enough to recover from it.
That is as much as we
may ask of ourselves.
That is enough.
What is it that
would help you?
If you held me.
What will happen
to your wife?
This was not
the way we started.
So we must have taught
each other how to behave.
I am to blame for it
as much as she.
She will live her own life.
She knows that now.
And us?
We will shape each other.
This isn't the right way.
Yes, it is.
We're behind that fence.
Oh!
For heaven's sake!
I have to rent this.
Waste of money!
What do you mean?
No one will see us.
The music comes
from the heavens.
Fair winds, Sabine.
Madame is lucky
in her friends.
He loves it.
Do I look very flushed?
No, you look beautiful.
Are you flattering me?
Is that wrong?
Call me  madame again.