Ooh! ln all my years,
never have I seen the streets...
so full of bustle and hustle
and assorted commotion.
Our princess is to wed.
Ohh, wonderful!
And who's the lucky prince?
Not a prince at all.
Just a no-account street rat!
No way! Try it phonetically.
It's Aladdin!
Aw! Some of you don't believe.
In colour!
There's a party here in Agrabah
There's excitement in the air
People pouring in
from near and far
'Cause Jasmine and Aladdin
are gonna have a weddin'
There's a party here in Agrabah
Everybody will be there
So if you're a pauper or a shah
Do somethin' with your hair
You mustn't wear
an outfit that's naughty
A turban that's unravelling
just won't do
No earrings that are
tasteless or gaudy
You're gonna look gorgeous
when I get through
There's a party here in Agrabah
So I'm going to paint the town
If you want to see what colours are
Follow me around
Aladdin's gettin' married and it's
gonna be the wedding of the century
My buddy's gettin' married and
you're gonna see just how much I can do
- You've heard of
your safari bar mitzvahs
- Wow!
- You've all been to a luau sweet 16
- Ahh!
Well, none of them compare
to what this is
The food'll be disgusting
By evening you'll be busting
There's a party here in Agrabah
and it's got us all aglow
If a street rat could've come so far
Maybe I could do it
- Sure, there's nothing to it
- There's a party here in Agrabah
But we're not sure
that we'll go
For although the bride is la-di-dah
The groom is awfully low
And now we take you down
to the palace, where everyone
has celebrated all night long.
Without Jafar and all of his malice
Everybody's happy
What could possibly go wrong?
There's a party here in Agrabah
and we're gonna rob 'em blind
While they're all munching caviar
create a small disturbance
I will sneak up from behind
There's a party here in Agrabah
and the loot is pouring in
I like this wedding stuff so far
Maybe if I'm pleasant
I'll get to keep a present
We've ordered just
a few tasteful flowers
And valets who'll
carefully park for you
The bridesmaids have
been dressing for hours
Girls, you look just lovely
And so grown-up too
There's a party here in Agrabah
Guests are filling up the room
But there's something missing
Yes, aha
Where is the groom
Hello.
Somebody's gonna be late
for his own wedding!
Hold on, Genie.
There's something I need.
I gotcha.
It's a bachelor party, big boy!
- None for you.
You're the designated flyer.
- No.
This is for the wedding.
Well, that's, uh--
that's a nice dagger.
Interesting nuptial accessory.
It's a, uh, a bit sharp.
- It belonged to my father.
- Your father?
You never said a word
about your father.
Oh, I've got to let the caterer know!
Chicken or sea bass?
He's not coming to the wedding.
He died a long time ago.
- Sorry.
- That's okay.
I never knew him.
Maybe if I did,
I'd feel ready for this.
Al, are you getting cold feet?
No, Genie. It's just that...
I-l've always been a street rat,
stealin' what I need to survive,
- runnin' from the guards,
- Uh-huh.
- Iivin' my life alone.
- Ohh.
I'm takin' a big step today
into a new world.
Today's topic: fears
of the future family man.
AI from Agrabah, share with us.
I never had a father to show me
how to raise a family.
No role model.
Get a little deeper.
What do I know about families?
Genie, what if
I'm no good at it?
Ah, if my father were here--
Al, little buddy, if your father were
here, he'd be as proud of you as I am.
I just wish he could see this.
There's a party here in Agrabah
And the party's all for me
Just look, you guys
at where we are
And how our dreams
have come to be
There's a party here in Agrabah
and I can't believe it's true
After all this waiting
here we are
We'll finally get to say
"I do"
I never, ever had a real family
I never, ever had
a real, true friend
Someone who could just
understand me
Hey, come on, Aladdin!
This mush has gotta end!
There's a party here in Agrabah
and it's starting right away
Let's get ya dressed
'cause you're the star
Hey, come on
It's your wedding day
Aladdin's gettin' married
and it's gonna be
The wedding of the century
Amazing how Aladdin
could've come so far
- They're finally getting married!
- Look at all these presents!
We're finally getting married.
- I'm finally gettin' married!
- They're finally gettin' married!
At the party in Agrabah
There's a party in Agrabah
A party goin' on now! Gotta
party! Gotta party! Help me!
I can't stop myself!
Somebody rub the lamp!
Ah, you know I feel it!
That's enough.
Why do you walk in the open
while I suffocate like an animal?
Someone has to keep
a cool head, Sa'luk.
Someone will have no head
if this is another wild goose chase.
The oracle is the real thing.
This time I'm sure.
Hello, and welcome to Lifestyles
of the Rich and Magical.
That's right. We're taking you
to the marriage of the millennium.
And who's this coming
on the lovely stretch camel?
Oh, it's Cleopatra and Caesar,
and they're bringing a salad.
How wonderful!
Oh, look, there's Osiris.
Oh, Osiris!
Osiris, can we have
a word with you?
Oh, no, the crowd is parting.
Who's coming? It's Moses!
- And your name is?
- I'm Thor.
- You're Thor?
- Well, it hurts.
Once again, this whole broadcast
has been brought to you by sand!
It's everywhere. Get used to it.
Come on. Come on.
I can see fine from back here.
Uh-uh. It's Aladdin.
Look, there's one thing
I get sentimental about...
and I'm sittin' on it.
- Huh?
- The loot, monkey. The loot.
Bad news, Al. The boutonnieres
clash with the cummerbunds.
Genie, isn't it
a little late for that?
What? What are you trying
to say? Out with it! What? What?
They're here.
Oh, no!
I'm late, I'm late
for a very important date.
- Your Majesty.
- Your Highness.
Your Majesty.
D-Don't look so solemn, boy.
This is a happy day.
Oh, look. It's a Kodiak moment.
Put that bear outta here.
Ohh! Hmm.
- Wow!
- Oh, yeah!
I never thought
this day would come.
Now I'm afraid that it
has come all too soon.
Oh, Father.
- You distract the guards.
- Part of your plan?
A large part.
It's time.
It's all so magical.
I'm not gonna cry. I'm not.
Oh, sorry.
- Well, we're here.
- Together forever.
Let me be the point man.
I thought the earth wasn't supposed
to move until the honeymoon.
Whoa! Oh, my word!
Stampede!
What is going on here?
Come here, monkey boy!
You were almost Dumbo toe jam.
Oh, they trampled the carpet!
That's a little redundant.
So this isn't a bad day
for you, really, is it?
It is an attack.
Not in this palace!
I think we're gonna have
a little problem with leaks.
It must be here somewhere.
Meet your match, Zorro!
Good birdie.
Polly want a little--
Say "cracker" and I'll
let you have it on principle!
- You have a lot of spirit.
- Ow! Ow! Ow!
And a lot of mouth.
- They fight like demons.
- Worse than demons.
- These are the Forty Thieves.
- Really? I get 39.
Forty.
Where is it?
Ah, at last.
- Can I see your invitation?
- Stay out of my way, boy,
and you won't get hurt!
Fool! You don't stand a chance
against the King of Thieves!
When I get up, I'll bow to you!
Mmm. Huh? Ohh!
That was for ruining my wedding.
Huh? Aah!
I guess there's really
no point to this now.
Freeze, sandbags!
Don't make me use the other end!
Mama always said,
"Magic is as magic does."
Cassim said nothing about
facing the powers of a genie.
Get the others out of here.
We'll leave the "king" to his plans.
Where's the King of Thieves?
I'll see you again, boy.
Ooh! This is not my fault.
This was not built to code.
Good luck gettin' back
the catering deposit.
- Oh, my!
- Fear not, O father of the bride.
- We can rebuild!
- Oh, please do.
We can't have a wedding
without a pavilion.
All right, a wedding pavilion
it is, my man.
Hey, I wanna see some resumés
on these guys.
And don't let the one with
the beak near any power tool.
Uh, yes, yes, Genie,
whatever it takes.
I am sorry about
all this, Jasmine.
Daughter?
What were they after, the gifts?
Not all the gifts. This is what
the King of Thieves wanted.
With all the other great stuff,
why go for this thing?
Your question is mine to answer.
The King of Thieves sought my sight
to find the ultimate treasure.
- Did someone say "treasure"?
- Genie?
Oh, it looks like an oracle.
I see all that has been
and all that will be.
Uh-oh. Uh-oh. Definitely an
oracle. Tells the future. Uh-oh.
Girlfriend,
where were you registered?
Okay, you know all,
so tell all.
Where is the treasure?
You know, the ultimate one?
I am bound by the rule of one.
One question, one answer.
I only want one answer!
Where is the ultimate treasure?
You have already asked
your one question.
You mean before?
Oh, that wasn't a question.
That was, uh, thinkin' out loud.
Very loud.
Aladdin, we could learn anything
about our lives, our future.
You have but to ask.
I know what my future is.
My future is you.
But my past is a blank.
My mother died when I was just a kid,
and I never even knew my father.
I have no idea
where I come from.
Your question is your choice,
but remember the rule of one.
Choose carefully.
Oh, sure, she warns him about
the one question thing. Hey!
I don't think you can help me.
My past isn't just one question;
it's a million questions.
Ah, but mere questions about your past
can be answered by your father.
My father?
My father is alive?
Abu? Where's Aladdin?
How long has he been up there?
Aladdin?
Are you all right?
- What's wrong?
- I always wanted to know
about my father,
but just now I'm not so sure.
What kind of man leaves his son?
Did he even care?
- Maybe I don't want to know.
- Yes, you do.
How can you be so sure?
Because I already know him.
Because I know you.
You showed me the world
When I was all locked up inside
You reached out your hand
And took me on
a magic carpet ride
One look at your smile
And I could see the light
Shining everywhere
People like you
don't come out of thin air
Oh, Jasmine.
You don't understand
There is so much
that you don't see
Just think if you can
What growing up
had to be like for me
Your father's a man
Who taught you who you are
Mine was never there
So how can you say
I don't come out of thin air
There's so much I want to know
You've got the chance to learn
If it means I'd have to go
I'll be right here
when you return
- Our wedding can wait
- I love you
- I think it's worth this small delay
- Maybe you're right
And won't it be great
To have your father see
our wedding day
- I've waited so long
to learn the truth
- It isn't too late
And now at last
we can finally say
Your father is really there
There's so much
that we might share
And you'll finally learn
- You don't come out of thin air
- Don't come out of thin air
- Have you chosen your question?
- I have.
Then ask.
Where is my father?
Follow the trail
of the Forty Thieves.
Your father is trapped
within their world.
The Forty Thieves? ls he hurt?
How long has he been their prisoner?
I'm sorry. I can only
answer one question.
- It's up to me.
- Take as long as you need.
I'll be back in time
for our wedding. I promise.
I should've stayed
with the genie.
Manual labour beats danger
any day.
Good. The trail's still fresh.
- Hyah! Hyah!
- Hyah!
- There.
Definitely should've
stayed with the genie.
Shh.
Whew. Well, they have
nowhere to go.
- We got 'em trapped.
- We?
They are 40 thieves.
We are you, a rug,
a monkey and me.
- Wait, don't count me.
- They're just standing there.
Open sesame!
Hyah!
- Let's move!
- Oh, oh! Aah!
- Whoa!
- Hang on!
I know, Carpet.
It's incredible. Wha--
How bad is it?
Yeow!
Oh, this is attractive.
Come on.
Hey!
You wanna not hold up traffic?
I wanna get in, get out
and go home.
Actually, I wouldn't mind
skipping right to the "go home."
- We could've had all of
the loot at the wedding,
- Shh!
but we followed the King's plan.
This is what we have to show
for our trouble in Agrabah.
- Nothing!
- Yeah! I agree.
- This oughta be good.
- Sa'luk is truly ticked.
Your time draws
to a close, Cassim.
Cassim? My father.
If you're talking about
spilling my blood, well, I
just don't see that happening.
Then let me open your eyes.
- Huh?
- Run! I've got him.
I'm Aladdin. You're my father!
His father?
I don't know
about your father, boy,
but I'll send you to meet
your other ancestors.
Let him go. The boy is my son.
I gave this dagger
to my wife years ago.
I told her to give it
to our newborn son, Aladdin.
It's true?
Oh, the boy is the son
of the King of Thieves.
You are the King of Thieves?
Like it or not, boy,
we are blood.
Look at you. I thought
I'd never see you again.
Has it been so long?
Blood or mud,
the boy is an intruder,
and we have rules
about intruders.
- Sa'luk is right.
- He knows our secrets.
- I hate intruders.
- Hey, me too.
He has found our secret lair.
He has seen too much.
He must die.
Yes!
- They must all die.
- Die?
He's your son. I'm his friend.
Cast a vote for mercy here!
Yes, Cassim, mercy
would be so like you.
Soft and weak.
- Maybe Sa'luk should be king.
- Yes, yes, he should be.
- Kill him.
- Huh?
Or the boy could--
Yes, the boy could-- No.
- What? What? Th-The boy could what?
- Speak.
- Nothing. Probably a bad idea.
- Let's hear it!
- No, no, no!
Well, it seems to me that--
Oh, never mind.
- What?
- Oh, no, please!
The boy could face
the challenge.
- Ahh!
- Oh, that's right, the challenge!
That's that. My son
shall face the challenge.
And I shall be the one
to test him.
- Yeah!
- A test, huh? Ah, that's not so bad.
Maybe it'll be multiple choice.
Escape? Not likely.
Our ride home is grounded,
and Al-- well, it's been
nice knowin' him.
- What's going on, Dad?
- Oh, the challenge is simple enough.
Only one man survives.
But you're my son.
You'll be that man.
Knock him dead, kid. Seriously.
No!
I thought our side won!
- Look, l-- I-l didn't mean--
- Get him!
Take him to the King.
Look, I don't even
know him, okay?
You killed Sa'luk. The code of the Forty
Thieves is very clear on this point.
- You're in.
- Hooray! Hooray!
- Congratulations, bub
- You've joined the club
And everybody here agrees
We got the finest blend
of nearly-honest men
Welcome to the Forty Thieves
A fraternity of thugs
that you can trust
There's nothing up
our 80 sleeves
- Got lots of grub to share
- Pull up an easy chair
Welcome to the Forty Thieves
Now you get to lie and cheat
Never have to brush your teeth
But we always aim to please
- Care for one another
- You'll never miss your mother
Oh, I love you guys.
Schemin' up a scam
out on the lam
Takin' whatever we please
- And if you like to lurk
- You're gonna love this work
Welcome to the Forty Thieves
Together we're the perfect team
Larceny is in the genes
Dare to share the family dream
Live a life of leisure
Countin' all your treasure
As an honorary member
of the gang
That no one alive ever leaves
- You gotta snatch and sneak
- Or else your future's bleak
We got a lifetime contract
that you're bound to keep
You wanna save your skin
You'd better fit right in
Well, well, welcome to the--
Forty
Thieves
Boy. And I thought I was blue.
You would know if Aladdin
is in trouble, wouldn't you?
I thought he'd be back by now.
AI will be back.
Listen to Genie, dear.
Genie knows.
You've got to get your mind off
this incessant waiting.
Here's a sure-fire way to cheer
up a bummed-out bride-to-be.
A heaping helping
of matrimonial magic.
Hey, that's-a no good.
What the wedding needs is a theme.
- It needs a groom too, but
let's work with what we have.
- Genie!
It's a joke. I do that.
Okay, let's see. This'll
be the second wedding for both of you.
I'm thinking we need something
a little more simple, a little
more elegant and less grey.
Did it, done it, own it.
I'm gonna throw some colours
at ya-- mauve, teal and salmon.
What do you like besides
the salmon? Okay, Madonna!
Don't keep it. Just put that
in the mix. Wink. Okay.
I see lasers! It's a miracle!
He believes! He believes!
- Thank you very much.
- I don't think so.
Tres gauche, right?
Hmm, maybe you--
you could elope.
No, you "cantaloupe."
But oh, "honeydew"!
I don't know whether to
put it under props or produce.
Please don't squeeze the tyres. They're
not ripe. And how about that gown?
Whether you're dancing with dwarfs
or simply biting the apple,
it says,
"I'm a princess for now."
- Uh, Genie.
- Hey, it's synergy.
The marketing guys are very
excited. It tests really well.
Thank you, Genie.
I'm sure it will be wonderful.
And thanks for cheering me up.
I'm sure Ali Baba and the boy
are on the road to Agrabah right
now. Isn't that right, Bob?
That's right, Bing. How 'bout
this town? ls it wild or what?
It's like one giant sand trap,
and me without my wedgie.
Hey, let's give a big hand
for Brooke Shields.
I find my son
and lose my enemy.
You did your old man proud,
Aladdin.
- I was just trying to stay alive.
- Huh!
If you didn't fight,
you would've been killed.
So says the code
of the Forty Thieves.
Does this code have any rules
that don't end in death?
It's a strict code.
But there is one thing that I added.
We never hurt the innocent.
Uh, for future reference,
I'm as innocent
as the day I was hatched.
Oh, brother!
My men don't even know
about this place.
Listen, boy,
there is a treasure,
the ultimate treasure.
Compared to this, a pharaoh's
tomb is a pauper's grave,
a sultan's fortune
nothing but lunch money.
And I am this close to it.
That's tantalizingly close.
But it's on an island that is
never in the same place twice.
- The Vanishing lsle.
- That would be a problem.
- What is this ultimate treasure?
- The big one, boy.
The Hand of Midas.
- It's just a myth.
- It's not a myth, boy!
It was once right here.
Look, there's your proof.
From stern to stem,
every piece of rigging,
every peg and board,
all of it, solid gold!
Ooh!
Adopt me, daddy-o!
- Touched by the Hand of Midas.
- And sunk by it.
Oh, you don't understand. You don't know
what it's like to have nothing.
To stare up at the palace
and know you deserve more.
To be called "street rat."
Yes, I do.
I knew exactly what I wanted
for my family-- the best.
I couldn't give up
and go back empty-handed.
But the weeks turned into months,
and the months turned into years.
I came back to Agrabah
one night,
but I couldn't find my wife
or my son.
I thought my family
was lost forever.
At that moment, I would've traded
anything to get your mother back.
We never wanted gold.
We wanted you.
I wanted a father. I still do.
Come to my wedding. This time,
you have an invitation.
Aladdin, l-l just don't know.
Dad, I'm not going back
to Agrabah until morning.
At least think about it?
Aladdin may never understand,
but it just wouldn't work.
I don't belong in his world.
The oracle doesn't belong
in his world either.
It belongs in the hands of two
enterprising treasure hunters:
you and me.
The oracle. It's probably
just another dead end.
It works! That's how
the kid found you.
- It knows everything.
- Everything?
And I know where
they stashed it.
Cassim, we are talking about...
the wedding of your only son.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity.
How can I pass it up?
- Captain, over here.
- Show yourself!
You're alone. Good.
So you are the one with information
about the Forty Thieves?
What would you say
if I handed you...
the King of Thieves?
I'd say, "What in it for you?"
I'll just sleep better knowing
that he's off the streets...
and on the executioner's block.
Everyone knows that the King
of Thieves cannot be caught.
What miracle do you possess?
Two words that will make you
Agrabah's greatest hero.
Open sesame.
- Hop on, Dad.
- Oh, no.
It's a rug. You sweep dirt under it.
You don't fly on it. At least I don't.
- Don't be afraid. It's fun.
- I am not afraid!
- Now get off that thing
before you break your neck.
- I trust Carpet with my life.
- Give him time. He'll come around.
- We'll take horses.
Horses were good enough
for my father and his father before him,
and they were always
good enough for me.
- He sounds like a father, all right.
- Uh-huh.
Whoa! This is the spot, men.
- But there is nothing here.
- Now. But watch.
Open caraway!
There is still nothing here.
When I get ahold
of that no good--
But I thought you said
it was "open sesame."
Easy. Whoa. Whoa! Hey, hey!
- Looks like Genie has everything ready.
- Yeah. Uh-huh.
Genie? You have a genie? Have
you used all three wishes yet?
Oh, please, don't go into it.
It's just too painful.
Oh, Al, you're back,
and your front!
- You're both here!
- That's great, Genie. Uh--
- Security's tight.
No big crowd.
Immediate family only.
- Perfect, because this is my--
- No lowlifes this time, other
than the parrot, of course.
Observe.
You have violated the perimeter
of the Aladdin and Jasmine wedding.
Prepare to be vaporized.
Thank you.
Armed and dangerous.
I'd like to see one of those
Forty Thieves get within
an inch of your wedding.
Allow me to introduce--
The King of Thieves.
- All units, we have a code red.
- Code red! Code red!
Code red! Code red!
Code red! Code red! Code red!
Come on, boys. Follow me.
- Cavalry, forward!
- Code red! Code red! Code red!
- Geronimo!
- Arapaho!
- Navajo!
- Pocahontas.
- Code red! Code red! Code red!
- C-C-C-C-C-Code red! C-C-C-C-C--
- Code red!
- Do not attempt to move, or
we'll be shooting ourselves.
- Genie!
- Back off, Al. This creep's got a
yellow sheet as long as my arm.
Genie, meet my dad.
Stand down, men.
Smoke 'em if you got 'em.
If you're Al's dad...
and the King of Thieves,
- I just want to know one thing.
- Yeah?
Will you be having
the chicken or the sea bass?
Come on, Dad. I can't wait
for you to meet Jasmine and the Sultan.
Ahem, Al. Don't you think we oughta
lose the "Agrabah's Most Wanted" Iook?
- What's wrong with the way I look?
- When you're here, you're
not the King of Thieves.
You're my dad.
Mmm, I had more practise
being the King of Thieves.
Oh, come on.
Enough of this dark past.
Let's roll out something
a little new.
It's a big, bright
beautiful future
Thank your lucky stars
you're alive
You got someone special
to talk to
A friend that you
can trust for life
You've been on your own
with no family ties
But those solo days are done
You'll be two of a kind
spending quality time together
As father and son
Building model ships
Takin' fishin' trips
Workin' hand in hand
Painting the palace
Mowin' the sand
First and ten to go,
with your daddy-o!
Once you break the ice
You can postulate
paternal advice
I see you're travelling at the speed of
light. That's the theory of relatives.
It's a fine
"fantabulous" future
I see fruit on the family tree
You'll be great
as a grumpy old grandpa
Bouncin' babies on your knee
You can fall asleep
on the comfy couch
After playin' one-on-one
Dreaming back to back
that you walloped the Shaq
Together as father and son
May be a bumpy ride
We'll make it side by side
Good afternoon.
I'll be your travel guide!
Move over, laddie
Make room for Daddy
Got a whole new shoulder
to cry on
Take a chance now
Give it a spin
You've had chums
for pallin' around with
But you never had
a friend like him
Put your checkered past
behind you now
No more living on the run
Face the big, bright
beautiful future
- Together
As father and son
My boy Aladdin must be born
under a lucky star...
to find such a treasure.
You are most definitely
Aladdin's father.
-And I have the DNA to prove it.
-Oh, it must have been dreadful.
- Trapped by the Forty Thieves.
- Uh-oh.
I try to block out the memories.
Say no more. Not another word
on the subject.
Yes, let's turn our attention
to happier thoughts.
- The blessed union of our children.
- Indeed.
It worked, Genie.
They love him.
It was the hat. Nothing does
the trick like a smart chapeau.
- It's more than that.
- Ah, to be back among
civilized people.
- Back among family.
- All he needed was a second chance.
- It's a miracle.
- You'll pay for this!
- You traitor!
- You sold us out!
- My nose!
- He's not in there!
You didn't capture
the King of Thieves?
Because he was not
at the hideout!
He had to be there.
Where else would he be?
- Uh, apologies, Captain Rasoul.
- What?
Well, the Sultan said
he won't be able to sentence
your prisoners until tomorrow.
What's more important
than sentencing my prisoners?
Why, the wedding. Princess Jasmine and
Aladdin are finally getting married.
Aladdin? You didn't capture
Aladdin with the others?
Why would he be with
the Forty Thieves?
Because his father is
the King of Thieves!
Ooh, where can he be?
Oh, I do hope nothing's wrong.
Perhaps we should dispatch
a search party, hmm?
Now, Father, I'm sure
he's on his way.
- Where is he?
- Hakuna matata.
Whoa! I was having
an out-of-movie experience.
My guess is he wants
to make an entrance.
Here's the monkey's lock picks.
You know how to use 'em?
I promise you, bird,
after this I go straight.
Straight to the dungeon.
We've been expecting you.
Do you think something is wrong?
- Genie, can you find him?
- I'll sniff him out.
I need a scrap of his clothes
or a lock of his hair or a shoe.
A shoe's good.
- Huh?
- Ohh!
- Rasoul, what is the meaning of this?
Your Majesty, meet
the King of Thieves.
- Dad!
- We seized him in the treasury.
- He was after this again.
- No.
And this is his accomplice.
Big misunderstanding!
It's a slap on the wrist and,
uh, community service kind of thing.
Now I know why
you really came back.
Your father is the leader
of the Forty Thieves?
B-B-B-But this is most p--
Aladdin, did you know?
I thought I could change him.
I had to try.
You can change my clothes, Aladdin.
You can't change who I am.
And the law is crystal clear
on what we must now do.
Father, isn't there
another way?
I'm afraid there is not. Take
the prisoners to the dungeon.
- Dungeon?
- For life.
Life?
There are some wishes that
even I can't make come true.
The oracle was right. My dad was trapped
in the world of the Forty Thieves.
Trapped by his own greed. I was
so stupid to think I could change him.
Trying to show him a better life
wasn't stupid, Al.
Leaving him alone with the
parrot, that was stupid.
Everything was perfect
before he came into my life.
I just want things
the way they were.
Genie, I need
my father's clothes.
A-A-A-Al, what, did you
wrap the turban too tight?
Come on! Why you wanna dress
in the King of Thieves ensemble?
Might I suggest something
that doesn't actually say, "Arrest me!"
It fits. Good.
I'm seeing-- I'm seeing nothing
for your future if you dress like this!
I'm breaking my father out
of that dungeon. The guards
will never know I was there.
Tonight the King of Thieves will
make his most miraculous escape ever.
Out of my life!
It's the cape talking, isn't it?
Since he's captured the King of
Thieves, there's no living with Rasoul.
Well, it wasn't exactly easy
living with him before.
- Who?
- I've come to say goodbye.
- Why are you--
- We don't have much time.
While the guards chase me,
you get out.
- I can't let you--
- Forget it.
They can't catch me.
He even sounds like me.
When the Sultan gives me my due,
I'll put the good word in
for you, the little people who--
It can't be.
He was here. I know it.
- The King of Thieves!
- No man could've escaped that cell.
He-- He isn't a man, I say.
He's a demon!
I want him, dead or alive.
Surround the block!
He's close. I can feel it.
- Well, which way did he go?
- I don't see him.
Look over there. Hurry!
There! The King of Thieves
on the roof!
Get up there! Now! Now! Now!
- Found him!
- Lost him.
- Which way did he go?
- I heard him over there.
- Over there!
- There!
Gotcha!
The King of Thieves.
Your charmed life is over,
Your Majesty!
You!
Yes.
Well, I guess I'll have
to settle for the Prince of Thieves.
We shall see if the Sultan
wants you in his family now.
Keep your hands off my son!
- Dad?
- Hurry, son. We must move.
- Did we lose him?
- I don't know, but I did
lose my lunch back there.
They won't be able to pick up
our trail 'til daylight.
By then, we'll be
long gone from Agrabah.
I'm sorry for what you lost.
But you can't go back now.
You know that. What are you doing?
I'm not going with you. I can't.
Well, you can't go back.
The moment they saw your face,
your life in Agrabah was over.
I have to go back.
Jasmine is there.
Kid, it's over.
You're a criminal now.
I won't do what he did.
I won't run away.
- I never ran away
from anything in my life.
- You ran away from your family.
I told you what happened. What else
could I do? What else can you do?
The right thing.
You should take this back.
- You can't!
- I won't walk out on Jasmine.
- Aladdin.
- I'm your son, but I can't
live your life.
Al, they'll lock ya up.
If there's a punishment,
I'll take it.
- So be it.
- We have the oracle!
- The treasure's just waiting for us.
- The oracle?
- I had nothing left to lose.
- Yes, you did.
It was supposed to be
a father-son outing.
- Go with him, lago.
- What?
You mean it? Really?
Go.
Good luck, kid.
From 40 thieves down to 7.
What are we to do?
How did they find us? How did
they learn the magic words?
- Another raid?
- Not again.
It is a good day to die.
Or to come back from the dead.
- Sa'luk?
- You're alive?
- Impossible.
I'm a survivor, like all of you.
No thanks to Cassim.
- The King?
- You saw him?
- What's he want us to do now?
He wants you to rot
in the palace dungeon.
Bah! The King of Thieves
is loyal to the end.
- Pushovers!
- Ouch!
He betrayed you, sold you out.
You have always hated the King.
Why should we believe you?
How do you think the guard
got the magic words?
He told him the magic words?
- I don't believe it.
- Me neither.
You've forgotten what life
was like before Cassim.
I remember a time
when crime was sublime
There was plenty of loot
in the lair
We'd plunder and pillage
and ransack a village
With nary a worry or care
Then along came this king
with his soft-hearted dream
But he ratted us out in the end
So rally the troops
We were meant to regroup
And return to our roots
once again
Are you in or out
Gotta know without a doubt
I'm the one you need
for a dirty deed
I'm the best
Success is guaranteed
Are you men or mice
Take a slice of my advice
You want a fearless leader
One that's strong and stout
Better vote for me
Are you in or out
- We used to be smart
- Yes, horrendously heartless
In a ravaging raid
we were rough
We knew that we had to
be blissfully bad
Then Cassim brought
this sensitive stuff
And we strayed from the path
of our rigorous wrath
- Now we're taking a bath in the dust
- Huh?
But we'll reclaim our winnings
Our humble beginnings
In turmoil and torture we trust
Are you in or out
Double-crossers or devout
Put your faith in me
Pretty soon you'll see
I'm the prince of generosity
Are you foe or friend
Here's the path I recommend
You wanna ride to fame
I've got the fastest route
What's it gonna be
Are you in or out
We'll go robbing
in all the right places
From Agrabah dunes to Paris
Imagine the fear on their faces
When we drop by
for cookies and tea
Come along, boys. Follow me!
Are you in or out
- If you're with me give a shout
- Yeah!
I'll lead you all the way
into the glory days
We'll begin a life of crime
that pays
Are you out or in
Make your choice now
Sink or swim
You can stick with me
or stay behind and pout
What's it gonna be
Consider carefully
Are you in
Or out
I know the treasure's limitless,
but I'm not crazy
about a 40-way split.
If it was just, uh, you and me--
I would never cut my men
out of the deal.
They're my family,
my only family.
I can always count on them.
I'm home!
Why don't they
look happy to see you?
We are. We're thrilled.
- Hurry, little friend.
- I'm wriggling. I'm wriggling.
I am growing impatient, Cassim.
Ask the question.
- We must be, uh--
- Just a little further.
Further out to sea.
- No. Ask it now!
- Now's good.
Where can we find
the Hand of Midas?
The Vanishing lsle
will appear at dawn.
I will show you the way!
There's your setting, Captain.
Frankly, my boy, your actions
were most disappointing.
It is tragic, Your Highness,
but the street rat...
has obviously followed
in his father's footsteps.
Aladdin is a criminal.
I object, Your Honour.
I object to that
outrageous statement...
and I object to a tertiary
character having any lines
during my big courtroom scene.
Here, take this to
a higher court. Ciao!
Your Honour, if I may enter
a plea of insanity,
because I'm crazy
about this kid.
Genie, I can handle this myself.
Sultan, I convinced my dad
to come here.
It was my fault.
I would have been better off
if I had never known him.
Aladdin, you found your father,
a father who risked his freedom
to see your wedding.
And you risked everything
to help him,
just as I would for my father.
Your father. Uh-- Oh, yeah.
Uh, well-- Uh--
Aladdin, I could not overlook
your father's crimes,
but what you have done,
well, you did it out of love.
And you came back to take
responsibility for your actions.
Let us put
this matter behind us.
I believe we have postponed
the wedding long enough.
Good call! Okay, let's give a big hand
for the wise and generous Sultan! Yes!
- Al's-- dad-- Sa'luk--
- Just take a deep breath, lago.
- Now, what about Aladdin's father?
- It's Sa'luk, the guy AI beat.
He's not beat. He's back,
and he's got Cassim.
That's his problem. He chose
to go back to that life.
Al, I know your dad made
a lot of bad choices, but that
doesn't mean you have to.
He is your father.
How can you do anything else?
I'm being as stubborn as he was.
Show me the way.
Yeah.
You have arrived.
- Help!
- Where is it?
- I see nothing.
- Nothing but fog.
- I've had enough of your trickery!
- No, this is it.
The Vanishing lsle. Watch.
Look out!
- The Vanishing lsle.
- On the back of a giant turtle.
And never in the same place
twice. Let's get closer.
Time to rock and roll, dude!
Now I am here. I am here.
- Huh?
- How 'bout a packet of Nutty Buddies?
- Genie, we need a distraction.
- Survey says,
"Show me turtle"!
Boom! Another fake blow
to the head! Boom!
Oh, no, he's got him in the half nelson.
Now he's got him in the full nelson!
Oh, no! The dreaded
Ozzie Nelson!
Rick, boys, maybe you wanna
come over here and see what's happening?
He's comin' in quick.
Oh, no, he's up! He's down.
And he's actually
inside the turtle.
We'll be right back
after a brief message.
Tickle, tickle, tickle!
It took me years to find my father.
I'm not losing him again.
- You came to help me?
- How could I do anything else?
Now, let's get that
treasure of yours.
Amazing!
There!
Whoa.
- Feels like Genie got carried away.
- No! It's the Vanishing lsle.
The turtle is diving.
We must climb higher!
We're almost there!
Don't you see, Aladdin?
We were meant to do this together.
Come on!
Pity I didn't find this place
years ago.
This would be much easier
if I were much younger.
Aladdin!
See? It pays to have
a junior partner.
Be careful. Don't touch
the golden hand.
Heads up.
The Hand of Midas!
Time to go, Aladdin!
Nobody's going anywhere.
Give the Hand of Midas to me,
Cassim, or your son dies.
-Sa'luk, your battle is with me!
-Don't worry, Dad. I can take him alone.
But you're not alone,
not any more.
You want the Hand of Midas,
Sa'luk?
Take it!
The Hand of Midas is mine!
And also, the life of your brat.
What are you staring at?
Oh. No! No!
No! No!
Hurry, son.
We're running out of time.
Come on, Dad. You can do it.
Yes. But it would be
a lot easier without this.
After all these years,
you finally have your treasure.
This thing? No.
This wretched thing almost
cost me the ultimate treasure.
It's you, son.
You are my ultimate treasure.
I'm just sorry it took me
this long to realize it.
The Hand of Midas can take its
curse to the bottom of the sea!
It's gold. It's turned
everything to solid gold.
Oh, we are sinking!
I didn't see where they went,
and they could be anywhere!
There they are.
Get up here, you blasted rug!
- You actually trust this thing?
- With my life, son.
Genie!
- Genie!
- Present!
Let's go home. We have
some unfinished business.
Yes!
Out in the open? No mask?
Pretty risky, if you ask me.
Even a wanted man can risk a bit
to see his own son's wedding.
So, you little turkey,
come to say goodbye?
Nah, I already said
my goodbyes.
Of course, the monkey had
to cry, and that got me goin'.
- You're not gonna live in the palace?
- With the newlyweds?
It'll be all lovey-dovey.
I'd just as soon keep my will to live.
Well, I don't know
where I'm going,
but you are welcome
to come along for the ride.
You're a good guy, Cassim.
But not too good.
So it goes short and sweet
They were wed down the street
May their marriage
be truly blessed
Happy end to the tale
And tomorrow's a sale
So I'd better go home and rest
Here's a kiss and a hug
Sure you don't need a rug
I assure you the price is right
Well, Salaam, worthy friend
Come back soon, that's the end
'Til another
Arabian night
- Congratulations, bub
- You've joined the club
And everybody here agrees
We got the finest blend
of nearly-honest men
Welcome to the Forty Thieves
A fraternity of thugs
that you can trust
There's nothing up
our 80 sleeves
- Got lots of grub to share
- Pull up an easy chair
Welcome to the Forty Thieves
Now you get to lie and cheat
Never have to brush your teeth
But we always aim to please
- Care for one another
- You'll never miss your mother
Oh, I love you guys!
Schemin' up a scam
out on the lam
Takin' whatever we please
- And if you like to lurk
- You're gonna love this work
Welcome to the Forty Thieves
Together we're the perfect team
Larceny is in the genes
Dare to share the family dream
Live a life of leisure
Countin' all your treasure
As an honorary member
of the gang
That no one alive ever leaves
- You gotta snatch and sneak
- Or else your future's bleak
We got a lifetime contract
that you're bound to keep
You wanna save your skin
You'd better fit right in
Well, well, welcome to the--
Forty
Thieves
Wait a minute. We're not
gettin' outta here, man!
We're not gettin' outta here!
Don't ya understand it, man?
This is it! Game's over, man!