This is Paris.
And I'm an American
who lives here.
My name, Jerry Mulligan...
... and I'm an ex-G.I.
In 1945, when the Army
told me to find my own job...
... I stayed on.
And I'll tell you why.
I'm a painter.
All my life that's all
I've ever wanted to do.
For a painter,
the mecca of the world for study...
... for inspiration and for living...
... is here on this star called Paris.
Just look at it.
No wonder so many artists
have come here and called it home.
Brother, if you can't paint in Paris,
give up and marry the boss' daughter.
We're on the Left Bank now.
That's where I'm billeted.
Here's my street.
In the past couple of years...
... I've gotten to know
practically everyone on the block.
And a nicer bunch
you'll never meet.
Back home everyone
said I didn't have any talent.
They might be saying
the same thing over here...
... but it sounds better in French.
I live upstairs.
No, not there.
One flight up.
Jerry!
Those are three of my pals.
Etienne, Maurice and Jacques.
I'm their man because
I give them American bubble gum.
I have a lot of
good friends in Paris.
A lot of very good friends.
And I am one of them.
Adam Cook is my name.
I'm a concert pianist.
That's a pretentious way of
saying I'm unemployed at the moment.
I live in the same brick pile
with young Rembrandt.
That's not me.
He's too happy.
I'm here on a scholarship.
Last year, I won the Hackenwall prize
and was sent abroad to study.
That's the eighth fellowship I've won.
And you know something?
I'm getting pretty homesick.
Not only that, but I'm beginning to feel
like the world's oldest child prodigy.
One time I ran out of fellowships
and had to go to work for a living.
I had to stop because
I discovered I liked it...
... and I didn't want to become
a slave to the habit.
It's not a pretty face, I grant you.
But underneath its flabby exterior
is an enormous lack of character.
I like Paris.
It's a place where you don't
run into old friends.
Although that's never
been one of my problems.
Strangely enough, I made a friend
over here once. I worked for him.
His name was Henri Baurel.
You know, the French music hall star?
Do you remember him?
I do, because that's me.
Adam was a fine accompanist.
I wish he were still with me.
My, how nice to be
in the old quarter!
You see?
Everybody recognizes me.
I guess I haven't changed
so much after all.
They've known me a long time.
But now, don't misunderstand.
I don't mean
to imply that I am old.
I'm not.
After all, I am only...
Well, what's the difference?
No, that's not me.
I am not that young.
Let's just say...
... I am old enough to know what to do
with my young feelings.
Right?
- Georges!
- Henri Baurel!
- Henri!
- Mathilde!
Adam?
You used to
sing it a tone higher.
I'm a big boy now.
My voice is changing.
- Shall I come up?
- No, I'll be right down.
Hey, Georges,
some coffee!
Henri, I'm going to
make you an "omelette á la confiture".
Don't kiss me.
You'll spoil my makeup.
You look great, Hank.
What're you doing?
Taking injections?
Something much better.
I hear your show's a big hit.
It is, "naturellement".
- When did you get over?
- Last March.
I phoned you,
but there was no answer.
I'd have phoned again, but I was
afraid you might be in.
March? I wasn't in Paris then.
Lise and I were
visiting friends in Juan-les-Pins.
- Some coffee, please.
- What are you working on?
- Same old concert.
- When will you give it?
When I can't figure out
any more reasons not to.
Some coffee, please.
I took Lise to hear
Weingarten play the other night.
It was her first concert,
and her eyes were shining two days.
Why didn't you take her to an eye
doctor? Incidentally, who's Lise?
That's the second time
that name has come up.
Adam, I am very happy these days.
I'll show you her picture.
- Are you married?
- Not yet.
Pretty. Very pretty.
- She looks familiar.
- She's Jacques Bouvier's daughter.
Jacques Bouvier?
My coffee.
Poor Jacques.
He was caught in the Resistance.
I took care of Lise all through
the occupation. She lived in my house.
Your house?
Shocking, but generous.
She was a little girl then.
We only became
in love after she left.
She's a little young for you,
isn't she?
No, not really. She's 19.
She's getting on.
What's she like?
Well, she has great vitality
and "joie de vivre".
She loves to go out, have fun and
dance. She could dance all night.
Sounds tiresome.
Kind of a wild kid, huh?
Wild?
Whatever gave you that idea?
No, she's very simple.
Very simple.
She works all day
at the Maison Nicole, the perfume shop.
I prefer not to
discuss the matter any further.
Be serious.
She's an enchanting girl, Adam.
Not really beautiful,
and yet, she has great beauty.
Very spiritual type, huh?
Not at all.
She's an exciting girl, Adam.
She seems to be
a lusty young lady.
No! She's sweet and shy.
An old-fashioned girl, huh?
Course not!
She's vivacious and modern.
Always yakking it up?
Don't be silly!
She reads incessantly.
Doesn't all that reading
make her moody?
Never.
She's the gayest girl in the world.
Look, let's start
all over again, shall we?
What's she like?
Good morning, Therese.
How are you today, "monsieur"?
I could be better, Therese.
I'm broke.
- Broke?
- That means I have no money.
When I'm broke I don't eat.
Then I get tired and depressed.
When that happens, the only thing
that helps is wine and women.
That should be very simple.
You are in Paris.
But even in Paris
that takes money...
...which is what
I don't have in the first place.
This isn't music!
It's uncivilized.
It's noise.
- Hi!
- Hi.
Jerry, this is Henri Baurel.
Jerry Mulligan.
How do you do?
I know you.
I've heard you sing a thousand times.
You're wonderful.
- Thank you.
- Excuse me.
Do you have
300 francs on you?
I'm going to Montmartre.
I need lunch money.
Sorry. Bought a postage stamp
and it broke me.
Please allow me.
No, thanks.
I never touch a guy
unless I've known him 15 minutes.
I've known him 15 years.
Lend me 300.
I wouldn't lend him money if I were
you. He's a bum risk.
Adam! For this you win a scholarship?
What's the matter?
Evidently the man doesn't like jazz.
- He's against it.
- What else is there?
I know what he likes.
He's strictly a three-quarter man.
Old Vienna.
Franz Josef!
The Palace of Schönbrunn.
- Kaffee with Schlagsahne.
- And Wienerschnitzel.
- Dog!
- Pig!
My card!
Gentlemen!
The Emperor!
Relax, sister.
I'm from Perth Amboy, New Jersey.
I can see disregarding perspective
to achieve an effect, but I believe...
Why don't you be
a good little girl and move on?
You won't buy anything.
You're just blocking out the sunshine.
I just wanted
to discuss your work.
I don't want you
to discuss my work.
I'm not interested
in your opinion of my work.
If you say something nice
I won't feel better...
...and if you don't
it'll bother me.
Thank you. Good day.
Do you mind if I look...
...or will you chew
my head off too?
Go ahead.
You're okay.
Thank you.
She's a third-year girl
that gripes my liver.
Third-year girls?
You know, American college kids.
They come here to take their third
year and lap up some culture.
They give me a swift pain.
Why?
They're harmless enough.
They're officious and dull.
They always make profound
observations they've overheard.
Say, do you have
a cigarette?
- I think so.
- Thanks.
Don't you like criticism?
Who does? Tough enough getting
it from those who know.
My first today.
My guess is the business
isn't very good.
Your guess is
right on the nose.
You know...
...I like these two.
Thanks. So do I.
I want to buy them.
How much are they?
Gee, I don't know.
You don't know?
I never thought I'd come to the point
where that would be an issue.
Offer me something.
15,000 francs.
For each.
Will that be satisfactory?
That'll be
good and satisfactory.
You sure you know what you're doing?
What do you care?
That's about $50 apiece,
isn't it?
I don't know.
I haven't changed money lately.
Oh, dear!
- What's the matter?
- I haven't got enough with me.
Come back tomorrow.
It's a cinch they'll still be here.
Why don't you come to the hotel?
I can pay you there.
Fine. Is it far?
Would you care if it were?
- What's your name?
- Jerry Mulligan. Yours?
Milo Roberts.
- Milo?
- Yeah, as in "Venus de".
Venus de.
Is this yours?
Maybe I should have
charged you more.
I'll be back.
Make yourself at home.
Here.
Thanks.
- Would you like some sherry?
- All right.
How'd you come by
these worldly possessions?
A rich husband or father?
A father.
- What's he do?
- Oil.
I should have known.
Suntan oil.
Really? I didn't know
there was so much in that racket.
- There's a lot of red skin in America.
- There must be.
Let's see now.
Where shall I hang these?
Maybe over on...
Here's a good place.
Good light.
Not too much sun.
That'll be fine.
By golly, you know, these are good!
I've seen hundreds of paintings
by young artists...
...and not one has
impressed me till these!
I'm glad.
Makes it easier to give up.
Give up?
It's kind of hard
for an artist to sell.
A writer, a composer can
buy a copy of what they create.
With a painter,
it's the original that counts.
Once that's gone,
it's out of his life.
I never thought of that.
Excuse me for a minute.
Hello, Tommy.
No, dear.
Don't come up.
Be a darling and wait
for me in the dining room.
I'll be right down.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to stay long.
Don't apologize.
I wanted you to.
I wish we had more time to talk.
Goodbye, and thanks again.
By the way...
...what are you going to do tonight?
Why?
I'm giving
a small party here.
There'll be an extra girl.
Why not come?
I don't know.
Do you have a date?
Well, then come.
You'll find the company very easy.
Nothing formal.
- Be here at eight.
- Okay.
My car can take you home.
He has nothing to do.
Thanks.
Me, me!
Jerry, do you have any bubble gum?
"Demain." Tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
- Répétez aprés moi. "Door."
- Door!
- Street.
- Street!
- Lady.
- Lady!
- Window.
- Window!
- Flowers.
- Flowers!
"Monsieur le" wise guy.
A very hard word.
Massachusetts!
An American song.
- I got.
Good.
Charleston!
Choo-choo train!
Soldier!
Napoleon!
Cowboy!
Hopalong Cassidy!
- Charles!
- Charlie Chaplin!
Airplane!
More!
- Good evening. I'm sorry I'm late.
- Good evening.
The moment I went to dress...
...the phone started ringing
like a steeple on Sunday.
Would you like one of these?
Fine, fine.
I've never seen so many
Americans in Paris before.
The Champs Elysée looks
just like Main Street.
Do you live here
all the time?
I usually go home to Baltimore
for Christmas and Thanksgiving.
That's quite a dress
you almost have on.
- Thanks.
- What holds it up?
Modesty.
- Cheers.
I see it's a formal brawl
after all.
What makes you think that?
The more formal the party is,
the less you have to wear.
No, you're quite wrong.
It's most informal.
Where is everybody?
Here.
Downstairs?
No, here in this room.
What about that extra girl?
That's me.
- The party's you and me?
- That's right.
I see. It's kind of
a little joke, isn't it?
In a way.
Well, lady...
...here's your dough back. I'll take my
pictures and run along.
Wait a minute.
Wait, my foot!
You must be
out of your mink-lined head!
I know I need dough, but
I don't need it this badly.
If you're hard up for companionship...
...they have guys in town who
do this for a living.
Call one of them.
What's so funny?
You! You're so righteous.
Stop defending your honor
so assiduously...
...and listen to me for a minute.
I don't need a paid escort.
And I'm not trying to rob you
of your precious male initiative.
I'm interested in your work
and want to know you better.
Is that such a crime?
Well, it certainly is
a roundabout way to do it.
Would you have accepted
a normal invitation?
I want to help you.
I think you have
a great deal of talent.
It doesn't hurt to have
somebody rooting for you, does it?
- It'll be the first time anybody ever did.
- Then let me.
Please?
How's the food downstairs?
- Very good.
- And probably very expensive.
Would it embarrass you
if I signed the check?
Let's go someplace I can afford.
How about the Café Flodair
on Montparnasse?
I feel like "jazz hot".
It's not expensive.
It better not be.
I'd like to show a little profit
at the end of the day.
How long did it last?
About two years.
I lost him in the war.
I'm sorry.
To another woman.
Somebody he met in California
while he was in training.
If he was the dog you
said he was...
...you must have been glad
to be rid of him.
I was, I guess, except that I...
Except it would have been
more satisfactory...
...if you could have kissed him off.
I guess.
You should get married again.
You need it.
- Why?
- Everybody does.
Everybody must
have someone to account to.
Especially when you don't work.
It keeps the personality together.
No, thank you.
Not for me.
- Besides, I have work to do.
- What?
Well, for the moment, you.
I want to bring you
to the attention of dealers.
They know me.
I'm a big customer.
We have a large collection at home.
I could sponsor you...
...talk about you, encourage you.
When you've done enough canvases
I could arrange your first show.
That is, if you'll let me.
It sounds great,
but what's in it for you?
Just the excitement of
helping somebody I believe in...
...and finding out if I'm right.
- Milo, darling.
- Tommy! I knew you'd turn up here.
This is Jerry Mulligan.
This is Tommy Baldwin.
He's on the "Paris Telegram".
Milo, I'm showing the Jansens
around and need your help.
What do you say?
Shall we go to his rescue?
Anything you like.
Follow me. You need radar to
find your way in this smoke.
- Who are the Jansens?
- Magazine illustrators.
- What're they like?
- Death.
- Look what I found.
- What a pleasant surprise!
- Jack, say hello to Milo.
- Hello, Milo.
This is Jerry Mulligan.
Jerry, the Jansens.
How do you do?
Isn't this the chap you
told me about at lunch?
Waiter, two more glasses, please.
Milo says you're quite wonderful.
I'd love to see
some of your pictures.
I'm having a private showing
tomorrow on a corner in Montmartre.
You paint?
So do we. Jack and I.
We work together.
Well, that's cozy.
Dance, you two.
I want to talk to Milo.
Come on, Jack.
Have fun.
There's a special doll over there.
Do you know who she is?
No. But she is lovely,
isn't she?
She sure is.
I'm very anxious
for you to see Jerry's work.
If you like it, you can get
him a mention on the art page.
Nothing to it.
- Lise.
- What?
Her name is Lise.
Let's dance.
We haven't for years.
Excuse me, Jerry.
You're going to have trouble
with that one.
No, I'm not.
He's just not housebroken yet.
When will you stop involving
yourself with young artists?
It never works.
If they're no good, you're ashamed.
If they are, they get too independent.
Just dance, Tommy, please.
All right. But I warn you,
he'll be out in four months...
...just like the composer
and the sculptor.
Lise! I didn't
see you sitting here!
What a pleasant surprise!
My wife and I were talking...
...and were wondering
what happened to her.
Let's go around the floor
for old time's sake. Do you mind?
You're certainly not
without your nerve!
Don't get angry.
This was perfectly harmless.
I haven't been able to take
my eyes off you since I walked in.
I only let you do this because
I didn't want a disturbance.
And I don't have a wife.
I threw that in to
make it look respectable.
That was very considerate.
Please, I would like to
return to my table.
In a minute.
I revise my estimate.
Make that two months.
This is the first time
I've done anything like this.
At least as a civilian.
I just had to meet you.
I don't know what type of girl
you think I am, but I'm not!
And now I would like
to return to my friends.
I thought you were bored with them.
You sure looked it.
You should see me now.
The music has stopped.
The elements are against me.
It was swell seeing you again.
I'll tell Elaine to call you.
What was your phone number?
It slipped my mind
the moment you said it.
Opera 2-5-7-4.
No, Lise. 2-4-7-5.
Thank you.
Good night.
Well, I'm tired.
Good night, darling.
I'll call you.
Say good night to Milo.
- Good night, Milo.
- Good night, Jack.
Don't I owe you something
for the wine?
Forget it. You do it next time.
If there is one.
Good night.
- That was fun, wasn't it?
- Was it?
That's a fascinating place.
I'd like to hang around
and paint it.
I can imagine
all the work you'll get done.
You've already painted
a Montmartre dive...
...and it wasn't successful.
- Wait a minute.
Don't tell me how
and what to paint.
I didn't like
your exhibition tonight!
I thought you were very rude.
Rude? I didn't mean
to be. I'm sorry.
Picking up stray women
is your own affair...
...but don't do it with me.
Is that clear?
That's clear. That's very clear.
Stop the car.
Sensitive artists!
You're touchy about yourself...
...but oblivious of others.
You don't understand
how they feel.
It's been fun.
Sorry you're stuck
with the pictures.
- I still like the pictures.
- Thanks a lot.
Jerry Mulligan.
I met you at the Café Flodair
last night. Remember?
You!
Yeah, me.
It's a beautiful day and I thought
I could drop by and...
Well, now, one moment, Mr. Mooligan.
Mulligan.
Last night you were an annoyance.
But today you're growing
into a nuisance.
Now please leave me alone and don't
call me again, ever.
Good morning.
Would you care for...
No, thanks.
I've had my breakfast already.
I've been up for hours...
...working, I might add, for you.
Do you know Jules Parmentier,
the art dealer?
I know of him.
He came to the hotel
and had coffee this morning.
I showed him your pictures.
He was very impressed.
He thought you
had great individuality.
He thought they were fresh.
- That's wonderful.
- Not only that...
...but he wants to talk
about your show.
- That's a long way off.
- Maybe not such a long way.
I don't have near enough
for an exhibition.
- What I do have, I'm not sure...
- That's not important.
Then I went to the Marais Galleries
and talked to Louis Dufond.
He's a very old friend of mine.
He's coming tomorrow
to see your pictures.
You don't waste any time, do you?
I hope not.
Come with me and we'll
talk about it over lunch?
I've something to do
this morning...
...but I could meet you.
How about the Restaurant Paul
on the Avenue de la Paix?
I'll see you there at one.
I'm sorry about that
little tiff last night.
I was tired I guess.
Forget it.
- I did.
- You did? That's not very nice of you.
See you at one.
Very nice for a summer perfume.
This is a little heavy.
I'll show you something else.
What's that one on the right?
- This one?
- No, the other.
This is very nice.
It's called...
It's called Escapade.
There's a saleslady free at the
other end of the shop, "monsieur".
Thank you, but what I want
is at this end.
I don't know which to choose.
They're both lovely.
I wish my husband were here.
He's so fussy about the way I smell.
Why don't you bring him later
and decide then?
That's an excellent idea.
He's in Milwaukee.
Dear, oh, dear.
I hate decisions.
I always get a rash if I
have to decide something.
Let me help you.
I'd have the man's point of view.
Yes, that's a good idea. Here.
See which one you like.
Not bad.
This is it.
"Nuit d'Amour." Night of Love.
- No contest, lady.
- Really?
Wear that and the Frenchmen will
never let you go back to Milwaukee.
I'll take it.
Would you send it to my hotel,
collect?
I'm Mrs. Edna Mae Benstrom.
I'm at the Granville.
Here's my card.
Thank you.
I think I'll put a little on.
It is good, isn't it?
You'll need protection.
I hope so.
You've been very kind.
Thank you.
Thank you both. Good day.
Good day.
Now, "monsieur", what
can I do for you?
You know what you can do
for me. Go out with me.
How do you know I'm not married?
That finger on your left
hand is awfully naked.
It's a pity you don't have as much
charm as persistence.
I do. You've only seen
my aggressive side.
I have a lighter side.
I'm loaded with charm.
I go to parties, put on hats
and do funny things.
You see? What do you say?
Come on.
All right. You win.
You can take me for lunch.
I can't. How about dinner?
No. That's not possible.
You have a date?
What about after dinner?
Say, nine o'clock?
I guess it would be all right.
- I'll pick you up.
- No. I'll meet you somewhere.
Do you know the Café Bel-Ami?
By the bridge?
- I'll see you there at nine.
- Fine.
There is no happier man in Paris
than "Monsieur" Mulligan.
At this moment.
Madame, you're delicious!
One's company, two's a crowd.
You get it?
Disappear!
Don't you see I'm busy?
Hit the boulevard!
Look! One hand.
Hello. What's new?
Who is this?
- Guess.
- Oh, Adam!
You always call at the wrong moment.
Wrong moment? You make me feel
like a rejected child.
When's the new number
going into the show?
The new number goes in tonight.
What? Tonight, Henri?
Yes, darling, tonight.
Are you having a party?
Need an extra man?
No, I was talking to Lise,
my dinner guest.
Give me a rundown on that menu.
What're you having to eat?
Magnificent pheasant.
I can drop everything
and be up in ten minutes.
That is, if I'm not intruding.
No, no. I see you later at the cafe.
Goodbye.
I'm hungry.
That Adam.
He'll never change.
What's the matter, darling?
Can't you come tonight?
If you can't,
it's all right, darling.
Don't worry.
- No. Of course, I want to come.
- You are a doll.
Would you...
Yes, thank you.
I wasn't sure you'd come.
I thought maybe you said yes
to get rid of me.
Not that it would have.
What would you like?
Would you mind if we didn't sit here?
- Why, no.
- Anything wrong, "monsieur"?
I'm sorry.
That's all right. I didn't feel
like sitting there anyhow.
Let's walk along the river.
All right.
I have a big thing for this spot.
One of these days
I'll paint it.
You're a painter?
You don't look like a painter.
There are those who'll say
I don't paint like one either.
But that doesn't bother me.
Discouragement stimulates me.
That much about you, I know.
Yes, you do, don't you?
But mark me well,
one of these days...
...the world will ring
with the name Mulligan.
Picasso will be remembered
as the forerunner of Mulligan.
This tree will be famous because
it was painted by Mulligan.
And when will this
golden age of art be?
Well, it's hard to say.
It's hard to say.
Civilization has a natural resistance
against improving itself.
It might take quite a while.
Quite a while.
- How do you feel now?
- Why?
A moment ago you were acting like
the police were after you.
I was, wasn't I?
Why?
No. Never mind, never mind.
Don't try to think up
what to tell me.
I don't have to know.
It's your business.
Candy. Would you like some?
I couldn't eat a whole one.
Go ahead. Try.
The night's young.
We should live dangerously.
Tell me some more.