She was the firstEnglishwoman
l had evermet.
And itseemed to me she knew
more about the world than anyone.
But it was a world Siam
was afraid would consume them.
The monsoon winds had whispered
her arrivallike a coming storm.
Some welcomed the rain,
but others feareda raging flood.
Still she came, unaware
of the suspicion thatprecededher.
But it wasn't untilyears later thatlbegan
to appreciate howbrave she was
and howalone she musthave felt.
An Englishwoman.
The firstl'd evermet.
Mother! Come look!
l think they've killed someone!
Louis, do take care by the railing.
Beebe, Moonshee, gather your things.
lt's time we went to shore.
l think we should wait
until someone from the palace arrives.
lf they were coming, they would be here
already. Besides, the ship is leaving.
My point exactly.
Goodbye, Mrs Leonowens.
Louis!
Pardon me.
Louis, come along, darling.
- Mother?
- Yes?
Why does this king need you
if nobody here speaks English?
The ways of England are the ways of
the world. lt's a wise man who knows that.
Memsahib, in less than an hour
the Newcastle sails,
not to return for another month.
Tonight we shall all sleep
in our own home, l promise.
Madam. A carriage... where?
A carriage? Wait, wait.
What is it?
Over there. This way, darling.
What do you suppose he's like,
this King Mongkut?
l heard that people used to be
forbidden to even look at his face
and that they revere him as a god.
- You mean like Jesus?
- No, hardly!
l suppose if he wishes his son
to be tutored in the ways ofthe West,
then l should be quite honored.
But why can't he just send him to London?
Then you wouldn't have
the chance to learn Siamese.
Gracious me!
Are we sure this is the right road?
How would we know?
lf you are not the lead elephant,
the scenery never changes!
Mother, look at those statues!
Mem Leonowens, KawRub.
Mrs Leonowens,
His Excellency, Chao Phya Kralahome,
the prime minister of Siam.
Have you any friends in Bangkok, sir?
No. l know no one here.
Sir is married?
A widow. Can you please explain
to me why you call me sir?
Women do not stand
in the presence of His Excellency.
How long are you in possession
of dead husband?
23 months.
How did he die?
Please convey to His Excellency that my
purpose here is as tutor to the king's son
and it is not necessary
to ask personal questions.
Please.
ln Siam, sir, it is custom
to first ask questions of personal nature
to be polite.
Mr Prime Minister, l meant no disrespect.
However, getting here
was something of a challenge.
Sir will be shown to palace quarters.
Mem.
l beg your pardon.
The king promised us a home
outside the palace walls.
lt's what was agreed upon.
ln Siam, sir, you will learn
everything has its own time.
Don't bother unpacking, Moonshee.
lt's only for one night.
lt shall be settled to our satisfaction
or we'll be leaving as soon as possible.
We don't have any money.
That is correct, but l do not need
to be reminded ofthat.
lt sounds like we're living in a beehive.
ln the morning l shall go to the king.
A monarch who fails to keep his word
is uncivilized, unenlightened and ungrateful.
There are principles at stake. Having a proper
British household with some privacy is one.
l don't think Siam
agrees with you, memsahib.
Mother, how can it be a proper household?
You haven't lived in England
since you were little
and l've never been there at all.
lndia is British.
That's what being colonized is about.
Father would have put him right in his place.
l'm very sorry l'm not
the man your father was.
l'm sorry, Louis.
But this is a good opportunity for us.
l should just... try to look at the positive side.
Assuming there is one.
Your father would have.
He was a brave man, wasn't he?
Yes, very.
And most considerate.
Which is more than l can say for this king.
Shall we go find your bed? Come on.
People of Bang Pli,
His Majesty's brother, Prince Chowfa,
has heard your cries forjustice.
Cut them down!
You. What happened here?
Burmese soldiers, Your Highness...
They said ifwe cut them down
they would return.
Unfortunate
your meeting so delayed, sir.
King's obligation reach
into every corner of Siam.
lt has given me the time
to think of many things,
including why you pretended
not to speak English.
l believe it wise to be cautious.
l will assume that our speaking now
is a great step forward.
Best not to assume too much.
When presented to His Majesty,
you and son will remember
to touch forehead to floor.
Although we have become
better acquainted with your customs,
we have certainly not forgotten our own.
Then how will you greet him?
With the utmost respect.
Mother, are those men speaking French?
Yes. Apparently a warship's
run aground where it shouldn't have.
lt appears sir must wait
to meet His Majesty another day.
No, l do not think so. Come along.
Mem Leonowens!
Mem! Wait!
Please!
Your Majesty, l am Anna Leonowens.
l am the school...
Stop!
Who?! Who?!
Your Majesty,
Mem Anna Leonowens and son Louis.
Your Majesty, we have been
kept waiting for nearly three weeks.
l appreciate that you have
issues of great importance,
but l imagine your son's education...
Silence!
Has she no understanding of protocol?
She has been advised.
You... are teacher?
Yes, Your Majesty, l am.
You do not look sufficient of age
for scientific teaching.
How many years have you?
Enough to know that age and wisdom
do not necessarily go hand in hand.
l doubt you would say same
for being bold and English.
They are rather inseparable, l'm afraid.
His Majesty has not dismissed you.
Follow him.
Come along, Louis. Up, up. Quickly!
You articulate logical answer
under pressure, Mem Leonowens.
That is very kind ofyou, Your Majesty.
But irritating superior attitude
king find most unbeautiful.
However, it will serve you well
given decision l now make.
First impressions can often be misleading.
Along with my eldest son,
you shall now teach all my children.
Come.
The royal family.
23 wives,
42 concubines,
58 offspring,
and 10 more on the way.
Each one unique.
Each one my hope for the future.
l understand your surprise.
Not as many as Emperor of China, but
he did not spend half of life in monastery.
King making up for lost time.
Mother, what's a concubine?
Attention, my most blessed
and royal family, we have company.
Two who have sailed from far, far away.
Presenting original pupil and heir apparent.
Prince Chulalongkorn.
This, my son, is your new teacher.
lt is a great honor, Your Highness.
Have l done something to offend you?
Of course not.
Then why do you punish me
with lmperialist schoolteacher?
He doesn't look too happy about it.
Dearest family,
l desire you all,
when of appropriate age,
to be educated in English language,
science, and literature.
This is a necessary
and practical gift l give to you
and you must never forget to honor your
renowned teacher Mem Anna Leonowens.
Hello, Your Highnesses.
l am pleased to meet you.
This is my son, Louis.
Must not forget head wife.
The Lady Thiang.
lt is my pleasure that you help
make her a fine scholar also.
Lady Thiang.
Welcome, mem teacher.
Prince
Thongkon Yai.
Prince Suk Sawat.
Princess Kannika Kaeo.
And Princess Fa-Ying.
l'm not princess. l'm monkey.
My deepest apologies.
l study her in English myself.
Well, Your Majesty,
l am most flattered by your welcome.
And l find the opportunity
to be in a school an exciting one.
Such devotion to progress
is to be commended.
Reform is vital for my country's survival.
As tiny feet change, so too will Siam.
But being in a country
with so many unique customs,
if l am to raise my son to be like his father,
which l very much hope he will be,
then l must feel free
to follow our own traditions.
As a father, l understand.
Good. Then His Majesty will appreciate why
having a home outside the palace walls
is of such great importance to us.
A home which had been promised
but so far has not been provided.
lt is my pleasure that you live in the palace.
But it is not mine, Your Majesty.
You do not set conditions
of your employment.
And you shall obey!
May l respectfully remind His Majesty
that l am not his servant but his guest!
A guest who is paid.
Education begins tomorrow.
He sounds absolutely dreadful, ifyou ask me.
He did unnerve me, l must say.
Moonshee, why does
the king have so many wives?
That is an excellent question
for your mother.
Mother?
l heard you, Louis.
Well, Siam is a monarchy
just like England.
And one way that a royal family
maintains its control
in the face ofwar and disease
is to have as many children as possible.
So he needs a lot ofwives
to take care ofthem?
A keen observation, darling.
Time for bed. Come and give us a kiss.
Does he love all ofthem?
ln a way.
Like you loved Father?
Things are very different here, Louis.
Even love.
Go on. Offto bed.
Mother, why doesn't Queen Victoria
have a lot of husbands?
Good night, Louis.
l will never forget you... never.
My heart is yours, Tuptim.
l will always love you.
...always, Tuptim.
Remember!
l will never forget you.
Presenting royal school, sir.
ls anything wrong, sir?
No. Nothing at all, Lady Thiang.
Louis, that will be your desk.
Yes. Well, l suppose class is now in session.
Sit down.
Greetings, Mem Leonowens.
My father wish to give sir this
to put on path of good teaching.
Well, l shall certainly
bear that in mind, Your Highness.
May l compliment you on your English?
Siam - population six million,
spreading across 49 bountiful provinces,
from Burma in west to Cambodia in east,
presided over by King Maha Mongkut,
Lord of Life, whose strength
and power reach everywhere.
Not in my house, they don't.
Son ofteacher is forgetting l am son of king.
Son ofteacher couldn't care less.
You will sit somewhere else!
l will not!
Louis, remember what l told you.
l'm sorry, Mother. But he started it.
ln my country, man never tell woman
he is sorry about anything... ever.
lf you had father, you would know that.
You don't have a father! You have a map!
Louis!
- lt's forbidden to touch royalty!
- l didn't! l shovedyou!
Get one ofyour slaves to shove me back!
Get off me!
Let me through. Excuse me.
Stop it, Louis. That's enough!
The nobleman, Thak Chaloemtiarana,
Siam's most prosperous tea merchant,
pledges eternal loyalty and wishes to present
his most beautiful daughter, Tuptim,
for His Majesty's royal favor.
What has happened here?
The British boy
pushed Chulalongkorn, Your Majesty.
Why?
Prince insult memory of boy's father.
998, 999,
1,000.
Finished.
You may go home.
Aren't you coming?
Not until Prince Chulalongkorn
finishes his task.
l'm sorry, Lady Thiang,
but supper will have to wait.
The prince has not yet been dismissed.
His Majesty King Mongkut
afraid schoolteacher
might get hungry during long night ahead.
He send food... for one.
Why does my father humble me?
He wants what's best for you.
For the moment, that includes me.
Why?
Most people do not see the world as it is.
They see it as they are.
And a good king needs a broader view.
Stay here, Your Highness.
What is that smell?!
She has been chained outside for six weeks.
All because she tried to buy her freedom.
Mem Leonowens, Jao Jom Manda Ung
is daughter of very influential family.
Yes. And when La-Ore offered her the money,
she took it. Her mistress took it.
Then she accused her of ingratitude
and chained her like an animal
where the prince and l found her.
Heir to throne must never be involved
in issue of bondservant.
lt will resolve itself in time.
Like my house?
You are learning.
Who would hang women and children?
They were Burmese.
So you've said.
But the puppet who leads Burma
has British strings.
Why would the lmperialists
use such covert tactics?
Because a war with one's neighbors
brings the British to the rescue.
Men like you, Alak, were not built
for so much peace and prosperity.
Peace makes men soft, Your Majesty.
The English define Burma as
a ''British Protectorate''.
Vietnam and Cambodia are known
throughout the world as
''French lndochina''.
What will they call Siam?
l have been doing much thinking,
mem teacher,
on why some in this life are masters,
like Jao Jom Manda Ung,
and others slaves.
That is something you need
to ask your father, Your Highness.
But you are teacher.
Teach.
This American woman - Harriet Beecher
Stowe - asked the same question.
Perhaps you should read her and then
we might continue our discussion.
A woman?
Yes.
Uncle Tom's Cabin.
l shall read it at once, mem.
You're trembling...
Do not fear, blessed one.
His Majesty is a kind and generous lover.
Come along, Louis!
Quickly. We don't want to be late for school.
Were you not commanded
to leave slave issue alone?
Your Excellency, l'm fully prepared
to obey His Majesty's commands
within the obligation of my duties.
Beyond that, l promise no obedience.
You will follow.
She tricked me!
She broke into my home,
set my servant free,
then came to me with an offer
to buy her and made payment!
La-Ore purchased her freedom once,
and l believe, had l given
this woman my ring first,
she would have taken it
and continued to hold La-Ore captive.
King's commitment to noble families
must not be compromised.
ln your letter confirming my employment,
you said you wanted Siam to take its place
among the nations ofthe modern world.
You spoke of building
something greater than yourself.
A country where no man is above the law.
Which is why l chose to come here.
Schoolteacher has outstanding memory.
l want my slave returned
and punishment ofthis insolent English
who dares stand before the Lord of Life!
Kralahome...
lf you would please honor
Jao Jom Manda Ung
with an explanation ofthe law.
Regretfully, l must inform you
that bondservants have the right,
by law, to buy their own freedom.
And what if every slave in my service
should bring me
the price oftheir freedom?
Am l bound to serve myself?
That would be most unfortunate,
my august mistress.
This is a pauper's ring!
Why did you intervene?
My conscience demanded it.
And boys' fisticuffs?
l beg your pardon?
l suppose, since you must be
both mother and father to son,
tendency to overprotect is strong.
Louis can fend for himself, Your Majesty.
lt was your son l was protecting.
Thank you for the supper.
Although l do not think it was necessary.
l know my son.
You would still be there.
Perhaps.
But then my point would have been made,
Your Majesty, not yours.
- l am king.
- Yes.
And l am his schoolteacher.
Which lesson do you think he learnt?
To respect his classmates
or to fear his father?
Husband must have been
very understanding.
My husband was never threatened
by my ideas or my opinions.
And because l am also such
l will allow you to always
stand upright in my presence,
providing head shall
never be higher than mine.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
l believe there has been enough insult
caused by this woman,
who believes herself
to be the equal of a man.
Not the equal of a man, Chao Phya.
The equal of a king.
l make this for you tomorrow.
Why, thank you, Fa-Ying. lt's beautiful.
These are monkeys at summer palace.
And this must be you.
l shall hang it on my wall at home.
l will make another for you yesterday.
Then l shall wait for it tomorrow.
- Lady Thiang.
- Good morning, Mem Leonowens.
This is Lady Tuptim.
She's new in palace, also like yourself.
l wish also to learn writing of English to...
to please His Majesty King Mongkut.
Yes, well, certainly.
But l should hope that
it would please Lady Tuptim as well.
And this is for you.
Make sure all ofyour books are open.
Who knows the next letter
in the alphabet after E?
- F.
Who can tell me which words start with F?
Fa-Ying loves the river.
Yes, she told me
all about herjourney to Ayudhya.
How it is the center ofthe universe.
lt is home to ancient ones
and their many legends.
l told her in England we have Camelot.
And a big round table.
Yes, that's right.
Everyone should have legends, l think.
lt allows us to dream.
You're an interesting mix
of fact and fancy, mem.
l suppose it's because
l'm always surrounded by children.
Teaching the young
is fulfilling endeavorment.
l didn't have a choice really.
Buddhists believe all life is suffering.
Take away pain of husband's death...
takes away mem's chance to grow.
- We might have preferred a different lesson.
- Yes.
But unique opportunity to change world
would have passed to someone else.
Louis. Do try and stay in the boat, darling.
He asked about your flag and the significance
of the white elephant. l had no answer.
Louis Leonowens!
Yes, Your Majesty?
l am teacher now.
The flag of Siam.
- Red is for?
- Courage.
- White?
- Compassion.
The white elephant is Siam's
most rare and honored creature.
Perhaps on journey to rice festival
we will all see one.
Rice festival?
Mother!
Mother, look!
There's Moonshee and Beebe!
l trust you will find ample space
for engaging in English traditions.
Even for growing of roses.
Out of curiosity,
is this because of our agreement
or are you simply trying to get rid of me?
Yes.
A little soap and water,
and we will have a fine house, mem.
Shall l make us some tea?
Yes. That would be lovely.
l remember my first rice festival.
People come from everywhere to see king.
He bless all crops, and it begin to rain.
l think he was a god.
And now?
He is also a man.
l feel very fortunate that we're invited.
One cannot see Siam's beauty
living in Bangkok, mem.
The mountains are so green and the skies
are more blue than even your eyes.
l must find Louis.
Louis!
- May l ask a favor, mem?
- Yes, certainly.
To send this.
l wish family to know
how happy l am here with king.
l'll tell Moonshee
to find a messenger straight away.
Mem...
May l ask a question?
Yes.
How did husband die?
ln my arms, actually.
How did mem survive?
Just as you will.
One awful day at a time.
Mem sha, Louis is teasing me.
He say in England coldness
fall from sky like tiny feathers.
Why would l lie about snow?
Please, mem, it is too hot.
Can make some now?
Just because your father can make it rain
doesn't mean l can make it snow.
At last l discover her limitations.
l have many, Your Majesty.
Father, will you make it snow, please?
Even for you, l cannot.
But l've seen photographs
of such phenomenon.
Blankets of it... up to here!
Louis... Smoke?
Me? Jolly good!
No. No!
But, Mother, he's the king.
My father smoked too.
Yes, but your father had already
achieved his full height.
l have been smoking since age six.
And some believe me
to be a giant among men.
Yes. ln intelligence
as well as stature, Your Majesty.
Which is why, Louis,
l'm sure His Majesty was only teasing.
l believe now is good time for all children
to spread amazing concept of snow
to cool off court. Yes?
Yes!
l simply meant to open conversation
in controversial fashion
mem is so fond of.
l do have my opinions,
but they're merely that.
l wish to compliment you for enlightening
children to open minds and taste life.
However,
at this time
l shall not offer cigar to your son
and you shall not teach this book to mine.
Chulalongkorn has many questions, but one
cannot plow new fields in Siam overnight.
l understand, Your Majesty.
Honestly, Louis.
l leave you alone for five minutes...
lt was his idea.
Just because Prince Chulalongkorn jumps off
a bridge doesn't mean you must as well.
How can anyone smoke those things?
Your father certainly enjoyed them.
ls that why you like him?
The king, l mean.
Because he reminds you of Father?
l think that cigar
has clouded your brain, young man.
Go on. Go to sleep.
You drag me out at night
and turn down five pounds a bushel?!
- French offer seven!
- What is the matter with you people?!
You seem to have a very high opinion
of the quality ofyour produce!
That is the best price you're gonna get!
l'm not gonna offer any more!
What are we waiting for?
The Englishman must not be harmed.
No one knows where
these death squads will strike next.
Then we must strike back
and with twice the venom!
Strike who, my brother?
The enemy still has no form.
Loyalists to Your Majesty
are strung up to rot.
Merchants who reject British traders
are murdered in their homes.
England may hide
behind Burmese assassins
but the stench is still British!
One of us is wrong about the British.
l will assemble the Officers at once.
No.
lf you are right about the British,
this war cannot be won on a battlefield.
Your Majesty,
if we do not stop
these colonial predators,
who will?
Now, we all know that this egg
will never fit into this bottle.
lt's a fact. lt's the truth.
And we rely on truth
to make judgments, don't we?
What if ourjudgment is wrong, even when
we know for a fact that it must be right?
Do we rely on our eyes
or do we believe in the impossible?
You see, one way to achieve
the impossible is to change the climate.
Leave us.
The French say l am uncivilized ruler.
l, who have spent entire life
attempting to teach self
history, literature, and science.
Why would they print such things,
Your Majesty?
You are English.
You should not be so surprised.
Well, l can still be appalled.
More importantly,
do you, as a foreigner, see me in this light?
l do not know all that you are, Your Majesty.
But l believe l know what you're not.
And you are not what they say.
Thank you, mem... for humble validation.
l have decided to give self
anniversary dinner
and invite important
English nobles and diplomats.
l don't understand.
French lndochina grows stronger
and more aggressive.
But if l improve our foreign intercourse
with your queen's special envoy,
French will think three times
before trying to undermine Siam.
That's very clever, Your Majesty.
As ifto sound English bugles
in own defense.
You shall take charge of all formalities
as mem is obvious choice
to make certain guests feel at home.
But... the anniversary is when?
Three weeks from yesterday.
Three weeks?! That's impossible.
Mem...
The egg
is in the bottle.
Only half a glass.
We cannot have the servant bowing
every time somebody walks into the banquet.
l understand.
Just for one night.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Sorry for nervousness.
This is first time in Siam history
that king allow everyone
to stand up in his presence.
But only for tonight.
Your country and mine
have much in common, Your Majesty.
Rich cultures. Long histories.
And now, it seems, Mrs Leonowens.
Yes.
My children's horizons keep
expanding under her tutelage.
My husband and l have been
stationed all over the Orient.
But l must say... l've never
seen anything quite like this.
Extraordinary, isn't it?
Grand Palace born from
the mind of King Taksin.
First man to unify all Siam.
Our country owes its creation
to a man they declared insane.
Well, these rooftops are a little nutty.
He endeavored to build an empire,
but the nobility that ran Siam
for generations had grown tired of his wars
and replaced him with Mongkut's
grandfather, someone they could influence.
Taksin they put in a velvet sack,
beaten to death with a sandalwood club,
and buried somewhere in palace.
Oh, dear.
lt sounds as though you admire him, general.
l admire vision, Lady Bradley, in all its forms.
Forgive me, Your Majesty.
l believe the sun set a little earlier today.
Mem.
You arrange all this
to influence positive future of Siam.
And now you steal attention away from it.
Well, that was not my intention,
Your Majesty.
Mrs Leonowens.
What a delightful surprise,
encountering such an enchanting
countryman. And so far from home.
Lord Bradley, this is indeed a great honor.
l'm half-crazy
All for the love ofyou
lt won't be a stylish marriage
l can't afford a carriage
But you'll look sweet upon the seat
Of a bicycle made for two
Gracious ladies, kind sirs,
on behalf of 68 brothers and sisters,
we thank you immeasurably
and bid you most gracious evening.
Your son bears a striking resemblance
to his father, Mrs Leonowens.
l had the good fortune
of serving with him a few years ago.
He was a courageous soldier, ma'am.
l thank you, Captain Blake.
Father, may l please kiss good night?
lf l may beg indulgence
for not wishing to break family tradition.
l will be there in your dreams
as you will be in mine.
- Good night.
You have
a remarkable family, King Mongkut.
A remarkably large one.
Hardly seems fair.
All these women for one man.
Makes me wish l was Siamese myself.
Mycroft Kincaid...
of East lndia Trading Company. Correct?
Guilty as charged, Your Majesty.
Mr Kincaid's company is merely one ofthe
ways we try to foster economic relations
with other countries, Your Majesty.
Also, l think, to arrive at forefront
of world in wealth and power.
Yes?
Still, progress through commerce is logic.
King find most practical
and excellent topic for discussion.
With all due respect, Your Majesty,
it is a little far-fetched to think
that commerce alone
will bring progress to your people.
Especially when they're awash
with superstition and fear.
Like your lovely concubines here
with their talismans,
worn, no doubt, to protect them
from us foreign devils.
A friend once said, Mr Kincaid,
English also have fantastical beliefs.
Or am l mistaking your country
for being land of Merlin and Camelot?
Point taken, Your Majesty.
However, there is no arguing
the superiority ofthe English.
And in the light ofthese dreadful massacres
up and down your border,
it's no wonder you're seeking our favor.
Superiority, Mr Kincaid? l do not recall
anyone being given the right to judge
whose culture or customs are superior.
Especially when those judging have
frequently done so at the point of gun.
Would you not agree, Your Majesty?
Quite.
Well... the evenings here
are certainly warmer than in London.
Hear, hear!
A night made to order for anniversary party.
Especially for a king who is
most charitable and forgiving.
To our host!
A true gentleman, generous in every way.
May history mark this occasion
as the first step
towards forging an alliance
between our two countries.
His Majesty!
And in honor
of our most distinguished guests
a waltz, as is European custom
of dancing after dinner.
l must tell you, Your Majesty,
that l have not done this in some time
and, seeing as the evening
has gone so well,
we wouldn't want to end up
in a heap now, would we?
l am king. l shall lead.
l never danced with
an Englishwoman before, mem.
Nor l with a king.
l want you to make promise, mem, to always
tell king what you think, no matter what.
Like to man from East lndia Company.
l always have.
Mem.
You're humming.
Yes, l suppose l am.
As alarming as this may sound, Beebe,
l'm feeling rather at home here now.
What charming people, hm? You remember
when this marketplace used to terrify us?
Like it was yesterday.
l was afraid that dinner might unsettle you.
All those Englishmen in uniform.
Yes. l thought it would
make me miserably homesick.
Quite the opposite.
l rather enjoyed myself. Even the dancing.
Shall we get some ofthese?
And how did His Majesty fare
amongst all your countrymen?
He was charming. Absolutely charming.
l don't think l'll ever forget how he stood
there, holding his hand out as if l was...
One of his 26 wives?
Well, thank you, Beebe.
l hadn't thought of it in that way.
Well, perhaps you should.
We have been searching
for our Burmese killers
here, here, and here,
except no one
has seen them for weeks.
Which is all the more reason
to keep looking.
Yes, but not up here.
You once told me
Taksin marched on Burma
through Three Pagodas Pass.
Could they not invade the same way?
To march an army through there
would take months.
Yes, and how long have we
been searching up North?
Assemble a regiment at once.
l have a surprise for you.
How...
How did you...
l'm not quite sure, actually.
Thank you, mem.
My family... is very important to me.
l shall leave you to enjoy every word then.
Your Majesty?
- You sent for me?
- Ah, yes.
But here...
Look.
Something tells me
my little monkey did not go to bed
- night of anniversary.
- Yes, l know.
l've been presented with drawings
of couples dancing ever since.
Come.
Sit, please.
Perhaps you should simply say
what it is you're trying so hard not to.
l share this with you, mem,
because l believe you to be trustworthy.
Events are happening which
l now believe to be of Burmese origin,
and l fear that military action is unavoidable.
But Burma is British.
Yes.
Then it is not the French that
you were worried about, was it?
l see.
On table, mem, is small gift of appreciation
for your many efforts at anniversary party.
Mem's hand
has been lonely without such.
lt is... most kind, Your Majesty.
lt's very beautiful.
Though l am terribly grateful...
lt is custom to bestow favors
for those who... who please king.
And mem has done so.
l'm sorry. l cannot accept such generosity.
l hardly think ten days' rain
warrants the call to battle, Louis.
May l suggest a retreat?
Mother, l think l should have
a topknot like the other boys.
l think you've gone a bit daft, darling.
With all this rain, it's no wonder.
l don't see why l have to miss school.
Because your classroom's under water,
and l cannot have you ill.
My mostprecious Tuptim.
l knowyou will understand
why lmust write this to you.
When you were torn from myheart,
l was left with nothing butmyfaith.
Which is why, iflam to live,
l must devote mylife to Buddha.
For onlyhe can give me peace.
l willneverforgetyou.
Fa-Ying was found
in the garden, riddled with fever.
Difficult even fora grown man
to survive such.
Cholera always in world
but still hardly at all in Bangkok.
- ls there nothing you can do?
- They have already begun. Listen.
Phra Arahan. Reminding soul
to go to heaven and not lose way.
lt is why mem must not be heard weeping,
as her soul will attach to sadness
and remain to comfort living.
His Majesty is grateful.
The little one has made
frequent mention of sir's name.
lnside!
l take all meals inside!
Your Majesty?
Being as the rain has stopped, the children
hoped you mightjoin them for a picnic.
Mem.
l will always remember
your feelings for my daughter.
And you shall never forget
you are not here to teach king.
The children miss you terribly, Your Majesty.
You cannot shut the world out for ever.
Believe me, l've tried.
When my Tom died, l thought
that my heart would never mend.
But then there was Louis.
He was my salvation, you see.
And yet you still refuse to live.
l beg your pardon?
A mother,
a teacher,
a widow.
But you're neverjust... woman.
That is not fair.
ln spite of all you say,
mem is not accepting passing of husband.
lt is why you so protect son,
and why you devote all time
to books and issues,
and why you cannot accept gift!
Why are you doing this?
Because you lie even to yourself.
So do not lecture me about living.
You are not qualified.
These hours are meant for sleep.
You startled me.
l thought it wise to do so.
May l ask what His Majesty is doing awake
at such an ungodly hour?
Gazing at the moon.
Yes, she's beautiful.
As the sun rises, she will surrender the night.
But she is always with him,
even when he cannot see her.
That must be a great comfort to him.
Yes.
This come from Bangkok.
You may find it of some interest.
- lt's from...
- Yes.
Please to read.
As monkey has stolen king's spectacles.
''Your Majesty, the United States
sincerely appreciates your generous offer
to help end this tragic conflict.''
''Unfortunately our country does not reach
a latitude which favors the elephant.''
''We are, however, highly grateful
for this indication offriendship.''
''Your good friend, Abraham Lincoln.''
l admire this man for what
he is trying to do for his people.
They say at the Battle ofAntietam,
70,000 men killed each other in one day.
And each one ofthose soldiers
has a father who grieves.
l'm father to all of Siam.
Mem is not wrong about moving on.
Neither were you, Your Majesty.
When we return, it is time for teacher
to teach Chulalongkorn and others
any subject she wish,
as long as king know first,
so can be prepared for consequences.
l will do my best, Your Majesty.
And l was always believing
Englishwomen slept in hats!
l have been wondering, mem.
When it's my son's time to become king,
will he be a good one?
Well, he is still a boy, Your Majesty.
But a keenly intelligent one,
with a warm heart and sympathetic soul.
Qualities, l believe, of a great king.
l want to thank you
for bringing me here - to Siam.
l cannot imagine anywhere l would rather be.
Were you happy in Bombay?
l was never unhappy.
But... l find myselftraveling
from place to place,
wondering where it is that l belong exactly.
And l find myself here.
Your path is as it should be.
My mind has taken me
down many roads of late.
All ofwhich lead absolutely nowhere.
What would Buddha say ofthat?
That roads are forjourneys, mem.
Not destinations.
Don't your wives ever getjealous?
l do not understand significance of question.
- Forgive me. l was prying.
- No. Please, continue.
Well, most ofthe world believes that
a man and a woman
should share a relationship
which is sacred only unto themselves.
Each one of my wives
believes same about king.
Not everyone can marry you, Your Majesty.
Good thing.
King need his rest sometime.
Burmese camp, General,
just over that ridge.
Let us hope they are better cook
than they are soldiers.
We will camp here tonight.
Your country owes you a debt of gratitude.
Your instincts were excellent,
Your Highness.
They ran offtoo quickly.
To His Majesty and the greatness of Siam.
You will not drink to your own brother?
You said my instincts were good.
And what are they telling you?
That you are not drinking either.
My soldiers needed palace uniforms.
You poisoned your own regiment!?
Yes. ln war, innocent people die.
But only a war will cleanse this nation
of its Western parasites.
Take comfort, Chowfa,
your brother and his children
will soon be joining you.
All the bodies were stripped
and left to the sun.
l fear Prince Chowfa and Alak
were cremated with the others.
May their souls rest in peace.
You couldn't have prevented
your brother's death, Your Majesty.
Send my armies north.
lf Burma wants this war, they shall have it.
Lord Bradley?
Lady Bradley, Mr Kincaid.
lf l might have a moment ofyour time.
l'm afraid a moment is all we have.
We are leaving on the next boat,
and so should you.
- My life is here, Lady Bradley.
- Nasty business.
All this sabre-rattling.
Not good for trade, l can tell you.
The king's brother is most likely dead,
as is his general.
l would hardly call his action unprovoked.
What can l do for you, Mrs Leonowens?
Are the British behind these attacks on Siam?
Huh! Stick to teaching, Mrs Leonowens!
lt's obvious you know nothing about politics.
Burma would not make a move
without England's blessing. That l know.
Precisely.
But ifthis crisis isn't resolved soon and a
country under our protection is threatened,
we will have no choice
but to defend our interests.
Our protection?
Our interests?
The ways of England
are the ways ofthe world, my dear.
They are the ways of one world, Lady
Bradley. One l am ashamed to call my own.
You forget yourself, madam.
Now ifyou'll excuse us.
No, l will not.
You raised your glass to him!
You commended him for his vision.
And all the while you were waiting
to take his country from him.
How the empire conducts its business
is really none ofyour concern.
The last time l inquired, Lord Bradley,
l was still a British subject.
A fact you would do well to remember
next time you're cheek to cheek with the king.
Forgive me, but my Lady Tuptim
is in great danger.
l am Phim.
Someone found her in the monastery.
She must speak with you.
Only Buddha can save her now.
What is it?
Oh, my dear girl.
What have you done?
What l have done is not result of king
or intention to dishonor.
A concubine's heart
is of no consequence to king,
consumed with matters
of the whole universe.
But, Tuptim, why did you not come to me?
The king might have understood.
You simply can't do this to him - not now!
lf love was a choice, who would
ever choose such exquisite pain?
This is what l need His Majesty to know.
lf such does not compromise you.
l will tell him anything you wish.
l thank Buddha for giving me direction.
And now, with mem before me,
l thank him for giving me true friend.
Halt!
Stay where you are!
Lady Tuptim, you are accused
of a traitorous act
against His Majesty, King Mongkut,
which carries the penalty
of death.
Please describe for the Court
the events as they occurred.
Why say anything
if l am not to be treated fairly?
ls this not the priest
whose letter was found
in your chamber,
written in English,
in hope, no doubt,
to disguise its lascivious intent?
Fear not, Tuptim,
all life is suffering.
Speak now, woman, or the cane shall be
applied to you at once.
My Lords,
His Holiness, Balat, is the only man
l have ever loved,
and being taken from him
was to deny
air to my lungs.
His Majesty does not need me,
but l need Balat.
He wrote to me to bid me farewell,
believing l was lost for ever to the inside.
So committed his life to monastery!
You will speak in your native tongue!
This priest disguised you
as the most sacred of human beings.
No, he did nothing!
l disguised myself.
When l knew he could not recognize me,
l became one of his brothers.
He never knew l was a woman.
My Lords, l speak the truth!
He gave you this robe
and you went to his bed!
That is not true!
And l condemn you
for your foul thoughts
and cruel hearts!
Cane her.
Stop it! Do you hear me?!
Don't you dare lay
another hand on that woman!
She has done nothing but to try
and find happiness! Do not touch me!
l will go to the king!
He will put an end to this savagery!
Thank you for seeing me, Your Majesty.
l was told by your prime minister
this was none of my concern.
lt is none of mem's concern.
And king is seeing you now
to tell you same himself.
Forgive me, but...
l do not wish for you to talk more
on this, mem. To king or anyone.
- l was only trying...
- Tuptim broke law!
By loving someone?
''Sacrifice your life for truth.''
''Persecute no man.''
Are these not the teachings of Buddha?
l am king! And l say enough!
You asked me to always tell you what l think.
What you think... and what you do
and how... and when you do them
are not the same thing.
lf you believe l wish to execute this girl...
But now, because you say to court
you can tell king what to do,
l cannot intervene as l had planned.
lntervene? After they're tortured?
Yes!
But you, a woman and a foreigner,
have made it seem king at your command.
You have made me appear weak.
And impossible for me
to step in and not lose face!
- But you are the king.
- To remain such,
l cannot undermine ability
to command loyalty,
- which l must have to keep country secure.
- You have the power...
Now is not the time to change
the way that things are done!
Well, if not now, then when?
How many more people must die
so that you might save face?!
Go home, mem.
You help enough for one day.
For the life of me, l don't know
how you people can stand this heat.
You have five minutes, Mr Kincaid.
l suggest you not waste them.
l don't suppose l could have a glass ofwater?
Right.
Then l'll come straight to the point.
As you know, l do a lot
of business with the Siamese,
many ofwhom have ended up
dead in recent months.
Which, as l have discovered,
is all part of some elaborate plot
to make you think we British are the villains.
l happen to know we are not.
The acquisition of a particular little piece
of information has cost me a small fortune.
But the fact is, when all is said and done,
l make more money
with Mongkut on the throne, so
l think l'm about to become your best friend.
Your Majesty, Alak will not stop
until all ofyour children are in velvet sacks.
Kincaid said he'll blame
the coup on Burma,
then launch a full-scale attack using
your troops already protecting the border.
Alak seeks to finish
what Taksin only dreamed of.
Taksin was insane.
No.
He was betrayed.
As we are now.
How long before Alak reaches the city?
A week.
Maybe less.
And my armies?
They will never reach the palace in time.
Then he has already won.
l will evacuate the royal family at once.
No.
Recall the army.
And announce to the people
we have just received glad tidings.
Glad tidings, Your Majesty?
Mother, doesn't chahng see kao
mean white elephant?
- Do you think they've found one?
- Yes. ln Prachin Buri.
Entire village has seen it.
The first in 20 years!
- l'll see to our tickets.
- l don't want to go, Mother.
l don't want to leave my friends.
- The king has done good things too.
- Your mother has much on her mind.
You said the Siamese people are just like us.
And what about Chulalongkorn?
Doesn't he matter any more?
Believe me, darling.
l wish this could all be very different.
lt is the right decision.
We must go.
Sir.
You of all are most aware
there are certain boundaries l cannot cross.
One being to contradict king.
Yes. And God help him.
Excuse me.
Passage for four on the Newcastle.
Thank you.
There is no white elephant, sir.
King invented sighting at Prachin Buri
so he can escort royal family
to greet imaginary beast, as in tradition.
l don't understand.
There is a traitor marching on palace.
Deception's only purpose is to hide children
in monastery in village of Nong Khai.
Please, mem.
My king believes you are wise.
You are only one who can persuade him
to stay with children
until army returns to Bangkok
and palace is secure.
Please, mem.
Everything in order, gentlemen?
We have fireworks to announce the
sighting and musicians for the journey.
Let us hope Alak is convinced.
l have just been informed ofthe nature
of your expedition, Your Majesty.
And l would like to ask a few questions
about the dangers involved
as l've heard, at times,
wild elephants cannot be reasoned with.
l am surprised Kralahome
took time to arouse such curiosity
rather than make sure
mem not miss her boat.
We have already missed our boat
so that l might speak with you now.
King cannot miss his boat.
lf it will not be inconvenient,
we should like to go with you.
Jungle is no place for proper English teacher.
No, it is not, Your Majesty. Which is why
the presence of one in your cortege
might help ensure your display.
Something l feel,
for many reasons,
l would very much like to do.
When a woman who has much to say
says nothing,
her silence can be deafening.
l wish to thank you, mem, for your courage.
l thought l never wanted to see you again.
l had a vision ofyoung Tuptim and of Balat.
l think by touching us all
they have fulfilled their destiny
and attained eternal peace.
Through birth and rebirth, we Buddhists
hope to learn from our mistakes.
You told me once that l had never
accepted the loss of my husband.
- l had no right.
- No, no. That was true.
l now realize that
it is not enough to just survive.
That life is... precious.
Especially ifyou're Christian
and only allowed to have one.
Why did you come back?
Because l could not imagine
a Siam without you.
The Royal Steamer
has been abandoned near Lopburi.
The King travels East on foot,
away from Prachin Buri.
lf he lies about a white elephant,
what other scheme has he concealed?
Are the children with him?
Yes.
Where would he take them?
There is a monastery in Nong Khai...
Mongkut spent half his life there.
His sanctuary.
The Chakri Dynasty comes to us.
We must not keep them waiting.
We cannot outrun them, Your Majesty.
Do not let them see your fear, gentlemen.
What has happened?
You and the children must
go on to Nong Khai without me.
l will meet you there.
l can see it in your eyes.
Something awful has happened.
Was not to be this way, mem.
Alak's army has found us.
lf he crosses the bridge,
everything l love will die.
- But they're only children.
- Yes.
And each one heir to throne.
Now... you must hurry.
- What will you do?
- Blow up the bridge.
But will that stop him?
lt will - if he's on it.
Your Majesty, promise me...
Promise me that l will see you again.
lf your Bible is correct,
whole world created in seven days.
Therefore
possible handful of men can stop an army.
But, Father, never has such
an expedition excluded royal children.
My son, there are many things you will
come to understand when you are older.
Why can't l stay with you?
Because l need you
to lead our family to the monastery!
There is no white elephant, is there?
Come. Come.
No matter what happens...
the moment you're ready
blow this bridge.
Throw down your weapons
or you and your men will be slaughtered
without mercy.
l hardly think women and children
with parasols are up to the task.
l think you will find l have more on
my side than just women and children.
lt's a trap, General.
Mother, come look!
The king is waiting on the bridge.
- What?
- There's hundreds of men on the other side.
Wait! Stop the carriage.
He's crazy.
He's bluffing.
...Defiant to the last.
As the sun sets,
so does the Chakri Dynasty.
He's brought the British!?
There is nobody! lt's a trick!
lt's the British!
Retreat!
There is no one!
lt's a trick!
There is nobody! lt's a trick!
lt's a trick.
Let me kill him.
No.
l want him to live with his humiliation.
You!
Why did you not go to monastery
like king order?
Because l lost one man to the jungle,
Your Majesty.
l was not about to let that happen again.
Mem Anna not fully to blame, Father.
After all, you did put me in charge.
To sound English bugles in own defense.
Yes.
When king say handful of men
could save all Siam,
he was most unusually
incorrect.
And it be then that all ears hear
what all eyes suddenly see.
Great white beast in infinite splendor!
Where's the beast?
Great white beast!
And as people rejoice
with overwhelming joy,
most excellent conclusion to expedition
echoed in every corner of Siam.
The end!
Perfect! You were wonderful!
Very, very good.
Mem, this is play to commemorate
monumental occasion
and we make fools of selves
because of insufficient practice.
l understand truly, Your Highness.
But the celebration was tonight!
We were duty-bound, were we not?
- Were we not?
- Yes!
l want you all to imagine next year,
when you've had time to perfect things.
Then your father will be even more
proud ofyou than he already is.
And you, mem?
Will you be?
l will always be proud ofyou, my children.
l... ordered this some time ago
for the children, you know.
lt's a fine example of scientific thinking,
as music is mathematical in nature.
Chords constructed from notes
in intervals ofthirds,
and so on, and so on.
Precisely.
l would like to know... why,
if science can unravel
something as beautiful as music,
why it cannot posit a solution
for a schoolteacher and a king.
The manner in which
people might understand
such new possibilities is
also process of evolution.
Everything in Siam has its own time.
Even if king is also wanting it to be different.
l still must go, Your Majesty.
So,
where is it you will be going?
England.
Home.
This is good, mem.
Very good for Louis as well.
What?
Am wondering if,
given circumstances,
it is appropriate
for king to ask
Anna
to dance.
l have danced with a king before,
Your Majesty.
And l
an Englishwoman.
Until now,
Madam Leonowens,
l did not understand supposition
man could be satisfied
with only one woman.
l was onlya boy,
but the image ofmyfatherholding
the woman he lovedfor the last time
has remained with me throughout the years.
lt is always surprising howsmalla part oflife
is taken up bymeaningfulmoments.
Most often theyare overbefore theystart,
although they casta light on the future
and make the person
who originated them unforgettable.
Anna hadshinedsuch a light on Siam.