Joe Blake and Terry Collins...
this is Lieutenant McCormick...
of the Los Angeles
Police Department.
Put down your weapons
and come out of the bank...
with your hands in the air.
One last big heist.
What a great idea.
Yeah, Joe knows best.
Yes, sirree, Joe knows
exactly what he's doing...
exactly what he's doing.
And what does Joe get me?
Stuck in a bank
called the Alamo...
surrounded by the entire
Los Angeles Police Department.
Look out there.
Remember now, people...
these guys haven't been
prone to violence yet...
in any of these incidents.
So everybody just stay
real calm, all right?
Joe Blake and Terry Collins
have finally met their match.
l think they're running
out of luck very quickly.
They're gonna need
more tricks up their sleeve...
than Siegfried and Roy...
if they think they're gonna get
out of this one.
lf you're just tuning in,
we're in front...
of the Alamo Savings and Loan
right here in Century City.
The place looks like a war zone.
The, uh, the troops are
moving in here.
The SWATteam is moving in.
The helicopters are moving in.
Lao-tzu says that
even the softest of things...
can pass through a horse
like invisible water.
Thank you...
for that completely useless
bit of information, Joe.
You know what
your problem is, huh?
My problem?
Yeah. l'm trapped like a rat!
Destined for an early grave.
Kate Wheeler.
You remember Kate.
Traitor...
liar...
queen of double cross...
empress of deceit.
Hey, duchess, OK,
l get your point, all right?
Oh, do you, Joe?
Do you really?
Because as l recall...
l remember warning you...
in the strongest
language possible...
that taking on
a full-time hostage...
was an error
of epic proportions.
We had no choice, OK?
Yes, we did.
Shoot her and bury her body
in the woods.
That was a choice.
Hey, you brought her in, OK?
l recall that!
You know what?
lf we'd have let her go...
she'd have gone
right to the cops, OK?
Joe, look outside.
She did.
That's exactly what she did.
Kate Wheeler's gonna get...
the thanks
of a grateful nation...
not to mention a sizable reward.
We've got shots fired
in the location.
Good evening, everybody.
l'm Darren Head...
and tonight we have
an incredible story for you.
lt's a story that's part
soap opera, part crime drama...
a story of betrayal and greed.
lt's part Bonnie and Clyde...
it's part Barnum & Bailey.
lt's the story of Joe Blake
and Terry Collins...
the most successful
bank robbers...
in the history
of the United States.
Now, shortly
before the bloody shootout...
that took their lives...
l had the opportunity to
interviewthese men...
in an exclusive interview...
when they broke into my house...
and by gunpoint...
made me tell their story...
from their point of view.
Now, the reason
l bring this up...
is that the footage
you're about to see...
was shot on a home video camera
by my personal assistant Julio.
So it's a little shaky
and a little wobbly...
not exactly professional.
Now, what happened in
the wide-ranging exchange is...
Blake and Collins revealed to me
for the first time anywhere...
the inside story...
of the daring robberies
that made them so famous.
24 hours later,
Blake and Collins were dead...
and we have an exclusive--
OK. Again.
24 hours later,
Blake and Collins were dead.
So tonight
on a very special edition...
of ''Criminals at Large''...
the inside story,
the true story...
of the Sleepover Bandits.
And...fade to black.
That was great, guys.
We're gonna keep that one.
-All right.
-Cut it.
We'll use that
with the ''B'' roll.
Got it. Roll!
Don't quit on me, brother.
lt's ridiculous.
lf it's not one thing,
it's another.
lf it's not downright apathy,
it's just meanness.
Total meanness.
Can't get any support
from anybody.
Nobody else has to
eat this crap like l do.
You got to jab to spar, man.
Hey, Joe.
Joe...
may l have a word
with you, please?
Hey, Joe.
lt's a violation
of my civil rights.
That's what it is.
Cruel and unusual punishment...
expressly forbidden
by the Constitution, you hear?
Prison is supposed to be
cruel and unusual, Terry.
That's the whole idea.
That's not what
l'm talking about.
What are you talking about?
Garlic.
Warden Currier has banned
the sale...
of fresh garlic
in the commissary...
because he doesn't
like the smell.
You see, Joe...
it's like a--
it's a miracle drug.
High blood pressure
and arthritis...
and cancer...
emphysema...
allergies, anything.
Garlic is the first line
of defense, always.
Hold on one second, Mario.
You see what l'm saying?
And l've got symptoms.
l don't care what
that doctor says.
Maybe now's not a good time
to talk about garlic?
Hey, Joe.
You--you know,
don't worry about it.
Once you come down
out of the ring...
don't do what l think
you're gonna do, please.
You remember what l told you,
right, Joe?
Don't--don't--
uh, don't do the, uh--
You really chipped
my tooth, Mario.
Joe, for God's sake.
Joe.
Joe, wait.
Joe, hey.
Joe, anger management.
Anger mana--Joe!
Anger management!
Joe.
Calm down.
Breathe.
You ever read the ''Tao''?
l'm sorry?
You know, the guy, uh, Lao...
Lay, uh, Lo-wi...Lu...
-Lao-tzu.
-There you go. Lao-tzu.
You know, Joe, l begged you
to stay out of the library.
You begged me to work
on my anger management.
Yeah, well,
medication's quicker.
lt's much more effective.
You know what?
l would like to sleep
in a comfortable bed tonight.
l'd like to have me
a cheeseburger...
french fries...
a big old chocolate milk shake
for dinner.
Ancient Chinese wisdom?
No. Just hungry.
Hold up.
l definitely chipped my tooth.
For the love of God...
does no one else hear
that infernal ringing?
Oh, yeah, sure,
go ahead and laugh...
but according
to the latest research...
tinnitus, which is what
they call it--
that's what l've got
in my ear--
l don't make this shit up--
is an actual disease.
Go ahead and laugh...
play basketball, have fun.
ln the meantime...
l've got goddamn Quasimodo
going off in my head--
bell tower, you understand me?
l got a bell tower in my head!
Hey, you the driver
of this thing?
Yeah.
Pretty easy to drive, is it?
Pretty easy. Uh-huh.
Joe?
Oh, my God.
Joe, what are you doing
in a cement truck?
Joe?
Joe, what am l doing?
Why are we
in the concrete thing...
getting shot at?
Just keep your head down!
Joe!
Take it down!
Joe. Jesus.
There's, like, a truck!
Joe, Joe!
How long you been planning this?
Just sort of came up.
Hang on to something.
Deer!
Plastic.
Don't you think we should be
looking for a road?
Joe.
Stop. Stop, please.
-Ma'am.
-Uh-huh?
We're gonna need
to borrow your car.
-You are?
-Yes.
Would you just unhook
your seat belt, please?
Come on. Here you go.
Very nice.
Thank you.
That's a really lovely dress.
-Come on.
-Thank you.
Get in the car.
OK.
-Ma'am.
-Yes?
Don't forget your purse.
Thank you.
OK, first things first.
We need, uh--what do we need?
We need clothes.
We're gonna need money.
A place to hide.
We better get
a new car pretty quick.
l don't feel good about driving
down Main Street...
wearing clothes that say inmate,
you know what l mean?
Hey, why are we stopping here?
This is where they
keep the cash.
Hey! Stupid!
What cash?
Didn't you say something
about needing money?
Well, yeah, but, l mean,
not right now.
Look, Joe, let's just
discuss this for a minute, OK?
l mean, l knowthat money's
on the list...
but it's not at the top
of the list.
-Bingo!
-Bingo what?
What do you mean, bingo?
Are you gonna knock over a bank
with a magic marker?
l mean, what are you
gonna do, write on them?
We don't even have a plan.
You have to have
some kind of plan...
to rob a bank.
We're wearing matching
denim uniforms...
that say inmate on them.
Unless these people are blind...
l don't think this is
gonna work, you understand?
Don't move.
Take out your gun...
thumb and middle finger
on the butt.
Hand it to me slowly.
Here we go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we'll be out of your way...
in just a second.
No phone calls,
no alarms, please.
Cash drawers open.
Take a bag, fill it with cash.
Cash, please.
Ma'am, is there any other cash
in the back?
-No.
-Don't touch that phone, sir.
-Are you sure?
-l'm positive.
Don't touch that.
Are you telling me the truth?
l'm telling you the truth.
You look very honest.
Quickly, please. Thank you.
He made no plan
whatsoever for this.
Here we go.
Put that right in there.
We'll take that. Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
l'll take that. Here we go.
OK. Thank you very much.
Oh, there's just never
enough time when you're working.
Thank you for your cooperation.
No phone calls, no alarms.
Here we go. Come on.
Take that.
Take this.
Sir, in case you need
to highlight anything.
Here we go. Come on.
Hey, hey, hey. Stop, stop.
Hey, hey. Whoa, ho, ho, ho!
What?
Sir, we need to borrow your car.
Find a bus, asshole.
Hey, come over here. This car.
You got the gun?
No.
Come back here, goddamn it.
Hold it!
Come on. Sit up and act regular.
Hold it right there.
Chest pain...
left arm a little numb...
accelerated heartbeat, spots.
l'm actually seeing spots.
Hang on.
l'm feeling nauseous.
Out!
Are you all right?
May l please go back to prison?
Not yet.
Oh, shit!
What's your name?
Cheri.
Zip up your pants, Cheri.
You, too.
l'm Phil.
So where's your mom, Cheri?
My mom doesn't
live here anymore.
And your dad?
Oh, he's fishing
for the weekend.
So your dad left you here
all alone.
Oh, no. He thinks l'm
at a friend's house.
And how about you, Scooter?
Oh, l told my folks
l had a soccer trip.
You lied to your parents?
Oh, you're kidding, right?
No, l'm not kidding.
l'm sorry...
who are you guys?
Hey, you're inmates.
What did you say your name was?
Uh, Phil.
You think there's
something funny...
about being an inmate, Phil?
We're bank robbers, OK?
So what's on our mind?
Parizo Del Mar.
Parizo?
Paradise.
My uncle owns this little hotel
on the water...
about 100 miles south
of Acapulco.
That's Mexico.
Right. That's where they keep
Acapulco, Terry.
But l have
sanitation issues, Joe.
We'll buy the hotel...
turn it
into a nightclub and resort.
l could wear a tuxedo...
sell margaritas
to the tourists.
We could have some fun.
You'd do that?
l mean, you and me?
Yeah.
Partners?
Partners.
Tuxedos and margaritas?
-Good, right?
-Yeah.
l can run the kitchen.
You can work the room.
lt's a high-risk business,
but, l mean...
considering the alternatives...
l got to say l think
that sounds really good.
l just have one question.
How do we pay for it?
Well...
we are bank robbers.
So where is it?
Below my belt
and above my knees.
You know what l mean.
You are gonna get us killed.
Maybe l'll save the day...
and we'll both be rich
and famous and on TV.
l think there's a way
to do it right.
l'm sure of it.
So, where is it?
ln Daddy's closet,
behind the golf clubs.
All right. l'm going.
What's the biggest problem
every time you rob a bank?
Getting caught?
Exactly.
There's guards to shoot at you.
There's tellers to hit alarms.
There's customers to get
in the way, right?
Right.
You need to control
the environment--
no guards, no tellers,
no customers.
Yeah, but if you
work at night...
you still got to deal
with the alarms.
But we don't work at night.
When do you do it?
Holidays?
No.
We do it
with the bank manager...
in the morning,
with the bank manager's keys...
and the bank manager's
vault codes...
because we kidnap him
the night before.
l mean, think about it.
We pick a town.
We pick a bank.
We find out who's in charge.
We pay him a little visit.
We spend the night with him,
like we are here.
The next morning,
we all go to work together...
before anybody else gets there.
And we take the money and run.
Tuxedos and margaritas, Joe,
just like you said.
Life will be like
one big sunset.
Want to see something neat?
Aim the shotgun at me.
What?
Aim it at me.
Freeze?
Pretty good.
But first you got to pump
a shell into the chamber...
like this.
Neat.
The conversation is over,
all right?
Well, l feel good
in this collar--
l've always liked this
kind of collar--
but you boned me
on the pants, Joe.
lt's really not fair.
lt's a low blow.
l picked those pants out for me.
l laid them out.
l specifically chose those.
Well, well,
look at you gentlemen.
Are the clothes all right?
Aren't we looking
a bit spiffy in plaid?
Oh, he likes plaid.
Two sugars, right?
Thank you very much.
Cheri, we're gonna
have to borrow Phil's car.
That's OK.
He doesn't mind.
The hell l don't.
That's a newtransmission.
So where are we headed?
Rufus.
Where's Rufus?
lt's up the road
a little ways.
What's at Rufus?
Pollard...
Harvey Pollard.
What?
Oh, you feel the need to shoot?
Well, go ahead and shoot, then.
What, you feel
the need to shoot?
Well, go ahead and shoot, then.
Oh, to hell with it.
Feel the need--
Draw!
Dog!
Joe!
Joe?
Joe.
What's up? l thought
you were still in--
No, got out early.
Terry...
say hello to my cousin
Harvey Pollard.
Glad to know you.
Any friend of Joe's, man...
Was it Harry?
Terry.
Those are wicked pants.
So, what are you doing?
Working?
Special effects--
well, stunt work, primarily.
Mostly training right now.
Damn squibs won't fire.
We're looking for somebody
who can handle a car.
l can do that. Why?
Banks.
You're fooling with me.
Well, hell, Joe, l'm just
the man you're looking for.
You want a beer?
Yeah, l'll take a beer.
Timer malfunction.
Draw!
l'm gonna get a beer.
He's honest...
and he falls real good.
Me, l'm gonna make a name
for myself in fire.
l've been practicing with gels--
you know, mostly on my hands...
but l need a suit.
Harvey, speaking of the job--
You ever wonder why a man
would set himself on fire...
and jump off the top
of a twelve-story building?
Gosh, no, l didn't, Harv.
Women love a man
who loves danger.
You guys were talking about
before--about the frontman.
You kept mentioning this guy.
Will you explain to the people
at home--and to me--
what exactly the frontman does
and who he is?
Well, Darren...
the frontman handles pretty much
everything else...
except robbing the bank.
He rents the rooms.
He gets the supplies, the food
that, you know, we would eat.
He drives the getaway car.
Joe and l maintain
what you call a low profile.
Right.
lf the frontman
is never seen in a bank...
we're never seen out of one.
l plotted all the banks
that we would rob...
from Oregon to California.
Our first bank on the list
was the Oregon City Bank.
So the schedules
and the routines...
and the bank guards,
the tellers, everything--
we got it all down...
but mostly we watched
our first hostage...
Darill Miller,
the bank president...
who didn't know it yet...
but he was about
to spend the night...
with the Sleepover Bandits.
That sounded good, right?
Yeah, it's pretty--
''Didn't know it yet, but he was
about to spend the night...
''with the Sleepover Bandits.''
lt's very newsworthy.
Look. lt's his job, all right?
l asked him to get me
a good mustache...
and he gives me something
that looks like...
it come out of
a Cracker Jack box.
This is not about the mustache.
We're going to work.
He got you a nice wig.
Look at you.
You look great.
Have you noticed the burns?
They're kind of flapping.
Hon, can you get the door?
Everybody, dinner
in a half-hour!
Howdy.
We're here to rob
your goddamn bank.
Now just get in there.
lt's OK, Mommy.
The important thing here--
The important thing
to remember--
The important thing...
is that we spend
a quiet night together...
and then tomorrow morning,
bright and early...
we all go down to the bank
together and--
it's really a reasonable
proposition...
if you think about it.
Sure.
Whatever you say.
That's the spirit.
Stop playing
with your food, Erika.
But it's too long.
Here.
Next time l want you to try
to wrap it around your fork...
just like Daddy does.
Cut mine, Mom.
Just a second, hon.
The sauce is too red.
lt's not too red.
Yes, it is.
The sauce is too red.
You know, actually,
Mrs. Miller...
this sauce is quite terrific.
-lt's delicious.
-lsn't it?
l hate it.
Thank you.
What time's the vault set for?
7:30.
Tomato lemon?
Lemon zest, oregano,
a little cream--
see, l cook a little.
Keys?
Two.
l have one.
The operations officer
has the other one.
There's something in here
l can't identify, though.
ls it basil?
Rosemary?
No, don't tell me.
lt's not that big of a deal.
lt's saffron.
Yes, it's saffron.
Bingo. l knew it.
You know, sometimes l put
a little sugar in mine.
lt cuts the acidity.
Sugar.
Thank you. l'll...
try to remember that.
Little tricks, you know.
Want to see something
cool that l can do?
Sure.
Monica.
What?
We've got guests...sort of.
You really think you're gonna
fool anybody in that getup?
l mean, you look like
Neil Young from that--
what was that album?
''After the Horses'' or...
lt was ''After the Gold Rush,''
and that's not the one.
lt's the one
where he's leaning...
against a tree in the snow
or whatever.
That's what l was
actually going for.
Getting out of the bank
is almost as important...
as getting into it.
The hostages were kept under
the strictest possible guard...
to prevent escape
or alarm of any type, you see?
See, we had to bring
their kids along...
the Miller children.
Butane?
Copy. This is Butane.
You're all clear and ready
to rock and roll.
Please turn your music down.
l can't hear a word you said.
You're ready to rock and roll!
Thank you.
OK, girls.
You just stay right here.
Everybody should be here
in ten minutes.
What's the all clear?
What's that?
Washington...on the inside.
What?
George Washington.
When it's all clear,
he's facing in.
Make it all clear, Darill.
Cool.
Three more.
Good morning.
Good morning, Darill.
Good morning, ladies.
ls this a joke?
No, ma'am.
This is a bank robbery.
Hurry it up.
lt's not a parade. Come on.
All righty, then.
Just have a seat
with everybody else.
lt's not gonna take long.
Monica?
l have to go to the bathroom.
No more juice boxes, Cloe, OK?
lf it weren't for the fact
that the kids had bladders...
the size of hummingbirds...
it would have been done...
Well, they drank a lot of juice.
One of these days,
you're gonna get caught.
lt's a very dangerous job.
Aren't you ever
scared and afraid?
When you know danger
the way we do--
l know it like an animal,
like a wild animal.
You know what they
call me in jail?
No, l don't.
The panther.
Ladies and gentlemen...
thank you very much
for your cooperation.
Please make no
attempt to escape...
because we will be monitoring
the police scanners...
and we'll kill you if you do.
When you're
a well-oiled machine...
you exude danger.
Sure.
People fear you.
They fear your presence.
The gun, really, is secondary.
Thank you.
Now listen.
We go our separate ways.
Two weeks from today, we meet--
-Klamath Falls.
-Klamath Falls, right.
You take this map.
lt's on there.
l want to go with Joe.
You can't do that.
You can't.
They're looking for two men...
and that's why
we're splitting up...
and going solo as planned.
What am l supposed
to do for two weeks?
You stay out of trouble.
Try that.
What about the minivan?
You leave it here.
l like the minivan.
lt's roomy.
l appreciate that,
but as it's a stolen minivan...
it's probably better
that you leave it here.
Let's go. We got to go.
Come on.
Well, what about my money?
There's yours right there.
We split it three ways,
nothing fancy.
l'm gonna buy me a fire suit,
first thing.
l bet l can mail-order
one out of L.A.
Way to go.
Good job, man.
You, too, buddy.
We did it.
Be careful.
Stay out of trouble.
What are you gonna buy
with your shares?
Paradise.
Two weeks.
Klamath Falls.
Be careful!
Joe Blake and Terry Collins...
this is Lieutenant McCormick...
of the Los Angeles
Police Department.
Put down your weapons
and come out of the bank...
with your hands in the air.
This could be a bad time...
but l just want to point out
that l did warn you that...
that woman was gonna be
the ruin of us.
Right. Understood.
But as our future looks
rather bleak and miserable...
l suggest we figure out
what got us here...
in the first place...
which brings us
back to that woman.
The most common symptom
of vaginitis...
is an abnormal
vaginal discharge, often...
...probably from an allergic
reaction to mites.
Out of gas.
Shit.
What is that smell?
lt's a gratin
with Florence fennel...
new potatoes...
clam and sorrel soup
with cream and mirepoix...
and stuffed quail.
Kate, l have a dinner tonight--
clients.
Tonight?
Oh, well, it's just for fun.
l'm going to the gym.
See you.
Sweetheart?
Yeah?
Why don't you go see a movie?
We're living in a powder keg
and giving off sparks
l really need you tonight
Once upon a time,
l was falling in love
Stop!
Oh, my God!
Are you all right?
Are you OK?
Come on.
l'm so sorry.
Hospital, hospital.
Cascade Memorial Hospital
is located at...
Can you wiggle your toes?
Voices.
22nd Avenue...
Hearing voices.
Where are the voices?
Are they--
Are those in my--
Hey, wait.
Uh, hey. You pull--
You pull--
You pull over and--
You pull over
and get out of the car.
You don't have to get
all huffy about it.
You need to pull the car over.
lt was an accident.
Listen.
l'll shoot you with this thing.
Oh, go ahead.
lt'll be an improvement,
believe me.
Will you listen to me, miss?
-Kate.
l'm a desperate man.
-Desperate?
-Yes.
You don't know
the meaning of the word.
Desperate is when
you wake up in the morning...
and you wish you hadn't.
lt's knowing that every time you
get behind the wheel of a car...
you're only a tree away
from ending the empty charade...
that your life has become.
So don't talk to me
about desperate.
Listen. On second thought,
why don't you just pull over...
and let me out right here?
Thank you for the lift,
but l'll be fine.
-No. No!
-l'll walk from here. Why?
l'm feeling very fragile
at the moment.
l don't think l should be alone.
You're insane!
l'm unhappy.
lt's not the same thing.
Hey. l'm a fugitive
from justice.
l'm a dangerous criminal.
Oh, well,
that explains the hijacking.
You hit me.
You can't expect to step in
front of a moving automobile...
and make it stop.
Yes, you can.
l've seen it done.
Would you not yell at me?
Well, can you slow down
or something?
l want to get out of here.
l'll jump.
That's what l'm gonna do.
How do you unlock this door?
Push a button.
Let--Let--
Unlock this door.
So where you headed?
l'll drop you.
l mean, you're
in no shape to drive.
So you're a fugitive, huh?
What did you do wrong?
Everything.
Alert. Your global positioning
system is rerouting.
Where is that coming from?
What is that?
Between the second set of trees.
The second set of trees,
right here.
Look at me! l'm on fire!
Just don't ask.
Lookee! Yeah!
What the hell is this?
Kate, Paul Bunyan. Paul, Kate.
Kate?
l ran out of gas.
And?
And she hit me with her car.
OK. She hit you with her car.
What the hell did you bring her
out here for?
Well, one, l had no choice.
Two, l may have suffered
a slight concussion.
And three,
she's mentally unbalanced...
to a spectacular degree.
l can hear you.
l tried to escape.
She wouldn't stop.
l almost jumped
from a speeding car, Joe.
Do you hear me?
l had double vision.
What was l gonna do?
Your left eye's a fraction
darker than your right one.
Nobody ever noticed.
l'm Joe.
l'm Kate.
Oh, what happened to your tooth?
All right. OK.
Why don't you just
get on your way, OK?
Act like you never met us.
Send us a postcard
from Crazy Town.
Can l stay here?
Just that l don't know
where else to go.
lt'll only be one night.
Please?
l'm not sure we can do that.
Absolutely no way. There's--
That's not possible.
l can't go home.
l can't.
l could go to the police.
l mean, what's to stop me
leading them...
straight to your hideout?
What are you
hiding from, anyway?
l mean, he wouldn't tell me.
He's very, very discreet.
Come here, Joe. Come here.
What are you--
What's with the pulling?
-l want to talk with you.
-What's that?
Jeez, this is
a very, very bad idea.
ln the history of bad ideas,
this is a humdinger, OK?
No. She's right
about the police.
Shoot her.
Bury her body in the woods.
What am l, invisible?
She said she doesn't have
anyplace to stay.
lt's none of our business.
lt is nowthat you
brought her here, isn't it?
Well, l needed a ride, OK?
l mean, there l was,
sprawled out on the asphalt, OK?
You knowthe hardest thing
about being smart?
No.
l always pretty much know
what's gonna happen next.
There's no suspense.
And don't think l didn't see...
the look in your eye
over there...
and feeling her little hair
and all that kind of stuff.
l'm implementing a 24-hour rule
from now on, OK?
lt's in effect.
Twenty-four hours.
Twenty-four hours and not
a minute longer, missy.
Thank you.
''Missy.''
Hey. l'll cook dinner.
l cook the dinners around here.
Sorry. Not familiar
with the outlaw code.
Does that mean l'm a hostage?
Well, l was in Las Vegas.
Don't get excited.
l'm not talking to you.
Well, Joe, you knowthe costs.
Hotel remodeling, real estate.
l've estimated $20,000
for the kitchen alone.
l mean, we're talking
about restaurant quality here...
and that's not to mention
the nightclub.
You know, l got a crippled
cousin up in New Hampshire...
that's going in for her seventh
operation on her leg, OK?
l got my mother's people
up in Ottawa...
the aunts and the uncles.
These bills add up, Terry, OK?
l'm duly impressed by any and
all charitable contributions.
How crippled?
Did you know you could bet
on lrish hurling?
Hey, hey, hey.
Excuse me, Harvey.
l'm trying to figure out
why my partner here...
when he wasn't
helping improve...
the Blake family
standard of living...
managed to spend $200,000.
l met a very lovely young
lady from the Netherlands...
down in San Diego...
Oh, color me surprised.
who took me
to this Oktoberfest deal...
and they had a big parade...
and she wanted to ride
on one of the floats, OK?
So l bought her one.
Now, we're drinking these
big steins of Holland beer...
and one thing leads to another,
and l'm throwing 50-dollar bills
out to the crowd.
The thing about lrish hurling...
is that it's like
football with sticks.
Stop it.
Stop it, please,
for God's sake, Pollard, OK?
OK.
You meet a girl.
You go to a festival.
-October festival.
-Oktoberfest.
You throw 50-dollar bills
to the crowd.
l notice you got
a new gold watch.
This is an 18-karat
gold watch.
l don't give a shit
how many karats it is.
Thirty-six grand.
lt's no big deal.
Did you ever think about
asking somebody for the time?
lt's a lot cheaper.
Anything else?
Well, yeah.
We stayed a couple days longer
than l thought we were gonna...
down in San Diego...
and l had to get her
back to the Netherlands...
so l chartered a private jet
to take her home.
Oh, of course you did.
-The Netherlands.
-Yeah.
Joe.
What?
Listen.
Let me try to explain
something to you.
Paradise doesn't
come cheaply, OK?
Now, l've figured this
down to the last nickel.
Now, and here's
the important part...
every nickel that we spend...
is a nickel
that we have to steal.
Now, that's a lot
of nickels, Joe.
l don't want to rob banks
for the rest of my life.
The stress level
is just too damned high.
Harvey?
Joe?
Dinner's almost ready.
Now, this is not bad.
lt's a little--
lt's a little chewy, but--
You boys ever eat and talk
at the same time?
We used to.
So, what sort of work
do you do, crimewise?
Bank robbery.
Well, they rob banks.
l drive the getaway car.
Harvey.
That's enough, Harvey.
Wait a minute.
You're not the--
the guys who go to
the bank manager's house...
you know,
the night before, and you--
They do.
l drive the getaway car.
Harvey!
For the love of God.
You're the Sleepover Bandits.
Oh, my God,
you're practically famous.
The Sleepover Bandits?
That's us?
Don't you watch
''Criminals at Large''?
You should.
They're watching you.
You're astounding, Harvey.
So...
you rob banks.
Well, that's impressive.
What, some little old ladies'
savings accounts...
and Cub Scout dues and homeless
orphan Christmas funds?
ls that what--
We never stole a penny from
anybody who earned it, lady.
That money's federally insured
by the government.
The government
steals money from people...
and we just take it
back from them.
Any more questions, Kate?
Got a spare toothbrush?
Didn't have time to pack.
God, nobody could be that sick.
Put that down.
May l?
What are you doing here?
Cleaning my teeth.
l mean, manic depression...
delusion, l understand
all of that.
lt's very impressive, but--
Do you know how many germs
are on your finger?
That kind of
defeats the purpose.
Well, if you don't
give me a toothbrush...
l don't have much option, do l?
l don't think you're crazy
at all, you knowthat?
l think you're bored.
l think you're bored
with your life...
and you're expecting
that some miracle's...
gonna drop out of the sky...
and suddenly make
everything better...
or at least hopeful because
you lost hope a long time ago...
and your marriage sucks.
But l'm sorry, Kate.
We can't help you.
You don't know me.
You only think you do.
You're joking.
Saw it in a movie.
How does it end?
With a wedding.
Beavers and ducks!
Suckers.
l'm not waiting for anything
to fall out of the sky.
l'm not bored. l'm angry.
Maybe he's right
about running out of hope.
lt's not entirely my fault.
lt's just that l picked
the wrong life.
The valley spirit is a woman.
Use her root
at the gateway of heaven...
and it will never fail.
What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
Not a clue.
l'm hoping that it means...
figure out what you want
and just take it.
Oh, please.
What, like robbing a bank?
Like that. Yeah.
lf only life were that simple.
Like a shadow on me
all of the time
l don't know what to do.
l'm always in the dark.
We're living in a powder keg,
giving off sparks.
Once upon a time,
l was falling in love.
Now l'm only falling apart.
Nothing l can do.
Total eclipse of the heart.
Once upon a time,
there was light in my life.
Nowthere's only
love in the dark.
Nothing l can do.
Total eclipse of the heart.
Oh, my God.
Give me a break.
Turn around, bright eyes.
l can't believe
you knowthat song.
Yeah. Bonnie Tyler.
''Total Eclipse of the Heart.''
lt's the ultimate
sappy chick song.
-lt's not a sappy chick song.
-lt's very sappy.
No, it's not.
Oh, please don't argue.
l'm having a really hard day.
This is the song
that all girls sing--
lt is an epic haiku to the--
A what?
lt's a haiku
to the complexity of love.
lt's also pretty
embarrassing for guys.
When that song was out, l used
to listen to it on the radio.
l have to admit,
l would get a little misty.
Really?
Yeah, a little...
and l would appreciate it if you
didn't mention that to anyone.
l won't tell a soul.
Thanks.
That's all right. l'll get it.
Oh, l'll get it.
No, no. Why don't you just
stay under the covers there?
You know what other song
jacked me up when l was a kid?
That song about the pony,
''Wildfire.''
You knowthat song?
Oh, l love that pony song.
-You do?
-l love all pony songs.
-Really? You know--
-Yeah.
lt's the one that goes...
Ride, pony, ride
That's ''Mustang Sally.''
Close. lt's a horse.
Wasn't the pony called Sally?
No. This pony
was called Wildfire.
He busted down the stall.
Busted down his stall
You don't remember that?
And they called him ''Wildfire.''
Joe?
Yeah.
l think l know what l want.
Amazing.
Joe, the 24-hour rule...
is all that stands
between us and chaos.
Are you listening to me?
We're at kind of
a crossroads here...
and l want you to be very clear
about my meaning.
l'm changing
the 24-hour rule, OK?
No, no, no.
You don't understand.
She's a missing person.
Missing, meaning that someone's
looking for her.
You get it?
l'm changing the 24-hour rule.
May l help you?
Oh, l'm sorry.
We're here to rob your bank.
What the hell is that?
lt's a disorder
that affects your ability...
to regulate
sleep and wakefulness.
l thought he was dead.
No. That's cataplexy,
a secondary symptom...
sudden loss
of voluntary muscle control.
l just have one question.
Why now?
ln Lare's case, emotional stress
is the primary ignitor.
Do you have a guest bedroom
here, ma'am?
Now we're just gonna ask you
to step right over here...
in the manager's office.
Go ahead.
You never know what's gonna
happen during a robbery.
-That's the thing.
-Sure, sure.
There's always a surprise
of some kind...
l mean, you know,
beyond your control...
but, l mean, the thing is that
you have to remain calm...
-under pressure...
-That's right.
and think on your feet.
No, no.
All l'm saying is it just seems
a little silly...
falling asleep
during a bank robbery.
Well, it may appear
silly to you...
but there's a perfectly
reasonable explanation.
Done.
l'm sorry. l'm a little nervous.
lt's OK, Larry.
There's nothing
to be nervous about.
You see, my body chemistry
is extraordinarily sensitive...
to suggestion.
Any symptom can be manufactured,
given the right circumstances...
and that, by the way,
doesn't mean that it isn't real.
Jesus, this stuff is hot.
Go get Mrs. Fife.
So l met this girl...
and, you know, l wanted
to impress her, so l said...
''You want to see me
light my hands on fire?''
You know, because
l bet she'd never seen...
anything like that before...
and she said,
''Well, what about your head?''
-l said, ''Look--''
-Your head?
Yeah, my head.
Like, l don't have
the proper gear...
for that kind of stunt,
at least not yet.
l said, ''No way,'' but she
wouldn't listen, you know?
Flaming hands wasn't enough.
She wanted to see me
set my head on fire.
So what did you do?
Singed off half my hair.
Little bit more, sweetheart.
Here you go.
-ls he coming around?
-Yes.
Because--because we really
need him to come around.
He's coming around.
Do you understand?
We don't have much time.
This is ridiculous.
lt's the emotion thing.
Nervous breakdown here.
Guys, we have a problem.
We got multiple bogies
at nine o'clock.
What the hell is that?
lt's the drive-up window.
Someone's at the drive-up.
At 8:00 in the morning?
-What do we do?
-Nothing.
Hello?
l'm telling you,
you act too eager like that...
and Dottie's never gonna
give you a second look.
Women do not respond to need.
lt's the police.
Good morning.
Where's Dottie?
Who?
The drive-up girl.
Oh, l'm sorry.
Dottie. Of course.
Uh, she's sick.
Sick with what?
Vaginitis.
She's been suffering from
an abnormal vaginal discharge.
lt's a common symptom...
a viscous fluid usually
associated with, uh...
well, vaginitis.
This usually
is associated with--
All clear, Bubba.
You all right?
That was great.
lt's exciting, right?
Yeah.
Why a college parking lot?
Always lots of cars around...
even in the morning.
Leave the Jaguar here.
No gambling.
l'll see you in Tonopah
in two weeks, you understand?
-Yeah. All right.
-Two weeks.
You hear me?
He'll get tired of her.
lt just takes time. You'll see.
l don't know.
Kate's a special lady.
Kate is an iceberg
waiting for the Titanic.
Has anybody seen Kate Wheeler?
Local authorities...
are investigating
the possible connection...
between the missing woman...
and the latest in a series
of bank robberies...
committed by
the Sleepover Bandits.
Wheeler vanished just 24 hours
before the robbery...
of the San Andreas Bank.
Her abandoned automobile was
discovered a short distance...
from the automobile belonging
to bank manager Lawrence Fife.
But a much bigger question
remains unanswered, people.
Who exactly
are these mystery men?
ln a related development...
a federal task force
has been assembled...
to try to piece together
this whole mystery.
ls there a connection
between the missing woman...
and the Sleepover Bandits?
ls Kate Wheeler associated
with the Sleepover Bandits...
or is she part of the gang?
We'll keep you updated...
right here as this whole story
unfolds on ''Criminals at Large.''
Harvey?
Yeah?
Do you remember what l said
about conspicuous behavior?
Keeping a low profile.
Are you achieving it,
do you think?
You bet.
Good boy.
What do you think of my boots?
Very lifelike.