Downloaded from
GlowGaze.Com
Ethan: IT'S BEEN THE SAME DREAM
EVERY NIGHT FOR MONTHS NOW.
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
I CAN'T EVER SEE HER FACE,
BUT I KNOW HER.
LIKE I'VE KNOWN HER
ALL MY LIFE.
AND IT FEELS LIKE SOMETHING
TERRIBLE IS GONNA HAPPEN
WHEN I REACH HER.
BUT AT THE SAME TIME,
I'M NOT SCARED AT ALL.
I WANT HER...
NO MATTER WHAT HAPPENS.
BUT I NEVER GET TO HER.
AND THEN I DIE.
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ GROANS ]
AT FIRST I WAS SCARED
I WAS LOSING MY MIND...
TILL I REALIZED
THAT WOULD BE NO GREAT LOSS.
I START JUNIOR YEAR TOMORROW,
SO INSANITY IS INEVITABLE.
WHAT'S WORSE IS WAKING UP
EVERY NIGHT
WANTING SOMEONE I'VE NEVER MET,
LOVING A GIRL
WHO DOESN'T EXIST.
I'VE BEEN STUCK MY WHOLE LIFE
IN GATLIN,
SOUTH CAROLINA'S LEAST-FAMOUS
MIDDLE-OF-NOWHERE.
BY THE TIME WE GET A MOVIE,
IT'S ALREADY ON DVD.
AND OUR THEATER ALWAYS GETS
THE TITLES WRONG.
WE'RE TOO FAR AWAY FROM
CHARLESTON TO HAVE A STARBUCKS.
HOW SICK IS THAT?
WE HAVE 12 CHURCHES
AND ONE LIBRARY,
WITH MORE BANNED BOOKS
THAN BOOKS TO READ.
SAME DAMN FAMILIES HAVE
LIVED HERE FOR GENERATIONS.
THEY KEEP REENACTING
THE CIVIL WAR
LIKE IT'S GONNA TURN OUT
DIFFERENT.
MAMA USED TO SAY
THERE'S ONLY TWO KINDS
OF PEOPLE IN GATLIN --
THE ONES TOO STUPID TO LEAVE
AND THE ONES TOO STUCK TO MOVE.
DAD CAN'T LEAVE HIS ROOM
SINCE SHE DIED.
PEOPLE SAID IT WAS GOD'S WILL.
I THINK IT'S THE ONLY WAY
PEOPLE EVER GET OUT OF HERE.
I CAN UNDERSTAND WHY YOUNG MEN
SIGNED UP FOR THE CIVIL WAR.
ANYTHING IS BETTER
THAN A LIFE STANDING STILL.
BUT I THINK EVEN THE DEAD
STAY IN GATLIN.
SOMETIMES IT SOUNDS CRAZY,
BUT SOMETIMES
I IMAGINE I'M ONE OF THEM,
FIGHTING FOR THE CAUSE
ON HONEY HILL NEAR GREENBRIER.
[ GUNFIRE, INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
Woman: ETHAN!
[ GASPS ]
[ INSECTS CHIRPING ]
I IMAGINE ALL KINDS OF THINGS
LATELY.
SOMETIMES...
I'M BILLY PILGRIM,
FROM VONNEGUT'S BANNED BOOK
"SLAUGHTERHOUSE-FIVE."
"TO BE UNSTUCK IN TIME,
"IN A CONSTANT STATE
OF STAGE FRIGHT,
NEVER KNOWING WHAT PART OF MY
LIFE I'D HAVE TO ACT IN NEXT."
I JUST LOVE THE SOUND OF THAT.
DAD?
I GOT BREAKFAST.
[ GROANS ]
IS THIS WHAT WE'RE WEARING
OUR FIRST DAY OF SCHOOL?
I'M A JUNIOR NOW, AMMA.
IF I DRESS LIKE I CARE,
I LOSE CREDIBILITY.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE GETTING
A HAIRCUT.
WHO SAID THAT?
I DID.
PAY ATTENTION TO THE DAYS
MARKED ON THESE CONTAINERS.
THANKS, AMMA.
YOU DECIDE WHAT COLLEGES
YOU'RE APPLYING TO?
ALL OF THEM,
AS LONG AS THEY'RE
A THOUSAND MILES AWAY FROM HERE.
AMEN TO THAT.
YOU GO RUNNING
LAST NIGHT?
YEAH.
HELP YOU SLEEP ANY?
I ENVY PEOPLE IN COMAS.
YOUR FATHER COME OUT
AT ALL?
NO.
Mrs. Lincoln: ...22.
"LYING LIPS ARE ABOMINATION
TO THE LORD.
"NOW, WHEN A WICKED MAN DIES,
HIS EXPECTATION SHALL PERISH;
AND THE HOPE OF UNJUST MEN
PERISHETH."
OW! MOM!
YOU GET AWAY NOW!
GO ON!
COME ON.
I GOT TO TAKE HIM TO SCHOOL.
WELL, WE HAVE TO
FINISH THESE NOW.
WELL, COME ON.
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENS --
WE'LL DO THEM TONIGHT.
WESLEY, WHERE ARE YOU GOING
WITHOUT KISSING YOUR MOTHER?
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU,
BOY, HEY?
NOW, YOU BE GOOD.
SO, IS SHE A GOOD KISSER
OR WHAT?
SHUT UP!
MY MOTHER HAS OFFICIALLY FLOWN
THAT EXTRA BAT-SHIT MILE
SINCE DAD DIED.
AND NOW SHE THINKS
THE END OF THE WORLD IS COMING
'CAUSE OF ALL THESE EARTHQUAKES
IN THE NEWS.
IT'S LIKE, HOW DOES LOVING JESUS
MAKE THAT WOMAN SO CRAZY?
[ LAUGHS ]
YOU KNOW, SHE DAMNED DADDY
TO HELL SO MANY TIMES,
I BET YOU HE DRANK
JUST SO HE'D GET THERE QUICKER.
MY DAD IS ACTING
LIKE OLD MAN RAVENWOOD.
THEY'RE ALL BAT-SHIT.
HEY, DID YOU HEAR THAT NEW GIRL
IN OUR CLASS IS A RAVENWOOD?
I THOUGHT OLD MAN RAVENWOOD
LIVED IN THAT HOUSE ALL ALONE.
YEAH, HE DID, BUT IT'S HIS NIECE
FROM OUT OF TOWN.
SHE JUST MOVED HERE.
WHY WOULD ANYONE
WANT TO MOVE HERE?
I DON'T KNOW.
IT'LL BE THE FIRST RAVENWOOD
ANYBODY IN GATLIN'S SEEN
IN ALMOST 20 YEARS.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
HOW WAS YOUR SUMMER,
SUGAR?
FINE, EMILY.
AND YOURS?
WONDERFUL.
WHY DIDN'T YOU GO
TO THE LABOR DAY CARNIVAL?
IT WAS SUCH A GOOD TIME.
I WASN'T UP FOR IT.
I DON'T...UNDERSTAND
WHAT'S HAPPENED.
I KNOW YOU DON'T.
I'M SORRY.
YOU SAID TO GIVE YOU THE SUMMER,
AND I DID.
I DIDN'T HEAR FROM YOU ONCE,
BUT I WAS A GOOD GIRL.
I DIDN'T CALL.
BUT I MISSED YOU.
HEY, NO BIG DEAL, RIGHT?
HOW'S ABOUT YOU AND I GO
SEE A MOVIE OR SOMETHING?
JUST US.
OH, THAT WOULD BE
JUST HEAVEN.
SURE. [ CHUCKLES ]
[ BELL RINGS ]
Mr. Lee:
EVERYONE, TAKE YOUR SEATS.
ETHAN, BABY,
I REALLY WISH YOU'D QUIT READING
THOSE KIND OF BOOKS.
THEY'RE BAD FOR YOUR MIND.
AS A REQUIREMENT
OF THIS COURSE,
YOU WILL NEED TO SELECT
A TOPIC FOR A TERM PAPER
BASED ON MATERIALS COVERED
IN CHAPTERS 12 TO 24.
Savannah:
IS THAT HER?
Emily:
MUST BE. WHAT IS SHE WEARING?
SHE LOOKS LIKE DEATH
EATING A CRACKER.
JUST TAKE ANY SEAT,
MISS, UH, UH...
RAVENWOOD.
ISN'T IT?
MAMA SAYS NOBODY'S SEEN
OLD MAN RAVENWOOD
LEAVE THAT CREEPY HOUSE
IN YEARS.
MAMA SAYS IT'S 'CAUSE
HE'S A DEVIL WORSHIPER.
Lena:
ACTUALLY, IT'S DUCHANNES.
WELL, UH, NOW,
THAT'S AN OUT-AND-OUT LIE.
I HAPPEN TO KNOW
FOR A FACT
THAT YOU'RE
MACON RAVENWOOD'S NIECE.
WELL, BLESS YOUR HEART,
SUGAR.
YOU MUST HAVE BEEN FIRST
IN YOUR LITTER.
[ STUDENTS MURMURING ]
MAMA SAYS DEVIL WORSHIPERS
HATE FRESH AIR.
MAKES THEM CHOKE.
WELL, WE ALL KNOW
WHAT MAKES YOU CHOKE.
Mr. Lee:
THAT'S ENOUGH, MR. LINCOLN.
AND THAT HAT'S GONNA LOOK NICE
ON MY CAT.
HE'S SUCH A FOOL!
THIS YEAR,
YOU WILL PARTICIPATE
IN THE ANNUAL REENACTMENT
OF OUR GLORIOUS VICTORY:
THE BATTLE OF HONEY HILL.
ETHAN?
THE REENACTMENT WILL BE HELD
ON THE DAY OF THE BATTLE,
DECEMBER THE 21st.
EVEN THOUGH THAT IS THE MIDDLE
OF CHRISTMAS BREAK,
YOU WILL BE EXPECTED
TO PARTICIPATE WHOLEHEARTEDLY.
[ "SUBTERRANEAN HOMESICK BLUES"
PLAYING ]
♪ GET SICK, GET WELL
♪ HANG AROUND THE INKWELL
♪ RING BELL...
♪ TELL -- GONNA SELL
♪ TRY HARD, GET BARRED
♪ GET FAR -- BRAILLE
♪ HIT BAIL -- SELL
♪ JOIN THE ARMY IF YOU FAIL
♪ LOOK OUT, KID
♪ YOU'RE GONNA GET HIT
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
ARE YOU NUTS?!
YOU ALMOST KILLED ME!
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
STANDING IN THE DAMN ROAD?!
I NEED HELP, GENIUS!
FORGET IT!
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT!
I'M SORRY!
LOOK, GET IN!
THIS IS A -- THIS IS A SHORTCUT.
NOBODY COMES DOWN THIS ROAD.
YOU'LL DROW--
IS THIS OLD MAN RAVENWOOD'S CAR?
YOU'RE ONE OF THEM, AREN'T YOU?
WHAT ARE YOU?
THE ALL-AMERICAN JOCK STAR,
PROM KING...JOCK?
LOOK, CAN YOU INSULT ME
IN THE CAR?
IT'S GETTING A LITTLE "TITANIC"
OUT HERE.
YOU KNOW, I NEVER UNDERSTOOD
WHY LEO HAD TO DIE IN THE END.
LIKE, WHY COULDN'T THEY
TAKE TURNS?
"YOU FLOAT ON THE WOODEN THINGY
10 MINUTES,
I'LL FLOAT ON THE WOODEN THINGY
10 MINUTES."
SHE KEPT SAYING,
"I'LL NEVER LET YOU GO,
I'LL NEVER LET YOU GO,"
AND THEN SHE LETS HIM GO!
IF I GET IN THE CAR,
WILL THERE BE MORE OF THIS
FASCINATING CONVERSATION?
'CAUSE I'D RATHER DROWN.
NO.
I GOT GROCERIES BACK THERE.
I CAN'T BELIEVE YOU TOLD ME
THE ENDING TO "TITANIC."
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN IT?
NO.
YOU REALLY ARE
FROM OUTTA TOWN.
HEY.
THANKS.
YOU KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE GOING?
RARELY.
HEY, I'M SORRY
ABOUT THOSE CLICHéS IN CLASS,
BUT I'M NOT ONE OF THEM.
"CLICHéS"?
"GIRLS WHO ONCE WERE HUMAN,
BUT FOR WHOM ABSOLUTE POPULARITY
HAS CORRUPTED ABSOLUTELY."
MM, BET YOU'RE REAL PROUD OF
YOURSELF THINKING THAT ONE UP.
YOU PROBABLY DATED
ONE OF THEM.
YOU CUT EMILY
LIKE A SURGEON.
YEARS WORKING
WITH THE BITCH VIRUS.
NO CURE YET, HUH?
WE CONTINUE TO RESEARCH
AND HOPE.
YOU BEEN
TO A LOT OF SCHOOLS?
YEAH.
THAT MUST BE NICE.
I ONLY EVER LIVED HERE.
MUST BE NICE.
[ CLICKS TONGUE ]
SO, WHERE YOU ALL LIVED?
PRETTY MUCH EVERY STATE
THAT SECEDED FROM THE UNION.
MOVED AROUND SINCE I WAS 4,
AFTER MY PARENTS DIED.
I ONLY HAVE MY DAD.
MY MOM DIED LAST SPRING.
HOW DID IT HAPPEN?
FIRE.
CAR ACCIDENT.
[ STAMMERS, LAUGHS ]
THAT WAS --
THAT WAS A DEAD-END CONVERSATION
ON A ROAD GOING NOWHERE.
I MUST HAVE MISSED THE EXIT
TO "FASCINATING."
YOU, UH...
BUKOWSKI?
HE -- HE ANY GOOD?
DEFINE "GOOD."
Ethan: I CAN DRIVE YOU
UP TO THE HOUSE IF YOU LIKE.
Lena: NO. THIS IS FINE.
NO. I DON'T MIND.
LOOK, I APPRECIATE
THE RIDE,
BUT I DON'T FEEL LIKE BEING A
HAUNTED HOUSE ATTRACTION TODAY.
NO, I-- THAT'S FAIRLY RUDE
AND NOT TRUE AT ALL.
PERHAPS IT'S BECAUSE WE HAVEN'T
BEEN PROPERLY INTRODUCED.
I'M ETHAN WATE,
BY THE WAY.
YOU'RE ETHAN WATE?
YEAH.
OH, MY GOD. YOU MEAN ETHAN WATE
DROVE ME HOME?
YOU'VE HEARD OF ME?
NO.
[ LAUGHS ]
I LIKE
YOUR CHARM NECKLACE.
AND -- AND YOUR TAT, TOO.
I MEAN, UH, ALSO.
THANKS.
[ SIGHS ]
"SOME PEOPLE NEVER GO CRAZY.
"WHAT TRULY HORRIBLE LIVES
THEY MUST LIVE.
"BORING DAMNED PEOPLE.
"ALL OVER THE EARTH.
"PROPAGATING
MORE BORING DAMNED PEOPLE.
"WHAT A HORROR SHOW.
THE EARTH SWARMED WITH THEM..."
THIS MAN IS A GOD.
Mrs. Lincoln:
IT IS THE NAME OF OUR LORD
THAT BRINGS SALVATION.
IT IS THE NAME OF JESUS
THAT GIVES US AUTHORITY
OVER EVIL SPIRITS.
PROTECT US, LORD.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
HERE. JUST WAIT FOR IT.
PROTECT US FROM THE DEVIL
AS WE FEEL HIM APPROACHING.
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
SEE, THAT BEEN HITTING
THE SAME SPOT EVERY NIGHT.
SINCE WHEN?
SINCE LENA DUCHANNES
CAME TO TOWN.
MY MAMA HEARD SHE'S FROM
A MENTAL INSTITUTION
BECAUSE SHE KILLED A BOY
ON THE TRAIN TRACKS IN ATLANTA.
OH, BULLSHIT.
BULLSHIT.
WATCH YOUR TONGUE!
WELL, MY MAMA SAID THAT
HER MOTHER KILLED HER FATHER
AND THEN JUST LEFT TOWN
LIKE THAT.
SHUT YOUR MOUTH,
EMILY!
ETHAN WATE, MAY I SPEAK WITH YOU
FOR A MOMENT?
RIGHT NOW?
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU?
I'M JUST SICK
OF PEOPLE IN THIS TOWN
PUTTING DOWN SOMEONE
THEY JUST DON'T KNOW.
[ CHUCKLES ]
AND YOU KNOW LENA DUCHANNES?
IS THAT WHAT YOU'RE SAYING,
ETHAN?
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M SORRY, BUT I DON'T THINK
I'M GONNA BE ABLE
TO GO TO THE MOVIES
WITH YOU THIS WEEKEND.
I THINK WE NEED
TIME APART.
AND I'M SORRY
TO HURT YOU.
LET'S GO.
DID I NOT SAY THAT TO HER
AT THE END OF SOPHOMORE YEAR?
HEY, SOME GIRLS
ARE JUST MAD DOGS, SON.
YOU CAN EITHER RUN
OR SHOOT.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
ETHAN? ETHAN.
CAN I TALK TO YOU
ABOUT SOMETHING REAL QUICK?
I WANT YOU
TO KNOW SOMETHING.
I STILL CARE DEEPLY FOR YOU
AS A FRIEND.
AND I PRAY EVERY NIGHT THAT YOU
DON'T GO STRAIGHT TO HELL.
OH, I-I WON'T GO
STRAIGHT TO HELL, EMILY.
I WANNA STOP OFF
IN NEW YORK FIRST.
[ BELL RINGS ]
Mrs. Hester: OKAY.
EVERYBODY TAKE YOUR SEATS.
HI, DARLING.
GOOD TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
HOW'S YOUR MAMA?
BOYS.
BILLY, GET DOWN.
OKAY, YOU SHOULD HAVE READ THIS
OVER THE SUMMER.
WE'RE GONNA START BY DISCUSSING
THE CHARACTER OF BOO RADLEY.
THE TOWN SHUT-IN
WITH A MYSTERIOUS PAST.
YOU MEAN
MACON RAVENWOOD?
SAVANNAH!
EXCUSE ME?
UM, MY MAMA SAYS I-I REALLY
SHOULDN'T BE READING THIS BOOK.
THIS IS
ONE OF THOSE BANNED BOOKS.
YES, WELL, I GOT PERMISSION
FROM THE SCHOOL BOARD
TO TRY IT FOR A SEMESTER.
OH, WELL,
I'M NOT READING ANYTHING
THAT WAS BANNED
FROM OUR CHURCH.
ME NEITHER.
MY MAMA
ALSO SAYS THAT...
I SHOULDN'T BE IN THE SAME CLASS
AS A RAVENWOOD.
SHE SAYS IT AIN'T RIGHT
THAT THEY GET TO BE
WITH US CHRISTIAN KIDS.
EMILY, SHUT UP!
MY MAMA SAYS
THE SAME THING.
SAYS HER WHOLE FAMILY
ARE SATANISTS.
THEY PRAY TO SATAN
STARK NAKED.
DEAR LORD...
EMILY, WHAT DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
YOU CAN'T PRAY IN CLASS.
DEAR LORD...
NOW, YOU STOP IT.
I HUMBLY PRAY YOU PROTECT US
FROM ALL THINGS EVIL...
GIRLS, I'M TELLING YOU THIS
RIGHT NOW. YOU STOP IT NOW.
THERE ARE UNNATURAL THINGS
AMONG US WHO SERVE...
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE THINKING.
...CHRISTIAN BELIEVERS.
PLEASE, JESUS, HELP ME!
[ CREAKING ]
SAVE ME
FROM THESE EVIL --
[ STUDENTS SCREAMING ]
SHE DID IT!
IT WAS HER!
SHE BROKE THE WINDOWS!
WHY WOULD SHE DO SOMETHING
LIKE THIS?!
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
YOU ALL RIGHT?
WHAT THE HELL WAS THAT?
[ HINGES CREAK ]
[ BIRD CAWING ]
[ HINGES CREAKING ]
LENA?
HELLO?
[ HINGES CREAK, METAL CLANGS ]
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING HERE?
I-I JUST CAME
TO SEE IF YOU WERE OKAY.
WHAT FOR?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
OKAY.
YOU CAN GO NOW.
GO AWAY!
NO.
YES!
GO!
NO.
JERK!
SORRY ABOUT EMILY.
SHE CAN BE MEANER
THAN CHICKENSHIT.
NEVER UNDERSTOOD
THAT SAYING.
YEAH.
ME NEITHER.
AND I SHOULD KNOW BETTER
BY NOW.
THEY ALWAYS HATE ME,
NO MATTER WHERE I GO.
WELL, THEY'RE A MESS OF FOOLS.
WHAT DO YOU CARE?
NEVER BEEN "ON THE OUTSIDE
LOOKING IN" YOUR WHOLE LIFE,
HAVE YOU?
[ SIGHS ] WELL, LET ME SEE
IF I CAN REMEMBER THIS.
IT'S BUKOWSKI.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
"SOME LOSE ALL SOUL.
"SOME LOSE ALL MIND
AND BECOME SOUL, INSANE.
"SOME LOSE ALL --
ALL...MIND..."
HOLD ON.
"SOME LOSE ALL SOUL
AND BECOME MIND."
[ LAUGHS ]
"SOME LOSE ALL MIND
AND BECOME SOUL."
OH, MAN.
I MEMORIZED THIS WHOLE THING
TO IMPRESS YOU.
DAMN!
YOU CAN'T HELP IT.
WHAT?
FITTING IN ANYWHERE,
DROOLING CHARM.
I NEVER KNOW WHETHER
YOU'RE INSULTING ME OR NOT.
I'M SORRY.
NO.
HEY, I LIKE IT.
YOU KNOW?
IF IT MAKES ANY DIFFERENCE,
UM...
I LIKE YOU.
YOU MAY NOT THINK SO LATER.
PBHT! OKAY.
UH, YOU CAN'T COMPLAIN
ABOUT NOT HAVING ANY FRIENDS
AND THEN MAKE A GUY WORK
THIS HARD TRYING TO BE ONE.
UNLESS YOU ACTUALLY DO THINK
I'M A JERK.
THEN I'LL JUST GO.
RUN AND TELL YOUR FRIENDS
ABOUT THE FREAK.
YOU REALLY THINK
I'M THAT GUY?
NO.
OKAY.
I SHOULD GET BACK.
YOU, UH, YOU READ THOSE CHAPTERS
IN "TO KILL A MOCKINGBIRD"?
YEAH.
I'VE READ IT TWICE BEFORE.
OH!
IT'S GOOD, ISN'T IT?
YEAH.
YOU EVER SEE THE MOVIE?
NO.
OH, IT'S GOOD TOO.
WE SHOULD WATCH IT,
ACTUALLY.
YOU EVER -- EVER READ
ANY VONNEGUT?
NO.
KURT VONNEGUT?
NO?
"SLAUGHTERHOUSE-FIVE"?
HE'S GREAT.
HE'S -- HE'S BANNED TOO,
ACTUALLY.
YOU ONLY READ
BANNED BOOKS?
UM, I DON'T ONLY READ
BANNED BOOKS.
BUT, I DON'T KNOW,
I JUST --
ALL THE -- ALL THE BOOKS
THEY LET YOU READ
ARE, LIKE, PRETTY BORING,
I GUESS.
THANKS.
I'M SORRY I WAS --
OH, I-IT'S OKAY.
IT'S OKAY.
LOOK, YOU SHOULD GO.
MY UNCLE DOESN'T REALLY LIKE
PEOPLE BEING AROUND THE HOUSE.
I KNOW.
I SORT OF, UH...WENT INSIDE.
YOU WENT
INSIDE THE HOUSE?
I DIDN'T MEAN TO.
I JUST --
I GET IT.
PEOPLE THINK HE'S SCARY.
BUT HE'S JUST BOO RADLEY SHY,
RIGHT?
OKAY.
HEY, UM...
I GOT YOU SORT OF A "WELCOME
TO SUCKASS GATLIN" GIFT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I THOUGHT YOU COULD PUT IT
ON YOUR -- ON YOUR CHAIN.
Macon: LENA?
WE HAVE A GUEST?
HE'S LEAVING.
HELLO, SIR.
MANNERS?
THAT'S NICE.
I-I-I GO TO SCHOOL WITH LENA.
I'M ETHAN WATE.
PLEASURE TO MAKE
YOUR ACQUAINTANCE.
YOU LILA EVERS' BOY?
YES, SIR.
YOU KNEW MY MOTHER?
LENA, WHY DON'T YOU ASK
YOUR FRIEND IN FOR TEA?
Tell him
you can't stay.
I'D LOVE TO.
THANK YOU, SIR.
HE'S NOT SCARY.
MR. WATE,
MAKE YOURSELF COMFORTABLE.
OH, I-I'M SORRY ABOUT WALKING IN
UNINVITED BEFORE.
NO PROBLEM AT ALL.
IT'S SO RARELY
THAT WE GET VISITORS
FROM OUR...BELOVED GATLIN.
DON'T BE A SNOB, UNCLE.
IT'S NOT THEIR FAULT
YOU NEVER SPEAK TO ANY OF 'EM.
AND IT'S NOT MY FAULT
THAT I HAVE A PREDILECTION
FOR GOOD BREEDING,
REASONABLE INTELLIGENCE,
AND PASSABLE PERSONAL HYGIENE.
[ CHUCKLES ]
BUT SINCE MY FAMILY FOUNDED
THIS TOWN,
I HAVE NO ALTERNATIVE
TO CALL IT HOME.
SO...
THERE WE ARE.
OH,
THAT'S A BEAUTIFUL PIANO.
OH, YES.
DO YOU PLAY?
NO.
LENA, WHY DON'T YOU
PLAY SOMETHING FOR OUR GUEST?
'CAUSE WE'RE NOT
IN A JANE AUSTEN NOVEL.
THEN WHY DON'T YOU
GO MAKE US SOME TEA?
AGAIN, WRONG CENTURY.
WELL, THEN, WOULD IT DISTURB
EITHER OF YOU
IF I...RAN MY FINGERS
'CROSS THE IVORIES?
I FIND IT
VERY THERAPEUTIC.
UNCLE'S UPSET.
SCHOOL CALLED.
PUT ME ON PROBATION
UNTIL THE WINDOW THING
GETS INVESTIGATED.
THAT'S CRAZY.
THAT WAS NOT YOUR FAULT.
[ PIANO PLAYS ]
VOICE OF REASON
IN A TOWN OF BUTTERMILK MINDS.
LENA, I COULD GET TO LIKE
THIS FRIEND OF YOURS.
I MEAN,
IT'S LIKE BLAMING YOU
FOR THE LIGHTNING
ON HONEY HILL.
[ Laughing ] OH, YES,
I HEARD ABOUT THE LIGHTNING.
IN FACT, A SIMILAR OCCURRENCE
TOOK PLACE IN VENEZUELA
FOR MANY YEARS
AT LAKE MARACAIBO.
YOU CAN LOOK IT UP
ON GOOGLE.
UNCLE LOVES GOOGLE.
IN ANY EVENT, I'LL SORT IT OUT
WITH THE SCHOOL.
BUT I UNDERSTAND
YOUR INDIGNATION, ETHAN.
PROBATION!
IMPLIES A SOURCE OF AUTHORITY.
WHAT IS THAT SOURCE?
A BUNCH OF SEXUALLY FRUSTRATED
HOUSEWIVES
WITH MINISCULE MINDS
AND VOLUMINOUS BACKSIDES.
[ LAUGHS ]
NO, THERE'S ONLY TWO KINDS
OF PEOPLE IN GATLIN --
THE ONES WHO ARE TOO STUPID
TO LEAVE
AND THE ONES WHO ARE TOO STUCK
TO MOVE.
MY MOTHER USED TO SAY
THAT EXACT SAME THING.
IS THAT SO?
SHE WAS A LOVELY WOMAN,
YOUR MOTHER.
I WAS SO SORRY
TO HEAR OF HER PASSING.
OF COURSE, I ONLY KNEW HER
THROUGH HER BOOKS.
I READ EVERYTHING SHE WROTE
ON THE SOUTHERN PLANTATIONS.
YOU PLAN ON BEING
A WRITER?
I DON'T KNOW YET.
MAYBE.
WHAT IF I HAD
A MAGIC WAND...
MACON!
...AND I COULD LET YOU SEE
YOUR WHOLE FUTURE?
WHAT WOULD BE THERE?
AND DON'T SPARE ME
THE GORY DETAILS.
WELL, SIR, I'M NOT SURE.
UM, ONE THING I DO KNOW,
THOUGH, IS COLLEGE.
I'M DEFINITELY PLANNING
ON GOING.
OH, REALLY?
WHERE HAVE YOU APPLIED?
ALL OF THEM.
AS LONG AS THEY'RE
NOT TOO FAR FROM HOME.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I MEAN, UM, AS LONG
AS IT'S A LOCAL COLLEGE.
UH...UH,
SO I CAN STAY WITH DAD.
I-I'LL GET
MY TEACHING DEGREE,
AND -- AND PROBABLY TEACH
AT THE HIGH SCHOOL...
OR MAYBE I'LL TAKE OVER
THE LIBRARY FROM AMMA...
I-I'LL PROBABLY MARRY EMILY
ASHER AND WE'LL HAVE TWO KIDS.
BUT I'LL NEVER MAKE
ENOUGH MONEY FOR HER,
SO I'LL START DRINKING...
GET THREE DUIs
AND LOSE MY JOB.
AND, UH, HAVE AN AFFAIR
ON AND OFF WITH SAVANNAH SNOW
TILL I'M 49.
THE KIDS WILL LIVE WITH
THEIR MOTHER AFTER WE DIVORCE.
THEN, WHEN I'M 52,
I'LL HAVE MY FIRST HEART ATTACK,
ANOTHER ONE AT 63.
I'LL MOVE INTO AN APARTMENT
ABOVE THE WAYWARD DOG BAR
AND HELP THEM SWEEP UP
AFTER HOURS FOR FREE DRINKS.
AND THEN WHEN I'M 64,
I'LL HANG MYSELF.
UM, BUT THEY WON'T FIND THE BODY
RIGHT AWAY.
NOT UNTIL I STINK.
WELL, YOU'VE GOT IT
ALL PLANNED OUT.
GOOD FOR YOU.
ETHAN, ARE YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
UM, YOU'LL HAVE TO EXCUSE ME.
[ Laughing ]
I'VE NOT BEEN SLEEPING TOO WELL.
[ HINGES CREAK, METAL CLANGS ]
WHAT DID YOU DO TO HIM?
I AGREED TO LET YOU ATTEND
WHAT PASSES FOR A SCHOOL
IN THIS TOWN,
BUT NO FRIENDSHIPS.
COULD YOU NOT AT LEAST LET ME
PRETEND UNTIL MY BIRTHDAY?
YOU REMEMBER WHAT HAPPENED
AT THE LAST SCHOOL?
THIS WINDOW SHATTERING
IS JUST THE BEGINNING!
THAT BOY IS A DANGER
TO YOU!
DON'T INVITE HIM HERE
AGAIN!
[ Voice breaking ]
OH, I WOULDN'T WORRY.
I'M SURE
HE WON'T BE BACK.
[ INSECTS CHIRPING ]
YOU CAME BACK.
YEAH.
I-I'M SORRY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT THE HELL
HAPPENED TO ME IN THERE.
IT'S NOT YOUR FAULT.
I HOPE THIS DOESN'T
SOUND WEIRD,
BUT I THINK
I'VE BEEN DREAMING ABOUT YOU
EVERY NIGHT FOR MONTHS.
THAT DID NOT SOUND AS CREEPY
WHEN I --
IN MY HEAD.
[ LAUGHS ]
CAN YOU FORGET
I SAID THAT?
SURE.
OKAY.
UM...OH.
YOUR PRESENT.
RIGHT. GREAT.
THE PRESENT.
THAT'S WHY I CAME BACK.
UH, SO IT OPENS.
SEE?
UM...E-C-W, G-K-D.
DECEMBER 21st, 1863.
DECEMBER 21st?
YEAH.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
IT'S MY BIRTHDAY.
I'LL BE 16.
WOW.
THAT'S...
THAT IS AMAZING.
I DON'T -- YOU KNOW, I DON'T
BELIEVE IN SIGNS USUALLY,
BUT THAT -- THAT SEEMS
LIKE A PRETTY BADASS SIGN.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SO Y-YOU'RE 15
AND YOU'RE A JUNIOR?
THAT'S --
YOU MUST BE A BRAIN.
YOU -- YOU SKIP A GRADE?
YEAH.
WELL, CONSIDER THIS
AN EARLY SWEET 16 PRESENT.
[ VIOLIN PLAYS ]
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
ETHAN!
GENEVIEVE!
[ SCREAMING ]
NO!
ETHAN!
[ GROANS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
DAD!
DAD?
OH, AMMA,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I'M LOOKING FOR SOME BOOKS
YOUR MOTHER HAD.
I HAVE TO RETURN THEM
TO THE LIBRARY.
YOU ALL RIGHT?
HOW DID I GET HOME?
WHAT -- WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT?
WHEN I GOT HERE,
YOU WERE ALREADY IN BED.
GLAD YOU'RE GETTING
SOME SLEEP.
AMMA!
HOW DID I GET HERE?!
WHY ARE YOU SHOUTING?
I'M SORRY. I'M SORRY.
HEARD YOU HAD TROUBLE
AT SCHOOL TODAY.
MY FATHER ALWAYS SAID
TROUBLE FOLLOWS THAT FAMILY
LIKE STINK
ON A FLY'S ASS.
YOU BETTER STAY AWAY
FROM THAT GIRL.
YOU DON'T NEED TO TAKE CARE
OF US, AMMA.
I PROMISED YOUR MOTHER
AND I WANT TO.
NO, I D-- AMMA.
I'M SORRY.
I JUST...
I DON'T THINK
IT'S ANY OF YOUR BUSINESS.
WHERE'D YOU GET THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
DON'T LIE TO ME.
WHAT'S WRONG?
YOU LISTEN TO ME.
YOU GO AND BURY THAT
IN GREENBRIER
AND FORGET
YOU EVER FOUND IT.
I NEVER SAID
I WAS IN GREENBRIER, AMMA.
[ INSECTS CHIRPING ]
[ HINGES CREAK ]
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING ]
[ WHISPERING CONTINUES ]
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
[ HINGES CREAK ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ GROANS ]
Lena:
MY FAMILY'S...DIFFERENT.
DIFFERENT HOW?
WE DO THINGS...
WE DO DIFFERENT THINGS.
SO, LIKE, WHAT,
YOU'RE FROM EUROPE?
YOU KNOW HOW SOME FAMILIES
ARE MUSICAL AND SOME HAVE MONEY.
WELL, WE HAVE POWERS.
POWERS?
YEAH.
WHAT WAS THAT OUT THERE?
THAT WAS MACON.
HE HAD THE HOUSE "BOUND."
IT'S A SPELL TO PROTECT ME
WHEN HE'S NOT HERE.
A SPELL?
YEAH.
IT WON'T HAPPEN AGAIN.
OKAY.
LENA...
ARE YOU A WITCH?
NO.
[ SIGHS ]
I MEAN,
CALLING US "WITCHES"
IS LIKE CALLING
THE SMART KIDS "GEEKS"
OR THE ATHLETES "JOCKS."
WE PREFER THE TERM
"CASTER."
I DIDN'T MEAN TO BREAK
THOSE WINDOWS.
MY POWERS
ARE GETTING STRONGER.
I CAN'T ALWAYS CONTROL IT.
YOU LOOK NAUSEOUS.
YOU WANT A COOKIE?
THE SUGAR WILL HELP.
I MADE THESE LAST NIGHT.
FROM A COOKIE MIX.
OKAY.
WHAT ABOUT THIS?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU DON'T KNOW?
NO.
IT WASN'T ME.
I MEAN,
IT WAS SOMETHING ELSE.
SOMETHING HAPPENS
WHEN WE BOTH HOLD IT.
OKAY.
HOLD ON A MINUTE.
SATAN HAS NOTHING TO DO
WITH Y'ALL, RIGHT?
THAT IS SUCH A MORTAL THING
TO SAY.
GOD.
WELL, THERE IS EVIL, LENA.
YES, THERE ARE EVIL CASTERS,
ETHAN.
I MEAN, ARE YOU TRYING TO SAY
THAT THERE ARE NO EVIL MORTALS?
ONLY DIFFERENCE IS,
YOU ALL MADE UP SOMEBODY ELSE
TO BLAME FOR IT.
I'M JUST TRYING TO
FIGURE THIS OUT.
SO, YOU HAVE POWERS,
OKAY?
WHAT ELSE CAN YOU DO?
[ WIND WHISTLES ]
I COLLECT POETRY.
I'M NOT MEANT TO SHOW A MORTAL
ANY OF THIS.
IT'S OKAY.
NO.
I SHOULDN'T HAVE.
YOU KNOW,
I JUST HATE HIDING ALL THE TIME.
FEELING LIKE
EVERYBODY'S WHISPERING ABOUT ME.
BEING AFRAID OF PEOPLE
FINDING OUT I'M THIS FREAK.
SOMETIMES YOU JUST WANT TO
BE NORMAL.
WHAT ARE YOU SMILING AT?
LENA, YOU'RE A MIRACLE.
WHY WOULD YOU EVER
WANT TO BE NORMAL?
YOU'RE NOT
WHAT I EXPECTED.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
DON'T GET MAD,
BUT I'VE DREAMT ABOUT YOU TOO.
I JUST DIDN'T THINK
YOU WERE REAL.
Macon: LENA?
OH, IT'S MACON.
YOU'VE GOT TO GO.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME?
IT SCARES ME.
DOESN'T IT SCARE YOU?
YOU WANNA GO OUT
WITH ME?
[ LAUGHS ]
WAIT.
AM I GOING OUT THE WINDOW?
[ RUMBLING ]
[ VINES CREAKING ]
WHOA.
CAN YOU MAKE ANYTHING GROW?
LENA?
GET OUT.
OKAY.
HOW ABOUT FRIDAY, MOVIES?
FRIDAY, I CAN'T.
IT'S A HOLIDAY.
WHAT HOLIDAY?
IT'S A HARVEST THING.
FAMILY COMING FROM OUT OF TOWN.
OKAY. SATURDAY.
LENA!
I DON'T KNOW.
HURRY UP!
SAY YES.
YES.
CAN I SEE YOU
TOMORROW?
I DON'T KNOW.
GET OUT OF HERE!
OKAY.
[ GRUNTS ]
ETHAN?
YEAH?
PROMISE ME IT'LL BE A REALLY
NORMAL, AWKWARD TEENAGER DATE.
I SWEAR.
I WON'T EVEN CALL YOU AFTER.
JERK.
WITCH.
JOCK.
[ GROANS ]
SEE YOU TOMORROW.
YOU COULD HAVE MADE A LADDER,
YOU KNOW.
[ ENGINE SHUTS OFF ]
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
KEEP YOUR DISTANCE.
THANK YOU KINDLY
FOR YOUR COURTEOUS WELCOME.
I FELT SOMETHING TONIGHT.
I'VE BEEN FEELING SOMETHING
EVERY NIGHT
SINCE YOU BROUGHT
THAT GIRL HERE.
WELL, IT'S THE ONLY PLACE LEFT
I HAVE TO PROTECT HER.
SO YOU BRING DARKNESS
TO THIS TOWN.
I CAN FEEL IT LIKE A HAND
TWISTING MY INSIDES.
WELL, THAT'S NOT LENA!
SARAFINE?
YOU SAID SHE WAS GONE
FOR GOOD.
YEAH.
WELL, WE...WE DID HAVE
AN AGREEMENT, BUT...
SHE'S BEEN SHADOWING LENA
FOR THE PAST YEAR.
AND THERE HAVE BEEN
SOME ACCIDENTS.
MACON, NO DANGER
BETTER COME TO THAT BOY
BECAUSE OF YOUR KIND.
YEAH, WELL, THEN YOU KEEP HIM
ON A LEASH!
WHAT HAPPENED
AT GREENBRIER?
I DON'T KNOW!
LENA WAS HYSTERICAL.
BOY WAS UNCONSCIOUS.
I BROUGHT HIM HOME,
CALLED YOU.
YOU'RE THE SEER.
YOU TELL ME WHAT HAPPENED!
THIS IS THE SACRED PLACE
OF MY ANCESTORS.
YOU HEAR?
YOU WANT SOME ANSWERS,
YOU SHOW ME SOME RESPECT.
YEAH.
I...I APOLOGIZE.
ETHAN HAD
SOME KIND OF CHARM.
IT HAD A DUCHANNES POWER
IN IT.
WELL, THAT WOULD BE
SARAFINE.
MAYBE SHE'S USING THE CHARM
TO GET TO LENA THROUGH THE BOY.
YOU TELL THEM I HAVE TO KNOW
WHAT SARAFINE'S UP TO.
YOU KNOW,
IT WOULDN'T BREAK YOUR FACE
TO ASK FOR SOME HELP
INSTEAD OF EXPECTING IT,
LIKE YOUR FAMILY'S BEEN DOING
WITH MINE FOR TOO MANY YEARS.
NOW, DON'T YOU ROLL YOUR EYES
AT ME.
THEN PLEASE ASK THEM KINDLY
WHAT SARAFINE IS UP TO.
BROUGHT YOUR FAVORITES,
UNCLE ABNER.
SHRIMP AND GRITS.
FRIED OYSTERS.
AND A COCONUT PIE.
HMM.
NO WONDER
HE'S NO LONGER WITH US.
PAY NO ATTENTION TO HIM,
UNCLE.
[ SIGHS ]
UNCLE ABNER, WE ARE IN NEED
OF YOUR INTERCESSION.
ALONG WITH AUNT IDA
AND AUNTIE MAY...
I HUMBLY CALL UPON
YOUR SPIRITS.
WHAT ARE THEY SAYING?
NOTHING.
NOTHING YET.
TELL THEM THEY HAVE TO HELP US
STOP SARAFINE.
"SOME THINGS
CANNOT BE STOPPED."
[ ROCK MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ SIREN WAILING ]
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
Lena:
THIS IS YOUR FAVORITE SPOT?
Ethan:
IT'S ALL ABOUT THE SIGN.
YOU SEE UP THERE?
MM-HMM.
THAT'S THE ROAD TO FREEDOM.
[ CHUCKLES ]
MY MAMA USED TO SAY,
"GET OUT OF THIS TOWN
AS SOON AS YOU CAN.
"GO FIND OUT
HOW OTHER PEOPLE LIVE AND THINK
BEFORE YOU FIND A PLACE
THAT'S YOURS."
AND I'D SAY,
"MOM, UM, I'M 9.
HOW DO I DO THAT?"
LITTLE ETHAN.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
SO THAT'S WHEN SHE TOOK ME
TO THE LIBRARY.
AND, UM, SHE SAID,
"ETHAN, THIS IS MY CHURCH.
"THIS IS WHERE MY FAMILY GOES
TO CELEBRATE WHAT'S HOLY --
IDEAS."
OH, WOW.
SORRY.
[ LAUGHS ]
DON'T KNOW
WHERE THAT CAME FROM.
[ SIGHS ]
I WISH I'D KNOWN HER.
LET'S GET OUT OF HERE.
LET'S GO.
WHERE?
ANYWHERE.
LENA, MOST PEOPLE SPEND
THEIR ENTIRE LIVES
WAITING FOR A MOMENT
THAT'S GONNA CHANGE EVERYTHING.
IT NEVER HAPPENS.
WE CAN START OUR LIVES
RIGHT NOW, OKAY?
WE JUST GOT TO SAY YES.
WE JUST GOT TO GET IN THE CAR
AND JUST GO.
I CAN'T DO THAT.
WHY?
WHEN I TURN 16...
I MIGHT NOT EVEN BE
WHO I AM NOW.
WHY?
WHAT -- WHAT COULD HAPPEN
BESIDES GETTING
YOUR FIRST HANGOVER?
WHEN A FEMALE CASTER
TURNS 16,
WE FACE WHAT THEY CALL
THE CLAIMING.
MY POWERS
WILL BE CLAIMED
FOR EITHER THE LIGHT
OR THE DARK,
DEPENDING ON
MY TRUE NATURE...
WHATEVER I'M DESTINED
TO BE.
THAT'S -- THAT'S WHY MACON
BROUGHT ME HERE.
WAIT.
WHAT'S MACON?
HE'S A DARK CASTER,
BUT HE'S CHOOSING TO BE LIGHT
FOR ME NOW.
HE CAN CHOOSE?
THEN WHY CAN'T YOU?
THEY SAY THAT A FEMALE CASTER'S
TRUE NATURE CHOOSES FOR HER.
I DON'T KNOW WHY.
BACK UP.
WAIT A MINUTE.
YOU'RE WORRIED
THAT WHEN YOU TURN 16,
YOU'RE GONNA BE AN EVIL...
BITCH...WITCH CASTER?
I HAVE 75 DAYS LEFT, ETHAN.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I'LL BE.
I DON'T KNOW
WHO I REALLY AM INSIDE.
Mrs. Lincoln:
NOW, IN THE LAST YEAR,
LENA DUCHANNES HAS BEEN
IN THREE DIFFERENT SCHOOLS
IN THREE DIFFERENT TOWNS.
I-I CHECKED.
AND IN EVERY SINGLE ONE
OF THEM SCHOOLS,
THEY HAD ACCIDENTS,
THEY HAD UNNATURAL WEATHER,
THEY HAD...
WELL, THEY EVEN HAD DEATHS.
[ CROWD MURMURING ]
NOW, I HAVE A PETITION HERE
SIGNED BY OVER 300 GATLIN
PARENTS WHO DEMAND...
DEMAND THAT LENA DUCHANNES
BE EXPELLED...
EXCUSE ME.
...AND FURTHERMORE THAT
THE RAVENWOOD PROPERTY BE --
[ CROWD MURMURING ]
OH, MY GOD, MAMA.
EXCUSE ME
FOR MY UNTIMELY INTERVENTION.
PRINCIPAL HERBERT.
MAYOR SNOW.
AND THE REVEREND STEPHENS,
I BELIEVE.
YES, SIR.
MM.
MRS. LINCOLN.
HOW DARE YOU...
ENTER THE HOUSE
OF THE LORD?
SINCE MY FAMILY OWN
THE LAND IT'S BUILT ON...
AND I UNDERSTOOD THIS
TO BE AN OCCASION
FOR ALL MEMBERS
OF THE COMMUNITY.
NOW, I'M SURE
Y'ALL HAVE BETTER THINGS TO DO
ON SUCH A BEAUTIFUL DAY,
SO I'LL BE BRIEF.
THE ACCUSATIONS
AGAINST MY NIECE --
ALL SPURIOUS LIES.
FOR, ACCORDING TO
THE WEATHER CHANNEL --
AND YOU CAN VERIFY THIS
ON GOOGLE --
THERE WERE UNSEASONABLY STRONG
GUSTS FROM THE EAST,
WHICH CAUSED UNTOLD DESTRUCTION
UP AND DOWN
THE SOUTH CAROLINA COAST.
SO MY NIECE WILL GO BACK
TO THE INSTITUTION
THAT GATLIN PRESUMES TO CALL
EDUCATIONAL,
AND SHE WILL BE PERSECUTED
NO LONGER.
I THANK YOU ALL
FOR YOUR COOPERATION.
Mrs. Lincoln: YOU HAVE NO RIGHT
TO TELL US WHAT TO DO.
NO MATTER
HOW MUCH MONEY YOU HAVE.
OH, MRS. LINCOLN,
YOU'RE RIGHT.
MY WEALTH SHOULD OFFER ME
NO ADVANTAGE.
HOWEVER, SINCE MY ANCESTORS
FOUNDED GATLIN,
MY HOLDINGS DO GIVE ME
A LITTLE LEVERAGE.
FOR EXAMPLE,
IF I WERE TO DONATE THE OLD MILL
TO, SAY,
A DRUG REHABILITATION CENTER...
OH, MY GOD.
[ CROWD MURMURING ]
THERE AGAIN, I OWN THE LAND
THE WAYWARD DOG MOTEL STANDS ON.
ITS CLOSURE WOULD CAUSE
A LITTLE INCONVENIENCE
TO ONE OR TWO
OF YOU GENTLEMEN.
YOU'D HAVE TO TRAVEL OUT OF TOWN
TO SEE YOUR LADY FRIENDS...
WHEN YOUR WIVES BELIEVE
THAT YOU ARE ATTENDING
YET ANOTHER MEETING
OF THE AMERICAN CIVIL WAR
REENACTMENT SOCIETY.
SO MIGHT I PRESUME
THAT THIS MATTER
IS NOW COMFORTABLY LAID TO REST?
I'M NOT AFRAID OF YOU
OR YOUR EVIL KIND.
GOD OUR CREATOR
WILL CONDEMN YOU TO HELLFIRE
ALONG WITH TERRORISTS,
ATHEISTS, HOMOSEXUALS,
DEMOCRATS, LIBERALS,
SOCIALISTS...
GREENPEACE AND ALL THE OTHER
UNNATURAL ABOMINATIONS.
MY DEAR MRS. LINCOLN.
IF I WERE YOU, I WOULD WELCOME
ANY KIND OF FIRE.
MIGHT GIVE YOU
THE OPPORTUNITY
TO BURN THAT UNFORTUNATE HAT
YOU'RE WEARING.
[ CROWD MURMURING ]
[ BELL TOLLS, WOMAN LAUGHING ]
[ LAUGHTER ECHOING ]
SARAFINE.
[ LAUGHING ]
WELL, I WOULD HAVE EXPECTED
TO FIND YOU
IN SOMETHING
A LITTLE MORE CHIC.
OH, COME ON, MACON.
SHE'S PERFECT!
SHE'S A PILLAR
OF THE COMMUNITY.
YOU'RE RIGHT ABOUT THE HAT,
THOUGH.
ISN'T IT TRAGIC?
BUT IF YOU BORROW THE BODY,
YOU HAVE TO BORROW THE CLOSET.
AND, MY DEAR,
YOU WOULD THINK THE WOMAN
INVENTED THE HOUSECOAT.
[ CHUCKLES ]
SO, LET'S SEE NOW.
HAVE YOU MISSED
YOUR LITTLE SISTER?
NO.
OH.
DON'T BE UNKIND.
YOU USED TO LOVE
PLAYING IN THE DARK.
REMEMBER?
I CAN FEEL
YOUR POWERS WANING.
HMM.
THAT'S SO SAD.
THEY'RE FADING.
AND YOU KNOW WHY THAT IS.
THAT'S WHAT COMES OF PRETENDING
TO BE SOMETHING YOU'RE NOT.
OH!
DADDY'S TIE-PIN.
THAT IS SO SWEET.
THE CURSE IS GONNA CLAIM HER,
MACON.
YOU'RE NOT QUITE SURE,
THOUGH, ARE YOU?
MM.
IF YOU WERE CERTAIN,
THEN WHY BRING THE BOY INTO IT?
I DIDN'T BRING THE BOY
INTO IT.
LOVE BROUGHT HIM IN.
LENA AND THE MORTAL HAVE BEEN
ON THEIR WAY TO EACH OTHER
SINCE THE DAY
THEY WERE BORN.
THEY HAVE THAT TERRIBLE THING,
"DESTINY."
EVEN YOUR LILA
SENSED THAT.
AND YOU KNOW
THE LAW OF THE CURSE --
NO CASTER
MAY LOVE A MORTAL.
MIND YOU, IT COULDN'T HAVE
WORKED OUT BETTER
IF I HAD PLANNED IT.
THAT FIRST LOVE --
OH, SUCH JOY.
SUCH BEAUTY.
[ Voice breaking ]
AND THAT FIRST HEARTBREAK.
SO BITTER.
SO PAINFUL.
IT'S ENOUGH TO TURN
ANY GIRL DARK...
MORTAL OR CASTER.
[ LAUGHS ]
I'M SO EXCITED.
LENA'S BIRTHDAY
IS GONNA FALL
ON THE MOST POWERFUL SOLSTICE
IN 5,000 YEARS!
MORE ENERGY IS GONNA BE RELEASED
THAN EVER BEFORE,
AND THIS EARTH'S CYCLE
WILL BE OVER.
SHE'S GONNA BE MORE POWERFUL
THAN EITHER OF US, MACON,
AND SHE WILL LEAD US ALL.
TOWARD WHAT?
AN AGE WITHOUT HIDING.
I'M -- I'M SO...
TIRED OF HIDING!
THESE PARASITES HAVE HAD
THEIR OWN WAY LONG ENOUGH,
DON'T YOU THINK?
OH!
HERE'S A GOOD GAME.
NAME ONE SPECIES
THAT'LL MISS THEM.
SEE?
YOU CAN'T!
BECAUSE MORTALS DO NOTHING
BUT CONSUME AND DESTROY.
THEY INVENT IDEAS...
LIKE GOD AND LOVE
AND RIGHTEOUSNESS...
AND THEN THEY USE
THOSE SAME IDEAS
TO KILL ANYONE
WHO DISAGREES WITH THEM.
YOU REALLY WANT TO HANG OUT
WITH THOSE PEOPLE?
THEY PRAY
WITHOUT TRUE BELIEFS
AND THEN WONDER
WHY THEIR SPELLS DON'T WORK.
THEY DON'T EVEN VALUE
THEIR PATHETIC LITTLE LIVES
TILL SECONDS BEFORE IT'S TAKEN
FROM THEM.
POOR THINGS.
IT'S OUR TURN, MACON.
DARLIN', COME BACK.
COME BACK.
LENA WILL PUT AN END
TO THEM.
NO.
LENA WILL NOT TURN DARK.
SHE'S TOO STRONG.
SHE HAS GOT NO CHOICE
IN THE MATTER, MY DARLIN'.
THE CURSE
HAS ALREADY BEGUN.
NO.
THAT IS A LIE!
[ CROWD MURMURING ]
WHAT'S A LIE,
MR. RAVENWOOD?
MY APOLOGIES.
LENA WILL RETURN TO SCHOOL.
AND THAT IS AN END OF IT.
[ CROWD MURMURING ]
Man: KEEP IT MOVING.
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
WOW!
YOU AND LENA DUCHANNES.
YEAH.
DON'T TELL ANYBODY.
AW, COME ON, AND MISS THE CHANCE
TO SEE EMILY SHIT NAILS?
I BET LENA
COULD ACTUALLY DO THAT.
WHAT?
♪
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
WHICH ONE OF YOU LUCKY BOYS
IS ETHAN WATE?
WELL?
WHICH ONE OF YOU HAS THE POWER
OF TONGUE?
M-ME AM.
I'M...ME ETHAN.
ETHAN!
DO I KNOW YOU?
NOT A BIT.
I'M RIDLEY DUCHANNES.
FOLLOW ME.
YOU'RE A RELATIVE
OF LENA'S?
HONEY, YOU ARE LOOKING AT
THE RELATIVE.
UH, OH --
THIS IS MY FRIEND LINK.
SINCERE PLEASURE,
LINK.
H-- OH, EP--
I-- WA-- HUSH...
GET IN.
OH, I-I WASN'T INVITED.
I DON'T THINK
HER UNCLE WOULD, UH, LIKE --
TRUST ME,
FAMILY'S DYING TO MEET YOU.
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER, REVS ]
[ ENGINE SHUTS OFF ]
RAVENWOOD.
BEEN A LONG TIME.
[ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
LENA AND I ARE MORE LIKE SISTERS
THAN COUSINS.
I'M SURPRISED
SHE HASN'T MENTIONED ME.
BUT THEN, I'M SURE
I COULDN'T COUNT HIGH ENOUGH
ALL THE THINGS
LENA HASN'T MENTIONED.
[ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
OH.
WHY, THANK YOU, KIND SIR.
I LOOK OKAY?
ALWAYS GET A LITTLE NERVOUS
SEEING THE FAMILY.
YOU HAVE LOVELY EYES.
MM.
YOU'RE LUCKY
THOSE LIPS ARE SPOKEN FOR.
MAY I?
MM.
SUCH A GENTLEMAN, TOO.
NIGHT, MOTHER.
RIDLEY!
OH...
[ DOORS CLOSE ]
...I TOLD YOU TO STAY AWAY.
WHY, I COULDN'T MISS
A HOLIDAY WITH MY FAMILY,
NOW, COULD I, MAMA?
WELL, WELL.
RIDLEY, MY DEAR.
WHAT AN UNPLEASANT
SURPRISE.
UNCLE MACON.
HOW OLD AND WEAK
YOU LOOK.
I DISTINCTLY REMEMBER
FORGETTING TO INVITE YOU.
AND I TOLD YOU NEVER TO CROSS
THIS THRESHOLD AGAIN!
[ GRUNTS ]
WHAT?
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE
TO HIM?
INVITED HIM TO DINNER
WITH THE FOLKS IS ALL.
WELL...
WHY DON'T YOU ESCORT
YOUR UNDERDRESSED FRIEND
INTO THE DINING ROOM?
I WASN'T --
DEL.
WHA --
Ridley:
HELLO, CUZ.
DON'T YOU LOOK PRETTY.
ETHAN?
[ STAMMERING ]
AW.
AIN'T THAT SWEET?
HE'S ALL CHOKED UP.
MUST BE LOVE.
OH!
MACON...
IT'S ALL RIGHT, LENA.
SHE CAN DO
NO REAL HARM HERE.
YOU SURE ABOUT THAT,
MACON?
DON'T YOU SASS YOUR UNCLE,
NOW!
DEL, WHY DON'T YOU GET
TWO PLACE SETTINGS
FOR OUR UNINVITED GUESTS?
THANK YOU.
YOU SIT NEAR ME,
SUGAR.
SIT RIGHT OVER HERE.
Larkin: SIS?
LARKIN!
ETHAN, THIS IS
MY YOUNGER BROTHER LARKIN.
I DIDN'T THINK
I'D BE SEEING YOU HERE.
AND WHO IS THE STIFF?
LARKIN, MEET ETHAN WATE.
WELL, WELL.
[ GASPS ]
AND THIS IS
OUR DEAR SWEET GRAMMA...
WHO WE ALL
JUST LOVE TO DEATH.
WE WEREN'T EXPECTING YOU,
CHILD.
LET ME HAVE A LOOK
AT YOU.
[ WARBLING ]
[ GROANS ]
WHY IS IT, RIDLEY,
THAT WHEN I LOOK INTO YOUR EYES,
ALL I CAN SEE ARE HERS?
YOU TWO ARE AS THICK AS THIEVES,
AREN'T YOU?
MOTHER!
[ SILVERWARE CLATTERS ]
[ GROANS ]
HOW ABOUT A LITTLE MUSIC,
AND WHY DON'T WE ALL JUST
SIT DOWN AND ENJOY OURSELVES?
AND LET'S HAVE SOME WINE.
[ "THEME FROM 'A SUMMER PLACE'"
PLAYS ]
Aunt Del:
SOMETHING TO DRINK?
HERE.
ALLOW ME.
[ GASPS ]
MAMA'S HOMEMADE MACAROONS.
OH!
I'VE MISSED THESE.
SO, CUZ, ANY BIG PLANS
FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY?
NOTHING TO CONCERN
YOURSELF WITH.
YOU WON'T BE INVITED,
"CUZ."
WELL, LENA, DARLIN',
YOU SHOULD.
BE CONCERNED, THAT IS.
SUCH AN IMPORTANT
BIRTHDAY.
THAT'S ENOUGH, RIDLEY.
I HAD HOPED THAT WE'D HAVE
A HOLIDAY MEAL
THAT WE WOULD ALL SURVIVE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
JUST TO BE WITH MY FAMILY
AGAIN, CUZ.
YOU'VE BEEN CLAIMED
BY THE DARK.
YOU'RE NO LONGER PART
OF THIS FAMILY.
RIDLEY, SWEETHEART, THERE'S
NOTHING WE CAN DO FOR YOU NOW.
I'M SO SORRY.
NO HARD FEELINGS, MAMA.
BUT LENA AND I
ARE THE SAME.
I WONDER,
WHEN SHE GOES DARK...
...WILL YOU SHUT HER OUT
TOO?
THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOU THINK YOU CAN KEEP LENA
SO GOOD, SO INNOCENT?
WASN'T I THE SAME
BEFORE I WAS CLAIMED?
AS I RECALL,
YOU WERE A SPOILED BRAT
FROM THE MOMENT YOU WERE BORN.
MAYBE I WAS JUST
UNLOVED.
I DID THE BEST I COULD.
AND LOOK AT WHAT I AM NOW.
OH, THAT'S RIGHT.
BLAME THE MOTHER.
YOU THINK LENA IS A GOOD GIRL
NOW, BUT IT WON'T MATTER.
EVEN IF HER TRUE NATURE
DOESN'T CLAIM HER FOR THE DARK,
THE CURSE WILL.
IT'S ALREADY STARTED.
I'M WARNING YOU.
WHAT CURSE?
PAY NO MIND TO HER LIES.
YOU KNOW IT'S TRUE.
[ GASPS ]
AW, LOOK AT MY MANNERS.
HERE, HONEY.
LET ME SERVE YOU.
[ GASPS ]
GET AWAY FROM HIM!
[ RATTLING ]
OH, REALLY, CUZ?
LENA, WILL YOU STOP THIS?!
STOP IT!
[ SILVERWARE CLATTERING ]
[ LAUGHS ]
AW, JUST ANOTHER GOOD GIRL
GONE BAD, I GUESS.
Gramma: LENA, CHILD,
THERE'S NO NEED FOR THIS.
WILL YOU STOP THIS
IMMEDIATELY?!
[ GASPS ]
BREAKING WINDOWS ON POOR,
HELPLESS LITTLE MORTALS!
SHE'S ALREADY CLOSER TO THE DARK
THAN I WAS!
YOU KNOW THAT'S A LIE!
I WANT YOU OUT OF HERE!
[ LAUGHS ]
Aunt Del: RIDLEY, DON'T MAKE ME
GET UP FROM THIS TABLE!
I AM SO SICK
OF EVERYONE TREATING YOU
LIKE YOU'RE
SOMETHING SPECIAL!
THERE'S NOTHING SPECIAL
ABOUT YOU!
GO ON,
YOU TELL HER, MACON!
YOU KNOW
HOW SHE WILL BE CLAIMED!
I SAID GET AWAY
FROM MY BOYFRIEND, YOU WITCH.
[ SCREAMS ]
Gramma:
[ SIGHS ]
OH, LORD.
[ Weakly ]
BOYFRIEND, HUH?
IS HE GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT?
Gramma:
HE'LL BE FINE.
WHAT CURSE
WAS RIDLEY TALKING ABOUT?
RIDLEY WAS JUST TELLING STORIES
TO GET YOUR RAGE GOING,
TO LOSE CONTROL.
YOU MUSTN'T LET HER.
LARKIN, HELP ME
TAKE HIM TO MY ROOM.
OH, HE WILL.
[ LAUGHS ]
SITTING THERE EATING
THROUGH A CASTER COMBAT,
LIKE YOU'RE TWO SANDWICHES SHY
OF A PICNIC.
Larkin: BETTER BE A SANDWICH
WHEN I GET BACK.
I'M STILL HUNGRY.
DO YOU SEE THE WAY
SHE LOOKS AT THE BOY?
THERE'S NO GETTING
IN BETWEEN THEM NOW.
THEN IT HAS BEGUN.
[ INSECTS CHIRPING ]
Ethan:
HEY THERE.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
LIKE I WAS IN A TORNADO
INSIDE A DINING ROOM.
NO BIG DEAL.
I'M SO SORRY ABOUT RIDLEY.
I DIDN'T KNOW SHE WAS BACK.
YEAH.
SHE'S SORT OF A BITCH,
ISN'T SHE?
SHE'S A SIREN.
SHE CAN MAKE MORTALS SEE, THINK,
OR DO WHATEVER SHE WANTS...
ESPECIALLY MEN.
ISN'T THAT, LIKE, THE WORKING
DEFINITION OF A BITCH?
MM-HMM.
SHE WASN'T ALWAYS
LIKE THAT.
WE WERE LIKE SISTERS.
YOU KNOW?
TRAVELED TOGETHER SO MUCH
WE SHARED THE SAME SUITCASE.
DID HOMEWORK,
WATCHED DISNEY.
WE WERE JUST KIDS.
Lena: THE NIGHT RIDLEY
TURNED 16, SHE RAN AWAY.
SHE SAID SHE COULD FEEL HERSELF
TURNING DARK.
SHE SAID SHE HAD TO GET AWAY
BEFORE SHE HURT
ANYBODY SHE LOVED...
BEFORE SHE HURT ME.
I FOLLOWED HER.
THEN IT HAPPENED.
[ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
WHOO-HOO!
I SAW IT ALL.
SHE LOVED ME.
I KNOW IT.
IT'S NOT FAIR
WHAT HAPPENED TO HER.
AND THE SAME THING
COULD HAPPEN TO ME.
IT WON'T.
DID YOU SEE ME TONIGHT?
I CAN'T CONTROL MYSELF.
LENA, I DON'T BELIEVE
THAT WE HAVE ONE FATE
AND NO CHOICE.
WE MAKE OUR OWN LIVES.
Ethan: TWO, PLEASE.
THANK YOU.
THIS IS LENA.
LENA.
Man: HI, LENA.
Lena: HI.
HERE.
I GOT TO GIVE YOU THE MONEY.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
THANKS.
THERE YOU GO.
YOU GOOD?
YOUR KIDS ARE GOOD?
OH, YEAH.
GOOD.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
Woman:
YOU GOT THE TICKETS?
HI.
Boy:
GET A LOAD OF THIS.
[ CHUCKLES ]
YOU KNOW, MAYBE YOU HAVE
ETHAN FOOLED, BUT NOT ME.
OH, SHUCKS.
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
AH, CHILL, GIRL.
CHILL, CHILL.
[ BIG-BAND MUSIC PLAYING ]
Emily:
SEE THE LOOK ON HER?
[ LAUGHS ]
I SEE
RIGHT THROUGH HER.
HI.
JUST, UH, JUST ONE, PLEASE.
Man:
ALRIGHTY.
THERE YOU GO.
DO NOT LET THEM BOTHER YOU,
OKAY?
Man:
BEFORE WE SET OUT,
HELP YOURSELVES
TO SOME SCRAMBLED EGGS
AND FRENCH TOAST
RIGHT HERE...
YOU BY YOURSELF?
Man #2: YEAH.
I'VE BEEN UP SINCE 5:00.
FEELING PRETTY GOOD,
THOUGH.
MM.
YOU WANT MILK DUDS?
WHAT DO YOU PUT THEM
IN YOUR POCKET FOR?
I HAVE TO HIDE SOME FOR MYSELF,
BECAUSE LINK NEVER SHARES.
[ CHUCKLES ]
Man: ALL RIGHT.
YEAH. I'VE BEEN DOING BETTER.
...ALL BY MYSELF.
OH.
I'M SO SORRY.
I DIDN'T REALIZE
I HAD THAT.
NO, IT'S OKAY.
I WANNA SEE.
[  KNOCK ON DOOR]
Woman:
BE RIGHT THERE.
[ VIOLIN PLAYS ]
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
Soldier:
YEAH, WHATEVER YOU CAN FIND!
THERE'S GOLD IN THERE
AND SILVER!
GET IT ALL!
HURRY UP
BEFORE IT'S ALL GONE!
[ SNARE DRUMS PLAYING ]
[ SHOUTING CONTINUES ]
Woman:
[ SCREAMS ]
ETHAN!
[ MAN GROANS ]
DON'T YOU DARE...
OKAY.
DON'T YOU DARE GO ANYWHERE.
DON'T YOU DARE,
ETHAN CARTER WATE!
COME BACK.
WAIT, ETHAN.
[ SNIFFLES ]
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
BODY OF MY BODY,
MARROW AND MIND,
SOUL OF MY SOUL,
TO OUR SPIRIT BIND,
BLOOD OF MY HEART,
MY TIDE, MY MOON,
MY SALVATION, MY DOOM!
[ GASPS ]
GENEVIEVE.
WAS I SHOT?
WHAT HAPPENED
TO YOUR EYES?
[ GROANING ]
[ GUNFIRE, EXPLOSIONS ]
FORM UP, COMPANY!
[ RIFLES COCK ]
[ MAN GRUNTS ]
Sarafine:
OH, MY DARLING LENA,
DO YOU SEE NOW
HOW YOU MUST BE CLAIMED?
WE ARE THE DESCENDANTS
OF GENEVIEVE.
HER DARK POWER IS IN OUR BLOOD!
OH, HOW I'VE MISSED YOU,
MY DAUGHTER.
YOUR MOTHER, SARAFINE,
HAS COME HOME FOR YOU.
Lena:
[ SCREAMS ]
[ CROWD MURMURING ]
GUESS SATAN HATES SEQUELS,
TOO.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S OVER.
[ SIGHS ]
THERE IS NO MORE.
IT'S SERVED ITS PURPOSE.
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Macon: LENA?
THE CURSE BEGAN WITH YOUR
GREAT-GREAT-GREAT GRANDMOTHER,
GENEVIEVE KATHERINE DUCHANNES.
SHE HAD THE TEMERITY
TO FALL IN LOVE WITH A MORTAL,
YOUR ANCESTOR,
ETHAN CARTER WATE.
IN 1864, HE DESERTED.
CAME HOME TO HIS GENEVIEVE.
BUT HE WAS KILLED
IN FRONT OF HER EYES,
BY UNION SOLDIERS
WHO WERE RANSACKING GREENBRIER
DURING THE BATTLE OF HONEY HILL.
AND IN HER MADNESS,
IN HER GRIEF,
SHE USED A SPELL
THAT IS FORBIDDEN TO US.
TO BRING HIM BACK TO LIFE.
A SPELL
THAT LEFT A CURSE?
NO CASTER
MAY REVERSE DEATH.
SO SHE LOST HER SOUL,
CONSUMED BY DARKNESS FOREVER.
Ethan:
BUT THE SPELL WORKED.
IF GENEVIEVE LOVED HIM,
WHY'D SHE KILL HIM?
IN THAT KIND OF DARKNESS,
THERE'S NOT EVEN A MEMORY
OF LOVE, ONLY POWER.
EVERYTHING HAS A PRICE.
Lena:
YOU TOLD ME MY MOTHER WAS DEAD.
YOU LIED TO ME.
WHY?
WHY?!
Amma: LENA!
OUR WORDS, OUR LANGUAGE
CANNOT EXPLAIN
ALL THAT THERE IS.
THERE ARE OTHER WAYS
SOMEONE CAN DIE TO US.
Macon:
NO, I'LL TELL HER.
YOUR MOTHER, SARAFINE,
IS THE MOST POWERFUL DARK CASTER
OF ALL OF US.
SHE LIVES IN THE DARKNESS,
IN THE SHADOWS.
IF SHE DOES APPEAR, IT'S
IN THE GUISE OF SOMEONE ELSE.
SHE HAS NO LOVE FOR YOU.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS TRYING TO
PROTECT YOU FROM.
SO I'M GONNA BE CLAIMED
FOR THE DARK NO MATTER WHAT?
NO, NOT NECESSARILY.
I KNOW YOUR TRUE NATURE.
IT'S STRONG.
SARAFINE RECOGNIZES IT
TOO.
SHE KNOWS
THAT WITHOUT THE CURSE,
YOUR TRUE NATURE WOULD CLAIM YOU
FOR THE LIGHT.
NO. I BELIEVE
THE CURSE CAN BE BROKEN.
BUT YOU NEED TO HAVE
A WILL THAT'S SO STRONG
YOU CONTROL
YOUR OWN NATURE.
THAT'S WHAT I TOLD HER.
THE FIRST THING YOU HAVE TO DO
IS TO GET RID OF HIM.
WAIT. WHAT?
SARAFINE'S USING YOU.
THAT'S NOT TRUE!
LISTEN TO ME, LENA.
NO, LISTEN TO ME, LENA.
ETHAN, MACON'S RIGHT!
IF YOU'RE TO BREAK
THIS CURSE,
YOU HAVE TO CONTROL
YOUR EMOTIONS.
AND LOVING THIS BOY
PUTS YOU IN TERRIBLE DANGER!
HOW COULD YOU KNOW?
YOU NEVER LOVED ANYONE.
YOU DESPISE MORTALS.
YOU NEVER EVEN HAD A FRIEND,
EVEN IN OUR WORLD.
HOW COULD YOU KNOW?
I KNOW THAT NO GOOD CAN COME
FROM US LOVING A MORTAL.
LENA, LISTEN TO ME.
THERE'S GOT TO BE A WAY,
ANOTHER WAY TO BREAK THE CURSE.
MACON!
[ THUD, CLATTERING ]
DON'T EVEN THINK THAT,
YOUNG MAN!
YOU'LL GET
THE BOTH OF YOU KILLED.
YOU HAVE TO GET OUT
OF HER LIFE.
DO YOU HEAR ME?
LENA...
SAY YOUR GOODBYES.
Ethan: MACON'S KEEPING LENA
AT RAVENWOOD.
HE WON'T LET ME SEE HER.
HE THINKS KEEPING US APART
IS THE BEST THING FOR HER.
BUT HE'S WRONG.
I KNOW LENA.
I KNOW HER LIKE I KNOW MYSELF.
AND I CAN FEEL HER
SLIPPING AWAY
INTO SOME PLACE
WHERE I CAN'T REACH HER.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
Woman:
GO AWAY! GO AWAY!
HI, DEAR.
OH.
HELLO, MRS. LINCOLN.
HI, DEAR.
HI. JUST A MINUTE.
[ DOORKNOB RATTLING ]
OH, DEAR.
THIS DOOR
SEEMS TO BE STUCK.
IT'S JUST THESE OLD HOUSES.
THEY'RE SUCH A NUISANCE.
YES, MA'AM.
THEY WARP.
[ CHUCKLES ]
LINK'S NOT HERE.
OH, I KNOW.
I KNOW.
HE'S AT
SAVANNAH SNOW'S PARTY,
WHICH IS WHERE
ALL THE KIDS ARE.
I HAD TO MAKE QUITE A NUMBER
OF PHONE CALLS
TO GET HIM AN INVITATION
ON ACCOUNT OF HIS...
WELL, ON ACCOUNT
OF HIS FRIENDSHIP WITH YOU.
UM, I'M SORRY YOU HAD TO GO
TO THAT TROUBLE, MA'AM.
WELL, YOU SHOULD BE
AT THAT PARTY, ETHAN,
KICKING UP YOUR HEELS
WITH YOUR REAL FRIENDS,
WITH THE CHILDREN
WHO BELONG IN THIS TOWN.
I'M NOT MUCH UP
FOR A PARTY TONIGHT, MA'AM.
OH, WELL, THAT'S A SHAME.
WELL, SEE,
I-I MADE YOU SOME BROWNIES.
I THOUGHT MAYBE I COULD COME IN
AND WE COULD TALK.
MY FIGHT'S NOT WITH YOU,
SON.
IT'S NOT.
NEVER HAS BEEN.
IT'S JUST THAT GIRL
WITH HER SEDUCTIVE QUIRKINESS,
AND YOU BEING MOTHERLESS
AND ALL.
MAY I COME IN?
NO, MA'AM.
I-I-I DON'T THINK SO.
DID I HEAR YOU...
CORRECTLY JUST THEN,
ETHAN?
DO I HAVE TO ASK YOU
AGAIN?
MAY I COME IN?
NO, MA'AM, YOU MAY NOT.
BUT I HAVE
MADE YOU BROWNIES!
I-I'VE MADE YOU BROWNIES
FROM SCRATCH!
[ GLASS SHATTERS ]
[ CREAKING ]
OH, WELL, SLAP MY ASS
AND CALL ME SALLY!
[ LAUGHS ]
LENA BOUND YOUR HOUSE.
OH, THAT'S SO SWEET.
AS IF.
I'M ON YOUR SIDE, SON.
WHAT'S A LITTLE CURSE
WHEN IT COMES TO TRUE LOVE?
ANYONE CAN SEE
YOU AND LENA ARE JUST MEANT
FOR EACH OTHER,
TILL DEATH DO YOU PART!
[ LAUGHING ]
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
[ WIND WHISTLING ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
LENA?
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
GET OUT
OF THIS HOUSE.
L-LENA.
KEEP HER BOUND.
LENA.
LENA,
CAN WE PLEASE JUST GO OUTSIDE
FOR ONE SECOND AND TALK?
I NEED --
GET OUT!
NO!
PLEASE, SON,
FOR YOUR OWN GOOD.
YOU SHOULD REALLY LISTEN
TO THEM.
NO!
I'M SICK OF LISTENING
TO YOUR FAMILY.
I HAVE BEEN CHASED,
SPUN, HYPNOTIZED,
PARALYZED, AND DAMN NEAR KILLED
BY YOUR FAMILY.
I'VE BEEN GOING OUT OF MY MIND
FOR THE LAST TWO WEEKS.
AND NOW YOUR MOTHER SHOWS UP
ON MY DOORSTEP
AND DAMN NEAR GIVES ME
A HEART ATTACK!
BUT YOU KNOW WHAT?
I DON'T CARE ABOUT THEM,
ABOUT THE CURSE.
YOU ARE NOT GOING DARK
AND YOU ARE NOT LOSING ME.
NO MATTER WHAT YOU DO,
NO MATTER WHAT THEY DO TO ME,
I'M STILL HERE.
NOW, WHAT DOES THAT
TELL YOU?
Macon: HOW COULD THE BOY
BREAK OUR SPELL?
HE HAS NO POWER.
IT'S NOT WE WHO PROTECT HER NOW.
IT'S THE BOY.
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
AMMA, WE NEED YOUR HELP.
WHY COME TO ME?
THE WAY YOU TALKED
ABOUT THE LOCKET,
ABOUT THE CURSE.
EXCUSE ME, MISS AMMA,
BUT I THINK YOU KNOW MORE
THAN YOU'RE SAYING.
PLEASE, AMMA.
THIS ISN'T THE PLACE YOU'RE
GONNA FIND ANYTHING YOU NEED.
MEET ME IN THE BACK.
[ RUMBLING ]
[ HUMMING ]
[ HINGES CREAK ]
Ethan: THIS MUST RUN
UNDER THE WHOLE TOWN.
THE WHOLE COUNTRY.
GATLIN IS LIKE THE CAPITAL
OF CASTER AMERICA.
IT USED TO BE
UNDER WASHINGTON, D.C.,
UNTIL NANCY REAGAN
MADE THEM MOVE.
SHE WAS THE ONLY MORTAL
THEY WERE EVER SCARED OF.
THEY KNOW A CASTER'S HERE.
AMMA, WHY DIDN'T YOU
TELL US ABOUT THIS?
A KEEPER
HAS TO BE ASKED.
A KEEPER,
AS IN YOU'RE A...
THE CASTER LIBRARY
HAS BEEN THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF SEERS LIKE ME
FOR GENERATIONS.
SOMETHING I HAD NO CHOICE
ABOUT EITHER, BY THE WAY.
AND THESE BOOKS HOLD
THE HISTORIES OF THE CASTERS
FROM AROUND THE WORLD,
THE LAWS THAT KEEP BALANCE
BETWEEN LIGHT AND DARK.
HEY!
GET AWAY FROM THAT!
MACON COMES HERE EVERY DAY
AND READS EVERY BOOK HE CAN
FOR THE FORBIDDEN SPELL.
HE FOUND NOTHING?
MNH-MNH.
BUT YOU CAN DO IT.
GOD GIVES US
WHAT WE CAN HANDLE,
EVEN IF WE DON'T BELIEVE IT
OURSELVES.
CLOSE YOUR EYES.
SEE WITH YOUR MIND
WHAT YOU'RE LOOKING FOR
AS IF YOU'VE
ALREADY FOUND IT.
[ HINGES CREAK ]
I KNEW IT.
"BOOK OF MOONS."
IT'S THE MOST POWERFUL BOOK
OF THE OTHERWORLD.
IT'S AS ALIVE
AS YOU OR ME.
STRONGEST OF EVERY SPELLS,
GOOD AND BAD.
DID MACON LOOK THROUGH IT?
NO. HE COULDN'T.
THE BOOK CHOOSES
WHO READS IT.
ITS LAW IS
"LIKE ATTRACTS LIKE."
THERE...
THERE'S NO WRITING.
OH, IT WON'T REVEAL ITSELF
SO EASY.
A CURSE THIS DARK
TAKES ITS TIME SHOWING ITSELF.
THE DARK WILL TEST YOU.
DON'T WORRY.
YOU'LL FIND IT.
JUST LOOK UNDER "HOW NOT
TO TURN INTO YOUR MOTHER."
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ SIGHS ]
COME ON.
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING ]
Ethan: I'VE BEEN TAKING LENA
TO THE CASTER LIBRARY
FOR WEEKS NOW.
BUT LENA'S GETTING DISCOURAGED.
THE LONGER THIS THING TAKES,
THE MORE I SEE A CHANGE IN HER.
[ THUD ]
WE'LL -- WE'LL FIND A WAY,
OKAY?
YOU'RE JUST A MORTAL.
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW?
HEY, I CAN MAKE WIND.
MAYBE NOT A HURRICANE,
BUT I --
WHY DON'T WE
JUST ADMIT IT?
A-ADMIT WHAT?
IT'S ALREADY STARTED.
I'M TURNING INTO A DARK BITCH.
I CAN FEEL IT.
NO, NO, NO.
LENA, YOU'RE JUST STRESSED.
IT'S NOT --
IT DOESN'T MATTER
WHAT CAUSES IT.
I'M TURNING, AND YOU'RE
JUST TOO STUPID TO SEE IT.
OKAY, NOW YOU'RE A BITCH.
[ SPITS ]
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
REALLY?
IS THIS NECESSARY?
I'M AGREEING WITH YOU!
[ SNIFFS ]
OKAY.
I'M JUST A DUMBASS MORTAL
WHO CAN'T MAKE HIS OWN THUNDER.
BUT I KNOW THERE'S NO WAY
WE'RE GONNA FIGURE THIS OUT
UNLESS YOU STOP FEELING
SO DAMN SORRY FOR YOURSELF
ALL THE TIME!
[ SCREAMS ]
GO AHEAD!
START AN EARTHQUAKE.
SEE WHERE IT GETS YOU.
EVERYBODY HAS TO DEAL WITH SHIT
IN THEIR LIVES, LENA.
[ Voice breaking ] WHAT ARE
YOU YELLING AT ME FOR?!
YOU WANT TO BE
A NORMAL HUMAN?
WHAT DO YOU THINK
THAT IS?
WE DON'T HAVE POWERS TO JUST
CHANGE THINGS WHENEVER WE LIKE.
BEING HUMAN
IS FEELING BAD!
[ Voice breaking ]
IT'S FEELING PISSED OFF!
IT'S FEELING SCARED
AND NOT BEING ABLE
TO DO ANYTHING ABOUT IT
UNTIL YOU DON'T FEEL THAT WAY
ANYMORE,
UNTIL YOU CAN JUST SEE
YOUR WAY OUT OF IT.
AND I YELLED AT YOU
BECAUSE I CARE ABOUT YOU.
THAT'S WHAT NORMAL PEOPLE DO
WHO LOVE EACH OTHER
WHEN ONE OF THEM
IS ACTING LIKE A BRAT!
NOW, WOULD YOU PLEASE
STOP RAINING ON ME?
[ SIGHS ]
♪ OOH, OOH
I'M SORRY.
YOU'VE GOT TO
GET AWAY FROM ME.
[ Voice breaking ]
I DON'T KNOW WHAT I DO.
IT JUST HAPPENS.
YOU STILL DON'T GET IT,
DO YOU?
I DON'T WANT TO BE
ANY FURTHER AWAY FROM YOU
THAN I AM RIGHT NOW,
ONE WAY OR ANOTHER.
I'M SCARED
I'M GONNA HURT YOU.
WELL, LOVE'S A RISK
FOR ANYBODY.
I MEAN "KILL YOU"
HURT YOU.
GO AHEAD.
KILL ME.
♪ OOH, OOH
♪ OOH
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLES ]
OH! AAH!
WHAT PART OF
"YOU CANNOT TOUCH IT
IF YOU ARE NOT A CASTER"
DON'T YOU UNDERSTAND?
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
THERE WERE CASTERS
IN THE CIVIL WAR?
CASTERS HAVE BEEN FIGHTING
ALONGSIDE MORTALS FOR CENTURIES,
EVERY WAR, EVERY SIDE.
JUST 'CAUSE THEY'RE SUPERNATURAL
DON'T MAKE THEM ANY SMARTER.
YOU KNOW,
WHAT I CAN'T FIGURE...
IS YOU GO TO CHURCH
EVERY SUNDAY?
MM-HMM.
HOW DO YOU BELIEVE IN ALL THIS
AND STILL BELIEVE IN GOD?
GOD CREATED ALL THINGS,
DIDN'T HE?
IT'S ONLY MEN THAT GO AND DECIDE
WHICH ONES ARE MISTAKES.
MY MOM CAME HERE,
DIDN'T SHE?
WITH MACON?
THEY MET HERE MANY TIMES.
MACON LOVED TEACHING HER
ABOUT HIS WORLD.
MACON LOVED HER, DIDN'T HE?
NO ONE KNOWS WHAT MACON CAN
AND CAN'T FEEL, BUT...
LILA SURE GOT CLOSE.
ETHAN?
SHE LOVED YOUR FATHER.
[ HARMONICA PLAYS ]
YOU GOING SOMEWHERE?
WHEREVER LENA IS.
EVEN IF THAT'S IN GATLIN.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
I DON'T KNOW WHAT POWER
YOU HAVE OVER LENA, BUT, UH...
I'VE COME TO ASK YOU TO...
LET HER GO.
I DON'T HAVE ANY POWER,
MACON.
I JUST LOVE HER.
THEN JUST PUT AN END
TO IT.
I CAN'T.
[ CHUCKLES ]
EVEN IF IT MEANS
DESTROYING
THE LENA YOU LOVE?
HM?
IT CAN'T,
BECAUSE THERE'S NO WAY
THAT WHAT LENA AND I FEEL
FOR EACH OTHER
IS GONNA TURN INTO SOMETHING
WRONG OR EVIL.
THERE'S NO WAY.
AS LONG AS I LIVE, I'LL NEVER
UNDERSTAND YOU CREATURES.
YOU HAVE NO REAL POWER.
YOU LIVE AT THE MERCY OF FORCES
OUTSIDE YOUR CONTROL...
AND YET YOU BELIEVE
THAT WHAT YOU FEEL
WILL SOMEHOW MAKE IT
ALL RIGHT.
GOTTA HAVE SOME FAITH,
MACON.
[ VIOLIN PLAYS ]
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING ]
[ WHISPERING STOPS ]
LENA?
YOU OKAY?
[ METAL CLANGS ]
LENA?
[ INDISTINCT WHISPERING ]
Ethan: LENA?
YEAH?
I-IS SOMETHING WRONG?
NO!
I-I THINK I FOUND SOMETHING.
YEAH? WHAT?
LET, L-LET ME SEE.
WELL, IT'S A LOT TO READ
AND A LOT TO TAKE IN,
AND I REALLY GOT TO CONCENTRATE.
OKAY.
SO I WAS WONDERING...
[ SIGHS ]
WELL, I'VE GOTTA DO IT
ON MY OWN, KIND OF.
YOU KNOW, AND IF YOU'RE HERE,
YOU'RE JUST GONNA DISTRACT ME.
AND I WAS WONDERING
IF YOU WOULDN'T MIND
GOING HOME NOW.
AND THEN, WHEN I'M DONE,
I'LL CALL YOU LATER.
IS THAT OKAY?
SURE.
WHATEVER YOU WANT,
OKAY?
THANKS.
I LOVE YOU.
OKAY.
I'LL TALK TO YOU LATER.
LENA?
Amma: HE'S GONE.
[ SOBS ]
[ HINGES CREAK ]
[ SOBBING ]
IT'S OKAY.
SHH.
TALK TO ME.
LENA.
THERE'S ONLY ONE WAY
TO BREAK THE CURSE.
GENEVIEVE USED
THE FORBIDDEN SPELL...
TO GIVE LIFE
TO THE ONE SHE LOVED.
TO BREAK THE CURSE,
THE ONE THAT I LOVE...
HAS TO DIE.
OH, GOD.
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO?
I WON'T HURT ETHAN.
NEVER.
THEY'RE ONLY OUR WORDS,
AMMA.
THEY CAN'T EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING.
THERE ARE ALL KINDS OF WAYS
SOMEONE YOU LOVE CAN DIE.
Ethan:
THAT'S ALL THE BOOK SAID?
YEAH.
ALL IT SAID
WAS TO REVERSE THE CURSE,
I NEED TO DO
THESE CERTAIN RITUALS,
CASTER STUFF,
EVERY NIGHT AND EVERY DAY
RIGHT UP UNTIL
THE CLAIMING.
AND WHATEVER HAPPENS,
HAPPENS.
HEY, WE KNOW
WHAT'S GONNA HAPPEN.
I WANT YOU TO DO SOMETHING
FOR ME.
BETWEEN NOW
AND MY BIRTHDAY,
I DON'T WANT TO THINK
ABOUT THE CLAIMING.
SEE?
NO TATTOO.
I JUST WANT TO BE
WITH YOU
AND DO NORMAL
BOYFRIEND-GIRLFRIEND STUFF.
GREAT.
WELL, HOW ABOUT TONIGHT IS,
UH, THE CHRISTMAS DANCE AND...
YOU COULD BE MY DATE.
IT'S P--
[ GASPS ]
IS ETHAN WATE
ASKING ME TO THE DANCE?
OH, MY GOD!
I'M THINKING ABOUT IT.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
NO, THEY'VE GOT PISS PUNCH
AND THE CHAPERONES GUARDING
THE MAKE-OUT STAIRS.
IT IS GOD-AWFUL.
[ LAUGHS ]
SOUNDS PERFECT.
♪
I STILL DON'T KNOW
WHAT TO GET YOU.
HUH?
I MEAN, WE -- WE DON'T
CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS.
OH. [ SIGHS ]
WHAT DO YOU WISH FOR EVERY YEAR
THAT YOU NEVER GET?
[ CHUCKLES ]
♪
OH, WELL, NO.
[ BOTH LAUGH ]
NO, IT'S NOT -- YOU'RE GONNA
THINK I'M SO NOT COOL.
THAT'S OKAY.
I DON'T THINK YOU'RE COOL NOW.
[ LAUGHS ]
UM...
♪
SNOW.
REALLY?
[ LAUGHS ]
YEAH?
WELL, YOU KNOW WHAT?
I JUST --
I ALWAYS WANTED ONE OF THOSE...
W-WHITE MOVIE CHRISTMASES.
I MEAN, LOOK AT THIS.
THIS IS, LIKE, PATHETIC.
THIS AIN'T CHRISTMAS.
[ LAUGHS ]
YOU KNOW THAT SET-UP'S
TOO EASY.
YEAH, I KNOW.
THAT'S WHAT
YOU REALLY WANT?
♪ WHEN I FEEL YOU IN MY HEAD
♪ I'LL TURN AWAY
TO MY NEEDLE AND THREAD ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I WAS
NEVER YOURS TO SEW ♪
♪ AND YOU WERE
NEVER MINE TO WEAVE ♪
♪ SO SAD THAT I SHOULD GO
♪ AND I PRETENDED
I WANTED TO LEAVE ♪
HOW AM I GONNA SURVIVE
A LIFETIME
OF YOU SURPRISING ME?
[ CHUCKLES ]
♪
♪ AND THE DREAM...
♪ JUST SEEMS ALL WRONG
HEAR HOW QUIET IT IS?
♪ THE FIGURE SAYS
♪ I'D RATHER STAY
AND BE RIGHT WITH YOU ♪
♪ BE ALL AND RUN...
Lena:
GOODBYE, ETHAN.
♪ WHEN I FEEL YOU
IN MY HEAD... ♪
[ SNORING ]
[ GROANS ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
Amma: ETHAN?
[ EXHALES DEEPLY ]
ETHAN!
DID YOU COME HOME LATE
FROM THE DANCE LAST NIGHT?
Ethan: UM...
CAN YOU GET THIS TURKEY
OUT OF THE REFRIGERATOR?
YEAH.
I DON'T, UH,
I DON'T REMEMBER.
I MUST HAVE BEEN
PRETTY TIRED.
BUT I SLEPT REAL GOOD FOR
THE FIRST TIME IN A LONG TIME.
OH, THAT'S GOOD.
LENA COMING OVER FOR CHRISTMAS?
WE GOT ENOUGH FOOD.
LENA?
LENA DUCHANNES.
LENA DUCHANNES?
[ CHUCKLES ]
WHY WOULD I INVITE
LENA DUCHANNES OVER FOR DINNER?
I BARELY KNOW HER.
SHE DOESN'T SPEAK
TO ANYBODY AT SCHOOL.
DO YOU KNOW HER?
EMILY'S MOM SAYS SHE WAS
IN A MENTAL INSTITUTION.
I DON'T KNOW WHETHER I TRUST
WHAT EMILY'S MOM SAYS,
BUT SHE'S KIND OF
A WEIRD GIRL.
HEY, EXCEPT FOR THAT DAMN
CIVIL WAR THING AND MEALS,
I'M STAYING IN MY BED
THE ENTIRE WINTER BREAK.
[ SLOW PIANO MUSIC PLAYING ]
Reverend Stephens:
I DON'T WANT TO PREACH TODAY.
INSTEAD,
I JUST WANT TO TALK TO YOU.
ABOUT A WORD
WE DON'T HEAR MUCH ANYMORE --
SACRIFICE.
IT'S NOT WHAT I'D CALL
A MODERN WORD.
PEOPLE HEAR THE WORD "SACRIFICE"
AND THEY BECOME AFRAID
THAT SOMETHING WILL BE
TAKEN AWAY FROM THEM.
OR THEY'LL HAVE TO
GIVE UP SOMETHING
THEY CAN'T LIVE WITHOUT.
"SACRIFICE," TO THEM,
MEANS "LOSS,"
IN A WORLD TELLING US
WE CAN HAVE IT ALL.
BUT I BELIEVE TRUE SACRIFICE...
IS A VICTORY.
BECAUSE IT REQUIRES
OUR FREE WILL,
TO GIVE UP SOMETHING
OR SOMEONE YOU LOVE,
FOR SOMETHING OR SOMEONE
YOU LOVE MORE THAN YOURSELF.
I WON'T LIE TO YOU --
IT'S A GAMBLE.
SACRIFICE WON'T TAKE AWAY
THE PAIN OF LOSS.
BUT IT WINS THE BATTLE
AGAINST BITTERNESS.
THE BITTERNESS
THAT DIMS THE LIGHT
ON ALL THAT IS OF TRUE VALUE
IN OUR LIVES.
[ MUSIC CONTINUES ]
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
[ ENGINE SHUTS OFF ]
Ridley: WHAT DO WE DO NOW,
AUNTIE SARAFINE?
SHE GAVE HIM UP.
Sarafine: SHE LOVES THAT BOY.
THE CURSE WILL STILL WORK.
BUT WE'LL NEED
HIS FRIEND.
OH, MY SUGAR DARLIN'?
HE'S READY TO GO
WHENEVER I CALL.
CAN I DO IT AGAIN?
YOU CAN'T TELL ANYONE.
PROMISE ME YOU WON'T TELL
A LIVING SOUL?
I WON'T, I SWEAR IT.
AHH.
OKAY, ONE LAST TIME.
TRY IT AGAIN.
[ GASPS ]
THAT IS SO COOL.
I'LL LET YOU KNOW
WHEN TO DO IT, SUGAR.
YOU'LL HEAR ME
LOUD AND CLEAR.
JUST LIKE YOU ALWAYS DO.
YOU HAVE NO IDEA
HOW MUCH I JUST LOVE YOU
TO DEATH RIGHT NOW.
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ]
READY? FIRE!
FIRE!
AWESOME.
[ WIND WHISTLES ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
COME IN.
ARE YOU READY
TO GET DRESSED?
IT'S REAL PRETTY.
[ EXPLOSIONS IN DISTANCE ]
YOU'VE DONE
THE RIGHT THING.
HOW WILL I KNOW
IF IT WORKED?
WHEN THE CURSE HAS BEEN PAID,
YOU'LL FEEL IT.
YOU'LL KNOW.
OH, PEOPLE ARE STARTING
TO ARRIVE, SWEETHEART.
IT'S TIME.
MAVIS,
YOU LOOK VERY S-SPECIAL.
WELL [CHUCKLES]
IT IS A VERY SPECIAL DAY!
[ GIGGLES ]
MOM?
HI, SUGAR.
Mr. Lee:
CAREFUL WITH THAT.
JUST 'CAUSE THERE'S NO BULLET
DOESN'T MEAN IT CAN'T BURN YOU.
YOU'RE BOTH LATE.
TAKE A RIFLE AND LOAD.
YOU TWO ARE GOING
TO GREENBRIER.
UM, HELLO, EVERYONE.
AND, UH...
OH, THANK YOU FOR COMING.
UM...
THE MOON WILL BE OUT SOON,
SO WE SHOULD,
UH, WE SHOULD START.
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
UM...
[ SPITS, CHUCKLES ]
EXCUSE ME.
AS THE ANCIENTS HAVE FORETOLD...
A NATURAL WILL BE CLAIMED.
FOR IT HAS BEEN PREDETERMINED
BY THE FIVE ELEMENTS
THAT UPON THIS NIGHT...
AN OLD CYCLE SHALL END
AND A NEW CYCLE SHALL BEGIN,
WHEREIN THE POWERS OF LIGHT
AND DARK WILL MERGE,
AND THAT UPON THIS CHILD
WHO BECOMES A WOMAN...
LENA DUCHANNES...
HER TRUE NATURE
WILL REVEAL THE TRUE NATURE
OF ALL POWER...
FOR THE NEW CYCLE.
♪ DA-DOO
♪ YA-DA-DA
♪ YA-DA-DA, DA-DA-DUM-PA
♪ YA-DA-DA-DA-DA
♪ YA-DA-DA
HEY, HALT!
OR SHOOT ME.
I'M SO GODDAMN ITCHY,
I SWEAR,
I'D JUST RATHER BE
A CASUALTY.
THIS IS SO STUPID.
I WISH I WAS...
YOU WANT -- YOU WANT TO
JUST KILL EACH OTHER?
COME OVER,
WATCH A MOVIE?
"ALIENS"?
BLU-RAY?
ALL RIGHT.
ON THE COUNT OF THREE.
[ RIFLES COCK ]
READY.
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
ONE.
TWO.
THREE.
[ GRUNTS ]
WHAT'S WRONG?
I DON'T KNOW.
[ GUNSHOT ]
ETHAN?
ETHAN?!
ETHAN.
LENA.
NO.
CEASE FIRE!
ETHAN!
WHERE IS ETHAN?
GREENBRIER!
GET THE HELL OUTTA HERE, GIRL!
ETHAN!
NO!
ETHAN, NO, NO!
LENA -- LENA, I DIDN'T K--
LENA, I SWEAR.
NO, DON'T!
DON'T!
SORRY.
I'M SORRY.
Ridley:
YOU CAN'T TRUST THEM, CUZ.
THEY'LL TURN ON EACH OTHER
FOR NO REASON AT ALL.
[ WIND WHISTLING ]
[ BREATHING HEAVILY ]
LENA, I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN IT.
OKAY?
[ WARBLES ]
AAH!
Sarafine:
WELCOME TO THE FAMILY,
MY DARLING, SPECIAL GIRL.
[ NECKLACE JINGLES, CLATTERS ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
STORM'S COMING, MR. LEE.
SHOULD WE STOP?
[ INDISTINCT SHOUTING ]
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
[ ALL SCREAMING ]
[ WIND HOWLING ]
Macon:
LENA, STOP!
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
MACON?
[ Weakly ]
STOP THIS, PLEASE.
MACON.
MACON, WHAT HAVE YOU DONE?
THE CURSE...
HAD TO BE PAID.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
SOMEBODY YOU LOVE
HAS TO DIE.
THAT WAS A SNEAKY TRICK,
MACON.
NO FAIR.
MACON?
I PROMISED HIS MOTHER.
[ Voice breaking ]
I CAN'T LOSE YOU!
[ SNIFFLES ]
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
IT'S ALL RIGHT, LENA.
NO.
DON'T LET THEM FOOL YOU.
CLAIM...
YOURSELF.
[ SOBS ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLES ]
UH-OH.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
I THINK THIS IS
JUST BETWEEN YOU AND ME, MAMA.
FINE WITH ME.
RIDLEY!
DON'T BE AFRAID.
SHE'S ON OUR SIDE.
SHE'S OUR LENA.
YOU LISTEN TO ME.
YOU'RE MY DAUGHTER.
I ALWAYS WANTED YOU WITH ME.
THEY TOOK YOU FROM ME.
THE MOON APPEARS,
AND IT WILL CLAIM YOU
AS YOU ARE DESTINED
TO BE CLAIMED!
ACCEPT IT, SWEETHEART.
THERE'S NOTHING
YOU CAN DO!
[ WARBLING ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
NO ONE CAN DO THAT.
LET ME GO!
SHE'S MORE POWERFUL THAN YOU.
LENA!
LENA, LISTEN TO ME.
IT WAS HER IDEA.
OKAY, SHE TOLD ME
YOU WERE GOING DARK ANYWAY.
I WOULD NEVER HURT YOU.
YOU REMEMBER WHEN I LEFT,
SO I WOULDN'T HURT YOU?
LENA?
GO.
THANKS, CUZ.
[ LAUGHING ]
YOU KNOW, YOU'RE A LOT MORE
LIKE ME THAN YOU CARE TO ADMIT.
WELL, NOBODY'S PERFECT.
LENA, YOU HAVE
GREAT POWERS.
I CAN TEACH YOU
HOW TO USE THEM.
HOW TO BECOME
THE MOST POWERFUL DARK CASTER
WHO EVER LIVED.
OH, THAT'S SO SWEET OF YOU,
MAMA.
OH, BABY.
THIS MORTAL YOU THINK YOU LOVE?
YOU CAN NEVER BE TOGETHER.
I KNOW.
DID YOU EVER LOVE ME, MAMA?
[ LAUGHS ]
[ SIGHS ]
YOU KNOW,
I DON'T REMEMBER.
NO MOTHER DOES, REALLY.
IT'S NOT EASY, YOU KNOW,
PUSHING ANOTHER FEMALE
OUT OF YOUR BODY,
A YOUNGER, MORE PERFECT VERSION
OF YOURSELF,
WITH EVERY OPTION
AND NO MISTAKES.
[ LAUGHS ]
ANYHOW, LOVE IS JUST A TRICK
OF THE MIND, YOU KNOW?
IT DOESN'T REALLY EXIST.
THERE'S NO SUCH THING IN NATURE.
LOVE'S A SPELL,
CREATED BY MORTALS
TO GIVE THEIR FEMALES
SOMETHING TO PLAY WITH
INSTEAD OF POWER.
I WANT YOU TO HAVE POWER.
I WANT YOU TO BE
WHO YOU TRULY ARE.
AS LONG
AS I'M JUST LIKE YOU.
THERE'S DARKNESS IN YOU.
DON'T YOU TRY AND DENY IT.
I DON'T.
WELL, THEN CLAIM IT.
CLAIM IT AND COME WITH ME,
BE WITH ME.
WE CAN RULE OVER
A NEW WORLD,
OUR WORLD.
[ WARBLING ]
[ GROANING ]
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IT IS A NEW WORLD, MAMA.
BUT IT AIN'T ALL DARK,
AND IT AIN'T ALL LIGHT.
AND IT AIN'T ALL OURS.
[ GASPING ]
I REMEMBER NOW.
I REMEMBER NOW. I DID LOVE YOU.
I DO LOVE YOU.
I DID LOVE YOU.
I LOVE YOU, DARLIN'. I LOVE YOU!
YOU REALLY SHOULDN'T USE WORDS
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
[ GASPS ]
YOU STILL NEED ME!
YOU'VE DONE ENOUGH, MAMA.
YOU MUST BE CLAIMED!
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMING CONTINUES ]
[ CREAKING ]
[ SCREAMING STOPS ]
[ FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING ]
MACON?
[ WARBLES ]
YOU ALL RIGHT, CUZ?
YEAH.
MACON SAID THIS WAS THE ONLY WAY
TO PROTECT YOU BOTH.
[ SOBS ]
Lena:
I COULD HEAR THE SOUND.
THE SOUND WAS ME BREAKING.
I CRIED BECAUSE HE HAD LIVED.
BECAUSE HE HAD DIED.
I WAS SHATTERED, I WAS SAVED.
I ONLY KNEW THE GIRL I WAS,
WAS GONE.
HE WAS RIGHT.
NO GOOD CAN COME
FROM LOVING A MORTAL.
THEY CAN'T SURVIVE OUR WORLD.
GET OUT.
GO, ETHAN.
CLAIM YOURSELF IN DEFIANCE,
IN HOPE...
IN LOVE, IN FURY, IN GRATITUDE.
CLAIM THE LIGHT.
CLAIM THE DARK.
CLAIM IT ALL.
NOTHING CAN STAY.
YOU ALL SET?
YEAH.
WE SHOULD BE IN NEW YORK BY
THURSDAY IF WE MAKE GOOD TIME.
WE'RE GONNA GO STAY
WITH LINK'S COUSIN IN BROOKLYN.
COME HERE.
I'LL CALL YOU
AS SOON AS I GET IN.
YOU CALL WHENEVER YOU CAN.
BYE.
HI. UM...
LENA, RIGHT?
HI. YEAH.
ETHAN WATE.
YEAH, I KNOW.
OH.
[ CHUCKLES ]
UM, SO, I WANTED, I--
YOU KNOW...
UM, I'M SORRY
THAT WE NEVER GOT TO HANG,
BUT I ALWAYS WANTED
TO TELL YOU
I THOUGHT YOUR --
YOUR, UH, POEMS
IN CREATIVE WRITING...
JUST REALLY GOOD.
THANKS.
THAT'S REALLY NICE
OF YOU TO SAY.
YOU'RE LEAVING?
YEAH.
UH, COLLEGE ROAD TRIP.
[ CHUCKLES ]
I'M GOING TO CHECK OUT
NYU.
GREAT.
IT'S GOOD.
OH, COOL TITLE.
BUKOWSKI?
HE ANY GOOD?
DEFINE "GOOD."
[ LAUGHS ]
KEEP IT.
A "GETTIN' OUTTA GATLIN"
PRESENT.
REALLY?
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
COOL. THANK YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
SEE YOU.
ETHAN'S COMING.
ALL RIGHT. BYE.
HEY. [ SIGHS ]
IS IT ALL RIGHT IF WE GO SEE
MY MOM AT THE SANATORIUM?
IT'S ON THE WAY.
SURE.
[ ENGINE TURNS OVER ]
Ethan:
"THERE IS A PLACE IN THE HEART
"THAT WILL NEVER BE FILLED;
"A SPACE.
"WE WILL KNOW IT
MORE THAN EVER.
"THERE IS A PLACE IN THE HEART
THAT WILL NEVER BE FILLED...
AND WE WILL WAIT AND WAIT
IN THAT SPACE."
[ WOMAN VOCALIZING ]
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
♪ COME TO ME
LENA!
♪ DON'T LET ME GO
♪ RUN TO ME
[ WOMEN VOCALIZING ]
♪ COME TO ME
♪ NEVER LET ME GO
♪ RUN TO ME
♪ RUN
[ VOCALIZING ]
[ SONG ENDS ]
[ WOMAN LAUGHS ]
[ Thenewno2's
'NEVER TOO LATE" PLAYS ]
♪ THE HOUR GETS LATE
♪ A SPIRITUAL LAKE
♪ VISIONS IN THE WAVES
♪ WATCHING THEM BREAK
♪ A SPIRITUAL LAKE
♪ VISIONS OF THE WAVES
♪ WATCH THE LIGHT CHANGE
♪ WATCH THEM AS THEY BREAK
♪ IT'S NEVER TOO LATE
♪ TO THROW IT ALL AWAY
♪ NEVER TOO LATE, NEVER
♪ IT'S NEVER TOO LATE
♪ TO THROW IT ALL AWAY
♪ YEAH
♪ THE LOVERS, THEY WAIT
♪ TO DECIDE THE FATE
♪ WHAT CAN I SAY?
♪ IT'S NEVER TOO LATE
♪ WHAT'S IT GONNA TAKE
♪ TO DISGUISE A FATE?
♪ WHAT CAN I SAY?
♪ IT'S NEVER TOO LATE
♪ NEVER TOO LATE, NEVER
♪ TO THROW IT ALL AWAY
♪ IT'S NEVER TOO LATE
♪ NEVER TOO LATE, NEVER
♪ TO THROW IT ALL AWAY
♪ YEAH
♪ IT'S NEVER TOO LATE
♪ NEVER TOO LATE, NEVER
♪ TO THROW IT ALL AWAY
♪ VISIONS OF THE WAVES
♪ NEVER TOO LATE, NEVER
♪ IT'S NEVER TOO LATE
♪ YEAH, YEAH
For more new Movies visit
GlowGaze.Com