Good morning.
Oh, hello who likes to see you.
Oh, look there is.
Is she?
Dude, if I would be nervous.
His fabulous bag, she is so refined.
Sorry, I arrived late.
We had to go shopping.
Go to right, I'm so tired.
Go my friend.
Lui Buton, never saw so well.
Tell me if that Liston color is not real.
I would say beautiful.
I had to strive to have it.
Sorry to make you wait.
Okay.
Fix what you can.
But I need the list, because
we will have a luncheon at 1.
I'm sure it will be ready.
I know darling, you also miss.
Cuidala well, no scolding.
Ok.
I hope you give me a red bone.
I want to do better today.
It has an appointment, go.
Nice pedigree.
Please, this dog is pursuing cars.
It's better than a doodle.
I give it a week.
Hey, talk to my leg.
Good for you.
It is not easy to deal with the newspapers.
But it is when you can laugh.
I would be happy with one. Arréglenlo.
Rogue.
Ok, how about girls?
What do you think of this?
OH please do not go with your hair.
This?
That is, took me 2. Let's see.
We will leave at least 2
day until you find something.
If you get something.
Perfect.
Something of Armany.
Oh, and he left.
Sure.
Small beauty.
This?
Is allergic to that.
What do you think?
I love that.
Fabulous.
Love, Love?
Oh, I'll give you everything you want.
Yes.
No, no to you Patrick.
Hi Jacky.
I love this smell, in the morning.
Beautiful.
I loved the new design that did.
Thank you.
Your welcome.
For everything. Seriously.
For giving me the opportunity
to be myself.
Oh, Daddy Good job.
Very symmetrical.
Yes, yes.
Well done Daddy.
Go Daddy to rest,
You did good friend.
Hello beautiful.
Blocking my sunshine.
That the sun shines more.
Why do not you my wife?
What is that smell?.
What?
The sweat on my tail.
Oh, the macho that I have for you.
None.
So ... should be the fertilizer.
Rude.
You're covered with that.
Clear.
I am a escabador.
An appetizer my heart.
I got it myself.
Very sabrozo.
This is very annoying.
I am tempted.
I leave here in case
you change your mind.
Sorry we have guests.
Yes. Your guests.
Do you want to go have a drink later?
There is a good place for the garage.
Okay, forget it.
I am here.
1 hour late as usual.
Hello.
How do you keep your job?
Oh, sure you do not preserved.
Where is it? Where is it?
Go to find it.
Come on, go get it.
Am I Lassie?
You are not very useful.
Yes, I understand.
It's just that I wanted to
promote a new cosmetic.
These are news
wonderful. They are the best.
Yes.
Okay, great. Adios.
Is everything all right?
Oh, dear.
I do not know how I will.
Yo, I took a plane at 4 o'clock.
And we were stuck.
And the nanny of Chloe, was
3 weeks before your baby.
You 're not going with Chloe.
No, obviously he was on vacation.
But this is a business trip.
For the city, for 10 days.
She is very sensitive.
In addition comb his hair.
Leave caregiver.
Caregiver.
No, no.
Never leave in the
the hands of a stranger.
Never, not in a million years.
But you are not a stranger.
What?
Here is the schedule of Cloe.
Try to accomplish as much as possible.
Oh, but you can skip
Wednesday of this.
Just please.
I'm going to trust you.
My greatest treasure.
Cuidala well.
I love you sweetheart.
I love you so much.
Adios.
Fun both.
Ok, goodbye.
¿Day games?
Oh ... good luck.
Do not worry Chloe.
She will return soon
that you know it.
It is not that bad.
You do not know anything.
It's so cute in his little outfit.
She is not the case, is a pig.
Rachel spoke of chiuahua.
Angela is not a chihuahua.
She is a scrub, arrogant,
and manipulative of chiuhahua
Beverly Hills.
She has no leadership, no
can keep a job.
Never arrive on time.
I can not be late to all my appointments.
You know how he began his schedule?
With their massages, party
birthday parties for dogs.
Nonsense.
And I have to change 4 times a day.
Look at him.
- She is so ...
lrresponsable.
Dispossession.
I need refrezcarme.
Good girl.
Hi Mom.
Who is that attractive
chiuahua from there?
Oh, the gardener.
You're adorable.
Than ever.
Wow.
Perhaps it is already gone.
Sorry.
I just ...
Excuse me while
defend your garden against
The dangerous birds.
Hey bird.
That is a hot dog.
Excuse me Miss.
Good legs.
Hey, sorry.
Sorry.
Gardener.
Your dog is bad, very bad.
Very dirty.
Can you get your dog here?
But my heart has to speak.
Just want to say.
If you know someone who
lamba inside your ears.
Oh, you take the most expensive.
Or, share a moment in the sun.
I will have the honor degree of
to be with someone special.
Keep your tongue.
I do not think so Daddy.
You mean not now.
I mean, ever.
I see. Clear.
Well ...
Duty calls.
Please have a wonderful day.
Thank you very much.
Rachel, get up.
I have to go to my pediquiur.
And you have to do my waffles.
Stand up.
Say.
Hello Angela.
What?
You're a genius.
I can be ready in 30 minutes.
Ok, goodbye.
Pack your things Chloe.
lremos travel.
A trip?
Oh, where are we going?
I love this house.
There are no more.
Hello.
I like this house.
Live here.
That's good.
I'm beginning to think that
Hunting season is here.
Nena.
Hello.
Does anyone forget something?
I am walking by myself.
I die hungry.
'll Take anything.
Wait, are not supposed
that would see the guy?
Now.
Wait a minute, I
Remember the name of the club.
You have ...
Shut up.
Guys, I'm going to go with Brian.
It's so cute.
Will be better than me is doing
something good or reservations.
Here you go.
Are you kidding me no?
This is good for 1 thing only.
Try it yourself.
Bad dog.
Very bad dog.
Rachel, what did you do?
She is faking.
No.
TONTITA.
She is so cute.
We have to take it with us.
Yes, levantame for good food.
Do not take a dog for an appointment.
Hey wait.
Come back here.
Solo, agrégelo to the account.
Hello.
Rachel Want to dance?
Dance.
Ok, it's a bit strange.
I will continue.
You know, if it were not upset.
That would be really fun.
There you are.
You are so annoying ...
Hey bájenme.
Who are you?
Rachel, help me.
Someone please.
I was abducted.
Well ...
Good night.
Seriously.
Chloe, salt.
Chloe I'm not kidding, you seriously.
Excuse not to have given ...
Sea salt go fast.
What happens?
Chloe was lost.
I do not know where he was.
He does not always like to walk anywhere.
Less run.
Good.
What?
Pelas of dogs.
They are criminals, always do this.
How do you find them?
I know something.
Mexico City.
There is not much we can do.
You did everything you could.
Why do not you wear your
dress and accompany us?
I will keep looking to Chloe.
And if I can not find
I'm going to Mexico City.
Where am I?
You are in dog fights.
Dog fights.
This is bad.
I was born for purchases no fights.
And unless I feel it breaking.
Nice wine princess.
Chloe's clothes is not pink wine.
A chihuahua disappointed.
You do not want to meddle with Miss thin.
It's a gladiator.
A gladiator?.
You. He knows a fighter.
Delgado is the best of the best.
No girl listen to Rafa.
The devil dominates the dog fights.
That was before he fell
that slender back.
What is he saying?
That dog always prays
before a fight.
Did not speak Spanish?
My name is Chloe, no girl.
And why would speak Spanish?
Hey, you're a chihuahua friend.
Hello, I'm Beverly Hllls.
Did you know that is the capital
of shopping in the world
California is a gringo.
That's right, and the only
why I'm here.
It's because I stole.
Do you think I am a volunteer for this?
But I am a pacifist.
¿Pacifica?
No, pacifist.
I believe in the fun.
If you're worried about something, you stop,
if you stop, do not fight you.
So I guess that does not
There is nothing to worry about.
That's a relief.
How nice that you feel better.
Now you can stay a little quiet.
I can not wait until that fight
and wait for Rachel to come.
My senses are old.
Where is it? Where is my Chloe?
What's happening?
Hello.
I am a friend of Rachel.
Are you the guardian?
I am Sam.
Your garden is very nice.
And when you have an
house, you call yourself ...
Thank you very much.
Where's Rachel?
Forget about it buddy, Where's Chloe?
What are you hiding?
Chloe is lost through there
and Rachel are looking for.
The love of my life is
out problems.
Want to send this
to the city of Mexico.
If.
It was about time. I want recommendations.
And now the challenger.
It weighs as 6 pounds,
I huahua to Chichi.
Thank you.
They are very kind.
This is very nice looks like a parade.
Sorry, you had not seen.
They call me Diablo.
Well, it's nice to meet you.
Sure I'm in the wrong place.
Maybe I can talk to
the counselor or someone.
Stop talking.
You know, I know a dentist in
Beverly Hills who can do something
In this regard.
What?
Only I do not want you
drop a tooth in your work.
No, tell me anything.
Hey quiet friend.
It sounds as if it were to come.
The door.
It should not be much.
Rage, rage.
She was going.
Poor thing.
Ok, that's all.
What are you doing?
Wait.
Hey brother, give me the conbinación.
We will not let Delgado.
Return.
This is very inappropriate.
Hey, that's an Cashman.
Adios.
Dájame.
I know it is deficil leave,
but I gotta go now.
The show is all for you girl.
Not this time Diablo.
Move, move.
Delgado will find you.
Wait for me.
I love this chihuahua.
lnglés please.
Over here, over here.
My botita.
Your what?
Forget about it.
That tell your mother, sir.
Come on.
Hey Get off me.
Do not understand.
I got it.
I hope you help me otherwise.
I'm sure there are many more.
Why?
She llevava something.
Diamonds in his neck.
What?
Care.
What is this?
Day of the Dead.
It's so beautiful.
It is what humans do
to honor their ancestors.
Keep them alive in their hearts.
To remember who they are.
From which they come.
You're my dog.
Thanks brother.
I see you, kid.
Wait.
See you.
Wait, that's all.
It is rule number 1
princess of the street.
Each dog goes solo.
Now, Get lost.
My name is not a princess is Chloe.
And I'm lost.
I want you to find me.
Look princess, I mean ...
Look kid.
I have my own problems.
I can not go back to fighting.
I have to leave the city.
How far is Beverly Hills?
Very far.
Come on.
If you can find out
the way back.
You can live in soon in the state.
Where ever you do not
noticed I am a little big for that.
But you have the perfect size
for a dog guardian.
Of course, because Daddy, the fled.
Did you have a watchdog
under the name Papi?
What I say.
So what will you do?
Do not follow with questions
before I change my thinking.
I do not know the name but
believe it is not a hotel.
The Carfei.
There is one here.
Did you know?
They should.
We stayed.
We have a golden card.
Why me?
Of all the dogs in Mexico.
A Chihuahua with boots.
It will be fun, and you'll see.
Here is the GPS.
Lit.
Diablo, go to the ride that chiuahua.
Go, go.
Wait a second.
What's that sound?
Mójate.
Why did you do that?
The devil is your flavor.
Sure, it is chanel number 5.
Congratulations.
Now I lost another boot and it stinks.
I do not smell anything.
Are you kidding?
I smell like a wet dog.
You are a wet dog.
Look at Miss.
Ash.
Sorry.
We are trying to stop the fighting.
And we do not have time to look for
Each dog lost in Mexico.
This is not just any dog.
This is my dog vip.
Which means they try everything.
Let me tell you something.
Go back to your hotel.
I'm going to hang a picture of me said.
And I see I can do.
Thank you.
Your welcome.
Hello.
Yes, this is fantastic.
You know it was you called,
and was concerned that
No one was there.
Yes, we left.
For Mexicans.
Can I talk to her for a second?
Let me put it to the phone.
How is my little baby?
I miss you, miss you.
Ok.
Here is your highness.
The hotel.
I already feel like home.
Delgado thank you, thank you, thank you.
Do not worry.
Adios.
Maybe you should wait out here.
Whatever.
I do not want badly interpreted.
But individuals can be a little
by dogs that leave to enter.
Okay.
I'll stay here.
Eat good food at a time.
Thank you.
Sorry.
It would be kind enough to get my card.
You'll find my name
in the rear.
Hello?
Her out of here!
What?
E always been to the veterinarian for years
Dares not!
This sorry -
a big mistake
lnmenso
What?
Oh no
I'm ... dirty
Let us see that there are
Figures
What was going to wait?.
If you are a princess
It was so humiliating not believe
Relief?
I'm here to apologize
see the detective ramirez
On this basis someone miss
Five minutes please
Do not look now, Hanna
montana to 1 o'clock
What are you doing here?
I mean what are you doing here?
It is not obvious? To find a clue
Angela your friend told me everything
When you come back
speaking good English?
Not only did it to cover it
So let me go alone
and make me see how silly?
It needs no help for it
What makes you believe that I need
Now aid of a gardener?
Oh no, she does not
Not that I have a problem
with that word but
Actually I am a landscaper
And I'm not here for you
I'm here for her viv
is like a family to me
I sent an email with the description
the dog to all of our stations
Who described it? De-nothing
You see such a picture would be of more help
And what will we do now?
Us?
Nothing
You go back to your hotel and waiting
Please
Okay there is nothing
-What you can do?
Must be able
We can start looking for pasting photos
I need your dog
I'm with her friend
Clue is in trouble
Boby-fool Come, let us begin
Boby where are you going?
I can not believe that JamaiHeteiland
this will be lost
Smile
Thank you
- It will be on the cover of the magazine
This house is unbelievable
That scuger
Come here FIESTERA-No.
Really no need
Thank you
JamaiHeteiland not believe they are not in trouble?
Oh please bet that
this in your favorite place
I know this seated and secure
waiting for a hunki fuski
Thank you
I must be hungry
That is our churro
Our churro-sorry but ...
I saw it first
Better be careful boys
Such as CHIHUAHUAS Luce warriors
Now look, and lost
Suter of my favorite skin
And had to sleep
in a box and still there
So do not push me!
Okay
It's what I thought
It's time to read the paper
A dog is kidnapped
Come pink
Do not be hero
I can smell
Move Hurry up
Above, the roof-I got scared
Come Hurry up
Here
Here no
Where are we going?
Oh not a trap
And that? I am thinking
Why do I want?
Had already bitten once
I love you let me leave
I saw you in the newspaper
The most was that close to estube
Vamonos
Where are we going now?
There must be someone
It's the only way out?.
Delgado? -What?
Why do I pursue this?
Vasquez should have sent
Vasquez, who is?
They do whatever for money
Plicía to the state for years after
But always escapes
How to know all that?
You were a criminal or something?
Or something
Sleep something
It's a great journey and
Tomorrow is a big day
What to say when he said he wanted
trying to make the hero?
No matter
It is the shoe JamaiHeteiland
What is it?
The shoe JamaiHeteiland
Good job! -You must be here
I can feel
Wait for me!
He says he saw a chihuhua
Estubo here
Having my JamaiHeteiland?
I'm going to kick some tails
Style boby
If you? -Anyone else looking for that dog
There are a lot of money in this chihuahua
Understand?
Can not find it before we did
Well
Come on baby, come
Come
Ok, here is where we go out
Stretch and go
And what is your plan? This is the deal -
You have to wait to return
But where are you going?
Delgado?
These strange know?
I guess this is my source of water
That is better
Alli remember this plan, no?
Do not you have to eat seriously, no?
Just swallow my legs
Ok here we go
Come on, you have to
That frightens
Help me!
Someone Help!
Alli is someone help me!
This only saw him on animal planet
What are you doing?
Help me!
Let him!
Do not you EFSA Commas rat
Are you okay?
Hello?
You are an angel?
I'm dead?
No, and I am not an angel
Rescataste me as a hero
This is my true color
I am in heaven?
Something that's bebverly hills
Ah bebverly hills
These little far from home
That look you can attend
My name is Manuel
I have the job
help lost dogs
As you
Really?
What can help me get home?
You saved my life
It's the least I can do
Delgado?
Delgado ¿?
What about Thomas?
You really are you?
What happened? Where have you been?
No one has seen since
you know .. A time.
Look ...
I am doing a job security.
I'm taking a chihuahua
rich back Beberly Hiils.
Had been lost.
Take her to the assistance center then.
So to find its owner.
It is not so simple.
Other dogs are searching the
Informants are everywhere.
Until the El Diablo are looking for.
Does the devil?
Is that why you do it?
That offender is behind me.
It's just u ntrabajo.
Can you make the official
Mendez assist me in this?
Sure, that's fine. I see it I can do.
Walk.
I saw someone who can help us.
Really?
Me too.
Where is your collar?.
You are not the only thing you can do things.
What?
I gave him my necklace to Manuel.
And it will lead to the master.
Manuel ¿?
Who is Manuel?
The cute little mouse who helped me.
What saved from being eaten by a lguana.
¿Lguana?
An iguana?
That's the biggest lie!
The lguanas are vegetarians!
Sorry, I did not know
lguanas many in my life.
Without your collar identification, there is nothing
that keep you apart from any stray dog.
She said that the boat would return soon.
What boat?
That ship?
What happened to the''no
talk to strangers''?
Do not say anything iguanas.
There my God ...
What can I say?.
You are an angel.
The skies were all believed ...
It is the most TONTITA throughout Mexico.
Yet we can go to eat something.
Where did you get that?
Please do not eat me man ... I
wife and 300 kids to feed.
Huyamos!
Where is the chihuahua.
¿Chihuahua? Do not know
any chihuahua.
Where did you get that?
Of course, if you want to know one, could
arrelgar something for the right price.
You are about to be eaten.
That is the mood!
Hurry up!
're Straining my patience Chaparrita.
Your patience is exhausted.
Where is he?
By the source, close to the port.
I did not know he was your friend.
I told him just a cocitas.
Please do not hurt me.
See, that the Big One
Final us was afraid.
You know, I do not think
We had fear.
Chico is not our problem.
Come on, we can do is ..
Oh, I guess ... when
say something like that ...
Delgado ..
Yes?
What do we do here?
It's where we will meet with the Coyote.
A coyote?
A smuggler''''
They help dogs as
us to cross the border.
You used to be a police dog, right?
It's like met Sergeant Thomas.
That's why as you could do those things.
I do not want to talk about it.
¿Quit?
Are you fired?
Did you do something wrong?
Yes, I did something wrong, OK?
Are you happy?
Forget it now.
Okay.
Well.
Alli is.
Come on now.
And no more questions.
Well.
What happened? ¿Hiriste someone?
Forget it!
Just Forget it!
I get mad.
Well, you're not the
most charming traveling companion.
Well! That here we split.
What?
Wait .. What are you doing?
This train will take you to Tijuana.
But ..
But nothing!
The coyotes will take you to
the border from there.
Get comfortable.
Good luck.
But ...
I promised.
Do not walk away ..
Do not turn ... not turn.
Thin!
Coming!
Chloe!
Come on!
Skip!
If it were easy.
Come on! You can do it!
Skip!
Heavens!
Come on!
Could use some help.
I pull you.
Thin!
What can I say?. A
promise is a promise.
So speaks thin.
Lost .. Please .. A lost dog
Chloe!
Not that ...
Daddy ...
Daddy!
You ...
The vague.
Where did you get that smell?.
Perhaps you have not noticed, but
This is a private rest area.
You mean the scent taco?
Do not fool!
The perfume.
It's Chloe.
She is a Chihuahua U.S..
Their ears are
punteagudas .. And his nose ...
It is like a blackberry.
Really?
A arrears?
She is careful with the clothes?
You know .. Where is he?
The last time I saw her,
Delgado was running with.
If.
Delgado ¿?
Who is this thin?
I want to hear more.
Come with me.
It seems that got a couple of friends.
Just what we needed.
Stray dogs.
Daddy was a stray dog.
What kick there.
Hello friend.
The inspires me every day.
What inspires you to you Rachel?
Then we talk about that.
Hello.
Look at that.
How are you?
Hello!
If it is nice.
They can go with us, but you will have
to give them a bath, that stinks.
I can handle that.
You stink.
Bad guy.
Boy, I love this.
I think I fell in love with this gringo.
I think he likes.
I think your looking for you.
No no!
Wait!
Look'm clean,
did not know who felt.
Now if.
I had never brushed their teeth.
And it's mint!
It is rare ...
Daddy, this is great.
We must call room service.
Or rent a movie.
Have we found a home, Daddy?
I do not know.
But for now are safe.
Sam did it for me.
See you tomorrow.
We're going guys.
No, you can stay with me
I do not think that is the problem.
Well.
Daddy! What you see, mate?
It is a big place my friend.
And I will be small. But looking
something bigger than everything.
My heart ...
Sorry. Where are you?
I'm from Beverly Hills.
Where is that?
Well, it feels like a long way from here.
Miss ..
What is that?
It is a boot ..
Poredi the others.
All the dogs in Beberly
Hills have to use them.
It must be very dirty there.
No, in fact, is the place
More clean it.
It is very foolish to use a botita then ..
Pedro ... do not be poorly educated.
Pedro know something ...
You're right.
Rachel.
Let Sleeping Beauty, go!
Detective Ramirez called it.
A white Chihuahua and a German shepherd,
were seen in Puerto Vallarta.
They were not sure if it was,
that was not using his collar.
What?
Someone stole the necklace to Chloe?
I will show them who I am!
I was sore stomach ..
Insurance was the enchilada.
I thought about the dog .. No
we should have stolen her necklace,
Now never home ...
Get out of here.
Saquemonos this, you do not
we know where we go ..
I feel naked ...
For alla!
Come back!
Jump from me!
Care!
To learn that.
You have my diamonds!
Let him!
Quick, come!
To hide!
Quick, Hide.
What's happening?
Delgado, what is going on?
We are in trouble.
Hide, the distract.
- Okay.
Do not leave no matter what happens.
Delgado ..
What are you gonna do?.
Something silly.
Beware of dog!
It was not so difficult.
There is God.
Go my luck ..
Thin!
My God ..
My lucky dog ..
Did you see that?
I just jump from the train.
I alone.
And I was in motion.
I told you to stay there.
We are in this together.
I could not leave here.
Never had a friend like you.
You should have been
girl. Look around ...
You should have been.
I told the police that
I found the necklace on the floor.
But I do not believe.
I went to deliver the diamonds,
and tratron of arrest.
I regret the confusion sir.
The rat ..
... is smart.
Oe .. Such needs help.
I tried to give him, but
always escabuyia.
Habil ... habil mouse.
He knows he needs ...
A dog.
But it is street.
If it is ..
But it is a very good dog.
Thanks for returning the necklace ...
Congratulations.
Ya got home.
Also you go.
I know my friend.
Come on, everything will go your time.
Don 't get on the furniture.
Good luck finding your dog.
Thank you.
I have just spoken to the
Police in Puerto Vallarta.
They say that there was a problem with a
dog on the train to north this morning.
It was with a German shepherd.
That's it.
Thank you.
Call me if you learn something.
Finding headed north ...
Bone they were
with my diamond ..
I think it's Karma ... or something like that.
If you steal, eventually
you stole.
That does not matter to me.
What are you going ahacer then?
Silence.
So Britany says that will come with
Scooter .. I know that it is bone, half crazy.
Please God ... that street.
But do not say ..
I have to support it, no?
Wait a second ... What is no longer
This tree had happened before?
No.
Wrong.
We walked for hours.
But I sense something ..
¿President?
Do you notes?
Oh God ... you can not smell ..
Right?
No.
What happened?
Okay, you can tell me.
That is why the police.
I let go ... and that
I could not follow a trail.
And now here we are,
walking in circles.
Sorry girl.
What was that?
Pumas.
I'm afraid slim.
I know.
Well, we better move.
We have to get out of here.
Well ..
Come on. Do not talk.
Thin.
What happened to you?
Why can not smell anything?
Well ...
My partner and I ...
We were on a raid.
I was ahead.
Before I knew,
left me without a conscience ..
It was all very fast.
While she was unconscious,
my companion was wounded.
Never came into being
the same after that.
Neither I nor.
Debi have meaning come.
I lifted the following day
and could not smell anything.
Are you injured?
Not ..
They say it's all in my head.
In my head.
We found
The stop as much as you can
while run, understand?
They are just cats, you can do. --
I need a miracle.
Care!
- Run if you say so.
You can!
You can do it!
Do not be afraid.
Have them!
Chloe runs!
Run and hide!
Here ...
Aca no!
Say hello to my little friends.
Good time you guys came.
I am Moctezuma.
Come with us if they want to live.
Yes, I want to live.
I have seen it all.
Can you help us return
Moctezuma to civilization?
Clear.
But it is very dangerous to walk these
by obscure places where this.
Spend the night here with us.
Where are we?
They are in Chihuaha.
The birthplace
Our powerful race.
I was born in Beberly Hills.
You see, all your
ancestors come from here.
Some took to the civilization ..
But we stand.
Did you hear what he said, Delgado?
I come from a powerful race.
If, powerfully annoying.
You're upset that we
Small dogs saved.
Very small dogs.
Tonight we will celebrate his arrival.
Thanks Moctezuma.
Please ...
Dime Mocty.
Anyway ...
All this for my Mocty?
If, for you.
When he returns to a chihuahua
home is cause for celebration.
Even a Chihuaha of Beberly Hills?
Clear.
No matter where you come,
're one of us.
Small but powerful.
¿Almighty?
But I'm just a puppy.
¿Dog?
No.
Do not insult you.
Do not insult the Chihuahua race.
No more ..
Is it not more?
It means, no more.
We are not CHIHUAHUAS
toys or fashion accessories.
No more!
Not born to use hats
Fools and handbags use.
We were not known with
derogatory names.
We have been told Juguetitos, and
pequeñuelos for long.
No more!
Names like fifi, fufu,
Puki, Pumpkin, trespass against us.
No more!
Yes, the small but we chihuahas
not for dicersion of humans.
What we know that the
power of our inner strength.
No more!
Yes, we are small,
but we are powerful!
No more!
Join us Chloe. Join this''no more''
Find your bark.
My bark?
Yes, what makes you powerful.
What makes you .. Your.
We are Chihuahuas.
Oyannos barking!
That was embarrassing.
Do not worry little, your bark
come when you need it really.
The last happens is a cat ..
Come on, open!
The sweet smell of success.
I smell something else.
Where is the suitcase?
Where is the suitcase
that is my diamond
Be careful with your nose.
I do not feel good doing this.
I do not feel good ..
Now for that.
The iguanas are supposed
who have the blood cold.
Well, you know who was born in captivity.
Born under the light of a lamp.
And parallel. We have a job to do.
So you were the
rata to the collar theft.
See, you got.
Hey, you have me confused with another rat.
We are here.
No, it is.
He did.
And now the love of my life
alli is in trouble.
Not for us.
Just trying to save her.
If.
Dog pursuing hellish that.
Tell me about this diabolical dog.
Chloe.
You can stay if you want.
This place is awesome Mocty.
But there is someone in this house that
time is concerned and surprised me.
And I miss it.
Does your heart?
My heart?
What does that mean?
The love of your heart.
Nor even gave it a chance.
We come CHIHUAHUAS
in many shapes and colors.
But when a view, not with your eyes, but
with your soul, there we are all equal.
Listen ..
That the pumas ...
Thank you.
But of course, we are Chihuahua.
Civilization at last.
We accomplished Delgado.
Thin!
Let's see who wins.
That was great.
Yeah, sure, it was.
Delgado, look.
What?
Are you?
Bonita toga.
I can not believe that
Rachel is looking for me.
Well, we go for help.
I always wanted one of these.
Is that they are very intelligent.
He would make a great company.
I think they are right for each other.
Someone got a girlfriend.
I have a home.
I understand.
Rachel!
Ramirez was found to Chloe.
How about that?
We must go.
Ramirez is waiting for us.
I told you the match.
This is the place.
Chloe!
Hello!
How about here?
U.S. dog ...
Well here we go ..
What?
Excuse me Miss.
Please, go ahead.
I have seen this before gringo.
That van.
My Chloe has been there.
Perrot very well.
You're the daddy.
Now go for it.
Get your princess.
My heart ...
Deshariamos that we never thought of it.
Come on, apurale.
Now porphine may be because of my diamonds.
Rapido, or return.
Oh no ...
What?
What do you say?
Chloe!
We have to get it!
Chloe! Where are you?
I'm going!
Where to get me?
Diablo good job.
Good job.
I've given a lot problems,
I hope it is worth.
Let's call the owners for the reward.
Yes, sir.
Surprise!
Sueltameee!
Daddy, what are you doing here?
Salvandote!
Run!
Come over here.
Go!
Catch these chihuahua!
That does not escape.
Daddy .. So now what?
I will protect my heart.
Not Chloe.
My head ..
I need an aspirin.
That hurt.
Do you support?
You 2.
What do you do here?
It is not what you think man.
Do not try to steal this necklace.
Of course ..
Maybe if ..
What comes to my partner
say is that if such a hurry,
You can continue using their tracking this.
I can not.
What?
Not even gonna try it?.
What is the point of
to be a German shepherd?
I can not.
She needs you.
I can not smell, do you not understand?
Then do it.
It smells.
That's it.
You can do it, go!
I feel something ...
Rat ...
Nachos old ...
Chanel No. 5.
It's got!
I have a Chiuhuahua to save!
Don 't wear the necklace.
What got.
You did something good.
You know you did something good.
Do not follow ...
- Te blushing ..
It could have gone anywhere.
Chloe is the necklace.
He wants us to the chihuahua.
Come on, come on.
Care.
The structure is fragile.
There is no sign of the dog here
You're lucky to be here
Lights confused
Where are you going?
Looking for the rest of your tail?
It was here that these girl
Can olerte
Come here
Here is that these
Hola a less
What's going on?
What is it?
Cloe all right?
You are very brave JamaiHeteiland
Get out of here
Run!
Vamonos
Come Catch Me
Sorry I have to go
Best careful dog
Or end up as a piñata
Do not call me for anything fast
Come
Popy
Say goodbye to your heart
No
No more
Finish
That is my bark
Ladra
It's all yours official
Mr. Vasquez-see that?
Ladra
I saw
It is time to finish what I started
I no longer scare
So why is shaky?
Because I am a chihuahua
Grave error
Let him in peace
Cloe you doing?
This mouunstro took my sweater
Care
That ended!
I was stripped of everything!
Now we are equal
Cloe
Girl?
She is ...
Dead
I'm
Your Popy
Talk to me
Feel my ears with your beautiful voice
Without you the sun does not shine
The flowers do not beauty
Cloe, there is no way
returns to Beverly Hills
And always take care of your garden
Your love is rain
that falls in my yard
Not even begins to like
Popy that was beautiful
Again
She came back!
Are you okay?
Cloe estubiste where?
Rachel you missed all the fun
You are a rude chihuahua
Small but dangerous
Hello
So you're the dog gardener
No, I am a paisajero
Ops
True
Well, goodbye small
Delagdo
That look you can take
as a security dog
Thanks for the offer but
someone has to go after the devil
I think apart princess
I retired for now
You miss
I miss you too
But his is not the goodbye, I am
sure that we will again
Do not turn
Such a look can use an extra pair
Where is believed that official?
Accept the job?
Official
Well done
Cloe, Popy go home
Better we go
Travel insurance
Thanks detective
Adios small
Thanks JamaiHeteiland
Never forget
Now we
Bring your suitcase, I carry the suitcase
-Let 's put it up
Hurry
Popy we succeed
Hey hey
Welcome
What a surprise!
I took pictures of the most beautiful gardens
Do not believe where is my JamaiHeteiland?
Actually I need it ...
- It is better to know what to say?.
I made some arrangements and
You will adespedir
You've worked very hard
Cloe?
You can put the unrest there? -Si
Chloe!
Rachel? Hi -
Hi-Hi
What?
He was in the bathroom
Where is my JamaiHeteiland?
Alli this
Hello darling
Hey come here
My baby my little angel, I miss you so much
Sure
What is that smell?.
It's something like urban
But it is fabulous
That is number five mexico
I can not believe that there
Period my best dress
So you're not already a more
chihuahua princess from Beverly Hills?
Beverly hills, but if princes, no more
How you say what you do
Friday night, in Spanish?
I?
And you?
Good
After how you try
I can not believe I fuistea rescue
As it would not make
Popy you are my heart
I think I will mourn
Cloe
A Popy likes
If that is what friends ask
Delgado received a medal
Honor, for good service
Shortly after the devil was adopted
a rich, who were engaged wing fashion
Moshe became the face
Officer mintymutt
But the encouragement of
this dog the whole day fresco
The friends of JamaiHeteiland
have a reality show
So I think you can dance?.
Chico and his friend came to Beverly Hills where
Quick learned a new word in English
Blimp
These are JamaiHeteiland and I
on our first date
And who knows that you have
some taquitos in the future
Let's say that my heart set on Wow