♪ ♪
(deep rumbling)
MAN:
How did we end up here?
This place is horrible.
Smells like balls.
We don't belong
in this shithole.
(computer playing
electronic melody)
(quietly):
Shit.
(electronic melody stops)
Hey, Sam. Hi, hon.
Dad, what kind of... Shut up!
What kind of flowers
did you say you wanted?
Alchemillas, or something
that smells nice.
You know, something
soothing. Listen...
It all smells like
fucking kimchi!
(sighs) Okay, something
that looks nice.
You know, anything
but roses, okay?
I hate this job.
(electronic tone)
♪ ♪
(long sigh)
WOMAN (over intercom): Riggan,
everyone's set for one-four.
They're ready for you.
Riggan, they're ready for you.
♪ ♪
(closes zipper)
MAN (over speaker):
Paul, just wait for Mr. Thomson.
Mr. Thomson.
Steve.
It's Daniel.
Okay.
MAN: Oh, hey, buddy.
Hey.
How you doing?
Pretty good. Good.
You know, I'd be a lot better
if I could get, uh,
Ralph to stop,
you know, acting.
It's gonna be fine.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And he was yelling, "I love you,
I love you, bitch."
What do you do with
a love like that?
How is th... That is not love,
and you know it.
Why do you insist
on calling it love?
You can say what you want,
but I know what it was.
What about you, Nick?
Does that sound
like love to you?
Sorry I'm late. Uh, does
that sound like love to me?
Look, I'm the wrong
person to ask.
I only knew... heard the man's
name mentioned in passing.
I wouldn't know. You'd have
to know the particulars.
But I think what
you're saying is,
love is absolute,
right? Yeah.
Yeah.
The kind of love
I'm talking about is...
the kind of love
I'm talking about,
you don't try and kill people.
It was love, Mel.
To Eddie, it was.
I don't care
what anyone says.
He was ready
to die for it.
Ask her what he did
after she left him.
(sighs) He shot
himself in the mouth,
but he screwed that
up, too. Poor Ed.
(laughs):
Poor Ed, my ass!
The guy was... dangerous!
WOMAN: Well,
how'd he screw it up
if he shot himself
in the mouth?
He used to carry this .22.
We lived like fugitives then.
Okay, Ralph, Ralph, Ralph.
Fugitives are scared, you know?
Fugitives are on the run.
Yeah.
So, you know,
how many times do we...
Can you just give me
a little more of that?
You know, fear or something?
Yes, great idea.
(panting): We lived
like fugitives then.
I never knew if he was gonna
come out from behind a bush,
or-or a car,
and just start shooting.
(trembling):
The man was crazy.
He was capable
of anything.
WOMAN: Christ,
what a nightmare.
Yeah. He used to call me up
at the hospital and say,
"Son of a bitch,
your days are numbered!"
(panting):
That's too much?
It's a little bit too much,
I can tell, because...
I just want to
give you a range.
WOMAN:
Holy shit!
Someone call 911!
Oh, my God, is he breathing?
Yeah.
Is that blood
coming out of his ear?
It's okay. He's
still breathing.
Where are you going?
Well, did someone
call for help?
Do not move him!
Wait for an ambulance!
Did someone call for help?
Well, that's gonna be
a fucking lawsuit!
Okay, where are you going?
The understudy will be ready
in less than five minutes.
Forget the understudy.
We're gonna have to
cancel the first preview.
But it's a full house!
We would have to refund
the entire...
Just do it. Just do it.
What happened? How's Ralph?
He'll be fine.
Wait, wait, wait.
Will you fucking wait?
Listen to me, Jake,
it was gonna be a disaster.
That guy's the worst actor
I've ever seen in my life.
The blood coming out of his ear
was the most honest thing
he's done so far.
He's not that bad.
(whispers): Okay, he's
fucking terrible, but...
Listen, you have the press
in your dressing room
in a few hours...
I'll make something up.
I don't know, I'll think
of something, I'll riff.
Listen, hold on.
That wasn't an accident.
What...
Hey.
What do you mean?
I made it happen.
Oh, okay.
Are you drunk?
Just find me an actor,
a good actor.
Give me, uh...
Woody Harrelson.
He's doing
the next Hunger Games.
Um, uh, Michael Fassbender.
He's doing the prequel
to the X-Men prequel.
How about, uh, uh,
Jeremy Renner?
Who?
Jeremy Renner!
He was nominated.
Oh, okay.
Uh, he was the Hurt Locker guy.
He's an Avenger.
Fuck! They put him
in a cape, too?
God, I can't believe this.
I don't care-- just
find me someone.
(whispers):
Ralph will sue us.
He'll sue us,
and he has a case.
Just make it go away.
Look, you're my attorney.
You're my producer.
You're my best friend.
Right? Now, go out there and
do what you were born to do.
I don't care how
you do it, just go.
Just make it go away.
How do you suppose
I do... how...
WOMAN (on TV): ...all
the fastest fights and splits.
And when we come back,
an exclusive interview
with Robert Downey Jr.,
who's busy following up
his billion-dollar
Iron Man franchise
with the equally successful
Avengers series.
He will take us
behind the scenes...
(heavy sigh)
That clown doesn't have
half your talent,
and he's making a fortune
in that Tin Man getup.
(sighs)
We were the real thing,
Riggan.
(mumbles)
Okay.
We had it all.
(deep breath)
We gave it away.
Breathing in.
We handed these poseurs
the keys to the kingdom.
Breathing out.
You listening to me?
I smile to it.
Breathing in,
I embrace my anger.
(chuckles)
Yeah. Embrace it.
But I'm not going away.
You know I'm right.
(exhales)
(quietly):
Fuck.
Look at that.
These people don't know
what you're capable of.
MAN: Why would somebody go
from playing the lead
in a comic book franchise
to adapting Raymond Carver
for the stage? I...
You know,
as you're probably aware,
Barthes said, "The cultural work
done in the past
"by gods and epic sagas
"is now being done
by laundry detergent commercials
and comic strip characters."
This is a big leap
you've taken.
Yeah, it is.
Absolutely.
Absolutely. And...
(clears throat)
you know... like you said,
that, uh, uh,
Barthes said, uh...
See, Birdman, like Icarus...
Okay, wait-wait. Hang on.
Who is this Barthes guy?
Which Birdman was he in?
Uh, Roland Barthes was
a French philosopher,
and if you knew anything
about the history...
Sure. Now, is it true
you've been injecting yourself
with semen from baby pigs?
I-I'm sorry. What?
As a method of
facial rejuvenation?
Wh-Where did you read that?
It was tweeted by...
@ProstateWhispers.
(laughs): No, that's not true.
I know, but did you do it?
No, I didn't do it. I just...
I just said it's not true.
Okay, I'll just write
you're denying it.
No, don't write anything.
Why would you write anything?
I didn't... I didn't do...
Don't write what she said.
I didn't do it. I didn't put
any baby pig's sem...
MAN: Just, if you will,
are you at all afraid
that people will say
you're doing this play
to battle the impression that
you're a washed-up superhero?
No, absolutely not,
absolutely not.
That's why 20 years ago,
I said no to Birdman 4.
Oh...! Birdman 4?!
JAKE: Thank you, everybody.
You do Birdman 4?
Thanks for coming out.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
We're expecting
some great pieces.
(sighs)
Guys in publicity...
now want a Times feature,
which is the worst idea
right now.
(deep breath)
What are you doing?
I don't want to look
at this anymore.
That-that was a present
from the crew.
D-Don't fuck with those guys;
they're union.
I don't care.
How'd it go?
Good.
They talk about Ralph at all?
He did it, you know.
The motherfucker did it.
Threatened to sue us.
Didn't even wait to get
out of the hospital.
What'd you say?
What did I say?
Shit. Goddamn it.
I said, "You motherfucker,
"are you threatening me?
Where am I gonna put this?
"I swear to God, I so much as
get a letter from a lawyer,
then the press is gonna get
the pictures off your computer."
That's what I said.
What pictures?
He has a thing
for nuns in diapers.
Why do you care?
You shouldn't have any
knowledge of that, anyway.
The point is, is I
made it go away.
That's right.
That's great.
Yeah, it is fantastic,
except one thing.
What?
We don't have an actor.
Uh-huh.
And if we cancel
the first preview,
the press is gonna
smell blood,
and we can't afford to lose
any more money at all.
Okay, what do you think
I should do?
Well, we hired an understudy;
let's use the understudy.
No.
Riggan, listen to me.
Please, for the
love of God, listen.
Our perfect dream actor is not
gonna knock on that door
and go, "Hey, fellas, when
do I start?" You know?
(knocking)
Can I talk to you for a second?
Yeah, what's up?
Did you find another actor?
No.
Okay, well, Mike's available.
He is?
Mm-hmm.
Mike who?
I thought he was doing
the thing...
He was. He quit.
Or got fired.
Mike who?
Which is it,
quit or fired?
Well, with Mike,
it's usually both.
Mike fucking who?
Shiner.
Yes!
Jake.
Oh, my gosh.
How do you know Mike Shiner?
We share a vagina.
You think he'd
want to do it?
Mm-hmm.
How do you know?
'Cause he told me
he'd want to do it.
Yes! Yes.
Jake, Jake.
Ask me if he sells tickets.
Fine, does he sell tickets?
He sells a shitload
of tickets.
Okay.
Now ask me if the
theater critics love him.
Do theater critics love him?
They want to
spooge on him.
Hey.
Lesley?
Right on his face.
Everything for
a reason, right?
You think he'd come in
this evening?
I'll call him and find out.
I'll call his agent.
(whispering):
Oh, baby. Amazing, amazing.
Annie?
Clear the theater,
send everyone to dinner
and give me some lights.
We got a put-in tonight.
Who is it?
You'll find out.
It's intimidating, isn't it?
You have any idea the people
who have walked on these boards
before you?
Geraldine Page,
Helen Hayes,
Jason Robards,
Marlon Brando and now...
Riggan Thomson.
(chuckling): Yeah.
Hey, thanks for coming in
on such short notice, Mike.
I really appreciate it.
This is what I do.
You-you-you wrote
this adaptation?
I did, yeah.
Ah, and you're directing
and starring in your adaptation?
I am, yeah.
That's ambitious.
Well, thanks.
Well, it's a good theater.
I can't speak for your play,
but let's, uh,
let's do
a little bit of it, yeah?
Oh, I didn't expect you
to come in and,
you know, just jump right in.
It's first preview
tomorrow night, man.
Let's-let's get to work.
Okay.
Well, you know, look,
you know,
feel free to take the script up
until you feel comfortable.
No, no, no, no, let's just...
let's just do-do some of it.
All right.
Okay, uh, hey, take
a look at page 20.
I-I'm good; I don't need that.
What?
I don't need the script.
Just give me a cue.
What are you talking about?
Feed me a line.
Well, how-how...
how are you gonna...
Feed me a line.
Okay, all right.
Okay, uh, let me think.
Uh...
Yeah, uh...
Hey, I'm the wrong
person to ask, okay?
I didn't actually
know the man.
I only heard his name
mentioned in passing.
Mm-hmm.
I don't know.
You'd have to know
the particulars,
but I think what you're saying
is love is absolute.
Is that what I'm saying?
Am I saying love is absolute?
Yes. Okay, yeah.
The kind of love that
I'm talking about is absolute.
The kind of love
that I'm talking about...
You don't try to kill people.
How do you know the lines?
It's a thing I have.
I don't know, it's a gift.
Wow, okay, well, that's...
(chuckles)
Oh, come on, man.
I've been...
I've been helping Lesley
get off book for like a month.
Oh, right, right.
These lines are...
That makes sense.
Right, right, right.
That's good.
Okay, okay.
Give me my cue again.
Hey, I'm the wrong
person to ask.
I didn't actually
know the man.
I've heard his name
mentioned in passing,
but, you know, I didn't know.
You never know the particulars.
I think what you're saying,
though, is that...
C-Can I make a suggestion?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, sure.
I mean, do you mind?
No, no, no, not at all.
Not at all.
Oh, okay.
Take a look. Okay.
No, no, for-forget that.
Just-just...
Stay with me.
Yeah.
"I'm the wrong person
to ask," he says,
Right.
but what is that?
What's the
intention in that?
I think...
Is he fed up with the subject,
so he's changing it?
Is he deflecting guilt
over the marriage?
And here's the thing, you've got
four lines after that
that all say
the same thing.
Right.
"I didn't even know the man."
"I-I only heard his name
mentioned in passing."
"I wouldn't know."
"You'd have to know
the particulars."
And the particulars, I mean,
it sounds like my grandmother,
but-but-but the point is,
you don't know the guy.
Right.
We fucking get it.
Yeah.
Make it work with one line.
"I didn't even know the man."
Right?
Yeah, right.
(clicks tongue)
Wait, how-how do...
You know my lines, too, huh?
C-Can we not get hung up
on knowing lines?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Can we just work on this,
Yeah, yeah, right, right.
tear it apart, whatever?
So-so-so why don't you just
give me that same thing again,
but cut it down.
Uh-huh.
Try it. Just try it.
Okay.
Uh... Hey, I'm the wrong
person to ask.
I didn't actually know the guy.
Oh! No!
But that's the thing, see?
"I'm the wrong person to ask."
What is it?
I think it's "fuck you."
Fuck you. Don't-don't put me
on the spot, man.
I...
Don't-don't make me feel
self-conscious about my marriage
while my l...
my wife is sitting...
Right there.
...right there.
Yeah.
Can I sit down for this?
Yeah, sit, sit.
Good idea.
Okay. Thanks.
Yeah.
So-so just-just give it to me
as a "fuck you."
Right.
Try it, lay it on me.
Yeah.
Let's just do it. Come on.
Give it to me. Fuck me hard.
Well, I'm thinking. Okay.
Just-just give it...
Yeah, right.
Come on! Don't talk about it!
Okay, I'm giving...
Just fucking do it!
Hey, I'm the wrong
person to ask!
All right?
I don't even know the guy, okay?
What's your point?
What's my point?
Yeah, what's your point?
What are you saying?
Spit it out.
Oh! Oh!
You're saying what?
What are you saying?
You're saying love is absolute.
Yes! Yes!
The kind of love that I'm
talking about, it is absolute!
The kind of love
that I'm talking about,
you don't...
(crying)
You don't try to kill people.
Yeah. Good.
I don't know,
what do you think, boss?
Wow. Okay.
You want to do
this with me?
What do you think?
Everybody's back.
Larry needs to see him
for a fitting.
I'll take that as a yes.
So who are you?
That's Sam, my daughter.
Oh, your daughter?
Wow, that's amazing.
You don't look anything
like each other.
What do you do?
Um, I'm his...
She's my assistant.
Works for me.
Mm-hmm.
And does she talk, uh,
and speak?
She does, yeah.
Mmm.
She can even sit or stay
or roll over
if you have any treats.
Hey, welcome aboard, Mike!
Thank you, Captain.
(softly): Yeah.
Um, I'm Mike Shiner, by the way.
Oh, I know who you are.
I, uh, I saw you in
Hothouse at the Geffen.
You were great.
Oh, thank you.
Your ass is great.
Dude, seriously?
See, you see,
that was just me...
Larry?
This is the theater,
sweetheart.
Don't be so self-conscious.
He's here.
Okay, thank the Lord
and pass the biscuits.
I finally have
an actor to dress.
How have you been, Larry?
Better now that you're here.
Take off your clothes.
See how we do.
Okay.
You just gonna stand there?
This is the
theater, honey.
Don't be so
self-conscious.
We'll have to start
from scratch
with less than 24 hours.
Here, try these.
Holy shi...
What's happening?
Where are you underpants?
Under the bed at home, I think.
Okay, uh, n-no.
O-O-Okay, okay.
Everything's too small.
You're not kidding.
Oh.
Oh, that's nice.
Forgive him, Larry.
Mike's like
my five-year-old son.
Neither of them has
clean underwear.
Or pubic hair, I imagine.
Okay, I can alter the suit,
but we're gonna have to make
new trousers and shirts.
And underwear.
What are you doing?
Waiting on Larry.
LARRY: I'm finished!
Then I'm just standing
with my cock out.
Well, get dressed.
Riggan's daughter
is hanging around,
and I don't need her
to walk in here.
Lesley.
No, Mike, you haven't seen her.
She's always hanging around,
watching everyone.
Like Little Miss Creepy.
Mm-hmm.
Les?
I don't know if it's the drugs
that fried her brain or what,
but I just don't want her
running to her father
saying you showed her your junk.
Then we should ask
her to leave.
Oh, God, really?
Mm-hmm. Sammy?
SAM:
It's Sam.
Fuck.
Sam. Lesley.
Oh, listen, um,
when I said that,
I didn't...
Don't worry about it.
He's a handful, huh?
How is it that you always manage
to find a new way
to humiliate me?
Oh, to be fair,
you make it really easy.
What the hell was
she doing here?
She brought me down.
And stayed?
Well, she is
a little... something.
Listen, Mike,
this is Broadway,
and I'm here, finally.
Now, please, just
do me a favor,
I'm begging you,
don't fuck it up!
Lesley.
Come here. Come here.
(exhales)
(whispers):
Play with my balls.
(grunting):
Don't do it!
MIKE (laughing):
Yeah! Ow!
RIGGAN: I don't care,
just sign it.
JAKE: Listen to me.
No, you listen to me.
I can't afford
to listen to you.
LARRY: I'm gonna have
to go shopping again!
Just sew something,
you old fuck.
Just get him whatever he wants!
His agent's asking
for four times what we were
paying what's-his-name.
Well, just go into
the reserve, Jake.
The reserve is gone--
we spent it on fog
and those fake trees and the...
It's a dream sequence, Jake.
dancing midgets.
I've gotta... Don't say...
You're not allowed to
say midgets anymore.
The reserve is gone!
You didn't see what I just saw.
I'm telling you,
this guy's the real deal.
I could feel it in my bones--
he's the actor
we've been waiting for.
Come on, just get
the contract done. Please, Jake.
I'll get the money.
Okay, I'll do it.
Okay.
Get that smile off your face.
You're freaking me out.
Okay. Sorry. You're right.
(whispers): Hey!
Is it true?
Yeah. Yeah, he said yes.
Shiner? Holy shit.
When can I meet him?
He's in a fitting
with Larry right now.
LESLEY: Hey, guys.
I'm going to Starbucks.
You want anything?
I'm good, I'm good.
She has a great ass.
Yeah, she does.
Hey, I have some
news for you, too.
Is it good or is it bad?
'Cause right now I really...
I missed my last
two periods.
I think it's
really happening.
(exhales)
Well...
Is that good or bad?
Riggan!
It's good. It's good.
It's great.
Well, say something else.
Uh, uh... okay...
Uh, are you sure
it's mine?
(soft chuckle)
Well, you know,
there's you, there's Jake.
I'm joking.
You know, that masseur
wore a condom--
yeah, I'm pretty sure
it's yours, yeah.
(chuckles):
Idiot.
(Riggan panting)
Are you excited?
Yeah. Yeah.
Me, too.
Oh.
What?!
You're not funny!
I...
(whispers):
What?
Hey.
Mmm...
♪ ♪
(exhales)
LESLEY (in distance):
I'm telling you, he did love me.
First preview tomorrow.
♪ ♪
Here we go.
MIKE (in distance):
In front of us, in the room!
I mean, I... I... I rode
with him in the ambulance
to the hospital.
(Family Guy playing on TV)
LESLEY: I will never get
that image out of my head.
Right before he did it,
those eyes,
they were so...
sad and-and lonely.
LAURA:
Did you have to treat him?
MIKE: No, I didn't have to,
but I did...
ANNIE: Music... out.
(dialogue continues)
Cue 34, 35, ready.
MIKE: He was in terrible shape.
His head had swelled up.
It was twice the size
of a normal head.
He's good, huh?
He's incredible.
Yeah.
MIKE: I've never seen anything
like that in my life...
I think he's
drinking real gin.
What?
MIKE: Ask-ask Nick.
I-I want you to ask Nick
if he thinks that that's love.
LESLEY: Oh, honey,
can't we just go...
He'll agree with me.
(Mike, Laura and Lesley
all talking at once)
LAURA: You don't know
how he's been lately.
He's been depressed;
I've been worried about him.
You've been what?
Let me tell you...
let me tell you guys
something about real love.
Then I'll tell you something.
We all should be ashamed
when we talk like we know
what we're talking about
when we talk about love.
Oh, for God's sake.
Are you getting drunk, Nick?
I don't have to be drunk
to say what I think.
Nobody's drunk--
we're just having a few drinks.
Exactly.
Well, you've had
more than a few.
What are you, counting?
Hey, leave her alone.
If you're not drunk,
don't talk
like you're drunk.
Shut up!
Do me a favor, for
once in your life,
honest to God,
shut up for a minute.
(light audience laughter)
Anyway... like I was saying,
you want to know
about real love,
there's this old couple...
had a car wreck
out on the interstate.
Some drunk kid...
plows his old man's pickup...
right into their camper.
By the time
I got down to the hospital,
this kid, fucking teenager,
was dead.
So we took the old couple
up to the O.R.,
and we worked like hell on them
through most of the night.
By the time...
we were done with them,
we just, you know,
wrapped them...
in their full body casts.
The husband, the old man...
was depressed...
for the longest time.
Even after I said to him, "Look,
your wife's gonna pull through,"
he was still depressed.
(sighs) So... I went up
to the mouth hole
and I asked him.
(chuckles softly)
And he told me
it was because he couldn't...
see her...
through the eye holes.
Couldn't see his wife.
Can you imagine?
MIKE: What?
I'm telling you...
this guy's heart was breaking
because...
(Mike groans)
he couldn't turn
his goddamn head...
and just look
at his goddamn wife.
MIKE:
Shit.
(exhales)
I mean, it was killing this guy.
I-I am so tired of this.
Is this water?
It was killing the guy.
Did you replace my gin
with water, man?
No. No.
RIGGAN: Mike, come on.
LESLEY: Oh!
"Come on," what?
Come on, you're drunk.
I'm drunk?
Yes, I'm drunk.
I'm supposed to be drunk.
Why aren't you drunk?
This is Carver! He left a piece
Shit, Mike...
of his liver on the table every
time he wrote a fucking page.
If I need to be drinking gin,
who the fuck are you
to touch my gin, man?
Don't fucking do this now.
Listen, you fucked
with the period,
you fucked with the plot so you
could have the best lines.
You leave me the fucking
tools that I need!
Shut the fuck up.
(booing)
Oh, come on, people,
don't be so pathetic.
Stop looking at the world
through your cell phone screen!
(jeering)
Have a real experience!
Does anybody give a shit
about truth other than me?
Come on. Come on.
I mean, the set is fake.
Come on, Mike.
The bananas are fake.
LESLEY: Cut it out, Mike.
There's fucking nothing
in this milk carton.
Shut up.
(jeering continues)
Your performance is fake.
The only thing
that is real on this stage...
LESLEY:
Mike, please, for God's sake.
Shut up.
...is this chicken.
So I'm gonna work
with the chicken.
(Lesley gasps)
(audience laughter)
MIKE: That was interesting.
Bring the curtain down.
Hey, that's
good bird, man.
(audience jeering, whistling)
Get him out of here.
How do you want me
to do that?
(Family Guy playing on TV)
JAKE: Hey. Hey, wait.
I want him gone.
No. What?
We cannot do that.
Of course we can do that!
It's our show!
Listen to me, please.
No, you listen to me.
Listen to me.
Get him the fuck
out of my play.
I'm not gonna
stand up there...
It was a preview!
Nobody gives a shit
about a preview!
Nothing matters until that
old bat from The New York Times
is sitting in that audience
opening night.
No. We're getting rid of him.
I don't give a shit.
I'm not gonna
stand out there...
Just shut up!
Shut up and listen
to me for once!
As soon as we announced
he was taking over,
the advance doubled,
and that took less than a day.
We can't afford
to lose a preview,
we can't afford
to lose any more money,
and we can't afford
to lose Mike.
(panting):
This has been about...
this is about being... respected
and validated, remember?
That's what you told me!
That's how you got me
into this shit!
You're the director.
Get him under control, okay?
(panting)
Fuck.
This isn't the '90s anymore.
Your zipper's down.
(quietly):
Fuck!
(zips pants)
Hey.
You were really
good, cabrón.
(growls)
Hey! Out in front of the theater
in ten minutes!
Don't overthink it.
(knobs squeak)
(faucet running)
WOMAN: What the hell
was going on up there?
I didn't know
you were here tonight.
That guy's
an asshole, huh?
Yeah, what are you...
what are you doing here?
Sam and I are gonna grab
a bite after she's finished.
No, no, I mean here. Now.
Well... I know how much
this means to you.
Oh. Thanks.
I appreciate that.
So what's happening?
With the play?
You saw what's happening.
No, no. You and Sam.
Oh. It's...
you know, it's great.
It's the same.
Do you talk to her?
Yeah. We talk. I...
You know, it's just been so
crazy around here, you know?
You understand
where her head is at
these days.
Yeah. Of course.
You know, she's trying
to stay away from everything
and everyone that got her
into rehab in the first place,
so, you know.
Yeah, yeah. I know.
I really do.
I get it. I get it.
But, you know,
that's all she's had,
so she's confused.
Yeah. I get it.
Look, I know you're
caught up in all this stuff,
but you just have to...
"Stuff"?
Uh, uh... you know
what I mean.
(sighs) Riggan, you don't have
to be a great father right now.
Y-You just have to be one.
Oh, sorry.
How's that going?
I'd rather not talk about that.
You drinking?
Yeah, I'm having a beer.
Okay.
So...
what's going on with you?
Me? Oh.
Yeah.
(chuckles):
Nothing.
Everything's
the same, I guess.
I'm going back to teaching.
Oh, yeah?
Hey, uh...
I'm thinking of refinancing
the Malibu house.
What? I'm sorry?
I'm thinking of refinancing...
No. I heard you.
I just need a second.
That's gonna be Sam's house.
Why would you...
For this play?
(exhales)
I need the money.
Do you have any idea
how crazy that sounds?
What do you want me to say?
My health lasted
longer than the money--
go figure that out.
What's going on?
Riggan, look at me.
(quiet grunt)
I got a chance
to do something right.
I got to take it.
I got to.
You know, it's funny,
I was sitting here
waiting for you,
and all of a sudden
I couldn't remember
why we broke up.
Hey, you know, the last time
I flew here from L.A....
George Clooney was sitting,
like, two seats in...
in front of me with a nice pair
of cuff links and that...
fucking chin.
(exhales) We ended up
flying through this really...
really horrible storm.
I mean, the plane was, like,
rattling, shaking, and, uh...
(clears throat) all the people
on board are... crying.
I mean, crying.
Praying, right?
I just sat there.
They're crying; I sit there.
And I'm thinking:
Oh, boy, the next morning
when Sam looks at the paper,
it's gonna be Clooney's face
on the front page, not mine.
(wry chuckle)
You know? Boom.
(snorts)
How do you...
(soft laugh)
Did you know Farrah Fawcett died
the exact same day
as Michael Jackson?
Is that crazy?
(kiss)
Why did we break up?
Because you threw
a kitchen knife at me,
and an hour later
you were telling me
how much you loved me.
You know, just
because I didn't like
that ridiculous comedy
you did with Goldie Hawn
did not mean that
I did not love you.
That's what you always do--
you confuse love for admiration.
It's your house--
you do what you want with it.
You just make sure
you're there for our daughter.
(quietly):
I will.
You're not
Farrah Fawcett, Riggan.
We should have done
that reality show
they offered us--
The Thomsons.
Shut up.
That would've been good.
Crazy, druggy,
wise-ass daughter,
MILF-y wife
with the perky tits.
People would have wanted
to see that.
Shut up.
More than I can say
for this piece of shit.
Shut up.
♪ ♪
The sun bed is here.
What does that mean?
It means there is
a sun bed out there
being delivered to in here.
Well, who ordered a sun bed?
Mike. He said it's
for his character.
Part of his process
and that shit.
Fuck.
He said he has
to be a redneck.
(whispers):
Son of a bitch.
Goddamn it.
♪ ♪
RIGGAN: Let's go. Walk.
Where are we going?
To get you some coffee.
Did I do something
to disrespect you?
Not yet.
Look, I have a lot riding
on this fucking play.
Oh, is that right? Oh.
Yeah. People know who I am,
Fucking bullshit.
and it...
Mike...
Bullshit. They...
they don't know you,
your work, man-- they know
the guy from the bird suit
who goes and tells coy,
slightly vomitous stories
on Letterman.
Well, I'm sorry
if I'm popular, Mike.
Popular? I don't give
a shit. Popular?!
Popularity is the slutty little
cousin of prestige, my friend.
Okay, I don't even know
what the fuck that means, so...
Here.
Mmm, it-it means...
it means my reputation
is riding on this,
and that's worth a... a...
Lot.
A lot. Exactly.
Right. Right.
Fuck you! Yes!
If this doesn't
work out for you,
you fuck off back
to your studio pals
Right.
and dive back into
that cultural genocide
you guys are perpetrating.
You know, a douche bag's
born every minute.
That was P.T. Barnum's premise
when he invented the circus,
and nothing much has changed,
and you guys know
that if you crank out
any toxic piece of crap,
people will line up
and pay to see it.
But long after you're gone,
I'm gonna be on that stage,
earning my living,
baring my soul,
wrestling with complex
human emotions,
'cause that's what we do.
Right. Oh, so that...
is that what tonight
was about-- you wrestling
with complex emotions?
No. Tonight was just about
seeing if it's even alive,
seeing if it can bleed.
No, this isn't
a back lot, Riggan.
This is New York City.
This is how we do things.
Where you going?
They have coffee here.
♪ ♪
(sighs):
Thanks, Tommy.
They were laughing
in our fucking faces.
MIKE: Tonight
they were laughing;
tomorrow they'll be
tweeting. Fuck 'em.
Who cares?
These are the people
who pay half price
to watch us rehearse.
Stop fucking caring.
This play is a drama.
We're doing Raymond Carver.
This play's about...
You don't know
what this play is about.
I do know what
this play's about.
No, you don't.
Oh, man.
That's what
previews are for.
That's why they
call them previews.
That's where you figure out
what the play is.
I mean...
Okay, look, look.
Listen to me.
Do you see the woman
at the far end of the bar?
The one who looks like she
licked a homeless man's ass?
Yeah.
The only thing that matters
is what she writes about us
in 500 words in the Times.
That's, uh...
Tabitha Dickinson, yes.
Yeah.
Well, believe it or not,
the only opinion that matters
in your theater is hers.
If she likes us, we run;
if she doesn't, we're fucked.
(quietly): She does
look like she licked
a homeless guy's ass.
Do me a favor.
Don't get your panties in
a twist over a fucking preview
like some rookie, and don't
tell me how to do my job.
This is my town,
and, to be honest,
most people don't give
a shit about you here.
You're Riggan Thomson, right?
MAN: Sorry to interrupt you.
Would you mind
having a picture with us here?
No, no, no, no.
Just... Oh, thank you.
Would you mind?
What?
The button's on the bottom.
(whispers):
Okay. Get in there.
BOY: Who is this guy?
He used to be Birdman.
BOY:
Huh?
(click)
Okay.
Ah, great.
Oh, you're such a doll.
Okay.
Thank you. You're so sweet.
Thanks.
Handsome.
Thanks. Thanks for... Oh.
MAN: O-Okay,
sweetheart, come on.
Are we good here?
I'm gonna go home.
All right.
See you tomorrow.
Oh, wait.
I-I want to know something.
Why Raymond Carver?
I was a kid...
in, uh, high school
doing a play in Syracuse,
and he was in the audience.
And he, uh...
(clears throat)
sent this back...
afterwards.
Little note.
"Thank you
for an honest performance.
Ray Carver."
Yeah.
Yeah?
That's when I knew...
I was gonna be an actor.
Right there.
(snickering)
Oh...
What's so funny?
Nothing. It's just,
it's on a cocktail napkin.
Yeah, so?
He was fucking drunk, man.
(pats arm)
WOMAN: You headed
to Hollywood, Mike?
No.
No. Hollywood's
heading here, Tabby.
Good luck with that.
"A man becomes a critic
when he cannot be an artist,
"the same way that a man
becomes an informer
when he cannot be a soldier."
That's Flaubert, right?
He's a Hollywood clown
in a Lycra bird suit.
Yes, he is.
But tomorrow night at 8:00,
he's going out on that stage
and risking everything.
What'll you be doing?
Don't you ever worry that
I'll give you a bad review?
I'm sure you will,
if I ever give you
a bad performance.
Miss Dickinson.
Mr. Shiner.
♪ ♪
BARTENDER:
Thanks for coming in.
(indistinct chatter)
♪ ♪
Hey.
What are you
still doing here?
Nothing.
Nothing. Um... your costumes are
hanging in your dressing room.
(sniffs)
Oh, great, great.
Oh, I got that coconut water
that you wanted.
Um, if you want
the fake stuff,
Hey.
it's not open
till tomorrow. What?
Uh... I'm not sure
that I said thank you.
For what?
For everything.
I mean, you've been doing
a really good job,
and, you know, honestly.
Yeah.
I've been so
preoccupied with all...
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, well, I...
just wanted to say that, and...
(clears throat)
(panting quietly)
What is that?
What?
That smell.
What is it? Look at me.
(mumbles): I don't know.
Look at me!
What? What?
Goddamn, you got
to be shitting me.
Dad...
Where is it?
Can we not do this, please?
Dad?
Where is it?
I can't believe this.
(Sam groans quietly)
Wha... What is this?
Chunky peanut butter.
This. This.
What is that?
Ah.
That's pot.
Relax.
"Relax." You can't
do this to me!
To you?
Oh, shut up! You know
what I'm talking about.
Uh, yeah, you're
talking about you!
What else is new?
No, don't do the thing...
The thing where I
make it about me?
Look, I'm trying to do something
that's important.
This is not important!
It's important to me!
Okay? Maybe not to you
or your cynical friends
whose only ambition
is to go viral!
But to me, this is...
my God, this is my career!
This is my chance
to finally do some work
that actually means something!
That means something to who?
You had a career, Dad, before
the third comic book movie.
Before people started to forget
who was inside
that bird costume!
You are doing a play
based on a book
that was written 60 years ago
for a thousand
rich old white people
whose only real concern
is gonna be where they go
to have their cake and coffee
when it's over!
Nobody gives a shit but you!
And... let's face it, Dad,
you are not doing this
for the sake of art.
You are doing this because
you want to feel relevant again.
Well, guess what, there is
an entire world out there
where people fight to be
relevant every single day,
and you act like
it doesn't exist.
Things are happening in a place
that you ignore,
a place that, by the way,
has already forgotten about you!
I mean, who the fuck are you?!
You hate bloggers,
you mock Twitter.
You don't even have
a Facebook page!
You're the one
who doesn't exist!
You're doing this
because you're scared to death,
like the rest of us,
that you don't matter.
And you know what?
You're right.
You don't!
It's not important, okay?
You're not important--
get used to it!
Dad...
(Sam sighs)
(lighter clicks)
(exhales heavily)
(gasps)
LAURA: In the days
before Nick's depression
started to eat away at him,
he never knew I was pregnant,
and I never intended
on telling him.
I guess we make choices in life,
and we choose to live with them.
Or not.
I didn't want that baby.
Not because I didn't love Nick,
and not because I didn't love
the idea of it,
but just because I wasn't ready
to love myself.
There's a distance
to it all now.
A wistful distance
underscored by a gentle breeze
Actors in position.
and the sound of the birds
Music out.
laughing at the whimsy
of it all.
We have Laura onstage.
Lesley?
Roll it.
Roll it, go, go.
What?
I think I'm hard.
No, you're not.
It's just that sometimes
you don't consider
other people's feelings,
that's all.
No, no, no, I'm getting hard.
Feel that.
(squeals) What?
Come on.
You got to be kidding me.
Let's really do it;
let's really fuck.
No, are you crazy?
No, it'll be incredible.
Stop it!
It'll be so real.
Trust me, trust me.
Cut it out, Mike.
Get off!
I'm serious, Mike.
Don't call me Mike;
call me Mel, Mel.
Get off!
Okay, just let me...
(pounding)
Terri! Terri!
Mike!
Don't stop.
No, Lesley, don't stop.
Kiss me.
No!
Come on, kiss me, kiss me.
Terri, I know
you're in there!
Get off me! Get off!
Damn, Terri!
(groaning)
Ed?
Why?
What are you doing here?
I just need you
to tell me why.
Take it easy, all right,
take it easy.
I know this is hard.
(audience laughing)
Shut up! Shut...
Shut up!
Okay, just don't do
anything stupid.
I know...
Hey!
Eddie, please!
What's the matter with me?
Why do I always end up having
to beg people to love me?
Eddie, please, give me the gun.
Look at me.
I was drowning.
I'm just not capable of lo...
You-you deserve
to be loved, Eddie.
You do.
I just wanted to be
what you wanted.
Now I spend every fucking minute
praying to be somebody else,
somebody I'm not.
Anybody.
Okay, j-j-just put
the gun down, Ed.
She just doesn't
love you anymore.
(thunder rumbling)
You don't, do you?
No.
And you never will?
(softly):
I'm sorry.
(sighs)
I don't exist.
I'm not even here.
None of this even matters.
I don't exist. I don't exist.
Ed?
No.
I don't even exist.
Ed! Eddie, Eddie!
No, Eddie, no!
No, no, don't do that!
(gunshot)
(audience gasping)
(thunder rumbling)
(applause)
LESLEY (sniffles):
You're such an asshole!
MIKE: An a...
Are you kidding me?
That's the best I've
seen you onstage ever.
Why would you do that?
What the fuck?
We were onstage!
It's like my head's
a jar of Bolognese.
Give me the blood rig.
I'll fix it.
What is this?
Listen, they're supposed to be
two people who are in love.
They're fucking in a motel,
having sex with each other.
You've got to be shitting me.
You-you can't get it up
in six months,
and now you want to fuck me
in front of 800 strangers?!
Look, I need it
to feel real, okay?
I-I need that intensity.
You've known that
about me from
the beginning.
Oh, fuck you!
Oh.
Look, I...
I was in the moment.
I thought that you were, too.
I'm sorry.
(applause)
I told you to stop,
you fucking animal.
(applause continues)
You were brilliant.
Brilliant.
What is wrong with you?
(audience shouting, cheering)
(chuckles)
I want your shit
out of the apartment.
Wait, what?
Hey, no, no, no, wait.
Okay, look, look,
look, look, look,
I-I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Can we just...
Look, can we...
No, we can't, Mike!
You know, maybe up here
you're Mr. Truth,
but in the real world
where it counts,
you're a fucking fraud!
How's that feel for truth,
you dick?
Oh, sorry.
What's going on?
He's such an asshole.
What'd he do now?
Oh, nothing,
he just tried to fuck me
in front of an entire audience!
Oh, my God.
Right?
That's kind of hot.
(sniffles, sobs)
(grunts)
Why don't I have
any self-respect?!
Oh, you're an actress, honey.
I'm pathetic.
Look at me.
(sniffling)
You know, I...
I've always dreamed of
being a Broadway actress
since I was a little kid,
and now I'm here, and I...
I'm not a Broadway actress.
I'm still just a little kid.
And I keep waiting for someone
to tell me I've made it.
Hey.
You made it.
I did?
Sadly, it was with Mike Shiner
in a fake motel bed
in front of, like,
800 people, but...
(laughs)
Oh, shut up!
(sobbing continues)
(knocking)
Oh, God.
RIGGAN:
Hey, is she okay?
Yeah, she's gonna be fine.
(sighs, sniffles)
Look, none of this
is your fault, okay?
Okay, look,
you're beautiful,
and you're talented,
and I'm lucky I have you.
Okay?
Okay.
(sighs)
That was kind of sweet.
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Two years, and he's never said
anything like that to me.
Hey.
You're beautiful,
and you're talented,
and I'm lucky to have you.
Okay?
We're gross.
(laughing):
We are.
(sighs)
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Do it again.
MIKE: Can we talk about this
like two mature artists?
I mean, what really
is the big deal about...
Fuck you!
You're not ready yet.
That's fine.
Hmm.
Fuck.
Actresses.
They drive me fucking crazy.
Riggan? Riggan.
Your gun is ridiculous.
I can see the red plug
in the barrel,
so you look like a kid
with a plastic toy
when you point it at me.
I don't feel threatened at all.
Get a better one.
Have some self-respect, please.
Hey, apart from that,
I mean, uh...
I thought that was
a pretty fun crowd, huh?
Yeah, I...
(pedestrians shouting
indistinctly)
I don't think it's high enough.
Me, neither.
What are you doing up here?
Uh, adrenaline.
I just got out of rehab.
It's the closest thing
I get to a drug.
You went to rehab?
Yeah.
Cool.
Yeah, it wasn't all Dr. Drew
or anything,
but that dude
from American Pie was there.
Yeah?
MAN: Jump!
Eat me!
Okay, then jump
on my face!
(chuckles)
I love this city.
Yeah?
Why do you act like a dick
all the time?
Do you just do it
to antagonize people?
Maybe.
You really don't give a shit
if people like you or not?
Not really.
That's cool.
Is it? I, uh...
I don't know.
Hey. Hey!
What?
Let's play a game.
A game?
Mm-hmm.
What are you, eight?
What are you, 78?
Truth or dare.
Oh, come on, let's-let's...
Oh.
Truth.
When we first met, you made
a comment about my ass.
Why'd you do that?
You have a terrific ass,
and I noticed that.
And then I just commented on it.
Truth or dare?
Dare.
Really?
Yeah.
Okay.
Okay, there's a bald guy,
he's gonna walk right under you.
I want you to spit on his head.
No.
You said dare.
Truth.
No, it's too late, and...
(scoffs)
(hocking)
You happy?
Yeah.
MAN: Ew!
(chuckles)
(laughs)
Truth or dare?
Truth.
You're boring.
Mmm, truth is always
interesting.
Uh...
do you want to fool around
with me?
No.
Really?
Why not?
That's a second question.
It's a second part.
I'd be afraid
I couldn't get it up.
That didn't seem
to be a problem for you onstage.
Well, that's because nothing
is a problem for me onstage.
I want to ask another question.
You already asked
another question.
One more.
Go ahead.
If you weren't afraid,
what would you want
to do to me?
(sighs)
I'd pull your eyes
out of your head.
That's sweet.
I'd put them in my own skull,
and I'd look around
so I could see this street
the way I used to
when I was your age.
Good night.
♪ ♪
(indistinct chatter in distance)
(distant chatter in Spanish)
(door opens and closes)
LAURA:
Don't kill the messenger.
He's an asshole.
I told you.
You fucking prick.
He's playing you, Riggan.
This is it?
Page 12.
This can't be it.
"Riggan Thomson, better known as
the face of the Birdman films,
tries not to lay an egg
on Broadway."
Yeah, where's the rest of it?
There is no rest of it.
(muttering)
Don't worry.
Somebody will be using that
to scoop up dog shit tomorrow.
How can you be so calm
about this?
What are my other choices?
Aren't you scared at all, Laura?
About what?
About being
humiliated out there.
(chuckles) Wouldn't be the
first time I've been humiliated.
Shit, well, of course it won't.
You're an asshole.
(door opens)
And by the way,
I'm not pregnant,
so there's one thing
you don't have to worry about.
(door slams)
Forget about her.
He stole your front page.
He's stealing your show.
He thinks you're a joke.
Now two million people
agree with him.
Maybe you are, Riggan.
Maybe that's what you are.
A joke.
Whoa, what the hell is going on?
(grunts)
Hey! Ow, that hurt!
Get up!
Back away!
So, Carver's the reason
you became an actor, huh?
What?
Listen to me.
This is my fucking show.
I did the work,
I raised the money,
I arrange the fucking press.
Oh, Jesus.
They called me
for an interview.
I told them the first thing
that came into my head.
Really? Really?
We got the cover
of the Arts section,
for Christ's sake!
You told them the first
thing that came to your...
Fuck the Arts section!
You told them the first thing
that came to your head?
Right, because that's
you, Mike, right?
You're Mr. Natural,
Mr. "Fuck the scene,
just stare at my massive
hard-on," right?
That's the truth
of the moment.
Did you think
it looked massive?
Shut the fuck up.
Shut the fuck up!
You don't get hard on my stage
unless I tell you to.
Your stage?
Yeah.
Oh, let me tell you something.
This stage has belonged
to a lot of great actors.
Really? Really?
But you are not
one of them, pal.
So you wrote your
own lines, huh?
Yeah. Ow! I did, actually.
Yeah, you wrote a few changes
and you mumbled a little bit,
you self-absorbed prick!
Hey! I'm self-absorbed?
Look at you.
Yeah, yeah, you nobody
spiteful piece of shit!
Nobody?
Yeah!
My massive hard-on got
50,000 views on YouTube.
A cat playing with a dildo
gets more than that.
Hey!
Get the fuck out of here.
I don't care about any of...
Yes, you do! You care.
No, I don't.
I'm a theater actor.
I don't give a shit.
You care.
Everybody says,
Goddamn it.
"Oh, Mike is so honest.
Mike is so...
Ow! Hey! Hey! Ow! Hey, hey!
motherfucking truthful!"
Listen to me.
Fuck. Shit!
You said in the interview your
father was a drunk like Carver.
Is that true, Mike?
I'm...
Is that true?
No, no.
What?
'Cause my father was.
My father was
a mean fucking drunk.
You understand?
Okay.
He beat the shit out of us.
That was okay, though, you know,
'cause at least
when he was beating us,
he wasn't thinking
about taking...
(crying): taking us
out to his toolshed.
Because when we got
out to the toolshed,
that son of a bitch
would smile and get...
say, "You want to get
down on your knees
"and unbuckle my belt?
Oh, Jesus.
Or do you want me to take it off
and use it on you?"
After a while, I made
myself numb, so, you know...
(crying continues):
But my...
My little sister...
(sobbing)
Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey. Oh, God, I...
Uh, I didn't know.
I'm-I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, that-that is,
that's fucking horrible, man.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm sorry.
It's also not true.
See, I can pretend, too, you...
Oh! Whoa.
Don't fuck with me, Mike!
I'm telling you.
You're-you're a
little bit crazy.
You have no fucking...
You know what?
You should start
using that onstage.
Yeah? Yeah?
You have no fucking idea.
So, "Working
with Riggan Thomson's
like waltzing with a monkey"?
Huh?
I might have said that.
Yeah, you...
Come on!
Let's go. Come on.
Yeah?
Yeah. Come on.
Yeah, why don't you
get your wings
and your fucking bird suit, man?
Oh.
(grunts)
Ow!
Hey!
(grunting)
Don't think
you can try to fake...
Come on.
Don't try to fake me.
No!
Ow!
(grunting)
I'm gonna crab up on your
ass and choke you out!
Don't you...
I'm gonna fucking
choke you out!
Get off me!
What are you looking at?
What are you gonna do?!
You gonna replace me?
You gonna go get fucking
Ryan Gosling or some shit?
What do you think my friend,
Tabitha, is gonna do
to you in the Times,
you fucking dilettante!
You are lame, Riggan,
rolling around
with that poncy theater fuck
in an 800-seat shithole
like this?
(panting)
Oh, you really fucked up
this time.
You destroy a genius book
with that infantile
adaptation.
Breathing in,
I control my rage.
Now you're about to destroy
what's left of your career.
Breathing out, I embrace
these mental foundations.
It's pathetic.
Breathing in, I am calm.
Let's get the hell out
of here while we can.
Breathing out,
I ignore this mental formation.
This is a mental formation.
Stop that shit!
This is just
a mental formation...
I'm not a mental formation.
...from the past.
I'm you, asshole.
Leave me alone.
You were a movie star,
remember?
Pretentious but happy.
I wasn't happy.
Ignorant but charming.
Now you're just a tiny,
bitter cocksucker.
I was fucking miserable.
Yeah, but fake miserable.
Hollywood miserable.
What are you
trying to prove?!
That you're an artist?
(moans)
Well, you're not.
Fuck you!
No, fuck you!
You coward.
We grossed billions.
What are you,
ashamed of that?
Billions!
And billions of flies
eat shit every day!
So what?
Does that make it good?
(panting)
I don't know if you noticed,
but that was 1992!
You could jump right back
into that suit
if you wanted to.
We're not dead.
Look at me.
Will you look?
Look, look at this! Look!
Look, look! I look like
a turkey with leukemia!
I'm fucking disappearing.
(panting)
This is what's left.
I'm the answer to a fucking
Trivial Pursuit question!
You're an imposter here.
Eventually, they're gonna
figure you out.
What part of this don't you get?
You're dead. Please...
We are not dead.
Oh, please.
Just stay dead.
We are not dead.
Stop saying "we"!
There is no we.
I'm not fucking you!
I'm Riggan fucking Thomson.
No.
You're Birdman.
Because without me,
all that's left is you,
a sad, selfish,
mediocre actor
grasping at
the last vestiges
of his career.
What the hell
did you do that for?
I like that poster.
(chuckles)
It's always "we," brother.
Fuck you!
Shut the fuck up!
Leave me alone!
You're fucking...
so fucking annoying!
Shut up!
(panting)
Hey. What's up?
Um, well,
one hour till curtain.
Yeah, cool.
Why don't you try to
rest a little bit?
Yeah, that's what I'm gonna do,
I'm gonna lay down.
Almost there, buddy.
Last preview.
Okay, okay, cool.
How you doing?
Good. Great.
Good. Uh, the money
came through.
I just need to transfer it
into the account.
There you go. Thank you.
Good. That's terrific.
So, yeah, I'll go,
uh, do that.
Thanks for stopping by.
Yeah.
Okay.
You know I'm proud of you,
don't you?
(grunts)
This took balls.
And you did it, okay?
I know.
Hey, I think we ought
to cancel the preview.
What?
I'm tired, dude.
I can't do this anymore, Jake.
I can't.
(chuckles)
That's a joke, right?
You know,
I don't think this is for me.
The whole...
(sighs)
They're laughing at me.
There is a three-block
line of people
waiting for you.
It's a full house.
We're-we're sold out.
Really?
Yes!
And the French
ambassador is coming.
And the prince of Saudi Arabia
is bringing one of his wives.
And I didn't want
to tell you this,
but Martin Scorsese...
is casting his new film,
and, you know,
don't tell anybody.
No, no, no, I won't.
I think that should be
between you and me, okay?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay?
Okay, yeah.
Yeah, I can, I can be ready.
I can be ready.
Good.
Cool. Thank you.
(sighs)
Christ.
How is he?
(closes door)
He'll be fine.
(relieved sigh)
Poor creature.
Is it true?
Scorsese?
Yeah.
And the new Pope, too.
You're an asshole, Jake.
I'm the one keeping
this afloat!
(sighs)
♪ ♪
Hey.
Are you okay?
Yeah. Yeah.
No, I think I cut
my hand shaving.
Well, I-I just wanted
to say... I'm sorry.
What for?
Well... I knew
what Mike was capable of,
and... I brought him in anyway.
No, no, no, no, no.
You did good, you did good.
Are you kidding?
You did great.
Tomorrow's my...
first opening night
on Broadway.
Mine, too.
(chuckles)
And I just want you to know
that no matter what happens,
that...
I'm really grateful to you.
Oh, no, no. Me, too.
Hey, this is exciting.
Hey, we have a full house.
Jake just told me.
Yeah, that's great.
♪ ♪
(sighs):
Oh, God.
♪ ♪
(door creaks quietly)
(horn honks in distance)
(flicks lighter)
(man shouts indistinctly
in distance)
For fuck's sake,
just jump already.
How did you know
I'd be up here?
Well, I didn't know, but I...
kind of hoped, maybe.
Where's Lesley?
Lesley? Uh...
Lesley's moving on.
Smart girl.
Oh, thank you.
I appreciate that support.
You ready
for your last preview?
Sure, yeah.
Who did that to you?
Could've been anybody,
I guess.
(chuckles softly)
Yes.
I'm sort of hoping
it was Lesley.
Well, it wasn't Lesley.
Oh, my God.
You fucking kidding me?
No.
(indistinct chatter,
laughter in distance)
Jesus Christ!
No, no, I-I...
He... (groans)
I think maybe I deserved it.
(siren wailing in distance)
Fuck.
Hey.
Tell me something,
what is...
what is the worst thing
that he did to you?
Seriously.
He was never around.
Yeah?
I mean, so what?
That was it?
No. It was...
how he tried
to make up for it
by constantly trying
to convince me
that I was special.
(quiet laugh)
Okay. Look.
Look at me.
He was right, though.
About what?
About your being special.
You know, y... you've
been hanging around here,
trying to make
yourself invisible
behind this fragile little
fuckup routine of yours,
but you can't.
You're anything but
invisible; you're big.
And you're kind of
a great mess.
It's like a candle
burning on both ends,
but it's beautiful.
No amount of booze
or weed or attitude
is gonna hide that.
I am glad you're an actor
and not a writer,
'cause that was...
like...
Oprah...
Hallmark...
R. Kelly bad.
Yeah, well, I wasn't...
Mmm.
(horn honking in distance)
(Mike clears throat)
Truth or dare?
Truth.
No.
(slow footsteps approach)
Truth.
No.
Truth or dare?
(door creaks shut)
MIKE: Do you have any idea
where you're going?
Absolutely not.
♪ ♪
(indistinct talking below)
How do you do it?
Do what?
How do you go out there
every single night
and pretend to be somebody else
in front of all those people?
I don't pretend
out there, I told you.
I pretend just about
everyplace else,
but not out there.
That's a shame.
What are we doing here?
What do you mean?
I mean, what are
we doing here?
♪ ♪
RIGGAN:
Fucking teenager.
By the time
we got to the hospital,
the kid... the kid was dead.
So... we took the old couple
up to the O.R., and we...
worked like hell on 'em...
through most of the night.
The... husband, the old man,
was depressed
for the longest time.
Even after I told him
the wife was gonna pull through,
he was still depressed.
So, I went up to the mouth hole,
and I... I asked him.
♪ ♪
And... he told me it was
because he couldn't see her,
the wife, through the eye holes.
Can you imagine?
I'm telling you,
this guy's heart was breaking,
'cause he couldn't turn
his goddamn head
just to see his goddamn wife.
So...
I guess the question
we should ask ourselves is:
What do we talk about
when we talk about love?
(applause)
(applause continues)
(whistling)
♪ ♪
LESLEY: Mel and I
had been together five years,
and I don't know how many times
I'd heard the words,
"I love you,"
(whispers): There you go.
but it wasn't till that...
The blood rig
should be good now.
Okay.
Be ready to go
in two minutes.
Okay. Here.
That was amazing.
Yeah, good, right?
Yeah!
Yeah. Yeah, I think so.
(Lesley continues monologue)
It's actually going well.
(panting):
Yeah.
Hey, uh...
I think we need to talk.
No, no. (chuckles)
Yeah, I guess you're right.
But we will eventually,
because that's the only way
I'm gonna get a chance
to say I'm sorry.
I really am sorry.
We could've made great parents.
(applause)
Horrible. We would've been...
Awful. We would've
raised, like...
Serial killers.
Justin Bieber.
(chuckles)
(applause continues)
I really wanted to be a mom.
But my body
doesn't seem to agree.
♪ ♪
(exhales)
When I imagined myself
on Broadway,
I never saw
the dancing reindeer.
Nice touch.
(exhales)
♪ ♪
LAURA: In the days
before Nick's depression
started to eat away at him,
he had no idea I was pregnant,
and I never intended
on telling him.
I guess you make choices in life
and you choose
to live with them.
(Sam laughs)
Or not.
I didn't want that baby.
Not because I didn't love Nick,
and not because
I didn't love the idea of it,
but because...
I just wasn't ready
to love myself.
(Riggan panting quietly)
There's a distance to it now.
(quiet grunt)
RIGGAN:
Hey, Jimmy, you got a smoke?
LAURA: ...underscored
by a gentle breeze...
and the sound of birds...
laughing at the whimsy
of it all.
♪ ♪
(rain falling)
(indistinct chatter nearby)
Jimmy!
Hey!
God!
(strained grunting)
Hey!
Jimmy!
Jimmy! Jimmy!
(grunts)
Hey!
Goddamn it.
(strained grunting)
Shit!
Fuck!
(strained grunting)
(rainfall continues)
(panting)
(quietly):
Fuck.
(grunting):
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
(panting)
Hey. Aren't you Riggan Thomson?
Shit. No, no.
Holy shit, let me
get an autograph.
Don't be a dick;
let me get an autograph.
Fine.
MAN (calls): Hey, Birdman!
Dude, you fucking rock!
Birdman!
Look over here.
Oh, shit!
WOMAN (laughs): Oh, gross!
Aw, shit, shit...
(panting):
Fuck. Shit.
Oh, my God!
Do you see that?
(panting, whimpering)
Can we take one picture?
Not now. Oh, give me a break.
No, just one picture.
Kids! Get right next to him!
Please!
Hey, Birdman!
You suck!
Get the fuck out of here.
(man laughing)
(drums playing)
WOMAN: Hey, Birdman!
(panting)
(quietly):
Oh, fuck.
(pants, whimpers)
MAN:
Hey! Hey, Riggan!
Riggan, fuck,
I'm missing him.
It's the Bird-fucking-man!
Hey! Come look at this guy!
Birdman!
Hey, Birdman!
Whoo, yeah!
Yeah, baby!
Whoo!
(excited chatter)
MAN:
Birdman! Birdman!
(man speaking indistinctly
over P.A. system)
MAN:
Where you going, man?
WOMAN:
You look so old in person.
RIGGAN:
Fuck you!
(people shouting indistinctly)
WOMAN: Sir! Sir!
Where are you going?
Sir! Where are you... Sir!
What are you doing?
I'm waiting for Jake.
This is my attorney,
Mr. Roth.
What?!
We're pursuing financial
remunerations
for the injuries
Mr. Pinkus...
I got a play to do!
No, excuse me, sir...
You can't go in there.
No, I got...
You can't... (grunts)
ROTH: ...Actors' Equity is
a very strong union, sir!
(Riggan panting)
(thunder sound effect)
(low grunt, panting)
Knock, knock, knock!
(people gasp)
Terri! Terri!
LESLEY:
Ed?
(excited chatter, laughter)
What are...
what are you doing here?
Why?! I just need you
to tell me why!
MIKE: Okay, take it easy, Ed.
I know this is hard.
Shut up! Fuck you!
Shut up! Shut up!
(audience quiets)
LESLEY: Eddie, please!
(panting)
What's wrong with me?!
Why do I always...
beg people to love me?!
LESLEY: Eddie, please, just...
please just give me the gun.
(audience members
talking indistinctly)
I just wanted to be
what you wanted.
Now I spend every fucking...
day trying to be somebody else,
somebody I'm not!
Put the gun down.
She just doesn't love you.
LESLEY:
Oh! Eddie...
(Mike groans)
LESLEY: Look at me.
I was drowning.
I'm just not capable
of that kind of...
(ringtone playing)
You deserve to be
loved, Eddie. You do.
RIGGAN: I just wanted
to be what you wanted.
Hello?
RIGGAN:
Now I spend every fucking...
Mr. Roth? Okay, don't...
don't leave. Please don't...
Is that a threat?
What wheelchair?
Okay, Mr. Roth, please
just hear me out.
Will you hear me out?
Uh, d... don't hang up.
Don't hang up. Okay, listen,
give me ten minutes
to grab my things--
give me ten minutes--
and we can meet to disc--
please don't hang up.
Goddamn it!
The motherfucker hung up!
♪ ♪
(Mike and Lesley shouting)
(gunshot)
(audience gasps)
(applause)
(applause fades)
SAM:
Dad?
Dad.
Hey.
Are you okay?
Why?
You s-seem sort of...
No, I'm good.
I'm good. This is good.
You want some?
(softly):
No.
Mmm, okay.
Do you really think you'll be
ready for opening tomorrow?
Yeah, yep.
Yeah.
Well, I mean,
previews were pretty much
a train wreck.
We can't seem to get
through a performance without...
a raging fire
or a raging hard-on.
I'm broke.
I'm not sleeping, like,
you know, at all.
And, uh, this play
is kind of starting
to feel like
a miniature,
deformed version of myself
that just keeps
following me around and, like,
hitting me in the balls with
a... like, a tiny little hammer.
I'm sorry,
what was the question?
Never mind.
Tonight wasn't bad.
I know.
It was... it was weird,
but it was kind of cool.
Yeah, really? You think?
Yeah, I think people liked it.
Yeah, well...
What are you doing,
by the way?
Homework?
No, I don't...
No, um, my, uh...
When I was in rehab,
they made us do this.
Really? What is it?
It's, um...
these dashes represent
the six billion years
that the Earth has been around.
Yeah?
And so each dash
represents a thousand years.
And, um, this is...
how long humans have been here.
150,000 years.
I think they're
trying to remind us
that that's all our ego
and self-obsession are worth.
I was a shitty father,
wasn't I?
No, you were...
You were fine.
Yeah.
That's right, I was...
I was just fine.
Um...
I can't...
Dad?
What?
Oh, shoot. Oh, I'm sorry.
That's... you just wiped out
the entire human race.
I know. (chuckles)
There it goes.
Oh, I'm sorry.
(sighs)
Hey, um...
you're becoming
a trending topic.
Really?
Yeah.
I should probably tell you
about this
before anybody else does.
(indistinct shouting on video)
350,000 views
in less than an hour.
(sighing):
Fuck.
Believe it or not,
this is power.
MAN:
Hey, it's the Bird-fucking-man!
Hey! Yeah!
Hey, look, it's Riggan Thomson!
MAN 2:
Whoa, look at that.
MALE NEWSCASTER:
1,300,000 hits
in the last two hours.
FEMALE NEWSCASTER: What you're
seeing is Birdman actor
Riggan Thomson running
through the streets
of Times Square.
Hey, give me another one.
In his tighty-whiteys.
You got it.
Oh, come on, that takes
a lot of balls.
Or not.
Ouch.
What do you have to do
to get a job
in this town these days?
I know, like, why do actors
have to resort to this?
Come on, just put out
a good film, you know?
Thank you.
That's going over
to Ms. Dickinson.
MAN:
Yeah, yeah, give me a minute.
FEMALE NEWSCASTER:
This guy has just gone berserk.
(newscast continues
indistinctly)
Hey, um, that's on me.
She's a friend of mine.
Okay.
Thank you.
(grunts)
(sighs)
There you go.
That was...
20 years before I put on
that goddamn outfit.
I don't care.
Okay, I was just...
(stammering)
You know, before you
come tomorrow, I just...
It doesn't matter.
Okay.
(sighs)
I'm going to destroy your play.
But you didn't even see it.
Um, you know, did I do something
to offend you?
I-I'm so sorry...
As a matter
of fact, you did.
You took up space in a theater
which otherwise
might have been used
on something worthwhile.
Okay, well,
I mean, you don't even know
if it's any good or not.
I didn't...
That's true.
I haven't read a word of it
or even seen a preview,
but after the opening tomorrow,
I'm going to turn in
the worst review
anybody has ever read,
and I'm going
to close your play.
Would you like to know why?
Yeah.
Because I hate you
and everyone you represent.
Entitled, selfish,
spoiled children.
Blissfully untrained, unversed
and unprepared
to even attempt real art.
Handing each other awards
for cartoons and pornography.
Measuring your worth
in weekends?
Well, this is the theater,
and you don't get
to come in here
and pretend you can write,
direct and act
in your own propaganda piece
without coming through me first.
Uh-huh.
So break a leg.
(scoffs)
Wow. You know,
what has to happen
in a person's life for them
to become a critic, anyway?
What are you writing,
another review?
Um, is it any good?
Is it?
Is it bad?
Did you even see this?
Let me read it.
I will call the police.
You won't call the police.
Let's read your fucking review.
"Callow." Callow is a label.
Just, uh, "lackluster."
That's just a label.
"Margin..."
Marginalia? Are you kidding me?
(scoffs) It sounds like you need
penicillin to clear that up.
That's a label, too.
These are just all labels.
You just label everything.
That's so fucking lazy.
You just...
You're a lazy fucker.
You're a lazy...
You know what this is?
Do you even know what that is?
You don't. You know why?
Because you can't see this thing
if you don't know
how to label it.
You mistake all those
little noises in your head
for true knowledge.
Are you finished?
No, I'm not finished.
There's nothing in here
about technique.
There's nothing
in here about structure.
Nothing in here about intention.
It's just a bunch
of crappy opinions
backed up
by even crappier comparisons.
You write a couple
of paragraphs,
and you know what,
none of this
costs you fucking anything.
You risk nothing.
Nothing, nothing, nothing.
Well, I'm a fucking actor.
(sighs)
This play cost me everything.
So I'll tell you what.
You take this fucking...
malicious, cowardly,
shittily-written review,
and you shove that
right the fuck
up your wrinkly,
tight ass.
(chuckles)
You're no actor.
You're a celebrity.
Let's be clear on that.
I'm gonna kill your play.
(chuckles)
(belches)
MAN:
"Tomorrow!
"And tomorrow, and tomorrow!
"Creeps...
(horn honking)
"in this...
"petty pace...
"from day to day,
"to the last syllable...
(woman whooping)
"...of recorded time.
"And...
"all of our yesterdays...
"have lighted...
"fools!
The way to..."
Hey, give me a pint
of whiskey, please.
"...dusty death...
"out...
out..."
CLERK:
$6.50, my friend.
"brief candle..."
Huh?
$6.50.
Here, just,
I don't know what that is.
"Life...
Just take it.
"is but a...
How about your...
"walking shadow.
"Poor...
"player
"struts and frets his
hour upon the stage,
"and then is heard no more!
"It is a tale
"told by an idiot
"full of sound and fury
signifying nothing!"
Where you going, man?
Was that too much?
I was just trying
to give you a range.
It's a little bit too much,
I can tell, because you...
I just wanted
to give you a range.
I just... that was
a little too much.
That-that was a little
too much. Was that too much?
(fading): I was just trying
to give you a range.
(sighs)
♪ ♪
(pedestrians chattering)
God.
You look like shit, brother.
You get that mongoloid look
when you're hungover,
don't you?
(chuckles)
Yeah.
Let's go.
Come on, get up.
It's a beautiful day.
Forget about the Times.
Everyone else has.
Come on.
Stand up.
So you're not a great actor.
Who cares?
You're much more than that.
You tower over these other
theater douche bags.
You're a movie star, man.
You're a global force.
Don't you get it?
You spent your whole life
building a bank account
and a reputation,
and you blew them both.
Good for you. Fuck it.
We'll make a comeback.
They're waiting
for something huge.
We'll give it to them.
Shave off that pathetic goatee.
Get some surgery.
60 is the new 30, motherfucker.
You are the original, man.
You paved the way for all
these other little clowns.
Give the people what they want.
Some good, old-fashioned,
apocalyptic porn.
Birdman: The Phoenix Rises.
Pimple-faced gamers creaming
in their pants.
A billion worldwide, guaranteed.
You were larger than life, man.
You saved people from
their boring, miserable lives.
You make them jump, laugh,
shit their pants.
All you have to do is...
(screaming)
Man down! Man down!
That's what I'm talking about!
Bones rattling!
Big, loud, fast.
Look at these people.
Look at their eyes.
They're all sparkling.
They love this shit;
they love blood.
They love action,
not this talky, depressing,
philosophical bullshit.
(bellowing)
Yes.
And the next time
you screech...
(screeches)
...it'll explode
into millions of eardrums.
You'll glimmer
on thousands of screens
around the globe.
Another blockbuster.
MAN: Hey, that guy's rising
into the air.
You are a god.
Up there!
Hey, who is that?
Hey, you all right?
See? There you go,
you motherfucker.
WOMAN: Oh, look,
there's a man up there!
Gravity doesn't
even apply to you.
MAN: What's he doing?
Jesus, what... Oh!
Wait till you see
the faces of those
who thought
we were finished.
Listen to me.
Let's go back one more time
and show them
what we're capable of.
We have to end it
on our own terms,
with a grand gesture.
Flames.
Sacrifice.
Oh, my God! There's
somebody up there!
Icarus.
Oh, my God!
You can do it.
You hear me?
You are...
MAN: Birdman!
(indistinct shouting)
WOMAN:
Hey, is this for real,
or are you shooting a film?
A film!
You people are full of shit!
MAN: Hey, man,
can I help you?
You should be careful.
Sorry, can't talk.
I'm late.
Music.
(orchestra playing)
(music stops)
You okay, man?
You want me to call
somebody for you?
Do you know where to go?
Yeah.
I know where to go.
Oh, hey!
No, wait! What the...
(Riggan laughing)
Oh!
(chuckling):
(laughing continues)
Whoa!
(sighs)
(wind whistling)
You see?
This is where you belong.
Above them all.
MAN:
Hey, hey.
Hey, you!
Hey!
(horns honking)
♪ ♪
WOMAN:
How long you in town for?
WOMAN 2:
Oh, about two weeks.
Oh, really?
You'll get to see a lot.
Stop the music.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
I beg your pardon.
Hello, sir?
Hello, sir,
you did not pay me.
(rants in native language)
What are you doing?
Where you going? Hey.
Hey, are you deaf, idiot?
This guy didn't pay me, man.
That fucker is crazy.
(ranting continues indistinctly)
(speaking Spanish)
(tires squealing)
WOMAN: They got benefits
and everything. It's nice.
MAN: We got to go walk
clear to Fifth?
Yeah, sure, yeah.
You said 15 blocks, right?
Yes.
Three alternates!
That's it, four teams.
Not a bad first act, huh?
Not bad at all.
It's going really well.
I didn't think Hollywood
could do Broadway.
I never would have
expected it from him.
If the second act is half
as good as that...
It's pretty glorious. See?
The whole evening
has been fabulous.
Right, right?
What we talk about
when we talk
about Riggan Thomson?
It's fantastic, really.
How long's the intermission?
Birdman can act!
(crowd chattering)
Oh, wow.
I just came to say hello.
It's going great out there.
You're so good.
I mean it. You're...
Thanks. Come sit.
I really mean it.
ANNIE (over intercom): Places
for the final scene, Riggan.
Places for the final scene.
You need to...
No, no, no. It's fine.
Just sit here for a second.
Look at all these roses.
I hate roses.
And you hate roses.
(chuckles)
Are you okay?
You seem...
You seem, I don't know,
you seem abnormally calm.
(chuckles)
I am calm.
Yeah, I'm great, actually.
You know, I got this...
little voice
that talks to me sometimes.
Tells me the truth.
It's comforting.
Kind of scary,
but it's comforting.
I'm gonna pretend
I didn't hear
you say that.
Okay.
(chuckles)
You wouldn't believe
the crowd outside.
They said some people paid
up to $500 a ticket.
Really?
Hey.
Can I tell you something funny?
Sure.
You remember
our last anniversary party?
Seriously? You're gonna ruin
a nice moment with that?
Yeah, all right,
but do you remember the party?
The party where you fucked
Janet Rossbach in our bed?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
try to skip over that part
for a minute, yeah.
Oh, gladly.
And you threw all the guests
out of the house?
And you threw all the furniture
out the window?
I remember.
And you locked yourself
in the bathroom.
Riggan, why are
we talking about...
I drove out to Malibu,
and I just sat on
the beach for a while
looking out at the ocean.
Riggan?
And I...
walked...
straight into the water.
And I tried to drown myself.
I was up to my chest
when I felt the first one
on my back.
It was like somebody was holding
a frying pan against me,
really burning,
and then they were on my chest
and all over my legs.
The water was full of jellyfish.
(laughs)
They were all over me.
I-I had to fight my way
out of the water.
I went up to the-the beach.
I was rolling around
like a maniac in the sand,
(laughs):
crying.
You said it was a sunburn.
Yeah, I know.
And you believed me.
To be honest,
I didn't give a shit.
(whispering):
Man.
I love you.
And I love Sam.
I know.
I really wish I wouldn't have
videotaped her birth, though.
Why?
'Cause it... (sighs)
I just missed the moment,
really.
Don't have it. I...
I should've just been there
with the two of you.
You know?
Just... the three of us.
But I wasn't.
I wasn't even present
in my own life,
and now I don't have it,
and I'm never gonna have it.
No, you have Sam.
Not really, I don't.
I mean, she's...
No, no, no, listen.
She's just going through...
No, no, no, I get it.
I understand.
Yeah, no, she needed
to have a dad and...
instead she got this guy
who was a three-day
viral sensation.
It is so pathetic, I can't...
No, come on, there are more
pathetic things than that.
Yeah, like?
That mustache.
(chuckling)
ANNIE (over intercom):
Riggan, we are in the motel.
Last scene has started.
You're not here.
Last chance for places.
You better get
back to your seat.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(whispering):
20 little leopards
laughed at two lofty lions.
20 little leopards laughed
at two lofty lions.
(sniffs)
Mmm, mwah, mwah,
mwah, mwah, mwah.
Mmm, yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
Ah, ee.
Ah, oh, ooh-ooh.
Yum, yum.
Ooh, yum, wah-ah-ah-ah,
yum-yum-yum, wah.
Yum, yum, yum, yum.
(jazzy drums playing)
Break a leg, Mr. Thomson.
♪ ♪
(man coughing)
Let me put the blood rig on.
Hey!
Riggan! Hey!
(thunder rumbling)
Terri! Terri!
Eddie!
What are you doing here?!
Why? I just want you
to tell me why.
Just take it easy, man.
Just tell me why.
I know this is...
Shut up!
Eddie, please.
What's the matter with me?
Tell me what's the matter.
Why do I always end up
having to beg people to love me?
Eddie, please,
just give me the gun.
It was me; I was drowning.
I'm just not capable of...
You deserve to be loved, Eddie.
You do.
I just wanted to be
what you wanted.
What you wanted.
Now I spend every fucking minute
trying to be something else,
someone I'm not.
MIKE:
Just put the gun down, Ed.
She doesn't
love you anymore.
(thunder rumbling)
You don't, do you?
No.
And you never will.
(crying):
I'm sorry.
(exhales)
Well...
(laughs uncomfortably)
I don't exist.
I'm not even here.
Bang!
(whimpers)
(whispering):
Bang.
(gunshot)
(audience gasps)
(rain falling)
(cheering and yelling)
(cheering continues)
(whooping)
♪ ♪
(machine beeps)
(knocking at door)
Yes?
(door opens)
Is he, um...
He just woke up.
(machine beeps)
I thought I lost you, buddy.
What the hell happened?
I was watching you
on that stage,
and then all the sudden,
you had that goofy
look in your eye,
(laughing): and you were
just, like, honestly...
What is wrong with you?
He tried to...
I'm happy!
He's alive; my best
friend is alive!
And... he happens to be
the fucking man of the hour.
RIGGAN: What is that?
You have to be shitting me.
Read it.
I don't believe this.
"The Unexpected Virtue
of Ignorance."
Read it.
Oh.
"By Tabitha Dickinson."
Read it out loud.
"Thomson has
unwittingly given birth
"to a new form which can
only be described
"as super-realism.
"Blood was spilled both
literally and metaphorically
"by artist and audience alike,
real blood.
"The blood that has been
sorely missing
from the veins
of the American theater."
(sighs)
(chuckles)
You're happy about this?
Yeah, happy?
I'm fucking euphoric!
This is... this is
the kind of review
that turns people
into living legends.
He shot the nose off his face!
He's got a new nose!
And if he doesn't like that one,
we'll get him a new one.
We'll use Meg Ryan's guy.
Who gives a shit?
They're lighting candles
for him in Central Park.
Turn on your TV. Where's the...
...spontaneous vigil
for actor Riggan Thomson.
They're praying for him
all across the country.
He did it. You did it.
I've been reborn, brother.
And I can see the future.
This play is gonna last forever.
It's gonna open
in London and Paris,
and the studio
is gonna call again,
and we're gonna get some
book deals-- you'll see.
So you can see the future?
Yeah, I can see the future.
How about that, huh?
Did you see that coming?
Why aren't you saying anything?
This is what you
wanted, wasn't it?
Riggan, this is
what you wanted.
Yeah, yeah,
this is what I wanted.
Okay, listen,
you're gonna get hit
with a brandishing
a weapon charge, okay?
If anybody talks
to you about it,
it was an accident.
(softly): Okay.
Is that what this was?
An accident?
An accident.
That's what I want to go...
(door opens)
Did you intend to
shoot yourself?
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
You motherfuckers!
Get the fuck out! Get out!
This is a hospital!
Are you coming back...
Get the fuck out of here!
Move!
This is a hospital!
Get the fuck out!
Ma'am, get back!
Get the fuck out, you assholes!
Get back!
Okay, out!
(elevator bell dings)
This is a personal matter!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
A personal matter!
Hey, hey, get out!
I don't give a shit!
Hey, Sam! What did it feel like
the night your father tried....
I don't give a shit
if the press wants to know.
Get the fuck out of here,
you fucking parasite!
(shouting continues)
(machine beeps)
Lilacs.
(chuckles)
Are you laughing?
Yeah.
What's so funny?
I can't smell them.
(laughs wryly)
(snorting)
What are you doing?
I'm posting a photo
on your Twitter page.
I have a Twitter page?
Yeah, I set it up today.
Let me see.
No way.
No, you look hideous.
Oh, wow, thank you.
I appreciate it.
I'm just kidding.
No, I'm actually not.
You-you do look hideous.
(chuckles)
You got 80,000 followers
in less than a day.
Really?
Yeah, I'm gonna scare the shit
out of all of them.
Let me look at it.
Uh-uh.
It's done.
Uh, I'm gonna go get
a vase for the flowers.
Okay.
(machine beeps)
(sighs)
(door opens)
(door closes)
Oh.
(groans, muttering)
(woman speaking indistinctly
over P.A.)
(groans)
(grunting)
Oh, my.
(toilet flushes)
Bye-bye.
And fuck you.
(machine beeping)
(sighs)
(birds singing)
(grunting exhale)
♪ ♪
Dad?
(panting)
(chuckles)
(Sam laughing)
(Riggan laughs)
♪ ♪
(music ends)
9movie.in
em2ok@yahoo.com