Subtitles ripped by Erkki Härö
[Girl]
I wanna be the best surfer
in the world.
[Child Giggles]
[Child]
I'm gonna be the best surfer
in the world, not you.
[Man]
She's just slotted in there.
Look at that wave.
Anne Marie Chadwick getting
the best wave of the day.
[Man]
Anne Marie...
[Screaming]
[Exhaling]
[Dialing]
[Ringing]
[Man's Voice] Hey, howzit,
wave riders. It's hump day,
Wednesday, February 3.
Waves are averaging 14 feet
in 18 seconds.
So there's definitely some
size out there in the water,
and it's moving our way.
There's a little bit of morning
sickness out right now,
but it should clean up
as the winds pick up...
[Dialing]
[Phone Ringing]
[Man] It's flat.
Yeah, right.
I'm looking at it.
Anne Marie?
What's up,J.J.?
Tell Eden she's a hottie.
Hook me up.
Tell her yourself.
How's Pipe looking?
Ho! It's going off.
It's at least double overhead.
- You better get down here.
- Okay. Thanks, J.J.
Pen. Pen, come on.
Get up.
Pen. Get up.
It's double overhead.
# Could you be loved #
# And be loved #
Lena. Hey, Lena.
What?
It's double overhead.
- What?
- # Could you be loved #
# And be loved #
##[Continues]
How's it coming?
I can't get the rails right.
They're too pinched.
You wanna get wet?
I got to glass before work.
It's perfect Pipe.
For real?
For real.
- Move it.
- Yeah, move it.
- Move. Let's go.
- Let's do it.
Okay, got my noodles.
Let's go.
##[Continues]
[Woman]
Turn it up.
# Could you be loved #
- Whoo!
- # And be loved #
[Lena]
It's going off!
# Could you be loved #
# And be loved #
##[Continues]
What's up, bro?
Great.
The Rat Pack's here.
Hey, what's up, guys?
Hey, Rico, what's up?
Hey, girls.
We should have
been here an hour ago.
If you would have gotten
moving, we would have been.
We're all right.
What's up, Tamayo?
Hey, how's it, girls?
How is it out there?
Oh, it's pretty nuts.
Broke my board.
It's pretty heavy out there.
Your girl got her head
on straight this time?
Does she?
You know it.
[Shouting, Whooping]
- Oh, look who's here.
- What are you girls doing here?
We came to surf Pipe.
Why don't you check out
girlie bowls?
Why don't you crawl back
into the cave you came from?
Why don't I knock you
in the head, drag you
in there with me? Huh?
I like girls that
are rough and soft inside.
I'm gonna have
to marry you, girl.
Let her go.
Seriously, let her go.
We're out of here.
Okay.
What's this I hear about
you surfing the Pipe Masters?
It's a surfing contest,
not a drowning contest.
Hey, stop hassling my girl.
She's gonna dominate.
Let's see it.
I don't mind girls
that can charge Pipe.
Chick thinks she can
charge Pipe. That's cool.
You think you can
surf it for real?
I dated you, Drew.
I guess I can do anything, huh?
I'll get my boys out there.
We'll block every wave you want.
No matter how big it is,
we want you on it.
Let's see what's gonna happen.
- Let's do it.
- Don't talk bubbles to me.
Lets see it.
##[Rock]
So meet us
at the shower at 7:45?
Okay.
And stay on the inside.
Be careful, Pen.
Okay. All right.
[Shouting, Whooping]
[Anne Marie]
Oh. Looks like the reef's
breaking down.
Oh, he got shut down.
It's heavy out there.
It's fierce.
Ohh.!
[Lena]
Oh, he hit the reef.
That's gotta hurt.
I think we should
start at the sandbar
and work our way over.
I won't
argue with that.
##[Rap]
# Now we all know summertime
is a bummer with no duckets #
# Honeys want money
Exposed like their tummy is #
# The one time you can
just sit right there #
# No way you can't feel it #
# They're coming up skimpy
with the coverup #
# I got a long joint for ya
MBug cover song #
# Do what summer does and #
# Shine #
# Bright like the view of
the sky inside the pipeline #
# It's a cruel, cruel summer #
# It's a cruel #
# Leaving me here on my own #
# It's a cruel, cruel summer #
# It's a cruel #
- # Now you've gone #
- Yeah! Go, Lena!
# So we're walking
across the beach
Bumpin' MBug tunes #
# When we spot three lovely
jewels, sweet ladies
having a bad day #
# They looked at me
with sad faces
Every day they'd say to me #
# Hot summer streets
and the pavements are burning #
# I sit around #
# I said you got to be kidding
baby, summer is thejoint
Whatcha thinking #
# Trying to smile, but the air
is so heavy and dry #
# I don't give a f...
Need a new rush #
# Let me get a hold
and slap back
with the new stuff #
# Strange voices are saying #
# Strange voices #
# What did they say
Things I can't understand #
# What did I say #
# Tough luck #
# It's too close for comfort #
# This heat has got
right out ofhand #
# So the Bleste grabbed 'em
dragged 'em to the sea
splashed 'em in #
# And that's it #
# It's a cruel, cruel summer #
# Now you've gone ##
I want to get a boat so we can
go around the island and get
some killer secret spots.
Guaranteed.
There's so many.
Oh, God, I know.
Hey!
What's this horseshit
on the sandbar crap?
You're not gonna
win the Masters
surfing the sandbar.
Talking this crap on the beach.
"I dated you, Drew.
I can do anything."
This isn't Pipe.
Pipe's over there.
Let's go.
The Pipe's over there.
The boys are gonna
block for you.
Let's do this.
Let's go.
Come on.
Whoo! Yeah!
Let's go, man.
Actions speak
louder than words.
Oh, that's the view
I remember.
What, the one of me leaving?
It's my favorite too.
[Drew]
Come on, pick it up.
Like that wave, huh?
Next one's yours.
Welcome to the arena, girl.
Let's get you
into something big.
[Man] What's up, Anne Marie?
Where you been?
Thought you were behind us.
Today's your big day.
Let's do it.
[Drew] Hey, everybody,
this is my girl, Anne Marie.
She's with the boys.
She's gonna get some waves.
Any of you get in her way,
you're gonna deal with me.
Here we go.
Paddle.! Paddle.!
Come on.! Move.!
Watch out.! Watch out.!
Spring girl's wave.
Hit it.!
Come on! Paddle in!
- Come on!
- Paddle.! Paddle.! Paddle.!
What the hell is that?
- God.! You ain't even paddling.
- Girls can't surf Pipe.
What the hell was that?
What the hell is she afraid of?
[Chattering]
- This ain't a beauty pageant.
- Oh, if you do that again,
you're barred.
Come on, Anne Marie,
you got to do it this time.
No fooling around.
Let's do it.
This one's yours right here.
Don't blow it. Or I ain't
gonna help you anymore.
Come on. Paddle, paddle.!
This one's yours, Anne Marie.!
Go.! Go.!
[Man]
Yeah, yeah, yeah.!
Ohh!
[Eden] You were in the perfect
spot. You were right where
you needed to be.
[Lena] Whatever.
That thing was a beast.
Just dropped out.
[Penny]
How big was it?
[Lena]
It was solid. It was,
like, triple overhead.
She totally had it.
Yeah. She just needed
to paddle a little harder.
[Lena]
I don't know.
[Eden]
It's all in your head.
It's all up here.
If you just
would have committed,
you could have made that wave.
Whatever.
At least she went.
That wave was huge.
- I would have never gone.
- [Eden]
She was perfectly positioned.
If she had the balls to charge...
[Penny] Why does the sun
rise in the east?
What?
Why does the sun
rise in the east?
Because it sets
in the west.
Because that's the way
the Earth rotates.
Do you remember
that Superman episode...
where he was, like, spinning
around the Earth backwards...
trying to rotate it
in the other direction?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
To bring back time?
- I thought you finished.
- I did. I'm just checking it.
- It doesn't look like
you're finished.
- Geez. Stop picking on her.
She's getting it done now.
[Anne Marie]
We're on our way to school.
She should have it done.
- She's just checking it.
- I did it last night.
I'm checking it.
[Anne Marie]
Penny.! Penny.!
What?
Flippers.
- No ditching.
- Okay.
- It sucks to be you.
- Yeah, it does.
Someone's got to go
to college, honey.
Not me.
Oh, shoot!
It's Mr. Pakui.
[Eden]
Remember how he had
pee stains all the time?
[Lena]
Looks like he learned
how to shake right.
Hi, Mr. Pakui.
Anne Marie,
This is the eighth time...
your sister's been tardy
in the last month.
I know. Traffic...
If you think surfing is
more important than school,
we got to make
other arrangements.
You know what, Mr. Pakui,
The only other arrangement
I can think of is my mother.
And she just so happens to be
with her latest meal ticket
in Vegas...
who apparently isn't so cool
with the kid's menu,
you know what I mean?
So right now,
this is the best
arrangement I can do.
You know,
Penny's a smart girl.
Yeah, she is.
Just like her sister was.
Is. Present tense.
I learned that much
while I was here.
You better watch it, girl.
I'm doing the best I can do.
That's all I can say.
You can do better.
All right.
God!
Like, he's so ripping
in that aloha shirt anyway.
I thought he was hot.
You did kind of peak
in seventh grade.
Shut up, Lena.
Sexually, she means.
What is this, like,
bag on Anne Marie?
Whoo!
[Beeping]
Seventeen fifty-three.
That's kama'aina price?
No kama'aina for candy.
Ohh.
Come on, Leilani,
it's breakfast.
Yeah.
Breakfast? Right.
Sorry, girls. $17.53.
This has corn syrup in it.
It's a vegetable.
It's nutritional.
No. It has sugar.
It turns into fat. And fat
comes out like me. Okay?
So, $17.53.
All right,
I've got five.
- How much do you have?
- I got some cash.
- Hold on, I got, like...
- What is this?
I don't know, like 70, 60...
That's pathetic.
What is that?
I didn't say I had a lot.
I said I had some.
[Anne Marie]
What happened to the five bucks
I gave you yesterday?
I bought food for Sammi.
It's not even our dog.
Dog's gotta eat.
So do I. I'm hungry.
- Eat the rest of this Twinkie.
- I don't want it.
I want breakfast.
- Twinkie is breakfast.
- ##[Rap]
It's Keala Kennelly.
She's living the life.
Must be here for the contest.
Check thosejet skis out.
- So fine.
- All right, let's fill
these bad boys.
Let's get on it.
It's gonna be a busy day.
She's with her Billabong
sponsor. Introduce yourself.
No.
Why not?
It's not weird.
Because it's weird.
Yes.
No.
- Hi. Can we have
your autograph?
- Yeah, sure.
I'll get you a pen.
Thanks.
Hey, I remember this shot.
[Lena]
What a life.
She gets a grand every time
she's in a magazine.
Five grand every time
she's on the cover.
- You surf?
- Yeah.
She gets free clothes,
boards, watches, sunglasses.
The girl doesn't have
to open her wallet.
[Eden]
You score one good wave
at Pipe Masters...
and you'll get sponsored
just like her.
You'll get flown
all around the world.
Surf Indo, Australia, Tahiti,
you name it.
Surf the world, baby.
And you'll get paid to surf
uncrowded, perfect waves.
We'll see you
at the contest.
Okay. Thanks a lot.
[Eden]
All you need to do
is get noticed.
- Surfer girls.
- Local girls.
You know you're
just as good as her.
We gotta go to work, guys.
We're gonna be late, again.
[Echoes]
# Come on #
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
[Tires Screeching]
# Take you from wherever
to wherever you are #
# Get your thing
Get it on #
Girls, you're late.
I know. Sorry.
- # Get your thing
Get it on, superstar #
- [Beeps]
# Oh, no #
Sorry.
# Superstar #
# Get your thing
Get it on, superstar #
As a reminder,
our Pro Bowl guests
are arriving today.
They are V.I.P. returning guests
and deserve the highest level
of service.
You must remember
we depend on our guests...
for the survival
of our business.
##[Continues]
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
# Take you from wherever
to wherever you are #
# I can't stand
to be held back #
# All the ladies
all got my best #
and a superstar #
It's like
this one packed for Vegas
and landed in Hawaii instead.
- I'm putting it on.
- # All the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
# I could lead the whole set
but never go too far #
# It's a jam for the ladies
and a superstar #
Guys, guys,
it's up, it's up.
Look, Anne Marie Chadwick.
Look at the picture.
Shit.
"A wild card entry.
This North Shore local
first gained notice when she
dominated in thejunior NSSA. "
You dominated.
No.
Wait. You're wearing
my bathing suit bottoms.
"She dropped out of
the competitive circuit after
a near-drowning incident."
- Yeah, they love
bringing that up, huh?
- That was three years ago.
It's over with.
You're gonna go pro,
and you're gonna win this thing.
- I want to be on the Internet.
Oh, crap!
- [Knocking]
- Oh, my God.
- [Woman] Hello?
Is somebody in there?
Be there...
I'm stuck.
- Put your shoes on.
- Help me, I'm stuck.
- Help me. Ow! Ow!
- Hello? Anyone in there?
- Where's my dress?
- Will you open this door?
- One second.
Be right with you.
- Shoes.
- [Knocking]
- Open this door right now.
I'm not fooling around.
- Oh, my shoes.
- Why was this door locked?
I'm sorry. It gets stuck.
Maintenance will come up
and look at it any second.
- What's going on in here?
- Just cleaning up.
We're picking up the clothes.
What happened to all the clothes
that was on the floor?
We fold them up
and put them on the bed.
I left the clothes on the floor
so that you would know
they need to be dry-cleaned.
That's actually why
we had the dry-cleaning bags
for that specific purpose.
Then why don't you
put them in the bag?
No problem.
That's a cute top.
Like, I need for you guys
to put all of my crusty clothes
inside of the bag.
What about the bags
in her boobs?
Her boobs are as big as my head.
And I have one big head.
[Chattering]
[Eden]
Excuse us.
[Chattering Continues]
Don't mind us.
- Football players.
- Excuse us.
- It's all right.
What?
[Chattering, Laughing]
Paddle, paddle, paddle.
Look at that.
They're beautiful.
All right,
next time, you're paddling.
How about you take a sweet,
luscious run right about now?
Oh, yeah, I don't think so.
You can go for it though.
You're the one
in training, not me.
Do you smell that?
Beer's gone.
Oh, damn it.
Penny?
Pen!
Pen?
Penny?
Frickin' pain
in my royal ass! God!
##[Rock]
Yeah. Yeah.
Stop it. Stop.
Let go. Let go.
You too good for us?
Penny.
Penny, get up. Get up.
We're going home.
- I'm not going with you.
- It's not a request.
Go away.
Leave me alone.
- Get up. Penny, get up.
- Leave me alone.
- Get out of my face.
- I'm not kidding.
- Stop.
- Penny!
- Stop! Leave me alone!
Get off me!
You're such a bitch!
- Why can't you leave me alone?
- 'Cause I'm all you have.
- I'm all you have.
- I don't want you!
I don't care!
You're the one
who made Mom leave!
You were screwing up
all the time!
You know what, fine.
Fine.
Chill out.
- We're over this.
Turn the music up.
- You all right?
##[Music Playing Louder]
[Vehicle Approaching,
Brakes Squeaking]
[Vehicle Door
Opening, Closing]
[Penny]
Thanks for the ride.
[Vehicle Driving Off]
[Door Opening, Closing]
[Anne Marie]
I shouldjust send her
to military school.
[Eden]
Shave her head.
That ought to send a message.
You guys are such hypocrites.
We totally partied at her age.
We did not.
We were not 14.
More like 12.
Whose fault is that?
You guys were supposed
to be my examples.
What?
Oh, please?
Like we forced you during
freshman year to climb the rain
gutter at the Volcom house...
and steal their rum.
Oh, shit.
I don't
remember that.
Don't worry about it.
We turned out fine, right?
Housekeeping.
Oh, shit! Ohh!
Aw, that reeks.
What is that?
What is that smell?
I'm not...
I'm not doing this.
- What is that smell?
- Freakin' nasty,
that's what it is.
- It reeks in this room.
- This royally sucks.
- Oh, my God.
- All right.
Let's just get started.
Oh, sick.!
What?
Ohh.!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God! That...
- I'm not cleaning that up.
- We have to do it.
- I'm not cleaning it.
- We got to get it done.
- It's so sick.
No-neck pigs.
Ohh!
Help me make the bed, Lena.
Football players are so nasty.
I don't even know
where to start.
They think
they can do anything.
This is ridiculous.
Oh, sick!
- What?
- Get it off, Anne Marie!
It's stuck!
It's not coming off!
- What is it?
- It's a condom.
- Grab it! It's stuck!
- No, don't touch it.!
Get it off!
Get it off.
- Anne Marie, get it off!
- Put some gloves on.
- Oh, get it off!
- Just relax.
I can't get it if you're
friggin' tossing around.
Nasty.
Oh, my God!
Ohh.!
Oh, sick!
You know what?
That's it.
[Woman]
Ooh, wedding and honeymoon
in the same place?
Let's go snorkeling.
I am not snorkeling
with this hair. Give me a break.
Those masks leave
the worst marks on your face.
There's, like,
a hundred people spit in them.
Anybody in room 215?
215?
Anybody in 215?
Gentlemen, 2 15?
Anybody in room 215?
No? Anybody in room 215
out in the water?
What?
Suite 215?
Is it yours?
Oh.
Ohh! God!
Jump!
I swear to God that's a condom.
I'm in 2 15.
I think I won something.
I'm in 215.
What'd I win?
Hi. I'm Anne Marie.
I'm the housekeeper
of your room.
Leslie. O-line!
O-line!
Do you have a sec, Leslie?
Sure. Take all the time
you want, sugar-wooger.
Step one.
Step two.
And step three.
You got it?
Thanks for
your time, guys.
- No problem.
- You got schooled by the maid.
I'm on vacation.
You don't have...
You still got schooled.
You don't have
to clean your room
when you're on vacation.
You got schooled.
But you don't clean your room
when you on vacation!
Am I on vacation?
[Laughing]
It was gross,
It was disgusting.
I don't care what they did.
They are V.I.P.
Pay the highest rate.
They don't pay good money
to be scolded by a housekeeper.
You can pick up
your last check next week.
Surf's up, Anne Marie.
They peed on the floor.
There was puke
all over the curtain.
Please don't suspend me.
We need the money.
I'm not suspending you,
I'm firing you.
- What?
- Well, if she's fired,
I quit.
Me too.
Fine.
You're seriously
going to fire all of us?
No.
I'm firing you. They quit.
So don't get any ideas
about collecting unemployment.
[Sighs]
You guys, don't quit.
We need to make rent.
You could have stayed
down longer than that.
I'm tired of holding
my breath, Eden.
[Anne Marie]
God, shejust loves
pissing me off.
Look at her.
She's not out here to get waves.
Shejust wants to get attention.
What does she
see in those guys?
They're such burnouts.
- Same thing you did.
- What?
Cut body
and a nice cutback.
Oh, great.
She got a bad attitude.
It's not who she is.
Inside.! Got it.!
I'm on it.! Get off!
Hey, beat it.!
Hey, hey, hey.!
Got it.!
Hey.!
Hey, where you been?
I'm on it.! Get off!
[Anne Marie]
Drew, I got it.!
Hey!
- I had the section.
What's your problem?
- You need to grow up.
It's not my fault you broke
your board, you stupid kook.
You're a kook.
Don't drop in on me again.
That's right, go home.
Beat it.
Donkey.
Can you glue it
back together?
No.
Yeah, I was
just driving by.
Okay.
Well, actually,
the guy at the hotel told me
where I could find you.
So that was pretty awesome,
you know, surfng.
Right.
Hey, listen.
I wanted to apologize for
my friend back at the hotel.
Leslie's kind of messy,
but when your ass is
hanging out in the pocket,
he's the guy you want
protecting your backside.
So next time your ass is
hanging back in the pocket,
he's your guy.
I'll remember that.
- What's up, Anne Marie?
- Hey, Ben.
You broke your board.
That sucks. I bet
you were charging.
Something like that.
Hey, don't I know you?
- I don't know, maybe.
- Yeah. You're that
quarterback, right?
- Yeah, I play some football.
- That's right, huh?
Nice shoes, bro.
Thanks.
I was wondering if, maybe,
you've taught anybody?
Taught anybody?
Yeah. How to surf.
No.
Well, you know,
I've got some free time.
That's nice.
Look, I'd...
I'd love to learn.
It's not easy.
I know. But it looks
really fun out there.
- You can get hurt.
- I'm sure I could
handle myself.
This guy Rick, he'll set
you up with a spongeboard
and some baby waves.
- He's gentle.
- And you are?
Not.
Right.
- Check it out.
- Who's GQ jock?
Ho ho ho.
[Horn Honks]
What was that all about?
I don't know. He wanted
lessons or something.
Anne Marie! Lessons?
Money? We're broke?
What?
He didn't say
anything about paying.
Well, did you ask?
- You guys going tonight?
No. What time?
- Go, go, go!
- I don't know. I'm kinda lost.
- Go get him.
Hey! Hey!
How much?
What? What?
- How much?
- [Honk Honking]
- I got to call you back.
Oh, shit!
Hey! Watch where you're going!
Hurry up! Go get him.
Come on.
- Okay, hurry, hurry, hurry.
- Hey. Hey, listen.
- How much?
- I don't know.
What's the going rate?
- Twenty bucks an hour.
- Twenty?
Too much?
- Fifteen?
- The hotel charges $150.
I'll pay that.
Whoa!
One hundred and fifty bucks.
For surf lessons?
That's it, right?
What else
are we talking about?
Got any friends?
- Sure I do.
- Whoo! Yeah!
##[Radio, Fading]
- What's with the face, Pen?
- What face?
Don't worry, honey.
It's just one afternoon.
You'll have time to get
pregnant and go on welfare.
Good idea.
It'll be fun.
- We'll play rip off the tourist.
- We're not ripping anyone off.
Anyone who pays
$1,000 a night for a room is
just begging to be ripped off.
[Lena] I saw those guys walk
into Tommy Bahama yesterday and
drop four G's on silk boxers.
[Anne Marie]
How is that possible?
It's underwear.
[Lena]
Those guys got money to burn.
They play in the NFL.
[Penny]
I don't care about the money.
Anything is better than this.
[Singing]
Oh, my God!
Yeah, right.
[Penny]
Let me out here, you guys.
Penny!
Who unloaded the mothership?
I thought his friends
would be hot at least.
[Penny]
This is so embarrassing
to be seen with you.
You gonna teach us how to surf?
Guys.
Busted.
- Come on, it's 150 each.
- [Penny] What if we see
people we know? God.
Whatever.
It's surf lessons.
This is what jocks look like?
- A hundred and fifty bucks.
- Let's go surfing, big daddy.
What's up, girls?
This is Lena and Eden.
I'm Anne Marie.
- Hey.
- We gonna surf today?
Watch out.
I'll make sure
you drown out there.
How's it going? Matt.
Nice to meet you.
- This is my
little sister, Penny.
- What's up, little mama?
Little surf baby.
You're gonna surf in that?
- Hell, no. I'm gonna surf
in my da-da-da-da's.
- In your what?
My da-da-da-da's!
- Da-da-da-da!
- [Laughing]
You're wearing
nut huggers.
Some might call them that.
I call them nut containers.
You're gonna teach me to surf.
One, two, three.
Snap up!
- No duck butt.
- Oh. Oh, yeah.
# Somebody tell me
where the party at #
# Where the plates alive
and the hot girls are at #
# Where this dawg can
find himself a kitty cat #
# One who can use her mind
but don't have an attitude
Let me know when you see her #
# Let me know when she's close
Let me know when we're near #
# If not bein'lazy
we can go somewhere #
- # It's a party over here #
- # Party over there #
# Everybody jumpin'#
# Everybody movin'
'cause the bass is thumpin'#
# Now make some noise
You bring the girls
and I'll bring the boys #
- # Yahoo #
# Let me know where it's at
Make some noise from
the front to the back #
# Let me know where it's at
Make some noise from
the front to the back #
# Let me know where it's at
Make some noise from
the front to the back #
# Let me know where it's at
Make some noise
And do it again #
# There's a party over here
There's a party over there #
# There's a party over here #
- Ohh!
- # There's a party over here #
# There's a party over there
There's a party over here #
Are you ready?
All right. Start paddling!
Paddle! Go! Go!
Yeah.! Yes.! Get up.!
Get up.! Get up.!
Put your head in the center!
Lean forward! Hula hands!
- Come on! Go!
- Whoa! Ohh!
- # Yahoo #
Come on, get back out here!
One more time!
# Let me know where it's at #
# Make some noise from
the front to the back #
Hey, I'm giving a lesson.
# Let me know where it's at
Yeah, make some noise from
the front to the back #
# Let me know where it's at #
There you go.
Come on. Paddle! Paddle!
- # Make some noise
And do it again #
- Whoo!
Whoo!
That was so good.
That was incredible.
Whoa!
Are you psyched?
Yeah, totally.
Let's go out and catch
one of those big ones.
- Out there?
Well, sure you can handle it?
- Yeah. Definitely.
Come on, Matt.
You got it. You got it.
Paddle, paddle, paddle.!
Harder. Come on.
You got to dig.
All right, Anne Marie,
I'm right there with you.
Don't worry about me.
I got this mastered.
I am a football player.
Oh, shit.!
Ohh!
A couple more, you've got it.
Just a couple more waves.
Dig.! Turtle.!
Get under your board.!
Turn it over.!
- [Gasping]
- Don't give up.
Come on. Paddle.
Got to make it over this wave.
Here we go. Paddle, paddle.
Hey! Hey!
Get out of the way.!
Harder!
There you go.
You okay?
Oh, man,
that was intense.
It's getting big out here.
Sure you don't want to go in?
No. I mean,
are we safe out here?
That depends what you think
is safe, but, yeah, pretty much.
Oh, man.
[Matt]
How about this one here?
No, this one's not a wave.
Oh, almost.
We'll get you one, Matt,
I promise. Come on back.
Oh, man.
Just be patient, Matt.
We'll get you one.
Anne Marie,
we're leaving!
Hey, sweetie,
why don't you come over here
and help me out a little bit?
Gonna need two of us
to carry this thing.
We should go. It's getting late.
I'm not leaving
until I catch one.
- How about this one?
- Turn around, quick. Quick.
Eggbeat. Eggbeat.
There you go, Matt.
This is it.
Paddling. Start paddling.
Go! Paddle! Paddle!
Stand up. Stand up.
Whoo-hoo!
Whoo! Yeah! Yeah!
There you go.! Yeah.!
- Whoo.!
- Yeah!
- Yes!
- There you go.!
Goodjob, Matt.!
- [Yelling]
- Yeah.
- Good job.
- Yes!
Hi. Welcome to the Lanakai.
That's all right.
I'm just dropping him off.
Why don't you come in
for a drink?
[Laughs]
Um, yeah. No, I'd
love to, but l, um...
But what?
I have to get back
to my side of the island.
You know what I mean?
Uh, no. Why?
'Cause I'm in training.
Pipe, uh, line.
Pipeline.
Master. Pipe Masters.
Right.
Pipe Masters. Right.
[Sighs]
Well, uh,
I tell you what. Uh...
I've only got 40 bucks.
For what?
For you.
For the lesson.
Oh, right.
But if you want
to come up to my room,
I'll give you the rest of it,
the money.
l-I would
really like to do that,
but see those guys over there?
They see us
heading up to your room,
half the island's gonna have us
sleeping together by tomorrow.
Really?
It's the coconut wireless.
That's very serious.
It's great. Yeah.
In that case, you wait here,
I'll come right back
with your money.
All right. Well, wait.
I'll come up.
You sure?
Okay. I don't want to ruin
your reputation or anything.
Thanks.
I'll worry about that.
All right.
Okay. You go up the elevator,
I'll go up the back way.
It's so sneaky.
It's likeJames Bond.
Just shut up.
Excuse me.
# I lie awake #
# I've gone to ground #
# I'm watching porn #
# In my hotel dressing gown #
- [Sighs]
- # Now I dream of you #
- What the hell is she doing?
- # But I still believe #
- Hey. Where you going?
- Hey.
I just... I didn't...
I didn't know if that
was your room or not.
It's my room.
Yeah.
[Chuckles]
Come in.
Okay. Thanks.
[Clears Throat]
# And it feels so bad #
Oh.
- Looks different at night.
- Yeah. It's pretty nice.
I'm gonna...
I'm just gonna go...
Yeah. It's right there.
Yeah, I know where it is.
Thanks.
# I'm nearly with you #
# When I'm weak
I draw strength from you #
# And when you're lost #
# I know how
to change your mood #
# And when I'm down #
# You breathe life over me #
What are you doing?
Uh, I'm just trying to
find the money that I hid.
- What, from the maid?
- Yeah, right.
Uh, let's see.
- One, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine...
- Whoa, wait.
That's... That's way,
way just...
That's... That's a $1,000.
I'll be here a week.
That's $150 a day.
So I gave myself a $50 discount
for paying up front.
Are you trying
to buy me?
No.
No. I just don't
want to lose you.
# When I'm weak #
# I draw strength from you #
# And when you're lost #
#I know how to change
your mood #
Can I ask you
a really weird question?
[Chuckles]
Yeah.
Are you wearing my cologne?
Yes. Uh-huh.
It, uh,
it smells good on you.
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing]
You should
probably get that.
Yeah. Right.
Hey, you.
[Ringing]
Yeah?
Hey. Hey, sweetheart.
Are you feeling better?
Yeah, I know.
I tried to call earlier,
but, uh, no one was there.
Yeah, I miss you too.
I miss you too.
It's been hectic.
Matt, I'm gonna...
Listen, let me call you back,
all right? All right.
I love you too.
All right, bye-bye.
[Hangs Up Phone]
- Sorry.
- Guess that's why they have
that no fraternization rule.
What do you mean?
Management gets
call from irate wife...
wondering why maid
is in husband's room
at 2:00 in the morning.
That's not my wife.
Wife, girlfriend, boyfriend.
No, really.
It's not my wife.
Look, it's my niece.
Actually, my...
my sister's daughter, Rebecca.
There she is.
So.
I swear.
She's beautiful.
Yeah, she is.
She's a sweetheart.
Sorry about that.
It's just, uh, kinda strange
with the time difference.
I should probably go.
It's getting late.
All right. Do we have
a surf lesson tomorrow?
Definitely.
All right.
Okay.
Bye.
I thought you were
just giving him lessons.
I did.
Huh. Yeah, in what?
Penny didn't finish
her homework.
- You weren't here to help me.
- She's got to do her homework.
Don't give us shit 'cause
you were out there working it.
Shut up.
Don't deny it.
You were working it
like a rib without sauce.
Shut up... Ow!
Well, what happened?
Oh, my God. Nothing.
Oh, sure.
Tell me what happened.
No.
Did you get some play? Huh?
- Did you? Did you?
- We kissed for two seconds.
It wasn't a big deal.
I'm sure you did.
How much am I supposed
to buy that for?
What do you take me for?
I don't know.
Seriously.
What else? Come on.
Here, this will
pay the bills.
There's, like, $1,000 here.
I feel like your pimp.
You must know how to kiss.
Or you must know how to
do something else.
Good night, Penny.
You're going to bed now.
Hey.
What's up?
Look, I hate
to be the buzzkill here,
but the contest is in a week.
And I just don't think
that it's time for...
I know.
But I did promise him
another lesson tomorrow.
- Can't you just
blow him off?
- No.
- Why not?
- Because he already paid me.
Exactly.
Eden.
I wanted to rent
a jet ski tomorrow.
Put you into some size.
Get you ready for Pipe.
I'll meet you
at the launch at 4:00.
Why not earlier?
I'll meet you there
as soon as I can.
- Where we going again?
- A little spot the hotel does
not tell the tourists about.
Oh, my God.
You drive like you surf.
I drive like I wished I surfed.
Wow. This is beautiful.
Yeah. I used to come here
when I was a kid.
I've been dreaming
about surfing all night.
Aw, Minnesota's got surf stoke.
# When I was young #
- # I fell in love #
- [Laughing]
- # She was a goddess #
- Watch out.
# With the world
inside ofher mind #
# Now that I found you #
# I don't know how to #
Yeah.
# If I could fall #
# In love #
# Again #
# I'd fall in love #
# With you #
Whoo-hoo!
# I would #
How many sisters
you got, Minnesota?
Uh, five.
Five?
Five.
Really?
You're the only boy?
Uh, yep.
Explains what?
Well, that explains it then.
That's why you're not
intimidated by women.
[Chuckles] Yeah.
Why is that funny?
Because I'm scared
shitless of women.
My sisters would beat me
on a regular basis.
See, look.
See how I can't
extend my finger?
Yes.
Because my sister Dana
broke it when I was eight...
just because I wouldn't
get out of her room.
Because it's broken that way,
when I throw the football,
it gives it a nice little zip.
[Vehicle Approaching]
A nice little touch?
Exactly.
[Vehicle Stops,
Door Opening]
Uh, I think we got company.
Oh, great.
Yeah, I do. We gotta go.
You know those guys?
Really?
Yeah.
Prepare to get vibed.
This place is kapu.
That means off-limits
to you, haole.
What's up, guys?
This is a local spot.
Yeah, and I'm a local.
He's not.
What's up, haole boy?
Drew, back off.
We grew here,
you flew here.
It's not his fault.
What are you doing on
our beach, haole boy?
You don't live here,
you don't surf here.
We'll be out ofhere
in five seconds.
This is a local spot.
- This place is for the boys.
- You know not to bring
this guy here.
Why don't you relax, bro?
Bro? You telling me bro?
- Drew, stop it.
- You want some of this?
Don't even touch me.
- Don't touch her.
- What are you gonna do?
I've got his wallet.
We're out of here.
Let's go surf.
- Drew, stop!
- Linemen aren't here
to protect you, haole boy.
Walk away. Stop it.
Why are you being like this?
Don't touch her.
What are you gonna do?
Drew! Both of you!
That's enough! Stop!
Get off! Get in the car!
Stop it! Get in the car!
Stop it. Get in the car.
Get in the car.
Walk away.
You're an asshole.
I do what I do best.
Relax, bro.
You kicked his ass.
You stupid monkey.
Go back to the mainland.
[Water Lapping]
This is bullshit.
[Eden]
Kawela's?
And you expected
to make it back
in time?
I rented a jet ski.
I know. I'm sorry. I said
I was sorry a hundred times.
Whatever.
She's good, man.
Hello?
##[Reggae, Indistinct]
What'd she say?
She's messin' up,
man.
##[Continues]
[Phone Clatters
In Cradle]
[Sighs]
Ah.
Everything okay?
Oh, yeah.
We'll be okay.
I can see why
the tourists here
never leave their hotels.
Oh, don't say that.
That's not real Hawaii.
They're just...
They're just crazy.
They're so protective of
their land and their waves,
especially.
And their women?
[Yelps, Laughs]
[Laughs]
What?
I'm glad I'm here.
# Gimme more
I can't get enough #
# I need your big love #
Whoo!
I have to go
to practice.
I'll get up.
No, no, no.
Sleep in.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
You can sleep.
Bye.
[Door Closes]
Oh, shit.
[Phone Ringing]
[Ringing Continues]
[Moans]
[Phone Beeps]
Hello?
Lena, it's me.
- Hey. Where are you?
- Don't worry about it.
- You're at his room, huh?
- It's none of your business.
I just wanna make sure
Penny gets to school okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't worry about it.
What happened?
- I will tell you everything.
- Come on, little hooch.
- [Laughing]
Oh, my God.
- All right.
- Bye.
[Sighs]
[Birds Chirping]
[People Shouting,
Indistinct]
[Chuckles]
- [Man]
Room Service. Can I help you?
- I'd like to order breakfast.
Of course, Mrs. Tollman.
What can I get you?
Uh, the blueberry waffles.
[Shower Running]
[Knocking]
[Woman]
Housekeeping.
Well, aloha.
Look at you,
little miss princess.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
[Laughing]
So the glass slipper
fit, huh?
I even went
in the pool.
Shut up!
You're so irritating.
Was it my fault
he abducted me...
and forced me to eat
blueberry waffles?
Blueberry waffles?
Where? Nice.
Outside.
What are you doing?
Helping.
Why? You're not
a maid anymore.
Don't be mad at me.
I'm not mad.
[Lena]
Mmm.!
These are so good.
You didn't save me any
whipped cream though.
Some guy thinks you look hot
in a bikini, and you forget
all about the contest.
That's not fair,
and you know it.
Champagne?
How cheesy are you?
Shut up.
I'm not mad.
It's just...
I happen to know that
you kick ass out there,
and you worked very hard
to get to where you are.
I know.
Pipe is in three days.
Every single sponsor
is here,
and it's just you
and one other girl out there.
I know. I got it.
Okay?
People would kill
to be in your shoes.
I got it!
Hey, listen to me.
Contest comes first.
Nothing changes that.
[Sighs]
[Loud Roar]
# Last day
of the rest of my life #
# I wish I would've known
'cause I didn't kiss
my mama good-bye #
# I didn't tell her
that I loved her
and how much I care #
# Or thank my pops
for all the talks
and all the wisdom he shared #
# Unaware, I just did
what I always do #
# Everyday, the same routine
before I skate off to school #
# But who knew that this day
wasn't like the rest #
# Instead of takin'a test
I took two in the chest #
I'm gonna whip it around.
# Call me blind
but I didn't see it comin'#
# Everybody was runnin'
but I couldn't hear
nothin'except gun blasts #
# It happened so fast
I didn't really know this kid
though I sit by him in class #
# Maybe this kid
was reaching out for love #
# Or maybe for a moment
he forgot who he was #
# Or maybe this kid
just wanted to be hugged #
# Whatever it was
I know it's because #
# We are, we are
the youth of the nation #
# Little Suzy, she was only 12
She was given the world
with every chance to excel #
# Hang with the boys
and hear the stories
they tell #
# She might act kinda proud
but no respect for herself #
# She finds love
in all the wrong places #
# The same situations
Just different faces #
# Changed up her pace
since her daddy left her #
Whoo!
# Too bad he never told her
she deserved much better #
# We are, we are
the youth of the nation #
This is it.
This is it,
right there.
# We are, we are
the youth of the nation #
# We are, we are #
# The youth of the nation #
# The youth of the nation ##
Yeah!
Shit.
Anne Marie!
Hey, Anne!
Anne Marie.!
[Gasping]
Eden, I'm over here.!
Get on. Get on.
We gotta get outta here.
I got you. I got you.
Hold on.
[Eden]
What's wrong?
- Eden, get outta here!
- Oh, shit!
[Anne Marie]
Bail.! Bail.!
[Gasping]
[Coughing]
[Panting]
[Both Panting]
You all right?
Where were you?
I was right behind you.
I couldn't get in
without getting crushed.
You whipped me in way too deep.
You need to kick out earlier.
Okay, are we done
with our excuses now?
I wanna go in.
We'll rest for a minute.
I don't wanna get some rest.
I almost died out there.
You did not almost die.
You were under for,
like, five seconds.
Stop being such a Barbie.
What did you
say to me? What?
A Barbie?
What is your problem?
All I'm saying
is that if you
can't handle this,
there's no way
you're gonna be ready
for the Pipe Masters.
Then you go. If you're
so friggin' ballsy, Eden,
you go.
I can't.
I wasn't invited.
I don't know
what the hell
you want from me.
What I want from you
is to get your own life
and stop living through me.
Get your own dreams.
So that's it.
You're gonna run off
and be a pro ho, huh?
At least I have someone
that's interested in me.
[Engine Starts]
Why does this seem
so familiar, huh?
Run away when things
get tough.
I'm stressed out. I think
I'm gonna ditch my kid...
Shut up!
and run away with some guy
I met in California.
Shut up! I'm not kidding!
Sounds a little bit
too familiar.
Leave me alone.!
Like mother,
like daughter.
- Shut up!
- You're just gonna quit?
Get outta my face.
You're gonna prove
these guys right?
Assholes who think that you
can't surf Pipe because
you don't have the balls.
I guess so then,
'cause I quit.
I quit!
You're not a quitter.
You're just scared.
Hey. Oh, my God.
What's wrong?
[Crying]
Are you okay?
No.
[Lena]
Yeah, Rochelle Ballard rips.
[Both Laughing]
Oh! Closeout!
[Penny] Wiped out.
[Lena]
Sorry, Rochelle.
Where's Anne Marie?
Who cares?
Let me play.
[Penny]
Hey, it's my turn.
[Eden] You got beat.
[Man On Radio]
It's hump day... Wednesday.
We've got that high-surf
advisory in effect...
for the north-and
northwest-facing shores.
[Radio Continues,
Indistinct]
[Eden, Echoing] Sounds
a little bit too familiar.
Like mother, like daughter.
[Echoing]
# What you gonna do
gonna do, gonna do #
[Eden] This is your dream.
This is what you were
born to do.
- Don't throw it away
on this guy.
- [Anne Marie] Eden.!
# What you gonna do
gonna do #
[Eden]
You're not a quitter.
You'rejust scared.
[Young, Old Anne Marie]
I'm gonna be the best
surfer in the world.
[Eden, Echoing]
And it's just you
and one other girl out there.
It's just you
Shit!
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Wow. You look...
What?
Where'd you get that?
- The dress.
- From a store.
- He bought it?
- Yes, he bought it.
So what?
So I can see your boobs.
Great.
I think she looks
beautiful.
Thank you.
- She looks the way
he wants her to look.
- Like Baywatch Barbie.
- Penny, shut up.
- Is he gonna buy you
implants too?
Penny, I just can't
do this right now, okay?
Man, that girl
could rip.
Who is that?
You.
That was the first time you
beat me at the Menehune contest
in Haliewa.
You were such
a cocky little shit.
[Laughing]
Always talking all that trash
and how you would be
number one.
I was so pissed at you
'cause I knew you would be.
All talented and shit.
The boys were spinnin'.
Remember that?
They had to throw up some
bullshit rule barring you
from the boys' contest.
I'm gonna be late.
He's leaving in a few days
with a tan, and what are you
gonna be left with,
a pair of shoes?
[Applause, Cheering
On Videotape]
I wanted platinum.
##[Hawaiian]
At least it's an "E."
It is?
It'd better be.
He said it was.
1½ "E."
Everybody think I'm sexy.
I'm the sexiest...
You ain't sexy.
[All Laughing]
He don't know
anything.
Very Tiffany's.
He likes
your little sum-sum.
A little lovin' one night.
And then you get yourself
a little upgrade.
[Woman]
That's good enough.
Good evening, miss.
Welcome to the Lanakai.
Jimmy, are you kidding me?
It's me. It's Anne Marie.
Holy shit!
You look insane.
Thank you. God.
All right.
Wow. You look...
Weird.
No. Gorgeous.
Really?
Let's go
show you off.
Oh!
##[Drumming]
[People Chattering]
[Woman]
This is great. This is great.
##[Drums Stop]
[Man]
Okay.
Now it's time for a few
of you lucky men to learn
how to do the Tahitian hula.
- Do we have
any volunteers?
- [All Shouting At Once]
Some intelligent men.
Some men of size.
[Excited Chattering]
Here I go.
- All right. Wish me luck.
- [Emcee]
Come on. Let's push it up.
##[Drumming]
Get those hands
up in the air.
Rip it! Rip it!
[Laughing]
[Singing, Shouting Continue,
Indistinct]
[Emcee]
Come on. Let's go.
Everybody.
[Singing, Shouting,
Indistinct]
Throw your hands
in the air!
[Continues Shouting,
Indistinct]
# Shake your thing
Come on #
# Shake that thing
Shake that thing #
# Show me that thing
Show me what you got
Shake that thing ##
##[Hawaiian Guitar
Playing Softly]
[Woman Chattering]
[Cell Phone Dialing,
Ringing]
[Man's Voice]
Hey, howzit, wave riders!
We got that
high-surf advisory
posted again.
Right now, it's a macking
15 to 20 feet.
Out in Pipeline tomorrow,
the girls have the place
all to themselves.
[Door Opens]
[Woman] What are we supposed
to talk about with her anyways?
[Laughing]
Windex, I guess.
Or Comet.
[Woman] The only person
who knows anything about
Windex or Comet in our house...
is Carmen, but not me.
[Woman #2]
I hope she doesn't think
he's gonna marry her.
[Woman #1] Of course
she does. Prince Charming come
to save her from the toilets.
[Woman #2]
And get some of that
ten million a year.
[Woman #1, Laughing]
Oh, God. Matt and the maid.
[Woman #3]
Oh, my God. Did you guys
check out that dress? Hello?
[Woman #2]
Where does she think
she's going anyway, the prom?
[Woman #3]
I thought her shoes
were totally cute.
[Woman #2]
Trust me on this.
He made her up.
The whole Matt Tollman makeover.
Did you see the shoes,
the dress, the bracelet?
[Woman #1]
His classic line.
[All Laughing]
Oh, my God.
Do you guys remember
the Denny's waitress?
[Woman #2] Oh, that's right.
[Woman #3]
I knew she looked familiar.
Matt loves to slum.
That's just how he is.
Come on. That's his style.
He likes those cheap little...
Cheap Barbie...
[Gasps]
Here. They're all yours.
Oh, my God.
Oh. My God.
Was that just her?
Oh, it was.
She was here.
Our dancer tonight
is Chief...
What's your name?
Leslie, but everybody
call me "Poon Daddy."
[All]
Aloha, Chief Poon Daddy!
##[Drumming]
[Woman]
Oh, yeah.!
Ow.! Baby, go.!
[Laughing]
Come on.!
Shake your thing.!
[Emcee]
Let's hear it for this guy.
Isn't he great?
[Woman]
You got milk
in those coconuts?
[Second Woman]
Shake it, shake it, shake it.!
Oh, yeah.!
[Luau Chatter Continues]
[Matt] Anne Marie.
Where you goin'?
Anne Marie?
Stop?
What the...
Oh, man.
Uh, Anne Marie, uh...
##[Drumming Continues,
Muffled]
Anne Marie.
What the hell
are you doin'?
I don't know, Matt.
What am I doing?
The other day,
when I was ordering
room service,
the guy on the phone
called me Mrs. Tollman,
and I didn't correct him.
'Cause for a minute,
I liked the way
it sounded.
And I was just wondering
if the Denny's waitress
felt the same way.
[Sighs]
Listen...
You know what?
I'm fine, okay.
I know what I am,
and I'm fine with it.
What? Who are you?
I'm the maid
that you slept with
on vacation.
I'm the great story you tell
when someone asks you
how you learned to surf.
[Sighs]
You don't trust anybody,
do you?
Can I?
Can I trust you?
To do what?
I mean...
What do you want?
What do I want?
Oh, my God.
I want...
Penny to quit smoking
and to go to college.
I want... I want to be able
to pay the phone
and the electricity...
and the rent
all in the same month.
I want a girl
to be on the cover
of Surf magazine,
and that would be great
if that girl were me,
but any girl would do.
And I want...
[Sighs]
I mean, I wish
my mom would come home.
And I really, really
want to win Pipe Masters
tomorrow.
That's what I want.
Well, do it.
Matt, you don't
understand, okay?
Pipe... Pipe is
the heaviest wave
in the world.
Okay, you don't just
get worked there.
You die.
People die there.
And what happens
when I just...
when I paddle out
and I don't take off
on a single wave?
I don't care if I make a fool
out of myself, but I do not
want to embarrass my family.
And that's what Lena
and Eden and Penny are.
They're my family.
[Sighs]
Just tell me
what to do, please.
You want me to tell you
what to do?
Yes.
You know what to do.
No, Matt,
I honestly don't.
Just be the girl
I met on the beach.
Who? Who was she?
A girl who'd never
ask a guy what to do.
[Man On P.A.]
Good morning, everybody.
Welcome to the Pipe Masters...
here at Banzai Pipeline
on the North Shore of Oahu.
You're gonna be watching
women's surfng history today...
as these girls take on
the deadliest waves
in the world.
Imagine the Niagara Falls
dumping into two feet of water
over hard-rock lava...
with razor-sharp reef
and underwater caves.
[Man On Radio]
It's gonna be a macking 20 feet.
Good luck to all the ladies
competing today
at the Pipe Masters.
They may be the best in
the world, but they're gonna
have their hands full today.
If you're going down to watch,
it's not a day for a dip
in the water.
Anne Marie,
you all right?
Mm-hmm.
[Tires Screech]
You guys get out here.
I'll go find
some parking.
[Man On P.A.]
Pretty much an impossible
score at this point.
She's way behind,
but she's still gonna try
and put it on the line.
Looks like she's
goin'for this one.
Oh.! She broke her board.
Any day at Pipeline,
it's critical, but today,
one false move
and the consequences
could be disastrous.
More surfers have died here
than any other spot
on the planet combined.
This is the first time
the girls have gotten
to compete at Pipeline.
The entire surfcommunity
is here today...
every sponsor, talent scout,
the entire surf media... looking
to find the next surfsensation.
Get one good ride here today,
and you'll put yourself
on the surfng map.
Out there all by herself
is Lynette MacKenzie,
now that Megan's
on the beach
with a broken board.
She's in on a nice one.
She's comin'in.
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
You really have to commit
if you are gonna
get those waves.
But I'm sure
it'll better the score
she already has.
Good luck, Layne.
Thanks.
I could use it.
I'm here
for the competition.
Are you a volunteer?
She's a competitor.
You need to sign
this release form.
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
"In case of death
or dismemberment"?
Thank you.
You'll be in heat four
with Kate Skarratt.
You can go ahead and wait
in the competitors' area.
Thank you.
Good luck.
It's looking pretty solid
out there, isn't it?
[Laughing, Chattering]
Oh, my gosh.
There's Kate Skarratt.
She kills at Pipe.
And there's Rochelle Ballard.
She's queen ofback door.
- Oh, my gosh.!
Layne Beachley is...
- I know who they are.
What? I'm...
You're good.
I'm just saying...
they're...
they're really good.
[Car Alarm Blaring]
Shit.!
[Man]
Come on. Let's go.
[Tires Screech, Horn Honks]
Hey! What's up, man?
[Man]
What's up?
Where's parking around here?
Anywhere, I guess
Whatever you can find.
[Announcer]
Looks like she's
goin'on this one.
[Excited Chatter]
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
Hey. Hey, Anne Marie.
Look what I found.
[Announcer]
Next heat, Keala Kennelly.
Hey. Just driving by.
What's up,
surfer girl?
- Do the damn thing.
- [Both Laughing]
- Shit.
- [Announcer]
Twenty-foot swell on the rise.
[Anne Marie]
Pretty weird out there.
It's a super-clean,
west-northwest swell.
Pipe and back door
are both open.
[Lena]
Yeah. Just be patient.
Don't get too anxious.
It's four-wave sets
with 20-second intervals.
Take your time.
[Penny]
Don't take the first wave
of the set.
Third wave
looks the best.
[Announcer]
Here comes Kennelly
taking off. Steep drop.
She makes the bottom turn.
She's fierce, man.
Gets covered up.
Oh.! She makes it out.
Let's give her a warm
round of applause.
I'm way out of my league.
Hey. No worries.
Just go out there
and have fun.
[Laughs] "Fun."
[Announcer] Up next,
from Australia, we have
Kate Skarratt in red.
[Sighs]
She's a goofy foot, which
favors her at Pipeline.
Loves charging big waves
and has taken first place
at Teahupoo,
another barreling
left-hander in Tahiti.
Surfng against her,
we have wild card entry,
Anne Marie Chadwick,
a formerJunior NSSA champion
who dropped out of
the competitive circuit...
after a near-drowning incident
at this very spot
just three years ago.
Five, four, three,
two, one.
[Air Horn Blasts]
[Chattering]
[Panting]
We've got 20-minute heats
today with the top
four waves scoring.
Wave selection is critical.
If you pick the wrong wave,
wipe out, get caught inside...
You could spend the rest
of your heatjust trying
to get back to the lineup.
How's it goin'?
Good.
Nice set approaching.
Got good sets out the back.
We have really good
consistency with swell.
It's on the rise.
Probably gonna get up
to about 15 to 20 feet.
Kate Skarratt's goin'
on this one. She's paddling,
gets to her feet.
Makes the drop.
Solid bottom turn.
[Clicking]
Look at that pit.!
She's setting her line,
racing to make it out.
Trying to get
to the shoulder.
Traveling...
Oh.! She didn't quite
get around that last turn.
She'll get some kind
of score for it.
Looks like it's a 4. 1
that came in on the board.
Water patrol's
checking on her.
Looks like she's okay.
If she doesn't need a ride,
she can paddle back out.
So Chadwick all alone
by herself out there,
yet to even score a ride.
Go, go! Paddle!
Headed for her first ride.
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
[Announcer]
Backs out.
Shit!
- Beautiful wave. She's not
gonna get any more like that.
- What a waste of wave.
She should've gone.
That would have opened up
perfectly.
Shit!
When you're out there all alone,
you can psyche yourself out.
You can do it, girl.
- Chadwick will have to wait
for the next set.
- What are you doin'?
Kate Skarratt's paddling
into one of the best
waves of the day.
0h.! Look at this wave.
It is a bomb.
Oh.!
She's a little overextended
and goes down.
[Gasps]
- Hope she's okay out there.
Kate Skarratt down.
- Ooh.
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
Great pickup.
Gets her on the sled,
out ofharm's way.
Hang on.
Okay, everybody, as the ski
comes up on the beach,
please give them some room.
The water patrol
needs some space to work.
Skate Skarratt has gone
down on that last wave.
They're carrying
the backboard down.
This isn't good.
We need Dr. Leland Dao
to report to the medical tent.
Leland Dao, please report
to the medical tent.
We need you down here
immediately.
[Sighs]
Come on. Come on.
Charge it!
Go, go, go!
Go! Go!
Go!
[Announcer]
She sets her rail.
Makes the drop.
Textbook. Oh.!
It's setting up perfectly.
Look at that.
Beautiful wave.
She should get
a nice score for this one,
Yes!
high enough to take her
into the next round.
- [Announcer]
Oh.!
- [All Groan]
- Oh, she got so worked.
- [People Groaning]
[Crying]
[Announcer, Indistinct]
[Woman] I don't see her.
Where is she?
Man, is she all right?
[Gasping]
Oh!
[Announcer]
Anne Marie's taking
a heavy beating out there.
[Gasping]
[Coughs]
Grab my hand.
I got you.
Hang on.
[Announcer] Not that she cares
right now, but thejudges'
scores havejust come in...
and they've awarded her a 4.6
for the last ride,
which will move her
into the next round
over Skarratt.
- Anne Marie!
- Are you okay?
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
[Overlapping Voices]
- [Lena]
Is she gonna be all right?
- Is she gonna be all right?
She'll be okay.
Just give her some room.
[Coughing]
Is she
gonna be okay?
I think so.
[Announcer Continues,
Indistinct]
[Neck Cracks]
I'm gonna put
some ice on it.
Lift your head.
Just lay there
and relax for a minute.
Hey.
If you tell me to be the girl
on the beach right now,
I'm gonna kick your ass.
[Laughing]
Oh.
So how are you feelin'?
I've been better.
Yeah.
My, uh,
my first NFL game,
I got blindsided
by Warren Sapp.
I tell you,
I've never been hit
so hard in my life.
I lay there praying something
was broken so I wouldn't have
to get up and finish the game.
You think I'm faking?
No. I know
you got rocked out there.
Just like I did.
But Leslie sat me down,
said that was the hardest
I'd ever be hit and that I would
regret not going back in.
So l... I went back in.
And you won the game.
No. Actually, we lost.
[Laughing]
And I got my ass kicked.
But there's this one
beautiful pass...
one perfect spiral
right into Omar's fingertips...
and a touchdown.
[Sighs]
Look, I can't talk you
into goin'back out there.
It's... It seems crazy.
But I know how good you are,
and I know how much
this means to you.
I just don't want you
to spend your life wondering
what could have been.
[Announcer]
Heads up on the beach, people.
Big set approaching.
Hey, everybody, we have
a set out the back.
Watch your kids.
Watch your belongings.
The water is coming
over the berm.
It's dangerous out there.
The water patrol already
has their hands full,
so we'd appreciate it
if you'djust back up.
Here today we have
a rising swell,
so I wanna give
a little word of warning
to everybody to watch out.
Guys, look, this is really
not a good time.
Can I get a picture?
What?
Can we get a picture?
We're working these chicks here.
They think you're some kind
of great hockey player
or something.
You're kidding.
No joke. We wanna
get this thing done.
Sorry my pits stink.
That's just the way it goes.
Let's go. Right here.
Smile.
You're on vacation.
This way, this way.
Fluff your bangs
a little bit.
A little more attitude.
Beautiful.
One more.
All right, great.
Hey.
You goin'
back out there?
Yup.
It's just a stupid contest.
It's not worth
getting hurt over.
I'll be fine.
Hey.
- What?
- Be careful.
[Laughing]
Yeah.
- [Blasts]
- [Announcer] That sounds
the start of the next heat.
Chadwick's pretty much
got her hands full
this next round.
Keala Kennelly from Hawaii.
She's a charger.
She'll go on anything.
She goes like a man out here.
Bit of a paddle battle
going on out there.
Looks like Chadwick
and Kennelly are
paddling for the peak.
Chadwick's got
the inside position.
- Lf a big set approaches,
she's gonna get the first wave.
- Come on, come on.
This paddle battle
is really about who's
gonna get the first wave.
Chadwick in position,
heading for the first wave.
Starts to paddle.
She's goin'for it.
Oh.! She... She pulls back.
Kennelly's wide open.
She catches a wave.
[Sighs]
Time and time again,
man.
She's out,
making it look so easy.
But, folks,
it's not easy out there.
Chadwick starts to paddle.
She paddles for it.
Doesn't quite get it.
[All Groan]
What a waste of wave.
[Announcer]
That's gotta hurt when
you know you need a score,
and you're going up against
one of the best surfers
in this event,
and you don't go.
Plenty of time being
allowed here for Kennelly
to get back in position,
and she's paddled
right inside of Chadwick,
and she's looking
to catch her next wave.
Keala Kennelly.
Hands together,
ladies and gentlemen.
Keala Kennelly.
A great two-ride out here
at the Pipeline.
[Crowd Cheering]
Keala's got sack.
She goes like the men out here.
For some reason, Chadwick
has yet to even ride a wave.
I don't know what's going on.
I don't know if she's just
psyching herself out or if
Keala's putting it to her.
What are you doin'?
What?
You gonna take a wave
or just sit there
like a buoy?
Look, you're never gonna
catch a wave sitting
all the way over here.
Follow me. I'll get you
into one. Give the crowd
something to cheer about.
Let's get you a wave.
Come on.
Follow me into the lineup,
and I'm gonna tell you
to go on a wave.
And when I tell you to go,
you gotta go.
Paddle your little heart out.
You can't hesitate.
You can't pull back.
You can't hold back.
No fear, all right?
'Cause if you hold back
for a second,
you're gonna eat shit.
Come on. Follow me.
[Announcer]
It looks like the next set's
approaching.
This is the one. Go.
Paddle! Paddle!
Go, girl!
Paddle.!
Ah!
Go.!
Oh!
[Crowd Groans]
[Man]
You all right?
I'm okay, I'm okay.
Get back out there then.
- [Blasts]
- [Announcer] With only
two minutes left in her heat,
Chadwick struggles
to get back into the lineup...
so she can catch
a scoring wave.
Chadwick has yet to even
score a good ride,
a scoring ride.
She needs to redeem herself.
Keala is absolutely
dominating this heat,
and Chadwick needs to put
a scoring ride on the board.
[Gasping]
Ouch.
Are you all right?
That was nasty.
It's okay.
I want another one.
- You want another one?
That's the spirit.
- Yup.
Shake off that last wave,
and let's do this.
Less than 20 seconds left.
Feel that adrenaline.
Use it. Come on.
Anne Marie Chadwick
only has one more chance.
On the outside. Here comes
one of the best sets
of the whole day.
We have lines
stacked to the horizon.
[Kennelly]
Here comes a set.
This is the one.
All right, come on.
Go.! Go, go.!
[Crowd Cheering]
[Woman]
Go, girl.!
- [Announcer]
Chadwick's out there.
- Paddle hard!
- Go! Go! Go!
- [Crowd Cheering]
[Kennelly]
This is yours.!
Don't pull back.!
- Go, go!
- [Kennelly]
Go.! Go.! Go.!
Oh, my gosh!
[Laughing]
[Crowd Cheering]
Oh, shit! Yeah!
- Whoo!
- Yeah!
- Oh, she makes it.!
[All Cheering]
That's my bitch!
[Cheering Continues]
Yeah!
That was insane!
- Whoo!
- Waiting for
thejudges'scores.
They're coming in.
Looks like unanimous tens
across the board,
but not enough
to overtake Kennelly
and move into the next round.
- But she is a hero
with the crowd here today.
- That's my sister! Whoo!
That's my sister!
[Laughing]
Just words
don't explain it.
For Anne Marie Chadwick
to get a ride like that...
with the entire North Shore
surfng community watching...
[All Whooping]
That was insane!
# My face to the sky
dreamin'aboutjust how high #
We're so proud of her.
# I could go, and I'll know
when I finally get there #
Can I have your autograph?
I taught her
everything she knows.
# There's a time #
[Girl]
That's our girl.
# For every star to shine #
Hey.
That was awesome.
Thank you.
Hey, you should, uh,
check out the board.
Boards By Eden.
[Woman]
Hey, Anne Marie. Excuse me.
Hi.
I'm Jessica from Billabong.
I'd love to talk to you
about being on our team.
- Wait your turn, honey.
- Okay.
- Does she know
she got beat?
- Nice, isn't it?
Hey.
Yeah!
[Laughing]
Whoo!
[Screeching]
You did the damn thing,
girl.
Thanks. Hey.
Hey.
You were so amazing.
Oh. Are you okay?
I'm so happy.
Oh, that was insane.
But I still
think you owe me
a few surf lessons.
Oh, yeah?
Wanna go out there?
Only if you're gentle.
Not a chance.
[Chuckling]
# Yeah #
# Everybody
got their something, yeah #
# Make you smile
like an itty bitty child #
# Everybody
got their something #
got their something, yeah #
##[Vocalizing]
# There's a time
for every star #
for every star ##
##[Rap Beat]
# Work out #
# Werdplay
Five, four #
# Bounce, bounce #
# Now, we all know
summertime is a bummer
with no duckets #
# Honeys not touchin'
and I fill up the room #
# It's the one time
we can just sit on our flat #
# Relax with a bangin' chick
and do somethin' with it #
# Without worries #
# Sunday to Monday
we hungry #
# It's all up front
and coverin'the tummy #
# Once a week
Bounce on the beach #
# It's a'ight though #
# Tight flow rope
come from Tommy #
# It's tough, some kid open
It's lovely #
# Coppin'assortments
on the corner
They love me #
#Buff city, double "E"
Cuss on beats and freaks #
# Runnin'with the summer
till we puttin'up the tree #
# Sunny beach, pumpin'Bananarama
The bangingest bodies
have bikinis on #
# I'm grabbin' 'em,
unravelin' the straps when I
bring her back to the cabin #
# Summer sucks without
this, that and those #
# It's a cruel, cruel summer #
# It's a cruel #
# Leavin' me here
on my own #
# It's a cruel, cruel summer #
# It's a cruel #
# Now you've gone #
# So tell me to ease out
Better to move or doubt #
# Which one you'll play about
Find a chick to get out #
# So I'm walkin'
across the street
to the public pools #
# When I spot this lovely jewel
A sweet cutie, never met her
but yet she knew me #
# She said #
# Ain't you that kid
from that rap group #
# Please, darlin', may I have
the honors of remaining
anonymous for the time bein' #
# Later, I'll bust a rhyme
for you #
# What's the matter
Havin'a bad day #
# She looked at me with sad face
and began to say to me #
# Hot summer streets and
the pavements are burnin' #
# I sit around #
# I said, you gotta
be kiddin', baby #
# Summer is the joint
What you thinkin' #
# Tryin'to smile
but the air
is so heavy and dry #
# Aw, sweetie, don't be sad
Possibly where you are
It'll ease that #
# Strange voices are sayin'
Uh, what did they say #
# Shh #
# Things I can't understand #
# Uh-uh #
# It's too close for comfort #
# This heat has got
right out ofhand #
# So I grabbed her by the hand
dragged her to the pool #
# Splashed her in
and that's it #
# It's a cruel, cruel summer #
# It's a cruel #
# Leavin'me here on my own #
# It's a cruel, cruel summer #
# It's a cruel #
# Now you've gone ##
##[Acid Rock]
# When I was young #
# I fell in love #
# She was a goddess #
# With a world
inside ofher mind #
# When she moved on #
# Something went wrong #
# She took my power #
# And the love
I had inside #
# Now that I found you #
# I don't know how to #
# If I could fall #
# In love again #
# I'd fall in love #
# With you #
# If I could change #
# A grain of sand #
# Into a pearl #
# I would #
# I pray, in time #
# I'll come to find #
# A way to break through #
# And save
this heart of mine #
# What am I to do #
# If I can't have you #
# If I could fall #
# In love again #
# I'd fall in love #
# With you #
# If I could change #
# A grain of sand #
# Into a pearl #
# I would #