Watch full movies online at www.awooh.com
We'll catch them
on the reach, Sam!
The reach is ours,
Charlie!
We're going over!
Whoa!
Watch it! Watch it!
We're cutting inside!
Inside what?
Hike hard, Sam, hike hard!
What are you doing?
Take the tiller!
Head as far up as you can.
We're gonna go over!
l'm not strong enough!
You're gonna
have to be, Sammy!
Here we go!
We're coming for you!
Yeah.
Yeah, buddy!
yes!
We got them, buddy!
Tess!
He's doing it again!
Come on, Sam!
God, that boy is
just too good!
We're gonna
catch them, Sam!
Come on, let's go!
Bear off when l say, Sam.
When l say.
Charlie, look!
But we're gonna hit it!
Man up, Sam!
Bear off when l say!
When l say, Sam!
Come on, Sam!
No way he's gonna make it!
Charlie,
we're gonna hit it!
We'll hit the boat! Charlie!
Now!
Sam, we did it!
We won!
Shitl
St. Cloud boys,
Iet me take your picture.
Hold on a second.
Ew!
You've got to look good.
This is for the newspaper.
You look good.
Ready? Sexy poses.
Sexy pose.
Congratulations, boys.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Give it to me.
l really thought
you had them
this time, Tessy.
Next time.
Ooh, thank you.
Charlie, l just
wanted to say great race.
You really closed out,
Thanks, man.
Yeah. You know,
they won't let you
pull stunts like that
in college races ,
St. Cloud
Yale-Stanford,
third race this season.
Mark it down on
your calendar, St. Cloud,
'cause that's when
l'm gonna smoke you.
Come on, Sam.
Don't look at me like that.
Oh, l guess there are
some things you
can't buy, Connors.
Owned.
Where do you think
they're going, Charlie?
Everywhere, Sammy.
They're going everywhere.
Don't wory, that's
going to be us one day.
You and me, bud.
Setting sail at
sunset cannons,
It's not like it
would be the end of the world.
l'm just saying,
l could work for a year,
fill the coffers,
and then go to Stanford.
You said yourself
it was too expensive,
even with the aid, Mom.
l didn't say it
was too expensive.
l said it was expensive.
Mom , I don't want you
having to work double shifts
at the hospital all the time.
You got in fall,
so you go in fall.
You can't put life
on hold, Charlie.
It doesn't wait for you.
l want to be there
when you spank Yale.
l do, too.
l want to be there
when he spanks Yale.
Spank it!
Eveybody's dressed so fancy.
You look beautiful, Mom.
Gorgeous.
Charles Percival St. Cloud,
captain of the sailing team
and winner of the Keating
Scholar-Athlete Award.
Charlie!
Charlie, baby,
Iooking good!
Congratulations.
We expect big things
from you, young man.
Expecting big
things myself, sir.
Stop it.
Straighten up,
Iook sharp.
This suit's so lame.
Sammy!
Put me down, Sullivan!
Sammy's on a rampage.
Don't make me
hurt you, Green!
Come on,
what do you got?
Come on, come on, come on.
You want to tap out?
We made it.
AIl right, All right.
You're up!
Hey. Kegger at the
point tonight.
Your attendance
is required, okay?
It's our last hurrah.
We're gonna have
hurrahs all summer long.
We ship out next
week for boot camp.
Everything got accelerated.
Next week?
Hoorah.
No. l'm gonna puke.
l'll be there.
Don't mess with me, Green.
You're late.
Oh, yeah, l couldn't
find my glove.
You're late, Sam.
Do you want to make
Majors next season?
Yeah, l'm gonna try.
Yeah? You're gonna ty?
Yes, definitely, yes!
'Cause l don't want to
waste my time here with you.
Yes! Yes! Yeah!
Yeah?
Okay. Then l'Il
make a deal with you.
l'll practice with you
for one hour every day,
right after l get off work,
up until l leave for Stanford.
l'll meet you at
sunset cannons every day.
But if you keep me
waiting like this
just one time,
the whole deal's off.
No, l won't. l won't.
You'd better not.
No. l swear.
No, l won't,
Okay.
Then let's do this.
Stop.
What?
Fundamentals.
Get over here.
Put your hand out;
palms up.
you see these wide seams?
Mmm-hmm.
That's the correct way
to hold a baseball.
l didn't know l
was gonna get to go
to baseball camp this summer.
That's because rich kids
go to camp, Sammy.
Do you have a trust fund
you're not telling me about?
Not really. No.
No, you don't.
But you know
what you do have?
Good looks?
No, you got me.
Get back over there.
Hustle,
Hey. l pulled an extra shift.
You are on Sam duty,
Mom, l have plans.
Make sure he gets in
bed at a decent hour.
Mom.,.
l'll bring you
donuts for breakfast.
Make mine chocolate!
Okay.
Hey, wait!
Hey, Sam!
Catchl Go!
How could you let that go
between your legs?
I could play
better than that!
Hey, buddy,
your dinner's ready, okay?
Sam, l'm putting
your dinner in the oven,
all right?
Okay!
Stop!
Jeez! What the.,.
What are you doing?
You're on Sam dutyl
No one babysat me
when l was 11 , Sam.
Look, it's the
7th-inning stretch.
Can you please
just get me to Tommy's
by the bottom of the 8th?
No. It's not exactly
on the way, Sam.
Sweet ride.
You're going out
like that?
Crucial game.
Nerd.
Blow me.
Dick.
Hey, keep an eye
out for cops,
out for cops.
Whatever.
Sammy! Cheer up.
Come on, Sammy.
Sammy, baby.
You just can't wait,
can you?
Sully and Green
Ieave for basic training
in a week.
No, Charlie,
l mean to get out of here.
Come on. l'm gonna
see you all the time.
That's what Dad said.
Yeah, but l'm not Dad.
l'm not gonna ditch you, Sam.
l'm not gonna ditch you.
Cheer up, man.
Not an option.
You got one second
to cheer up.
You're lucky that
wasn't my throwing arm.
Or what?
l'd have to kick your ass.
Hey, what are you doing?
Ow! My nose!
Shut your window, man.
l feel a draft.
Dude. Watch it, punk.
Calm down, l'm driving!
l'm driving, l'm driving!
Sam! l'm driving!
Come on.
Charlie?
Mom's gonna kill us!
Don't worry,
l'll take the blame.
God, l hurt so much.
What's that?
They're looking for us.
Who?
l don't know.
Whatever happens, please,
just don't leave me, okay?
l won't.
Charlie.,. Charlie!
Charlie!
please don't leaye me!
I won't!
Give it up,
The kid's flatlined.
He's a lost cause.
There's no such thing
as a lost cause, Quiet.
Come on. Come on.
My word.
Thank you, Jude.
Hey, Hey. Hey.
Welcome back.
Where was l?
lt's okay.
You've just got to relax.
Where's Sam?
Everything's okay,
but you gotta stay still.
Where's Sam?
You got
to stay still. Okay?
Shh, Everything's okay.
Sam?
Hey, Sam?
Sam! Sam?
You've got to rest.
Come on, come on.
Sam! Sam!
No! No!
No, please! Stop! No!
That's my brother! Sam!
l can't leave him.
Oh, my God,
l'm sory, Sam!
No! Sam! l'm sorry, Sam.
Dispatch, be advised, 351-BT,
from fatality accident.
One conscious, one DOA.
Through our Lord,
Jesus Christ.
God, whose mercies
cannot be numbered,
accept our prayers
on behalf of the soul
of thy servant departed
and grant him an entrance
into the land
of light and joy.
and the fellowship
of thy saints,
through Jesus Christ,
our Lord,
Most merciful Father
who has been pleased
to take unto thyself
the soul of this thy servant,
grant to us, who are
still in our pilgrimage
and who walk as
yet by faith.,.
Charlie.
in glory everlasting,...
through Jesus Christ,
our Lord.
Amen.
Charlie?
lf you want to drop
the glove in now?
l can't.
Charlie.
l'm sory. l've got to go.
Don't.
You're late.
l thought we had a deal.
We do.
We do have a deal.
We meet here evey day
at sunset cannons.
promise?
l promise.
Good morning,
Quincy. This is meteorologist
Banner Gwynne.
Now, for all you
sallors out there,
we have green flag wind
conditions this afternoon,
so today is the day to
get out on the water.
You all right, boss man?
Right. So them
geese are back,
and they've done nasty things
to my grass again.
And they've crapped
over every headstone
in the whole place.
That one's the leader, Him.
Hmm, Do the best
you can with the grass.
Yeah, well, the best
l can do is to shoot
the buggers, Charlie.
You want to run
around Seaside with
a rifle, Alistair?
What about
a high-powered crossbow?
You remember
Mr. Cosimono?
We put him in
over Peach Tree Hill
about a month ago?
Yeah, the dead guy,
Yeah.
He's coming up.
Why?
Because the police suspect
his wife may be responsible
for his untimely demise.
You're joking.
l shouldn't laugh.
It's not funny,
Oh! Speaking of
untimely demise,
it's me and Cindy's
anniversary tomorrow night.
We're going to Maddie's.
Want to come?
Yeah, l'Il try.
Will you actually
ty, though?
'Cause last time
you said you'd try,
you didn't really try,
did you, Charlie?
You just ended
up staying here.
And this time,
Cindy has arranged
a little friend to meet you.
Are you even listening?
No, of course you're not.
You got that glitch
in the sprinkler system
fixed, didn't you?
That would be a no.
But it's not my
fault this time!
Don't look at me like that.
It's actually not my fault.
l called the sprinkler guy,
and he said he couldn't
come till next week.
So l was like,
''All right, cool.
Come next week,''
But more important,
all right,
listen to me about this.
Cindy's got this
mate over staying,
and she is a waitress
at the Red Dog lnn.
Charlie? The Red Dog Inn.
You know about the
Red Dog Inn, don't you?
Mmm-hmm.
AIl right. Okay.
So we've been
telling her about you,
and she really wants
to meet you, all right?
Hey!
Who's got the green thumb?
What?
The garden around
my father's grave
needs to be
completely replanted.
And?
And maybe you could do it!
Any flower preferences?
Yeah, living.
l prefer living flowers.
Good, l'll get right on that.
Yeah, that'll be great,
getting flowers.
Sorry. Thank you.
Bye!
Anyway,
so she's a little
bit naughty,
a little bit saucy,
a little bit promiscuous.
Mmm?
The waitress, Charlie!
Please keep up, mate.
Red Dog Inn.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, buddy.
Hey, can you read signs?
No rubbingl
lf l was going
to rub one out,
l wouldn't do it in
a graveyard, St. Cloud.
People are always
tracing these headstones.
Lieutenant Sullivan.
Sir!
At ease.
You haven't changed,
St. Cloud,
How's your mom?
She moved to Portland.
Hey, were you here
when they brought Green in?
Drove over a land mine.
He was a real mess,
Not by the time l saw him.
Everybody looks great after.
l'm glad to hear
there are some perks.
Hey, what's with this stuff
all over the stone?
lt's the geese, man.
There's something
corrosive in their shit.
Don't worry, l'm on it.
Thanks.
l wish l was there
with you guys,
l'm glad you weren't,
Charlie,
Yeah. l'm glad you weren't.
You don't have
to go right away.
Got to face it sometime.
AIl right.
l'Il say hi to
Sammy for you.
He's not there.
l don't get it.
He's totally cute.
Puppies are cute.
He's weird.
He's misunderstood.
He works in a graveyard!
Yeah, wounded.
Hey.
Hi.
You're funny.
$97.50.
So, maybe you want to
take me out on your
boat sometime, Charlie?
Yeah. Yeah, sure.
l love sailing.
Cool.
Well, maybe
l can take you
out sometime, too.
yeah!
Enjoy your toy plane,
Charlie,
lt's not for me.
lt's for the geese.
So, what do you
wear on a sailing date?
l wouldn't put too
much thought into it,
seeing as he
hasn't been sailing
in five years.
So, what's new in Quincy?
Not much.
Man, you got it!
Great, let's go
hit the lake,
No. Not till
after practice.
Back up, back up.
Get out of here.
Please? Can we just go now?
What's our deal, Sam?
We practice evey
day at sunset cannons,
come rain or shine,
come hell or high water.
Yeah, that's the deal.
Let's go. Grounders.
Nice.
What's wrong?
Nothing,
Remember, two hands.
Don't sit back
like that. Charge.
Something bad.
l didn't want to tell you.
Sox lost a home-and-home
to the Yankees.
l'm kidding, dork.
l saw Sully today.
Did he say anything?
About leaving?
You know Sully.
l think he was good with it.
I think he really
missed Green.
l think l'd miss you.
A little bit, Maybe.
But you don't have to.
Because we got
this thing wired,
Yeah.
AIl right, you ready?
Here they come.
lt's about to get bloody.
lncoming!
Whoa! Retreat!
Excuse me.
You all right? l'm sorry.
Oh, my Lord,
Charlie St, Cloud.
Yeah.
I brought you
back from the dead.
Does that ring a bell?
You're the paramedic.
l'm the paramedic.
Florio Ferrente.
It's so good to see you.
You want to grab
a cup of coffee?
Catch up?
l can't, man.
l've got to get back to work.
l'm sory.
You can't have
a cup of coffee?
So, what.,.
What have you been up to
the past five years?
Are you in love?
You married?
No. It hasn't happened yet.
No?
You're sick.
Yeah. l got the big C.
l'm sorry.
Nah, don't be.
l have no regrets.
l lived a full life.
ls that really
a consolation?
That's the only one
there is, Charlie.
Plus, l got to
witness a miracle.
How many people can
say that to Saint Peter
when they reach
the pearly gates? Huh?
You were a
complete flatline.
Nothing.
And then.,.
You must think about why.
Why what?
Why you?
Why did you get
a second chance?
God just doesn't show off.
There's got to be a reason
God gave you a second chance.
Well, if there is one,
l haven't figured it out yet.
Yeah, well.,.
l don't think it's
gonna come to you
working in a graveyard.
You're a young man.
You should be
out in the world
living your life,
Don't squander this gift
you've been given.
One of Quincy's own,
she will seek to become
the youngest skipper ever
to compete in the grueling
VELUX 5 Oceans
race around the world.
Eveybody's excited,
This is a first for the town.
So, one of you
tie the main down.
And l need
the cockpit tidied up.
She was fully at whole speed
going downwind,
handled super light,
No, whether l win
this race or not,
let's hope that l do,
right, Tink?
l mean, Coach?
No, but whether
l win it or not,
it will not be because
l didn't have a great boat.
Thank you so much, guys.
That girl is gonna
sail around the world?
Yeah.
Is that the girl?
She's hotI
She's all right.
''All right''?
Is there a swimsuit shot
anywhere in there?
What are you gonna do
with a swimsuit shot?
Everything.
Come on.
you want it?
Give me the magazine.
Sam, you're gonna wreck it.
l'm totally gonna wreck it.
l'm gonna wreck it repeatedly,
Charlie.
''Tess Carroll,''
Well done, Charlie. Mature.
You only left me
with the cover page.
Charlie!
l cannot believe
that you're here!
Hello!
Hi.
lt's our anniversary!
Yeah.
No, not our anniversary,
because we're not going out,
but me and Cindy's.
l wouldn't miss
your anniversary, man.
l know you wouldn't
and it means a lot.
What's that?
Nothing.
You all right?
Yeah.
What are you doing?
Doing a bit of drawing?
Very nice, Come on inside.
It's gonna be well fun, mate.
''This man's just got to go!''
declared his enemies
But the ladies begged
"Don't you tey
to do it, please"
No doubt this Rasputin
hed iots of hidden charms
Hey!
Hey, Cindy!
Happy anniversary,
Thanks.
He's really talented.
Oh, l know.
Come meet Rachel.
Right now?
Yeah.
Rachel, this is Charlie,
the one l told you about.
Hi. Hey.
Cindy said you wouldn't show.
Only because we never see you
out at night, Charlie.
Ever since the werewolf bite,
l tend to only come
out during full moons.
The moon isn't full.
Then I guess it's
your lucky night.
Let's hear it for Cindy!
Hey.
How's the weather
looking, Coach?
Look. Low-pressure system
coming down from Alaska,
See how tight those isobars
are on the back
of the depression?
Not good.
That means more wind.
Too much wind.
This test run can wait.
The electronics
aren't even installed yet.
My boat gets shipped
back east in a week.
l need to get
out on the water.
Look, obviously l'Il
stay clear of the storm.
Didn't you used to
be Charlie St. Cloud?
Charlie! My man.
Been a long time, huh?
Come on.
Jagerbombs, now.
Let's go.
Hey, why are you so
interested in that loon?
l'm not.
l ran into him
for the first time
since high school
the other day and.,.
And?
And he flummoxed me.
Listen.
Eveybody in town knows
this St. Cloud kid,
totally certifiable.
When we were growing up,
Charlie was unbeatable
on the water
even got himself
a sailing scholarship
and eveything.
Glory days,
huh, Charlie?
Hey.
No, that's okay, man.
l'm good. Thank you.
Come on, St. Cloud,
don't be a woman.
Have another.
lt's not like there's
a big demand for you
as a designated driver.
So take the drink.
Wait, Charlie!
Come on, take it easy.
l'm fine.
You want a piece of me,
you pathetic townie creep?
Your boy just saved
you from a beating.
No, you're probably right.
l'm sory, man.
How is everything?
How's Goldman Sachs?
I heard the layoffs
have been pretty brutal.
Just a better opportunity
to weed out the weak.
Yeah. But you're
good, right?
You still have full
dental and everything?
Yeah.
Hey!
What are you doing?
l was just looking
at your boat.
l'm sory if l scared you.
You don't scare me.
l'm harmless, l promise.
l'm not...
Really?
You didn't seem so
harmless up at Maddie's.
Yeah, that.
l can explain that.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Connors is a dick.
AIways has been.
You don't
remember me, do you?
Yeah. Yeah, l do.
You do?
l do.
l already replanted
all the flowers
by your father's grave.
No!
High school.
We took an AP class together.
And you don't remember.
Of course l remember you!
You sat at the
front of the class.
Had your hand up
the entire semester.
Busted.
Yeah.
And you won
the Commodores' Cup.
Yeah.
You got a big
sailing scholarship
to Stanford, right?
l deferred.
For a while.
Anyways.,.
l should get going, l guess.
Yeah, it was.,.
lt's good catching up.
Yeah.
Flukes!
Flukes?
Flukes.
Like a whale tail.
Uh-huh.
Can l show you something?
Yeah.
See, there's a.,.
There's newer technology.
You can fabricate
organic lines.
This would completely
change your boat,
There's no drag.
There's virtually
no cavitation,
Yeah. l know.
l wanted to do
something similar.
But everyone told me
structural stability
was more important.
That doesn't apply here.
Why?
Because this eliminates
direct stress on the keel.
That's basic!
Are you serious?
Sorry.
Anyways.,.
ls that my boat?
Yeah.
You drew my boat.
Good luck with the race,
and be careful out there.
Thank you.
How's my girl?
Bored.
Thet's what I like to hear.
Where are you?
I was just
passing Whidbey Island,
heading into Puget Sound.
Okay, good girl,
Keep going southeast.
That storm's rolling in,
Iooking really haiy.
Aye-aye, Captain!
Over.
AIl right,
If you can't make it through
a little low-pressure system,
then you have no right
being in that race,
Come on!
Come on.
This is what
you were made for.
The first leg is
an all-out 8,000-mile sprint
to Cape Town.
Boom shaka-laka.
l would kill that.
You would never catch me.
Slider?
No, I don't feel like
retrieving balls today.
See, rounding Cape Horn
is where it gets tricky,
The southern seas are tough
for even the most
experienced sailors
because of the,..
Blood-sucking Sea-Monkeys.
lcebergs.
Of course, the
icebergs.
You could never
do this race.
Why? Why can't
I do the raçe?
lt's a solo race.
You couldn't take being
alone for six months.
No way.
l could do it.
What? If it wasn't
for me, you could go?
No, Sam, l didn't say that.
l just said l could.
I won't, of course,
but I could.
Don't let me stop you.
Oh!
Getting angry?
Trying to bring
the heat, Sam?
The heat? Tha't not heat.
You want heat?
Bring the heat, Sammy,
Let's go.
So scared.
Come on, Sam,
Falling asleep here.
Oh!
You okay?
Strike.
Did you see that?
There's lightning!
Let the Mud Games begin!
Hey, guys.
How long are we
gonna do this for? Hmm?
This isn't a game.
Get out of here!
God, what the hell
are you doing?
Hi.
l'm sory about the noise.
l apologize.
l just got carried away,
Hey! You did a lovely
job with the flowers,
No, I'm fine.
I just hit some
rough weather last night.
Have you had
that looked at?
What?
No, It's fine. I just
need some sleep. I'm fine.
l could clean it up for you
and see if it needs a stitch.
lt's pretty...
It's kind of gross.
l'm right down the hill.
A little sting now.
Is it fatal?
Definitely.
AIl done.
You don't need stitches.
Not a stitch?
No
It was a drunk driver
wasn't it?
l'm sory. What?
Your brother.
ls that why you
gave up sailing,
Stanford, eveything?
Christ, that was tactless.
l'm sory.
l must be concussed
or something.
No. No.
Maybe we could talk.
Another time.
Yeah. Yeah, l'd like that.
l'd like to talk with
you sometime, Charlie.
Yeah, maybe when l get back.
ln six months.
Come on,
l can do this.
Hey! Hey.
l know how to cook.
Yeah?
I mean, would you please
have dinner with me tonight?
At my place?
Charlie, in a few days
l'm going to get in my boat
and sail away
for six months.
Six months.
So, not really much
of a prospect, am l?
Are you a good cook?
Excellent.
Beer or wine?
Surprise me.
Okay.
AIl right, l will.
Well, you have to
make her pizza,
Okay.
What? pizza's delicious.
l'm not arguing.
l think pizza is delicious.
Good.
Remember me telling you
that l kissed Jenny York?
Yeah.
Well, l lied.
Hey.
Believe me,
you're not missing much.
ls she a Sox fan?
Absolute fanatic.
Really?
l hate baseball.
You're insane.
You don't agree?
Well.,.
lt's so boring!
Agree to disagree.
Come on,
They stand around
for nine innings,
and they don't do.,.
What about golf?
Golf?
Yeah, or shopping?
Football. That's my sport.
Oh, come on.
Oh, please!
No way,
Yes!
You didn't strike me
as one of those chicks
who likes neckless
'roid-heads,
Well, l do.
Come on, hairier
the better.
yeah. More wine?
Yes, please.
Are you moving?
No, that's all Sam's stuff.
I couidn't get rid of
my ded's stuff, either.
This one over
here contains
thousands of vintage
Red Sox baseball cards.
Really?
Yeah.
Why the obsession
with a team from Boston?
According to Sammy,
our dad played
for the Red Sox.
Did he?
No.
He tried out for
the Triple-A team
in Pawtucket.
That was the last
we saw of him.
Can l have that
sketch someday?
lt's yours now.
Thanks.
So, l haven't shown
you my route.
You're limping.
Yeah, l told you,
l got tossed
around pretty good
on my last sail.
So l'm starting in Boston,
and then l'm going
to make my way south
towards Brazil.
And then l'm going to go
through the.,.
Charlie, what are we doing?
l don't know.
No, l.., Charlie.,.
l leave in a week.
l know.
l think l should go.
Can l walk you?
No.
Come on, let me walk you.
No, Charlie.
Timing,
it really is eveything.
l'm sorry.
Tess?
Tess!
Come find me!
l found you.
What are these?
Burn marks.
lt's where the paramedic
shocked me.
They're beautiful.
Hardly.
Hey.
They saved your life.
They're beautiful.
This doesn't
change anything.
l knew you'd find me!
Here we go!
Hike! Hike hard!
lt's choppy.
Whoa, hey!
Thank you.
For what?
For this.
Stand by to come about!
Aye-aye, Captain!
Sorry.
It's been a while.
lt won't happen again.
''trust your heart
if the seas catch fire
''and live by love..,''
''by love though
the stars walk backward''
How did you know that?
l heard you read it.
Were you at my
father's memorial?
Oh, my God.
lt's E.E. Cummings.
lt was my dad's favorite.
l like it a lot.
l don't understand it at all.
lt's about taking chances.
Sailing around the world.
l wish you could
come with me,
lt's a solo race.
So you could be part
of my support team,
l could see you
for a couple days.
l can't.
Why? Come on,
you don't have
any holidays?
l just can't.
You just can't.
Oh, shit.
What?
Nothing.
l left something at work.
What? Well, hold on,
l'll come with you,
No. l won't be long.
l'll meet you at the cottage.
Sam. Sam!
Stop!
Sam, stop!
You're late.
l couldn't.,.
l couldn't help it, Sam.
l knew you'd be late.
l could.., l could
feel you forgetting me.
No, Sam.
lt's like,
without you,
l feel myself
start to disappear.
Be nothing.
There's nothing to
be scared of, Sam.
Do you want me to go?
No.
Then why did you
bring her?
l didn't mean
to spy on you.
Charlie, it's okay.
Sam and l made a deal.
Charlie, you don't
have to explain
anything to me.
No, we made a,..
We made a pact.,.
You don't.
..,that evey day at sunset
l would meet him here.
Charlie.
l can't lose Sam, Tess.
l can't lose Sam.
Let's go.
No.
The more l'm in your world,
the less l can be in his.
Charlie, at some point
we all have to let go.
l can't lose Sam, Tess.
Goodbye, Tess.
Good luck with the race.
You didn't die in
that car crash, Charlie.
Actually, l did.
l can't come to
Cape Town because
evey evening l play catch
with my dead brother
in the graveyard.
But l'll be here
when you get back, Tess.
Because, of course,
l never leave.
You.
Come on.
Let's go for a walk.
Bobbo! Come here!
Hey!
Hello?
Charlie?
l never can tell
if your machine
has picked up.
it's your mom.
I just reaily miss you.
Give me a call sometime,
okay?
I love you.
Bye.
You all right,
boss Man?
You look dirty, mate.
What happened to you?
Please say you
got laid at least.
ls that a no, is it?
Oh, well.
Thanks, babes.
Can l have your attention?
Bobbo!
Julie, can you get Bobbo?
Julie!
Julie?
We've got a boat missing out
of Quincy Harbor.
Whose boat?
lt's the Querencia.
Tess Carroll's boat.
She was out sailing
during the storm
three days ago,
There's been no
contact since.
She was out sailing
during the storm
three days ago.
Three days ago.
Is it fatal?
l just hit some
rough weather last night.
Yeah, I got tossed
around pretty good
on my last sail.
The Coast Guard's
overextended,
so we're asking for volunteers
to join the search.
lt's too late.
Tess?
Why are you the only one
who can see me, Charlie?
I can see you
because I can see Sam.
Sam's dead.
Your boat never
came back, Tess.
You never came back.
No, l.,.
You're in between now.
No, l lied to Tink.
l lied to him. l.,.
I sailed stralght
into the storm.
l remember,.. l remember
l saw the old
Cape Flattery light.
Everyone sees the light.
No, you didn't.,.
l've seen that light, Tess.
Charlie, l'm getting cold.
l'm scared.
l wanted you to find me.
That's why.,.
That's why l came here,
'cause l wanted
you to find me.
You were supposed to find me,
because you're
supposed to help me.
You were supposed to find me.
I cannot be dead.
Please, Charlie, find me.
Tess!
She's dead, that girl.
Tess.
She took a boat
out in that storm.
She...
She never came back.
You still got me.
Yeah, l know, man.
l know.
Mr. St, Cloud?
l'm not on duty.
This is
a personal matter.
l'm Carla Ferrente.
Florio was my husband.
l tried calling
earlier. He..,
He died last night.
Florio wanted you to
have his medallion.
Are you sure?
l'm sure. He said it
was the answer for you.
To what?
''Why you?''
That's it?
That's it.
l've never seen one of
these without a cross.
lt's not Christ,
It's Saint Jude.
Jude is the saint
of all lost causes.
There's no such thing
as a lost cause.
Yeah.
Well, that's what my Florio
used to always say.
God just doesn't show off.
There's got to be a reason
God gave you a second chance.
You're not dead.
I just really
hate geese, mate.
I just hate them.
They're dirty,
they crap everywhere.
Where's Tink?
You fueled up? Let's go.
What are you doing, man?
Hey, hey!
Get your hands off my boat!
In case you haven't heard,
the Coast Guard
called off the search.
Well, then give me your keys.
l'm taking your boat.
The hell you are.
l know
where she is, Tink.
Do you?
l know where she is!
That's it, whack jobI
Go back to your
coffin before l.,.
l know where
Tess is, Tink!
And she's running
out of time!
Charlie! Shut up!
Charlie! Go.
Go back inside.
He's not worth it.
She's running out of time!
Tink, we're going,
all right?
What are you doing?
Sorry about that.
The key's in the ignition,
all right? Go.
Go, go, go, go, go, Quick!
Go, go, go, go! Go!
Stop right now!
I don't think
he's gonna make it.
you son of a bitch!
Oh, he made it.
Stay down,
stay down, stay down.
You frigging nutjob!
Relax, relax.
Calm down, all right?
Calm down!
Where are you two
taking my boat?
Cape Flattery.
That's 20 miles
from Tess' last
known position.
But it's exactly
where she would have been
if she sailed straight
into the storm, Tink!
She's about to
sail around the world.
She would have
wanted to test her boat
in heavy weather,
You didn't even
know her, St. Cloud.
How could you possibly know
what she would have done?
Because it's what
l would have done, Tink.
That's what any
sailor would do.
l'm good. l'm good.
You all right?
l'm gonna let
you up, all right?
Relax.
All right. AIl right,
Charlie. Say you're right.
Say she wanted to
test the boat. Okay?
It doesn't matter
'cause we both know
that no one can survive
for three days in
these cold waters.
Just listen to me, Tink.
She's alive.
She's alive, Tink.
Flattery Light!
What time is it?
Midday.
We've covered eveything
up to Spike Rock,
Let me grab the wheel.
Come on, l got it,
lt's my boat.
l know what to do. Come on.
Come on.
Keep your eyes open.
Get some rest.
lf we start now,
we could make it back
to Quincy by sunset,
What is it you do
in the woods
every night, man?
lf l told you,
you wouldn't.,.
You wouldn't believe me.
l would believe you.
You're my mate.
You know, she might
not even be out there.
What's up, Charlie?
We going back?
Or are we moving on?
l'm going to find Tess.
Charlie?
Forgive me, Sam.
l love you, Charlie.
Sam?
Over there!
Outer rocks! That way!
Just bear right,
all right? Slow down.
We should be
coming up on it.
We're clear on
the starboard side.
AIl right, that first
one's going past us now.
There it is!
Goddamn it, Tess!
It's at 10 o'clock,
about 10 meters off.
l can see it,
l can see the base!
l'm bringing her back.
Bear right, mate!
Bear right!
l got it,
l got it, l got it.
Get as close as you can!
Hey!
Charlie, what are you doing?
Charlie! Charlie,
the water's like ice!
Don't be an idiot, mate!
Please wait for
the Coast Guard!
If we wait,
it'll be too late.
You won't last long enough
to save her, mate, Please!
This is why l was
given a second chance.
No! Wait! Charlie!
We need immediate
medical assistance
for one,..
Two!
He just dove in!
Make it two people!
Tess?
Tess.
Charlie!
I won't!
Come find me.
Sit tight.
Sit tight!
Never steal
another man's gin.
Water.
Yeah, all right.
Welcome back.
How you doing?
How is she?
Yeah, she's good, mate.
Yeah, she's good,
She's recovering.
Doctor said she
had hypothermia.
And when you hugged her,
your body warmth
kept her alive.
Look, well done, mate.
Proper hero.
l heard you were back home.
lsn't this
Bemelman's old boat?
lt's mine now.
They were gonna
strip it for scrap,
so l took it off their hands.
l always loved this boat.
Well, l'm gonna fix her up,
make some modifications.
Oh, yeah? Some flukes?
Yeah.
Some flukes.
You know,
that was the last
conversation l had
before l woke up
in the hospital bed.
Really?
Yep. Well, unless you include
Tink's radio chatter.
Which l don't.
You have a good memory.
Well, there's one thing
l'll never forget.
lt's that you saved my life,
Charlie St. Cloud.
She's a blue-water cruiser.
Where you headed?
Evermhere.
As soon as she's sound,
l'm gonna sail
around the world,
Well, good luck.
Do you want to go
for a spin?
No, not today.
Come on, Tess.
You're gonna have to get back
on the water eventually,
l will. l will.
lt's not the water that
l'm afraid of, Charlie.
lt's you.
Me?
The way you
make me feel.,.
l don't know,
l've been having
these visions,
or maybe dreams,
but they're more
vivid than any dreams
that l've ever had, And.,.
And you're in them.
And we're in them, And.,.
Never mind.
They're not dreams, Tess.
They're memories.
''trust your heart
if the seas catch fire
"and live by love though
the stars walk backward"
How did you know that?
lt's E.E. Cummings,
It was your dad's favorite.
lt's about taking chances.
Just take a chance, Tess.
My legs are still
a little wobbly.
No worries.
l miss you.
l'm okay, Charlie.
l'd give anything
for you to see me,
what l'd have become.
But no one ever gets to see
what could have been.
Sorry l had to
break our deal.
lt was time.
l mean, it's beyond anything
we ever imagined, Charlie.
l hurt as bad as
the day you died.
You hurt because
you're alive,
We'll always be brothers.
promise?
Every day?
Come rain or shine?
Come hell or high water?
l promise.
l'm gonna pretend
l like that,
Watch full movies online at www.awooh.com