Have our lookouts been
given Octavian's insignia ?
A golden eagle.
We've had it in sight since sunrise--
By sunset we'll have
those gold feathers.
Let Octavian know
we are coming !
Let the enemy hear the voice
of Antony's legions !
[ Shouting In Unison ]
[ Shouting, Distant ]
He's on his way.
Signal my Lord Caesar's ship.
Does it fly his insignia ?
My orders are to be followed
exactly as issued.
And may the gods grant that Antony
has not changed his plan of battle.
There he goes,
as he's done a hundred times on land--
straight for the center.
If only it were on land, and we
were there to protect his flanks.
But we're not.
This and all other dispositions are
to be signaled to Admiral Euphranor...
aboard
Queen Cleopatra's barge.
Euphranor ! But surely
he's in command of--
In command of moving toy ships
on a painted ocean...
so that Egypt's queen can more
clearly follow her war upon water...
to which she has committed
Marc Antony and 20,000 Romans.
Just as he said he would.
Lord Antony and his escorts have moved
out by themselves after Octavian.
- He's already broken
through their center.
- They let him through.
The Roman line
will close behind him.
Not if we engage and hold them,
as Antony said.
They won't engage. Agrippa will
pull them back and back, behind Antony,
as Antony
chases Octavian.
What reports
do you have ?
Lord Antony is already through the
center of the Roman line, Your Majesty.
He is now deep within the Roman fleet,
in pursuit of Octavian.
Faster ! Faster !
They've increased their own speed,
my lord. We're too heavy to catch them.
Then we'll slow them down.
Start the ballistas.
Javelin throwers.
Aim high.
Overshoot rather than under.
Ballistas. Javelins.
Ballistas !
Octavian's ships are so much faster
than our Egyptian tubs.
Why doesn't Agrippa keep him away
from Antony's ballistas ?
[ Ramos ]
Ballistas!
My lord !
A direct hit on the enemy.
One bank of oars has been destroyed.
He's coming around
broadside.
We've got him.
Collision course.
We'll ram him,
board and destroy him.
Octavian !
Octavian! Now is
your time to be a Caesar.
- Where is he hiding ?
- My Lord Octavian is not on board.
And now we close the trap.
Now we hit my Lord Antony
with everything we have.
No word of Lord Antony ?
By now he must have Octavian.
You, yourself, said
he rammed Octavian's ship.
It may be Lord Antony rammed a ship
flying Octavian's insignia, huh ?
But if it is Octavian's ship--
If Octavian is on board--
And if Lord Antony
fiinds and kills Octavian,
he is still surrounded
by half the Roman fleet.
- Then send him help.
- I've none to send.
They're pulling
our ships apart now.
They've got Antony alone
and cut off,
closing in on him like a pack of dogs
on a wounded bear.
- Lord Antony's ship ?
- Gone.
- And Octavian's ship ?
- Burning, helpless.
Would you say, Admiral,
that Lord Antony is dead ?
How is the wind for Egypt ?
Fair.
We'll sail at once.
Man the oar-banks.
Hoist anchor.
We sail for Egypt !
My Lord Canidius !
Remember always, that after
the battle of Actium,
with Octavian dead
and Antony dead,
you saw the victor...
sail away
on her golden barge.
She's going.
Cleopatra's going !
- Leaving me !
- My lord.
My lord, our casualties are heavy.
We have little armor left.
Our men need regrouping,
someone to give them courage.
My lord, the dying are calling for you.
The living need your help.
You can't leave them.
Listen to me !
Caesar, news ! Great news !
Cleopatra is leaving the battle.
Antony is following her.
We have won a great victory.
[ Euphranor ]
Weigh oars!
Her Majesty is most anxious
to see you. Will you come below ?
Perhaps if you wish to remain here,
she will come to you.
Shall I
send you food ? Wine ?
Her Majesty's orders.
She's afraid you might...
harm yourself.
Please.
Octavian has crossed
from Syria into Egypt.
He can be here
in a matter of weeks.
There are two full legions
here in Alexandria...
who have remained
loyal to you.
They and their offiicers...
are waiting for you
to command them.
If not to me,
won't you speak
to Rufiio at least...
or to anyone
you choose ?
Antony,just say
what you want done and it will be.
It's been so long since you've
looked at me. Don't turn away,
even like this,
with your eyes
fiilled with hate.
How they burn with hate.
Why, Antony ? Why ?
Because I ran away?
They told me
you were dead!
What... could I do ?
Where could I go...
in a world suddenly without you,
except to my son
and my country,
Caesarion and Egypt ?
I wanted to save them
from Octavian.
You would have
wanted me to go.
commanded me to go.
Tell me
you would have!
[ Sobbing ]
They told me
you were dead.
[ Sobbing Continues ]
They told me you were dead.
You were quite right.
I am dead.
[ Sobbing ]
The armies of my Lord Caius
Julius Caesar are advancing even now,
without opposition,
upon Alexandria.
Caius Julius Caesar ?
So now Octavian has
stolen all of the name.
My Lord Caesar
wishes it to be known...
that he no longer has a quarrel
with Cleopatra of Egypt.
Then let him take his armies
out of here and go home.
He has charged me to say that the choice
of war or peace now rests with Egypt.
And that for himself,
he desires only peace.
And what are his terms for
this unconditional peace ?
A small token.
A demonstration.
A gesture. An indication of Queen
Cleopatra's good will and good faith.
What does Octavian want ?
Marc Antony.
The, uh,
head of Marc Antony ?
Take this to him
as my answer.
Egyptian generosity.
Octavian may have two heads
for the price of one.
Either two... or none.
I've been told
you come here to sleep.
- Not to sleep.
- To pass the night then.
I'm not alone.
The, uh-- The old boy and I
exchange memories of life.
It's like having a roommate,
or should I say... tomb-mate ?
If he were in your place, would I fiind
Caesar here, do you think, hidden away,
wrapped in moonlight
and endless self-pity?
Self-pity again ! You repeat yourself!
Find new reproaches for me.
Until now it has just been
a part of your being drunk.
Singing sad songs
for Antony.
Your time would be better spent, it
seems to me, negotiating with Octavian.
Why did you not give
my head to Agrippa ?
It would be no great loss to me.
Dying the second time
is painless, they say,
and possibly
a great advantage to you,
the basis, perhaps,
of a great new alliance with Rome.
- I do not want a great
new alliance with Rome.
- Then what do you want ?
I have come for Marc Antony.
What is left of his army,
Rufiio, my son and I,
all of Egypt
are waiting for him.
There is little time.
Marc Antony ?
There is no one here
by that name... alive.
Time for what ?
For Marc Antony
to appear in shiny armor,
swords flashing
in both hands ?
Pfft, Agrippa.
Pfft, Octavian.
Stand back ! Rejoice !
Marc Antony will save the day !
Antony, you say ?
He died at Actium,
running away.
He tried to run on the water,
the story goes, but you were
not there to hold his hand.
Rufiio, my legions,
waiting.
For what ?
To ask of me what they carry
in their eyes, in their hearts,
in their sleep at night...
as I have in mine.
Why are you not dead ?
Why do you live ?
How can you live ?
Why do you not lie
in the deepest hole of the sea,
bloodless and bloated and
at peace with honorable death ?
You... begged forgiveness
from me for running away.
You wept and gave your reason. A mother
to her child, a queen to her country.
Where and how can I weep
and beg ? From whom ?
The thousands and thousands
who can no longer hear me ?
Shall I give my reason ?
Shall I say simply...
I loved ?
When I saw you go, I saw
nothing-- felt, heard, thought
nothing except your going.
Not the dying and dead,
not Rome, not Egypt,
not victory or defeat, honor or
disgrace, friend, enemy, future or past,
only that my love was going
and that I must be with her.
That my love,
my master called.
And I followed.
And that only then,
I looked back...
and I saw.
How right you were.
'' Have as your master
anyone, anything...
but never love.''
How wrong--
How wrong I was.
Antony, the love
you followed is here.
To be had
upon payment of an empire.
Without you, Antony,
this is not a world
I want to live in,
much less conquer.
Because for me...
there would be
no love anywhere.
Do you want me to die
with you ? I will.
Or do you want me
to live with you ?
Whatever you choose.
Are we too late, do you think,
if we choose to live ?
Better too late...
than never.
[ Apollodorus ] My lady, there is
disturbing news from the city.
The people are frightened. Some are
beginning to leave their homes.
During the night, hundreds of notices
were secretly posted everywhere.
They were found this morning
stuck up in the marketplace,
even painted on the walls of temples
and other holy places.
Signed by Octavian Caius
Julius Caesar Augustus,
promising the Egyptian people
peace if they surrender to him...
and destruction
if they do not.
I've had all
of the notices removed...
and I've ordered the death penalty for
anyone who spreads the false rumors...
that Lord Antony's men
might desert him.
And what penalty if the rumors
might come true ?
How do you know ?
I know the Romans.
There is only one commander
they will never desert.
His name... is Victory.
But yet,just now, you let
Lord Antony go as if--
If you could have seen him,
how proud he was,
unafraid,
as he used to be.
All of my attendants--
Have they been given their freedom ?
Have they gone ?
Yes. They wanted
once more to tidy up.
Octavian can do
his own housecleaning.
The captain of the guards
and three of his best men
are to report to me at once,
disguised as merchants.
They are to escort
Caesarion out of Egypt,
for the time being.
And you ?
Your Majesty, please reconsider.
There are two of Euphranor's ships,
very fast, in the East Harbor.
And would you roll me
on board in a carpet ?
No.
There are no more Caesars to go to,
at least not for me.
- Then it is still your intention to--
- To remain in Alexandria.
In the last possible place
anyone would look.
Literally,
the last possible place.
- Your Majesty, I have never
questioned your decisions.
- This is not the time to begin.
- Let me stay with you.
- Charmian and Eiras will look after me.
If Lord Antony should--
When Lord Antony returns,
you will be here to tell him
where to fiind me...
waiting for him.
Together, we will then do...
what he thinks best.
Is that clear ?
- Yes, my lady.
- Was there anything more ?
I have always
loved you.
And I have always known.
Rome has never known
such an army.
We should be taking on
the combined powers of Asia.
It seems almost a waste
of time to slaughter what's
left of Antony's army...
- and what's left of Antony.
- There will be no slaughter.
I doubt there will
be even bloodshed.
Has a battle ever been won without
a blow being struck ? I wonder.
At any rate, let me
make it clear once more.
I want Antony alive,
and I want her alive.
She must be taken alive.
Queen Cleopatra's second procession
into Rome will surpass her fiirst.
The ring
your father gave you,
it is yours now...
to keep.
Wear it with pride
and with honor.
I'm afraid.
I know I shouldn't be.
Who told you that ?
All kings and
especially queens are afraid.
They just manage
not to show it,
something ordinary people
cannot do.
Hail... Antony !
- How near is Octavian ?
- Very near. Over that low ridge.
As it grows darker, the glow from
his campfiires will light up the sky.
Our troops must fiind it
attractive to watch.
Inviting, even.
Antony's legions warm themselves
at their own fiires.
Yes. I could feel
the warmth as I rode by.
- How many legions has he ?
- Twenty.
- And we ?
- Two. The 1 2th and one made up from--
Made up from what was left
of the others.
As I remember it, Caesar
held Alexandria with two.
How are they deployed ?
Rufiio.
Cavalry to the left, cavalry
to the right, infantry to the center.
Three elephants deployed
to stamp out a fly.
My lords Octavian and Agrippa have
all the strategic brilliance...
of two vestal virgins.
We can draw back here to softer ground,
too soft for cavalry,
and make our stand
against their infantry.
Stand ? And let them stamp on us ?
No. Let the elephants stand.
We flies will bite
and buzz and tickle.
At the fiirst light
of day...
while Octavian's glow
still lights up the sky,
we will attack.
By sunset both our loyal legions
will have grown larger...
and even more loyal,
I promise you.
Good night.
Rufiio,
tell the guards, please,
- I am to be awakened just before dawn.
- Of course.
And, Rufiio,
if, for whatever reason, the guards
should forget or misjudge the time,
will you, yourself,
wake me ?
The guards will wake you.
- But if they don't ?
- Then I will. Never fear.
I never fear.
Not anymore.
Rufiio !
[ Horse Whinnies ]
Rufiio.
Ha !
Fight !
Fight!
Fight ! Fight !
Why don't you fiight ?
Is there no one who would grant Antony
an honorable way to die ?
Before me,
this was carried by another Roman
killed by Rome.
Another...
Caesar.
No.
We will have him.
We will have them
both together.
Where is she ?
Her Majesty
said to tell you...
she can be found in the last
possible place anyone would look.
Literally,
the last possible place.
[ Sighs ]
She might have waited.
Once more, it seems,
Cleopatra is out of reach...
and I must hurry after.
Throughout life...
and now beyond.
One woman, one love !
Nothing changes,
except life into death.
Will you help me ?
- Help me to die, Apollodorus !
- I want to ! But I can't.
I've always
envied Rufiio his...
long arms.
The ultimate desertion--
I from myself.
Else how could I have missed what
I must have aimed for all my life ?
Will you fiinish me now ?
Where is my sword ?
I beg you to fiinish me.
I lied to you.
I let you think the queen is dead.
But she's alive in her tomb,
waiting for you.
Cleopatra waiting ?
There will be...
just enough time...
if you'll help me.
Perhaps, my lady, if we were
to bind his wounds tightly--
It would only give him pain.
Let him sleep.
Sleep.
Will you come tonight...
so that I can sleep...
the dark sleep ?
They did meet, after all,
the lovers.
They will always meet.
Be lonely for me.
But not for very long,
I promise.
I thought always
I would die...
so well...
as becomes a soldier--
a soldier's death.
I lived always
as I saw fiit.
Unfiittingly.
I would make it up,
I thought, in death.
I expected--
I expected too much
of me in death,
as in life.
Are you holding me ?
Never so closely.
Even closer.
You and I will
prove death...
so much less than love.
You and I, we will--
we'll make of dying...
nothing more than one...
last...
embrace.
A kiss...
to take my breath away.
There has never been...
such a silence.
[ Marching Footsteps ]
Turn him over.
Strange people.
Poisons that smell like perfume.
See if you can fiind more.
Have it analyzed.
Test it on one of the badly wounded.
My lord, they have
found Queen Cleopatra.
She is locked in a building,
that is to say, a tomb.
Hurry.
Oh, Marc Antony is with her, they say.
He's dead.
- What ?
- Lord Antony is dead.
Is that
how one says it ?
As simply as that.
'' Marc Antony is dead.''
'' Lord Antony is dead.''
''The soup is hot.
The soup is cold.''
''Antony is living.
Antony is dead.''
Shake with terror when
such words pass your lips,
for fear they be untrue and
Antony cut out your tongue for the lie.
And if true,
for your
lifetime boast...
that you were honored
to speak his name even in death.
The dying of such a man...
must be shouted,
screamed.
It must echo back
from the corners of the universe.
Antony is dead !
Marc Antony of Rome...
lives no more !
You needn't lower
your head before Caesar.
I never did.
But if he were here,
I'd be happy to.
I am Caesar.
If it pleases you,
Octavian.
- Look at me.
- If it pleases you.
After all this time
and all that has happened,
I suppose you are still
beautiful, in a way.
You flatter me.
My interest is impersonal.
Should you have any intention--
Now you flatter yourself.
The fiighting is over.
Your country, your possessions
and you are mine by right of conquest.
I will permit you to rule Egypt
as a Roman province and return
your possessions.
There is one condition.
You will fiirst accompany me to Rome.
- Behind your chariot ?
- Look at me !
Would the proud citizens of Rome
wait for hours in the hot sun...
to see my dead body
dragged through the Forum ?
I will have you
closely watched.
Octavian,
when I am ready to die,
I will die.
And what if I promised
no harm will come to you,
that you will be returned
safely to Alexandria ?
Look at me !
What more could you ask ?
You have not spoken
of my son.
Your son ?
I'd forgotten him.
Where is he ?
Safe.
If I go with you to Rome,
would you permit
my son to rule Egypt ?
And his sons ?
And theirs ?
I will do
everything I can.
Do I have your word
as a Roman emperor and god ?
Yes.
- When will you require me to go ?
- As soon as possible.
At the moment I am very tired and would
like to rest. If you will leave me now.
Do I have your word...
that you will not
harm yourself in any way ?
I swear it...
on the life of my son.
Must the guards
remain inside ?
I have sworn, after all,
on the life of my son.
- And now I must make ready to go.
- There's little to do.
First I shall want
something to eat.
Something
to sustain me on my way.
- Some fruit perhaps ?
- Bring it to me.
Charmian.
You then, Eiras.
You have never been without us.
You cannot leave us behind.
Perhaps...
there may be enough
for us all.
Bring me a tablet
to write on.
I shall want a message
brought to Octavian.
Words are wasted
on such a man.
I've wasted so many
on so many men.
A few more,
one last request.
Will he grant it,
do you think ?
I may never know.
But in this case,
I think I shall.
I will serve Her Majesty
as always.
It is I who have
always served her.
You will both wait...
to dress me
for my travels.
I will wear--
I want to be
as Antony fiirst saw me.
- The dress of gold.
- He must know at once,
even from a great distance,
that it is I.
This will be
the last thing you do.
Drop this to one
of the guards outside for Octavian.
But be sure to wait.
Now let me see if the fiigs
are as they should be.
[ Sobbing ]
The taste of these,
they say, is sharp...
and swiftly over.
How strangely awake I feel,
as if living had been
just a long dream.
Someone else's dream,
now fiinished at last.
But now...
will begin...
a dream of my own...
which will never end.
Antony.
Antony, wait.
[ Men Laughing ]
From the Egyptian queen, my lord.
A message for Caesar.
Read it, Agrippa.
Whatever she wants will be granted
upon her arrival in Rome.
We will discuss it
as she walks beside my chariot.
What is it ?
'' My one wish, which I
implore you to grant,
is to be buried
at the side of Antony...
and to remain there
until all things end.''
Was this well done
of your lady ?
Extremely well,
as befiitting...
the last
of so many noble...
rulers.
[ Narrator ]
And the Roman asked,
''Was this well done
of your lady?''
And the servant answered,
''Extremely well,
as befiitting
the last of so many noble...
rulers. ''