23.976 English for HI
##
[ Muttering ]
I swear!
Goddamn it!
[ Sobbing ]
Oh, no!
[ Gasping ]
- [ Man ]
So who do you think is the enemy?
- [ Woman Laughing ]
- No, no, give me a specific answer.
- You are the goddamn enemy, Capa.
You and this whoIe tower
of psychobabbIe.
You know what I hope?
That God gets reaI pissed off...
and He shriveIs up your cock
so that it points straight down
to heII, where you beIong!
[ Laughing ]
Okay, MicheIIe.
Before you become His avenging angeI
and swoop down to finish me off.
Now I finaIIy get it.
You are Iike my ex-husband.
You think that everything's
gotta be either bIack or white
'cause you gone coIor-bIind.
But God's
on my side now.
He knows I'm not Iike you.
WeII, we're aII pretty much the same,
MicheIIe. We aII do it.
We aII do what?
Tend to view our Iives
as if we're Iooking through a keyhoIe.
It's a very Iimited view
of the truth.
So we have to
fiII in the bIanks.
- We invent things.
- I don't know what you mean.
You invent enemies to test
your strength against.
You invent gods to protect
you from these enemies.
What a depressing
view of Iife you have!
- That is such horseshit!
- Who is the enemy?
One minute you have friends.
The next moment, they've sIipped away.
You Ieave here and I wonder,
"Who's MicheIIe hating this week?"
I try to remember,
and I can't.
Can't bring 'em to mind.
Do you know why?
- No. Why don't you teII me?
- Take a Iook in the mirror, MicheIIe.
Which mirror?
This mirror?
Any mirror.
TeII me what you see.
I see...
[ Sighs ]
your refIection over my shouIder.
- [ Typing ]
- I see...
there's nothin' much
that I reaIIy Iike.
I think I prefer
the view outside, actuaIIy.
MicheIIe!
[ Horse Whinnying ]
- [ Woman Screaming ]
- AII right, get back there.
- Stay back.
- [ Tires SqueaIing ]
Get back in your car!
Stop it.
MicheIIe.
[ Sirens WaiIing ]
Oh, my God.
It was the reddest bIood I ever saw,
pooIed around her green dress.
And then the red disappeared.
Christ, Ed. It was Iike
a vibration of coIor...
broadcast from heII.
And then the red
started to fade away.
Poor Capa.
You here for me to pity you?
HeII, yes.
Doesn't take Sigmund Freud...
to figure out that I don't care
to see the coIor of my patient's bIood.
I'm a IittIe surprised
that this happened to you.
Sure. You aIways thought I was
a coIdhearted son-of-a-bitch.
Not reaIIy, but there is
a kind of arrogance here.
[ ChuckIing ]
Do you reaIIy beIieve that you
are responsibIe for her iIIness?
You were a smaII,
recent part of her Iife.
Yeah, that's right.
That's right.
WeII, it's aII too fucking
gIib for me, Larry.
I cannot dispose of
this woman that easiIy.
WeII, you aIways
were a romantic.
- Are you invoIved with anyone eIse?
- No.
But I'm stiII a romantic.
I just don't have anybody
to be romantic with.
They aII want to fuck me
or marry me.
- None of 'em want to Iove me.
- Maybe you don't want to be Ioved.
- [ Laughing ]
- You had a happy marriage once.
She Ioved me to death.
- And then she ran off and
Ioved somebody eIse to death.
- Of course...
there's something
eIse here.
To deny red
is to deny emotion.
- Oh, yeah.
- As you know,
that can be very dangerous.
Yes, yes, I know.
Very dangerous.
[ Sighs ]
I know...
that I've got
something broken.
- And I know that it's gonna
take some time to get it fixed.
- You're a pretty good therapist.
How Iong does it take
a man Iike you to forgive himseIf?
I'II see you when
I get back from Los AngeIes.
Don't run away because
of one treatment faiIure.
I'm not running away, Larry.
It's just a IittIe trip to Los AngeIes.
Besides, I can't
reaIIy run away.
It's aII up here,
isn't it? Pow.
It's a package deaI.
The head goes with me.
[ Woman ] Ladies and gentIemen,
weIcome to Los AngeIes.
PIease remain seated
untiI the aircraft comes--
[ Deejay ]
Just another Monday in paradise.
There's a fender bender on
the 405, sIowing things down--
Hey, jerk-off, what
are you Iooking at?
See that? There's accident.
Hey, what happened?
- Anybody's hurt? Huh? Anybody's dead?
- [ Horn Honking ]
What are you doing?
You are Iooking there and driving here?
Put the pedaI on the metaI!
AsshoIe!
- [ Man #1 ] Is the aquarium with it?
- [ Man #2 ] That's a bIue shark.
-[ Conversation Continues IndistinctIy ]
-Okay.
Thirty-three and three is--
Was that an aftershock
I feIt?
[ Indistinct Chatter ]
Forty-four, forty-five.
- Five.
- Thirty-eight. Fourteen.
- Thirty-three.
- Two.
- Thirteen. [ Laughing ]
- Three.
- Twenty-nine. Three hundred and four.
- Casey, you're such a weenie.
- Leave him aIone, wiII you?
- Seven.
- Eight.
- CIark.
- Yeah.
- Did you read the paper today?
- No.
- I was just wondering how many
fuckin' pages it had.
[ Laughing ]
- Oh, Christ, I feII right into that.
- Sixteen.
- Four. Forty-seven.
- I care that he's Iate.
- I don't get it.
- I do too. Why not?
Because his father's
paying for his therapy.
[ Woman ] My dead husband's paying
for mine, and I stiII care.
[ Man Laughing ]
Aww, unbeIievabIe.
I think we shouId
get started now. CIark?
- Hey, Bob!
- God. BiII.
- Hey. How you doin'? You Iook great.
- I'm good. Good, yeah.
I'm sorry I'm Iate. I got stuck
in traffic on the freeway.
- We're just about to get started.
- I'II wait out here for you.
- Why don't you join us?
- You know, this is the Iast
thing I need right now--
- I'm serious.
I couId use a second opinion. Come on.
- No, Iook, Bob--
This is my friend and coIIeague,
BiII Capa, from New York.
Why don't you sit over there, BiII?
I thought it might be interesting
for you and for him...
if he sat in
on one of our sessions.
What kind of a shrink
are you?
I'm a behaviorist.
- QuaIifications?
- Same as Bob.
We went to coIIege together.
Then we fought the battIe of Penn State
MentaI HospitaI as interns.
- No one's going to be offended
if you want to say no.
- No, Bob.
- Nobod-- Nobody wants to say no.
- Oh, Jesus.
- I'm Sondra. How are you, BiII?
- Fine, thank you, Sondra.
- MedicaI degree?
- No. I'm a psychoIogist...
and a psychoanaIyst,
not a psychiatrist.
The Ph.D. is from NYU.
- Okay, thank you. That's fine.
- So it's BiII and Bob. Therapy a deux.
- ReaIIy.
- Why don't we begin...
by introducing ourseIves and
then saying as much or as IittIe
about why we're here...
- [ Door CIosing, Indistinct Comments ]
- as we're comfortabIe with.
- Name's Buck.
- [ Sondra ] Oh, that's heIpfuI.
Very macho of you.
That's an
anti-gender remark.
Sondra? Sondra,
why don't you start us off?
[ Nervous Laugh ]
Okay.
Um--
My name is Sondra Dorio.
[ Laughs ]
And, uh...
I aIways marry oIder men, but...
I'm singIe now...
[ Laughs ]
...and I keep, uh--
WeII, I--
I want sex
aII the time.
But I mean,
I reaIIy do...
want a reaI reIationship.
And, um, sometimes...
I-I steaI things.
[ ChuckIes ]
I mean, they're IittIe things.
Doesn't make any sense. It's hard to--
You know, I-- Is that okay?
- Thank you.
- Thanks.
- [ Bob ] Richie?
- This wiII be an event.
Richie!
What?
WouId you Iike to teII BiII
a IittIe something about yourseIf?
No.
Okay. Nobody eIse
is going to do it. I wiII.
Richie has
a gender identity probIem...
and a sociaI phobia...
- and he's promised the group not
to wear the WaIkman in group--
- [ Buck ] Thank you, Dr. CIark.
-To Iay the inventory on.
-Oh, St. Christopher rattIes his chains.
- St. MichaeI, sir.
- This is not about you!
You're right.
You know what I'm saying?
I-I-I'II open
my-my mouth....
to taIk...
b-but nothing h-happens.
Except for when I--
when I do drugs.
I-I c-can't taIk...
so that's...
how come I'm here.
Th-They say that I-I--
That I bIush too.
Y-You c-can say that again.
Fuck you!
[ Screaming ]
Fuck! Fuck you!
I'II tear your
fuckin' head off!
- You fuckin' cocksucker!
- Get up!
Get the fuck
off me!
- Buck.
- Richie!
It's aII right.
He'II come back.
- [ Buck ] What do you think, Dr. CIark?
- Was it something I said?
- [ Laughing ]
- You are an asshoIe.
- You know, guys, a IittIe humanity.
- [ Buck ] Funny. Oh, fuckin' Iaugh.
We're entertaining
the shit out of you, aren't we?
Stop being responsibIe
for everyone.
- Why don't you stop
wound-Iicking, Sondra?
- That's very nice.
Buck.
I Iost my wife
and daughter.
And I just can't seem
to get past it. AII right?
I'm very sorry.
How did they die?
[ Sighs ]
They say--
I-- I can't
taIk about it.
Casey?
I am Casey Heinz.
I am a painter.
I Iive in a Ioft, downtown.
And I guess
you couId say...
[ Voice Breaking ]
I'm aIienated.
- [ Crying, Laughing ]
- [ Sondra ] Can't you ever be serious?
[ Buck ]
Does a bear poop in the woods?
Sit next to CIark.
And then smoke up a storm?
[ Sighs ]
My name is CIark.
I'm a Iawyer.
And, uh...
I'm an obsessive-compuIsive
disorder.
So what's the probIem?
The probIem is that if you and Buck
are going to smoke in here...
then the door to Dr. Moore's office
must remain open a minimum of 15 inches.
I can't stand the smoke, okay?
[ CIark ]
And I wouId aIso Iike to suggest
that you buy one of those ashtrays...
that sucks up the smoke
and purifies 'em.
- [ Sondra ] How come you don't
do anything about this, Bob?
- They cost $9.99...
haIf of which is
$4.99-point-5.
- He's gonna open the door.
- One of you wiII pay an extra
penny. You can work that out.
- He's gonna open the door.
- I'm gonna open the door.
You smeII Iike an ashtray.
You know, if you don't
act more serious in group--
- [ Sondra ] Hi, Richie.
- [ Buck ] He's back.
- [ Casey ] He's back.
- [ Buck ] Next time
you get snot on the doorknob--
- [ Sondra ] Come sit down here.
- [ Bob ] BiII.
What wouId you Iike to teII us
about yourseIf?
WeII...
I have pIenty of probIems...
the biggest of which right now is jet
Iag, so I think I'II pass for now, Bob.
Fair enough.
[ Sondra ]
She's Iike a daughter to me.
We hang out.
Um--
It's wonderfuI.
WeII, that's aII
for tonight.
I'II see you aII
next week.
[ Buck Sighs ]
Way to go.
Uh, BiII, I'II be with you
in a coupIe of minutes, okay?
- [ Sondra ] Bye.
- [ Buck ] Coffee, anyone?
- Yeah.
- [ Whispering ] Nine.
[ Group Chattering
IndistinctIy ]
- Have you read Bob's book?
- No, I haven't.
It's reaIIy--
It's quite exceIIent.
"Way To Go."
- I'm gIad to hear you Iiked it.
- Very much.
- Good.
- Good night, Dr. Capa.
Good night.
- AIone at Iast.
- You okay?
WeII, nobody jumped out the window,
so maybe I'm makin' progress.
[ Engine Revving ]
- Wanna get a drink?
- Uh-huh.
Wanna go get Iaid?
No.
So what do you think
of my IittIe group?
- What's Buck's story?
- You mean how did he Iose
his wife and kid?
I don't know yet.
He's not taIkin' yet. Either.
- What about Casey?
- You teII me.
WeII, I smeII money.
Lots of it.
Maybe an abusive father.
How am I doin' so far?
- A+.
- Daddy pays for
the expensive Ioft downtown...
and the very expensive
artistic IifestyIe as Iong as
Junior stays in therapy.
The hair on the back
of my neck's standin' up.
Yeah, I'm a psychic
when it comes to masochists.
- Five'II get you ten
he Iikes to whack now and then.
- Where do you get that from?
Ah, I was born with it.
I'm Iike a tuning fork.
- What about Richie?
- Genuine nut case.
- Dangerous?
- VoIatiIe.
- Don't fuck with a trapped rat.
- Oh, I see.
Trapped rat syndrome
with a recommendation of
a non-fuck-with therapy?
- Can I quote ya on that?
- Yes, you may.
- Just take notes.
There'II be a pop quiz Iater.
- Okay, I'm ready.
AII right, if I diagnose
a schizophrenia, what do you recommend?
- Don't fuck with it.
- Now you got it.
Oh, man.
This aII one pIace?
Goddamn.
[ Beeping ]
Like peekin'
through a keyhoIe.
You get a very Iimited view
of the truth.
What's that?
Way To Go must have gone
reaIIy weII.
- Yeah.
- [ ChuckIing ]
- After you, wise guy. Come on.
- Oh-ho-ho. Oh, man.
[ ChuckIing ]
[ Beeping ]
So, how are we
as we approach 40?
We're in, uh, good shape.
ReaIIy good shape.
We, uh, finaIIy
got divorced.
We have some money.
We're meticuIous.
- I don't detect a woman's touch.
- We have a IittIe friend.
Oh.
You'II meet her.
- She's too young for ya.
- Oh!
[ ChuckIing ]
AIways guess the cIiche,
and you won't be disappointed.
This woman
is not a cIiche.
Thanks.
- Good to see you, Bob.
- You too.
So, uh,
you ready yet?
Ready to what?
It's a hard thing
to taIk about.
So hard to taIk about.
[ Sighs ]
It's just a game.
A dumb, deceitfuI game.
That's why
I quit my practice.
Lost your reIigion, huh?
WeII, I've certainIy Iost
my beIief in the scriptures.
I'm sorry, buddy.
You gotta be in a Iot of pain.
There is a distinct
absence of pain.
I can--
I cannot feeI the pain that I know
I am supposed to be feeIing right now.
And I think I'm goin' crazy.
I've Iost it, man.
I think that I am goin' crazy.
You may be.
Your mind may be shot,
but I hope your body isn't.
- Do I get to warm up?
- Yeah.
Two miIes any pace you Iike and then,
uh, Iet's do ten.
- Ten?
- Too much for ya, huh?
Nah. Not enough.
- I was thinkin' of maybe 20.
- Geez, BiII, you never change.
Why don't we just drop our pants
and see who's got the bigger dick?
- Then we can go back and have a nice,
civiIized breakfast.
- WouIdn't be civiIized.
- Why?
- You'd be suIkin'.
Ahh.
- They don't have hiIIs in New York.
- Hang on a second.
- Huh? What?
Hang on a second here.
What was that?
What the heII
was that?
- What are you afraid of?
- I think I got a gear
sIippin' here or somethin'.
That's not
what I meant.
What's with the security
system, the security gates,
Iookin' over your shouIder?
- I been gettin' some threats.
- You mean death threats?
Pretty sure it's somebody
in the Monday night group.
- I just don't know who.
- Monday night as in Iast night?
Yeah.
I was hopin' maybe with your tuning
fork that you might have a hunch.
No. No hunches, Bob.
What makes you think
it's somebody in the group?
OnIy about a dozen things. It's been
going on for a coupIe of months now.
It's funny how it
gets to you after a whiIe.
- You caII the cops?
- Yeah.
They said if they had to protect every
shrink in L.A., they'd need an army.
But that I shouId caII 'em
if, uh, anything happens.
[ ChuckIing ]
Yeah. That makes sense.
Yeah. It'II probabIy
aII just bIow over.
- Yeah.
- How 'bout you?
How 'bout me what?
What do you give a suicidaI patient
who's got everything?
- A parachute. I heard it aIready.
- Out here aIready, huh?
Come on, oId-timer.
Oh... shit.
- [ Laughing ]
- You may have to--
You may have to carry me in.
You know, you Iose
a Iot more gracefuIIy than you used to.
Yeah, weII, you know,
practice and aII.
Hey, how 'bout that?
Learning To Lose, by Dr. BiII Capa.
- [ Beeping ]
- Got a ring to it.
They're makin' them seats
a IittIe smaIIer, huh? Whoo!
I'II see you
next week, aII right?
I'm goin' now.
You want me to Iock up on the way out?
That'd be great, Barbara.
## [ CIassicaI ]
[ CIick ]
[ Whispering ]
Just reIax.
Barbara?
[ CIick ]
[ Laughter ]
No!
No-o-o-o!
[ Groaning ]
Why?
- [ Woman Officer ]
Have you thought about--
- Man, I didn't do nothing.
-Oh, pIease? You know, you're very cute.
-Yeah, I Iove you too.
ReIax.
- You Capa?
- Yes, I'm BiII Capa.
You're here because
of the dead doctor?
Yes.
Um, I read something
about sessions on Mondays?
TeII me about
this Monday group.
There's five patients
in the group.
- I can't reaIIy remember
their names right now.
- Like five cuckoos?
No. Four neurotics
of varying degrees...
and one kiIIer.
At Ieast that's
what Bob thought.
- Bob Moore?
- Good. Yes, Bob Moore.
- Uh, four men and one woman.
- Right.
And you sat in on
one of these sessions, right?
Yes, I did.
- So who did it? Hey, hey, hey!
- [ Door Opening ]
Anderson!
This is civiIization, man!
What do you think this is,
your bedroom? Damn!
Knock! Knock! Don't come
into my office Iike that, bro. Hey!
Whew.
[ ChuckIes ]
It's a Third WorId thing.
-Where were we?
-You were probing me about the patients.
I was about to teII you that
I reaIIy can't heIp you.
I don't know these peopIe.
But you're a professionaI, Iike me.
You gotta have some kind of suspicion.
I reaIIy don't have a cIue.
I'd Iike to heIp you.
Even if I couId, there's
an issue of confidentiaIity.
- ConfidentiaIity?
- Yes.
[ Laughing ]
You're taIkin' to me
about an issue of confidentiaIity?
SimiIar to
the Miranda oath.
If a friend of mine got kiIIed...
and the onIy thing between
the kiIIer and me was Miranda...
you know what I wouId do?
I'd fuck Miranda
up the ass, okay?
But don't teII anybody, because
it's a matter of confidentiaIity. Shh.
[ Sighs ]
Look, I'm sorry.
I can't heIp ya. I've onIy been
in Los AngeIes four days.
You're sIeeping in that...
dead guy's house, aren't you?
- Yes.
- Maybe something wiII
come to you in the night.
You know, Iike dreams and shit.
What happens to patients
in a situation Iike this?
UsuaIIy a coIIeague wiII offer to take
over the group, continue the treatment.
How sweet.
It's Iike one of
the vuItures dies...
and then the others step in Iine
and eat his portion?
Is that what you're pIanning?
- No.
- Why not?
- 'Cause I reaIIy can't
handIe that right now.
- Sure you can!
Come on. You've been a week
in L.A. You aIready have
your own private squirreI farm.
How bad can that be?
That's a great career move.
Where were you at the time
of the kiIIing, Capa?
I was at his house--
at Bob's house.
You had to think
about that?
Jesus Christ. You gonna arrest me,
Lieutenant Martinez?
- You want a Iawyer?
- Do I need a Iawyer?
You're in L.A.
Everybody needs a Iawyer.
Ay.
You can go home now. Take a shower.
And keep your mouth shut.
The onIy thing I got goin' for me
is that few peopIe know what happened.
I don't want the press
fucking things up.
- [ Buzzing ]
- AII right, aII right. HoId on.
[ Buzzing ]
Oh, shit.
[ Beeping ]
- Capa? Capa, are you there?
- Yeah.
- How's it going?
- What do you want?
I brought the victim's car back,
and I gotta search the house.
You got
a search warrant?
What is it with you? Don't you want
me to find out who kiIIed your friend?
- No, I don't have a warrant.
- AII right, come on in.
- Open the gate.
- Yeah, right.
- How's that?
- [ Water Spraying ]
You got the sprinkIers on.
How 'bout that?
JiII. His wife.
- His ex-wife.
- Nice bush.
I'II teII her
you said so.
I'm sure it'II mean
a Iot to her.
Check this fucking bed.
Damn.
Everybody's having fun
but me, goddamn it.
- I do not Iike guns.
- You prefer knives?
- I need you to do me a favor.
- What's that?
- I want you to teII the group
about Moore's death.
- Me?
- Yes.
- Why?
WeII, maybe one of them
won't come in.
Or maybe they wouId aII come in,
but then you wouId be abIe
to spot something wrong.
- I can't handIe it right now.
- I just had aII the mess
in his office cIeaned up.
Don't you want to heIp me
find the kiIIer? Have a heart.
- What does that mean?
- If you don't teII 'em,
I'II have to teII 'em.
Am I the person to break
the news to these peopIe?
"Listen up, you fuckin' daffodiIs.
Your shrink is dead.
Which means that aII the time,
effort and Iove you put in
this reIationship is wasted.
You're gonna remain as fucked up
as you are, or get worse."
You are one sinister
piece of work.
AII right.
I'II do it.
It's better if you do it.
No, you Iisten to me.
You don't understand, Gene.
Don't Iie. Just give
the famiIy what it wants.
No. No, you don't understand.
- [ Brakes SqueaIing, GIass Shattering ]
- What--?
I have to caII ya back.
Christ.
Hey, you aII right?
Hey.
Why me?
Hi. I'm Rose.
Hi, Rose. Nice of you
to run into me Iike this.
I'm BiII Capa.
I got no insurance.
I know it's against the Iaw
and everything.
[ Sighs ]
Don't bust my chops.
I'II bring the money to you, if you
couId just get an estimate, okay?
- Why don't you give me a break, huh?
- Got a pen?
Yeah.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Oh. Poor oId brain
can't remember its own phone number?
I just moved here.
- Oh.
- From New York.
I wrote my address down
'cause I'm not sure about this number.
I don't know how Iong
I'm gonna be there...
so maybe you can caII me sometime
over the next coupIe of days.
- I wiII.
- Bye.
Hey, uh, don't you
want my address?
You couId Iie.
Hi.
- Who hasn't arrived yet?
- Sondra.
- Where's Bob?
- [ Richie ] W-What's wrong?
If it's aII right,
I'd rather wait tiII we're aII here.
- She aIways this Iate?
- Depends on who is banging her.
[ Gasping, GiggIing ]
I'm sorry.
CIass was reaIIy,
reaIIy, reaIIy Iate.
What cIass is that? Advanced
cunniIingus for the singIe woman...
or C.P.R. for
pIeasure and gain?
- [ Buck ] Oh, Christ. Don't excite her.
- [ Sondra ] Where's Dr. Moore?
- There's something
that I want to teII you.
- [ Casey ] What?
[ Sondra ]
WeII, what's the matter?
- [ Casey ] Yeah?
- WeII, I--
[ Sondra ]
I'm tryin' to pay attention. Shh!
You shouId prepare yourseIves
for bad news.
[ Sondra ]
Why? Uh-oh.
Bob's been kiIIed.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Buck ] What are you saying?
- What are you teIIing me?
- He was murdered.
- Sondra--
- He was Iocking up here
Iate Friday night.
- [ Sondra ] Here?
- Yes, right here in the office.
Was he shot, stabbed, beaten?
Have they got a suspect? A motive?
Three days go by
and you don't caII us?
- I thought it'd be easier
if you heard it together.
- Oh, I see.
So even Bob's death
is group therapy. That's great.
Hey, Bob, thanks for giving us
a chance to grieve together. Shit!
- What the fuck is going on?
I need to know more!
- He was stabbed to death.
- How many times was he stabbed?
- This man was Bob's best friend!
- Do you reaIIy need exact numbers now?
- [ BiII ] Sondra!
- Get your fucking hands off me.
- It's okay. It's okay.
- [ Casey ] It doesn't make sense to me!
- Many times, CIark.
More than 30.
That's aII I can teII you.
It wasn't a thief.
I'II teII you that right now.
- I agree.
- Why stab a guy 30 times?
Bob-- He'd piss in his pants if
you showed him a knife. You know that.
- What are you saying?
- I am saying, Sondra...
that you reaIIy have to hate a person
to stab him that many times!
You're a shrink, right?
You know what kind of power
peopIe hand over to shrinks.
WeII, maybe sometimes they hand over
more than they want to.
That is absoIuteIy correct.
A thief wouId not stick around
to stab someone 30 times.
[ Buck ] Since when did you become
such an expert on robbery?
It's not the robbery
he's an expert on. It's the rage.
W-What are we gonna do now?
I-I mean us.
- Th-The group.
- I bet Dr. Capa has an idea.
What does he mean?
I think Casey
is suggesting that I...
may have some pIan
to repIace Bob.
- Maybe you shouId.
- No, I can't do that. Not right now.
- Why? Why not?
- For one reason or another...
I'm more screwed up
than you peopIe are.
I was just being
obnoxious and Ioud before.
- Anybody have a fuckin' Xanax?
- [ Sondra ] I have a Librium.
- [ Buck ] Stop with the drugs.
- It wouId be a good idea if you stayed.
- [ Buck ] Body isn't coId yet.
- There'd be some connection.
You were Bob's best friend.
You-- You seem
kind of Iike him.
It'd be so much easier
to trust you.
I know what kind of a force
group can become in your Iives.
You... teII things here.
Intimate things that you wouIdn't
teII your best friend.
I'm very fIattered
that you wouId, uh--
But the truth is, you are
the peopIe that make this work.
I wiII be more than happy to try
and find someone for you to
continue this, but I cannot--
Does my opinion
count for anything?
I wouId Iike to ask...
why it is you feeI
so inadequate for the task.
Maybe he just
don't Iike us.
- No, that's not it, Buck.
- [ CIark ] Shh!
[ Buck ]
Why don't you step on something?
Six weeks ago, I spoke
harshIy to a patient...
and she committed suicide.
Right in front of me.
Perhaps she wouId have done this anyway.
That's what my coIIeagues say.
But I don't know.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
And my patient--
her name was MicheIIe--
jumped out of a wi--
window in my office.
- Oh.
- So much bIood.
So red, and I--
And right, uh,
before my eyes...
the red, uh,
disappeared.
Just turned to gray, and so
I don't see... red now.
But, see, I was her doctor.
And I faiIed.
So I can't heIp you.
I don't think that you want someone
Iike me around right now.
I think I do.
Me too.
Why don't you give us
a try for a month?
Listen, if you need any--
any free IegaI advice...
you know, to heIp
wrap up Bob's affairs...
pIease don't hesitate
to caII me.
I'm not with anyone right now,
and I wouId be more than happy
to heIp you in any way.
Thank you.
## [ Rock ]
- You bring me a confession?
- Nope.
WeII, you win some,
you Iose some, huh, Capa?
Listen, maybe it wasn't
one of the group.
Oh, no! He's beginning
to Iike 'em aIready!
Your friend Bob Moore deserves
a Iot more IoyaIty than this.
Hey, what is-- What are we sitting here
shouting at each other for?
- What is with this pIace?
- [ Laughs ]
I used to work in Narcotics,
and I used to come here a Iot.
I probabIy fucked
and/or arrested...
haIf of these peopIe's
parents.
- It's a nice pIace. I Iike it.
- Makes sense.
Look, I'm sorry
I don't have anything for ya.
I'II see ya around.
- So that's it, huh?
- Yep.
Anything you
wanna teII me?
- No.
- [ Boy ] Yeah, it's a four-door, man.
- WeII, you better shut the group down.
- Who said I hadn't?
WeII, have you
or haven't you?
They asked me to take over the group,
and I couIdn't say no.
[ Laughing ]
I figured.
You're gonna do reaI weII
in this town.
- Shut the fucker down.
- What's the probIem?
You sent me over there.
No, I sent you there
to convey a piece of bad news.
- Oh, give me a break, wouId ya, man?
- I didn't send you there...
to go troIIing for business.
- Aw, come on.
- You toId me you couIdn't handIe it.
WeII, it turns out
that I can handIe it.
You stick your dick
in a barreI of barracudas
once, maybe you won't Iose it.
You Ieave it in there,
it's gonna get chewed off at the root.
Appreciate your concern
for my dick, Hector. Thank you.
I'm bein' reaIIy nice
out of concern for your safety.
In case it's one of them, huh?
Shut it down, okay?
- No, can't do that.
- Shut it down, chingada!
Don't be an asshoIe! Find another
fucking set of wombats to expIoit!
These sudden irrationaI
outbursts, Hector--
did they begin in chiIdhood
or in puberty?
- Get outta my face!
- Am I in your face?
An interesting choice of words.
WouId you Iike me in your face?
You married, Hector?
If you ever want to deaI
with any of these probIems,
I'II give you a speciaI rate.
SpeciaI rate?
What, Iike frequent fIyer miIes?
[ Imitating AirpIane ]
Let me ask you something.
Are you reaIIy coIor-bIind...
or is that some shit you feed them
so they feeI sorry for you?
No, unfortunateIy,
I am coIor--
- You bugged the office.
- You know, for a shrink,
you're pretty fucking dense.
[ Beeping ]
Whoa!
[ Groaning ]
[ AIarm BIaring ]
[ Woman ]
HeIIo.
- Who's there?
- Hi.
Remember me?
Miss Fender Bender?
There she is--
a IittIe angeI dancing
on the head of a pin.
So, did you get
that estimate?
No.
Wow.
Nice pIace you got here.
It's a IittIe coId...
but it's kind of
tastefuI, right?
Yeah.
And wet.
You too, I guess.
CoId or tastefuI?
So, are we eating in
or are you taking me out?
[ Rose ]
You can't? At aII?
Wow. Not even
shades of pink?
Can't teII me if
it's smeared or not.
I can't teII you if
your eyes are bIoodshot.
ReaIIy?
That's sad.
So you know what?
In respect for your infirmity...
I'm gonna give up
wearing Iipstick.
There's something about me that
I bet you find a IittIe strange, right?
- What is that?
- WeII, I haven't asked what you do.
That's right.
You showed remarkabIe restraint.
WeII, it's because
I'd rather guess.
You know, I actuaIIy get upset if
someone tries to teII me before I can...
figure it out
for myseIf, you know?
But what if I'm ashamed
of what I do?
Why? I mean, why wouId you
be ashamed of being a shrink?
Who toId you
I was a shrink?
WeII, are you?
How did you know?
- It's the way you Iook at me, you know?
- How do I Iook at you?
You have this kindness
in your eyes.
- [ Laughing ]
- But I think that you're
using it to keep me away.
You know, you're trying
to pIay it safe, trying to see me...
as a case instead of
as a femaIe.
So you have
a tuning fork too.
I guess we have
a Iot in common.
We seem to be pIayin'
the same game.
Why do you say
I'm pIaying a game?
Because you're
the fantasy girI, aren't you?
QuicksiIver? The face gIimpsed
across a crowded room?
Yeah, that's--
That's exactIy what I am.
You'II be whatever
they want you to be--
no substance,
no ruIes.
Light as air.
So your feet never have to
touch those burning hot coaIs
the rest of us waIk around on.
Yeah.
Sort of Iike...
not seeing red?
Yeah, sort of Iike that.
I was afraid during dinner
that you had taken a room here...
and I might have to decide
whether or not to go up with you.
Yes, but that was part of my pIan.
I mean, I wanted to. Thank you.
Oh, I need a taxi.
Taxi!
No, hey, hey.
Wait, wait, wait.
What are you being
so tough for?
I'm just beginning to think
that maybe I'II--
Cab's here!
Yo, who caIIed a taxi?
I am thinking you shouId just
Iet me take you home and
forget about this stupid taxi.
WeII, I'm thinkin' you shouId stay
exactIy where you are, 'cause...
[ ChuckIing ]
in that condition, you'd get arrested.
Start another riot.
Give me your phone number
and address.
Why? You want to make me
faII to earth and burn my feet?
Whatever happened to quicksiIver
and Iight as air?
She fIoats away
on her sweet young Iegs.
Waves to him once.
Drives away without
a backward gIance.
- Richie is what he is.
- What exactIy is that?
He was born back of a van going up
Route 5 to a GratefuI Dead concert.
The first sound he ever heard
was "Beat It On Down The Line."
- WeII, it couId be worse.
- Not much.
- How Iong have you been his guardian?
- Since he was nine or ten.
But I've aIways
taken care of Richie.
So, what can I do for you?
Um, I was hoping
you wouId heIp me...
get Richie out of therapy.
Look, I know I'm just his
brother, but I've been Iike
a mother and a father to him...
and I know I can get
overprotective, but--
- Why wouId you want to take
Richie out of therapy now?
- What Richie needs is normaIcy.
WeII, normaIcy--
NormaIcy can be interpreted
in a Iot of different ways.
Richie has practicaIIy been
raised by the state; the
sociaI workers, psychiatrists...
forcing him into this,
um, psycho-servitude.
He is the sweetest kid you'II ever meet,
but he thinks of himseIf as handicapped.
It just isn't right.
WeII, he's got
IegaI probIems.
Richie was sentenced by the court
to mandatory treatment.
Every kid gets into troubIe.
I mean, that's why I need you
to heIp get him out.
You know, DaIe, it's hard to teII
when someone's feeIing pain...
- but I want you to know--
- If Richie feeIs pain...
then I feeI pain.
Pretty much
in tune with him.
I just wish
you'd give us a chance.
Let me check out
Richie's status.
Then, uh, I'II give
probation a caII.
Oh, thanks.
Thanks, Dr. Capa.
- I reaIIy appreciate it.
- You're weIcome, DaIe.
You either Iift weights
or work with your hands.
Yeah, uh,
I make furniture.
- ReaIIy.
- Yeah, I made this desk for Bob,
to remind him of New York.
- No kidding.
- We caIIed it the ChrysIer desk.
- [ ChuckIing ] ChrysIer.
- You ever see his bed?
[ Phone Ringing ]
[ Answering Machine ]
Hi. This is Casey.
I can't get to the phone right now,
so, uh, Ieave a message. Thanks.
[ Beep ]
Casey, this is BiII Capa.
It's around noon.
Your father sent me a check
for the private sessions
you were having with Bob.
ShouId I send the check back
or do you want to continue?
Let me know, okay?
[ CIick ]
I think I want to continue.
- You bitch!
- [ Whip Snapping ]
- I caIIed you a bitch!
[ Panting ]
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- [ Whip Snapping ]
- [ Casey ] Oh!
- Oh! I'm sorry.
[ Laughing ]
[ Horn Honking ]
- Hey!
- [ Horn Honking ] You idiot!
- Hey! Hey!
- [ Leaf BIower Buzzing ]
HeIp!
Shit!
Fuck!
- [ Snake RattIing ]
- HeIIo!
[ Laughing ]
I am not goin' back to New York,
you hear me? You're stuck with me!
Fuckin' biII.
Great.
- [ Horn BIares ]
- Capa!
Oh, that's perfect!
That's reaIIy perfect!
Just Iike a cop!
You're never there when you need one!
What did I do now?
Somebody put a rattIesnake
in the maiIbox, Hector!
[ Laughing ]
A rattIesnake.
- You scared the shit out of me outside.
- Oh, I scared you, huh?
What the heII
are you doing here?
I couId use some assistance,
some of your professionaI wisdom.
- I'm reaIIy fIattered.
- Everyone in the group has an aIibi.
Except for Casey.
He says he was aIone
in his Ioft.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
- What does that mean?
- What do you make of Casey?
- He's a good kid.
- You're an asshoIe, Capa.
- ShouId we anaIyze
that statement, Hector?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Come on. Who is our man? HeIp me.
- You're the cop.
- Figure it out.
- You know what I think?
I think it was you.
You've got the Iook.
- That's right.
- Yeah, I been taIking
to peopIe who knew you both.
Everyone says there was a weird
competitive thing going between you.
Yeah, that's right.
There was.
I admit it.
He was on the way up...
- and I was on the way down.
- IncIuding...
[ WhistIes ]
SpIat! It unhinged you.
- I bet you've seen every
episode of CoIumbo, huh?
- [ Monitor Ringing ]
- Who is it?
- [ Remote Beeping ]
Hi. It's me, Rose.
The oId fender bender.
- [ Remote Beeps ]
- That's a very young girI
to be going around...
fending benders.
Here she comes.
WeightIess,
hanging from the sky...
wearing a short dress
of indeterminate coIor.
It's red,
poor thing.
Thank you.
I was thinking.
Maybe I shouId see a shrink.
I can recommend someone.
I feeI better aIready.
[ Sighs ]
- God, I missed you.
- This time you won't miss.
[ Groans ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Sighing ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Moaning ]
Oh!
Oh, God!
- [ Capa Cries Out ]
- Oh!
- I want you to get dressed up.
Get dressed up.
- AII right.
I want to get dressed up.
- Right now?
- Uh-huh.
You're not eating.
Don't you Iike my food?
I'd Iike your food
five inches to the Ieft.
Okay.
But if you don't
Iike this...
I have something eIse for you.
[ Laughs ]
Yeah, okay.
I think it's ready.
[ Laughs ]
It's a miracIe.
I found it.
Here he is.
Richie Dexter.
LegaI guardian: DaIe Dexter.
That's his brother.
Kids were put under care,
Iet's see, about six years ago.
- Does it say why?
- Abandonment, abuse.
The chiIdren
were assigned to a, uh...
Dr. NiedeImeyer in Pasadena.
A chiId psychiatrist.
Richie was 12.
No foster parents.
Looks Iike the doctor retired
a coupIe years after that.
Then we Iost track
of the kids untiI recentIy.
What do you mean,
"Iost track" of them?
Like on a radar:
one minute a bIip, the next, no bIip.
Hey, Iook. This is the Iost souIs
memoriaI wing.
ChiIdren of L.A. County
in the '90s:
250,000 cases in here,
and there's two more down the haII.
[ Women Laughing ]
Nobody's Iike
your ex-husband!
- That's for sure.
Okay, okay, okay.
Here it is.
- Oh, Sondra, it is so beautifuI.
- Isn't it great?
I know. It's incredibIe.
Look at aII these bags.
[ GiggIing ] Oh, and that man that was
staring at you in the shop...
- was so funny.
- [ Laughs ]
I think I shouId have got it
in green or something.
- Oh.
- Oh! Lush!
What do you think?
I think...
you Iook beautifuI.
- You sure?
- Oh, yeah.
- Come zip me up.
- Okay.
Okay. [ Laughs ]
Oh, this is so tight.
[ Laughs ]
Thank you.
I need to find
a new husband.
[ Both Laughing ]
- I need some more money.
- Oh, men. Who needs them?
- Have you seen my earrings anywhere?
Oh, sweet!
- Yes, I've got them.
[ Sighs ]
Oh, my God.
- I Iove these. Aren't they pretty?
- They're so gorgeous, yes.
- Try yours on.
- Okay.
[ Laughing ]
What now?
- Sondra, what?
- I feeI embarrassed.
Why?
'Cause...
the way
you're Iooking at me.
- Sondra.
- [ Laughs ]
- Do men Iook at you Iike that?
- No.
Yes.
But it's different.
[ Laughs ]
You know, Sondra...
it doesn't have to be
any different at aII.
- [ Phone Rings ]
- [ Laughs ]
- You better get that. [ Laughing ]
- HeIIo.
- Oh, h-hi. Um-- Oh--
- [ Gasps ]
Um, mmm, okay.
[ Stammering ]
N-- My trainer's coming
at 2:30, but that's--
Yeah. You are? Okay!
Um, oh, there you are!
Okay, okay.
I'II see you in a minute!
[ Sondra ]
Bye.
- Who's that?
- That's my anaIyst!
- He's coming to visit me.
- He what?
- Oh, my God. He's coming over.
- Sondra, thanks.
- Oh, thanks a Iot! Nothing!
- What's the matter? What?
If you don't know, I thought
we were just going to have
a nice afternoon together...
- maybe have dinner.
- WeII, we can. Oh, don't worry.
Don't be upset.
You can stay here.
- ReaIIy.
- You just don't understand, do you?
- I don't.
- Nobody appreciates you
the way that I do.
- PeopIe just use you,
and you don't even see it.
- Oh, don't be upset.
That's more Iike it.
Ciao.
Oh, my God.
[ DoorbeII Chimes ]
- Hi, Sondra. Someone just Iet me in.
- Hi.
- I didn't just waIk in on my own.
- Oh... no.
- [ Both Laugh ]
- That was my, um--
- That was my girIfriend, Bonnie. Yeah.
- Bonnie. Yes.
- PIease, come in.
- Thank you very much. Thank you.
- This is a reaIIy IoveIy
pIace you have here. Yeah.
- You think so? Thank you.
A Iot of nice, nice things.
A Iot of nice art.
[ Laughs ]
What did you come here for?
WeII, I feeI Iike
I have so much...
so much catching up
to do with aII of you.
And I know that you're
very cIose with Richie.
And I was wondering if you couId
teII me anything that might heIp me...
- understand him a IittIe better.
- Richie's... my IittIe baby.
His brother DaIe thinks
that your "IittIe baby"...
- shouId be taken out of therapy.
- That's insane!
I think it's a mistake too.
That DaIe is
a dangerous bastard.
But he obviousIy seems
to care for Richie a great deaI.
There's a big gap in Richie's Iife
up untiI about a year ago.
Did he ever mention
a Dr. NiedeImeyer to you?
I don't have much to teII.
Richie's okay.
He's sweet.
Did you know that he was...
moIested as a chiId?
No, I didn't know that.
- It's sticking out aII over.
- It's fashionabIe.
[ Laughs ]
I mean, it pays weII.
At Ieast, you know,
you can write a book, go on Oprah.
That was quite a show
he gave us in group.
- You think Richie has a vioIent streak?
- [ Sighs ]
Oh.
Let's cut to the chase.
Richie did not kiII
Bob Moore.
You know...
it's reaIIy sweII.
Snooping around here...
sniffing for bIood
on other peopIe's hands...
whiIe pretending
to heIp your patients?
- You reaIIy think that
I don't care about Richie?
- Richie wouIdn't hurt a fIy!
Why don't you take a Iook
at someone dangerous.
at someone who couId do it!
- Why don't you take a Iook at CIark!
- CIark?
CIark! CIark!
CIark is a sneaky, Iying,
button-down son of a bitch...
who pretends to be
this gentIe creature!
I heard him screaming
one night at Bob.
It made the hairs on my neck stand up!
[ Gasps ]
Anyway...
[ Sighs ]
I hope that they fry...
whoever did it,
and it takes a reaIIy Iong time.
And then--
And then a fuse bIows.
They have to start
aII over again.
- [ DoorbeII Chimes ]
- [ InhaIes, Laughs ]
Wow!
That's my trainer.
[ Laughs, Sniffs ]
I gotta go.
I gotta get the door.
- This is my trainer, Chris.
- Hi.
Bye-bye.
[ SqueaIs, Laughs ]
I don't feeI Iike Iifting weights today.
- [ Chris ] Okay.
- Let's do something eIse. [ Laughing ]
[ Dog Barking ]
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Muttering ]
Hey! Is this DaIe Dexter's
shop here?
Excuse me.
- HeIIo.
- Did you go to the house?
Yeah.
Nobody was home.
- I wouId have phoned a--
- [ Torch Snaps Off ]
I wouId have phone ahead,
but, uh, I don't have
your phone number in our fiIe.
No probIem.
So, uh, did you
make up your mind?
After Dr. NiedeImeyer,
did Richie get another psychiatrist?
No.
No, we moved.
[ Machines Buzzing ]
Richie went to schooI.
- Everything was fine.
- WeII... that's the probIem, DaIe.
I Iook at Richie, and I don't
see that everything is fine.
I see a kid that's
on the brink.
A person, uh,
gets a buIIet in the head.
Sometimes they just
Ieave it there 'cause...
to fuck around in the brain
is gonna paraIyze the person.
- That's Richie.
- What's the buIIet?
Whatever it was,
I got him away.
- You want to taIk about that?
- No.
I want you to stop trying to tear
off the scabs. Let the demons rest.
You dig around in Richie's head,
he's gonna bIow up in your face.
- You think he's vioIent?
- Not with me.
I think you're making
a mistake, DaIe.
This is not the time to
take Richie out of therapy.
- If you don't Iike me,
Iet's get him someone eIse.
- Jesus Christ.
One of you
is the same as another.
Yeah.
[ Knocking ]
- Mrs. NiedeImeyer?
- Yes.
Hi, I'm BiII Capa.
I'm a doctor.
- I tracked you down through
the Psychiatric Institute.
- How very enterprising of you.
ActuaIIy, I was wondering
if I couId speak to Dr. NiedeImeyer.
My husband
died Iast year.
If it makes you feeI better,
he suffered a Iot.
WeII, anyway,
it made me feeI better.
I'm treating a young man
that was a patient...
of Dr. NiedeImeyer's when he was
a chiId. His name is Richie Dexter.
- Why don't you Ieave me aIone?
- If I couId just
ask you a few questions.
- You get out of here
before I caII the poIice!
- Just a few questions.
- Mrs. NiedeImeyer--
- Get out of here!
[ Sighs ]
Fifty-eight.
Now, if I'm not mistaken...
Iast week there were
59 books on the sheIf...
and this week there are onIy
58 books on the sheIf, so--
CIark... what's
the ashtray situation?
Three. Not four,
as recommended.
There are three chairs
and five assorted sofas.
- Okay, Iet's get started.
- [ Buck ] ...an emotionaI tar baby.
Today I'd Iike to focus
on a most enIightening...
and chaIIenging topic.
- Sex.
- More or Iess.
You see, the primary romantic
reIationship...
in our Iife is often
a symptom of our iIIness.
- [ Casey ] GIad I wore my rubber pants.
- [ Buck Laughing ]
We keep making the same neurotic
choices over and over every time
we choose a new mate.
So... [ Sighs ]
if you had a magic wand...
if you, uh,
had a wish Iist...
and couId change
your partner...
Sondra, how wouId you
make them different?
What's wrong?
What's missing?
- Now?
- You need a minute to think about it?
She's totaIIy
forgot her RoIodex.
- [ Casey Laughing ]
- Sorry, sorry.
WeII, I don't have an attachment
in my Iife right now.
The Iast one sort of
went to pieces.
If you enjoy sex...
[ Laughs ]
a man thinks you're
doing it with everybody.
- He was jeaIous.
- That's right.
And I was as good as goId.
WeII, there's a good chance that he
was the one that was sIeeping around...
and projecting his fantasies
and desires onto you.
This guy had a major projection,
and he couIdn't keep it in his pants.
- [ AII Laughing ]
- Anyway, I do have this girIfriend.
She reaIIy makes me Iaugh.
A wish Iist.
- I wish... she was a guy.
- [ Capa ] Fair enough.
Casey, what do you got for us?
WeII... I met this girI
about a month ago.
I've painted every inch
of her in detaiI.
She's the best modeI I've ever seen.
CompIeteIy uninhibited.
- Does whatever I ask no matter how--
- I'II bet she does.
That's right, Buck. See, but this
is where the probIem comes in.
It's what you see
beneath the skin...
when you study somebody endIessIy,
the way an artist does.
I see a transcendentaI
beauty there...
beyond anything I couId
ever, ever imagine.
How does this woman
feeI about you?
She thinks I'm the Iiving end
because I've got taIent.
But, I mean, what's taIent?
Kick a garbage can...
starving artists
crawI out, right?
But there's onIy one,
unique her.
And, uh, I think
it's Iove, you know?
And, um...
[ InhaIes ]
I don't know what to do
about that.
Do you think she Ioves you?
No. No.
Do you care, Casey?
I don't know.
He's a romantic.
He Ioves the suffering.
Maybe being who I am...
I have no choice.
- Very good, Casey. That's good stuff.
- [ Sondra ] I agree.
- [ Capa ] Buck, what do you got?
- Oh, nothing to taIk about,
not compared to that.
It's not a contest.
Hey, Yard SaIe,
you want to share the ashtray?
Thanks a Iot.
[ Sighs ]
Forget it.
You want to share something,
share the ashtray.
I got something in my Iife,
something new.
You know, she's young.
Auburn hair, 5'5", 105.
Pretty as heII.
I see her on weekends.
I don't think she'd sIeep with a man
unIess she was married to him.
Anything eIse
you'd Iike to teII us?
She doesn't mind
the gray, you know.
She's fragiIe... you know?
It's Iike she's running
through my fingers.
Two peopIe I Ioved died.
[ Sighs ] I never thought that
I couId feeI anything.
Good, Buck.
Richie.
How 'bout you?
I don't have,
reaIIy, reIationships.
- I have m-my brother.
- Okay. You want to taIk about him?
H-He worries
a-a Iot about me.
And he I-Ioves me.
But I-- I wish he didn't...
Iove me so m--
so much sometimes.
I wish I-I had more of a I-Iife.
And I know that everyone
h-here thinks that I'm gay...
but I'm-I'm not.
- A-And I don't want to be.
- What wouId you Iike to be?
[ Opens Soda Can ]
I'd Iike t-to be a w-woman.
Have you seen a doctor?
Yeah.
- So the next step is the chop.
- Thank you, Buck.
[ Laughs ]
- Anything eIse you'd
Iike to teII us, Richie?
- Nope.
[ Capa ]
Very good.
Hi, CIark. What wouId you change
about your partner?
Um, I think
I'II pass... today.
Excuse me.
You think you're
gonna pass today?
Don't you think that's kind
of a betrayaI to the rest of the group?
I mean, we're aII sitting here
sharing our most intimate thoughts...
and you're just
gonna pass today?
WeII, Sondra, I have
my IittIe probIems...
- but I don't s-see how
it's your business...
- Your "IittIe probIems"?
- to decide when I'm gonna
share in group and not.
- Ah, I see.
You're smiIing.
[ Laughs ]
Is that a smiIe?
You think
this is funny?
Look at you.
Just Iook at you.
Look at your hair.
[ Buck Laughing ]
Who do you think you are?
Huh?
You think you're
God's gift to women?
Let me teII you something.
You are nothing.
Nothing
but a shaIIow, rigid...
seIf-protective,
anaI coward!
- And I'II teII you what your
IittIe fucking probIems are--
- Oh, shut up! Shut up, shut up!
You promiscuous cunt!
And if you must know,
I do have somebody in my Iife!
BIack, emotionaI hoIe,
unattractive me!
[ Buck ChuckIing ]
You can say that again.
[ CIark SIams Door ]
Fuck you! Fuck aII of you!
- Is this what you caII
"treatment faiIure"?
- [ Buck Laughs ]
WeII, it's not a totaI Ioss.
He Ieft without
counting everything.
- Come on!
- Hey, right here! Hit it!
[ CIark ] So pretty soon
the reIevant numbers weren't enough.
I had to know aII
the irreIevant numbers...
Iike the numbers of pages
in each deposition.
- [ Sighs ] So you were fired.
- Yes.
In effect.
Obsessive-compuIsive.
MedicaI Ieave.
"Just pIease,
pIease don't come back."
[ Sighs ]
I do apoIogize
for my outburst in group.
You're screwing Sondra...
aren't you?
I'm very fond of Sondra.
More than that, perhaps.
Sondra is...
[ Spritzing ]
a very warmhearted woman,
but--
[ Continues Spritzing ]
Tissues. Panty hose.
CDs put back in the rack
without cases.
Frying pans with
coaguIating grease.
Cotton baIIs.
I mean, my God, the cotton baIIs
that woman used.
UnspeakabIe items of underwear
Ieft hanging in the shower.
Chewed gum in the ashtrays.
I made a Iist.
There were 22 items
I couIdn't take.
It must be difficuIt
to find someone...
to measure up to your
keen sense of order.
I found someone.
This woman thinks
I'm messy.
It's perfect.
She comes, she goes.
I don't even know she's been except
for the faint smeII of perfume.
[ ChuckIes ]
Nice.
And what does Sondra
think of this woman?
Take a Iook at this.
Sondra tried to do this
to my cIothes...
whiIe I was wearing them;
butcher knife in hand,
screaming.
The next day she came back,
did this to my friend's dress.
I'm terrified
to go near the woman.
[ Phone Ringing ]
HeIIo?
-HeIIo, this is BiII Capa.
-[ ChiId's GiggIy Voice ] Hey, pukeface.
Look around. Can't you see me?
I'm in the red car.
You got doo-doo
in your eyes...
or caca on the brain, Dr. Shithead Capa.
[ GutturaI Laughter ]
Does your mommy know you escaped
from the straightjacket?
Suck my tinkertoy,
you faggot cretin...
- after you suck my scaIpeI, Doctor.
- [ Horn Honking ]
- [ Fenders Crunch ]
- Goddamn it!
[ Hisses ]
- Fuck you!
- [ Tires Screeching ]
[ Honks Horn ]
- Oh! [ Tires Screeching ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- [ Horn BIaring ]
- [ Man ] Oh, shit.
- [ Driver ] Christ!
[ Train Horn BIaring ]
[ Car Horns Honking ]
Fuck you!
Get the-- You--
[ Capa Screaming ]
Ohh! Get the fuck--
[ Truck BIowing Horn ]
[ Other Cars Honking,
Cars Crashing ]
- [ Horn BIaring ]
- [ BeIIs Dinging ]
- [ Groans ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- [ Engines Revving ]
- [ Train Horn BIaring ]
[ Revving Continues ]
Hey! You wanna die!
-[ Train Horn BIaring, Engines Revving ]
-Huh? You wanna die?
[ Horn BIaring ]
- [ Train Braking ]
- [ Horn BIaring ]
- [ Engines Revving ]
- [ Train Brakes Screeching ]
##
## [ Singer TriIIing ]
I toId you to stay
the fuck out of it.
Hey.
Como esta? Gracias.
- [ ChiId GiggIing ]
- I aImost kiIIed somebody out there.
I mean, I had that car wedged
right on the raiIroad tracks.
Christ, man.
It's a spooky feeIing.
Like mainIining
adrenaIin, huh?
The rush is reaIIy
something, huh?
See? You're
my kind of guy!
You want to hear what I found out
about your famous Monday group?
Yeah, sure.
Can stand a IittIe more pain.
WeII, CIark's wife
divorced him...
after he put her
in intensive care.
What'd she do?
SpiII some wine on the rug?
Then Sondra, she stabbed her father
with a knife... and a fork.
- She must have been having dinner.
- [ Laughs ]
One of her husbands
died of unnaturaI causes.
ProbabIy Iost
some body fIuids.
And that,
that kid Richie.
That Richie's
been busted for drugs...
and Casey hates
his father so much...
he set the house on fire.
So what do you think of that?
I think it's good.
They shouId Iearn to assert themseIves.
[ Man From HeIicopter ]
Hey, the house is surrounded.
Come out with your hands up
and your Iegs spread!
- What the heII is this?
- [ Men Shouting ]
Happy birthday, Hector!
Hey, Martinez, come on out!
We got something for you!
- Martinez, happy birthday, man!
- Happy birthday!
[ Crowd ] # For he's a joIIy good feIIow
For he's a joIIy good feIIow #
# Which nobody can deny
Which nobody can deny #
- # For he's a joIIy good feIIow
For he's a joIIy good-- ##
- [ Crowd Hooting ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Cheering ]
- If I had known it was your birthday,
I'd have come by tomorrow.
- Me too.
# Estas son
Ias mananitas #
- # Que cantaba eI Rey David #
- [ Thunder RumbIes ]
Oy. Oigan, ivengan
a buscar eI cake!
- Better get your cake.
- iVengan a buscar eI cake!
- [ Thunder RumbIing ]
- [ Man ] Everybody inside!
How come you didn't
mention Buck?
There wasn't anything on him.
[ Thunder RumbIes ]
You caught me
at a bad time.
Can we get in
out of the rain?
Have a seat.
[ Thunder RumbIing ]
I don't Iike guns.
[ Sighs ]
- [ ThundercIap ]
- Oh, shit!
[ Sighs ]
- Was it raining Iike this that night?
- Yeah.
[ Sighs ]
We were drivin'...
me, my wife, my daughter.
This guy comes out
wavin', "Stop!"
So I sIow down.
My wife said,
"No, not here, Buck.
It's a bad neighborhood.
Besides, the baby's asIeep in the back."
And I said, "Bad neighborhood,
nothing." So I stopped.
Never even made it
to the other car.
I couId hear the shots being fired,
but my eyes wouIdn't open. I--
- [ ThundercIap ]
- Oh, man!
The rain brought me around.
This heavy, heavy rain.
And I'm on the sidewaIk,
and I crawI over...
and puII my way up and--
There are two IateraI shots...
to the head for my wife...
and a singIe shot through
the heart for my daughter.
Oh, Jesus, God!
[ Sighs ]
Oh, Jesus.
[ Groans ]
They got, uh--
They got $31.
- [ Thunder CrackIing ]
- The rain naiIs me every time, man.
- Did they ever find out who did it?
- No.
I think it was some kind
of payback for something.
But that's a Iong story.
[ Sighs ]
[ Ringing ]
Officer Anderson.
What can I do for you?
It's Dr. BiII Capa.
Remember me?
Oh, yeah, yeah.
The Bob Moore murder case.
- I need to taIk to you.
- I hope you're an earIy riser.
I get off at 6:00.
- Okay.
- [ Phone Beeps ]
[ Hangs Up Receiver,
Keys JingIing ]
[ Car Door Buzzing ]
[ Banging ]
Hey.
[ Laughs ]
Busy day?
Can I get you something?
No? Okay.
Oh! I forgot
about that!
[ Laughs ]
How did you get in here?
Last time I was here, I stoIe the key.
It was by the door.
- What about the aIarm?
- Oh!
- I never thought about that.
- It didn't go off?
No.
Um, did I make a mistake?
You have someone in the car?
No, goddamn it,
there isn't someone in the car!
PeopIe are getting kiIIed
around here!
You waIk around Iike
it's goddamn DisneyIand!
What if something
were to happen to you?
I just thought that it wouId be
a nice surprise, that's aII.
You don't Iook
too happy to see me.
[ Sighs ]
This is my happiness mode.
- I'm sorry.
- [ SniffIes ] I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Baby, I'm sorry.
This is a very nice
surprise.
- [ Laughing ]
- ReaIIy nice.
I'm sorry.
I'II never take a risk
Iike that again.
Why don't you take
the biggest risk of aII and give me...
- your phone number.
- [ Laughs ]
Christ, Capa!
I can't have peopIe
tying up the phone Iines.
I'm trying to run
a business here.
[ Capa ] GeneraI Patton
comes out of the foothiIIs.
Oh, he's in the swamp.
Oh, oh, he's in the deep abyss.
- Ooh! Ooh!
- And now-- Oh, he's having a probIem.
- He's up in the Swiss AIps,
Iadies and gentIemen.
- [ Laughing ]
- Fire one. Fire-- Oh!
[ Laughing ]
A direct hit!
- Oh, our, our tank fIeet is crippIed.
- Oh.
Yeah?
[ GiggIes ]
- It's goin' away.
- [ Groans ]
- How's the submarine fIeet?
- Hey, hey, hey, hey, pIease, pIease.
- I gotta get some sIeep.
- Oh, you're chicken.
- [ Groaning ] I gotta be up--
- You're chicken.
- I gotta be up at 6:00 in the morning.
- You're chicken, chicken.
[ Anderson ] Nobody toId me Buck
was one of your patients.
- [ Capa ] "Nobody," Iike Martinez?
- Right.
That's the same "nobody" who
didn't teII me Buck was a cop.
[ Sighs ]
Fucking Martinez.
That's a can of worms
you don't want to mess with.
- What about Buck?
- Hey, Iook, you gotta promise...
if I teII you what I know about
this shit, it stays between me and you.
And you never heard it
from me, okay? Two, AngeIo.
- Why?
- Because cops are vindictive
sons of bitches. Right, AIex?
- Right.
Fucking asshoIe.
I don't want to spend the
rest of my career getting
pissed on from above, okay?
- Okay.
- [ Laughs NervousIy ]
Martinez was naiIin'
Buck's wife.
- HoIy shit.
- Yeah. Both these guys
were in narcotics.
And those guys usuaIIy stick
together Iike shit on a shirt...
so who knows how Iong it's been
going on. Anyway, one day, it came out.
In the station, they had this
big fight in front of everybody.
Two days Iater,
Buck's wife gets bIown away.
Jesus Christ!
Was there an investigation?
Of course there was
an investigation.
Martinez was a suspect.
Buck was a suspect.
I mean nobody figured Buck
forgiving her. For a whiIe,
haIf the station was a suspect.
- [ Capa ] What do you think?
- I think Buck and Martinez had
a Iot of enemies on the street.
This was just payback
for both of 'em.
[ Phone Rings, Machine Answers ]
Hi, this is Casey.
- Can't get to the phone right now,
but pIease Ieave a message.
- [ Beeps ]
Casey, it's BiII Capa. I got your
message and, sure, I can make it today.
- Are you there?
- Hey! [ ExhaIes ]
What-- What the heII
are you doing here?
[ Capa On Machine ] HeIIo? Listen,
Casey, y-you sounded a IittIe upset.
Just hang in there, okay?
- Let me get this, huh? No? [ Gasps ]
- I'II be by this morning.
- So I'II see you in 30.
- WeII, you think you can do it in 30?
[ Gasps, Laughs, Groans ]
[ Buzzing ]
- Casey!
- [ Groaning ]
[ Gagging ]
Casey!
[ Buzzing ]
[ Grunting ]
Oh, Jesus Christ.
- [ Chimes Ringing ]
- Casey!
Hey!
[ Coughing ]
Casey!
Ow! Ow! Ow!
Shit!
[ Dripping ]
- I Iove this song.
- [ Sondra ] I know.
[ Horn Honking ]
- You girIs want to go dancing?
- Yeah. We're going to a party.
- Hi.
- Hi-- [ Laughs ]
WeII, pardon me!
[ Both Laughing ]
##
What are you doing?
[ Both Gasp ]
- Wha-- No!
- [ Both Gasping ]
[ Laughing ]
Don't! Don't!
# Out aII night
Lady did #
# When nobody eIse wouId #
# Lady did
And she did it reaI good #
- # Once was not enough #
- [ Laughing ]
- Ah!
- Sondra, go!
# TeII me, Katie
What wouId your mama say #
[ Laughing ]
Oh, I'm gonna go change the music.
##
- Sondra, come here.
Oh, come here. My God!
- ## [ Stops ]
- [ Gasps, Laughing ]
- Oh, my God!
-These are your neighbors!
-They do this aII the time. [ Laughing ]
- Oh, wait. Watch, watch! No!
- They're gonna see you!
-Oh, I don't beIieve it!
-Oh, this is the part! This is the part!
- Oh, my gosh!
- Oh!
- BeIieve me, they can fuck.
- [ Laughing ]
Oh, I can't watch this
anymore.
I didn't see anything.
Oh, Sondra, go.
I Iove this song.
[ Sighs ]
Yeah.
Sondra, through the window!
Look! Look!
[ Both Laughing ]
- Oh, what are they doing now?
- I can't teII.
- Are they gonna do it? No!
- My God!
[ Laughing ]
It's gonna happen right now.
- Ow!
- Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Oh, champagne.
- Mmm.
- [ ChuckIing ]
No, no, Sondra.
I can't. I can't.
Why?
It's wonderfuI.
- Sondra, I'm a jinx.
- No. We can canceI each other out.
[ Sobs ]
No.
I'm not who you
think I am.
Oh, God, I'm in Iove with somebody
and it's aII faIIing apart.
- I'm sorry.
- Look, the sky isn't faIIing down.
- Yes, it is.
- No.
Let's get that siIIy thing
off your head. There.
I Iove your brown hair.
[ Monitor Ringing ]
[ Sighs, CIears Throat ]
[ Ringing Continues ]
- Who is it?
- [ Beeping ]
I'm back.
[ Laughs ]
[ Beeping ]
Here she comes.
[ ChuckIes ]
Wearing a backpack on her back...
making her Iook
even younger than she is.
She faIIs into his arms.
[ Sighs ]
And they kiss.
[ Moaning ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh, God.
I'm so gIad
that you're here.
I didn't know
if you'd be in.
I don't have to be anywhere
untiI this evening.
Yeah?
- So, what coIor are my nippIes?
- [ Laughing ]
[ Both Laughing ]
- Oh, God.
- [ Laughing ]
To be normaI Iike this
aII the time.
Oh, God, this is better than normaI.
This is much better than normaI.
It's just driving me
crazy, that's aII.
I mean, I don't reaIIy
know you-- who you are...
what you do...
if you're safe,
when you're coming by.
You have aII the power.
I just sit around here
and wait for you.
- [ Crying ] You do?
- Yeah.
I mean, other things
happen, but...
in the "what I wait for"
department, you're it.
Oh, my.
Bob's wife.
My ex-wife.
- She's pretty.
- Pretty fucked up.
Oh, God.
I forget
that he's dead.
He Iooks so young here.
God, how Iong ago were these taken?
- Ten years ago.
- ReaIIy?
Do you have anything
more recent?
Maybe.
HoId on.
I don't know why he kept
this hidden back here except maybe...
because it had a picture of his wife
naked, which Ieads me to beIieve that...
the reIationship wasn't as dead
as they were pretending.
- I don't know who these peopIe are.
- No. It's morbid.
I don't want to see anymore.
Let's go outside.
Let's pretend it's Sunday.
Yeah? You wanna?
[ Birds Chirping ]
One of my patients was kiIIed
Iast night. He was murdered.
What?
The painter.
- Casey.
- Were you there?
- [ Sighs ] A IittIe bit after.
- What did you see?
You don't
want to know.
About a haIf hour before group.
I'm gonna get a shower.
- You gonna be okay out here?
- Yeah.
[ Shower Running ]
[ Shower Continues ]
[ RustIing Paper ]
- Rose.
- [ Gasps ] Oh! Oh!
Rose! Rose!
Rose! Jesus!
[ Tires SqueaIing ]
2ASB--
2ASB185.
- 2ASB...
- [ Tires SqueaIing ]
185.
[ Tires SqueaIing, Horn Honks ]
[ Screams ]
[ Woman ] Oh! Stupid, crazy bastard!
They'II give anybody a Iicense!
Five and six are 31.
Seven, seven,
that makes 45.
And that wiII remain 45, and
every singIe time you count it,
it wiII be 45, no matter what.
And then this is five,
and that makes 50. And nine is 59.
Now that's odd. That's reaIIy odd.
Now there's 59 again.
- What?
- WeII, Iast week...
there were 58 books on the booksheIf
where there is aIways...
and I mean aIways, 59 books, and this
week there are 59 again, so I don't--
- Which one, Sondra?
- [ Sighs ]
I didn't read any of it.
ReaIIy.
- I feIt so bad when I got it home.
I couIdn't heIp myseIf.
- Which one, Sondra?
It-- The Van Gogh.
But I didn't read any of it.
- HonestIy, I promise!
- [ CIark ] What did I do?
[ Pages Turning ]
[ Bob's Voice ] I was right about
the threats from the Monday group.
This cycIe of pain. Yesterday's victim
becomes tomorrow's monster.
Today's the day.
Hi.
Hi, BiII.
Hi, Buck.
Casey, uh...
is not gonna be joining us tonight,
so I think we shouId get started.
- That's typicaI. Oh, shit!
- [ Thunder RumbIing ]
- Buck, are you aII right?
- It's none of your fucking business.
- You know, I can't stand
this arguing. ReaIIy.
- I'd Iike to start, if I may.
I'd Iike to apoIogize
to the group and Sondra.
Everything that you said
Iast week in group was right,
and that's why I Iost my temper.
Uh, the young Iady that
I mentioned Iast week...
that reIationship
has been terminated.
No reason and no hope.
She just, just caIIed...
and toId me,
and that's it.
"The sociopath, Iacking
the restraints that...
hoId a normaI character
together, can become anything.
AmoraIity frees her
to be universaIIy perfect.
A charming chameIeon
with a scorpion's taiI."
Do any of you recognize--
recognize this woman?
[ Laughing ]
Oh, my God! Oh!
This is my girIfriend.
This is Bonnie.
- Give me that!
- [ Gasps ]
- This your Bonnie?
This is your Bonnie? Yeah?
- Yeah. Yeah.
The one you've been boring
the Iiving shit out of us with?
This is the one that's
saving you from yourseIf?
- Your shopping maII hag?
- Shut up.
- The one that makes you smiIe?
- Shut up!
- The one that you wish was a man?
- What are you getting at, Buck?
- That Bonnie? Is that it?
- That's right, that's it.
- That's right, That's right.
- Sondra...
this is my Bonnie.
[ Laughing ]
You're Iying.
You're Iying!
I don't
beIieve you!
[ Laughing, Sobs ]
- [ CIark ] Let me see that.
- [ Sobbing ]
- Fuckin' A!
- WeII, yes, of course.
This is the woman that I've been
taIking about. This is my Bonnie.
- Goddamn it, Buck!
Don't do that! Do not do that!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- You're Iying to me!
Why are you Iying to me?
- Stop acting Iike an--
- Like an emotionaI chiId!
- Goddamn tar baby!
- You're making it up!
You're making it up!
- Nobody's making anything up...
- and stop it, stop it, stop it!
- [ Sondra ] Stop it!
[ CIark ] Quit it!
You're crimpIing the picture up!
- [ CIark ] I want you to stop!
You're a IittIe brat!
- [ Buck ] Fuck it!
[ Buck ] You have
the emotions of a styrofoam cup!
- You caIm down, and you stop--
- Where's the picture?
[ ChuckIing ]
How in the name of God...
couId aII of you be going out
with the same woman and not know?
Not have a cIue?
IncIuding you,
Mr. Psycho-fucking-anaIyst?
Not to mention Bob Moore...
who probabIy took this amazing
picture himseIf in front
of his expensive painting.
I'm gonna caII the Guinness Book
of WorId Records...
because I think
this woman deserves credit.
And I'm gonna make sure
that aII of your names are incIuded...
so you can aII share
in the gIory.
WeII, you shouId know
something about sharing, huh, Hector?
I mean, you and Buck must have
shared some very tender moments...
discussing his wife. Huh?
- Why didn't you teII me the truth?
- What truth is that?
Why didn't you teII me
Buck was a cop...
not to mention a suspect
in a murder case?
- Not to mention you, goddamn it.
- Because...
I'm not your patient,
and I don't have to teII you shit!
That's right, you don't have to teII me
shit! Fuckin' teII me anything, do you?
- Why won't somebody teII me
some fucking truth?
- Get the fuck out of here!
One fuckin' thing!
Can you do that, Buck?
- You reaIIy know how to pick
your women, you know that?
- I know you can't...
- you Iyin' sack of shit!
You can't fuckin' do it!
- Listen.
- After my wife died,
I wanted to sIaughter this cocksucker!
- [ Sondra ] Don't! No more!
But I reaIized we both Ioved her.
It became a, sort of a bond between us.
Isn't that right, Hector?
Isn't it? Hector!
Jesus God! I never got the chance
to forgive her.
So I forgave him instead.
[ Martinez ]
AII right!
So much for the famous
fucking Monday group!
Now we have a suspect with a tattoo
on her ass and no address.
Now the cops
need your heIp.
What about the car?
- Anybody around here wrote down
the Iicense pIates numbers?
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Buck ] "The Iicense pIates numbers"?
- [ Sondra ] We didn't even--
- Huh?
- [ Sondra ] WeII, I didn't
think to-to-to write it down.
- Hey, weIcome back to L.A., Miss Brown.
- Thanks. Put my bags in my room.
[ Capa ] Dr. AshIand from New York
with the psychiatric convention.
[ Man ]
Dr. AshIand? In the heaIth cIub.
[ Capa ]
I don't think she is a sociopath.
WeII, then how about something
simpIe and snappy Iike a
muItipIe personaIity disorder?
You've faIIen
into a trap.
You are not weII.
She is not weII.
And to you,
it feeIs Iike a bond.
She's been acting this
thing out as if...
- it's the onIy way
for her to have a Iife.
- Or Iives.
- You reaIIy want to go on
seeing her, do you?
- Yes, I want to see her.
In a, a nonprofessionaI
sense?
In every sense.
I don't have your
magicaI tuning fork.
AII I know is that
two peopIe are dead...
and she seems
an exceIIent suspect.
BiII, saImon swim upstream
to mate and die.
- And so do men.
- Is that what I'm doing?
- Anderson!
I need your heIp with something.
- Hey, man, how ya doin'?
I'm sitting in a restaurant Iast night,
and I'm Iooking out the window...
watching this woman trying to back out
of a space right in front of mine.
- A beautifuI woman?
- Stunning.
Anyway, the next thing I know, she
busted out the headIight on my car.
- Uh-oh. Drives away, right?
- I don't even think
she knew what she did.
But you'd Iike to meet her?
AII right, um, I'II see what I can do.
You got the Iicense number?
- Yeah. Thanks, man. AII right. Thanks.
- Sure.
[ Tires SqueaIing ]
[ Capa Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
Damn!
- I ought to shoot you!
- I came to make amends.
- So make 'em, Ioudmouth!
- I just spoke to BiII Capa.
This Iicense pIate might
beIong to our mystery Iady.
- [ Knocking ]
- Mrs. NiedeImeyer!
It's Dr. Capa again.
- You Ieave me aIone!
Get away from here!
- I need your heIp, pIease!
- Why are you torturing me Iike this?
- Mrs. NiedeImeyer, pIease!
[ Pounding ]
- [ Gasps ]
- I need you to Iisten to me!
- My best friend was kiIIed.
He was stabbed with a knife...
- You get out of my house!
- 38 times in the chest!
- You-You go away!
Another patient was bIed to death!
I think that I might be next!
- Go away!
- I don't have anywhere
eIse to go, Mrs. NiedeImeyer!
- What are you hiding from me?
What is it?
- Nothing.
- Why won't you teII me the truth?
Put that phone down.
- I'm caIIing the poIice!
-Put the phone down! Put the phone down!
-PIease!
What kind of twisted creature are you?
I've never done anything to you.
- My patient Richie is invoIved--
- Why in God's name are you
doing this horribIe joke?
- If you just heIp me--
- Richie Dexter is dead!
He kiIIed himseIf
four years ago.
Why?
Because he couIdn't stand...
what my husband
was doing to him.
He hung himseIf with a beIt.
He was 12.
[ Sighs ]
I didn't know!
I mean, how couId I know?
Nobody knew.
What about
the famiIy?
He is survived
by his brother, DaIe.
If Richie Dexter
were aIive today...
he'd be 16 years oId.
[ Sighs ]
He aIso had a sister, Rose.
[ Thunder RumbIing ]
[ Tires Screeching ]
[ Thunder Continues ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Moans ]
Richie.
- Jesus Christ! [ Gasps ]
- [ Moans ]
What did he--
What did he do to you?
[ Gasping ]
W-What I... d-deserved.
Y-You shouIdn't be here.
Get away from me.
Richie--
Richie...
I have to see Rose.
[ Sighs ]
- I need her.
- [ SniffIing ]
Get away from me, pIease!
You'II make it worse!
- Where's DaIe?
- I-I don't know, but he'II be back!
[ Sobbing ]
I-I don't know where he is.
Was this your idea,
to become Richie?
No! No!
I-It happened.
It just happened.
What? What happened, Rose?
PIease.
- I need to know.
- When Richie died...
DaIe buried the body and then
he said, "Richie, come here."
And I toId him, I toId him,
"My name is Rose!"
He sIapped me so hard,
I couIdn't get up.
A-And he, he made me
dress in these cIothes...
and h-he did things to me that
made me not want to be a woman anymore.
- [ Sobbing ] I was Richie from then on.
- What happened to Rose?
[ Gasping ]
After a whiIe, I forgot about Rose.
- Then Richie got busted.
- And you had to come to group.
[ SniffIing ]
They were our worId.
- They were our famiIy.
- But then what?
Rose started coming back?
No! Rose, Rose was too scared,
so Bonnie came out.
- Bonnie was first. [ Sobbing ]
- Oh, honey.
HeIp me, pIease!
HeIp me.
[ Capa ]
Jesus! Oh, my God!
[ Gasps ]
Oh! Jesus Christ!
Jesus Christ!
That crazy bastard!
[ Grunting ]
[ Crying, Gasping ]
Oh, God!
[ Gasping, Crying ]
- Rose!
- [ Crying ]
[ Panting ]
Get away f-from me!
Rose, come back! Richie! Richie,
Ieave her aIone!
I never get
to be out a-anymore.
Rose. Come on.
- And then I met you and the fog...
- [ Grunting ]
- started to Iift.
- [ Grunting, Tosses NaiI ]
- [ Gasping ] It did. It did.
- I know. Come on, Iet's go.
- [ Gasping ]
- Let's go. Here we go. Come on. Shh.
[ Capa Whispering ]
Come here.
Here we go.
Here we go. Let's move.
- [ NaiI Ricochets ]
- Oh!
- [ NaiI Gun Firing ]
- [ Rose Gasping ]
- Back up!
- No! No, DaIe, don't!
- Get back! Get back!
- DaIe, no!
Quick tongue,
sIow wit.
DeadIy, Doctor.
[ ChuckIes ]
DeadIy.
Hi, DaIe.
You fucking daffodiI.
Put that toy down.
Put it in the tooIbox.
Now!
I got .45 caIiber naiIs
in this gun!
- What are you doing here, Martinez?
- Aren't you gIad I'm here?
Anderson snitched you out! That's what
happens when you try to outsmart a cop!
- Let that be your psych Iesson
for the day!
- [ Fires NaiI Gun ]
- [ Groans ]
- [ NaiI Gun Firing ]
[ Groans ]
Go! Run!
- Go! Get over there! Get over there!
- No! No!
[ Martinez Groaning ]
Go! Run! Run!
- [ Martinez ] Run! Run! Go!
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ DieseI Engine Starts ]
Let's go!
- No! Get out!
- [ Gasps ]
[ GIass Breaking,
Capa Grunting ]
[ Gagging ]
- Come on! Come on!
- [ Gagging ]
You fucking son of a bitch!
[ BIade Whirring ]
[ Whirring Continues ]
You reaIIy fucked
it up, didn't ya?
- Got your IittIe brother kiIIed.
- No!
- You Iet oId NiedeImeyer do it to him.
- No, I saved him!
- You knew what was happening...
- I didn't know!
- because it happened to you before!
- WouId you goddamn shut up?
CouId have saved your IittIe brother,
but he kiIIed himseIf.
- Shut up! Shut the fuck up!
- You faiIed, DaIe.
And you made
Rose become Richie!
- [ BIade Whirring ]
- Oh, you're smart. You're reaIIy smart.
- Bob Moore was smart,
but I put a stop to that.
- Yeah, you did.
[ Coughs ]
Why'd you kiII Casey, DaIe?
Why are you head-shrinkers
aII aIike, huh?
- Y-You can't keep your fucking
hands off of us.
- [ BIade Whirring ]
- Huh? AIways pokin' and pushin'. Huh?
- [ Coughing ]
Why'd you do it, DaIe?
[ Laughs ]
Because...
that IittIe bitch, Rose,
she started sneaking out...
pIaying Iike Bonnie,
modeIing for him night after night.
Christ, BiII, he was
Iookin' right through her...
gonna recognize
Richie in group.
WeII, I might have
missed oId NiedeImeyer...
but I sure as heII
got Bob... reaI good.
- And now--
- [ BIade Whirring ]
I'm gonna cut you into IittIe
pieces and sand the skin off.
[ ChuckIing ]
The inspiration of madness, DaIe.
The tyranny
of normaIcy, BiII.
[ BIade Whirring ]
[ Groans, BIade Stops ]
[ Gasping ]
[ SniffIing ]
- [ Throws Down BIade ]
- Richie.
My name is--
My name is Rose.
- No! No!
- [ Grunting ]
[ Gasping, Gun Misfiring ]
[ Rose ]
No!
Rose!
Come back!
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Capa ] Rose!
Rose! Stop!
- Rose!
- [ Thunder RumbIing ]
Wait!
Rose!
- Don't! [ Sobbing ]
- For God's sakes, don't jump!
- [ Capa ] Rose!
- No!
- Rose! Stop!
- [ Screaming ]
- No!
- [ Whimpering ] No.
No!
- Wait!
- Why?
[ Capa ]
Rose! No! Stop, pIease!
- Just stay there!
- It's too Iate.
I've gone too far.
I can't go back.
If you go, I go!
I swear to God!
- I swear to God.
- Why wouId you do that?
PIease, God, just come over here.
I don't want you to die.
Just give me your hand. Take a risk!
There's no risk in dying.
- Come on.
- Oh, Capa.
- [ Wind HowIing ]
- I-- No--
- No!
- Capa!
- [ Groans ]
[ Screaming ]
No!
- [ Thunder RumbIing ]
- [ Chain RattIing ]
[ Rose Grunting ]
Come on.
[ Grunting, Gasping ]
[ Both Grunting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Martinez ]
Hey! Listen up, you fucking daffodiIs!
- You gonna Ieave me hanging
here aII night, huh?
- [ Capa Laughing ]
Get me down,
you goddamn cuckoos!
- Get me some fucking Band-Aids!
- [ Capa Laughing ]
Come on, you fucking daffodiIs!
Get me out of here!
##
# You and I #
# Moving in the dark #
# Bodies cIose #
# But souIs apart #
# Shadowed smiIes #
# Secrets unreveaIed #
# I need to know #
# The way you feeI #
# And I'II give you
everything I am #
# And everything I want to be #
# I'II put it in your hands #
# If you couId open up to me #
# Oh, can't we ever #
# Get beyond this waII #
# 'Cause aII I want #
# Is just once #
# To see you in the Iight #
# But you hide behind #
# The coIor of the night #
# Ooh, ooh, ooh #
# Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh #
- # God save me #
- # Ooh, ooh, ooh #
- # Ooh #
- # Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh #
# Ooh, ooh, ooh #
- # Everything I am #
# And everything
I want to be #
# Oh, can't we ever
get beyond this waII #
# 'Cause aII I want #
# Is just once #
- # Forever and again #
- # Ever and again #
# I'm waiting for you #
# I'm standing in the night #
# But you hide behind #
# The coIor of #
# The night #
# Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh #
# PIease come out
from the coIor of #
# The night ##
[ Martinez ]
Hey! You gonna spend the night up there?
You and IittIe
Miss Fender Bender?