come here
here take this
you too take this
and you too
you will go to heaven mam i swear
what's on the news today?
clerks have a salary raise
long live boy, how much?
depends on your rank.
between 750 and 1000
is there a raise for widows too my son?
this woman does not buy the paper.
she a free rider
it doesn't say so
sure there is dear, for retired,
widow, orphan, everyone!
mashallah you know all the laws sir
3rd rank retired will get 1000 lira!
the landlord will come to
your door tomorrow
i wrote this on the newspaper
this man writes for the newspaper
without a break
is your bread hot, boy?
it is
now, i would put some butter on this bread
it would go so well with 100 gr olive
what the hell man?
don't do it they will see you
they will put us in trouble accidentally
Abdi!!!
What?
Come help me with this
When will this garbage truck come?
No idea
The municipality never works
I wrote a complaint to the newspaper
You write but same shit, never changes
Dont litter for one day
Dont talk too much
I dont have place at home
She's right
The truck never comes to this street
You get money for nothing
When this man spits on the street
set up your watch
7.30
Give me a cigarette
You never buy a pack
your superior is looking out the window
he shouldnt see me sitting here
what a pervert is your superior
look he is checking out chicks
he would even jump on a female fly
throw that cigarette away
dont smoke in front of me
yes sir
did you clean everywhere well
only two street and the park left sir
with allah's help i'll finish in half hour
but
they are complaining
what is it?
the garbage truck isnt coming since last week
i will deliver the news to the center
i'll deal with it
go to the arcade
roger that sir
mom what did you ask for?
half kilo meat and 2 kilo potato
let them know i ask for it
i'll pay later
run!
still standing, run!
like we are rushing with
shit to the tannery
for the superior,
two kilo potato
don't put the bad ones,
he'll knock the hell out of me
dont get me started with your superior
he doesnt pay but asks for the best
goods
we didnt sell anything yet even
i'll go get the meat till you weigh that
fuck off
selamun aleykum
aleykum selam
my superior sends regards
he wants half kilo meat
dont make me shit on your superior
grocer grocer
you bloody man look at here
what do you want
make your motherfucking boss come out
this milk is open.
Şemsi,
who opened this milk?
i dont know sister
who would do that?
lady,
why would i send you opened milk
are you out of your mind?
they also ate the bread
like they want to make me mad
you wont get away with it
why would i do bad to you lady
i will tell the municipality
Mr Şakir
What do you want my lady
Ah Mr Şakir brother
i want to make a complaint about this man
look they opened the milk
someone drank it
they also ate the bread
no really
i didnt drink her milk or anything
shut up
are you calling me a liar?
here, look someone drank this
dont worry my lady
after this moment
the laws will take care of this
i got them sir
take them to my mom
mr grocer
send a new milk to the nice lady
immediately
and a whole bread
sir, i swear
shut up, do not deny
if you dont obey i will shut your
grocery for three days
i will send it okay
go run
i will shut it okay?
you also watch your steps
do not sell bad goods to the citizens
i will burn you all
will law number 342
what does this guy want from us?
are you going to my house?
hmm
talk like a lady
look at my face
my mom is waiting for you for cleaning
so what? i am going
smile a bit
dont touch me
i will marry you
my mom will leave the house
in the afternoon
so what? i dont care
i will come then
you are playing with me
they are sealing the deal
hmm what the hell are you looking at
dont let your superior see you look at his girl
he will eat you alive
this girl is going to kill me
hey Hacer
you didnt come to my house on thursday
the house is full of shit
i took my brother to the hospital
he has measles
come tomorrow at least girl
tomorrow i cant
mr doctor's day
do not chat here be quick
you will do the ironing too
sshht
come here
what?
dude
dont keep looking at her legs so obviously
its not nice
your superior will cut your throat
if he sees you
i am doing my job, dude
this is his house
he told me to clean the street
five times a day
not even a dust on the ground
dude
the superior will marry her
rubbish
he is the superior of the municipality
will he marry this?!
-singing-
i am tired of him
he wont let me be
who?
that street cleaner
is it bad girl?
the fortune knocks your door
you take it for granted
alas
if i had 40 hearts
i wouldnt give him even 1
there are many guys chasing me
who would marry a crazy girl like you
if you keep like this you will stay on the shelf
thank god i wont have to marry this one
singing
if only he had a better voice
he sings like a donkey
Allah
i dropped the bucket on his head
you kept trying till you got yourself wet
i am sorry cleaner
i didnt mean to
no my dear it is okay
if you could send me soap too
i would take a good bath
why are you laughing?
she is flirting with me
i swear it wasnt on purpose
dont think bad about me
you can drop it again lady
let me dry your jacket
thank you lady
do not bother
i will dry it myself
please dont be offended
oh you made it smoke again
there is no sugar in the market
you should drink sweet so it warms you up
he is shaking like a dog
all of a sudden he became a playboy
did that mad girl wet him?
yeah
what is this?
i am asking you
something happened sir
they wet him sir
pardon him
who wet him?
are you playing games at work?
no dear
not important
your servant flirted with me
while i was cleaning your street
she wet me
flirt
you pervert
you seduce people's daugter's at work
look at me, i can make you crawl
sir
this idiot does not know what he is saying
do not take him serious
go away, do not tell me about my old man
dont i know how faithless how corrupt he is
tidy up yourself
yes sir
mind your steps
if i see you around her
i will crash you
yes sir
fuck off
man you dont have a brain
this guy got his eyes on her
she is like his fiancee
what fiance?
he even broke her.
(took her virginity)
no dear
she doesnt look broken
she is sound
would a superior of the municipality
give his heart to a servant?
has my mom left?
she left, she went to gossip
and left me with this much work
shut up woman
dont talk about my mom
think about your fault
what is my fault?
you know it?
get needle and yarn and come here
we'll talk
you and your mother are crashing me
dont talk too much
you with a cleaner i command...
shut up dont talk
bite this
flirting with a street cleaner
aman, you talk too much dont
shut up
dont deny
he told me himself
you poured water on his head
dont talk
"i poured water"
i tripped and the bucket fell on his head
are you crazy or what?
the neighborhood is shaking with the news
everyone heard it
you made a fool out of me
dont talk
stay away a bit
i did a good thing if i flirted with
the street cleaner
ooh, it serves me right
shut up woman, dont make me mad
i will slap you
you cant do anything
am i your wedded wife?
from now on i will flirt every guy i see
i will wave at them
you'll see
if you do it
i will shoot you
you will not marry me
you keep playing with me
my father has been waiting for three days
why didnt you come?
of course there is a plan in my mind
what are you planning?
plan, plan, you get shit
wait
my mom will die
we will have the house to ourselves
i will get a promotion too
so i will wait for a ll that?
i cant
your mom wont die before us
dont worry
girl i will shoot you
are you crazy girl?
"she cant wait"
dont give me hope for nothing
i know what to do now
what will you do?
will you wave at other men
from the window?
come meet my dad in three days
or i marry the first person i meet
girl dont drive me crazy
wait a bit
everything at a time
let me go
let me
why are you putting these here?
put them in the garden
they will steal it
what are you talking about
they belong to the municipality
its not good to leave them in the garden
Abdi?
Yeah
There is a line job
Oh good
We will get some money
If it is a lot we can share the money Ömer
Okay?
Okay
Let's go
Run run run
Tell us what you want
Find a tube for me my dear
Please
The doorman cleared off from here
Very difficult
There is a long line
If you want you find it
(the hand gesture means money)
I'll get your 20 lira
let me get the empty tube
Oh my dear
Please get some for me too
Run get the tube Ömer
I'll get 20 lira lady
I'll give it my dear
What can I do?
I cant cook my food
They are blackmarketing my dears
I wrote this to the newspaper
Write sir, write
Hold this
My son, if you find it, a pocket of sugar too
We'll see
My son, can you get me two breads?
Tomorrow's Sunday we cant find it
Please my son
You write it to the newspaper
they will send you
Hacer!
Girl please come on Monday
ı wont come to this street again
Allah make him fall
Do not come
I am not dying for you
My future is bright
I will be the chief
Would i marry a servant like you?
What is happening to this girl
The superior wont marry her
I believe she is upset
He is afraid of his mother
The woman is a witch
She wont give his son to anybody
She will keep him like pickles in a jar
Come on line up, line up
My friend, when will the tubes come?
In half hour
Make me the third, i'll give you 10 lira
No i cant
They will be offended
Whats wrong with this brother
It's a good deed
The old woman cant cook her food
She is going crazy
Fine
You're not a stranger
Ömer, watch out they are blocking you
leave the line, go get some sugar
Will you buy some for me?
I can but my superior will get angry
Why is he being nosy?
I dont know
He said if he sees me looking at you
he will shit in my mouth
Dog!
Dont be afraid
How many?
Who will eat 10 breads?
Dont distort the line
The lady has been waiting for half hour now
Here
10 breads change everything
The bread is here!
Dont push, dear
dont distort the line
give us 12 breads
give way to the lady
open up
Allah be glad with you
I will never forget this favour
It's no big deal, dear
Alright, bye bye
I would become a skeleton
if we waited in line with you every day
Is the sugar over?
Dont mind it
your future aunt
stop this jibberish it's night time
you dont appreciate good voice
you are a cucumber man
if your voice is good
what did the crazy girl like in me then?
Look boy, you will get yourself in trouble
because of that girl
Check everything before bed
You are not yourself these days
Dont worry
I will make the tea in the morning
Before you come
Good night
You too
I am a handsome man
Allah created me well
Mashallah
That prick didnt come to meet me officially
It' s been 3 days
What happened?
Dont make us kill
Do not speak of the superior again
Do you understand?
Allah make him fall
He said he cant marry me before
his mother dies
Should we kill his mother dad?
Go away you son of a donkey
He is fooling you idiot
Look, if i see him around you
I'll kill that guy
Get up take your sister to work
Keep your eyes on this girl
If the superior disturbs her
Shoot him
Hey street cleaner, look here
Look
There, in front of you
I see orange skins
look look
over there
clean those too
his eyes are like binoculars
sure sure
they eat and litter
dirty, my dear
i will write this to the newspaper too
write it, say hi for me too
you pricks
fuck off, shoo
at least 5 lira
Where does that idiot live?
Over there
He dare get near you
He cant do anything
Dont worry
go to your works
shoepainter
you go boys i'll start work
what is it brother?
there is an idiot superior
in this neighborhood
he is disturbing my sister
look at that corrupt man
he is my superior
so?
Tell your superior we take men's livers
out of his body
My brother stayed 6 months
(in prison)
Now i see who ate those 10 breads
What did you say?
Look at that corrupt man, i say
We will shoot i swear
Give me the other shoe brother
The motherfucker played with my sister
Then he called it quits
Why dog!
If we were back in the hometown
we would kill him
but he is a superior here
Son of a donkey kicks my ass too
Shoot him
Easy to say
Give it
Take it easy
Shoepaint
Come here street cleaner
come
Who were those?
Lady Hacer's brothers
What do they want?
They are not in a good mood
Why?
Hacer!
Girl, Hacer!
Yes, Selma sister
Girl, when they come from school,
take the kids to the park
They wont let you work in peace at home
Sure, sure
Didnt i tell you not to walk around this
street when this girl is here?
You did
Fuck off
clean somewhere else
Yes sir
She will go to the park
The flower of my two eyes
Welcome to the park of our municipality
We find it nice
Do not bother you
We have to play with other people's kids
It's the struggle to make a living
What can you do?
difficult
I am really tired of this
Serving everyone
You are late for getting married
you would have had babies by now
The superior of yours, he played with me
Let that guy go
Is there no men left out there?
I am not dying for that rat face
Long live girl
there are many who are chasing me
of course you're a fancy girl
i will get married immediately
get married girl
i have to get married till
tomorrow evening
no way
he'll see
i'll find a suitable match
will you marry me?
huh?
what happened Murat?
Thank you very much
You're welcome
I'm getting married man
I'm getting married
I'm getting married old lady
Let me take your garbage
I'll clean the whole neighborhood
Litter lady, litter dont worry i will clean
I'm getting married
I wont leave any garbage in this street
I will fuck their mothers
I'm marrying
What's happened to that guy?
He fell in love
Stop girl
I said stop
Get out my way
Everything's over between us
It cant
I'll kill you
Like you can
Send my letters back
I am your man
What a man
there is no man who can't oppose
to his mother
talk good with me
i'll be your husband soon
i wont believe your lies anymore
i made up my mind
I'll marry Abdi
What what what what?
That street cleaner?
Dont you have any dignity?
I'll kill you
Go slow man
Are we dead huh?
You are disrespecting the superior man
Take this
To our sister huh?
Help
If you are men come one at a time
You are binge-eating man
I'll be a groom
I need the strength
Man, what happened to the superior?
Get well soon superior
are you sick?
i catched cold
did you fight or something?
i said i catched cold
if somebody disrespected you...
i catched cold!!!
you corrupt man!
prick
you got your eyes on my fiancee
you dishonest man
the black sheep of the municipality
you try to seduce the clean family girls huh?
no i swear my superior
she asked me to marry her
shut up man shut up
i will get you fired
you are already fired
fuck off
fuck off man
find yourself a job
i will get your shops closed for two days
shit, you cant close them
take this
i hope we can help this girl get married
this stupid whimsey wont like any husband
if she wants, let her marry that guy
she will become a whore otherwise
dont make us killers
he works at the municipality anyway
he is a clerk with a salary
how much does he make?
they get good money, dad
dont underestimate his job
do you want this, girl?
dont let her decide
she has no idea
tell the street cleaner, we will wait for
him to meet us tomorrow
welcome
i find it nice
come in
that him?
he is
come closer soldier
not soldier
why did you bother soldier?
no not soldier
whatever the shit it is
come in
let me see
ehh not bad
no more meatballs?
eat those first
drink that with your mouth
cheers
to your dignity, health and well being
very well made, Lady Hacer,
you cook very well
enjoy
Your daughter loves me dearly
It's love at first sight
I am not a man you cant love
I am a handsome man
I have a salary
I have insurance
Go to bed boy, dont listen to us here
I am dying for a cigarette right now
Come on soldier, you're going slow
I am not a soldier yet
it is no good anyway
do you know what love is?
love makes your heart hurt
then am i an unlovable man?
anyone who sees me will fall in love sir
my voice is also very nice
i am going to sing, look, listen, okay?
we give up, you sing so good,
wonderful
you are working for nothing brother
can i call you son in law?
call me so, father
father
yeah
my father
my dear father
hope they break their hands
get their lives back my god
mom
yeah my son*
i wanna tell you something
tell me my lovely son
i am in love
who is this girl my son?
will you get me that girl?
i will? why wouldnt i?
who?
tell me, for gods sake
Hacer
What what what what?
Who?
Hacer
Ayy im dying
Why is this happening to me?
Mom
Hope your mom dies
Mama what is happening?
Ohh, she is dying
Shut up man, everyone's sleeping
i'll write this too
do not sleep motherfuckers
I am getting married here
Newspaper
It's writing
Do you have any good news?
Two men got shot
One bank has been robbed
No way
What else?
Bomb explosion in a cafe caused 30 injuries
what else?
what else ah, and..
car accident
a taxi and a bus crashed
all the people in the taxi died
you killed my spirit in the morning
go do your job
come
come here
come here my son
old lady
you make me want to be a cat
let me bring you some hot tea
why are you shouting at
this time in the morning
and you, why are you sleeping
like donkeys till late?
you bothered old lady
wohoo the cleaner is comfy
of course he is
he is getting married
dont touch them man
stole things again? profit of short day
mind your own business
dont throw this godless woman
i cleaned it just now
street cleaner
come here
dont linger
run
yes superior
who are you to sit in front of me huh?
no sir
no such thing happened superior
i busted you while not doing
your job at work
i will report this
i see that you are doing a strike uh?
nonetheless sir
i clean everywhere i swear
what are those?
cats
i dont want stray cats in the neighborhood
find a big pocket
catch them all
throw them away to the outskirts
come on man
you will do whatever i tell you,
immediately
no i cant sir
its a sin
what?
are you opposing me?
okay
youre fired
its over
fuck off
sir
the god will punish us i swear
big sin
dont teach me my job man
i told you to throw the cats
you will
dont do it man
yeah, i dont and he shit in my mouth
be careful my son
what are you doing?
sorry old lady
collecting the cats
catch it it ran away
catch it, its runing
curse you
here take it
take it, take it
dont you have a brain?
why do you run after so many cats?
what shit would i do?
my superior told me to
he is being jealous dont listen to him
he says he will fire me
is it good before marriage?
these shit in my mouth i swear
poor you
what kind of a donkey man are you?
dont talk to me like that
in front of my fiancee
my lion
your job is cleaning the streets
he cant make you deal with cats
i agree
let the poor things go
let them go
what can he do to you?
will you get me fired?
is that what you want?
the prick is coming?
sit down
why are you standing up for that donkey?
where are you man?
dont you see he is dying
nobody defend him
you are not my respondent
i am talking to him
where are the cats?
you would collect and bring them?
i collected them sir
look they are all here
you did that on purpose
i wont let you get away with this
go get them son of a donkey
yes sir
shame on you, prick
stop
what do you want?
you cant marry anybody else than me
i'll kill you
you cant do anything
i made up my mind
i am marrying Abdi
nobody can change my mind
with a street cleaner
if you were a man you would marry me
you didnt wait
i will make you pay it
what will you do?
i will catch all those corrupt
brothers of you
hmm, you'll see
i have marlboro
marlboro 25
walk now you dealer
you cannot escape the law
i know why you do this
so he told you he would catch your
brother huh?
he is doing it because of you
it's obvious
dad he is doing that to me too
nothing will happen
dad, lets put the rings
okay man shut up
so he still wants you huh?
hhım
all the mad people find her
you could only find this cucumber man huh?
what would i do, is there a husband?
really
its hard to find it these days
should i bring the rings tomorrow dad?
fine,bring them
no way we cant
while my son is in jail
i cant let you put those rings on
she's right, we didnt think that
i'll talk to my superior
like he will listen to you
he will
he wont let me down
i will ask him he will bail
your brother out
dear, let him speak and we'll see
dont you worry
he will listen to me
my superior
forgive my brother in law
he wont sell cigarette again
she will come at my feet and beg
there is no way out
my superior
what did he say?
you will go ask for it
yeah?
he will see now
Hacer
Girl Hacer stop
Stop what are you doing?
Let me go
Open the door
Dont make me crazy
Open it
I told you to open the door
Open the door, open
Open
What do you want from me?
Dont shout my mom is sick
I hope she dies
What do you want?
What do you want from my brother?
Slow, you know what i want
Did i tell you i wont get married?
You left me alone
It's all because of my mother
Are you a man?
Shut it, dont tell me i am not
Release my brother
You marry me
go talk to your mom
i will
go out now
what happened girl?
nothing
mother
get up
what?
mother
i decided to marry Hacer
allah make you fall down you
go away go away
i dont have a son like you anymore
ah ah
my time all wasted
my lion is marrying a servant girl
mind your langauge i'll make her a lady
what?
i'll die instead
she is a bitch, do you understand?
huh?
nobody asked your opinion
i'll marry her
she is not a bitch
she is a lady
hope you go blind
crawl
choose that whore over your mother
hope you drink blood
hope god makes you like his
are you the devil or what
oh he will kill me
help neighbors
my son lost mind
he'll kill me
help
save me people
save me neighbors
ahhh
he's gone mad
for gods sake
save me
help
neighbors save me
he's gone mad
he's gonna kill his mother
for gods sake
ayy he's gone mad
ahh help me
save me please save me
die bitch
thats a sin
hold on tight old lady
help me
he will throw her down
old lady hold on tight
dont move
wow
she is a woman like a falcon
hold on tight old lady
i dont want you as a mother
i broke my back
wheres my hat
that's our groom!
lion groom
im going
run my son
take Apo's taxi from the corner
no man, who am i to ride on a taxi?
its a shame son
a groom shouldnt walk to the bride's house
i'll pay for it
thanks.
my heart is pounding i swear
look
its gold
18 carat
i bought this
taxi is here
Apo good bye my dear
aaa you got out of the jail?
yeah i did
wait a minute
dad told me not to let you in
one sec
take these at least
give them to my fiancee
it contains very valuable candies
guess this is the tradition
they make the groom wait in cold
he's waiting outside
you see, we make the groom wait outside
because of you
let him wait
who does he think he is?
he is a street cleaner i command
talk mother
i swear
i have always liked Hacer
she is very skilled
and a nice lady
so we thought
We decided to ask for her
with Allah's commandment
go check that
go on mom
you were saying the girl
i am freezing open the door let me in
you'll wait
my father is talking business inside
man, is it acceptable to make
a mighty groom shake like a dog?
he is crying off, dad
well, i cant make the guy wait longer
we made our decision
we want to put the rings on
soon i will get a promotion
we have a house
tell them mom
we will make her comfortable
i'll feed her very well
make him a lady
this man needs an answer
who the hell is he?
kick him out
noo not appropriate
we need to respond nicely
nobody can steal Hacer from me
i will give everything i have for her
eh congrats
lets talk to him
dad im freezing
lets put the rings on for gods sake
not gonna happen, soldier
why dad?
dont call me dad, man
dad
i even brought the rings
18 carat i swear
so what?
my daughter wants the superior
what?
yeah, we will give her to the superior
sorry about that
what about me?
dont shout in front of my house
i want my fiancee
want my fiancee!
let me go
you fooled me sons of donkeys
mind your language man
dont talk that way
go mind your own business
or i'll break your legs
is that so?
give my flowers and candies back
go get it
look at me
dont be a macho
or i burn you
here
go
walk away
shit on your flowers
oohh what a pleasure
as of now im like this
i wont work
good for you
throw it baby throw it
let shit rule the street
i am a prick if i clean it
good man dont clean it
he is doing it to make you jealous
he can eat shit
spit, brother, spit
it's 7.30 man
the motherfucker is acting like a lord
street cleaner! dont smoke that
man, is it good to smoke
while doing your duty?
i can smoke so much that
i could fuck its mother
are you opposing to your superior?
i'll get you fired
do it
good job man
dont be afraid
he cant do any shit
im not afraid
its your fault you let him
do these to you till now
from now on, it's like this
if i were you
i would kidnap that girl
i'll kidnap
good man
you're a slow man, it was your fault
shit on my head
go get her mount her
i'll mount
close her mouth
see if they give her to
you or not after that
im going
good
i am a slow man
i'll show them how fast i am
good job girl
you got my appreciation
if you did not attempt to
engage to the street cleaner
this guy would not chase after you
i wont be a cleaning lady any more
i will be the lady of my own house
i wont have to wash other people's clothes
thank god we have seen these days
ahh
mom
you'll be mine
let me
let me go
dont shout girl
help
wont let go
dont be scared
i dont have bad intentions
i'll do you
İsmail told me to
let me
stop
dont move
let me
stay still girl
help me
let me go i say let me go
dont touch my sister
you corrupt prick
motherfucker
animal
take it take it
get out of here
get out
animal
you corrupt son of a donkey
take this
What happened?
He mounted our sister
why prick
hold the man
what happened?
he attacked Hacer
son of a donkey
dad catch him
oh i got off cheap
what are you looking for here man
did the street cleaner pass by?
what street cleaner?
our ex brother in law
shit your ex brother in law
he strangled your mother and
mounted Hacer
why prick
no he didnt pass by
shit we missed him
he cant run away
i wanted to steal a tape after
so long time
such a bad luck
there he is!
catch him
dont run away
come here im gonna kill you
these men will kill me
İsmail, why did i take your word?
he cant run away now, quick
what are you doing here?
come here
come
we missed the motherfucker
he cant be far
he must be somewhere here
he cant get away from us
let go come on
the cliants really liked the guy
bring him to me after the song
dont mind the audience
let me go please
i swear i didnt do this on purpose
my father in law will shoot me
i took our doorman İsmail's word
street cleaner!
i havent seen such talent before
my lion
you have a big treasure
i didnt do it on purpose sir
forgive me
they are after me
they will shoot me for dignity
nobody can touch you in this casino
we dont let them shoot men here
dont worry
let me introduce you to the boss
allow me to go
come here
you will breathe a bit, come
well i understand all
but why are you carrying this with you?
state property sir
debted to me by the municipality
they make me pay if i lose it
so you won't accept our offer, huh?
i cant sir
they will fire me if i do
mine is a secure job
i have insurance, retirement
plan
two suits every year
son here you will earn more than your
annual salary in a month
what?
so will i have vacation for 11 months?
what a son of a dog is this
he is barganing hard
no i swear not
its not appropriate
i wont make people gossip about
a clerk of the state entertaining people
dont get me started with your municipality
alright, 1000 a night, okay?
what a thousand?
What? A thousand?
for a thousand i wouldnt only sing
i would fuck my father in law's mother
im gonna kill that womanizer
dont go anywhere till we come back
not even peeing
watch the door
if someone walks in, shoot them
okay
walk
we will find that dog easily in the cafe
he cant go anywhere anyway
dont make it bleed please i beg you
this is dignity
women dont have right to speech
you stay this way
my dad will lead us
dont move
so he didnt come in the evening?
yes
where might he have gone?
no idea
what happened man?
Abdi tried to kidnap the girl
Good job man
no we cant find him
i wont let that dog live
he had his eyes on my fiancee
beware
dont try to hide him
or i will make i hurt!
he cant do this on his own
for sure some prick told him to do it
what happened superior*
you shut it, shut it
you made him this
lets go home
this street cleaner is mad, he can
do anything
lets put the rings on dad
uh?
sure sure
bring the rings, im tired of this
here is a brand new star
real people's man
can you tell us about your life please*
tell them yourself
well i am a worker of the municipality
with the collar number 2548
called Abdi Şakra
Hasan and Seher's son
I guess my mother is his second wife
He is from Yozgat Sefaatli town
I was born in 1948
I am literate up to third grade of
primary school
I havent commited any crimes
Except for the attempt to
kidnap my fiancee of course
after military service i have served the
municipality for exactly 9 years
dad
he became a singer
our ex brother in law dad
we were gonna shoot him even
look at that
our girl has no luck eh
he must be making so much money
snap. we missed him
was he such a handsome man
we paid a lot but we bought the best one
dont be scared now
you are in the arms of a superior
who the hell is the street cleaner?
aaa where did that come from?
look what the street cleaner did to me
what's happening girl?
tidy yourself up
you are with your fiancee
man, i'll kill you
are you a curse or something?
ah mom
ah mom what have i done?
what happened happened,
stop crying
shit
you rejected the good groom
now cry
ah ah you found a good opportunity
why would you call it quits
donkey man
Abdi
Oh I took you for granted
He was such a kind man
Go talk to him dad
Man he wont even let us in
Good evening
Huh, thats all we need
wont my fiancee greet me?
your fiancee is fainting
what happened?
whats wrong?
come in come
Hacer
Is there something wrong my Hacer?
Get off me
Are you sick?
Okay, dont touch the girl man
Why not?
She is my fiancee
We havent put the rings yet
Here
I brought the rings
Put our rings immediately dad
shut it
how am i your dad?
my real son is mr Abdi
Why would i give my girl to a superior
while there's Abdi
Abdi
My voice is also nice
I also have talent
Fuck off from here
Stop
One second
Get him out of here
I love her
I love Hacer
Good luck love
Thank you
Oh love i can eat your lovely cheeks
Good luck sweetie
You too sweetie
What's up lion?
I'm scared
I swear I'll pee my pants
Dont worry man
Come one, show off
With Allah's help I'll make it
dont worry
come in
aa how did you get in?
my son
get away
why do you call me your son?
you are the best of sons
i didnt know it
my daughter is dying for you
brother come get this girl
who do you think you are talking to?
Will i marry a servant like your daughter?
There are plenty of women chasing me
Abdi forgive us
Come on Abdi, it's your turn
My future is bright
I will shine like the sun soon
I wont marry your scabby girl
let me pass
our fault
we shouldnt have come here
why dont we make her marry the superior
go come on lets go
my throat
who bring these to the stage?
i told you this bear cant be a singer
fuck your mot..
come down!
look he is still there, come down
Abdi
why did you come?
singing is not my type of job
its no good
its a shitty job
no job security
i have my very well job already
while i have the municipality job
sure of course
you didnt give my place to anyone, did you?
of course not dear
here
you lock the door
dont worry
good night
you too sweetie
come kitty come
eat my son eat
youre late
so many news
tell me about it
the government has fallen
no way
who will rule now?
i dont know
did the government fall son?
yes
i made the government
fall with my writings
he did
dont throw this for even a day
man when will the garbage truck come?
i dont know ask the superior
the superior doesnt leave the flat
since he got married
the godless doesnt of course
he has the softest woman
would he go out
check your watch
7.30
enough
wow
doomsday happening inside
hope they get worse
i am so tired of you
whats happening here man?
she is handling the superior, very good
enough
here take it
hit him, break it for gods sake
im tired, im tired
only one person rules this house
go, go away
i dont wanna see you
what kind of a man are you?
what kind?
she is right
you cant slap the bitch on her face
ha-ha if he does that
i'll show him
mom shut it
at least you shut up
why would i shut up?
i am a servant in my own house oh
either she or i leave this house
do you understand?
girl
dont shout
they all heard it
everyone's listening to us girl
who is listening to us?
street cleaner
why is this street so dirty?
huh?
you never clean it
i cleaned it lady
look
as a dirt we have this
and this
your slippers lady
dirt
Thank God
Abdi you are the beloved human being
thank god you didnt marry that crazy girl
wow what is this?
the end