- Handme the flashlight.
- Here it is.
- Kit, l´vegot theshovel.
- You do?
Lucy, get the box.
- What areyouputting in?
- lt´ssupposedto be a secret.
- My dadthinksl´m atyourhouse.
- Mymom thinksl´m atyours.
Let´s dig deep.
So no one will find it.
- Dig it deeper!
- We don´t wanna get caught.
I want some dirt.
When we were tengrowing up
in Georgia, Mimi, Kit andl...
knewexactly what we wanted
out oflife.
- Lucy, get the box.
- This is fun.
So weput ourdreamsin a box,
and we buriedit.
We have to keep it dry.
We made apact to dig it up
at midnight...
the dayofour
high schoolgraduation.
Pack it down.
- Let´s be best friends forever.
- We will.
Now, ldon´t even remember
what our wishes were--
except forone.
We wishedthat we´dbe
best friends forever.
Well, that wish
didn ´t come true.
lseeyou on thestreet
andyou walk on by
Baby
You make me wanna hang
myheaddown andcry
lfyougave me
halfthe chance, you´dsee
My desire burning inside ofme
Butyou choose
to look the other way
l´ve hadto work
much harderthan this
Forsomethingl want
Don´t tryto resist me
Openyourheart to me, baby
lholdthe lock
andyou holdthe key--
- Lucille Wagner!
- Pop?
- Baby, we´re gonna be late.
- I wasjust--
- Did you practice your speech?
- I almost have it.
Lucy, how´s it gonna look ifthe
valedictorian messes up her speech?
Okay.
Don´t wrinkle your robe.
just ironed it forya.
Okay, big day! Come on!
See ya on deck! Let´s go!
Toads do look like frogs.
It´sjust one´s, you know,
in the water and one´s not.
It doesn´t--
It could happen to anybody.
Hey, Mimi!
I know you want me.
Ho!
I´m gonna look
drop-dead gorgeous.
You should see my dress.
- Hello! Watch where you´re going!
- You ran into me, Kit.
What, you´re too perfect
to bump into anybody?
- What?
- Perfect.
Sweet, proper...
nerdy and virginal.
- I´m not--
- You´re a virgin.
I told y´all.
just get us in the picture, okay?
Hold my purse.
No, don´t push the button.
Wait till I get over there. Honey!
- Mama, what are you doing?
- One second. Stand up straight.
- I am. I will.
- Tuckyour tummy in.
- Smile.
- Mom, I´m smiling!
Bigger, darling.
- Lucy, your speech was wonderful.
- Thankyou.
I hope you´re gonna continue
studying music in college.
Actually, Lucy wants
to become a doctor.
Voice classes would make
nice electives.
No time. We´re looking at a double
major in biology and chemistry...
ifshe wants to get into
the best med school, huh?
Henry, I´ll show you how
to start that truck for tonight.
All right.
See you later.
- Bye, Ms.J.
- Good luck, Henry.
I´m all he´s got, you know?
Congratulations, Lucy.
Thankyou. Thanks.
Here it is.
Honey, what´s wrong?
I´m fine.
Pop, I worked really hard
to be the valedictorian.
Course you did.
Why didn´t it feel
like anything?
What do you mean, you didn´t
feel anything? It felt great!
Pop, I never went
to one football game.
You don´t like football.
But you´re supposed to go,
and it´s supposed to be fun.
And like all the parties
at Hemmings Field and stuff...
I never went to any of´em.
I never stayed out late.
I neverjust hung out.
´Cause you had
a head on your shoulders.
You stayed home, and you studied.
There´sjust a lot ofthings
that I wanted to do that I didn´t.
And I was up there getting
my diploma, and I was like...
´´Is this it?´´
Come on now. Didn´t we both
work hard for this?
You´re right.
I guess it´sjust the pressure
of graduation. You´re right.
Girls, hi!
Lucy.
Mimi, not now. Okay?
- Are you comin´ or not?
- Coming where?
It´s graduation night!
Oh, God, Hemmings Field.
I totally forgot.
So, are you comin´ or not?
I have plans.
I´m sorry.
Come on. You okay?
Do you want something?
Yeah. Are you coming
at midnight or what?
Excuse me?
Kit, we made a pact, remember?
Oh, you´re not serious!
Well, look, you can
really go without me.
I have better things to do
than dig up some old box.
Standinghere
lookingat allthe world
The guitar guy is such a hottie.
That´s Ben Kimble.
I heard hejust got out ofjail.
Killed a guy.
I don´t believe you.
Yeah! Everybody´s talking about it.
Oh, too bad!
Well, ifanyone could have him,
it´d be you.
But I´m offthe market, remember?
Oh, please!
Dylan´s at UCLA doing...
God knows what
with God knows who.
That´s not true.
Right.
Whatever.
- Are you ready?
- Yeah, yeah, just two seconds.
Okay, hold on.
Henry, are you ready?
I´m ready.
That´s okay. Go on.
Why are you stopping?
This isn´t how I hoped it would be.
That´s weird, ´cause this is
exactly how I hoped it would be...
or pretty accurate.
- Maybe ifwe get into bed.
- That´s a good idea.
These are nice sheets.
- Can I hear the list again?
- Oh, Luce, come on.
Please, please.
just one more time.
Thanks.
All right.
Reason number one:
We´ve been lab partners for three
years so we really trust each other.
- That´s really important. Okay.
- Trust is very important.
Reason number two: We are both 1 8
and have never done it.
Very important!
Reason number three:
We both want to do it.
Reason number four--
Please, Lucy, come on. Please.
I´m, I´m begging you.
Please, let´sjust do it.
- Okay, yeah, we can do it.
- Yeah?
Okay, so let´s--
- I´ll go this way.
- Okay, I´m going this way.
Let´s do this.
Please don´t laugh.
You´re killing this.
- Your first time should be special.
- Yeah, this is special!
Listen, do you want to spend
the rest ofyour life...
knowing that you did it for the
first time with your lab partner?
Yes, yes, I do.
And I´ll tell you why.
Because you know what it´s like
for a guy to go to college a virgin?
No, I´m telling you
they, they--
They´re ostracized!
They treat them like lepers!
I´m sorry.
- What´s up, Mimi? How´s the fetus?
- Drop dead.
- Is it mine or what?
- I can´t believe we went out.
- I´m trying to do the right thing.
- Yeah? What´s the right thing?
Ignoring me
for the past five months?
Letting your friends call me a ho?
Spreading rumors?
I´m repeating what I heard,
that you let some guy...
do you in his car
over Christmas break.
jerk.
It´s ten paces
on the other side.
- What are you doing here?
- Where´s Lucy?
She´s not comin´.
- You have a flashlight? Good.
- Gimme back my flashlight!
Let´sjust get this
over with, okay?
God, I don´t even remember
what we put in here.
Me either.
Here, hold this
for a second, Lucy.
My Bridal Barbie!
She was my wish.
- You´re gettin´ your wish.
- I know.
Lucy, I think this is yours.
- My locket.
- What did you wish for?
I wanted to find my mom.
Did you ever find her?
No, she lives in Arizona and my pop
doesn´t think it´s a good idea, so--
What did you wish for?
- A key chain?
- No, the world.
That I was gonna get out
ofthis crappy town...
go all the way to California...
put my feet
in the Pacific Ocean.
There´s a wish that´s not
coming true for a while.
- A lot you know, Kit.
- What´s that supposed to mean?
Slide Records recording contest?
- So?
- So I´m going on Sunday.
You´re going to California
to audition for a record company?
- Yeah.
- You´re pregnant.
- So? I´ll wear something slimming.
- And what?
You thinkyou´re gonna become
this big, fat, pregnant star?
- I have a pretty good voice.
- How are you gonna get there?
- I found a ride with this guy.
- What? No, that is crazy.
You can´t go to Los Angeles
by yourselfwith some guy.
So? Then come with me. I´ll sing
lead, and you can sing backups.
- It´s not something we should do.
- It´s stupid is what it is.
Okay, fine.
You know what?
You can just forget
all your past!
Oh, wow.
- Oh, my goodness. Look at us!
- Let me see.
- I was so chubby.
- Singing.
- I have to go meet my friends.
- Yeah, it´s getting late.
Yeah.
Hey, you guys.
I´m leaving Sunday at 7:00 a.m.
ifyou all wanna come.
What do you mean you´re not
coming home for the summer?
Dylan, listen to me,
you have to come home.
Because! I haven´t seen you
since Christmas.
Don´t you miss me?
- Excuse me.
- Dad, customer!
Dylan, we have to plan
the wedding.
All right.
I love you--
Dylan?
- Hey, darlin´.
- Hey, Pop.
Dr.Johnson called today.
Good news.
Got me a job at the hospital?
All those discounts I gave him
finally paid off.
- Cool.
- Yep.
Can I askyou a question?
It´s about Mother.
- Has she ever tried to see me?
- No, she hasn´t.
I was thinking,
maybe she´s afraid to visit me.
Luce, you do not have
to feel any guilt...
about your mother leaving us.
This is not about us.
She was the one who walked out
on a three-year-old.
She´s the one that should
feel guilty. All right?
All right.
Nobody brings four suitcases
on a road trip.
Look, Dylan asked me
to go see him in LA...
and I can´t get there
looking like a skank.
You better hope it all fits.
It will, okay?
I´m not going to the audition.
You can drop me off in Arizona.
- Fine.
- Fine. Shotgun.
- Yeah, right. I´m sitting up front.
You must be Lucy.
Yeah.
So you´re taking us to L.A.?
Yeah. I´ll get your bag.
- You okay? Sorry.
- Yeah, I´m fine.
- Move it, Ben! Let´s go!
- I´ll get the door foryou.
Hey, who´s the guy?
That´sjust Ben.
He´s really cool.
Let´s hit it.
Where´s the bathroom?
Second door.
There´s no soap.
What´s the deal with Lucy?
- What, are you hot for her?
- No.
I wouldn´t even try, Ben.
Seriously, she´s not like us.
She´s way out ofyour league.
Want a chip?
Get outta here.
What are you doin´?
- What´s with this music?
- Well, I like it.
Can we listen to something else
for ten minutes?
No.
Come on, Ben, please?
Be a nice guy.
Okay, five minutes.
just five minutes.
Thankyou.
ldon´t wanna be a fool
ln thisgame fortwo
So l´m leavingyou behind
Bye, bye, bye
Don´t make it tough
l´ve hadenough
Bye, bye
Baby
- Ben!
- I can´t listen to this.
- You said five minutes.
- Forget it.
Like this is any better.
- Why are we stopped?
- I´m tired.
Let someone else drive.
No, nobody drives
the cruiser but me.
- Okay, whatever.
- Where are we gonna sleep?
There´s a field.
I got a tent and sleeping bags.
A field?
No, I don´t sleep in a field.
I saw a sign for a Hilton
back there.
How much money do we have?
I can´t believe
you only brought $40.
I have expenses. I had to have
my homecoming dress custom-made.
I was voted queen, you know.
Oh, my dream come true.
- Did anybody make a plan?
- What do you mean?
How faryou´ll drive each day?
Which towns you´ll stop in?
How much gas money you´ll need?
Okay.
We have $486, right?
Which means...
for food, gas--
Is it enough?
It´s gonna be tight.
Oh, my gosh.
It´s a love room.
Oh, man!
Look at the walls!
- I´m not sleeping here!
- This is what we can afford.
Is this run by the hour?
I´m not sleeping here.
- Where you gonna sleep?
- I don´t know.
This place is disgusting.
I´ll take this bed.
So how come
you´re going to L.A.?
My uncle might have
a job for me there...
so I´m gonna check it out
and if I like it, I´ll move there.
What about your band?
Don´t you have a band?
No, I wasjust filling in the
other night. I don´t have a band.
Mimi said that she didn´t think
you´d come with us on the trip.
Neither did I.
You sorry you did?
Not so far.
Well, good night.
Good night.
Hey! It´s freakin´ cold!
- We´re in here.
- I´m in here.
I just need
to brush my teeth.
- What are you doing?
- You´re so touchy.
Mimi, how do you know Ben?
-Just from around.
- Gosh, don´t you think he´s cute?
- He´s all right.
- I can´t believe he was in jail.
- What?
- Yeah!
He like killed a guy.
What? That´s what I heard.
Excuse me?
He killed somebody?
No, he did not kill anybody--
I don´t think.
Okay, he had a car, he was
coming to L.A. Don´t be upset.
I´m on a road trip with a killer and
you´re telling me not to be upset?
- He´ll hearyou.
- Oh, my God.
What´s up?
Do you know him at all?
He used to hang out with some
ofthe guys at the trailer park.
So he may have
killed someone, okay?
So what? He did his time.
He paid his debt to society.
Oh, my God.
Ready to go?
Yeah.
Hey, you wanna ride up front
with me today?
No, that´s okay.
The backseat´s fine. It´s okay.
- I´ll check us out, okay?
- Yeah.
- I´ll be back.
- I´ll come with ya.
No, it´s okay, I´m fine.
- Will you please get me some chips?
- No, Mimi.
Open the door.
I´ll get my own chips.
Y´all, wait for me!
So when he came home
last Christmas, he proposed.
He´s comin´ home as soon as
he´s done with school next spring.
You´re seriously
gonna marry that loser?
You don´t even know him.
- What´s wrong?
- Nothing. Itjust kicked, is all.
- Can I feel it?
- Ifyou want.
It kicked again.
- What about Kurt?
- He´s the father, isn´t he?
- Yes, Kurt´s the father.
But it wasn´t working out,
so I dumped him.
You´re gonna raise this baby
all by yourself?
I´m gonna go wait in the car
with Ben, all right?
That´s so typical of her.
She´s not thinkin´ about her future.
How´s she gonna get by with a baby?
Well, she brought this
upon herself.
What?
- Hello.
- Hi, Pop.
Sneaking away in
the middle ofthe night?
l´m veryupset withyou.
Dr.Johnson went...
to a great deal oftrouble
to get you thatjob.
- I´m sorry, okay?
- Sorry?
You are coming back now! And
you will regard that as a command!
You´re usually so levelheaded...
andyoupulla stunt like this,
lam so surprisedatyou.
You workedso hard. Areyou
gonna startslacking offnow?
What are you writing there?
Stuff.
Are you mad at me or something?
Why would I be mad at you?
I don´t even know you.
- No!
- Oh, no, it sounds bad.
Look at all that smoke.
What´s wrong with it, Ben?
It´s the head gasket, I think.
- Give me your shirt.
- Here.
Whoa! What are you doing?
Nobody touches this except
for specialists and myself.
Because it´s an antique
and I don´t want people to--
- It´s your radiator.
- No, it´s the head gasket.
No, your radiator´s cracked.
What year it this? ´73.
Oh, that´s like 350,
plus labor.
Great! Great!
I´m hungry.
How long does it take
to get a tow truck?
- Ben´s only been gone two hours.
- I´m so hungry.
Won´t you stop saying that?
We heard you. You´re hungry.
So what?
We don´t have $350.
Even if he gets a tow truck...
we don´t have enough money
to get the car fixed.
I´m gonna be stuck here in--
Where the hell am I? Where am I?
Louisiana.
Stuck in some
butt-hole town, Louisiana.
I am never gonna get to LA
to see Dylan.
He´s gonna be so upset.
Whatever.
Excuse me?
Could you be more self-centered?
- You´rejustjealous.
- What?
I´m not blind. I know how girls
like you looked at me in school.
You would´ve given anything
to trade places with me.
Girls like me?
I can´t help it if I´m popular,
sojust lay off.
Girls like me?
I didn´t make the rules, Mimi.
It´s not my fault...
everyone thinks
you´re a trailer-trash skeeze.
- Stop it!
- Don´t touch me like that!
- Guys, don´t!
- You´re pregnant!
You´re a redneck!
Girls! Mimi! Stop!
Stop it! Stop!
I´m so sick ofthe two ofyou...
bitching and fighting
every damn second ofthe day!
For once,
would you just shut up?
I don´t know why the hell I asked
the two ofyou to come on this trip.
We don´t belong together.
This was a mistake, okay?
I´m sorry, partner,
that´s the best I can do.
It´s a cracked radiator.
He said he´d get it ready
by tomorrow.
How will we get the money
to pay for it?
I have an idea.
I´m gonna call my father
and have him come get me.
You´re leaving?
This trip´s over.
Wait, I have an idea!
You know what?
I´m sick ofyour ideas, Mimi.
I should´ve known you´d make
a mess ofthis trip.
Fine, run home to your daddy,
but don´t try and blame this on me.
Lucy, I haven´t asked you
for anything in a really long time.
But I´m gonna askyou to stay.
Please hang up the damn phone
and just stay with us!
Come on, Lucy.
Hello?
I do.
I have a really good idea.
Yeah, it better be good.
Okay, I have something
to say.
I know we´re not all getting along,
but tonight´s important.
We really need the money.
So could wejust be civil
and get through this? Okay?
Okay.
All right!
Y´all ready?
Yeah.
- That´s cute.
- Thankyou.
Wait.
It´s all the tips
we can get, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- So?
Ifwe wanna put on a show,
we have to be sexy.
Now you´re talkin´.
- Whatcha got?
- Let me wear those feathers.
All right, next contestant´s
a brand-new act.
And for all tourists that don´t
know how the rules go in my club...
here it is, plain and simple.
You´re thejudge.
Ifyou hate ´em, tell ´em.
Ifyou like ´em, pay ´em.
We got baskets going around.
Put the money in there.
Be loud, be fair and be generous
ifyou like what you hear.
So, come on, give ´em
a warm welcome.
- They lookyoung.
- It´s past their bedtime.
lsawhim dancing there
bythe recordmachine
Get offthe stage!
- Mimi, come on!
- I can´t do it.
- You can do it.
- I thought so, but I can´t.
- Please do it for me.
- You just gotta go do it.
- No, you do it.
- I don´t know if I can.
You´ve got the best voice.
Come on, please for me.
- Okay, okay.
- Thankyou.
- You okay?
- No.
lsawhim dancing there
bythe recordmachine
lknewhe must have been
about 17
The beat wasgoingstrong
Playing my favoritesong
lcouldtellit wouldn ´t be long
tillhe was with me, yeah, me
tillhe was with mesinging
llove rockandrollsoput
anotherdime in thejukebox, baby
llove rockandrollso come
andtakesome time anddance with me
Hesmiledso lgot up
andaskedforhisname
But that don´t matter
hesaid ´cause it´sallthesame
Hesaid, can ltakeyou home
Where we can be alone
Andnext we were movin´on
andhe was with me
Yeah, me
Andnext we were movin´on and
he was with me, yeah, me, singing
llove rockandroll
´Cause itsoothes mysoul
Yeah
llove rockandroll
And we were moving on
andsinging thatsame oldsong
Yeah, me
Roll, roll, roll
Now.
It´s so amazing.
Lucy, come here.
- How much is it?
- Enough for the car and the trip.
Perfect.
You wanna come dance with us?
No. We should get outta here before
somebody realizes you´re underage.
Come on, just a
little bit longer, please?
- All right, you go ahead.
- Thankyou.
- Hey, she with you?
- What?
Is she your girl?
No.
Yeah. Watch this.
Move your hands, please.
We´re gonna get a little freaky.
Hey, what´s up, baby? Come on.
- What´s wrong?
- Will you stop it?
Excuse me. Hey, I don´t think
she wants to dance.
I think she does.
You should mind your own business.
- Will you leave me alone?
- Excuse me. I´m talking to you.
My nose!
Let´s go.
Oh, damn!
Is this livin´ or what?
There´s a mini-bar!
Y´all, you could swim
in this bathtub!
Look, I´m--
I´m not mad at you
for what happened there. Okay?
There´s bathrobes!
- Where are you going?
-Just going out.
Are any ofyou guys tired,
´cause it´s 3:00 a.m. and I´m wired!
- Who wants some of mama´s punch?
- Me, please.
- Madame.
Go, Lucy! Go, Lucy!
What are you doing?
You go, girl!
I have seen one, y´all.
Yeah, but have you touched one?
She has!
Give us the details!
It´s always the quiet ones.
Say it loud. Say you
touched one and you´re proud!
Lucy touched one!
She did!
Okay, the best thing
that ever happened to you.
- That´s easy.
- What?
Reaching my goal weight.
Third year at fat camp,
the summer before eighth grade.
Wait, that camp you went to
every summer was a fat camp?
Yes, and I loved it.
For two months...
my mama wasn´t around
to pick on me for being fat.
Being fat isjust
unacceptable to her.
Okay. The worst thing
that ever happened to you.
That´s even easier.
Reaching my goal weight.
- You said--
- It turns out...
that being prettier
than my mama...
is even more
unacceptable.
Oh,Jesus.
Yep.
One morning I woke up,
and she was gone.
Pop really wouldn´t
say anything about it.
I thought she was coming back,
and Pop told me she wasn´t.
They fought all the time.
You know, I think
that shejust got fed up...
and took off
without even thinking.
And after a while, it was
Just too late to come back.
I know she wants to see me.
She´sjust scared, that´s all.
I´m gonna be so sick later.
Mimi, be glad you´re pregnant
and you couldn´t act stupid with us.
That´s not why I don´t drink.
I just don´t see the point in it.
So you never partied?
Once.
Over Christmas.
There was one ofthose parties
at Hemmings Field.
And this guy
was drinking this beer...
and I remember
it was in a blue bottle.
And I was real mad
at Kurt because...
he blew me offagain
to hang out with his friends.
So I had a few beers.
I had more than a few.
This guy, you know, he seemed--
He seemed real nice...
´cause when I couldn´t walk,
he offered to drive me home.
It´s no big deal, Luce.
It happens to girls all the time.
Did you go to the police?
No.
I´m from a trailer park.
I got drunk and got in his car.
So, Kurt´s not the father?
I saw this ad in a magazine.
So I called up this lawyer in
Atlanta, and she sent me this stuff.
Um, all these pictures
and letters...
ofall these people
who want babies.
- I was supposed to pick one.
- The guy...
what was his name?
I don´t know.
Why did we stop being friends?
People drift apart.
Promise me we won´t
drift apart again.
Come here.
And where have you been
all night?
Thankyou.
For what you did
last night, I mean.
Thanks.
Scoot over.
I´m never drinkin´ again. Honest.
This burrito is so good.
Don´t mention food.
- What are you doing?
- Chilling.
- Wake him up.
- Y´all, he´s been driving all day.
- We can´tjust stay here.
- We should just let him sleep.
- Uh-uh.
- We´ll let him sleep.
Lucy, get his keys.
He told us we couldn´t drive
his car. I can´t do that.
Why not? It´s not like we´re
gonna drive this over a cliff.
- It´s stupid to stay here.
- I´ll drive.
Get his keys.
- Yeah, get his keys.
- Why do I have to get his keys?
Because Kit and I voted
and you lost.
Get the keys.
Yeah, Lucy, get his keys.
- This is stealing.
- It´s not stealing if he´s in the car.
No, it´s kidnapping.
Okay, stop.
Oh, I got it.
Go, go.
You failed driver´s ed,
didn´t you?
Maybe.
- Move over.
- Oh, God.
Guys, smile for the camera.
Go ahead, turn it on, turn it on.
Let´sgo, girls
l´mgoin´out tonight
andl´m feelingallright
l´mgonna let
it allhang out
Wanna makesome noise
Really raise my voice
Yeah, l´mgonna scream andshout
Get a little outta line
lain ´tgonna act
politicallycorrect
lonly wanna have agoodtime
The best thingabout beinga woman
ls theprerogative
to have a little fun and
Oh, oh, oh
Go totallycrazy
- Hi! Did you have a good nap?
- Yeah.
Stop, stop the car.
Don´t be mad. You looked so sweet
when you were sleeping.
- Wejust didn´t wanna wake you.
- Stop the car.
- It´s against the law to park here.
- It´s my car.
- We´re almost at an exit.
- Stop the damn car!
- Mimi, go talk to him.
- Uh-uh, you go talk to him.
- Nobody´s gonna go talk to him.
- I know, he´s mad.
And he has killed before.
Mimi, you said
he didn´t kill anyone.
- I said I thought he didn´t.
- Oh, my God.
- It´s okay, I´ll go.
- I´m sorry.
God!
Be careful, Lucy.
- We´re sorry.
- I´ve been in a car full ofchicks.
Do you have any idea what it´s like
being surrounded by girls?
Being a girl yourself,
I know, stupid question.
But I´m a guy, okay?
I´m a guy.Just a guy.
And I have been listening
to girl talk and watching you do...
your girl things for days.
I´m not complaining, ´cause,
let´s face it, I´m outnumbered.
But that´s my car.
It´s my car, and it´sjust--
It´s the one thing that hasn´t
been taken over by chicks.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Ben?
- Yeah?
Were you really in jail?
Yeah, I was.
- So you killed a guy?
- What?
Who said I killed a guy?
Everybody back home.
Oh, man.
No, I didn´t kill a guy.
What did you do then?
I was in college, and I get
this call from my stepsister.
She wants me to come get her ´cause
my stepdad is beating her up.
My mom can´t stop him, so...
I drive home in
the middle ofthe night...
and she throws her things out
the window and climbs out...
and then I drive her back
to school in Ohio with me.
- And you went tojail for that?
- That´s the thing.
There´s this law...
against driving a child that´s
not a relative across state lines...
and my stepdad ofcourse
pressed charges.
But, you know, it´s okay.
I only got six months...
and I had to stay in Ohio
for a year´s probation.
My sister got to go live
with her mom.
You all really thought
I killed a guy?
Yeah.
What were you thinking getting
into a car with a homicidal maniac?
- Why are we stopping?
- You´ll see.
- Mimi, you okay?
- Oh, yeah, I´m fine.
Look.
It´s like you have to whisper.
Hello!
Man. We gotta make time. The next
hotel is still an hour away.
Ben, do you have enough
sleeping bags for all of us?
You serious?
You really want to camp here?
Yeah.
It sounds like fun.
You gotta keep your thumb
on the outside like this.
Right. Now, the trick is...
you don´t want to let him know
that you´re gonna hit him.
Maybe like look away first.
And then, when he least expects it,
you throw your whole body into it.
What are you doing to her?
I´m teaching her how to fight
because every girl...
should know how
to throw a decent punch.
That was decent.
I´m gonna go to bed.
I´m gonna go to the ladies room.
Where is it again?
Third bush after the rock
over there.
- This one?
- That one, yeah.
What are you always
writing in there?
Poems, mostly.
Can I hear one?
Okay. One.
But you can´t laugh.
´´I used to think I had
the answers to everything...
but now I know that life
doesn´t always go my way.
It feels like I´m caught in the
middle, and that´s when I realize...
that I´m not a girl,
and not yet a woman.
All I need is time,
Just a moment that´s mine.
And while I´m in between,
I´m not a girl.´´
I liked it.
Really?
Yeah, really, I like it.
- What?
- You got ash on your face.
- Where?
- I´ll get it.
There.
- What´s wrong?
- What happened?
Something bit my ass.
- Let me see.
- It´s a snake bite.
No, Mimi,
that´s a mosquito bite.
Don´t look!
- How could I not? It´s nothing.
- But it could´ve been a snake.
All right! We are outta here
at the crack ofdawn.
Nothing´s biting my ass.
So we´ll be in Tucson today?
- Around 4:00, I think.
- Are you nervous?
Should I call and tell her I´m
coming, or should I just show up?
- I should just show up, right?
- Surprise is always better.
She´s gonna be
real happy to see you.
lhopeso.
You´ll call and tell me everything
about the audition, right?
-You could still come with us.
-We don´t leave town until tomorrow.
I´ll be fine, okay?
You know where we´re staying
ifyou need us.
Bye.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
I guess this is it.
I guess, yeah.
What?
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Can I help you?
It´s me, Mama-- Lucy.
Come in.
You have a really nice house.
Thankyou, Lucy.
Tucson seems like
a really nice city.
It is.
Can I askyou
why you´re here, Lucy?
I wanted to see you.
And why was that, Lucy?
Well, you´re my mother.
Why do you keep
saying my name like that?
Hold on a moment.
Hello?
Sweetie, tell Joey´s mommy I said
you could swim for another hour...
ifyou put on more sunscreen.
I don´t want you to burn.
Daddy will pickyou up at 5:00.
I love you.
- I have brothers?
- Well, yes.
- How old are they?
- Ten and seven.
Do they know about me?
Lucy, I think we need
to have a talk.
Whoa
Wait, seven, eight.
Five, six--
Come on in. Here.
- What happened?
- What´s wrong?
- Get some towels, please?
- I´m fine.
So, Luce, you got to see
your mom, right?
- Yeah, I saw her.
- And what happened?
just thought you might want
some dry clothes.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
I´m fine.
I´m okay.
I know.
Really, I´m okay.
What happened?
She said...
that she never wanted me.
She said that my father
made her have me...
and that I was
Just a mistake.
I look like her, you know?
I have her eyes and her hands.
It´s her loss, Luce.
It´s weird though, you know?
I don´t have a mother.
Well, you have us.
Yeah.
Trying to call your dad?
I can´t.
I will in a minute.
You got that poem
you read me?
- Yeah.
- Can I see it?
Yeah, sure.
It´s right here.
What are you doing?
Stop worrying so much.
Come on. I made you something.
Okay.
This is my surprise?
Wouldn´t it be sad if it was?
Like if I just totally sucked
at cheering people up.
I wrote some music
foryour poem.
Will you play it for me?
Will you sing?
just use this part
as the chorus.
- Yeah.
- Like that?
Go my way
Like that?
lt feels like l´m caught
in the middle
A little low there.
That´s when lrealize
l´m not agirl
Andnotyet a woman
Alllneedis time
A moment that ismine
While l´m in between
l´m not agirl
Thankyou.
It´s no trouble at all.
Hello, you have reachedPete
andLucy. Please leave a message.
Hi, Pop. I´m just calling to say
that I´m fine, okay?
And you were right about Mama.
You were right.
I love you, okay?
I´m fine. Bye.
l´m not the kindofgirl
you take home
lfit makesyou happy
lt can´t be that bad
Then whythe hell
areyouso sad
lfit makesyou happy
lt can´t be that bad
Then whythe hell
areyouso sad
It´s too cold. It´s freezing!
Don´t even! Don´t.
- I can´t believe we´re here.
- I know.
Ben, you know, there are
a lot ofcolleges here in L.A.
Hey, what if I didn´t go back?
I could go to school here.
I mean...
why don´t I do something
for me for once, you know?
I wanna stay.
I´m gonna stay.
Good.
Look how happy she is.
Fill this out, turn it in over
there. The audition is in six days.
Wait. Where do we turn it in?
You turn it in over there.
Fill this out--
- What about music?
- You know what?
I´ll get some flyers printed up.
I know a few guys in L.A.
I´ll try to put a band together,
and I´ll see you at the hotel.
- Okay. Great.
- Hey, where you going?
Baby? Hi, it´s me!
Guess where I am.
L.A.!
Okay. All right.
Then I´ll come to you.
All right.
Then how ´bout tonight?
Then how ´bout
tomorrow morning?
Dylan, I´m in Los Angeles!
I came to see you!
Fine.
What am I gonna say?
Me too.
He´s really busy with finals
and all. Yeah.
We´re fine.
So who wants to go sightseeing?
- I do!
- Okay! All right. Lucy?
I´m kinda tired.
Yeah, I´m pretty beat.
Well, I need you.
We can´t drive your car, remember?
Don´t wreck it.
All right!
Wait, we´re on Melrose--
I thought we were going
to see the Hollywood sign.
- We will.
- But I think it´s back that way.
I know. But we´re gonna
make a stop first, okay?
Kit, you can
see Dylan tomorrow.
- Kit, come on. Let´s go back.
- No.
- Kit, let´s go back. Please!
- No! I want to see him now.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Kit, lreallyshould wait
in the car.
- How do I look?
- You look really great.
Don´t you guys want
to be alone together?
I want you with me.
Come on.
- Surprise!
- Honey.
Hi! Oh, baby.
Kit-Kat, I thought we were
gonna make plans tomorrow.
Oh, I know. I just really wanted
to see you. This is my friend, Mimi.
You two know each other?
Yeah. From school.
Right, Mimi?
- Right.
- Yeah.
Oh. Well, aren´t you gonna
invite us in?
Yeah, I would, Kitty-Kat, but I´ve
got this friend here, and he´s--
you know, he´s really upset,
and we´re supposed to, like...
you know,
hang out or whatever.
Do you need money for the pizza?
- Your friend sounds really upset.
- Wait, Kit, hold on.
- Oh, God.
- Who´s she?
We´re supposed to be
getting married.
I was-- I was gonna tell you,
I just, you know...
didn´t want to do it
over the phone.
Dylan, you gave me a ring.
You proposed and gave me a ring!
Kit, I mean,
I´m sorry, you know?
Oh, my God.
It was Dylan, wasn´t it?
It was you.
You were the guy at Christmas.
- Wasn´t it? It was him, huh?
- What are you talking about?
That night when you came over,
you had that rip in your shirt.
- That was the night that he--
- Kit, what is your problem here?
- Kit, I have to go.
- No, Mimi, come back here.
I want him to admit it.
Admit it!
You´re getting all worked up
over nothing, Kitty-Kat.
My name is not Kitty-Kat.
I am not your pet!
Hello?
- Excuse me, where´s the phone?
- It´s right over there.
Yeah, can I make
a collect call, please?
They said I lost the baby.
´´Lost it.´´
Like it was my keys
or something.
Isn´t that the stupidest
damn thing you´ve ever heard?
I´d decided to keep her.
I was standing on the beach...
and my toes were
in the Pacific Ocean...
and she kicked.
It was like this sign.
Don´t touch me, Luce.
I´m already crying.
Okay.
I would have made a good mom.
just what were you thinking,
running away...
with a pregnant girl!
Lucy, I´m waiting
for an answer.
Do you know what it took
to come here?
I had to take cash out ofsavings
for plane fare and hotel.
I worked hard to earn that money
foryour college education.
I´m sorry.
So you made a mistake.
I understand.
Everybody makes mistakes.
You´re forgiven.
I´m gonna take you girls back
to where you belong...
and we´ll forget about
this whole crazy thing, all right?
Okay.
Who´s that boy you were with?
How old is he anyway? Is he the one
who put the crazy idea in your head?
Hejust gave us a ride.
That´s all.
Hey, sorry it took me so long.
We got a band.
- What are you doing?
- Packing.
My father says I have
to move to his hotel, so--
Until the audition?
How are we gonna rehearse?
I´m not going to the audition.
Look, I have to
go back with him, okay?
Ben, he´s my father, okay?
I just can´t--
And with everything happening
with Mimi, I just think I should go.
- No, I get it.
- Don´t be like that.
I get it. It´s okay.
It´s fine.
Did you see
how fast he went down?
It´s ´cause you threw your body
into that punch, like I taught you.
You did really good.
Hey, come here.
Thankyou.
- I´m sorry.
- It´s okay.
It´s not your fault.
Got it?
I can´t believe
this trip is over.
I know. God, doesn´t it feel like
we left home a million years ago?
Yeah.
- Hey, y´all, thanks.
- For what?
For coming on this trip with me.
Thankyou.
Mimi and I were talking...
and we were thinking--
That you need to stay
and go to the audition.
Guys, I can´t do that.
- I can´t.
- You´ve got to.
Kit and I voted, and you lost,
so you´ve got to go.
All right, baby,
ready to head home?
- I´m coming.
- Ladies...
let´s roll.
Come on, let´s go.
We tried.
Here you go, buddy.
- Thankyou, sir.
- I´ll take that, sweetie.
Good-bye, Lucy.
Good-bye.
It´s gonna feel good
to get back home, won´t it?
Look, honey...
I´m sorry I yelled at you.
I wasn´t angry at you.
I was angry at what you did.
- Okay?
- Okay.
I don´t want to be like her.
We´ll just get back home, and
everything´ll be back to normal.
You just wait and see.
Don´t make me do
what she did.
Don´t make me run.
just let me go, okay?
What are you--
lusedto think
lhadthe answers
to everything
But nowlknow
That life doesn ´t always
Go my way
Yeah
Feels like l´m caught
in the middle
That´s when lrealize
l´m not agirl
Notyet a woman
Alllneedis time
A moment that ismine
While l´m in between
l´m not agirl
There isno need
toprotect me
lt´s time that l
Learnedto face up to this
On myown
l´veseen so much more
thanyou knownow
So don´t tellme
to shut my eyes
But ifyou lookat me closely
You willsee it in my eyes
Thisgirl willalways find
Her way
l´m not agirl
Don´t tellme what to believe
l´mjust trying to find
the woman in me, yeah
My baby!
This time, we didn ´t make
any wishes forthe future.
We saidgood-bye to ourpast.
Now, none ofushasany idea
where life´sgonna take us...
´cause what we have isnow.
Andright now,
we have each other.
- Let´s do this thing!
- Action!