You lived with him when he was nothing.
You suffered his youth
and endured the years of struggle.
You're entitled to half
of everything he has.
l'm not married,
so l don't know what it's like...
to face the conclusion
of a decades-old relationship.
And l don't have children, so l can't say...
how the final disposition of the offspring
would impact me emotionally.
But l can say this much.
You have it within your means
to grind your husband into the ground.
l don't know if l want to go quite that far.
Mrs. Arnold, you came to me
because you wanted financial protection.
lf you want sympathy,
you won't get it here.
You won't get emotion from me,
l'm not an emotional person.
What does grinding him
into the ground involve?
Going for his weakest spot.
He's a public man, a politician.
-You threaten his image.
-How?
We immediately begin documenting
his sexual improprieties.
That's awfully personal.
Table for two, please.
Nonsmoking.
By the window, if you have it.
Tesio.
Tesio, go and notify Albert
that we have a situation.
l have no tables. They're all reserved.
Are you familiar with the city ordinance...
Title 2, Chapter 160, Section 010?
''All persons shall have equal access
to public services,'' and so forth and so on.
ln short, l have every right
to be in this restaurant.
Not so long as that restaurant
has a dress code...
-and that dress code requires a tie--
-Tie? Right here.
Well, l guess it's time for me
to be moving on. Thank you very much--
l don't need the help. lt's not necessary.
No, no!
Why don't you pick on someone
your own size, you big, ugly chump?
Mrs. Arnold dropped by
to say hello on her way out.
She looked like she'd seen a ghost.
What did you do?
Told her what her options are.
l don't think she wants
to destroy her husband...
and l don't want this firm being known
for ruining Frank Arnold.
Don't tell me how to do my work.
Go easy on this divorce,
or l'll put another attorney on it.
Who are you trying to protect?
A law firm, a wife, kids....
Things you know nothing about, Grey,
and l feel sorry for you.
-Well, don't lose too much sleep.
-Hey, lighten up!
You keep going at 190 miles an hour,
you're going to hit something.
All right, take this stick...
and l want you to crack me
right on the top of the head, all right?
Forget it.
Honey, you have to do it.
lt's not going to hurt me, l swear.
We talked about this
all the way from Detroit.
Yeah, but that was talking.
Talking is different than doing.
Right, and if it wasn't, we could
talk our way into a million dollars...
and a nice high-rise penthouse.
We have to do the doing,
not the talking. Come on.
-You're going to cry.
-Have you ever seen me cry, honey?
-No, but l've seen you sad.
-That's not crying, is it?
You can cry and not feel sad,
just like you can feel sad and not cry.
Now, come on.
We've got to hurry with this.
We've got things to do, all right?
Now, however much you love me...
that's how hard you hit me, okay?
-l love you a lot.
-Well, then...
the harder you hit me,
the more l know you love me.
-Okay.
-That a girl.
All right.
Dinner.
You killed my daddy!
Help!
This is a goddamn joke.
She's looking at us.
Give her the $25 smile.
Where in the name of all that's holy
have you been?
l hit a man with my car.
There.
l almost had that lady's purse,
but you blew it.
-l had it right in my hand.
-Tough. We don't steal.
But we cheat.
-A little, but we don't steal.
-We lie.
A little more than we cheat,
but that's not right, either.
lt's because of the times.
Right, we don't steal,
and we don't break any laws.
-Some laws we do.
-Not the good ones.
Stay there. l'll come get you.
This stinks like trouble.
God, l don't need this. Where are you?
Rocky Feller's House of Beef, on Randolph.
Did anyone see you enter?
l don't think so.
l'll be there right away.
All done.
You should have joined us, ma'am.
Wasn't that was a great meal, honey?
Sure dirty.
This angel's not only
the cutest girl in the world...
she's also the smartest.
Why don't you spell something for her?
How about ''asphyxiate''?
A-S-P...
T-bone! Heavy on the meat!
Easy on the bone! Potato! Hot potato!
No, thank you, l've ridden
better-looking meat than that. Bear right.
...l-A-T-E.
You ever seen anything like that?
That's a big word for such a little girl.
Hello, Doris.
Let's go.
This is the gentleman l mentioned
on the phone and his daughter.
-Pleased to meet you.
-Nice to meet you, also.
l'm William Dancer. Bill.
She's a pretty little girl.
You must be very proud.
Doris....
l'm extremely grateful
for your kindness, ma'am.
You're a lucky man
to have such a good-hearted wife.
No, we're not married--
Good night, and good luck.
We'd like to repay you for the meal.
-That's not necessary.
-No, the child here...
makes a real pretty refrigerator picture.
She can draw just about anything.
Thank you, no. Good night.
We didn't get nothing but dinner.
She looked like $50 for sure.
We take what we get.
-We had her, Bill. The guy screwed it up.
-You know...
that's just the kind of lady
you should be praying for to be your mom.
Why? Who needs a mom?
You don't have a mom,
and you came out all right.
Grab some napkins
and use the washroom.
Okay.
Here.
Go brush your teeth.
-l brushed my teeth in Detroit.
-So you brush your teeth in Chicago now.
Okay.
lf you're not back in five minutes,
l'll come.
-ln a ladies' bathroom?
-That's right.
Don't fool around in there.
What'll you give me for this?
lt's not much. A ruby?
l don't know. You look at it.
Look, l'll give you $15. Take it or leave it.
Done.
Now get out of here, before l call the cops.
Thanks, you jerk.
-l'm sorry about your ring, honey.
-lt's okay.
l'll get you another one.
That would make me feel nervous.
Why would a ring make you nervous?
When someone gives you something
to remember them by, it means they'll go.
lf they're going to stay, you don't need
anything, because they'll be there.
You worry too much.
Tell me about the Frank Arnold divorce.
lt sounds wonderfully filthy and sick.
You know l can't tell you anything,
so why do you ask?
He's incredibly corrupt.
What if you need a favor sometime?
With the material l'm gathering,
l'll get favors for the rest of my life.
Like what kind of material? Photos?
Let's change the subject.
Something's wrong.
Something's bothering you.
l can't stop thinking
about what happened last night.
What's there to think about?
lt happened. lt's over.
You'll never see those people again.
-Hello?
-Walker.
lt's mine.
Don't you want any?
l'll have what you don't finish.
That won't be anything pretty soon.
What part don't you want?
-The meat?
-No, you need the meat.
No, l don't.
All right, l'll take the meat.
You eat the egg. You need the egg.
Okay. Here's the meat.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
Look, after we finish here...
l need to check into a job...
and then we'll go to the art museum.
-l hate the art museum.
-Will it hurt you to learn a thing or two?
All you learn from the art museum
is how to keep your mouth shut...
and how to walk
without making your shoes squeak.
All right, then l'll put you in school.
-No, welfare people would take me away.
-Not if l have a job and a nice place to live.
You haven't got legal custody. We'd get
caught and cops will throw you in jail.
ls that a nice thing to say?
We wouldn't even be talking about this
if you'd got money out of that lady.
We'd be on the road.
You didn't because she was too pretty.
-She was too smart.
-And she was too pretty.
-She was in a hurry.
-She was going to catch onto us.
-And she was too pretty.
You're pretty, and l don't leave you alone.
She was too pretty.
All right, if l say she was too pretty,
will you put a cork in it?
Promise?
She was too pretty.
l knew it!
Hubba-hubba.
Grey!
Grey.
Slow down! My legs are moving so fast
my pantyhose are melting.
Mrs. Arnold called. She sounded pissed.
She needs to see you tomorrow,
so l told her 2:30 pm, okay?
Fine.
Walker called. He has a dinner meeting
and probably won't come over.
But if you need to have sex,
that's what he said...
go ahead over to his place
after your dinner.
Call him and decline.
-Mr. Oxbar--
-l really have to go.
-We ain't beggars, right?
-Right.
Then what's the point
of going to find that lady again?
-Are you hungry?
-Not much.
Well, l am. There's no harm in showing
our face around her again...
to see if she'll offer another meal.
That's begging.
No, begging is asking in a pathetic fashion.
You're splitting hairs, Bill.
Hell, l'd rather sing for my supper
than sit in a parking lot.
They stink to all holy heaven.
Look, we're going to wait in the garage...
we'll look like we're doing some business,
and if she comes out...
if she feels kind, we'll take her kindness.
-And if she doesn't come out--
-We freeze our nuts off.
You don't have any nuts
to freeze off, honey.
Come on, baby. What's the matter?
This is the place. Let's go.
My lips are chapped
and l have to find my lip grease.
Women.
Now you've really killed him!
There are no broken bones,
no contusions, no abrasions.
A few lesions, not of your doing.
That wound on his forehead
is a day or two old.
l did that yesterday.
You hit him twice?
What he needs is soap...
a razor, a good meal, bed rest...
and then a good swift kick in the behind.
You're crazy to let a person like that
stay in your house.
The little girl is his daughter.
She could use a little soap, too.
This is a matter for the city...
not a single woman living alone.
l'm sure it looks worse than it is.
l appreciate your concern, but it's okay.
Sorry, l fell asleep,
seeing as how l was so extremely tired.
You'll get to go to sleep
in just a minute, okay?
-Thank you for coming up.
-Don't be silly.
This is the stuff
of 10:00 news lead stories...
but you're over 21 .
l'll sleep with my door locked.
l'm in the building. l can be here
in two seconds if you need me.
-Thanks.
-Good night, dear.
This is very excellent.
l never knew pizza was so good
when it was hot.
Think Bill would want some?
l think Bill's better off resting.
His whole life is nothing
but a thousand miles of bad road.
The doctor said he's going to be fine.
Don't tell Bill he saw a doctor.
lt's against his faith.
Oh, no. That's his
afraid-to-die-alone groan.
You keep eating,
and l'll go see how he is, okay?
Okay. Tell him to hold on...
and tell him to be strong
and don't leave me.
He's going to be all right.
He's not going anywhere.
lt's me.
-Where am l?
-ln my apartment. l hit you with my car.
ls it yesterday?
l hit you again.
-Where's my child?
-She's in the kitchen eating pizza.
Bigtime.
lt's a shame we don't steal.
Your daughter's had a bath,
and l have a room ready for her.
l'd like you to at least stay the night.
-Are your folks religious people?
-Not really.
-l'm surprised.
-Why?
Because you're a saint.
There are fresh towels in the bathroom.
l'll see that your daughter gets to bed.
Thank you.
l have the apartment wired for security.
There's a man downstairs.
l need only touch a button.
l don't mean to be harsh or unkind...
but l don't know you,
and you're in my home.
Now, if you have any dishonest inklings,
l caution you that l'm no fool.
l understand, ma'am.
Ma'am...
for the record...
l'm no criminal.
Good night.
How many people live here?
-Just me.
-Whose are all those clothes?
They're mine.
-How come your bed's so huge?
-l like a big bed.
You got an awful lot of pillow
for just one person.
Well....
How come you have so many TVs?
l must have seen three already.
How's this?
lt won't be the most beautiful outfit
in the world, but l think it'll do.
How come this smells so good?
lt's clean.
Why don't you take
that room next to mine?
That'll be your room for tonight.
Try that on,
and l'll come to say good night.
Ma'am, you're so nice.
My name is Grey.
-Mrs. Grey?
-No, just Grey.
-What's your name?
-Curly Sue.
l bet l know why they call you Curly Sue.
'Cause you got all that beautiful curly hair.
No.
lt's because this guy we wintered with,
Tampa Joe Reilly...
thought l looked like
the big oaf in the Three Stooges.
He said it so much that it stuck. See ya.
How come you don't have any kids?
You have plenty of dough for lots of them.
lt would be hard for me to have children.
l'm not married.
Kids don't come from weddings,
you know.
-They come from right down--
-No. l know.
The proper way to have a family
is to start with a wedding, isn't it?
Well, unless you have a baby first.
l want to have seven babies.
l'm naming them Monday, Tuesday,
Wednesday, Thursday, Friday...
Saturday, and Bill. After Bill.
Can l ask you
why you call your father Bill?
Well...
if l'm in a crowded place and l yell...
''Dad! '' 50 guys would turn around.
lf l yell ''Bill! '' maybe two will turn around.
lt's a timesaver, really.
You better get some sleep.
Good night.
Excuse me, where is the guy
you were with yesterday?
-He had to work late.
-ls he a cop?
No. Good night.
-Ma'am?
-Yes?
l bet he loves you a lot.
l hope so. Good night.
l know how you can tell.
-How?
-He lets you eat first.
Sweet dreams.
-Hi.
-You okay?
-Yeah, l'm fine.
l mean, l feel like l got hit by a car.
You got hit by a car.
-You okay?
-Yeah.
Come here.
What's the matter, baby?
l've never slept by myself
since l was a baby.
You'll love it.
You don't get kicked so much.
But what if l get scared?
There's no reason to be scared.
Know why?
Because when you're alone...
angels come to the window.
You open it up...
they float into the room over your bed.
And if you're asleep...
they'll come down...
and kiss your eyelids...
and they give you the sweetest,
most wonderful dreams you'll ever have.
-ls this true?
-Sure, it's true.
You sure?
Yeah. Now, come here and give me a hug.
Come on.
-l love you, Bill.
-Oh, baby.
l love you, too, honey.
You know, we're very lucky today.
-You go to bed.
-Okay.
-All right? Get some rest.
Go on.
We have now come to the end
of our program day...
and we'll join you tomorrow
at the regular time. Good night.
Play ball.
Shoot, she's mad.
-You're nuts!
-Will you keep your voice down?
Am l hallucinating?
You have two derelicts in your apartment.
-lt's a long story.
-And a weird one...
which l'm stopping
as soon l can focus my eyes.
l'm sorry l hit you. l didn't recognize you.
That speaks well for our relationship.
l was ripped from my sleep
by a screaming child--
That damn urchin
gave me a pop you wouldn't believe.
Knuckle punch, in the nose.
l asked you to keep your voice down!
l told you last night you were itching for it,
buying those two food.
How the hell did they end up here?
l hit him with my car again.
Exactly what time
were you born yesterday?
lt's crazy, but it's true.
Did you ever think that this monkey
is throwing himself in front of your car?
Jig's up, Bill.
You are an educated woman
in a position of responsibility...
in major law firm,
making a tremendous living.
What happened to you?
What caused you
to invite vagabonds into your home?
l'm not stupid!
l had my bedroom door locked.
Oh, then you were perfectly safe.
l didn't sense any danger.
lf l had, l wouldn't have done it.
No danger? l got slugged twice
in five seconds!
That was an accident!
l'm sure when you got into bed
you scared the hell out of Curly Sue.
Curly Sue? That's cute!
What is she, the lost Stooge?
l don't know what the hell
is going on here...
and l can't explain so you'd understand.
English, French, Hebrew, Mandarin,
it'd be the same.
You're nuts!
And you're abusive and insensitive!
Don't get holy because
you've endangered your life for no reason!
You can let yourself out.
No! l'm not leaving you here alone
with them in the house. No way, babe.
Then sleep on the sofa.
The guest rooms are taken!
Hi.
Anise?
Could you call my housekeeper and tell
her l have guests, so she's not alarmed?
All right, just to make this fair...
to make sure there's no suspicion...
l'm going to allow the little lady to deal.
Okay?
-Okay.
-Deal, honey.
That seems fair.
Shuffle them up.
She's gotten better.
Okay. Why don't you deal?
-l'm going to raise $10.
-$10, okay.
l'll stay, you've taken half my paycheck.
But if you win, l'll work for you for a week.
Crybabies never win, lady.
Shut up. You can barely see over the table.
l may not be able to see over the table,
but l have the other half of your paycheck.
-Bill?
-lt's the missus!
Trina?
Trina, l'm home!
What is going on?
Open the door, please!
Open the door!
Why was the door locked?
-The child must have done it.
-Yeah.
-How's the gentleman?
-He's really sick.
Yeah, he's really....
l only saw him for a second this morning.
And, l went in there, and he was just....
God, he's all sweating and everything.
l just kept running by there today.
l wouldn't even go in.
l'd just run by, and he'd be groaning
and making all sorts of noises....
Kind of freaks me out.
-Do you smoke cigars?
-Yeah.
-l wish you wouldn't in my home.
-Yeah. l understand that.
That's reasonable.
See, l don't usually smoke cigars.
lt's just that my friend had a baby.
Your dad sure ate a lot
for someone who doesn't feel well.
Well, he's like a camel with a hump.
You know how camels
keep food and water in their humps?
Only his hump is his stomach.
l'm sure he feels awful, but
when you've a chance to load the hump...
you load the hump. That's our philosophy.
You're a smart little girl.
l'm very smart. l know a lot of stuff.
Do you know how to read?
Sure.
l can also do math
and spell extremely large words.
Like ''asphyxiate?''
-Yeah. A-S-P-H-Y-x--
-Try a small one.
Excuse me?
Spell ''cat.''
l will later.
How about right now?
l can't.
Just as l thought.
-Hi.
-What's going on?
-l'm recuperating--
-Knock it off!
-What are you doing with that little girl?
-What do you mean?
Has she ever been to school?
-Briefly, from time to time.
-She's completely ignorant.
She's not ignorant.
-She's illiterate.
-That's not ignorant.
You're using her, aren't you?
-No, ma'am.
-Liar.
You use her in your little cons.
lt's pathetic. lt's criminal.
l guess it's time to go.
Go ahead. You're not taking her.
-You're going to stop me?
-The police will.
You're going to call the police?
You're not taking her out of here.
You're leaving, and she's staying.
-You don't know a thing about this.
-l know neglect when l see it.
-She's not neglected.
-She's abused.
-l am very serious, Mr. Dancer.
-Kiss my ass, lady.
l've raised that kid from a baby.
We've beat worse things
than some do-good, high-rise legal eagle...
with a jones for arms-length social reform.
Now step aside, before l throw
your pampered ass in the closet.
You don't scare me.
l've got nothing to lose but that kid.
You try taking that kid away from me,
l'm going to knock your damn head off.
lf you love her...
give her a chance.
Okay. How?
Does the state of lllinois
know what's right for her?
Sure, they'll teach her how to read,
and how to be a freak.
And when people bitch about welfare,
they'll be bitching about her.
Bill, you can't feed her.
You can't clothe her.
How do you know
she won't freeze to death...
or get beat up or kidnapped?
What if something happens to you,
and she ends up in the middle of nowhere?
l get by. l survive.
l've been doing it her whole life.
Where's her mother?
She's buried in Florida.
You want to know the rest of the story?
l'm not her father.
l met her mother one night in a bar.
Some people get VD
from a one-night stand, l got a baby.
She knows all about it.
We've got no secrets.
lf there was another life for her...
l'd cut my throat to give it to her.
l didn't come in here to ruin your life.
Our paths crossed, and you ended up here.
You're right.
You got scammed. l got a knock
on the head, and the rest is bull.
l've got a lot of tricks.
l've been at it a long time.
You play something until it's over...
and this is over.
No tears.
l must be crazy.
Stay as long as you like.
l'm sorry.
You better go to sleep.
-Did Bill give me to you?
-No.
He's always looking for somebody.
A father always looks
for the best life he can give his child.
There's nothing wrong with my life.
l didn't mean that.
lt's just that as you grow up and become
a young lady, there are going to be...
things...
and situations that will be...
difficult for a man.
All the stuff that happens to women,
l already know.
The boobs, the kissing,
the babies, the crabby time...
the not wearing lipstick till you're 16...
the underwear bank robbers wear
on their faces....
-There's a little more to it than that.
-Half of it, l don't care for.
Pink dresses, kittens,
spending time in your bathroom...
crying when something's real cute....
Frankly, that makes me lose my belly.
Well....
You're a very smart little girl
who knows herself very well.
But, l promise you, there will be times
when you'll wish for a woman to talk to.
-l doubt it.
-Okay.
Well, we talked about it...
and you can think about it.
And if you feel you have
the need to discuss it....
Bill will take care of it.
Better get some sleep.
Good night.
Do you mind if l watch TV for a while?
For a little while.
-Did you see Bill this morning?
-Nope.
-What time did you get up?
-lt was still dark.
What's wrong?
He's gone.
-Did he leave a note?
-No.
Did he leave a ring? A little one?
-Then he'll be back.
l hope you know
you're making me miss Flipper.
You've got to work. lf you don't go
to school, you have to work.
Everybody's got to do something
when they get big.
l'm not going to be a bathtub washer.
Really? What are you going to be, then?
Maybe a lawyer.
You know how long
you have to go to school to be a lawyer?
-How long?
-Twenty years.
Slap my butt, no way.
Do you want to save your marriage?
What about the pictures
and the tape recordings?
lt's terrible, it's disgusting,
but before we go on, l need to know:
Do you want to leave him?
That's what l thought.
Let's work on that.
Are you all right?
You seem a little nice.
Thanks.
-How was your day?
-Total pisser.
l'm too tired to lecture you
about using that kind of language.
Sorry. lt slipped out.
-Did Bill call?
-Nope.
Shouldn't he be home by now?
Hello?
Hi.
Guess what?
l got a job.
Great!
Yeah. lt's not a great job, but it's work.
l get my first paycheck in a week.
l haven't done that in a long time.
-l'm very proud of you.
-Yeah?
lt's no big deal, really.
lt just feels better to be working.
l know.
-What's your problem?
-You.
She doesn't take to change very well.
She'll be all right.
-May l help you?
May we help you?
l feel like an idiot.
You look very pretty.
Very, very....
Where are the shoes l gave you?
She's got nice hair.
These?
These tights itch. Pants. What are these?
These things stick to your butt.
Bill?
ls everything all right?
l feel like a goddamn fool.
Can it be that bad?
You look great!
Think so?
You've got a tag on you.
You don't need it.
l need it for Sue. She gets a runny nose.
-You look really pretty.
-Thank you.
So, you hungry?
Yeah. Let's eat.
l hate this.
Good evening.
Kiss, kiss.
These are my friends.
William Dancer and his daughter Susan.
What a lovely little girl you are.
-May l?
-May you what?
Kiss your cheek.
ln a pig's eye.
-Good evening.
-We've met.
Yes. Bill Dancer, Chairman of the Board,
First lllinois State Bank.
Very powerful man.
-No.
-No?
City Ordinance.
Title 2, Chapter 160, Section 010.
Ring a bell?
My God!
Take my coat.
This was a joke, yes? lt was a joke?
A little funny, no?
Hang our coats.
To be entirely honest with you,
you smelled quite bad.
You see, the other day,
there wasn't all that many options for--
Your table is right this way.
When you suggested dinner
l didn't realize you were bringing the kids.
l thought it would be a nice surprise.
You succeeded mightily.
You remember Walker.
Yes. Good evening.
You'll pardon my incredulity.
l presumed you'd be gone by now.
l'm not.
You look like you got hit by a razor
and a bar of soap.
-Scotch and soda?
-Right away, sir.
Where did you get the spiffy new duds?
From me.
Boy, you two have hit the jackpot.
How's the grub?
You were late, and Susan got hungry.
So we went ahead and ordered.
l'm suddenly not very hungry.
What did you order? Beans?
Let's call it an evening.
-No, it's fine.
-No, it's not.
l'm not going to eat this,
l'm not going to take that.
Come on, Sue.
This time, keep going.
Sit down.
You had no right to do that.
Told you this was a bad idea.
lt's no fun being somebody's toys.
That's what we are.
-l'm ashamed of us.
-Don't ever say that.
Excuse me, but l am.
Tell me what's going on?
l don't see you for a few days
and you're playing dress-up.
You're serious about this?
How did you get to be a lawyer?
You send in a couple of bucks
and a label from a box of Frosted Flakes?
Good night!
Bill!
Bill, come on.
Hush up.
l'm so sorry.
Good.
lt won't do us any good.
lt's too late. We're offended.
Just knock it off, all right?
Walker's an ass.
lf you took anything he said to heart...
you're just as big an ass as he is.
This thing's a joke, you know that?
The whole thing's a joke.
The coat, the gloves, everything.
lt's not doing any of us any good.
Get it? Do you see what l'm saying?
Bill, where are you going to go?
l'm going to go. We'll be fine.
We've never had a problem
finding a place to stay, all right?
Go back there. We'll go this way.
We'll be just fine.
l don't want you to leave.
l'll tell you one thing...
we're not going back
into that stuck-up hash house.
Me, either. Let's go somewhere else.
Anywhere. Your choice.
How about if we take you out?
Bill, you don't have any money.
We don't need money.
lt never stopped us before.
-Okay.
-Come on.
A toast to Tiffany and Adam.
Health, wealth, and happiness.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
lt's okay. He does it all the time.
l'd like to make a toast...
He's a pro.
...to the bride and groom,
Tiffany and Adam.
May you always have a passion for life.
And may your life be filled with passion.
Now my wife Doris would like
to say something. Doris?
Would you like to say
a few words to the bride and groom?
l couldn't.
For Adam and Tiffany, please.
She has a few things to say.
Come on, stand up and say something.
First of all, it's just so good to be here.
You know, it's just...
such a great event.
And...
l can hardly remember
the last time l saw little Tiffany...
when she was just that big.
But now she's....
About here?
l guess it was at...
our wedding in Vegas.
lt was a beautiful wedding,
but nothing like this.
-No.
-Oh, boy.
-Very well-put.
-Thank you.
-Salute!
Hi. Cold out there, huh?
Oh, boy.
Okay. Tickets, sir?
l had them. Didn't l have them?
You're holding up the line here.
Why don't you step to the side?
-No, l got them.
-Maybe you dropped them.
Excuse me. l'm sorry.
-Did l give you the tickets?
-No, you didn't give them to me.
Sorry, maybe we dropped them outside.
What should we do?
Go to the box office, sir.
They can help you out.
Go by the box office, okay?
There we are.
What?
Where'd you get the popcorn?
Thirsty?
-Grey?
-Thanks.
Thanks.
This is great!
Come here.
Chicago.
Department of Children
and Family Services.
Abuse and Neglect.
-Grey!
-Good morning.
Bernie, what a pleasant surprise.
Did we have a meeting?
l've stopped trying to fix meetings, Grey.
You're never in.
That's not true.
Obviously something is bothering you.
What are you doing?
Every time l've called the last few days,
you're not in.
l've had personal business to attend to.
l don't know if personal business...
or the time it's taken from work
has anything to do with it...
but you've got this Arnold divorce
all screwed up.
Nothing's screwed up.
l told her to return to her husband.
-She did.
-What's the problem?
He wanted her out.
That's why l told you to go easy.
He wanted out,
but not to give up everything.
l guess it's his tough luck.
Do you have photographs of Frank Arnold?
-l'll say.
-Destroy them.
No.
Not if he's going to screw her
out of what she's entitled to.
Destroy them. No opposition on this.
He wants the grounds. He wants the kids.
And try spending a little more time
in the office.
Are you Susan Dancer?
Hiya, pigeon.
You're looking sharp.
l can't talk.
Where's the ring?
Tell me where the ring is.
l pawned it. Ogden and Madison.
This situation is totally unnecessary.
l'm an attorney.
The child was in my care, in my home.
Her needs were being met.
There was no reason to take her away.
Ma'am, you aren't a legal guardian.
She can't possibly understand
what's happening to her.
She's in protective custody.
She's being properly cared for.
ln 48 hours, a shelter-care hearing
will be called in juvenile court.
You're welcome to attend.
l love this little girl.
lt's understandable, but...
from my position,
it's completely irrelevant.
Yo, Dancer. You're out of here.
Your lawyer just posted bond for you.
You got a cute lawyer, too.
Did you ever get those
plantar's warts taken care of?.
My aunt Bernice had hers cut out.
-Frank Arnold?
-Pumpkin, l'm on the phone.
You know, they're so sensitive.
Aunt Bernice had those.
The schnauzer stepped on her,
l thought she'd go through the ceiling.
ls he in? Yes or no?
Have a seat, let me finish my call,
and then l'll tell you.
Try those air-pillow insoles.
Maybe the water kind. Put them
in the fridge and freeze your foot.
l need to see him.
What a pity.
He has a meeting in five minutes.
l'm sorry. He has a meeting right now.
l'll call you right back.
lf you want to do business with the city--
Missy!
What the hell?
l'm Grey Ellison, your wife's attorney.
l'll get back to you.
Who do you think you are,
busting in here like this.
-l'm in a hurry.
-Lady, so am l.
Your wife loves you. She wants you back.
Other sources say
you don't want her back.
l'd like you to work it out,
and l'd like a favor from you.
Are you nuts?
l got a list of names
and some pretty racy photos...
of a certain city official in a blue Speedo.
l don't want to be a bitch...
but l have a problem,
and l need some strings pulled.
You never destroyed
those photographs, did you?
You took them to Frank Arnold
so he could pull strings at the D.C.F.S.
You learned a few tricks
from the old master, didn't you?
Bernie, l want you to buy me out.
You realize how many people would...
kill for what you've achieved
in such a short amount of time?
You got a partnership,
a corner office big enough for basketball.
What are you giving it up for? Love?
You got your value system
all screwed up somewhere along the line.
l think it was screwed up before.
l got to admit...
you're the last one l ever thought
would go quality-of-life on me.
Honey....
Grey, l think you owe me an explanation.
l don't owe you anything!
Four years together
doesn't mean anything?
At least, after the way you've behaved,
you owe me an apology.
Did you turn in my friend
and his daughter?
What makes you think that?
Did you?
There's nothing to hide,
it's a concerned phone call.
Yes or no?
What difference does it make?
-Just answer me!
-Yes.
l thought so.
Grey....
up yours!
Grey? Grey!
Wait, Grey! Stop the car.
There it is.
That's it.
They cut my hair.
-Let's get out of here, okay?
-Okay.
Am l out of this jam for good?
Almost. They have to run
a check on your family.
That's easy. There isn't any.
Then they'll run a check on me,
and if everything...
meets with their approval,
l'll get temporary custody.
And then, with your permission,
we'll start the adoption proceedings.
What does Bill say?
He can't adopt you, honey.
Not now, anyway.
Because he's shiftless.
lt's more complicated than that.
Anyway, it doesn't matter...
because l'll have you and he'll be with me.
-Why didn't he come with you?
-He had to work.
You know that for sure?
That's what he said. Why?
You don't have to be a genius
to figure it out.
He got me a mother, didn't he?
He can leave anytime he wants now.
Bill?
l can't read it.
lt says:
''l'm in the living room.''
Hi.
Come here.
Look. No swearing...
no gambling, no spitting, no punching,
and no kicking.
Put a sock in it. l know what l'm doing.
Want us to walk you in?
No, l got it, but thanks for asking.
All right, give us a kiss.
Please. We're in public.
Good luck.