Makkhi, do you know what the
sweetest thing in this world is?
Mango.
I bet. By the time we grow up..
..there'll be sugarcane growing
in the entire village. - How?
The land belongs to our father.
So we're its owners, aren't we?
Makkhi is a fool.
Everything in this house
belongs to the two of you equally.
And why would Mr. Pandey
distinguish between his children.
He's a father to the two of you.
Step-father.
He's only Makkhi's father.
If he really considered me his son..
..he wouldn't have
treated me like a servant.
Don't say that, son.
You were only two years old
when your father passed away.
You can never imagine what a
widowed mother has to face.
That's when Mr. Pandey married me.
Accepted you as his son.
He gave you his name.
'Your son's stars
are very fortunate.'
'Make him a businessman.
- I see.'
Makkhi is weak, son.
He's a fool.
Doesn't concentrate on studies.
But he's my son after all.
I gave birth to him.
He's your brother.
- Step-brother.
Astrologer, check my
horoscope as well.
You need to pay his fees first.
You've money to show
this dimwit's horoscope..
..but not for us.
Insolent.
Why are you crying?
I'm cursing your fate dimwit.
I see.
The day I become someone..
..I will make you
father-son's plight so bad..
Just the thought makes me laugh.
Move.
Move!
Move aside.
What's going on here?
Come on, out with it.
Everyone leave behind
your goods and step aside.
Come on.
This is strange.
Do you know the penalty of
killing a police officer?
21 years of
imprisonment along with thrashing.
And if this police
officer shot you..
..then guaranteed promotion.
And a medal too.
This was just the trailer.
The real picture starts now.
Here. Here.
Give it to me.
Give me money.
Give me.
That's a nice caller-tune.
Forward it to me.
Hi. Bye.
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no don't
hit me. Don't hit me.
That's just great.
You made me tired.
I didn't come here to beat you.
You robbed the
bank and I robbed you.
Answer the call, whose call is it?
My mother.
- Give my regards.
On that note I remembered.
Why you..
- Sir.
I was just asking if he's
got a mother. - She's dead.
If you continue doing this..
..then someday I'll
send you to your mother.
Remember that.
Stop. Yes.
The force is finally here.
Welcome. Please, welcome.
Hello, sir.
We're present on duty, sir.
Where are the rascals?
On that note I just remembered,
Chaubey..
..how is your respected father?
He's doing fine, sir.
- Good.
Look, the robbers are lying inside.
Let those poor things go.
- Let them go.
But then how will
you get promotion, sir?
I'll tell you how, Chaubey.
Make a report.
The police surrounded the robbers..
..and there was cross-firing.
And one of our
young police officers..
..was wounded in the cross-firing.
Wounded? But
everyone's absolutely fine, sir.
Who was wounded, Chaubey?
- Me, sir. Me.
Does anyone else want promotion?
- No, sir.
No, no.
- Next time.
Hold this.
Let's go.
''Fearless.''
''Strong hearted.''
''Looks like a rock.''
''Always first to fight.''
''Fearless.''
''A fighter, always willing.''
''Looks like the leader.''
''Fearless.''
''He does the impossible.''
''His roar breaks
the deadly silence.''
''Fearless.''
''When it's a
question of his honour.''
''He can even lay down his life.''
''He's the savoir.''
''The fearless one.''
''He's brave.''
''Never lets his prey out of sight.''
''Always strikes his enemy.''
''The fearless one.''
''He does the impossible.''
''His roar breaks
the deadly silence.''
''Fearless.''
''Strong hearted.''
''Looks like a rock.''
''Always first to fight.''
''Fearless.''
''A fighter, always willing.''
''Looks like the leader.''
''Fearless.''
Makkhi.
Get up.
There's no water in the tap.
What should I do?
The tank must be empty.
- How?
The tank will be filled
only when we have electricity.
Your father doesn't have servants.
I don't have a father either.
If I had a father I
would've made it really big.
Chulbul, mind your language.
If you're so proud of yourself..
..then why don't you
install a generator?
This is your house as well.
And I've heard..
..that you're really prospering
in your police job these days.
Really?
Pandey.
You're jealous of my progress.
You're a grown up now
don't you have any manners.
Mother, people have
conducted a research.
They say that eating bread increases
the blood-count in the body.
Give me two extra bread pieces.
It'll increase the
blood-count in my body.
Give a glow on my face.
You're strange, Mother.
- Father.
I'm leaving, Mother.
Get up.
- Chulbul. Chulbul.
Have you gone mad?
Listen.
Mother has the
duplicate keys to the safe.
Take the money from mother..
..and buy a portable
generator from the market.
Buy the most expensive one.
Miser.
Get up!
If you wake me up like this..
..God won't forgive you.
- Really?
Which God? The God
of 'Makkhi's' (flies).
Chaubey, is everything fine?
Yes, sir. Everything's fine.
But, sir, my left hand
has become useless now.
It becomes very inconvenient for me.
You're absolutely right, Chaubey.
Don't worry. I've sent an
application to the government.
Soon I'll get a spray
fitted in your bathroom.
Can we talk?
- Yes, sir.
This is Rs.100,000 for you.
- But, sir..
Yes. I accepted money for
letting the robbers run away.
The government gives
Rs.50,000 to the wounded..
..and Rs.100,000 for the deceased.
And that too to the
dead soldier's wife.
You're the first
soldier in this country..
..that's getting Rs.100,000.
And you're also
receiving it yourself.
That's great.
Sister-in-law, there's
another benefit in it. - Yes.
His left hand is useless now.
So he'll drop the bad habit
of chewing tobacco. - Yes.
Shall we go, Chaubey?
- Yes.
And resume duty soon.
Give it to me.
Sir is just.. He's too decent.
That's 50,000.
Will it be sufficient?
And my commission.
- What? Commission.
It's your brother's money.
And you want
commission from this as well.
Yes. I am asking for it,
and not stealing it.
Ask Chulbul for it. I
can't give you anything.
Why? Aren't you my mother?
Don't talk nonsense, Makkhi.
What nonsense.
You always support Chulbul.
I feel like I don't have a mother.
I feel like an orphan.
Fine.
Okay.
Here. Keep this.
And don't talk such nonsense.
Chulbul has lost his mind.
And you've become so dramatic.
I want 2000 more.
Here. Are you happy now?
Makkhi, run.
Run, Makkhi.
I won't keep running each time.
When we do want to get married..
..then why don't I discuss it now.
Isn't it, Teacher?
I've already spoken
to your father, son.
Its best that you forget Nirmala..
..and leave quietly.
- Or else what will you do?
Makkhi.
- What Makkhi?
He doesn't know me.
He doesn't have any
stature before me.
The stone with my
name floats on water.
You can try it if you want.
It sunk.
It's just a figure of speech.
But let me tell
you clearly, Teacher.
There are just two
ways that I know of.
Either give your
daughter in marriage properly..
..or else I will abduct Nirmala.
How will you abduct her?
Where will you take her?
Your greedy father doesn't
want a loving daughter..
..but a rich one.
You're very strong, aren't you?
Go and deal with your father first.
Then you can talk to me.
Let's go, dear. Come on.
Let's go from here.
Let's go.
Stop. We're here.
Brother has come to
the Police Head Quarters.
Hello, Minister. Please come.
Smile.
Please come. - Lallan,
order for sherbet. - Yes, sir.
Chulbul Pandey.
- Go on.
Yes, sir.
How are you, Pandey?
- Absolutely fit, sir.
Good.
Let me introduce you
to him. Mr. Chedi Singh.
The president of the 'Lok
Manch' Student's Council.
He works along with minister Dayal.
Inspector Chulbul Pandey.
You wanted to see him, isn't it?
I've heard a lot about you.
- Thank you.
But only for the wrong reasons.
Tell me.
There have been three robberies in
your area in the past two months.
And I heard that this time the
police also surrounded the robbers.
Why didn't you shoot the rascals?
When we shoot a bullet..
..it's not assured
who it's going to hit.
It's normal for people to be
present in a public place.
Who will look after them?
You two continue your arguments..
..I'll go take my rounds.
Look after the minister, Pandey.
- Yes, sir.
I'll be right back.
Are you scared of the robbers?
I'm not even scared of my father.
Come.
I've heard that you've
taken all the money..
..for letting dacoit
Murari Singh go scot-free.
I didn't even know
that the dacoit I caught..
..his name is Murari Singh.
How did you find out?
Murari Singh is one
of our party workers.
His responsibility is fund-raising.
And this time you looted
the fund that he gathered.
I won't ask you to
return the money..
..but you will work
for me, won't you?
What if I refuse?
You shouldn't lock horns
with the ruler of the jungle.
I'm slightly stubborn.
Think about it.
There're more hunters and less
lions in the jungle these days.
Don't roar too loudly..
..or else you
might be skinned alive.
You've faith in yourself.
I've faith, courage
and strength as well.
And I'm crazy beyond imagination.
Chotu, take a photo.
Smile.
Just this much.
It'll come handy for
adorning the garland.
Stout ones on that side.
Slim ones on this side.
And fitter ones, follow me.
What's wrong with the police force?
Sir, he ducked in 'Teli' alley.
Come quickly, sir.
We're police officials.
There's firing going on outside.
At least keep the latch closed.
Thankfully I was there.
What if something
would've happened to you?
Do you know how
hurt I would've been?
Are you married?
- No.
Who else is there in the house?
- My father.
He's sleeping inside.
Has he been looking for
a groom for you? - No.
That's good.
Take this.
You look very stern.
Shall we go?
Its call from your mother.
Why don't you answer it? Answer it.
No, it's my girlfriend.
- Girlfriend?
Yes. Yes.
Its time for you to die.
There's always a first time.
Always a next time.
Next time. You too.
Next time.
Why do you come to
me whenever you fail?
Do you come to me
when you're with a girl?
Now go face him. Rascals.
That Pandey is really crazy.
He's after me.
Save me.
If you can't beat them..
..you can at least try
to stay out of his sights.
What do you mean?
Disappear. Completely underground.
And don't surface
until I don't tell you to.
I'll think of something
to do with Chulbul Pandey.
Get lost.
It's the power of his police post.
That Chulbul Pandey is
just a cheap inspector.
Get him suspended
for a false charge..
..then we'll have a fair
fight and see who's stronger.
Tell me something, Kasturilal.
What do you think?
Who's the biggest
villain in Lalganj?
You're the biggest villain here.
Here.
Break the coconut.
See that.
I always thought
that I was the hero..
..and he thinks I am the villain.
Do I look like a villain to you?
Tell me something, Kasturilal.
What do you think is going
on in my mind right now?
Right now.. you look very angry.
What are you saying?
If I really was angry..
..I would've smashed the
coconut on your head and not his.
You're my future father-in-law.
How is your daughter?
- She's waiting for you.
To come and marry her.
And you're trying to
break this alliance.
What have I done?
- That's the problem.
You haven't done anything.
Go and do something.
Go find out everything
about Chulbul Pandey.
Where does he go, where he lives?
What does he eat, his house,
relatives, property.
Everything.
He has really made me suffer a lot.
Now I will make him suffer.
Clear this up.
The government has given me an offer
for government quarters. - Is it?
Forget this nonsense
and come with me. - Why?
Why should I go?
Who will look after
Makkhi and Pandey?
Makkhi and Pandey are
not concerned about you.
I said I won't go anywhere.
I can sever all my
relations for your happiness.
Have you thought about
a mother's condition..
..when she has to choose
between two of her sons.
I was just teasing you.
You get excited, get breathless..
..and make me run around.
Where is your pump?
How many times have I told you..
..always keep your pump with you.
But no.
Here.
I've been repeatedly
asking you to leave..
..because if we stay
here too long..
..then soon Mr. Pandey
will need a pump as well.
But we won't wait a
day after the marriage.
Whose marriage?
- Mr. Pandey's.
Mr. Pandey?
- Chulbul Pandey.
Is Sumant Kumar here?
There's no point in
thinking about someone..
..who isn't there anymore.
Let's go home.
Let's go, Father.
- My bottle of alcohol.
Don't create a scene.
Let's go.
- She's beating me.
You're drunk, Father.
She doesn't let me drink.
'Erotta'. 'Erotta'.
I want a drink.
What was he calling you?
I don't know.
What does 'Erotta' mean?
- I don't know.
Was he drunk?
- Yes.
How do you know him?
- He's my father.
I see.
Then he can call you anything.
It's his right.
Yes, Mr. Shukla,
we'll deliver the goods.
But first pay the
previous outstanding.
What is it?
I want to marry Nirmala, papa.
I know.
Talk to the teacher.
Can I ask you something?
It's my life, so it
should be my choice.
No need to argue.
I know your likes and dislikes.
I toil here day and night
to make your life better.
And all you're
concerned about is love.
This factory doesn't
function on its own, Makkhi.
I owe a large sum of money to
the bank which they loaned me.
My last hope was that I'll get
something from your marriage..
..so that I can repay the loan.
Who will repay the loan?
I didn't build this factory.
Why are you breaking my alliance?
- Quiet, useless.
Did you have to fall in love..
..with that poor
teacher's daughter?
I will take every decision
for you until I am alive.
You can stay with me if you agree..
..or you can leave my house.
Where did you go..
leaving all this open?
Do you want anything?
How much?
- Rs.250.
You're robbing a police official.
I don't have change.
- That's okay.
I'll collect it some other day.
I wanted a single piece.
Why are you giving me two?
I always repay debts.
Next time you can return
it and take your money.
Give it.
Can I leave?
Rs.500 for chatting for a minute.
That's another 500.
I dropped them.
For those two pots.
You made a mistake.
I never charge for mistakes.
I'm paying their price
and not doing charity.
I'm giving it willingly, keep it.
Or else I could've
slapped you as well.
I'm not afraid of
being slapped, sir..
..but certainly of love.
''I keep staring at you all day.''
''Your eyes..''
''Your eyes dwell in mine.''
''Your bewitching eyes.''
''Have stolen my heart.''
''The heart skipped a
beat when I first saw you.''
''Love blossomed
and made me smolder.''
''I dream only about you now.''
''I fell like I've changed.''
''Your bewitching eyes.''
''Have stolen my heart.''
''It starts with you
and ends with you.''
''My world.''
''It was my secret, but
the eyes revealed it.''
''I belong to you. I
belong only to you.''
''Your memories make me restless.''
''You're so close yet
so far. What to do?''
''Your bewitching eyes.''
''Have stolen my heart.''
- How are you?
''Your bewitching eyes.''
Since the birth of
politics in our country..
..we've been fighting
over only five issues.
Food. Clothing. Water.
Shelter and electricity.
When will we move ahead of them?
Remember.. Lord Ram
satisfied his hunger..
Sir, do you want tea?
..by eating Shabri's
half-eaten berries.
So, friends, if you want
to save Uttar Pradesh..
..from poverty and criminals.
The Swarna's will have
to walk hand-in-hand..
..with the mistreated
Dalits (untouchables).
Glory to Mr. Dayal!
Mr. Dayal seems more of a
confectioner than a minister.
He speaks so sweetly, isn't it?
He spoke about Lord Ram.
He'll surely win the election.
- Forget it, sir.
People have become
very advanced these days.
I can see that.
Look, the people want a dutiful
minister and not a religious one.
How should our minister be?
- He should be like Mr. Dayal!
Haven't you heard?
Cast your vote but
don't vote your caste.
I feel ministers like Mr.
Dayal are useless.
On that note I remembered you
didn't introduce yourself to me.
Kasturilal Vishwakarma.
I'm looking after
the arrangements here.
And you are?
- I am the Robin Hood here.
Robin Hood Pandey.
- Robin Hood Pandey?
What is your cell number?
You want to know.
How should our minister be?
- He should be like Mr. Dayal!
What should I do? - I will
lose my job, try to understand.
I don't want it, I've sufficient.
- Keep this money.
Try to understand,
Rajo, try to understand.
What is your name?
- Sumant Kumar.
Why?
I won't allow such things here.
Why were you giving
money to that girl?
She's my sister, Rajo.
Your real sister?
- Yes.
Do you know her?
No.
But I do want to know her.
I never saw you here before.
I work with Mr. Dayal.
I am his P.A.
- What drink?
Tea? Coffee?
- P.A. Personal assistant.
I see. P.A.
Why are you wearing
different shoes?
It's not a style statement.
I've polio.
Weren't you given the two drops?
Father didn't get
time from his drinking.
You look so cute when you're upset.
I feel like biting your cheeks.
Don'tjoke.
- What else should I do?
Why did you call me when you
don't want to do anything?
I want to marry you.
Elope with me.
- No.
Why not? Don't you love me?
Love is important, Makkhi.
But we can't elope and get married.
Father won't be able to
tolerate the humiliation.
Find another way.
Talk to brother Chulbul.
Maybe he will find a solution.
What can he do?
He likes to see me sad.
Then you think of what to do.
I can't understand anything.
Nirmala. Nirmala.
On that note I remembered.
Tiwari, how is sister-in-law?
- She's still alive, Sir.
Why did you call father
to the police station?
What has he done?
Do you know the two of them?
- No.
Your father tried to
rape their sister.
When they tried to stop
him he thrashed them instead.
Look at how they're trembling.
I always stay with father, sir.
I'm seeing them for the first time.
Sometimes father
drinks too much but..
..couldn't have
misbehaved with their sister.
I swear.
Fine, I believe you.
If he wasn't your father..
..I would've locked him up
under sections 126 and 228.
I won't lock your father up.
Will you smile or
stand here like a statue?
No.
Whoever makes her smile
will get a reward of Rs.1000.
1000.
- Come on.
Once a man was
urinating on the street.
Tiwari called him and
said ''Hey, come here''.
''Doesn't anyone catch you?''
Do you know what he replied?
''No, sir, in this city
we've to hold it ourselves.''
One day a rich man called
a poor man and asked him..
..''Tell me.. is kissing
hard-work or pleasure''.
He replied, ''Sir, it
must be pleasure''.
''If it was hard work you
would've made me do it.''
What do you say?
500 for you and 500 for me.
700 for you and 300 for me.
'Erotta'. 'Erotta'. 'Erotta'.
Fool.
She laughed.
She laughed. She laughed.
Give me my money. Give me my money.
My Rs.1000.
''He didn't know that
love is a enchanting.''
''He's been smitten..''
''That he has no place to go.''
''Your intoxicating eyes.
These intoxicating eyes.''
''They're enchanting.
''Your intoxicating eyes.
These intoxicating eyes.''
''They're enchanting.
''Don't try to stop me.''
''I want to drink from these eyes.''
''It's a cruel night, I
want to feel alive.''
''I want to savor it.''
''The officer in the
station is having hiccups.''
''I think he's taken a sip as well.''
''Build a brewery in your station.''
''And drink it straight.''
''He's a flamboyant.''
''I want to savor it.''
What are you doing, Makkhi?
Aren't you ashamed?
Stealing in your own house.
What was your requirement
which we couldn't fulfil?
Forgive me, Mother.
I just want to marry, Nirmala.
I don't have any other option.
I don't want to hear anything.
This is cheating, Makkhi.
I won't deceive you, Mother.
I will give this
money to the teacher.
He'll give it to father..
..and this money will
come back in this house.
And Chulbul?
What will I tell him?
Let me get married.
I will steal this money from
father and keep it back in the safe.
Great, son.
That's not what I thought.
Instead of
apologising for this robbery..
..you're promising
me to steal again.
Mother. - If you have any
other such corrupt intention..
..then don't mask them.
Tell me about them.
I am helpless, Mother.
Let me take this money today.
- Take it away, take the money.
But I'll regret it all my life..
..that I..
I gave birth to a thief.
Mother.
You got it.
You're looking lethal today.
Can I sit?
Sit.
Do you know why I am here today?
- No.
I want to marry you.
What?
I can't get married.
Why?
You look fine.
Do you want to remain
unmarried all your life? - Yes.
And what if you find a
strong and fearless man like me?
Still you won't.
- No.
Any reason?
I can't leave father.
That means.. you won't get
married until your father is alive.
I won't get married
as long as he's alive.
Did you make these toys?
Yes.
You're an artist.
Erotta. Erotta.
My bottle is empty.
Get me another bottle.
Look after your father.
Try to change him.
And I will wait
for him to pass away.
For you.
There's good news for you.
That pot-seller
refused my proposal.
That means I'll have to
stay right here with you.
Mother.
That's just great.
'Every father worries
more for his weaker son.'
'That doesn't mean that
Mr. Pandey doesn't love you.'
'But Makkhi is weaker, son.'
'He's a fool.'
'He doesn't concentrate on studies.'
'But he's my son.'
'I gave birth to him.'
'He's your brother.
- Step-brother.'
'Again the same thing, Chulbul.'
'If you harbor such hatred
in life then I will die.'
'You want to kill me, that's it.'
'You don't love your mother.
- I do.'
'So, son, say yes for me.'
Look, sir.
Fine.
I want to compromise with you.
Let's forget the past.
Can't we live like father
and son from today? Together.
Your family is
dead with your mother.
Don't try to be a
part of our family.
Leave us alone.
We're not related any longer.
You're drunk the entire day.
You'll realize one day when
I will leave you for good.
Let's go.
- I can't walk.
Get up. Father.
- Look, the train's approaching.
I will kill myself. I will.
- Wait.
Don't make a scene.
I will kill myself.
- Get up, Father.
Get up, father.
- Otherwise I will kill myself.
I am fed up of you.
What are you doing?
- Get up, Father.
That's the reason why brother Sumant
doesn't want to see your father.
Have some shame.
You've made a mess.
Erotta. - Enough of this
daily charade, father.
Get up now.
Come on.
- I won't come.
There's a train
approaching on this track now.
Get up, Father. Get up, Father.
Get up, Father.
Enough of your charade.
Come on.
Get up, Father.
- Come on.
What are you doing?
He's shoving me in the car.
I want a drink. Also some ice.
Get me some ice.
To hell with alcohol.
No.
Here.
Take it in. Take it in.
Come on. Take it in.
Slowly.
Take it in.
That's it.
Sir.
Sir, we've brought everything.
But we couldn't find any
money in the cupboard, sir.
Mother must've hidden it..
..to keep it safe from
Mr. Pandey and Makkhi.
We'll find it.
- Yes, sir.
Stop. Stop.
Reverse it.
You don't have a rag
to wipe your nose..
..and you're getting new
suits stitched for yourself.
Great.
Where did you get the money from?
My marriage has been fixed.
With Nirmala.
- I see.
It was mother's wish as well.
I see.
Strange, mother
never mentioned it to me.
Are you getting married for
mother or yourself? - Both.
You must have
invited the entire village.
Won't you invite me?
- Of course I will.
I will if you attend it.
But you won't come.
- I will.
I will surely come.
I will come with my wife.
- Did you get married?
I haven't yet, but I will.
And before you.
I am elder to you.
I'll take your leave.
And listen.
- Yes, sir.
Don't charge him money.
He's my brother.
- Ok.
Come on.
You stay drunk all day and
slander your daughter publicly.
She's your daughter.
Why don't you do something
about her? - What should I do?
Look, I don't know
how to twist words.
I like your daughter and I
want to marry her. - Yes.
I am educated and
a Brahmin by cast.
I'm a police officer.
Respect, honour and wealth.
I've got everything.
But your daughter
isn't ready to accept me.
What am I lacking?
You don't know her.
She's very stubborn.
She won't get married
until I don't die. Erotta.
She told me that.
Explain to her. Nicely,
strictly or threateningly.
Do whatever you think is right.
But make her agree.
And if you can't do that
then shame on such a father.
What happened?
Will you keep my daughter happy?
- No, no.
I will beat her, torment her.
And then ask you for dowry.
That's strange, father.
You haven't noticed
my love for her yet.
Come and take my
daughter on the 27th..
..I will explain to her.
I will explain to her.
- How?
Prepare for the marriage
and leave the rest to me.
One more thing.
Your daughter is getting
married in a wealthy family.
And spectacularly.
Don't stay drunk.
I've stopped..
drinking.. from right now.
I'll take your leave.
Look after yourself.
He's my father.
Wake him up.
Father! Father!
You're so strange.
I'm indebted to you now.
I asked you to forsake
drinking and not the world.
Come on, enough of mourning.
He's dead now.
Let her be a part of my life now.
Get up.
Increase your speed
and show some agility.
What are you staring at?
I want to give you a better life.
I want to marry you.
Come on.
Quickly pick up your suitcase.
Go inside and come out quickly.
Chulbul Pandey,
congratulations for the marriage.
Thank you father.
Come, Chulbul.
Welcome.
Thank you very much.
Teacher, the
arrangements are really nice.
Oh no, son. It's all your grace.
If it's my grace, then
can I get married first?
What do you mean?
Stay alert.
Come, come.
Come ahead.
Why did they stop playing the band?
It's nothing, sir,
they're being stubborn.
They say that they won't
play for two marriages..
..for the price of one.
Send Tiwari.
Look, Chulbul sir is
very soft at heart..
..and fearless by mind.
And if you act smart
with a fearless man..
..I will take you to
the police station..
..and beat you between two legs..
..that you won't be
capable of playing anything else.
Get it.
Come on, play it.
Play it.
Excuse me, priest.
Shall we do a little bit of walking?
The parents of the bride
and groom come forward..
..and bless the new couple.
Priest, she doesn't have anyone.
And my situation is slightly..
There must be elders in your family.
Yes. It's me.
I will bless myself.
May I stay happy.
And may she enjoy a
happy married life.
We're married now.
I don't believe it.. that
you're your mother's son.
I feel like spitting on your face.
That's strange Pandey.
I'm no Good Boy..
..that to forgive you each
time you spit on my face.
Get out of here.
- We're leaving.
We didn't come here to
take your permission.
Stop all this.
There isn't going to
be any marriage here.
Teacher.
There isn't going
to be any marriage.
Father.
What is your name?
My name.. suites my personality.
Robinhood Pandey
alias Chulbul Pandey.
Chulbul.. Pandey.
What you did today,
Mr. Pandey, wasn't right.
I did the right thing.
Spend few months with me..
..and you'll know what I do and why.
Why would your
father call you 'Erotta'?
Do you know what it means?
- I know.
What is it?
- Wretch.
Someone who has lost her honour.
You didn't tell me
when I asked you earlier.
I lied.
- Why?
You know me now.
Spend few months with me..
..and you'll know
what I say and why.
What did you do for which
he would call you 'Erotta'?
Find it out?
You can't be an 'Erotta'.
Your father was short-sighted.
''Your eyes are like the mirror.''
''They tell me what
is in your heart.''
''I didn't utter a word.''
''My eyes narrated everything.''
''You stole my heart at
first sight, sweetheart.''
first sight, darling.''
''My life was
filled with loneliness.''
''But it was flooded with love.''
''The spring finally dawned..''
''..when I fell in love with you.''
''You stole my heart at
first sight, darling.''
first sight, sweetheart.''
The booty that comes inside,
should be here..
That goes outside
should be outside.
What's going on?
Can't you see?
Do you think you own it?
Scoundrel.
Is this how you beat poor people?
Move aside. Move aside. Move aside.
Come sir. Come.
- He killed my son.
Sir. - Sir, he
thrashed my son so cruelly.
Sir.
Sir, Makkhan
Pandey has thrashed him.
Makkhi.
Sir, get my son treated.
We wantjustice, sir.
- Fine.
Now I will keep
thrashing Makkhan Singh..
..until you don't ask me to stop.
Come on get up.
Make me a betel leaf.
- Okay.
Down with!
- Chulbul Pandey!
We won't tolerate!
- ?Atrocities of the police anymore.
The rights of the police
have been misused, Mr. Malik.
Firstly Makkhanchand's
marriage was hijacked.
Then he was publicly beaten.
I accept that
Makkhanchand made a mistake.
But there's something called as law.
You might have to pay dearly
for legal action, Chedi Singh.
Many criminals die
everyday in police encounter.
Don't you read the newspaper?
I do read the newspaper,
Chulbul Pandey..
..but maybe you don't.
There's often news of
dead police officials.
Please relax, sir.
It's their family matter.
They'll solve it amongst themselves.
No one's going to benefit if
you include politics in this.
We will include politics, Mr. Malik.
Today Prajapati Pandey is helpless..
..tomorrow it can be someone else.
Who else will the people
look up to other than me?
If you don't take strict
action against Chulbul Pandey..
..then I will set the
entire village ablaze. - No, no.
Sir, please don't do
anything like that.
My son is hurt.
It's my grievance.
And anyway I don't want
to aggravate this matter.
What do you mean?
If Chulbul.. apologises
to Makkhanchand publicly..
..then I'm ready to end
this matter right here.
What are you saying?
- That's more like it.
Wait, sir.
Mr. Pandey, apologise
right now and end this matter.
Makkhanchand, I
humiliated you publicly.
I apologise, please forgive me.
There, the problem's solved.
He has apologised.
Please, come.
One thing is clear, Chulbul.
You don't like me and nor do I.
When we've to live separately..
..then why not live happily.
Pandey.
It's a family issue.
I apologise again.
Brother-in-law, Dayal sir
has talked to the commissioner.
You slapped Makkhanchand
in front of Chedi Singh.
I can slap Chedi Singh
in front of Dayal sir.
Great, Brother-in-law.
Then Dayal sir will surely agree.
You're a fearless man, Pandey.
You always say everything clearly.
I hear clearly as well.
Chedi Singh is the
youth leader of my party.
And you want me to oppose a
member of my party for you.
Why?
If an old ruler wants
keep his reign intact..
..then he has to
sacrifice his children as well.
Chedi Singh isn't your son anyway.
The truth is, Pandey..
..I dislike Chedi
Singh as much as you do.
He takes undue
advantage of my name..
..and runs breweries.
Supplies illegal arms.
And keeps all the profit himself.
Think of a way by which..
..Chedi Singh stays in the
party but stays under my control.
I have many ways.
But it depends on
which one you want to use.
I can stop your suspension.
You stop Chedi Singh.
No matter which means you use.
But my reign should remain intact.
But tell me one thing..
..why do you wear your
goggles at the back?
So that I can keep an eye on
the front and at the back.
15 people are in serious condition..
..due to drinking poisonous alcohol
in Madanpura area of Lalganj.
They've been admitted in
a government hospital..
..in serious condition.
Police has seized
consignments of alcohols..
..from five breweries.
And they're searching for the
owner of all these breweries.
''Munni was mortified, darling,
just for you.''
''Munni's cheeks are red, eyes are
intoxicating and gait's bewitching.''
''She lost her mind,
darling, just for you.''
''Munni was mortified, darling,
just for you.''
''Munni's cheeks are red, eyes are
intoxicating and gait's bewitching.''
''She lost her mind,
darling, just for you.''
''Munni was mortified, darling,
just for you.''
Did you send money for the people..
..that were
admitted in the hospital?
Sir, I gave them so much money..
..that now they'll drink whiskey.
''A figure like Shilpa,
Bebo's attitude.''
''Bebo's attitude.''
''A figure like Shilpa,
Bebo's attitude.''
''Bebo's attitude.''
''My gaits so filmy.''
''I've lots of attitude.''
''My attitude's worth millions.''
''I became famous for you.''
''I grew restless for you.''
''Munni was mortified, darling,
just for you.''
''Munni, everyone
talks only about you.''
''Munni.''
''You are famous everywhere.''
''You're so bewitching and lovable.''
''Munni.''
''He's such a fool.''
''He's here without a penny.''
''He doesn't know those after me..''
''O my damsel!''
''He doesn't know that
almost everyone is after me.''
''I lowered my standard, darling,
just for you.''
''Munni was mortified, darling,
''You're intoxicating
like a bottle of alcohol.''
''Make me feel young again.''
''Your lips are luscious
and eyes are bewitching.''
''They steal my heart.''
''You turned stunning, darling,
just for me.''
''Munni was mortified, darling,
''Munni's cheeks are red, eyes are
intoxicating and gait's bewitching.''
''She lost her mind,
darling, just for you.''
''Munni was mortified, darling,
just for you.''
''I turned so youthful, darling,
''You turned so entertaining.''
''Just for you.''
''Munni was mortified.''
''You turned famous.''
''Darling, just for you.''
Let's go, Munni, to your Munna.
Now I will make him.. lose his mind.
Why are you here?
You're so strange.
There's a warrant for you.
You're making the
headlines everywhere.
I've been running the
breweries for the past 11 years.
I never do adulteration.
I know it's your plan,
Chulbul Pandey.
And I will win this game as well.
I could've killed some..
..from those whose life I saved.
Are you threatening me?
- Threaten.
On that note I remembered.
Which is that big animal?
Elephant?
Elephant.
That is me.
And which is that small
animal that we.. shoo away.
Dog.
- Dog.
Him.
And what should the dog do..
..if the elephant steps
on his tail?
Sir, its best that
he leaves quietly.
Because there's just one
thing that a dog has..
..that saves him in
difficult times.
What do you want?
I don't want it now.
Hold it.
Until I keep getting
this bag filled with money..
..your hearing will
keep getting delayed.
And when it stops.
I will fill you with so many holes..
..that you'll be confused which
hole you should use to breathe..
..and which one to fart.
Click it.
Brother, smile.
Let's go.
This issue is taking
political mileage.
It's an inside news.
Chulbul Pandey is under
Dayal sir's protection.
Kill Chulbul Pandey.
What are you saying?
Don't you dare do that.
The elections are upon us.
And it'll prove
beneficial for Dayal sir.
One mistake from your side..
..and your name will be
cut off from the ticket list.
Be careful, sir.
You're my future son-in-law.
I'm quite worried.
Sir, smile.
You will kill
Chulbul Pandey and not me.
Me? No, no, no.
How can I do it?
Chulbul Pandey is
such a stubborn man.
What if something happens to me?
I finally managed to befriend him.
Do you want your
daughter to marry me..
..or should I look for another
girl. - No, no, I want to. I do.
You're putting my life at stake.
Find another way.
There's an old rule of politics,
father-in-law.
If you want to defeat the enemy..
..then find the
traitor amongst them.
Hail Sri Ram.
Why don't you return
the teacher's money..
..when the alliance is broken?
Why are you worried?
Teacher didn't ask for the money.
Anyway, he has broken
the alliance and not me.
Switch off the light, go to sleep.
Come on.
Don't make noise.
Stop. Stop!
How are you brother Makkhanchand?
Where are you going?
How are you?
Any problem?
I need money, sir.
I want to get father treated.
Prajapati has fallen sick.
Please help me.
- No, no.
I tried to help you last time.
But your father turned his back.
I don't want to be
humiliated anymore.
This time I will
do anything you say.
Give me one chance.
Sit in the car.
Do you see that man?
The one that's batting.
Tolu Rastogi.
Dayal sir's aide.
Can you deal with him?
- I can mop the floor with him.
That's all I want.
If you can deal with him
then you'll be my aide.
My right hand.
Run, run.
Take two, two.
Hey boy, return the ball.
Chedi Singh.
- Makkhi is with him.
When you aren't
related any longer..
..then why think about it?
Don't you know that
Chedi Singh is a big rascal?
I can understand
making a mistake once.
But making the same mistake again.
That's foolishness, isn't it?
That Chedi Singh is
taking advantage..
..of the differences
between us brothers.
You called Makkhanchand
your brother after so long.
It felt nice to hear that
you consider him your brother.
Why don't you explain to him?
Rajo, I can explain to him
only when he answers the phone.
It hurts to see your
brother in pain, isn't it?
Everything's not lost yet.
Serve the meal, I'll try once more.
I don't understand one thing.
You're giving ordinary
mangoes to such a big minister.
When mangoes can get the
job done then why pay money.
You want to keep your
father alive, isn't it? - Yes.
Then do as I tell you.
Don't ask too many questions.
Go out.
Dimwit, stupid.
Come on.
Only you can do something,
please do something. - Yes, I will.
I will.
Please save him.
- Okay, please.
God bless you.
- Please go.
Sumant.
- Yes.
Come here.
Yes.
Who else is there in your house?
Hello.
What does your elder son do?
There's shortage of
water in my village, sir.
If you could install a tube-well..
..it would make things better.
Give me your name and
the name of your village.
We'll see what we can do.
I've brought
mangoes from my orchard.
They're absolutely fresh.
Fine, keep them here.
Lets leave.
- Thank you.
You come.
Okay.
I want a tube-well
installed in my fields.
Village, Samastipur.
Name, Makkhanchand Pandey.
Samastipur.
I've heard your name before.
Are you Chulbul Pandey's brother?
It wouldn't have made
a difference if I was.
Do your work.
I don't know any Chulbul.
Uttar Pradesh's home
Minister Dayal Sahu..
..passed away in a
bomb blast in Lalganj.
This blast occurred when Dayal sir..
..was tending to his
public like on every Monday.
His cruel murder is a
big shock to our democracy.
Madam. Madam, you can't go inside.
Hello. Madam.
There's an ordinance
factory in Lalganj.
Only licensed contractors
are supplied gun powder.
In our
investigation we've found out..
..that the explosives
used in Mr. Dayal's murder..
..was from these factories.
We've suspended the licence..
..of all the explosives
factories in the area.
There are some small
ministers we doubt.
But we're sure to
find the guilty soon.
And we'll start
arresting them soon. Thank you.
Prayer.
Makkhanchand Pandey.
You just disappeared after
making such a big explosion.
Wow, son.
I am proud of you.
After what you did..
..now my son-in-law is
the only candidate left..
..from Lalganj assembly.
- Thank you.
Great.
Why didn't you tell me there
was a bomb in the box of mangoes?
What are you saying?
You're still a novice.
You don't understand politics.
Would you have done
it if I had told you?
You used me.
I never invited you to help me.
You came to me yourself.
Now.. I've a very
special job for you.
Come in, I'll tell you.
Congratulations.
Go on.
The thing is, brother..
..that the hands of the
law and Chedi Singh's legs..
..both are very long.
The minister has been murdered.
The police will
apprehend you some day.
And then Chulbul Pandey
is in-charge of the case.
He won't spare you.
Before he comes here and kills you..
..take this gun and
kill your brother. - What?
I am absolutely right.
You don't have any other option.
One of you has to die.
He isn't your kin anyway.
He has always tormented you.
Kill him.
End his life.
Who will look after father
if anything happens to you?
Think about it.
Do this lastjob for me.
I swear I will
reward you so handsomely..
..that you'll always remember.
Makkhi.
Chedi Singh has sent me.
To kill you.
Then kill me.
What are you thinking?
You've killed Dayal sir.
I'm not here to kill you, Brother.
I am here to apologise
to you and sister-in-law.
I made a big mistake.
I didn't know there was a
bomb in the box of mangoes.
Our factory was burnt down.
'Brother Makkhanchand,
the factory is on fire.'
Father received a shock.
I need to get him treated.
I did everything for father.
And you sought Chedi Singh's help.
- I was helpless.
I beg you, save father.
He's dying.
Save father.
I'm taking your blessings.
If you wish to..
..then please bless me.
Forget it.
I am happy without your blessings.
Can I sit?
I met your doctor.
He was saying that you'll
live only for a few more days.
I slapped him.
And you got a longer lifespan.
Look, Mr. Pandey.
The arrogance and
pride that I see in you..
..is not real.
All my life I've
been shocked many times.
First was my father's death.
Next was your arrival.
And then my mother's death.
And now if you leave me..
I will go crazy.
Look, it'll sound
strange after so many years.
..but now.. I will..
I..
I will call you papa.
You finally gave me your blessings.
You're so strange,
Prajapati Pandey.
Hey, look there.
I will give you good reward.
Your mother's last remembrance.
Her inhaler.
How did you get hold of this?
Catch him.
'Who are you?
- Hello, Aunt.'
'What do you want? '
'Bless me.
- Bless you.'
'Is Chulbul Pandey your son?
- Yes.'
'Where is my money? '
'Tell me.'
'Return my money.'
'Return my money or else.. '
'Return my money or
else I won't spare you.'
What are you looking for?
'Keep this aside, what
will you do with it.'
'Chulbul Pandey is wanted.'
'Just return my money.'
'Why are you doing
like this, mother?'
'Just return my money and
I will return you this.'
'What happened?'
'Chedi Singh's last salutations.'
Glory to you!
'Arrange everything back
to normal here. - Yes.'
'I don't want a police case.'
'And I'll keep this safe.'
My puff.
I didn'tjust kill your mother.
I also set your father ablaze.
You've already killed your brother.
Why do you want to live any longer?
Hello.
- Give the phone to Chedi.
Go join your family.
I.G.
Yes, friend.
Tell me.
- Brother, Chulbul Pandey is alive.
I saw him with my own eyes.
He's coming to you with full army.
What nonsense?
This is a foolproof news,
brother. Be careful.
Did you kill your brother?
Come on.
No!
No! No! No! No!
That's Makkhi. No! No!
Who asked you to bring this here?
Brother.
Scoundrel.
Douse the fire.
Take the box.
Makkhi.
My parents sacrificed 101 rascals..
..and then I was born,
Chulbul Pandey.
I'm the God of those rascals.
I'm here to take revenge.
Get up!
You've hurt me a lot,
Chulbul Pandey.
You call yourself the
God of rascals, don't you?
Brother. Brother.
Brother.
For the first time I
am happy to see you.
'Give it to me.
- He gave her a terrible death.'
'He gave her a terrible death.'
He gave her a terrible death.'
'With my money?'
'Give me the money or I'll hit you.'
'Give me my money.'
Seeing this tractor
I remembered that..
..I've to get you
married to master's daughter.
He's getting sentimental?
Papa, why are your eyes wet?
You're strange, Mr. Pandey.
You got this dimwit married.
That's exactly what I wanted.
Happy ending.
It's not the ending, father.
It's just the beginning.
I wish your mother was present.
On that note I remembered,
Robin Hood Pandey.
I'm pregnant.
Better mend your ways.
Quiet.
- You quiet.
Sir.
- Chedi Singh is dead.
But his money.
Have it disappeared.
He also has a brother.
What if tries to take revenge?
Then I'll fill him
with so many holes..
..that he'll be confused
where to breathe from and..
''Fearless.''
''Strong hearted.''
''Looks like a rock.''
''Always first to fight.''
''Fearless.''
''A fighter, always willing.''
''Looks like the leader.''
''Fearless.''
''He does the impossible.''
''His roar breaks
the deadly silence.''
''Fearless.''
''Strong hearted.''
''Looks like a rock.''
''Always first to fight.''
''Fearless.''
''When the sky reins fire.''
''He comes like a
cool breeze of wind.''
''Saves everyone.''
''Fearless.''
''In difficult times.''
''He stands tall to
the competition.''
''And challenges every difficulty.
''Fearless.''
''He does the impossible.''
''His roar breaks
the deadly silence.''
''Fearless.''
''Looks like a rock.''
''Always first to fight.''
''Looks like the leader.''
''Fearless.''
''A fighter, always willing.''
''Looks like the leader.''
''Fearless.''