Keep it going! All right, shake it out!
Keep moving!
Shake it out!
Are you talking to me?
Me and my brother, itjust used
to be me and my brother.
We used to do things together.
We used to have fun.
We used to roam the streets.
There was people suffering
ofpain and hunger.
Some people, their tongues
were hanging out of their mouth.
Just got to get fixed up first.
Things aren't always
gonna be this way.
You know that, don't you?
He used tojuggle apples.
He used to amuse us.
He used to entertain us.
What else do I got to do today?
In fact, all three of us
been going places,
Iooking and searching for things...
..going on adventures.
They told everybody
they were brother and sister.
My brother didn't want
nobody to know.
You know how people are. You tell
them something, they start talking.
I met this guy named Ding Dong.
He told me the whole earth
is going up in flames.
Flames will come out ofhere
and there, and they'lljust rise up.
The mountains are gonna
go up in big flames.
The water is gonna rise in flames.
Creatures will run every which way,
some of them burnt,
half their wings burning.
People are gonna be screaming
and hollering for help.
The people that have been good will
go to heaven and escape the fire.
Sackers! I need sackers!
But ifyou've been bad,
God don't even hear you talking.
A man can earn three dollars a day
if he wants to work.
Sackers! I need sackers!
- You ever sacked before? When?
- Last year.
- Whose place is that?
- The owner's.
Don't any of you go up there!
Silver tongue.
You all right?
- You live around here?
- No. No, I don't.
- Where do you live?
- In Chicago.
Oh, yeah?
- What's that in your hair?
- In my hair?
In my ear?
That's what you call a makins.
- What's a makins?
- A cigarette.
It's tobacco in a bag, and you put it
and roll it up. But I'm gonna save it.
- You like it out here?
- Yeah.
- It's nice.
- I love it here. I like the wheat fields.
You have any brothers and sisters?
- No.
- I have a brother.
- What's his name?
- Bill.
- Where?
- Somewhere over there. I don't know.
I got one.
Let me see.
Don't lose him.
There he goes. Look, look.
Oh, you lost him.
I don't think they like us.
Abby's it!
Abby's too slow.
You didn't get me.
For a thousand years on Thy side are
but as yesterday, when it is passed,
and as a watch in the night.
As soon as Thou scatters them...
Amen.
Ho!
Come on!
- Get in closer!
- Line 'em up!
The farmer didn't know
when he first saw her
or what it was about her
that caught his eye.
Maybe it was the way
the wind blew through her hair.
Why do you wear a black hat?
Let me see your hands.
Get some spoons
and I'll meet you over there.
I'll be in the field here.
Does your sister
keep you warm at night?
- What did you say?
- You heard me.
- Let me go!
- OK!
Too bad you ain't got no real food left.
I'm kind of hungry.
I got a little potato.
You know anything about that woman
out there, the one with the black hair?
You haven't heard anything about her,
where she's from?
You want me to find out?
You've wasted more than 1 2 bushel in
this row. I'm docking you three dollars.
- What? That's not fair.
- Then leave. You're fired.
- Forget it. Don't fight about it.
- You wanna stay?
Then shut up and get back to work.
They treat you like jack shit out here.
I wouldn't worry about it.
If I see a doctor, I'll see if I can
get him to give you something for that.
OK.
I appreciate you coming out, doc.
That's all right.
I'll be checking on you
as time goes on.
You never think
it's gonna happen to you.
How long would you reckon I have?
You know, you can tell me.
A year. Maybe a year.
He knew he was gonna die.
He knew that there was nothing
that could be done.
Go slow.
You only live on this earth once.
In my opinion, as long as you're
around, you should have it nice.
Excuse me. I forgot where I was.
Don't worry.
- Where are you from?
- Chicago.
Wait a minute.
- Where do you go from here?
- All over.
Wyoming.
Do you think I like it?
- I saved your life today.
- No.
- Yeah, I killed this shit.
- Thanks.
I'm always looking out for you.
You deserve a medal.
Are you cold?
It's only for a while.
Then we'll go to New York.
- And then what?
- Then we're there and get fixed up.
I wanna see everybody working!
Everybody moving it along!
Shake 'em! Come on, let's go!
From the time the sun went up
till it went down,
they were working all the time.
Non-stop. Just keep going.
You didn't work,
they'd ship you right out of there.
They don't need you. They can
always get somebody else.
That's at a profit
of 4.75 dollars an acre.
Multiply that with 20,000,
you're talking over six figures.
- Big year.
- Your biggest ever.
Should make you
the richest man in the Panhandle.
Get out while you're this far ahead.
You have nothing to gain by staying.
- Get down from there!
- No!
Hold it, I got to clean up!
This farmer, he had a big spread
and a lot ofmoney.
Whoever was sitting in the chair
when he'd come around,
why, they'd stand up
and give it to him.
Wasn't no harm in him.
You'd give him a flower,
he'd keep it forever.
He was headed for the bone-yard
any minute,
but he wasn't really squawking
about it, like some people.
In one way I felt sorry for him,
'cause he had nobody
to stand out for him,
be by his side, hold his hand when
he needs attention or something.
That's touching.
We' Il probably be all done
by tomorrow.
You still planning on going north?
The reason I ask is...
..maybe you'd like to stay on here.
It'd be easier than now. There's not
that much work after the harvest.
The pay is just as good.
It's an idea. You could think about it
and let me know later.
I got to run.
Who's that?
My brother.
He's stuck on you.
- There are people around.
- There's nobody around.
Stop it.
He doesn't have any family either.
Why don't you tell him you'll stay?
What for?
I don't know.
Something might happen.
What's your mouth hanging open for?
Don't tell me. I already know.
On account of your unhappy life
and all that shit.
I'm telling you
we got to do something about it.
Can't expect anybody else to.
Last load!
Hup! Shut her down!
Are we gonna stay?
If she wants to.
You'd rather go?
I'd rather be the king of Siam.
Did you put aspirin in this?
20 dollars.
- Want a bite?
- Thank you very much, sir.
- Did he ever buy you anything?
- Lots of things.
He'll come back, I'm sure.
I don't think so.
Why not?
'Cause if he wanted me to be with him,
he would've took me.
Oh, that's not true.
Maybe I wasn't pretty enough
or something stupid like that.
What happened to your ear?
A dog bit me when I was little.
We were playing.
Can I have a puff?
He was tired ofliving like the rest,
nosing around like a pig in a gutter.
He wasn't in the mood no more.
He figured there was something wrong,
the way they always got no luck,
and they ought to get it
straightened out.
He figured some people
need more than they got,
other people got more
than they need.
Just a matter
ofgetting us all together.
Chicago! Well, go ahead!
You never used to be like this.
People have always been giving
me a hard time. Don't you start it, too.
Big federal case.
You don't have to decide
anything final now.
Just if we're gonna stay.
Yeah, I could stay. Sure. I got to keep
my brother and sister with me.
I'll try and come back,
'cause I like staying with you.
You're so much fun. I love you.
I want you to be really good.
Don't do anything wrong.
If you do, I'll get you.
I love you. Don't do nothing wrong!
I've been thinking
what to do with my future.
I could be a mud doctor,
checking out the earth underneath.
Why are you doing this?
When I was your age,
I was all by myself in the world.
I used to sit and wrap cigars
till after dark.
My skin was as white as paper.
I never saw the daylight.
This is not so bad.
Don't make me laugh.
Wait a minute.
- Where are you people from?
- Chicago.
- What did you do there?
- Nothing.
- Your brother, I mean.
- He worked in a factory.
I can remember
the first time I ever saw you.
I'd never seen
hair as black as yours,
skin so pretty.
Scared I'd never see you again.
Run!
Safe!
So I went to work in a mill.
Couldn't wait to get in there.
Began at seven and
had to have a smile on your face.
And one day you wake up...
..you find you're not
the smartest guy in the world.
Never gonna come up
with a big score.
When I was growing up,
I thought I really would.
- Where did you learn that?
- Watched the girls at Baker Hall.
Actually, I could have been a dancer.
I think I love you.
What a nice thing to say.
Never thought he'd have the guts.
- Who'd know but you and me?
- Nobody.
It's all that matters, isn't it?
You talk like it was all right.
There'd never be the chance
to enjoy his money anyway.
What makes you think
it's only a couple of months?
The man has got one foot on a banana
peel, the other on a roller-skate.
We'll all be gone in a couple of years.
Who's gonna care we acted perfect?
I held out a long time.
I had rich men pay me compliments.
- Have I ever said anything...
- You don't have to.
I hate it,
to see you stooped over out there.
Them looking at your ass
like you were a whore.
I hate it.
As you will answer
at the dreadful day of judgement...
..that if either of you
know any impediment...
For richer and for poorer,
for better and for worse,
in sickness and in health,
to love and to cherish
till death us do part.
Bless this ring that he who gives it
and she who wears it may abide it...
Thank you.
You're like an angel.
I wish I was.
Does all this seem strange to you?
Why don't you move your things
in the house while we're gone?
All right.
Bye.
Did you see there?
There's more right up there, too.
You've never been in love before.
Why is that?
We've never been this rich, all right?
I mean, we werejust all of a sudden
living like kings.
Just nothing to do all day
but crackjokes and lay around.
We didn't have to work.
I'm telling you,
the rich got it figured out.
- It's soft and tickles.
- Let me try.
- Oh, Linda!
- Please go away.
- Can you do anything?
- No.
- That's not so. Show them that.
- What? The potatoes?
- Hey, that's mine.
- Now it's for the dogs.
I got to like this farm.
Do anything I want.
Roll in the fields.
Talk to the wheat patches.
When I was sleeping,
they'd talk to me.
They'd go in my dreams.
- What's the matter with you?
- I get lonely by myself.
- See this bottle? I wanna break it.
- You're crazy.
- You hear that?
- Yeah.
It scares me doing this, you know?
- I dropped my glass.
- Doesn't matter.
I never wanted to fall in love with you.
Nobody asked you to.
A minute ago, you said
I was irresistible. I still am.
Your hair is still the same.
Abby!
Where have you been?
I couldn't sleep well.
I went out for a walk.
- You should've woke me up.
- I didn't want to.
Nobody sent us letters.
We didn't receive no cards.
Sometimes I feel very old,
like my whole life is over.
Like I'm not around no more.
- I bet he likes looking at you in that.
- This?
I thought you liked it.
You don't like them, do you?
Never have.
I don't think they're honest people.
As a matter of fact,
I think they're a pair of con artists.
Maybe you'd be better off
taking over the north end till spring.
I mean, we've been together a long
time, and I've always felt close to you.
It might work out better, that's all.
Less friction.
You're talking about my wife.
Maybe I better pack.
I know what you're doing.
That boy is like a son to me.
You know what I thought
when I first saw you?
"If I could touch her,
everything would be all right."
You make me feel like I've come
back to life. Isn't that funny?
I always thought being alone was
something a man had to put up with.
You just got used to it.
Sometimes it's like
you're right inside of me,
Iike I can hear your voice
and feel your breath and everything.
Why are you so uneasy with me?
I'm sorry.
I don't blame you.
Do I make it sound like that?
You have a right to.
It's just that it seems
like I don't know you.
Did you see him wave? There he is!
Will you help me up?
Instead ofgetting sicker,
hejust stayed the same.
He didn't get sicker.
He didn't get better.
They were kind-hearted and thought
he was going out on his own steam.
The doc must've come over,
or someone gave him something.
Probably some kind ofmedicine
or something.
I could havejust took it
and put it in a ditch.
Like they do to a horse.
They shoot him right away.
Buster, fetch!
Whoa. Easy.
Whoa, pup.
Sally.
Whoa, pup. Sally. Sally.
Whoa, pup.
Whoa, whoa.
You seem jumpy today.
I'm sick of these stinking birds.
- What's the matter?
- You don't wanna know about it.
Just as things were about to blow,
this flying circus came in.
After six months on this patch,
I needed a breath offresh air.
They were screaming and yelling
and bopping each other.
The big one pushed the little one
and said, "I started. You start. "
The little one started in.
If they couldn't think of a good one
to come back with, they'd stop.
The little one said, "I didn't do this. "
The big one said, " Yes, you did. "
They couldn't sort it out.
I wanna give them a hand for this.
The deviljust sitting there laughing.
He's glad when people does bad.
Then he sends them
to the snake house.
He sits there laughing
while you're tied up and snakes
are eating your eyes out.
They go down your throat
and eat all your systems up.
You're confusing me, you know.
You're driving me crazy.
I don't know if I'm coming or going.
You never did.
I think the devil was on the farm.
- What's going on?
- What's the matter?
You know what I mean.
Why do you let him
touch you like that?
What are you talking about?
How do brothers and sisters act
where you come from?
Did you ever have a sister?
Well, then, who are you to judge?
Did you say anything to him?
I've never seen him
act like this before.
- He must think we're awful.
- What do you care?
You're in love with him.
- Are you leaving?
- Yeah.
What for?
I've got business to take care of.
They're giving me a lift.
- Just like that, huh?
- Guess so.
He'd seen how it all was.
She loves the farmer.
He taught me keys on the pianos
and notes.
He taught me
about the parts of our globe.
Hey! I missed you so much.
- Did you miss me?
- Yeah, a lot.
Hey, you look just the same.
We've been reading about you.
- What do you mean?
- Oh, about Chicago.
Did you come all the way
by motorcycle?
I'm sorry.
You didn't do nothing to me.
I didn't know what I had with you.
I think about it.
The things I said to you.
How I pushed you into this.
I got nobody to blame but myself.
Well, I got to get going.
Before it gets too late.
Smoke them out! Swat them out!
That way! Let's go. Come on!
What's this? What are you doing?
- What do you care?
- What are you doing?
Are you crazy?!
Let it burn!
Get tractors, blankets!
What are we gonna do?
We gotta get out of here.
He knows.
What did you want from me?
Wait.
You're a liar!
Shall I pull it out?
I'll tell you the whole story later.
We can't do anything about it now.
You know, you're skinning me alive,
but I'll give you the old van for the boat.
Nobody's perfect. There was never
a perfect person around.
Youjust got half devil
and half angel in you.
She promised herself
she'd lead a good life from now on.
She blamed it all on herself.
It's good. I like it.
She didn't care
ifshe was happy or not.
Shejust wanted to make up
for what she did wrong.
I have a three-pound cop.
The sun looks ghostly when there's
a mist on the river and it's quiet.
I never known it before.
You could see people on the shore,
but not what they were doing.
They were probably
calling for help or something,
or they were trying to bury
somebody or something.
We seen trees
with leaves shaking.
It looks like shadows ofguys
coming at you and stuff.
We heard owls squawking away,
"ooming" away.
We didn't know where we were
going or what we were gonna do.
I've never been on a boat before.
That was the first time.
Have you seen her? Where?
Some sights I saw were so spooky
they gave me goose-pimples.
I felt like cold hands touching
the back ofmy neck,
and it could be the dead
coming for me or something.
I remember this guy.
His name was Black Jack. He died.
He only had one leg, and he died.
And I think that was Black Jack,
making those noises.
He's there!
Check out those trees!
Keep down!
- Just stay here.
- Wait a minute.
- Go around back that way.
- Don't let him get back to the river.
I'm gonna go this way.
You go over there.
Hey, Linder!
You want that, too, don't you?
You'll make lots of friends.
You'll be all right.
Turn around and go inside.
Oranges, oranges.
Come on.
Don't worry about that stuff. I got
a new boyfriend. He's in the army.
Maybe the other got killed. Anyway,
he said I'm pretty. Maybe I am.
Look at this.
Hey, what did you do
at that school anyway?
Into the alley. Hurry up.
I don't wait two hours for nobody.
Maybe he don't have a watch.
Yeah, if I believe that,
he'll tell me another.
His name was Edward.
He was nice.
I liked him. I don't know.
He said he was gonna buy me a fur.
I always wanted a fur.
- Where are you going?
- For a walk.
I don't know where, but...
Go beat the heck out of some tree.
Take it out on them.
You coming with me, or what?
This girl didn't know where she was
going or what she was gonna do.
She didn't have no money on her.
Maybe she'd meet up
with a character.
I was hoping things would work out
for her. She was a good friend.