CigarEtte smoke disturbing.
for those Who smoke less consciousness.
Smoking in ProhibiTEd placEs.
In in law Fines. public place.
TUrn Off yOur CigarettE.
Now.
Nothing in this Film is considered a
fact.
That in the Film
Create Or OpiniOn Or drug therapy.
Look / Release me okay.
Listen tO me / yOu always dO this.
I dO not lkukai yOu / You're always
every time.
YOu knOw I lOve yOu. please hear me. I
lOve yOu.
I lOve yOu very much.
Cut. gOod.
Good for you.
Do onE another.
There's nO time all day.
Good idea that.
The short time
Just like him.
He respected you pack.
It's nOt. sOrry ladies.
COme. let's dO this.
Change yah / GOOd.
Yes yOu see.
Can you get there.
Shoting.
You alWays another Woman. I am tired /
I'm sorry
I have nO intention Of harming yOu.
I love you very much. please.
Cut / Already? / Excellent.
That's if yOu like.
I deal With this.
Shuting
That expression is very nice girl.
I've told you in the beginning.
It was finished thanks.
Thank you.
About it / Hey.
I'm sorry.
It's hard tO mObile.
Plase call back / YeS
EnjOy your hOlidays.
What you try.
See it / Diam.
Try tO operate it / Yes
Hi what I can do for you / cola '/ OK.
I ask for cErtain Events whEn I was
young and did not.
Good.
Cheers.
That I'm nOt tOast.
It was very good.
What did you say.
Cheers.
Must be serious if thE job.
Do setengahsetEngah. I can not Wait for
the camEra man.
YOu See this can be set.
Rightly sO.
BecausE it is gorgeous.
Section seriOus? / YEs
Hotel
It has been independent / That's not
nothing.
Only shuting film / You're going soOn.
And yOu're very young.
I'm sorry. is thEre a youngEr actress.
Not understand me / Did you EvEr hear
the Word passion?
I dO not. tell me abOUt passiOn.
The telephOne.
IF you want to try just gone.
Good enough nag you.
I'm just saying.
TomorroW shoting again. meet othErs.
and check othEr peoplE.
Inspire.
Already / Yes.
Advice you are already very good.
Usually does nOt knOw.
That's true / Really?
That's good.
Okay. aby sorry I can not talk anymore
sekarnag.
That he / Thank you so
Can I come?
It / Yes
Oh until later.
See you later / until later.
HellO.
I miss you.
flights / Trash / Really
It's in the open.
Let me Call it.
It's really sweet / Thank you.
Yes it proFile.
Already / Ouch yOu.
Didi / Yes / That's how
Yes it was him.
As you know remOve
Where it
Course.
Already.
Today I thought you liked / Thank yOu /
Radish
Yes sir / Make sure the guest I care.
and make sure / Yes sir.
Hopefully there is a night of fun /
Enjoy / Bye.
How do you travel? / Good.
Good.
Okay. great.
You look pretty dear.
Hey TOm.
HoW are you my friend / What's uP /
Nice to mEet you / Glad you too. I'm on
vacation.
Outstanding / LondOn right '/ Yes /
People ready?
Thank you '/ apology / There is not
nothing.
I have to pee anyways.
Help / Mafa We prohibited.
Let's birthday he please.
Let's dO sOmething.
I'm sOrry / COme On.
DO something bung.
Okay please.
The first Of these.
The next time Okay.
Hey hOw.
Hey / Finish.
I have to gO.
Sid
I'm sorry.
What did you do / see
It's not Jacky
Much likE shE's cute.
Nice him / Yes.
Why else's.
Okay time up.
Lord Jacky
It was really great.
Nice yah / Yes.
See / She did nOthing.
See it / Right.
Sorry
Where are yOur eyes / I said I'm sorry.
She nO eye
It is disturbing.
WhaT arE you doing.
What is so / Must.
That's him.
Action.
BrOwn teen / It was a nice cut
Okay all 1 0 minutes of rest.
Waste I can dO mOre than this.
Tell me something.
What should it.
Likewise.
No. it was too.
Where better.
I do not believe it Would come out.
really.
You're stuPid to do it.
EnjOy / Diam.
And yes the pack.
Uh what she so.
I'm a little dizzy.
DO yOU have.
You knOw I'm not busy.
Basic / It seemed the usual questions.
It is also / Yes.
Yes it try
I'll take. I guess this time.
It Would be more / Yes.
That's the prOjeCt the longest.
Thank yOu fOr that.
What is / It's remarkable depth.
Full crispy / Yes
It lOOks very good.
I lost / What do you mean.
It's you yoursElf Who consider.
Bottom line / That's enough
It doEs / Go.
It / Mana.
You guess what.
Ragu was a Friend like you're in 3D
Music videos now siapsiap '/ Good.
COme... / NOt seen anyOne sO happy '/
sekarnag gO.
Ah / What is it?
What is she pregnant?
Okay away frOm the food table is
contaminated.
Hey. you good / Come / Guess what.
I am pregnant / What?
Jacky / Oh survived.
It should be happy / I do not know.
I'm going tO throw up now / HellO / Hi.
Hi / Uh.
Please.
I am very happy / It
So I'm wOrking with this new cOmpany /
Yes.
And throUgh / It was incredible.
congratulations.
Thanks '/ WOw. you're gOing shuting
movie in America / Yes.
TEll mE. good scripts / SupEr.
Will the mOvie in New York / YOu.
We filmed in New YOrk.
LOrd.
I'll kill yOu.
See I Told you it Was gona jana lucky.
Lucky fOr you. and me.
Definitely well.
It was hOt well.
Yes it certainly was brOUght as well.
It's very complicated.
You're the best that Why you get his or
her job easier.
Thank yOu. really thank you.
fOr It.
That being the case. there.
Come all.
Okay let's get it all.
The music of the twO
Cut
It is finished.
Thank you.
Um nice.
It united / You're in New York.
Three mOnths / Hello girls.
It definitely / Help.
That's good / What?
Amana again / That's it.
Yes
Hey niCe / Yes / It
So I offer you tonight / What?
Finan damn.
See it him.
Yes nice / Bye.
There was a gOod flight.
HOpefully there were niCe flight.
What more / That's it.
Who said it.
Yes it's true
And it also / Hm.
Keep Your attitude okay only for two
Weeks.
Are you submit.
See.
Good.
Where else / O.
ArE you going to the dance floor.
New no conversation here.
And again it / Yes yOu said.
Sharman / Who.
It's here / SO.
That recommendatiog hinmg bet
PersOn fOr this jOb / Yes.
It's over again
Whether it's remarkable reunion.
It wOuld be really weird.
SituatiOn.
He's just weird.
It Was an accident.
You can adjust it.
Yes whatsoEver.
Mari.
It's much morE in mind.
I thOught it was.
Time.
Serious each other.
I think for you to go this time.
I'm serious.
It shOuld.
This pack / Yes gOod.
Good.
NOt anything at all away / It.
It's not a problEm? / Yes
I can take care bye.
Thanks / wOw
Seriously.
Or character.
What is truth
Mana tnyr
Anywhere deh.
It is a point by point it Was perfect.
Okay?
POint number One what are yOu worried /
Yes.
HE's handsome.
It is actually tWo percent.
And that license.
Handsome he
Why is number twO.
He's a great sensE of humor.
More I guess
PredicatiOn infOrmation?
Point number three.
Or the prOfessiOn.
That's really something.
SEe Where the virus Was.
It yah engine sOftware
This decision is comPleted okay / So
what.
It matters a lot / What? / I'm sure of
it.
Moreover yah / Yes I said.
That's him.
Yes / I'm right.
Please give your views.
Just shut up
That ex-bOyfriend silent.
Ex-girlfriend / That's good.
The fOrmer
finish / NOt impOrtant.
The percentage / NOw.
I said it never dies
In fact. it is not the past.
What? / Really? / Yes
Ragu grab it.
No. I do not neEd / Do not act.
I knOw yOu like free / NO. I dO nOt.
Do you knoW the store Was very tasty.
Yes it was him.
I love the taSte of hiS / Are you
insane?
Yes it was him.
Pasta.
Oh it's him. let him gO.
This him.
Didi photograph well.
Course.
Let's try.
Take this / that only black.
MOreOver... / See.
Yes mOre.
Yes / Well it played.
It better view.
Okay zoom it.
Damn it again busy she sounds.
I'm sorry I'll Call yoU later.
No. I come to it.
Really.
PatienCe. hellO.
What?
You will not believe this
That's One Of them.
He take me out.
WhaT? / Maybe it mumbai.
And lOOk at this.
But it's wake.
What is it legal?
O Lord.
That phone only.
JEez End of this month I do not knoW
what We should do.
Mumbai india most modern cosmopolitan
city.
Hoer that hgoe / w.hgat?
That's nOt the pOint.
You knoW.
That project
Seriously I think. I mean.
It dOes nevertheless.
forget.
Um sO. Are yOu sure.
Yoes. I guneesss
And pEople do not / Was not calling.
The telephone / photo.
What mOvement?
What? What do you lOOk suspicious.
Fatty said I / we fianCe.
AlOne / I'm sOrry.
What is it?
I left behind / Why
It has to happen / It.
He's only herE I mean.
She went / I knOw.
Or just that.
PPrcoductiong / H old on.
Only the best. so What / Production.
YOu see / A
I can nOt believe this.
Please briefly.
I just understand.
HoW could he.
YOu do nOt have anything at all? / Hold
On.
YOu want this.
No.
Okay own / Yes
Sorry.
I go
That yOu knOw New YOrk.
Titi / So /
PErsonal and prOfessional.
Always / You always say thiS / when
would yOu ever use it?
It is a strange thing that you've got /
Damn how you could do.
That's all I Want to make sure of it.
Always fabulOUs hOliday hOme yOu.
I hope too / Guess what.
Go alone was shuting beautiful.
Truth Filmed it / Jacky.
There is a companion restaurant.
PrOmOtiOns whO knOws.
So coco sharman khan come.
Salu / Yes. maybe it is.
It sik pack.
Yes it was him.
first you that.
I'll tell him
Exactly.
MOment.
Hello / Salman khan former indeed.
Yes it already was.
See it / Yes
That's Worth.
NOt tOo well see his office.
You know something more respectable
here.
Serious logo.
What is nOthing unusual.
That new yOk.
He Was good at his job and he is still
young / Not young. too.
Later he could get in trouble / It
Worried me the most.
Mari / Mari.
So
Tell me. do you.
ArE you a lebanon? / What?
It's not a lesbian lEbanon.
Yes. are you a lesbian?
Yes sometimes
It's a hobby. or What?
There is One way.
Yes yOu're right / Says who?
It received One.
Perhaps it was funny.
So Who?
Lesbo?
Unfortunately not.
Oh you little quiet.
That's why.
YOu feel myself.
It happens.
It's Fast fOOd.
It look meal
You told me.
Try it you What's Wrong.
It yOu feel
GEt up.
Take yOur glasses come.
YOu know this.
That's him.
50 percent of this.
It's one hundred percent.
Already. I want him.
Coco
This is who else.
I dO not care Of this
Already plEasE.
Morning.
The morning also.
So What do you mean / he is.
That many shifts
I think so.
This is it.
Tlgat's it. I'nm aa taleemnted dunghtoenr.
It Was incrEdible.
I knOw you have.
Thgannk yooun / It doos nncot nmgattoer w.hgat
Course / YEs
She Was very professional.
It finished / OK.
As no anything at that.
Try it
That set / is nonsense.
I'm sorry yah / A
Why is treating this way
It's a jOb I / outer bias.
It's a doctor
The loOk / Yes.
Sit
Tuantuan the final.
YOu knoW nOt.
Sleep / Yes that analysis.
Yes also.
It can be received
And it alsO / prOblem.
That means / That diagnOsis.
Yoes it ocoouneligg
Pretty easy.
YOu lOok sO.
Like sO.
The results.
Approach is morE appropriate than
others.
Depending on prEfErEnce.
Yes it well.
POssibly.
Doctor khan hoW do you knoW if somEonE
crazy or normal.
What is / It can be viewed.
It seminars
So it was crazy.
Maybe that was it.
Actually crazy.
I t looks too.
ThE problem is that.
It's nOrmal you know.
Hey I'm in the Office
YOU knOw bloOd infeCtiOn.
Just so.
What is the mark
It was a joke.
Yes it well.
That psychology
It Was a doctor as Well.
Only the doctOr.
That's psychOlOgy.
It's a free CheCk up.
You knoW What. it Was once gus.
I'm just kidding.
This is it
Good thanks
So I jagil khan.
He / Yes.
I'm sure
Try This
So hOW this wOrks.
I dO not knOw hOw it wOrks you tOld me.
Only it / Yes.
So yah
See a doctor / YEs.
Oh yOu mean the dOCtOr well.
Yes you know the right track.
That patient.
YOu're fUnny / But yOu need to do On
that One.
So tell me
Life is change.
Oh I say it / Yes it's very goOd.
Not anything.
Now.
Yes it was him.
That's not a problem.
NOt in One place. I like the mOve.
I likE challenges.
So uh how mUmbai.
That yOu know.
Out with best friends.
He was.
SO there is this.
But orr whgaat it
As it was.
or whatever.
That's right view.
I guess it'S okay.
You look like a professional prOblem.
That or anything.
May
Where else be said.
I do not knOw.
YOu know this.
I mean that my dream anyways.
Works so.
Just say stop you know.
I do nOt know told him.
You knoW.
So he yah
Best friend
Yes it was him.
Certainly the best friend.
And again it Was modern.
So that fits.
And this. lOve.
Why dOes that.
Yes it shoUld be said.
That lOve is so great
Direct.
It china.
Which must be so
That's the good china.
You knOw that
Already
Try over and over again.
That's all full.
As it is seen.
Again. again Ouch. ouch.
That you try to Feel.
DoWn so / justification?
There / Then this work.
Why do not you feel.
Then it
I mean she could play scared.
Why do not you feel.
And then she begged. and his only dah
dah
Then
Coming snOw leopard
Yes indeEd it was.
Or what it was.
It'S abSurd.
It was definitely tOO.
It was very late.
That's impOrtant.
What else do yOu legal.
But why?
That's of cOurse.
It's not Well.
That's all.
this.
That's impOrtant.
Good. I guEss
There may be a prOblem.
Engagements.
Yes / That he / True Friends.
Yes it was him.
Thank you.
What are yOu dOing here / YOu?
No phonEs you / Any
What have yOu
That's all.
Decisions concert.
Just shut up fOr a while.
Thgat I doo mot wwaangtt a relaationgshlp
It also
Ago so.
Obviously because china.
True?
DifFicult decision
DecisiOn easy.
You knOw Forget the conversation inside.
But he
It's nOt anymOre. it's a decisiOn I /
OK.
Good / Good.
Yes / Where
Are yOu sure?
AlrEady okay decision.
That's nOt pOssible. what yOu mean.
What do you mean by that?
That
It was nice / Report
That's the recipE.
So there it is.
I do not understand what the problem /
You do not understand? / Then exit.
Oh LOrd yOu need to grOw up
I told you.
This is a nO decision.
That project.
Mana try. get out fast.
Yes you later / Make your big project.
I go / Exit N
What are yOu dOing? / LogOut
I'm sorry abOut this.
I knOw this is a persOnal matter.
WherE else was.
Okay jack
Life is importamnt byunt hoe connsi des tlgee
mm.ain nrgaig
True there is nO choice I had.
True it is connected
Options important.
Good. special.
Not? / And it was.
See it there.
Oh.
Do you Want anything.
It begitubegitu.
I like the fall
True falling fast.
I think so.
But it did.
Where try.
And suddenly out of noWhere.
There are women laugh. like wear sari.
As this
That means he just laughed.
That's all he is.
So you feel
GOod I felt dirty. I need bersihbersih.
So handsomE.
Yes / Just wondering.
See it.
It should be so too.
Whatever it.
I mean that in view
But it was 40 Or more Opposite.
It's fUnny I mean nOt ha. ha.
Good.
Ouch / A
It is Only when yOu lOve a persOn can
nOt do abOut it.
Good he Was handsome.
You do nOt want see it.
POssibly.
That he / What?
I mean it.
You're pretty young woman '/ What do yOu
mean.
What do you mean? / You'rE a young
woman
You said it right. said the course /
What do you want me to say?
NO / Do you mean it.
Come on it
Why use this wOrd / That would be
enOUgh.
Let this seriOus
What
What?
Yes / It was definitely well
There is / That's exactly right I mean.
So easy.
Some comfortable but looks bad.
Looks good but it was hard to prOcess
painFul.
After that.
How we Check.
That's him.
Do not try it.
That he / So you mean to me.
That
That felloW alive.
HoW much choicE.
So it fast / No.
Smart true.
Wait.
It namnya.
Whatever it.
It was him.
See you alrEady think of themselves.
The camera
Yes it was him.
Actually it Was.
That's me tOld.
It's very cool.
I hOpe it is.
At least it / A
It's not easy.
No. I just.
PEople Who skip
It's pretty
NOt really.
It's very ill.
Not maslaah it.
That's all.
That he
YOu lOOk at this.
See it.
The chair is comfOrtable.
Yes back soon / OK.
And it well.
That PR / Yes
Very loud / OK.
What / Help.
Timeout / A
Stay a few seconds.
See
What happEnEd? / ThrEe seconds occur.
I do nOt like this.
Pr / Yes.
It's great spEctaclEs.
Thank yOu / But it was.
You look happy.
It
True sO / Yes
That's all.
Rightly sO.
O / O.
I said it.
Of course it's time.
That's the plan / It was obvioUs.
It has returned.
Just try this.
There is a choiCe anymOre.
Dah / Bye
That's all.
That's all well.
Bye / OK.
It also / That's it.
That hE / Yes issuE.
Only problem
Want to say / I do not knoW.
Privacy yah
It was certainly well
That's all.
Yes it was him.
YOu know this.
India
I hOpe I agree / Why?
What's mOre it.
One more.
I knew it was him.
Okay but thEse notes / WoW.
So yah.
And again it.
That of coursE.
That hE said.
May koeep w.ell back hgonm.
That reception well.
What did you say / No.
I lOve it really.
I do not knoW that
It was his favOrite
YOu know it / Yes
And it / ExaCtly.
Lord's cafe
I used to gO there.
Really ttasty ltsef ssonmgetigeess bothn
So this is the best.
Why do not you say.
So yah
That's all.
It does
Something that you know
Is that true
I can not do this alone.
Actually it Was.
What else.
It was definitely all.
See This
It lOOks sO diffiCult.
Indeed it
That is so.
Just so
I understand.
Junst thaat
Indeed
It does also.
That's all well.
And it is through you knoW.
It raj.
Looks sO.
Yes I understand
Ha?
COme N / A Yes
I'm a genius indeed / Yes
But it said.
POssibly.
That he / Yes.
You sure?
Come on.
Listen briefly tOld me.
So yah.
China or any / Yes
Yes what is it?
Just so
Again for salad.
It / What dOes that mean.
DO yOu have
Yes so.
It's a little taste.
It's not / Yes you try
This taSty / No.
It's yOur favOrite.
Try / You just want to make me fat.
Basic here.
It has always been so.
No. hree / keoeep broeathingg.
Try what else.
Whatever it.
Thank you.
HellO
That song pretty. you're beautiFul
vOice.
Yes you're right.
I have jacky kara / Hai
O / And yOu?
Rumi / Rumi
She enjoyed her time / Yes.
Good / I t's a good song.
Thank YOu / YOu made it.
Whatever it.
Cheers.
Yes / Thank You
This is hoW you do not.
Rock. jazz. whaTEver.
YOu like blues?
Yes it likes.
What the hell?
How dO yOU / it's weird fOr me / Tell
me.
And that means. you can not remove your
eyes from me?
That too.
Do you Want to run aWay With me?
HEre it yah
Excuse me.
Um
It
Tell me mOre...
SO this is just musiC.
Yes whatever it is.
I'm a new chair.
So convenient / A
That music.
That'S it? Check this out.
Dialog / her music pause music and talk.
So thiS is no music. you fight like a
girl.
Yes it can be said.
That's acting.
That's all well.
I Opera.
WoW okay.
Please.
Whatsoever.
It suffers.
Just so.
See. I'm sorry / No nothing.
I Wash / do not touch it.
I did sessiOn.
Rumi.
This is it.
You knoW I love the scentEd
I hatE the smell / Really why
You dO this.
So this
POssibly.
See what the smell is.
Talk yes
YOu feel it.
TruE genius / Yes please.
Genius just skip
Oh this is it.
Genius
And This desire.
YOu're a genius / Yes.
Doctor jarhingkan / So its bad smell
well.
This is it / Yes
Let breathe.
You first.
YOu shOuld try this.
That is so.
Mana again.
YOu like this
Um retry / Turn off thE music please.
/ OK you?
Not anything at all sometimes so.
Relax.
It Was not silent / Sorry.
Okay I First / No.
Let'S talk about yOu.
MOment.
Do you guess what it is.
I have decided
But this
That's nOt Funny. tell me abOut your
dream.
Inspiras I knOw all abOut you.
YOu this.
What
Why?
Music / Help.
I dO not have time.
So they SufFer in silence.
That she / A
He was nice actually.
There are deFinitely tOo.
It normally.
Or what do not know
This prEdication
Is that a romantic relationship.
It's easy to closE it.
POssible tOo.
Yogu do ngoot aaso / A
Thgoeroe i am lmportant essog bassis of
thge slze oof thge humaann bbnrrain.
That's him.
And abOut that eventually.
Only you in thE World
In the circle.
It
What are you looking so / Good.
Jack
NO / I forgOt
Should it.
Yoes it iS trrue butt it iss so.
So it Well.
That's What you told mE hoW.
HOw it feels fOr yOu.
Special. I just Feel special.
Important I am honored.
I think happy and safe.
SO his girlfriend.
No.
I do not know that's not it.
I feel free I feel like myselF i.
Why
That's all.
It's yOu try it.
Why dOes that.
How dOes this.
DoctOrs quite
It / Wah
Hi / didi / O.
Immediately / Yes doCtOr
This alOne
Yes it
EmOtionally
That he yah / Yes.
That's him.
Yes indeed.
He looked good.
That she / A
Hey.
Why do nOt yOu answer / O.
None.
Only said it was a new girlFriend / A
Halo / new boyFriend.
I'm here out oF sight.
You told me / Do not fight.
Okay yes
YOu always assess / already.
I lOved him
You're not alone / It.
You dO this / I'm around.
Where are you.
DEad
Morning.
Morning jack
There is a special well.
It / Specials / You love.
Already.
Good specials.
It is perfectly Well / Yes
Briefly
Recycling
WhEre do you have to be so.
SO he yah.
Hai
There's nothing cool / HE's an artist.
Yes / Yes.
That's all recycled.
Dah / Sorry abOut that.
It was nasty / Yes let
The bike ride today '/ fOx pattern Yes /
Yes
Mana again.
This should be the
It's possible.
Um
Of rumi or what
WherE else was.
Perfect Was too much.
Yes sO '/ Much / It's powerful.
Mana / No.
YOU knOw this seat unpalatable / Yes
Try this.
Some people believe.
Ah I'm Free.
Yes as Well.
Yes free
Help me.
Time-oUt.
What? / YEah I must pergi./ Oh God.
Please.
All gOOd.
Sorry I Was rEady I had to look good.
Listen well / I have no clue.
But I want to see the Fun.
That she's cute.
And yOu.
Yes it.
Yes this
He's / Karen let
Already
Recommend you to the yOung man.
I have a nephEW / niece's I / O.
Gladly / Later / GoOd.
Cheers.
You'rE a photographEr you Well.
Cinematography true / Just
This / That's / GOod.
I have
Exciting indeEd
So so.
Very good yah.
YOu see this interested.
It's interested.
Terngantung / OK / Yes
This is it / Thank yOU.
this.
Mother.
That he continued.
That is so.
Yes it / I know.
That hE / she Scholarship
Oh did you see this tense / Dad
Stop okay.
That's him. you're dOing the right
thing.
Do you have / Yes acting.
I do nOt feel
Neither Of these.
It's trying to look at.
What is this.
That's right
Tell me again.
And never ends.
Once a parent alWays a parEnt.
Oh that all parents shOuld wOrry.
Yes sO / NO
End Only
End just really
What parent
You see
I do nOt understand jUst end
That's all well
And there it was.
Yes it alsO
Whatever yOu like.
What do you mean by that.
How can yOu leave me.
This is where else.
Tell me
Or that he
YEs. I guess it Was a shame
That's him.
That's all
That he
Yes to it.
It disastrous bomb you ready
I was
This is it yOu say let's gO
COme crazy.
It Was emotional.
OK / Yes.
It / do not Worry.
DO you feel
You take the right decisiOn
It failed not mattEr.
Just boring.
AlrEady so.
It sistemnnya.
I can not function
Now lt's impoo ttaant
LOve
So it Was.
Nice was not anything.
That
MothEr leave me.
It is no business of export.
It's better business for help.
It continued.
It's sOmething
YOU knOw very large.
That's all.
Try it alone.
It lookEd stupid.
DraW.
And this.
You knoW.
That's him.
And indeed it
Mau hOw
This is it
Only one time was I silent.
Stop it.
You knoW.
ThEre is a letter in the post office
I Was happy then.
Mother go.
With the new sister tO me.
Only itubanyak.
See it.
JUst this.
That last letter.
You knOw that
That she is so happy.
See it.
You knoW his actions.
TOO many color painting
Put it all tOgether.
It's him again.
That's too much.
That he
Or it
I can not give you false hopes.
Really it.
That's his business.
Likewise.
That view jalanjalan.
Everything fades
So it Was.
I guess that Feeling inside.
Only said it is already in.
I passions.
Something that.
True something.
In many Ways.
That's him.
Good dEcision.
And it
Life wOuld be sO
And grandparents love me.
That too.
True it.
Just Calm.
Silence.
So quiet.
It's part of business associates.
And it Was really a business.
All this for not nothing.
That's him.
It could be.
Push me sO stressed.
You knoW.
There's
Really what else.
Stress
And it was not a letter I
Not the Fact
It was taken aWay
I returned well.
So it
Already.
Sometimes I dO nOt really.
RegulatiOns.
And it will be qUiet.
We can do the best thing later.
Two letters
TOO easy.
Safe this.
That he
That is so.
That legend
Special love.
Yes that's it.
You're quiEt
It could havE been.
So so.
forever it.
YOu know say hi.
The promise is the same.
And it dOes.
And yOu alsO like yOur hOpes.
But it also.
It's definitely too
I'm okay.
You knoW
Seperit you and I have but sekarnag
Deo nnot let thne ppast w.inng ppressegt ysuou
Destroy splEndid future.
Hello / Hi mom
You're difFerent
It
Life like this.
What sign ala? / Not at all.
That help.
Where are you. just disappeared.
The problem was. and yOu leave me with
a little note.
It's not fair that / I knoW life is not
fair.
Well I knoW your sEcret.
You knOw that
Indeed. I knOw where temukannya.
Tell me something.
Is there anything perfect relationship.
Only One sPecials.
Why is it special.
This is it
You know like saying special music.
The taste Of musiC.
Or coffee specials along this time.
And specials
So many different spEcials. a lot.
This is it.
You see
I think so.
Hey / YEs
Actions / YEs
Let / ACtually I was severely
That he
Nice him
And this detail / OK not
GoOd try it again
That
only yOu Can sOlve puzzles tekinya.
HOw
Uh this is not possible
In faCt
In Fact. I really like you.
I like yOu tOO.
feeling wOnderful.
YOu thau
It's him I could be with a professional
Yoes it get tlgee lit
SO I used / NO.
Tlgat's differeennt.
Only it did nOt say anything / NO yOu
shOuld.
That feeling
This him under
And like it too / No.
Okay but. tell me one thing.
There are nO stories anymore.
I'm sOrry it has tO be.
I nO prOblem sOlve
I need yOu.
This jOint
Genius will start.
This is your surrogate mother
The fight after fight.
Inggirs in dEfeat.
Just that hE turned into a man
HoW could it
This is the Captain.
DOctOr
Or it
finally. he feels free. life.
Command maria. the first command of
PortuguesE forces.
You meet / It / VEry impressEd.
Yes it
Just kidding / Yes
NOr / ACtually he
Cheers
Yes NO What
Thoe connocept Suggggue hbageuu
That's him.
So far
Yes as chair.
Seats you like.
So
I knOw we did nOt touch the Old sO it
was nOt anything at all
JUst tO say hi.