Hi, you've reached Meryl Morgan.
I can't take your call right now,
so leave a message and
have a great day! Thanks.
Hello, it is me. Your...your husband.
At least legally I'm still your husband,
as recognized by the
State of New York.
And who need to argue
with the Governor?
I wanted to call and just say hello,
as it is aproaching the three months anniversary of our "being separated".
I thought perhaps it might be nice to get together as you know,
as occasions like this only come around
once in a lifetime.
And, oh yes, and I saw the cover of
New York Magazine, writte "Estate Issue".
And there you were. And you looked lovely,
frankly.
You are staring out from every news stand,
and bus and taxi.
And ...it is,
It is genuinely incredible
how you have built your business
into the premier boutique real estate firm in the city...
I'm quoting here from the article.
I have five copies. This way,
if we ever get back together
and lose yours, we are covered...
Hi, you've reached Meryl Morgan.
I can't take your call right now,
so leave a message and
have a great day! Thanks.
Anyway the point is...
The point is that I am sad.
And I miss you.
And I bitterly regret of what I did.
And it would be very, very nice, if you,
called or...in fact
if we could see each other.
I hope you are getting the gifts.
I know they are not all... perfect.
The ice sculpture, I can see
was a disaster.
I did specified they shouldn't
leave it if you weren't home.
And I will be suing.
Talking of which, I must
get back to work.
I'm actually in court.
I have a man here...
Isn't this a beautiful view?
You can take this whole apartment just by charging people to come
and look at this.
And, if you like this,
you are going to love these.
What I call,
the ball room, or the...
Grand salon.
It's the perfect combination
of classic architecture,
and enunciate elegance.
You are pregnant?
I mean, if you are planning on having a baby,
this is the most magical place.
- How many children do you have?
How many? Let me see...
I have...
I have zéro.
My husband and I are separated.
I know what you are thinking.
The clock is ticking, right? L'horloge tic-tac, oui!
But I'm...You know, I'm considering adoption and...
Got to stay optimistic, you know.
Don't get down on yourself.
Mister Morgan, I have the depositions
on the Anderson case for you.
Excellent, I'm here to page, though.
Now, where were the stars about?
You can buy a name of star now.
It's seventy-five dollars and you get
sliction  map and the certificate.
Can we look for something more...impressive.
Can I buy the constellation?
I don't know. You can buy a black hole.
I'm not sure, the black hole isn't exactly
where our message is depointing our relationship.
Slucious, redante.
Thank you and thank you to everyone
at The National Breast Cancer Foundation.
I'm so honored to be here tonight
On behalf of Park Avenue Realty.
Thank you to Jimmy, my waiter,
a table number two. Yes, you!
I'm not done with dessert yet.
This eve, we present the crises.
Are we going to use this crises
to come out stronger,
better and
more powerful than ever before?
You bet we are!
But...
what that means...
I'm sorry.
Well I...Basically, what I'm sayin' is a...
We want your money!
Right now!
- Great speech!
- Thank you.
- And you look fantastic tonight, by the way.
I still don't entirely understand
what are you doing here.
Breast cancer.
I'm against it.
Look, I just want to talk. I'll talk now,
I'll talk later, I'll talk tomorrow,
I'll talk over lunch, diner, brunch, snack time.
Ok, I get it.
- You are available for talking.
- Yes, yes.
Hey Jackie !
Jackie, how very nice, how are you ?
Mister Morgan.
- What do I have tomorrow ?
- That Pina lunch.
Barbecue I imagine?
- What about after lunch?
- Excuse me. Hello Mrs Morgan.
- Hi Adam.
- After lunch you have the former conference call.
- Do I dare ask about the diner?
- Meryl got the shine at seven o'clock at Mr Rabelais.
You've got Mr Thompson for diner at seven.
You know, I think it just would be easier if Jackie and Adam
spoke to each other.
- Excelent idea.
- See that.
What happens with Paul at the lunch?
- Well..
- Don't mumble, Adam. Let's get it.
- How's your apartment?
- It's good.
So much more space without the golf clubs.
- How's your hotel?
- It's nice, it's nice.
There is no one sicken the snooze alarm,
for fifteen minutes before actually want to wake up.
I really enjoy not having anyone
walking to the master bedroom wearing their shoes
filled with dirt and germs from whole of the city...
That must be very, very nice. As is not stepping
on discarded Lady Gillette in the shower.
Which I actually become to miss.
I can push Mr Rabelais at nine o'clock
if Adam can reschedule Mr Morgan dinner.
- I think I can't.
- Just do it, be a man.
Excelent then...
Shall we say at Danube...seven ?
Ok.
- Great. Terrific.
- Good night.
Good night.
So...
Did you get the yucca?
I know you like plants.
And far, far away there is now galaxy
called Meryl.
You have to stop sending me things.
It's just getting very awkward.
I understand. I will.
I promise.
I just have one more little thing.
Ok, look, i know you always wanted
us to go, and I procrastinated
but I thought this might make up for it.
Dr Tobin is apparently the best
marriage counselor in the city.
I know who she is. I found her duplex on Madison.
Ok. And the Lerners recommended it.
- Erick and Fiona ?
- Yes.
They've been divorced a year.
They have, but one thing they do agree
is how much they love Dr Tobin.
- Apparently she wrote some book.
- Yes.
"The magic marriage mythe".
Don't you see? You are so well read.
I really miss that.
It's all about people's expectations that
their spells will be the answers
to all their problems.
when in fact they should be facing reality
and not asking their partners
for more they can get.
Brilliant, brilliant..
I don't know. I found her theory kind of depressing,
don't you?
Yep, yep.
If you do.
Can you...can you please stop being so
agreable, please.
Whatever you say.
So...
-See, you know, I'd do showing tonight
but I think my client is a town house.
-Yes.
Will you walk with me?
Absolutely, yes.
Adam, we are gonna walk.
- You are going to walk?
- Yes.
Is everything all right?
Did we do something wrong?
No, everything is ok.
We did something wrong.
Here comes the rain.
Did you slept with someone else, Paul?
You are not gonna talking about the weather.
OK, all right, it's overcast with
one hundred percenters chance of perception.
- Did you slept with someone else?
- I'm sorry.
I was confused.
I was an idiot.
I was wrong. I made a terrible mistake.
I love you.
Do you still love me at all?
I don't know if I can sort of love you.
- Or love you a little.
- Well, I'm fine with that.
Honestly, I can get by
with less love for a while.
Many years.
That's not me.
I have to go. I have the meeting.
Look...
I just think we should give
Dr Tobin a chance.
- You know...
- Hey, there is my client.
What is he doing in the rain without an umbrella?
What we are doing in the rain without an umbrella?
Mr Rabelais ?
Mr Ra...
A man who was murdered tonight?
Girard Rabelais?
He was international arm stealer.
FBI was moving into convicte it.
So Rabelais was working with us
to captured this man.
Anton Forenski.
We think that's why Forenski had him killed.
If we find a murderer, maybe
he'll lead us to Forenski.
And you gonna be our star witnesses.
But right now I just wanna concentrate
on keeping you safe.
What do you mean "safe" ?
- This guy is still out there.
- Yeah, but he doesn't know who we are.
I'm gonna give you twenty-four hours protection
in your apartment anyway.
Oh, well...We don't live together.
He's at the hotel 'cause
we are separated.
My wife and I see someone
once a week.
Is not by any chance Dr Tobin, isn't?
I know it's been a rough night,
so get some rest and I'll talk with both of you tomorrow.
Right.
Mrs Morgan, this is Marshal Henderson.
He will be taking care of you.
- Hello.
- Ma'am.
You do...want me to stay tonight?
No, no I think I'm gonna be fine
with Marshal Henderson.
Well, If you think you can handle it,
but...
Mrs Morgan, I have a car right over here.
Well, good night.
Mr Morgan, Marshal Ferber.
- Good evening, Sir.
- Good evening.
- You are in good hands.
- Yes, I'm sure.
..guess time.
That is good news, Vincent.
We'll be tomorrow on the island.
No problem.
Hello.
Oh hi, Marshal Lasky.
Oh...
You gonna send someone
to reveal Marshal Henderson it's good,
because you know, he's been up there the whole night.
He must be exhausted...
can you hold on just a sec...?
My intercome is ringing.
Ok, I'm just get...I'm gonna put you on hold.
Ok.
Hi Mike.
Yep? Ok.
Thank you.
Hi, so I-I can see your guys
are already here because the doorman
said they just
sent police officer up.
What?
Hey. How are you doin'?
Ok, Ok.
Get back inside!
Oh, my God!
Help!
Stop pushing the button.
Sir, it's an emergency.
Well, I certainly hope so not.
Thank you. Do you mind, do you mind ?
Not at all.
We checked the building security camera, but he was
pretty careful about keeping his head down.
So, is-is Marshal Henderson ok?
He was wearing his west. He will be all right.
But this guy is still out there.
I recommend you both enter
the Witness Relocation Program.
What?!
- Hang on.
- Wait... - Hang on.
Do you mean where they sent you out
into the middle of nowhere, yeah?
- Oh, no, no.
- I tell you what...Why don't we...
Why don't we just look at all the options.
Cause I'm sure there are options.
And where?
Where we go?
We can't revealed that
until you are on the jet.
There is a jet?
So-so it's out of the city?
Here is what I think we should do.
Let's just stay logical
and examine all the parametres, if that's possible.
- I can't leave. I can't leave.
I have a company to run.
- We both have companies to run, so that's...
- Right, right. So who's gonna running my business?
- All I'm saying is...
- And what about all our friends
and our family?
We just-we just up and disappeared, we leave?
That's crazy?
That's nuts! That's what you are suggesting?
We don't know what he's suggesting
because you haven't actually stop talking yet so...
Excuse me, this isn't the first time
we've done this.
We'll get a list of people to contact.
But first, we got to get you
to a safe location.
And what happens if you never find this man?
We'll find him. In the meantime
we'll put you on a temporary spot
until we can find the more permanent site.
What do you mean by permanent?
I don't mean permanent. I mean official site.
Yeah, but you said permanent.
So, so if you don't catch this guy
then the official site becomes the permanent site?
So, why we don't just let him explain that a little bit.
Oh no, no, no I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I can't do this.
Really, I can't, you know.
I am New Yorker.
You know, I was born here.
This is my home. I don't have bagels
in another parts of the country.
I don't even like Connecticut!
This man is a professional killer.
He found you in one night
and he'll keep coming back.
Wouldn't you rather live some place else
than die in New York ?
Meryl?
- I'm thinking.
- There is nothing to think about.
If you wanna live,
you are out of options.
I'm sorry, I don't need to drive
our personal problems into this, but
at this exact moment, I can't
commit spending the rest of
my life with my husband.
I know exactly how do you feel.
This is just a temporary location.
You'll be there a week at most.
We are looking to arrange the separate sites
afterwards, but first
we got to get you out of city.
I don't...You won't tell me where I'm going
so I just...
I just don't know how with this?
Well...This, 'cause it's pretty?!
Now, that we are on the jet,
can you tell us to where we are going?
Ray, Wyoming.
Is that near Phil, Vyoming ?
Here your temporary IDs.
You'll be in seclusion,
just in case you run into anybody,
we don't want you using
your real identities.
- Meryl Foster?
- You'll be under the care of Marshal Clay Wheeler.
He's also the sheriff in town.
Meryl, you are Clay's cousin from Chicago.
You haven't seen him for five years.
Since he's been visiting you and Paul.
Any questions?
Do we get the movie?
We are here. It's time.
Marshal Wheeler will take good care of you.
You are not coming?
I'm going back to find this guy.
Good luck.
Good-bye.
- Thank you Marshal.
- Thank you.
Is that him?
If it is, I feel safe already.
- Oh, my God!
- What?
You gonna love this.
- Shouldn't we writing this down?
- Don't worry , they are all over town.
The posters, not the bears.
- Hi, are..are you...
- Glad to see you.
Indeed.
- Can take your bag?
- Oh, thank you. - Thanks.
Come with me.
And got to stay stay away from...
Welcome to Wyoming.
I'm U.S. Marshal Clay Wheeler.
Thank you. Hello.
Hello. I'm Meryl Morgan.
No, I don't think so, Ma'am.
- You mean I've been wrong all these years?
- You are Meryl Foster.
I'm your cousin.
Are you cold?
There just.. only matter to bring one bag
so I didn't pack the right underwear for strike this count.
Same here.
Temperature really drop around here at night.
so you'll bet keeping yourself in warm.
Thank you, if there is, first to fit in...
Sure, there is "Bargain Barn".
Gotta to swing up there anyway.
I've never been to "Bargain Barn".
- Are you pulling on my leg?
- We don't have them in New York.
- What's got to do with anything?
- That's why I've never been to one.
I'm still not following you.
They don't have "Bargain Barn" in New York.
So that's why I've never been to one.
We also never been to one in Chicago.
Which is where we from.
- Oh, I see... - Oh Jeez...
It's huge. I have no idea.
Astonishing.
It's all about folk .
This can be right.
A sweater... for nine-ninety-nine?
It's not right. It's two for one.
- C'mon.
- Where is man's wear?
Wait a minute.
Okay, see that woman, see that woman,
guess what is in his bags!
- French's bread?
- Guns. Big guns.
- Oh Lord, she's comin'.
- Oh my God, it's Sarah Palin.
Actually my name is Emma.
Emma Wheeler,
but you can call me Deputy Wheeler.
- Oh... so. So, you are married?
- Oh yeah.
That's what she needed.
A couple more guns.
- I love them. Do you have mere?
- Just for bargains.
Actually , I'm a member of PETA.
People for the Ethical Treatment of Animals.
So am I... except mines:
People for Eating Tasty Animals (PETA).
You got to know when you appreciate her humor.
Sometimes I think that will help.
Hey, I just want to say that
I think what you people are doing is very brave.
And it will be an honor to protect you
and I hope you'll be real comfortable here at us.
Thank you. Thank you very much...
I must say I imagine there is to be
less multiform, but this "Bargain Barn" is fantastic
so we move it here down to road,
in Applebee's....
Well this is Cody, Ray's forty-five miles that way
and there is no "Bargain Barn" in there.
Here is Ray.
That was it.
Could we do it again.
I think I missed this.
So, if that's Ray, where are we goin'?
Oh, a few miles outside the town.
We like to get away from the hustle and bustle.
C'mon in. Watch where you step.
Yep, that is it.
Home, sweet home.
- Very, very nice.
- Yes, I love what you've done with the...
- ...the heads.
- Thanks.
Yeah, we killed all these animals ourselves.
Oh, that's great. I hate when you have
the decorator do it for you.
Well, I got brother around the Cheyenne
he's happy to garment so ...
That's handy. Any word from New York?
- No, ma'am.
- So, you folks are hungry? We got pleanty to eat.
- No no me, I had my fill on the four stars of New York flight.
- Chicago.
Chicago.
Well, you probably wanna be gettin' some shower...
I 'll show you to your room.
Hope you'll be comfortable in here.
We fixed up this spare bedroom.
Not exactly the Ritz.
We usually only have one witness at the time.
The last was Vito "The Butcher" Emanuel.
Murdered five people before he turns
state's evidence.
- So, you actually do this all the time?
- Yeah.
About ten yers ago the government asked
if we can hide somebody for a week.
There was since then a couple of times a year
they bring the somebody by.
Mankind is interested, actually.
Now they want me to retire.
So, you two are gonna be our last.
Well it's an honor
and that's a lovely witness room but um...
Mr Morgan ... Mr Foster and I
are separated.
We are thinking of seeing a therapist, yeah.
So, how do you want to handle the sleeping arrangement then?
- Well I'm... I can sleep on the couch. - No, no I'll sleep on the couch.
- No, no, I'll sleep...really...
I'll be fine on the couch.
- And, um, do you have a cable?
- We have an anthena.
We got bunch of DVDs.
John Wayne and Clint Eastwood :) mostly.
That's great. That's great.
Oh but I see you have a computer.
So that means you-you have a Internet?
You are on-line?
We do, but you'll need a code .
- Which you are not gonna give me.
- No.
Try to contact somebody back home
is just too big risk.
I guess the same goes for the phone,
'cause I just have a couple of things I have to check on.
- If I can make one quick call.
- And, you know, you can supervise the calls.
- There is no dial tone.
- There is a code.
So, I guess that is about it.
There is towels and soap in the bath.
Great, terrific. Is there a code?
It's all right, silly.
- You sure you gonna be happy on that thing?
- Yeah, I'm good.
I'm good.
All right.
Good night.
Good night, good night, bye everyone.
Look Paul, I know how hard you are tryin'.
Really I do, I'm not not completely oblivious.
And believe me, it would...it would be so much easy
if I just can make myself forget.
But...
When I look at you, I just feel regret.
And sadness and-and deep desire to see you sufferin'.
intense  pain.
Listen that's not a problem, that's not a problem.
I have more than willing to hurt myself.
Or would you prefer to do it. Whatever takes...
Just, tell me what to do.
Tell me.
I don't know.
- I don't know.
- The thing is, Meryl...
I'm just trying to be realistic.
You know, I'm human. I made a mistake.
I am not perfect.
No, I know you are not.
But, I was so in love with you.
And now I'm just...
I'm just...
I'm so dissapointed.
And I don't trust you anymore.
All right.
Good night.
Jackie,
did you hear about the Morgans?
- Of course I heard, totally devastating.
- They are in protected custody.
- Adam, I heard.
- What we gonna do?
What we can do?
We can...
- Yes?
- There is a client here for Mrs Morgan.
Sure, send him back.
- Can I help you?
- If you are busy, I'll come back later.
Not at all. He was just leaving.
Yeah, I'm in the market for two bedrooms,
friend refer me to Meryl Morgan.
- Would you have a seat?
- Yeah.
Excuse me.
I'm Jackie. Mrs Morgan's assistant.
She's not in today.
Can I give you one other agent to talk to you?
You know, if she's as good as everyone says,
I'm sure she's probably workin' the way.
She is.
- I'm sorry for takin' of your time.
- Not at all.
Nice lookin' muffin there.
Enjoy your breakfast.
Howdy.
- How about bet I wake you?!
- Oh no, no I didn't really sleep.
- It's too quiet here.
- You're hungry?
Smells good.
Oh, that's impressive.
I've never turn my oven on.
Oh look at that, fire comes out from everything.
You want sausage or bacon above,
with your eggs and pancakes?
Oh,no, no thanks,  I'm actually vegetarian.
- Good mornin'.
- I got news for you , sheriff.
Your cousin here is a vegetarian.
Yeah, what a things gonna happen' in your own family?!
- Howdy.
Good morning.
- How did you sleep?
Not really it needs . Very, very quiet, isn't it?
I thought I've been actually hearin'
my cells dividing.
I kept prayin' for a siren.
Yes, or rumbling subway or something.
Speaking of New York,
have you heard anything?
No, ma'am. You can ask
every five minutes...
What they told me, I'll tell you.
I saw a photo of a young man, isn't it?
I tell you he was something.
That's our boy.
- Clay Junior.
- Oh, does he live in Ray too?
No, he married a girl from Omaha
so he moved to a big city.
- Big city?
- Omaha.
Here we go,
sunny side eggs, sausage and bacon,
home fries, homemade biscuits and country gravy.
- Can I get you anything else?
- No thanks just an angiogram.
We gonna make a rounds.
It will be the best for you to stay here.
The minor people see you there,
the safer you are.
But it's a shame, cause Ray is the
friendliest place on earth.
Help yourself with anything
in the fridge if you are hungry.
- We will be back in couple hours.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
I can't believe this is happening.
Well, at least you didn't have
the whole breakfast.
I feel my organs shuting down one by one.
I thought Disneyland was
the friendliest place on earth.
No, no Disneyland is the happiest
place on earth,
Ray is the friendliest place.
People probably get confused all the time.
What if we never get out of here?
What if we never get to Lincoln Center again,
or see the Mets, or see our friends,
or sit on Great monument with New York Times,
walk with the Shakespeare in park,
or go to Noble,
or order chinese?
Good , do you know how long
will take to order a chinese,
it will be a weeks, and it will be cold.
Ok, stop, stop. Now listen to me, listen to me.
We are here and there is nothing
we can do about it.
There is no phone calls to make,
there is no connections to work,
there is no favors to call in.
I think you should treated
as a vacation.
A welcome break in your busy schedule.
- Okay.
- Good.
Ok, you're right. Ok.
God, I'm going mad as a hatter...!!!
At least you are going your best shot.
That's really all we can ask.
They did say not to leave.
Oh, c'mon...
Perhaps I can come with you,
to protect you.
And I really won't to be alone on my own.
God, I can't breathe,
air is too clean.
I'm gonna to shower.
Paul.
- Paul, don't move.
- Sorry?
There is a bear behind you.
Yes, there is.
Oh, shit!
No, no, no! Don't run.
The poster said not to run.
Wait. Hold on. I'm gonna to get it, okay, Hold on?!
Come back! No, Meryl!
Come back!
Come back! Please.
Meryl! Meryl! Meryl! Meryl!
Okay, oh God, okay.
Keep calm!
Ok avoid direct eye contact,
And speak in a false monotone.
Nice to meet you.
My wife is a member of PETA.
- I'll be meaning to join.
- Don't shoot at bear...
- I don't have a gun!
- because the bear
almost always lives...
long enough to mold the shooter severely.
I don't have a gun!!!
Soothing... Soothing...
Sorry... sorry...I don't have a gun...
- No gun.
- Wait, wait! there is one last thing... - What is it?
- You don't need to hear this?
- What is it?
Ok, at a last resort a summon cannonball position
covering your neck and your head
with your hands and your arms...
I didn't need to hear that!
I know that. I told you that.
You never listen.
- This is exactly...
- Do we knock this enough?
Oh my God, Paull, he's comin'...
- Run, run!
- It says not to run!
Run! Run!
Run! Run! Run!
Okay, he's goin'.
Yeah, he's goin', we gonna be okay.
My eyes, I can't see.
That was close...
Oh no...
There you go.
Ok, let's have a look, see here.
- You are from Chicago, Mrs Foster ?
- Yeah, that's right.
I've always dream about Chicago...
Oh, well I'm sure one day you will get there.
Oh, no I don't wanna go.
I just always dream about it.
Is this gonna be much longer?
Because my husband
- is very uncomfortable.
- Oh Lord I'm hurt.
Oh, yeah. Oh, look at him.
He's a mass.
He should see a doctor.
Laughter really is the best medecine.
So... You sprayed yourself with
the bear spray, Mr Foster.
Oh no, actually I hurt him.
I mean unintentionaly, of course.
Anyway, do you think maybe
he should see a specialist?
Well, I'm the only doctor in town
so I'm better specialist as gets.
Do everything from geriatrics
to pediatrics.
Well don't want to confuse us too.
No. You don't.
And it's a great thing about being a doctor in small town.
You've seen it all.
Anyway, physiologically,
is all the same. Body is the body.
So, see if we can take care
of that boo boo in your eye, Mr Foster.
You see, just calling it boo boo
makes me feel better already.
Let's go next door, the exam room.
Say, would you like to come with us Mrs Foster?
- No, it's fine.
- Be careful there, Mr Foster.
Say, do you like stickers?
Here, let's take a little visit to giraffa room.
"You've reached Trish Pinger at
"Gotham adoption agency"...
please leave a message."
Oh, hi Trish. This is um...Meryl Foster,
um...
Meryl Morgan calling.
I just...I was...I was just calling to thank you
so much for everything that you've done for me
but I'm now...sort of in the middle of something,
I might be relocated...
I won't might be in New York...
I'm..I'm in God knows where.
That not sound very stable right now, right?
Probably I can't believe you gonna
help me adopt a baby...
Got to sue them for that.
Ok, I'll walk... Good night.
Good night.
Paul.
I called "The Gotham adoption agency".
I filed for adoption
two months ago.
You did?
So, I wanted to tell them that
I couldn't go through it now.
Two months ago?
Must be a big decision for you...
I really thought about tellin' you...
but I didn't ...
really know where we were at...
And,and to be honest,
you know, from the time when we started
having trouble getting pregnant,
you weren't exactly support it...
You know, I'll always find it possible
to believe what... you say that,
'cause between fertility doctors and the injections,
and the woman who chanted over my sperm...
C'mon, I've apologized for that so many times!
That I was pretty supportive.
Was I enjoying having sex on a scheduled time
exactly to your ovulations?!
Maybe not as much I should have done.
And I'm very sorry about that.
Or talking about reproducing
every second of every day.
It wasn't every second of every day,
I just wanted to be a mother.
And I wanted to be a father.
I was the one who suggested adoption in the first place.
So why we've never meet with an adoption agency?
Because by that time you were
become so wired,
and so crazy that they will not
bless us to raise
a goldfish,
and let alone a baby.
You know I was wired from a hormone shots...
and I'm not normally that crazy.
And instead of you staying home...
and dealing with it...
you flew off to LA on a business meeting...
And then... Oh right!
I know what I did.
I slept with someone else and I'm so sorry!
I'm so sorry! I'm so sorry!
I'm so sorry!
I don't know how many times I suppose to say that?!
I thought you've been completely irrational.
This two are worse than Vito "The Butcher".
I  kind of like them.
I wish there's somebody who can help them.
Yeah. Muzzles!
- You think that I'm unreasonable?
- You aren't.
Is that helpful?
Is that constructive?
Is that mature?
It's mature. I don't know what it's "mature".
Oh, that is mature. Yes, mock my accent.
Mock my heritage.
We got to get them out of the house.
Yeah sure, go ahead.
I don't know what to do.
There is all these meetings being reset.
All these clients.
You think you've got problems?
She's the president of the firm.
Nothing happens here without her.
And everybody is looking at me like:
"Where is she"?
I'm gonna lose my job.
Without him I'm superfluous.
I can't used to you even with him.
Meryl Morgan's office?
She's not in, today.
Hello Mrs Pinger, yes...from the adoption agency.
What?
Meryl called you?
Yesterday?
Do you happened to...have that number?
Yes.
Could you just hold?
Hold on, just one moment.
Yes?
Thank you so much, Mrs Pinger.
All right!
This is Mike, Clarence,
Jackson and Wendy.
This is the one I'm gonna put you on, Meryl.
No, I'm sorry. No offence for Wendy.
But I'm allergic to you..
And I had once
very bad horse experience.
I was thrown.
It was on the carousel park department, still you know...
- You ride, Paul?
- Well I do, a little bit, yes.
I had some lessons when I was a child.
You had riding lessons?
Well, I've never knew that.
Yes, well I didn't tell you everything, so...
Yeah, I knew that.
Hey!
Hey, I'm not on my horse!
I'm not on my horse!
Get back on, we got target practice next.
All right, c'mon Meryl, your turn.
All right, let's just get this over, will ya.
All right, this is a loaded gun.
- See, don't point that at another person while you are on stroke.
- Okay.
And, are you left-handed or right-handed?
Well, I...you know I write with left hand,
but I play tennis and badminton with my right hand.
I text with my right hand.
I cut right...I cut cake with my left hand.
Ok, we gonna do it like this.
Line it up to the sight.
To the can. Don't make gun goes up
it's gonna hit back.
- Okay.
- Move your shoulder. Ok?
- Yeah. - Don't put your finger
on the trigger if you are not ready to shoot.
All right.
This is nothing, you should see
how long takes it to order dinner?
There you go!
- Good hit off.
- That was good.
- Wow, it's very, very loud.
No, no. 'Cause I got two more cans.
I'm just gonna cock a gun for it.
Fascinating. A week ago she was
basically armored.
- All right.
- Yeah, I know.
- When you are ready to go.
- Ok.
Keep your finger of the trigger.
You are ready.
- Missed!
- I think it's my turn now, isn't it.
- No, I'm not done yet.
- I think you're fine, it's my turn.
- I'm not done yet.
- It's my turn now, it's...
This thing is loaded.
Let me give you two NRA (National Rifle Association) class.
- Paul's turn.
- Thank you.
You are rude. Selfish.
- Just do it like you wanna kill.
- Right. Thank you.
Pull lever. Relax.
Relax.
Find your target.
Take a deep breath.
Easy.
God in heaven that hurt.
- Agony.
- Yes.
Could you take it just for second?
I think I'm really done some damage.
Meryl, I think I have a welt. A quite big welt.
Look at that.
- You see that?
- Yes. It's quite...
Ugly.
It's really easy to hurt your shoulder
shooting of riffle.
- I didn't.
- Could you just..wait outside?
Play with the toy.
Thank you.
- You ever shoot before, Meryl?
- Nop.
Nop, never held a gun before in my life.
But I could use wandering some
intense negotiations at work.
- I'm a real estate broker.
- You kidding?
No.
My Mom is getting on
and she's movin' in with me.
I can't get any buyers on her house.
Oh, it's lovely, it's...
But you know...
when a market likes this, you really need to focus
more on presentation. And...
I mean, just, you know...Just out of the
top of my head think
maybe that cheers sitting on front line
it looks very, very comfortable.
But have you ever considered
moving inside the house?
No.
- Let's just think about it. It's...
- I will.
Would you mind to come around
and take a look at the place?
- Oh no, not at all.
- Do you spare her call?
Absolutely. I'm used to being separated.
- The shoulder.
That's not separated. Just a tiny little bruise.
You aren't a school girl.
- Hi there.
- Hey! - Hey!
How's your arm healin'?
Oh, it's nothing, it's nothing. I just went to the doctor
'cause Meryl was so worried.
Can I...give you a hand?
- Yeps, yeah.
- No problem.
I really just wanted to apologize,
for any trouble we may caused you.
I know there's been certain amount
of screaming and shouting, so...
That's okay, I know what is like.
Me and Clay had a few countainers.
Really?
That's quite unconfident to hear
'cause you two seem so happy.
We are, but that doesn't mean
that we hadn't call on foot a few times.
Really?
How'd you two touched things out,
if I might to ask?
Well...
He bought me a Remington 270 with
the night scope and "Emma" engraved on it
And he gave me some cows.
I love cows!
Great! Brilliant! I wish I
thought of the cows thing. That's good.
Yeah, there is just one time
we were really buttin' heads.
Something about his brother.
It's not important but...
Anyway, God were we hardly talkin',
and...
he asked me on a date.
A date?
Yeah, just like two kids in the high-school.
He asked me out, we went out to dinner,
we talked and it work like magic.
Very interesting.
Well, speaking of work,
I'm pretty much done here so...
See you later.
Thanks for coming.
Just while we standing here
I just want to point on a few things...
This whole railings is brand-new
and actually Doc' built it himself.
Fresh color paint.
I don't know if you guys wanna go inside
kind a getaway of the land.
- I'll stay here.
You stay with me?
Listen, before you take those shoes off
you wanna go around
this biggest yard?
I'll be right back.
You know, that kitchen little showzen...
you can take it down,
you can build a gorgeous playing room down.
What's up?
This may sound strange,
but...
Would you like to go on date with me?
- You know, that does sound strange.
- Just, it's been a while sice we dine together.
We just had a dinner in New York.
And I thought it went well until the murder.
- Meryl, you're comin'?
- Oh, yeah. Just one minute.
I'll be in. Sorry.
Shall we say seven-thirty?
It's a place called "Annette's"
I'm told this is the only place to eat in town.
Literally.
And it would just be a chance to sit and talk
like we used to before infertility
and unfidelity.
And separation.
I will pay.
Well, if you gonna pay...
Luckilly, I called to had gotten the table
near the mayonnaise.
- You must know someone.
- And I know you said no more presents, but I...
went on-line with Emma's supervision and
downloaded a CD of New York noises,
that you can sleep.
Car hornes, subways, women
fighting in Bloomingdale's.
I think you might be actually on it.
- Well, thank you.
- Very welcome.
- To your salads.
- Thanks.
Oh, actually I asked for mine
dressing on the side.
- I thought you are kidding.
- Yeah I know, that always gets a laugh.
- Have you been waitress a long time, Kelly?
- Oh, forever.
I can't get by on nursing
there is not just enough sick people in town.
- That's so unfair.
- Oh that's not so bad, most people around here have two jobs.
Sometimes three. I'm office assistant fire chief.
Oh really. Then, could you ask the gentlemen behind
us to please put down his cigarette?
Well, I can't do that. That's Earl and he owns this place.
- Why this calls Annette's?
- Annette was his wife.
She divorced him about ten years ago,
he doesn't want be paid.
Excuse me.
Hi. I'm Meryl Foster,
I'm Clay's cousin,
and this is my husband Paul.
We are visiting from Chicago.
How do you do. I'm Earl Granger,
my granddaughter Lucy.
- Howdy.
I was just wondering would you mind terribly
blowing smoke in another direction.
Thank you.
Chicago. I don't know how you
do things in Chicago,
I've never been there,
but, this is God's free american country,
we don't take kindly the outsiders
tryin' to tell us how to live.
Well, people in Chicago are just as
Americans in God's weariness
as people in Wyoming,I mean
not me specifically, I'm an agnostic.
Next saying you've been tellin' us
you are democrats?
Well, there is gotta be a few of us in town.
Fourteen. We know who they are.
Thirteen. Will Harry died a month ago.
Of natural causes or... ?
You are not getting smart with me,
are you tea drinker?
You know what I did to the last man
who called me that?
I steal his crockett.
- Doc'!
- Howdy, Fosters.
- How are you tonight?
- We are good, we just had a lovely evening at "Annette's".
Must be Earl's night-off.
Yeah.
- You okay? - We just need to call
Clay and Emma, they said they picked us up .
They are playing a poker with Millers
and Caseys .
Just take my truck.
That one right there.
Oh, we couldn't possibly.
- I don't need it 'til tomorrow.
Doors are open, keys inside.
- Really?
Around here everybody leaves the keys
in case somebody need a ride.
You don't do that?
People do take each other's car, but..
The return policy is little bit fuzzy.
You'll be sure to return mine, all right?
- Okay Doc', thanks.
- Thank you.
Which one is it?
I don't know, they are all exactly the same.
Are we lost?
Certainly not.
Certainly not. I turned
right to the broken fence.
And left after the second big rock?
Second big rock?
Then we are lost.
I'm going right up here.
No, I'm going around.
- Can I ask you something?
- Yeah.
Why her?
You want to discuss it now?
- In the middle of absolutely nowhere?
- I know it's probably not the time, but...
Why her?
I mean, you meet lots of women,
you 're always at lunches and meetings, so...
Why her? And it was just she was pretty?
Who says she was pretty?
She's quite idiot, actually.
- A leper. Elephant-man had a sister...
- I Googled her.
Yeah, I just put under "loose legal ladies".
She's pretty.
So, what she like?
Reserved and little bit cynical.
I know, I can see that.
That make sense.
It's probably like, you know,
going to a spa, very
quiet, and cool and laid back.
Nobody nagging you,
or asking you questions
like some crazy, neurotic woodpecker.
you won't get an abolition...
until you passed out...
It was nothing. It was really nothing.
You know, I was stupid,
I had a few drinks.
I was upset about us...and...
just happened, I did not enjoy it.
I was just feel quilty all the time...
and her parfume smelled little bit like a burrito.
And...you...are...easily
the sexiest, the most exciting woman I've
ever been with or ever wish to be with it.
Hm.
I sort of believe you.
Good.
Progress.
Maybe wasn't the fragrance.
Maybe she just smells like a buritto.
Very possible.
Hi.
- Good morning, Lucy.
- Lucy.
- Doc'.
- Hey, Doc'.
Hey, Fosters.
It's a store.
It's a real store.
What was a hangle with kashmir?
When they say they haven't, they just say go and look.
Excuse me, but you've never known, when you stick...
So, you are a lawyer?
Ah, sort of.
Well, this is about my granddaughter, Lucy.
She's gonna be the next American Idol.
Is she? That's great, that's lovely.
Good.
Cheer her Dad sick,
her mother is off to the army.
So that's leaves it up to old grandfather
look after her.
Truth is, I-I need a will.
Ah...
Ok well, the problem is
I really don't practice that kind of law.
- What you practice?
- No, no ! He can't do it, he can't do it.
Hey listen, I got to go,
I told Doc' that I'll help him with the house today, you know.
So, I'm just gonna go and show it.
I 'll see you later and have fun.
I got my financials cleared back to 1953.
Good, great that's sounds fun.
Okay. Okay.
But you know what? Despite our cultural differences,
I think you and I are going to be good friends.
Or not.
It's completely up to you.
Eighteen.
- You had it?
- Yes, yes, yes.
- Window shut.
- Excellent.
Well done.
We got N 32.
N... N thirty-two.
N 33
Hey, how you've got it away with Earl?
Really well, yes, I made such a beautiful will,
he asked me to kill him.
- Oh look at you, country lawyer.
- Look at you, country real estate person.
- Well, is the doctor having enough money for his Mom's house?
- Yes, she's incredible, right up to date.
Well, it was just second thing thougt.
You know what they say: "Location, location, location".
Next step is B4.
B4.
That's so funny.
Like "before".
Like B-4 and after...
Where is the fire when you need one?
G46 says!
G46!
Oh my God. Bingo!
Bingo!
- God, Bingo !
- I'm out.
Yes!
Ys!
- Why we are so happy?
- We just won fifty dollars. That's three sweaters.
Please, listen to me.
You can not call that number.
We've been through all of this Jackie,
you heard what a Marshall said?!
We couldn't endanger their safety.
- There are rules here.
- Wait, God you are scary,little man.
Haven't you ever done anything
to break the rules?
Hello, Jackie Drake,
Mrs Morgan's assistant ...
Adam?
Oh my God...Oh my God, I'm so sorry,
It was a reflex.
I took self-defense course.
I got an A in teaser and...
Would you like to go on movie with me tomorrow?
Couldn't be drain.
Couldn't be...
I was really suprised.
- Congratulations.
- Great night.
See you tomorrow.
Mañana.
Good night.
Well, I'll go... Good night.
Come in.
Hello.
Hi. Are you asleep?
- Very much so, yes.
- I hate to interrupt that. Just to see this!
Good God.
Is that ice?
I don't know.
I've never seen anything like it in New York
outside the Planetarium.
Let me not to the marriage of true minds
Admit impediments.
Love is not love
Which alters when it alteration finds,
Or bends with the remover to remove:
O no! it is an ever-fixed mark
That looks on tempests and is never shaken;
Shakespeare (Sonnet 116). From my wedding.
Was he there?
We've never got his gift.
- It was my vows to you.
- I know.
Well, at the time I thought you've written.
I was so disapointed when I found out.
Do you remember your vows to me?
"There was once a girl from Nantucket".
- No, that's not it...that's not...
- It's all right, it was a long time ago.
God, it's amazing how many stars.
I promise never to take you for granted
I should word you in kind
Never allowed my affections to be recanted
or stop mumbling at your behind.
Also Meryl...I should vow,
Your vict, your fusil to condemned animal slaughter,
Your wisdom, your laugh
Your inability to boil water.
To be your best friend to the rest of my life
And to thank to God you are not sure about
fulfilling your into being my wife.
And the next thing I heard was:
"Do you, Meryl Judith Baker,
take this man to be your lawfully wedded husband?"
And I said: "I do".
And then I heard:
"Do you, Paul Michael Morgan, take this woman
to be your lawfully wedded wife?"
And your mother said: "He doesn't!".
But I ignored her and then I heard
"I now pronounce you man and wife."
Then...
I don't remember.
- "You may kiss the bride."
- Right.
Right.
- You may kiss the bride.
- Yes.
And then we had a buffet
beginning with meatless pigs and blankets.
You may kiss the bride.
Oh, really?
You sure?
Very, very honestly.
Sorry. Sorry.
Sorry, we have to practice that.
Aw, that was awkward...
Hey, Marshall Lasky.
Yes, Sir.
Right.
All right, take care.
They got you separate sites ready
and they want you to leave tomorrow evening.
Tomorrow?
Yep.
Wow, that's soon?
Well, the good news is
you still got to go to the rodeo.
And the rodeo dance.
Yes.
Doctor Simons' office.
Yeah, is that the doctor Simmons
in Columbus, Ohio?
No, this is the doctor Simmons
in Ray, Wyoming.
Sorry, my mistake.
There is somebody using your name
in Claymont, Ohio.
You know what?
- I had enough running for me.
- Really?!
- Yeah.
- You are probably tired out of last night.
God, I was amazing.
Yeah, I'm realy glad that
I was there to see it.
Yeah.
All right.
Wait.
Listen.
We got through the whole adoption thing.
It is possible that I did drag my feet a little bit.
You would be a terrific mother,
caring, supportive,
- and completely smudering.
- I'm so looking for it, that.
But I am not sure that I would be good at it.
- Really? That's what you are worried about?
- Obviously, yes.
What makes you think
I would be a good father?
Well..
If I had to pick one thing...
I would say it was the mouse.
What you are talking about?
Don't you remember, you know
we had a mouse in our apartment,
and all the sudden the cereal box
started moving?
Oh yes, yes.
The shaking granule.
Yes, and I ran out, tried balcony,
you know, you could just taken a broom
and swept it off,
but instead you stood there
for hours trying
to coxswain little guy into a shoe box
using your own breadth for safe bars.
Yes, terrible waste for cheese seems, eventually.
Led to his death.
When I saw that, I just...
I knew you'll be a great father.
Especially if we adopt a rodent.
Thank you for being honest.
Listen, while I am...speaking honestly.
I wonder if we might also discuss
the whole business of separate sites.
I don't want to preassure you.
No, no, actually I've been thinking about it too.
You know, why don't you finish your jogging
we'll talk about it when you come back, ok ?
Ok.
- Take the bear spray.
- Ok.
Take the bear fly.
Thank you.
Clay?
C'mon in.
- Hey, Clay?
- Yeah?
I just looking for Emma in the house.
Is she around, I just wanna to talk to her.
She's gone in to Cody for supplies,
will be back about an hour.
As you can probably see,
the things are going much better between me and Paul,
but you know, some very big decisions
need to be made regard our future
and possibility
that we are not goin' back to New York...
An the fact is, well...I slept with someone else
while Paul and I were separated.
Emma will be back about an hour.
I kind don't know what to do.
Grab a bucket.
Ok.
Which of these are skim?
Put your butt down there,
get that stool.
Grab above the teet.
Good luck.
You know there is a school thought that says:
What Paul doesn't know, won't hurt him,
and suddenly guess sound narcissistic if I do tell him.
But how can I expect complete honesty
from him if I'm asking any less of myself?!
Isn't that just the height of hipocrisy?
Could be.
- I don't hear much help going on over there.
- Oh, sorry.
Aw.
- Is this hurt them?
- No, if you are gentle about it.
I get it.
See, I get it...
You are telling me to be honest.
But to be gentle.
I was telling you the ease up on her teet,
but I guess it work both ways
That's very wise.
I doubt that.
Start to talking about it isn't easy.
It's like that book "Men are from
Mars, and women are from Venus".
- You read that book?
- I read the cover.
Pretty much sound it up.
Bang it up buddy you do good?
Howdy.
I'm glad you came.
Thank you, Ray!
Keep your dancin' shoes on!
'Cause...now we gonna kick it!
C'mon, you dance.
Follow me.
- I wanna tell you something.
- I know.
- I'm very light on my feet.
- No. Well, yes.
But something else.
I thik we should go to this
official site together.
You do?
Yeah.
That's so great.
- That's so great.
- I know.
- And... one other thing.
- Yeah.
- When we were separated...
I slept with someone else.
It just happened once.
Once.
Really, and it was just
because I was just...I was feeling,
you know, just hurt... and rejected.
- You are upset?
- No. No. No.
I'm... What I'm?
A little suprised.
If you gonna be mad, be mad.
But, please...
Please, don't stop talking to me.
Yell, scream, I don't care
but honestly...Whatever you want!
There is nothing to scream about.
We were separated,
you ran out, this things happened so.
There it is.
- Hey, Paul.
- Howdy.
- Do you wanna ask me something?
- No.
Do you mind?
No, no, no.
Do you wanna talk?
No, no, not should do.
I always want to talk.
Go ahead.
It's okay, never mind.
Hey, excuse me.
How you doin'?
Howdy.
i'm lookin' for two friends of mine,
Paul and Meryl.
Aw, the Fosters. They are probably on the way to rodeo
but they are stayin' at the Wheelers.
Wheelers. And where is that?
Ok, so go down this road and
when you see the broken fence make a right.
And when you come to second big rock...
Good morning.
Better shake your legs if you wanna eat.
Do you know where Paul is?
Thank you.
Hey, can I ask you a question?
What you think this is fooling?
Isn't this, I mean,  what screwed us up in the first place?
Not talking?
Is it? Sorry it was stupid of me,
I thought it was sleeping with other people.
But maybe you are right. Yes.
You know, never mind.
All right.
What would you like me to do?
Would you like to beg for informations?
Then I will. What was his name?
- Larry.
Larry. Are you serious?
Larry, he's recently divorced,
he just asked me for dinner.
That's all right, I think i got the picture.
You probably had a few drinks and...
you mourned about your horrrible husband,
went back to his apartment. I got it.
No, no, we back to our apartment.
Right, we are selling the place.
Thanks so much for telling me.
Look, we both made mistakes.
I made a mistake, your seem to be just litte like revenge.
Are you serious?
Revenge...I mean...Do you...
Do you not know me at all? And all you've been
thinking that I will sleep with someone for revenge?
I would sleep with someone to hurt you?
- Well, at this point I don't know what I'm thinking.
- Oh, my God.
- Screw you.
- Meryl, can I just say this?
Meryl, can I... can I speak?
No.
Not to me.
- Meryl!
- Ready to go?
- I think I'm gonna pass on rodeo. I'm sory.
- Yeah sory, me too.
I've a lot of packing to do.
I'm sorry.
Okay, then.
Hold on.
I know it's not my business, but...
I watched you two over the past few days...
Laughing together about
inside New York jokes.
I don't find them funny, but...I think
you can always tell
a lot about a couple by the fact
that they still laughed together.
Thanks, I appreciate that.
I think guys...I think he's funny.
Makes me laugh.
But, if we gonna stay together, then...
you know, I guess we have to
scaled back on our expectations.
I want expect everything from him
and he won't expect everything from me.
You can not expect everything from each other,
where is that make any sense?
you got to stop thinking about,
just get over the bullshit
and make it work.
She said something like i was gonna...
C'mon, honey, let just go.
We'll pick you up
and take you to the airport.
- What was that?
- Oh my God!
- Oh my God, it's him.
- We got to call Clay and Emma.
- The phone is the code.
- Christ!
What? Are you kidding?
Oh God, I'm out of bullets.
Something I've never expecting to hear you say.
We go outside.
C'mon.
Up. Up.
- C'mon! - I'm sorry!
- C'mon!
Ok, we gonna find Clay.
It'll be easy.
He wear a cowboy hat.
Nice drive, cowboy.
It's been a while since...
anybody ride this bull eight seconds more.
That's Clay.
He's in the box.
Go. Go. Go.
Got yourselves a big hands for gold fighting Clowns.
Oh my God.
Sit.
Just sit.
Nice drivin', buddy!
Thank you.
Make claps for Tom O'Rea...
...he'll be riding the Applebee bull killer.
Last three cowboys get down on this bull,
got dumped right out of the game.
Let's see Tom break catch free!
Get him, boys.
I can't see.
Oh, my God.
What's that noise?
Just run!
- Just run!
- I'm running!
I don't have a choice.
Meryl, you're all right?
- No! I really think I hurt my leg.
- oh God!
I don't think I can walk.
Oh my God, we never gonna way from him.
What?
Where is he?
All right, wait there.
I'll be back in a minute.
Wait, wait! What are you doing?!
Where are you going?!
Please, don't leave me.
You get...Keep your head down.
Aw! Bulllocks!
Hey, I've got plenty of room on my wall
for another head.
Drop it, son.
Stay back away from my lawyer.
If you just point out, say even if you kill me,
you'll have two more, these two will testified against you.
- Three.
- Four.
- Five.
- You are six, dump.
- Six.
You're all right?
Are you crazy?
You could be killed.
I'm just very touched
that it will emoted you.
Of course it would have.
Oh God, I had this...this horrible moment where...
- I pictured what life would be like without you.
- That's exactly what I had.
When you were laying spured in the dust,
all I wanted to do is to protect you.
I lost all the physical fear.
When it's coming back now tough,
what in the God's name I was thinking?
I know exactly what you were thinking.
You were thinking that...
that we were meant to be together,
because, look what you did.
You risked your life for me.
That's so nice.
- No.
- Sorry.
No, no.
I am sorry.
I'm so sorry
for nearly curing an incurable romantic.
I want you to expect everything from me.
You not gonna get it,
but I promise to try and do it.
I love you, Meryl.
If you are in fact Meryl?
I can hardly see, I'm sorry.
I'm Meryl.
Trust me.
Cause I trust you all over again.
Good bye, Lucy!
I hope I get to hear you on the radio soon.
- Earl.
- Lucy.
- Eat the meat.
- Take care.
- Earl, I think we become good friends.
- Think what you want.
- Or not, whatever.
- So.
- I don't know what to say, except...
We are really truly, sorry... about...
- About everything.
- Don't be.
The Fed's are so happy with us
they link Clay to keep his job.
Is that right?
That's great news.
- Oh, congratulation.
- Thank you.
Mr and Mrs Morgan , we are waiting for you.
Okay, well I suppose this is it.
If whoever get attacked by the bear in the Central Park
we would be the one to know what to do.
- You stay in good care of my favorite cousin, ok?
- Emma.
Really thank you for everything and...
And remember...
Clay, I'm better hug you,
you won't like it but I'm gonna hug you.
Thank you. And listen
if you are ever in New York...
Something has gone terribly wrong.
Ok. Let's go home.
Adios.
- Sheriff, your life just got a whole lot simpler.
- So it's yours, baby.
SIX MONTHS LATER
Isn't it amazing she slept the whole flight?
Isn't that amazing?
They'are not meant to do that.
She false it.
- No, she's perfect.
- Perfect, but nameless.
Or probably we finally come up
with a name on the road home.
She could be Midtown Morgan.
59 Street Richmond.
Hey, there's Adam and Jackie.
Hi!
Get their bags.
- Should I get the cart?
- You are the cart, go.
Hey...
Thank you, honey.
- You are my girl.
- Go.
- Hurry, get that, get the phone.
- Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes.
Hello ?
Oh, hello Adam, I missed you.
No, no I'm taking the day off tomorrow,
so you do not need to come in.
Yes, I'm sure.
Oh in that case have fun,
moving Jackie's mother furniture.
I see many happy years ahead of you.
Ok, bye.
You know what I wish?
I wish as an older, wiser couple
we could give them an advice,
like Clay and Emma gave us.
Or we just could send them to Ray
for the weekend.
Rae.
We call her Rae.
R A E.
Rae.
I quite like that.
- Do you like that?
- Yes.
And you?
What are your thoughts?
- Rae.
- Rae Morgan.
Hey, this is our new apartment, Rae.
The one we have to get cause
I didn't want to stay in the old one,
where your Mama slept with Larry.
Just don't need to hear this.
Come here, little girl.
3000 square feet and...
a berry space ship master bedroom.
And come to see this view,
come and get this view, little Lady.
Oh right here, look at that.
Can you believe?
Isn't that something, it is, it is!
That is quite beautiful view.
What?
- How are you feeling by the way?
- Good.
Very good.
If I'm asked,
this one comes out Chinese as well.
by radojka
www.subscene.com