What is love?
Love?
...Love is life.
Love? What is love?
Where does it happen? Why does it
happen? And how does it happen?
I believe that God predetermined
all our emotional relationships.
But then He left it to us
to find each other.
He made us all couples
and for every one of us...
there is a soulmate.
A soulmate? What nonsense!
I don't believe in all this...
I'm absolutely sure that somewhere,
someone was made for me...
and that someday I shall
certainly meet him.
OK, but will someone
please tell me...
how will I know who was
made for me?
I mean, will she be wandering about
with a placard with my name on it?
When I see her, will there be a clap
of thunder and a flash of lightning?
How will I recognise her?
I don't know what others will do,
but I will recognise him.
He will speak to me, He will
give me a sign...
and my heart will realise
that this is him.
What is all this?
This is love
Love!
However far apart they may be...
Their paths will meet,
whatever happens...
When two people
are made for each other.
Made for each other.
The Heart Is Crazy
Like the heart and its beat-
Made for each other.
Like the eye and its sight -
Like the monsoon and the rain -
Made for each other.
One lover, one beloved
Made for each other
When God gave them a heart...
It was one heart in two pieces.
He wrote one name on both...
He wrote 'Radha' and 'Krishna'.
Now these hearts beat together,
They come together
and they part.
When two people
are made for each other.
I don't know when,
Like a silent thief...
like a silent thief...
The first look of love...
Took my heart away
In love's very first game
of hide N seek...
I hid myself in
the shelter of his eyes.
Now I'm frightened...
...because like a silent thief...
the first look of love...
Took my heart away
My hair disheveled,
I walk like I'm drunk
If anyone sees me
They will ask what's up.
How can I go home like this?
Jimmy, get Rahul.
Rahul's not here.
Go and look for him then!
And fast!
I'll be right back.
- Shruti, have you seen Rahul?
- No, I haven't.
I don't know when,
like a silent thief...
the first glance of love...
took my heart away.
Rahul! How often have I told you that
I get anxious when you're late...
Sorry, Nisha, I got this idea
at the last minute...
and I thought that if
I shoot out of the stage...
the audience will freak out
and that's what happened.
What's the fuss all about?
Look here, Rahul... I'm fed up
with your last minute entries
Hey kid, I'm the director.
I do what I want.
I can change whomever
I like, even you.
Yeah, but you'll never
get another dancer like me.
If I want I can
get Shruti to dance.
Nisha! Fight with
Rahul later please.
It's time to go on stage.
Take the mike.
I want to thank
you all very much...
for making this dance show
such a big success.
As you all know, this is the
last night of this show.
However, I promise you that
we'll be back in three months...
with a new story, new songs
and a new name.
Yes, 'Maya' is the name
of our new dance show.
Rahul, this new play 'Maya'...
what's it all about? Tell us.
Yes! Tell us about it!
Okay...
I don't know.
What?!
If you didn't know that,
then why did you tell everyone...
that we'll do a new show
called 'Maya'...
and that we'll do it
in three months?
Now look, even I don't know
who or what Maya is.
But I do know that in three months,
we'll do a show called 'Maya'.
Do you have in mind
a girl who's like Maya?
Right now, Maya is not even
in my perception.
Hey, Nisha! I've got
a girl in mind.
Rahul! Aren't you talking
about Pami, the Colonel's daughter?
Rahul, are you in love
with a girl like Maya?
No, I'm not in love with anyone
but lots of girls love me.
But Maya is the kind of girl
that anyone would love.
Maya is the kind of girl for whom
you would leave even Soni.
You'd better watch out
if you cheat on my sister.
Ballu, shut up.
What does she do?
She spins dreams.
Is Maya beautiful?
Very.
This Maya must do something...
Maya dances...
but only for herself.
Excuse me, but she is a feeling,
a fantasy, beautiful...
and a dancer. But we've got to
find her in three months.
So who is she?
Maya is all these things
and yet she is only Maya.
We've gone around in circles
and we're back where we started.
Are you trying to
make us look dumb?
I've done chores all my life!
But I'll decide this today!
Silly girl!
Where were you?
- I was outside.
- Now you have to come with me.
I'm tired of the promises
your uncle makes everyday.
So, today we're going to have a
fight and you have to take my side.
Bravo, bravo! What a performance!
Wonderful!
Panditji... excuse me, Panditji
Go on, Chandni... er, Shanti
Please allow us to have a teabreak.
Break whatever you want.
Please allow me to have
a word with your students.
By all means.
Watchman! Gardener!
Shankar and Ramu, if you don't mind,
perhaps you'd all get back to work!
Where are you going?
Why are you driving away
my audience?
Please be quiet.
You gather the servants here so they
can't get on with their work!
I have to do it all
by myself.
As of today, no music recitals.
From today...
only you will sing and only
you will listen. No audience.
Even in my own house my songs
aren't appreciated.
So how will others
appreciate them?
Because of your aunt's behavior,
I never became a great singer.
I know, I know...
Now have a cup of tea.
No, I don't want any tea.
Have a cup of tea...
and sing a song for me.
Will you listen to my song?
- Really?
- Certainly.
So let me have the tea!
Here, this is your parcel.
It's from Ajay!
There must be a cassette in there.
- Hear my song first.
- Later, uncle... please!
See that? You have always
driven away my audience!
What are you dreaming about?
I was thinking
how fast time flies.
It seems like yesterday that
Mr. Khanna and Geeta...
had that accident and
Pooja came to our house.
And now, it seems as if we have
no existence without her.
And I have never seen such
close friends as Pooja and Ajay.
Hey, fatty! How are you?
Shut up, I'm not fat.
I've heard that nowadays you're
really packing your food away.
Don't do that or
no one will marry you!
Idiot! Don't worry about my marriage!
Who's going to marry you?
By now, you must have finished
cursing me. So I'll proceed.
I'm having fun, as usual, and work
and girls are keeping me busy.
Tell you what? I never realised
how handsome I am.
Oh really!!
Don't make faces.
If you wish I can fax you
a list of my girlfriends.
For your information, I've left Tina
because she doesn't like Hindi films.
Thank God. She was really stupid...
- And now my heart is elsewhere...
- Who is she?
Don't yell, I'm telling you.
She's called Dolly.
There's no need to worry.
She really likes Hindi movies.
And yes, I forgot
to tell you something.
I may be coming to Bombay
for a few days.
- When?!
- There's no need to stand...
Sit down.
It's not fixed as yet.
As soon as I get to know,
I'll tell you.
OK, I'm off. Dolly is coming and
even though you haven't told me...
- I'll give her your love.
- There's no need.
OK, I won't...
Hey! Here she comes!
OK, I'm going...
Give mum and dad my love!
Hey Nisha, where've you put that
cassette you took from my car?
You know there was a really
important track on it of our play.
Anything that goes into your room
vanishes forever.
You have no manners. You must knock
before coming into a girl's room.
Is there a girl here?
I am! Stupid!
And seriously...
Look, don't talk to me
in this girly girly way. Please!
You have also entered my room
when I had nothing on. So?
- That's different.
- Why is it different?
Go on now...
get my cassette.
First say sorry,
then you'll get the cassette.
- Must I say sorry?!
- Yes.
- Say sorry to you?
I'll fix you, Nisha!
Come on, give me back my cassette!
- Give it to me!
- I won't!
- Now say you're sorry!
- Sorry for what?
Sorry that you've wasted
my time and made me run.
- I won't say I'm sorry.
- Say sorry!
And quickly say that you
won't annoy me ever again.
- I'll never annoy you!
- Say: Rahul is the best.
Never...
Okay! Rahul is the best.
Whatever happens I shan't
dance in your play!
So be it. There are plenty
of dancers like you!
There's no one
who dances like me!
Pooja... my marriage
has been arranged.
Marriage?!
Anjali, what's up with you?
You're going to marry someone...
you haven't chosen?
Someone you hardly know?!
I do know him.
He's the son of Mr. Kapoor.
I've known him for years.
But you don't love him.
Well, Pooja... love will
happen in due course.
What are you saying, Anjali?
We're not children
any more, Pooja.
It's time we emerged from
our world of fantasies.
We are Indian girls.
The lovers of our dreams and
our husbands are not the same.
Someone else chooses
our husbands for us.
We learn to love them.
This is the truth and...
the sooner you realise it,
the better.
Don't make this mistake, Anjali.
Someone, somewhere is made for you
and you should wait for him.
Perhaps this one is him.
I'm sure that this is the one
who was made for me.
And who knows?
This might happen to you.
Tomorrow you might marry a man
whom you merely know...
and slowly you might realise that
he was the one you were waiting for.
Nothing like this
will happen to me.
I'll choose my husband myself.
There can't be
a girl like this.
Meaning?
Rahul, this character
is a mistake...
and Maya exists
only in your dreams.
Modern girls aren't like this.
What do you know?
You're not a girl.
Maya is not one of these
modern girls.
She's something else...
She is my Maya.
Your Maya, indeed!
What do you know about girls?
You know only one. And that's me!
What do you mean? I don't know
anything about love...
and yet I'm making this
love story. What of it?
Rahul, your Maya
is really crazy.
Don't you call
my Maya crazy!
You are the only one
who feels this.
- Nobody else is saying anything.
- Definitely!
Rahul, I think Nisha is right.
I don't understand this
Maya character either.
Her character seems false.
Looking at it from
a psychological point of view...
I'm sure that you're
on your own trip.
- Do you also want to say something?
- I think we need a lunchbreak.
Look, I don't know if there is
such a girl or not...
and I don't want to know.
Whether she is a lie,
a fantasy or mad or whatever...
If you cannot understand this,
I am very sorry.
I can't do anything
about this, but...
under no circumstances am I going
to change the character of Maya.
I think Rahul's right.
You shut up.
You are Rahul's yes man.
- I was only saying that...
- Okay... what were you saying?
Do you know of such a girl?
Is your Soni like this?
No.
Do you understand the
character of Maya?
- No.
- Should we do this play?
That's exactly what
I have been saying!
But...
An innocent face...
Mischief in her eyes...
Oh my!
An innocent face;
mischief in her eyes...
She stands far away from me,
looking shy.
Oh my!
She lets me catch a glimpse of
her face, then she turns away.
If you look with my eyes, friend,
you can see her.
She's no ordinary girl,
she's a magical being.
What else can I say
to describe her.
Last night she appeared in my dreams,
her hair flowing wildly.
When I woke up, I wished
I could go back to my dream.
If this how I feel
without meeting her...
what will happen when I do?
Her eyeliner is dark like the
first cloud of the rainy season
She moves like
a wave on the ocean.
From what special substance
did God make her body?
I wish that one-day, magically,
she becomes a reality.
Perhaps you haven't noticed
but everyone is staring at us.
So what? I don't care.
I'll be back in a moment.
Have you come shopping?
Alone?
Very good! Never make the mistake
of going shopping with a girl.
- Do you like it?
- I like it very much.
I like it very, very much too.
Let's go.
Once you've tried it on.
You like it and I like it...
Let's go, please.
To hell with Rahul!
- What did you say?
- Nothing, nothing at all.
Off you go!
Who is it?
Why are you laughing?
What's up?
Where are your jeans?
Come on, I'm wearing my jeans.
It happens, y'know.
Who's there?
Crazy!
Everybody clap...
Open the cake box.
How did this happen?
What happened and
when did it happen?
How did this get swapped over?
I had ordered a chocolate cake.
You've brought someone
else's parcel.
I'm so stupid!
I should have checked.
It's all right, dear.
Other people celebrate their
birthdays by cutting a cake.
I'll celebrate mine
by cutting sandwiches.
Let me see who got my cake.
- Who's this Pooja?
- I don't know.
- And who's this uncle?
- Must be Pooja's uncle.
The first time I send you
to do something...
and you go and get
the boxes mixed up.
What have I done? I brought the
parcel the shopkeeper gave me.
But you should have checked.
Excuse me, but it wasn't up to me
to check. Next time, do it yourself.
I am hungry.
This cake looks really good.
- No one's eating this cake.
- Why not?
Because it belongs to someone else.
They must be eating eating
our sandwiches, too...
There's an address written here.
It's nearby. Go and deliver it.
Have you gone mad?
Rahul, this is someone's
birthday cake.
It was ordered with love
for that person.
Someone's party will be ruined.
Go and give it back.
I'm not going.
Rahul be damned!
Jimmy, let's go and give it back
and say 'Happy Birthday! '.
- What did you say?
- Nothing.
Good evening. Are you uncle?
No, I'm aunty.
Actually, by mistake
I got your cake, aunty.
The sandwich man!
That's right. Here's your cake...
Wishing you a happy birthday.
Thank you and sorry.
Why sorry?
Because I've eaten
your sandwiches.
That's all right. Actually, I ate
a bit of your cake on the way here.
No wonder...!
OK, I'll be off Uncle
No. Come in and
have some cake.
No thanks. I've got something
to do. I'm in a hurry.
Just a minute. Just one minute
Let the person who bought
this cake, thank you.
That poor man, whose sandwiches
you picked up by mistake...
has brought the
cake back.
Go and thank him.
He's at the door.
The cake has brought
a twinkle in my eyes...
and a musical rhythm to the
strings of my heart
Strange man.
Why are you buying
all this stuff?
Oh, Anjali...
Today is Valentine's Day
Don't you know about
Valentine's Day?
The man you love most in the world
is called your Valentine.
On this day, all lovers
tell each other...
about all the love they have
in their hearts.
This is all about love.
You won't understand.
But whom are you buying
all these things for?
- For myself.
- What?
You see, I don't have a lover.
So there's no one to buy me
all these lovely things.
I'm doing this
for my own pleasure.
You've gone quite mad.
Do you know, today isn't
an ordinary Valentine's Day.
After many years, today it falls
on the same day as the full moon.
Do you know what this means?
I don't, but I'm sure
you're going to tell me.
It means that if you believe
that someone is made for you...
and you are waiting for him
with a true heart...
you will certainly
meet him today.
And you really believe this?
Of course, I'm absolutely sure
that before midnight today...
I shall meet my soulmate.
Pooja! You're really mad!
That I am.
I'm going home. If you want
to come with me, then come on.
Rahul, we all came together
and we'll all go together.
This is a very boring party.
If you want to come, then come on.
Rahul, you don't get any better.
See, it's such a beautiful night...
and you're so unromantic.
Look, everyone's so much in love.
You think that
they're all in love?
Sit down.
Tell me something, Nisha.
You think you know what love is?
Love is when you're so fond of
someone, that your heart tells you...
you want to spend your whole
life in his arms.
That's what we call love.
You think the people here want to
spend the rest of their lives...
- with each other?
- I think so.
Girls are so daft.
Do you know, most of these romances
will be over before tomorrow?
They'll fight over
small things...
and will never see
each other after tonight.
And next year, you will
see the same faces...
at the same places
in different arms.
- Boys are also really stupid.
- I'm telling you the facts, Nisha.
You must realise that you need
to know someone really well...
- to spend your life together.
- That's right.
And in order to know someone well
you need to spend time together?
True.
In today's world,
whose got the time?
Look; among all these party guests,
no one's known each other...
for as long as we've
known each other.
Does that mean that we can spend
a lifetime with each other?
Come on, don't just accept
what I'm saying...
but just tell me, could you spend
your whole life with me?
Here you are, Rahul!
And everyone wants you outside!
Why?
The thing is, my friend, people here
want to hear you sing a song.
- No way!
- Oh, come on!
Tell me, could you spend
your whole life with me?
Yes, Rahul. I could
spend it with you.
I could spend my
whole life with you.
The moon whispered something...
which the night heard...
The moon whispered something,
Did you hear...
It said "fall in love"
The moonlight came to my street
and to my house,
To say "fall in love"
What can I say,
what can I do,
This strange thing
that has happened to me.
It is a sign or did my heart
whisper "fall in love"
There is someone,
I don't know who.
But I am certain that
there is someone.
He is somewhere in my dreams,
but I cannot see him
I am here...
he is somewhere there
Then whose voice was it...
that said "fall in love"
I have given my love to him,
he does not know.
How can I call him unfaithful,
I have tried to say so much,
he does not hear.
Oh my sad heart, be careful...
when you "fall in love"
You're really crazy. Is there
something wrong with your brain?
Going home like this
without telling anyone!
You said we had come together
and we'd all leave together.
Then you go and run away
all on your own.
You know that we're all worried.
You stupid idiot!
Er... this is not 6711237,
is it?
No.
I'm sorry, I thought
it was someone else.
You're right.
I am someone else.
Please excuse me.
It's OK.
Hang on, one minute...
don't hang up the phone.
Yes?
The music you're playing...
that's Pundit Shiv Kumar Sharma's
new album, isn't it?
Yes.
I just love it. Actually, you know,
I wanted to buy it.
- Where did you buy it from?
- 'Rhythm House'.
I haven't been there. Do you think
they would have it in stock?
How would I know?
Oh right, stupid me...
how would you know?
You don't work there. I'm really
sorry about all this.
Nice voice.
How could you do this to me?!
You scared the hell out of me!
Now I'm not going to give up
until I've got you.
Wait till I get
my hands on you!
How about it?
Ballu! What are you up to?
Why, what's wrong, Rahul?
I told you that after
this drum roll is over...
the spotlight should
move from me to Nisha.
- And I thought...
- Shut up.
Come on, Nisha...
do it again.
What?
- Please pack up early today.
- Why? What's special about today?
Nothing. Come on.
Good. C'mon, everybody.
Let's take it from the top.
Rahul, you forgot?
Today is her birthday.
Really? Why didn't
someone tell me?
Why didn't you tell me?
There are some things, Rahul, which
one knows without being told.
Even then... you people
should have said something.
Honestly, you guys
are the limit...
You've been forgetting
my birthday all these years.
This is just another year.
Stop putting on an act and
take us all out to dinner.
What is it?
You remembered!
So why didn't you say it?
There are some things which
one knows without being told.
Come on, let's rehearse!
What are you guys drinking?
- I want some.
- This isn't for ladies. So relax.
No, I want some.
I told you that this
isn't suitable for you!
Today's my birthday.
I'll do as I please.
OK... suit yourself.
Give me another glass.
Nothing.
You're in love? Give over!
I know your kind of love.
It changes every week.
Not my kind of love...
but your kind of love.
The marrying kind? Really?
Who's the girl. Do I know her?
Really well.
Tell me who she is, please!
- Must I?
- Shoot!
Forget it.
That hurts!
Didn't I tell you?
It's not for ladies!
Please, Ajay!
Tell me who she is!
Right then. We'll do this.
See that waiter?
- Which one?
- The one serving the water.
- So?
- Keep looking at him.
If there's still a glass of
water on that tray...
by the time he gets to our table
then I'll tell you her name.
Excuse me!
A glass of water, please!
That's cheating.
You can't do that.
Don't say anything.
Say nothing at all...
Take my shoes and give me money.
I'm afraid.
Don't leave me I'm scared
It's really late. Now quietly
go to sleep! Good night!
First promise me
that you won't leave me.
OK, baby, I shan't leave you alone.
You won't leave me, even if I ask
for an ice-cream, will you?
No, I won't.
You won't leave me, even if
I don't dance well... will you?
No, I won't.
Not even if I call you names...
donkey, monkey... will you?
Of course, I won't.
You won't leave me, even if I tell you
that I love you... will you?
There she is...
still asleep!
Come on, Pooja!
It's seven in the morning!
The sun is up, Pooja.
What the hell...!
What are you up to, you idiot?
Is this the way to wake someone up?
I'm so sorry, but seeing you fast
asleep, I just couldn't resist it!
How could I miss out on
such an opportunity?
Listen, get ready quickly.
We've got to go to the airport.
Airport? Are you going somewhere?
No. WE are going somewhere.
WE? And where are we going?
Well, it's not far from India,
it's very near.
We'll return by tonight's flight.
Get ready quickly!
I can't understand a word
of what you're saying!
It's very simple.
I have to go on some business.
It will take me just an hour, just
sign some papers and then I am free.
If you come along, you'll see a new
city as well as do some shopping.
And anyway I am leaving for London
tomorrow. That leaves only today...
which I want to spend with you.
But Ajay, I must find out if
it's okay with Uncle and Aunty.
I've already got their approval.
It's only you who has to decide!
So fatty, are you coming or not?
- Of course, I am coming!
- Then hurry up and get ready.
- The flight is on time.
- Wait a minute...
- What's that under your eye?
- Where...?
Now wait, you fatty...!
Never mind.
I'll get you for this.
Come and get me.
You're going shopping, aren't you?
We'll see!
The heart is crazy,
the heart is mad.
The very first time lovers meet,
it sets their bodies on fire.
Very slowly it teaches love, it makes
them laugh, and it makes them cry.
It keeps them awake all night, it
steals the sleep from their eyes
It shows true and false dreams...
it makes them laugh,
and it makes them cry.
Those who follow the heart
are known to be crazy
They discover their destination,
but cannot find the path.
I don't need to see his face,
I don't need to know his name either.
I don't need to think or worry,
because my heart will know him.
We all listen to what
the heart says...
the heart doesn't
listen to anyone,
I've given my life to him,
yet everyone knows, but he.
So be it, give up these stories,
all these signs of madness,
All people's worries are
all thanks to this crazy heart.
Well, Ajay Sahib...
it's time for you to go.
Now I have to go.
Did you say something?
Pooja, I want to say
something to you.
Say what you want to say.
This quick business trip of a couple
of days was all a pretence.
I came here for something else.
It's been eight years
since I left India.
In these years I've earned
enough of respect and money.
But life has been too hectic.
I want to settle down now.
And whenever I close my eyes...
to think whom I would like to spend
the rest of my life with...
it is always your face
that I see.
I don't know how or when my
feelings for you turned to love.
But I don't know anything
about your mind.
Or if there is anyone
in your life or not.
That is what I came here
to find out.
I don't know what
you think about me.
I don't even know if you would want
to spend your whole life with me.
But I know for sure that I love you
and I want to marry you.
I'm going towards
the departure gate.
Once I've got there I'll
turn round and look.
If your answer is yes, then
you'll be standing here.
And if you're not here
then I'll understand.
And one more thing. Don't forget
that whatever your decision is...
we were friends, we are friends,
and we'll always be friends.
And who knows, tomorrow
it may also happen to you.
Perhaps you will marry a man
whom you only know...
but whom you don't love.
Then you will realise later
that he was the man...
for whom you were waiting.
But why did you keep
standing there?
Sometimes I'm so happy when
I make someone else happy...
that I can't think
of anything else.
You should have
seen his face, Anjali!
He was so happy. I have never
seen him so happy ever before.
And your happiness?
You don't love him, Pooja!
Love will happen in due course
and we are Indian girls.
We can't choose our own husbands...
so someone else chooses
our husbands for us.
We learn to love them.
Isn't that true?
At last you have left your girlish
dreams and become a woman.
No, Anjali. The girl
has become a woman...
but she has not
given up her dreams.
She believes in them
completely, even now.
She is sure that Ajay is the one
for whom she was always waiting...
and perhaps it was HE who was
taking HIS time to show her.
I'm certain that Ajay will
make you very happy.
- Hi, doctor...
- There's no need to worry.
It's a small fracture.
She'll go home in a week or so.
I told you Nisha would start
dancing again in a week.
I was talking about going home,
not about dancing.
She won't be able to dance
for about three months.
Three months?
Yes, Rahul.
Her heel is very delicate.
If she doesn't take care then
this fracture could recur...
and it could be more serious.
Does she know this.
May I see her?
Of course. You don't
need my permission.
Whose going to get me
a cup of tea?
God! You won't learn to knock.
Don't give me a lecture. I have
something very important to discuss.
Okay, what is it?
Can you see me properly?
How many fingers?
See, your Doctor Kapoor isn't up
to much, in my opinion.
Get a check-up with
another doctor.
Why?
This doctor was talking about
getting you discharged in a week.
- So what?
- No, no I can't allow this.
It's been difficult getting you
admitted into a hospital.
You should spend at least
a month or two in here.
And while you are away,
we'll also have some peace.
You're always making
fun of me. I hate you.
She has gone mad
with the pain...
I'm sorry that I've put you
to so much of trouble.
You've taken all the money
from the sponsor...
and how will you get
a dancer so quickly?
And for three months, I...
There's no need for you to worry.
Why do you think you're
such a good dancer?
In this town there are
many such dancers.
But you'll never get...
We'll never get
another dancer like you.
Now you don't worry about this.
You have a nice rest and I'll
come see you in the evening.
I'll bring some food.
We'll eat together.
Why are you worried?
It will all work out.
How will it all work out?
We've taken money from the sponsors
and paid a deposit for the stadium.
And most of all, where will we
get another dancer like Nisha?
Come on, friends, if we try, do you
think we can't find one good dancer?
These days there are
so many dance schools.
There is one close to
our rehearsal hall.
We'll find a dancer
there tomorrow.
How about that, Rahul?
Come on! Relax!
Whatever happens
will be for the best.
Let's go and have
some cold beer.
No, thanks. You go ahead.
I'm not in the mood.
Lay off, he's tired.
Come on, let's go.
Maya, I'll find her.
Water, water...
The sandwich man!
Shanti... has a parcel
come here by mistake?
I haven't come for
a parcel today.
Then tell me what
I can do for you.
- I want to meet your daughter.
- I don't have a daughter.
- No daughter?
- No.
Then sir, this
Miss Pooja Malhotra...
Pooja is like my daughter.
But how do you know her?
I saw her last night.
Last night? Where?
In the dancing school.
She dances beautifully.
- And so?
- So, I wanted to meet her.
- Why?
- I wanted to ask her something.
- What did you want to ask her?
- Sort of, would she, with me...
- With you... what?
- If she wanted to work with me.
What work?
I'm doing a play and I'm
looking for a dancer.
You are doing a play.
Are you a director?
Yes. I am sorry.
I am sorry! Why didn't you
say that in the first place?
I said so, when you asked me.
- Actually, I am a singer.
- I see.
I've done years of practice.
As it happens with
many great artistes...
you really don't meet
many connoisseurs.
You've met me today.
You don't know how lucky you are!
Sir, I have come to meet Pooja.
Now that you have met me,
you will meet Pooja, too!
I won't give you more
than seventy-five rupees.
Eighty rupees. No less.
Only last week I bought it
at that price.
This is the right price.
Taste it and see how sweet it is.
I will give you only
seventy-five Rupees.
- Show me the watermelon.
- Here you are, sir.
Seventy-five is the right price.
How many do you want, Madam?
- Just one.
Pack this for Madam.
But...
It's your first sale in the day.
And you're haggling for 5 bucks!
Be a sport!
Recognise me? We met last night
at your dancing school. Remember?
You must have heard of me?
- No.
- Well, never mind.
Actually you are
a pretty good dancer.
Actually, I'm doing some music shows
and I need a special dancer...
for a special role. When I saw you
dancing yesterday...
I thought that you would be
ideal for this.
So what do you think?
Would you be interested?
- No thanks.
- I've had it!
Damn the watermelon!
My career's at stake!
Excuse me, but perhaps
you misunderstand me.
I'm talking to you about
no ordinary show.
It's a very high-class show with
a very high-class audience...
and I am sure you will also enjoy
doing it. Why don't you try it once?
I'm a dancer.
But I am afraid of dancing on stage
in front of an audience.
- Why are you afraid?
- I don't think I can do it.
Excuse me, I'm sorry,
but you see...
I'm really in difficulty.
The thing is that my lead dancer
has fractured her foot...
and I've already taken all
the money for the show.
Now if the show does not go on, not
only will I suffer monetarily...
but my reputation will
take a big blow.
Please just once come
to the rehearsal hall...
and if you don't want to,
you don't have to do the show.
But please, just once...
please come to the rehearsal.
You'll have to take someone else.
You don't know that
I'm a very stubborn man.
- What are you up to?!
- I'll not go until you agree.
Please come just once
to a rehearsal.
Everyone's looking at us.
- Promise you'll come?
- I'll come. Promise.
- What time?
- At two O'clock.
- Can you come at one?
- Okay, I'll come at one.
You know that we are
neighbors, don't you?