What are they like, these girls?
They're very good. A bit wild.
Spend their money quickly. Work hard.
-Are they literate?
-Some of them.
ln and out of reformatories
from the day they were picked up.
Jobs like this. lt's degrading.
They shouldn't use human beings
to move earth.
No.
And it's not efficient.
lf they were to give me
two more excavators...
...l'd be a year ahead of the plan by now.
You're an impatient generation.
Weren't you?
Yes, we were. Very.
Don't be too impatient, Comrade Engineer,
we've come very far, very fast.
Yes, l know that, Comrade General.
Yes, but do you know what it cost?
There were children in those days
who lived off human flesh.
Did you know that?
What is your interest in this girl,
Comrade General?
She may be my brother's child.
-Yuri Andreyevich?
-Yes.
My half-brother, l should say.
lf she is...
...she's also Lara's child.
The Lara?
The Lara, yes.
This is a new edition of the ''Lara Poems.''
Yes, l know.
We admire your brother very much.
Yes, everybody seems to, now.
Well, we couldn't admire him
when we weren't allowed to read him.
No.
Come in.
l sent for you, Comrade.
You're not in any trouble.
l'm General Yevgraf Andreyevich Zhivago.
l'm looking for someone.
Do you understand?
The person l'm looking for
would be my niece.
Please sit down.
Your name is--
Tonya Komarova, Comrade General.
They found you in Mongolia, didn't they?
-Yes, Comrade General.
-What were you doing there?
l was lost, Comrade General.
How did you come to be lost?
l've forgotten.
Was Komarovsky your father's name?
l suppose so, Comrade General.
You suppose so?
lt's a common name.
Do you remember your father?
No.
Do you remember your mother?
Yes, l remember my mother.
What was her name?
''Mammy.''
What was she like?
l mean, what did she look like?
Big.
Big?
l was little. She looked big.
-Can you read?
-Yes.
''Lara. A Cycle of Poems, by Y.A. Zhivago.''
Not me. My half-brother.
The person l'm looking for...
...would be this man's daughter.
This would be her mother.
''Lara.''
Did anybody ever call your mother Lara?
l don't know. l don't think so.
She's nice.
l'm not your niece, Comrade General.
Well, l'm nobody's idea of an uncle.
But if this man were my father,
l should want to know.
Did your mother ever tell you
your father was a poet?
Comrade General, my father wasn't a poet.
What was your father?
Not a poet.
Did you like your father?
l've forgotten.
But you liked your mother?
Yes, of course.
Does the name ''Strelnikov''
mean anything to you? ''Strelnikov''?
''Varykino''?
That's a place, not a person.
''Gromeko''?
-Gromeko?
-Yes.
You see...
...he lost his mother...
...at about the same age you were...
...when your mother lost you.
And, in the same part of the world.
Now is life's artful triumph
of vanities destroyed...
...for the spirit has vanished
from its tabernacle...
...its clay groweth black.
The vessel is shattered, voiceless,
emotionless, dead.
Committing which unto the grave,
let us beseech the Lord...
...that He will give her eternal rest.
Yuri?
You and your husband will dine with us,
Madame Gromeko.
Thank you, Father.
Will you lie down, then, Yuri?
Your mammy and l were great,
great friends, you know...
...so now we are going to look after you.
Thank you.
That's mother's.
lt's yours now.
Yes, Yuri. Mammy left it to you.
ln her will.
Do you know what a will is, old chap?
Money.
No, Yuri, just this.
Your daddy has all the money.
Can you play it?
l thought all the people in this part
of the world could play the balalaika.
You don't live here, do you?
No, we live in Moscow.
That's a long way from here,
but you will like Moscow.
-Won't he?
-ln a bit.
lt takes time
to get used to things, doesn't it?
Mother could play it.
Well, your mother was an artist, Yuri.
She could make this common
little instrument sound like two guitars.
Your mother had a gift.
Perhaps Yuri's got a gift.
Would you like lessons?
l can't play it.
Say good night to Yuri, Tonya.
He's your brother, now.
Good night, Yuri.
Good night, old chap.
Good night.
The Gromekos dldn't know
what to make of hlm.
He made hls reputatlon as a poet
whlle he was studylng to be a doctor.
He sald that poetry was no more
of a vocatlon than good health.
What he needed was a job.
Pretty?
Very.
Yeah. lt's their right to be pretty.
What will you do next year, Zhivago?
l thought of doing general practice.
Think about doing pure research.
lt's exciting, important, tender, beautiful.
General practice.
Life. He wants to see life. Well....
You'll find that pretty creatures
do ugly things to people.
What's your name?
Antipov.
Address?
15 Patrofka.
l'll have these.
We have permission
from the chief of police.
-Well, you claim them at the station.
-When?
Now if you like.
Very well.
He's my brother.
Well, take him home, Miss.
Before he gets into trouble.
Pasha, please!
lt's got to be done.
Pasha, why has it got to be done?
For them. For the Revolution.
-Pasha, they don't want a revolution.
-Yes, they do.
They don't know it yet,
but that's what they want.
Give me some of those, Comrade.
Pasha, are you a Bolshevik?
No. The Bolsheviks don't like me.
And l don't like them.
They don't know right from wrong.
Pasha Antipov, you're an awful prig.
Why did you tell him l was your brother?
Well, what else could l have told him?
You could have told him l was your fiance.
Pasha, don't be silly. l'm--
Monsieur Komarovsky has come to see
my mother on business.
People gossip around here.
lt's the system, Lara.
People will be different
after the Revolution.
Will you come?
No, Pasha.
l've got exams to take, Pasha.
l've got to get my scholarship.
Hello, Auntie.
There's a letter for you.
From Paris.
Lovely writing.
She's coming home next month.
Tonya? Oh, that's good!
He does seem to be very well informed.
And such a handsome figure of--
Good evening, Mama. Madame.
Larissa.
You can work in there, dear.
Monsieur Komarovsky's here.
Good evening, Larissa.
Good evening, Monsieur.
He advises some very important people.
Yes, l know.
l believe he has government connections.
l don't know, l'm sure.
lsn't he very expensive?
Monsieur Komarovsky advises me
out of kindness, Baroness.
He was a friend of my late husband.
Oh, l see.
Allow me.
Tuesday, if l can, my dear. Goodbye.
Where did you get this?
A friend gave it to me,
Monsieur Komarovsky.
You're not to go
to this peaceful demonstration.
No, Monsieur.
lt may not be as peaceful as they think.
That's all l have to say.
Tell your friend that she's a silly creature.
Yes, Monsieur.
How old are you now?
Seventeen, Monsieur.
A hundred and three.
Oh, dear.
And l was so looking forward to it.
Oh, never mind. l'll be all right here.
You will take Lara, won't you,
Victor Yppolitovich?
lt is so stupid of me!
lt's her first long gown.
l think you'd better call it right off.
Yes. l'll stay with you.
Nonsense! l'll be perfectly all right.
l've got a book.
lt's so disappointing for her,
Victor Yppolitovich.
There's so little opportunity
to mix with good society.
Very well. Get your coat.
We're late, if we're going.
l want to avoid Kropotkin Street.
''Brotherhood and freedom.''
Yuri, what splendid words.
''Justice, equality and bread.''
Don't you think they're splendid?
Yes, l do.
''Brotherhood and freedom.''
Brotherhood and fiddlesticks!
You're frozen through.
You've no right, Annushka. lt isn't fair.
We'd given you up, Monsieur.
My niece. Coat, Lara.
Charmante.
Come, my dear.
How's the Foie de Veau, Gascoigne?
As always, Monsieur.
-All right. Not too much--
-Not too much mustard, Monsieur.
-Jambon Farcl en Crote.
-Oul, Mademolselle.
Wine, Monsieur?
A little light wine, yes.
Oul, Monsleur. Mademolselle.
This place must be dreadfully expensive,
Monsieur Komarovsky.
lt is.
Why not ''Victor Yppolitovich''?
l can't.
Mother made this dress.
Very nice.
She's clever, isn't she?
Your mother? Yes. Fine little woman.
No doubt they'll sing in tune
after the Revolution.
Prepare!
Mount!
Tote sabers!
What, what?
What?
-Good night, dear.
-Good night...
...Victor Yppolitovich.
Go inside your houses, please.
All these people will be taken care of.
Go inside, please.
Get inside.
Yuri, please. No trouble.
Take him inside, sir,
or l'll put him under arrest.
Yuri, l beg you.
Tonya's coming home tomorrow.
Daddy!
There, now, that's enough.
Your mother, your mother.
Mammy!
Mammy, how are you?
Me? Fit as a fiddle.
Turn 'round.
Well, they've taught her something.
-Look at that!
-lsn't Yuri looking well, Tonya?
Yes. Well, let's get along, dear.
Yes. Run along, you two.
l brought you this. lt has a piece in it
about young Russian poets.
Oh, good! Thank you.
Does it mention me?
lt begins with you. You're the best.
Very intelligent nation, the French.
They have their heads together.
Yes. They're looking at the paper.
They're head over heels--
Annushka, stop it!
Good marriages are made in Heaven,
or some such place.
Victor Yppolitovich?
l want to talk to you.
No, Pasha.
lt's important.
All right.
How did you do it?
l didn't.
A Dragoon did.
Oh, Pasha, darling!
Come, come.
-Where's your mother?
-Asleep.
Pasha, l can't deal with this.
Have you got any iodine?
-Yes, but--
-Get it.
Will it hurt?
Pasha, darling!
Pasha, you must go to a hospital!
l daren't for a day or two.
-Will you do something for me?
-Oh, yes. What?
Hide this.
Oh, throw it away!
No.
There'll be no more
peaceful demonstrations.
There were women and children, Lara,
and they rode them down.
Starving women asking for bread.
On Tamskaya Avenue, the pigs
were eating and drinking and dancing!
Hide it for me.
Thanks, Comrade.
Pasha, darling, l'm not your comrade.
Lara?
-Yes?
-Who is there?
lt's only Pasha.
You came in very late last night, dear.
The time went so quickly.
Good.
Are you going to church?
Yes.
You know what our Lord said
to the woman taken in adultery?
Yes, Father.
He said, ''Go and sin no more.''
And, did she?
-l don't know, Father.
-Nobody does, child.
The flesh is not weak.
lt is strong. Only the sacrament
of marriage will contain it.
Remember that.
Monsieur....
lt's Number Six, this evening, sir.
The most important person here.
Sorry, l'm late.
l've been waiting nearly an hour, Victor.
Have you ordered?
No.
Well, you should have done.
You chose it, Victor.
You've grown up a lot, haven't you?
Yes.
What did you tell your mama tonight?
Victor, don't!
-May l smoke?
-Yes, of course.
You like it, don't you? Cigar smoke?
Come along, my dear.
Sant!
Drink, drink.
Up, up, up.
Where did you tell her
we were going, your mama?
She didn't ask.
-That's because she knows.
-No, she doesn't.
You'd both take an oath she doesn't.
But she does.
And you both know she does.
Victor, don't!
What?
Torment me.
Torment? Oh, what a little hypocrite it is.
l'm going, now, Victor.
Whatever you like, dear.
You see, you'll always come back.
Stay, darling.
Stay.
Wake up! Here, take this.
You show it to someone
if you lose your way.
Professor Boris Kurt. And, you find him.
Now, go on.
Professor Boris Kurt.
But, Boris, this is genius.
Really, l thought it was Rachmaninoff?.
l'm going for a smoke.
And how's the general practitioner?
A bit scared of his finals.
Well, l don't think he need be.
How do you like the idea of marrying
a general practitioner?
l like it very much.
But no general practitioner has asked me.
No?
l thought you nomads were hot-blooded.
A slow lot, these general practitioners.
How do you fancy
a professor of pathology?
Does he write poetry?
Alas, no.
Then l'm afraid it's out of the question.
Excuse me.
That's a marvelous girl, Zhivago.
Yes, l'd noticed.
lt's for you.
How would the poet like to see
a bit of general practice?
Boris, thank God you've come.
This is very good of you, Boris.
Yes, l know it is. My assistant.
-How do you do?
-Where is she?
This way.
When did she do it?
About eight o'clock this evening.
Do you know what it was?
Why didn't you get a local doctor?
-l couldn't.
-No, l suppose you couldn't.
Come on in.
Turn her over.
All right.
Water.
Now, Yuri. Come on, dear. Come on.
Now, Yuri.
Come on, dear.
Come on, Yuri.
Sorry.
Well, my dear, that's it.
That's it. Good.
Good.
ls she going to live?
Water.
-She is, isn't she?
-Yes.
Funny thing.
There's a man, speaks on public platforms.
ln with the government.
ln with the Liberals. ln with everybody.
And he risks it all.
For that!
That's not how poets see them, is it?
That's how GPs see them.
That's how they are.
You know, from here, she looks beautiful.
Zhivago, l think you're a hard case.
There's a child in the case.
A child. Her daughter.
Oh, for heaven's sake, Boris--
She might have thought about ''Lara''
before she did it.
Does the girl know?
l'm afraid she does.
-ls she here?
-Yes.
Tell her that her mother's going to live.
Wait a minute, Victor. Yurian.
Yes, of course.
What are we going to say about this?
-Must we say anything?
-l'm afraid so.
l'm taking her to the hospital.
We'll have to say something.
You know that needn't be difficult, Boris.
-What is the name of your assistant?
-Zhivago.
Andreyevich?
Yes, why? Do you know him?
No, l knew his father slightly.
Fine.
Cheer up, Yuri. l'll have the poor bitch
in hospital tonight.
What's his name?
That's Victor Komarovsky.
He says he knows you.
He executed my father's will.
Uncle Alex turned it down.
By Komarovsky's account
there wasn't much in it.
And what there was
belonged to Komarovsky.
Oh, he's a very good businessman.
But l doubt that he's crooked.
Very good company. Knows life.
He's had a bad scare tonight.
You don't mind coming here, do you,
Victor Yppolitovich?
No, no. lt reminds me of my youth.
-l went to the hospital again.
-And?
She wants you to go and forgive her.
For her suspicions.
You can tell her the truth
if you like, Larissa.
ls this him?
Yes.
-He knows nothing about--
-No.
Pasha, this is Monsieur Komarovsky.
Please.
-Will you eat?
-No, thank you.
l hope you don't think this is impertinent,
Pavel Pavlovich.
Not at all.
l am...l have been advising
Larissa's mother for many years.
l'm interested in what happens to her.
There's something l have to tell you.
And that is this:
l am committed to the Revolution.
Nothing...
...not even Lara,
has more importance for me.
You misunderstand.
Your political views do not concern me.
So far as that goes, l'm probably
more in sympathy than you suppose.
l have a few contacts of my own,
which might surprise you.
How do you propose to live?
l've been offered a teaching post.
-May l know where?
-Gradov. lt's in the Urals.
l know it. Not much of a place.
lt's beautiful country,
Monsieur Komarovsky.
lt'll be a quiet life, won't it?
That's what we want.
Well, you'll excuse me.
Will your salary be adequate?
Adequate. lf not more.
Pavel Pavlovich, my chief impression is,
and l mean no offense...
...is that you're very young.
Monsieur Komarovsky,
l hope l don't offend you.
Do people improve with age?
They grow a little more tolerant.
Because they have more
to tolerate in themselves.
lf people don't marry young,
what do they bring to their marriage?
A little experience.
l'm 26. My mother died, needlessly,
when l was eight.
My father died in prison.
l have fended for myself.
l've worked my way
through higher school and university.
l am familiar with things
that you can hardly guess at.
All this is an experience
of a kind, certainly.
l've no amorous experience,
if that's what you mean.
None whatever. Lara's 17.
That speaks for itself.
You probably find this situation comic.
We don't.
We're going to be married next year.
l hope l haven't offended you
by speaking plainly.
Not at all. Admirable.
A young crusader.
Oh, he's not--
He's a very fine young man.
That's obvious.
You're very generous,
Monsieur Komarovsky.
Larissa, l want to talk to you.
Monsieur Komarovsky, will you--
l beg you.
Drop this affectation of addressing me
as ''Monsieur Komarovsky''!
Under the circumstances,
l find it rather ridiculous.
Lara, l am determined to save you
from a dreadful error.
There are two kinds of men, and only two.
And that young man is one kind.
He is high-minded. He is pure.
He is the kind of man that the world
pretends to look up to and despises.
He's the kind of man who breeds
unhappiness, particularly in women.
-Do you understand?
-No.
l think you do.
There's another kind.
Not high-minded. Not pure, but alive.
That your tastes at this time should incline
toward the juvenile is understandable.
But, for you to marry that boy
would be a disaster.
Because, there are two kinds of women.
There are two kinds of women and you,
as we well know, are not the first kind.
You, my dear, are a slut.
l am not!
We'll see.
And, don't delude yourself
that this was rape.
That would flatter us both.
The master's not at home, Miss Lara.
Not at home?
No. He went to
the Sventytskis' Christmas party.
Are you going there, Miss?
Please don't say l told you.
No, thank you, Piotr.
Merry Christmas, Miss Lara.
Oh, thank you,
and Merry Christmas to you.
Merry Christmas, Yuri Andreyevich.
What's the matter?
We had an appointment this evening.
Where are you going?
Haven't you got the letter? l left a letter--
l've not been home. l'm going home, now.
Where're you going, Lara?
l've a right to know.
What's in this letter?
Are you breaking--
-lt's all in the letter.
-What is?
Everything.
Don't!
Yuri, there's an extraordinary girl
at this party.
l know. l'm dancing with her.
You're keen tonight, Victor.
l like to win.
Silence!
Silence, everybody! Silence, please!
l have a very delightful announcement
to make.
Oh, Madame Sventytski!
Yes. Why not?
l have to announce that Dr. Yuri Zhivago--
Doctor Zhivago,
he came third in all Moscow.
Now, listen, please!
Dr. Zhivago is betrothed in marriage to--
My dear Victor!
My dear man!
Get her out.
What?
Get her out. Get her out!
Yes. Yes. l'll get the police.
No!
l don't want you to get the police.
l do not want the police.
l just want you to get her out!
Let her go!
Please!
Quiet, please. Please. Give way.
Please, would you mind?
Would you mind? Thank you, thank you.
Our destinies seem to be interwoven,
don't they?
Yes.
l was a close friend of your father.
l knew you were his business partner.
Rather more than that.
l was present at his death.
Also, l am in contact with your brother.
Yevgraf?.
l should say l'm in contact with those
who are in contact with him.
Oh, l disagree with Bolshevism.
Thank you.
You seem to know your trade.
But, l can still admire Bolsheviks, as men.
Shall l tell you why?
Yes.
They may win.
l'd like to meet him, Yevgraf.
He sent me a marvelous letter.
He likes my poetry.
That would have pleased your father.
Your father was not a bad man, Yuri.
lf l may call you Yuri?
l hardly knew him.
You perhaps may not credit this...
...but he was devoted to your mother.
l suppose l may continue to rely
on your professional discretion?
You mean, will l tell anyone the truth
about that girl?
That's what l mean, yes.
You may continue to rely
on my professional etcetera.
You are fastidious, aren't you?
What happens to a girl like that,
when a man like you is finished with her?
lnterested?
l give her to you.
You shouldn't smoke. You've had a shock.
l give her to you, Yuri Andreyevich.
A wedding present.
Where have you seen that girl before?
What makes you think
l've seen her before?
Haven't you?
-Yes.
-Where?
l'm not supposed to say.
lt was on a case. Not very nice.
No, don't tell me,
if you're not supposed to say.
ln bourgeols terms lt was a war
between the Allles and Germany.
ln Bolshevlk terms lt was a war between
the Allled and the German upper classes.
And, whlch of them won was
a matter oflndlfference.
l was ordered by the Party to enllst.
l gave my name as Petrov.
They were shoutlng for vlctory
all over Europe...
...praylng for vlctory, to the same God.
My task, the Party's task,
was to organlze defeat.
From defeat would sprlng the Revolutlon.
And, the Revolutlon would be
vlctory for us.
The Party looked
to the conscrlpt peasants...
...most of them wearlng
thelr flrst good palr ofboots.
When the boots wore out,
they'd be ready to llsten.
When the tlme came, l was able to take
3 battallons wlth me out of the Front Llne.
The best day's work l ever dld.
But, for the moment,
there was nothlng to be done.
There were too many volunteers llke me.
Mostly, lt was mere hysterla.
But there were men wlth better motlves,
men who saw the tlmes were crltlcal...
...and wanted a man's part.
Good men, wasted.
Unhappy men, too.
Unhappy ln thelr jobs.
Unhappy wlth thelr wlves.
Doubtlng themselves.
Happy men don't volunteer.
They walt thelr turn and thank God
lf thelr age, or work, delays lt.
The ones who got back home wlth
the prlce of an arm or an eye or a leg...
...these were the lucky ones.
Even Comrade Lenln...
...underestlmated both
the angulsh of that 900-mlle-long front...
...and our cursed capaclty for sufferlng.
By the second wlnter of the war...
...the boots had worn out...
...but the llne stlll held.
Thelr great coats fell to pleces
on thelr backs.
Thelr ratlons were lrregular.
Half of them went lnto actlon
wlthout arms...
...led by men they dldn't trust.
Come on, you bastards!
And, those they dld trust--
Come on, Comrades. Come on!
Come on!
Comrades! Earthshakers!
Show them!
Charge!
At last they dld what all the armles
dreamed of dolng:
They began to go home.
That was the beglnnlng of the Revolutlon.
Deserters.
Replacements.
Tote arms!
Come back.
Stick together!
Stick together and we'll be all right.
And be ready for them.
Turn around, lads!
-Don't go any farther.
-Come on, lads. Turn around.
Pigs to the slaughter! Look at you!
Turn around, lads.
Listen, lads.
Ten miles up that road are the Germans!
-Rubbish.
-Not rubbish.
They're coming. And they're coming fast.
You've let them in.
They're coming for your wives...
...your houses, your country.
Your country, Officer!
Yes, my country! And proud--
Get back in your ranks!
Get back!
Get back in the ranks!
Are you a nurse?
Yes.
-Are you all right?
-Yes.
Then help me.
Doctor, l ought to tell you,
l'm not a trained nurse, l'm a volunteer.
l see. Right.
Why did you volunteer?
-l came here to find my husband.
-Very gently.
-Have you ever seen an operation?
-Yes.
We'll manage.
They're in the next village, brothers.
The Germans.
-Your Honor--
-Keep still.
Did you find your husband?
No.
Your Honor....
Yes, we'd better be off.
You know, you often look at me
as though you knew me.
l have seen you.
Four years ago. Christmas Eve.
Were you there?
No wonder you look at me.
Did you know Victor Komarovsky?
Yes, l did. That young man,
who took you away--
My husband.
A lot of courage.
He made the rest of us look very feeble.
As a matter of fact, l thought you both did.
Good man to shoot at.
l'd give anything never to have met him.
The tsar's in prison.
Lenin's in Moscow.
Civil war has started.
Good!
Civil war, good?
Not good, Comrade Nurse, inevitable.
But Lenin in Moscow!
This Lenin, will he be the new tsar then?
Listen, Daddy.
No more tsars, no more masters.
Only workers in a worker's state.
How about that?
Are you a doctor?
-Yes.
-Follow me, please.
l can't deal with this.
Order of the Provisional Government.
You'll have to try, friend.
''lf you could see how hard
we have been working here...
''...l feel sure you'd forgive me, dear,
for not writing more regularly.''
When was that written?
July 20th.
Eight weeks!
''But now the war seems
really to have stopped.
''The hospital is emptying,
and l shall have more time.
''l may even get time to write some verse,
if l've not forgotten how to.''
Oh, l do hope so!
''Larissa Antipova is still here,
and l admire her more and more.
''She seems to have the strange gift
of healing, which doctors don't believe in.
''She often does the wrong things,
but it always seems to work out right.
''How is Uncle Alex?
-''Can he still get his English tobacco?''
-Would that he could!
''Can Sasha say his letters yet?
And how is Auntie Anna?''
He didn't get my letter.
''Most of all, my dearest, how are you?''
Strangely upsetting.
He doesn't know she's dead.
Can't see what difference it makes.
They're at it again!
l wish they'd decide once and for all...
...which gang of hooligans constitutes
the government of this country!
Cheer up, Sergei.
Don't you want to go home?
There's fighting at home, Your Honor.
l've had enough.
Red Guards and White Guards,
this old man's had enough.
Your Honor is a kind gentleman.
And, the nurse is a kind lady.
Finished?
Just about.
ln a couple of weeks
you'll be with your little girl.
lf l can get on a train.
l want to be with Katya
more than anything in the world.
Yes, of course.
But, now that we're going, l feel sad.
Sad.
Really sad.
-Well, we've been here some time.
-Yes.
This must have been a lovely house, once.
Don't you think?
What are you going to do?
ln Gradov?
Yes.
l'll be all right.
l wish l could think so.
You could run a laundry.
What will you do?
l suppose l'll go back to the hospital.
lt's funny to think of you there.
l used to pass it on my way to school.
Do you ever come to Moscow?
From Gradov?
lf only there were someone
to look after you.
Of course, if there were,
l'd be destroyed by jealousy.
Zhivago, don't.
My dear, don't, please!
Now, look what you've made me do.
We've been together six months,
on the road and here...
...and we've not done anything
you'll have to lie about to Tonya.
l don't want you to have to lie about me.
You understand that, Yuri?
You understand everything.
Come on, Comrades! l'm in a hurry.
Going home, Kuril?
Home, Your Excellency?
Petrograd. l'm joining the Red Guard.
What about your wife?
Sometimes, Comrade Nurse,
women have to wait.
Right!
Goodbye, honored Doctor.
Want some advice?
-Said the millstone to the barley.
-That's right.
Adapt yourself!
Goodbye, Durinev.
Goodbye, Your Honor.
Goodbye, Andr.
Goodbye, Simyon.
l'll never forget Your Honor.
Never!
Goodbye, Zhivago.
Goodbye. Thank you.
Pilenko.
Goodbye, brothers!
The doctor is a gentleman.
Right. Written all over him.
He's a good man.
God rot good men.
Yuri!
This is Comrade Yelkin,
our local delegate. He lives here.
How do you do?
Welcome.
Comrade Kaprugina--
lt's not for you to welcome us, Comrade.
Comrade Kaprugina is the chairman
of the Residents' Committee.
-Yes, of course.
-Your discharge papers?
Oh, yes.
l signed them myself, l'm afraid.
Holy Cross?
What?
-Holy Cross Hospital. lt's on--
-The Second Reformed Hospital.
Good. lt needed reforming.
Medicals report
to their place of work at once.
Yes. l believe there's typhus?
You've been listening
to rumormongers, Comrade.
There is no typhus in our city.
Well, that's good news.
l'll report tomorrow.
When you've started work,
you'll get a ration book.
l've always worked.
Whatever is the matter?
You are.
There was living space for 13 families
in this one house.
Yes. This is a better arrangement,
Comrades.
More just.
Well, it is more just, Tonya.
Why did it sound so funny?
ls it good to be home?
Sasha?
Who else?
lt's your daddy, Sasha.
Sasha!
Naughty boy!
No, don't say that.
May l come in?
Watch carefully.
l am about to ignite the last half
of the last cigar in Moscow.
Good meal?
-Very.
-Say something.
That was very good, Tonya.
That was nothing.
She's been saving that salami
for three months.
Have you, darling?
l got it for a clock.
She's a marvel. Coffee, you observe.
Stop it, Daddy. He knows l'm a marvel.
Did you write any poetry?
Quite a lot.
ls it good?
Yes, l think so.
Can l see it?
Well, of course.
What happened to Nurse Antipova?
Your letters were full of her.
Yes, l suppose they were.
That's the girl who shot
friend Komarovsky, isn't it?
Yes, Daddy. You know it is.
She's gone home to her little girl.
-Oh, we shan't see her then?
-No.
What a pity!
Farewell, the pleasures of the flesh.
What l don't understand is
how we're going to stay alive this winter.
You have no right whatever
to call me from work.
As a Soviet deputy, l--
That gives you the power, not the right.
lt's noticed, you know.
Your attitude is noticed.
You should have called the area doctor.
l want this done quietly.
Why, what is it, typhus?
l'll take him away. Get me some transport.
lt isn't typhus.
lt's another disease
we don't have in Moscow: starvation.
That seems to give you satisfaction.
lt would give me satisfaction
to hear you admit it.
-Would it? Why?
-Because it is so.
Your attitude is noticed, you know.
Oh, yes, it's been noticed.
Hello.
The stove's out!
What's the matter with you?
No wonder he's losing weight!
She lets it out as soon as you've gone,
and she lights it before you come home.
We haven't enough fuel.
l told myselflt was beneath my dlgnlty
to arrest a man for pllferlng flrewood.
But nothlng ordered by the Party
ls beneath the dlgnlty of any man...
...and the Party was rlght.
One man desperate for a blt of fuel
ls pathetlc.
Flve mllllon people desperate for fuel
wlll destroy a clty.
That was the flrst tlme
l ever saw my brother.
But, l knew hlm,
and l knew that l would dlsobey the Party.
Perhaps lt was the tle ofblood
between us, but l doubt lt.
We were only half-tled, anyway,
and brothers wlll betray a brother.
lndeed, as a pollceman, l would say
''Get hold of a man's brother...
''...and you're half way home. ''
Nor was lt admlratlon
for a better man than me.
l dld admlre hlm, but l dldn't thlnk
he was a better man.
Besldes, l've executed better men than me
wlth a small plstol.
Now you'll have to live
like the rest of us, Doctor.
Bring that! Bring that back!
Oh, listen to His Excellency!
l want no anarchy!
l want this carried out correctly.
What are you doing?
Re-allocation of living space,
Comrade Doctor.
Fifty square meters
for a family of less than five persons.
Dammit, whose house is this, anyway?
Father, be quiet!
All right, 50 square meters.
What're you doing with my things?
They're being stored.
They're being stolen.
Just a minute!
And where did you get this?
l pulled it out of a fence.
l told them who l was.
The old man was hostlle, the glrl cautlous.
My brother...
...seemed very pleased.
l thlnk the glrl was the only one
who guessed at thelr posltlon.
You're just as l imagined you.
You're my political conscience.
l asked hlm hadn't he one of hls own.
And so he talked about the Revolutlon.
You lay life on a table and you cut out
all the tumors of injustice. Marvelous.
l told hlm lf he felt llke that
he shouldjoln the Party.
Cutting out the tumors of injustice,
that's a deep operation.
Someone must keep life alive
while you do it.
By living.
lsn't that right?
l thought then lt was wrong.
He told me what he thought
about the Party and l trembled for hlm.
He approved of us, but for reasons
whlch were subtle, llke hls verse.
Approval such as hls
could vanlsh overnlght.
l told hlm so.
Of course, l can't approve this evening
something you may do tomorrow.
He was walklng about wlth a noose
round hls neck and dldn't know.
So l told hlm what l had heard
about hls poems.
Not liked?
Not liked by whom?
Why not liked?
So l told hlm that.
Do you think it's ''personal,
petit-bourgeois and self indulgent''?
l lled.
But he belleved me.
And lt struck me through to see
that my oplnlon mattered.
The glrl knew what lt meant,
what lt was golng to mean.
They couldn't survlve
what was comlng ln the clty.
l urged them to leave and llve obscurely
somewhere ln the country...
...where they could keep themselves allve.
We have, used to have,
an estate at Varykino, near Yuriatin.
The people know us there.
He dldn't reslst.
l offered to obtaln permlts,
passes, warrants...
...told them what to take
and what to leave behlnd.
l had the lmpertlnence to ask hlm
for a volume of hls poems.
And so we parted.
l thlnk l even told hlm
that we would meet agaln ln better tlmes.
But perhaps l dldn't.
Fifty persons!
Fifty persons only!
Tonya, here!
Get back!
Fifty persons only!
Fifty persons!
Only 50 persons!
Charming accommodation.
That's very good.
l'm an intellectual.
Shut up, you ''intellectual.''
Shut up, you lickspittle.
Forced labor.
Attention, Comrades.
Your train will leave tomorrow morning.
Health regulations for the journey:
Night soil will be emptied
every morning without fail.
Straw to be replaced at ten day intervals
and the old straw burned.
ln the event of fresh straw
being unavailable, old straw to be turned.
This is disinfectant. Use it.
ln this wagon is a detachment
of Voluntary Labor.
Liar.
You are required by Military Committee
to show them all assistance.
One carriage is occupied by sailors
of the heroic Kronstadt Sailors' Soviet.
So you'll be in good hands.
They're idiots.
Attention, Comrades.
ln approximately 1 1 days' time
you'll pass through the Urals province...
...where White Guard units,
aided by foreign interventionists...
...and other criminal reactionary elements,
have recently been active.
The Military Committee assures you...
...that the criminals have been
completely routed in that area...
...by Red Guard units under the command
of People's Commander Strelnikov.
There's a man.
Clap him.
The line is definitely clear.
Long live the Revolution!
Long live anarchy!
Lickspittle! Bureaucrat!
ls that necessary?
Six volunteers l've signed for,
and six l'll deliver.
l'm a free man, lickspittle.
There's nothing you can do about it.
l'm the only free man on this train.
The rest of you are cattle.
Help me, brothers, for the love of God.
Come on!
Yuri, the child is dead.
lt wasn't my child, dear...
...and his little soul's in Heaven now,
that's certain.
Who did it, Comrade, the Whites?
The Whites?
No, Strelnikov.
Well, then, you must have done something.
lt wasn't us, Comrade.
The commander said
we'd sold horses to the Whites.
lt wasn't us, it was those pigs in Kuniko.
We told him, but he didn't believe us.
l expect you were lying.
-As God's my witness.
-But he isn't.
Commander Strelnikov is a great man.
A commander, Sasha,
and he lives on bread and water.
Does he?
l don't know. They say so.
lt's true.
No one knows where he comes from.
And they never know where he is.
-He's back up the line.
-Yes?
Someone's for it.
Oh, really, not again!
What this time?
Never mind, Father.
Get a good night's sleep.
l know what l'm going to do.
Look!
The Urals.
Look, Sasha, look.
That's where we're going, darling.
Through the mountains and into the forest.
Then it'll be much warmer still.
Will there be wolves in the forest?
Strelnikov!
That's Strelnikov.