I just feel really closed to you
This is a free fansub
by
luckywith007@yahoo.com
You are really closed to me
With this way, we can share everything
Looks.
They're still so in love
How great is that?
So, what do you see it's going?
Well, tonight we're just going back to my place
This is your house?
- Beautiful!
- Thank you
I'd like to come home to a nice place
You are happy?
Happy? Yes, I am it.
Tripp, since you are awake...
Come on, pop
Don't you knock?
Your mom...
She snores like a rhinano
And then music's just started.
Hello.
You should be Melanie.
- Melissa.
- Oh Melissa?
Melissa. OK! Alright
- You're having a goodtime.
- Bye, pop
You live with your parents?
Is that a problem?
Are you kidding me!
- I'm just sleeping.
- Stepping down the stair.
- Unbelievable!
- The shelter is put.
You moved the umbrella upstair?
We gotta get rid of that thing.
You know, it's gonna get to us
And she's out
Another bites the dust.
And he's still here
Failure to launch
Welcome on board.
Papitas fried.
- Good morning, mom.
- Good morning.
- Goodday, pop.
- Good morning, son.
Did you sleep sound last night?
OK, Honey there you go
You are the best, mom!
Are you kidding me?
Do not you forget your afternoon snack.
- Thinks fast!
- Good-bye.
So you dumped Melissa?
Technically, she dumped me.
- What's happened?
- Last night...
We're at a restaurant. She saw a couple holding hands
And then she decided to hold my hand.
SO...she smiled at me
Next thing I know is she give me her look!
- Dude I'm so sorry.
- Did Not it pass anything.
It was its hour to know to my parents.
- ¿The parents? Not.
- Bye-bye Melissa.
- Again.
- ¿What do you mean?
I mean, my... friend
That you fear him al love.
Crap. Not, not, not. Him do not I fear al love.
I love al love.
Looks, I have had many girlfriends. Well?
And at times I am the nail
That removes another nail.
Other times, with luck I am the
that serves to explore other...
Areas of its sexuality. Well?
But always we entertain. Thanks!
I entertain, they
Also. Is good for the two.
And it would say that is good for
The civilization as an all.
- If but people thought thus...
- They Would Sleep either for the nights.
In a double bed with sheets of
Superman that you have since the 6 years.
There is who sleeps in a small one
In the basement of its mother.
It is an orthopedist and I need it.
Al less do not I live of my parents being able
Follar in all the continents.
I am a wandering man.
A plant rodadora.
A search engine truly. And
a truth that have found...
is that the children are the
Greater happiness of the parents.
Therefore not abandonment the house
of my parents, because...
- ¡They would miss Me!
- Amen, brother.
And nevertheless, in North America
They criticize us as we live.
We should celebrate
Our way of life.
- We Are men that still live at home.
- ¡Yes!
We have not to ask excuses
By as we are or who we live.
- ¡Not!
- AND in this table, men...
I see three winners.
And the ones that be there outside and they see
Another thing, that come to discuss.
Because alone with a load of dynamite
They will remove me of the house of my parents.
- ¡That boy already is 35 years old!
- He Is that he it is not fair...
¡35 years!
We were good parents, already
We should have finished.
I do not blame al our by being remained, my house
It is better than any that be paid.
Our son is he overloads.
He flies so much that is not logical...
That have own apartment.
- I know It.
- AND has many pilot... friends
That they leave it to be remained in their houses.
I would say that all is matter of
Being afraid to give them hams.
Itself it cannot be built a
Marries without a... hammer.
¿Someone wants a door knocker of Guava?
I learned to do them in Maui.
They cause forget you the problems.
It takes, affection.
¿And who is my wahini hot?
- ¿Bev? What is that?
- I did it Me in Hawaii.
Is Lono, the God of the fertility.
And Bud was done another. They want to see it?
- ¡Not!
Is that... ¿What has passed them?
- ¡Douggie went of house!
- ¿What?
- ¿You are joking?
- ¡Yes!
- ¿When?
- ¡Two months ago!
Incredible.
¿As many times to the week
They believe that we do it?
I cannot believe it. How did they do it?
Douggie is very good but...
¿How did they achieve that themselves away?
- It Knew a girl.
- ¿A girl?
- Tripp brings an each week.
- We Say that has not known...
To the adequate one.
I do not want another reclinador.
I want somewhat new.
This is new.
A supporter for the glasses.
I do not speak of that. OK.
It buys what want...
but you notice that will have a
Lover in the next 6 months.
If I have that reclinarme...
That be interesting.
- In agreement.
- OK. Somewhat important it passes.
You are choosing seats.
Hello, Dolly. Son. You see it?
- Dad... chooses your seat.
- I want this.
- It Sold.
- Not, is of balls. It do not I want at home.
Dad, you relax you. Itself the
It will carry when abandon you.
- We will Not buy it.
- I will buy It.
I have own money.
To be not that return to
Dancing, you are without a weight.
Excuse.
Is mine.
- ¿You Are going to buy it?
- Not.
¿You want a cup or a blanket?
- Not, I need my 20 minutes.
- ¿Why?
Clarify me the head.
I come here to relax me.
¿You know what relaxes me to my?
I light the channel of prescriptions
Of kitchen. Immediately functions.
Each which uses what functions him.
OK, sight, to the salespersons not them
it imports because I bring him coffee...
and the selection of music is a
soothing mixture of the 70s...
And smooth jazz. Is almost narcotic.
And generally the people leaves me in peace.
Of course.
- Already I see of what you speak.
- ¿Pleasant, truth?
I make fun of my parents,
But this is magnificent.
- I Am Paula.
- I Am Tripp.
Generally me do not I go to bed
With nobody in the first appointment.
This does not it count as the first appointment.
It would be it if you ask me that
We take a cup this night.
- ¿We Take a cup this night?
- Do Not I be able.
- ¿Lunch tomorrow?
- Sure.
Expects. Tomorrow is Saturday.
- At times as Saturdays.
- Not, I will do something with my nephew.
¿And Monday?
- We will see Us here.
- Marvelous.
- ¡Hello!
- Hello.
Paula, good news.
Is Thursday of champagne.
Yes, the second time that
Is Thursday this week.
Three weeks ago of the same thing.
- AND will be permanent.
- ¿How the schedule of summer?
Well. But for the beverage.
- Health.
You silence you, prostitute.
It lament. I did unpleasant sounds?
Are not you, is that damned one
Bird outside of my window.
¿What type of bird
It possessed pious at night?
I believe that sounds pretty.
- You Knew to a type today.
- Thus same was.
- AND is pretty also.
- I also knew one.
¿Really?
Is a radiologist.
- That is better than other.
- It Offered to do me a revision...
Of complete body, free.
- That is not cheap.
- I know It, I am very touched.
¿How pretty?
Pretty.
Tripp is very good type. Is
Intelligent, sweet, nice.
Our encounter was very
Good. I believe that has potential.
- ¿Then ready the launch?
- Basing on the evaluation...
of personality, I believe that its
son this house... will leave
And will live alone for June 15.
¡Hallelujah!
They would be surprised of as many as
Adult children still live at home.
My opinion is that the cause
Main is lack of self-esteem.
- Oprah speaks of that always.
- Oprah does not know neither crap.
When I was a boy, nobody
Had self-esteem, and we grew well.
You are a rock, Al. You do
A better woman of me.
Many youths that would owe
Being capable of being gone, they do not be able.
That it is known like
"Failure of launch".
And that is my role. The youths
they develop their self-esteem to bias...
of a romantic relation,
So I simulate him a.
We have a memorable encounter,
we will know us better...
in some coincidental suppers, he me
will help with my emotional... crisis
and then I know to its
friends, if is that has...
and then abandonment that something teach me,
but what is important is that...
He establishes ties with me.
He is removed of you...
And itself mute away.
¿How you are sure
That will fall in love with you?
I will see me pretty, me entire
of what he likes...
And I pretend that i like also.
Thus is like functions.
- ¿AND the sex?
- Al, never I have sex...
With the clients. Besides, I have
that to maintain to Tripp motivated...
and admit it, after it
men have sex with a...
- ¿We should do something?
- Good, do him the life but difficult.
Already they know, but tasks, but
Responsibilities, those things.
I believe that you should know that Tripp
Has had difficult separations.
I promise them that when this finish...
Tripp will be an adult
Independent and autosuficinte.
¡Do not help it!
- Is going to run.
- ¡Do Not do it, do not do it!
- I have You, I have... you
- Care. I will run.
¡You will not do it, will not do it!
- ¡Crap!
- Is a bad word, Jeffrey.
Is also the bastard, but
Alone it signifies not married parents.
You look at, look at...
Is going to arrive... ¡Al final!
- ¡In its face!
- ¡You Sit down!
Very well, good attitude before the sport.
- Very well.
- Go, me magpie the front.
Very pretty... P of loser.
You will not be able to continue thus.
You will walk to your house.
- Very good uncle.
- Are 6 miles. Will delay two days.
- Hello, small.
- Hello, mom.
- Tripp, we go.
- OK. There is but papitas and sauce?
I went not to the store today.
But can go you.
And you said that need your
Pants of basketball.
- I put Them in the washing machine.
- Thanks mom.
But it was forgot me to light it.
Will have to do it you.
- ¿To Wash?
- AND... your bath needs cleaning.
I left you the things in the walkway.
And when to put an end to the gloves
Of rubber, you veered them al reverse.
Good-bye.
Your mom is sick.
This is very pleasant. Never
I was before in a sailboat.
It would be amused... if never
I step again land sign.
I would like but if
You left of the spring.
But I do not want to remove you al sea in
The first appointment and that fall.
Up to now I am very impressed.
A beautiful place, a simple food.
I assume that this technique
Has functioned before.
Thus is, lady.
- ¿This time Functions?
- ¿You Know what? Well yes.
We are going to walk.
I have not had just had lunch.
Yes, you finished.
In serious I am not of the
Small that do not eat. I want...
- I wanted all that.
- Technically, the sailboat is not mine.
In fact, is not mine at all.
- ¿What?
- I seeing ships.
I would love one thus, but not
Is the adequate moment in my life.
Besides, the owner of this
Ship is just behind you.
¡Hello, Mr. Axelrod!
I thought that was of trip.
Was, but now not.
¿What is this? A holder?
¿You eat in my ship?
Not.
¿When did it redesign the wagon?
- Oh... a buyer.
- Can be. How fast is?
- 73.
- The wood is somewhat dark.
- The wife chose it.
- He Has beautiful lines.
And is very fast.
And yes that is navigation.
I will think it.
- Thanks by its time.
- Yes, lady.
Thanks.
¿And you left that was itself?
One must give him space, Mr. Axelrod.
Now...
I go after her.
¿Excuse, lady?
- ¿Yes that is navigation?
- "A history of Philadelphia".
Very well. Well.
Assuming that to cause to pass
by owner of a yate...
was a brilliant idea
But with defects.
- ¿How do you see the remainder of the day?
- Do Not I know it.
I have so much hunger that cannot think.
- The seagulls were eaten my lunch.
- ¿I carry You to a restaurant?
- ¿You will cause pass for the owner?
- Not.
The restaurants that
They are mine they are in Europe.
Hello, Ace.
Is happy me that have come.
I thought that you were at home.
I fell in an enormous crack.
- I frightened Me.
- ¿You Came out with the lazy girl?
Paula. I did it, we have lunch together.
- ¿There Will Be a second quotes?
- There Will Be a second appointment.
But the relation is
It condemned al failure.
Yes. And why?
- You Live with your parents.
- Is right.
Our life is
it designed to avoid...
Any relation of couple.
We have left a single time. Is a
Good small and I a good boy.
We entertain and I will tell them something.
Nothing... is condemned.
Another accident.
¿What do you do?
Recalls, we are visitors here.
It takes.
- ¿You give Him peanut?
- Yes.
She eats that all the time.
This is what wants. A
Regalito of the city, baby?
Is not a boy, Tripp.
Looks the peaceful thing that is.
A bit of chocolate, baby.
- ¿A bar of protein?
- All they love the chocolate, baby.
- It is saying that not.
- You Look at to the eyes.
It says not, Tripp.
¿Friend?
¿What does? That is a squirrel?
Not, an ardillita listed.
Care with the bike.
Hello. I am Tripp.
You should be Kit.
- Is a sinsonte.
- ¿Who did what do?
- ¿The sinsonte?
- ¿What is?
¿Do not you listen it? That uncomfortable sound.
Already I listen it.
I investigated it. They can imitate
you alarm of cars, telephones...
And to other birds. I called to
Control of Plagues and they told me...
that enjoyment to one of the but
Talentosos singers of the nature.
- ¿Yes?
- I Am going to kill it.
OK, I am ready.
Hello.
- They Look at that.
- AND they look at that.
- Pretty shoes.
- ¿Yes? Thanks.
OK, good, we go.
- ¿You Are ready?
- Yes.
OK, that entertain a lot.
- Thanks.
- Good-bye, Kit, luck with the...
- A bribe of ardillita.
- Of course.
- AND was not an ardillita normal.
- You Are right.
Was large, like a wildcat
Gigantic, an ardillita bear.
I am lucky to be here.
- ¿What says the doctor?
- Do Not I need to consult it.
I have a special cream at home.
- ¿Cream for ardillitas?
- Yes.
- ¡What luck!
- I know It.
- ¿You like the Japanese food?
- It fascinates Me.
And also I will ask a dessert
enormous, I will drink too much...
And I will speak of my old bride and groom.
- ¿That intimidates you?
- For nothing.
- Health, Paula.
- Health.
Well. T-r-i. Double
P. To eat squid.
- ¿You Need aid?
- I have It, I have it.
Looks, sight...
- I Admire your confidence.
- Thanks, I I am very...
Ambi... dexterous.
¡Crap! I feel it.
Excuse. The squid was greasy.
- I feel It.
- Is Not easy.
I have not said anything.
You speak me of you. Why dedicate you?
I... am a teacher of boys
With special needs.
¿How you have the hand? Itself you
It passed the effect of the medicine?
Good... again at home.
Again at home.
- I passed It very well.
- I also.
- Well.
- I entertained.
¡You silence you, crazy bird!
- Hello, Kit.
- ¿What? Hello.
- ¿They can see me?
- Yes.
Barbaric.
- ¿What?
- Supper and a spectacle.
Good evening.
Good evening to you.
¿In what type of ship is seen if same?
It do not I know, but yes I know that
I should leave to open sea.
Should ask some questions.
¿He likes the velocity?
¿He likes to listen the sound of the motor?
¿Wants to go of the point TO
Al point B quickly?
If that he likes, needs a
Ship with a powerful motor.
OK, OK, that is. Being able. That I am I.
Is the best. But perhaps
Want to take it to him slowly.
Listening the wind and the waves.
That the dawn and the
Sunset be its guides.
Knowing that al can turn around
World with half a tank of gasoline.
Now...
if that seems him well...
Perhaps it need a sailboat.
This is not a hobby.
This... is a way of life.
That is passion. What has passed you?
- ¿TO my?
- I want to feel the wind.
I do not want to feel... I
I want to cause the wind. OK?
- Sight...
- ¿To Be windy? Itself does not be windy...
- It anchored in the spring.
- I want to be the powerful type. Being able.
- I want to feel the propela underneath...
- The ones that drink coffee with a lot of cream...
Are not powerful types.
Expects, wait, slowly, Paula.
Was my better friend.
Since was a cachorrito...
Alone a pelotita of hairs,
was too small...
Be risen to my bed.
And now...
¿Has a napkin?
The life saved me. You know?
And now I cannot do anything by him.
Is happy me so much that be here.
Of course.
¿I can remain to
Alone with him a minute?
- Thanks.
- I Will Be outside.
Thanks, Gretchen.
When want.
The phase of the crisis
Emotional is criticism.
I cry, he cries. He unites us totally.
¿How much while will sleep?
Half an hour. It came to be fixed a tooth.
- ¿Which is its real name?
- Do Not I know it.
I alone them clean the
Teeth and them short the balls.
- That is so sad...
- Was a precious dog.
- She was destroyed.
- This is what needs.
Good option.
There is.
- Hello, Paula.
- Hello.
These are my friends
Demo and Ace. She is Paula.
It is a pleasure to know them.
Lament a lot your loss...
- Thanks.
- Pretty. How you are?
Hello.
The majority of the men
they to have sent flowers...
Chocolates, perhaps. But...
I should I say that this did not expect it me.
Any it can send you flowers, Paula.
Now I am going to count you the major secret.
Action of fingers is called.
Fast fingers in the trigger.
Is a double trigger.
But bombs of painting in less
Time signifies victory.
We are going to see.
When leave and the bombs of painting
fly to you to 200 miles per hour...
I guarantee you that you will not think about
The deceased and marvelous Mr. Fred.
Go. Really they fly so fast?
¡I am very sorry!
- ¡Good shot!
- Thanks.
He is well.
We are going to shoot him the strangers.
The first one that give to the
Small earns a beer.
That type laughed at my. Who they are?
- The Babies of the Devil are called.
- Are Not evils.
Will be an excellent test
Of our dexterity.
- ¿They are champions?
- We will Not gain.
¡I am outside!
¡You are mine, rubiecita!
¿I remained was?
Did not it know that they sold beer here.
It do not they sell.
¿You can give me a?
Not.
¿It is hot, truth?
It was a pleasure to speak with you.
¿Paula?
¡I feel it!
¿Account if is an accident?
I want that come to my.
¡Not thanks, I will remain
Here to the end!
¡Now!
I am outside.
- ¡I Am outside!
- ¡Did Not you die in vain!
¿Where is, Paula?
The deditos, the deditos...
¿Chime?
You leave, salt, be where be.
While but quickly
You lose, but quickly will go.
¡Go!
¿And now who laughs?
¿Of where that left?
- ¡Hello, Kit!
- ¿It was amused, truth?
¿You know what? I am going to powder me the nose.
Seems that no longer you are sad
By the death of your dog.
If had one and there was itself
They died, this would help a lot.
Yes that has control of the space.
- ¡AND a marvelous hair!
- Thanks.
- You have to remain you with this.
- Is marvelous, a lot, Tripp.
¿Already we can go us?
Knowing the friends is very
Important. The men need...
knowing that not alone we they like
They, if not also their friends.
Well. The high one is
Pretty. Why it is dedicated?
It designs software. Works in its
Basement, but does a lot of money.
Not, that is the small one. The high one
Has just said good-bye of a store.
- ¿How to choose?
- This goes very well.
I am happy. Then already we can go us.
Not until me the sign. If not
It gives it me, the friends do not want me.
I believe that they are giving it you.
Oh, yes.
Tripp goes passing each
Step perfectly.
I believe that tomorrow it
I will leave that something teach me.
There are two forms to rotate a sailboat.
They veered toward the wind or against him.
That is something that itself is not owed
doing with a novice on board...
- So I will try it.
- Wait, wait.
- ¿Why is evil?
- Is Not evil, is amused.
We go, ponte there.
¡We go, small!
¡By God!
The threat to be beheaded
It does it but interesting.
We do this knot, thus...
OK. Port side and starboard and all that.
Too many words. Alone
I want tostarme al sun.
- It Takes the rudder.
- ¿What?
¿Really?
Him it is called to be al command.
¡Wait, wait! What will you do you?
- I Will Descend to cover.
- ¿What do there is in cover?
Beer, wine, papitas, ron. I do not know.
- Is Not my ship.
- Do Not I know what I do. In serious.
- You are sailing.
- ¿AND if I collide with something?
I believe that you will be well.
I am sailing.
¡Is precious!
I thought that to leave in
sailboat was good idea...
But... ¡my God! Is marvelous!
You should buy it. Me
I imagine that is expensive. And what?
I like, but not...
I do not want one new.
What I would love...
Is one old of wood.
Is but difficult the maintenance.
But when you have one...
Is like to be part of something.
As if were connected.
To the original people that
they sailed to the unknown thing...
and things said as:
"¡Mierda, what a large wave!"
Do it. You buy it to you.
¿To whom imports him
While can sail?
I am working in that.
But one must be ready.
Is a very large commitment.
And if you are not ready, alone are...
an old solitary one with a
Very expensive ship by paying.
¿Who says that you have to be alone?
- ¡Hello!
Did not it know that you were at home.
All in the work
they went to drink, but...
that place where they go not me
Likes. Neither they neither.
OK, we will remain at home and
we will see some of those movies...
To drink that you like.
Yes.
I smell something.
¿You smell something?
Tripp and I... we have lunch crab.
Not, is not that.
I smell diversion.
- ¿What?
- You Are a dirty amusing one.
That is absurd. Tripp
Is a fascinating case.
- Does Not it fit in the usual profile.
- ¿Losing immature?
Not even I understand
Why lives at home.
Has a good work,
Normal social habits.
Is... attraction.
Very sweet.
Is pleasant that come out with
Someone so candy every day.
Was a day of work
Successful. That is all.
- Well.
- AND al final of the day...
I looked at to the eyes and I saw it.
I have it hitched. That
Already is being moved from house.
It was finished. I have to leave it.
- ¿You Will Leave Paula?
- ¿What happened?
Same old the same thing. All
goes well and with facility...
We pass it and suddenly, of the nothing.
It is put serious. I hate to tell it, small.
- But it is hour to carry it home.
- You do It again.
- ¿What?
- That thing.
The woman itself about and you
You put an end to the relation.
Small, is simple.
The diversion was finished.
Look at that.
¡Hello, small!
They see here, they see here.
¿What tells me, Demo?
- ¿Where you were?
- ¿Where was?
- I will ask You something, Demo.
- ¿Yes?
¿How surfeamos without waves?
- ¿We Go after him?
- Now is a passenger.
¿Passing? It it was carried
To an underwater trip.
¡You carry me to my!
Crap, that son of dog bit me.
¡Was, was!
- ¿A dolphin bit You?
- Yes. And is not any dolphin.
Was a gigantic white dolphin.
I am lucky of still be alive.
¿What?
Nothing.
- Go. This is your house?
- Yes.
- Is precious.
- Thanks.
I like to arrive at house and that be beautiful.
- Ahead.
- Thanks.
- Is very pretty.
- Thanks. You want to drink something?
- Yes, clear.
- ¿Beer, wine?
- Came, fantastic.
- A cup of wine.
Thanks.
Hello mom, dad. I thought that they would leave?
¿To leave? Not, we premiere
The new chairs.
Hello.
Tripp. Who is your amiguita?
Mom, dad, she is Paula.
Paula, my mom, my dad.
¡Go!
Hello. How is?
Hello.
It is a great pleasure to know them to both.
Hello, Paula.
¡You live with your parents!
¿Is a problem?
Not.
For me not.
¿You would remain to have dinner?
I would love, thanks.
¿Why?
It smells well and I have a lot of hunger. You not?
I am hungry, but my
Mom, this... she cooks.
As it does almost every night.
Here, where I live.
With them.
The same house in which I grew.
That is pretty.
I am going to cut the lawn.
- Already we are going to eat.
- I Will Cut that of the neighbors.
¿Really there is not problems? Not
I want to bother the family.
There is not problem. I will put another cover.
Thanks.
I will help dad.
¿There is... something that be able
Doing to help?
It lament, did not have
Idea that would bring me.
But you are doing it very well.
Good, you not. I do not know what to tell you, affection.
Your so correct... program
You are going to have that to deviate you.
- It Is going to leave you.
- ¿What?
The only reason why brings
girls is when is ready...
Leave them.
¿Really?
Good...
That will not happen.
Paula... affection...
I thank you that you
You have remained to have dinner.
- Should have been very uncomfortable.
- For nothing.
¿For nothing?
¿It does not matter to you that
My parents be down?
They sleep in their chairs.
- Do Not look at.
- Payment by her. I look at if I want.
Alone I say that... they would be able oírnos.
¿Why? You are of the ones that they shout?
¿Paula?
¡They are awake!
They raise themselves early. Listen,
News. All is well.
The things are well. Tripp is well.
In fact is fantastic,
I do not have that to tell them to him.
They are their parents. Alone intent to say...
That they should be very proud of him.
Good... they have a precious house.
Young lady, pardon. Not
It can eat in the store.
I need to buy a weapon.
¿How much is this grandota?
Is a shotgun caliber
Twelve. Is very powerful.
For a woman of its size,
I would recommend something but...
Compact.
Alone I aim, predicament the trigger. Bum!
- Yes. Why goes him to shoot?
- ¿1200 dollars?
¿How much they are worth the bullets?
Cartridges. The shotguns use cartridges.
As be.
- 15 dollars the box of 25 cartridges.
- OK.
I do not need all the box,
Alone I need... one.
¿Something it knows?
At times I also look sad.
There are many pressures in the life.
¿I can give him the telephone of
Who could help... it?
- Not, not.
- A helpline.
Listens, ray of sun. I not...
I am suicidal. I have a
Problem with a sinsonte.
¡OK!
- It can Not kill a sinsonte.
- ¿Why not?
In the first place, by the book
"To kill a sinsonte".
- You Give me a copy.
- Is Not a manual.
Is an American novel
Classical. It do not you know?
- I Know many things. You give me the weapon!
- ¡Not!
- ¡Yes!
- I will Not be sold it.
The sinsontes are protected
By migratory federal laws.
- To Kill one s a crime.
- Look at, this is an insanity.
I have also the right. Such
Time does not know the 6ta amendment.
¿Right to a fast public judgment?
You... are in my list.
¡I bought some marvelous
Shoes to sail!
Hello.
¿What is happening?
Nothing. I bought shoes for the
Next time that sail with Tripp.
And not alone they are pretty.
Tripp says that they are practical.
They have some cositas in the
fund and Tripp says that...
Expects, wait, slowly. You look at.
- ¿What happened last night?
- I Tried to finish with her.
- ¿AND you failed?
Yes.
The sex was fantastic.
¿You had sex with him?
Is not much.
¿And that rule of never
Having sex with the clients?
Oh, yes. Never I have
Sex with my clients.
They are my rules. The change if
Is necessary. I know what I do.
- Your parents were not at home.
- Not, they were down.
- ¿AND you up?
- Yes.
Looks, I continue in control. He was thing of
Once, situation of emergency.
Is very complicated, now not
I have time to explain you...
As the business functions.
Do not you have that
Explain it to me, I am not an idiot.
I have a contract.
I have fiduciary responsibilities.
¿And since the point of view
Fiduciary, you had orgasms?
¿Habábamos with you? Not. Clean that.
¿We can speak of this in another part?
It does not it matter, they can be remained if they want.
- ¿AND now what will you do?
- Do Not I know it.
I am in small, unexplored territory.
My mom believes that he is his
Dog, but I I do him all.
- Does Not comb to a setter Irish.
- ¿You Have a setter Irish?
¡I have a yellow farm laborer!
Is somewhat old, but
We should meet them.
I have so much luck. A lot of luck.
You look at. And you look at to my.
We go, you look at. You are
Intelligent, attractive.
You like the original trilogy
of The Star Wars...
because it is about counting the
history and the myth before...
the special effects it
They ruined all. We go!
¿What woman did not want to be with you?
- Therefore are many.
- They are lost it.
You show me a man that he likes
"The Empire Counterattacks", and is...
a man that him not
It fears to the imagination.
¡As when Luke arrives at the cave,
And it asks to Yoda what there is!
And Yoda says... him
Alone what you carry with you.
But he enters of all forms,
Because him does not he fear to his mind.
To walk the road
Of the Jedi, for that.
¡That are you! You are Luke!
- I have to do pipi.
- ¿Do Not you have just gone?
Immediately return. You do not go. OK?
- I will Not go anywhere.
- Fantastic.
But in serious, you do not be going to go.
¡Hello, Paula!
¡My God! Crap!
You frightened me terribly.
¿What do you do? Do not you come around here often.
Alone... already you know...
Having lunch with a friend.
¿Always you caress them the hands?
Not, I touched them. Alone I touched them.
My friends never touch me the hands.
You put me in a very difficult position.
OK. What do you want?
Not.
Alone they will drink coffee. Not
You have to marry him.
In the first place, is the
Fool of the computers.
Is sufficiently evil to come out with
A loser that lives with its mother.
And on top you told me
That was a handsome vague one.
Not, do not I believe to have done that.
Did not have option. Itself it
was going to tell Tripp...
And you are my unique one puts on file of negotiation.
- You should take it as a polite one.
- Is a gnome.
Is not a gnome, is... is...
Is cariñosito and... rare.
By love of God.
¡Already I go!
I expect that you like the fish.
¿And how Paula does
That? Seems to be difficult.
¿Does not it confuse that life with its real life?
¿What causes thinks you
That has a real life?
Is a somewhat strange work.
¿How one enters that field?
It does a pair of years itself
fell in love with a type...
that did not want to leave of
Living with its parents. I do not know.
I suppose that as did not be able
fix it him, fixes...
to the other losers
That there is there outside.
- Do Not offend you.
- I will Not do it.
- If you want to go you, I understand it.
- It Forgives that the door closed you.
I not am not... sleeping well.
¿Really?
I neither. I have a lot
on top, and my head...
Not, not.
Not, I want to sleep. But not
I am able because there is a bird...
next to my window and pious
All the night. And pious, and pious...
And I bother me and not achievement that be silenced.
I have a shotgun
Of air compressed.
¡Thus it is done!
Yes.
¿You received my message?
Not. ¿you Know what? I have
The dull telephone.
I spent the night with a friend.
My teacher, the Miss.
Kent, has a friend.
- That is pretty.
- Are lesbians.
You do not do the one that it does not matter to you.
You are jealous because you like.
You are the one that the neckline looks him.
Lies.
I do not listen anything.
Will come.
He always comes.
¿As many times you charged it?
Two times.
For kill it not, alone to do him
Damage and that go far away.
Yes.
¿Kit is the abbreviation of Catherine?
Yes. The abbreviation of
Toolbox.
- Is Not an abbreviation.
- ¿You Play cards or something?
To the 10 years I had a
Testicle that did not descend.
¡Wait!
There you are.
Until tomorrow, little bird.
I gave him.
¿You charged it but of two times, truth?
¡By God! Why
You left me to do that?
- ¿Is well?
- Do Not I know it.
- ¿Where did we give him?
- ¡Do Not I know it!
- ¿Is dead?
- I, I...
¡Not!
Looks, sight... the pellet.
Then alone we gave him a blow.
¿You know to resurrect the heart?
- Yes, but...
- Do it.
- Is a bird.
- ¡Do it!
Revising vital signs.
¿Where is the pulse?
- To Revise respiratory ways.
- ¡Do Not do him damage!
¡Do not I do him damage, do not I know what I do!
OK, suavecito. Is tiny.
My God, does not function. Dies!
¡Do something! We lose al patient!
¡Not if I am on guard!
One, two, three...
¡You move away of the light, amiguito!
I am hungry.
You ate frituritas, two dogs
Hot and a market of peanut.
- Did Not I take ice cream.
- My Error.
Well. I can eat a
Bar of dry fruits?
That is good, learns to negotiate.
- We Go.
- ¡You Expect me!
We ask if Paula needs something.
Perhaps a finger of
Telephone Royal number one.
Do not you return without one.
Tripp and Jeffie they are seen very pretty together.
Yes. Listens, when have a
minute, I want to speak with you...
on the matter that to leave
With my better friend by money.
- ¿What?
- Today should be the day in which him...
you show al type your intense one
Passion by something that you does not interest.
- Sight, I do not know what you listened...
- Ace counted it me all.
You do not worry, I have not betrayed you.
The truth is that support
Your final objective.
But if truly you want
help it, and I believe that you want...
you have to know the facts
Concrete. Beginning for the fact...
that Jeffrey is not
The nephew of Tripp.
¿You have heard to speak of Amy?
Amy was its first love, and died
Six years ago. You did not tell it?
¡My God!
I am the worst person of the world.
Hello. You arrived at house.
- I am happy.
- I have to leave Tripp.
I will cancel my contract
And... I cannot do it.
- ¿What happened here?
- Nothing, I tripped.
It continues counting your history.
Tripp was compromised to be married.
- OK.
- AND Jeffrey, its nephew...
Is not its nephew. Not
They are a family at all.
Jeffrey is a son of the woman
that he was going to marry with Tripp...
And died.
- That is very sad.
- I know It.
¿To whom imports him?
- ¿Excuse?
- Never you spoke thus of a client.
- Do Not I know which is the problem with this.
- Because...
He passed through a real tragedy.
Tripp is not the client
Adequate. Is an ethical problem.
¿Who is that?
¿What?
In... is Phillip.
¿Who is Phillip?
- Phillip is...
- I...
¿I said that you could leave?
Good, good, good.
- Is pleasant.
- That is pleasant.
It looks, I do not see the
Complication. You like Tripp.
Dile that you like.
I should I tell you something. Him
I counted to Paula it of Amy.
¿What? Why?
You never would do it.
Neither you mention its name.
Amy is its former-promised.
Died six years ago.
- To Lose a love is the major pain.
- Thus is.
If you cry is well. We veered.
I am well, small.
Did not you have the right. That is... Is my life.
You are right. And normally
I believe that all they have the right...
To walk its own road.
But you are not in yours.
¿OK? You are seated close
Of the road, in a rock.
It is the unique thing that could do,
They given the circumstances.
¿Circumstances?
That it is the other thing that I should I say you.
I feel badly, because I told him
To Paula that would not say anything.
The deceit is a poison, not
I can have it in my body.
Damned be, al grain. We go.
Your parents hired to Paula
So that go of house.
That is crap. Of what do you speak?
- They paid Him for being your girlfriend.
- ¿TO Paula?
Yes. Is a professional. Is its work.
- ¿You are telling Me that is not real?
- Not.
¡Not, is real! Very real.
OK, you are uncomfortable. Looks but
there of the sense of treason...
¡You focus you in the future! OK?
I believe that you are able
Resolving this. In serious.
I believe that the two have an opportunity.
- ¿You are leaving It to cook?
- Yes.
- Strange. You know what?
- It Smells well.
I know it.
¿They can open?
Hello, did not it know... not...
It knew that they would be here.
We neither. Ahead.
- Thanks.
- Tripp is in the kitchen.
Well.
Hello, my girl. They see here.
- ¿What happens?
- A small... family supper.
All the people to
the ones that but I want...
you join in the same one
Room. Very good.
Listens. We can speak?
Of course, we will speak a lot
In the supper. Right now...
I am cooking.
¡Mom, dad! They want but came?
- Suffices, suffices. -
A little but for T-I.
- Tripp, I do not know that to say.
- Do Not speak thus, mom.
I did this beautiful supper today
Give them the thanks.
To the people that
I want but. All you.
Is a blessing. Mom.
Dad.
Affection.
That is well, son.
Ahead.
I am too much touched.
I have to announce something.
Paula...
the last weeks...
that I have passed with you, they have been...
Incredible.
Surprising.
Happy.
And surprising.
I mean that thanks to you...
there I am experienced emotions
That neither knew that had.
So they say that I am crazy...
But I believe that we should live together.
¡That is my boy!
¿You want water, affection?
- Thanks.
- Is marvelous.
I am very proud of you, son.
Well. And the thing is, mom and dad, that
It lived there up since the 3 years.
And has been marvelous.
You two are the better
Parents that a son could want.
Alone I expect to be able to give him my children...
Our children.
The half of the love and the
respect, comprehension and support...
That you two have given me to my.
What I mean is
that is hour that Tripp...
Open the wings.
This is very unexpected.
This is the plan. We fall the room
of the east, we expand the bath...
and we convert all the second
Flat in a suite main.
So that there be space for
You two, and for us two.
Under the same ceiling. What seems them?
I do not understand.
- ¿You Want that Paula come to live here?
- ¡Yes!
Is the perfect solution. Mom,
Dad. to falls them you well.
Paula, to you they fall you well.
We will be all here, under a
Alone ceiling, a great happy family.
- I Am very touched with this.
- Wait, wait a second.
- Breathes deep...
- Tripp, I believe that we should speak...
Because the idea is very large and...
I have thought it a lot. Will function.
And the best part is...
Mom, dad.
That they will not have to pay him but
To Paula so that be my girlfriend.
¿I said somewhat bad? We go.
All they have what want.
Paula, no longer you have
That to pretend that you flavor.
And mom and dad. They wanted that was me.
I go.
¡Tripp, wait!
¡Tripp!
I do not want to listen you.
Please. Do not you understand.
You are right. Expects.
cNo I know as much as you charge for day, but...
this is everything that
I carry on top. 300 dollars.
- ¡We Go, Tripp!
- ¿Suffices for this night?
Above all because we did not have sex.
- Please, you leave me to explain you.
- Salt of my damned car.
Good, your parents paid him money.
My grandfathers pay to my
Kangaroo and i like equal.
I cheer me by you. We speak of another thing.
Well. The 32 is pleasant.
But I believe that I see me
To my same one in a 37.
- ¿What your you believe?
- Do Not buy a ship, friend.
They I love the ships.
Not, not the ships they charm you.
You like the idea of the ship.
The reality is that they spend
your time, your wallet...
And your emotions.
And al final, the heart will break you.
Because it does not matter as much as the
You want, she does not want you.
You look at, is a boat. Is of wood.
You do not buy a ship.
¿You want to feel pain?
You close you the door of the car in the hand.
That is the type of things that
They say: "Alive with my mother".
- ¿What?
- In serious.
I tell it you as the friend.
If you say those foolishness in the park
Of play, not hard nor 10 minutes.
Thank you so much for to give me
Some minutes of your time.
- ¿Why you do not sit down?
- Not, not.
Thanks, not. Alone I want to give them this.
- ¿What is?
- Your money.
I am returned them. I know that
this will not fix anything...
And I know that nothing will be able. But...
They given the circumstances not
Sits down me well to remain me with him.
In serious, please, take it.
- ¿What?
- This never it passed me.
I want that they know it.
Seemed a simple case.
I suppose that I trusted me too much.
It do not I know, he... Not
it answers my calls...
I continue thinking about that all
the time, I do not know where...
You are lover of our son.
We go, we will scale some rocks. Rises.
Not.
You carry two weeks of mourning. We go.
¡Tripp, we go, is open!
It wants that among. It enters al car!
¿Is not marvelous this, small?
¿How goes you, Tripp? You feel it?
- This rock is pleasant.
- Is happy Me that we have come.
- Yes.
- We Go well. It is amused.
¿They want some zanahorias?
Tripp, you should call
To Paula. It wants to see you.
Already suffices, Demo.
¡The cord, Ace!
Continues with your ballet.
She also feels very badly.
Is unhappy, Tripp.
Leave it to pass, small.
My error.
I knew a specialist that
It sent me its patients.
Alone they needed a push.
Looks, Paula, this has to stop.
Do not you sleep and the unique thing that you
I have seen to eat in three days...
Is a market of mints.
You do not worry about my. Me
I will go in a pair of weeks.
¿What? Where do you go?
Return to Red.
- ¿What will you do in Red?
- Not Yet I know it.
That is stupid. What will you do
In the meantime, to live with your parents?
That... is very badly.
Me do not judge. OK?
You are not the but indicated. Very funny.
¿You know what? I am the one that
Has a real relation.
You lie to gain you the
Life. Believe you very intelligent...
But do not you know anything. You believed
That never they would discover you?
You could be happy, but
You spoiled it.
Now you act as its was
It blames of all the others.
But you are alone you. And you believe
That Red is the solution?
Kit, alone because al end you convinced
to someone to be gone to bed with you...
but immediately...
You not an expert in relations does.
Tripp...
- Returns, friend.
- Tripp...
Hello, friend.
Hello, small.
A chokoala bit you. That
Never it passes. Is a reptile of peace.
I have a theory. Is not the
First time that this passes you.
I believe that is because your life is
Incompatible with the natural world.
Therefore the nature rejects you.
You are crazy. They give me water?
Slowly.
I have travelled the entire world.
That I know, you are the unique one...
human that has been bitten for
a dolphin, an ardillita and a...
vegetarian lizard
During the same year.
And you are badly friend. Me not
you have asked never...
By my relation with Kit.
Friend... ¿you Have just left me
Falling of 40 feet of height?
If we speak of friends, me
you betraied and used the blackmail...
To obtain a girlfriend.
Is right.
- Lament to have left to fall.
- It does not matter.
It is certain that utilized you,
But not by wickedness.
You look at. As many
Opportunities is going to have?
It saw an opportunity to love, and the
It took. It is what we want for you.
¿They give me counsel my two friends
Losing that live with their parents?
- I Am an owner of my house.
- ¿What?
I was bought from it mom does
Years. She has where to live...
and then me do not they nail with
The tax of inheritance.
- Intelligent.
- AND Demo chose a wandering life.
- Technically still lives there...
- Yes.
But he is able, because in
His heart... is a to wander.
I believe that we try to say that
we two are happy...
And completely functional.
And you, Tripp...
It you are not.
¡Mom!
¡Dad!
¿Dad?
Hello, Tripp. What do you do here?
I came to seek my things. What do you do?
- Feeding the fish.
- Already I see.
You are naked. In my room.
Is my naked room to be.
Is my house. And I can do...
What one want to do in its house.
- I Used clothes 40 years.
- Now we will have 40 but of...
- ¡Nothing of clothes!
- Nothing of clothes.
Is well. I will leave you
Feeding the fish.
Thanks by coming for here.
Dad, in serious. Was
So evil to have me here?
You be not an idiot, son.
- Your mother and I we want you.
They - ¿Why did not say something?
Alone they had that... to tell it to me.
You needed time later
Of the death of Amy, Tripp.
¿Who knows as much as
Time is the correct one?
¿Two years, six years?
Then I found me with Bev and
Ours, they used to Paula.
And its son is very happy now.
I believe that lives in Seatlle.
Married a girl India.
In short...
Seemed but easy.
But easy.
Is well.
It hears...
i like what you have
Fact with this place.
- I like. I want you, son.
- AND I to you.
¡The hand swims but!
It continues frightening to the fish.
It returns when want, son.
- Mom.
- Tripp.
¿You have seen what there is there up?
Dad is naked in its naked room.
I know it, always wanted one.
It tried to do it in the dining room...
but I convinced it that the
First flat is problematic.
- ¿You Are well?
- Yes. I came to seek something of clothes.
I feel it.
It was a very ugly thing what we did.
When we knew to Paula...
when we hire... it
I did not want that were you.
During years feared the
Day in which you were yourself.
Always I thought that you
It would throw a lot of less.
Then I realized that
Alone was a part of the all.
Did not it want that were you because...
Being alone with your father frightens me a lot.
- ¿What?
- I Am landfall, Tripp.
Is not alone by the naked room.
Since your father withdrew...
I am usual to have you here.
As a filter when your
Father is in a bad mood.
And now we have that
Learning to know us again.
And...
¿And if him not flavor?
¿Still you love it?
Against every forecast.
All will turn out well.
¡You are going to miss me!
Is certain.
I called them to all, because
Obviously we have a situation.
And all we feel heads,
But the fault is not the matter.
We have to find a solution.
Two people that love pass it badly.
We are going to put us the caps to think.
- This shirt weighs as 100 pounds.
- ¡Albert!
¿What does this seem them?
We send flowers to
Paula in name of Tripp.
And flowers to Tripp in name of Paula.
- ¿AND then what?
- Then...
- They will love themselves.
- ¡Jesus!
By the flowers.
Thanks, Phillip. Now...
We go all to seek a
Plan that do not be idiot.
Hello.
Listens.
I revised all the CD. But if...
they remain some of mine
or I carry me some yours...
We declare it a tie. OK?
OK. Sure.
OK.
- The hatred.
- I know It, I also.
Therefore... alone...
We finish with this immediately.
OK, sight.
I know that I am a girl and I should be
good with the emotional... crap
but it I am not, so
I will tell it. Lament that...
I indicated you that you
you fell in love with a client...
and that that you to go crazy and
You to return a total dog.
Go.
It should have been very difficult to say that.
I thought that would be it, but
Facility came out with me.
Therefore thanks.
And... I it lament
by to have indicated...
that you have not had a relation
in 5 years because I am...
the only person that tolerates your
Strange and violent changes of spirit.
Thanks.
- Good-bye.
- I will miss You.
And I to you.
- ¿I can carry You al airport?
- Sure.
Along the way we pass for house
of Phillip to return you...
The shelter that you lost.
¡Go, this is fantastic!
Is marvelous.
We wait for that its mother
Dwells to live up.
- Beautiful feelings.
- Runs, runs, runs.
Hello, small.
Looks In The Cabinet.
¿Why?
¡They expect! What do they do?
I feel it.
I tried to do it quickly
So that not to hurt.
¿It worries you to do me damage?
- A refreshing change.
- There will Not be evils consequences.
Of all forms already they are hated.
- ¿How will they be?
- We Revise.
OK. Looks this.
¿This is going to be thus? Because...
Your note says: "Hello,
We need to speak".
Yes, I wrote it after
Tie me to the chair and to cover me the mouth.
- ¿Then do not you want to speak?
- ¿With you?
Step.
- Do Not I see him the face. There is another angle?
- Of course.
Looks this. I installed 27 cameras
That they cover each inch of the place.
- ¿They Were you lit last night?
- Yes. Not!
I helped with the knots. That of
The feet head of anchor is called.
- I was able safarme.
- Do Not you know safarte about an apron.
This is ridiculous, by say not immature.
We can be without saying nothing.
Is well. I will begin.
I believe that carry you as an idiot.
I believe that with those
Pants see you fat.
Very well. Sexy.
- Do Not I understand it.
- I Said that the idea was stupid.
Hello.
¡We should do that business about the flowers!
¡Wait, wait!
They are going to say something.
Tripp, I ask pardon.
My work was manipulator and deceitful.
But the second that knew it about
Amy, was going to finish with all.
But I did not be able, because informed you before.
I feel it.
I accept the excuses.
Thanks.
We go. Do not you mean anything?
- I Have a question.
- Of course, what be.
¿How many but there was, before my?
I ask because such
time we can meet us...
and to do a group of therapy of
Support. And if already the group... exists
I want to know if is a small group,
as a team of basketball...
Or one large... as the Chinese.
- Someone is in a bad mood.
- Your mother still did... you
Tortillas to have breakfast.
And I did not enter your life because
I wanted. Your parents called me.
Your life was in a boss
It extended to postpone things.
- I Hope I could speak thus.
- It Is easy when they are hitched.
Not, I have spoken with
Men hitched before.
¿You want to speak of my life? And yours?
Perhaps it should not to judge. It owes
there to be a reason why...
you became a chupadora of
Souls, murderer of dogs and harpy.
I do not understand. Do what has
That to see the dog in that?
- Good question.
- ¿You rise Him the volume?
They are the of the PC, so...
To be not that...
I was well before
Appearing. Entertained me.
And I ruined it all.
¿Therefore you wanted to leave me?
Good, was not thus.
You presented me your parents
So that I left you.
- It Called its attention.
- ¡Thus is!
¡You cause it, she causes you!
¿What do you be going to do, bebito, will cry?
I feel it.
- ¿Why did you do it?
- Because you looked at me with The Look.
The Look not...
¿Why has it to speak of The Look?
- ¿What look?
- The look that says...
You like me.
- That should be horrible.
- ¿I use The Look?
Yes. Not.
Never I wanted to do you damage.
I believe you.
¿But what I know about you? All the
time that were together...
Was a lie.
I found a woman to which to want...
And resulted to be a total fraud.
- ¿You Have real feelings?
- Of course that yes.
- ¿Why?
- ¡By you!
And créeme, I did not want that,
Because had a good life before.
Was not good but... was well.
Was empty, but al less not me
Realized the unhappy thing that was.
But now... by your fault...
I am extremely slope of
It complete unhappy that I am.
Thanks therefore.
Normally i do not like
the TV reality, but...
This is very exciting.
¿You are crying?
We go, Tripp.
¡Moves!
Ours small moves. Moves!
- Is rolling.
- ¡Advances!
- By God... ¡advances to the end!
It do not do, son. That
She advance also.
¿And now what do we do?
Good, is very simple.
You have to decide...
if you want to pass you the remainder
of your life entertaining you...
Or you want to pass it with me.
You silence you, not all it
That you say is perfect.
We can entertain us a little bit one. Not?
¡Hallelujah!
The spectacle was finished.
Do not you need to see that.
It come on outside to play
Soccer. I will teach you a pair.
¿You need a hand?
Tranquil, all is low control.
- ¿Why is the champagne?
- Is Thursday.
Thanks.
Is a pleasure.
Health.
Well, captain.
¿Where do we go?
There there is a lighthouse. We can go there?
Of course. Is your work.
¡Tripp, care! God,
I told it too late!
¡I feel it!
- ¿Tripp?
- ¿You should Not notify me?
¡I am very sorry! You are well?
Yes, alone the air removed me. Such
Time myself I am paralyzed a lung.
Some bruises, but nothing. And you?
I will seek you a device
Of flotation. OK?
Yes.
- You Remain you there.
- Very good idea.
Crap.
¡Oh, crap!
Me do not bite, do not bite me.
¡My God!
Is incredible.
¿What do you tell me, huge?
¿Still you need it?
Not, I am well.
I am very well.