Our India is the best..
of all the world by far
..of all the world by far
We are it's buds.
It is our garden, all ours, ours.
Our India is the best..
..of all the world by far
This way.
Our tomorrow is based on our today
What we choose to do today will decide..
..what happens to us tomorrow.
The choice isn't between good and evil.
That's easy.
The real choices of life
are choosing between..
..the lesser of two evils,
or the greater of two goods.
Now what do you choose,
Zooni, what's your choice?
Oh, leave my little girl alone!
Just listen to your heart dear..
..not your father's philosophy!
Try and take some decisions..
..from the heart rather than the brain, Zulfi
If I'd used my brain you wouldn't be here,
Nafisa my love.
So? Zooni?
Papa, Mama, I really can't decide.
I'll do whatever you say.
So that's it. It's decided.
Zooni will not go to Delhi.
I found my prince.
When will Zooni find hers?
When will some footballer
hit her head with a ball?
Any regrets?
Regrets?
I praise God every day that the
great Zulfikar Ali Beg's..
..penalty kick missed the goal..
..and hit me, square on the head.
It was my worst kick ever!
Any regrets?
Regrets?
That's why I tended to you
in the hospital for a week.
We must accept that Zooni..
..may have to live her life without
that special someone.
That perhaps she will never marry.
And when we're gone
who will look out for her?
We must give her the
chance to live her life.
We need to support her independence.
Be her strength, not her weakness.
Madam Mehbooba
Bobo, the name is Bobo not Mehbooba
Whatever you command your highness.
By the way, your bags weigh
more than your brain!
Obviously! Haven't you heard that saying?
Which one?
- “The buffalo is bigger than the brain.”
No dummy, it's “Is the brain bigger
or the buffalo?”
Fatty! - Not Fatty, Fatima.
Don't know why you girls insist on
distorting perfectly good names.
Yes, Ruby. - Not Ruby, Rubina.
Come on.. take the bags at least!
We have to represent Kashmir,
at a Republic Day performance..
..at the President's Palace,
in front of the Chief Minister of Delhi..
..and what do I have to pull this off?
A bunch of wild cats!
If we're a bunch of wild cats
what does that make our leader?
Who said that?
You've carried your knitting?
When we're upset,
we say things to distract
“Have you taken your knitting?
Kept your ticket safely?
Don't get off at a station on the way.”
God keep you safe.
Papa.. papa! When papa's upset,
not just his voice
His walk also changes.
Yes, and he can't even cry in front of all these girls.
But I have no such problem!
I know you have to do this..
..but I don't know why, I'm afraid.
Afraid of what ?
Loosing me to some prince?
Oh, I wish!
One look at you,
and he'll be on his knees
Heaven forbid! Will he be a porter?
Kneel to get my bags? - Hush!
Not a porter, not your bags,
he'll take your heart away.
With some poetry maybe..
..”Every once in a while
I get this feeling in my heart..
..that you were made for me, all apart.”
“You were living in the
mountains somewhere..
..before there was me.”
“You have been called down
to this earth, only for me.”
God keep you safe, my child,
God keep you safe!
God keep you, mama.
Have a safe journey.
Be sure to say a prayer for me
at the Jama Masjid. - Yes, mama.
Take Zooni for an eye test in the big city..
..and you, Rubina take care of my baby!
Relax Aunty.
Don't worry, I'm here aren't I?
That's what I'm afraid of Fatima.
It's Fatty, aunty.
Bye dear, Bye Zooni!
Mama! Mama!
Yes, my child !
If the Prince recites poetry
what should I say?
“May my life's breath find refuge in your heart..
..destroyed in your love may my life depart.”
Bye Mama!
Why do you do this?
You can say something as well.
Now listen up Rao.
We're here for just 7 days.
5 days to the show, and 2 for holidaying.
I want to sight- see Delhi,
not your bald head.
Stand straight like a man!
I'm not even a man any more Madam.
After years of bowing to
government officers..
..I have come to this sorry state.
Today if I have children,
even they will be born bent over.
I have no interest in your
family planning program!
Where is that tour guide?
I am the Balwaan.
Not the Cartoon Network.
You are exactly what you look like!
Now tell me what's the problem here?
Where do I start?
From the head light to the exhaust..
..there are problems and more problems.
I mean your tour guide.
Where on earth is he?
“Don't look around the city
Forget the wasteland too”
“Behold God's greatest creation.
Rehan is just above you.”
You Mr. Romeo. Stop this cheap poetry!
You didn't applaud me, now at least help me
Oh, you're blind.
Yes, you didn't see that?
Are you blind too?
Thank God, I'm not.
That's a nice thing to say to a blind person.
If I was blind, I couldn't have seen..
..the most beautiful thing in the world, you.
“Your beauty made God make a mistake,
what more can I say ?.
So that you don't caste an evil eye on yourself,
he took your eyes away.”
Zooni, where are you?
I'm coming Fatty.
Fatty? Is that your name or your dog's?
Come on Balwante..
..hit the gas!
Heavenly!
If wish I was a roll of wool..
..wrapped around her fingers..
If you were a roll of wool,
with the needles.. I'd..
I wish she'd make a sweater out of me,
wear me, even in the summer.
Wow! What a thought!
Zooni, stop encouraging his nonsense.
“I am not the flower jasmine,
I am the flower rose.
I am your lifelong admirer,
not of your friend sitting close.”
Hey Mr. Guide, your cheap poetry
is going to get you nowhere.
So, who are you knitting this sweater for?
She's knitting it for a prince,
not for a devil like you.
And if she was interested in you ..
..she would speak up not sit silent.
Oh, so she does speak ?
I knew she was blind,
thought she was mute too
Zooni! Don't talk to him,
You don't know these men..
Looks like you know men very well.
Stupid guide
“If you sit there in silence, regret it you will.
So often after silence love
has awakened, stronger still.”
“There is no limit to human desire..”
“There is no limit to human desire, no dearth.
After 2 yards of burial cloth,
we still want 2 yards of earth.”
Superb!
Superb! Outstanding!
“I'll look pain square in the eye,
face every test laid out for me.
For the sake of your friendship,
dear friend, I'll even love my enemy.”
Oh yeah, I love your style!
The emperor Shah Jahan once walked
these lanes of the Red Fort.
And so did Mumtaz,
his very, very beautiful wife.- Careful!
I can manage myself.
But how will I manage myself, around you.
Shall we?
Bobo, tell me, what does he look like?
Killer, girl, a real killer.
He's simply obnoxious!
He looks ok, so I thought
he must be a nice guy..
..but he called me a stupid girl.. so..
And forget all his sweet talk..
.. the way he looks at women, it's shameful!
And he told me he doesn't believe in God,
can you imagine that?
Look even the crows are cawing.
It's a sign.
Stay away from that Rehan guide.
“How can you stay away from me and go?
How can your heart forget me so?
That fragrance on your breath is me.
How ever will you stop, not breathe?”
Great! Fabulous!
Come on, let's go.
Come.
If the moon was to recommend me.
This is what he'd say to you.
I want to drop the veil of decency.
I want to cross the line with you.
I insist on destroying myself.
On destroying myself in you.
If the moon was to recommend me.
This is what he'd say to you.
I want to drop the veil of decency.
I want to cross the line with you.
Your charms are like a gentle breeze.
Let them touch me as you pass.
Your every move a graceful branch.
Please move into my heart.
Come into my arms,
any excuse will do.
For I must, I must destroy myself in you.
If the moon was to recommend me.
This is what he'd say to you.
I want to drop the veil of decency.
I want to cross the line with you.
If I tell you my true intentions.
I'm sure they'll make you blush.
If I make you hear my heartbeats.
I'm sure they'll leave you flushed.
But I cannot hide my feelings true.
For I must, I must destroy myself in you.
If the moon was to recommend me.
This is what he'd say to you.
I want to drop the veil of decency.
I want to cross the line with you.
I insist on destroying myself.
On destroying myself in you.
Stand straight. Looking at you
I'm getting a backache.
And you Mr. Cartoon Network..
..we have to leave for rehearsal
at exactly 9 AM tomorrow.
So then leave.
It's me. Rehan.
I know. Only you can be so impudent.
I want to be even more impudent.
I want you to run away with me.
I want to show you Delhi.
Without your bodyguards,
don't say no, not without thinking at least
You'll anyway be thinking about me so...
God forbid, the crows are cawing.
I'll wait for you after the rehearsal tomorrow.
With these crows.
You have had more girls in your life
than there is mileage on my bus.
Why do you want this blind girl?
What can I do Balwante,
everyone wants the moon.
There's just one headlight in the sky,
that shows us the way.
Now you want that too?
“They say in love you always loose sleep.
I wish someone would love me,
I bloody sleep and sleep and sleep.”
Let's go.
Zooni! You must be tired, go to sleep.
I am awake after so many years.
I can't sleep now. I can't sleep now.
I want to be even more impudent,
I want you to run away with me.
Why aren't you concentrating?
Can I use your phone ?
Pick up, mama!
This is one decision you'll have
to take on your own Zooni .
Oh Lord, how silly of me.
Of course there's no point in your..
..going sightseeing when you can't see.
Okay. You can go back to the
hostel after rehearsal.
Fine! At least you'll be away from
that Rehan guide.
Brother, tell me something.
You stand here all day.
Don't you wish you were inside
on the President's chair?
Why should I think that?
In the police we regularly get promoted.
But once you're President,
there's no scope of promotion at all!
You're a very jolly man!
All thanks to my grandfather.
Grandfather?
- My grandfather worked for the British.
All day long he would hear them say
'Jolly Good' this and 'Jolly Good' that.
When I was born he was losing his memory.
All he remembered was 'Jolly Good'.
So that's what he named me. Jolly Good.
Yes, yes have a laugh at me.
Even the officers that pass by here say..
..”Jolly Good..Singh” laugh and move on.
I think that's great.
Thanks to you, the country
is run in good spirits!
“I felt God himself had blessed me.
When all she did was to address me.”
Look, I sent Rana with Balwaan and the bus.
No, I'm not coming today.
So what if I didn't tell you earlier.
I'm telling you now.
Let's go.
- You left work without permission?
So?
My father says that if a person
can't be loyal to their work..
..they can't be trusted for anything.
I've left work for you and you're
giving me a speech on loyalty?
My mother says there is
nothing bigger than loyalty.
If you're done with your mother and
father's sermons can we go?
Why am I saying all this to you ?
Why are you saying all this to me?
So that I go back to work?
Yes.
Think about it, if I go today
I won't come back tomorrow.
I'll go back to the guest house,
you'll go back to work.
Tomorrow you'll take the day off
and then we'll go, ok?
You've heard what your parents
have said. Now hear me.
If I go today I will not come back tomorrow.
You'll come. Let's go.
“I don't live the life of the selfless,
nor do I grab another's wine.
If she has love let her come and declare it..
..to ask her, to follow her, I decline.”
God be with you.
Greetings Ms. Zooni.
Greetings Mr. Jolly
You know what happened yesterday?
Yesterday I said good morning to 20 people..
..and they all said good evening to me instead.
How can so many people be wrong?
It was my watch that was wrong.
It stopped in the morning..
..so I said 'good morning' to
people all day long!
I can't see Rehan today.
I can't see him either.
I think he's like me.
Completely clean at heart..
..and completely muddled in the head.
“I couldn't quench my thirst with water
so I set off for the bar.
I gave up complaining to God about you..
..for He is the most smitten by you, by far.”
I'm with you now.
So, how are you going to
show Delhi to a blind girl?
Can you see me?
No.
What's my voice like?
Like the thunder before the storm.
What do I smell like?
Like the earth after the first rain.
What do I feel like?
Like a prince in a beggar's clothing
And just like this you will see Delhi.
Watch out! This is the Gateway of Blood.
The emperor Aurangzeb had his brother..
..Dara Shikoh beheaded,
and hung his head up here. - there.
Exactly where you are standing.
And the British government
killed two sons and..
..a grandson of Bahadur Shah Zafar,
right there, behind you.
Please. That's enough.
Let's leave from here.
This is the bloody history of Delhi.
The Mughals, the British,
a lot of bloodshed had happened here
That's why, till today, tears of
blood flow from these walls.
Scared? What did you think?
I wouldn't get back at you for yesterday?
And what did you think,
I'd get scared so easily?
When I have never seen any colors..
...how can the color of blood scare me?
Now you're scared.
I'm going. I'm going to Delhi,
to get her back.
It's been 4 days.
That's enough to understand life.
What'll be happening to her without us?
Just think?
She's brought up on home food,
she must be starving.
The Delhi crowds,
who will look out for her?
I'm not there.
I can't take her agony any more, I'm going.
Are you going for her sake or for your own?
You were right, Rehan.
You did show me Delhi.
They say, the feelings one
gets for the country..
..in front of the Eternal Soldier Flame..
..one gets for love in front of the Taj Mahal.
Feelings, love, that's all just talk.
When it comes down to basics
then needs are everything.
Needs of the stomach, needs of the body
So you believe needs are everything..
..and feelings are nothing? - Yes.
So all this time you're spending with me..
..is this also to fulfill some need?
You shouldn't tease a man like me.
My needs are great.
Even one chicken is not enough.
Even one girl is not enough.
So, Mr. Rehan, how are things with you?
And how are you Zeenat?
Forgotten how I am?
Come and meet me, I'll remind you.
It's my fault actually.
He's been busy with me.
That's what makes Rehan guide so special.
So, when do you plan on
being busy with me again?
“I can't explain the ways
of this market to you,
He who is sold, can't ever be a buyer anew.”
You'll never improve. Ever.
Good evening.
You seem to know her very well.
That's me.
I told you I only believe in needs..
..not in feelings or love.
And I only believe in love.
Meeting that guide on the sly.
Forget Helen,
I can't believe you lied to me!
This is just why I lied to you.
You're less of a friend and more of a Hitler.
Hitler? I was just protecting you.
Not me. You were protecting
my blindness.
Zooni, how do I explain it to you?
He just isn't right for you.
Perhaps, but when I'm with him
I feel happy, feel alive.
And this feeling is special.
Very special.
But I don't like that Guide.
Not one bit.
And I don't care what you say.
I'll never let you go with him.
Never.
Turn off your light.
Jolly Singh! Could you please allow
my good luck to come in? Please?
Don't insist.
This tough Sikh has a soft heart.
I'm sorry but rules are rules and
rules are never Jolly Good.
It's ok. I know you're only doing your duty.
But still, I will be singing for him.
People say that after so many years
of independence..
..our Republic Day has lost all meaning.
That it's just another holiday.
But it's not just a holiday for me.
This day marks the birth of my country.
They say that the state
of our country is like..
..that of our old monuments.
What's beautiful was only in the past.
I am blind so I don't see the
faults in my country..
..but why can't those who see,
see the beauty here?
What Emperor Shah Jahan had said
of my home state of Kashmir..
..we believe that's true for all of India.
If there is a heaven on earth..
..it is here, it is here, it is here.
The earth here changes color at every step.
The language here has all the colors best.
The climes wear green on their head.
The sky lays a blue sheet over it's bed.
Golden river, Green ocean,
Every part so dressed.
My colorful, colorful country,
my country full of color.
Motherland, I bow to you.
The sun with its rose-tinted
neck plays around.
The yellow scarf of flowers
covers the shy ground.
Color in the veil, color on the mound,
bright, bright color all around.
My colorful, colorful country,
my country full of color.
Bright red faces all around,
smiling and glowing in fervour.
Colorful laughter, colorful happiness,
relationships full of color.
Color in promises, color in memories,
color, color, more color.
My colorful, colorful country,
my country full of color.
The color of love here runs so deep,
once its on it's there for keeps.
The color of true love so still
simply glistens does not spill.
Color in charm, color in manner,
all colors full of flavor.
My colorful, colorful country,
my country full of color.
The earth here changes color at every step.
The language here has all the colors best.
The climes wear green on their head.
The sky lays a blue sheet over it's bed.
Golden river, Green ocean,
Every part so dressed.
My colorful, colorful country,
my country full of color.
Go Zooni, he's waiting outside for you.
He said I am the cutest of all the girls.
After you of course, Zooni. Go.
Stop. You're not going anywhere.
Certainly not like this.
With your hair all over the place.
You haven't even worn your stole properly.
I can't let you go like this.
You're really..
Ok, Ok, that's enough of that.
Go now.
Let's go.
“The fire is in the sun,
but it's the earth that does the burning.
The eyes fall in love,
but it's the heart.
..that does the suffering.”
You're looking exceptionally
beautiful this evening.
Really?
You're looking exactly the same to me.
You have brought me here? You ?
I thought you don't believe in God.
Will you just keep quiet for a bit?
Shut your eyes now.
Rehan, my eyes are always shut.
Rest your eyelids
They say this blessed water does miracles.
I hope that's true.
No one has ever asked for
such a blessing for me.
I'm not asking for you,
I'm asking for myself.
Perhaps if your eyes are open
you'll keep your mouth shut!
It's so loud!
This is the real Delhi.
The quiet museums, Red Fort,
that's not the real Delhi.
This is the sound of Delhi.
the essence of Delhi
I wish I was deaf as well ...
Just a minute. Wait here.
Yes, it's me.
Yes, yes, I got it alright.
Rehan, you're watching me, aren't you?
What's this madness?
I just wanted to show you.
Show what? That you're such a fool?
- I'll call you later.
Boys, and girls you know..
..they impress each other
on their first dates. So I too.
Your life is very precious Zooni..
..don't waste it on anyone.
Certainly not on me.
My mother says, to gain something
you have to loose something.
Oh God!
Mother says this, father says that..
..where is Zooni in all this?
What does Zooni say?
Nobody's ever asked Zooni
I'm asking you. Tell me.
I like you.
Let's go.
Now you're scared.
Our destiny has brought us
these precious moments today
Look at me up close,
imbibe me in every way
You're still scared.
Just in case your fate has
another card to play
Think we'll never meet again, just suppose,
not till this lifetime is forever closed
I'll manage from here.
Come in to my arms, hold me close,
we may never again have this night's repose
Think we'll never meet again, just suppose,
not till this lifetime is forever closed
Come in to my arms, hold me close,
we may never again have this night's repose
Think we'll never meet again, just suppose,
not till this lifetime is forever closed
Where is Rehan the gorgeous?
What's the time, Bobo?
Ten thirty
My watch is fine, why is he late?
It's our last day.
Maybe he's getting you a gift, so he's late.
He himself is a gift.
No news?
No.
No Fatty. Nothing yet.
Mama.
How are you my child?
We saw the performance on TV.
It was fantastic.
When everyone stood up to clap.
Your father and me..
I want to speak to you about something.
What is it? Tell me.
When papa and you first met.
After he tended to you in the hospital..
..if he had suddenly disappeared.
What would you have done?
I would have asked him why
he was misbehaving.
And told him to stop his
nonsense immediately.
Misbehaving? Who is misbehaving?
So is that what I should do?
Who is he?
Who is who?
So do you love him?
Do you love him? What are you saying?
Give me the phone.
Just a minute. - Give me the phone.
I'll deal with this.
So what have you decided?
Nothing. I don't think he loves me.
Just remember one thing dear..
..give your life for the one
who gives you his love..
..but give your self-respect only to..
..the one who is willing to be
destroyed for your love.
This is Humayun's tomb.
It was constructed for him
by his wife Hamida.
Take a look at what a wife
made for her husband.
And you can't even make me breakfast.
Don't worry, I'll start building
your tomb right away.
Come... - I am blind and you are the
one who can't see me...
“If by mistake I have made a mistake..
..then please consider it a
mistake and forget it.
But only forget the mistake..
..even by mistake don't ever forget me.”
Heard that? Great!
Take them ahead.
Let's go. - But our guide?
Move it! Look here, the Qutub Minar.
No Zooni, Fatty was right.
You should love a prince,
not a devil like me.
It's too late now.
Now this devil is my prince.
I can't give you anything.
Remember I told you, I believe in needs,
not in feelings or love.
Women are like cities for me.
I spend some time in one.
I get to know it, get immersed in it and..
..and then move to another city.
This is me, and I can't change.
Look Rehan, all this stuff about princes
is good in dreams and stories.
In reality I have found you.
We haven't met by chance,
we've met by destiny.
If not the rest of our lives, we can spend..
..the next 12 hours together, can't we?
Perhaps that's all we have,
just today, just now.
Don't come close to me,
this storm will destroy you.
“May my life's breath find
refuge in your heart
May my life's breath find
refuge in your heart.
Destroyed in your love may my life depart.”
How can you love me so much?
How can anyone love another so much?
I promise you this Zooni Ali Beg..
..the next 12 hours will be the
most beautiful of your life.
The raindrops have a conspiracy.
They have a silent wish, a plea.
Look, just see.
Softly, slowly this gentle breeze.
Says so much, listen please.
Why the distance between you and me.
Look, just see.
Never again will the winds be this shameless.
Never again will our steps falter so blameless.
This rain is not so straight, it has a twist.
It's telling us something as it pours and mists.
Just understand it.
Softly, slowly this gentle breeze.
Says so much, listen please.
Why the distance between you and me.
Look, just see.
Desire, like a fire-fly, glows bright then dim.
It's such a sweet predicament that we're in.
Don't discard the request
from our lips like this.
Don't call this wish of
our breathe remiss.
Just touch, Feel this.
Softly, slowly this gentle breeze.
Says so much, listen please.
Why the distance between you and me.
Look, just see.
Rehan! Wake up. Wake up.
My train is at 10.
If you don't wake up I'll miss it.
I spoke to Fatty and she's bringing
my things to the station.
We don't have to go to the guest house.
How much you sleep?
Wake up! Don't you have to
go to work as well?
And don't you dare miss work today
See I forgot, Mama had told me
to get the eye test done.
And Papa has asked for a chess set.
Can we stop and get one on the way?
Do we have time?
Rehan! Are you listening?
Oh, I didn't even say goodbye
to Jolly Good Singh.
You please tell him for me.
Here's my address...
Will you write to me?
Your wife's first visit home after marriage?
I want to say..
No, Rehan. You made no promises
and I will not ask you for anything.
I always wanted love to be the
most important thing in my life..
..and now, thanks to you, it is.
You were wrong Rehan.
I am not destroyed in your storm
I am rejuvenated.
Now your picture will
remain with me always.
And now I can't leave.
Not until you step off my stole.
God be with you Rehan, be happy.
Now can I say I told you so
No
I won't say it. I'll never say it.
“May my life's breath find
refuge in your heart.”
“Destroyed in your love
may my life depart.”
Fatty! If not for me at least
pull the chain for Zooni.
With pleasure.
What's going on?
What is the guide doing here?
The brave heart is taking the bride.
He wants to marry you?
What? Who is he?
Where is he from?
What does he do? What does he look like?
He wants to marry her!.
They love each other.
So what did you say?
What could I say?
I said he must ask my parents.
What did she tell him?
She's our daughter..
..she wouldn't give any answer
without our consent.
Zooni, I have complete faith in your choice.
Yes, my darling, tell him yes.
And we're coming to Delhi
right away to get you married.
Come quickly mama, I miss you.
Now where are you off to?
We're going to Delhi aren't we?
We'll need tickets.
As usual he runs away the moment
there are tears in his eyes.
God keep you mama, God keep you.
God keep you my child, God keep you.
Our daughter has found her prince.
She has found her prince.
When did you get your eyes checked last?
I don't remember.
Many years ago in Srinagar.
This is the problem.
We doctors go on about checkups
and no one listens.
These days science has
progressed so much.
What was impossible 5 years ago
is today possible.
What do you mean?
Retinal replacement can help you.
The chances are very slim..
..I warn you, but there is still a chance.
Are you saying Zooni will be able to see?
There's a chance..
We'll take the chance doctor.
I'll check the first available date.
There won't be any problem doctor?
The operation must go well.
Don't worry our best team is on it.
I'll meet you after the operation.
Rehan! You're hugging me
for the 10th time.
I'm not complaining but please don't worry.
I'll be fine.
If you're so worried then why didn't
we wait for mama and papa?
We could have done this after the wedding?
Let's go, it's time.
Don't forget to get mama and papa
from the station.
And Jolly Good wants to
come here later as well.
You're going to the
President's Palace, right?
Yes.
I love you very much.
I know.
After the bomb blast in Peshawar..
..Pakistan the independent Kashmir Front
has demanded..
..that both India and
Pakistan leave Kashmir.
They want an independent Kashmir..
..or else there will be many more
attacks to come.
The Chief Minister is alive..
..but as per early reports,
8 security officers have been killed.
And at least 15 others are
badly wounded.
The main building has not been
harmed very much..
..but the left side of it has been
completely destroyed.
2 terrorists have been captured and..
..the IKF have claimed responsibility.
Their demand is that India
and Pakistan leave Kashmir.
And let it be an independent country.
My Child
Mama I can see, I can see.
Yes, my darling.
Papa I can see.
You can cry in front of me now papa.
I can see you cry. But where is Rehan?
He's not with you?
Didn't he get you from the station?
Papa, where are they taking us?