It's a great pleasure-
It's a great pleasure to
have all of you here today.
I thought you all might
begin your tour here.
I really didn't want a bachelor
party in the first place.
I'll tell you why. It's not
that I'm against tradition.
There's just something bizarre about
having a strange, naked woman...
dance around me while
my friends yell out,
"Go for it, Ben.
Last night of freedom, Ben. "
Last night of freedom for what?
Which is what I told
my best friend Alan.
I didn't want any strippers.
I didn't wanna get lucky.
I was lucky enough just getting married.
All right. Quiet!
Guys!
All right. I'm not payin' for
that. It already was chipped.
We're here to, uh, wish Ben
good luck and good riddance...
as he heads down that
rocky path to matrimony.
And, uh, hey, you know what.
Ben's dad Richard and his grandpa
Max are here. Where are you guys?
Those guys
- Watch out. You guys gotta pace yourselves.
Knowing Ben, I'd have to
say that he's probably,
- uh, one of the most loyal guys that I've ever met,
- Like a dog!
and, uh, monogamous.
And so this is probably
gonna be the last time...
that you're gonna spend in
a room with your friends...
and a n-n-naked
woman...
other than your wife, man!
So you can close your eyes
if you want to. Close 'em!
But then you're gonna be
missin' Juanita, the bull tamer!
You don't have to do this.
You really don't have to do this.
Very nice.
Ole!
Pop?
Pop? Max?
Call 911.
How did this happen? Hmm?
What's the difference how it happened?
- I wanna know how it happened.
- It happened.
It makes a difference to me.
All of a sudden he has a
heart attack out of no place?
Mom, can we please not
talk about this now?
What is it you don't want to talk about?
Mrs. Holmes, if it's any consolation, I
think he was having a really good time.
- Alan, shut up.
- Okay.
- Come into the hall.
- What is in the hall?
A vending machine. Come on, butchki.
- Who's hungry? I'm buying.
- All hours of the night-
This is insane.
He probably just ate some spicy food.
It was spicy, all right,
but it wasn't food.
- Butchki!
- What?
Richard, you are the silliest old tart.
Grandpa, what came over you?
Hmm?
- Hey.
- Ben.
- You all right?
She was the most
beautiful woman I ever saw.
What about Nana?
Did you ever take a good
look at your grandmother?
Woman looked like Tolstoy.
I was never attracted to her.
Oh, maybe in the beginning,
because she was the only
woman I'd ever been with.
Well, you know, that's great. That's, uh
- That's loyalty.
Loyalty? It's fear.
Did you ever feel her arms, her-
Oh, Ben, I used to
dream about other women.
What it would be like
to hold them and to-
- Okay. - Touch
them and to-
- That's- -
Smell them.
Grandma smelled. She had a
very distinct smell. It was a-
Ben. Ben.
Listen to me.
Don't tie yourself down.
Even if you love a woman, it fades.
Marriage is a prison.
Ben!
Could I help you out? Here we go.
- You just passed my room.
- Sorry.
Feel better.
Hi.
- Hi, sweetie.
- Honey.
Oh, why does everything feel so
much better now that you're here?
- How's he doing?
- He's stable.
- You know, physically, at least.
- Great.
What happened?
What do you expect? He's an 80-year-old
man with high blood pressure...
and a naked balloon-popping
toreador is a rough combination.
- It didn't pan out. It's not funny.
- It's not funny.
- Be serious.
- There's something I want to do.
- Okay. Why? - I wanna be able to remember
this moment in 30 or 40 years.
Think my next husband
will get a kick out of it.
Oh, that's nice. Okay.
It's the night before I am flying
down to Savannah for our wedding alone,
because Ben's grandfather, who we
will now refer to as Larry Flynt,
has partied himself into intensive care.
- What do you have to say?
- Put the video camera away.
No, no, no, honey, you're not
going to get off that easy.
No, I'm saving it for my vows.
I have already finished my vows.
What's in 'em?
You know why? Because it's
easy for you. I'm a writer.
- Oh, really? - I can't just slap something
down on paper like you do.
Ben, listen.
You don't have to be brilliant...
or witty or clever or polite even.
Just have to be honest.
Come on. Say something.
What are you feeling?
Are you nervous? Are you
happy? Are you scared?
Am I scared? What would I be scared of?
- I'm scared.
- You are? Why? Now you're making me scared.
Because it's a big thing. It's our
marriage. It's the rest of our lives.
It's
- It's scary.
I know. I'm not scared.
- The only thing we
have to tear- - Yeah?
- Is this video camera.
- Hey! Come on! Just say a few words for posterity.
What, what, what
What
What, what
Follow me to the scene What
Really? You think I can
rent shoes down there?
I can't believe I forgot my shoes.
I hear they have shoes in Savannah
now. The whole South has 'em.
All right. Wedding dress. Check.
Check for the minister. Check.
Valium for Bridget's mother. Check.
- Ball and chain for you. Check.
- Not listening to you. Check.
- Here, look. Here you go.
- Thanks.
This is your present,
okay? It's a book of quotes.
I crossed out the ones I'm
gonna use in my toast. Listen.
"To say that you can love
one person all your life...
is like saying that one candle will
continue to burn as long as you live. "
- Think about that for a minute.
- I will. That's profound.
This is used.
I forgot the rings.
That's not funny. No, don't do that.
I forgot the rings, so-
Come on, man! No!
Relax. I'll catch the next plane.
Son of a bitch!
I'll see ya in Savannah.
Hey, I need to go to the city.
- New York! New York City!
- No, I can't.
Don't take the Van Wyck though.
Hurricane Amanda is headed
for the Southeast coastline.
The eye of the hurricane is
presently located 200 miles...
east of South Carolina
and Savannah, Georgia.
North, northwest-
Excuse me, folks.
Just the line's movin' forward.
No. Well, I love you.
I love you more.
No, I love you more.
No, you more.
Okay, I have to go, because I just
made another passenger nauseous.
Okay?
That's my fiancée.
Goin' down to get
married, so we're a little-
Oh! Jack Bealy, Snap-On Tools.
Ben Holmes, scared of flyin'.
- Yeah, I was married once.
- Yeah?
To me marriage is just one big lie.
You don't say.
In the morning I had to
say, 'Don't be silly, honey.
Your breath is fine.
You smell like a rose. "
Then I had to say, '"No, honey.
I never noticed that
18-year-old girl...
with the fantastic body and halter
top that delivers our newspaper.
She can't hold a candle to you...
and the 30 pounds you've put on
since we stopped having sex. "
So when's the wedding day?
May cancel it. I may have to call back.
I didn't mean to throw a wet towel on
ya with my whole marital disaster tirade.
It's all right. It was a nice story
actually. It was very touching.
- Nice girl?
- Very nice.
As a matter of fact, I just happen
to have a picture of her right here.
- Wow, what a knockout.
- Yeah, she's beautiful.
- Oh, baby, come to Daddy.
- Well, take it easy, Jack.
What I wouldn't give
for an ass like that.
- Huh? Here we go.
- Hi.
- This is me.
- Really?
Well, this is your
lucky day, sweetheart.
We got just about enough
room for one of you, darlin'.
Must be destiny, huh?
- Careful.
- Okay.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
- Sorry.
- Hmm?
I was reading what you were writing. My
eye just kind of wandered over. Sorry.
Do you work for Hallmark?
Even if I had seen you looking
at it, that wouldn't bother me.
Well, I don't care either.
I'm absolutely fascinated you
can't admit you saw me reading it.
If I had seen you reading it, I'd
be perfectly happy to admit it.
Then why did you close your computer?
I'm known to do that from time to time.
I'm a rebel. I'll open it, then
I'll close it again just like that.
Don't get next to my fire,
because you'll get burned.
This is not working properly.
Stewardess, this isn't
- Miss? Thank you.
You're a little jumpy
for a rebel, aren't ya?
My seat belt's not functioning properly.
He's a scared flier.
Jack Bealy, Snap-On Tools.
Sarah Lewis. And you are?
Ben Holmes. Really, I'm not that scared.
- Jack's- - I can assure you
absolutely nothing is going to happen.
I speak from experience. I was
a flight attendant. There you go.
Oh, yeah? In one of
those little uniforms?
Please stay calm!
Oh, my God!
Hold on!
Oh, my God! This is a disaster.
- Daddy.
- Oh, for heaven sake.
- Let's go live- -
On the other hand,
you can never have too many of these.
- It's fabulously colorful.
- Give you that.
How tar do you think I could throw it?
Don't you dare, young
- Give me that now.
To the hospital for minor injuries.
Ceramic clown from the?
- Brewsters.
- My God! That's Ben!
There's no official word
on the cause of the crash.
There may have been a foreign object-
Let's get some help!
She hit her head.
Everyone's pretty shook up.
We had a couple of passengers go to
a local hospital with concussions.
Oh, my God. There he is again.
Call me! Oh, Ben! I love you.
Call me! No. Go back.
There you have it.
The latest information-
Hello? Ah, Ben!
Hi, honey. Yeah, I'm fine. No, I'm okay.
I'm a little frazzled.
I mean, I was in a plane crash.
This place is a nightmare.
People are running around.
I guess they lost everything.
I don't care about any of that.
I'm just so happy you're okay.
I- I-I just
wish that-
- Ben! Ben, listen.
- Tell him, um-
- What happened?
- You just get yourself down here sate and sound.
The thing is, I'm a little bit scared
to fly before I was in a plane crash,
so I don't feel much like getting-
- Jesus!
- You are a god.
- You are a god amongst all men. Do you realize that?
- I'm on the phone.
- Sorry.
- Do you mind?
- What in the hell?
- Just one of the passengers.
- He saved my life!
- She's kidding.
It's a joke.
I'm gonna get a rental car
and drive down there, okay?
I'll call you w-w-when
I have a finalized plan.
Okay, great. Thank you, sir.
Sorry. I couldn't contain myself.
It's amazing when you think about
it. We almost died today. Dead.
Isn't there a rent-a-car this
way? Are we goin' the right way?
It I died, how many people would care?
I mean, really care. You'd have
your shares of "What a shame.
What a waste. She was so young. "
- But no real crying.
- It might be in that terminal.
No eating disorders,
no attempted suicides.
Nothing. Absolutely depressed.
You know what? I'm thoroughly depressed.
I just need to shake it off.
So what were you thinking?
I was thinking how it would
affect our frequent flier miles.
What do you do for a living?
I'm a, uh, jacket copywriter.
Huh. What does that mean?
- Means I write jackets to books basically.
- Oh.
Do mostly fiction, but
I do some nonfiction.
You do blurbs. You're a blurb
writer. You're a "blurbologist. "
I'm a jacket copywriter.
As you can imagine,
- due to today's minor
incident- - Oh, sh-
Nada cars. Non cars. Cars nyet.
You should have called as
soon as you got off the plane.
Why didn't I think of that
when I was unconscious...
and bleeding from the head?
So, cars nyet. We can check
the other airports though.
No, that's all right. You can go ahead.
I'm not that big a fan of the idea
of getting on another plane today...
or tomorrow or ever, it that soon.
But you go ahead. I think I'm gonna be a
ground transportation kind of guy from now on.
I'll be right back.
How ya doin'? Did ya get a car?
- This is Vic. He's gonna give us a ride.
- All the way to Georgia?
Sure. We split the cost of
the car, the gas, whatever.
- Great.
- Good. Let's go.
- Okay.
- Wait, wait, wait. We don't even know this guy.
- He's Vic.
- Oh, he's Vic.
Great, he's Vic. He chops us
up, leaves us in the woods.
That's why I asked that you
come along to protect me.
How do you know that I'm not dangerous?
I said, hallelujah to the 16 royal fins
You're gettin' down on your knees
And it's time for your sickness again
Come on and tell me what you need now
Tell me what is making ya bleed
We got two more minutes sayin'
we're gonna cut you what you need
What's your story, Ben?
What's down in Savannah?
- My wedding, Vic.
- No kiddin'. That's great.
- Isn't that great?
- Yeah, it's a blessing.
- First marriage?
- That I know of, yeah.
Yeah, I was married once.
One day I walk into the house
and I hear the shower runnin'.
I had Chinese food with me, figurin'
it would be a nice romantic surprise.
She starts singin' in the shower.
What's that song? "Up in the
sky"? "Up with the eagles"?
- '"Wind Beneath My Wings. " Very touching song.
- "Wind Beneath My Wings. "
Suddenly there's another
voice in the shower with her.
- Oh, no.
- A baritone.
Uh-oh.
Now it's a freakin' duet.
So I walk in the bathroom and
there she is... with my brother.
- Oh! - I grab my brother and throw
him through the window naked.
He broke his leg in
two different places.
Dare we ask what, uh,
became of your wife?
I put the wind beneath her ass
and sent her packin'. Divorced her.
She never got a penny, the
lyin', whorin', adulteratin' pig.
What about you, sweetheart?
What's your story?
I'm going down to visit my brother
and hang out with my nephew.
That's nice. Kids.
- Yep. Got any?
- Nah. But I see 'em all over.
Come on, come on
So what else have you
jacket copywritten?
What else did I do? The low
point of my career was...
I did the blurb for a thriller...
about a woman-
an archaeologist-
who finds love in the pyramids.
It was called Me And My Pharaoh.
- I have that book.
- No, you don't.
Yes, I do. "A scintillating
tale of erotic mummification. "
I wrote that line.
Oh, my God! That's
why I bought the book.
Anybody who could find embalming
either scintillating or erotic...
had to be read.
- It was brilliant.
- Well, you know, I mean, it's all about adjectives.
I was gonna go with "engaging tale
of erotic mummification" first.
- But then I said, no, scintillating.
- Right on the money.
It's still selling now,
but at least I get to write.
What do you do?
I haven't settled down to
one particular thing yet.
Worked at galleries, sold cars,
tried out for "Aladdin On Ice. "
Um, wedding videographer.
I got fired, though, because
apparently nobody wants a crash zoom...
to the priest during the ceremony.
I was a exotic dancer, hostess
at the New York auto show.
- That's a gift.
- Yeah.
Let's see. What else?
- Is there anything else?
- I don't think so.
- Kids, we should get goin'.
- You got it, Vic.
Two wayward travelers stuck
in a Geo with a guy named Vic.
Don't you think this is just
a little bit over the top?
Oh, so what if it is?
Knock, knock.
- Steve! How are you?
- I'm good, real good.
- Virginia, nice to see ya.
- Well, hi, Steve.
Bridget.
Yes. I mean, hi. Hi.
Steve? How are you?
- It's been a long time.
- Yeah.
You look wonderful.
Thank you. So do you.
- So, how are you?
- How is he?
Just the most successful
lawyer in Savannah. That's how.
Youngest member at his
firm. Handles all my work.
Which I appreciate, 'cause there's not a
contractor who gets sued more than your daddy.
And what's so funny about that, Hadley?
God, you are an unpleasant woman.
Gale force winds it the hurricane
stays on course for Savannah.
Anybody want some weed?
The experiment was a complete
failure. The U.F.O. landed-
It's sinsemilla. It’ll
take your head right off.
That's great, Vic. You think you should
have your head taken off while driving?
- Can I have some?
- Atta girl.
You sure you don't want, Ben?
No, that's okay. I had some
peyote for lunch, so I'm all set.
He's getting married. Don't
forget. He has to be responsible.
Not necessarily. You know,
look at the Fitzgeralds.
F. Scott and Zelda,
crazy, married couple.
They drove a-
Had to know about that.
- Whoa! Hey!
- Sorry. Sorry.
Oh, shit!
Uh, what's that?
- Do you hear that?
- What's what?
Hi, honey. How are the
bridesmaids' dresses comin' out?
Good. No, everything's tine. I
just got a little bit delayed.
Car trouble, in a manner of speaking.
But I'm fine.
Everything's gonna be okay.
Yes, I know. Well, I love you too.
Well, hoo-hoochie, I love you so much.
Baby, no, because I love
you more. I love you more-
Honey, I can't do this right now.
- I'm gonna miss my wedding.
- Oh, relax, Benjie.
It's a simple drug bust. It's
not like we killed anybody.
This may be an everyday event in your
life, but speaking as a non-felon-
I'm on a bit of a time
crunch here, too, okay?
If I don't make it down to Savannah by
Saturday morning, I lose 25,000 bucks.
Are you on Dig For Dollars? You told me you
were going to visit your brother and nephew.
Yeah, I know.
Okay, kids. Here's the situation.
Vic DeFranco was driving
with an expired license.
Plus he's got three priors
for possession and selling.
And there was ten ounces in the
vehicle that he admits is his.
Did anybody else know
there were drugs in the car?
- No, sir. In fact, I just
met this man- - You can't-
You can't ask us these questions
without an attorney present.
You haven't advised us of our rights.
I believe that's called-
Oh
- Ah! A Miranda violation. That's it.
This is a very simple procedure.
You tell me you didn't do anything illegal.
you sign a statement. And you go quietly.
Sir, I'd like to be considered
separate from her, sir.
- Hmm. What part of quiet didn't you understand?
- What are you doing?
Why me?
Well, I think that went well.
- I'm not that happy with how that went.
- No?
No, not really.
I haven't known you that long, but I
think something may be wrong with you.
- May we have two tickets
to Savannah, please?
You want these seats together?
It's totally up to you.
- Just give me one second. Can I talk to you?
- Yeah.
I just, uh
- I don't want to be rude or anything,
but in situations like
this, I think about...
what I would want Bridget to do
it the situation were reversed.
I wouldn't necessarily be
that comfortable with her...
riding down on a train
together with some guy...
who she had a, you know,
kind of a connection...
or a chemistry or spark,
whatever, some kind
of a thing like that.
You know, and-
The look on your face is
telling me you have no-
You're not feeling
or you're not sensing-
- You have no idea what I'm-
- Oh, no, no, not really.
Fascinating. Okay.
Maybe we just shouldn't
ride down together,
because at this point I really
made kind of a chump out of myself.
Okay.
- Have a nice nuptial.
- Thank you.
Other than the drug bust and
the plane crash, it was, uh, tun.
So long, Sarah.
- Farewell, Ben.
- Okay.
'Oscar Wilde: One
should always be in love.
This is the reason one
should never marry. "
Well, what did he know?
What you writing there, mister?
My wedding vows actually. My
fiancée and I are writing our own.
Oh, that's sweet.
Isn't that sweet, Emma?
- It's sweet as pie.
- We didn't write our own vows.
It's kind of a new thing.
It's nontraditionalist.
We were so nervous. It was hard
enough to do what the preacher told us.
I didn't really think about it at all. It
just seemed natural, the order of things.
I had doubts. I'll be honest.
- You did? You never told me that.
- I don't tell you everything.
You better, you old geezer.
It seems like it worked out
pretty well for both of you.
Oh, we're not married.
We're having an affair.
I'm happy for the
first time in 34 years.
- I don't believe this.
- I don't have any regrets.
My children are long gone, and
I gave my wife 30 faithful years.
Until I met Ned, I
always was convinced...
that sex was some horrible
obligation God put on women...
like cramps or high heels.
For all those years, she never
experienced a genuine orgasm.
Wonderful. Could you watch my stuff?
I'm gonna go pull the emergency cord.
- Hi. How are you?
- Hi.
- Truck.
- What do you have?
A truck? Can I see? Hey,
hey, let me see your truck.
- Grab my nose. Oh!
- Grab nose.
What are you doin'?
What are you doin'? Slap
me five. Slap me five.
- Five!
- Slap me five.
Something's wrong. He
should have called by now.
He can take care of himself.
He's a grown man, isn't he?
Daddy, what is it exactly
that you don't like about Ben,
besides the tact that he's from
New York and he voted for Clinton?
- That's not enough?
- I voted for Clinton.
All the best presidents sleep around.
Help.
Hello? Oh, hi, Steve.
Ooh.
Oh, nothing, just, uh, you know,
staving oft a nervous break down.
Oh, well, thank you, but I can't.
No. No, no, it does.
It does sound like fun.
But quite frankly, a series of
rabies shots sounds like tun...
compared to another
evening with these two.
Bridget, come watch the biography
of Newt with me. He's amazing!
He is not. He's an imbecile.
- No, he's not. He's a damn genius.
- Well, then, you're an imbecile.
Maybe I can come by
for just a little while.
The train will be underway momentarily.
We apologize for the inconvenience.
Hello!
Can you hear me?
Is anybody out there?
No, but leave a message,
and we'll call you back!
Hi.
I wasn't expecting an answer.
I wasn't expecting to find
some crazy woman on the roof.
Wanna come up?
No, not really. I think probably that
the top of the train might be off-limits.
I know. How many times in your life
you gonna see a view like this? Come on.
Seize the moment, Benjie. Come on.
I am. I'm eye level
with the sunset here,
so I have a better view because I'm-
Come up.
Okay, buddy, this time, we're gonna
do it with a little more feeling.
- Okay. - We're
just gonna-
Echo!
I am alive!
Just a little
- Open. Just push out.
Push out. No one can hear
you. Just throw it out there.
I am somebody!
- I think-
- Oh, God.
I think He heard me.
Excuse me. I'm fine.
Let me show you how
I do it. Okay, ready?
All right, here we go.
Oh, God!
Stella!
Well, that was nice. You
know, I mean, as sunsets go.
This is interesting. I don't
remember the rooster car.
- Do you remember seeing roosters?
- No, I'm a vegetarian.
Oh, no, not again. Didn't
you two hear the announcement?
When we stop outside Youngsville,
no one on the Savannah-bound train is
supposed to board the last three cars.
- We uncouple there, and then we reroute.
- What does that mean?
That means this train's
going to Chicago.
Aah!
I got you. I got you.
You try to seize the moment, you
end up getting yourself killed.
- Will you jump? It's not going that fast.
- It's too fast!
I got you. I got you. There you go.
There's another one coming tomorrow
afternoon, or there's a bus station in town.
Okay, thanks!
I'm starting to get the feeling that there's
maybe a hint that I'm not getting here.
Just spell it out for me!
- That pretty much spell it out for ya?
- I'd say it does.
Whoo! Yeah! Whoo!
Hey! Come on! What are you doing?
- Oh! Come on!
- Oh!
Whee!
Oh, come on!
Ah! It kills. It kills. Ah!
Ow!
- Not exactly a hub city, I guess.
- No!
But we'll come back in the morning.
- What do we do for the next 12 hours?
- Come on.
- I have an instinct about these things.
- No! It's hailing! No!
How are you?
It's so good to see you!
- You gotta see Linda. Remember Linda?
- Hi!
Hey, you guys, look who came.
Bridget's getting married this weekend.
Hey, hey, hey, hey
- Ouch! It kills! It kills!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey
Oh! Oh, man!
- It's open 24 hours.
- What are you doing? No, no, hey.
Benjie, they cannot kick us out.
- Please, get up.
- Oh, God!
I love this place so much.
- Oh! Oh!
- This is dry. It's the best thing I can say.
Oh, my God, this is heaven.
Baby has an old witch
doll My baby rang his bell
I didn't have the time to
tell my baby fare you well
Hey, hey, hey, hey
Takes him down.
I just wish we'd stayed in touch.
- I regret not keeping the friendship going.
- We're friends.
Steve, friends.
I regret that too.
How can I just let you walk away
Let you leave without a trace
When I stand here taking every breath
With you Ooh, ooh
You're the only one who
really knew me at all
So take a look at me now
There's just an empty space
There's nothing left here to remind me
Just the memory of your face
Take a look at me now
- Do you remember that song?
- Yeah.
I thought you would.
All I'm saying is that I don't
understand the idea of living...
with just one person
for the rest of my life.
How do you make a choice like that?
That's like choosing what
you're gonna wear in 25 years.
It things worked that way, everyone
would still be wearing hot pants.
- Ya dig? - I never wore hot pants,
so there goes your whole argument.
Hey, life is supposed
to be a ride, right?
You want to be on your deathbed saying,
"I played by all the rules," or "I lived"?
'Cause I lived. I loved.
I fought. I broke hearts.
I screamed. I bled.
I guess thinking like that can
explain your hostility toward marriage.
I don't have hostility toward marriage.
I just have hostility towards my husband.
You're married?
Yep. Twice, actually.
you saw him. I was
kissing him at the airport.
My husband Carl was a hustler
from the first day I met him.
Who am I to talk? I was a dog walker.
He convinced me I should invest
in a bagel store down in Savannah,
because he thought they
couldn't make good bagels.
That's why they lost the Civil War.
Of course, we had to
invest all my money,
because Carl's was tied up
in some phony tax shelter.
- Is that your $25,000 you were talking about?
- Yep.
I am going to sell the place, get
the last in a string of divorces.
of course, he doesn't know
about it, or the divorce.
Wow. What a story.
So do you think it's a
terrible thing I'm doing?
You know, deceiving my husband?
No, I
- It's none of my business.
Well, I do.
Beg you listen me, don't
be kissin' me till I'm done
I'm some champion of
reason like seasoning
Pepper your thoughts with
spice and entice you to a space
Where bass players or layers are leaps
Think what I think with
my prayers, it's nice
My world is everything
I've become contained
In the hum between voice and drum
I'm comin' from the same
place I'm still runnin' from
Even sittin' in the garden
I can still get stung
- Hi.
- Hello.
I'm gonna go outside and take a walk.
Will you watch my stuff for me?
- Yeah, sure.
- Okay.
My Jesus
Mr. Spiro, hi. It's Sarah Lewis.
Yeah, listen, I'm on my way down to
sell the bagel shop. I should be there-
What?
No.
Mr. Spiro, I think
that's a misunderstanding,
'cause the man who called couldn't
possibly have been my husband.
No.
No, Mr. Spiro, actually, my husband
- He's coming with me to sell the property.
- Hi.
- No, no, no, no. I have these. How ya doin'?
- It's okay. I can pay for them.
- It's the least I can do.
- Two for the 9:30 to Savannah, please.
- Thank you.
Residents of Savannah,
Georgia, are at risk...
for the hurricane to make
landfall by tomorrow afternoon.
Where's my wallet?
Fun in the sun.
You've already won.
We're taking you to Miami.
Hey, Ben, you know what this is?
This is one of those real estate
things where they give you prizes.
You look at one of their condos. I used
to do phone solicitation for these guys.
I was wonderin' why you hadn't
mentioned phone solicitation.
They'll take you anywhere it they think
there's a chance of you buyin' a condo.
I'm sure you've done this
before, but it's not my speed.
Benjie, make you a deal, okay?
I will get you on the bus. I'll get
you down to Savannah for your wedding,
if once we're down there just for a couple
of minutes, you pretend you're my husband.
What do I have to do? Treat you badly
and get you to make bad investments?
No. We have no other option. What
options do we have? Zero. None.
Yet still somehow, they seem
more appealing than this one.
I'm going another way. Wait, Sarah.
- I don't wanna be your husband.
- Ben. Ben.
- Do you think I like these?
- I don't know. Everybody's different.
No, Ben, this is not for me.
This is for a little person.
- I know, your nephew.
- No, not my nephew, my son.
- You have a son?
- Yes, I have a son.
I have a ten-year-old boy who lives
in Savannah with my first ex-husband.
And, um, I haven't seen
him in, like, two years.
I wanted to take the money from the
store, and I wanted to give it to him...
for college or school
or whatever he wanted.
It didn't matter to me, but I
can't go in there empty-handed.
So, please?
Hey, everybody. I want your
attention for one second.
I'm like to introduce
two new sun seekers.
Okay, Ben and Sarah.
- Holmes and Lewis.
- Just married.
Yes, I'm keeping my name.
What am I? His slave?
They missed their bus, so I
thought we'd give them a ride.
Actually, as it turns out, they
are looking for a place to live.
We were gonna stay with his parents, but I can
take that for a week before I poke out my eye.
No offense, honey, but
really, they're not human.
And guess what, everybody. You're
gonna love this. Ben is a doctor.
We came to the right bus.
Tell 'em what your specialty is.
What's your specialty, pooky?
Tsk.
He's a surgeon. Yeah.
- Going to be.
- Going.
He's shy. Brain surgeon.
That's why we're
relocating down to Miami.
Let's face facts. It's like one
big emergency room down there.
No offense. No offense.
Every day I get in the queue
Too much, magic bus
Get on the bus It takes me to you
I'm so nervous I just sit down and smile
Okay, one hour fiesta. A little taste
of Mexico, and you can drink the water.
Ben Holmes. Sorry
about the collect call.
I'll reimburse you when I get
- Okay. Is Bridget around?
Uh-huh. She's out to
lunch. Okay. Who's Steve?
- Come on.
- Yes.
Hyah, hyah, hyah.
Hyah, hyah, hyah, hyah.
Hi.
You wanna go on the
spinning sombrero ride?
- No, not really.
- Oh, come on.
Bunch of 70-year-olds
are going. Come on.
Sarah, there's two
kinds of people in life.
The kind that look at the
spinning sombrero ride and think...
that there's maybe some
amusement to be had there...
and the kind that look at it and
think, "Where will I throw up after?"
You really should get some thrills
in your life before you die.
- Nausea is not a thrill.
- Shh!
I've noticed you around.
Everybody, say, "Come on, Ben. "
Come on, Ben!
All right.
Whoo!
Don't throw up on me, Tony.
Let it out, baby!
Murray!
Hey! Stop the ride!
Stop the ride!
Give him some room.
Where's Dr. Holmes? Anybody
see Dr. Holmes? Dr. Holmes!
Dr. Holmes, I think we, uh
- I think we need you.
Step back. Let the
doctor do some work, huh?
- Uh, all right. Call 911.
- Somebody call 911!
We're gonna get your head back here.
Okay. Listen for breath,
check for a pulse.
Hey, you know what. Step back, guys.
Let him breathe a little
bit, huh? Step back.
Excuse me, guys. Excuse me.
Dr. Keller, this is Dr. Holmes.
He suffered an acute
myocardial infarction...
that was complicated by
ventricular fibrillation.
Okay.
But he's going to be fine. You
saved his life. Good work, Doctor.
Good work.
Hey, everyone, I think out
of respect for Florence,
we're gonna stay here
in town tonight, okay?
I made arrangements at a local motel.
We really have to get on the road,
so we're gonna part ways here.
- I absolutely insist. See ya
outside. - No, no, no, we're-
Wow. What a passion pit.
It's the honeymoon suite. Imagine
what the wedding must have been like.
Mm-mmm.
I think I'm gonna take a bath.
- Hi.
- Door won't close.
Need some help?
Thank you.
Oh, yeah. Oh.
If I call three times a day
Come and drive my blues away
Be ready to play
Do your, do your
If you want to have some luck
Give your baby your last buck
And it you can't be
With the one you love, honey
Love the one you're with
- I heard you said you didn't love me
If I need attention
Call, I'll call you on the phone
I'm gonna head down to the gift shop.
- It's Ben.
- Okay. Thanks for clearing that up.
If my radiator gets too hot
Yeah, Dad, uh, wire the money to, uh,
Cash-O-Gram office in
Orin, South Carolina.
Yeah, Ben, Orin, South
Carolina, but what are you do-
- What is he doing in South Carolina?
- I'm handling this.
What are you doing in South Carolina?
What's going on? Are you coming
through the Bermuda Triangle?
Could I talk to you guys a second?
- Certainly.
- Yeah, sure.
I was wondering- I
mean, I- Are you happy?
- You're asking if we're happy?
- Yeah.
- We're very proud of you.
- That's not what he asked.
- He asked if we're happy.
- I heard what he said.
- Why shouldn't we be
happy? - I mean, uh-
With your lives together,
with your marriage.
- What kind of questions are these?
- What's this about?
Well, on the way down
here, I met this woman.
- Oh, Ben, you idiot!
- Would you let him talk?
What woman, you idiot?
She's just
- It's not like that.
It's just that she's completely
different than anyone I've ever met.
Please! They always are!
This is not good timing.
- You're supposed to be getting married.
- I know, Mom.
I want to know how, when you got married, how
you knew you were the right ones for one another.
I understand. Listen to me.
Ben, when I met your father, I had
an opportunity to marry Sam Wellman.
- Sam Wellman?
- Shh! Will you please?
- Who is now a very prominent
businessman- - He sells pools.
They're not even built-in.
They're the kind you blow up.
- Some are built-in.
- Even they leak.
It's okay. You know what? It's tine.
I was just curious, but it's-
Dad, I appreciate it if
you could wire the money.
- I'll be down there as soon as I can, okay?
- Okay, kid. Take care, huh?
Yeah. Bye-bye.
Thanks.
- Whoo! Okay. Okay,
now, we're honeymooning.
All right.
But, I mean, it seems like
what you're saying, though,
is that marriage itself is good.
Oh, you know, yeah
- You gotta remember your parents were young once.
They went out dancing.
They made love in the
back seats of cars.
Then they got married and had
kids, and the kids, they slowly...
sucked the life right out of them,
until all their passion, all
their visions of a life...
of great adventure are
reduced to hoping to be able...
to sit on a goddamned toilet in peace!
Well, I'm gonna get
something to eat, Joe, so I-
- I can't believe it!
- How weird!
- Ben! Oh my God!
- Hey!
- What's going on? Hey, Debbie.
- Hi!
- How are ya?
- I'm good.
- What are you doing here?
Uh, it's
- You would not believe what happened to me.
Tell me about it. When they closed
La Guardia, I couldn't get a flight...
out of Newark or J.F.K.,
but, uh, luckily, uh,
Debbie here had a vehicle.
Uh, well, there's a certain symmetry
there. Best man, maid of honor.
- You know.
- Well, not really.
- This is Joe.
- Hi. Farrell.
Head of the Sunshine
Seekers Real Estate Company.
Joe, uh
- Joe gave me a ride down here.
And it was a pleasure. Quite a couple.
- So, you guys staying here?
- No, no, it's like the only place for miles.
You know, we thought we'd
stop, get a bite to eat, pee.
- Yeah, so come on. We'll give you a lift.
- No, no, no, no, no, no.
- You're not taking the good doctor away from us now.
- The good doctor?
So, maybe you guys should just eat,
and I’ll just come back down
and meet you in say, you know-
- Fifteen minutes? Is that good?
- Great.
- Let me grab the stuff out of my
room. - You got a- You got a room?
- Yeah, the honeymoon
suite. A little ba-da-bing.
That's right. Rehearsing
for tomorrow night.
- What's tomorrow night?
- Hey, this kid's gettin' married.
Yeah.
That's
- that's funny. He's already married.
That's true, you know,
but, uh, in my heart I'm already there.
But we all have lives to lead, so let's move
on with that, and I'll see you guys in a bit.
Nice talking to ya, Joe. Okay, guys.
You gotta have heart
Please, ma'am, I need
your signature, ma'am.
Signature? For what?
Look at this. It says
"'damaged. " Do you see?
- Can you read, young man? D-
A-M-A-G-E-D, damaged. - Damaged.
We're very proud of Ben.
If he's late, believe you
me, he has a good reason.
What I don't understand is
how, in this day and age...
of A.T.M.'s and cell
phones and the Internet...
and Voyager Two,
could it take two
days- two days-
to get from New York to Savannah.
Oh, don't drink out
of the bottle, darling.
Thank you.
We are really very proud of him.
This is ridiculous.
I'll put an end to this right now.
Pretending to be a doctor, listening to
my parents' advice on my personal life.
Sarah? Sarah?
And where's my lousy maid
of honor? Where's Debbie?
Huh? Can I not at least have that?
Who's supposed to be pouring me drinks while
I'm being stood up by the so-called groom?
Answer me that. Thank you.
Honey, he'll be here.
It's all gonna work out.
It's true, Bridge. Husband
and wife, that is something.
It must be nice to see your
parents back together, though.
Yeah, talk about a match made in hell.
What do you mean, "back together?"
What do you mean you're separated?
Oh, honey, baby, sugar lump,
it means your father has
an apartment he stays in...
- when you're not here.
- I'm never here.
I stay there a lot.
When were you going to tell me?
Honey, we didn't want
to spoil your wedding.
This is your special time.
Well, it would have been.
Okay.
Get me outta here.
Whoo!
- Look who's here. Hey, Ben.
- There's Ben.
I want to buy this man-
Whoo!
Get out there.
How can you resist it?
You look like you should be writing to your
congressman to protest cuts in Medicare.
Really? That's exactly
the look I was going for,
compliments of Sun Seeker Phyllis.
Listen, Sarah, I just ran into, uh-
Shh. You can't do two
things at one time.
- Well, the plans that
we sort of- - Okay.
You obviously didn't win your fiancée
over on the dance floor either, did you?
How did you and Bridget meet?
- Uh, at a party.
- And?
- It was a surprise party.
- Oh, what a beautiful story.
It must have been a magical night.
No wonder you can't write your vows.
No offense, but I'm not sure I should
be taking romantic advice from you.
- You think?
- Failure's a fantastic teacher.
You could learn from my
mistakes. I could tell you...
everything I hated about my husbands and
my boyfriends so you don't do the same.
- Should I get a pad?
- Get a scroll.
- A scroll?
- Aw, okay.
Never forget her birthday. Make a
really, really big deal out of it.
After sex, hold her for a little while.
- You know, talk to her like a human being.
- Ah.
Uh, oh, and do not
wear your socks to bed.
- Why?
- No socks to bed,
because you might not be all
that attractive to begin with.
No. Keep going.
Always, always side with her
in an argument with your mother.
Um, listen to her like you mean it.
Supportiveness is a
really, really sexy turn-on.
- Never, ever hit.
- No.
No. And, um,
- no matter what annoying
habits she has, - Mm-hmm.
just realize that she's dealing with a
huge mountain of imperfections every day.
So you might just want to let it go.
- That's it.
- That's it?
Yep.
- Hey, can I sit there?
- Hey.
- Hey- Aaah!
Ohhh! - Oh!
Uh, let's get some air.
- Why? - I'm
just- I'm hot.
Grilled prawns or something?
One second.
- What's the matter with you?
- Hmm?
- What's the matter with you? -
Nothing's the matter with me. Do, uh-
- Do you know how to swim?
- Of course I know how to swim.
Aaah!
I'm tellin' you, I
saw him come out here.
That
- That's him down there. That's him.
- I don't see anything.
- There's a body at the bottom of the pool.
No, I think that's just a big drain.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Oh, and P.S.
- you're a moron.
Hello? Excuse me? Hi. Hi.
- Do you know Ben Holmes?
- I'm sorry. Know who?
Ben Holmes. Is that Ben
at the bottom of the pool?
I don't know, but I
could go ask for you.
It's not Ben, okay?
He's afraid of the water.
He goes to the beach in a suit
and tie. Come on, let's go.
I found it! I got it, I got it.
- What?
- Godamn contact lenses.
You oughta just stick with glasses.
Oh, hey, guys? What's
going on? What's happening?
- Hi.
- Hey, Alan.
This is Sarah. Sarah, Alan.
- This is my best man at my wedding.
- Hey. How are you?
Debbie. This is the maid of honor.
- Hi, Debbie.
- Hi.
So, how'd you two hook up?
Uh, I wouldn't say that
we're hooked up, really.
I sort of barely know this person, but-
You were on the bus, right? Yeah,
we rode down on the bus together.
There's a whole group of
folks. Rode down together.
Okay, and the whole pool thing?
She fell in the pool, and uh,
didn't look like she
was a strong swimmer.
She was kind of flailing around, so I-
There's no lifeguard on duty
if you see the sign there,
So I jumped in, and you
know, hauled her out.
Then, in the course of that,
the contact lens fell out.
Here you go, miss. You oughta be
careful with these, because they're-
Here you go. It's your contact lens.
That's a great story.
Bridget's really lucky to be
marrying such a great swimmer.
Whoa! What happened here?
Well, perhaps after you dry off,
you'll come back in for another dance?
- You got it, Herman.
- Dr. Holmes, you don't mind...
if I dance with your wife, do you?
Yeah. You don't mind, do you sweetie?
- All right, all right. Well, I'll see you in there.
- Okay.
I'm pretty disappointed in you, Ben.
You know, everybody's always
telling Bridget she's so lucky...
because you're such a nice guy.
Debbie, I am a nice guy, all
right? This is not what you think.
Okay. Whatever, Dr. Holmes.
Okay?
- Alan?
- Ben, you don't need to explain, okay?
Remember, I'm the guy who begged you...
to sleep with more women
before you got married.
I am not sleeping with her, man!
Okay? There's nothing going on!
Why
- Why won't you listen to me?
- Maybe because I'm getting married tomorrow?
- All right, look, Ben.
It you're not gonna take
advantage of a night...
that's gonna get you through many
sad, pathetic, lonely years, then-
My God.
I'll see you in the
lobby in five minutes.
I hate to remind you, but
we had a deal, remember?
You were supposed to be my husband if
I got you a ride. Do you remember that?
Yes, I remember that arrangement.
I did not, however, presuppose
the tact that Debbie...
is now on her way down to tell
my fiancée that I am holed up...
in a hotel room in South
Carolina somewhere with a woman...
claiming to be the wife
of the good Dr. Ben Holmes!
What was I supposed to do? The
Sunshine people think we're married.
They would have stoned us. As it is, I already
feel bad enough about not buying a condo.
Why don't you just
tell Bridget the truth?
What kind of marriage do you
have if she doesn't believe you?
- Just explain why you're with
me- - Sarah, I'm not with you!
We're not together! This
is not a relationship!
I just happen to be traveling
alongside a natural disaster!
- You know what? I
really feel sorry for you.
'Cause at least when I was getting
married, I could admit I was scared.
- Well, save me your pity, because I am not scared.
- You know what?
You have such a problem with
honesty, Ben, you know that?
- Oh.
- You can't tell your fiancée what's going on.
You can't explain something absolutely
simple and innocent to your best man,
and you are with me, Ben!
You could have left a
hundred times, but you didn't!
- I tried to!
- Then why are you still here?
I'm leaving! All right, tine!
You wanna talk about honesty?
Let's talk about honesty.
- Bring it on.
- You complain about your life, nonstop, all the time.
It's all your fault.
You are a beautiful, incredible woman.
You could have any guy you wanted,
but you keep picking these losers.
And the only thing I can think of
is that you choose these guys...
who are intellectually inferior to
you so that you can control them,
but still feel conveniently
wounded when the relationship ends.
You're the one that's afraid of commitment.
You back out of every job you ever have!
You run away from anyone and anything,
and you think it's so
unconventional and liberating,
when in tact, it's just
cowardice and juvenile...
and unable to face the real world!
Ha! Okay, you want honesty,
I'll give you honesty.
Do you know why you can't
write your marriage vows?
Because you are absolutely terrified
that you have nothing to say.
And why would you, Ben? Because
you run around so scared...
that life is gonna throw you this
curveball that'll completely shatter...
this crystal clear, perfect existence that
you've created for yourself in your Day Timer,
that you blurb your way out of feeling
anything emotional, anything real.
You have no emotions, and that's
what makes you a shitty writer, Ben.
You know what? At least I
don't sit around obsessing...
that no one's going
to come to my funeral,
because I have relationships
that last longer than a week.
- My funeral is gonna be packed!
- You know what, Ben?
That is just great. And
I know your eulogy...
is gonna look so nice on
the back of a book cover.
I just think you are an
immature, selfish person.
Well, I'm obviously wrong.
Have a fabulous time in Westchester.
I do hope you enjoy the minivan.
God! How great it must be to be
so cool and above everyone, huh?
It must be great! Let
me ask you somethin'.
How cool is it to abandon your kid?
I was 17 years old, okay? Fuck you.
You don't know anything about it.
- All right, well, try 27, Sarah,
- Nothing.
because seventeen's not working anymore.
Okay, Ben, take your marriage Clift
Notes and have a nice wedding, okay?
- Have a nice divorce.
- Okay.
Four, three, two, one.
- Okay, I'm leaving.
- Hey, Deb, he's comin'.
Five minutes. There he is. I think he's
- Come on!
No, no, no, don't-
- Well, that was smooth.
- You're getting married tomorrow, Ben.
What's your point?
Well, you see, if I'm
gonna turn my life around,
I can't very well
break up your marriage.
I'll have bad luck for the rest of
my life, karmically speaking, and I-
I am getting married tomorrow,
I have nonrefundable tickets to Hawaii,
and I cannot make
myself leave this room.
Well, I like you too, Ben.
I-
I can't go through with a
marriage like that. I can't.
Ben, relax. We didn't
even get to second base.
Have you seen Dr. Holmes and his wife?
We're doing the raffle.
He's not Dr. Holmes,
and she's not his wife.
Okey dokey? Okey dokey?
I'm gonna tell her.
I think at the very
least she deserves that.
If I can feel this
way about someone else-
Hey! Come on!
- Why does this have to get dangerous?
- Get in, you freak!
God!
Is that your ride?
Yeah. Yeah, it was.
Now what are you gonna do?
I don't know. Let's go get
the money my father wired.
That should get us a cab at least.
This is actually the
perfect car for this trip.
It's already been wrecked, totaled
and destroyed. What else can go wrong?
Well, you asked.
Really. That's interesting.
That's not really that funny, actually.
I think we should just sit here
and wait for the locusts to come!
Oh, my God.
- Oh.
- Yeah. All righty.
- Yeah.
She's on tire, Ben.
Well. I guess we should, uh-
Yeah. We should-
I am slipping!
This is so wrong.
But it feels so right to me.
Oh, good evening.
Good evening. Good evening.
- Hi, Joe.
- It is a good evening, isn't it?
Dr. Holmes, or whoever it is you are.
We made a call. There's no Dr.
Ben Holmes in New York City.
Unless you're a
veterinary brain surgeon.
Well, all God's creatures
are welcome in my office.
But the way you two carry on, you
oughta be ashamed of yourselves!
- You tell 'em.
- There is the matter of your bill.
Thank you very much.
I'm really sorry.
- Let's look at this bill here.
- Seems a little excessive.
No, if you add the two and the
two, that's tour, and then, uh-
Run! Jesus! Jesus!
How long do you think
before they call the police?
- Oh, about five minutes ago.
- All right.
Yesterday I was just trying to
get married, today I'm a fugitive.
Okay, I get it now.
This is a sign. This
whole thing is a sign.
I am not supposed to get
married. Loud and clear.
We have to be in
Savannah in the morning.
The fuzz are after us.
Hey, Ben, how much was that
car we saw back in the lot?
The disaster car? It was $150.
'Cause I'm thinking that if, uh-
It somebody went into
this place right here...
and did, you know, a little bump and grind
for the good old boys, they could, uh-
they could probably walk out of there
with that amount of money in their pocket.
Strip dancing?
You're saying you'd just go in and strip
dance? I'm talking about something serious.
Ben, let's weigh out
our alternatives here.
On one hand, what do we have? We
have a little harmless dancing...
that gets us to Savannah where
I have $25,000 waiting for me,
and you have what, 130 of your closest
family and friends waiting for you.
And on the other hand, we have
- oh, look, we have nothing.
Oh, there's nothing there. So, we have
dancing, going to Savannah. Oh, nothing!
- I see where you're going with this.
- You know I'm right.
The fuzz.
All right. Am I being
too prudish about this?
Is that what it is? Maybe I
am. I just gotta open my mind.
You go in there, you take your
clothes off, you have the power.
Post-feminist. It's aggressive.
You have the power and control.
I know what I'm doing. Watch my back.
Watch your back? What,
are we on Mod Squad now?
- Hiya. How ya doin'?
- Good.
I was wondering if y'all
had any entertainment.
- We got a pool table out back.
- What would you say to somebody dancing on it...
for a set price of, I don't know, $150?
I could guarantee you
a really good show.
- $150 seems like a lot of money.
- What? Look at her.
I am looking at her. I'm not interested.
How much for you to dance?
- Excuse me?
- Ben,
I think this is one of these places...
where everyone would much rather
see you dance than see me dance.
- You mean- - Get your
hands off of my man
Get your hands off of my man
It's not funny anymore,
because I don't even like...
to be naked at home
in my shower by myself.
- So, it was okay for me a minute ago?
- Well, it's on your resume.
If you want me to blurb you
a novel, I could do that.
So much for power and
control, big guy. Get up there.
- All right, I'm sorry.
- There you go.
Oh, watch me ride
I'm a sexual animal
Eat you like a cannibal
Prime for the energy
I'm inflammable
Yeah, I finished my beer So come here
And get nice while I Lick your ear
Put your legs over there
And kinda swing on a chair
I swear you look wicked
When your hand is in your hair
Eyes half closed Cute little nose
And like a pound of self raising
I roll and roll
Step out of my clothes
Like I'm doing the right thing
It was pumping and she was frightening
Yeah, lightning flashed
and thunder roared
They're really cheering for
you. You're doing a great job.
Nope. Everyone in here
is looking at your ass.
This is where I'm lost all night
If loving you is wrong
I don't want to be right
I don't wanna be right
Don't wanna be right
If I come first Well, that's not worse
One take like an earthquake
I'll take a delight in making
the bedsprings sing all night
If loving you is wrong
I don't want to be right
- Whoo! Ha ha! Can do! Let's check it out.
- Come on.
Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Look at that!
Convertible style.
I'm a sexual animal
Eat you like a cannibal
Well, I didn't have...
the g-string and the cowboy boots, but, uh,
I think it was a good showing nonetheless.
Don't be too proud of yourself.
You weren't that good, Ben.
Don't be jealous.
It's amazing, because the things you find
so exotic and interesting right now...
are gonna be the same things that
you're gonna hate me for in the end.
Why am I hating you in
this scenario? What's-
Okay? Trust me.
A lot of stuff’s happened really
fast. You're just not registering it.
It's registering, okay? I'm
a gay dancer and I'm proud.
I'm a gay, gay strip
dancer and I love it.
Registered. Cha-ching! Change!
The password is "denial,"
okay? You've known me two days.
Two days. Now we're on our way
down to go break up your marriage.
That has nothing to do with you.
I don't believe you.
I don't either.
Amanda is beginning to gather
strength as it continues...
its journey in the Atlantic.
It's currently a category two hurricane.
The hurricane is continuing
its push towards the northwest,
and that means the coastlines
of Georgia and South Carolina-
He'll make it.
That's it right there. Yep.
- Oh, my God, that's Carl.
- Carl?
My husband.
Surprise, sweetheart. Who's this?
I know it's not the guy you're trying to
sell the place to, 'cause I got an injunction.
Bullshit.
This is so fake.
You can't even get an
injunction that fast, all right?
- What are you doing this to me for?
- Carl.
- I have to get back pretty soon,
so- - This is my place, okay?
- I bought it with my money.
- Your place?
- Yeah.
- For chrissakes, Sarah, we're married.
You wanna sell the place? That's
fine, we'll sell the place.
You can send the money down to your
kid it that's what your worried about.
Now, come on.
Come on, angel. You
got no place else to go.
I'm not going, Carl.
You ungrateful bitch.
- What?
- Hey. Hold on.
- Nobody's talking to you, my friend.
- Okay. Just cool it.
- Sarah, get in the car.
- I'm not going, Carl. Forget it. Not going.
- I said get in the car, now!
- No, I'm not getting in the car!
Goddamn you. Hey, what's your problem?
You sleep with her and you
think that means something?
- You don't know what you're
talking about. - Don't you tell me-
- Ohh!
- You all right? You okay?
- Did you find my thumb?
- Get outta here, Carl.
- Go! Go!
- You know, I got news for you, buddy.
- You're just the next number on the list.
- Just go home, man.
You know what happened with
her kid? What did she tell you?
Carl, don't. Carl, don't.
- She let the dad raise him? Well, that's bullshit!
- Shut up.
The kid chose the father.
She was never even around.
But even a
six-year-old could see.
You can't trust her.
Enjoy the ride, pal.
- Hey, are you okay?
- Yeah.
Oh, Jesus. Now I can't even go see him.
Who? Your little boy?
Hey.
- Why? Because of $25,000?
- Yeah.
Aw, Sarah.
I don't know anything
about raising kids,
but I don't think $25,000
is gonna win him over.
I think he wants to see you.
Can't win him over. He obviously
doesn't want what I have to offer.
Sarah, you have the most
incredible ability...
to make people absolutely
crazy about you.
No, I have the ability
to make people crazy.
That's what I can do. Really well.
Sarah, everybody loves you.
You just-
You just think they're all wrong.
When does your wedding start?
Well.
Seventeen minutes late.
Ben's usually very prompt.
You must be so very proud of him.
I hate to interrupt, but
I think the hurricane...
may arrive before the groom.
Good Lord.
Ben, where are you?
Look, we'll-
I just wanna get my
bearings here for a second.
Okay.
- Well.
- All right.
Two strangers arrive at a
wedding. One invited, one is not.
And as the guests arrive and
the appetizers are served,
the true drama unfolds
just minutes from the altar.
I don't think I'm gonna be able
to blurb my way out of this one.
Nope. Probably not.
Okay. All right.
I'm just gonna run in there...
just put a quick stop to this
whole wedding thing, you know.
Maybe grab a few gifts on the way out.
- You need anything?
Bread maker? - Um-
- Cuisinart?
- No, no, I think I'm good.
Yeah.
You will be here when
I come back, won't you?
Oh, well, you know me.
I would not presume.
All right. Wish me luck.
Ben, do me a favor and just
forget about luck, okay?
Forget about loyalty, forget about...
being nice, forget about polite, okay?
Because this is the rest of your
life and possibly somebody else's too.
- Yeah.
- You know?
Yeah.
Just be honest.
If her father happens to
shoot me on my way out,
I guess I'll see you in heaven.
Yeah. I don't think I deserve heaven.
Ah, Sarah.
You deserve so much more than you think.
You deserve to be with somebody...
who will be really, really
depressed if your plane goes down.
- Hey, Ben.
- Hey, man, what happened to you?
What, did you go swimming?
- Ben! Honey, honey, come on.
- I have to talk to you!
- Dad, I can't right now.
- We just want to talk to you for a minute.
- I can't right now! -
Benjamin! - Get in there!
- All right, Benjamin.
- Barbara, please.
I want you to listen to your father.
- Ben? We were thinking about...
- Yes.
what you were telling us on the phone,
and the thing is, nobody
knows if it's gonna work out.
It's all a leap of faith.
It just so happened that
in my case, I was lucky.
My heart told me to
do something, I did it,
and 32 years later, here I am.
Don't speak. You'll ruin the moment.
You have got a lot of nerve!
Now, maybe this is how they
treat women back in New York,
but here in Savannah, we
have a little more respect...
for the sanctity of marriage.
- Oh, do you hear yourself?
- I am not talking to you, Virginia!
- Where's Bridget? I want to marry her.
- Who the hell are you?
- Someone who gets to a wedding on time!
- Hi, we haven't met. I'm Ben.
Steve Montgomery. I used to go out with
Bridget and I'm still in love with her.
- Can I see your invitation?
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Excuse me! Somebody should be asking
for your invitation, all right?
P.S.
- you shouldn't even be having a wedding!
- I saw him in the hotel last night with some woman!
- Whoa! Hey, untrue!
They are just travel
friends. And she's ugly!
Why do you New Yorkers
have to be so unpleasant?
- I like New York.
- Put 'em up!
- Ben?
- Yeah?
Um, in about five minutes, we're
supposed to be joined for eternity,
and I was wondering...
if you were gonna get dressed.
Well, if it's eternity, it can wait.
No, no, I think technically
eternity starts immediately,
especially when there's
ice sculpture involved.
- Well, Bridge.
- Yeah.
The truth is-
I'm sorry.
This always happens
at weddings, you know?
I'm sorry I took so long to get
down here. Something happened.
It's okay. I know.
Debbie told me, and I told her that
it didn't matter because I trusted you,
and I knew you wouldn't cheat on me.
And then I threw up. But, um
- Everything else was going wrong.
Everything was going wrong,
and my parents are separated,
and then this guy Steve, who-
Bridge, you know what?
I always thought that there was this one
perfect person for everybody in the world.
And when you found that person,
like the rest of the world just
kind of magically faded away...
and the two of you would
just be inside this kind of...
protective bubble,
but there is no bubble.
I mean, or if there
is, we have to make it.
I just think that life is more
than a series of moments, you know?
We can make choices, and we can
choose to protect the people we love,
and that's what makes us who we
are, and those are the real miracles.
Stop me when it just becomes glaringly
obvious that I have no idea...
- what I'm talking about.
- No, I know what you're talking about.
I do. I know exactly
what you're talking about.
Farewell, Ben.
I fell in love with you
the moment I saw you.
And when I saw you up there on the balcony,
I fell in love with you all over again.
None of the plane crashes
and the hurricanes...
and the other people
will ever change that.
Because when I'm on my
deathbed, I'm gonna know...
that I married the only
woman I ever really loved.
I think you just wrote your vows.
I love you so much.
- Get her out of the rain!
- Guys, hold on.
You guys, it's only rain.
All right, all right.
I'm okay. I'll be right back.
- It's okay.
- Bridge! Bridget!
You wanna get married like this?
Let's go get married...
under a waterfall in Hawaii!
- Okay.
- Okay. Let's go.
Morning smiles
Like the face
Of a newborn child
Better said unknowing
Rejoicing
From the sight of a long lost friend
Speaks to me of course
But I feel
I have nothing to give
I have so much to lose here
In this lonely place
Tangled up in our embrace
It's nothing I'm not feeling how to fall
Wind in tow
Grapes the flow trembling on the vine
- Nothing needs to shelter
- Don't hit my house, bad lightning.
You're gonna burn us down!
But I feel
I have nothing to give
Well, there's one quote
that pretty much sums it up.
It's from a bishop in the 16th century.
He said, "Marriage has less beauty...
but more safety than the single life.
It's full of sorrows and full of joys.
It lies under more burdens,
but it is supported by
all the strengths of love.
And those burdens are delightful. "
I have nothing to give
Sometimes the people we
meet change us forever.
I've never forgotten Sarah, and
I'm pretty sure I never will.
Wherever she is, I
really hope she's happy.
In the end, all you can do is
commit to the people you love,
hope for a little luck...
and some good weather.
Hearts gone astray
Keeping hurt when they go
I went away
Just when you needed me so
You won't regret
I'll come back begging you
Don't you forget
Welcome love we once knew
Yeah
Where life's river
flows No one really knows
You're someone left to
show the way to lasting love
Like the sun it shines
Endlessly it shines
You always will be my eternal love
Whenever love went wrong
Ours would still be strong
We'd have our own Everlasting love
This love will last forever
Open up your eyes Then you'll realize
You've always been my everlasting love
Need you by my side Come and be my bride
Never be denied Everlasting love
From the very start Open up your heart
Feel the love you got Everlasting love
Everlasting love
If you're dumb and confused
And you don't remember
Who you're talking to
Concentration
Just seems to fade
'Cause your baby is too far away
There's a rose in a fisted glove
And the eagle flies with the dove
And if you can't be
with the one you love
Honey, love the one you're with
Don't be angry
Don't be sad
Don't sit quiet
Good times you had
'Cause there's a girl
Right next to you
She's just waiting
For something to do
There's a rose in a fisted glove
And the eagle flies with the dove
And if you can't be
with the one you love
Honey, love the one you're with
Do-do-do-do
do-do-do-do
Turn your heartache
Right into stone
'Cause she's a girl
A girl alone
So get it together
And you can fight
You're not gonna need any more goodbye
There's a rose in a fisted glove
And the eagle flies with the dove
And if you can't be
with the one you love
Honey, love the one you're with