Englewood. Englewood.
Anyone for Englewood.
Hello.
Mrs. Arbus?
That's right.
I'm Jack Henry.
Welcome to Camp Venus.
It's terrific to be here.
Come on in. Thank you.
I don't wanna be any bother.
Oh, no, not at all. We're
delighted to have a photographer here.
It's simply...
I n order to get permission, you
must take them off.
No one ever mentioned that.
And there are two rules.
Yes?- The first one is:
No erections.
And no staring.
I'm sorry.
Please, go ahead and disrobe,Ms. Arbus.
We're used to it. Aren't we, Jack?- Hm.
To tell you the truth, I need a
moment to myself, if that's all right.
I understand. - We'll leave you alone.
Oh.
How pretty.
Belonged to a friend.
Okay, boys, let's move them in.
Jimmy, get in the back. - Okay, boss.
Mother?
Grandma and Grandpa are here.
Thank you, Gracie.
Welcome to the Allan
Arbus Family Photo Studio...
...run by my son-in-law, Allan...
|My talented son-in-law, Allan.
...and his number one
assistant, my daughter Diane.
This also happens to be their home.
So it's a real family business.
We hope you'll all become part of our family.
Look! Mommy, look!
...Macy's, Bergdorf's and all the
other great stores across town.
Hello, Diane.
There must be someone moving in upstairs.
Clearly.
There was no way for me to know|this
would happen tonight, Mother.
Diane, we're holding the show here|this
year to help you and your family out.
I know. We're grateful.
Where did you get that dress?
Well...
...you gave it to me, Mother.
I gave it to you last year.
I n the living room, please, Merta. |
- Yes, Mrs. Arbus.
Easy, Jim.
Easy.
There we go. Hang on.
Hang on, hang on. Set it down.
You got it?
You okay?- All right.
Keep going, boys,all the way to the top.
Diane.
Not now. - Come on.
Here, let me help you with that, Rose.
Your father's already driving me nuts.
I know, Allan.
He wanted to trim it with monkey.
- A monkey?
I said no.
To all the greatest fur buyers in America:
My wife, Gertrude, and I welcome
you to my daughter's home.
Thank you all for coming.
She's really something.
Thank you all for taking the
time to join us this evening.
As you know, for the past 30 years...
...Russeks has been|the
biggest buyer of pelts...
...and producers of fur
garments in the world.
And like us, you all don't want
to let only New York ladies...
...have the luxury of world-class
furs. - I need gloves. Like this?
Now, do we?- Of course not.
So without further ado... - Finally!
...ladies and gentlemen,observe the fox.
Stealthy, luxurious,the colors of autumn.
Each individual coat truly a thing of beauty.
Lustrous, dark-hued,naturally cloud-soft.
Crafted with the distinctive
flair and elegant styling...
...women of discriminating taste
have come to expect from Russeks furs.
And the leopard.
The spotted and graceful
dancer of the jungle.
Notice the matching hat,
purse, mirror and cosmetic case.
This prestigious ensemble
will be the cornerstone...
...of our fall advertising campaign,to
be photographed, of course...
...by the Allan Arbus Family
Photo Studio which later...
There really isn't an occasion
when you can't wear leopard.
Friends, prepare yourselves...
...for the unbearably
soft appeal of chinchilla.
The silkiest and most sensual
fur that money can buy.
This one's jammed. Get me the
Hasselblad with the wide-angle.
Okay.
This delicate fur... - Excuse me.
...and certainly.
All set, Charlie. - Got everything?
That's it.
Good luck to you.
Diane? You got it?
What?- The Hasselblad.
Yes, yes. I'm sorry.
Come on.
Let's go upstairs for the studio tour...
...take a look at the wonderful
work my son-in-law's doing.
Vogue, Harper's Bazaar, Seventeen.
My husband has... Has shot campaigns for...
...Chock full of Nuts, Sunbeam|and many more.
But his main focus for the past 10
years has been the daily new Russeks ads...
...for my father's world-renowned
store that run in The New York Times.
May I ask, uh, what do you photograph,Diane?
Me? Um, oh, no, I'm...
I'm not the photographer.
No, my husband is.
But, uh, what do you do?
Um...
Well, I...
I take light readings and I,
uh... I... I... iron clothes.
I, um...
I provide straws for the models so that their
lipstick doesn't smudge, and I, uh...
...I accessorize their clothes.
I rearrange their hair.
I... It's not that much.
Diane, uh, do you have any
fashion tips for a friend?
Um, as a matter of fact, yes, yes, I do.
One's, um...
One's nails should, um... Should only
be slightly longer than the pads of...
Of one's...
One's fingertips, and...
For chrissake, what now?
Excuse me.
Are you all right?- I'm sorry.
Everyone, dessert is
served|downstairs in the living room.
Diane?
Uh...
I'm okay, Allan. I'm sorry.
Just need a moment. Okay?
Are you sure?
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
Diane?
Maybe you should take some time off.
Allan. |- I could hire an assistant.
I bought you that square-format
camera 10 years ago...
...you haven't even used it, Diane.
Maybe you could take a class.
Is that your secret?
Yes.
My answer is no.I'm not
gonna leave you during the day.
What's yours?
Come on, tell me. What's your secret?
I unbuttoned my dress on the porch tonight.
What?
Allan, I...
I don't wanna be like that.
Like what?
I'm your wife, I shouldn't do that.
Dee...
You know I think you're brilliant.
No, you think I'm strange... - No.
...that I can't be normal.
I never said that.
Even our own children think I'm strange.
I love you.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night.
What do you think?
I don't know.
I don't know. It's all so predictable.
You know we have the golf course in about 20 minutes.
With swimsuits and puppies.
The client's gonna love it.
Mm-hmm.
Mother?
Go ahead, take it. - Okay.
What is it, Grace?
There's something wrong with the plumbing.
I need you to turn off the
main water valve, the big one...
...and bring me Daddy's
tool kit and a bucket.
You're a good girl. - Okay, Mom.
Uh, Grace, tissue.
Trash.
Oh, yuck.
Oh.
Ew!
What was that?
It's nothing.
Okay, Gracie, let's go.
Taxi!
Yes?
Are you washing a dog?
Excuse me?
Do you have a large dog?
A dog?
Your dog's hair is in my pipes. It's
causing problems with the plumbing.
Perhaps you should check the basement...
...Diane.
Hello.
Are you a new neighbor?
I'm a friend of Lionel's. - Lionel?
The man who lives upstairs?
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll, uh, get out of your way.
Time to sleep now, Gracie.
Okay, Mom.
Allan.
Christ, what is that?!
I fixed my drain for you.
Thank you.
You still think I have a dog?
I have 10 dogs.
I don't think you have a dog.
I haven't seen any dogs going up the stairs.
I'm not feeling very well right now. I can't find my rabbit.
Oh, okay. Then I'll, uh...
|I'll... I'll come back later.
You saw me the night I moved in, remember?
Yes.
I definitely saw you.
You trying to seduce me, Diane?
No.
No. - No?
God, no.
Is that why you came up
here|in the middle of the night?
I, um...
Well, I would like to, uh...
I'd like to take a portrait|of
you and your... Your wife.
I don't have a wife.
Well, then I would like to
take a portrait of you, just you.
When?
Now.
It's not a good time for me.
Come back tomorrow night at 9.
Tomorrow?
Okay.
Do you have trouble sleeping, Diane?
Actually, it's "Diane. "
Why would you want to take a portrait|of
someone you've never seen, Diane?
Most nights I have trouble sleeping.
Did you get the key?
The key?
Diane, come back tomorrow night at 9.
Hey, watch it, Vern.
I forgot something.
Looks like gin rummy.
Foo-Foo, don't you bother Donald,
now,you keep still for Mummy.
They're adorable, aren't they?
And such beautiful coats.
I'll be to bed soon, darling.
I...
I thought I'd go for a walk.
Okay.
Be careful.
Lionel?
Hello?
Do not go near him,ladies and gentlemen.
He has taken lives already.
In captivity, we have the upper hand.
But isn't Lionel a good doggie?
Drink a cup.
Turn around.
Don't look at me.
Take off your camera.
Just put it on the table.
Please close your eyes now.
I only wanna take your portrait.
Diane...
...please close your eyes.
Step back from the window.
Are your eyes closed?
Yes.
Don't turn around. Keep your eyes closed.
And please disrobe. - What?
You can keep your undergarments on if you like.
The bath is getting cold.
I don't want to.
I think I should go.
I'm sorry.
Hello.
Take anything in your tea?
Now, tell me something.
Tell me something about yourself.
Are you rich?
You look rich.
My parents are.
So you were a spoiled child?
Did you eat caviar? Did you have servants?
Yes.
What were their names?
Scott was my chauffeur...
...Gisela was my German nanny,and
Catherine was my French nanny.
Did you ever show your nanny|your tits?
Now, when you were a teenager...
...there must have been a doorman you
made love to in the basement...
...or a chauffeur, a
gardener,|an elevator man?
Did you ever give him a blowjob on
the way down to the lobby?
No. - No?
Did he want you to?
Well, did he?
Probably.
How could you tell?
I...
He used to stop the elevator between floors.
And?
And stare at me.
Did you like that?
It terrified me.
Of course, but...
But did you like it?
One time I showed him my underwear.
So? Then I'm right.
Chauffeured girls don't expose themselves.
They don't show their tits.
Don't they?
- I don't know. Do they? You tell me.
Where have you been hiding?
I suppose I did. I exposed myself.
Till my father caught me.
Where did this occur?
I n the bathroom. - To whom?
To the neighbors.
I would touch myself in front of the window.
Really?
Did you ever see anyone watching?
I saw you...
...through my window.
And right away I wanted
to come into your home.
And when you were young, did
anyone like me ever come to your house?
There was a little boy. He had...
He had a purple birthmark across his face.
I saw him in the park and I...
I followed him all the way|to
his front door in the Bronx.
But he disappeared before I could...
Shortly after that, I dropped
doing that sort of thing.
And I planned on going so many places.
Where?
All sorts of places, everywhere.
Where? Tell me.
A doll hospital...
...the city morgue...
...the insane asylum...
...dumps, flophouses, everywhere, I...
And instead,I was my husband's assistant.
Join me?
Would you like to|take off your slippers?
Wanna step in?
My condition is called hypertrichosis.
When I was a teenager, I woke
up every morning at 5 a. m...
...to shave every part of me that
stuck out from my clothing.
Grew back so quickly it
was hardly worth the effort.
Besides, it made me prickly.
Would you please close your eyes again?
Can I trust you to keep them closed?
Yes.
Well, just in case, put this on.
Do you like to go swimming?
Yes.
Did you get the key?
That little boy...
...was so beautiful.
Have a cookie.
I must be brave.
I must be brave. I must be brave.
Twenty, 19.
Oh, my God!- Good morning.
I'd better go.
Sleep all right?
Lint brush.
Thank you.
Will you come back?
Do you want me to?
You still need to take my portrait.
Tell me a secret.
I wanna live in a big house someday.
Out of the city.
With a big back yard and a dog.
Leaving Manhattan gives me hives.
Tell me another secret.
I actually had a dream we
were gonna have another baby.
A baby?
Huh.
Now it's your turn. What's your secret?
I think I'm ready to take some
time off from the business.
Really?
What are you gonna do instead?
I'd like to take some photographs...
...of my own.
Of what?
I don't know.
Our neighbors.
Good. Yeah.
I think that sounds great.
Allan?
Is it okay?
Sweetheart, it's wonderful.
Thanks, sweetheart.
Where you going?
Just up to the neighbors. I...
I thought I'd try Mrs. Rebushong first.
Eat your broccoli, Sophie.
Who is she?
She is, uh, Althea.
Oh.
Uh, she's, uh...
...an admirer.
An admirer?- Yes.
Who does she admire?
At me, I guess.
Why isn't she your girlfriend?
Well...
She doesn't touch me.
Goddamn it.
Hey.
I'm here.
Lionel?
I'm here for the picture.
I'll be right there.
Hi.
Take off your camera.
-We're going out.
- Now?
Come on.