Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
She saw me first
completely naked.
We were only seven, but
yet I have such feeling.
I played for first time
doctors and nurses with her.
She saw my cock
and did not run away screaming.
Anyway, Allison and I
were made for each other.
So I knew
that when she was moving ...
that fate
would bring us back together.
Berke.
Berke Landers.
I agree. Allison McAllister.
Of all canteens in the world
precisely they walked inside the mine.
It was perfect. I was dating
with the most beautiful girl.
And we played still governor.
I was the first time in my life
love and it would last forever.
Was I just an idiot.
We need to talk.
You know, everything in life ...
even the nicest things ...
eventually comes to an end,
right?
Trends persist,
moldy bread ...
people die.
I mean ... Remember
we met for the first kiss?
That feeling those butterflies in your stomach?
If we kiss each other now ...
was feeling, frankly,
more or less disappeared.
I've already packed all your stuff. That
makes things easier, I thought.
My parents, Frank and Beverly,
present "Love Matters."
That sounds cool.
This is for both partners
a good scolding.
And you have eye contact.
Coolio, you want one sometime?
We are right back.
Here are the CD's, Mom.
Guests are angry
if you do not know their CD.
You were home early yesterday. You okay
okay between you and Allison?
Not really. Can we talk?
- You know our rule.
If we are not happy ...
- Never mind.
What is it?
Frank, and Allison Berke
have problems.
Communication Problems?
- Limits on the scan?
Dependency?
- No, it's not.
Sex is.
She dumped me.
Poor guy.
I would rather not talk about.
I want to go home.
- It's good.
That's right. Look at that to
all those beautiful ... Is that my little sister?
Hey grab happy, feet home.
That's my sister.
Should you not for a pajama party?
I'm a year younger. He received
pink roller skates on his birthday.
It was a nice gift.
Have I anything to you?
Come on. That boy there
set free navel piercings.
Okay, here it is.
- So?
I said I was out of town. As
he sees me, he goes by 't lint.
You're Fri
There must get used to it.
You had him to see. It takes a while
before it has processed.
Have you already incorporated?
Allow me.
Who is that?
Are you first in the U.S.?
- Well, Lucky. So hot you?
Hear what it sissy says?
My father was a diplomat. I lived
abroad. Shanghai.
And I have acted in Amsterdam
Swing Town with The Lads.
He was already so familiar to me.
- He talks like Madonna.
She is here.
- Who? Madonna?
It is perfect.
- You are not going her.
Then you give her your dick
onto a platter.
If you do, you will
its slave. You do not want.
Felix, I piss sometimes longer
then take your dating.
Okay?
- I think so.
It is wild to it.
Luckily I could catch you.
I'm also glad.
Will you dance with me?
She is your friend anymore.
- And that's not so bad.
Later, go to my other school.
Sometimes you wanted to marry her?
Who does that?
- Tell me not Macaulay Culkin.
I call her.
Do not. Do not be so familiar.
You've called her for forty times.
Aside.
He calls himself Striker.
# Love Scud? #
What he said when he gave this to you?
Oh, he asked them if I went out.
You should not so lightly
Duplication.
I think he is a splatter.
Not believe that you was dating him.
Hear that? The neighbors scream al
Now go along.
Just look from where you fall.
A little more left.
Other links.
Go to your feelings and turn t then
at. How hard is it not?
I stand there alone.
- I'm scared of you
I love you. Do you understand?
How you dress you?
Do you have servants for?
A Midsummer Night Rock?
Shakespeare
with a touch of contemporary music.
How did you get this number?
He has no taste,
if he hates us.
Both.
Lazario, your brain surgery successful?
What are you happy.
Did your exam or something?
No, I had a 5, 7.
Shit. Heavy shit, man.
- It is annoying, nothing more.
For example, I hear. If they
who wants to flap his turd, let her.
Provisional.
- What do you mean?
If I lose all Allison,
it is not such a turd flap.
He has something to fall Allison.
You're asleep, Landers.
Nice diversion, "crazy legs".
Someone with such emphasis
take it seriously?
Listen, give up on the nou.
No way. I
Back Street Blow Jaw who remembered that.
Knap caught with your head. Soon
you shoot three-pointers with your ass.
Berke, let me have a look.
- Go back train.
Berke, talk to do with me.
How can you replace me now
by that guy?
Nobody can replace you.
It was just time
to try something new.
So everything goes well
between you and the Striker?
No, it's just different.
Know what I mean?
He is different than other boys.
He has developed.
We even participated in the auditions
for the spring musical.
You hate musicals.
False.
King of the Elves of row
Helena is near here.
I see no ball.
What happened to your face?
- Long story.
A Midsummer Night's Dream?
Will you audition?
Maybe.
I want to help you best, though.
- Are you serious?
You know her songs?
She is the new Josie Mitchell.
Joni Mitchell.
- I can help.
Shall we drink morning coffee?
- Seems a good plan.
"I want to help you best, you know."
Did you see Dennis back at me?
You must pick a monologue
for your audition.
This is good. Lysander.
She sees not Hermia ...
Wait. You should not everything
row chant.
Never mind. We start again.
It is difficult, but the story
is actually pretty good.
Hermia, it is a girl ...
lives in Athens
with her dominant parents.
She has everything. Beautiful clothes, a
intact skin, and boys galore.
Of all the boys in Athens ...
her heart belongs to
the noble Lysander.
But Demetrius appears
the scene.
Hermia's father has promised her to
him. He is as handsome as Lysander.
Maybe even prettier. And
He does everything to get to Hermia.
Lysander may therefore be shaking.
I understand.
You put it very well.
We are beginning.
I do not oscar, Kelly.
I want my girlfriend back.
Hello. How are you?
All new faces.
I am Dr. Desmond Forrest-Oates.
Head drama and much more.
The intention is that today
separating the wheat from the chaff.
Who knows is there among you are
a new star.
The next Peter Wong,
I say.
Hi, Petie. Cool T-shirt.
Who is not selected,
not despair.
You could always behind the scenes
work. That's nice.
Just kidding. I could not resist.
You turn me on to.
The procedure is simple.
We begin with the singing audition.
Discard the loose diaphragm, for now
it is time to impress.
Nice.
Who wrote that song?
Myself.
You expect applause? This is
an audition, not a television show.
Who is next?
Bentley Scrumfeld.
He is a member of The Swing Town Lads.
You know your boys groups.
- I follow the music closely.
I like them so well.
I would like to accompany me.
- Write on.
This is my favorite song.
He is the best so far.
Very well, Mr.. Striker.
Very impressive.
Well, this was it.
- Wait.
Who are you?
- Berke Landers. I'll audition.
Ah, Berke Landers. Lucky me briefly.
I read a monologue
Oberon in 't Act III.
Very happy.
But first I want to sing.
We sing first
and later we nominate.
Jessica, help me.
I sink into quicksand with that guy.
Sing first, then read.
No matter which song?
- That's right.
Projection, Mr.. Berke.
Can the little louder?
What are you doing?
- Nothing. Chester riding the ficus.
Is it a bike?
No, the dog of my aunt
staying here.
And it is hormonal upset.
Kelly is at home?
Kelly, your sister. Is that home?
Why?
- She has helped me. Give at her.
Well. One moment, please.
Since when
my friends call you?
Since today.
How did you find me?
You were not bad.
I thought you knew
you had to sing. You were cute.
Tell it to Allison.
I hope that you can play along.
I hear you gasping.
Warning. Staff.
Just go my way.
Move, please.
Sorry.
Demetrius, great.
HART, Hermia.
- Are you serious?
The school goes out of his roof, people.
Dance group? Worthless stuff, say.
Helen?
Good news?
- Sorry, but I did like that role.
That's just good.
Look, there you stand.
I hope that servant three
No need to sing solos.
Congratulations, Miss Woods.
It is a key.
- I know.
That you can better
not blow it.
Bobby DeNiro once said to me.
Well, I read in one article.
He said: The fact that God
has blessed you ...
does not mean
that there is never anything can go wrong.
Anyway. Until Thursday
the rehearsals. You too.
Dr. Forrest-Oates,
that is a problem.
Next week
the basketball play-offs.
Listen, mister.
This is your stage debut
and take you seriously.
All of your game is half as much as I
have given to this production.
, Or not. That is the question.
Those were my glory days.
Although it is not bad.
Thursday. And no more excuses,
mans sport.
Come on, Jessica. Come on.
Excuse me, I am teacher.
Where you going, Landers?
So Lysander loves Hermia
and they of him ...
but she is promised to Demetrius
Helena who is in love.
What a hoot, huh?
The breaks from pleurisy.
Mickey Rourke once said ... He was
a feast of Liza Minelli.
Mr. Landers, glad you're here.
And thanks that you have not showered.
Super.
The secret is obviously
that the four young lovers ...
their own destiny
not in their hands ...
because living in the forest ...
- Fairies.
Fairies, right.
These are spirits, of course.
In particular, Titania, Oberon and Puck.
Little Stevie.
- Steven.
They enjoy it for
playing with human feelings.
It is interesting to see
how those elves ...
Look, we have wings.
- It comes from your ass fairy dust.
Come along, monkey.
Hermia, you are so sexy and everything.
Hey, Red. Follow us.
You see us, but you must
obey us, bunch of suckers.
Someone flirts with you chick.
Give him ass.
Demetrius, what are you doing here?
Lysander, give to my right
your feeble claim.
En garde.
- They do not fight in this document.
Now.
Hell with, you.
From bad to worse.
Are we dreaming?
A musical? You call my sister?
- It helps me with things.
My sister?
- She did understand.
This is not about her.
You sit still behind Allison
on. And that's ridiculous.
See you on the field.
We need somebody else to find him.
Difficult. Just take those old woman from
# Titanic. # She never came over.
I mean not just anyone.
You do it with technology Dora Lynn?
Last week they shot
to anyone with a staple gun.
It is not useful.
- Thanks to Dora Lynn ...
Dickie is standing Berg Well poop.
We ask her
to an apartment building.
Why would she doing?
- That's your problem.
Berke I edit it.
Dennis heard it.
That girl on your kicks.
Nonsense.
- Why should I invent?
This is a great opportunity.
The Stanley Cup for blind dates.
Those eyes, that mouth, those breasts.
- Do not forget anything?
Well, she is clumsy.
She's a disaster. Everywhere she goes,
accidents happen.
Rare accidents, I mean.
She could not go to school six years.
She was in coma.
Berke, she is pretty.
She has a great body.
And they shall not appear to require.
What could be wrong with her?
Your turn to get the ball.
- No way. Get you 'm only.
Would you like to do something for me?
- What then?
Berke, not nervous.
I am own free will.
We never really talked.
That was because I
too busy with Allison.
You had your hands full with that whole ...
- Coma-stuff?
You know, Berke. You just
start again.
I would bring misfortune.
That was then.
I pick up the thread of my life
again. And you must do.
Would you like to excuse me?
I must ... because
Pee?
Can I have some tea?
Oh, what a great music.
Tits.
Bill, please.
This is not good.
I'd be lying,
but this is three times nothing.
I want to hear emotion.
"I wish I could pick." I
want to see you pluck, you understand me?
Theseus enters.
Servants, a lover makes love
the daughter of your lord.
That is outrageous.
You are shocked.
Look shocked.
I said shocked, Mr.. Landers.
Not if you can not poop.
Dear heavens. Go ahead, Del.
Now, let the hunters them
with horns wake.
You would have let me know
if you had had a stroke?
Are you lost?
I've specified as stagehand.
Then you hear where to sit.
Say I confused, sir?
It's like I still dream.
I came with Hermia into the forest
Athens to leave ...
to go to a place where our
The Athenian law is not threatened.
Keep that but for the premiere.
- Sorry.
I would like to know
you do here ...
but if a stranger my friend
would steal, I would do the same.
Only I 'm involved here.
You drop your sword.
Sorry.
I have a big game.
Exchange.
There was an accident.
- You have luck.
Next week the play-offs.
Give them their Thurs
I just go.
Play more comfortable.
At home we have no real piano.
You only busy, huh?
Yes, I was in my bare ass
on the field.
For love.
Play something for me.
It sounded good.
- I am ashamed.
I like to write songs.
- What is it?
Forrest-Oates finds
my number nothing.
I admire you because you
that vulnerable stage draw.
I thought it was a very beautiful song.
This is a song of mine.
Boaster.
Berke, what do you
of half naked women?
Where are we going?
Dennis and I have discussed
and we find that you need it.
We got special guest
tonight.
A young man by his girlfriend
is put aside.
See ya, casanova.
What is that?
- Monday we always crazy, people.
Behold my tasty body
in this corset.
Police.
ID cards, and some quickly.
Can someone let me fall?
Please.
We are astonished.
The police are not calling every day ...
stating that your son
was picked up into a sex club.
Your father and I have discussed
and we are incredibly proud of you.
Because you pick up your life again.
Most children can not.
You do. You climbed back on your horse,
harness or should I say?
I am arrested.
Are not you angry?
Why? You're just curious.
We did not realize you were so perverse.
Who wants frozen yogurt?
Berke might want to go home
It's a crazy jerk.
Make me frozen yogurt.
Pull her up.
Ladies and gentlemen,
prisoner number 6943.
Well done, Landers.
You're photogenic, you know.
Take care with your accent.
You sound like Mary Poppins.
What are you talking about?
If I were you ...
Do you have makeup on?
That's it.
Watch out, Landers.
Your spot on with your life.
Who nou fighting sticks
in his pants?
Peter Wong was injured.
How fortunate you are singer
and not a dancer.
I kill you,
oetlul pretentious.
This is my theater.
My version.
Forrest-Oates is my boyfriend.
That was intense.
I've never
see a bone sticking out so far.
Everything will be okay
according to the nurses.
Peter will soon
will walk again.
As Kevin Spacey once said:
The show goes on.
The premiere is already over three days.
Those who sign up to volunteer
the role of Lysander?
Hand away, little Steve.
You already have a role, Striker.
I know,
but I want to nominate someone.
I feel very flattered ...
but a man of 34
you can not keep pace.
I had honestly
Berke Landers on the eye.
Very interesting. Has anyone
a useful idea? Hand away, Steve.
He is inexperienced, but he does have
a certain kind of enthusiasm.
I do it.
You do it? -Yes.
But fixed ordering pizza, Jessica.
Keep that ice on your buttocks.
Otherwise, the swelling worse.
I need you, but not really.
What we have swords?
- Seven.
Kites, eight.
If Allison does not appreciate this ...
- What then?
You know your text well.
Yes, but then my singing?
- My song sucks.
Rewrite it.
- I never pick Forrest-Oates.
You have
more savvy than he.
That he sees differently.
He gave me a key.
He is an idiot, Allison.
My name is Kelly.
What did I say? -Allison.
Nietes.
Sorry. -I shoot you dead.
That thing is dangerous.
Put it's gone.
It is my white boy
with an arrow in his arm.
I thought he was not real.
I want to see it.
It looks awful, huh?
The physician makes your arm and better than
play the stars of heaven.
Your arm does not look so ...
Oh, my God.
Thursday, Kelly
quarter to twelve at you.
Felix, but it is Kelly.
She helps me to rehearse.
Keep her in the eye.
These actors are all ...
Gay?
- That they are not.
I love her in the eye.
When your parents go away?
- Today. Forget it.
You want to organize a party.
I should have a look inside.
What should he a music store?
- Tap dance shoes.
And that proves once again ...
that man needed to celebrate.
You have the pressure,
but can I talk to you?
Miss Woods, come inside.
What a nice hair clip.
It's about my song.
"Pocket full of dreams."
I wrote that song
for Diana Ross.
Miss Ross,
I have a swinging song for you
You are in my hand, buddy.
Unfortunately interfered lawyers
with it.
And then there was a lot of chatter.
And before you know,
The deal does not.
It is a good song.
I like to sing.
But would you mind if I
place a few comments?
A few comments?
Oh, long slow night
accelerate ahead.
I thought, as you said:
The song does not.
Would you do me a favor?
Read again what is on that poster.
Eating and drinking is forbidden ...
It reads: Twelve songs
composed by Dr. Forrest-Oates.
Oh, that? -Yes.
It does not say: Numbers rewritten
by Miss hellion.
The text of Shakespeare.
Which song do you know yet from Macbeth?
Bill Shakespeare's a great poet,
but he is not Burt Bacharach.
Sorry I'm late.
- Does not. I'm taken.
We have
find a girlfriend for him.
What was Forrest-Oates?
- An even bigger jerk than I thought.
Maybe you do to brighten it.
- A present?
First rehearse. Good?
Still 21 hours to go and I start
worse still sing.
We let the songs for what they are.
We carry the text.
Theseus has just
awakened everyone.
In this scene you play and Hermia.
I pretend I'm Allison.
That will not be easy.
- Go ahead.
Theseus says: Now, let the hunters
awaken them with horns.
Hermia and then says: "And I am everything,
were as conspicuous shared.
And I saw everything twice.
I know.
Say I confused, sir,
't bring me a reproach ...
It is me, if I still dream.
I came with Hermia into the forest ...
planning to leave for Athens
for a place ...
us where the Athenian Law
not threatening.
And then they kiss each other.
So I will kiss Allison.
But in this case ...
Let me guess, Berke was with you.
Felix, where are you?
- On a party.
Berke Tell them to go.
Everyone asks about him.
We need to your home.
I'm impressed.
The turnout is not against.
Where is Felix?
Take deep breath,
otherwise you completely flip.
I'm looking there.
- I will murder him.
Look at, by my player.
- Have you seen Felix?
You sound tense.
Got stage fright?
Or are you in love with you-know-who.
How about the party?
- What I think of it?
What do you mean?
- What you see in the Minkukel?
Go back to the porch
light and put it orally.
This is Striker.
- Until the show.
What is this?
- Nothing. I plague her.
I get this to myself.
- He takes you to, that's different.
You better go.
You think I Allison
would cheat?
Where is the food?
Is it me,
or bowl tastes weird?
There are lumps in.
I was wondering where you were.
I just want to talk about Striker.
You never keep up, huh?
You can all drop dead.
Hi.
Sorry about this festival.
My brother is quite a jerk.
Rather.
I'm thinking to give away
he leaves his sex hidden.
That was a joke.
Kelly, why are you with me for?
You might have better things to do
than to raise a loser.
You're not a loser.
- Allison thinks so.
Allison is a stupid bitch.
I've really done everything
for that girl.
They just do not understand.
I can not.
Kelly, I think your great,
but I can not.
You're the sister of Felix.
Fuck.
Kelly, wait.
So what I meant.
What was that?
- It's not what you think.
What is it?
Why am I suddenly happy
that we previously left?
I knew nothing about a party, Berke.
Otherwise we paid a deejay.
- Put your furniture well again?
Judy just pooped in our pool
and you want a deejay?
Why are we so cool.
We trust you.
You are my parents.
Stop it.
Poor Judy.
- I'll get the shovel.
Interesting.
- It wasn 't.
I saw it myself.
He kissed you.
I do not know why.
Berke is somewhat confused.
I kissed him.
It is indeed quite confused.
He loves other ...
but that's my problem, Felix.
I'd be lying if I said
I enjoyed it.
But Berke has not
how wonderful you are ...
he has a problem.
I agree. Berke.
I wanted to thank you for any help.
All songwriters
Using such a thing.
If there is anyone who called
can improve, it's you.
I believe in you, Kelly.
Toi, toi, toi.
Let's deal with mortals
again.
This will him
and think.
Give the sourpuss only my dose.
- Wake up.
And I'm gone.
In the forest
where the delicious smell ...
I will meet my Lysander.
Maybe you should
dreaming about someone else.
You were the first.
Nobody can replace you.
I've enchanted your ex-girlfriend.
You were the ultimate couple.
She is your friend anymore.
I pick up the thread of my life
again, and you too.
We make him mad?
- Yes, we do.
The costumes of the servants there.
- Thank Buddha.
Your wife called,
they can not come tonight.
She said why not?
- She talked rather incoherent.
And there is something, sir.
Del Molden Junior is sick.
- My dance partner? Shit.
You go wash your mouth.
He has spoiled drinking bowl.
He can not occur.
Not that it matters, because this
production is a fiasco anyway.
That said, does anyone
role of the drunkard to play?
Fine. Is there anyone at all
who can dance a little?
A dance step, a twist,
or some nice movement.
The basketball coach
calls me sometimes 'crazy legs'.
Really, dude?
Wait a minute. Take it
one half only to turn back.
Follow me.
This I learned
by watching.
Should you not prepare you?
- I'm in the grime.
You must do something for me.
Ladies and gentlemen, take place.
The show will begin.
It's over. After this performance
I stand on the street.
Remove the canvas but on the comedy
which is a great tragedy.
I pray for you
have you ever
read a piece of Shakespeare
and there is nothing to understand?
but after tonight
you everything is clear
as Shakespeare may be dead,
We are here
William Shakespeare wrote a lot,
very long time ago
on the beautiful Hermia
and the two boys who adored her
They said Hermia, marry me
but she wanted only one
the fairies come at night
out and the ball tonight
because I love him
- And I love her
he could handle him
and therefore
devised the elves a list
in this Midsummer Dream
See, here comes Helena.
- The beautiful Helen.
You call me beautiful?
Recall that clean anyway.
What Kelly looks beautiful.
Demetrius and Lysander
love you, Hermia.
Oh, happy clean.
Word, Hermia, softened.
Lysander, give to my right
your feeble claim.
You have her father's favor Demetrius.
Marry him and leave me Hermia.
You married him?
Bastard.
- Asshole.
You really feel the tension.
- Tell me about it.
Why do not you like me?
there is a girl
that says she loves me not
that's the girl I go for
Look, she has everything
what a girl should have
and therefore I do not understand
why they do not love me
Hermia, I make sure
you are in love with me
you going to give me
never
one girl was so much me
I beg you, Hermia
Please love me
Bitch. -Flicker.
Asshole.
In your eyes
This powerful juice flows down ...
and if you wake up ...
then again tastes you salvation, top level
if you see your former sweetheart.
About 20 minutes are you on canvas.
I want to talk to you.
Just walk with me?
I could eat a drink.
Keisha, you are not suitable
for. She wants a blow up doll.
I sometimes call them for advice.
- Really?
Yes, I had pimples on my balls.
Not anymore, though.
Gentlemen, would you do me a favor?
In the fourth act, first scene,
is a special effect.
That huge flash, you mean?
- Right. Does this thing make?
No, a whole village
destroy.
I wonder if you do not
could ignite a bit earlier.
Mr. Dan is. Landers still there?
We let 'm just scared.
I give you a sign.
Sorry I did not believe what you said about Striker.
Too bad you this way
had to come back.
I have no right
to ask you something ...
but if I could make a wish ...
I wish
that everything was as before.
We are friends again.
As for the rest of ...
that would be handed over to fate.
Did I mention that you are
$ 47 could earn them?
Not bad.
Mr. Scrumfeld, we agree.
Remember it well, gentlemen.
If I throw up my sword ...
The music was good, but you know
that song Pocket full of dreams?
We call it Pocket full of ass.
- That's it. The number is adjusted.
This is different.
A spell is pronounced.
The lovers sleep.
While she rests, grows the love of
Demetrius for the beautiful Helen.
Oh, long slow night
accelerate ahead.
Come, comfort me a while,
I forget myself.
let me sleep
because when I sleep,
I dream that you are with me
you are mine,
and all my fears are gone
I float in the air
the nightingale whistle a beautiful lullaby
So let me close my eyes but
and sleep, and perhaps to dream
I see that face again
I want to caress
and cushion
but that happens only
in my dreams
So let the moonlight shine
the boy
to whom I wish
and when he dreams
perhaps he dreams of me
I look at the clouds
and I whisper
against the twinkling stars
they tell me that love
just a dream away
So I keep dreaming
Now, let the hunters them
with horns wake.
Say I confused, sir?
It is my dream as I have.
I came with Hermia into the forest ...
to a place where the Athenian Law
We no longer threatening.
However ...
What?
- But?
Lord, we are endlessly
sleep, as you surely know.
Things change,
and love blossomed.
The soul will always Hermia
associated with mine ...
but unfortunately we
goodbye forever.
Because my heart
belongs to another.
Ho nou a minute.
It was not easy.
You can not just text
change. It should not be reconciled.
Well, I can do that.
Sometimes it along, sometimes it is against.
What do you say that?
Stop cheering.
Do it now.
What do I do?
Applause.
Are you crying?
- No, you press on my wound.
Do write it this way.
You took aim at my chair, right?
Admit it.
- A little.
You see, stouterd.
Great.
Moment.
I'll be back, I promise.
You're so in love with my sister, huh?
You're not bandy?
- No, but I'm not happy.
But if they do get a boyfriend
will, I'm glad it's you.
Well done. It was really laughing.
I must really go.
- Do you have something with Dora Lynn?
Are not you afraid that ...
- An accident?
No, Dora Lynn
has now finally happiness.
Bye, guys.
Let's go get Chinese.
That's okay. Nothing wrong.
He flew at least 6 meter
off of the stage.
And when they rose
as a beautiful rocket.
What it looks burnt.
- Tomorrow we'll do it again.
What did you think of my stage debut?
Especially in the end it was nice.
- Yeah, I was good, huh?
Tomorrow we play again.
- How is it off?
We can gum song
sing again.
I'd rather get shot.
- I thought the bow was not real.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org