- You got all your stuff?
- Yeah.
When you get there,
be sure and call us.
- We want to know where you are.
- All right.
- How are you fixed for money?
- I'm okay.
You better take this 50...
in case you run
into a little trouble.
You never know what's gonna happen
between here and there.
Thank you.
Boy--
Don't worry too much.
It's just the smart people
that have to worry.
The Lord will take care
of the ignorant ones.
- You paying attention?
- Right.
See you.
Any person who alters...
forges, knowingly destroys...
knowingly mutilates...
or in any manner
changes this certificate...
may be fined not to exceed $10,000...
or imprisoned
for not more than five years...
or both.
When the moon
Is in the seventh house
And Jupiter
Aligns with Mars
Then peace
Will guide the planets
And love
Will steer the stars
This is the dawning
of the Age of Aquarius
Harmony and understanding
Sympathy and trust abounding
No more falsehoods or derisions
Golden livin' dreams of visions
Mystic crystal revelation
And the mind's true liberation
Excuse me, ma'am.
Could you spare some change?
That's a great hat you've got.
Can you spare
a couple nickels or dimes?
Beautiful horse.
I've never ridden a horse.
Is it difficult?
Would it be possible for me
to ride it a little ways?
Just once, for a minute?
Lady, could I ride--
Come on. Please?
Woof, forget it.
I'll get you one for Christmas.
Spare some change?
You know,
like nickels, dimes, quarters?
- You want me to give you some money?
- Right.
Why?
No reason, except she's pregnant
and we haven't eaten for two days.
I don't believe you.
- Where you from?
- Oklahoma.
I know how it feels.
I used to come from Kansas.
Sodomy
Fellatio
Cunnilingus
Pederasty
Father, why do these words sound
So nasty
Masturbation
Can be fun
Join the holy orgy
Kama Sutra
Everyone
Get the horse!
Stop the horse!
Go get them!
Once upon a looking for Donna time
There was a 16-year-old virgin
Oh, Donna
Looking for my Donna
I just got back
from looking for Donna
San Francisco's
psychedelic urchin
Have you seen
My 16-year-old tattooed woman
Heard a story
She got busted for her beauty
And I'm gonna show her
life on Earth can be sweet
Gonna lay my mutated head
at her feet
I'm gonna love
to make love to her
Till the sky turns brown
I'm evolving
Through the drugs
That you put down
Looking for Madonna
Yeah
Man, you're a real cowboy.
Don't get off. We still got
15 minutes left. Take off.
- I got some things I gotta do.
- Yeah? Like what?
I want to see
the Empire State Building.
Then tomorrow, I want to go
on that boat ride around Manhattan.
- You see the Statue of Liberty.
- Sounds real good.
If you have any ideas
about things to do while I'm here--
I don't have too much time.
I'm going in the army
in a couple days.
I think we can help you.
Hashish
Cocaine
Marijuana
Opium
LSD
DMT
STP, BMT
A&P, IRT, SPC
- Alcohol, cigarettes
- Claude.
Here, man.
Claude, speak to me.
Is she really pregnant?
Yeah, I am.
That's what she says.
"That's what she says."
That's what she knows.
- I am.
- Jeannie, you don't know anything.
- I know who the father is.
- Yeah?
You know that, you know a lot.
If the baby comes out white
and squishy, crying his ass off...
then we know Woof
is definitely the daddy.
But if he comes out all beautiful
and chocolate brown...
that's mine.
- "White and squishy"?
- Yeah, man.
He come out and see
your crazy black ass standing there...
he's gonna be spitting
watermelon seeds in your face.
You always open up your mouth
before you even think.
Look, when this baby
comes out and sees me...
he's gonna be so happy
and so proud.
Do you know what he'll say?
I'm
A colored spade, a nigra
A black nigger
A jungle bunny, jigaboo
Coon, pickaninny, mau-mau
Uncle Tom, Aunt Jemima
Little black Sambo
Cotton-pickin' swamp guinea
Junk man, shoe shine boy
Elevator operator
Table cleaner
at Horn and Hardart
Slave, voodoo zombie
Ubangi-lipped, flat nose
Tap dancer, resident of Harlem
And President
of the United States of Love
Bad shit
If you invite this man to dinner
You're gonna have to feed him
Watermelon, hominy grits
and shortening bread
Alligator ribs and pig tails
With some black-eyed peas
Lord, chitterlings
Collard greens
And if you don't watch out
the boogie man will get you
Boo
Yeah, I'm talkin' about y'all
So you say
Say something to boogie man.
Go on.
Boogie man.
It's his first day in America.
He just got off the boat.
Did you have a nice trip?
Manchester, England
Across the Atlantic Sea
And he's a genius
He believes in God
And he believes that God
believes in Claude
That's him
Claude Hooper Bukowski
Finds that it's groovy
to hide in a movie
Pretends he's Fellini
and Antonioni
And also his countryman
Roman Polanski
All rolled into one
I believe in God
And I believe that God
believes in Claude
That's me
I'm black
I'm pink
I'm rinso white
I'm invisible
Ain't got no home
Ain't got no shoes
Ain't got no money
Ain't got no class
Ain't got no scarf
Ain't got no gloves
Ain't got no bed
Ain't got no pot
- Ain't got no faith
- Look here, man.
Ain't got no mother
Ain't got no culture
Ain't got no friends
Ain't got no schoolin'
Ain't got no shine
Ain't got no underwear
Ain't got no soap
Ain't got no A-train, Ain't got no mind
Ain't got no smokes
Ain't got no job, Ain't got no work
Ain't got no coins
Ain't got no pennies
Ain't got no girl
Ain't got no ticket
Ain't got no token
Ain't got no God
Yeah
Ain't got no grass
Ain't got no acid
Ain't got no clothes
Ain't got no pad
Ain't got no apples
Ain't got no knives
Ain't got no guns
Ain't got no garbage
- Ain't got no draft card
- Burn it
Ain't got no Earth, Ain't got no fun
Ain't got no bike, Ain't got no pimples
Ain't got no trees
Ain't got no air, Ain't got no water
City, banjo, toothpicks, shoelaces
teachers, football, telephone
Records, doctor
brother, sister, uniforms
Machine guns, airplanes, germs, M-1s
Bang, bang, bang
M-2, bang, bang, bang
Where you going?
I got a lot to do today.
Thank you.
What?
I want to show you something.
What is it?
Just come here, please.
- What?
- Look at that.
- That's the chick on the horse.
- That's not her.
What do you mean?
Look at it.
Short Hills.
It's real close.
- That's today?
- That's right.
You want to go?
Why?
Don't you want to meet her?
Don't you have
to be invited to those?
Would you like to come
to a party with me?
You guys spread out. Mingle.
Sit, my dear.
Steve?
- Great party, huh?
- Yeah.
There's an odd-looking
character over there.
And here to the right,
that chap over there.
That colored gentleman over there
with the girl.
See those two girls there?
Do you know them?
Why don't you just
unobtrusively...
see if you can find out
who they are, how they got here...
who invited them,
and come back and let me know.
Sure thing.
Hi, I'm Steve Wright.
- What's your name?
- Hud.
Are you supposed to be here?
- I mean, who brought you guys?
- Mr. Berger.
Enjoy the party.
They're with Mr. Berger.
- Mr. Berger?
- Yeah.
Who's Mr. Berger?
I don't know.
Don't even suck on it
if you don't want to burn your lips.
- Now?
- Now start puffing on it.
- There. See?
- Sheila?
Just a minute.
What's taking so long, love?
- We're smoking grass.
- I'm getting dressed.
Sweetheart, come on. You have a lot
of people waiting to see you.
Will you relax, Daddy?
- Hurry up.
- What's going on here?
- They're getting dressed.
- Open the door this minute!
- I'm taking care of it.
- I can see you are.
Yes?
There's no excuse
for this performance.
Hello.
Excuse me.
Mr. Berger?
- You can call me George.
- I think that it's a private party.
I think you and your friends
better leave, please.
- You do?
- Yes, I think that's the thing to do.
Excuse me, everybody.
Everybody, please quiet down.
I think that you and you're--
I just wanted to say a few words,
then we'll go.
- I don't care what you have to say.
- I know. Everybody, listen.
We weren't invited to this party--
I just want to talk for a second.
- I don't care about that.
- I know you don't care.
- I think you better leave.
- Please, just give me two minutes.
All right?
- Please.
- No, I think you better go.
I'm losing my patience.
This is a private party.
-You were not invited. You better leave.
-You don't understand.
- I have nothing to understand.
- You have something to understand.
You don't understand what this man
will be doing for you.
- I don't want to hear about it.
- You should hear about it!
- You know what he's gonna do for you?
- I don't care!
You should care because
he's gonna be fighting for you.
He's going to Vietnam to fight for you,
to save your life!
- I want you out!
- You should care!
If you want me out of here,
you'll have to throw me out.
That's exactly
what I'm gonna do.
I won't muss myself up
fussing with you.
I'll get the police if I have to.
Penguin.
Now, my friend, Claude, here
is in love.
He saw this chick on a horse--
- Excuse me.
- Jesus.
Now, let's deal with this
as gentlemen.
- Quietly.
- Good.
- May I give you a word of advice?
- Yeah.
Get your ass out of here, now.
Is that it?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
Now, listen.
Claude here is in love.
The girl he's in love with
is sitting in this room.
He just wants to sit here
and look at her for five minutes.
He just wants to look at her
and have this picture in his head...
when he's off there fighting
in the jungles.
Is that so much to ask?
This is for you, man.
Wait a minute.
This is what you want.
Sheila, is that okay if Claude
just sits here and looks at you...
for a few minutes
before we go?
You've got a hell of a nerve,
young man.
I got life, mother
I got laughs, sister
I got freedom, brother
And I got good times, man
I got crazy ways, daughter
I got million-dollar charm, cousin
I got headaches and toothaches
And bad times too
Like you
I got my hair, I got my head
I got my brains, I got my ears
I got my eyes
I got my nose
I got my mouth
I got my teeth
I got my tongue, I got my chin
I got my neck, I got my tits
I got my heart, I got my soul
I got my back
I got my ass
I got my arms, I got my hands
I got my fingers, Got my legs
I got my feet, I got my toes
I got my liver, Got my blood
- Watch out!
- Oh, my God!
Got my guts
Got my muscles
Lafayette Johnson.
Jeannie Ryan.
Woof Daschund.
The court is about to pronounce
sentence upon each of you.
The sentence of the court:
You be confined to the workhouse
for 30 days...
or pay a fine of $50.
Your Honor,
I don't think you understand.
We haven't got any bread.
I'm sorry.
There isn't anything I can do.
- Your Honor?
- Yes, sir?
What if one of us has the money?
- Which one?
- I do.
You may proceed
to pay your fine.
Proceed to the clerk's office.
- Excuse me, Your Honor.
- What's your name?
Wait a second.
Put down George Berger.
- Bukowski.
- Just one second. Claude, listen.
Let me get out of here.
I'll go and get the money.
- Then I'll get everybody out.
- This is my money.
I'm sorry, but my dad gave me
this money in case of trouble.
- This is trouble.
- Don't be stupid, man.
This is your last chance
to get us out of here.
Just stop it. This is mine.
I'm getting out of here.
- Don't you trust me?
- Of course not.
Look, man, don't be stupid.
How will you get the bread?
You don't know anybody on the streets.
He's not. He's just gonna leave us
in here to rot, that's all.
- I can make some calls.
- Yeah, call my mama.
You better know what you're doing.
You sure better, George.
What's that?
Excuse me.
You're in our way.
What?
You're blocking our way.
Would you move, please?
Sure.
Hi. Remember me?
Yeah.
Come on in.
We have to get to school.
Great.
Just get in, will you?
What do you want?
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Jesus Christ!
What do you think you're doing?
You can't drive this car!
We're only covered for Dad and me.
I got a little problem.
I need some bread right away.
It's $250.
I need it now.
- This is all about money?
- Yeah. You got any?
We really don't have
any time now.
We've got to be at school.
So will you just stop the car?
Just let me drive.
- What do you want me to do?
- Tell him to stop.
Stop.
My friends are still in jail.
You could ask your old man
for the bread to get them out.
- Ask my father for the money?
- Yeah.
Right.
He got us into this.
At least he could get us out of it.
- He got you into this?
- Yeah.
He told you to dance on the table
and break all the dishes?
There's a left here
at the bottom of the hill.
- I think you're really crazy.
- What are you talking about?
The man got the kids in jail.
We want the money to get them out.
- Coming up is a left.
- It's impossible.
- Why is it impossible?
- He won't even give me a credit card.
- With that house you live in?
- It's coming up here!
- Two hundred and fifty dollars.
- Right here!
Turn left! Right here!
Jesus! You missed it!
What did I miss, Steve?
The school.
It's back there.
I'm sorry.
We'll help you, okay?
We'll try to get you some money.
So you can stop the car now,
and I'll drive.
- When?
- Right after school.
About 4:00.
We'll have it for you at 4:00.
That's my other problem, man.
- What?
- You're full of shit.
You won't ask your old man for
the bread, and Junior is full of shit.
What am I doing here?
- And men?
- What do you mean?
Do you have any sexual attraction
towards men?
- Am I a homosexual?
- Yeah.
I wouldn't kick Mick Jagger
out of my bed...
but I'm not a homosexual.
Can you tell me why you're so uptight
about having your hair cut?
She asked me why
I'm just a hairy guy
I'm hairy, noon and night
Hair that's a fright
I'm hairy, high and low
Don't ask me why
Don't know
It's not for lack of bread
Like the Grateful Dead
Darling
Give me a head with hair
Long, beautiful hair
Shining, gleaming
steamin', flaxen, waxen
Give me it down to there
Hair
Shoulder-length or longer
Here, baby, There, Mama
Everywhere, Daddy
Hair
Grow it, Show it
Long as God can grow it
My hair
Let it fly in the breeze
And get caught in the trees
Give a home to the fleas
in my hair
A home for fleas
A hive for the buzzin' bees
A nest for birds
There ain't no words
For the beauty, the splendor
the wonder of my hair
Flow it, Show it
I want it long, straight
curly, fuzzy
Snaggy, shaggy, ratty, matty
oily, greasy, fleecy
Shining, gleaming, steaming
Flaxen, waxen
knotted, polka-dotted
Twisted, beaded, braided
- Powdered, flowered
- And confettied
- Bangled
- Tangled, spangled
And spaghettied
Oh, say can you see my eyes
- If you can
- Then my hair's too short
- Down to here
- Down to there
Down to where
it stops by itself
They'll be ga-ga at the go-go
When they see me in my toga
My toga made of blond
brilliantined, biblical hair
My hair like Jesus wore it
Hallelujah, I adore it
Hallelujah, Mary loved her son
Why don't my mother love me
You know, Danny's mother said
Danny said to say hello.
He's in second year
of dental school...
and the girl he's dating
is beautiful, nice.
It's got a lot of mayonnaise,
the way you like, both sides.
- Eat it.
- Thanks, Mom.
- It's good. Eat it.
- I will.
Give me your pants.
I'll wash them.
- Why?
- They're dirty.
They're fine.
They're not dirty.
It'll take a minute.
The pants are fine, Ma.
What do you say, Pop?
What do you say, what?
Nothing, Ma.
- If you need money, get a job.
- You talking about money?
- What do you need money for?
- Nothing, I just need it.
- Who is she?
- Who is who?
- The girl?
- What girl?
- Who is the girl?
- There's no girl.
You can tell us everything.
We understand everything.
What are you talking about?
I just need some money.
If you need the money,
tell us the truth.
What are you talking about?
Goddamn it. Every time
you come home, there's trouble.
Why don't you clean yourself up?
Why don't you get a haircut?
Get a haircut,
and I'll give you the money.
You'll give me the money
if I get a haircut?
For Christ's sake,
do something to make us happy!
- What?
- Will you give me $500?
- Give me your pants!
- My pants are clean!
They're clean,
for Christ's sake!
How much you need?
The draft is white people...
sending black people...
to make war on the yellow people...
to defend land they stole...
from the red people!
LBJ took the IRT
Down to Fourth Street, USA
When he got there
What did he see
Tricky Dick on LSD
FBI
CIA
Come on.
Wait, Berger!
- How you doing?
- How are you?
- All right.
- Listen, first...
I want to apologize for Steven.
He's very young,
and he really doesn't understand.
Tell me who do you love
Man
Tell me what, man
Tell me
What did you love, man
Old-fashioned melody
Listen, I was thinking.
Would you like to get married?
What?
- To whom?
- Me.
I'm having this baby,
and, if you were married...
the Army couldn't take you--
They wouldn't take you because they
don't take people who are married...
and having a baby.
We're all encased in sonic armor
Beltin' it out
through chrome grenades
Miles and miles of Medusan chord
The electronic sonic boom
It's what's happening, baby
It's where it's at, Daddy
They chain you and brainwash you
when you least expect it
They feed you mass media
The age is electric
I got the electric blues
Folk rock, rhythm and blues
Do you, Sheila Franklin
Take this man to be
Your lawful wedded husband
I do.
Do you, Claude Hooper Bukowski
Take this woman to be
Your lawful wedded wife
I do.
I now pronounce you
man and wife
Hare Krishna
Krishna
Hare
Hare Rama
Rama
Love
Drop out
Be in
Take trips, get high
Laugh, joke and good-bye
Beat drum and old tin pot
I am high on you-know-what
Marijuana
Beads, flowers
freedom, happiness
Right there.
Are you all right?
Where you been?
Where have we been?
Where have you been, man?
Watching the water.
Let me see your eyes.
Let me see those.
My God, black basketballs.
Look at my face.
Look at the sky.
Look at the stars.
- See the stars?
- Look at that.
Everybody,
a shooting star right over there.
Quick, everybody, make a wish.
Will you take me home now, please?
Why do you want to go home?
It's Claude's last night.
Right?
Are we going to do something?
- Yeah, we'll do something.
- Yeah.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
It's Claude's night.
What do you want to do?
Take Sheila home.
She's all yours.
Have a good time.
- I'm just taking her home.
- I know.
Have a good time anyway.
Come on, Jeannie.
Come on.
Get your pants off and come on in!
You want to go home?
- You're just taking me home, right?
- Yeah.
- No, you know what I mean.
- I'm just taking you home.
Because nothing's gonna happen.
No, I'll go home by myself.
No, I'll take you home.
- I don't feel like it.
- Why not?
I don't have to explain everything
to you...
do l?
Come on, Claude!
The water is filthy.
Listen, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be so--
I'm really sorry.
I wasn't trying to upset you.
That's all right.
It's just sometimes I get so--
I understand.
Are you upset?
No, you are.
I'm sorry. It's my fault.
- You're going away tomorrow, right?
- Yeah.
So, what's the point?
You mean, if I wasn't going away,
it would be different?
Maybe.
- I might not go.
- Right.
- You expect me to believe that?
- I'm serious.
Forget it.
I don't believe you.
Where did everybody else go?
They're around somewhere.
Jeannie's still up there.
Where are our clothes?
Where did they take them?
Funny.
You guys are so mature.
Don't look at me.
I didn't have anything to do with it.
Don't worry about it.
They're around.
Taxi!
Don't go! I've got your purse!
Sheila, wait!
I don't believe it, man.
What happened?
What the hell did you do that for?
- It was fun, man.
- Fun?
I'm really sorry.
I didn't think she'd ever
pull a stunt like that.
We know where she lives.
We'll give her clothes back tomorrow.
I won't be here tomorrow.
Are you still serious
about that shit?
That's none
of your goddamn business.
It is my goddamn business, man.
What do you want?
You want to be a hero with a gun,
a big macho dude in a uniform?
- Is that what you want?
- I can't talk to you.
I'm standing right here.
Talk to me.
I think you're ridiculous.
I am ridiculous.
I'm totally ridiculous.
I'm ludicrous.
I don't want to go over there
and murder women and babies.
Go ahead and be ridiculous,
and I'll do what I have to do.
Who are you doing it for?
I'm doing it for you, man.
Don't hand me that.
Don't do it for me.
If the shoe was on the other foot,
I wouldn't do it for you.
Give me my clothes.
How will she get home? She doesn't
have her stuff. She has no bread.
You better get that stuff to her.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Wasn't that what you wanted?
You're telling me
I'm ridiculous?
Where do I go
Follow the river
Follow the gulls
Where is the something
Where is the someone
That tells me
why I live and die
Follow the children
Follow their smiles
Is there an answer
In their sweet faces
That tells me why
I live and die
Follow the wind song
Follow the thunder
Follow the neon
In young lovers' eyes
Down to the gutter
Up to the glitter
Into the city
Where the truth lies
Follow my heartbeat
Follow my hand
Where do they lead me
And will I ever
Discover why I live and die
Why do I live
Why do I die
Tell me why
Tell me where
Next.
- Woodrow, Sheldon?
- Yes, sir.
Everything off, please.
Your socks.
Have you got some problem
with your socks?
No, sir.
Then take them off.
Sergeant.
Black boys are delicious
Chocolate-flavored love
Licorice lips like candy
Keep my cocoa handy
I have such a sweet tooth
When it comes to love
Once I tried a diet
Of quiet rest
No sweets
But I went nearly crazy
And I went clearly crazy
Because I really craved for
Chocolate-flavored treats
Black boys are nutritious
- Black boys fill me up
- Up
Black boys are so damn yummy
They satisfy my tummy
- Black
Black boys
White boys are so pretty
Skin as smooth as milk
Hair like Chinese silk
White boys give me goose bumps
White boys give me chills
When they touch my shoulder
That's the touch that kills
- My mother calls them lily
- Mama says lilies
- I call them picadillies
- Picadillies
- My daddy wants me to stay away
- Daddy
But I say come and play
White boys are so groovy
White boys are so tough
Every time they're near me
Just can't get enough
White boys are so sexy
Sexy
They're so long and lean
Love those sprayed-on trousers
I love the love machine
My brother calls them rubble
They're my kind of trouble
My daddy warns me no, no, no
But I say white boys go, go, go
White boys are so lovely
Beautiful as girls
Love to run my fingers
And toes
through all their curls
Give me a tall
- A lean
- A sexy
- A pretty
- A groovy
A juicy white boy
Yeah, give me a white boy
- White boys
- Yeah
White boys, come on
and lie down beside me
Doors locked
Blinds pulled
- Lights low
- Move it!
Flames high
My body
My body is walking
In space
My soul is in orbit
With God face-to-face
Floating, flipping
Flying, tripping
Tripping from Pottsville
To starlight
Tripping from starlight
To moonville
Red black, Blue brown
- Yellow crimson, Green orange
- Trainee.
Purple pink
Violet white
White white
All the clouds are cumulus
Walking in space
Oh, my God, your skin is soft
I love your face
How dare they try
To end this beauty
They keep us underfoot
They bury us in soot
Pretending it's our chore
They ship us off to war
In this dive
we rediscover sensation
Walking in space
we find the purpose of peace
The beauty of life
You can no longer hide
Our eyes are open
Wide
How you doing?
- I'm all right.
- Yeah?
Look, I've got something.
Where is he?
Nevada.
So, I was thinking
of writing him.
- What do you think I should say?
- I want to say something.
Tell him that--
I want to say that Jeannie says hi.
You're gonna write him?
Why don't you come with us?
- Where are you going?
- Nevada.
We are?
Aren't you serious about anything?
I'm always serious.
When are we going?
As soon as Sheila's ready.
I can't just take off
and go to Nevada.
I guess not.
- We'll see you.
- Wait a minute.
- How will you get there?
- Car.
- You don't have a car.
- I'm gonna get a car.
- Lafayette?
- How will you get a car?
What are you staring at?
And who's that?
What are you doing here?
Come on.
- I said come with me.
- I heard you.
I'm asking you,
who is that woman?
- Are you a friend of my Lafayette?
- I ain't Lafayette no more.
- Don't bother her, all right?
- What have you done to your head?
Never mind.
Just go on back home.
Is that his child?
- Don't be talking to her.
- Is that your child?
You wouldn't understand.
What do you mean?
ls that your child or isn't it?
What kind of question is that?
Maybe it is and maybe it isn't.
What?
I knew you wouldn't understand.
You don't understand anything.
I understand just fine.
You explain it to me.
Do you understand about cosmic
consciousness and all that shit?
That's what I'm talking about, baby.
All I'm talking about
is Lafayette Junior here is your child.
I just want to know
if that's your child too.
Never mind that.
Come on!
- Where are we going?
- I'm taking you to the bus.
- You're going back home.
- I don't want to go home!
You're going back home.
Understand me?
- I want to stay with you.
- You can't.
- Why not?
- Because you can't. I said so.
Look, we've got a friend in trouble,
and we have to help him.
Baby, that's all you need to know.
Why don't you just go home?
I never said you couldn't
help your friends, Lafayette.
Goddamn it, woman!
I ain't no Lafayette!
Shit!
Don't you understand nothing?
How can people
Be so heartless
Be so cruel
Easy to be hard
Easy to be cold
How can people
Have no feelings
You know I'm hung up on you
Easy to be proud
Easy to say no
Especially people
Who care about strangers
Who care about evil
And social injustice
Do you only
Care about the bleeding crowd
How about a needing friend
I need a friend
How can they ignore their friends
Easy to give in
Easy to help out
Who say they care about
Social injustice
Hi, Steve.
Come out of the car.
- I just want to talk to you.
- You want to talk? Talk.
I'd like to talk to you outside.
I don't want to talk to you.
Don't worry about a thing.
I'll handle this.
- What do you want?
- The keys.
Cool out, baby.
- You're taking the car?
- Just for a few days.
- Coming with us?
- No, I'm not going with you!
- All right.
- Sheila, come on.
Out of the car. What--
I'm not into any heavy
preference trip...
Iike who the father is.
I don't care.
I think they're both beautiful.
Don't you?
But how can you not care
about that?
If a woman carries a child, don't you
think she should know who the father is?
I admit that I have this dilemma.
But it will be resolved real soon.
It's not like a big crisis or anything.
It's not like a world war.
I don't know
what you're so uptight about.
I fell in love with someone.
We had a child,
and we were gonna get married.
That's why I'm uptight.
- Yeah?
- And you're holding it up!
I'm not holding it up.
You don't see the way it is.
This is really a great thing
that's happened to all of us.
Everybody's really happy about it.
The guys are really happy.
I think it would be great
if you could be happy about it too.
- You're crazy.
- Yeah, I'm crazy.
We're all crazy.
Let's shake on it.
Let's not.
Come on.
If all you men could be standing
where I'm standing...
and seeing what I'm seeing...
you'd know how it feels
to be truly proud of our country.
The United States Army...
is the greatest fighting force
in the world.
And now, you men...
are going to be thousands of miles
away from home in a few days.
You'd better take some
of that greatness with you.
And this afternoon,
while you're on leave...
you'd better take some of it
with you too.
Sergeant!
Shut the damn thing off!
Ripped open
By metal explosion
Caught in barbed wire fireball
Bullet shock
Bayonet
- Electricity
- What do I turn off?
Move out!
- Electronic
- Attention!
Data
Processing
Black uniforms
- Company!
- Attention!
Mail order
Rifles
Get some results!
Two hundred
And fifty-six
Vietcong
Captured
Prisoners in Niggertown
It's a dirty little war
Three, five, zero, zero
Take weapons up
And begin to kill
Watch the long, long armies
drifting home
Everybody out!
- Company!
- Attention!
Now can all you men hear me?
Good morning, starshine
The Earth says hello
You twinkle above us
We twinkle below
You lead us along
My love and me
as we sing
Our early morning singing song
Singing a song
Humming a song
Loving a song
Laughing a song
Sing a song
Song a sing
Song, song, song
Sing, sing, sing, sing, song
- Hi.
- What can I do for you?
We're going in.
There's no civilian contact allowed
on the base right now. We're on alert.
We're not civilians.
We're friends of a guy on the base.
You probably know him.
He's a private.
- I don't know him.
- Really nice guy with blonde hair.
- He's short.
- I don't know him...
but you'll still have to turn
your vehicle around and go off post.
If you need some help,
I'll be glad to assist you.
Otherwise, back your vehicle up
and turn it around.
Listen, we don't want
to make any trouble.
- Turn around and you won't.
- Just let me make a phone call.
You don't make it here.
You make it where I tell you to go.
You just said you wanted
to give me some assistance.
I'll help you turn around.
That's all.
- You don't understand--
- Chief, this is it.
Turn around and go.
We clear?
- You get my drift?
- You don't understand, man.
- You don't understand.
- We've driven five days straight!
- Listen, my man--
- I just want to see my friend.
I'm telling you
to get the hell off my post.
Turn around and go that way.
That's what I'm telling you.
You listen to me.
I'm not listening to you. Got that?
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
- What's your name?
- George.
- What's yours?
- Sheila.
Yeah?
- Is your husband on base?
- I'm not married.
I'm visiting my brother.
Wait a minute.
Okay, this time I'll do it.
That was a good one.
Let me do that again.
I'll blow one,
and then you blow one...
and see if they can,
you know--
You blow one
through one of mine.
Very good.
Where is your car?
Right over there.
God Almighty.
Let's pull over there.
Let's stop here.
Company, halt.
- Dismissed.
- "Dismissed"?
You cutie-pie!
Come here, my cutie!
That's my hat!
What are you doing?
Hey, baby!
How do I look?
Very authentic.
Company!
- Yes, Sergeant.
- Let's move it out.
Double-time, soldier.
- Sir?
- In the car, soldier!
- Are you an asshole, soldier?
- No, Sergeant.
That's too bad,
because I am.
How you doing, man?
I want to be an Air Force major
I want to live a life of danger
- Stay in the car.
- What are you doing?
- Get in the trunk.
- What?
- Get in the trunk quick.
- Why?
Everybody's waiting. We have a big
picnic planned for you in the desert.
- Come on, get in.
- The base is on alert.
They're taking head counts all the time.
If I'm not here, I've had it.
It's just for a couple of hours.
I'll have you back in time for dinner.
- I can't.
- What do you mean?
We just drove 2,000 miles to see you.
Everybody is waiting.
Just trust me.
I have it all figured out.
You're making it sound
like I don't want to come.
Then come.
Get in the trunk.
I can't believe you're here.
I just can't believe it.
Traveling all that way?
I appreciate your coming here.
I can't tell you.
Don't tell me, just come with us.
Just get in the trunk.
You don't understand.
This isn't a game.
What will I tell everybody?
- Did Sheila come?
- Yeah.
- And Jeannie?
- Everybody is there, man.
How is Sheila?
What are you doing?
Give me your clothes.
Attention!
At ease!
Sound off when your name is called.
Here, sir.
Give me your attention, men.
I just received word we've been
alerted for overseas movement.
I want you to secure your web gear,
get your duffle bags packed...
and get on this red line.
Sergeant, you have three minutes
to have these men ready.
Let's go, men.
Move with a purpose.
Let's get it all quickly.
Let's snap to it
like you got a pair.
Let's go. Move it, quickly.
Get on the red line.
Get your duffle bag packed.
Let's go over there.
What the hell's wrong with you,
soldier?
Didn't you hear
what the captain said?
Get your helmet liner!
Get your pistol belt!
Get it right now!
Let's move like you got a purpose!
Get the doggone coat on!
Quickly! Let's go! Move it!
I don't know what's the matter with you.
You act like you don't want to go.
I don't want to go, but if you have to
go, I have to go. We all have to go.
So let's move it right now!
Let's get on the red line.
Let's go.
What are you waiting on?
Get that web gear on!
I want that brain bucket on your head!
I want that duffle bag on the red line!
Soldier, there's a war on!
Listen up!
When I call your name,
sound off smartly and move out!
Yes, sir!
You better get your head
out of your ass! Let's go!
This way, soldier!
Move out!
You better move, soldier!
Where are you going!
What's the matter with you? I said
put your duffle bag on that truck!
The vehicle right there!
Get it on there now!
We starve look
At one another
Short of breath
Walking proudly
in our winter coats
Wearing smells
from laboratories
Facing a dying nation
Of moving paper fantasies
Listening for the new-told lies
With supreme visions
Of lonely tunes
Somewhere
Inside something there is
A rush of
Greatness
Who knows what stands in front of
Our lives
I fashion my future
On films in space
Silence tells me secretly
Everything
Singing our space songs
On a spider web sitar
Life is around you and in you
Answer for Timothy Leary
Dearie
Let the sun shine
Let the sun shine in
Why don't you let the sun shine
Just let the sun shine in
You ought to let the sun shine in