I go for a walk along the creek,
watch the fishes
in the bleak water.
I am sad because of you,
my dear Saniye
with the waving hair.
I am sad because there’s no
love in your eyes.
I am sad because of you,
my dear Saniye
with the waving hair.
I am sad because there’s no
love in your eyes.
Cahit, are you fine?
Do you want to drink something, Seref?
Yes, coke.
Give me another beer.
You are thirsty today, right?
Yes, pal.
Why don’t you drink water then?
I’m not an animal.
How was the concert?
Piss off, Maren.
Asshole!
Fuck you!
- Motherfucker!
Hey you!
Hey tramp!
Hey, I'm talking to you!
Such a hot chick
and you drive her off?
Are you a queer?
Seems that you are gay- ...
Are you fucking insane?
Piss off Cahit! Go home!
Stop that bullshit!
Go home!
Go home now!
My bitch brought me here.
She said to Schiller that
she was afraid of her husband.
What am I?
"I'm afraid of my husband!"
She's so false!
But I know the right people.
I will take it out of her.
What kind of people?
- Security guys.
I'll get her down.
She doesn't know what she's up to?
Last time I was here too.
- You were 13 too ...
Cahit Tomruk please.
There are thousands of ways to kill yourself?
Why do you drive against a wall?
Who said that I wanted to kill myself?
There's no skid mark.
You are not allowed to
smoke here, Mister Tomruk.
Where does the name Tomruk come from?
- From Turkey.
I mean what does it mean?
No idea...
- The names always have such a nice meaning.
Really?
Yes. Much more as our names here have .
At least for the first names I know it for sure.
If you want to bring your life to an end just do it.
But you don't have to die that for.
Bring you life to an end
and move away.
Do something useful.
Do something.
Go to Africa.
Help people.
Do you know a band called "The The"?
Pardon?
They have a song
"If you can't change the world, change your world"
You want me to bring you the record?
- Got it already.
Am I allowed to say something Doc?
You are nuts?
Are you Turk?
Would you marry me?
What?
Piss off!
Nice to meet you,
Cahit Tomruk.
Cahit Tomruk... Sibel Tomruk...
Excuse me,
are you looking for something?
A beer.
Sorry we don't have beer.
But you can have a coffee.
The shame that you have brought
on us is inexcusable.
The biggest gift
for a human being is life.
There is no bigger gift
then life.
Who do you think you are that
you throw this gift away so easily?
You can be glad,
that you are still alive.
Do you have the key, Yilmaz?
See you later...
Can't you see what you do to him?
He perishes.
Look at me!
If something happens to dad I kill you.
Give me one too.
There’s no sense in suicide.
The only thing you achieve
is to make us and you sad.
Do not forget that.
I thought that they let me be!
Let you be? Couldn't I teach
you anything!
Don't say that mother.
Oh, Sibel...
How long are you going to stay here?
- I don't know.
Don't panic with all this
lunatics in here!
You don't die like this.
- How don't you die?
Perpendicular.
- What perpendicular?
You have to cut perpendicular.
Perpendicular sux.
- I see
Can you get me a beer?
If you marry me?
I only fuck men.
- Really?
You know what? I'll get you a beer.
Tonight at midnight in front
of the hospital. Ok?
Where's my beer?
- Follow me.
Where in Turkey do you come from?
- Mersin
I was told Mersin is beautiful.
- Yeah I know I'm born there.
We come from Zonguldak.
You know Zonguldak?
Why do you want to die?
I asked you something.
Do you like my nose?
Touch it.
My brother broke it because he
saw me holding someone's hand.
And now touch my tits.
Have you ever seen so hot tits?
I wanna live Cahit. I wanna live
I wanna dance I wanna fuck
not only with one guy.
Do you understand?
I'm not deaf!
Bullshit!
Do you marry me now Cahit?
- Forget it!
Shit!
Are you fucking crazy girl?
That's not a game!
We pretend to be married.
Do you understand?
- No I don't!
That's just an excuse for my parents
so that I don't have to live at home.
Ok we live together but
I promise I'm a good roommate.
I go shopping, cook, tidy up
the rooms, clean the restroom.
We have separate rooms, we don't fuck, we don't have anything together.
- And your parents?
They are just your parents-in-law.
You don't have a close relationship.
Relationship? We don't have a relationship at all?
From time to time they come
to our place and we come to theirs.
And then we pretend to be wife and
husband or how did you imagine this?
Why me?
Because my parents would
accept you. You are Turk.
What's going on?
Get off!
Why?
l said: Get off!
Because in my bus.
There is no space for godless
dogs like you guys!
Get off, you too!
What's going on?
That's not even your bus.
It belongs to the city council.
Piss off!
Hey wait!
What’s your name?
She has a window to the street.
Her admirers throw little
stones on her windows.
My dear is the one
with the most beautiful eyebrows.
Look for a lover too
and sum up your bride money.
Tell me, are you completely insane?
Are you an actrice?
Do you want an Oscar?
You do not understand that:
She is in troubles.
That's non of your business
I don't know?
Otherwise she wants to kill herself.
Bullshit!
As if that would be so easy.
That's women!
In order to soft-soap you,
they tell stories.
Do you know what it means to get married?
- No, I don't know.
Problems!
Look at me. Am I married?
No. I don't owe anyone anything
and I live in peace.
You lie. You got married!
That's different.
That was in order to stay here.
Basically that's the same.
Then get married,
for gods sake!
God blesses you! I'll be at
the wedding and dance with you.
One more thing...
- What?
Birsen?
Do you know this guy?
- No, but our daughter knows him.
She knows him then.
How can you give our daughter
to a foreigner?
She made many mistakes.
Maybe it becomes better now.
She made mistakes,
because you spoiled her like that.
Since she was a little child!
When do they come?
- Whether you want or not: Tomorrow.
Tomorrow already?
They are supposed to come,
for gods sake!
You only get us into trouble!
From which city
do we come once again?
From Mersin.
Not Malatya?
- No, man. It was Mersin.
Fuck your Mersin.
Friends, what's wrong with you?
That's not you fucking business!
Do you have to yell like this?
- Hurry, I'm queued too.
Just a second.
- How do you talk with me?
Sorry. Never mind.
Ok.
There is no alcohol
in the chocolates, right?
No.
- Sure?
Do you wanna bullshit me?
Really? - Holy shit,
there's no alcohol in there!
Fuck your alcohol!
With alcohol they are too expensive anyway.
Don't yell at me!
That was just a question!
You ask 100 times the same shit!
Which house number?
- 8.
How does you hair look like?
- That's new fashion.
That is a proposal and
you look like a fag!
They wont give you their daughter like this!
What was the name once again?
- Güner.
So you are the uncle of Cahit?
Yes... That means,
I'm his youngest uncle.
How many siblings are you then?
Ehm... just a second... we are a lot...
Seven.
- Yes, seven.
Respect!
You are your nephew all over.
May be.
Where do your parents live?
My parents are... dead.
My condolence.
Thanks.
Do you have any siblings?
Yes,
I have a sister in Frankfurt.
Don't you see each other?
Yeah...once in a while.
You don't have a proper Turkish!
What happened?
I dumped it.
That was a joke!
Is there any alcohol in
the chocolates?
No, no! Of course not.
Where do you come from?
From Malatya.
From Mersin.
That's because, a part of the family comes
from Mersin, the other part from Malatya.
They moved from Mersin
to Malatya...
What a scattered family!
- Yes, exactly!
Thank you.
- l hope it tasted good.
Where did you meet my sister?
I work in the hospital.
Cahit visits me there from time to time...
like two or three times a week...
Once he visited me and saw Sibel.
Well and then we decided to buy chocolate.
You are the manager of a factory?
- Yes.
Actually I'm the manager of 'the' factory.
That's an event and culture location in Altona.
I'm the boss there.
- I will come and visit you.
Yes you are welcome.
Isn't he a little bit too old for you?
I like him.
Couldn't you find a better one?
We ate and drank.
Thanks a lot. - You're welcome.
Let's get to the main topic.
We came,
with God's permission
for my nephew Cahit
to ask you for the hand of your daughter.
Sibel!
Yes, father...
Did you decide?
Yes, father.
What can we do?
When two young people agree
and like each other.
What shall we say?
God bless you.
- Thank you.
Cahit, kiss your father's hand.
Thanks.
I'm coming already!
Are you crazy?
- Hi Cahit.
Do you have coffee?
The coffee machine is gone.
Tell me, a Turkish mariage
costs a shitload of money, right?
Who is going to pay that?
- I got the money.
Where from? - I always knew that one day I will
run away from home. So I saved money.
Damn, why didn't you do it?
Because of my mother.
- Oh yea.
Is your sister going to come?
- No.
Why? - That's none of your fucking business.
Who is your witness to a marriage?
Your brother?
My cousin Selma from Istanbul.
She's hot you know ... - I don't fucking care
And she brings a pack of Turks with her?
No, she comes alone. She is divorced.
To get rid of me we could do the same thing.
- Good idea.
Here you are! - What's that?
- I guessed so I don't know if it fits.
You guessed right.
I missed you!
- How was your flight?
They searched me again for drugs.
Where is my brother-in-law?
- He's busy...
Let me have a look. Your ass became nice.
Where did you meet?
That's a long story.
- Tell...
Where should I begin?
- At the beginning.
Selma.
- Cahit.
Take care of them.
Thanks. - What shall I do now?
Kiss you? - Later
What?
- Later.
Sibel Güner,
Born on June 16th in Hamburg,
marital status single, German citizenship.
Is that correct?
- Yes.
Cahit Tomruk, born on August 25th 1960 in Mersin
Turkey,
Marital status widowed, German citizenship.
Is that correct?
Yes that is correct.
- Then you can go for the wedding ceremony.
How did you wife die?
Cahit!
- Shut the fuck up! Am I clear?
What's going on?
- I didn't understand.
Don't you speak German?
- Yes I Do.
We meet here to celebrate the wedding
of Sibel and Cahit.
Welcome.
Let's ask the couple
with your applause
to the dance floor!
Cahit we have to dance.
- I don't dance.
But we have to!
- No we don't, ok?
Please Cahit.
l beg you.
Cahit the people are looking!
You German slut.
- Yes that's me.
What's that.
- That's your room.
You are going to eat here.
- Allright.
I pick you up in half an hour.
- Allright brother.
You want as well?
Yes.
Don't you wanna carry me into the room?
Hoppaa!
May I ask you a question?
- yea sure.
How was your wife called?
What's up?
Get lost!
Piss off now!
Katharina.
Get me another one.
- Actually I wanted to close down now.
Already?
Well everything has to come to an end?
Do you know where I can sleep tonight?
How about your husband?
He drove me off.
- Super...
Well if you want...
You can sleep at my place.
But only if you want.
Are you aware that you steal a bride?
You mustn't get married,
there are so many alternatives.
Tell me one.
You could have studied.
in of another city.
As if I would have school-leaving examination... - you would have
being able to marry someone else.
Not such a tramp!
I'm too young to become married
seriously and to become housewife!
Come to me.
To Istanbul.
Oh my god that's a girlie room.
That's incredible.
I cut off your cock soon!
What did all this cost?
Enough to go bankrupt.
And who pays the rent?
- I don't know.
I wont pay your part.
Could you finally stop moving?
Let, ...
Do you want to make a model out of me.
Fine.
Done.
Take a shower.
Can I help you, Maren?
Are you in a good or in a bad mood?
Both.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
Who cut them?
My roommate.
Since when do you have a roommate?
Since a couple of days.
Do you fuck?
- No.
What?
Is she nice?
she needs a job.
Hi I'm Sibel.
You're Cahit's flat mate right?
- Yes.
You're looking for a job?
- Yes, I'm I a good hair stylist.
Well then...
Hello, I've got an appointment for 11 o'clock.
- yes, take a seat.
Do you want?
- Yes.
Is it ok if she does it?
- Sure no problem.
Thanks. How do you like it?
Just cut the ends.
- Ok.
Shall I wash them?
- No, I just did and they are still wet.
That looks hot right!
- Yeah, yeah!
Next thing is a tattoo!
Such a huge one!
Yeah!
Maren is a hot chick!
- Yes!
She has a hot ass?
- Yeah I think so too!
She has a really hot ass.
Do you like my piercing?
- yes!
Yes it is hot, really hot!
Do you want to go dancing with me.
- Yea sure.
I want to show off with you.
But I say at whom ok?
Ok!
Cahit, I go to fuck!
Did you see the guy?
How many heads did you wash
to afford this car?
Yilmaz has connections. He gets it cheaper.
Do I really have to join you?
Bullshit!
We are married for half a year now
and we have never been there.
I don't wanna, I don’t wanna!
- Oh please Cahit!
Fuck your 'oh please'.
Your Turkish really improves!
It's your turn, play!
Whether take this or this!
It's your turn
- Yea brother I play!
How could you give your girl to him?
Do not interfere in ours
family affairs!
Hey guys. Last week I was at the "Pasha"
A very nice club. Everything available there.
Scandinavian, African ...
Turkish? - My cellar is full of Turks.
Play brother.
You have to come with us!
Brother-in-law!
Where to?
To a Brothel.
What shall I do in a brothel?
What a question!
Do you know the brother
of Michael Jackson ?
Siki Ceksin
(you will fuck)
Why don't you fuck your own wives?
What did you say?
Why you don't fuck your own wives?
It's your turn.
Do not ever say the word 'fuck'
together with our wives again!
Did you understand me?
- What?
As much as you understood me?
- Calm down.
Galatasaray becomes master.
What the fuck?
I kick you in the ass!
I fucking hit you!
- Calm down!
And how is your husband like?
Very sweet.
And in bed?
Okay.
Does he suck?
Like a cat.
You can be glad!
Mine sux like an ox
and sometimes he moos.
Hey wait a second.
I was at the factory.
You are not the manager there ...
you just clean the tables.
Why did you lie?
Imagine if you were me.
You clean the fucking tables.
Would you have given me your sister?
Do you love her?
Yes.
I love her.
Can I get another beer please?
Make it two.
And I'm looking at him and
ask what’s going on
because he has totally
cauterized eyebrows.
he said he's lovesick
Do you want one more?
- No, thanks.
I could tell you some nice stories.
Really?
- Yes. - I'd love to.
At my place...
Do you live nearby?
-Yes around the corner.
Hey!
You do one mistake after another!
You are fine right.
Why?
You fuck better.
It wasn't a bad idea to marry you.
I learned it from my mother.
Ah... My mother asked me
about children today.
Let's make some.
If it's getting too worse I tell
here you are infertile.
That's a good divorce reason.
Do you want to go at the "Taksim" tonight?
Hello.
A whiskey please.
What's that?
Thanks.
Did you see her?
- whom?
My wife.
That little girl is your wife?
- Yes, and?
Why do you look like this?
I thought you don't fuck.
We don't fuck.
Why don't you fuck
if you are married?
I want to get in.
Sorry but without girl you can't enter.
- My wife is in there.
I don't give a fuck.
- You don't? - Yea.
Fuck you!
- Hey, fuck you. - No, no.
Hold on.
That's my husband.
Ok, that's your husband.
But calm down.
Don't make a riot in there.
- ok.
It's ok guys.
Peace!
Sibel!
I'm sorry that I ran away.
It's ok.
I've gone crazy?
Everybody does.
Hey babe. Are you all right?
- What do you want? - Can't you see I want you!
Piss off!
- Hey, keep cool babe!
Hey, that's my wife.
- What? - Cahit!
What Cahit...
Hold on!