"We love our mothers unknowingly,
and only realize how deep-rooted
that love is
at the ultimate separation."
I don't know what happened.
When I was little,
we loved each other.
I still love her.
I can look at her,
talk to her,
be next to her.
But...
I can't be her son.
I could be anyone's son.
But not hers.
You have cream cheese
all over your mouth.
The other side too.
I wiped both sides.
It's good, you got it.
There's just a drop more over there.
No, the other side.
It's okay.
I hate when you put
make-up on in the car!
It's totally unsafe.
Can Antonin sleep over on Saturday?
- As long as...
- You don't want to cook, I know!
- Why don't you fuckin' shut up?
- What are you doing?
I listen to the morning news!
That jerk is just busting our balls!
Your balls!
I find him very, very cultured.
Just the other day,
you said he annoyed you.
Hubert, if you're not happy...
You'll do what you want,
when you're 18, in your car.
But I listen to the news in mine.
You weren't even listening!
- Yes, I was.
- Okay, I'm all ears...
If you're unhappy, take the bus
like kids of your age!
I've had it.
- Hey...
- What?
What do you want?
We can talk.
I'm not just your chauffeur.
I'm letting you savor
your news program!
"Savor!", now...
You're the spitting image
of your father.
Can't talk like everyone else.
Always calling attention to yourself.
You both think you're king shit.
Take a pill!
Rude individual.
- You ran the light.
- No, I didn't!
- It was red.
- Yellow.
- It was red!
- Yellow!
Red! Red! Red! Red!
You're a crappy driver,
you put on make-up...
I said if you're not happy,
get out and take the bus!
Do a survey to see
if your friends' parents
drive them to school!
Stop asking me to do surveys!
It's such bullshit!
50% of my friends get rides
to school.
You take me for a nitwit!
Get out and walk.
I'm late.
I don't have time for this milk run.
I'll miss class.
Take the short cut...
I said I'm late. I am late!
Don't you understand?
Should I say it in Spanish?
What a joy giving you a lift.
Have a nice day!
I KILLED MY MOTHER
Have you thought about a title
for your painting?
It's in my notebook.
Take a look, it's right there.
Title: The Son
Congratulations, champ!
I'm sure you'll get a gold star!
You'll find the annual salary,
work conditions, and benefits.
For the second half,
you'll interview your parents.
It's all on the sheet, anyway.
Now get into teams.
- Ma'am?
- Yes.
Can I use my aunt's profession?
No, Hubert.
We're establishing statistics
on what parents do most.
Can't you use your parents'
I never see my father.
And...
my mother is dead.
Well, of course...
you can use your aunt's profession.
- I'm sorry.
- It's ok.
I didn't know.
You know when you stare
at a light...
Then you close your eyes,
and it's black and then
green florescent spots pop up...
It's weird because you feel like
you can control them, but...
Shut up!
You're early.
I was training a new recruit.
Never takes long.
- Hi, Hubert!
- Hello.
Staying for dinner?
No, I can't, I have to...
Hey, new recruit!
Come on stay.
We'll order sushi...
No, I really have to go home.
Too bad. Another time then.
What about your homework?
Have you been working hard?
Yeah! It's crazy.
We're sweating bullets.
How was your day?
- I'm talking to you.
- Normal.
- You're not asking about mine?
- No.
Why?
If something special happened,
you would've already told me.
The same goes for me.
But since it was another wasted day
in a class full of morons,
iron-pumping sex addicts
who can't conjugate the verb "to be".
Not worth talking about.
It's so uninteresting.
Do you think other kids
use that tone with their mothers?
Do you think other mothers raised
their kids like you did?
This isn't a hotel!
I'm not just a cook who feeds you,
and drives you around at your whim.
We could talk.
We used to talk.
"Used to."
I was 4 and had no one else.
The steak is good.
It's tasty.
I'm glad.
At least I'm not breaking
my ass for nothing. I should...
...hire a maid.
Yeah... I know!
You've said it 40 billion times!
You have Alzheimer's.
Anyway...
Antonin is gonna come
before dinner on Saturday.
But I'll cook, we'll have toast.
Oh really?
And it's too much to ask me first?
I asked you in the car
this morning.
Impossible, Denise invited us over.
Are you kidding?
I asked you in the car this morning
and you said yes!
See, I'm totally right.
You've got Alzheimer's!
Don't go there, Hubert Minel!
Don't be manipulative!
I'm fed up with this bullshit...
Okay, then...
I'll go to Antonin's.
Problem solved.
Out of the question!
Denise is expecting you.
She loves you!
She wants you to be there!
She bought a big beautiful
veal shank! 40 bucks! We're going!
I don't give a shit!
I have a life too!
I'm seeing Antonin on Saturday!
Have fun with Denise
and her shanks!
Do that and say goodbye
to your weekly allowance.
Blackmail, now! Great!
Grandma would be proud to see...
I'm in charge of that inheritance
until you're 18!
If you're not happy, go live
with your father! Am I clear?
I hate you.
Well, go on, Hubert! Hate me!
Hate those who contradict you,
those who are right!
I've also hated people in my life.
Am I dead? No, I'm still here!
Stop singing
when you're uncomfortable!
Classic reaction!
I'm not uncomfortable,
This conversation is over!
Fine!
Tell Denise I can't come,
that I'm not free...
Tell her I'm sorry
I couldn't make it.
She'll be sad, but
that's the least of your worries.
People's feelings aren't
your concern.
When I try to imagine what the worst
mother in the world is like...
I can't do better than you.
How nice.
Lovely evening.
She didn't want me.
I'm just a burden.
She wasn't made to be a mother.
She got married
and had a kid because...
that's what everyone
expected of her.
That's what everyone
still expects of women.
Well...
almost everyone.
For the sa... the salaries,
it will...
It'll be between 35 and 45 grand.
I'm going to talk to you
about the social advantages.
Social advantages
are really insane because...
You!
I need to talk to you after class!
Do I look fucking dead,
for Christ's sake?
Okay! Everyone, please!
Quiet down, everyone.
Go back to your seats, guys!
Please!
Hubert, come here!
Hubert Minel!
I want to talk to you!
Why did you say that
to your teacher?
Don't touch me!
Hubert, get in.
It's my job to make sure
you're safe and sound! Get in.
Look, I have...
I have candy!
Why did you lie to me?
It was inevitable I'd find out.
I don't have class now,
let's get a bite.
Isn't it illegal for teachers
and students to hang out?
Not as much as killing your mother.
You're right, I shouldn't see you
outside of class,
but the other teachers do it, so...
I used to come here
when I was your age.
I know...
It's a dive, but...
This place has a special aura.
Greasy food, bitter coffee,
the seats are too red, but...
- So?
- The Smoked Meat Royal, please.
I'll have the same
with mayo for the fries.
And to drink?
Water.
I should've known it was stupid
telling you that my mother was dead.
I was a jerk to make that up,
I apologize.
I could never stand my father.
And it hasn't changed.
People think that with time,
you start loving your parents
and things work out.
But we haven't spoken in 10 years.
For me, it's my mom.
We're totally incompatible.
We have absolutely nothing
in common.
"The mother of a son
will never be his friend."
Cocteau.
"Love thy father and mother."
God.
You're Catholic?
I believe there's something,
someone...
But I don't know if it's God,
or Buddha, or...
I don't know.
But I know
He gave me the wrong mother.
Why are you a teacher?
I don't know.
O sinister, cruel woman,
The gloomy pitch
of your shrill voice
Brings forth a sad song
that haunts me
And I escape into a lush,
horrific meadow
We should be able to kill ourselves.
In our heads.
And then be reborn.
To be able to talk,
look at each other,
be together.
As if we never met before.
If my mother and I were strangers,
I'm sure we'd get along.
Don't tell him that, you twit!
He'll be there any minute!
No!
I knew it! I told you!
What a nutcase.
- Hi, Mom!
- Hi, Hubert!
Can I have a quick word?
- No, my show's on.
- You're taping it!
Come on, you're taping it.
I have to talk to you.
I found the perfect solution.
Oh yeah?
For us. For our relationship.
- Are you listening?
- Yes.
I think I should move
into my own apartment.
Really...
I saw an ad on my way from school.
We could visit it.
It seemed nice, and clean.
It's in a good neighborhood.
I'd be close to the subway, close
to school, close to my friends!
So, no more driving me around.
You've never even done
your laundry here! You'll go nuts.
Well, here... it's because
you're always on my back!
Yes! That's why!
I won't have the choice there.
I won't live in a pigsty!
I'll have to clean up my own shit.
I know it'll work.
- With Grandma's money?
- Yes, exactly.
That's what I was thinking!
We're really on the same wavelength!
Yes, it's a good idea.
I'm so happy, Mom.
I love you! I love you!
- Okay, so you're happy?
- Yes.
I'm gonna visit it. I'm so happy!
I love you, my sweet little mommy!
Crappy crap.
I rented this flat
to a bunch of pigs.
It was so goddamn filthy,
I had to repaint.
Okay, guys, here's the bathroom.
Toilet, bathtub, shower,
sink with medicine cabinet.
It's clean.
Here's some place for your junk.
And buddy,
here you have a closet.
A fucking big one.
Can shove lots inside.
Corridor, corridor, corridor...
And here's the kitchen!
End of the line, passengers!
If you're interested...
I'll put in a stove,
fridge, the works.
Cool!
It's perfect for me.
Yeah, it's really nice.
I'll be in touch real soon.
Okey-Dokey! Sounds like a plan.
There's one thing...
I don't want any trouble.
The neighbors like peace and quiet.
Okay? Fine...
I've gotta run. I've got work to do.
Let's go.
Mom, I have to talk to you.
- My show's about to start.
- It'll take two seconds.
Wait till the commercial.
Mom...
I saw the apartment.
Which apartment?
The one I told you about.
It's so perfect for me.
I can't believe it!
The bedroom's big,
the bathroom's perfect.
Heat and electricity are included!
Hubert...
I thought it over.
At 16, it's nuts to have
your own apartment.
Wait till you're 18, okay, honey?
Excuse me?
Yesterday you said
it was a great idea.
Are you screwing with me?
We talked about it yesterday!
Hubert Minel,
it makes no sense to move out at 16.
You're dreaming in colors!
You poor thing.
You make me sick!
You lead me on!
Go, go, go...
What are you doing? Are you crazy?
No, no, no, no!
What about the ants?
- Ants!
- Fuck the ants? Fuck you!
Get your ass over here
and clean up this mess!
Fuck you!
When I say it, I mean it.
It's true, I love her.
But it's not the love of a son.
It's strange...
if someone hurt her,
I'd want to kill him. I'd kill him.
And yet,
I can think of a hundred people
I love more than my mother.
Oh, you bastard!
Smells good in here!
I just came back
from a PTA meeting.
I peeked at your art.
Hubert, I didn't know you painted!
- It's fabulous.
- Thanks.
No, really, you both amaze me.
So I thought you could redo
my office!
You could throw things on the wall.
You know, splatters, splashes!
Help me out!
Humans call that "dripping", Mom.
That's it, dripping.
You'd have a free hand!
It's an ad agency,
not a tax office.
I'd love to.
Wonderful!
Say yes or I'm kicking you out.
Come help set the table.
No, no, no! I'm so zen here.
Total Nirvana!
Come on, lazy head!
Crazy bitch!
No, stop it!
Hello!
Hubert? Are you home?
There you are.
Look what I bought.
I'm sure you'll hate it.
Yes, ma'am.
It's lovely.
I don't hate it.
It's kind of...
It's kind of safari.
I like fur patterns.
It warms up interiors.
And it goes so well
with that painting.
It goes with the...
The tiger's stripes.
That's why I bought it.
It's lovely.
I love you.
I love you too, sweetheart.
I'm telling you...
so you won't forget.
Now this is what I call
a beautiful plate!
These eggs are terrific!
- You like it?
- It's delicious.
Did you add coriander?
- Yes. I know you like that.
- I sure do.
You did it for me.
It's good. It gives it
a little Asian-lndian taste.
They put it in couscous too.
Moroccans... North Africans.
Gives it an international flare.
How was your week at work?
Good.
It's a bit frenzied, but...
it's fine.
What's that noise?
Am I hearing things?
It's the washing machine.
I did a wash this morning.
You did?
- That's nice.
- Yep.
The dishes too?
Have you been brainwashed?
That's Denise!
Denise!
- Hello, sugar! How is she?
- Fine!
Why go?
You're brown enough already!
You have to keep up a tan, girl!
Take a look... the suit you got me
from Fort Lauderdale!
- Foxy!
- Cute, huh?
Hi, lovie!
Mister is doing the dishes!
What's the occasion?
What'd you give him?
I want some for mine!
- For your husband or son?
- Both of them!
You're nuts!
You always crack me up, Denise.
We're off to get a tan,
but will be back.
Want to eat with us?
I'm making pesto pasta.
I'll cook and when you get back,
we'll eat together.
How nice.
I just need 5 minutes.
Go ahead, I'll have a little chat
with your son.
Come see my hibiscus.
It's gorgeous.
It has a huge salmon red flower!
- Two feet big!
- Mine hasn't bloomed yet. Salmon?
I need a tan! I'm white as a ghost!
No, you're not.
Sylvain isn't keen
on us getting tan.
He keeps showing me
articles on cancer...
It's not even real sun!
You're right, I'll tell him.
Hello!
We met at PTA meetings.
Helene Rimbaud,
I'm Antonin's mother.
Of course!
- How are you?
- Very well.
I'm waiting for my mother.
She likes getting tanned,
it's not my thing.
Our boys...
Two months in a week!
- Two months?
- Yes.
- Two months... what?
- That they've been together!
Chantal Lemming!
Chantal Lemming?
Cabin 13, your turn.
- I'll quit on my birthday.
- So will I.
- We'll do it.
- Yes, ma'am.
Anyway, it's too expensive.
That's for sure,
they cost a fortune.
Now I know why Hubert's
been so strange...
You think?
The laundry, the pesto...
He was paving the way.
Poor baby.
He was obsessed with
Leo DiCaprio in Titanic.
He wrote him a letter in English.
So cute.
He used to tell me everything.
Now I'm criticized
for everything I say.
Every word, every move is wrong.
It's as if...
It's as if everything was erased.
I don't know.
It feels like...
it's all over.
Our special moments, our trips...
It's as if it all disappeared.
Funny, isn't it?
It's a big deal...
being...
a homosexual.
Big stuff.
I have to go to the market.
Come! I'll drop you at the video
store then come back to pick you up.
- What do you say?
- Sure.
I love you, sweetheart.
I love you, too.
Hurry up before it closes.
- Hurry!
- I'm coming.
Dammit.
I won't set up camp here.
I've been waiting forever!
Two minutes or I'm gone!
Fed up with this.
Next!
Phone number, please.
450-555-6352
You've got 2 regular films
and one Blu Ray.
A "Blue" what?
We have an offer,
three new releases for three days.
But not with Blu Rays.
Want to exchange it?
Fuck!
That was the last time!
I'm twiddling my thumbs
while His Majesty chooses his films!
- You don't understand anything.
- Of course not, I'm an idiot!
Why drive off if you're gonna stop?
To piss me off?
- Do a survey...
- Another one!
I wonder if your friends' mothers
drive them to the video store.
Next time, take your bike.
I can't keep doing you favours.
"Favours?"
It was your idea
for me to come with you!
How should I know
you'd wank off for 45 minutes?
Your selfishness blows my mind!
There was a line!
Should I have trampled on people
because mother dearest tarries?
You had to start yelling
in front of everyone!
- Yelling!
- Yes, yelling!
And you're not yelling now?
I think it's time you go live
with your father.
I'm at the end of my rope.
The end!
I knew you had Alzheimer's,
but I didn't know
you were also blind!
- Now it's something else.
- Yes!
What about today?
You didn't notice a thing!
- What?
- The laundry, the dishes!
Everything! The dinner!
I tried to make you happy!
Congratulations, Hubert.
Sweet Jesus, how fantastic!
You cook, you clean,
you wipe shit once a year!
Want a medal for finally acting
like kids of your age?
Stop comparing me
to "kids of my age!"
Stop doing that!
I'm not like them!
And you're not like their mothers!
- We're unique!
- Yes, Hubert! You're always right!
Yes, I am right! I'm right!
I hate you!
I can't stand you!
You can't stand anyone.
Not me, or anyone else!
I don't want to live
with you anymore!
I just want to vanish.
Escape to a desert island!
I'd dig a hole in the sand
without air, without water...
And before kicking the bucket,
you'll call me:
"Mom, I'm hungry,
I'm thirsty. I'm sorry!"
You're never content.
Stop talking when I am!
Listen to me once in a while!
We could try to communicate!
It's no wonder you're still single!
You're just like your mother:
fucking crazy!
What are you doing?
Stop.
Open the door.
It's open.
Open the fucking door, it's locked!
Need a hand?
How can you laugh?
- How can you laugh?
- I'm laughing inside.
It's open, go on.
What the hell are you doing?
What are you doing?
Don't crawl over me!
Hello! I'm here.
You're laughing too!
Your fat ass!
Don't touch me! Don't touch me!
Excuse me!
- Move your foot.
- Don't touch me, dammit!
Did you forget your keys?
Help me with the groceries.
Help me with the groceries!
Fine, little man,
we can both play that game!
Hubert?
Antonin?
You have to call your mom.
You can't just turn up
here like this.
I can't house runaway students.
I could lose my job.
I didn't run away.
It's just a break.
I know, it's old-fogey here.
This used to be
my grandmother's place.
Very intelligent running away!
Are you referring to...
when you ran off
from the video store or from home?
Watch your tone.
Where are you?
At Antonin's.
I'm not coming home
tomorrow either.
You're taking roots
at your friend's house?
At least here...
I love them.
And they love me.
When will your purgatory be over?
So in your mind,
living with you is paradise?
I don't know when I'll be back.
But for now, go to the 3rd drawer
of my night table.
Under my drawings is an old copy
of "Philosophy in the Bedroom".
Trust me, time will fly...
You can't talk
to your mother like that!
I'm sure she's not easy
to live with, but...
When I was little,
my mother and I were like friends.
Her work colleagues
told her what a spoiled brat I was,
and how they would've
already whacked me!
They're the type of ladies who say:
"It's particular."
It's so irritating.
When people say "particular",
they lack the intelligence
to understand "difference".
Or to appreciate it. Or have
the guts to admit they hate it.
My mother often says
that I'm "particular".
Good morning.
Good morning, thanks.
Hubert?
I could get into a lot of trouble
if anyone found out you're here.
Don't worry.
Why can't I be like the others?
Kids my age
think their moms are pains
but they still love them.
I don't think I was made
to have a mother.
Maybe your mother
wasn't made to have a son.
Page 131.
Letter number 26.
Tourvel refuses Valmont's love.
Fucking whore.
But deep down, Tourvel...
Hub?
Daydreaming, Vicomte?
Yes, and you?
How are you?
Nothing...
just some homework with a friend.
This afternoon?
I'm on my way.
Who was that?
My father.
What did he want?
He wants us to rent some movies...
watch them and eat spaghetti,
like when I was little.
You never talk about him.
Yeah, I know.
Well...
My parents split up when I was 7.
My mom says my father...
got scared,
that parenting wasn't his thing.
And then he left.
He didn't go far, but he left.
Now I hardly ever see him.
At Christmas, Easter...
He sends cards and money.
His loss.
- Hello, Hubert. Come in.
- Hi!
I'm so happy you invited me over.
Because...
It's been hell at home
with Mom lately.
I've been staying
at a friend's house.
- No fucking way!
- Stay here.
You said we'd have
a spaghetti night! You lied!
We will,
but first we need to talk.
The atmosphere is perfect,
what a blast!
Want to drink something?
Hello, Hubert.
So?
Your mother and I have made
an important decision.
Your report card is a disaster.
Despite your proficiency in French.
Who cares? It's October.
I'll work harder.
We're sending you
to boarding school.
Excuse me?
In Coaticook, near Magog.
It's a nice place,
in the middle of nature.
You'll find pictures
on their website.
The countryside will inspire you.
You'll like it.
No, I won't!
Hey guys, I'm in 11th grade!
Nobody changes schools
in 11th grade!
I don't want to go
to boarding school!
If it helps you graduate, you will.
Ad augusta, per angusta.
"To high places by narrow roads."
The atmosphere will be different.
It's much stricter.
You need supervision.
- And your mother...
- Can't handle me?
- It's not that.
- What the hell is it, then?
Lower your voice!
Can we try to talk
as civilized adults?
No, we can't!
Who are you?
We haven't seen each other
or talked in 4 months!
We never spend time together!
You're always working!
And boom, you're here!
Attacking in full force!
You're ruining my life.
What the fuck is this?
Fuck you!
Enough, Hubert!
Richard, calm down.
I am very calm!
I don't want to go to the country.
I don't belong there.
Why not? The country is calm.
That's not the point!
They're fucking rednecks!
Fuck!
I made some tea.
I know it might seem
a bit "British psychopath..."
- Milk or sugar?
- Milk, please.
Take off your coat.
No, I'll keep it on.
I read what you wrote
for French class.
Your stories and poems,
your novel exercise.
Well...
I know I should've spoken with you,
but I couldn't resist.
I signed you up for
the "Young Author" contest.
Since it had to be sent in
by a teacher
and it didn't occur
to your French teacher...
What's wrong?
I shouldn't have?
No, it's not that.
What is it then?
My parents are sending me
to boarding school.
They're forcing me.
It all happened very quickly.
That's why you've been
so down all week.
When are you leaving?
Tonight.
I came to say thank you
for everything.
Well...
I have to go and finish packing.
I don't want to be late.
Hubert...
Yes?
In any case,
you're still eligible
for the "Young Author" contest.
Good luck in boarding school.
I'll come see you on the weekends.
Wait.
Here.
Page 218, last stanza.
- Thank you.
- Get out of here.
Mother, I confess
The snares of a spurious world
Steer away my feeble keel
I must owe all happiness
To maternal tenderness
So, are you suicidal?
You know boarding schools
are full of fags.
So I bought you a chastity belt.
Not really...
But,
I made you something.
So you'll think of me, and...
you won't cheat on me
with the first fairy?
This is me.
This is you.
And...
this is your little mommy.
This was in the mailbox.
It's for you.
- Well...
- Yeah, I'm going. Don't worry.
I'm off.
Jesus...
What are you doing?
I'm walking you to the bus,
of course. We'll wave bye-bye.
You send me to boarding school,
ruin my life,
and you want to "wave bye-bye?"
The minute before I turn 18,
I'll call you,
and it'll be the last time
we ever talk!
And those crumbs on your face
when you eat like a pig,
your fucking Alzheimer's,
your revolting clothes
that make me want to barf,
your ignorant
suburbanite expressions,
your manipulation,
you can shove it up your ass!
What would you do if I died today?
I'd die tomorrow.
Dear Hubert,
"You're a fish from great depths:
blind and luminous."
You're swimming in troubled waters
with the modern world's rage,
but with the frail poetry
of another era.
After you left, my father called.
He said:
"It's me.
I just wanted to hear from you."
Ten years of silence,
ten seconds of sound.
Life is absurd.
I decided to visit a friend
in British Columbia.
I don't know when I'll come back,
or if I will.
I'll never forget you.
Julie Cloutier XX
Time's up.
Give me your tests now.
Now or I'll take off points.
I Killed My Mother
I bet most people believe
that hating your mother is a sin.
They're hypocrites.
They've all hated their mother.
Maybe for a second,
maybe for a year.
Maybe no longer, maybe they forgot.
I don't know.
But it doesn't matter.
They still have.
What do you want?
To become your friend.
And your bun, too.
If you don't want it, I do.
- I'm Hubert.
- Yeah, I know.
I'm Eric.
Thanks.
It's not that bad. You can wear
what you want at night.
No, thanks.
Carcinogenic and fulvous.
Flavorful and delicious.
Why did you just turn up now?
My mother.
She hates me.
What do you mean?
She hates me. That's all.
She's selfish and ruins my life.
What's your life?
I don't know. What's your life?
My life...
Well, it's not about having
a mother who hates me.
It's more about
not having a mother at all.
Was that really awkward?
Just a tad.
Come on, let's go.
Sorry.
We're going out tomorrow,
wanna come?
Mom, sorry to wake you up,
my sweet mommy.
- What's wrong?
- Mom!
Did you have an accident?
I'm so happy to see you.
We have to talk. We have to talk.
I want us to talk.
What?
About what?
I was in the subway,
and I realized...
You know, we were traveling...
I thought that
if I could put together
each... little... thing
that I want to tell you about
but that I never told you because...
because I'm not that talkative.
You know very well
that I'm not really
a loquacious guy, right?
But if I could put together
all the things I want to tell you,
and tell you them in one go,
it would take 100 years.
One hundred fucking years
to tell you everything.
And when I was in the subway,
I thought of you so much!
I thought of you
with all the graffiti and colors...
It was dirty.
It was beautiful.
It was so fucking beautiful!
I was looking and then I thought:
"We have to talk.
We absolutely have to talk!"
Sometimes I hear you say:
"We don't talk anymore.
We used to."
That's what I think too!
And then I think
that if I don't tell you now,
if I don't tell you now,
it'll torment me in my grave!
lt'll follow me to the grave
and say...
A small voice will say:
"You should have told her! Hey!
"Enough is enough!
"You didn't tell her,
you didn't tell her!
"You had to tell her
but you didn't!"
- Hubert!
- Okay?
What is it?
Are you on drugs?
Are you taking drugs at school?
Oh God!
It's not a big deal.
It's not a big deal!
What's important...
is that we're together.
Now!
Do you understand?
That's what matters, and the rest...
We don't give a fuck.
- We're good.
- Go drink a nice glass of milk.
- Because I feel good.
- You're all wet.
I feel so good!
I feel good. We're good.
I love you so much!
So do I darling.
- I love you...
- I love you too.
Now go to bed.
Drink some milk,
it's an anti-poison.
You're laughing...
I'm laughing because I'm happy!
I'm happy too...
It's beddie-bye time now. It's late.
Well... thanks for the lift.
My pleasure, sweetheart.
Where are you guys going to paint?
At Anto's mother's agency.
We're going to do some dripping
like Jackson Pollock.
Jason... who?
"Jackson" Pollock.
Mom...
We talked a lot last night,
didn't we?
I just want...
I was on speed.
It's just that speed
makes you talk a lot.
I don't know what I said.
I don't want you to think that...
Have a nice day.
Mom...
Please find confirmation
of your child's enrollment
at Our Lady of Sorrows
Boarding School for next year.
Hello, sweetheart!
Oh, my cake...
I'm thrilled with my purchase!
I found a dapper jacket
at Suzie Coquette's.
It's so cute.
It cost me 8 dollars,
but it's worth 40.
Look how lovely it is.
It's a Mario Fabuli
and it fits me like a glove.
Look how cute it is.
It'll go great with my grape pin!
Tahdah!
It fits me perfectly.
Do you like it?
It's cute, isn't?
It's ugly.
You're in a good mood!
I'm pissed off
but I still have taste.
Is your goal in life
for us to become enemies?
- You enrolled me for next year?
- Listen.
No, I won't listen.
You're the one who needs to listen
because I've had it!
Maybe you think
I'll call you in 3 years
to tell you how grateful I am
for boarding school,
but if that's what you think,
you have it all wrong!
Get it?
What's gonna happen is...
when I leave,
I'll cut off all ties
and I'll never speak to you again!
Too bad,
I bought you filet mignon.
I was going to make
your chive mashed potatoes.
Lil' cake...
Lovely evening in store.
You think you can buy me
with filet mignon and a cake?
Next time it'll be peanut butter!
You're sending me
to a fucking boarding school
where I'm far from
everything I love and know...
And it's all because
you were incompetent!
You didn't know how to be
a mother! You were too lenient.
This is the result.
It's your fault!
You won't have this problem.
You'll never have kids.
How do you know
I'll never have kids?
Homosexuals don't have children.
Anyway, I really enjoyed
finding it out
from a complete stranger!
"My boy and your boy,
two months already!"
I said: "Wow, oh my God!"
I was so happy to get the news.
Who... who told you?
Tell me who told you, please!
Antonin's mother.
He's your boyfriend,
and you know what?
What hurts the most
is that you didn't tell me...
that you don't trust me and
don't know how much I love you.
I don't want to hear that!
I'm sorry...
If you loved me, you wouldn't
send me away. You love me badly!
You don't know how to love me!
Stop loving me!
Let me go!
- Sorry, I didn't mean...
- Don't touch me. Enough already.
Enough already.
- I'm sorry...
- No.
Go to Antonin's.
Eat over there and ask them
to drive you to the bus because...
I won't be able to tonight.
- I didn't want to hurt you.
- Enough.
It's fine, Hubert.
I'm off to New York tomorrow.
Can't wait.
Too bad you have to study
to be financially independent
otherwise you could've come with me.
Bite me.
And you, Hub?
How's boarding school going?
What tact! Well done.
What?
Is it that terrible?
If it's really that bad at home,
you can stay here on weekends.
But your mother loves you
just the way you are?
I mean, she loves
you unconditionally. Doesn't she?
You told her about Anto and you,
didn't you?
No.
Dessert?
Strawberry angel food!
Bipolarity, may I help you?
Crappy crap.
"Full batt."
When I say it, I mean it.
Deep down, I love her,
but it's not the love of a son.
It's strange...
if someone hurt her,
I'd kill him.
And yet,
I can think of a hundred people
I love more than my mom.
It's a paradox having a mother
that you're incapable of loving
but incapable not to love.
The only thing to kill
in this lifetime
is the enemy within,
the hard core double.
Dominating him is an art.
How good an artist are we?
Dear Hubert,
My friend and I rented bikes to ride
from Vancouver to San Francisco.
Wind in our hair, iridescent
twilight, cheap motels. Bliss.
How are you? Boarding school?
Your mother? Julie XX
- Accounting, hello?
- Mrs. Lemming?
Speaking.
Principal Nadeau, Our Lady
of Sorrows Boarding School.
I don't know how to say this but...
Your son, Hubert, he...
He ran away.
Excuse me?
He was present at breakfast,
but was missing during roll call...
We looked everywhere
and then found
a letter addressed to you
in his room.
Since we thought
he might be in danger...
we read it.
What does it say?
It says:
"I'll be in my kingdom
if you want to talk to me."
Do you know
where "his kingdom" is?
Yes, it's in Montmagny.
I better hang up now.
Mrs. Lemming, we'd appreciate it
if you'd call when you hear from him.
You know...
We've never had a run-away
situation here before.
But there's a first for everything!
If I may, Mrs. Lemming,
from what I could observe,
it seems your son...
I know you're a single-mother.
Don't you think he'd benefit
from a male presence at home?
A little male authority
might do him good.
Don't you agree?
That's the damn limit,
you arrogant individual.
Who the fuck do you think you are?
Do you teach "Mothering 101"?
My manic-depressive mother
spent half her life in the hospital.
I married a coward who left because
fathering wasn't his cup of tea.
Fifteen years I've been waking up
at 5:30 to get to work
and drive through goddamn traffic
so my son can eat and go to school!
- Mrs. Lemming.
- Shut the fuck up!
Goddamn stupid-ass machos!
You're always quick to judge us
as you strut around
in your goddamn Bugs Bunny ties!
You throw your red underwear
in with the whites!
Do you like pink socks,
motherfucker?
So don't try to tell me
that my son ran away
because I'm a single-mother!
You all have 150 IQs and you, you...
You auto-congratulate yourselves
with your endless diplomas,
and when a 17-year-old escapes
from your establishment
you dare tell me
that I'm a bad mother?
You persecute me with your
questions and petty insinuations.
You project
your incompetence on me!
Go fuck yourself,
you son of a bitch!
And if I don't find a reimbursement
in my mailbox by next week,
I'll come and make you cough up
every last penny!
Have I made myself clear?
Did you remember to bring
my clothes?
Thank you.
Thanks.
I figured it wouldn't be a big deal
for you to miss a day of school.
With your grades and all...
I also knew your mom left
you her car.
Yes, Hubert,
that's what you figured because...
I'm just your maid,
your whore, is that it?
You don't give a fuck
that I might get in trouble.
What's your mom going to do?
Take me to court?
Grow up, dammit! You're so selfish!
Stop looking at me
with those puppy eyes!
I don't feel sorry for you just
because you fell down the stairs.
I love you.
Antonin?
Chantal.
I've heard a lot about you.
Doesn't surprise me.
You lived here
when Hubert was little?
Yes.
We moved to the city
after the divorce.
It belongs to his father now.
Where is Hubert? On the rocks?
Yes.
Subtitles by Karen Nathanson
Subtitling TITRA FILM Paris