Every living person
on this planet
has their own unique
pair of eyes,
each their own universe.
My name is Dr. Ian Gray.
I'm a father,
a husband
and I'm a scientist.
When I was a child,
I realized that the camera
was designed exactly like
the human eye,
taking in light
through a lens,
forming it into images.
I began taking
as many pictures of eyes
as I possibly could.
I'd like to tell you the story
of the eyes
that changed my world.
Remember these eyes.
Remember all the details
in these eyes.
Okay.
It started when I was
a 26-year-old PhD student
living in New York.
It was Halloween,
eight years ago.
You okay?
I'm watching the moon.
Can I take a picture
of your eyes?
Why?
It's just something I do.
Okay.
Yeah?
I've perfected this.
Hi.
Do you know the story
of the Phasianidae?
The... No.
What's that?
It's a bird...
that experiences all of time
in one instant.
And she sings the song
of love and anger
and fear and joy
and sadness
all at once...
all combined
into one magnificent sound.
Where are you from?
Another planet.
What does the bird
sound like?
It sounds like this.
Lean closer.
Geez...
It's more like noise.
Yeah.
And this bird...
when she meets the
love of her life,
is both happy and sad.
Happy because she sees that,
for him, it is the beginning,
and sad because she knows
it is already over.
Hey, hey, do you want
to get a drink?
I don't drink.
Like, anything?
You're not gonna regret this
in the morning, right?
Your identity confirmed.
I finished that
transcription factor program.
Last night?
No.
This morning.
'Cause, bitch, I don't play.
Got the input genes,
and then you put
your transcription factor...
Wait a minute.
You... stink of vodka.
I mean, like, bad.
Like, it smells...
Yeah, I know, I know
I reek off vodka.
Stop talking so loud.
Okay, I consolidated
all your data
into one database.
You are welcome.
You're amazing.
I hate you.
Well, I love you...
that's why I do it.
Oh, hey.
You got a new rotating student.
It's a first-year.
Oh, sh...
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Have fun
babysitting, buddy.
You need gum.
You need...
to have fun babysitting.
Karen.
Hi. Ian.
Can I...?
Follow me.
You're attempting to make
- color-blind mice see color?
- That's the idea.
But after failed experiment
352...
we'll see.
Why?
Why what?
Do so many experiments fail?
Why are you interested in making
color-blind mice see color?
Oh...
Why not?
How are you testing
that they see color?
As the new rotating
lab assistant,
your job will be
to do very boring,
very repetitive
experiments,
be a glorified note taker,
and not ask me "why"
every five minutes.
Okay?
Cool.
Commencing experiment...
3-5-3,
response to photo pigment
protein in Mus musculus.
The control subjects
B Beta,
G Gamma,
E Euphoria,
P...
Psychopannychia.
I don't know what that means.
Look it up.
"G" as in
goodness gracious,
"H" as in help me, please,
"Z" as in Zoolander,
are the mice muted
with the photo
pigment protein.
When we animate
the lines...
color-blind mice
stare straight.
Whereas...
fingers crossed...
the muted mice... shh...
...track the lines
with their eyes.
Holy shit.
Holy fucking shit.
Is this on the background
of PAX6 overexpression?
You're a first-year?
I know... it's surprising
I can put together a sentence.
Sorry, I... I asked
my last three lab assistants
not to come in
and I'd sign their credits.
Anyway,
this is just one step
in a very, very long... process.
This is a rough estimation,
but let's just say
that the human eye
has 12 working parts, right?
Simplest eye having one.
So if we can
fill in the gaps...
the evolutionary gaps...
using single mutations,
we can map out
the most logical progression
of the most basic eye...
to the most complex,
fully formed human eye.
I don't understand...
why take the time?
We know that it evolved.
It's an assumption;
it's not a fact.
When you're no longer
a first-year, you'll see
how important facts are.
Right.
Each of these animals has an eye
that's best selected
for its environment.
It would be...
cleaner... less variables...
if you... had an origin.
Go on.
You start with one...
to get to 12.
But what if you had zero...
a non-seeing organism...
and built, genetically,
an eye from scratch,
a zero to 12?
It'd be a perfect proof,
unassailable.
Non-seeing organisms
don't have the PAX6 gene.
How do you know? Has anyone
ever checked all of them?
I don't think anyone
has ever checked...
all of them.
You've thought of this before?
Why did you look surprised?
Because so have you.
Okay.
Who were those girls?
Which girls?
The ones at the
Halloween party
in the S&M outfits.
S&M outfits...?
I-I met one of them;
I don't know her name.
I don't know her face, but
she had these most amazing eyes.
So specific.
Central heterochromia.
Oh, reminds me.
Guess what I did.
What?
I... figured out an improved
implementation technique
for Daugman's
biometrics algo.
You ever feel like
when you met someone,
they fill this hole
inside of you,
and then when they're gone...
you feel that space
painfully vacant?
Are you okay, man?
Yeah, yeah, I'm okay.
Are you okay?
What did you just say?
Did you just...
The way you talked was,
like, poetic.
It was weird.
Shut the fuck up.
So weird, dude,
I can't believe...
Oh, shit.
This guy is painfully vacant.
Ian, look at him...
he's so painfully va...
He's so painfully vacant.
Fuck off.
Can I get a-a pack of Verdict
and a Powerball?
How much is that?
$11.11.
Eleven...
Lucky elevens.
Thanks.
Karen.
Mm-hmm?
What are you doing?
Five percent of all animals
don't have vision,
and there are
8.7 million species.
So I blasted PAX6
at the database,
but nothing came up.
So I started sequencing
by myself.
How many did you sequence?
12.
You've done 12.
So how many do
you have left?
Like, approximately
426,000.
Are you going to write
426,000 names
on the window?
I'm going to find it before
I get to the end of the window.
Okay.
What are you doing?
I'm... I'm not doing anything.
You know we could be looking
forever and find nothing.
Turning over rocks
and finding nothing is progress.
So, are you gonna tell me
where you're from?
So many places, I don't know.
Which places?
Mm...
To make it short,
I was born in Argentina,
and when I was 11, I moved
to France with my grandmother.
And your-your parents?
Next.
So, what do you do?
Why did you sleep
with me that night?
Poor judgment.
I was lonely
for a long time, and...
...when I saw you that night,
I... I had the feeling
that I had known you.
Actually, I felt like
you knew me.
What do you mean?
Like we are connected
from past lives.
I don't believe in that.
What do you believe in?
I'm a scientist;
I believe in data.
A scientist?
Mm-hmm.
What kind of scientist?
Molecular biology.
I'm most fascinated
with the eye.
The eye... the-the eyes?
The eyes.
Why the eye?
The eye is
the one sticking point
that religious people use
to discredit evolution.
They use it as proof of a...
intelligent designer.
Intelligent designer...?
God.
I'm looking to end the debate
once and for all with...
...clear, clean facts.
Data points of every stage
of eye evolution.
Why are you working so hard
to disprove God?
Disprove? Who proved that God
was there in the first place?
Anyway,
let's get some real
data points on you, okay?
Be my guest.
I prefer talking
about myself anyways.
Okay.
Um, what's your favorite,
um...
Candy?
Strawberry Mentos.
Food?
Veggie burritos.
I'm vegetarian,
you should know that.
What's your favorite flower?
Dandelions.
Okay. Why?
'Cause, they're free, wild,
and you can't buy them.
What's your favorite
field of study?
The stars.
What's your favorite animal?
The white peacock.
You ever see one?
No.
There's one in New York.
I'll take you to see it.
So, you're gonna see me again?
Maybe.
You know,
in Indian mythology,
the white peacock symbolizes
souls being dispersed
throughout the world.
Did you ever think
it just symbolizes
a lack of melanin or pigment
in the cells?
The control subjects "T..."
"T" as in tsunami.
"G" as in...
Gnome.
"P" as in...
Pneumonia.
"M" as in...
Mnemonic.
I start to see these elevens,
like, everywhere.
Too many elevens.
The amount was
so staggering, so unlikely,
that I followed them.
And when I followed them,
I found your eyes,
which then led me to you.
Because I found you
through your eyes.
Also unlikely...
like life itself.
I know.
I sent them to you.
Bullshit.
You know you have it.
Have what?
But you're scared of it.
I have what?
Okay.
You live in this room, right?
Mm-hmm.
Reality.
You have a bed, you have books,
um, a desk, a chair, lamps.
Logic.
But in this room,
you have a door...
to the other side.
See?
Light comes through.
It's open
just a tiny bit,
but it is open.
You keep trying to close
that door because you're scared.
But you won't always
be scared.
What's behind the door?
Besides my dirty laundry.
You have to go
in to find out.
You know
what I'm talking about.
I have no idea.
You will.
Oh...
You want to move to my place?
You have a place?
Mm-hmm. Of course.
Can I move in tomorrow?
Is this your family?
Yes, it's my grandmother.
Such an eccentric beauty.
And...
...my parents and me
when I was a baby.
Um, the white peacock.
But you have
met him before.
Mm!
This is a proof
of the spirit world.
"El Ángel de la Resurreccion."
What?
It's the name of the statue,
of the statue
in St. Anne's Cemetery.
It's in
St. Anne's Cemetery?
Mm-hmm.
But look at the eyes.
They're alive.
Yeah.
It's amazing what you can do
on Photoshop these days.
There's no Photoshop!
The eyes appeared
just when she took the picture.
Just...
You're so beautiful.
Let's get more boxes.
19 days gestation period.
She is ready.
Fame, science grants,
fortune await you.
If you find that PAX6 gene,
we'll be well on our way
to all of that.
Recognition makes me
extremely nauseous.
Well, it is important
that people know about the work.
To me, the best thing about
living like a lab rat...
is that sometimes...
really rare times,
you actually
discover something.
On the night of a discovery,
when you're lying in bed,
you are the only person in
the world that knows it's true.
Can you promise
me something?
Promise you something?
Mm-hmm.
What?
Promise.
I can't promise
if you don't tell me what...
Promise first.
Before you tell me
what it is?
Mm-hmm.
I keep my promises.
Whatever, I won't tell.
Promise.
Okay, I promise.
I want you to burn me.
Burn you?
I don't want to rot
in a box when I die.
Oh, you mean like
cremate you.
Mm, yeah.
Oh, no, no.
I don't want to be cremated.
This is a big disagreement
I didn't know we had.
Cremation
is like obliteration.
I mean, what if in the future,
the scientists...
what if they can reconstitute
ourselves through our DNA?
I want to be clear with you.
Hmm?
I don't want that.
You don't want what?
I don't want to be cloning.
"Cl-Cloneed." Cl...
"I don't want to be cloning."
"Cloneed."
No, but I'd reconstitute
myself first,
and then I'd reconstitute you,
and then I'd ask you,
"Do you want to be alive?"
And then if you didn't,
I'd kill you.
No, but then we could be
together forever, like, like,
for real, scientifically.
You can't do...
Reanimated, reconstituted.
You have a hard time
letting go.
Don't worry.
We'll find each other again.
I love your smell.
What is it?
I won't tell.
Come on, tell me.
Mm-mm. Mm.
Will you marry me?
Next?
Can I help you?
We'd like to get married.
Do you have
your I.D.'s?
Yeah.
Yes.
Okay, first you have
to get your marriage license,
so you have to
fill these out.
Okay.
You're gonna have
to wait 24 hours
before you can
actually get married.
24 hours?!
Yeah.
Why?
Well, this way,
you have 24 hours
to decide whether you want
to marry this young man.
But I want
to marry him!
In 24 hours.
So...
Okay. All right. Yeah.
So we can't get married today.
Okay...
This system really...
kills the spontaneity
factor, huh?
We're already married
in the spirit world.
Shit.
Hello?
Hi.
Hi. What's up?
You called, like, five times.
I did.
Why-why would I do that?
Why might I call five times?
I don't know.
I was running the
electrophoretic drill...
you know,
just another Tuesday...
and I started
sequencing the genes
of this strange worm
called Eisenia fetida.
Go on.
And, uh...
I-I found the PAX6
master switch.
No.
Yeah.
Are you serious right now?
You fucking with me?
Do you know what this means?
We found an origin species,
and we can build
an eye from scratch.
Holy sh...!
Um, uh, does it...
does it have
the same amino acid sequence
as humans?
I-I can't even...
I can't even talk right now.
I feel like
I'm gonna piss myself.
Can you just come in here?
Okay, I'm coming in right now.
You're amazing.
Bye. Bye-bye. Bye.
Who was that?
That was Karen, uh...
my rotating...
well... my lab partner.
I have to go into
the lab, right now.
Do you want to come with me?
On our wedding day?
It's... well, it's not...
technically,
it's not our wedding day today.
And we've been
married... forever
in the spiritual world, right?
Sofi, please,
come in with me.
It's really important.
Sure.
Yeah?
Mm. It's fine.
Let's go.
Well, d... don't
be upset about it.
Let's put our rings on.
I don't want to;
it's bad luck.
I don't believe in luck.
I do believe we've
known each other
since forever, though.
Really?
Yeah.
You know how?
When the big bang
happened,
all the atoms in the universe,
they were all smashed together
into one little dot
that exploded outward.
So my atoms and your atoms
were certainly together then,
and, who knows, probably...
smashed together several
times in the last 13.7
billion years.
So my atoms have
known your atoms...
and they've always
known your atoms.
My atoms have...
always loved your atoms.
Let's go.
Karen.
Hey.
Hi.
Hi. This is...
Sofi, this is Karen.
Karen, this is Sofi.
Hi.
She's my wife.
Welcome. Um...
What do you want to see?
I want to see
everything.
Uh...
So, I have this gel.
And it aligns?
The alignment crossed
PAX6 proteins...
98% identity.
Are these the worms?
They-they can't see anything.
Not for long.
You know, um...
I should... I'm gonna
go take a shower.
You've seen it.
I should... take a shower,
Shower?
brush my teeth...
Wait a minute,
you're gonna go
right now?
Um... yeah.
Yeah, I'm sure you want to show
your wife around the lab and...
Okay. Are you sure?
Okay. Well, uh...
this is amazing.
The beginning
of something...
amazing.
It was nice
to meet you.
Amazing stuff, Karen.
Bye.
What's wrong?
I know something's
wrong, so...
You leave me every day
to torture little worms?
We're not torturing
worms... Sofi.
If you're interested,
we're modifying organisms.
In this case,
they happen to be worms,
that are blind,
and we're modifying them
to have vision.
You can make blind worms see?
Kind of.
I mean, we can now, maybe.
You think that's a good idea?
Do you think it's a bad idea?
I think...
it's dangerous to play God.
Sofi, I believe
in proof.
There is no proof
that there is
some magical spirit...
uh, that's invisible,
living above us,
right on top of us...
How many senses do worms have?
They have two:
smell...
and touch.
Why?
So...
they live without
any ability to see
or even know about light, right?
The notion of light
to them is...
unimaginable.
Yeah.
But...
we humans...
we know...
that light exists...
all around them,
right on top of them.
They cannot
sense it, but...
with a little mutation, they do.
Right?
Correct.
So...
Dr. Eye...
perhaps some humans...
rare humans...
have mutated to have
another sense...
a spirit sense...
and can perceive a world
that is right
on top of us...
everywhere...
just... like the light
on these worms.
So you're a mutant.
Mm-hmm.
And I'm not the only one.
Aah! Oh, sh...
Jesus!
Are you okay?
Here, let me see.
I got formaldehyde in my eye.
Get the splash kit.
What is it?
Aah! Fuck!
What is it? Tell me!
It's-it's... yellow!
It's right over there.
It's yellow. Call Karen.
Fucking call Karen now.
Where's the number!
The number's
by the door.
By the door.
Got it.
We should do this
every Friday.
How many fingers
am I holding up?
12.
He's not blind.
So that's good.
I think you're gonna be fine.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
You're gonna feel fine in...
12 hours or something.
I'll call tomorrow
and check in on him.
Thank you.
Yeah, of course.
This is funny.
Yeah. It's, um...
...strange.
Find me.
Whoa.
Whoa what?
We are in the middle
of two floors.
We stopped.
Hmm.
We should call the super.
The super what?
The super.
The superintendent. Um,
the guy that fixes
the building.
Can you call him?
I don't know this guy.
I don't have his number.
Of course you don't.
Here.
It's under "super."
What?
Your phone is dead.
It's dead?
Yeah.
Now, come on, relax.
You're so irresponsible.
Okay...
Want me to call Karen?
Don't be a child.
You live in this
fairy, magical...
fantasy land.
It's a fucking lie,
and you know it's a lie.
That's...
it's a lie that you want
to believe, like a child.
Like a child.
Okay. Okay.
Come on.
What's gonna happen?
I got... I'll boost you up.
No, no, no, you go first,
Come on.
and you pull me up.
Sofi, come on...
I'm not going first.
You go first.
Look at you.
You're so scared. Come on.
Be careful.
Look how easy that was.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Sofia, come on!
Give me your hand.
Oh...
Okay, come on.
Sofi?
Sofi? Sofi?
Sofi!
Hello?
Can I come over?
No.
Maybe.
What if I bring you something
that I know will
take your breath away.
It has an eye.
I mean, just
light-sensitive cells, but...
we did it.
Mutations are holding.
You did it.
That's the first step in
a really long process.
It's gonna end
as a worm in a box
if you don't get your ass
back in the lab.
Why don't you
eat something.
He claims to have
put to rest the notion
that the eye was made
by an intelligent designer.
Dr. Gray, you made some mutants
in a laboratory,
and now you expect
all religious people
to what, just
throw away their beliefs?
Well, I... I expect
them to fight me
every step of the way.
But I do implore them to look
at the evidence and data
that we've collected here.
These specimens are
practical examples
of every stage of
eye development.
Dr. Ian Gray, uh,
thanks for being here.
Thanks for having me.
Uh, the book is
The Complete Eye.
All right.
How'd I do?
Why do you do
that thing with your face?
What-what do you...?
That thing where you're,
like...
You did nothing with your face.
It was good,
it was good.
Man, you should have joined
the private sector, Professor.
It's-it's crazy.
Iris biometrics is...
exploding
all over the world.
I'll take love over
money any day.
Wow, that's...
that's mature of you.
You think I could
really get a job there?
Thank you.
You all right?
Any more drinks?
Uh, yeah, I just...
there's a smell,
I can't place it.
Maybe it's your perfume.
Any more drinks?
Uh, no, actually,
we'd like to know
what your perfume is?
You don't
have to answer that.
I'm, I'm ju...
It's Trésor.
Trésor?
- It's lovely.
- Thank you.
I'm okay with... drink.
It's Trésor.
It's French.
Are you hitting
on the...
waitress in front
of your pregnant wife?
I don't know if you know this
about me, Kenny,
but the gene for jealousy...
recessive.
That's... that's
good, for him.
I'm going to the dance floor
with my pregnant, lovely wife.
I'm gonna get
her number for you.
Please. Thank you.
I'm so looking forward
to brainwashing
this child with you.
You know what
I was thinking?
What?
What if we turn
the garage into a lab?
And the baby could be
our first test subject.
That's a great idea.
Is there something
ethically wrong with that?
No.
You know what
I want to do?
I think we should leave.
I'm, uh, picking up
a prescription
for my wife, Karen Gray.
How about if I sing to you?
¶ Beautiful dreamer ¶
¶ Wake unto me... ¶
¶ Sounds of the rude world ¶
¶ Heard in the day ¶
¶ Lull'd by the moonlight ¶
¶ Have all pass'd away... ¶
Shh...
¶ Beautiful dreamer ¶
¶ Wake unto me ¶
¶ Starlight and dewdrops ¶
¶ Are waiting for thee... ¶
¶ Say hello to the camera. ¶
Sofi, come on.
Be nice.
Come on, act like a lady.
Hello.
I want you.
I want you more.
Don't stop.
I want to know
what's turning you on.
I-I...
I never do this.
I sometimes think about
the cause and effect of it,
and I think about how... and
I don't feel guilty for this...
...but I think about how
if I hadn't called you
into the lab that day...
...she would...
maybe still be here,
and you would be with her.
Can I tell you something that
makes me feel like a monster?
That day in
the elevator,
Am I going to be stuck
with this child
the rest of my life?
And then the next moment,
she was dead.
We were never gonna be...
together, Karen.
I just never got...
closure.
I never got to say...
good-bye.
Kiss me.
Iris scanning is a new
identification measure taken up
by the more sophisticated
hospitals.
We-we know
what iris scanning is.
We've had it in our lab
for a... for a decade.
Well, it's still new
to the general public.
Now, we are not yet
legally required
to scan eyes, but we
adopted the technology
and use it with the
parents' consent.
I-I'm fine with it.
Do you, uh...?
- Scan, yeah. Do the scan.
- I dim the lights.
The system is non-obtrusive,
and in all actuality
is just taking
photo of the eyes.
There you go.
Come here, Tobias.
Oh, thank you.
You got it?
Y... Yes, I got it.
Thank you.
What happens then is,
the computer finds
a bunch of points in the
crevices of the eye...
Yeah, we-we understand
how it works.
Oh, forgive me.
These systems are sort of new.
Can you tell?
Paul Edgar Dairy?
Sounds like a pirate.
If this happens,
I'm supposed to punch in a key
and reboot.
Wait.
There we go.
So I'll just
put in his info.
What is his name?
I like Paul Edgar Dairy.
It's fine.
Tobias... George Gray.
After his grandfather.
- Hello?
- Hi. Is this Ian Gray?
It is.
My name is Dr. Simmons.
I work in conjunction with Yale
and the Greenwich hospital
where you and your wife
gave birth in July.
Y-Yeah, yeah.
Is every... everything okay?
Yes, everything's okay.
Please don't be alarmed.
We would, however,
like to run
a few simple tests
on Tobias.
His test results may suggest,
although highly unlikely,
the... the possibility
of early autism.
You know I'm a doctor.
What test results?
The... We've pinpointed...
Uh...
Can you hold on
a moment, please?
Karen, listen to this.
Yeah.
We've pinpointed
an array of molecular compounds
that appear in the urine
of children with autism...
and Tobias showcased
a few of them.
I promise it's unlikely,
but worth checking out,
and we have very simple,
non-obtrusive tests,
and we'll be done in an hour.
What was your name
and affiliation?
Dr. Janet Simmons.
I run a research lab
on child autism
in conjunction with Yale
and the Greenwich hospital.
Simmons, you said?
Janet Simmons.
Our clinic is in Stamford,
not too far from there.
It's important
to check this soon.
There's...
no alarming rush, but...
we could see him today.
Okay. Thank you.
You'll hear from us.
Tobias.
Look here. Look here.
I'm not sure I understand
how this is testing for autism.
The blood and urine tests will
check for molecular compounds.
This test is
purely perceptual,
tracking the child's
eye movements
and attractions.
Okay, that's enough. I'm...
Yeah. The test is over.
If you are calling regarding
an existing child,
please enter your seven-digit
session number.
This Dr. Simmons
is up to something.
Child autism, my ass.
I keep running through
her studies.
What was she doing?
Two images side by side.
Two images,
similar but different.
Tobias would look
at one or the other.
Do you remember anything
specific about the images?
Something connected
to something?
Something we could look up?
There was a...
farmhouse.
There was, um...
Dan's Diner in Boise, Idaho.
Whatever that means.
Well, that's a real place.
Hello.
What can I get you?
Um, just a cup of coffee.
Sure thing.
I'm not from around here.
I was wondering, uh,
is there anything interesting
in town to see?
Not much around
these parts.
Unless you, uh,
fancy visiting some cows
down at the dairy farm.
There's a dairy farm?
Mm-hmm.
That'll be a dollar.
Oh.
Of course.
Where is the dairy
farm located?
Uh, take a left,
about two miles down the road.
Can't miss it.
We'll have 'em through
in a moment.
O-Okay.
Come on!
Is this the dairy farm?
Indeed it is.
These are milking cows?
These are meat cows,
not milking cows.
I'm Julie Dairy.
This is my family's farm.
Julie Dairy?
Uh, Paul Edgar Dairy.
Are you related to him?
Yes, he's my father.
Is he here?
You're clearly not
with the biography association.
The, um, I'm sorry.
I don't follow.
Some documentary crew came
through here a few months ago,
wanting to do a story
on the great Paul Edgar Dairy,
the only black farmer in Boise.
They took some pictures.
I liked the story, and
they said they'd follow up.
You okay?
How you doing there?
I'm okay.
I'm just, uh, having a moment
of déjà vu.
Can we fetch you some water?
Or a cup of tea?
I'd really love to meet Paul,
if that was possible.
What if we just start at
the beginning and break it down?
In the hospital,
Tobias's eyes come up as a match
with Paul Edgar Dairy,
which is not correct,
because Tobias has blue eyes
and Paul Edgar Dairy
has brown eyes.
Uh, no, iris biometrics
is not based on color.
It's based on
the unique crypts,
furrows and shapes
in the texture.
So maybe Tobias and Paul
have the same iris pattern.
Statistically impossible.
Second data point.
Tobias and Paul have
some kind of connection.
It's not our test,
so we don't know.
And the third data point
is that
Paul Edgar Dairy dies
before Tobias is born.
Was conceived.
Was conceived,
because Tobias is born
in July,
and Paul Edgar Dairy dies
in September 2012; that's...
...that's ten months.
Okay, what-what are you guys
talking about right now?
This... you guys sound
like crazy people.
Okay? What is this
connection referencing?
Doctor...
Ja... Dr. Simmons.
From Yale.
She did this test on Tobias.
Dr. Simmons?
From Yale?
She's one-one of five people
who have access
to the eye database.
What?
My company owns a patent
on iris biometrics
and consolidate all their
data into one database.
And Simmons is one of five
people that have access.
But you have access
to it, too.
Sort of.
I can find the
iris code, okay?
Run it and see
if it's in the system,
and then check the IP address
and check-check when
and where it was registered.
I can do that.
How do you do that?
Look into that.
Okay, other eye.
All right.
Okay.
So I can't get your name
or biographicals,
but I can see that
you are in the system.
Amazing.
Right?
And that...
you were registered
at the lab in 2005,
and the same should be
for Karen and myself.
What are you thinking, Karen?
Well, check this out.
So Paul and Tobias
have the same iris patterns,
let's just say,
and there's some sort
of connection.
So the next logical step
in our scientific inquiry
is to find someone
that we do know
who's a duplicate in the system.
Like a family member
who has died.
That's it.
We need another match.
Guys, this is
statistically impossible.
You're not gonna find anything.
Can you get a scan
from a photo?
It has to be high-res
and in focus.
Technically,
I can do it, but...
I have hundreds
of high-res photos
of people's eyes.
All right.
You can scan these.
Give me the hard drive.
This is ridiculous.
Who do you want me to run?
Hmm, run my father.
Tobias George Gray.
All right.
He died two years ago.
He's in the system, and...
and he's registered
- at Heathrow 2006.
- Okay.
That makes sense.
He-he was traveling there
frequently.
Try, um, my Uncle Basil.
He died seven years
ago of cancer.
All right.
Not found.
Try your grandparents.
My grandparents.
Yeah.
Bev and Barry.
Bev...
She's in the system.
Registered...
at Schiphol Airport,
Amsterdam, in 1998.
How many people are
in the database?
There's, like,
hundreds of millions.
There's a billion soon.
Try my grandparents.
Okay.
Right there.
Judy is in the system.
She was registered
in a nursing home in New Haven
in 2009.
And Malcolm?
Malcolm...
Not found.
Not registered.
All right, so anybody else?
Sofi.
Okay, try-try Sofi.
Okay.
Sofi.
She's in the system.
Yeah, that makes sense.
She was probably scanned
when she came through Customs.
No. It says that...
the IP address coordinates
say that she was scanned
in a community center
in Delhi, India.
She must have traveled there.
Three months ago?
That doesn't make any sense.
That's not right.
It's an error.
It's only the seventh one
we tried.
I need to get some air.
What the fuck
is happening?
Did you put him to bed?
Yeah.
You should go to India.
I can't go to India.
Can't or won't?
India is not
Boise, Idaho, Karen.
There is someone there
with Sofi's exact iris pattern.
The eyes and the brain
are connected.
If-if the cellular structure
in the eye
is reoccurring
from person to person,
then maybe something
in the brain
carries over as well,
like a neurological link...
Maybe the eye really is
some kind of...
window to the soul.
Soul, Karen? Soul?
Is my wife really using
the word "soul"?
Like you hold
any validity in that?
Call it whatever you want
to call it.
Dr. Simmons was testing
a memory connection
between our son
and Paul Edgar Dairy.
And it wasn't our test,
but you can go to India,
and you can find this person
with Sofi's eyes,
and you can do the same.
I can't go there.
It's just India.
Why can't you make...
Not India. I can't go there!
I can't go back there!
I can't go back
to that part of my life!
I can't do it!
I gotta just let it go.
The man I married...
I don't think he would let
his own grief,
even if it was overwhelming,
get in the way
of what could potentially be
the greatest
scientific discovery
the world has ever seen.
This is bigger than you.
It's bigger than me.
It's bigger than Sofi.
Then-then maybe you should go.
I would...
but I-I didn't know Sofi.
It's a false positive,
you understand?
It's an error;
it has to be an error.
It's st... it's a statistically
impossible data point.
If I drop this phone
a thousand times,
a million times,
and one time it doesn't fall,
just once,
it hovers...
in the air...
...that is an error
that's worth looking at.
You're so fucking stubborn.
Technology has barely touched
Mira Devi's daily life.
In her hut, muscle,
not machines,
gets the chores done.
That is about to change for Mira
and perhaps millions like her.
At this center,
her irises are scanned
with biometric devices.
They're uploaded and then sent
to a massive server.
Once this information
is processed,
out comes a 12-digit number
for her and her only.
India's unique
identification program
started just a year ago.
If it succeeds,
India will become the
first country in the world
using biometric data
for identity purposes
on a national scale.
Whoa.
First time to India?
It is, actually.
Yeah.
Darryl Mackenzie.
Uh, Dr. Ian Gray.
Oh, "Doctor."
Well.
Two men, both doing good work.
What do you do?
Well, I'm in sales,
but, uh...
...also do The Man's work.
The Lord's work.
Oh.
Uh, of course.
Good night, Dr. Gray.
Uh, have a good night.
Hope our paths
cross again.
Hello.
Uh, can I help you?
You seem like the boss
of this place.
Boss? No, circus manager,
more like it.
I'm Priya Varma.
How can I help you?
I'm Dr. Ian Gray.
I'm visiting from America.
I have a very strange request.
Yes?
I'm looking for someone
who was scanned here
a while back.
The thing is,
I-I don't have their name.
All I have is a picture
of their eyes.
This is what their
eyes look like.
They may not be
this exact color.
Uh...
Why are you looking for her?
Is she in some kind of trouble?
Her?
Uh, no, of course not.
She's not in trouble.
She's-she's incredibly special.
So you do recognize them?
I do, if it is
who I think it is,
but why are you looking for her?
Here's another photo.
Okay, um,
this doesn't make sense.
These are her eyes,
but this isn't her face
around them.
That's exactly why
I'm looking for her.
Salomina.
Salomina?
Yeah.
Sweet girl, uh,
very smart girl.
But, uh,
I haven't seen her recently.
When was the last time
you saw her?
Uh, a few months ago.
Could you help me find her?
Um...
I could make a donation
to the community center.
I mean, I'm-I'm going
to make a donation
to the community center.
I don't want to sound crass,
like I'm bribing you,
but I am kind of bribing you.
No, no, no, of course.
I mean, of course, any donation
would help the center.
Uh...
It's very important.
Please.
Okay.
You meet me tomorrow at 12:00
at the Okhla market, okay?
All right, I-I'll take a...
You want me to take
a photo of you?
You want to see?
You see? Okay.
Hello.
I almost didn't come.
Yeah, I was worried.
What changed your mind?
I, um...
I did some research on you.
Uh-oh.
Come.
Hello.
Do all these children...
do they eventually end up
at the community center or...
Some do,
but there are over
one million people
living in this
30-block radius alone.
According to the registrar,
Salomina and her parents
live here.
Somebody's here... I'm gonna
ask this lady here.
Okay.
...Salomina.
Ah, Salomina...
What's wrong?
What'd she say?
She could be living
like a stray dog.
She's totally alone.
Her mother's dead;
her father's dead.
She knows the address
of the community center,
but Priya said she hasn't
been there in weeks.
There's a million people living
in a ten-block radius.
It's gonna be impossible
to find her.
Well, you shouldn't give up.
You flew halfway
around the world.
You should keep looking.
At least give it a few days.
I'm gonna go to bed.
Good night.
Bye.
What am I doing here?
You're mad.
It's a smoke signal.
Someone she knows will see it.
I'm glad you didn't
put my number up there.
Hello?
Hi, yes?
Yeah, my niece has eyes like
the picture board, cash reward.
Are they just like the ones
in the picture?
Yes, I think so.
Like, exactly?
Uh, very much so.
How old is your niece?
Eighteen.
My other niece is 15.
Oh, no, um, sorry.
Thank you, no.
Sorry, wrong person.
Bye.
Hello?
Do you speak English?
Yes, I do.
I'm sorry,
what-what were you saying?
I have the eyes you took up
the advertisement for.
How old are you?
Twenty-four.
No, sorry.
The person I'm looking for
is much younger.
No, thank you for calling.
Sorry.
Very good!
I'm the best!
I'm the very best?
I'm the very best.
Very good.
Dr. Gray, are you...
are you religious?
Am I religious?
I thought you researched me.
I'm not religious.
Why not?
Religion is based
on scripture written by men
thousands of years ago.
Those beliefs can't be
changed or challenged.
They're fixed.
In science,
great thinkers
have written things
very long ago,
but every generation
improves upon them.
The words are not holy.
Einstein is a brilliant man,
but he's not our god.
He's one step in the evolution
of knowledge,
but we always continue
to step forward.
You know...
a scientist once asked
the Dalai Lama,
"What would you do
if something scientific
disproved your
religious beliefs?"
And he said,
after much thought,
"I would look
at all the papers.
"I'd take a look
at all the research
"and really try to
understand things.
"And in the end, if it was clear
"that the scientific evidence
disproved my spiritual beliefs,
I would change my beliefs."
That's a good answer.
Ian...
...what would you do
if something spiritual
disproved
your scientific beliefs?
Hello, love.
The bank called today.
They said that $2,000 a day
is going to some sketchy
Planet India company.
It's, like, 20k already.
What's going on?
I put up a billboard.
I-I know it sounds
a bit extreme,
but it's all I could think of.
Ian, it's been weeks.
I think you should come back.
Karen, what-what happened
to turning over rocks
and finding nothing is progress?
I'm down with
the big picture of all this.
I'm the one
who wanted you to go.
But failed experiments
are not unknown to us, right?
We regroup.
We look for more matches.
We try again.
Please come home.
Do you speak English?
A little.
A little?
Yes.
What's your name?
Salomina.
Salomina?
Yes.
Salomina,
I-I'm Ian.
My name is Ian.
Are you hungry?
Yes.
- You are?
- Yes.
Come on.
Let's get you some food.
Priya, I found her.
Where are you?
I'm going to the hotel.
Um, hey!
Can you meet me there?
Listen, I'll be
right there, okay?
What's your favorite food?
Strawberry.
Strawberry?
Just strawberry?
What's your favorite color?
Pink, purple, blue and green.
Pink, purple... blue and green?
Blue and green.
That's so many.
See my finger?
Can you follow it?
Very good.
Very good. Very good.
You okay?
You comfortable?
Yes.
Are you there?
Yeah.
I want to show you something
that will take your breath away.
Karen, this is Salomina.
Salomina, this is Karen.
I need my lab partner.
Okay. Yeah.
I'm ready.
Okay, so, Salomina,
it's a very easy game.
I'm going to show you
three things, and you pick
the one that's
your favorite.
Okay.
You understand?
Yes.
Okay.
Commencing experiment one.
Memory connection
between subjects
with identical iris patterns.
Got it.
Salomina.
"S" as in...
Shut the front door.
"A" as in...
Amazing.
"L" as in...
Love you.
"O"...
Open-minded.
"M" as in...
Maestro.
"I" as in...
Ian Gray.
"N" as in...
No way this is true.
"A" as in...
Afterlife.
Okay. Let's start.
You ready?
Yes.
Yes? Okay.
Here we go.
Alpha, correct.
Beta, correct.
Charlie...
...correct.
Delta,
incorrect, but it...
it's not a good one.
Echo, incorrect.
Sort of.
Okay.
Foxtrot, incorrect.
Gamma, incorrect.
Howie, incorrect.
India...
correct.
Joker, incorrect.
Kimo, incorrect.
Love...
correct.
Incorrect.
Universe, correct.
Vito, incorrect.
Wendy, incorrect.
X-ray, incorrect.
Yoga...
...correct.
Okay.
What's the tally?
44 percent.
Which is, um,
a touch above random
by an unfortunately
standard margin.
How do you feel?
I think numbers don't lie.
I didn't ask what you think;
I asked what you feel.
I feel...
kind of foolish.
I'll see you soon.
Okay.
I make bad test?
What?
No.
No, you did fine.
You did perfect.
It's just a stupid test.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
Give me an update
on the archivist images.
We've collected
hundreds of images
at high enough resolution.
Just, uh, waiting
on your approval to scan.
No time like the present.