Let us be honest with ourselves.
I believe that we always knew
that this won't work.
Crankcase?
I care a lot...
and in certain way
if I love you, and I don't want to hurt you.
Crankcase should say something.
Not you have left
of speaking from the day that I met you.
Does it excuse, your you are?,
if you are, Sofía Bunuel.
My God, we are your admirers I number one.
I have watched your movie a million times.
I have the DVD.
It is very sweet, thank you.
Would you give us your autograph?
Clear.
Alone he/she writes "For Todd: maricón
pathetic I will never be with vos."
Of agreement.
Thank you.
He/she looks, you what you said...
but you have to listen to me.
All that that you, is that I need space.
Not I know that it will happen...
perhaps with
the time who knows.
Nobody knows.
But now I need
that you give me my space.
It is well.
I want to make it, I want
to give you the whole space that you need...
but I don't think that you have that
to finish with me.
I have to leave.
Please wait, not me dejeas this way,
he/she speaks a little more with me.
Not I can.
Good-bye.
He/she has a new message.
The following message,
it was not still listened.
"It is Bobby, I read your script yesterday, you know
it is supposed that it is soft pron of first..."
Hello what you make here?
Alone I came to look for...
I don't know that I came to look for.
Does he/she wait, are you crying?
A little.
He/she was conversing with my mom.
I believe that she has many problems.
She won't be... depressed
as everybody it is?
No, she is convinced
that he/she is dying.
- Is it sick?
- Not I know, I don't believe it.
The doctor doesn't see him/her anything bad.
But this so afraid one,
and one doesn't eat to help her...
I feel so bad for her.
In any way, I will go soon there,
and I will see like I fight with that.
I should go.
I Will Go to Michigan,
and I will stay with the grandmother.
What is there of your work?
I need to write, and you don't know that
here in Michigan I cannot make it?
Not it requires a lot of effort.
He/she will also give me the opportunity of
to write on what I always wanted.
About Genghis Khan?
No, on the other thing.
On the secondary?
If, don't say this way it because it sounds stupid.
It is alone that you wanted to write
that since you had fifteen.
I believe that if I write on that, I will give him/her
less attention to her, and more to my life.
How will Sofía feel?
I believe that well,
it has just finished with me.
Sofía left me.
Are you joking?
When?
He/she makes an hour and a half, there was traffic.
- Maybe it is only...
- No.
He/she finished, he/she left.
Shit, shit!
Please, you could control yourself.
I had a horrible day...
Not I can support that you act
as if it was the end of the world.
I sit down it affection.
It is that it is so beautiful!
It is so amusing and grandiose.
Crankcase, I sit down it! As you you are?
Are you well?
No.
You that this will sound as something
that a mother has to say, but...
it is the true.
You will be well.
I mean, these things take time.
Sometimes, a lot of time.
You know, still treatment of forgetting...
to Rodney Portchman, of second grade.
Not count the history of Rodney,
please.
Single treatment of telling you
that you will be well.
Your you know that the women
they always liked tí...
since small eras.
And one day at least you wait for it,
you will know a wonderful girl.
Not I want to know a girl...
I don't want to know anybody,
alone I want to be alone with my grandmother.
And their cat.
You are a nerd!
Will you leave tonight?
Not you.
Maybe, why?
It is Friday at night.
Will you go out with Gabe Foley, not?
Be quiet!
I have to live through you, I am very
youth to have my own life.
Ok, but I would like it
that you didn't speak this way.
As it is.
Lucy, they come to the kitchen.
How was your day?
Well. What does it happen?
Anything.
Good it passes something,
it is not so important.
Can he/she wait?
I have some things that to make.
I want go to see Dr. Bennet today.
Why?
I found a species
of bundle...
in my chest.
My God.
Not we still know anything,
it is possible that it is not anything...
if there is something... it could not be anything.
Mom.
Your papa took me to the hospital
on Tuesday in the morning...
to make me some tests.
He/she should go with you.
No.
It is better than you go to the school we will try
this as any other problem.
Is it well?
If.
Lucy.
Everything will be well.
Seriously.
Hello grandmother.
He/she waits, grandmother.
I am me, Crankcase, your grandson.
Agnes is my mom,
he/she is also your daughter. Hello.
Not I can believe that still this alive one.
Not I can believe that I lived
to see your face another time.
Thank you, I am also happy,
although he/she would not say it in that way.
Do you believe that it can happen?
Through the door.
Where is the cat?
Dead
Do you know how to cook?
A little.
Not I have eaten anything
in three weeks.
Seriously?
I ate something of pasta.
When he/she dies...
do you want this house?
Not I believe that it is so simple.
It is my house, I can be given it
to who wants.
Good, thank you,
then we will see.
I am hungry.
Hello.
Hello, I am here.
Thanks to God.
Crankcase, this it is the worst idea
that you have had in your life.
I know it, you mentioned it several times.
Well, I go it stops there.
No, he/she listens,
alone you allow me to attempt it.
I still believe that this
it is exactly what I need now.
Alone I need to regroup myself...
Somebody calls you.
Hello.
Crankcase, are you?
Avi?
I am now for the mountain,
the service works bad.
As you got this numero?
I have my methods,
your mother gave it to me.
Esucha, this is an emergency,
we have to speak now.
You gave Avi this number.
What does he/she spend?
Now I have to make this.
I call you later.
I am walking for the Sep, there is
such a hot girl that...
you would fry eggs in their bottom.
Leaving that of side,
she has a problem...
she doesn't understand, and fracamente
me neither, why...
he/she has to go to bed with the type
that him this installing internet...
if he/she is already making it
with their yoga instructor?
Maybe because dijistes that you wanted
the scene to be able to seduce her?
If, I don't believe that he/she can
to convince her with that.
Something more?
It could be that her really
he/she wants to have internet of wide band.
Do you make yourself the comic, now?
He/she listens, tell to Mónica
that he/she is a nymphomaniac, well?
For their dramatic childhood, he/she has
sex with many types.
It is the only way that he/she has
an orgasm, that is everything.
That is alone a phase,
you will overcome it.
Grandmother, you could hang the telephone,
please?
Where devils these?
I am outside of the city for some days,
I cannot speak now.
I will send you a new script
on Monday or Tuesday.
You should have seen it,
with their top and a short...
Hey, friend, my grandmother this in the line.
Grandmother is not angry with you
I told it to you three hours ago.
To where do you go?
Alone I will throw the garbage.
What?
Already return.
Thank you.
Fuzz!
Does it excuse?
The name of the dog is Fuzz.
Ah! Hello, hello Fuzz.
Your you should be the male nurse.
Did you come to take care Phyllis?
No, in fact he/she is my grandmother.
Your grandmother?
Not wise that taenia
children or grandsons.
If, we don't come to visit her
very followed.
From where are you?
L.A.
Los Angeles.
I was there once,
a long time ago.
Not you could sweeten yourself.
No, I liked it, I liked it a lot.
I Am Sarah.
Crankcase.
A pleasure to know you.
So you come at time to happen with
your grandmother, that is pleasant.
If, I will be here for a while.
We are being about arriving
to an agreement in which I take care of it.
It is enough work.
Him you, I am worried for that reason.
Don't worry.
No?
No, you anger well.
Thank you, I appreciate it.
Devils!
It will be better than I leave,
before my daughter...
look at me like to the person
more shameful of the world.
I hate that look...
probably because
he/she made it to my mother.
It is a beautiful night.
If, I suppose that it is it.
Hello Lucy, do you want to go ahead?
No, it is well.
I already return.
Hello.
This will sound strange, but my
parents don't know that I smoke...
so I ask you you not to count them.
Do you have one now?
No.
Perhaps. Why?
Because I will take it of hostage.
I speak of the radiology center for
to confirm Sarah's consultation Hardwicke...
that it is reserved
for tomorrow Tuesday.
it Traveled with their fingers their legs
until arriving to the crotch...
being about controlling
for not passing over the one it limits.
We have to maintain this professional.
Perhaps we can consider it
as services 'Special to the client'...
you Notice on Poyecto
"West L.A. high School."
"Sofía - I miss You. And I sit down" it.
Hello.
Hello Phyllis, how does he/she go you?
She is Mrs. Hardyng.
Hardwicke.
To who he cares it.
Grandmother, I take charge, thank you.
I sit down it.
Good, I made some cookies.
Thank you.
They are very wrapped up.
If.
After baking them I put them
in a plate and I wrapped them with plastic...
to give you the impression that...
The truth is that I am
terrible cooking.
It is a fact.
No. Thank you.
My grandmother is hungry.
Totally hungry,
what is enough agitator.
The truth, that was
an excuse to come here.
I know that it is strange,
but it is a beautiful day...
and I have to walk the dog...
and I thought that perhaps you wanted...
If, well.
Grandiose. Seriously?
Alone you give me one minute.
In the airplane, when leave here...
I fastened my computer and I began to reread
some mails that I sent him/her.
They were as thirty.
In most, clear,
they spoke of our relationship.
And I don't speak to you of short messages...
but of long and letters of love.
Treatment hopelessly of
to be romantic...
or what is.
And although it sounds shameful,
I realized...
that it was the best thing that I have written.
Because it was frank and idealistic...
as the artists they would say: that it is
the prettiest history that I never saw.
And I am writing it.
Then, when I saw myself there
reading the mails in the turbulence...
among in panic.
I began to feel panic,
as it had never felt it.
And I believe that me this happening because...
I cannot imagine
to feel something like that more for anybody.
Never more.
He/she listens, never in my life I received one
letter like those that your you sent him/her.
Neither I wrote this way one.
You are fortunate of not having more anything
that to do especially with that girl.
But you already know that.
I should sound so young for you.
If, well, jodete friend.
We go, it was not my intention.
Him you.
You know, I show off of being
somebody that knows how to listen...
but when I know somebody new
alone I want to speak.
Why is that?
Perhaps in fact you are not
so good listening.
No, it is not that, if I know how to listen.
Then it is so...
I see myself to myself speaking of the career
of Nelson, Lucy's paintings.
He/she should have my own motivations,
commitments, but not.
And that I am thinking...
Where am I? Who am?
Let me him to ask something.
What do you make exactly? With your days.
You know, that is so typical.
Always the same supposition.
"If you don't have work or you don't go
to the school, you are always so alone."
That ridiculous!
Most of the days don't have neither
five seconds for my same one.
I have to take to somebody, to solve
the house problems, the food...
without mentioning
other 15 more tasks.
I sit down it, not the wise thing.
Well, you that not,
but my family neither knows it.
I can feel resentment of all,
especially of Lucy.
Without caring that that
make everything it disappoints him/her.
Good, it is normal, she is
an adolescent and you their mother.
Would it be strange that he/she didn't feel this way, not?
I sit down it.
I have to think on that.
And to find what fails.
Perhaps it should force me more.
God! Not I want to remember my life...
and to see how much she resembles me.
It was very pleasant, thank you.
Of anything, it was very good to speak with you.
Clear.
Well
Shit.
What does it happen?
I need to have the last word.
If?
If.
Good, I will go inside, and me
you scream something while I leave.
- Grandiose.
- Perfect.
You will be well.
What do you find to make ésto again?
Perhaps tomorrow...
I sit down it tomorrow I am not able to,
I have a commitment.
Good, don't worry.
On Wednesday?
If, it would be grandiose.
I will come to see you.
I suppose...
Crankcase.
Will it be grandiose? That idiot.
Mom, I no longer want to speak of
this doesn't want to fight with you.
Not it is a fight,
it is not anything important.
What I mean is that basically
you will be alone there, take it to the cinema.
Do you have idea of the embarrassing thing that it would be?
That would be definitively very serious,
really.
Are they clever to make history?
Perhaps be right affection, it will be
uncomfortable and we don't know anything about the type.
Forget it. Alone you forget it.
I thought that perhaps they would rot
to make something good for somebody...
but both
they unite in my against.
This is happening because all
we are very afraid.
So I will tell you the same thing that to her.
What is that they find tomorrow
we will fight together with it.
You daughter wants to request you apologize,
and that if you really want it, her...
it will cross the street right now
and he/she will invite the madwoman's grandson to leave.
He/she is a sweet boy,
I feel bad for him.
It hurts him/her the heart.
I will be with you the whole time.
What does it happen?
Alone I have curiosity.
Pensastes that perhaps can stay
blocked in one of those positions?
Yes.
Does he/she list to sleep?
You know that the yoga increases the circulation...
and that it also reduces the anxiety?
If, I read it.
Maybe you should prove it.
Do you know what?
Lament if I seem
distracted lately.
This well.
Good night.
Do you have my pills?
If, they are tranquilizing
very strong, these.
Is it safe to take them once and for all all?
I love them.
Who did change the sheets?
I made it.
Who is Sofía?
How do you know about her?
The flames in your dreams.
What you make in my room
while I sleep?
It is a good question.
Good, he/she is my girlfriend.
But he/she doesn't want to be
more with me.
Is it beautiful?
The truth, is spectacular.
That is very important.
he/she was walking
down the street...
looking for to alquien for me...
a woman...
I Am Sofía.
that is looking for
to a man.
I am completely
in love of tí.
Now, I have hopes...
that that feeling
it will be good...
and I continue imagining...
if it will go out with me
this night.
Good-bye.
Hello, how these?
If?
Do you know where these?
Alone regrouping me.
I can take you to house if you want.
No, I am well,
I have to continue running.
My mom and I fight.
In fact it was not a fight,
it was...
She wanted that me...
he/she asks you if you want to go
to the cinema or something.
I told him/her that it would be uncomfortable and...
probably the last
that you want to make.
Do I mean, a girl as me?
It would be as making charity.
It is strange.
They allow you to leave in one
school night?
In fact not.
If you take me to the cinema,
will an exception be?
I don't know it.
Of agreement,
discover it and you warn me.
What does it happen?
It is possible,
I believe that perhaps...
my toilet is covered.
Perhaps?
Which is the variable?
The water is running outside...
and the floor all wet one is.
I will see it, before I should take a shower and then
I will commit suicide.
I believe that I will say it to alone Paige.
He/she will get scared less if I tell it to him
and you see that I am well.
I believe that you are right.
But I want that your
say it to Lucy.
It is better this way.
He/she told me: discover it and you warn me.
Not it was what waited,
I found that it is...
Interested?
If something like that.
I worry about him to be uncomfortable.
Make it.
Do you believe?
If. You should make it.
And you should also take me with you.
But it is worth them that me
say that it happens.
I really want an ice cream.
I have been thinking of that
the whole day. Who does want to come with me?
How? he/she waits...
do you want to go to take an ice cream?
Do they know what?
Go without us, Lucy and me
we will go for a walk with Fuzz.
We go, it will be good.
Does it hurt you?
No.
The chemotherapy can be hard,
perhaps me of nauseas...
and he/she can get tired.
These afraid one?
If, sometimes.
But now not,
now I feel quite strong.
You are not very strong.
I took twenty dollars of your handbag.
Seriously? When?
A while ago, in February.
Seriously?
If...
he/she loved you a while ago it.
I sit down not well for that reason.
Apologize.
Only for curiosity.
For what reason did you need them?
It is stupid.
He/she wanted to begin to save,
you already know for the future...
but non taenia anything,
so he/she needed a collaboration.
Good, at least you are reponsable
financially.
I tell it to you because,
I don't want us to have secrets.
This well to stay sews for
yourself, do you know?
If, but I don't want.
I always tell you the truth.
Because you always
do you tell me the truth, well?
It is well.
If you say that everything will be well, I believe you
because I know that you don't lie me.
Because you never lie me.
Perhaps to others.
Perhaps to Lucy.
Perhaps to dad.
But not to me.
Alone I want to know...
if truth will be well?
Hello.
What does it happen?
I came you to look for,
we are for today the other time.
How did he/she call himself?
Pardon?
The girl to which you wrote him/her
all those letters.
Sofia.
Was your first love?
There were other girls in the school
but with anybody it lasted.
It projected my fantasies
in those girls...
and when it felt that they liked
it felt that...
they also faked that they liked,
and there was not anything to make.
Alone they lasted a couple of months.
Was Sofia different?
If, good you already know.
No, in fact I believe that it was same.
They come, there is something that I want to show you.
This is touching.
Do you know to where we go?
I sit down as if we were
to a Castle to give something.
I love it here.
I have all those fantasies
of science fiction, of being able to say...
Of seeking that not you
that I was in other lives...
that I can walk for this forest,
as in another time...
and in a different place.
I love it.
My husband has an adventure.
I discovered it a while ago,
and non hize anything in this respect.
I tell myself to my same one...
it is due to the girls...
We have a very comfortable life, very
clean, am I good in that, do you know?
And the matter is that it is a type
very decent and he/she knows how to stay.
It is their credo I suppose, I don't know it.
It should sound very bacano for tí.
No, not you neither that to say,
I cannot say anything.
The thing is that I no longer sit down that I love him.
Not as you the owners...
to that girl that hurt you,
especially when it is good.
The same day that fights with her,
the same day that we speak...
it was also in doubt
if he/she loved her in that way.
I would like it a lot
to hug you now, would that be strange?
Lucy cannot know about Nelson.
Not there is problem.
Well.
You know what I mean...
You know, she asked me
if he/she could invite you to the cinema?
Specifically in day of school, for him
general I don't allow it to leave in days of week.
That is responsible.
I will make an exception.
I suppose that tomorrow you will have...
Yes I have another commitment.
Not I know when we rot
to make this again.
Perhaps in a couple of days,
perhaps but.
I have many things that to make.
I have to go to the store.
I will accompany you.
- Ok.
- It is well.
It had never been in New York, I loved it,
I remember that was seated alone...
eating my wings, in Mets,
where have all those things...
and schoolgirls' pictures.
And suddenly I had this feeling
that it was awake.
Finally awake.  And my life
it was exactly where it should be.
And the other day sat down away from the school
waiting Paige...
and she came running, I enter to my choche,
and he/she began to be on their day...
and I had the same feeling again.
As if diciera: It is "ésto, it is here
where I should be, here with her."
Alone he/she would want to be able to appreciate
everything a little but.
I imagine how many moments
good this way pus to have, do you know?
I want to return to New York,
and to sit down alone in Meet.
I would like to be person's type
that he/she ate up that chocolate...
and to eat it right here,
inside the store.
Good, you would should.
I believe that I should say you a little
but about as this my life.
Of agreement but later
I want to tell you something.
This well, your first.
Well, alone I mean...
that your husband should be crazy.
So, what did you want to tell me?
Anything, was not so important.
First message.
we Need to talk about plans to long
term like when you will come home?...
you Call me, good-bye.
Mr.?
Salt of there.
What?
I am I, want to show you something,
it is important.
These well dressed one.
If, today is, do you remember?
The appointment with the handsome one of in front.
If, alone I thought that...
with all that happens,
you would no longer want to go.
When it scares me something of the life,
I investigate in internet.
In the last days...
I read all that was me possible envelope
the situation that we are facing.
Seriously?
The most probable thing is that they finish
making a mastectomy.
That will be very difficult...
we will have to take care of it and to support her.
And in 3 weeks
the chemotherapy began.
Her that said?
Yes, but in these days much people...
he/she makes the chemotherapy and radiation.
And doesn't that kill you of the fright?
Undoubtedly if but...
as I am not an oncologist neither anything...
alone I can help
with that of tonight.
He/she thought of eating something before.
Do you like crankcase the pizza?
Here they have an exquisite pizza.
Yes, I adore the pizza.
I was as you of small.
Very feminine?
Precocious.
I sometimes like it.
Do you joke? She is grandiose,
I rented their movie in DVD.
And I read the other day that
it goes out with Colin Farrell.
I will go to the bathroom.
Control you, you a man.
Not you are weak, neither pathetic.
You have to continue ahead.
I know you.
Not you of what you speak.
My worst fear is that when leaving the bathroom
after throwing me a good one shitted.
And that all this covered one
of... you already know...
of my shit.
And I will know to another type
in the bathroom.
Is that your worst fear?
It is among the worst.
It continues putting on better.
Hello.
Hum... hello.
Were they known in the bathroom or something?
Your you are Eric Watts?
If, I suppose that I am it.
Did You Work in Julieta of N.Y.?
I love it, I love that work.
He/she didn't know it.
If, I made the car.
Camaro?
Impressive, very impressive.
Basically, I changed it,
I armed it again.
That which requires a lot
money, which I don't have.
Hence, that work.
What do they make?
The time happening.
Not exactly, Lucy's mama
it forced us to watch a movie...
because I am very depressed lately.
We should leave, we have money...
for the goodies
and Paige is hungry.
Well, enjoy the movie
and the food.
It was a pleasure to know you,
be which your name is.
Tell me something.
You were born in the suburbs
of Michigan, in a school average.
Count me on soccer, and the bands
of garage like that of Johnny.
Who?
I am very old.
Not you did go to the secondary?
I went to a school deprived in L.A.
With many privileges,
anything of drugs.
Not him you, I felt never that was...
a classic experience,
as always I wanted.
For example, there was not
a soccer team.
Neither it is here as the 50
I mean, perhaps be not
as fascinating as L.A...
But we are not completely frank.
We make things.
As what?
If. As what?
Let us watch the movie
of Colin Farrell.
No, better not.
That it passes with you and that type?
The pass very well today, Paige.
Seriously?
Undoubtedly if.
I will sleep.
This well.
Thank you to pay for me today.
If, good night.
Crankcase?
If?
Would you marry me?
If.
to listen their messages,
one press.
Not he/she has new messages.
This is my room.
If, shelter you.
Why?
I believe that I am going out with the marshal
of field of the soccer team.
Not you, what it is but popular
that that?
Are you speaking to me seriously?
Not we are leaving really.
Alone the time passes, a lot.
He calls himself Gabe.
And I like it, alone that...
you acordás of the type
of the commercial center?
Eric?
He/she is their best friend,
they make everything together.
They are very different, Gabe inspires
trust until it seems arrogant.
Have you kissed him?
If, something like that.
Not really.
He/she defines to kiss.
Why not?
My papa has an adventure.
The thing is that I am not
angry with the...
I say, if he am but...
I am angry with my mom.
That doesn't sound exactly.
Him you. It is that...
I am not able to understand it.
She is so cold and superficial.
She is obsessed with making
of our lives as if it was a cover.
He/she sometimes screams for anything, and other it is shown
too much calm. It is difficult, and more now.
Because you tell me this?
Not him you, I sit down it.
Your mama said that
you were a painter.
Not I am a painter.
Alone I make it from time to time.
You know, to calm down
and not to leave my stalls
In fact,
that it is not my problem
Which is your problem?
He/she scares me to kiss Gabe Foley.
You overcame it, it trusts my.
In their moment, you will know
to the fair person, and everything will be well.
My mother doesn't know anything about my father.
So, thank you.
Grandmother?
Not you have to make that...
I will clean everything when it finishes.
Can you wait?
That it is that noise?
My cellular one?
If.
Insurance is my boss that is...
calling to warn me
that I no longer have work.
You are a salesperson of inputs
of swimming piletas?
That? I am a writer.
What do you write?
I write books for children.
That well, I love children.
Not it is true.
I liked them.
Now I feel the effect them. But I can read
one of your books.
Not I have one with me
so it will be difficult.
I had loved it
to read them before dying.
Grandmother, I hate to be me
who tells you this...
but not these dying.
That is not happening.
So, please
you could stop to say that.
You know that it is a
funeral service?
Oh, God.
When you find my body, single flame
to people that knows about this.
They fixed everything.
They will put me in a bag
and they took me to the morgue.
I asked them to incinerate me.
The number of the mortuary of Michigan...
it is in the table of the living,
you want to see it.
They should bring
the delivery.
That is a relief. The soup
that you prepared it is disgusting.
Four days have passed,
it was concerned, I thought that maybe...
You that Lucy told it to you, him you.
He/she made it so that me not...
Lucy is not anything.
Sick, enough sick person am.
I have cancer of he/she suckles.
Tomorrow I should go...
to the hospital, there me... shit!
They will intersect... my God.
Shit!
Sarah, looks at me.
I am here,
I promise you that everything will be well.
Everything will be well.
Not I wanted...
"For Sarah"
"There was a bear once
of called peluche Pandy"
Pandy had a perfect relationship.
AND one day, the boy to who belonged
he/she left it thrown in the street.
He had been replaced...
by Colin Farrel.
Jesús! Hello!
You go to my room,
I will be there in one minute.
Who is she?
First we will have
a conversation.
Grandmother, do allow me to explain to you something, this well?
You look at me, you look at me.
Not this well to open the door
being without clothes, in fact...
it is not well, to make anything that it includes
to other people when these without clothes.
I am using a sweater.
Listen to me!
Which is your problem? I am taking care
your best interests here.
Now, if you don't want to give the impression
that you are completely crazy...
did you listen my advice, well?
Put on pants.
Let us never speak of that.
Fact.
As this your mom?
This well.
He/she had their first
chemotherapy yesterday, so...
something is bad.
You could visit her.
She didn't say exactly that him
it would like that, so maybe...
If, it is a little tired.
It is good to see you.
I came until here,
because I am with a problem.
That night I felt that I have
with you a great connection.
And maybe you can...
If. Tell me...
This will sound...
Good, what is.
Seemingly Gabe, he/she could not wait
to that found the anger to kiss him...
then the one decided to kiss
to my best friend.
It has been awful in the school...
I refer to drama... many looks
stealthy in the parking lot.
Anyway,
there is a party tonight...
and it was supposed
that he/she would go with him, and now...
I mean,
I have not spoken with the one.
You should go.
- Seriously?
- Yes, you should go.
To be grandiose,
to be kind with all...
to pass it well, if you make that
you will be a rock star.
They come with me.
Not I am clever for that.
Seriously, if I enter with you? Your you are bigger,
intelligent, mysterious...
If, I am mysterious.
Flattering you am totally,
that is to say... we go.
It would be grandiose and I will owe it to you...
for always.
This is similar to a dream that I had, but
it was naked, but with my slippers.
Ladies and gentlemen...
incredible and beautiful Lucy Hardwick.
That it is dressing designer's dress,
and accompanied by this type.
- Hey, like you are?
- Howard Porchnik.
- Pardon, like your name is?
Porchnik.
- Porchnik? And your father?
- Rodney Porchnik.
- Is your father here?
- This in Bermuda shorts, but he/she would not make the party.
That that was?
A million years ago
my mom liked her papa.
You have left that so well.
And are you?
I am their best friend. Do I know them?
My God, Madison is here.
We go, there is so much
that I have to tell you.
This well, walks.
Sure?
Sure, I will give a turn.
Hey, these here.
I love parties.
As these?
Well, very well.
That good.
If you need to speak with somebody or alone...
not you, here I am when you want.
We go for drinks.
That type is so pretty...
and amusing.
This type is a complete imbecile.
He/she could have been the son of an imbecile.
Mama, you won't believe
what I am seeing right now.
Crankcase, I am Sofia.
These there?
If, hello. As these?
God, I miss you.
They have passed so many things
that I don't know for where to begin.
Alone I sit down that all my life
he/she is falling to pieces.
I cry the whole time
and you are the only person...
with the one that I can speak
when I sit down this way.
My best friend.
As these?
Crankcase?
You are your the pathetic maricón
that he/she enters with Lucy?
I will have to call you later.
You believe that you can come to my neighborhood,
to take you to my girl, to speak with my friends...
without having consequences?
That?
Are you deaf, stupid?
Already listen to you, I believe that the
answer to your question...
it is if you have some deficiency
to learn.
Or alone you are an idiot average?
Of agreement, an idiot
above the average.
What do you say maricón?
- That devils?
- That type is a good one my friend.
You are a complete imbecile.
No, I am not it.
I believe that all know...
that I am not the imbecile
in this situation.
- Your these mistaken one.
Be quiet.
Not mine, not of this type,
which is their name. She is grandiose.
It is beautiful...
intelligent and incredible.
And you ruined him.
That it passes with you?
That it passes me?
How could I allow you to manage my car?
You know that it is the first time in
my life that you/they have hit me?
As he/she feels?
It hurts.
Not I am a fan.
He/she should tell you something.
Or rather to speak
in this respect, aloud.
Well.
Something happened when he/she had eleven.
He/she had this friend, Ethan.
We made together of all.
Not it is strange to be a boy's friend
when you have eleven.
I went to their house one day.
And we were making...
games, boys' things...
not him you.
Not I believe that their parents
they were at home.
It was as the game truth or challenge.
As any game.
We take out ourselves some garments,
I am not even sure...
that...
It is well.
I got scared, and the he/she got scared...
he/she started to the defensive
saying that...
it was my blame that there are
arrived so far.
And he should have told it to him
in the school because...
everybody...
It was so humiliating.
The professors came to see me...
Lucy, Lucy, that type of things
the whole time passes.
Seriously. That happens. Not it is so
important.
- One eats you feel.
- Then my he/she suckles and me...
we, never speak
on that.
It seemed always that
he/she gave him/her venguenza.
That it was like a pervert.
Not you are a pervert,
you didn't make anything bad.
Then, why he/she made me
to feel in that way?
You should stop your mom to accuse.
You should allow it to go.
She was not there when the
did he/she need, why would I should...?
Because he/she can die.
I sit down it, I should not say it.
You know the difficult thing that it was
for my...
to say that. If you are about getting scared...
- Congratulations.
- Treatment that you wake up.
The world there out is confused...
and it scares and it is never
as you wait for it.
This well...
to be afraid, but you cannot leave that
those feelings transform you into idiot.
Not when it is about people that
he/she really loves you.
People that needs you.
Do I suppose that we finish, certain?
If. We finish.
Not I can... this should not happen.
Don't come closer but...
Please.
He/she only wanted to know
if you are well.
Everything hurts.
It is my blame him you,
I am responsible.
But you should listen this Crankcase.
Never but you will play my daughter.
- Not you can see it
- He/she waits, I sit down it.
You have to leave.
Sarah.
That it passes with you?
Him you.
If you don't want to speak with me, well.
But don't send to Phillys
with excuses saying that not these...
Where you could be, I am the only one
person that you know here.
- Certain?
- A lot.
One week has passed...
five days...
and he/she wanted to call you
to the cellular one and...
but I thought that perhaps you were
annoying with me.
He/she listens, I am not angry with you.
If you speak seriously you kiss me.
Lucy, I am not able to,
I cannot see you more.
Not I am the boy.
Good, I will discover who is it.
In fact, if you think it,
you will realize that you already know it.
Mom.
I don't feel well.
I believe that I need...
Clinic of Sr. Hardwicke
I am Lucy, I need
to speak with my papa.
Lucy, him not this here, came out to...
Mom, will I try to get up, well?
I will take you to the hospital,
but you have to help me.
Not I can get up alone.
Does it list?
He/she has what we call
intermittent fever.
Your count of leukocytes lowered a lot,
their body cannot defend.
But speak with half Hardvard,
and they will give you a new drug call...
I sit down it a lot... it was not.
What step?
Do I go for a soda, do you want something?
No, I am well.
Hello?
Hello Sofia, I am me.
Who?
Crankcase.
Crankcase!
- Crankcase Webb.
- Crankcase! Lover!
This it is not a good moment.
he/she Listens, I am in Soho, and everybody
it is drunk, and me also.
is the party of new year, do you know?
Not it is new year, it is October.
Good, it seems as new year,
he/she listens affection...
I Really want to speak with you,
it is about calling myself but late. Of agreement?
If, this well. It is alone that...
Hello?
What does it happen to you?
Not I am able to be.
I am 26 years old, I am healthy,
I am capable, I have many opportunities.
My friends are marrying, having
children and I are so far from that.
Did reason come here?
To be about understanding
that it passes with my life.
From when you attempt it?
Good, eleven years ago, I believe.
A lot of time.
You have not made an effort enough.
Perhaps you should think
in working of another thing.
If, it could be...
Not him you, I have this idea that
something will come and my life changed.
It was mistaken.
Crankcase, I am 133 years old.
Grandmother, that is impossible.
Pass all my life
being about discovering something.
And do you know what?
Not he/she goes well.
I cannot say anything.
I will be died soon
and your will still continue I live.
So he/she stops to complain.
Hello.
Did they leave?
Paige was sleeping,
he/she wanted to stay but...
he/she wanted to be alone.
This well.
We should converse.
Not I am sure for where to begin.
You can begin saying me why
are angry conmingo?
It was very hard...
there am...
I felt alone therefore time that...
I believe that it accuses you
for almost for everything.
You know, they said that this week,
it will be the it finishes that I will make the quimio.
They say that the operation was a success...
and that they didn't see
any cancerigenic cell.
So all the what an one is happening now,
it is alone serguros to be.
But you that everything will be well.
He was not before.
He/she was very afraid.
Not I want to lose the part
where finally it is able to know you.
Not I know that it can happen later,
I don't know it...
But I will continue loving you.
Waiting that you
you can also love me.
I made errors, sure.
But I will always be there
for you.
Alone there is a thing that
I want that make for me.
What?
You have to stop to smoke.
This well.
- This well?
- I will make it.
Dumiendo, má should be.
Dear Sarah.
I have been about writing
this letter for a while.
The letter type that you never received.
the same as in the one that there am
worked all my life.
I Remember when taenia thirteen years
sat down in my room...
listening the same song
time and again.
he/she Thought like he/she could write
something beautiful, something honest.
perhaps he/she could make
that somebody loves me.
I take a time for that.
being about acting
as a boy...
without responsibilities.
AND I never got it,
because escaping was always.
to Be alone,
but instead of that, I met you.
knowing you made me
to think that anything is impossible.
I Hope you have
all the moments that you deserve.
I Hope you return to New York
and you feel Met...
with the paintings of the river Hudson.
AND I wait that when you go,
take to Lucy with you.
Because you that he will like.
I sit down It to have made
your more complicated life.
I sit down for everything,
but more I sit down it...
for not having had
the opportunity to tell you...
that without caring that it happens later...
I will always be grateful
for each moment that passes with you.
AND without caring that I continue looking for
the appropriate words...
all that wanted to tell you
it is "Thank you."
Grandmother?
Chekea some of my books of children,
brought from Los Angeles, he/she calls himself Pandy.
On an adorable bear
that it is indestructible.
Perhaps it doesn't please you
because he/she doesn't have drawings, and you...
Grandmother?
Phyllis! Grandmother, awake.
Grandmother.
Mortuary to call in any
moment at 248-182-971
You wrote me a letter.
It is very cold here.
Seriously, I had forgotten that,
this is ridiculous.
I was surprised it.
I will miss you a little.
That good.
Perhaps do want to walk or something?
Not I can, I have to return inside.
This well.
I see you somewhere around.
Good-bye, Sarah!
He/she waits.
Not you will say the last word.
Of anything.
Blocked?
If, I suppose that if.
It was so close.
Of what?
Of finishing.
That it happened?
I sit down that he lacks something.
Some idea?
About what is it?
My grandmother, died.
Do I sit down it, was it pleasant?
If, very pleasant.
Did a lot of time pass with her?
Near the end.
That is good.
It is pretty that you write of her.
No, I don't have any idea...
I am so disappointed.
It had been grandiose if leave...
he/she gave you that incredible idea
and simplemte left.
Any waiter had made it.
Do I sit down it, can I stuff it?
I Am Crankcase.
Janey, a pleasure to know you.
If not these very busy one...
perhaps you can see
in what I am working.
It is a draft, but I want
the opinion of other eyes.
Ok, but I tell you,
I am very bad criticizing.
Grandiose.