Losing Diana was like
losing a part of me.
I thought nothing could change
the way we felt about each other.
I thought we were invincible.
Someone once said, "If you
want something very badly...
set it free.
If it comes back to you,
it's yours forever.
If it doesn't,
it was never yours to begin with. "
I knew one thing...
I was David's to begin with...
and he was mine.
You light up my life
We met in high school.
David was a senior,
and I was a freshman.
On Wednesdays
after Glee Club...
he'd drive me and my best friend
home from school.
I used to watch him
in the rearview mirror.
I fell in love with his eyes.
When I was 19, David proposed to me
on the pier at Paradise Cove.
Our parents were against it.
They said we were too young,
we really didn't know each other.
But David said that a life
without risk is like no life at all.
So we eloped.
I graduated
from architecture school...
and got a job
at a small firm.
Diana helped support us
by selling real estate.
I spent all of my free time
working on a design of my own.
It summed up everything about
architecture that mattered to me.
It was my dream house.
D?
Have I ever told you
I love you?
No.
I do.
Still?
Always.
We had our differences.
He used to take his clothes off
and leave them on the floor.
It made me crazy.
What do you think this is?
Leaving your shoes
on the table?
- What is the problem?
- I don't need to do your laundry!
Honey, I'll pick it up.
You don't have to get violent.
What about this?
Peanut butter sandwich?
Put that down! That is serious.
You're gonna hurt somebody.
- Hurt somebody, huh?
- You're out of your mind.
Okay, now, fine.
Goddamn it!
Come on. Let's just relax.
Did I hurt you?
I'm sorry.
- Really?
- Yeah.
You were kidding?
D, your pants are on fire.
You have no idea.
We never had much money,
so for entertainment...
David would show me architecture
that moved him.
But sometimes I'd have to ask...
"Why are we looking at
a stupid car wash?"
And he'd just say,
"No, not stupid.
Don't just use your eyes. "
He made me look at things
differently.
David, this is a steal.
Nobody even knows about it yet.
- It's beautiful.
- You could build a house here.
Make a name for yourself.
The house will be brilliant because
it will be a David Murphy house.
I found an incredible property
in Santa Monica by the ocean.
It was the perfect site
for David's house.
- How are we supposed to do it?
- Borrow money, like everybody else.
I'm telling you, these leverage-
stockbroker-buyout guys...
You should see the junk they buy.
They would go crazy
for a house of yours.
It was brilliant, even though I
didn't understand a word of it.
We had to tighten our belts
for the loan payments...
but it was our future,
and I got to build my house.
Then the recession hit.
The real estate market dried up...
and I hadrt closed a sale
in six months.
Construction fell
to its lowest point in years.
People were being laid off
everywhere, and I was one of them.
- I feel really bad about this.
- I don't understand. What happened?
The bank has called in
the demand note.
Can they do that?
You don't have any income
right now...
so they could attach
your assets.
What assets?
Your house.
Gotta keep up those payments.
I'm sorry.
David, I'm scared.
We don't have any money.
What are we gonna do?
I'll wait tables
or drive a cab or something.
I'll take care of you.
Make it go away.
I was desperate.
We stood to lose everything...
the house I'd been building,
even our own home.
I swallowed my pride and borrowed
$5,000 from my father.
It wasrt enough.
We needed $50,000.
Money...
D.
- What?
- Get up. Get dressed.
- What's the matter?
- I got an idea. Come on.
- What time is it?
- Chop, chop.
Hi! How you doing? Okay!
Cigars. Cigarettes.
Lighted yo-yos.
- Oh, yeah!
- Oh, my God!
Oh, honey.
That's the spirit!
Keep 'em coming. $50,000!
That's what we want! We're winners!
Go, skinny, skinny!
Put some money in the kitty!
Eleven. It's a winner.
We got a shooter now, folks.
We got a shooter.
A lucky, lucky lady shooter.
Keep it coming.
- Stack it, don't rack it.
- Seven, come!
Nine!
Denzel Washington ain't fine!
- All set, folks?
- Who's the one?
And I have...
Why don't you put it on?
It suits you.
Well, I can't afford it.
That's too bad.
Yup.
I really think
you oughta have the dress.
Let me buy it for you.
You want to buy me this dress?
Yeah.
Why?
I've enjoyed watching you.
You've earned it.
No, I haven't.
The dress is for sale.
I'm not.
Boom! Skinny, skinny!
We got a new shooter now.
Coming out. Seven.
Roll 'em now, girlfriend.
Seven!
Come on now! Come on now!
- How are you doing?
- Can't lose. I'm up over $9,000.
I can't believe it!
- It's so great!
- Hey, this is my wife, D.
These are my girls.
They're gonna be moving in.
Kiss 'em.
I'm winning 'cause we're winners!
Skinny, skinny!
- Did I ever tell you I love you?
- No.
- I do.
- Still?
Always.
Five thousand.
This little pile here?
You guessed it.
Five more, D.
What do you think this is?
Five more.
Play with it, roll around with it.
Enjoy yourself.
Oh, my.
And the grand total is...
$25,040.
So we're halfway there,
like, in an hour.
I figure about...
two hours tomorrow,
we'll be home free.
Come here.
What?
I love you.
I know that.
No, I mean
even without the money.
Last call for wagers.
No more bets.
Come on, black.
Here we go. Here we go.
Yes!
All right. Double zero.
No more bets, please.
Yes. We won.
Forty-one hundred.
We said we wouldn't go
below 5,000.
- Do you want any more coffee?
- No, thank you.
Tails, we quit;
heads, we go for it.
Two out of three.
Last call for wagers.
No more bets.
Okay, I'm feeling lucky.
I say we put it on red.
All of it. Red.
I feel red.
Do you feel red, D?
We can do this, huh?
I'm going to put it all.
All right.
I'm puttir it on red.
Okay.
No, it's black.
- What are you doing?
- It's black.
No, it's red. It's red.
Go with your instinct, right?
- No more bets.
- Come on, red.
Gotta get it.
Come on, red. Come on, red.
Too late, young lady.
Place your bets.
Bank side, player side.
All set?
Cards, please.
Turning for the players.
Pass is to the right, please.
Player draws nothing.
Player has zero.
And set.
Player side, banker side.
- Any other bets?
- Who's that guy?
That's John Gage.
He's a damn billionaire.
That's a rich son of a bitch there.
He's down over
a million dollars already.
See them little gold things
he's playing with?
Ten thousand dollars apiece.
Every time he lays one down,
10,000 big ones.
Look at him, how cool he is.
That son of a bitch must get more
pussy than you can shake a stick at.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to offend.
- Player wins.
- What y'all doing, gambling?
It's about time.
- Y'all married?
- Let's go.
- Stick around, gamble a little.
- Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Would you mind
lending me your wife?
Is that your wife?
Excuse me?
For luck.
You'd have to ask her.
May I?
- Go for it.
- I don't think it's a good idea.
- We should just go.
- Just for a moment?
- I'll go.
- Go ahead. It might be fun.
What do we got to lose?
- Well?
- He ain't gonna bite.
You go and see what happens.
- Go ahead.
- We'll be here backing you up.
Thank you.
See if she can get a little
of that money from him.
Do you think
she'll ever come back?
I'm just bullshittir you.
Have a seat.
I've been losing all day long.
You appeared, I win my first hand.
You brought me luck.
I'd say that's a sign.
Wouldrt you?
- Would you like a drink?
- No, thank you.
Candy?
Place your bets.
- Bank side, player side.
- Hundred thousand.
- Any other bets?
- Just like that?
- Just like that.
- All bets set.
Twenty-dollar tie-in.
Not like that.
Sorry.
All bets set. Cards, please.
Turning for the players.
What we want...
what we need...
is a nine.
We don't like that.
Player draws nothing.
Cards for the bank, please.
Bank's a winner with
a natural eight. Pay the bank.
I guess I'm not so lucky
after all.
Do you like cards?
Not especially.
Wish I had asked you sooner.
Dice?
Yeah, I guess so.
Sam.
Mr. G.
One.
Excuse me, Mr. G.
- Maybe I should go.
- This shouldn't take too long.
- What?
- This.
Now...
I hope you find this
interesting.
Pit. Tadross.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, it's here now.
- I'll take it.
- I understand.
Yes, sir. Thank you.
Goes for $ 1 million.
It's a bet.
That's a lot of money.
There you are, Mr. G.
One million dollars.
Oh, boy!
Bet it all.
Excuse me.
Coming out.
Crap 11 or any 7.
This time it is a come out roll.
How much goes now? Get 'em down.
Pick two.
Now just throw a seven.
You wanna throw an 11,
that's all right too.
Arert you forgetting something?
Winner!
Winner seven.
Everyone.
Think I oughta quit now?
I think I should.
Credit my account.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Sweetie, that was amazing.
That was incredible.
Oh, my God! Unbelievable.
Hi. John Gage.
Oh, hi. David Murphy.
- Hi, David.
- Congratulations.
This is my wife Diana.
I guess you met.
Hi. Diana?
- Diana.
- Hi. Thank you both.
Very generous of you, David.
Are you staying at the hotel?
- Actually, we're just leaving.
- You're leaving?
- We're on our way out.
- No, don't do that.
We got to celebrate.
Let me arrange a room for you here.
- That's very nice, but...
- I insist.
Please, it's the least I can do.
Okay?
Really, just sign for it.
Anything you want.
Oh, there's some lovely shops
off the lobby.
Have you seen 'em?
Let's go.
How 'bout that?
Wow.
Hey, D. What do you think?
Godfather?
You won a million dollars today.
He won it.
You won it for him.
This feels nice.
Don't get it.
Just stay right here.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Hello. William Shackleford.
Hi. David Murphy.
For Mrs. Murphy,
from John Gage.
- Oh, well, thank him for us.
- I'll do that.
Mr. Gage is hosting a gathering
tonight at his suite at 9:00.
If you can find the time in your
schedule, he'd be most pleased.
- Look what you got.
- What?
Gift from Gage.
Really?
Open it up.
That's $5,000.
How do you know that?
I saw it in a store downstairs.
Oh. Lucky for him
you like black.
Yeah.
It's not the pale moon
That excites me
That thrills
And delights me
Oh, no
It's just the nearness
Of you
It's not your
Sweet
Conversation
That brings
This sensation
Oh, no
It's just the nearness
Of you
In the future, just check into
a hotel and start all over again.
Stick 'em under the sheets.
That's strange. Am I right?
- Good night.
- Thanks.
Who is that guy, Shackleford?
Someone who works for me.
Someone I trust.
He killed someone once.
Tell me...
where do you see yourself
in, say, ten years?
I wouldn't mind being
a billionaire like yourself.
Nice shot.
I mean, beyond money.
What would satisfy you completely,
let you sleep well at night?
What, are you saying
you're not satisfied?
Who is?
I am.
She mean it?
I hope so.
Well, then you may not have won
in Vegas, but you're a lucky man...
'cause I got money, security,
I have businesses...
but you have something
that I just don't have.
I guess there's limits
to what money can buy.
Not many.
Some things aren't for sale.
Such as?
You can't buy people.
That's naive, Diana.
I buy people every day.
In business, maybe, but not
when real emotions are involved.
You're saying you can't buy love?
That's a bit of a cliché.
It's absolutely true.
Is it?
What do you think?
- I agree with Diana.
- You do?
Let's test the cliché.
Suppose...
I were to offer you $ 1 million...
for one night with your wife.
I'd assume you're kidding.
Let's pretend I'm not.
What would you say?
He'd tell you to go to hell.
I didn't hear him.
I'd tell you to go to hell.
That's a reflex answer because
you view it as hypothetical.
But let's say that there were
real money behind it.
I'm not kidding.
A million dollars.
The night would come and go,
but the money could last a lifetime.
Think of it.
A million dollars.
A lifetime of security...
for one night.
Don't answer right away.
But consider it.
Seriously.
We're positive, okay?
Then you've answered my question
and you've proved your point.
There are limits
to what money can buy.
It's late, and I hate to admit it,
but I have a meeting.
May I have one dance?
Of course, with your permission.
You know something? I think you
better get on to that meeting.
You don't want to miss out
on your next billion.
Understood.
I wouldn't part with her either.
Good night.
Can't sleep?
No.
Me neither.
I just keep thinking about it.
It's so weird, isn't it?
Yeah.
David, I think you
want me to do it.
What are you talking about?
Don't be ridiculous.
Well, maybe we should
just talk about it.
I don't want you to do it.
- But you'd let me do it?
- No.
Why? Do you want to do it?
No.
But I would.
I'd do it for you.
For me?
I can't believe
we're even talkir about this.
Think about what this money
could do for us...
what it could do
for our future.
You could finish your house.
You could pay your dad back...
get rid of our debts.
After all,
it wouldn't mean anything.
It's just my body.
It's not my mind.
It's not my heart.
You think we could
do something like that?
We both slept with other people
before we were married, right?
Yeah.
So we'd just have to
look at it like that.
I slept with Bubba Aruzio,
for God's sake.
If I can sleep with Bubba,
I can sleep with anyone.
- You slept with Bubba?
- You knew.
No, I didn't know that.
When did you sleep with Bubba?
When you were off sleeping
with that slut, Olivia Daigle.
Olivia Deagle.
And she wasrt a slut.
Olivia Beagle.
Let me in.
- She wasrt a slut.
- Yes, she was.
- She wasrt.
- She was.
She wasrt.
Unfortunately.
Thank God we can laugh about it.
Yeah.
That's easy to say now.
After...
We'd just have to forget
it ever happened.
And never discuss it,
not even once.
I mean, because nothing
will have happened.
Nothing that matters, anyway.
We have a brilliant script,
really very special.
- Major.
- It's a vehicle...
a comeback vehicle
for Diana Ross.
With Billy Ray Cyrus.
It's kind of A Star Is Born.
So...
your first screenplay sold
for half a million.
- Should've been two.
- Except our lawyer caved in on us.
That won't happen again.
We're gonna get a lawyer
that's tough, that's savvy.
Someone who will step
on his grandmother for us.
Mr. Green, a David Murphy
would like to speak to you.
He says it's urgent.
Put him on the speaker.
This is an old college buddy.
- It'll only take a second.
- Jeremy?
Davey, I'm in the middle
of a meeting. What's up?
Well, listen,
we need you to close a deal.
- What kind of deal?
- A very big deal.
Ooh, big deal. Go on.
We're in Vegas at the Hilton.
We met John Gage.
You know who he is?
Sure, I know who he is.
A billionaire and major poon hound.
He is?
Go on.
He offered us a million dollars.
Million dollars?
For what, your kidneys?
For one night with Diana.
What do you mean?
- One night, like...
- Yes.
Could you excuse me for a second?
Let me get this straight.
He offered you a million dollars
for a night with your wife?
As in your wife Diana?
And you agreed to it?
I don't know what to say.
How could you
do something like that?
How could you negotiate
without me?
Never negotiate
without your lawyer. Never!
For a woman like Diana, I could have
got you at least two million!
Obviously, you don't want to
get screwed, and then screwed.
Hey, stay, please.
This is damage control.
Two seconds. Eat cookies.
There's cookies coming.
You don't understand.
We've heard enough.
- You're hired.
- We love your style.
Great. Gladys, check
the gentlemers schedules.
- Call me next week. Wednesday?
- Great.
See you then.
Thanks for coming.
- No. Thank you.
Okay, David,
before we go any further...
let's get the moral issue
out of the way.
- Leave that to us.
- I was referring to my fee.
I get five percent.
Do you want to elaborate
on the verification clause?
Verification.
That means you pay even if
the relationship isn't consummated.
You mean, if I'm impotent.
It's important for a lawyer
to cover contingencies.
I can live with that.
The John Garfield clause?
That's if you die in the act.
I have no problem with that either.
Can I have your pen?
- You're pretty good, you know?
- Thank you.
You should come work for me.
We have a deal.
A million dollars will be deposited
in your casino account...
in the morning.
So.
You can go.
Gentlemen...
I think it's time
for men of good will to...
take leave of one another.
It's all right.
I don't bite.
So...
what, should I go undress?
Cheer up. You got to find a more
creative way to think about this.
Look at it like an episode
of The Dating Game that went awry.
Ladies and gentlemen...
we wish to welcome you
to ourjamboree.
First punch, over he went.
I couldn't believe it.
I know we could have
gotten two million.
Here's your Buddha.
Davey, no point getting out
the crying towel.
You got a million bucks, buddy.
A million bucks.
Take the ribbon from your hair
She's an amazing woman.
She really is.
Couldrt have gotten 500
for my girlfriend.
Not that I'd do that.
But it's okay that you did.
This is a different situation.
She agreed to it.
You've gotta remember that.
It's not like it's hard duty.
He's a great-looking guy.
For a million bucks,
I'd sleep with him.
Maybe not.
Hey, buddy!
Come on.
Come on!
What have I done?
D!
It's me!
Where is she?
Where's my wife?
Diana!
Please!
Where did she go?
What happened to her?
- Where'd they go?
- Up, up.
Up where?
D!
They sent for me.
They said you were ready.
Come here.
You missed a button.
Thank you.
I want to show you something.
What happened?
Lights went off.
I see that. Why?
Look.
Can you turn those off too?
I'm working on it.
Who made the decision?
We both did.
Nah.
Do it for your own reasons,
or don't do it.
- You don't know him.
- I know he didn't stop you.
If you were mine...
I wouldn't share you
with anyone.
You have no right
to judge David.
You're the one
who has to buy women.
You think I have to buy women?
Why me, then?
I bought you because
you said you couldn't be bought.
I can't be bought.
We're just gonna fuck,
as I understand it.
You might enjoy it.
Don't bet on it.
I think I will.
Heads, we do...
tails, we call the whole thing off,
turn the boat around, go home.
No hard feelings.
What do you say?
It's your party.
This is my lucky dollar...
so I can't lose.
Trust me.
Nothing's gonna happen
you don't choose.
- I love you.
I told myself it was over...
like a dream that vanishes
in the morning light...