Sorry.
This is a very special
song for our group.
True. That's why you people are
singing it with full strength.
- What lies? We started it for church.
- Right.
Sings in the local trains like
this, "you know or don't know".
She is so funny. Isn't it?
Hi mons...
-
- no... no... no...
<or sings like same,
you know, or don't know>
where are you going?
- Very sad.
- Hi mala.
- Jagi my piggy.
- Yes shaali my kaali.
- What's the matter?
- When your flight will take off?
- Means?
- When you'll tell mala?
- What?
- You know...
come... come... i'm your love...
50 times i asked her for
friendship then i came for a date.
- If i'll say l word then i'll get gpl.
- Jignesh...
you are a stud. You bring
airhostess on a date at airport.
- You.
- Let's go.
There they are...
why are you standing outside? Go inside.
- In ac.
- Entry is banned.
- Banned, why?
- Some matter of bomb.
Means, have to stand over here
in heat. I don't believe this.
Let's go mala, our group is very
fun loving. We'll enjoy a lot.
Tell me one thing didi, what i'm
doing at airport on my off day?
Oh sorry mala! It's like this our special
friends are coming back today and you know...
- then have to brought flowers and sweets...
- that i haven't brought.
Why you bring me? I don't know them
and i came like an idiot to receive them.
I hate airports.
I love airports.
After a long time when people meet
so every meeting has a new story.
I know stories but i
hate stories too much.
Specially those stories
which ends on airports.
Why? Is it a joke to get
inside, stop the plane? Try to
shout them down with bullet
by considering as terrorist.
- Aren't you too much romantic?
- No. I hate romance.
I mean, seriously guys. Sad
couples all around, before marriage
they doubt and fight and just
after marriage, 'we are bored'.
Not at all.
- If he find the right person.
- Made for each other, bullshit.
It happens in dreams not in real life.
It happens, swear.
Tell me where it happens?
I'm curious tell me.
For that have to hear a story
and you don't like stories.
What kind of story? Love story.
- In which heroes, heroines an villains.
- Villains are a bit less.
- But fights, songs and misunderstandings.
- Err full on!
- And climax at airport.
- Absolutely right.
- Sounds horrible, no thank you.
- Listen, by the way flight is late.
- I'll feel bore then i'll tell you clearly.
- Okay.
- Have to.
- Mala, it's like...
once upon a time girl and a boy...
story starts from a dream.
In dream a man having sword in his hand in
full drama costume is ridding a horse.
Hold it... hold it... hold it.
- Is this your dream.
- No.
- Then how you know?
- Because jai saw those kind of dreams.
- And who is jai?
- That, who is watching this dream now listen.
Listen.
Hello.
I just be back.
- Jai.
- Emergency mom.
- But your exams.
- Its aditi.
She needs me.
I'm sorry, we tried completely
but we aren't able to save her.
I want to say something.
Radha isn't among us today.
I remember that day till today,
when we saw her first time.
Big black eyes, innocence on
face but too much mischievous.
She stayed with for a while, touched our
life. We'll never forget radha, aditi.
Come.
Together we pray, wherever
radha go, stay happy,
remember us and at least
learn to catch the rats.
- Was radha a cat?
- Yes.
- Cat's funeral.
Even her funeral was done properly.
- Are you all mad?
- We all aren't, aditi.
She picked radha from college and
since then she was like her daughter.
Everything is on extreme for aditi.
Love, hate, attachment.
She hadn't do anything by weighing.
But how come you guys
took all this seriously?
No... no... actually
we also felt it silly...
...but not jai.
Jai only knew one thing.
Aditi was depressed.
Only aditi's smile was necessary for him.
- Did you like aditi too much?
- Yes too much.
And booms like jai but if jai could
see anything except aditi then.
- Mom.
- Yeah.
I'm over here.
Pumi aunty.
Thanks.
Yes pumi speak.
What?
Again.
This is the limit. That son of bitch.
No... no... no... it's useless.
Police complaints are enough.
Okay if you want to write
letter to police commissioner.
I'm going to talk to newspaper.
Yeah... yeah... till the time we haven't
suspend him he'll not learn the lesson.
Yes... yes, i'll see you in the office.
- This is the limit.
- Your old friend inspector vagmari.
Who else would be? He bang a 14
years old boy in police lockup.
Can you believe it? That man...
- he needs his own bamboo.
- Mom... mom... mom... mom.
Calm... take the breath
inside and release it slowly.
- Really.
- What do you wana have in breakfast?
- Is it your turn?
- Yes.
Your turn but it's my mood.
- Mom.
- Yes.
Yesterday night, again
i dreamt that dream.
Which dream?
Same, that somebody is having a
sword in hand and ridding a horse.
You haven't put pepper on it.
I'm not sure but i felt it before...
i think he's dad.
Dad... your dad.
- My husband.
- I think so.
Ridding a horse and
sword in hand. Oh come on!
How could you?
How could you think such like that jai?
- I just...
- you know that how much he hates uproar.
It's far for him to fight but he
can't even see somebody fighting.
He lost his life in it.
He went to stop somebody's
fight and never came back.
Mom... mom... mom... i'm sorry.
It's dream what can i do?
This is depressing jai that you
are dreaming that kind of dreams.
Jai singh rathore aka rats was
world's most non-violent person.
Seriously if ghandi-ji is alive
then he must cry after seeing jai.
And he suffers from
acidity after seeing aditi.
Fatu you, your mother... your father...
your whole family, son of swine's.
What the hell is going on?
Jai, i'm going to give him a lesson.
- Come dog i'll show you.
- Aditi are you mad?
- You called aditi fatu.
- Not her, you.
Me.
- What's the problem?
- Lets go from here.
- Vivak it's enough now.
- Keep your cat collared...
...otherwise she'll come
under my car, understand?
From same place your mom picked you up.
Jai if she isn't stop shouting
then i'll bang you out.
Is jai afraid of you?
- Yeah.
- Isn't it?
Go jai and bang his face.
- Who? Me.
- Come swine... come.
Nileash leave my hand
otherwise i'll bang your face.
Leave... leave... leave...
aditi what are you doing? Look
at his face he'll kill you.
I didn't want to fight but you
haven't leave me any choice.
I'll not spare anything, you'll
take everything in your hand.
Let's go, today will
have to teach you lesson.
Okay, yours...
- what?
- Your dad is college trusty.
- Yes, so?
- If i'll bang you then i'll be expelled.
- You'll be banged, understand.
- And nothing will happen to you?
Because it's your father's college.
You don't know my father, my band
will be struck more than yours.
What?
- He'll say, it isn't right to act like this, next time.
- Next time don't do it, end.
Leave it, my father is hitler... hitler.
- What'll he do?
- First of all he'll stop my pocket money.
Every time old-man do the same.
What are you talking about? Then...
...you aren't able to
eat anything in canteen.
I have so many friends. This neleash
i fed him too much. Why neleash?
- Off course, dude.
- So sweet, dude.
You are good friends, superb.
Okay listen vivak, after all that will
any problem stays between us. Fight finish.
Finish, dude.
Is there any gang war
is going on at college?
Will you offer me a drink
in friendship bond?
- Will you offer me?
- Off course.
Nando give two cokes.
- Cheers.
- Hay pay the money.
Vivak face was worth
watching after you left.
He stared at coke for two minutes.
And thinking and nobody dared to laugh.
But rats you had to gave him one punch.
Aren't your mom wash
your face with soap?
- You use too much abusive language.
- Leave it dude.
I haven't watch your
kind of coward in my life.
It's not about cowardness miyaoon,
i don't like fighting you know that.
Not even to save friend?
Vivak isn't my friend and it's much
more necessary to save him from you.
Smart.
Fatu. (fatu=coward).
- Aditi you are insulting rats.
- Don't call him rats.
Only i can call him rats, okay.
- Rats... rats... rats...
- shut up booms.
What happen to you?
I was... i mean... she was fighting
without any reason with aditi so...
look friends; i can't do this fighting.
Dad made only one promise with mom...
that i'll never raise
my hand on anybody.
So you can call me coward,
fatu whatever you want to say.
Makes no difference.
Hold on... hold on.
If somebody misbehave with me makes
no difference to you, isn't it?
If somebody rise hand on me then also
it doesn't makes any difference to you.
You'll never rise your
hand on anybody, right?
Right.
Miyaoon.
- Poor guy.
- I know.
- He's only fulfilling his dad's, what's the word?
- Dreams...
following his dad's words.
What?
Actually savitry aunty
modified truth a little bit.
She described jai's dad a
combination of mahatma gandhi and
gotham budh but in reality amar
singh rathore was bit different.
Amar last time i'm telling you
to stop coming in amar's dreams.
You stop making him coward.
I feel shame after seeing him.
He's rathore. Rathore of ranjhor.
If i want to make him rathore of
ranjhor then i never quit ranjhore.
You and your whole family is mad.
Mad, crazy, foolish male.
Jai is calm and simple boy
who don't rise hand on anybody.
Will you hide him under your
feathers throughout the life?
What do you feel savitri that he'll not carry
his customs after living away from his customs?
You can take the rathore out of ranjhor but
you can't take the ranjhor out of the rathore?
You'll see savitri, one day he'll
brighten the name of ranjhore,
rathore family and whole rajhistan
and you won't able to do anything.
Exactly, rathore family of ranjhore
village was very serious due to its manhood.
That's why, after amar singh's death
savitri aunty runaway from there.
Then jai was only five years old.
It was ranjhore village custom that boy have
to fulfill three conditions to become a man.
- What?
- Not now jiggi.
Why? She has to know those
three conditions otherwise
how come she understand
the story. Isn't it correct?
I'm not good in storytelling.
Everything has its
right time to come out.
Oh really! Then when
right time will come?
- After the end of the story.
- Stop it you two.
Then what happened?
Now straight jump on the last day of the college
and our farewell party were at aditi's home.
Where aditi's dad offered
jai a cheque of one million.
To forget aditi.
Oh shit! Really! I don't know.
She's pulling his leg
why are you slipping?
Okay don't do that again.
- Seriously.
- Sorry.
But piji and pumpkin are
the world's coolest parents.
Okay... okay... wait for me...
where are you?
We were talking about that day fight.
Look scratch is still on vivak's face.
Aditi lets dance.
Dance.
- And me.
- A little bit. One dance.
Rotu my lovely rotu if i'll dance then
rest of the party will be at garden.
Let's go.
- Jai let's dance.
- Sure one second.
Let's go miyaoon your attitude is enough.
You'll not dance today then
you'll never dance in life.
Jai breaking news i can't dance.
I know only papoo can't dance.
- I forgot.
- Go to dance floor then i'll show you.
- What we have to talk?
- May be he don't want to marry right now.
So it's alright, we only
talk about engagement.
Aditi is 20 years old. She is
with along with jai for five years.
Before that different kind of questions
rise up in the family, we do the announcement.
What do you think?
- Otherwise so many proposals will come.
- Absolutely.
So shall i talk to jai's mother?
First talk to jai. It'll be better.
Coca-cola on the rocks.
- Once more.
- Be careful friend.
Make it strong.
What happen routlu? Say it.
Nothing dude. Sometimes i
feel... i wish there is somebody.
- Who?
- Anybody.
To whom i'm visible and i can see her.
And then rest of the world go to hell.
Like jai and aditi.
- Rautlu... rautlu...
- enough.
Cheeky tell me, if you'll fall
in love then which song you sing?
Me?
Just a second.
Jai which song you'll sing?
Sorry a secret.
- That i'll sing only for her.
- Rats will you sing or have a slap?
Are paying mercy?
What a demo is it?
Madam.
Amit you son of a bitch.
Amit once you haven't looks
nice. Second you are poor. Third
if you sing like this then
which girl gone like you, jai?
Some poor or simple girl will be
found. Who sings much worse than me?
Sad. Aditi isn't poor otherwise
you can marry with her.
Amit don't be an ass. Go to your
room otherwise you gona have a slap.
I was in my room. I was studding
peacefully when you frogs disturbed. And
this is my home too, understand. Tell
all of them to go home. Let's go. Come.
Amit... amit.
Pijay and pumpkin are also worried.
Don't know what they do
in their room all day?
- Not working nor studying.
- But he paints.
What he paints? In my opinion
he just need a physiatrist.
Hello! Your brother is
sharper then all of us.
Are you mad? He insults you
more than anybody in the world.
Yes so he can get some reaction.
- What kind of reaction?
- Your anger.
Let's go goodnight. I pick you
up for college tomorrow morning.
Alright.
- Hi savitri aunty.
- Hi.
- What happen?
- Suddenly she realizes that college is over.
Sit, i bring water.
Sit.
Poor baby.
So now what's next?
- Further studies or...
- i haven't think on it till now aunty.
Don't know where college
five years has gone?
On phone beta. One
phone. (beta=daughter).
But you know jai was telling me that
you are thinking to join film school.
Yes, but dad is saying to do mba.
He has a point but now these days we
badly need intelligent film makers.
I mean for how long this silly movies will be
on? All this violence, gore, mixture and nonsense.
Don't waste your time mom because aditi
also going to make these mixture movies.
- You don't say.
- Whom you are listening aunty?
- Piji wants to meet you tomorrow morning.
- Why?
Do you forget his promise? College
finish welcome to the family.
- The jai singh rathore.
- Suite belongs to your father or it was rented.
Now everybody can't follow your style.
Dude tell me one thing, all the time that much
sweet and polite, can't you bore of yourself?
Amit shut up.
Here comes your watch-women.
Don't say anything to your
jai, he'll feel so hurt.
Amit i'm warning you. Yesterday
night i wasn't say anything.
Nothing, come on are you jerk?
Open the door i'll teach you a lesson.
God damn.
- Aditi.
- Listen.
Amit stop it.
- He started.
- Quite... quite...
i don't want to hear anything.
Err guest come at home. Go
and set yourselves properly.
Come son, we'll talk differently.
- Wow nice! Somebody is looking handsome.
- Somebody is looking gorgeous.
Okay, thank you.
- Sit... sit... sit...
- thank you.
So both of you will
together take my interview?
Interview.
Do you know why we call you over here?
- I think yes.
- So you are ready?
Yes. I means i was thinking first i do
mba but it can be done later on. Isn't it?
Yes... why not but son are you sure?
Yes absolutely, have to
do something for money.
For money?
Not only for money, status, respect,
success. Everything starts from here.
But jai, is money that much necessary?
If that is only about money
that i can't be that much happy.
I love you guys.
If i stay with you guys then
i feel that i'm at my home.
But your mother?
She'll be very happy and
she was waiting for that day.
How is it going guys?
Beta jai is frankly saying that
he's doing all this for money.
Obviously. So...
and after marriage he wants to stay
with us like a housemaster son-in-law.
- Excuse me.
- Wedding
who's wedding? Housemaster
son-in-law means what?
Jai are you willing to marry me?
- Oh shit!
- When did i talk about wedding?
Means what we were
talking about till now?
I was talking about job.
What job?
You said that when your
college is over so i join you.
I felt that you called
me for that purpose.
- What about wedding? You want to marry me.
- How dare you think such like that?
Ask your parents.
- Jesus.
- Christ.
They didn't want to
marry but that's crazy.
You said that from the first day of the college love
and always stay together and made for each other.
Like all of us aditi's
parents were confused.
Yeah.
The matter was that jai
and aditi were not in love.
Not in love.
Of course not.
- How could you think about it?
- What is the need to think in it?
Always you stay together or on phone. We haven't
saw you separated for five years so we think...
mom at least had to asked me once?
God this is so embarrassing.
- Shit...
- it's okay.
Alright. If you felt like this so thanks
you tried but nothing is such like this.
- Confirm you don't want to marry.
- Mom please.
We are sorry. We both are sorry.
We are too much ashamed off.
Enough! That's enough,
we'll finish this topic here.
But seriously there's one thing,
no matter what you don't want to
each other, but you wants to marry.
Yeah, definitely.
When we like someone, from that way.
Someone?
And how would you find that someone?
Why?
It will be found when time will come.
Allright.
From last five years how many guys
you have been noticed?
And that someone, your mr. Right will
sit next to you,
and you both will be laugh on him.
And if you found that someone, then
what do you think?
He wouldn't have problem with this
kind of friendship,
look! It's your life and you have to
think about this.
We all want that we found someone
special but how?
You both are meant to be special
for each other.
You tell me if you are in love with
aditi, then would you have
any problem?
Me?
I wouldn't tell you because i thought
that you and aditi are...
it's true we'll never find in life.
Nonsense!
We will find that special person.
And definitely we will find, wherever
he is hidden.
You looking for a guy?
Yeah! For you.
Idiot!
Hey! Correct, you both know each
other very well,
you have to find love for each other.
Jignesh patel!
Perfect plan.
It's completely makes sense,
look! Jai!
If aditi found a girl for you,
he let you meet her.
Either she supports your romance,
then why she have a problem with aditi
guys!
That's brilliant.
Jai! Sit!
Jai! I'll find you a stupid, silly,
romantic girl.
And you find a tough guy for me.
What do you say?
Superb!
Are you with us?
Ofcourse!
It's our time too.
Who knows? May be we'll find a
special person like crying bombs.
All these are with me.
I told you, today will be cover
charge, i can't come.
Come on boms, let's go somewhere else,
it's your old habit,
jigi, you pay for it.
Make it fast, our love is calling us,
come on, come on.
Don't worry,
i'll pay you when i'll get a job.
It's an account,
mine too.
Listen! Park it carefully,
sorry sir, we don't park horses,
take it, and listen!
Drink him some water.
Did i saw two guys came to disco
on horses?
I love this city,
anything could happen here.
They will never find someone else
in life.
I don't understand that why they
don't love each other?
Go, and take out the car,
what?
Go fast, start the car, i'm coming, \
you want me to hit you?
One minute,
please get away from it,
it's our personal matter.
I went to doctor,
why?
My reports has come,
you knew it, you knew it.
You knew it, and that night you
did with me.
Why nalini?
Don't be dramatic,
i have seen your scarface behind this
innocent face.
How many people you want to
give this sickness?
How many people you will drink them
death wine of your lust?
What they both have done wrong with
you?
Why you are behind these youth?
Look!
I am taking her to hospital,
do you have any problem?
No!
Thanks!
Don't be scare, this sickness
don't effect from touch.
Come on! Nalini!
No!
Leave me! I will take revenge from
this world,
i want to give this sickness to all
of them, leave me,
no! It's wrong, come with me.
No! No!
Meghna! Right?
Yes!
You already met jai,
that boms, rotlu, shali, jigi and
me, aditi, jai's best friend.
Just friends? Aren't you?
Before they thought there's something
between me and jai, but it wasn't.
Guys! There was something like that?
No!
Guys! Do we have a coffee?
Coffee! Coffee!
I am getting late, i should leave.
One coffee,
i am really getting late.
I'll carry you on,
i'll drop you.
Ok!
Guys! Guys!
Jai!
Take a car.
Shall we?
Ah!
Let's rock!
Jai singh rathore,
isn't it heavy name?
I've heard my garndpa wanted to
suggets my name zoravar singh rathore
that means zorro,
then?
Mom said that she fly jump from
third from.
But grandpa forgot that there was
two floors in our palace.
You lived in palace that actually
your name
should be his royal highness raj kumar
jai singh rathore.
Well! Your friends thinks you
are a prince.
They were talking about you all the
way.
I think that all was for you,
for me?
Why?
Why did you refused to marry with
jai?
What's the reason? He is poor
or ugly?
I am not in the mood of fighting.
May i sit for two minutes?
We were friends before?
What happen?
Why did you go so far away from me?
I went so far?
Really?
I was thinking today,
when any new factory has started
then why dad has gone to start it,
why not grandpa or uncle?
So?
Change your home, school,
are you mad?
I loved it, new place, new school,
new friends,
and that chinki, who came everyday
to play with you.
Shiya!
Shiya! Cute girl.
And in banglore,
that guy.
I teased you, your boy friend,
rana!
Rana!
He was just punk.
And that miss. Coaching, rag
laxmi ayer
poor! She did my entire home work,
do you remember any friend of mine?
Shit!
Even not any single.
Because i always had a friend.
I went to dehli and other people
came near to you.
I had other friends too,
so what?
What does it matter in our friendship?
Really?
And if tomorrow,
what's his name?
Yes! Jai!
Then if tomorrow jai,
didn't stay with you everytime,
and someone else nearby him,
that you won't care,
ofcourse not,
like today, i found a girlfriend
for jai,
but me and jai are...
what you've done?
Found a girlfriend for jai.
You found a girlfriend for jai.
Jai!
What's this?
He's a giant who ate fairy's mischief
son,
and he's dancing in his stomach.
Fairy's mischief son?
Meghna always played,
world is not like it's shown.
There is magic hidden is everything.
And she called this game what's this,
for example, what's this?
A trolly with full of luggages.
This is a giant cake with chocolate,
blueberry and strawberry icing.
So!
Good night,
good night, jai!
I pleased to meet you,
really?
Meghna! I...
again...
we'll meet again,
good night,
jai!
If i'll stuck in trouble again,
then will you come to save me?
Definitely!
I am going to watch james bond
tomorrow,
tvr,
at 08:00.
I am going alone, if something happens
there, then will you be there?
Where are you guys?
Did you gone to drop her poona?
Long walk? Hah?
Please, for sake of me, buy a mobile,
i'll gift you.
To hell with your privacy,
forget it, tell me.
What?
Did you get her number?
Yes!
Very cute, yeah, she's so amazing,
now i will slap you,
how many time you will say?
Tell me one thing?
Did you sung your song?
Song?
Have you gone mad? If i sung that
song on the way,
that she would left me alone,
forget it, are you happy?
Yes!
I have to find a nice guy for you,
if i needed a nice guy then i would
love with you.
I want a man, someone who can
take care of me,
if somebody misbehave with me then
he would broke his teeth,
ah! If you have in your mind like him
then tell me,
actually, exactly, i am going to meet
a same guy tomorrow,
shut up! Who?
Bond, james bond.
With meghna?
Yeah!
Where?
Tvr,
which time?
At 08:00.
Hai jai!
You are here,
hi! Meghna!
Hi!
Scoundrels! What are you doing here?
We came to watch picture and look
we have two extra tickets too,
really!
Show me,
shall we go,
next meeting after interval,
you are sitting alone?
Yes! Why?
Nothing, come on let's go,
jai! You must sit with your friends,
i came here with you,
shall we go?
Jai was happy and we were happy
for jai,
but all in this happiness nobody has
noticed
that how much aditi was trying to
be happy?
Stop the car,
what's this?
What what's this?
One minute,
it's an old tank,
wow! I thought it's a rocket launcher
it's a game, you won't understand,
i am going to slap you,
i have an imagination more that you,
really?
So...
what's this?
I know,
black lightning,
you know lightning,
but in black color,
witch, look at there,
her hat and her grass broom.
I swear i was just thinking about
this,
witch, who's coming to catch
childrens,
bye! Meghna,
good night, aditi.
Where are you going?
To drop meghna.
How long you will drop her,
her house is just here,
i know,
don't talk like idiots,
i will drop,
what?
Jai! You carry on, this time you
won't find a cab,
what?
What's wrong with you? I just want
to drop her and talk to her,
what happen?
You go,
go to her, say good bye to her,
you just go,
i always drop you home, jai.
You got a girlfriend then you will
forget your friends.
Jai singh rathore,
yes!
Whitle on your lips walk with jumps
what's the matter?
Nothing,
girlfriend,
what?
I have a girlfriend,
wow, congratulation my son.
Finally you told aditi your secret,
mom!
Tell me who is she?
Sandhaya,
not sandhya,
don't call her that,
like you don't know she loves you,
mom, she's a rotlu's girlfriend.
Who loves aditi,
nice group.
Mom!
Good night.
Stop!
What's her name?
Meghna!
Tell me the whole story,
perfect timing,
hello!
Mother! Mother! Come mother!
Long time no see,
i've never seen a unjustice, cruel
police officer like you.
No! There are lot of guys in
force like me.
You're making me a mock,
don't you regret for anything?
That boy's hand has broken, he got
a fracture,
that boy's hand has broken, he got
that was fine, from which hand he
stole, that hand has fractured.
If he stole, suppose he's a thief,
then find a proof, submit in court.
What's the meaning to hit him?
You have much time,
i investigate this matter just for
the transistor of rs. 1280.
Get some proof, take him to court
and send him to majestrate.
Give him two slaps and case finish.
You wants me to slap but it's natural,
if i didn't make you suspence then
my name is not savitri longer.
Allright!
How do you like champa?
Say it again,
what?
let's go from here,
for my sake let's go from here,
come here, you're showing your
eyes to a police officer.
I say it again,
champa!
Chameli!
Charulata!
What?
I forgot,
jai! What you suppose to do there?
You were suppose to hit him?
To a police officer?
He was misbehaving with you,
that's my problem.
And to fought with him you proved
him right.
Then what would be the difference
remains between my son and him?
What wrong my son did?
Somebody misbehave with his mother,
and he shouldn't say something,
amar! Don't start it again, please!
What do you mean? Do not
start it again.
I mean, enough.
I don't want to discuss ten times a
day,
if you wanted to made jai like you
then you should thought before death,
you want to make him coward,
he's the son of amar singh rathore,
that's what i am afraid of,
and i am afraid of this thing since
you went on horse to fight with some
family
and never come back alive,
so what i died in fight,
i was alone, i slap ten people before
death,
that eleven one attacked me from
behind.
If you came back alive to get ten
slaps then i would be happy,
you are a widow of a martyr.
You should be proud,
amar!
I'll kill you to enter in painting.
Why i am listening this?
Good night,
remember it, savitri.
One day jai will be complete three
conditions of ranjhor's man.
One! May i say again?
Speak!
He will be ride on horse,
second, he'll brake someone's bones,
third, he'll go to jail once.
Remember it, savitri,
these were the three conditions of
rathore man, lmpossible.
Jai wouldn't did it ever.
Did he?
Does he?
Whom he will kill?
That inspector.
And he'll really go to jail?
Hey guys, the flight is landed,
thank god,
one hour late,
then tell me, they will come out and
story will be incomplete.
Relax, mala! They will come,
lmmigration customs.
I need a coffee,
you got to be joking,
have your coffee later, please what
happen tell me.
Hi! Magan!
For whom this pop corn are?
Take this sharda your samosa!
Thank you!
If you complete your break fast then
should we work further?
Then it happend we could'nt meet
jay... but when he met... not alone!
Magna always was with him... you remember
the picknick? When magna was with us
how can we forget... your cheriet of fire
was fuel less!