JANE EYRE
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
(WIND HOWLING)
(SOBBING)
(DISTANT THUNDER)
(THUNDER CLAPPING)
I will die.
(MUFFLED CHATTERING)
St. John?
ST. JOHN: I found her at the door.
She's white as death.
DIANA: Hannah, some of that hot milk.
St. John, we would have stumbled upon
her corpse in the morning.
And she would have haunted us
for turning her away.
ST. JOHN: She's no vagrant.
I'm sure of it.
HANNAH: There's milk for you.
Here.
Ask her her name.
What's your name?
YOUNG JOHN REED: Jane Eyre.
Tell us how we may help you.
Your name?
YOUNG JOHN REED: Where are you?
Must hide...
(WIND CHIMES CLINKING)
St. John, we must get her warm.
ST. JOHN: Let us take her upstairs.
MARY: Will she die?
(FLOORBOARD CREAKS)
Where are you, rat?
I know you're here.
If you crawl out and say,
"Forgive me, Master Reed,"
I might consider it.
-Mama.
-John.
(GASPS)
There you are.
That book belongs to me, rat.
It belongs to my Uncle Reed.
Spoilt, miserable brat!
(GROANING)
-JOHN REED: Mama!
-For shame!
Mama!
You wretched imp!
She attacked me.
-I hate you, John Reed! I hate you!
-Hilary, take her! Take her!
Lock her in the red room.
JANE: No!
Please, please! No, it's haunted.
Please. It's haunted! No!
Please! Please!
If you don't sit still,
you will be tied down!
What we do is for your own good.
Pray for forgiveness, Miss Eyre,
or something bad will come down
that chimney and fetch you away.
Let me out, please!
Have mercy, Aunt Reed! Please!
(CREAKING)
(RUSTLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(RUSTLING CONTINUES)
(SCREAMS)
Do you know, Jane Eyre,
where the wicked go after death?
They go to hell.
And what is hell?
A pit full of fire.
Should you like to fall into this pit
and be burned there forever?
No, sir.
How might you avoid it?
I must keep in good health and not die.
(SIGHS)
What is her parentage?
She's an orphan.
Her mother was my husband's sister.
On his deathbed he exhorted me
to care for her.
I have always treated her
as one of my own.
If you accept her at Lowood School,
Mr. Brocklehurst,
keep a strict eye on her.
She has a heart of spite,
and I'm sorry to say
that her worst fault is that of deceit.
BROCKLEHURST: You can rest assured
that we shall root out the wickedness
in this small, ungrateful plant.
MRS. REED: And as for its vacations,
it must spend them all at Lowood.
(BELL RINGING)
You may leave.
You said I was a liar. I'm not.
If I were,
I should say I loved you, and I don't.
I dislike you worse
than anybody in the world.
People think you are good,
but you're bad and hard-hearted.
I'll let everyone know
what you have done.
Children must be corrected
for their faults.
Deceit is not my fault.
But you are passionate.
My Uncle Reed is in heaven,
so are my mother and father.
They know how you hate
me and wish me dead. They can see.
They see everything you do
and they will judge you, Mrs. Reed.
Get out.
(GIRL COUGHING)
ASSISTANT: Next. Show me your hands.
Stop there.
(COUGHING CONTINUES)
SCATCHERD: Very grand.
ASSISTANT: Next.
SCATCHERD: Step out of your fine dress.
Stay there.
ASSISTANT: Show me your hands.
JANE: My name is Jane Elliott.
ST. JOHN: Who can we send
for to help you?
JANE: No one.
I mustn't ever be found.
ST. JOHN: Join me to Thyself
with an inseparable band of love.
For Thou, even Thou alone,
dost satisfy him that loveth Thee.
And without Thee,
all things are vain and empty.
Amen.
ALL: Amen.
It's wonderful to see you up,
Miss Elliott.
Last week we thought
we'd be escorting your remains
to an unmarked grave.
DIANA: (CHUCKLES) She read
The Bride of Lindorf
and suddenly it's all
woebegone maidens and dramatic deaths.
JANE: I'm sorry to have
caused so much trouble.
DIANA: Nonsense.
MARY: You're the most exciting thing
that's happened here
since St. John's sermon
on the fall of Babylon.
JANE: I hope I'll not be eating long
at your expense, Mr. Rivers.
Then tell me where to place you.
Show me where to seek
work, that is all I ask.
You're not fit enough
to work. Is she, Di?
No. Stay with us.
You return to your posts
at the end of the month.
What must Miss Elliott do then?
I'll endeavor to help you,
if that's what you wish.
With all my heart, sir.
ST. JOHN: This school you
were at, Miss Elliott,
this charitable institution,
what did it prepare you for?
(GASPING)
Was it a thorough education?
Most thorough.
TEACHER: A little wit...
GIRLS: A little wit...
...will serve...
...a fortunate man.
Again. A little wit...
A little wit...
...will serve...
...a fortunate man.
Burns!
I will not have you
before me in that attitude.
All rise.
I see you are mortifying
this girl's flesh.
Sir, she was not...
It is your mission to render her
contrite and self-denying.
Continue.
(HELEN GROANS)
(TRAY SHATTERING)
The new girl.
This is the pedestal of infamy,
and you will remain
upon it all day long.
You will have neither food nor drink,
for you must learn
how barren is the life of a sinner.
Children, I exhort you
to shun her, exclude her,
shut her out from this day forth.
Withhold the hand of friendship
and deny your love to Jane Eyre,
the liar.
How do you bear being struck?
Miss Scatcherd hits me to improve me.
She's tormented by my faults.
If she hit me, I'd get that birch
and break it under her nose.
She'd find another soon enough.
My father used to preach
that life's too short
to spend in nursing animosity.
At my aunt's house,
I was solitary and despised.
She thought I could do
without one bit of love or kindness.
You are loved.
There's an invisible world
all around you,
a kingdom of spirits
commissioned to guard you, Jane.
Do you not see them?
Jane?
Have you something for me to do?
You're doing something already.
May I see?
These are wonderful.
St. John...
No, Mary, please...
See how skilled Jane is.
Is this how you perceive me,
Miss Elliott?
Well. How fierce I am.
Jane.
You're freezing.
Your little feet are bare.
Come into bed and cover yourself.
(COUGHING)
How are you?
I'm happy, Jane.
I'm going home.
Back to your father?
I'm going to God.
Don't be sad.
You have a passion for living, Jane.
And one day you'll
come to the region of bliss.
Don't leave me.
I like to have you near.
I will not leave you.
No one shall take me from you.
(COUGHS)
Helen!
(CRYING)
(CARRIAGE ROLLING AWAY)
Mr. Rivers? I wondered if you
had yet heard of any work I could do.
I found you a situation some time ago,
but I've delayed telling you
because the work is lowly
and I fear you'll scorn it.
I shan't mind what I do.
When I took over the parish
two years ago, it had no school.
I opened one for boys.
I now intend to open one for girls.
The schoolmistress will have
a cottage paid for by benefactors
and she'll receive ￡15 a year.
You can see how humble,
how ignoble it is.
Mr. Rivers, thank you.
I accept.
With all my heart.
But you comprehend me?
'Tis a village school,
cottagers' daughters.
What will you do
with all your fine accomplishments?
I will save them
till they're wanted. They will keep.
ROCHESTER: Jane.
You will be quite alone here.
I'm not afraid of solitude.
This is my first home
where I am neither dependent
nor subordinate to anyone.
Thank you, Mr. St. John.
It is small and plain, as I told you.
Then it'll suit me very well.
GIRL: Safe journey, Miss Eyre. Godspeed.
Goodbye, Miss Eyre.
-Safe journey.
-Thank you.
Bye, Miss Eyre.
Girls!
Goodbye.
DRlVER: Thornfield, Miss.
Wait here, Miss.
(DOOR OPENING)
How do you do, my dear?
-Are you Mrs. Fairfax?
-Indeed I am.
What a tedious journey
you must have had.
Your hands must be frozen. Here.
Goodness. How young you are.
I'm quite experienced, I can assure you.
Of course you are.
I'm sure we're very lucky to have you.
Leah, would you ask Martha
to bring a little hot port
and cut a sandwich or two?
Draw nearer the fire.
John is taking your trunk
up to your room.
I've put you at the back of the house,
I hope you don't mind.
The rooms at the front have much
finer furniture,
but they're so gloomy
and solitary, I think.
I'm glad you're come.
To be sure, this is a grand old house,
but I must confess that in winter
one can feel a little dreary and alone.
Leah's a very nice girl, and John
and Martha are good people, too,
but they are servants.
One cannot talk to them
on terms of equality.
JANE: Am I meeting Miss Fairfax tonight?
Who?
Miss Fairfax, my pupil?
Oh, you mean Miss Varens,
Mr. Rochester's ward.
She's to be your pupil.
Who's Mr. Rochester?
Why, the owner of Thornfield.
Mr. Edward Fairfax Rochester.
I thought Thornfield Hall
belonged to you.
Bless you, child, what an idea. Me?
I'm only the housekeeper.
Forgive me.
There is a distant connection
between Mr. Rochester and me,
his mother was a Fairfax,
but I'd never presume on it.
Heavens. Me, owner of Thornfield?
We shall have a cheerful
house this winter.
With Miss Varens here and with you,
we'll have quite a merry time of it.
I'm sure that last winter,
and what a severe one it was,
if it didn't rain it snowed,
if it didn't snow it blew.
I declare, not one soul came to
the house from November to February.
When spring finally came,
I thought it a great relief
I hadn't gone distracted.
(LAUGHING)
I've had Martha lay a fire.
I hope you'll be comfortable.
(FAINT CHATTERING)
GARDENER: Now, get that lot
turned over before frost comes down.
BOY: Do you want
the upper bit doing as well?
Yes.
MRS. FAIRFAX: We must open the
window in the study today
to let in some air.
I've never seen such
an ancient old house.
How beautifully you've preserved it.
Well, Mr. Rochester's visits
are always unexpected.
He doesn't like to arrive and find
everything all swathed up,
so I keep it in constant readiness.
Now, come and meet Miss Varens.
Did I mention she's French?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Will you ask her about her parents?
Mr. Rochester neglected to tell me
anything about her.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Her mother has passed away.
(GASPS)
Adèle is going to show us
her accomplishments.
Oh!
(SINGING FRENCH SONG)
How very French.
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
Very good. Very good.
Now, we're going to make a press.
Shut the book up.
Butterfly.
And what was it
before it was a butterfly?
Caterpillar.
"I shall leave and walk into town."
(GASPS) "Do not go," begged her maid.
"The Gytrash roams these hills."
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
A spirit of the North
that lies in wait for travelers.
It tenants the carcasses of beasts,
possesses horses, wolves, great dogs.
You know it only by its eyes,
which burn as red as coals,
and if one should chance upon you...
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Nothing. A mere story.
What nonsense.
MRS. FAIRFAX: Whatever brings
you up here?
I've been waiting to pour our tea.
I'm not in need of tea, thank you.
It's a quiet life, isn't it?
This isolated house,
a still doom for a young woman:
I wish a woman could have action
in her life, like a man.
It agitates me to pain that the
skyline over there is ever our limit.
I long sometimes for a power of vision
that would overpass it.
If I could behold all I imagine...
I've never seen a city,
I've never spoken with men.
And I fear my whole life will pass...
Now, exercise and fresh air,
great cures for anything, they say.
I have some letters to post.
Will you take them?
(PANTING)
(WOOD CREAKING)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
Up! Up, you cursed beast! Up!
(GROANING)
-Stand back.
-Are you injured, sir?
May I be of some help?
Where did you come from?
Just below, at Thornfield Hall.
I am the governess.
I'm on my way to post a letter.
Can I fetch someone to help?
The governess.
You may help me yourself.
Get hold of his bridle
and lead him to me.
If you would be so kind.
(NEIGHING)
It would be easier to bring me
to the horse. Come here.
I must beg of you to please come here,
Miss Governess.
Hold it.
Make haste with your letter.
For who knows
what might lurk in these dark woods.
MRS. FAIRFAX: Leah, go and
light the fire in the master's bedroom.
And tell Martha to prepare for tea.
LEAH: Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Rochester's here.
Go and change your frock.
He wishes to meet you.
-Leah, take her cloak.
-I have to change?
I always dress for the evening
when Mr. Rochester's here.
But all my dresses are the same.
You must have one that's better.
He's in a terrible humor.
His horse fell in Hay Lane,
and his ankle is sprained.
He's at the doctor this half hour.
Where have you been?
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
ROCHESTER: Let her sit.
I've examined Adèle and I
find you've taken great pains with her.
She's not bright, she has no talents,
yet in a short time she's improved.
Thank you, Mr. Rochester.
You've been resident here three months?
Yes, sir.
And from whence do you hail?
What's your tale of woe?
Pardon?
All governesses have a tale of woe.
What's yours?
I was brought up by my aunt,
Mrs. Reed of Gateshead,
in a house even finer than this.
I then attended Lowood School,
where I received
as good an education
as I could hope for.
I have no tale of woe, sir.
Where are your parents?
Dead.
-Do you remember them?
-No.
And why are you not with Mrs. Reed
of Gateshead now?
She cast me off, sir.
Why?
Because I was burdensome
and she disliked me.
No tale of woe?
MRS. FAIRFAX: I daily thank providence
for sending us Miss Eyre.
She's an invaluable...
Don't trouble yourself to give her
a character. I'll judge for myself.
I have her to thank for this sprain.
Sir?
You bewitched my horse.
I did not.
Were you waiting
for your people on that lane?
I have no people, sir.
I mean for the imps
and elves and little green men:
The sad truth is, they are all gone.
Your land is neither wild
nor savage enough for them.
Adèle brought me these. Are they yours?
Yes, sir.
Where did you get your copies?
Out of my head.
That head I now see on your shoulders?
Yes, sir.
Who's this?
The evening star.
-Were you happy when you painted these?
-Yes.
To paint is one of the keenest pleasures
I have ever known.
Then your pleasures have been few.
Are you satisfied with them?
Far from it. I imagine things
I'm powerless to execute.
You've secured the
shadow of your thoughts.
Yet the drawings are,
for a schoolgirl, peculiar.
Good night.
JANE: Come, Adèle.
Most merciful Father,
we give Thee humble thanks for this,
Thy special bounty.
Amen.
-Amen.
(FAINT PIANO MUSIC)
Sit nicely, please, Adèle.
(PIANO LID CLOSING)
ROCHESTER: Pilot!
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(PILOT BARKING)
ROCHESTER: (SHOUTING) Pilot, come here!
(GUNSHOTS)
ROCHESTER: Go on, further down!
ROCHESTER: By the river!
He's very abrupt and changeful.
What manner of man is he?
He's a good master.
He's fine company, too, when he...
(GUNSHOTS)
Except when he's in an ill humor.
Adèle.
ROCHESTER: I hate to reload.
(GUNSHOT)
(ROCHESTER GRUNTS)
(ADÈLE SPEAKS FRENCH)
(LAUGHING)
On three. One, two, three.
Ready?
Oh!
-Think that's it, sir.
-Take it down to the river.
Come on.
(PLAYING PIANO)
Keep it.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Take it away and disembowel it.
-Beautiful.
-Miss Eyre.
I'm not fond of children.
Nor do I particularly enjoy
simple-minded old ladies.
But you might suit me, if you would.
How, sir?
By distracting me
from the mire of my thoughts.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
That is how Maman used to say.
Precisely.
And that's
how she charmed my English gold
out of my English pocket.
MRS. FAIRFAX: Let's go and try it on,
shall we?
(SIGHING)
Your gaze is very direct, Miss Eyre.
Do you think me handsome?
No, sir.
What fault do you find with me?
I have all my limbs and features.
I beg your pardon, sir.
I ought to have replied
that beauty is of little consequence.
You're blushing, Miss Eyre.
And though you're not pretty any more
than I am handsome,
I must say it becomes you.
And now I see you're fascinated by
the flowers on the rug.
Come, speak to me.
Fact is, Miss Eyre,
I'd like to draw you out.
You have rather the look
of another world about you.
I don't wish to treat you as inferior.
Yet you'd command me to speak?
Are you very hurt by my tone of command?
There are few masters
who'd trouble to enquire
whether their paid subordinates
were hurt by their commands.
Paid subordinate?
I'd forgotten the salary.
Well, on that mercenary ground,
will you consent to speak as my equal
without thinking
that the request arises from insolence?
I'd never mistake
informality for insolence, sir.
One, I rather like. The other,
nothing freeborn should ever submit to.
Humbug.
Even for a salary.
Most free-born things
would submit to anything for a salary.
But I mentally shake hands with you
for your answer.
Not three in 3,000
schoolgirl governesses
would have answered me
as you've just done.
Then you've not spent much time
in our company, sir.
I'm the same plain kind
of bird as all the rest,
with my common tale of woe.
I envy you.
How?
Your openness, your unpolluted mind.
When I was your age,
fate dealt me a blow.
And since happiness is denied me,
I've a right to get
pleasure in its stead.
And I will get it, cost what it may.
Then you'll degenerate still more.
But, Miss Eyre,
if the pleasure
I was seeking was sweet and fresh,
if it was an inspiration, if it
wore the robes of an angel of light,
what then?
To speak truth, sir,
I don't understand you at all.
I fear the conversation
has got out of my depth.
You're afraid of me.
I'm not afraid.
I've simply no wish to talk nonsense.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
Do you never laugh, Miss Eyre?
Only rarely, perhaps.
But you're not naturally austere,
any more than I'm naturally vicious.
I can see in you the glance
of a curious sort of bird
through the close-set bars of a cage,
a vivid, restless captive.
Were it but free,
it would soar, cloud-high.
(DOOR OPENING)
MRS. FAIRFAX: Leah,
have you seen Mrs. Poole?
LEAH: Yes, ma'am.
The master's in no mood
for any more mistakes.
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
Who's there?
(FAINT THUD)
(LOUDER THUD)
(COUGHING)
Wake up, sir! Wake up! Sir! Wake up!
(HISSING)
The quilt! Give it here!
(COUGHING)
(ROCHESTER GRUNTING)
A noise aroused me from my sleep.
What noise?
There was someone at my door.
Stay here.
Don't make a sound.
(TICKING)
Say nothing about this.
You're no talking fool.
-But...
-I'll account for this state of affairs.
Say nothing.
Yes, sir.
Is that how you would leave me?
Jane, fire is a horrible death.
You've saved my life.
Don't walk past me
as if we were strangers.
But what am I to do then?
I've a pleasure in owing you my life.
There is no debt.
I knew you would do me
good in some way.
I saw it in your eyes
when I first beheld you.
Their expression did not strike
my very inmost being so for nothing.
People talk of natural
sympathies. You...
(WHISPERING) Good night then, sir.
You will leave me, then?
I am cold.
Go.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Has Mr. Rochester not sent for us today?
Why, he's gone away.
Were you not aware?
He left after breakfast.
He's gone to the Leas.
It's Mr. Eshton's place.
I believe Blanche Ingram is there.
She's a great favorite of his.
I saw her two years ago
when Mr. Rochester gave a party here.
She's a most elegant girl.
They sang a duet together.
They made a lovely harmony.
I was quite surprised
he didn't make a proposal,
but she has no fortune.
In every other way
they'd make a splendid match.
Perhaps it's his intention now.
He's far more likely to
have gone off to Europe.
He often goes without so much
as a fare-you-well,
and I don't see him for a year.
LEAH: I collected the burnt linen
from the master's room.
MRS. FAIRFAX: That's fine.
Just go make up the bed.
JANE: England is a great power, Adèle.
British ships set sail from here
to the outer limits of our empire,
navigating the five oceans
and four corners of our world.
From Canada, here,
all the way to the south of Africa
and the Cape of Good Hope.
Across the Indian Ocean,
to Australia and New Zealand,
and on to Burma, China,
India and Malaya.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Nothing.
On these distant horizons,
you will find all manner of men.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
He's coming back tomorrow.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
He's given me directions
to prepare all the rooms.
I'm to get more staff
from the George Inn.
Miss Ingram's coming.
Supplies to be got,
the linen, mattresses...
I'll go to the George now.
No, no, I'll tell Martha...
May I assist you, Mrs. Fairfax?
Oh...
(CARRIAGES APPROACHING)
(CHATTERING)
South-facing rooms
for Lady Ingram and Miss Ingram.
Colonel Dent and Mrs. Dent
must have the river view.
MARTHA: I reckon master's
taken a fancy to that Miss Ingram.
He may well have asked her already.
UNDERCOOK: I'll wager
he will by end of week.
You mark my words.
SOPHIE: Adèle.
(ADÈLE CHATTERING IN FRENCH)
What's she saying?
Mr. Rochester is here.
Everybody out.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
BLANCHE: Edward.
ROCHESTER: Allow me, Miss Ingram.
LADY INGRAM: I'd forgotten
how masculine Thornfield is
BLANCHE: I think you need more flowers.
ROCHESTER: I have the fairest
of all on my arm.
Come away, Adèle.
Tonight, he wants both of you
in the drawing room after dinner.
Not me, surely.
I'm instructed to tell you,
if you resist,
he'll come up and get you himself.
But I don't have a dress.
Don't worry, child, who'll notice?
Mademoiselle!
(LAUGHING)
LADY INGRAM: I thought you were not
fond of children, Mr. Rochester.
ROCHESTER: Nor am I, Lady Ingram.
LORD INGRAM: What induced you
to take charge of her?
ROCHESTER: She was left on my hands.
Why don't you send her to school?
ROCHESTER: She has a governess.
Poor child.
I had about half a dozen in my day,
all detestable incubi.
BLANCHE'S BROTHER: It's true.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
Mr. Rochester, beware the governess.
BLANCHE: Mama thinks
they're generally hysterics.
LADY INGRAM: Or degenerates.
I thank heaven I have done with them.
BLANCHE: It's a miracle
I survived my education.
I remember Miss Wilson screaming,
"You villainous child!"
That's right. She tried
to set her hair on fire.
Frequently, I might add.
Anyway, enough of this dreary race.
We shall have music
and a new subject.
Signor Eduardo, what shall it be?
(PLAYING HARPSICHORD)
ROCHESTER: I give you beauty.
BLANCHE: There's nothing new to be said.
I give you back male beauty.
LADY INGRAM: Well, that's my son.
BLANCHE'S BROTHER: Hear hear.
A man should pay no heed to his looks.
He should possess
only strength and valor.
Gentleman or highwayman,
his beauty lies in his power.
Then a pirate would do for you?
(CONTINUES PLAYING HARPSICHORD)
(SINGING)
Why did you leave the room?
I am tired, sir.
Why didn't you come and speak to me?
I haven't seen you for weeks.
It would have been normal
and polite to wish me good evening.
You seemed engaged.
You look pale.
I am well.
What have you been doing
while I've been away?
Teaching Adèle.
You're depressed.
What's the meaning of this?
Your eyes are full...
What is it?
There's a gentleman to see you, sir.
(SIGHING)
From Spanish Town, Jamaica.
And indeed I think
he does come from some hot place
because he won't take off his coat.
Mr. Richard Mason.
I've put him in the morning room.
Have I done wrong?
Bring him to my study.
Jane, this is a blow.
If I were to go to those people
and they looked at me
coldly and sneered,
and then left me one by one,
what would you do?
Would you go with them?
No, sir. I'd stay with you.
You'd dare condemnation for my sake?
For the sake of any friend
who deserved it.
(DOOR CLOSING)
Richard.
Fairfax.
How the devil are you?
Splendid.
I'm sorry. I see you have guests.
'Tis no trouble. Come.
(FAINT THUD)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(LOUDER THUD)
MAN: What on Earth was that?
-LADY INGRAM: Where is Rochester?
-Wait for me.
I'm here. Be composed. A servant
has had a nightmare, that's all.
I must see you back into your rooms
because until the house is settled,
she can't be properly looked after.
BLANCHE: Is there anything I might do?
Miss Ingram, ladies, please,
return to your nests
like the doves that you are.
I assure you, all is well.
LORD INGRAM: Noisy old house.
Come, my lily flower.
I told you it was nothing.
Please.
Come with me.
(GROANING)
Can you clean this?
(GASPS)
Yes.
ROCHESTER: Drink, Richard.
It will give you the strength you lack.
-RICHARD: Will it hurt me?
-Drink!
I must go for the doctor.
Sponge the blood away when it returns.
Give him water if he wants it.
Do not speak to him for any reason.
And, Richard,
on pain of death, do not speak to her.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(THUD)
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
(BREATHING RAGGEDLY)
(CLATTERING)
(WIND HOWLING)
(THUD)
(GASPS)
(DOOR OPENING)
How does he?
He is sleeping.
Hurry, Carter. Be on alert.
The sun will soon rise
and he must be gone.
Let's have a look, shall we?
Flesh is torn as well as cut.
Very, very unpleasant.
-RICHARD: Fairfax.
-Drive!
It's a strange night you've passed.
Yes, sir.
You showed no fear.
I was afraid of the inner room.
You were in no danger.
Mr. Rochester, who did that violence?
I cannot tell you.
Why do you protect them?
I drag through life a capital error.
Its consequence blights my existence.
For years, I've sought to escape it.
This spring, I came home heart-sore
and soul-withered.
And I met a gentle stranger
whose society revives me.
With her, I feel I could live again
in a higher, purer way.
Tell me,
am I justified in overleaping an
obstacle of custom to attain her?
There is an obstacle?
A mere conventional impediment.
But what can it be?
If you cherish an affection, sir,
then fortune alone cannot impede you.
Yes.
And if the lady is of noble stock
and has indicated that
she may reciprocate...
Jane, of whom do you think I speak?
Of Miss Ingram.
I'm asking what Jane Eyre would do
to secure my happiness?
I would do anything for you, sir.
Anything that was right.
You transfix me quite.
I feel I can speak to you now
of my lovely one,
for you've met her and you know her.
She's a rare one, isn't she?
Fresh and healthy,
without soil or taint.
I'm sure she'll regenerate me
with a vengeance.