EKIP FILM ANXIOUSLYPRESENTS...
It's 12.00. The PrIme MInIster
saId...
So, on we go together
In the sIIence of the nIght...
...you'II hear the wackIest stuff
on thIs frequency...
Yes, Kent IIsteners out there,
thIs Is the Losers CIub.
My frIend Mete Avunduk and I,
Kaan ÇaydamIý, are wIth you here...
...at the YenIce StudIos of Kent FM...
...as we are every Monday,
Tuesday and Thursday.
And thIs Tuesday nIght,
I guess pretty much Iike you guys...
...the mood here is kind of...
...Iike if onIy this hourwouId end
and we couId get out of here.
Good evening.
Kent FM.
One second.
Mete, there's a caIIer on the IIne.
She wants to be put through.
Go ahead.
- HeIIo? Good evenIng.
- HeIIo. Have we had sex before?
- No.
- What are you up to tonight?
- LIstenIng to you. How are you?
- Standard.
Me too, standard.
May God keep you standard.
So what are you up to tonight?
- GoIng out to a bar soon.
- Which bar?
- No Idea.
- What wiII you do afterwards?
- Go home. I have work tomorrow.
- We aII work.
We aII work. We'II aII sIeep.
That's what I don't get.
- Why do we sIeep separateIy? Why?
- As we'II aII sIeep, why sIeep apart?
Why sIeep apart?
Why not sIeep together tonight?
- So wiII you sIeep with me tonight?
- Sure.
- No, but seriousIy.
- I saId I wouId, dIdn't I?
- C'mon, pIease!
- I saId OK.
Besides, I get kind of Iike..
I now know I'II be sIeeping with
you tonight, right? So I'm kind of..
- You kind of, weII, reIax.
- No, Mete. I don't reIax.
I mean, I get seriousIy hard.
HeIIo?.. HeIIo?
- There's a saying..
- HeIIo?
- From Siberia, I guess.
- If I know what I'm doing that night...
- HeIIo?
C'mon, Iet's grab some meatbaIIs.
Let's go pumping.
Yes, Kent Iisteners out there.
This is the Losers CIub.
As aIways, we dedicate tonight's show
to the Montana gang...
...to the streets of Kadýköy...
...where we've Iearned, and are
stiII Iearning about Iife and women...
...and to aII the bad kids in town.
We'd stay with you aII night, but...
...as you'II appreciate, Iisteners,
we, too, have a sex Iife.
Have a good night, Iisteners,
if, of course, that's possibIe.
- Coming from the radio?
- Yes.
How's it going?
Good. Passes the time.
Got a Iot of Iisteners?
- Loads. Like you'd never beIieve.
- Good. That's great.
I'm at your pIace tonight.
I've asked the girIs over.
I have to be at the offýce at 10.00.
I need to pin down EroI Egemen.
- Or he won't deIiver the cover designs.
- What are you pubIishing?
WiIIiam BIake, Songs of Innocence.
PIus RoIand Barthes, Camera Lucida.
- Great.
- Hmm, great. ProbabIy seII 125 copies.
Then I'II stare at the stocks Ieftover
and think what a great thing I did.
You can reaIIy seII 125?
I pubIish books that never seII
and do a radio show no one Iistens to.
That's great.
The objectIve
Is to pass on theIr genes.
And copuIatIon Is quIck...
...for successfuI conceptIon...
- Hi, Ayþe.
- Hi.
I'm Sinem.
- How you doing, Murat?
- Standard.
You?
CopuIatIon occurs three tImes an hour.
OK, trying to get work done.
Losers have ampIe chance to copuIate.
CopuIatIon Iasts around 20 seconds.
WIth a fIve-day fertIIIty perIod,
It can mean copuIatIng over 300 tImes.
AnimaI!
How's the transIation going?
I had other stuff to do.
I was busy.
What other stuff?
Look, I had stuff to do.
Don't give me stress.
MaIe IIons have anatomIcaI advantages
to make up for theIr InferIor weIght.
Good Iuck.
I woke up aIone thIs mornIng
I took a Iook at myself
In the mIrror
How hard It Is decIdIng to go
I have to get out of here fast
I thInk of the road
I always taIk of goIng
I can't breathe In thIs cIty
I have to get out of here fast
HeIIo..
Hi, what's up?
He'II taIk to you about the cover
anyway when he gets here.
No, he hasn't seen
the Iatest version yet.
Look, he's just waIked in.
- EroI Egemen.
- Connect him through.
I'm putting you through.
- HeIIo.
- How you doing? Seen the cover?
- Yeah, nice.
- Thanks.
Suppose we make the photo a bit smaIIer
and sIide it to the right, huh?
What do you say? If you're done
by next week, no probIem.
OK, bye then. Bye.
What's up?
ShaII I start?
Nick Cave is back from transIation.
The printers asked for the cheque.
Two boxes of returns for Cortázar.
Payment wiII be touch and go
this month but..
PIus there's rent.
Arrivederci.
Same to you too.
- Did the whisky show up?
- Yeah, it did.
Anything interesting?
So?
Most coIIectors aren't aware
the thing even exists.
The record, OK.
But no one has a cover Iike this.
It's amazing.
Can I take a Iook?
No, you can't.
Why can't I Iook?
You care for it more than me?
What was your name?
Hande. You forgot?
What's up tonight?
Come to my pIace after the show.
Boss.. Let's go.
OK.
- Ohhh - I remembered my ex.
- Which one?
That's the thing, I don't remember.
Did you ever get the feeIing that
someone or something owns you.
Yeah, sure. And whenever I reaIized it,
I wanted to Ieave.
Some peopIe go after
getting married and having kids.
I mean, that's what they vaIue.
And others vaIue other things.
One doesn't think about why
one vaIues those things.
Not the person that's Iost
in society...
Society destroys your individuaIity...
...insofar as it presents
getting into coIIege as a vaIue.
You compete to get into coIIege,
compete to get into university...
...compete to get a good job,
compete to marry a gorgeous woman.
There's aIways pressure
to compete and win.
What, in fact, is winning?
Think of it as if you are Antonius
and you won the greatest victory
and you come to Paris and
stand under that victory arch..
...and aII the peopIe are under you
and you have the uItimate power.
If you think in that IoneIy moment,
'Hey, so what? What happens now?...'
...then you're the Ioser. That moment,
with the greatest victory, you've Iost.
WeII, does being aware of that...
...offer us everything Iife can't,
as an oId Red Indian once said?
Or, as a Iistener once said,
is art...
...Iike everything eIse, for sex?
How wrong can an oId Red Indian be?
Sometimes he may be wrong.
- Sometimes he says nothing.
- Sometimes he wants to taIk.
- Sometimes he wants to Iisten.
- Sometimes he wants to be aIone.
- Sometimes he wants company.
- Sometimes he wants to go.
- He goes sometimes.
- Sometimes he can't.
Sometimes he's afraid of
not being abIe to go.
- Some are born into endIess sunshine.
- Some into endIess night.
- Sometimes you die.
- Sometimes you can't.
Sometimes you can't die
even when everything says you shouId.
Sometimes you want
to get away from yourseIf.
Sometimes you go
just to be abIe to come back.
- Sometimes you cry a Iot.
- Sometimes you just can't.
Sometimes you drink. And sometimes
you want to drink reaIIy a Iot.
Sometimes you go to drink anyway.
Sometimes you jump in a cab
in Ac?badem, you say ''Kadýköy''...
...and sometimes the guy
doesn't even Iook at you.
Sometimes a woman comes aIong...
...she sits down across from you
and cries.
- Women aIways cry.
- Sometimes a woman says to you...
''The thing that scares me most is
a woman's tears'' Speaking for herseIf.
''If you reaIIy Ioved,''
she says.
But what she doesn't know is
that Ioving beIongs to a moment.
- Everything starts with water.
- PhiIosophy, too.
- HeIIo? Good evenIng.
- HeIIo. Have we had sex before?
- Excuse me?
- Are you technicaIIy a woman?
- Yes. BIoIogIcaIIy too, of course.
- When was yourfýrst opening?
What openIng?
Grand opening. We're taIking the fýrst pump.
La pompa. II pompino. Le pompier.
Hasn't happened yet.
In that case,
Iet's taIk in a few years.
- Why?
- Because tonight we're voting on...
...the most popuIar positions
of the 20th century.
For anyone who feeIs Iike caIIing,
our number is 2122721065.
This is Kent FM, the Losers CIub.
- God, you made so much stuff, mum.
- WeII, you haven't been in ages.
- I'm busy, that's why.
- You've been busy since you were a kid.
- Did you read the books I gave you?
- Yes.
- Did you read mine?
- Yes. Right away, in fact.
- Which was yourfavourite?
- The Dead.
'Why do those words aIways strike me
as dreary and coId?'
'Is it perhaps because there's no word
exquisite enough to be your name?'
- Which was yourfavourite?
- The SheItering Sky.
'The souI is the weariest part
of the body.'
'Because we don't know
when we wiII die...'
'...we get to think of Iife
as an inexhaustibIe weII.'
- They're hazeInut this time.
- Thanks.
- How's business at the bar?
- Not bad.
- The programme?
- That's OK too.
- Does the radio station pay you?
- No.
So what are you going to do?
I have a few things in mind.
WouId you Iike me to heIp out?
- No need, mum. Don't worry.
- I Iistened a bit the other night.
- Why did you do that to yourseIf?
- No idea. I enjoyed it.
Don't girIs get offended
when you taIk Iike that?
No idea.
Come in.
- Savin Group's ad proposaI.
- OK, thanks.
This week's programme Iist,
Miss AsIý.
Did you Iisten to
the Losers CIub Iast night?
- No. Why?
- PeopIe have caIIed to compIain.
- Those 8-10 idiots do that every show.
- This time it was a few more.
- There were 385 compIaints.
- How many did you say?
-385. The Iines were jammed.
- What happened?
They proposed sex to a femaIe Iistener
on the show.
Then they voted on the most popuIar
sex positions of the 20th century.
They're vuIgar. ShameIess.
How do you aIIow It?
- OK, I'II handIe it.
- OK.
- Buket!
- Yes?
Which position won?
- I went to Friday prayer the other day.
- When?
Tuesday. I aIways goes Tuesdays.
It's quieter.
- My boxers are worn out.
- I'II buy you some. Or gIve you mIne.
Its time to break fast in SeattIe.
- Tzatziki or strained yogurt?
- Just yogurt.
- You Iike aubergine?
- Love It.
- You masturbate?
- No.
- Never?
- No. What does It have to do wIth aubergIne?
- It doesn't.
- Good night, caIIer. Have we sIept together?
- What do you thInk thIs show Is?
- Man, we don't think on principIe.
- I don'tremember Iast nIght.
- I don't remember anything after 1980.
- Its time to break fast in New York.
- We're wasting our time here.
- C'mon, Iet's go to OIympos.
- Sure.
- Sweetheart, I Iick you.
- Me too.
- Who is this damn EroI Egemen?
- ReaIIy, who the heII is EroI Egemen?
Who the fuck is EroI Egemen
for god's sake?
As I see it, Iife is about being
in the wrong pIace at the wrong time.
What have you done in Iife?
Did you do a $500 miIIion saIe
or cross the Suez CanaI twice?
- I want Cem Akaþ's book.
- No doubt.
- Sure.
- SeriousIy?
- Can I come and get It?
- AbsoIuteIy.
- Your best position in the kitchen?
- AII of them.
- What?
- Makes no difference, or aII of them?
- AII of them.
- AIright, ever cooked eggs during sex?
- Yes.
- I'm getting turned on.
- Me too.. OK, take it easy.
I wish you great orgasms
in your Iife.
- Aren't memories Iost if they're shared?
- Memories hurt when they're shared.
Why does everythIng you taIk about
InvoIve sex?
We don't know anything
that doesn't revoIve around sex.
- So who the heII is this EroI Egemen?!
- Who is the fucker? Show yourseIf, man!
- We're doIng a boycott show nextweek.
- I actuaIIy hate you guys and your show.
- Yes.
- But I stIII caIIed.
Bravo.
Can I do the usuaI and ask
for a song not to be pIayed?
- Sure.
- PearI Jam's ImmortaIIty.
Sure. We're not pIaying
PearI Jam's ImmortaIity.
- We begin the boycott night.
- Beans with a ton of sugar get boycotted.
We boycott anyone who's not a
fan of the singer Orhan Gencebay.
We boycott anyone who disIikes
the footbaIIer George Best.
- SIedgehammer owners get the boycott.
- If you're rockers, why pIay TurkIsh
What's it to you?
- Are we off to OIympos?
- Let's go.
C'mon.
ShaII we head back?
Evening time.
Another awesome cover.
Right. It's that EroI Egemen touch.
SimpIicity.
Right, huh?
Mete, I dropped by Lütfü's on my way.
He had a coupIe of Ottoman documents.
- Did he say anything?
- That you shouId go take a Iook.
- Then he has something good for sure.
- For sure.
I'm putting pepper on the tomatoes.
Anyone object?
Good. At Ieast everyone at this tabIe
has read the Iatest Brautigan. CooI.
I'II start on the raki
in three hours.
- It'II take that Iong?
- What?
- For you to start?
- Yeah, it takes time.
I'm at the bar again that day.
Not drinking.
- I know. Sure. You never drink.
- I hate the damn stuff.
Fuck your radio taIk!
- What the fuck's going on with you?
- What?
I think it's great.
I mean, standard.
What was your name?
AsshoIe!
That's kind of an AngIo-Saxon name.
You from Nottingham?
Watch out, Kadýköy's a sIippery pIace.
Don't faII!
- You guys are shits.
- What can I do? I don't remember.
- NorwouId I with that many women.
- It's not in his genes, girI.
No, I mean,
why is one woman not enough?
Being enough or not isn't the issue.
Some guys spend 60 years with a woman.
- Some can't. That's aII.
- But you guys aIways have stocks on hand.
We're not taIking four orfýve.
Why does it have to be so many?
WeII, Header, it happens. That's why.
Nothing deep. Don't make a deaI of it.
Fine.
- What did Orhan VeIi say?
- No idea. What did he say?
How do I know? He must have had
something to say about it for sure.
AbsoIuteIy. Cheers!
God, I'm IoneIy!
Are you kidding? The other day
I thought I was dying of IoneIiness.
WeIghIng In at 250 kIIos,
it's Africa's...
- What's up?
- Standard.
Try some pizza on your mayonnaise
next time.
KiIIs the taste. The pizza's so gross
it's the onIy way I can eat it.
- Don't spiII it on the carpet.
- Don't worry. I got you.
How's the transIation going?
Good. Coming aIong fýne.
- Who are you?
- Þebnem.
- Want some?
- No, thanks.
- How's it going, Þebnem?
- Standard.
Great.
May God keep you standard.
The bottIe Iooks Iike
a beautifuI bIack woman, huh?
What do you reckon?
Liquid..
Like the bIood of a dragon
kiIIed before its time.
Gushing foam.
And burning.
As much as IoneIiness.
Distance is not a function of time.
Speed is distance divided by time.
AcceIeration and the coeffýcient of
friction are neither here nor there.
Being on the road
requires having speed.
The converse is to stop on the road.
Stopping is boring.
Stopping on the road doesn't mean
being on the road.
Stopping on the road
means stopping on the road.
You don't stop at the end of the road.
You stop either beforehand
or not at aII.
Sometimes cIear coIourIess water
flows by the side of the road.
And there are fýsh in that water.
The road cIeaves through hiIIs,
one of them an earthy green...
...the other perhaps ochre.
The water doesn't take on the coIour
of the Iand it flows through.
Though it may seem that way to you.
And aIso...
...the road never ends.
That's the waII of the Iabyrinth.
Yes.
The road never ends.
This is the Losers CIub.
Our number is 2122721065.
- Good evening, Iistener.
- Good evening, mister.
Your name?
Birdbrain, Iet's say.
Go ahead, Iistener.
The further away you are from yourseIf
the cIoser you actuaIIy are.
The pIace furthest away from you
in this worId is actuaIIy your back.
Big differences sometimes
bring peopIe cIoser.
ActuaIIy, aII journeys made
on the surface of a sphere...
...serve onIy to progress
towards the starting point.
- What are they saying?
- I vaIue two things in Iife.
- I don'treaIIy know, but I Iove It.
- one... one Is InteIIIgence. You have both.
- They're Into reaIIy deep stuff.
- Thanks.
But my theory Is thIs.:
that IIfe Is always about...
...not beIng In the rIght pIace
at the rIght tIme.
If you ask me, IIfe Is about beIng
In the wrong pIace at the wrong tIme.
It's more or Iess the same.
Yes, Iistener?
- HeIIo?
- Your name?
- BrIt.
- Where are you caIIing from?
Kadýköy.
I'm so IoneIy.
LoneIiness makes you a drag, Brit.
God damn me. I teII you,
IoneIiness is making me nauseous.
Me too, Brit. Me too.
Another morning wiII come.
Another new day wiII start.
And I'II dIe another death.
- So you're on a downer.
- Yes.
Life sucks.
So Iet's do this. Let's make you
the Chief of Sorrow for Kadýköy.
Give us a caII once in a whiIe
and report back, OK?
OK.
Look, suppose we do the ohm
and unIoad some of this stress?
- Ohm?
- Ohm. You know, Iike yoga.
C'mon, Iet's aII do the ohm.
Ohmmmm
Ohmmmm...
Header's flying.
For you, Brit.
Don't Iet us miss you.
I pIcture the sprawIIng past
Where Is my Iover?
Where am I?
Where dId we go wrong
for us to break up thatway?
I've Iost my sense of self
See the state I'm In
I pIcture the sprawIIng past
Where Is my Iover?
Where am I?
Where dId we go wrong
for us to break up thatway?
I've Iost my sense of self
See the state I'm In
My sorrow has grown so bad
It's spIIIIng out of me
If I bIamed fate a thousand tImes
ItwouIdn't be enough
Speak of happy thIngs,
my wIshIng stone
To tear-stung eyes
so Iong unused to smIIIng
- Wasn't our appointment at 1.00?
- I onIy just woke up. Sorry.
- Where's Kaan?
- At his offýce. He couIdn't get away.
WeII? How're things?
Any requests? Any compIaints?
No.
- I guess the show's picked up a bit.
- No idea. ReaIIy?
Not bad. And if we work a bit harder
it'II get even better.
In fact, we couId get some ads.
We couId even pay you.
- But?
- Tone it down a bit.
In the past week we received
600 compIaints and a second warning.
They'II shut us down because of you two.
But we don't pIan what to say
orwhere the show's going.
It's kind of Iike improvisation.
Do you have to beIch, swear on air
or proposition to every femaIe caIIer?
Don't know. Don't we?
The other night you spent 40 minutes
on a Ieek recipe...
...and 45 minutes
on premature ejacuIation.
- Is there nothing eIse?
- Don't know. Is there?
That's just the way it worked out
that night. What can we do?
We can't do the show any otherway.
It's our styIe.
I reaIize that. But this is Turkey.
They'II shut the station down.
TaIk to Kaan.
You're onto something good.
Don't Iet it go, I say.
You have my support if you want it.
Evening, Kent Iisteners out there.
This is the Losers CIub.
FaIIIng In Iove Is Instantaneous.
It's an Instantwhere suddenIy
everythIng appears brIghter...
...where suddenIy
even the paIest coIours begIn to gIow...
aII food bursts wIth fIavour.
You don't decIde to faII In Iove.
You justreaIIze...
...It's happened.
When wiII I see you again?
If you come to Beþiktaþ Pier
in three days, you'II see me.
Hey, what was your name?
Don't know. I don't remember.
Let's say 6.45.
- What are you up to?
- Resting my mind.
- I took a break.
- Since when?
Two.. Three.. Six.. Eight..
Hasn't been Iong.
Hey, I just met an awesome woman.
She's bIown my mind.
What's her name?
- I don't know.
- Where is she?
We're meeting in three days
at Beþiktaþ Pier. At 6.45.
Great.
The Beþiktaþ Pier in Beþiktaþ
or the Beþiktaþ Pier in Kadýköy?
No idea.
Good Iuck.
Thanks.
- HeIIo?
- Brit, I want to ask you something.
If someone said the Beþiktaþ Pier,
which one wouId you think it was...
- ...Kadýköy or Beþiktaþ?
- I have nothIng to do wIth pIers.
- Ask EroI Egemen.
- OK, got it. But which one?
- I'd thInk Kadýköy.
- Me too.
- I'd thInk BeþIktaþ.
- HeIIo?.. HeIIo?
Yes, heIIo, Iistener?
- There's a great IIon documentary on TV.
- Thanks, Iistener.
PIus there's a gIrI here caIIed Ceyda,
she's waItIng for Mete.
- TeII her not to wait. I'II be Iate.
- OK. Good Iuck.
He'II be back Iate.
OK..
Hey, turn on the radio, huh?
TaIking of being Iate,
I came earIy the other day.
- What do you mean?
- Let me expIain.
It was a morning Iike any other.
It was bIowing up a storm outside
and had started to drizzIe.
I'd sat down to a Iight breakfast,
had poured my coffee...
...and was eating
a smaII piece of cheese.
I asked if she wanted coffee.
She did.
She grabbed her coffee and sat down
on the chair beside me.
She was Iistening to the rain
and the ever-Iate spring.
I Ieaned over to the strawberry jam
in front of me.
I took a smaII spoonfuI.
As I Iifted the spoon to my mouth
the jam dribbIed onto my neck.
I reached down to spoon it off.
She grabbed my hand, pushed it away.
She Iooked deep into my eyes.
And put time on hoId.
With the tip of her index fýnger...
...she scooped the jam
out of the hoIIow of my neck.
She Iifted herfýnger to my Iips.
She sIowIy spread the jam
over my Iips.
She smeared the rest IingeringIy
over her own Iips.
She moistened her Iips with her tongue
and tasted the jam.
Hey, what are they taIking about?
The rain came down harder.
And mingIed with the wind.
She turned towards me.
She bent her head towards me.
She IightIy brushed her Iips over mine.
She tasted the jam on my Iips.
And I tasted the jam on hers.
Before drawing her Iips away...
...she teased my tongue one Iast time
with the tip of her tongue.
She Iicked my Iips.
She stood up.
She puIIed herwhite shirt
out of the waist of her skirt.
Without undoing the buttons,
she hitched it up to her breasts.
She wasn't wearing a bra.
She turned me towards her.
She sIowIy puIIed up my T-shirt.
She sat on my Iap.
GentIy, IingeringIy
she Iet her skin touch mine.
Her nippIes brushed my chest.
She puIIed up her skirt.
Then..
- Then?
- ''What happened?'' she said.
- What happened?
- I came earIy.
- Are you out of your minds?
- Hey, what's wrong?
What do you think? You had
phone sex with aII of IstanbuI.
Forget you getting the station banned,
you'II have us aII thrown in jaiI!
Let's not exaggerate now.
I've said it once, I'II say it again.
This is Turkey.
This American rock n roII,
free spirit attitude doesn't fly.
- We'II quit if you Iike.
- I'm not saying that. But tone it down.
The show can go a Iong way. You too.
Don't pass up this chance.
It has nothing to do
with passing up chances!
Look, Iet's do this professionaIIy.
We'II give you a fee for each show.
Things wiII be easierfor you. And me.
- But it's fýne Iike this, huh?
- You don't seem to understand.
- I'm saying I'II pay you for the show.
- WeII, I'm just fýne as I am.
Me too.
One way or other
you'II defýniteIy get something.
OK.
Can I use this?
I'm writing beer.
- Write whisky too. Cabs.
- Cabs.
- Hakký's MeatbaIIs.
- Ha, meatbaIIs.
Anything missing? Take a Iook.
Pay for ourfood, drinks and traveI
and that's fýne.
Even beer and whisky expenses is fýne.
Why don't you hand it over.
She might object to something.
Here you go.
OK.
- We forgot to write chocoIate.
- Fucking Jesus Christ!
- What time are we at Birdbrain's?
- Eight.
Do you think we're idiots
to turn down the money?
Can you put a price on what we do?
I mean, we're not worried about
Iosing the show, right?
- Let's not be sIaves to Ioose change.
- Right.
Are you sure
it's the Beþiktaþ Pier in Kadýköy?
Why did you go to so much troubIe?
I'm about to burst here.
It's no troubIe. Come any time.
Thanks for accepting the invitation.
It was great, Birdbrain. Thanks.
They pIay the same tune
in two different parts of the worId.
You're right, they do.
I got the new Sturgeon you pubIished.
- You mean 'More than Human'?
- Aha. It's great text. ReaIIy.
Sure, but that's another book
doomed to be buried in the stock room.
No one but Kaan wouId think
to pubIish the book anyway.
I'm Iucky then. If you hadn't
pubIished it, I'd never have read it.
Two things never change, you know.
My excitement when preparing the books.
And then my disappointment
after pubIishing them.
SüIeymaniye Mosque has a caretaker.
He's from the town of Van.
When he was young, his father
came to IstanbuI on business.
On his way back, he brought a photo
of SüIeymaniye Mosque as a souvenir.
The caretakerwas
a young boy at the time.
They hang the photo on the waII
in their house in Van.
For hours every day, the boy
gazed and gazed at that photo.
He became deepIy attached to the photo
his father had brought from IstanbuI.
His one dream in Iife now
was to see that mosque.
When he was in his 20s
he came to IstanbuI...
...and headed straight
for SüIeymaniye Mosque.
He saw the mosque.
He sat in the grounds and Iooked.
He went inside and prayed.
He just couIdn't Ieave the pIace.
Then he began sweeping up the Ieaves
in the grounds. He tended the flowers.
Without asking for anything.
Of his own free wiII.
The imam at the mosque noticed him.
And they decided
to take him on as caretaker.
On the upstairs floors
of SüIeymaniye Mosque...
...there's a secret room
for the caretaker.
No one but the imam and the caretaker
knows about this room.
He was given this room.
And rumour has it...
...that the view from there
is the very fýnest in IstanbuI.
In otherwords, getting to enjoy
such a perfect view...
...was onIy made possibIe
by virtue of an everIasting passion.
Thanks.
Birdbrain, if you'II excuse us,
we have a Iong trek.
- We're headed for Kadýköy.
- Just across the bridge, you'II get there.
Oh, by the way...
...I think that pier has to be
the Beþiktaþ Pier in Kadýköy.
Don't you agree?
How did you know
I'd be at the right pier?
Don't know. I suppose I guessed
you'd show up somehow.
- So you were that sure.
- I wanted you to be sure.
I thought if you reaIIy wanted
to see me again, you'd fýnd a way.
I see..
So a kind of test.
AbsoIuteIy.
What do you do in Iife?
I mean, generaIIy?
PresumabIy you're trying to ask
what job I do.
I'm an architect.
I work for an internationaI
architecturaI fýrm caIIed Berk & Smith.
Nice.
I'm into architecture.
Since when?
The Iast four days.
OK.. What do you do?
- I have a pubIishing house.
- ReaIIy?
- Which one?
-6.45.
- I have a few of your books then.
- ReaIIy? Which ones? I'm curious.
Enis Batur, So Much BIood in MiIk.
And Oruç Aruoba. What is Nothing.
But there must be a few more.
'Soaring on the gentIe wind
the guII set off for the sea.'
Great book.
Hey, where do you Iive?
- In Göztepe. On Minibus Street.
- You Iive aIone?
With my big sister. We've shared
since university. We both did uni here.
- Where are you from?
- Edirne.
- What does your sister do?
- She's a pharmacist. More questions?
What eIse do you do?
I take a few photos. When I have time.
PIus I have a smaII radio show.
You're invoIved in such great stuff.
Compared with yours, my Iife
suddenIy seems reaIIy boring.
Anything that becomes routine
is boring, actuaIIy.
That's why the grass aIways
Iooks greener on the other side.
So don't worry about it.
Yes, but things in Iife that aren't
routine can never be Iasting.
- Coffee?
- Medium sugar.
- Two medium coffees.
- Sure.
Do you go out Iike this a Iot?
Like this?
Like this.
Never.
Hey, man. Move your motorbike
so I can get out, huh?
It's stiII earIy.
Let's wander around.
- How you doing?
- Standard.
- I guess you went to the right pier.
- Aha. Yes.
- Any ice cream Ieft?
- Yeah, I saved you some.
Are you kidding?
You son of a bitch..
- Is this aII you saved?
- Not enough?
You don't Iike bIackberry, so I ate it.
And the raspberry, I did, you know..
Why don't you buy some for once
and I'II eat it.
What was the girI Iike?
TotaIIy different. I mean, good.
I haven't met anyone Iike her in ages.
Anyhow. I'm going to bed.
Don't spiII on the carpet, OK?
The guy's faIIen in Iove
and he doesn't know it.
Don't spiII it on the carpet.
I guess It's one of the thIngs
I thInk about the most.
HavIng nothIng Ieft to Iose
Is freedom, I guess.
But I don't know
who can get to that poInt.
OK, it's 1917 or so.
We're in Vienna.
- There was our KarI.
- Who, the king?
- KarI.
- Right, we know him as the king.
The guy with the beard.
There was Frederick too.
Frederick Ieft his dad's factories
and came to join us.
The three of us were spinning
theories there in an attic flat.
- I won'tforget. We were havIng coffee..
- Who is this KarI?
A German footbaIIer, I think.
KarI Marx. Open a book
and read once in a whiIe.
I turned to KarI and said,
''What eIse do we have to Iose?''
You know what he said?
''We have nothing to Iose
but our chains,'' he said. ''Kaan.''
''Fuck off,'' I said.
''With a mindset Iike that,'' I said,
''you'II screw up this century.''
''The century wiII faII apart,'' I said.
''There'II be a revoIution in Russia
any day,'' I said.
- WhIch In fact Is what happened.
- WeII, anyway..
Have a good night, Iistener.
Merry Christmas to you.
Bye then.
There's a Iistener on the Iine.
- HeIIo?
- EroI Egemen?
- Are you IIstenIng?
- Go ahead, Iistener.
Watch what you're sayIng.
How do you mean, Iistener?
Don't bItch about
peopIe's reIIgIon and faIth.
Know your pIace
or we'II put you In It.
- How wiII you do that?
- You doubt my word?
- Sure.
- Don't.
I see you came to the radIo statIon
wIthout your motorbIke today.
Jerk.
- Hey, Iet's have a party, Mete.
- Good idea. Let's do it.
A IoneIy hearts party.
We're drying up here.
It'II energize us.
Let's do it on the 16th. At Trip bar.
Get a few friends aIong. We'II chiII.
It's a deaI.
- Jump in, guys. I'II take you these days.
- Thanks, JackaI.
Ceyda, Murat, Zeynep.
Zeynep, Murat, Ceyda.
- HeIIo, everyone.
- Hi.
ShaII we grab some breakfast?
C'mon then.
SHOP FOR RENT
Thanks.
I'II caII when I get back.
Go on, go.
Where have you been, Zeynep?
We've been waiting for you.
America's expecting news from you too.
Sorry, Mr. CemaI. I've faIIen in Iove.
I couIdn't sIeep aII night.
- Everyone's taIking about the show.
- I guess.
I don't get it. In the end,
what we do is hardIy popuIar cuIture.
That's for sure.
WeII? What do you say? Isn't it crazy
that it's caught on Iike this?
No idea. I thought about it too
whiIe I was Iistening the other day.
You taIk about things
no one dares to discuss openIy.
And that comes across as sincere.
Even if they don't understand...
...orfýnd it ridicuIous, I think
it's your sincerity that grabs them.
I reaIIy don't know.
I can't fýgure it out.
- Did anything come of those threats?
- No. It's just hot air.
- A coupIe of wackos who keep caIIing.
- StiII, don't wind them up. Be carefuI.
- Don't worry.
- It's my job to worry.
I want to ask you something.
Do you think I Iead
a reaIIy empty Iife?
What do you think?
Don't know.. No.
I've aIways done what I've wanted.
The time came I went to EngIand.
The time came I got married.
The time came I had a chiId.
But I've done everything as I wanted
and at the time I wanted.
Sometimes I've paid a price for it,
but I've aIways Iived as I've wanted.
Not everyone is prepared
to pay that price.
- Isn't the missus coming?
- She's in Edirne with herfamiIy.
Good Iuck, good Iuck!
- What the heII is this?
- Fuck!
Oh my god!
LONELY HEARTS PARTY
THE LOSERS CLUB
I Iove it. They discuss everything
straight out. It's incredibIe.
- How you doing?
- Standard. You?
Who is this EroI Egemen?
Great!
Forget him, I say Mete is to die for.
Kaan. Kaan.
- HeIIo. Have we had sex before?
- Take a hike, dumbass.
What's up?
Mete, is it you?
Sometimes.
EroI Egemen.
Who's EroI Egemen?
Who is it?
Who's this EroI Egemen?
- EroI Egemen's here. You heard?
- No way.
My ass!
He's humping a girI in there.
They're bouncing off the waIIs.
Can't you hear?
EroI Egemen!
I was sIttIng, sIttIng
by the wIndow
I was sIngIng, sIngIng
songs...
The smoke,
the smoke of my cIgarette
Too bad, thIs Iover of mIne
has no faIth
The smoke,
the smoke of my cIgarette
Too bad, thIs Iover of mIne
has no faIth
The smoke,
the smoke of my cIgarette
Too bad, thIs Iover of mIne
has no faIth
- LOSERS CLUB/KENTFM/4.80/15.10
- HeIIo to heartsIck frIends
- LOSERS CLUB/KENTFM/5.00/14.50
...RULED TO TAKE KENTFM OFF AIR
FOR TWO 24-HOUR PERIODS...
- LOSERS CLUB/KENTFM/6.00/18. 70
- HeIIo to sufferIng Iovers
HeIIo to sufferIng Iovers
LOSERS CLUB
The bank caIIed.
They didn't get
this month's Ioan payment.
- Fine, I'II handIe it.
- OK.. PIus there's rent.
- SeIin, did the agency send that fax?
- Yes. Take a Iook if you Iike.
- Is this 6.45?
- Yes.
Are Mete or Kaan around?
- How did you fýnd this pIace?
- Through a friend. Are they around?
- What do you want with Kaan and Mete?
- To join the Losers CIub.
- Yeah right.. Fine.
- Yes.
- Kaan's busy, kId.
- Is he in there? Can't we say heIIo?
Why can't we quickIy see him?
We want to join the CIub.
What cIub? What goddamn cIub?
- The Losers CIub.
- Fuck off! You fucking idiots...
- HeIIo?
- What are you up to?
Working. You?
- Hey, Iet's go to OIympos.
- OK. Fine. When?
Now.
- You're kidding, right?
- No. I'II pick you up in an hour.
- I'd Iove to, but I can't.
- You can't or you won't?
I can't. I have a ton of work.
Are you OK?
I'm fýne. C'mon, we can reIax, have fun.
Besides, aII work and no pIay is not good.
- What's the worst that can happen?
- I'd get fýred.
You'd fýnd another job.
I can't come. I've got
a piIe of projects to fýnish.
- But I can break for coffee if you Iike.
- Forget it.
- See you tonight.
- OK, see you then.
Yes, dear Iisteners.
That brings us to the end of
tonight's edition of the Losers CIub.
EndIess thanks to you aII
for Iistening.
Keep heaIthy, happy and cheerfuI
untiI next week. Goodbye.
Good night to you aII, dear Iisteners.
What are they doing in there?
They're recording a fake tape
for the state censor during music breaks.
- We're done, boss.
- OK.
- You know what just hit me, Mete?
- What?
Censorship. Look, I think
everyone shouId be censored.
The state shouIdn't just censor
newspapers, TV and radio broadcasters.
They shouId censor magazines too,
even thoughts for that matter.
What buIIshit, everyone having
their own thoughts! Are we crazy?
For that matter, I say there shouId be
censorship spies out there. SeriousIy.
I say radio fýnes aren't enough.
They shouId fýne thoughts as weII.
Think of a woman? $1000.
Think of sex with that woman? $2000.
Then we've earned a fortune
for the broadcasting authorities.
There's a Iistener on the Iine.
- HeIIo?
- HeIIo. HI.
- HeIIo. Have we had sex before?
- No! What a meanIngIess questIon.
OK, can you ask me a question
that isn't gratuitous?
There's no such thIng.
For starters anything without an answer
can't be a question.
Questions onIy exist through
their desire to have an answer.
Except for one question.
This question might move you to
dead siIence or pure unbounded joy.
From what I understand, it couId
make you even more insufferabIe...
...than you aIready are
to the peopIe around you.
- If you're ready, I'II ask.
- Yes?
What couId be more serious
than death?
A caIIer on the Iine.
- Goodnight, Iistener.
- Have we had sex before?
- HeIIo?
- Night, Iistener. Go ahead
My name's Hakan.
I've been thinking of caIIing
for quite a whiIe.
But hearing what you've said tonight
I worked up the courage.
Go ahead.
Take as Iong as you Iike.
How to start?
I'm a painter.
I Iive with my mother.
Or rather, I used to.
I Iost my mother a year ago.
We were reaIIy cIose.
It was she who got me into painting.
There's no sorrow.. No pain Iike it.
I can't teII you.
I couIdn't eat for months.
CouIdn't draw.
In the end I couIdn't take it.
I thought, Iet me end it,
Iet me be spared this pain.
I thought, no one wiII notice
my absence anyway.
I'd even fýxed the whoIe thing,
when and how I'd do it.
It may sound crazy to you...
...but the night beforehand
I crossed your show.
I sat down and Iistened
right through to the end.
You did such a great job
Iaughing off IoneIiness.
I thought, I'II Iisten
the next night and then do it.
I didn't reaIize that I was
waiting for your show every night.
And whiIe I waited
I forgot to die.
I record the shows
and Iisten again during the day.
- Not every show presumabIy.
- WeII.. There's a few.
I caIIed to thank you, actuaIIy.
- Where are you caIIing from?
- Pendik.
In that case...
...Iet's make you the Chief of Sorrow
for Pendik. If you agree, of course.
Sure, Iove to.
OK then. Hey, we Iook forward
to hearing your reports now and again.
Thanks for everything.
Good night.
- Has EroI Egemen caIIed?
- Who is he anyway that he'd caII?
ShaII we go grab some meatbaIIs?
Yeah, c'mon. Let's go.
- Do you come here every night?
- Once a week. At Ieast.
- Good?
- Great.
Why didn't you spend Ionger
taIking to that caIIer?
We taIked to him, right?
What eIse was there to say?
I don't know. He poured out his heart,
and thanked you.
You couId have been
more sympathetic at Ieast.
That's what you think.
I don't get it. You don't
appreciate anything you have.
Why don't you take anything seriousIy?
Why do you aIways want us to be on a mission?
We're just two guys who taIk on air
and enjoy each other's company.
That's aII.
I know damn weII you don't
reaIIy beIieve what you just said.
We didn't ask anyone to Iisten,
or to Iike the show...
...or to take us seriousIy.
But they have taken you seriousIy.
What are you going to do now?
Finish our meatbaIIs and go home.
Same.
I just don't get it.
The show's this popuIar, fuck it,
and we're stiII not seIIing books.
I wish it was some use to us, fuck it.
But Kaan doesn't want to use the show.
WeII, I wouIdn't know about that.
But this show changed my Iife.
It saved me, I'm teIIing you.
No one had any idea
it wouId get this far.
You know what?
What we have now wiII end one day.
We'II miss these days.
I don't know.
Maybe other things wiII start.
Maybe this was our own revoIution.
- Beer?
- Okay
- Hi, Kaan.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Good. You?
I'm good too.
What time is it?
10.00.
Uh-oh!
- What's up?
- I have to meet my parents.
They're dropping by
on theirway to Edirne.
- CaII and say you'II be Iate.
- Can't. They'II be disappointed.
- What are you doing?
- I'II drop you off. It'II be faster.
- No need. I'II fýnd my way.
- Aren't they coming into Harem?
- I'II drop you.
- Kaan, I said no need. I'm fýne.
OK, I'm out of here.
See you tonight at the studio.
- The studio?
- I toId you, my friend wants to come.
Up to now, I've beIieved in everything
I wanted to beIieve in, Kaan.
Though I know that in the end
I'II die, that I'II suffer...
...I've beIieved in
everything I wanted to.
And whenever I've feIt cIose to
achieving something, I've Iost it.
You mean you're a dodo.
Yes.
In that case,
we're reading a poem.
Dodo bird isIand excrement..
Dodo bird dust and sorrow Iurking
in the shade of berry bushes..
- Wash, those dear tears..
- Wow..
- Your hooded eye, stormy shores..
- Wow.
Canyon-Iike river..
Linger on, deep in sIeep
SIeep. eeppp. eeeppp.
My goodness.
SmiIe from earth and sky.
I Iook through your sapphire eyes
FaIIing into the trap ap. ap. ap...
My heart, Iike faIIing wiId horses,
diary of Iove.. ove. ove..
Dodo bird, oh, obIivious to the gazeIIe,
echoing caII in my brain..
- Understand any of this?
- No.
My breast, trembIing,
with wounded waters..
My goodness.
Here we go.
Here we go, wow.
Instant death..
ObIivious to the gazeIIe, echoing caII
in your eye, Iake tremors..
- Dodo bird..
- With bIoody waters..
- Echoing in my brain..
- Dodo bird..
Of my breast with bIoody waters!
Dust peace sorrow Iurk in the shadows..
Here we go.
Water! MoonIess night
trembIing grains of sand..
BehoId the muIIet and wiId oIeander
BehoId the coming bastard. He'II be born..
- Wow.
- My goodness.
Yeehah!
- Are you guys the onIy ones here at night?
- And Header, that's aII.
Yourface is famiIiar. Have we met?
Kaan, why are you presenting
the show Iike that?
Why shouIdn't I?
It's kind of weird, isn't it?
My jeans get kind of tight
after eating so I take them off.
Interesting.
It's no big deaI.
C'mon, Iet's go.
You fýrst.
If that vase rotates one more time
I'II sIash my wrists.
- How many times have you watched this?
- Two or three.
No.. Four.
Zeynep, carefuI.
Don't spiII it on the carpet.
Don't worry.
- Four, fýve..
- It's a piIe of shit.
- Zeynep, carefuI!
- Eight, nine times.
Hey, didn't I say not to spiII it?
That carpet's speciaI.
I've watched it 13-14 times.
Sorry.
Or is it 15?
I don't remember exactIy.
- Kaan says a big heIIo to you.
- How is he? OK?
Same as ever.
I have something to give you.
These are for you.
- I don't understand.
- Most are originaIs. First edition.
Mum, these are something eIse.
Where did you fýnd them?
I got them in EngIand.
I've had them stashed away for ages.
You can put them in your store.
In the store?
Did you think
I wouIdn't fýnd out?
Thanks.
Come in.
- Miss AsIý.
- Yes?
Another penaIty?
- They're up to number one.
- No surprises.
They've been number two
in their time sIot for a whiIe.
It's not just in their time sIot.
They're number one for the whoIe day.
NO.1 LOSERS CLUB/KENTFM/8. 70/25.10
We're done for.
We need to ask you a question
for you to win the book.
What's the fuII name
of the Tennessee team...
...that pIayed in this year's
Super BowI fýnaI?
No! If I say I don't know, I'II Iose.
PIease don't ask.
- Good system. I IIke It.
- Oh, god. PIease.
- Sure, sure. It's aIIowed.
- Then Iet's ask another question.
No, I don'twant to Iose thIs.
Or suppose you ask another tIme?
I mean, any questIon you IIke.
If you gave me the book tonIght, say.
Have we sIept together?
Your voice sounds famiIiar.
ItwouId.
- But we've never sIept together.
- SeriousIy, you haven't?
- We've taIked, but not sIept together.
- Fine. One of us wiII anyway
Why make such a big deaI?
I'm stressed, don't harass me.
HeIIo? HeIIo?
Where shouId I come?
Where were you?
- I went to Hakký's pIace with Mete.
- Hakký was that important, huh?
- You knew I'd be staying over tonight.
- I'm here, aren't I, Zeynep?
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
Why do you make out with
every femaIe caIIer on the show?
- Don't be ridicuIous.
- It's me being ridicuIous, is it?
You're the one who constantIy
taIks about sex every night on the air.
Have we sIept together? Come over.
Let me Iick you.. And aII that.
Is that what you think
the show's about?
- That we don't taIk about anything eIse?
- Do you?
OK. No, we don't.
Suppose I introduced you to my dad
and he heard you on the radio?
- What wouId I say?
- Then don't introduce me.
- Why are you pushing it?
- Look..
You're the smartest,
most knowIedgeabIe guy I know.
Why do you waste it? Why don't you
do something that gets you somewhere?
Don't beIieve this.. In the beginning,
everything I did excited you.
Your books don't seII. You turn down
money from the radio station.
You take photos now and again.
Why don't you do something proper?
You're not 19 any Ionger.
This is who I am.
I've never hidden it.
I've never Iied to you.
I haven't changed.
If you aren't happy.. I mean,
if I'm not good enough for you...
...you can fuck off.
What then?
Nothing. She didn't smiIe.
Not at aII.
It was Iike she couIdn't smiIe.
Yet in the sky there was everything
you couId expect from a good sunset.
AII those warm coIours,
a gentIe breeze.
The smeII of her perfume.
If at that moment
an anviI had faIIen from the sky...
...it wouId have taken it
nine days and nights to reach earth.
I've had a job offerfrom America
that I'd been expecting.
CongratuIations.
I can't decide whether to go or not.
Why?
It kind of depends on you.
If you say, ''Don't go,''
I won't.
We'II give it a shot here, but..
But you have to teII me that.
TeII me not to go.
Can you?
If at that moment a bronze anviI
had faIIen from earth...
...it wouId have taken it
nine days and nights to reach her eyes.
A Iong, drawn out..
dark.. coId moment.
TruIy, that's how it was.
Thanks.
You OK?
Yeah, I'm doing better these days.
- Have you heard from Zeynep?
- We spoke at some point.
She's settIed in America.
I guess with aII the rockin' n roIIin'
I didn't reaIize I was so in Iove
But it wouIdn't have worked anyway.
Forget it, boss.
You know what's the probIem with women?
They faII in Iove with the quaIities
that make you who you are...
...and then try to take them away from you.
- How's the store?
- Good.
I say I shouId focus more
on the pubIishing business.
I reckon it's time for a change, huh?
What are we going to teII AsIý?
We'II fýnd something.
What's up?
Ceyda.. She's Ieft me.
You mean you were together?
We were madIy in Iove.
You didn't notice?
Sorry.
Hey, what's this?
I thought we shouId have dinner,
the two of us, as singIe guys.
I got ice cream too. Raspberry.
And I fýnished the transIation.
Are you OK?
Like you say..
It's no joke, we're totaIIy aIone.
Hey, is this fair? Is this justice?
Mete, Iet's hear a message of justice.
What justice?
You mean there's justice?
If there's justice,
what are they saying today?
- Where wouId we stand, Kaan?
- C'mon, give us that message.
Speak of Iove, brotherhood,
that kind of thing.
OK, Iet's Iove fairIy.
Let's Iove whoever Ioves us.
Let's want whoeverwants us,
or pretend even if we don't want them.
- At Ieast Iet's pretend for that night.
- So what you're reaIIy saying is...
- ...Iet's put up for the sake of the pump, huh?
- ExactIy.
Maybe we'II Iove with time.
That's what I'm saying.
Nice words. Nice words.
Look, I have tears in my eyes.
- I want justice!
- Look at the tears. Out of nowhere.
I want justice!
C'mon, Iet's hear a message of
Iove and justice from you too, Kaan.
I..
I want Iove and justice
for the whoIe of humanity...
...for aII peopIes, aII animaIs,
for aII vioIets and mountain flowers...
...for aII snowdrops,
for aII of us, for everyone...
...for everyone who creates
this worId and Iives in it.
Thank you, Turkey!
- God! Thanks.
- Amazing.
As aIways, Kent Iisteners, we dedicate
this edition of the Losers CIub...
...to the Montana gang,
to the bad kids in town...
...to the headIine-grabbing,
EroI Egemen Syndrome...
...which has taken
the medicaI worId by storm...
...to aII eviI spirits,
and to the streets of Kadýköy...
...where we're stiII Iearning
about Iife and women.
And we make this dedication
without the sIightest hesitation.
We won't be with you next Tuesday
or any other night thereafter.
This, and aII other editions of the Losers CIub,
have come to an end...
We wish you aII a good night,
Kent Iisteners.
If, of course, that's possibIe.
Goodbye.
The Losers CIub is over.
Even If I'm wIth you, my Iove
Even If we part or dIe
on thIs road
It's always IoneIIness, sweetheart,
IoneIIness for IIfe
LoneIIness for IIfe
Even If I'm wIth you, my Iove
Even If we see nothIng of each other
If we mIss one another
Even If we're together forever
If we're happy or sad
It's IoneIIness for IIfe
If I suddenIy thInk of you,
If I forget you now and agaIn
END
www.subtitlesworld.com