I've been thinking about what
were you said that concrete goal.
- And?
- I think, I've known it.
I'm feeling really good about this one, Al.
Lay down it?
- It's a girl.
- Cool! What's she like?
You know, smart, beautiful, popular...
A classic TGFY.
- Too Good For You, Al.
- But not for you?
Well, I'm sorta outside the whole highschool
foodchain at this point, wouldn't you say?
- See you gonna ask her out?
- Ask her out?
No. Bad idea, no.
I mean... where's the therapeutic value in that?
- So what's the plan?
- Simple.
I'm gonna have fun with her.
- Fun? What's that mean?
- Fun?
Fun means fun. Right?
Don't over think it, Al.
It's been nice known you.
- Next week?
- You know way, Al? You've made so much progress here,
- I think you're ready to face the world on your own way now.
- Keith?!
Don't worry, Al. You can cope.
- Keep it in mind!
- Hi, Anderson! How are you?
- Thanks so much. And how are you?
- I'm good, I'm just chilling.
- You're Rafael, are you?
- Yeah. And you're...?
- Natalie... Anderson.
- Oh, a head of... everything.
- I try to keep easy this.
- Only work, no play?
None. Zero.
- Do you working now?
- Oh, absolutely. It's a Key Club...
We're checking on the stranger students
making sure their adjusting okay.
- Oh, well what a thought.
- I can tell.
- You've nearly about 50-60 new friends.
- Hey, brother.
- 61.
- Yeah. It's nice to know somebody cares.
- Rain...
- Yeah.
- Natalie, come on!
Alright, so I'm gonna go.
It's nice to meet you. We'll talk to later.
- Comme on, let's go!
Zach! Breakfast is on the table!
- Natalie! Please get him up!
- Okay, okay!
Zach! Wake up!
Didn't come home.
- Morning!
Natie... Miles is a leftist,
you can have to work with the backhand!
We know, we must been the whole
practice fill in backhand today.
- According to my records last year...
- I'm over, Dead.
- ...she's catched with her service. 11 aces.
- ...aces. Thanks for reminding me.
- Natie is quicker now.
- If you'll being a recording job at least you'll rise 3 places.
- What's this "if" about?
- Bye.
- Natie, sit down have some breakfast!
- I've got Key Club this morning, Mom.
You need have some protein. Sit down, please!
I have a barn.
- A barn is not a breakfast.
- Bye!
In as for the straight subconstruction experinments...
The couples are:
Hobbs and Mertin, Carlens and Stevens,
Brent and Aldridge, Anderson and
Zetterstrom, Brandon and Davins...
- Zetterstrom?
- Haven't lied to you this far. I'm not gonna start now.
You wanna help?
- We don't need that for this.
- Look, you're not gonna be disagreable, are you?
Because Walt specifically promised
me an agreeable lab partner.
- Walt?
- You need to relax.
- Actually I need to learn this.
- Because why?
Because you need to a four on your AP exam
if you want to get a college credit location, didn't you know.
Then you'll be ahead of the game, right?
Then I can focus on that things
where good I and keep up my GPA.
Okay, so we need to fill this one with
natrium-tiosulphate and this one with nitrate...
Gotta keep up that GPA.
- It's kinda help if you wanna to get a job.
- A job?
- Can we just do the lab?
- I'd love to! Let's do the lab!
Except you're about ten years into the future...
We don't need chemistry.
We need time travel.
Mr. Miles, this is AP.
Keith is actually pretty sharp
when he press myself.
Okay.
- But a bit kind of...
- Left chemistry?
- Yeah.
- Try to make it work, okay?
- About this Natalie Anderson...
- Yes?
Walter, she's a complete, anal compulsive control freak!
How the hell do you expect in a work with that?
- But Keith, you were who...
- I'm kidding. Kidding.
I would pretty shake.
Who the hell do you think you are?
What do you think I am?
- Hey, Miss Key Club!
- Hey!
- So how are your adjusting?
- Oh, wow, you'll told me how am I done?
Well, you've got only one a 98 percent history
mainthemes so your beginmatch fall at all.
- I hate people like you.
- Hey, so listen, are you gonna be at the brink on friday?
- Are you going?
- It could happen.
Who's that guy?
Oh... he's just my lab parner. Nobody.
- See you don't remember?
- What?
Well, I've sit behind you on the sixth great play
when you were the princess and
I was russian soldier number three.
- I don't remember that.
- Of course not.
Princess never remembers lower people.
- Excuse me, well I'll cry for you.
- You should!
Should cry for me because
you're already on the early-decision tour.
It's posted in the front office.
- Why are they do that?
- Why Duke?
- Great faculty, division no.1, of the kind...
- I'm sure, you'll get what you pay for.
- Actually I have a partial scholarship.
- Ah, that's right.
- There it goes the positive...
- Tennis.
So they basically give you a punch of money
for banding a ball over a net.
Something like that.
Where did you apply?
Nowhere.
- Your're not gonna be to college?
- Not in Judeo Christian sense. No, I am not.
So, what are you doing after graduation?
- The sky's the limit.
- It's simple made it.
- Why are you taking in AP class...?
- I'm in packed.
Then you were placed here for what?
- I'm sure there's a very simple explanation.
- Of course there is Natalie,
and you're not can stop to you'll figured it out.
That's on like a challenge. You're on.
So this's all based some a little conversation.
- You know, he don't gonna be ovbious can be there tonight.
- Oh, he'll definitely be there.
Oh, your power positive thinking?
- Hi, Brooke.
- How do you do?
- Hi, Nat, can I have some brass?
- For what?
- Come on, I'll pay back tomorrow.
- Get out!
Let's go.
- What happened?
- What happended with the music?
- Can I help you?
- Oh, yeah.
- Who's that guy?
- What's he doing?
Relax, you'll like it! I promise! Listen!
What do you think for you can change this?
Because you'll like it. See?
Have a good time!
Senorita, let's go!
- What? Oh, oh, no...
- Turn away! And welcome back!
- It's interesting choice of music.
- Yeah? And you bear with bob?
Of course.
So what do you think gonna do after college?
I'm gonna own my recordlabor.
- You think big.
- Why not?
What about you, Natalie?
Oh, I wonder on a magazine.
I wanna be the editor.
Yeah.
My magazine. Why not?
Why not do something amazing?
- Whole life is infront of us.
- Nobody here is look at the state.
- No one wants to do anything, you know try anything new.
- Ja.
Keith.
Keith!
- The lab report is due tomorrow.
- Ah, yes.
But the real pressing question is,
how is Rafael Marques, your boyfriend.
He is not...
Great choice that Rafael!
Brainy stud! Perfect guy! Can't go wrong!
- You were at the brink.
- No.
But you were.
- If you weren't then how would you know?
- Because that's where everyone goes.
- What about the lab report?
- Hop in!
- Come on! I do my best work while I'm driving.
- I have your book.
By heating tin metal...
in air... at a high temperature...
we were produce a tin-oxygen product
called...
Wait!
So we need to convert two masses to moles
and dividing the greater mole quantile by the lesser.
Okay, so... 0,01731 tin,
and 0,0350 oxygen.
- So the mole ratio is?
- Mole ratio? What's that?
- It's the thing you have to figure out.
- But you are already knowing the answer.
Oh, come on, you're being a jerk!
I need to be back in office in fifteen minutes.
What's the rush? We're here in a yellow truck,
a road ahead of us and nothing but opportunities.
- Okay, what opportunities...?
- Choose a place!
- Pick a place! Right now! At random!
- Okay, I choose...
...the third point on our lab report
calculating the mole ratio.
I can't concentrate driving in a straight
line like this, this is not gonna work.
- Then turn!
- Where?
Anywhere.
Wow! Very funny.
The mole ratio therefore is two to one.
But now we need to find potential
oxidation numbers of tin and oxygen.
Which are?
It's time for our picnic scene.
Keith!
There he is! How's it going?
Move along, dear!
In case you haven't heard picnics
they usually take place outdoors.
Oh, is that what it says
in the official picnic rule book?
This's not funny.
Do you think our check is ready yet?
I know, my pumpkin love, I'm pissed off too.
Can you believe this shit?
It's been three months since that accident.
The nerve...
- Take me back to school now!
- Yeah! Let's go back to the library
and finish lab report in a safe,
acceptable way like everybody else.
Bone grafts are really starting to kick in now.
Hey, Ralph!
No, thanks.
- You said two one right for the mole ratio?
- Yeah.
Duke.
- You'll give a job like this one day?
- God, no.
- My dad used to work in a place like this.
- Ah, yes. Daddy Anderson.
An accountant? A salesman?
A Norwegian fisherman!
District manager for a phonecall company.
You're not very good at reading minds.
Well, that's 'cause I wasn't really trying.
He manages stacks of paper. Moving them from
side to side, every day, he hates his job.
When he was your age he dreamed of
going to Duke but they rejected him.
So he poured over every detail of your application,
night after night, until you finally got it right.
Natalie Anderson, the star of the household,
who loves beeing in the center of the attention.
She just wished it din't mean
having to play tennis all of the time.
How am I doing on?
Okay.
Actually this's not so bad.
Can I help you?
We just... are waiting for Mr. Richardson.
He said he'd to finnish a phone call.
Okay.
- Goddamn that Richardson!
- Yeah.
Who's he thinking of him, that monkey?
I'm sick of this shit! You know, tabby?
We're goin' straight to the top!
We're gettin' this monkey ass FIRED!
- ...allways take excuses, bullshit! We'd never payed out.
- We just have to be patient, honey.
Okay, so you're an only child.
Your Mom works for a diaryfresh. Your Dad is a...
... a buliding-constructor and you live
in a ranch house. So how am I doing?
Actually, I have two brothers, three sisters,
my dad works in real estate, mom helps near
and we live in a farmhouse.
Where are you, my beautiful?
In a big old farmhouse.
Where?
- Where do you live?
- Beaver Creek, off the Route ten.
That old white house?
- With big front porch?
- With big front porch.
Oh, that's such a great place.
That's where I live.
Okay, this is nice, but it's not enough to fill two pages.
Okay, but this is all of our pictures that we have.
Oh, really? Okay, would you mind you just like
draw something, and turn on page 2.,
because this is not enough to fit...
- Okay, I'll take pics for tomorrow, okay?
- Okay, thank you.
- So were you with that freak?
- He's not a freak. Did Raff cut?
- Well, you said that you'll back to be there.
- It wasn't actually a definite plan.
- I'd told to him you have to be a date.
- Did he say anything?
Oh, just that his parents will going out
tonight and he wanna do a pool-party.
- Cool.
- And he sounded really pissed you'd bulled him off.
- Natalie, what are you doing with this face?
- A lab report.
Oh, really? And you just decided it'll be fine
if you left me here the all full of this shit?
- It lasted record time.
- Because the lab report was so exciting?
I had to get it down. What's your problem?
- I'm saving a really shity day.
- What?
- Skinny envelope.
- Notre Dame? Oh, shit!
- Wait-listed.
- Really?
Oh, take supplied three percent for waitlists will
place, this is basically you'd rejection.
- No, no, we can out suffed to the application.
- Yeah, and what can I exactly do?
You can tell that the Notre Dame was
your first choice school
and we'll get an other letter recommendation
from the faculty. It makes this happened.
- Your power of positive thinking?
- Right.
Hi, Raff.
Who else has gonna go?
I've to do that tennis match.
Maybe afterwards if there is time.
Okay. Bye!
Everything is told in our control.
Come on, girl!
Yeah! Come on, Natalie!
The van der Waals-stated
subexctraction experiment. Okay?
A milliard of forces causes into molecule-attractions.
The strenght of these attractions is
independent on several factors.
Understanding this forces is...
Oh, God!
- Be careful would you?
- I'm gonna be in trouble for that?
Are you gonna punish me for this?
- I might have to.
- 'Cause you know how I feel about all that stuff.
Look, partner, you know the deal.
But those spiky heels really hurt me...
Keith, you've been a bad boy and
now you're gonna have to pay the price.
Do you mind?
- So we're on five P.M.?
- For what?
- A bowling-scene.
- Bowling? Are you serious?
- I'm going out.
- Tomorrow.
- Keith, I can't.
- It's not a date.
- Keith, maybe sometime...
- Friday?
I'll just schedule it with your assistant!
Okay, you do that!
Did you wrote it?
I've swapped the second into two paragraphs
and I've got out that stuff about history product.
It's a really bullshit, we don't really need that.
But I've filled in other things too.
- Great.
- I'm sending to you right now.
- Yes sir, editor in chief.
- Natalie, phone!
I gotta go. It looks really really good.
- Oh, it makes no difference.
- No, this will work!
- It's well!
- I'd got it.
- Alright, we'll talk to later. Bye!
- Bye!
- Hello?
- It would not be a date.
- Who is this?
- It's only bowling. Comme on, what were you so afraid of?
Keith... hi.
Look, I'll pick you up at five P.M. tomorrow after school.
- Did you happen to do the homework?
- Homework? ...Homework?
It's your turn to write up the lab notes,
don't you remember?
- You're screwin' with my grade here.
- Yeah and you're changing the subject!
I told you, I have plans.
Ah, look, you'll be home at nine o'clock,
then you'll have time for date afterwards.
- We'll see you in school.
- What... maybe.
With the lab notes...
- So who's on the phone?
- Oh, my lab partner.
- Did you have a nice time?
- Yeah.
- What's his name?
- Keith.
- Keith? Oh, I thought...
- Rafael. His name is Rafael.
- The South-American boy?
- Yes.
Why aren't you inviting him for dinner sometime?
We'd love to meet him.
Okay. Sure. It's really nice.
- So who is Keith?
- Oh, he's nobody. He's just my lab partner.
"A: It's not a date.
B: You are my lab partner.
C: Just to see..."
Clever.
"D: Bowling is the most popular sport in
America and it is important that we fit in.
E: It's not and will never be a date."
What is it? He like stucking you, or something?
- So what should we do about him?
- Oh, simple...
Okay, your papers on the "Great Gatsby" are doing
in two weeks. For those of you without a calculator
there are that's may 4th.
The way write a paper ...just go home, go into your room...
It's gonna be a strange for some of you, but trust to something...
5 PM - MEET LAB PARNTER ANTI-DATE
NOTE: DON'T BE A CHICKEN!
"The european heritage two-week-tour is a living classroom.
Students have an opportunity to a
quiet greater expect one of the world
and then increase their enthusiasm for learning."
Personally I'm interested in a quiet deeper
appreciating with french wine-drinking heritages.
And how about the Amsterdam weaken bequeath?
Although we all having enthusiasm
for learning. It's working already.
- Sign me up, baby.
- I'm in.
Oh, I told I'm in.
5 P.M.
Hey, can we meet a bit later tonight? At 9.
I've forgot that I promised to help somebody in english paper.
- The movie is at 8.
- Oh, shit.
- Well, we'll figure out something else.
- Thanks.
I don't know...
You really wanna base your relationship with
a great guy like Raff on lies and deceit?
Why don't you tell him the truth?
You're spending a couple of
hours with your lab partner.
- What I do with Raff is none of your business.
- My point exactly.
- I thought we're going bowling.
- We're saving now.
- Do you believe it or not, there are bowling balls on the bowling line.
- But not like these babies.
Cosmo, Patsy...
- A Walt ball.
- But we only need two.
If we were just bowling.
- Andy is an artist.
- That's great, but you've no any time.
First thing's first.
- You'll fixed it up with scrap parts?
- There aren't all scrap parts.
- We're creating life in that hadn't been matter.
- You and Andy?
I and my Dad.
- Are you close with your Dad?
- Hold this by there!
Are you?
He was alive before the days there
weren't electronic ignition. I need him.
So this truck is... your thing.
- Yeah, it's my thing.
- Interesting...
You're so talented, Keith!
You're so much academic potential!
What are you doing wasting your time in a damn truck?
Well, I did't say that, but... it's kind of true.
Don't listen to her honey bun! She's just jealous.
So... she's your girlfriend.
Look, you're out of time.
I gotta go. No bowling tonight.
Keep going! Go around the corner!
He's prompt! I like that in a man!
He's on time and need more and more, baby.
Shut up! Just dirve!
Sneak down the alley to make at
your boyfriend... sexy.
- Bye!
- I'll pick you up at four.
- Four?
- A.M.
He'll be gone by then, right?
What a wicked do we at 4 A.M.?
- Keith?
- It's not a date.
I'll pick you up right here!
At our secret spot!
What?
What it?
- Were you've done this before?
- Kissed?
- It could be a problem for you?
- I just don't think this can work any more, Natalie.
- Oh My God!
- What? I was kidding!
I'm kidding...
You know it's listening really cheesy but
- when I do that, I just wanna to be...
- Oh, don't rush! I've gonna be all covered.
We'll have a heart-ship bed that I ordered
and there will be candles...
- You know what I'm talking about!
- I know, I know...
- Hey, don't rush okay?
- Thanks.
Just think, years from now you're going to have a big huge family
and you're gonna wanna share stories
and one of the stories will be that when you were in high school
put a bowling ball at your chemistry teacher's front porch.
And his name was Walt.
I refuse!
Go! Go!
Get out, you really jerk!
- His last name is Marques.
- It's the thought that counts.
- We've been so screwed.
- Ah, yeah.
- If we're caught just swallow one of these!
- It's not funny shit head!
So who gets these?
Well, you can't give up now,
Patsy, you're gonna be state champion!
My daddy won't let me, Cosmo.
What's your daddy know about your bowling?
Well he's godly in at all
you know and to him it's just a game
- and to hang games is the devil's handiwork.
- Patsy, you are the greatest!
- You can make the nationals!
- I gotta respect my daddy's wishes.
He's had a hard life.
Particularly killed himself
raise us nine kids.
- There was my last game.
- Well, darling...
then it was my last game too.
"Dear waitress,
please find a home for our balls.
Cosmo and Patsy."
- This is the saddest day of our lives.
- Indeed it is.
- Natie!
- What's up?
I'm just putting in your last match.
You're now right 14th.
- Take a look!
- I believe you.
If you're staying in the top twenty,
you'll sent to that scholarship.
- Dad!
- What?
- Did you apply the Duke?
- Actually yes I did.
I did't get in. It was very compared of year.
You'd ever think about doing something different?
Different?
- For work.
- Such as?
- Something you may actually enjoy.
- Like what?
- Dad!
- What?
He's smart, confident, really hard.
I kinda think he's perfect.
- So what did you do last night?
- Oh, we just plunged on and talked.
Few other things...
Not that!
It's great that Raff is absolutely no presser.
- So there's that Courtney was illusinating?
- What?
She said she saw you with Keith
Zetterstrom on straight street.
- Oh, well I hung out with him a little bit too.
- Oh!?
- What? I'm not can have whatever friends?
- Not who were stucking you.
Keith is cool, he just, he does things in own way.
It's kinda perfect actually. It's Keith keeps me busy
and not were get at all upset about Raff.
It works so.
Alright, hey, if it works so for you, it's just great.
It does.
I gotta go. I've got tennis.
- Bye!
- Call you later.
Do you speak spanish?
It's superb!
- Are you learning any languages at the school?
- French.
- So have you ever been to Italy?
- Oh, yeah, I actually I stayed live there a couple of years.
We're planning a trip there. It's my dream.
Oh, yeah! I recommend!
Florence is one of my favourite cites.
Natalie tells that your planning is to attending to Penn State.
Oh, actually it's UPENN.
As she told that you're quite a sportman.
Oh, yeah, I've play football ever since when I was lower kid.
- Oh, you know Pete was a... tell...
- Not...
Okay, he was a great football player at the college.
I wasn't a great football player. I only played football.
Oh, soccer?
Football.
- Bon appétit!
- Would you like an other bean?
- My uncle says we can have any weekend next month.
- After 14th. After APs.
- Sure.
- So your parents are give you okay for this?
- Yeah. Yours?
- Something can be arranged.
- Just you and me... and the fireplace...
- Actually...
...we really need to talk.
I need be honestly to how I feel about this.
- What?
- It's beautiful. It's perfect. You're perfect.
Well, I actually thought you're waiting...
- But we can practice, right?
- Oh, yeah...
Come in!
Some guy on a track drobbed this all for you.
- I'll got it!
- Okay.
Thanks.
- What's that?
- I don't know. Chem lab notes?
Gosh! What is this?
- Carburator tunne up kit.
- Just what I allways wanted.
"guaranted not to raise your GPA"
9 PM MEET PARTNER NON DATE
- Keeps really start get in my nerves.
- What's that mean?
- He just does shit like this.
- Isn't he a little...?
- Something like that.
- He's crushed on you.
- He's crushed on his truck.
- Oh, whatever, just...
- ...don't encourage.
- I don't!
- Shit!
- Are you ready to go?
- Actually I have to take a shower.
- ... (=Am I awaiting you)?
No, that's alright. You go ahead!
I'll been there.
Alright. Goodbye!
- Bye!
Keith! We need to talk.
- Hop in!
- I'm not going to anywhere with you.
Cool, well then I'll come inside and
watch TV with Pete and Caroline.
No. No.
No!
- You can't just deliver shit into my house like that!
- But it works, didn't it?
Listen, I like you.
I like being friends with you.
But therefore we hang out from now I want
I gotta be a part of your plans!
- See, but there are no plans!
- Bullshit!
- You've got some whole scenario worked out.
- Is that what you think?
- Yeah, and you can't just expect me that drop
everything because you decided you wanna do some...
- I don't expect you to do anything!
You're free go at anytime! In fact,
what is Nathalie Anderson doing
hanging out a truck geek like me anyway?
This is cool. This is the scene
where we're at the crossroads.
You're being a jerk.
Oh, come on, miss bellequeen!
Stud boyfriend, tennis champ!
Don't you have better things to do on a Friday night?
Just go, leave, get out here!
You know I thought you're different,
but you're not different.
You're just another immature little boy!
You're right.
I'm wasting my time here.
And what about you?
Mr. Egomaniac?
Why are you always giving me gifts and
writing clever little notes all of the time?
Why don't you leave?
- Go ahead! Drive away right now!
- There's Keith! Stop, Al!
Keith!
Keith, swap!
They got me Super Smash Brothers and Gran Turismo 3.
And they're beating each other up, these guys allways...
- That's great, I'll to show you!
- Billy. Billy. Hi, Al.
- I've got Mario and Luigi and they battling each other...
- Go on. Great. Listen, this is, Sophie.
- Natalie.
- Hi! I'm Al.
She's a double agent, you can't trust her.
- they got all these monsters that are
battling and clashing at each other and...
- Oh, good. 'Cause I'm gonna kick your ass!
I'll kick your ass!
Come on, let's get out here! Come on!
- Let's go to your house!
- Billy... you know... Billy...
I'm on specially assignment tonight.
How-how about tomorrow?
- No, I got school tomorrow! Come on, let's go!
- Billy, we gotta go!
- Come on, sleep one more night there! One more!
- Billy, stand out the car right now!
- My parents don't care!
- Come on! Next time.
- Oh, no...
- Come on.
- Are we talking, Keith?
- Hang in there, Al.
You're doing just fine.
- Kick your ass!
- So how do you know them?
- The neighborhood.
Billy is what? Hyperactive or something?
So you're his counselor?
Tutor? Something like that?
Such a guy...
...turns out you aren't softie.
So, what is it?
Church programm?
The Y? Volunteer thing?
Let's get out here!
Come on, scap!
We've got a yellow truck,
the road in front of us...
and nothing but opportunities, right?
Turn right up here!
Right here! This dirt road up ahead!
Come on! What?
- Why here?
- Why?
It's not supposed to be a why, right?
Were you scared?
- Wow! Slow down!
- Just funny. Really funny.
- What?
- You chose this road.
So that's the Brink!
I've never been on this side.
- I've never been on that side.
- You're not missing much.
Really? I thought you're the Brink Queen.
It's getting on really old.
It's all about what you're wearing and who's
hooking up with who and showing off your boyfriend.
- Many essential information.
- Oh, yeah.
Down there they live and die by that crap.
But up here it's like...
...what have I ever care.
- You don't...
- What?
You don't care what people think.
You're just...
...you.
- Whatever that is.
- It's a good thing.
Really good thing.
So do you come here a lot?
Cool.
- I found your place.
- I don't know how you did.
Chances are probably one in a billion.
Stranger things have happened, right?
You know... we should probably leave.
- Yeah.
- We're lab partners.
- This is strictly a lab partnership.
- Absolutely.
- And Walter would be very very upset right now. So...
- Hello, Raff.
- Hi, beautiful! Are you ready?
I'm so sorry, I've just go ahead from a shower.
Actually... I don't really feel like
to go to the brink tonight.
- Why? What's wrong with the brink?
- Just that we've gone on since last six weeks in a role.
I know but we've promised to Trisha,
- and you know to Robbie.
- We'll see them all the time.
Well, you see me all the time.
So you're sick of me all the time?
Of course I'm not kidding sick of you
I'm just really be (off).
Had a long day, practice after school.
I was getting to call you sooner.
Okay, it's right. Just get some sleep
and we'll hang tomorrow, okay?
- Yeah, see you next happening.
- Okay.
- Okay, bye!
- Bye!
- Hi!
Natalie!
- Guess, where can I be next year!
- Notre Dame!
That's great!
We have to celebrate this!
- Okay, partner, now I've got a scene.
- Shoot!
It's the scene where you tell me the truth.
The big confession scene.
What are you doing after finish highschool?
Really.
- I'm going to London.
- London?
Me too! With Raff and Brooke and Travis!
We should meet up!
Not that London.
London Ontario. It's a classic
truckshow there every year in July.
- So you really are truck geek.
- You see I open up to you and you dump on me.
No, just because I know you have dreams
more than a truck show.
- The sky's the limit, right?
- Yeah, actually it is.
You, sure?
I'm sure you sell yourself short.
Are we... are we moving?
- We are moving!
- A step for moving into the space on a mission...
Keith, we have a problem.
- I think, there is an untreatable one in the space craft...
- Keith! Get up! Come on!
- Keith, it's gonna go over! Get up!
- He's taken on the body by trusted co-pilot
- called Natalie Anderson...
- Keith! It's gonna go over!
- "It's gonna go over!"
- Come on! What are you doing?
- Keith! Stop it!
- She's just saying: "Keith, stop it!"
Keith, come on!
- Shit! Keith! Hurry up!
- "Get up, Keith. Get up."
Keith, come on, get up or
you're gonna get killed! Keith!
Stop it! Stop the truck! Keith!
What the hell was that?
Are you crazy?!
If you do shit like that,
you could get yourself killed!
Don't mention what would've
happened to my truck...
Oh... oh yeah!
It's true you wanna go over?
- I wasn't even close.
- Yes, you were.
- You don't know how close is.
- Don't give me one of your stupid lines!
I know what close is.
Goodnight, partner.
Take care of yourself, okay?
MORPHINE, INDICATED FOR THE TREATMENT OF DEPRESSION
No, not C, Z. Zetterstrom.
Z, E, T, T, E... Are you sure?
- What do you think you do on?
- What?
- Using yourself phone on the school property?
- Hey... don't!
It was Duke, apparently there's
a problem with my trans courts.
- Oh, so everything is okay?
- Actually I have to go in the front office to deal with this.
Sucks.
- Bye!
Look, he's not gone for few days now so I was thinking
I should call him you know get him kinda homework at all.
I'm sorry, we don't get out any information.
But it's kind of emergence.
You know Keith is falling behind me,
it's in fact bad for me to perform the APs.
You have to speak to Mr. Miles regarding that.
Okay, look, he's my friend. He's gave me his number,
I'd just losted it. It's really not a big deal.
- I'm sorry, I can't.
- Where is he? Why isn't he come?
I'm trying to learn, but he doesn't care!
I think Keith's having a thought time at the moment.
- Thought how?
- Thanks.
- That's all I can say really.
- But... is there anything I can do?
- I knew this was a bad idea.
- What?
- Partner on your guys.
But it was random.
He chosed me?
- Keith chosed me?
- I'll make sure he gets your notes.
Randy Randerson's managed to set into final match.
- Wanna I come in?
- Maybe. No.
Shit, I don't know. I think, I just
to get some sleep, or something.
Are you puzzle with Keith?
- Where that come from?
- Do you?
As the matter in fact I have
absolutely zero plans with Keith.
- But you were hanging with him.
- I hang with a lot of people.
Is there any wrong with that?
I'm only had to be seen with you?
No, no. Relax, okay?
The match is over.
Sorry. It's just a screwed day.
So everything is okay?
He's just my lab partner and my friend.
Actually he's not even my friend
- so can we just let it go?
- Yeah, whatever.
So we'll talk to later.
Natalie, we have to talk!
I've lost a match.
Get over, Mom!
Natalie, come back!
Natalie, I'm talking to you!
- Yeah?
- Hi! Is Keith home?
- Keith?
- I'm his lab partner.
- May I help you?
- Are you Mr. Zetterstrom?
- Mr. who?
- This is the Zetterstrom house?
My name is Don. Don Sope.
Sorry. Wrong house.
Oh, quiz! Sweet! What timing.
Morning, Walt! Thank you.
Hey, partner, thanks for those notes,
I killed that quiz.
- Where have you been the last two weeks?
- Last two weeks?
- What, do you come here every day?
- There's some wrong with you, isn't there?
Yeah, yeah there is, with me,
definitely with you,
- with this sexy little freshman right here.
- I don't wanna be funny anymore, Keith.
Oh, well I hate to break it to you, Anderson
but you've never really been funny to begin, right?
What are you? Depressed or something?
Depressed? Yes, throw that out there.
Chicks find it incredibly sexy.
- I'm being serious, Keith.
- Why?
It never works.
You could have to told me.
Could I told you what?
- That you have problems?
- You don't know the half of them.
- Hey, Raff.
- What's going on?
What?
- The jacket...
- Oh, are you like it? I got it from K-Mart.
Raff, I was cold he lent it to me.
Oh, come on, you don't expect
him to believe that, do you?
See Raff we're part of this jacket smuggling ring,
but if you're quiet enough I swear
there's a fleece in it somewhere for you.
- Look, I'm not talking to you, okay?
- Hey, man, don't get mad at me.
- I only a supply dishing, okay? I don't create the demand...
- Shut the hell up!
Raff! Raff, it's just a jacket.
That's it! It's a jacket.
This is bullshit!
Raff, wait up!
Marques, it was a joke!
Raff! Raff!
- Was just a jacket, right?
- Yes!
- That's it?
- Of course, that's all it was!
Raff, come on...
I've class.
- So all was just a big joke to you, huh?
- I don't know.
- How is it?
- I don't know. I don't know anything anymore.
Why did you choose me your lab partner?
- Me?
- Don't bullshit me! Miles told me!
Walter Miles is CIA, you can't trust him.
- Where do you live?
- What?
Where do you live?
You've lied about it!
- Are you losing it partner?
- You lied about everything!
'Cause you know what, I've got some great pills that
you can take. But I'm sure you already knew that.
I just don't understand,
Natalie was one of the school's finest students.
- I needed the chemistry notes.
- You know very well that's not the way to get them.
- She made a mistake.
- She's been under a lot of pressure lately with
the tennis, the schedule and the homework...
I'm sorry but the faithing's school
properties are remarked one week suspension.
- What? What was just to suppose to do...?
- Natalie.
- I can make any exceptions to therefore.
- I needed the notes I have to take my AP!
Mr. Miles make sure you get thoes notes.
Just don't make a mass of those things
what there you worked so hard!
Please, can we leave just not?
- You don't wanna something to tell us?
- Stop the car!
What?
- I can't thinking here. I wanna get out!
- You're staying right where you are, missy!
Natalie!
What? The light was red!
- Hi.
...chapter 16th did we in history
and that's the mathematics contrast.
Okay, thanks.
- Are you okay?
- Fine.
- Are you gonna tell me what happened?
- Someting... I've had a hissy fit.
Natalie! You broke in the Keith locker.
And really what were you looking for there?
Oh, that's just great, I'm sure
you all just gossip in my ass at all.
I'm just tring to help you, okey?
Look, Keith is a loser! He's jealous, and
he's ovbious just wanna to break you guys up.
- That's ridiculous!
- Raff is pissed.
You'd talked to Raff?
- No, no! Natalie, just listen to me one second!
- Go! Go away!
Natalie!
Keith isn't a straight go!
Why are you let him to broke everything?
I'm going.
- Natalie!
- I'd like to warm up by myself once my life, Mom.
- See you at the match!
- Natalie! I'm not ready!
Natalie.
Natalie! Natalie!
What the hell...?
- I told you I'll talk to you later.
- I wanna know what's going on!
What's going on? That I have a match!
Whatever is you can tell me about it.
Okey, Natalie?
- It hasn't nothing to do with you.
- Because of it's about to do with Keith?
- It's about me.
- Then it's about me too!
Because there's a little thing about us,
when you ever know this!
I need a little time.
Then we'll get the lake house next weekend,
then I've to call my uncle...
- I'll call you later!
- Natalie!
Idiot!
Check your mind!
Hi!
- Are you Keith's dad?
- Yeah.
Keith.
Keith!
I'm looking what can I do for you.
- Does he have any brothers, sisters?
- No, just two of us.
I'm sorry. He doesn't wanna to see you now.
Okay.
Thanks anyway.
I don't,
I don't care where you're gonna be next year.
I don't care if you're crazy.
God...
I just know I wanna to be with you.
I don't understand what you're doing.
It seems so pointless,
I mean everything,
it just seems so pointless!
But when I'm with you, it's different,
I don't know why.
So we should actually go bowling.
- You know like with lanes and pins.
- Yeah, we should.
- Maybe tomorrow?
- Maybe.
- Are you even gonna be in school tomorrow?
- I don't know.
- I don't know about any this actually.
- What?
I mean a guy like me with a truck
gotta keep movin'.
Stop it.
I mean, you know, I'm not really feel
the hold touch thing anyway.
- Shut up!
- You got Raff.
Raff's good guy. Good for you.
We should just forget about it.
- Fuck you!
- You just did partner.
If you just fault to fit matches
what do you expect?
You're weighting grabb 15 points last month.
Great.
That's just perfect.
I would talk to Mr. Richard Honings,
he's a big guy of the DTTA.
No, all we need to do ask for an excuse to a doctor
to write a letter saying you were injured.
- But I wasn't injured.
- This is a 10,000 dollars scholarship we are talking about.
It's not my fault you wanna me to go
the most expensive school in universe.
- Duke is the best you've ever...
- Why would you sold yourself short?
I needn't finnishing in the other applications.
- Honey, you didn't have to.
- You didn't want me to.
There are billion other schools
and than or I could get a job
- Or something.
- You don't have to a comromise, honey
if we focus on this week the scholarship'll be back.
Maybe I don't wanna give it back.
Maybe I don't wanna play tennis
for six hours a day at the college.
Maybe I'm sick of it after 10 stupid years!
Thouht I ever cared of you?
Honey, there's no reason to give up on your dream now.
- Oh, are you even listening to me?
- It is almost june. It is too late.
You are right!
Everything is just screwed up!
- Hey, we are not done here!
- Come right back here!
Hi.
- We'd met. I was with Keith.
- Oh... hi.
- How is Keith doing?
- I don't really know.
Actually I haven't seen him much.
Does he so see that little boy? Billy?
Billy'd past away.
- May I help you, sir?
- 15 pumple the third please.
- What?
- I'm sorry.
- How to Keith's know him?
- On the chemo they've gona together.
- So you're his doctor...?
- Counsellor.
I was...
But he's gonna be okay, right?
How sick is he? Tell me!
I thought you'd knew.
I'm really sorry.
Keith?
Keith.
Please come outside!
Keith, come on!
Keith, open the door!
Let's talk to you please!
Keith...
- Thanks for calling.
- Sorry. I've to try to figure things out.
Yeah? And? Did you figured out?
Raff, we had a good time.
I really like you.
- Then why are you doing this?
- I'm just screwed a lot of things suffering now.
- Can we just leave it?
- No! We can't actually!
I couldn't find the caribbean mix
so after I'll give to get you later.
Yeah, yeah, later. I've heard that before.
I wasn't bulling you off.
Okey, things got complicated.
- You've started bullshitting me, Natalie!
- You wanted to know what really happened?
I know what happened, okay?
You let down that little yuck screwed your head!
- Is that what do you think?
- Yes. It's obvious!
- You've no idea what are you talking about.
- But I would known when you told me!
- Stop it!
- What were you thinking?
What the hell were you thinking?!
... you giving up yourself to a piece of shit?
Stop it!
You know I only hope good things for you.
'Cause really bad shit happens people!
I hope the God it never happens to you!
Welcome back, bad girl!
Alright ladies, gentleman.
Please leave your final reports on my desk...
and I want to make sure your glassworhts are cleaned,
your beakers and your testcubes aren't dirty.
If these aren't clean, you must clean them
or you'll lose points.
If anything is missing, please gonna sign me immediately.
Finally you make sure that your labdesks are cleaned...
Four test cubes, three beakers...
and a Bunsen burner.
Yeah, okay, everything seems to be in order. Keys?
Natalie, key?
The end of Chemistry as we know it.
You're such a goddamn glib little actor!
As far as I'm concerned this is
a really chickenshit goodbye!
Excuse me.
Don't worry, Walter.
She was adressing her remarks to me.
Hey! That truck-guy's here.
Said something about going out bowling.
- Okay.
- I've got.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Everybody bites it sooner or later.
I'm just in the AP class, ahead of the game.
- Always the joke.
- Al says it's a phase, it'll stop soon.
But, hey! At least it wasn't all
about the sympathy for the sick kid.
That's not fair!
Is Duke fair?
Is Europe fair?
At this rate I won't even make it
to London, Ontario. Is that fair?
Bowling.
That's what I get.
- We're not going bowling.
- Why?
We're saving that.
Turn left!
- So where are we going on?
- The sky's the limit.
I've never lied in thus far.
I'm not gonna start now.
What are we doing? Really?
- This is the goodbye-scene.
- Let's not... Okay?
Come on, Zetterstrom!
You can do it!
Okay. Wake up Natalie!
Don't you see what happened here?
You had a beautiful life,
and I had shit.
I hated your guts.
I wanted to take you down, I wanted to make you
as miserable as I am and that is exactly what I did!
Now, how's that for a goodbye?
- Pretty lame.
- Face it, Anderson! I screwed you.
I screwed you big time.
So you screwed me. So what?
Me? I made love to you.
Try again.
Try again!
I had it all figured out.
So I cut out a little early, who cares?
It's probably a good thing.
Life sucks, anyway.
But then I met you and it got weird.
And you were so amazing.
- And I...
- What?
What?
I just wanted a little more time.
So all in all, I'd say you're
the worst thing that's ever happened to me.
Goodbye partner.
I'm staying with you until you leave.
I don't care how much time we have!
Give up you stupid jerk?
I'm starting it up.
Now turn into the left till the get its place!
Then back a little bit.
Okay.
Perfect. It'll good for 50,000 miles.
translated: phoenixx
www.feliratok.hu