EXCUSE ME? HEY, THERE.
- MOM, DO YOU MIND?
- LET'S SEE WHAT WE DO ON THE 13TH DAY.
WONDERFUL, I UNDERSTAND.
THANKS, DAD.
- BONJOUR.
- THREE CHARDONNAY, PLEASE.
- NO, DO NOT DRINK WHEN FLYING.
- NOTHING FOR ME NOTHING, THANK YOU.
WELL, TO BE FOR ALL THREE.
I'M SO PROUD OF YOU, BABY.
ABANDONED GIRL WOULD CANCEL ANY VACATION,
THERE AND YOU.
THANKS, DAD,
BUT NEED TO GET OVER.
- HE WAS IMPARTIAL.
- YES.
WITH THE AGREEMENT OF BOTH PARTIES.
- I THOUGHT NEEDED SPACE.
- IT WAS NOT SPONTANEOUS ENOUGH.
- UNSAFE AND PREDICTABLE.
- I LIVE RIGHT HERE.
I HEAR YOU SAY.
YOU WERE THE ONE THAT IMPOSED RULES.
I THOUGHT THAT SOME RULES
IN OUR RELATIONSHIP ...
ABOUT "HOW AND WHEN" SUCH
PERFECTLY REASONABLE.
TOO MANY RULES, DEAR.
HAVE TO BE CAREFUL, DEAR,
WHEN SOMETHING GOES WRONG.
TO GET YOUR PRECAUTIONS.
THE FIRST TIME ME AND MOM
I DO LOVE ...
WE DID EVERYTHING POSSIBLE NOT TO NEGLECT
ABSOLUTELY NOTHING.
IT WAS NOT EASY.
DAD, CAN YOU TELL ME IN PRIVATE.
- CHANGE THE PLACE.
- AND THE EMERGENCY CODE IS ...
13D. BELIEVE ME, I KNOW WHO IS.
BUT I PROMISE I WILL TRY TO FORGET.
TRANSLATION: URBAN LEGEND
NOW WE HAVE VISUAL CONTACT.
- TARGET CONFIRMED.
- CONTENT.
PARK.
OF TIME UP TO 17 HOURS
AS TO DELIVER THE PACKAGE.
- AND THE HEAD WANTS TO CONCLUDE THE DEAL.
- YES, YES.
FINISH HERE AND ARE READY TO GO.
WE HAVE PUT ON ME AND MY WIFE
SECOND FLOOR AND MY DAUGHTER IN THE THIRD.
AND I MADE CLEAR
THAT WE WANT NEXT ROOM.
- OH, SURE. YOU WANT TOGETHER.
- RIGHT, BUT DID NOT HAVE TO AND A.
IS A SINGLE WOMAN. THE ONLY ...
FRESH DESP?R?IT?.
THERE ARE ALWAYS ALONE.
- DAD, ROOM ...
- NOT ONE TO ARGUE IN FRONT OF US RECEP?IEI.
THIRD FLOOR, IS NOT IT?
OVERLOOKING THE OCEAN.
ALWAYS DO SAME THING
WITH RESERVATION.
IT IS HIS DUTY. LOOK AT RECEP?IONER.
IT'S LIKE A FOX, YOU KNOW WHO ELSE WAS THE AND A.
AND TALKING ABOUT RICHARD.
I KNOW, MOM.
NOT TALK TO HIM, YOU REMEMBER?
YES, FOR US IS DEAD.
BUT DONT MIND THAT
THAT LEFT YOU FOR ANOTHER WOMAN?
WHAT?
NO, I DID IT.
FORGET WHAT I SAID.
- DO NOT SPEAK FRENCH.
- EXCUSE ME. EVERYTHING IS READY.
I'M GOING UP TO MY ROOM.
DESCEND LATER.
TAKE SOME LAXATIVES FOR FREE.
HONEY, IF IT WERE EASY,
I NEVER HAVE PEOPLE.
- BONJOUR.
DOWN?
YOU FORGOT TO WATER AND THE BUTTON.
ONE DAY MUST BE BORING
IF YOU RIDE THE ELEVATOR FOR FUN.
PLEASE.
UNBELIEVABLE. YOU SEEM SURPRISED
EVERY TIME YOU LOOK AT ME.
I DO NOT SPEAK FRENCH.
- DO NOT SPEAK FRENCH.
- I UNDERSTOOD THE FIRST TIME.
WHY DO NOT YOU TELL FROM THE BEGINNING?
I DO NOT KNOW, WHY DID YOU WATCH?
I WALKED TO THE BEACH. YOU REMEMBER?
YES, WELL,
AND MAYBE I CAME TO THE POOL.
EVEN YOU?
NO.
GO ROOM TO CHANGE.
BY THE WAY, I'M SPENCER.
CHARMED, SPENCER.
GOT A NAME?
JANE AND JENNIFER. SOMETIMES, JENNY.
NO, JANE. JUST JANE.
I'M GOING TO START SWIMMING.
SURE. BITE AS YOUR MUSCLES
SHOULD BE MEN?INU?I.
WANT A DRINK TOGETHER
TONIGHT?
SURE. I HAVE NOTHING PLANNED.
WHY NOT?
SUPER.
SEE MAURICE TERRACE,
AT SUNSET.
UNLESS IT FINDS YOU
SOMETHING BETTER TO DO.
NOTHING NICE.
I BROUGHT NICE DRESS.
OH, GOD.
OH, GOD. SUCK.
I GOTTA GET A DRESS.
WE PLANNED SEVERAL TIMES,
I CAN NOT BELIEVE YOU MISSED IT.
I KNOW, DAD. SORRY.
MY STOMACH GOES AWRY.
- WELL, GO BACK AND SOLVE TOGETHER.
- NO.
DAD, IT'S OKAY.
- DO NOT MAKE THE HERO, BABY.
- FATHER, BELIEVE ME, DO NOT WANT TO BE INVOLVED.
DEAR.
WE'LL BE WAITING ON THE BEACH.
- YOU'RE SURE SHE'S GONNA BE ALL RIGHT?
- YES, GO.
DISTRA?I SURE WITHOUT ME.
YOU'LL FIND THE PERFECT TYPE,
SOMEONE WHO IS NOT A LOSER.
DECENT AND FRIENDLY ...
BOTH IN BODY AND SOUL BOTH.
OH, GOD.
YOU CHOSE THE PERFECT MEAL.
SOMETHING TO DRINK, SIR?
- SOMETHING FOR YOU, BECAUSE I WAS LATE.
- OH, SORRY, HATE CHAMPION.
OH ... SORRY. PLEASE.
IT WAS A JOKE.
JUST KIDDING.
JANE ROBOT. ARE HERE
AS YOU OBSERVE, YOUR MANNERS.
YOU'RE A ROBOT PERFECT FOR BAD GUYS.
I KNOW.
COME ON, DO NOT WORRY.
SOMETHING WAS HAPPENING TO THE POPULATION.
IF YOU NEED SOMETHING LIKE THAT.
YES, STRANGE.
- THE BREAD AND BUTTER.
- YES.
WHAT WORKS FOR YOU?
OH, GOD. SHIT.
THAT'S WHAT I WANT.
YOU?
- I DO NOT KNOW.
- GO.
ARE YOU OKAY?
HI.
HIDING FROM SOMEONE?
YOU SEE THAT GUY ...
WHO READS THE MENU,
HIGH AND THE MUSTACHE?
HAS AN IMPRESSIVE MUSTACHE.
WELL, HE IS ...
A RUSSIAN DIPLOMAT.
A KIND OF PERVERSE.
IT HAS SAT NEXT TO ME ON THE PLANE.
DISGUSTING.
REALLY?
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN DISGUSTING?
I DO NOT WANT TO EXCHANGE
IF NOT ABSOLUTELY NECESSARY.
I HEARD AND THEY TALKED IN THE ROOM.
VERY STRANGE.
- DO YOU HOPE THAT WILL CHANGE THE ROOM.
- OH, NO, NO, NO.
I LIKE.
BEAUTIFUL VIEW, GOOD FOOD.
BUNGEE JUMPING.
I DO NOT WANT TO CONTRADICT YOUR HABITS
HAZARDOUS FOOD, BUT ...
BUNGEE JUMPING?
NEVER WILL MAKE YOU LOOK SEXY
VOMITING IN PUBLIC.
THAT'S WHAT I SAY AND.
- REALLY?
- YES.
YOU SEEM TO FEEL VERY COMFORTABLE HERE
BUT ...
BUT IF ALL WENT KIND ...
CONTINUE?
SURE.
ALL RIGHT.
SO ...
YOU SHOULD ORDER?
YOU KNOW WHAT? BETTER GET OUT OF HERE.
SERVICES ARE BAD.
I WANT TO SHOW YOU ... NICE.
THEY SAY THERE ARE MANY
FUN HERE.
TRUST ME. IT'S BORING.
- WANT MORE?
- OH, NO, NO.
I REALLY DO NOT DRINK SO MUCH.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE MORE EASILY RESIN.
WHAT WORK?
I'M A CONSULTANT.
FOR A COMPANY.
CONSULTING COMPANY.
I AM VERY BUSY.
TRAVEL A LOT.
I KNOW MANY, MANY PEOPLE ..
WELL
IF YOU COULD DO ANYTHING ELSE ...
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
I THINK OF AND TRY TO BE MORE FRIENDLY.
IN FACT, I ALWAYS WANTED
YOU KNOW MY NEIGHBORS ...
AND I NEVER HAD THE CHANCE.
YOUR WORKPLACE MUST BE
VERY NICE.
YOU ARE VERY BEAUTIFUL.
I THINK ... IS THE DRESS.
NOT THE DRESS.
ARE PRETTY AND NO DRESS.
AND NOT SEE SOMETHING HERE THAT HAS.
SAY YOU'RE BEAUTIFUL ...
... BEAUTIFUL AND I. ..
... AND GREAT ALSO.
THANK YOU,
I THINK I WANT ONE.
- I GET ANOTHER ONE.
- OKAY.
- GO.
HI, I WANT TO DANCE WITH YOU.
I'M SORRY, WHAT DID YOU SAY?
YOU ... I MUST SAY THAT DRESSED LIKE THAT
HAVE MANAGED TO SEDUCE ME.
- COME ON.
- WELCOME ... I HOPE YOU ...
YOU'RE A VERY ENTHUSIASTIC DANCER.
OH, GOD.
YOU'RE VERY KIND, BUT ...
I MUST RETURN TO MY PARTNER.
NO, YOU'RE MINE NOW.
EXCUSE ME.
BACK, AMERICANULE.
FINDS YOU AND YOU YOUR A PROSTITUTE.
OH, NO. IS A NE?N?ELEGERE.
SORRY, THERE ARE ...
THIS DRESS IS FOR PROSTITUTES?
IT WAS INCREDIBLE.
JUST JANE.
YES.
IT'S SOMETHING I WANT TO DO WELL.
YOU HAD THE LABEL.
OH, NO.
- NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
- IT'S OKAY.
NOT E. .. I ...
I CAN NOT AFFORD THIS DRESS.
I WAS RETURNING IT BECAUSE
I CAN NOT AFFORD.
EXCEPT WHERE MY FATHER
I WOULD BUY IT, WHAT ...
IT WOULD NOT DO IT ... BECAUSE ...
... NOT HERE.
OKAY, CALM DOWN. ARE YOU OKAY?
I CAN NOT BREATHE.
IT IS SO NARROW.
SORRY, YOU MUST TELL YOUR.
NOT THAT KIND OF GIRL.
NO SPONTANEOUS, NEVER
SO DO NOT DRINK AND DO NOT LIVE IN THE HASH.
LIVE A QUIET LIFE ...
AND NORMAL.
WHAT'S WRONG WITH A NORMAL LIFE?
HE AND KILL FOR ONE.
IT'S BECOMING WORSE.
YOU REMEMBER THE GUY FROM THE TERRACE
AT THE MUSTACHE?
RUSSIAN PERVERT.
THAT'S MY FATHER.
LOOKS LIKE BAD STAND
THE FAMILY SITUATION.
NO, NO. OH, GOD, NO.
NOT IN RUSSIA, NOR PERVERTED.
IS A PILOT.
YOU KNOW, PILOTING AIRPLANES.
WE CAME ON HOLIDAY WITH MY PARENTS.
I DID JUST THAT.
SUPPOSED TO BE HERE WITH MY BOYFRIEND
BUT ...
LEFT ME FOR ANOTHER, AND I. ..
SORRY.
GO AHEAD.
I CAN NOT BREATHE.
DRESS IS VERY NARROW.
YOU HAVE TO TAKE OFF.
REALLY, I NEED HELP
CLOSE IT.
- REALLY?
- YES.
SHOOT IT.
ALL RIGHT.
THEY DO.
ZIP ... IS BLOCKED.
BREAK IT, ALL RIGHT,
MY FATHER WILL PAY.
- LET IT RIP?
- YES, BREAK IT.
WAIT, COME BACK ... WELL ...
DO NOT MOVE ...
OH, GOD.
IT'S WELL DONE.
YOU.
- SO ...
- I LOOK AROUND ON HERE.
IN THIS ...
THANK YOU WERE ...
HONEST.
I FELT MOVED TO SHARE THE
WITH YOU ...
IT'S PRETTY HARD TO SAY.
BUT ...
I FEEL THAT ...
IT'S SO REAL.
SO ...
I WANT TO BE HONEST WITH YOU.
I NEVER TOLD ANYONE THAT.
I KILL PEOPLE.
SUPOR?I
BETTER THAN I EXPECTED.
WONDERFUL.
USUALLY KILL EVIL PEOPLE,
DO NOT KILL PEOPLE.
THERE ARE A KILLER
I AM A PROFESSIONAL.
I IMPROVE THEIR IN KILLING PEOPLE.
YOU'RE A WONDERFUL OBEDIENT.
EXCELLENT.
OBEDIENT.
I HATE WHAT THEY DO.
I AM A CROOK.
BUT I LIKE YOU.
TOMORROW I'LL SHOW YOU ... NICE
AND HOPEFULLY IT IS
JUST THE BEGINNING.
BECAUSE I LIKE YOU.
OH, GOD, IS VERY GOOD.
NO FAIR. YOU MUST EAT.
EVERYTHING, EVERYTHING.
OH, FRUIT!
- GO TO THE TOILET.
- OKAY.
IT WAS AN ACCIDENT HAPPEN.
SOMETIMES WEAPONS
AND EXCLUSIVE MODELS ...
WILL BE GOOD AS NEW.
WHY?
NEED TO KILL MORE PEOPLE?
JORDAN IS THE ENEMY OF THE STATE.
ARE YOU SURE?
BECAUSE FIVE YEARS HAS WORKED FOR US.
EVERYTHING MOVE FAST,
AND ALREADY HAS BECOME THE ENEMY.
WHAT THE HELL IS WRONG WITH YOU?
YOU MEET HER FOR A WEEK,
ALREADY AND THROW EVERYTHING OUT THE WINDOW.
IT IS A NORMAL GIRL.
- AND I FEEL NORMAL WHEN I'M WITH HER.
- WAKE UP.
THIS WORLD ONLY EXISTS BECAUSE
THERE ARE PEOPLE LIKE US.
AND I'M SORRY THAT PEOPLE
SHALL GIVE THE OTHER SIDE.
SOMETIMES FRIENDS BECOME ENEMIES
REMOVE AND NEED.
SHE TRUSTS ME.
AND I WILL NOT COMPROMISE THAT.
THESE TASKS ARE NOT OPTIONAL,
SPENCER.
YOU CAN NOT TURN BACK.
LOOK AT ME.
ARE YOU WHO ARE, SPENCER.
YOU CAN NOT CHANGE THAT.
I THINK THE BEST PART IS THAT
YOU FIND SOMEONE WHO IS ATTRACTIVE.
I KNOW.
I STILL THINK THAT EVENTUALLY
I'LL USUAL ODD IT ...
IT IS THE EMBODIMENT OF PHYSICAL PERFEC?IUNII.
BUT STILL NOT ANYTHING HAPPENED YET.
- SERVES YOU?
- OH, NO.
I'M FINE.
IT'S A LITTLE EARLY.
EARLIER?
YOU THINK EVERYTHING IS FINE THERE?
DO NOT LISTEN WHEN YOUR WORRIES.
SO I HEARD THAT YOU DO NOT WORK ...
CONSULTANT COMPANY
IS A STRONG BUSINESS, SIR.
JANE AND I TALKED,
GONNA START MY OWN COMPANY.
LOOK AT MY SHOES.
THEY ARE EDWARD GREEN, NOW 20 YEARS
THEY STILL DID NOT KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT LIFE.
WHEN YOU HAVE SOMETHING ...
... GOOD QUALITY ...
... AND IF YOU TAKE CARE OF THAT THING ...
YOU'LL HAVE FOREVER.
I KNOW YOU'RE WORRIED ABOUT JEN.
WHY I WOULD?
I AM CONFIDENT ...
... THAT NO ONE WILL EVER HURT.
IT WAS A GOOD SHOT.
THANK YOU, I WAS A GOOD EXPLORER
YOUNG.
INDEED, WILL LET YOU PULL?
NO, SHOOT THEM SLIGHTLY MOVE AND MARINES.
"ALWAYS FAITHFUL.
THAT WAS YOURS.
- I'M SORRY .. I THOUGHT ...
- STAY ALERT ALWAYS.
WE WERE SCOUTS.
DO YOU KNOW? JEN IS NOT A
PUPPET OF THE PORCELAIN.
IT'S FUNNY ...
... AND IS SWEET AND SMART.
THAT CAN DISCUSS ALMOST ANYTHING ...
... IN A MINUTE I TALK ABOUT
IMPORTANCE OF STRATEGIES OF WAR ...
... AND THE FOLLOWING CAN YOU TELL ME
CARRIE GRANT TOOK THAT WEIGHT.
IT ...
WHAT I WANT TO EMPHASIZE ...
... IS THAT NO MATTER WHAT HE SAYS.
CAN I TRUST HER.
I'M COUNTING ON IT.
SIR, THERE IS NO MIDDLE WAY.
SO ...
... WITH YOUR BLESSING ..
I WANT TO MARRY HER.
WELCOME TO THE FAMILY, SPENCER.
THANK YOU, MR. CORNFIELD.
PLEASE TELL ME SIR.
THREE YEARS LATER.
HOW BIG IS IT?
OH, THAT'S GREAT.
MOST OF THE REGION.
I'VE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING LIKE THIS BEFORE?
OH, MAYBE IN A MAGAZINE.
OR IN YOUR DREAMS.
I KNOW HOW TO HANDLE THIS?
I HOPE SO.
- OH, GOD.
- YOU'RE GREEDY.
THIS PLACE MAKE ME ...
THAT HURT, BABY.
SORRY, SORRY, NO ...
THIS WAY.
STAY HERE.
LOOK.
OH, GOD.
SPENCER ...
I HAVE REMODELED THE OFFICE.
IT'S SO ORGANIZED.
WELCOME ...
... NOW YOU CAN KISS ME.
HOW ARE SO LUCKY?
HOW COME ACROSS SOMEONE LIKE YOU?
THAT'S EASY.
IT WAS YOUR CHARM.
AND YOUR SHOTS.
SERIOUSLY, SHOULD NOT I R?SFE?I
SO MUCH.
ESPECIALLY BECAUSE ...
IN THIS WEEKEND ... YOUR BIRTHDAY.
NO, WE TALKED ABOUT IT.
YOU SHOULD NOT DO IN THIS CASE.
WITHOUT GIFTS, WITHOUT PARTIES.
IT'S JUST A DINNER TOMORROW NIGHT
WITH MY PARENTS, I PROMISE.
BUT I NEVER AGREED
NOT BE A GIFT.
COME SECRECY
A WEEK.
WE REACHED THE LIMIT.
KILL ME.
FLIGHTS TO NICE.
I SAID THAT WE CAN RETURN THERE
WHERE IT ALL BEGAN.
YOU KNOW? THE BEST PART IS THAT
WE GO WHENEVER WE WANT.
BUT BECAUSE I'M WONDERFUL,
I OPEN AT THE END OF THIS MONTH.
WHAT?
WE DO NOT WANT TO GO TO YOU?
ABSOLUTELY.
I ... IS ...
LOOK ... THINGS ARE A BIT
COMPLICATED AT WORK NOW.
AND HAVE A LOT OF THINGS TO DO
HERE.
IN ADDITION,
PARADE IS AT THE END OF THE MONTH.
AND YOU AGREED TO ARE GATE.
HORRIBLE COOK.
YOU KNOW WHAT TO DO AS NICE
BE WONDERFUL?
YOU.
I GOT EVERYTHING I NEED ...
... RIGHT HERE.
OKAY?
SPENCER.
- HELLO.
HE'S MAX.
HELLO.
HEY, I'M GLAD TO SEE YOU.
- WE HAVE A PARTY.
- FIESTA.
ALL RIGHT.
YES?
AND YOU CAN DRESS AS THEY PLEASE.
PERFECT.
OKAY, ONE MORE.
IF THAT MAKES WINGS AND FLY.
WONDERFUL.
THIS IS LESS OF MY SALIVA.
I DO NOT CLONED.
WELL, WE ARE GOING TO MAKE LOVE
RIGHT NOW.
YOU HAVE FUN.
ALL RIGHT.
SEE YA.
PARTY!
THIS IS THE BEST CHOICE
FOR CUSTOMERS AND INDEX I.
WELL, FOLKS, YOU HEARD IT.
THERE WE PUT IN PLACE IMMEDIATELY ...
SO ... TO WORK!
JANE!
- SHORT AND TO THE POINT! AS ALWAYS.
- THANKS.
DO NOT SAY ANYTHING IN SAN FRANCISCO!
- YOU WANT ME TO GO TO CONFERENCE?
- YOU KNOW ...
- I WANT YOU TO DOMINATE HIM!
- OKAY.
YOU FLY TOMORROW.
MR NOOTBAR TOMORROW E. ..
IT'S SO ...
NOT THAT ANYONE ELSE TO SEND?
THE CONFERENCE IS IMPORTANT.
I'LL TAKE THE WEEKEND AFTER. WE'RE GONNA BE FINE.
OF COURSE THAT I COULD NOT REFUSE.
IT'S SO UNPROFESSIONAL TO GO
WITH THINGS INSTEAD OF STAYING WITH YOUR HUSBAND.
AND THEREFORE I HAVE NOT MENTIONED IT.
CAN YOU GET IT TONIGHT OR NOT?
HELLO?
DAD?
IF YOU NEED ...
I LOVE DULCEA??.
AND I LOVE YOU. BYE.
NO, IT IS VERY SHORT.
YOU CAN MOVE BACK?
AN INCH.
THERE ... NO.
- HI.
- RIGHT THERE.
PERFECT.
CAN YOU COME TOMORROW AGAIN?
SORRY, YOU MUST TALK TO THEM.
SATURDAY, WITHOUT DRINKS AND MAKING
ACCOUNTING. THE PERFECT TRIO.
- SO?
- WELCOME ...
WHAT DO YOU PLAY?
WELL ...
IT IS A PIECE THAT HAS A LOT TO SAY.
YES, BUT WE LIKE TO SAY WE
AGATHA GARBAGE CEILING?
YES.
YES, WHY?
YES, YOU HAVE TRANSFORMED THE CONFERENCE ROOM
A PLACE OF NIGHTMARE.
YES, I KNOW.
HEY, LISTEN, DO ME A FAVOR ...
TAKE A NUMBER OF SOIL SAMPLES
FOR OLIVIA, RIGHT?
AND SOMETHING THAT IS EASY TO CLEAN.
IF WE DECIDE TO DO
SEX ON THE FLOOR.
OF COURSE.
WORKING ON IT.
- MIRIFIC.
- I LIKE IT MORE WHEN IT IS BAD.
SHOULD YOUR LAWSUIT.
PROBABLY.
BE MAD AT ME, YOU KNOW?
WHEN FLIRTING WITH OTHER WOMEN
BUT THAT'S ALL I HAVE.
DO YOU REALIZE THAT
ONLY HAPPENS IN PORN?
YES.
THE BEST PORN MOVIES.
I THINK I'LL TRY.
ONCE FINISHED OLIVIA
THE DIRTY WORK.
THAT WILL TAKE SOME TIME.
OLIVIA IS MUCH MORE MALLEABLE
THAN YOU ARE.
HEY, PLAYING A BASKETBALL, OR WHAT?
CAN NOT HAVE A SUPPORT WITH JEN.
I THINK I JUST SAW YOUR
BOAS AND THEY ON THE FLOOR.
YOU WANT TO COLLECT THEM FOR ME?
I HAVE JUST CRUSHED.
DID I JUST BOAS AND CRUSHED THEM
RIGHT THERE.
SEE YA.
TELL ME THE BOAS AND SMASHING IT,
HENCEFORTH.
FRANCE.
COME TO SEE ME.
SO WHAT HAPPENED?
NOOTBAR SENT ME TO SAN FRANCISCO.
NO, NO, I DO NOT SPEAK
PRESENTATION--
ABOUT SPENCER'S GIFT.
WHAT DID ABOUT THE TRIP?
HE WANTS TO STAY HOME.
- DO NOT WANT TO GO ON HOLIDAY?
- DO NOT WANT AN ESCAPE TO FRANCE?
- NO.
- WHO WOULD REFUSE SUCH A HOLIDAY?
WELL, SPENCER, IT SEEMS.
OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
HOW LONG HAVE YOU MARRIED?
ALREADY ... 3 YEARS?
- YES.
- SURE.
THAT'S YOUR PROBLEM.
I HAVE A PROBLEM?
EVERYONE TALKS ABOUT THE CRISIS
FOR SEVEN YEARS, BUT NONE OF THE 3 YEARS.
PEOPLE BECOME DISSATISFIED.
STAY QUIET
BUT YOU MUST BE VIGILANT.
BECAUSE IF YOU LET IT GROW
A LITTLE HAIR HERE ...
AND DOWN THERE ...
YOU GET THE FAT IN YOUR JEANS.
OKAY?
THE NEXT STEP IS DIVORCE, AND HE
GO WITH ONE OF THE REALITY SHOW, SHONDA.
OKAY? AND THAT IN MY EXPERIENCE
SAY.
YOU BETTER TAKE CARE THAT
SHONDA SPEAKS SIX LANGUAGES.
AND ONE OF THESE LANGUAGES IS SEX.
YOU EAT THAT?
LOOKS GOOD. STARVE.
NIGHT BEACH MOTEL
YES ...
TRIED TO COMMUNICATE
WITH ONE OF YOUR GUESTS
IT'S CALLED ...
SIR?
YES ...
GUEST'S NAME IS ...
ANNABELLA HENSLER.
JUST A MOMENT.
LOOK  FINALLY.
MUST MEET.
THAT WILL NOT HAPPEN, ANNABELLA.
YES, I UNDERSTAND THAT YOU LIKE TO
A KIND OF ZOMBIE IN THE SUBURBS ...
BUT AS I SAID THREE YEARS AGO.
NOT LET GO WHEN YOU WANT.
AND LESS IN THIS GAME.
I HAVE A JOB FOR YOU.
I DO NOT DEAL WITH IT.
YOU HAVE TO FIND SOMEONE ELSE
CLEAN UP YOUR MESS.
POVERTY  MY
IF YOU DO NOT
WILL BE YOUR MISERY.
AM IN ROOM 114.
I'LL WAIT.
JUST DO WHAT YOU SAY.
SPENCER.
- SPENCER?
- HELLO!
SPENCER.
YOU JUST CLOSE TO SOMEONE?
NO.
JEN IS BUSY WITH WORK ...
... AND I SHOULD DO SOMETHING ...
... NICE.
FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY.
SO HERE I AM.
YOU HAVE TO EAT.
WELL, THAT'S GREAT.
- GREAT, BUT CAN EAT ANYTHING ...
- WANT TO EAT YOURSELF?
NO.
OF COURSE NOT.
I ...
COME EAT.
WHO'S H?
MY FORMER BOSS.
JUST ...
I WONDER IF I
MY OLD JOB BACK.
SENDING YOU HUGS.
AND KISSES.
YES.
IS A FRENCH CUSTOM.
YOU KNOW?
WITH KISSES.
I CAN TAKE YOU TO DINNER DRESSED UP.
SO ...
WE'LL STOP AT HOME.
TO CHOOSE SOMETHING NICE FOR YOU.
I WILL LEAVE MY CAR HERE.
MEET ME OUTSIDE.
WHAT HAPPENED?
YOU LOOK LIKE AN AGITATED MONKEY.
I'M JUST EXCITED
TO DINNER TOGETHER.
YOU AND YOUR WIFE HAVE PLANNED
TO GO CRUISING?
YES.
WHERE TO GO?
I KNOW THAT THOSE WHO ARE
CRUISE CAPTAINS, SPENCER.
WHAT IS WRONG WITH YOU, BOY?
JEN SHOULD NOT COME HOME AND BE
ALL DARK, NOT SURE.
YOU ABSOLUTELY RIGHT, SIR.
I LEFT MY KEYS IN THE CAR?
THERE ARE TELEPATHIC, SPENCER.
- MAYBE ..
- THAT'S NOT SWEET SHOP ...
... IF YOU LEAVE THE KEYS IN THE CAR
COULD BE STOLEN.
THEREFORE MEN CARING
USE THE GARAGE.
- THANK YOU, SIR.
- THE KEYS ARE IN CONTACT.
SURPRISE!
I'VE DONE IT.
ALL RIGHT.
CONGRATULATIONS.
- I TOLD YOU THAT YOU ARE SPENDING ...
- ... FOR MY BIRTHDAY.
SURE.
VERY NICE OF YOU.
NOT WHAT YOU EXPECTED, HUH?
NO.
ALL RIGHT.
I WANT TO GO UP
TO CHANGE.
ALL RIGHT.
- DO NOT DELAY, I WAS EXPECTING.
- SURE.
SURPRISE!
GOOD JOB.
GOOD EVENING, NIGHT BEACH MOTEL.
YES, I MAKE CONTACT
ANNABELLA HANSER, PLEASE?
ONE MOMENT, PLEASE.
NO RESPONSE, SIR,
WANT TO LEAVE A MESSAGE?
NO.
NO, NO MESSAGE.
YOU HAVE A LOT OF WORK NOW.
- DO NOT KNOW IF I CAN GO THIS YEAR.
- WE SHOULD SEE MORE OFTEN.
- YES.
- SURE.
GO UP THE REAR.
COME WITH YOU.
MOTHER.
OH, DEAR.
JUST TELLS JEN TO COME TOMORROW
US TO NOT SPEND YOUR DAY ALONE.
I'M BUSY WITH THE PARTY.
SORRY.
- YES.
- WE CAN GO WITH YOU.
- YES?
- PERFECT.
WONDERFUL.
- SUPER.
- HEY, COME HERE!
FRI.
GOTTA GO ...
I TELL YOU
THIS GIRL IS ELECTRIFYING.
ALL RIGHT.
I NEED TO FILL MY CUP.
THERE'S SOMETHING OUT THERE
YOU THINK I'D LIKE?
OR SOMETHING THAT YOU'D LIKE THEE,
IS YOUR PARTY, YOU HAVE EVERYTHING YOU WANT.
- A LITTLE WINE ...
- FUN?
GO HAVE AN OPENING.
GET A KISS WHEN YOU RETURN.
I JUST HOPE
WAS A PLEASANT SURPRISE.
HE SEEMS A LITTLE DISTRACTED.
HAS A FULL HOUSE
WITH PEOPLE, LEAVE IT A BIT.
MAYBE KIRSTIE WAS RIGHT
WITH STAGE THREE YEARS.
YOU TELL ME, RIGHT?
YOU DO NOT SOFTEN, NO?
THINGS LIKE THAT ...
.. IT IS BETTER TO KNOW.
NOT HAIRY, BUT WE NEEDED
HELP TO FIT IN JEANS ...
WHY PREFER TO STAY HOME
INSTEAD OF GOING ON HOLIDAY?
GOD ...
A CRAZY.
WHAT HAPPENS TO YOU?
YOU SCARED TODAY AT NOON.
YOU STILL HAVE SEX WITH SPENCER
YES OR NO?
YEA, ALWAYS.
THEN THE MARRIAGE GOES WRONG.
GIRLS CAN GET OUT OF HERE, PLEASE?
COME ON.
SO, THIS IS DONE.
ARE YOU SURE YOU ALRIGHT?
- YES, WELL.
- BYE.
SEE YA.
WATCH WHERE YOU'RE GOING ...
WALK HOME.
MAYBE HE SHOULD NOT
LEAD.
NO, WRONG.
NO, NO, NO, SIT DOWN, WE'VE GOT.
NO, DEAR.
- NO.
- I HAVE HIDDEN, YOU REST.
IT ... IS YOUR BIRTHDAY.
WE'VE GOT.
- ARE YOU SURE?
- YES.
WELL, JUST ...
ONLY THIS,
I GATHER THE REST OF THE MORNING.
I LOVE YOU.
WHERE ARE YOUR PANTS?
IS SOMETHING WRONG?
NO, COURSE NOT.
ARE YOU SURE?
I MEAN ...
... ALL IS WELL BETWEEN US?
KIDDING, RIGHT?
COME HERE.
COME ...
ALL IS WELL.
MAYBE I CAN GET RID OF PACKAGING
FOOD, EVEN THIS TIME.
YOUR FLIGHT IS THE MORNING
SHOULD GO TO BED.
- I FEEL TERRIBLE TO LEAVE YOUR BIRTHDAY.
- DO NOT WORRY.
THERE'S ONE NEXT YEAR.
NO, WAIT.
I GAVE NO KISS FOR YOUR BIRTHDAY.
ALL RIGHT.
WE DO NOT WANT ... TO SEE OUR NEIGHBORS.
THEN SAY
WE SHOW PORN ENTRY.
AND THEN GIVES US NOTES.
COME ON.
- NOW I GOTTA GO.
- OKAY.
HERE ARE YOUR THINGS.
COME ON.
HEY, JEN!
JEN!
HEY ...
JEN.
HI, JACKIE.
ARE YOU UP EARLY
DAYS AFTER THE PARTY.
YES, THEY ARE THE WAY TO THE AIRPORT.
IT IS GOOD WE ARE OF THOSE PEOPLE
SLEEPING WELL, REGARDLESS OF THE NOISE.
OTHER PEOPLE MAY HAVE
PROBLEMS AFTER ALL THAT NOISE.
ANYWAY.
DOUGIE WANTS TO TALK
SPENCER ABOUT THAT HOLE ...
... WHAT IS THE PROPERTY ...
AND OTHER THINGS ... YOU DO NOT UNDERSTAND.
WE DO NOT WANT TO BRING LAWYERS
TO HANDLE THEM.
NO? BUT WE
THAT IS ON OUR PROPERTY.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
OH YES, PERFECTLY.
OF COURSE, BUT YOU UNDERSTAND ...
... THAT MUST
DISCUSSED THIS WITH SPENCER?
OKAY, THANK YOU, JACKIE.
- SORRY.
- BYE-BYE, GOOD.
ARE IN A HURRY, SEE YOU SOON.
SEE YOU LATER.
HEY.
YOU HAVE FUN LAST NIGHT?
OH, YEAH.
YES, IT WAS GREAT.
OF COURSE, PAY
FOR HER THIS MORNING.
HOWEVER, GOING TO TAKE IT ON SPENCER
TONIGHT, RIGHT?
YES.
ALL RIGHT.
DADDY HAS PROMISED TO BEHAVE WELL WITH IT?
NOT SO MANY WORDS.
YOU MAKE SURE YOU GET ON THE PLANE
AND LET US
SPENCER TO TAKE CARE OF, RIGHT?
WELL, CALL WHEN YOU ARRIVE IN SAN FRANCISCO.
I LOVE YOU.
LOVE YOU TOO.
- HELLO.
- WHAT IS IT?
ME.
ARE YOU?
YOU.
GOT MILK?
YES.
EVERYTHING OKAY?
I SKIMMED MILK AND
MINIMUM FAT YOGURT.
WANT OF BOTH?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
YOU MUST HAVE SEEN BEFORE.
ALMOST LIKE YOU DID IN YOUR PANTS.
YES, IT IS MORE THAN FUNNY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
KILL YOU, PARTNER.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING, SPENCER?
WANT TO GO UPSTAIRS?
SURPRISE!
I CAME BACK.
SPENCER?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WE NEED TO LOOK FOR SOMETHING.
UP IN THE BEDSIDE ...
- BRING ME THE BLACK 45TH.
- WHAT?
A WEAPON! GO!
- WHY HAVE A GUN?
- GO!
- YOU FOUND IT!
- WINE, WINE!
NOW, TAKE GUN AND SHOOT HIM IN THE FACE.
WHAT?
NO, IT'S CRAZY.
- PULL, PLEASE.
- OKAY.
SHIT!
ARE YOU CRAZY?
YOU TOLD ME TO SHOOT HIM IN THE FACE.
I THOUGHT THAT ONE COULD DO,
I HAD JUST DISTRACTING.
WHERE SHOULD I HAVE DONE
A SIGN OR SOMETHING!
I WAS BUSY
DO NOT KILL ME.
I SHOT!
HONEY, YOU NEED TO GO INTO THE CELLAR
AND BRING ME TAPE.
GO GET MY BELT.
- I CAN NOT MOVE.
- OKAY.
EVERYTHING WILL BE FINE, I GUESS.
SPENCE, WHAT HAPPENS?
WE ARE ABOUT TO LEARN.
MAKE IT WORSE.
SORRY TO BLEED YOUR SEAT.
- TOO BAD, HUH?
- YES.
A CONTRACT.
A CONTRACT FOR WHAT?
FOR A BUSINESS?
SOMEONE HIRED TO KILL ME.
GOD!
I THOUGHT WE WERE FRIENDS.
REALLY?
I HAVE NOT SEEN ANY INVESTMENT.
I COVERED EACH CUSTOMER
THAT I HAD.
I ALWAYS LET GIRLS
I WENT AND CLINIC
WHEN YOUR BALLS WERE INFLATED
AND WHEN YOU HAD THAT MUSHROOM.
I HELPED TO BURY YOUR DOG.
HEY, IT WAS A GOOD DOG, RIGHT?
DO NOT INTERFERE IN IT.
YES? AT THE END OF THE DAY
WILL BE AS DEAD AS HE.
THERE IS A REWARD OF 20 MILLION
ON YOUR HEAD.
GOD.
YOU OKAY, HONEY?
NOT SURE WHAT TO THINK.
BREATHE. ALL RIGHT.
HOW CAN SO WELL?
I WILL EXPLAIN ...
NO, YOU EXPLAIN TO ME NOW!
I WANT TO TELL ME RIGHT NOW!
JEN! BEN!
HI!
YEAH, MAKES NO NOISE.
CAN GO.
CAN BE ANY OF YOUR NEIGHBORS.
WHAT?
I DO NOT THINK ANY COMPETITION?
20 MILLION MAY BE
DIVIDED INTO SEVERAL PARTS.
YOU CAN SEE THE CAR.
IT'S JUST JACKIE VALLERO, SPENCER.
HE JUST WANTS TO TALK ABOUT
PROPERTY OR SOMETHING.
OR KILL YOU.
HELLO! OPEN THE DOOR.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- COME ON.
WHAT WILL YOU DO WITH IT?
IF YOU DO NOT KILL WILL COME AFTER US.
- IT'S OUR FRIEND.
- IS A LIAR.
WHAT, JEN?
- AND THE GUN?
- I THREW IT.
JEN, IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
HELLO.
SLOW DOWN!
STOP THE CAR RIGHT NOW!
- CALM DOWN!
- I HAVE THE RIGHT TO BREATHE ...
I DO NOT KNOW WHO THE HELL YOU ARE!
I AM, I JUST
DIFFERENT CURRICULUM.
WHO DO YOU WORK?
FOR THE MAFIA?
IF SAY, YOU COULD BE KILLED.
LET'S SAY I WORK FOR BLAH BLAH BLAH
AND GAVE ME A LICENSE TO BLAH.
I NEED AIR, NOW!
HONEY, YOU NEED TO CALM DOWN.
WE GOT MARRIED?
YES, WE'RE MARRIED.
- LOVE MATCH?
- I GAVE IN FRANCE.
I CONQUERED
WHILE YOU WERE AT WORK?
HERE IS YOUR END,
SPENCE.
SPREAD YOUR LEGS.
YOU WILL NOT GET SO EASILY.
GOD.
HERE, TAKE THIS.
BRACE YOURSELF.
IT'S ON MY SIDE! IT'S ON MY SIDE!
- DAMN.
- I LOST.
- ARE YOU OKAY?
- YES.
EVERYTHING WILL BE FINE.
- HIDE!
- WHAT?
HIDE.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
I WILL KILL HIM.
GET IN THE CAR.
- IT'S ...
- YES.
START TALKING.
I WAS RECRUITED FIRST
YEAR OF COLLEGE.
WHY DID YOU CHOSE?
PEOPLE SEEKING INDEPENDENT
MY PARENTS DIED,
I HAD NO FAMILY.
WE MUST MAKE A MOVE.
YOU CLIMB INTO THE CAR, TO ARGUE.
ARE YOU GOING TO KILL ME?
IF I WANTED TO DO THIS
ONE AT HOME.
SOUNDS WEIRD ...
LOGICALLY, YOU KNOW THAT'S TRUE.
YEAH, RIGHT.
- SPREAD YOUR LEGS.
- HOW MANY THINGS DO YOU HAVE ON HERE?
HOW MANY PEOPLE, SPENCER?
4 ... AND 9, 50.
IT'S ALL RIGHT,
OR IS THAT WHEN YOU GUYS
WRITE THE BOOK WITH MANY WOMEN
YOU HAD SEX AND MULTIPLY BY 10?
I HAVE NOT DONE SO.
50 IS MY NUMBER.
THEY WERE BAD GUYS,
FAR AS I KNOW.
IT WAS HARD TO TELL
THEN I MET YOU,
I LOVE AND I GAVE UP.
YESTERDAY I WAS CONTACTED BY A GUY.
GO TO A HOTEL.
YOU DISCOVER WHAT HAPPENED.
HONEY, YOU CAN SEE THE GUN.
WHERE DO THEY KEEP HER?
YOU SEE WHAT SIZE IS THIS?
S FATHER, TO RESPOND?
I THOUGHT YOU CHANGED IT.
RELAX, DEAR.
IT'S PRETTY EARLY TO CHECK IT
BY SPENCER, DO NOT YOU THINK?
AND JEN IS JUST PLACES A HOTEL.
YES, YOU'RE RIGHT.
SPENCER, I FOUND THIS.
EASY, IS MY FORMER BOSS.
ONE HEART AND ONE HEAD.
THE ASSASSIN WAS TRAINED
MUST LOOK ONLY TO MUSCLE.
IN SUCH STATES,
DEAD JUST A FEW HOURS.
COME SEE WHAT'S THERE.
HOW DO YOU KNOW IF YOU KNOW HIM?
ARE TRAINED, BABY.
SORRY.
I CAN SIT HERE
SPENCER. I DO NOT FEEL WELL.
YET ONE SECOND, SWEETIE.
I NEED TO KNOW INFORMATION ABOUT THE TARGET.
- CAN NOT LOOK RIGHT PLACE.
- WHAT HAVE I MISSED?
CLOCK! IS WRONG.
MUST HAVE LEFT A TRACE,
WITHOUT NOTICE.
- LOOK AT THIS.
- IT'S BROKEN. WITH HIS CARES?
- MISSING A PART OF IT.
- RIGHT.
OKAY, LET'S GO.
- DO YOU THINK HENRY DID?
- THE CONTRACT WAS MADE THIS MORNING.
IT WAS ANOTHER KILLER IN THE HOUSE.
I THINK WE SHOULD GET OUT OF HERE.
- ABSOLUTELY.
- GO HOME TO MY PARENTS.
YES.
DAD KNOWS WHAT TO DO.
THAT'S WHAT I DO.
I DO NOT WANT TO INVOLVE YOUR PARENTS.
I NEED THE HELP OF YOUR FATHER.
I THINK YES.
BECAUSE YOUR PLANS
FAILS.
I CAN NOT BELIEVE THAT YOU'RE GOING
TO INVOLVE YOUR PARENTS IN IT.
ARE YOU A SPY AND DOUBLE AGENT
AND I'M BAD NOW, BECAUSE
I INVOLVE PARENTS, REALLY?
WE WERE MARRIED FOR THREE YEARS, AND NEVER
I HAVE BEEN SEPARATED FROM YOUR PARENTS.
ARE ALWAYS AT HOME
AND YOUR FATHER ALWAYS TELLS US
WHY AND HOW TO DO IT.
MUST BUY
THE DISHWASHER,
OR GRASS CUTTING IT THAT WAY.
STOP, TALK
ABOUT MY PARENTS.
I'M YOUR HUSBAND.
WHAT WE DO
WHEN TO HAVE CHILDREN?
TALK TO ME.
WITHDRAW WHAT I SAID,
I LIKE YOUR PARENTS.
ARE EMOTIONALLY UNSTABLE,
RIGHT NOW.
- HEY, SPENCER, ARE YOU OKAY?
- YES.
YOUR GARAGE IS A MESS.
YES, WE HAD A PARTY AND ...
WE HAVE A PARTY TONIGHT
AND INDICATED THAT ...
DO NOT FORGET, PETE.
YOU CAN NOT RUN SO
BE IMPOSSIBLE TO DO
TO PROTECT YOU.
IT'S A BIT LATE FOR PROTECTION.
MY EMOTIONS COME TO LIGHT
THROUGH EVERY PORE,
I FEEL ALL SORTS OF SMELLS,
AND I FEEL LIKE VOMIT
EVERY BREATH.
- IT WAS A STRESSFUL DAY.
- MY KNEES ...
THEY ARE ALWAYS SO?
TAKE THE PILL EVERY DAY.
I KNOW, BUT I MADE A BREAK
LAST WEEK, REMEMBER?
SINCE I TOLD YOU THAT MAKE A BREAK
WITH THE REST OF THE PILLS
WAS CLEAR THAT IT OUGHT
TO BE CAREFUL.
I THOUGHT WE WERE TALKING ABOUT MY TECHNIQUE
AND TO NOT LEAVE YOU PREGNANT.
DO NOT YELL AT ME.
IT WAS YOU WHO SUGGESTED
S DO SATURDAY.
CAN WE HELP YOU?
- STOP.
- WHAT?
STARE AT US!
WE ARE NOT IN LIBRARY
TAKE ONE AND DONE.
NOT ALL ARE CORRECT.
IT'S CRAZY TO SIT HERE
TAKE ONE OR ALL, WHO CARES?
I CARE, SPENCE,
WOULD BE GREAT TO KNOW ...
IT'S A BABY IN ME.
DO NOT MAKE ME MAD.
YOU ARE NOT CRAZY
SCENARIO THIS IS CRAZY.
- TO SIT HERE ...
- DO NOT HELP ME AT ALL.
CAN I HELP YOU?
YES, YES, YOU ...
WHICH OF THESE TESTS IS MOST ACCURATE?
I DO NOT THINK THAT IS AN EXPERT
THE PREGNANCY TEST.
WELL, "FIRST RESPONSE"
IS VERY POPULAR.
YOU CAN TRY IT.
- WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- A PREGNANCY TEST?
- CHILD.
- YES.
THAT MAY BE YOUR LUCKY DAY.
STOP.
REMEMBER, IT'S FOR SALE.
WONDERFUL. IT IS ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
WITHOUT TRIAL.
MUST FOLLOW A PROTOCOL
FOR THIS.
WE GO TO A SAFE PLACE.
I FIND
WHICH WAS THE TARGET.
TO FIND OUT WHO CAUSED ALL THIS.
ONCE ABLE TO URINATE,
COUNT ON ME.
ONE MORE THING.
AND DO NOT MIND,
BUT TO STEAL A CAR.
NO BOTHER.
THERE'S SOMETHING WE DO DAILY.
GO AHEAD.
I CAN NOT BELIEVE THAT IS SO HUNGRY.
YOU HAVE ALREADY SAID.
REALLY?
TO EAT SO MUCH
AND IT SEEMS A GOOD IDEA?
YOU'RE JUST A LITTLE SCARED.
YOUR NAME CONTACT.
HERE SEUDO149 AND 0010 WERE
WAS CALLED FOR A CONTRACT.
PLEASE TELL US
SAFE MEETING PLACE.
WAIT FOR INSTRUCTIONS.
"SEUDO149?"
THAT'S MY CODE NAME.
NOT SO APPEALING.
SORRY, KORN WAS ALREADY TAKEN.
SEUDO149 CONFIRM CONTACT
AND STATE WHERE YOU ARE.
0010 AND THE STATE IS ZERO
AND I THINK THEIR GOAL
I BECAME.
NEGATIVE.
0010 HAS NO TARGET.
THERE IS AN ACTIVE AGENT.
PLEASE GO TO LOCATION
AND WAIT.
WHAT HAPPENED?
SOMETHING IS WRONG.
WHERE ARE WE GOING?
LET'S SEE WHAT ELSE I COULD FIND
AND YOU CAN PEE.
WE MANAGED, ARE INSIDE.
ALL RIGHT.
HORN, HORN.
THAT WAS THE FIRST LEFT-PARTY
THAT WE WERE MET HIM.
WHO DID THIS HAD SUFFICIENT PATIENCE
AS TO DOCUMENT MY LIFE.
- OUR LIFE.
I'M PRETTY SURE
YOUR FATHER HAS TO DO WITH IT.
- WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
- HMM. JUST AN OBSERVATION.
YES, A REMARK ABOUT
MY FATHER AND THAT PHOTO.
SINCE IT IS A PICTURE THAT HE TAKE.
SO, NOW MY FATHER IS A BAD GUY.
- ABSOLUTELY ...
- NO, YOU'RE RIGHT.
YOU ARE A LIAR
AND OTHERS.
WELL, MY MOTHER HAS A CORNFIELD
AND I THINK FOOLISHLY
EVERYONE WITH A WHEELCHAIR.
I THINK WE'RE IN A TERRITORY
COUNTERPRODUCTIVE
AND I THINK SOMETHING SHOULD HAPPEN,
MAYBE WE CAN SEE THE RESULT
TEST NOW.
VERY GOOD
THEY HAVE TO PEE.
GET MY GUN.
SIMPLY CAN NOT LEAVE ...
- PEOPLE TRYING TO KILL US.
- YOU MUST GO TO THE BATHROOM.
WAIT.
JUST OPEN THE DOOR,
'RE PARANOID.
JUST A MOMENT.
I CAN NOT PEE IF YOU STAY THERE.
YOU DID A THOUSAND TIMES.
BUT NOW THERE ARE MORE
PRESSURE, DO NOT YOU THINK?
BETTER?
HONEY, PLEASE, LEAVE A MINUTE.
IT WILL NOT LAST LONG, CLOSING THE DOOR.
- HI.
- ARE YOU HERE.
- AND YOU.
THERE WAS A PROBLEM
WINKHIGH ACCOUNT.
CUSTOMERS WERE CALLED TWICE
MAY WANT TO TAKE A LOOK A LOOK.
FORGET ACCOUNT.
I GOT THIS MONTH.
- ARE YOU SURE?
- YES.
- OKAY.
- WONDERFUL
STOP!
HONEY, I DO NOT KNOW WHAT HAPPENED, DO NOT SHOOT.
GOD.
ARE YOU OKAY?
HAD NO AMMUNITION.
I DID IT FOR THE GOOD OF THE CHILD.
THAT'S IMPORTANT RIGHT NOW.
LET'S SEE, WHAT SAY?
WHAT DOES THIS MEAN?
I HAVE TO TRANSLATE IT.
I'LL BE DAD?
A MOTHER TO SON.
NOT SURE IF YOU GONNA BE A FATHER.
I KNOW YOU MAD,
AND YOU HAVE EVERY RIGHT TO BE,
BUT CAN NOT CHANGE WHAT I WAS.
WHERE WE CHOSE NOT TO BE IN NOVEMBER?
- WE'LL SOLVE.
- HOW?
- I WILL KEEP SAFE.
TELL ME AND I WILL REMAIN.
S OVER, SPENCE.
I KNOW YOU DO NOT WANT TO END.
I DROPPED WHAT I WANT
WHEN I SAW THE TEST RESULT.
WHERE YOU GOING?
OLIVIA.
LET'S SEE WHO'S CALLING, HENRY.
MUST BE A JOKE.
WE HAVE A DELIVERY FOR YOU, SPENCER.
RELAX, BUDDY.
COME ON, GIVE ME A HELPING HAND.
APPEARS TO BE FROM A FACTORY IN TULSA.
YOU EXPECT?
YES.
PUT YOUR SIGNATURE IN THE UPPER RIGHT.
HELP?
- I THINK I'VE FINISHED.
- YES.
THANK GOD YOU'RE OKAY.
LOOK AT THE WINDSHIELD.
YOU REALLY UPSET.
SOMEONE WHO IS NOT
TRYING TO KILL ME?
THANK YOU.
LET'S GO STEAL A CAR.
NOW WHAT?
I DO NOT KNOW.
I THINK OF SOMETHING.
WHAT WE DO NOW, SPENCER?
NOW GO HOME
HAVE MONEY, WEAPONS,
PASSPORT. ALL PREPARED.
WHY SHOULD WE RETURN, SPENCER?
YOU KNEW THIS WOULD HAPPEN?
- THERE WAS A POSSIBILITY.
- YOU ARE A LIAR.
YOU LIAR!
I TOLD YOU EVERYTHING?
NO, I SAID EVERYTHING.
BUT WE'RE MARRIED
THOSE THAT ARE MARRIED.
THEY TELL LIES, TELLING PEOPLE
THINGS THAT ARE NOT TRUE
TO PROTECT EACH OTHER
WHEN ASKING QUESTIONS LIKE
"IF THEIR MOTHERS ARMS.
NOT YOUR MOTHER'S ARMS.
YOU LIED FROM DAY ONE
WHEN WE MET!
I DID NOT.
EXCEPT WHEN YOUR FATHER
RUSSIAN WAS PERVERSE.
WELL, AFTER I TOLD THE TRUTH.
YOU'VE NEVER TOLD!
AND I CONFESSED.
I KNEW THAT SLEEP.
I DID NOT KNOW THAT YOU SLEEP LIKE A DEAD MAN.
YOU HEARD WHAT I SAID.
BASED ON WHAT?
BASED ON WHAT HAPPENED AFTER.
PERFECT.
YOU COULD NOT HIDE IN THE BASEMENT
THAT SUSAN'S HUSBAND?
WHO?
THERE HAD TO BE A SPY.
I CAN NOT BELIEVE
THAT I MARRIED A SPY.
- WHO AM I, PUSSY ODOR?
- NO, I KNOW OF.
EXCUSE ME?
ARE YOU GOING TO COMPLAIN
OUR SEX LIFE NOW?
THAT'S WHAT YOU DO?
STOP THE CAR!
LET'S HAVE SEX NOW!
GO HOME TO MY PARENTS.
- DO NOT GO HOME TO YOUR PARENTS.
- YES, GO.
I SAID YES!
WE CAN NOT GO TO YOUR PARENTS.
YOU HAVE TO TRUST ME.
I LOVE U
AND I WILL PROTECT U.
I DID A GOOD JOB
I FOUND THE CAR
NOW GO TO OUR HOME.
ALL RIGHT.
ANYWAY, I COULD NOT GO
MACHINE FAILS.
DO NOT YOU SEE THAT LIGHT
MOMENTS OF THE FUEL?
YES, I APOLOGIZE.
CHECKING CONTAINER
WAS MY NUMBER ONE PRIORITY.
RUN!
SORRY.
STOP SHOOTING!
- I MISSED!
- REALLY?
TAKE CARE, MY HONEY!
- COME ON.
- WHAT MISERY!
DAMN.
I FORGOT THE PARTY.
STAY CLOSE. KEEP GOING.
HELLO, YOU ARRIVED?
WHERE TO GO?
WE HAVE HOT DOGS.
WE HAVE BABY CLOTHES TOO.
HE HAD NO WAY OF KNOWING THAT.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED HOW PEOPLE
THINGS ARE.
IF YOU WANT, USE THE TOILET IN THE HOUSE.
- HOW ARE THINGS?
- IN THE OFFICE.
STAY AWAY FROM WINDOWS.
SAFE IS THE FLOOR
CODE IS EVEN GIVEN OUR ANNIVERSARY.
- WHERE YOU GOING?
- TO TAKE ARMS.
WEAPONS, MORE WEAPONS?
WONDERFUL.
TED WALDFRIEDZEN?
OH, SWEDISH.
SPENCE, YOU ARE?
SPENCER YOU?
GOD, MOM.
NOW IS A TIME NOT TOO GOOD.
DO YOU?
KRISTIN?
NOT REALLY MAKES NO SENSE.
PUT THE GUN DOWN
IS THE LAST COFFEE DRINKING MOTHER.
I TOLD YOU, THERE'S A PRETTY GIRL.
- DO YOU?
- VERY CRUEL.
- DAMN! WHO IS THERE?
- DO NOT KNOW.
IF YOU SHOOT SOMEONE
MR. PERFECT BEFORE ME ...
... KILL YOU BOTH, IN PRINCIPLE.
DROP IT NOW!
MY LEG.
LET HER MOTHER LEAVE.
I GOT EVERYTHING YOU NEED.
I SPENT THE LAST THREE YEARS
LISTENING TO YOU ...
AS THE STORY OF YOUR LIFE PERFECT
TO QUIT RIGHT NOW.
MOVE THE LIVING ROOM, BOTH
LET.
LET'S GO!
COME BACK!
JEN, TO BE HONEST,
- I SPENT BEAUTIFUL MOMENTS TOGETHER.
- YES.
THERE YOU ARE, DEAR.
ANSWER YOUR PHONE, SIR.
MY BEST FRIEND IS DEAD
AND YOU CAN SAY THAT TARGET IS ALIVE.
PUT THE GUN DOWN, SPENCER.
HEY, GUYS ...
HE KILLED MY BOSS.
A BLOW TO THE HEAD, REMEMBER?
AND THEN TRIED TO KILL ME.
DADDY, IS THIS TRUE?
I MIXED IN YOUR LIFE
BECAUSE I TRUSTED
IN YOUR HUSBAND.
I HOPED TO USE IT AGAIN.
IT'S NO PIECE OF THE CLOCK.
EVERYTHING IS THERE.
ALL THE DIRTY WORK,
AND IN THE OFFICE WHEN I SAW
POSTCARD WITH NAME WRITTEN ON IT,
I KNEW YOU BACK IN GAME
AND THAT WILL COME AFTER ME.
SO I ENABLED CRIMINALS.
DO NOT TRY TO KILL YOU, SIR.
WHY NOT TELL ABOUT NICE
WHEN YOU TRIED TO GET MY BRAINS?
HOW DO YOU KNOW ABOUT NICE?
SUPPOSED TO BE IN THAT HELICOPTER.
BUT I SAW THAT YOU DROPPED.
YOU SAID YOU WAIVED
WHEN WE MET IN FRANCE.
YOU SAID YOU WERE IN LOVE.
I GAVE UP.
LOOK AT HIM
LOOKS AS IF ABANDONED?
IT WAS MY LAST JOB,
I'M OUT.
I GET OUT ... FOR US!
AND NEVER GONNA COME BACK.
SO YOU'RE NOT A PILOT?
PRETTY FATHER PUT THE GUN DOWN,
I SNIFF BULLETS ALL DAY
AND NOT GOOD FOR CHILDREN.
- HAVE A CHILD?
- NO, I WILL.
TO CELEBRATE.
- I BECOME A GRANDFATHER?
- YES.
GOD.
AND YOU FATHER?
FOR GOD'S SAKE, DAD.
OKAY.
IT'S AN EXTRAORDINARY MOMENT FOR
A "CIRCLE OF TRUST."
- A CIRCLE OF TRUST?
- YES.
COME ALL HERE.
MOM, COME JOIN US.
I DO NOT DO SUCH THINGS.
I KNOW, MOM, BUT I
THAT THIS IS NECESSARY.
FINALLY, I UNDERSTAND THAT SHOULD NOT
I BLAME
FOR MISTAKES MADE, RIGHT?
YOU, YES, AND YOU MUST UNDERSTAND,
AND I NEED TO BE AWARE
THAT I MARRIED A MAN ...
WHICH IS EXACTLY LIKE MY FATHER ...
A LIAR.
IF ANY OF YOU
WANTS TO SEE THIS CHILD ...
THAT IS WHAT THEY DO.
THERE WILL BE LIES.
WILL NOT BE STEALING CARS,
OR WEAPONS HIDDEN IN FURNITURE.
I WILL NOT TRY ANYMORE BECAUSE
YOU KILL EACH OTHER.
IN FACT, THERE WILL BE ASSASSINATIONS.
I SEE THAT I DO NOT WANT TO KILL
EVEN A BITE, RIGHT?
WE ARE TOGETHER?
- YES.
- YES?
GOOD JOB, DEAR.
ELSE SHOULD KNOW?
ANYONE?
ENGLISH IS NOT MY NATIVE LANGUAGE.
AND ALSO ...
THE THIRD WEEK
WHEN WE WERE TOGETHER
YOU SAID:
"I LOVE YOU" DURING SLEEP.
AND I SAID NO, BECAUSE
WANTED ME TO BE THE FIRST TO SAY IT.
THANKS, HONEY.
MOM?
REMEMBER WHEN YOU WERE SMALL
AND I WENT FOR A WALK?
- NO.
- NO? FORGET IT.
IN ADDITION TO TRACK KILLERS AND WORK
A GOVERNMENT AGENCY ...
I'D LIKE TO ADMIT ...
WE NEED TO TALK ABOUT THAT HOLE
ON OUR PROPERTY.
HI, JEN.
HONEY?
I DO NOT THINK IT IS A KILLER.
I KNOW.
RED WIRE IN BLUE,
AND IS LIKE NEW.
GREEN ON RED
IS DEATH, IS WHAT I SAY.
NOT SO, I SAID.
YOU COPY ME, JUST.
DO NOT COPY ANYTHING.
I HAVE NOT COPIED ANYTHING IN MY LIFE.
- REALLY?
- IT IS NOT ENOUGH, EH?
SAY YES. EH, BUDDY?
ENJOYING DADDY'S MUSTACHE?
- DO NOT YOU LIKE?
- HOW'S MY BIG BOY?
GREAT, YOUR FATHER THINKS THAT COPY.
WHICH DO NOT.
PLEASE TELL HIM THAT IT EMULATE.
SORRY, DEAR,
ALL GIRLS LOVE THEIR FATHER.
THIS IS DISGUSTING.
WE HOPE THAT ALL PARENTS
ARE BEAUTIFUL.
THAT'S SOMETHING PSYCHOLOGICAL.
THINK AND YOU'LL SEE THAT IT IS.
ARE YOU HERE TO TAKE CARE OF HIM
PARENT, AND IT TRAUMATIZED.
I DO NOT WANT TO SCARE HIM.
- I FEEL IT IS TOO SOON, ISN'T IT?
- IT'S NOT TOO SOON AND
WE HAVE TIME UNTIL DAWN
WILL BE GONE.
IT WILL BE GREAT. I HAVE PANTS IN NOVEMBER.
WELL, SPENCER CAN
TO TRUST US.
- IN ALL YOU HAVE TO TRUST SOMEONE, OK?
- RIGHT. HMM.
- BYE.
- HMM.