Let The Right One In
(Wind Whistles)
[Boy]
Squeal like a pig.
Squeal!
(Girl Humming Softly)
(Brakes Screech)
Squeal!
Squeal like a pig!
(Distant Male Voice Talking)
(Faint Thump)
(Faint Spattering)
(Footsteps Crunching)
[Man] The police have
ways to determine foul play...
Remember the house that burned
down in Ängby?
A house that burned to the ground.
They found someone in there.
Dead, of course.
In that case we knew it was arson
Because the person had been murdered.
So, how could they know that?
Yes?
There was no smoke
in the lungs of the person who died.
That's correct.
Did you figure that out? right now?
No, I read a lot...
What kind of books, I wonder?
(Mutters)
Newspapers and things like that.
Okay... I'm going to talk to
you about drugs.
What do you think are
the most common types of drugs...
(Door Squeaks, Slams)
(Boy Yelling)
Hey, Oskar...
What are you staring at? Huh?
You staring at me?
You better stop.
What a good piggy you are.
(Boys Snorting, Yelling)
(Panting)
(Man Speaking On Radio)
[Man On Radio] On the coast, just a few
degrees below zero.
Eastern Svealand... clear tonight...
Intermittent snow flurries...
Temperatures ranging from 20-32 degrees...
(Radio Continues)
(Hissing)
Excuse me...?
Do you have the time?
I don't have a watch.
What's that?
This? It's called halotane.
(Mumbling, Hissing)
(Groans)
(Hissing Stops)
(Faint Creaking)
(Creaking)
(Grunts)
(Rope Creaking)
(Coughs)
(Blade Rings, Gurgling)
(Rattling)
(Distant Barking)
(Panting)
[Woman] Ricky!
(Whines)
Ricky!
(Barks)
Beat it!
[Woman]
Ricky?
(Grunts)
(Ricky Whines)
Ricky?
(Ricky Whimpers)
[Woman] Darned dog!
[Woman]
Ricky!
(Panting, Lapping)
What are you staring at?
Well?
Are you looking at me?
Well, fuck off!
What's your problem?
Are you scared?
Squeal then!
Squeal!
What are you doing?
Nothing.
- What are you doing?
- [Girl] Nothing.
- Do you live here?
- [Girl] Yeah...
I live right here, in the jungle gym.
Seriously, where do you live?
Next door to you.
How do you know where I live?
Just so you know, I can't be your friend.
Just so you know.
- What do you mean?
- Does there have to be a reason?
That's just how it is.
Do you think I want to be friends with you?
(Train Rumbles)
(Wheels Screeching)
[Girl] You're supposed to help me!
Do I really have to take
care of this myself?
(Yells)
Say something!
Forgive me.
[Teacher] So no one knows why this boy
was murdered.
I realize that many of you may be worried.
The counselor will be here all day,
So go talk to her if you feel the need
Does anyone have any questions?
Is it all right to kill the killer
if you happen to meet him?
(Pupils Laugh)
That wasn't very nice, Conny.
[Boys] Oskar!
(Faint Trickling)
[Boys] Oskar...
Oskar!
(Voices Yelling, Whispering)
(Zipper Buzzes)
(Latch Clicks, Door Groans)
[Mother] You will go straight home
after school!
And you're not to leave the yard until
I come home.
But it was in Vãllingby.
So you think someone who murders
children
Can't take the subway?
Or walk a kilometer?
(Man Speaking On Radio)
(Mother Muttering)
Yes, that would be best...
No, Oskar will be staying
with his dad next week...
Murder in Vãllingby murderer drained
victim's blood
( Music Playing )
Senseless massacre in Beirut
(Oskar Humming)
No survivors in Arab murders manhunt
for killer continues
Eyewitness identifies murderer prior
to confession
Murder drained his victim
( Music Stops )
(Humming)
(Footsteps Clicking)
(Taps)
[Man] Just coming... hi, there.
I really don't think the death penalty
Has any relevance in our society.
It's just something
They've drilled into us...
Like the Russians or something...
[Man] Are you saying there aren't
any Russians?
[Gray Man] Of course there are Russians.
Never seen him before.
(Gray Man Laughs)
Who's been bitten by a snake here?
He moved into my building the other day.
With a little kid.
They're in Janne's old place.
- Should I ask him over?
- [Woman] Yes, ask him!
(Gray Man Coughing)
What the hell?
In that case...
(Chuckles)
He is welcome even if he has cancer.
Things not going too well?
Yeah, life stinks...
You just moved into number 15, right?
You don't have to sit here all alone,
join us and have a laugh.
No thanks, I'm in a hurry.
(Voices Speaking On TV)
[Oskar] Mom?
I'm going out for a while.
Aren't you going to watch the show?
No, it wasn't any good.
Stay in the yard, then, okay?
(TV Audience Applauds)
Well, I'll just watch this on my own, then.
You're here again?
So you're back.?
I want to be left alone.
Me too.
Go home, then!
You go home, I've lived here
way longer than you.
What's that?
This? It's a Rubik’s cube.
Is it some kind of puzzle?
Yeah...
You want to try it?
You can give it back tomorrow.
I might not be here tomorrow.
That's okay. You can borrow it till Monday.
How does it work?
You want each side to be a solid color.
Like this...
You smell funny.
Aren't you cold?
- No.
- Why not?
I guess I've forgotten how.
Guess I'll see you Monday, then.
Okay.
(Low Growling)
(Sighs)
(Car Whirrs)
(Men Speaking Softly)
Okay.
Thanks for tonight.
Good night, old buddy.
(Chuckling)
- See you tomorrow.
- [Lacke] Yeah.
- [Lacke] You're the best, Jocke!
- [Jocke] You too.
(Footsteps Fade)
(Cat Mews)
[Girl] Help me.
(Faint Growling)
Hello?
Please, help me.
Is something wrong?
(Train Roars)
Are you all right?
- Can you get up?
- [Girl] No.
(Low Growling, Moans)
[Jocke] I'll carry you.
and take you to a phone.
[Girl] Careful.
[Jocke] You don't weigh a thing...
(Girl Snarls, Barks)
(Jocke Groans)
Bloody hell!
(Moaning)
(Lapping)
(Cracks)
(Sobs Softly)
(Faint Yelling)
(Muffled Voices Murmuring)
(Door Slams)
(Cats Mewing)
(Voices Speaking Softly)
(Man Yells)
Never again...
Gösta? Hey, Gösta!
It's been ages. I haven't
seen you all year.
- Jocke...
- What?
(Stammers)
Jocke...
There was an animal behind...
I was out on the balcony and I saw...
And then I saw Jocke... and a little kid.
It was here somewhere.
Look!
What the hell is this? Christ!
[Gösta] It's blood!
It's blood, damn it!
[Lacke] Who the hell did this?
(Håkan Grunting)
Whew...
(Water Gurgling)
(Grunts)
(Bird Chirping)
(Chirping)
(Faint Dripping)
(Jaybird Squawking)
How did you do it?
I just twisted it.
Do I smell better now?
Um, what's your name?
Eli.
What's yours?
- Eli?
- Yeah.
My name is Oskar.
How old are you?
Twelve... about.
What about you?
12 years, eight months, and nine days.
What do you mean, "about 12"?
When's your birthday?
I don't know.
Don't you celebrate your birthday?
Your parents... they have to know.
Then you don't get any birthday
presents, do you?
No.
You can have this if you want.
It's yours.
I don't get how you did this...
You want me to show you?
Here. Go ahead.
Start with the corners....
Then you take this side. See?
(Mutters)
[Teacher] "slipping in and out of the
shadows, running quick and quiet.
and keeping out of the sun;
so soon they went back, grumbling
and cursing, to guard the door.
Muttering and swearing.
Bilbo was saved."
(Snaps)
Well then, that's it for today!
Has everyone handed in their slips
for the field trip on Thursday?
(Pupils Mutter)
Well then, class dismissed.
- Oskar, aren't you going?
- No, I have some things to do.
Samuel Morse
(Switch Clicks)
What were you writing down?
What do you mean?
Let me see.
(Boys Whispering)
No.
What do you mean, no? Give it here!
(Whips, Oskar Gasps)
(Whips)
(Sobs)
[Conny] Who's going to talk to his mom
now?
Wait for me!
(Conny Yells)
Oskar...
(Laughter Fades)
Oskar!
[Oskar] I fell down during recess.
I tripped on this rock.
Oh, honey...
You've got to watch your step.
Hmm?
[Oskar] Short, long, long, short, long.
Short, long, long, short, long.
Exactly.
Here...
What happened to you?
There...
Some classmates...
Where do you go to school, anyway?
Oskar, listen...
You have to fight back.
You've never hit them back...
Have you?
Start hitting back now...
Hard.
There are three of them.
Then you have to hit even harder!
Hit back harder than you dare.
Then they'll stop.
- But if they...
- Then I'll help you.
I can do that.
[Oskar] Come.
Come.
(Muffled Thumping)
(Eli's Voice Speaking Softly)
(Man's Voice Speaking Softly)
Move over.
(Sighs)
(Muttering)
Let's see, short, short...
(Tapping Within)
(Tapping)
s-s-s...
Ooh-hh...
Vuh...
Guh...
[Coach] Keep proper distance!
Not too close, not too far.
Keep the distance!
Nice and steady.
(Tapping)
Yes?
( Music Playing )
(Girls Squealing)
The after school weight-lifting
program in the bathhouse...
Can I sign up for it?
You don't have to sign up, just come.
At 7:00. Are you thinking of doing it?
Good.
- Yes.
- Good!
You'll train, then you can
go about 50 times.
At least.
[Oskar] Wait a minute...
(Coins Clatter)
Mixed candy.
(Snarls, Hisses)
Here.
No.
Too bad.
I can... Try one.
(Retching)
[Eli] I'm sorry.
Oskar...
Do you like me?
Yes, a lot.
If I wasn't a girl...
...would you like me anyway?
I guess so.
Why do you ask?
( Rapping )
Oskar! Hi buddy!
- You're early.
- Hi, Dad.
(Motor Whirrs)
(Whirrs)
(Whooping)
(Crunches)
[Håkan] There are people who recognize
my face
Who know I live here, with you.
- [Eli] Maybe you shouldn't.
- What else am I good for?
Could you do one thing for me?
Could you not see that boy tonight? Please?
(Crunches)
(Sneakers Squeaking)
(Players Shouting)
(Switch Thumps)
(Clicks, Grunting)
(Keys Jingling)
(Clicks)
[Håkan] What the hell?
- [Turtleneck] Where's matte?
- Don't know.
(Muffled)
hey! Matte?
( Rapping )
matte! Time to go home!
You can jerk off at home.
( Rapping )
(Bangs)
matte? What are you doing?
Open the door.
Matte!
(Thumping)
Let me down!
(Louder)
Let me down...!
(Funnel Clatters, Matte Yelps)
(Rattling)
(Splashing)
Help!
(Sizzling)
Matte?
(Thumping)
Help!
[Friend] Open the god damn door!
(Screams)
help!
Help!
(Voices Yelling)
(Faint Rumbling)
Help...?
(Banging)
Help!
(Bangs)
(Håkan Gasps)
- Get me down!
- What are you doing up there?
I'm trapped.
(Gasps)
(Birds Chirping)
(Humming Softly)
(Distant Train Wheels Clattering)
[Man On Radio] ...Police have not been
able to confirm the identity
Of the man who was apprehended last
night...
On suspicion of murder and attempted
murder...
In Vãllingby, in Western Stockholm.
Identification was difficult...
Because the man injured himself
severely before his arrest.
In sports...
( Music Plays Faintly )
[Man] Come on in. Through those doors.
(Distant Coughing)
Yes?
Excuse me.
I'm looking for my dad.
Has he been admitted to this hospital?
What's his name?
He's sick.
The police brought him in.
Do you know where he is?
Then he's on level 7.
But you can't just go in there,
it's a restricted ward
- I can call...
- No.
It's not necessary.
(Softly)
you poor thing.
(Respirator Hisses)
(Taps)
May I come in?
(Wind Whistles)
(Pops)
(Slurps)
(Slumps)
(Bangs)
(Monitor Beeping)
(Gasps)
Wake up, Virginia.
- A kid!
- What goddamn kid?
Why the hell would a kid
want to kill Jocke?
(Softly)
I don't know.
Jocke was the kindest person I know.
I'll rip that damned kid to shreds.
(Tapping)
(Whispering)
Oskar!
(Murmurs)
May I come in?
Don't look at me.
But say I can come in.
Come in.
(Window Creaks)
(Softly)
close your eyes.
How did you get here?
I flew.
Yeah, sure...
But you're not wearing any clothes.
You're ice cold!
Sorry.
Is that gross?
No...
"bulleri, bulleri bock...
How many fingers am I tapping you with?"
Eli...
Want to go steady?
What do you mean?
I mean...
Do you want to go steady?
Oskar, I'm not a girl.
No?
Do I have a Chance with you?
Couldn't we just
keep things the way they are?
I guess...
Do you do anything special
when you go steady?
No.
So everything's the same?
Yes.
- Then we'll go steady.
- Really?
Then we're together.
- Yes.
Good.
(Murmurs)
(Window Squeaks)
(Squeaks)
"I must be gone and live,
or stay and die."
Yours Eli
(Whistle Tweets)
[Coach] Lower school, skate with me.
Middle school, free skating.
Watch out for the ice pit over there!
Listen to me!
- [Teacher] Avila...?
- Understood?
(Chuckles)
Avila...
- It's called an ice hole.
- Ice hole?
[Avila] I mean, ice hole!
You want to swim?
Are you going to swim?
No.
Teacher, teacher? I have to go pee.
- Go behind the tree.
- On the ice?
What does it matter?
You make new ice, yellow ice.
[Conny] What are you going to do with
the stick?
I'll hit you... if you try anything.
Are you a brave pig, all of a sudden?
I'm going to skate over to you and
push you over.
You won't do anything.
Am I right?
Little Piggy...
Watch Out...
Look.
[Conny] Come on.
Mr. Avila will freak out...
So are you just going to stand there?
(Distant Screaming)
What's going on over there?
(Screaming)
Oskar! What are you doing?
(Kids Screaming)
(Screaming)
Come on.
(Buzzing)
Police
(Muffled Voice Speaking)
Yes, it is. Now he's coming.
They've called from school.
And you can talk to your dad, because I...
Hello?
I'm okay.
I don't know.
Is the bike working?
We'll see.
(Sputters)
(Diver Splashing)
(Splashing)
Hey, Oskar.
So you did go swimming after all?
I'm just kidding.
[Oskar] We're not allowed to be here, really.
This cellar is the best place.
We can do whatever we want.
And you know what? Today...
They tried to throw me into a hole in
the ice...
Oskar...
But I had a stick,
And I hit Conny in the head
So he had to go to the hospital.
Oskar...?
Huh?
Hooray!
( Pop Ballad Plays )
What were we going to do?
(Gasps)
(Chuckles)
We're going to mix.
It doesn't hurt at all.
(Low Growling)
All you have to do is poke your finger.
(Dripping)
(Faint Snarling)
(Moaning)
Eli?
(Lapping)
Go!
Get out of here!
(Belches)
(Sighs)
(Scratching)
(Snarling)
[Gray Man] Damn it, They had to use a
chainsaw to get him out.
Go tell the cops your story.
What's your problem, Gösta?
They'll ask me questions...
Interrogation! What do you mean?
They might shut me
into one of those rooms..
And shine bright lights in my eyes...
(Gray Man Chuckling)
- Jocke and I, we were this close...
- [Gösta] I'm sorry, but I can't do it.
[White Hat] In fact...
It's your duty, you witnessed a crime.
Hell.
I have nothing left...
Now that he's gone.
- But Lacke...
- stop that shit!
Don't give me your goddamn "Lacke, Lacke."
You don't understand shit.
You're cold, fucking ice cold!
(Mutters)
Ow...!
[Gray Man] You handled that just
fucking great, Lacke.
[Lacke] Virginia!
(Sobbing)
Wait! Can't we talk about it?
Listen...
(Footsteps Scuffling)
(Sobbing)
(Sharp Barking)
(Snarling, Yelling)
help me! Help me!
- Get the fuck off her!
- Help me!
(Moaning)
Ginia?
Wait up!
What's going on up there?
(Virginia Cries, Moans)
(Sizzling)
(Gasps)
(Faint Voices Echo)
(Whimpers)
(Faint Growling)
( R&B Music Plays )
- I didn't see that one.
- You never do.
Now I'll get you.
You can always dream.
(Tapping)
- [Dad] We have a guest.
- Good evening to you all.
So...
You look like
you're having a grand old time.
That's right.
[Visitor] And Oskar's here...
Right...
Dad? It's your turn.
Yes, yes. But we have a guest now.
You have it nice and cozy in here.
So you had a little something, then?
"I must be gone and live,
or stay and die."
Yours, Eli.
(Whimpering)
It ended up all wrong, you see.
It was supposed to be perfect, but their
calculations were all wrong.
Maybe there was something wrong with
the set square...
Or the ruler, or...
(Snarls)
Nothing to be scared of, kitty.
And it was more and more wrong.
And now I walk around and it feels like...
Pretty damn busy
around here tonight.
Come on in.!
(Cat Screeches, Lacke Babbling)
[Lacke] Ginia! Where the hell have you been?
(Snarls)
What are you doing?
I need to talk to you, damn it!
- We've been so fucking worried!
- No!
I have to hold you.
We've been so fucking worried.
- Are you crazy?
- Leave me alone!
(Screams)
[Lacke] What's happening with the cats?
What's happening with the cats?
- Let us out, you bastard!
- Let go of me! Help!
(Bangs)
(Screaming)
(Thumps)
[Eli] Oskar, is it you?
Yes.
(Bolt Clicks)
Are you a vampire?
I live off blood...
Yes.
Are...
Are you dead?
No.
Can't you tell?
But are you...
Old?
I'm twelve.
Though I've been 12 for a long time.
Are you guys poor?
- [Eli] You see the egg there?
- [Oskar] Mm-hmm.
If you sold that you could buy a
nuclear power plant.
It's true.
Oh. Sure.
Put your finger here.
(Clicks, Clatters)
Those rings...
Where did they come from?
I'm going home now.
I'm going to deliver chocolates tomorrow.
[Eli] To earn money?
Um-hmm.
But you can have money from me.
Here.
Take it if you want.
You stole this...
...from the people you killed, right?
- [Eli] It was given to me....
- By whom?
By different people.
I want to go home now.
If you'll let me.
Dad's stamp collection. His whole life.
One stamp...
80,000.
Eighty grand.!
Sometimes I tried to be interested. I
said, "I won't tell."
He just said, "no, there are others.
Thank you very much."
(Sighs)
There isn't a prettier place.
(Sighing)
Listen to the birds sing
and grow our own vegetables...
Lacke, you have to help me!
Of course.
- That child.
- Yeah?
She must have infected me somehow.
I don't want to live.
(Scrubbing)
(Chuckles)
(Panting)
(Thumping)
[Medic] Good morning!
Things are looking up.
You can probably go home today..
Won't that be nice?
I'll just unlock this...
And take a little blood sample.
There...
- Listen...?
- Yes?
Could you open the shutters, please?
Sure... No problem.
(Blinds Whizzing)
(Screaming)
Hand over your cap. Do it!
What's your problem? Give it to me.
What are you, some kind of moron?
Give it to me
(Moaning)
Go for it, Conny!
(Chuckling)
- Put up a fight...
- Are you blind as well as deaf?
- Hi.
- Hi. What's up?
Could I borrow your keys?
- Why?
- I'm going home.
- Sure. Here you go.
- Thanks. See you later.
- Who's the boss at your house?
- Well, well...
- What are you laughing at?
- Are you hard of hearing, Conny?
(Man On TV Speaking)
(Doorbell Buzzes)
- Hi.
- Hey.
You have to invite me in.
What happens if I don't?
What happens if you come in anyway?
Is there something in the way?
Tsk-tsk-tsk...
Tsk-tsk-tsk.
(Door Closes)
(Shuddering)
No!
You can come in!
(Sighs)
[Oskar] Who are you?
The same as you.
What?
What are you staring at? Well?
Are you looking at me?
Then squeal like a pig! Squeal!"
That was the first thing I heard you say.
I don't kill people.
No...
But you'd like to,
If you could.
To get revenge.
Right?
Yes.
Oskar, I do it because I have to.
Be me, for a little while
Please, Oskar...
Be me a little while.
(Train Rumbles)
( Loud Rock Music Plays )
(Loudly)
You Can Borrow A Dress From My Mom.
(Doorbell Buzzes)
[Mother] Oskar, can you open the door?
Let me in.
What are you up to?
(Doorbell Buzzes)
Coming! I'm in the bathroom.
Let me in, Oskar...
(Switch Clicks)
(Clicks)
(Bird Chirping)
Hi! I'm in the bathroom. Please don't
come in.
Do you want to meet me tonight?
I like you so much. Yours, Eli.
(Sniffles)
(Door Creaks Faintly)
(Door Latch Rattles, Lacke Sniffles)
(Utensils Clatter)
(Sniffles)
(Clicking)
(Mutters)
I can't see a thing...
No!
(Growls)
Huh?
(Lacke Groans)
Let go! Let go!
(Screams)
(Gags)
(Lapping)
(Muffled Knocking)
(Muffled Yelling)
(Knocking)
Thank you.
Oskar...
I've got to go away.
(Muffled Knocking)
(Silent)
Who murdered the man in the ice?
(Sniffles)
(Phone Rings)
(Rings)
Hello.
- Is that you, Oskar?
- Yeah.
It's me, Martin
Teacher was wondering if you're coming
to practice tonight.
How come?
Don't know. He was just wondering.
Maybe he wanted you to come.
I'm not sure...
By the way...
I think it was good, what you did to
Conny.
He had it coming.
[Conny] Damn, he's good at acting!
- You think so?
- Yes.
You coming to training tonight?
Pool
(Shower Splattering, Avila Chuckling)
Hi, Oskar.
Hi.
(Speaking Spanish)
[Martin] Hey, Oskar.
Hey.
Now we'll start water aerobics.
[Conny] Hurry up!
[Avila] Come on, Oskar!
(Speaking Spanish)
vamos, vamos! Uno, dos, uno dos...
Move your body...
( Pop Music Plays )
What? Christ!
(Speaking Spanish)
(Roaring)
(Door Closes)
[Avila] Call the fire department! Fire!
( Music Continues )
(Boy Yelling)
get out of here!
Out!
(Clicks)
(Blade Clicks)
Do you know who I am?
- Yes.
- Good.
Then you understand.
We're going to have a little contest now.
You'll stay under water...
...for three minutes.
Do that, and it's just a little scratch.
(Clicks)
If you don't...
I'll poke one of your eyes out.
An eye for an ear, okay?
But... that's impossible.
That's your problem.
(Splashes)
(Blade Clicks)
Three minutes.
Better take a deep breath.!
Five...
Four...
Three...
Two... One.
(Gasps)
- Jimmy...
- Shut up!
- Let's get out of here, Conny.
- I told you to shut up!
(Banging)
(Sobbing)
(Rattling)
(Signal Rings)
(Tapping Code)
(Tapping, Scraping)