Love Me If You Dare
I like this game very much.
Housing game, when the the banker lost.
I like bead game, I win;
Jumping game is for fools.
Unless girls.
I don't play guessing game; the
house-jumping is quite good for two persons.
Hide-and-seek is
quite good too.
But you can't play one game.
I say, never.
Even your best friend suggests.
It's a game that bury yourself
into a heap of concrete.
This game started
with a beautiful house.
A bus without driver.
A beautiful box.
A beautiful friend.
In fact, I made a mistake.
This game started long long ago.
It started with a sick word.
Like: Transfer.
Why not mammouth?
This made mother crys.
In all, doctor, thay
don't like anything.
Your situation is very
urgent...They all talk nonsense.
Their trousers are too bad.
Look! Imagine that what
they know about mothers.
Also some unlovely word, Like Kowalsky.
Don't search anymore. I
don't want to refer it.
Kowalsky.
Polish! And.
Don't forget the disgusting faces.
All this is the same thing.
That is "I don't feel well".
"No one feels so bad like
me on the Earth and Mars."
You love her. Wei?
Me too. I think she is
very pretty. Give it to me.
This is really cowry, right?
Oh! I have never seen a beautiful
rounded playground like this.
Never, never.
No. I have seen it, but not on Earth.
Me too.
Where? Is it real? Does it really exit?
Yes. My angel, here.
And here.
Julien, you go by bus tomorrow morning.
I will stay with mother for some time.
Let's go.
Go, go, My Juju, go.
Mother! You forget your cowry. Keep it.
My only cowry is you.
Oh...
Ok.
Oh! Dirty Polish.
Sophie? No. I am a dirty Polish.
Oh! dirty Polish.
There isn't any precious
things that day with Sophie.
So I will share with her.
Will you pay me back?
If you really want it,
please prove it. Dare you?
This is the start.
All the things begin.
My bus! Oh, no.
Dare.
What did you do? Please answer me.
Nothing.
I don't want to be hurt! Stop.
Stop! Shut up!
Julien! I don't want to be hurt.
He will not. He dare not..
Don't beat him.
You don't have the right to beat him.
Shut up! Think twice.
Father doesn't like Sophie.
He doesn't like her from the beginning.
The game started successfully.
If the box is in her hand,
she asks me to prove it.
I do it to win the box back.
So I give Sophie a guaranty.
It is absurd, isn't it?
Foolish game? Perhaps.
But this is our game.
1X7?
2X7?
3X7?
21.
4X7? 28.
5X7?
35. 6X7?
42.
7X7?
49.
Please show me some common
nouns begin with "A".
One.
"Animals".
Any else? Sylvie?
Abricot.Very good.
The common nouns begin with "B", Sophie?
"Brouter".
"Braguette", "Bistouquette".
Shut up! "Bigleux".
Go away.
The short fat ugly girl.
Do you feel interesting, miss?
I signed you zero, zero begin eith Z.
Go to the headmaster's office.
I'll see weather you laugh or not.
Julien, what are you
doing? Go with Sophie.
Go to the headmaster's office.
"Bander".
What? Bander begins with "B".
Discipline.
Discipline is the basic of respect.
Without respect, it's
the end of civilization.
Most residents.
Came down.
Corrupt politics! Whose
contribution is it?
Miss Kowalsky and Mr. Janvier!
Dare. Say it again, Mr. Janvier.
Let me share it.
What do your poor brain think of?
Dare you interrupt me?
Imagine it, sir.
It's really a great
game, but no one laughs.
Detach them.
Detach them, miss.
We are detached.
They never dare to do so.
Mr. Janvier, please
meet with miss Kowalsky.
Great spirits meets.
Do you know what the
word "punish" means?
You have comsidered.
Is it the future prepared for her? Ok.
I am not her mother.
Vulgarity is not in the lessons.
Miss Kowalsky!
I will meet your parents.
They don't speak
French. "Bite" in Polish.
Called hammer. Anything else?
Please wait, there must be your profits.
Don't go out or watch TV.
Don't eat sweets.
DOn't use light in the aisle.
Go to get your coat.
No. It's enough. Cool.
Did you do the same thing like me?
Go to your room! Don't disturb mother.
Julien!
Julien...Mother!
We have a good meal!
You are in bed that time.
You are lucky.
You know, My Julien...A
doctor came to see me.
I made five mistakes. Do you know?
Juju...I made ten
mistakes in the elocnte.
Do you want to lister?
I also did a very silly thing.
Friends are like glasses.
it looks smart, but hard to disapeaer.
And it is fatiguesome. But
luckily, It is cool glasses!
I, I have Sophie.
Now.
Animals begin with "A". Anticot.
Autruche, abruti.
Altaire. Four...Dare or not?
Dare. Zero.
Zero. Go to the headmaster's office.
Discipline.
Forever discipline.
I have told you early.
From now on.
It's an end, Eden.
Things get serious.
My daughter, your
childbirth will be in misery.
You must waer high-heel
shoe and bear banting.
desquamate operation, and
wrinkle-dispel operation.
And.
You will go kitchen.
it's not the end. You.
My son, I leave
something more grisliness.
crucifixion.
Disaster, dinosuar, atom-war.
Oil tanker wrecking,
misfortune. BUt especially.
Especially! The beautiful mother is ill.
"There lived a male hare."
"They are bedlamites.""I don't
want to go to see bedlamites."
"You have on choice."
"Here are all bedlamites."
mother, will you die?
Do I read well? Will you die?
I will, just like everyone.
Because I do the silly things?
Give!
let me do some clever things.
I will do it. Don't say it any more.
Dare not.
Close your ears, close your ears hardly.
Can you hear how I love you?
It's most important.
ok. What do you talk about?
Sophie writes with teeth.
It is important, isn't it?
Now one can attract you like Sophie.
Alice can not, your mother can not.
Ok. Use teeth.
How does she deal with ears?
Can you? Climb alone rops
with your eyes shut out?
Cup on head.
I don't believe you.
Do you think you are the
first playing "Dare or not"?
Ok. Good night.
Mother.
What is the most crazy
thing you have done? Fly?
Fly? How to fly?
Fly in the sky.
Let me see! Be quick.
Fly! Dare.
Later. When?
Soon.
I guarantee.
Tell him the story. What a bad idea!
It's you should lie on bed in this case.
Mother.
Will I be punished seriously or lightly?
I want to say.
Sophie invited me to
attend a wedding...No.
Silence.
Her skirt is so ugly.
So does her lover.
If I get married...You will
not tell the Abba, dare?
Dare, of course.
What will you do when you grown up?
Despot.
Despot? All are enslaved by one?
yes. A own palace, and many slaves.
I torture them every
Thursday, what about you?
Yes...I...No, it's idiotic.
Say it! No.
Say it quickly!
I want to make a flan,a
flan with abricots.
Or crude, a little
hot, in a bread-room.
flan like cakes?
Sure! Do you think something else?
flan...flan.
Yes, a piece of flan.
Excellent! Dare or not?
Yes, dare.
It's ok.
Is this why your pay is better?
The best worker uses the best tool.
It's your turn! Look!
This is my guarantee!
You have no right to copy.
Dare or not?
Dare.
Only this? BUt I can't see anything.
Women are more finished than men.
It's easier to be friend like this.
Remove the spread! Dare.
It's your turn, try hard! Dare.
Julien! I am looking for you everywhere.
The violin teacher is ill...We
will discuss it later. Please come.
Mother.
Ny Julien.
Good child...You can get better, yes?
You can get better, dare or not?
You haven't box. It's not
you to give the guarantee.
I will go and get it.
Hold your mother in the arm please.
I will go at once. Then
please show me how to fly.
What will you do coming here?
Julien, I...
Please leave. Father doesn't like.
Sure, I am only a partner to play with.
Next is draging feet. Dare or not?
I do two, and mother will be ok.
I do three, and she will come
back home to celebrate my birthday.
Good!
I do four, and she will come
back home tonight healthily.
Mother.
"Auroral life."
I am Julien's father,
are you Sophie's mother?
Her sister.
I want...
It is or not?
Can Sophie come my home tonight?
Are you sllep? Formally, yes.
there is some hearsay say
that you are pretending.
I saw some slanderous gossip on .
I will sleep for a while.
Can I go to your house
and sleep tomorrow?
No. You should never come to
my home. Please guarantee it.
Why?
Guarantee it.
Ok.
Good night.
Bad habit is just tarined like this...
I don't mean the broken cup.
But sleep.
Sophie and me, from this night on,
have slept together for ten years.
On the morning, something
serious happened.
Right! On the morning,
something serious happened.
Oh. blamed, blamed.
What's the time?
My examination!
What examination?
Mathematic examination.
You need not to take the examination.
I don't like that.
Ill, yes?
You are ill.
Julien!
What are these noisy things?
Open the door.
Blamed! blamed!
Julien! Open the door,
or I will barge in.
Julien!
Give it back to me.
Dare or not?
No. This morning can't. I am too whiny.
No, this morning.
This morning, Sophie will wear her bra.
Game starts again.
Miss Kowalsky.
Kowalsky, Sophie.Kowalsky.
The game's rule is silly.
Someone fooled before
changed opposite now.
Do you know what is changing opposite?
Only something about taste.
I am Julien. I am "Go away."
Make my life significative.
Just like play Beethoven on
the blackboard by fingers.
Miss Kowalsky.
Function vectorielle...
V1xV2 gets the same result as 2 modules.
multiple by the cosine of
the angle which forms them
You seem good at Function vectorielle.
Tell me weather I make a mistake or not.
Miss Kowalsky.
Tell me whether I was wrong.
Your vector begins with a point,
And defined by a fixed amount,
Which is more attractive than others.
Do you think you can do some
research on this theory with me?
This will be an index number.
Do you usually review
by yourself?    En¡­
This makes me deaf.
The answer to intrinsic function
Kowalsky
The square to 3¡­  En¡­
2m+1
I didn't allow you
To leave here.
f(x) has two different roots.
If m is between -1 and 1/3
I'll go, this is my
sister. What a pity man.
Be louder, I can't hear.
It works, isn't it? I did it;
don't keep such a straight face.
What can you do except seduce women?
The chief examiner
didn't have a good name.
She thought you are Kawasaky
It's the result to chew up
No result, you get no mark!
I have faced those
executioners for 20 minutes.
See how comfortable you are!
I never know her that bitch.
And she knows nothing about math.
Aurelie Miller, a taint.
To her there's only two things: She
had had sex with the teacher of PE,
And she had awful earrings.
Do you envy her?
Me? Yes.
Go to get a whore, as you like.
So¡­ you are envying.  Forgive me!
If you want to know my opinion of
Aurelie, OK, I wish you success.
You two seems like a pair to death.
Stop. To give her up would be a fault.
Bring me her earrings.
Miss Miller! Aurelie£®Miller
Do you have boyfriend?  Yes.
Now, you have two.
And you? Is that really your sister?
It's she who asked
me to come.   Get out!
If I scream, the school will be here.
No¡­ Oh!
What are you doing?
You are so coquettish, just like my car.
That why I like you.
Miller Aurelie
Is she still not here?
When will we meet again?
The third semester, partly.
Give me your earrings.
Reflect your golden hair on it.
Let your frozen stiff slave
wallow in your earrings.
You are crazy.
You are crazy. Ok, let me go, Ok?
Forget about those
vectors and functions, OK?
-Do you believe love at first sight?
-En, yes.
Na?ve.
Aurelie£®Miller¡­ You failed the exam.
Did my wage make you ill?
How is it?   I don't like blond woman.
You did it! You this son of a bitch!
Tyrant
That's enough! She has nothing at all!
You have forget that PE teacher;
the one with a strong biceps.
I've had sex with him.
His leg? It's just like your QI.
-You like him, this snowman?
-As the second choice, yes.
What do you mean by ¡°as the second
choice¡±? What's the first one?
It's your turn! Hurry up!
Go away!   Be calm!
Do you know the Easter bet?
it seems he doesn't know it.
You are all crazy! No!Igor
Let's talk something else.
Kick his ass.
Say you regret!
That's funny.
Say it!
You should not go.
Look at me carefully, jerk! I dare
do anything; beg me for forgiveness!
You would get nothing.
Bitch, give me the box.
Kiss me, can you?
I can.
I said: kiss me.
Anything wrong with
you? You are all crazy!
Get off my car, and I'll tell you.
Do you hear me? Get off and I tell you.
Do you hear me?!
Get off!!
You are both louts! Idiots!
Hold me
Love me
I can.
Is this a game to you?
No, I bet. You started it.
If I started it, you
would not hold it at once.
Poor taint! You are
going to miss the bus.
He must be older.
As a child, we think
it's a slow process.
But it beats you like a branch.
When someone comes to you,
or your father tells you that:
It's all over! You have unified exam!
Do you remember? Exam,
don't make yourself a loser.
Or I'll announce your
comfortable life an end.
Come on, Dad. It's not
so serious, be gentle.
Be gentle?
You little lout, don't you
feel that I'm now gentle enough?
I'll tell you that
Your game killed my wife
And your mother.
You are so contemptible!   Yes, I am.
I'm a contemptible
person, not a gentleman.
I'm so contemptible that
bring you up alone! Shit!
You are rubbish!   Yes, I am.
I can tear your face.
I can't believe that
Sophie poisoned you.
Poisoned you that you
don't say a word to me.
Unless when your friends
take me as the wager.
You choose it.
She or me, how is it?
Dare¡­
Or dare not?
Sophie!
Hallo, do you want to see
Sophie? She is not here.
What are you doing here?
I told you don't come.
You satisfied? You see
it? Is it interesting?
You promised me
I don't care.   I care!
I see nothing in my eyes,
sorry, I don't know.
Sorry, everything has been changed!
Come on, let's go.   Go where?
Your teenager's room? I
don't need your compassion.
You go by yourself.
Sophie, forgive me!
Go!
Dare or dare not?
You go!
Forgive me, I give a most
difficult bet to Sophie.
But Sophie never like easy.
This takes her a long
time, maybe it's too long.
During that time, my
father persuaded me.
Hallo, sir.
Is Julien here?
Excuse me, Mr. Janvier.
I come here to see Julien.
He is here.
Julien£¬do you hear me?
Keep silent, let me say something.
Do you miss me?
Because I miss you, you this tyrant.
Give you a straight face
is a difficult thing,
But I still feel that
it's not your illusion.
I want to forget the game when
we are talking. Just one time.
Do you like my skirt? I'm hesitating.
I took it from my sister.
There was once a red one.
Red like a nuclear bomb.
I know this is what I need to wear.
I must be sitting in front
of the mirror for 3 hours.
But I did it. See, I'm so beautiful.
I hope you like it,
otherwise I'll beat you.
Wait
What did I say just now?
The problem is
Even you say ¡°I like
it¡±, I'll not trust you.
I don't know when you are in game,
And when you are not.
I've lost myself.
Wait¡­ I'm not finish.
Say you love me.
I can never say this out first.
I'm afraid you think it's a game.
Help me, please.
Thank you.
Hallo.
Julien
Are you reviewing you courses?
It seems you are not.
Not now.
When? Tomorrow?
One year later. I'm sorry.
Don't say sorry to me.
¡° City plan¡±, do you really like this?
You are talking to a
expert, HLM, my speciality.
We had never talked about future.
Us two.
Our two futures.
¡°Our two futures¡±
Spontaneously, I'd say our future.
You need to believe that
present situation satisfied me.
I dream to see us keeping going
like we've been in these years.
You are a idiot.
OK, pass the exam, dare or dare not?
I'm sorry.
¡°I'm sorry, Sophie¡±. Good!
In fact, wa have talked
about future, just once.
Did I make a mistake,
in some place else?
You want to be a tyrant, to me , a flan
Stop! No, I don't want to delay you.
Go ahead with your job, I have exam
too, I investigate human beings.
You learn Sociology. What I
refer to is not human beinngs.
But man.
Male, man, and I have
difficult in review.
Use this, you are in the library.
There is no better place for
review than here, isn't there?
Yes.
Stop, you are doing something stupid.
Stop. Why?
It's just a bet. Come
on, let me work over it.
See you one year later.
What happened?
Hmm
You know what I am saying clearly.
Mo, I don't konw, tell me.
It is not easy to say that.
Can't you wait for one year.
There, in your study.
Be careful.
You want to hurt me, don't
kidding me, you won't.
Wait for me?
This is guaranty?
No.
Then you just go and see.
Sophie!Sophie, I love you.
I love you, I love you, come down.
What a fool.
Look at the fool sitting on the chair.
He makes a strange face
because of his lung.
This is only an excuse.
Isn't it easyer to
hold her in your arms?
Tell her I love her?
You feel your heart beating
when you think of this.
Hey! I am talking to
you! Do you hear that?
Of course you have heard
that, what a snaky fool.
What is worse, your mess is not end.
Do you want something?
Do you have skirt for banquet?
I don't have any banquet.
I will give you two pieces.
I have something to ask you.
What do you like to drink?
A cup of coffee.
A cup of coffee, just this.
Can I have a talk with you. No.
Sorry, but we have something that
we don't agree with each other.
Stupid things... For
example, your shoes.
My shoes? Yes, it is funny.
Your shoes fit your
trousers well, I swear.
It attracts my eyes that I
couldn't hear what you said.
Please.
I won't take it off.
That is you, you want to talk.
Monday, I will be off at
7pm, and I will come later.
OK. But, in fact,
I have a singing lesson after that.
You sing?
Yes, this is not my
life, it is only a job.
Isn't it the way you make
the hero save you, is it?
I am sorry, but this is the truth.
I don't mean anything else.
I am glad that you
take the singing lesson.
You want to be a singer? The
first thing is to earn money.
You pay 100 pounds
to become Terrisa's mother?
Damn it, I said I wouldn't talk to you.
Your shoes, and your trousers, make
me distracted! Let me do my work.
How do you do. How do you do.
How are you? Fine, and you?
Very well.
Can I invite you now?
No.
Where are you going? Don't
ask so many questions.
Monday, you will be off at 7PM.
Today is Tuesday.
Wait for me.
I want to invite you for dinner.
Go away! You too?
A serious traffic jam, a truck wants to
Drive back... Have
you got a lover? What?
Have you got a lover?
Why you ask me so? Nothing.
It's about the inside
contradition oratory
Contradition oratory! That
is conversation, isn't it?
So, do you have a lover?
You don't have to answer,
it is only a question.
I don't have someone else
in bed, if you want to know.
He is a soccer player,
Sergei Nimov Nimovitch
Forget it, I've give
him up this morning.
How cant you go out
with such arrant person?
I am tired of staying out for night.
Is there nobody else since this morning?
Except for Sergei? Greg, his
friend, Jerome and his father.
A French, two and three Kevin's
Prince Cendrillon
They are not serious, just for fun.
Very beautiful restaurant!
Champagne, please.
You did a good job. I
think you are tempting me.
Is this so impossible in your eyes?
Have you seen the girl downstairs?
Her skirt
is the same with the
one I dressed before.
How long ago? Four years?
I have seen it.
That doesn't fit her.
What a dress up person.
Did I look so stupid before?
Don't say that, you don't know her.
You didn't either.
Does it matter?
Hey, have you got the certificate?
My certificate is nothing remarkable.
Cheers.
Cheers for this moment, and
the things I have done for you.
I have waited for
years to tell you this.
Tell me what?
Tell you myself.
But you have been talking about youself.
Then say something.
My heart,
Sophie, I have got a lover.
You have got a lover...
Just this? No, not like this.
For years, keep silent for years.
I want to marry,
Do you agree?
You are asking me ?
You remember.
Did I say I want to marry you?
Yes you did. What did you say?
You... you really want to marry?
Because I need you.
Of course, marriage, is not
only one person's matter.
You keep them for the day you marry.
Listen, this.
Do you agree?
You agree?
You agreed.
She agree! She agree.
You will be my chief
witness at wedding ceremony
Thank you, Sophie, I will introduce you.
My fiancee, Christelle,
she is beautiful, isn't she?
No.
She is dressing the skirt
you dressed four years ago.
You tell me you will never hurt me.
Yes.
Gift.
We get apart.
Are you introducing for us?
Christelle,Sophie
My future
My past
Get up,my child.
Now,tell each other that you'll
Christelle
My child
Christelle Louise Bouchard
Do you want to tell each other,
in the god's house
Christelle
Will you marry
Julien Antoine Janvier,love him
cherish him,until death take you apart
I will
And you
My son,Julien
Antoine Janvier,will you marr
Christelle Louise Bouchard
Love her,cherish her
Until death take you apart
Julien !
Wake up,we are waiting for your promise
Will you
marry
Christelle?
Yes,I will
Good,so,my son,
if someone
Me!Me! I don't agree
on this marriage
Julien is already engaged to me.
Get her out.
Julien!
Ask her to get out!
Tell'em,do you dare
to?    Please go away.
Julien!
You have problems,you've
never finished your oedipe
You can never fuck her.
You pray for your life,not control it.
No,dad.
Stop!  Okay,i stop
I stop everything.
Look at me,Julien,look at me.
It's the last time  you look at me.
You've looked my face
enough,now it's over.
The game is over.
You don't exist anymore!
You are deleted in my life.
A girl's lies...
Don't do this,it's a game.  Let go of me
What a magnific bad woman.
This kind of friend,things
can only be in this way.
Isn't she great? Be ready all the time.
Be scrunched by a
train.That's just a joke.
A kid's bet
Julien!
What's marriage?
Beautiful suits,champagne
Some cream dessert. That's enough
Okay,you can do it next week.
Julien!
You love yourself,this is
the important thing,isn't it?
Julien,do you hear me?
I can be a real chief
witness at your wedding.
I'll be serious,I swear.
I won't spit.
What's this?
Julien!
Julien,can I move?
Julien,don't joke.
Go to hell.
Okay,you go with me.
We haven't seen each other for 10 years.
Coming!
Sophie!
Don't say anything,Sergei
Hey?
Nothing.
Where is it?The proposition
from the Club of D1?
I don't know,i've not called them.
Okay,we don't need to
see each other again.
If you want to cast me away for weeks
Make a reservation. I've done
enough with small savings.
I don't live with a "football player"
Do you think you can hold
me by your poor salary?
I will make some money.
I want big money.
The big bingo,the super
cagnotte on Friday,13th.
I'm good for that,right?
Yes.
And here,it's the worst.
Nothing,it's nothing in 10 years
After 3652 days and 3653
nights,I got nothing.
The game is over,game!The
thrill of my existance.
I'm wandering in my life,
just like wandering in
the tragedies of Racine.
Hermione verion man
Where am I? What have I
done? What should I do?
What kind of passion has catched me?
What kind of sorrow licks me up?
"Can't I know whether I love or I hate?"
Sophie murdered me,
butchered me, killed me.
Raped me.
There are also many crazy feet.
And, I feel it incomplete at last.
Bring me to the happy that never
experience since I was born.
Love, family, work, paraboloid attenna.
Racine, I said.
The final one.
Julien! The dustbin.
Julien, rubbish.
Julien! Kiss.
Go, Julien, children.
Clic,clac,patati,patata!
What can this gift do? Silence.
Don't say anything.
For the celebration
of our marriage memory.
Do you know keeping secret?
The secrets of dinosaur?
The secrets of espionage?
The secrets of little figure?
Ok, please keep secret.
Please hide this. This is for mother.
We will give it to her tonight.
Mother.
Don't look what we hide for you.
Nearly 35 years old, I won everything.
A wife, two children, three
brothers, four savings.
In the same box.
stay 6 years.
8 times every quarter.
Coition, round Earth 9 times.
Using the packing which can't be untied.
Ten years...
Haven't see my father.
Happy.
The perfect despot's
whole arm I imagine.
Like this. As an adult.
Have a calculater can show
210, but only reach 60.
Hello!
About 40 times failure with father.
Deceive the boss 96 times.
Yes, yes, Dorzac, I come.
No, I come, I will come
at 10 whip and spur.
You have the meet in
advance. Don't care me.
Monday's jam.
Now 97 times. See you later.
Hello, Sophie! Dare. 123
times nightmare in it...
I become a despot finally.
No, No, I listen, yes, yes.
Yes, I will come soon. ok.
The city changed.
so does death.
Dawdle away 489 hours in the base.
I hope she will sing the
"auroral life" for me again.
Should believe that I don't need her.
We can say.
Mother can fly because of this game.
There is much distance
from the original think.
Sorry. Please show your project.
Wait...They are here! Come.
hello, I am sorry, I am late.
The project is here. It has
been prepared for ten years.
6 months. Divide 20.
What did I say? 10 years!
Sorry! It has been prepared
for 10 months...6 months!
Day by day pasts, 10 years.
The bet ends today.
No news about her, even a little.
She forgot me.
I don't.
Watch her husband the whole day.
How can I forget her?
he became the nation's hero.
"Sexy Sergei", was chosen
by three women magzines.
I never hate football like that.
Hello, I am Sergei, I
will be a little later.
But I will come. What a buzy day.
Sorry, but this is my personal life.
How?
Yes...Listen, I don't know.
Is it the final edition?
I don't know...I...Do you like it?
Yes.
I can imagine Sophie's life.
It isn't like this...Stupid.
Stupid.
Yes, stupid...This snippet is stupid.
This is the working
meeting. I can't bear it...
The arrange bargain
is stupid. It's enough!
Do you know who directed this snippet?
Steffie Daniel.
It's stupid even the
pontiffs sign together.
This is not a game, Sophie.
Sergei! Yes?
I have the right to defuse,
haven't I? Haven't I?
Yes, you have.
Then, how can I decide?
You decide this snippet is stupid.
Wait, there is something on my back.
What is it? Your little black bear?
A little black bear, in
principle, not the puzzle dom.
Do you say good morning
to your wife recently?
Not from yestoday, what about you?
Do you say "I love you" to your husband?
Not, even 100 years.
I never say "duckbill" to you.
I am thinking that i
should make up this neglect.
duckbill.
She really forgot me.
Do you go out tonight?
I hate football. Dad, dare you?
This?
This? This?
This? This? This?
Dare you make a girl
crying in her wedding?
Dare you smile in the
unfortunate moment?
Dare you maintain dumbness 10 years?
I just hang up the phone with Margaret.
About his insurance story.
I only want to serve him.
I have my office.
But doesn't signed "Army of Salut".
Are you listening?
Yes? No, not in this ten years.
No...
Do you know life ehind office?
Are you worried about Dorzac?
Watch me.
It's too far, you should marry Dorzac.
Look what he brought to you.
Why are the musters of goods
sent here instead of the office?
I lived 10 years with
the breath pausing.
I feel like a dog...
Leak on the carpet and
wait someone clobber me.
A Monday evening, it happened.
It made me crazy.
There is Julien and the children.
Nice to see you.
Are the children here?
Yes, everyone is here.
Look at who is coming.
Sophie.
Hello, Julien.
Hello, Clo, I am so happy.
I come back...
Dare or not, Sophie?
e-mail? Send it here, please.
And Clo is here,
Julien, I want you stay.
Sophie?
Are you OK?
The Police? I'm Madame Nimov Nemovietch.
The strange man come again.
I have ever tested once,
they use only 1 min.
Oh, no.
That's my grandma's hangover.
I beg you.
Haven't seen for long
time, about 10 years.
He escaped from here.
Sophie! You are playing game again.
Pure happiness.
Great!
It can cut down everything.
Better than anaesthetic,cocain,high
purity cocain,reefer
Indian hemp,LSD,hallucinogen
Better than sex,blowjob,rave
party,complex sexual relationship
Better than the butter on the peanuts.
Better than Lucas,end of 2001
The dance of Marylin,and Schtroumpfette
Better than Lara Croft
Better than Jimmy
Hendrix,than Armstrong.
Better than the
walk-around by Santa Claus
Better than Bill Gates,then
the trances of Dalai-Lama.
Better than the collagen on
the lips of Pamela Anderson
Better than the drugs
of Rimbaud, Morrison.
Better than freedom
Better than life
Hellow? Yes.
It's Hospital Saint-Antoine,May
I speak to Madame Janvier
It's her speaking. Your
husband had an accident.
It's my best friend,we've known
each other since elementary school
And you have never introduced him to me?
Have you introduced everyone
to me?You see them everyday.
You see him every day?
Who's that guy?
If he was same as I think,I'll kill him.
He doesn't need you.
Are you okay,Madame Janvier?
Speaking the truth,this time,
I'm really angry at her.
I want her to have a rough
time, then, I would forgive her.
We are smiling at the end.
After all, it's a game.
Go!
Sophie!
Where have you been, Julien?
We are all looking for you.
I went to the toilet.
-Are you alright?
-I'm fine.
Whole night in the first-aid room.
Is this your pleasantly surprised?
Do you suffer much pain ?
No, nothing, never mind.
What did you do?
I'm sorry.
I don't know what's the trouble with me.
All will be better.
I'm here.
I even don't care the stealing.
I feel sorry for you.
Damn!
Prepare the Atarax for me.
That's all. It's the
sequelae of the bump.
What did I do?
Sophie!
Julien?
Sophie,forgive me.
Julien!
Oh! Idiot you are.
Take me back to the hospital.
Sophie!
Take the umbrella.
You will be wringing.
Dare you?
Julien! Look at me.
Say it!
When she hold me in her breast.
She susurrating everything.
I see the rose colored life.
She tells love with me.
Children.
Sophie, come back.
Shut up!
It's important to me.
I didn't remember the words clearly.
It's will there. The only
method could make me stop...
is a strong fist.
So silly you are.
Really silly.
Julien?
It's enough, wake up.
Don't leave me alone.
Wake up, wake, Prithee!
Come back! Prithee! Back
Don't leave me alone.
No, it's too easy for you.
Come, look for it.
Dare you?
Julien!
Do you hear me? I know you do.
Dare you come back?
Julien, I do!
Come on.
The last game.
We won't left each other, never.
To win the game, we must
have a beautiful box.
And a pretty friend.
And any other never mind.
There're somethings I would dare
to do, even if you didn't say.
For example?
Eat ants.
Abuse the unemployed men of ANPE.
Love you like a bedlamite.
Look! We win it like this.
Together, happy.
Finally at the bottom of the concrete,
we share our dream in childhood.
A love dream with no final.
"B"
Braquemart or bite.
Never mind.
Or bralder, what dou you write?
Write, I have never.
Anything else?
Bander, do you know it?
What about you?
Take it back?
How about your children?
Do you consider about them?
Then what would they think about?
You take an orange colored.
I want an orange
colored, do you like blue?
Because there's only one blue colored.
Give you a blue, you are so cute.
And give you another blue.
OK?
I love you.
Sophie, my best friend.
End.