sub2srt by ¿­³ë(Yeolno)
http://nfou.net/
Ah, little scoundrel.
There you are.
You are a bad boy.
Come on.
Hop on.
Like you always do.
Holy sacraments!
You'll kill yourself!
Only God knows how much
I loved you.
- Someone has died.
- Huh-uh.
- It's Pentecost.
- No no, it must be a very big fish
if they are ringing
the cathedral bells.
Florentino, lay down.
Let's do it again.
Please?
Tolling like that must
be for a governor at least.
Or...
What?
What is it?
America, you must
go back to college.
My driver will take you.
There is something I have to do.
My deepest
sympathy.
Your father
was a saint.
- My condolences.
- I'm so sorry.
We would still
have cholera
if it had not
been for him.
My sympathies,
Mrs. Urbino.
Let's go, Mom.
- See you all later, gentlemen.
- See you later.
Mama, I'll stay
if you want me to.
Fermina, I have waited
for this opportunity
for 51 years,
nine months
and four days.
That is how long
I have loved you,
from the first moment
I cast eyes on you until now.
I repeat
to you once again
my vow
of eternal fidelity
and everlasting love.
Florentino Ariza...
get out of here!
Get out!
And don't show your face again for
the years of life that are left to you.
And I hope there are
very few of them.
Florentino Ariza!
Florentino!
Ah!
- That's not a telegram, Carlos.
- Come on, come on.
Deliver this, please,
to Senor Lorenzo Daza.
Old house,
Park of Evangels.
New in town,
a rough diamond.
Owns mules,
lots of mules.
Thank you, Lotario.
Thank you.
Yes yes, I'm coming.
I'm coming.
Last time you charged me
400 gold pesos,
that's double what I paid for this
whole abbey cloister... what?!
Senor Lorenzo Daza.
Yes.
Oh, good news.
Good news!
No reply.
Look at the shape
of the letter.
Not "U" but "A."
M-me...
M-m... me...
mis...
mist...
mistook...
Senor, Senor!
Tak... mistook...
mistake-taken...
Good.
Very good.
Mistook, mistake,
mistaken.
- What do you want?
- Look, I didn't do anything.
Don't you greet
your mother?
Florentino,
have you eaten?
Have you eaten?
"Fermina Daza,
for I have learned
that is your majestic
immortal name.
I write
this very short note
in order
to let you know...
that I love you."
- You haven't been to bed.
- Shh!
- Are you ill?
- No.
You are so pale, my son.
Are you sure?
- I'm not ill.
- Let me feel your head.
Let me feel your head.
What are you writing,
a book?
No, a letter.
All these pages,
and they're just one letter.
But what kind of a letter?
Holy Mother.
It is a love letter.
Oh, my son,
who is she?
Her name is...
Fermina Daza.
They're new in town.
Her mother is dead.
Her father owns mules.
And, Mama, I have discovered
the reason for my existence.
Don't talk such
nonsense, my son.
That's it!
Come on, come on,
come on.
But there is money in mules.
Does Fermina Daza
return your love?
"I've discovered..."
I don't know.
We haven't spoken.
That's why I'm writing
the letter.
If I can find the opportunity,
I'll give it to her,
but she's always
with her aunt.
Then you must
win over the aunt, not the girl.
It's him!
It is the telegram boy.
Walk on.
Eh-hh.
- Let me stand next to her.
- No!
Senorita Daza,
all I ask is that you accept
a letter from me.
- Not now.
- When?
Afterwards.
Corpus Christi.
- Corpus Christi.
- Amen.
Welcome, Fernando!
Papa, I'm going
to wish
Mother Superior
a happy Christmas.
This is the greatest moment
in my life.
Give it to me.
It was very long.
I made it shorter.
Wait!
It's a flower
of promising.
Go.
And don't see me again
until you hear from me.
My Holy Mother.
It is cholera, my son.
It is cholera.
- No, Mama.
- My son!
I gave her the letter.
Now I must wait
for her reply.
Yeah.
Then enjoy your pain.
Take advantage of it now
while you are young.
And suffer, my son,
suffer all you can,
because these things don't
last your whole life.
May she answer soon.
She won't.
Florentino!
What the hell
you are doing?
It's not an American ship,
it's British.
It's the mail from Liverpool.
British.
Come here.
What is wrong with you?
This isn't love.
It's madness.
Give me, give me.
Up up up up.
No, wait wait.
Fly now, go.
What is wrong
with you?
You need to take
your mind off her.
Come with me
to the whorehouse if...
Yes?
Oh, how much is it
to send a telegram
to the village
of Piedras de Moler?
- Piedras de Moler?
- Uh-huh.
Uh... let me see.
It's...
it's not on our list.
You don't... you don't
send telegrams to Piedras de Moler?
- No.
- Th... then...
good day to you.
Senorita!
"Dear Florentino Ariza...
I am sorry that I have
made you wait so long
for my reply.
I ask your forgiveness.
Please, write to me
again soon."
"Crowned goddess, I enclose
what I know is
a worthless memento.
I also write this verse
in honor of my love for you."
"I think of you every moment.
Now that spring is here,
thoughts of you fill me with life.
I will love you forever.
Forever."
Shh-hhh.
Shhh.
- It's him.
- Of course it's him.
- Senorita Escolastica?
- Shhh.
Senorita Escolastica,
please turn apart so I can talk
privately to the young lady.
I have something important
to ask her.
What impertinence!
There's nothing that has to do with her
that I cannot hear.
Then I will not
say anything.
But I warn you,
you will be responsible
for the consequences.
- Fermina Daza.
- I am here.
We've written
too many letters
and too much time
has passed.
So now...
crowned goddess,
I make this vow.
I swear to you
my eternal fidelity
and everlasting love,
and I ask in all humility
to do me the great honor
of marrying me.
You...
you must give me time.
Fermina, say yes!
Fermina, I may not be married,
but I know about love.
Even if you're
dying of fear,
even if you are sorry later,
because whatever you do,
you will be sorry
all the rest of your life if you say no.
Believe me, I know
what I'm talking about.
Yes, very well.
I will marry you
if you... if you promise
not to make me eat
eggplant.
Who is he?
Who is this
Florentino Ariza?
Huh?
And Mother Superior
says that you write letters to him?
And you... you!
You are to blame.
No!
Aunt!
Daughter, daughter,
listen to your father.
Listen to your father.
Everything I do,
I do it because...
because I...
okay, I'll try.
I'll try, but...
but I have to... I have to ex...
I have to explain myself.
It's difficult because I'm a plain man.
But ever since
your mother died,
you've been...
a daughter...
a daughter is a jewel.
Is a jewel. I'm...
I'm... I'm a rough diamond, but you're...
you're...
you're the... the crown.
And I don't... I don't...
I don't work for me.
We didn't come here for me.
We came here for you.
For you!
But you don't know how...
just how beautiful you are.
You-you-you...
you're... you're...
you're much too beautiful
to marry a telegraph operator.
We have bigger fish to fry,
and believe me... believe me,
at your age,
love is an illusion.
Christ, by Christ I swear,
I swear,
I swear to Christ...
Good morning,
good morning.
You and I must talk...
man to man.
Ahhhh.
When my wife died
I set myself one goal.
One goal...
to turn my daughter
into a great lady.
Now that's... that's a long road
to travel for a mule trader.
I've never had a drink
this early in the morning.
Better start now.
You're going to need it.
I came to this town
because...
well, here was the possibility
of a grand marriage.
Then an unforeseen
obstacle
to the plan that I have
fought for with my life...
you.
So I've come to make
a polite request.
Get out of our way.
Have you spoken to her?
None of that. None of that.
This is a matter for men
and it will be decided
by men.
Be that as it may,
I cannot answer without knowing
what she thinks.
Don't force me
to shoot you.
Shoot me.
There is no greater glory
than to die for love.
Pack!
- Where are we going?
- To our death!
You'd better explain.
I'm not leaving.
Take it to him now.
- What is this?
- They leaving.
They going
to the country.
- Hurry up!
- Where are you going?
He's taking me away.
- Sit down!
- Fermina.
Don't you dare
talk to him!
- Where are you talking her?
- He's taking me away!
Get out of our way.
Hyah!
Get back.
¢Ü I think of you
every day ¢Ü
a little bit more ¢Ü
¢Ü I tear my reason apart ¢Ü
¢Ü Something inside me
gets destroyed ¢Ü
C'mon, mule.
¢Ü I think of you
every day ¢Ü
a little bit more ¢Ü
¢Ü And I keep
thinking of you ¢Ü
thinking. ¢Ü
- That's bad. Five more.
- Take away all I have, right?
Aunt Fermina!
Senora, may I help you?
Hi, princess,
What are you here for?
Cousin Fermina?
I have a surprise for you.
Cousin.
He wants me to fix
a wedding date.
- Will you?
- Of course.
- Excuse me, Senoritas.
- Make it well into the future.
Your father said he will
keep you here for a year at least.
A year is nothing.
We will exchange telegrams
as we used to exchange
letters.
And our love will triumph.
There is no man on Earth more
perfect than Florentino Ariza.
And you, Hildebranda,
are you in love?
A married man.
20 years older than me.
Do you
exchange letters?
No.
Secret glances.
It all seems difficult
and impossible now,
but I just know that we must
learn to be happy without love.
And in spite of it.
Happy without love?
Yes.
Happy without love.
I want to eat the tender flesh
of every word
she has written to me
over and over.
I hope I survive.
- But danger is everywhere.
- Fire!
If the suffering of your own
heart doesn't kill you,
the ever-recurring
civil war might.
And there is the disease
that comes between
the burst of bloodshed,
the deadly choking embrace
of cholera.
Dead collectors!
My daughter is...
She is even more impossible
to predict than war.
She grabs hold,
then suddenly she lets go.
- Daddy! He's dead, too.
- She grabs hold,
she lets go.
Florentino!
Up here!
Stop it, stop it.
It will be all three of you, I promise.
All in good time.
So which one
is it going to be?
No no, my beloved
is returning soon.
I have to keep myself pure.
And I will only lose
my virginity for love.
Oooh.
That is such a bad idea.
Don't go, Florentino.
I will be back...
but not for some time.
Let's go, let's go.
So the worst years
of my life passed.
I counted the eternal minutes
one by one
as I waited for her return.
But I do not mind.
I will keep watch
for all of eternity.
until I die if need be.
I stand vigil for her
beside the lighthouse.
My heart is like the sea...
endless and everlasting,
even while it is as turbulent
as the crashing waves.
Florentino, what are
you doing here?
Ricardo, the young lady I'm going
to marry is coming back tonight.
I'm waiting for her.
Come on.
Come on!
Ricardo the lighthouse keeper
is my only friend.
He does not understand.
I must be here
to will her home.
I delegate to you the authority
to run this household...
and turn over to you
the keys to your life.
Crowned goddess, you are
the coming of the dawn.
Like spring, you have
returned to the one newborn.
Mom, Mom, there it is, Mom!
Yes, yes. Come on, come on.
- That one, too? That one.
- No no, that one over there.
Thank you.
Coconut candy!
Sweets for your sweetie.
The Arcade of Scribes is not
a place for a crowned goddess.
No.
No, please.
Forget it.
Wh-wh-what do you mean
"forget it"?
I just...
I just realized
this... this moment
when I saw you.
What?
What did you realize?
What is between us...
is nothing more
than an illusion.
It... it clouded
my eyes.
I'm so sorry.
You... you just...
realized it?
Yes.
The moment I saw you.
Make him well.
Please.
- Dr. Juvenal Urbino?
- He's a busy man.
- This is urgent.
- No. Appointments only.
Cholera... my mistress
has cholera.
No, you can't go up there.
You need to wear a mask.
I'm Hildebranda Sanchez,
the patient's cousin.
She's upstairs.
I would like you to be present, please,
when I examine her.
Her father's with her.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you for coming.
I pray to God
you can do something.
They say you know more
about cholera than a...
Under the tongue.
Vomiting?
How many times?
Once, twice?
Twice.
Diarrhea?
- Severe?
- I don't...
- What?
- I... I don't know.
I've never had it before.
Sit up, please.
It is an intestinal
infection.
What?
It's not cholera?
No.
I'll prescribe medicine.
Three days at home
and she'll be well again.
Did you hear that?
Oh.
Doctor, wait wait.
Doctor, wait! How did you learn
so much about cholera?
I, uh, studied in Paris
under Professor Proust.
All the things you've done
for the city... the clean water,
- closed sewage...
- Your daughter.
- Yes?
- She's very beautiful.
Thank you.
Senorita.
I would like to, um...
take your pulse.
Stick out
your tongue, please.
Mm-hmm.
You are like a...
a new-sprung rose.
Thank you.
Do you like music?
What is the point
of that question?
Music is important
for one's health.
No! No, don't!
Doctor!
Do not go.
I saw it all.
I... I told your daughter
that she is like a rose.
True enough, but one
with too many thorns.
Up up up!
You open that window and apologize.
I have nothing to apologize for.
I closed the window to keep out the sun.
Don't backtalk back to me, okay?
Do as I tell you.
Say something... now!
I offer you my most
heartfelt apology, sir.
Her education.
Let me escort you
to the carriage.
Senor.
I... I would like
your permission
to write
to your daughter.
Ahh.
I will go and find her.
I won't let her go.
My destiny in life
is to love Fermina.
I will win her back.
Hildebranda, look!
Aye, beautiful!
Mmmmm,
another one.
Gala Placidia, I told you
not to accept it.
Oh, I know that,
milady,
but is hard to say
no to Dr. Urbino.
How many is that now?
Seven.
- You must reply.
- We're not going to discuss it.
We must hurry.
The Belgian photographer
is expecting us.
Gala Placidia,
help us to dress.
Oh, yes, milady,
it is perfect.
Ladies, very still.
I will count
to five now.
One, two, three...
four, five.
One, two, three!
Benny Centeno!
Benny, Benny, Benny...
Move aside!
Benny!
Champion!
Please get in, I'll take you
wherever you want to go.
Benny, Benny, Benny!
Who is Benny Centeno?
He just won the boxing
championship in Panama.
Oh.
This is so nice.
I could spend the rest
of my life here.
Oh, ay, my boots
are killing me.
I'll have to take them off.
I'll take off mine too.
Let's see who
finishes first.
Oh!
Mmm.
You won.
But now I realize it
wasn't my boots at all.
It is this wire cage
under my skirt.
Hmm, nothing could
be simpler.
Take it off.
I won't look.
Ay!
I am waiting.
We want to go home.
Whoa whoa whoa.
Read my letters.
I want your answer.
He's very beautiful.
When he covered his eyes
and I saw his perfect teeth
between those rosy lips,
I wanted...
oooh, eeeoh.
I wanted to devour him
with kisses.
What a whore you are.
"Dear Senor Urbino,
I give you my permission
to speak to my father."
Senora.
Forgive me for keeping
you waiting, Transito,
but I have to practice
my singing.
You never know when there's
going to be a funeral, eh?
But, please please.
So...
is there a problem?
You get the money
I send each month?
Thank you.
You are a kind man, Don Leo.
I am not kind.
I am just,
unlike my brother Pius.
Something had to be done.
Pius should have made
a proper provision for my son.
Well, he did not
and I did.
So?
I've come...
to ask if
you can help him.
- Who?
- Your nephew.
My son Florentino.
What kind of help?
A job.
Well, I thought he had a job
at the telegraph office.
Yes, but I'm asking you
to find him another job...
any job, as long as
it's far away.
Some port lost
in the jungle where...
where there is no mail,
no telegraph.
A broken heart.
Yeah.
Hmm.
Hmmm.
How about Villa de Leyva?
How far away is that?
Oh...
about three weeks.
I am nothing.
I will not heal...
not for all time.
I'm struck by
the lightning of love
and burned beyond repair.
She's a splinter that
cannot be pulled out.
She's part of me,
everywhere I go.
Everywhere, she is.
- Hello.
- Fermina.
What are you doing?
Turn off the light.
I want...
absolute darkness.
You forget, Doctor,
this is the first time
I've slept
with a stranger.
Do you love me?
Don't be frightened.
We are man and wife.
I want you to love every...
every moment
of our honeymoon.
I can't wait
to show you Paris.
It is a...
a city of love.
You have
a beautiful smile.
Thank you.
I think my sense of smell
is overdeveloped.
Well, that would be because
your olfactory organ's...
I'm sorry
I mentioned it.
Shhh.
Don't forget I have
met them before.
I remember it
very well.
And I'm still angry.
I've... I've never been able to
understand how your thing works.
How ugly it is.
Even uglier than
a woman's thing.
Yes.
Besides, I think it has...
too many bits on it.
That's astounding.
My doctoral thesis was
on the advantage...
I don't want
a medical lesson.
No. No.
This is going to be
a lesson in love.
The black flag!
That's the plague flag.
Give them a wide berth.
Please, help us!
Captain!
- They're dying of cholera!
- Cholera!
Please!
Good Heavens! Careful,
don't get too close...
Please, help us!
Captain! Help us!
Cholera!
Help me! Please.
Don't leave.
God! What's that?
Help me! Please!
Keep her safe, protect her
from harm.
Good night,
my crowned goddess.
Go go.
Go on and forget all about it.
This never happened.
Who occupies that cabin...
the middle one?
- Three women.
- Three women?
They have three cabins
and they both connect together.
It makes one big one.
- Who are they, these women?
- I don't know.
- You go on.
- We'll see.
- See her eyes?
- My, Rosalba.
He looks very sweet.
And so shy.
It's the shy ones
you must look out for.
- Carefully, it's fragile.
- Get out of the way.
He's staring at you.
Bye!
Fermina, my vow...
I've broken my vow.
You shouldn't have
come back, my son.
I had to.
Why?
Something happened and...
I had to be near
Fermina again, Mama.
- That's all.
- But she's not here.
What do you mean
she's not here?
She's in Paris
on her honeymoon.
She'll be gone a long time...
more than one year.
Maybe two years.
- That's not true, Mama.
- It is true, my son.
- No.
- It is true.
At least two years.
- No.
- No, Mama.
Please don't cry.
Oh.
Please...
please don't waste your life.
You must forget her.
You must find someone else
who will help you forget.
I can't forget, Mama.
I will
never forget, Mama.
I will never forget, Mama.
Senora, senora!
Be careful! Senora!
- Senora.
- Come on, boys.
Open fire!
They destroyed my house,
Transito!
They destroyed my house.
Come in.
I need a bed...
on the floor, anywhere.
Just until I can
rebuild my house.
Who knows how long
this war will last.
Come on, drink.
You must stay here.
- So you have the room?
- No.
It is a shame.
My own bedroom is too small.
But if you don't mind...
sharing with my son.
Florentino?
An emergency.
The Widow Nazaret,
her house has been damaged.
War has no respect
for anybody.
She needs a bed.
You can sleep in your hammock.
I'm so scared!
If it wasn't enough
to lose my husband,
now this.
He died three years ago.
Help me, help me.
My dead husband
always undid my laces.
Help me, please.
Help me.
I've never been
in the same bed
with any other man...
ay... other than
my dead husband.
He's in his coffin now
under the ground.
I'm so happy!
I'm happy
because only now
do I know for certain
where he is
when he's not at...
home!
Women.
Number one...
unknown lady in boat.
The first...
wondrous...
explosion.
Number two...
the Widow Nazaret...
while doing it,
only talks of
her dead husband.
Number three...
Esmeralda Arau...
a skinny,
wiggling tadpole
who'd walk me
through the ferns.
Number four...
Maria Estevez...
very dangerous.
We were so close
to the street,
anyone could
have heard us.
This is the cure
for the pain
of Fermina.
What is it?
Nothing, my son, nothing.
- For a moment I...
- What?
I didn't know
who you were.
It happens to me
more and more,
but it... it goes.
Give me your hand.
Ma... I have work
to do, Mama.
Work? What work?
You need to find a job and to get paid.
I can't keep you forever.
I... I... I have
something to tell you.
You are going
to marry the widow.
Oh, no.
- What did you say?
- Ma... Mama...
Did you say you had
something to tell me?
Yes, I honestly believe...
I'm getting over the worst.
What was her name again?
Fermina.
I begin to feel free.
The pain is gone.
It's gone.
Now, it took Paris,
the city of love, to bring about
this blessed
transformation.
But here we are
amongst our dearest friends.
We are happier than
you can know to be here.
And furthermore,
we are overjoyed
to no longer
be two, but three.
The great purpose
of marriage has made itself clear to all
and we thank you,
our dear friends, for your warmth
and your congratulations.
Well, I was wondering
how long it would be
before you came begging me.
- What do you want?
- A job.
I gave you a job...
at Villa de Leyva
and you threw it away.
It is different now.
I want to be
rich like you.
I am not rich.
I'm a poor man with money
which is not the same thing.
Why do you
want to be rich?
So that I can be
someone in society,
I need... I need to be worthy
of a great lady I cannot stop loving.
Who is she?
Married?
Yes, but I'm waiting
for her husband to die.
Is he old?
No, but I'll wait
for however long it takes.
- You're crazy.
- Why?
Because insanity
runs in the family.
You take after
your father.
You never knew him,
my brother Pius.
You know what
his last words were?
He said "The only regret I have
in dying is that I do not die for love."
He said that?
- He really said that?
- On his deathbed.
Nevertheless, all his life he fucked
everything in sight.
So...
you want a job in the River
Company of the Caribbean.
Yes, yes.
Well, are you any good
at, um, writing letters?
I think so, I...
I... I write poetry, too
I enter a poem every year
in the Poetic Festival.
I have never won, but...
So, you have a way
with words, huh?
- Yes.
- Good.
Perhaps you can tell me
what this means.
On my birthday last year
someone made
a speech in my honor.
He said I suffered
from lucid dementia.
Now what does that mean?
Lucid dementia
means you are clearly crazy.
I told you it
ran in the family.
Start tomorrow.
Clerk to the board of directors.
Tamales! Tamales!
Magic inks.
Very light blow.
Invisible ink
for your secret letter.