I busied myself
to think of a story...
which would speak to the mysterious
fears of our nature...
and awaken thrilling horror--
one to make the reader
dread to look around--
to curdle the blood...
and quicken the beatings
of the heart.
Tell the captain
we've got to take in...
the top sail!
She's going to rip!
Please, Captain!
We have to drop the sails!
All hands to the mast!
Take the wheel! Come on!
We're dead!
We've hit the ice!
Iceberg ahead!
Hard to starboard!
Help!
Hold on men!
Put your backs into it, men!
- Let's go!
- Captain, this is useless.
- The ice stretches for miles.
- Do you suggest we lay down and die?
The men are exhausted.
They can't go on.
I have not come this tar
to give up now.
They knew the risk when they signed on.
And we're gonna chop our way
to the North Pole if we have to.
Then you run the risk
of mutiny, Captain.
- Did you say "mutiny"?
- Yes, I did, sir.
We proceed north as planned.
- At the cost of how many more lives?
- As many as it takes!
There's something out there.
What the hell is that?
Who is your captain?
I am.
Who the devil are you?
I have no time to talk. Bring your men
and weapons and follow me.
- Now!
- Stay where you are!
I give the orders here.
Stop the dogs! Get them!
Leave them.
They're already dead.
Get back to the ship now!
Everybody back to the ship!
Bears don't kill like that!
Nothing does!
Maybe it wants that man.
- Or it wants the captain.
- It's the devil come for the captain.
For the last time, I made my way from
St. Petersburg to Archangel on toot.
From there I took
a whaling ship north.
When we hit the ice,
I used the dogs.
What's out there?
Listen to me.
I have spent six years planning this.
My entire fortune.
I will not be stopped by you
or some phantom.
Do you share my madness?
No, not madness.
What, then?
There's a passage to the North Pole,
and I will find it.
At the cost of your own life?
The lives of your crew?
Lives come and go.
If we succeed, our names
will live on forever.
I will be hailed
as the benefactor of our species.
You're wrong.
I, of all men, know that.
Who are you?
My name...
is Victor Frankenstein.
Oh, my wonderful son, Victor.
You are the handsomest,
kindest, cleverest...
most wonderfulest boy
in the whole world.
Madam, you will spoil the boy.
Would you and your daughter
leave us, please, Mrs. Moritz?
Come along, Justine.
Victor, this is Elizabeth.
She's coming to live with us.
She's lost both her mother
and father...
to the scarlet fever, Victor.
She's an orphan now.
You must think of her
as your own sister.
You must look after her,
and be kind to her.
Always.
Mother! How is the imminent arrival?
Oh, a little frisky today.
When you were a little boy, you
used to chase fireflies in the field.
Yes, and when I'd trap them
in my jar, they died.
- Do you remember how you cried?
- Yes.
Because you wanted to keep them glowing
by your bedside...
to light you as you read.
You were so hungry for knowledge.
Such a serious little boy.
You've become
such an earnest young man.
All these strange and ancient books.
You'll be an even greater doctor
than your father.
But you know, Victor,
life shouldn't be all study.
There's such fun to be had.
Give me that back, Mother.
Change partners and twirl!
Caroline, you mustn't
exert yourself. Please.
Don't worry, madam.
Your new baby will be a natural dancer.
Excellent.
You'll be the envy
of all the young ladies and gentlemen.
Please, Justine,
may I have this dance?
Madam.
Come on. That's it.
You must make a decision.
- The baby's in the wrong position.
- Cut me.
Oh, I cant.
Cut me. Save the baby.
She'll be all right.
Father's the finest doctor in Geneva.
Father?
Well, how is she?
I did everything I could.
Mother!
Bring her back.
Please bring her back.
Oh, Mother,
you should never have died.
No one need ever die.
I will stop this.
I promise.
Victor, you're completely obsessed.
Please explain what that is.
It's energy. It never disappears.
It merely changes form.
It's possible to convert this candle wax
into a mechanical dog's convulsions.
The applications of this
are limitless. Really.
Well, please come outside, Victor.
It's such a beautiful day.
Go away. I'm busy.
What's this?
It's for spraying down
the electric eels.
Now put it down.
It's not for playing with.
Don't do that.
Give me that.
Yes, come on! After all,
we should be grateful to Victor...
for abandoning his experiments
for one afternoon.
Well, who says I have?
- What do you mean?
- Look!
We're all going to die.
You knew this was going to happen.
Not for certain. But I had hoped
the conditions would be right.
But I've never seen one quite as large
as that. Look, it's wonderful!
- You shouldn't have done this.
- It's all right.
- We must take cover. A tree!
- That's exactly the wrong thing to do.
- It's a larger conductor than we are.
- What about Willie?
- What are we to do?
- Come on!
Spread out!
Elizabeth, take this.
- Come on! Quickly!
- What is that?
- Dig it right into the ground.
- Now what?
Everyone down. Quickly!
Give me your hands.
It'll be fine.
- That's good.
- I hope you know what you're doing.
Willie, don't look up!
Wait.
One, two, three!
Now.
So how do you feel, Elizabeth?
Alive.
Ladies and gentlemen,
dear friends...
gather around and listen.
As you probably know,
tomorrow my dear son Victor...
leaves me to pursue
what I'm sure...
will be an illustrious career
in a profession...
that I myself am not altogether
unassociated with.
Though, my--
My one regret is that his mother--
my late wife--
is not here...
to share the fire...
which our son fills me with tonight.
Yes.
She wanted you to have this, Victor,
on your graduation.
And in it she has written...
"This is the journal
of Victor Frankenstein."
The rest of the leaves are blank...
to be filled with the deeds
of a noble life.
We'd better go in
before they miss us.
Just a little while longer,
please.
I don't know when
we'll be alone together again.
Oh, dear Victor.
I'll miss you laughing at me.
I'll miss you making me laugh.
So...
how do brothers and sisters
say good-bye?
Perhaps they never have to.
I won't if you won't.
Are you my sister?
Sister.
Friend.
Lover.
Wife?
Yes.
Then come with me to Ingolstadt.
Marry me now.
- No.
- Then I'll stay.
I want more than anything else
in the world to be your wife.
But as long as you're away,
I belong here.
I want to make this house live again.
I want to make this
a great home for our children.
And now you must go,
and do the great things you need to do.
I want you so much.
I'll be here when you return.
Each holiday.
Every visit.
And on our wedding night.
Until our wedding night.
A lot of stairs, I'm afraid.
How was your journey?
Very good, thank you.
I made good progress in the mountains.
Good. I'm pleased. As I've said,
we've only got attic space.
That's exactly what I'm looking for.
But Frau Brach...
there will be a great deal
of scientific equipment and rigging...
to be delivered every day
for the next week.
I trust you've no objections.
I'm sure you appreciate the need
for a proper laboratory.
Oh, Putzi likes you.
This will be perfect.
The foolish and vain
force their views by the rod...
but "knowledge is power
only through God. "
Our motto. Easily forgotten...
by you young men in a hurry.
But perhaps the greatest mistake...
that all students make
during their time here...
is to suppose
that they can ever have...
an original or creative thought.
We have all imagined that in our time.
But gentlemen,
you have not come here...
in order to think for yourselves.
You are here to learn how to think
for your patients.
You must learn, therefore,
in the first place...
to submit yourselves...
to the established laws
of physical reality.
But surely, Professor...
you don't intend we disregard
more philosophical approaches?
Philosophical?
Those which stir the imagination
as well as the intellect.
Paracelsus, for example.
Ah, Paracelsus.
An arrogant and foolish Swiss.
Albertus Magnus.
His nonsense was exploded...
500 years ago.
Cornelius Agrippa.
A sorcerer, an occultist.
What is your name?
Victor Frankenstein, sir.
Of Geneva.
Oh, another Swiss.
Mr. Frankenstein...
here at the University of Ingolstadt
we teach...
and indeed hope to advance,
the science of medicine.
Chemistry, biology, physics.
We study hard science.
But surely, Professor, the greatest
advances come in combining these things.
We do not study the ravings
of lunatics and alchemists...
hundreds of years in their graves.
Because their kind...
of amateur, fanatical,
fantastical speculation...
does not heal bodies or save lives.
Only science can do that.
Now, have we your permission
to continue?
- Nice coat.
- Thank you.
Don't take it too hard. Krempe just
doesn't approve of public humiliation.
- I am not mad.
- My dear fellow, of course you're not.
In fact, that's just the sort of thing
I'd expect a rational person...
to say to a complete stranger.
Henry Clerval, by the way,
and I'm completely crazy.
- Victor Frankenstein.
- Of Geneva.
Why don't you look where I'm going?
That's Schiller,
ornament of the playing field.
- Really?
- You can tell he's new.
He goes around looking at things
with his mouth open.
What are you here for?
- Research.
- Very grand.
I'm here to become
a mere doctor.
I'm told that has something to do
with healing the sick...
but I find sick people
rather revolting.
Still, I'll have a good time...
get my degree--
if I can stop failing anatomy--
and settle down to relieve rich ladies
of their imaginary aliments...
and then relieve their very real
and beautiful daughters.
Who was that?
He was at the lecture.
That's Waldman.
Yes. Interesting case.
They say in his youth he could break
into heaven and lecture God on science.
Ran into trouble with the authorities
a few years back.
Something to do
with illegal experiments.
What kind of experiments, I wonder?
What was it you were saying?
Rich old ladies and their daughters?
Yes, it's a life of sacrifice,
I know, but someone's got to do it.
That is why the central nervous system
and its crowning achievement...
the brain, are as complicated
and mysterious a set of organs...
as you are ever likely to encounter.
Mr. Frankenstein,
the incision is yours.
Excellent.
Mr. Clerval, you may remove
the cranial lid.
"Henry has now fully recovered and
continues his struggle to pass anatomy."
I was always terrible at anatomy.
"Professor Waldman is very tolerant
of him and myself.
I am learning a great deal.
Professor Waldman is remarkable."
- And so is Henry.
- "God bless you all. My Love, Victor."
- That's very nice.
- "P.S. I've fallen in love."
- I beg your pardon!
- "She's dark, sleek and beautiful...
and always wags her tail
whenever she sees me.
Her name is Putzi, and she's the
friendliest sheepdog I've ever known."
"P.S. Elizabeth, I dream of how your
hair shines in the moonlight."
Of how your lips taste.
I dream of your arms and your breasts...
and of the time on our wedding night...
when we will be alone together
at last.
What else does it say?
It says, "I'm working very hard
and making lots of new friends."
Coffee, anyone?
Once and for all, Frankenstein.
Life is life. Death is death.
These things are real.
That is rubbish,
and you know it.
That premise has been repeatedly
challenged by your own staff members.
We don't know where life ends
or death begins.
Hair and fingernails continue to grow
after what we choose to call death.
We know that a man's brain, heart and
lungs may continue to pump and breathe.
Now, you know that!
Mr. Frankenstein of Geneva, I warn you,
what you are suggesting...
is not only illegal,
it is immoral.
Rubbish!
"Dear Diary, Why does no one
understand me?
P.S. I am not mad."
You! Explain yourself!
Professor, I'm sorry. Listen. I came
here to learn all about the new science.
Galvanism, Franklin's experiments.
The combination of modern disciplines...
with ancient knowledge
in an attempt to protect and create--
To create what?
So we can change things.
We can make things better.
You know that. We are on the verge
of undreamt-of discoveries...
if we've the courage
to ask the right questions.
Now, you must help me. Please!
Come on.
Lock the door.
Now, for thousands of years, the Chinese
have based their medical science...
on the belief that the human body is
a chemical engine run by energy streams.
But how do they explain--
Don't touch that!
Their doctors treat patients
by inserting needles like these...
into the flesh at various key points
to manipulate these electric streams.
I see.
So electricity is the key.
Now look at this.
Go on. Touch it.
- It feels warm.
- Yes.
Yes. How do you do?
- Turn it oft!
- I can't. It's not working.
Try to stay calm. It's simply
a matter of reducing the polarity.
- A monkey's arm is like a human's.
- No arm is this strong!
Now, this must work.
Let me help you, Professor.
You shall, of course, tell no one.
They wouldn't believe you anyway.
"Dearest Victor,
Nothing much changes here.
Mrs. Moritz continues to love
and torment Justine in equal measure.
Willie grows more precocious
every day...
and Father almost expires with pride at
the very thought of you and your work.
And l-- Well, I just miss you.
Very much.
Please write soon, Victor."
No, I'm serious.
You take vaccine, for instance.
Thirty years ago, the entire concept
of vaccine was unheard of...
and now we save lives every day.
- But that isn't the whole answer.
- What do you mean?
Eventually, the best way to cheat death
will be to create life.
Now you've gone too far.
There's only one God, Victor.
Leave God out of this. Listen.
Say someone you love has a sick heart.
- Would you give them a healthy one?
- Impossible.
We can do it.
If we can replace one part of a human
being, we can replace every part.
And if we can do that,
we can design a life.
We can create a being
that will not grow old or sicken.
One that will be stronger than us,
better than us.
One that will be more intelligent,
more civilized than us.
- In our lifetime?
- No.
How close did you get, Professor?
Too close.
Professor, I beg you,
let me see these notes.
My work now and its application
lies exclusively...
in the preservation of life.
I abandoned my other researches
many years ago.
Why?
Because they resulted in abomination.
You're not sticking that in me.
It's got a pox in it, I hear.
- Pox? They're giving us pox?
- That's right.
It's a vaccine that will prevent
a plague in this city.
Just tiny harmless amounts
of anti-smallpox serum.
- You just said pox!
- I said it was harmless.
It's a necessary precaution
without which this godforsaken city...
would be immediately
put under quarantine.
I don't care what you doctors tell me.
You're not sticking that in me!
Yes, I am! It's the law!
Now, sit him down, someone.
- Come on.
- You're not sticking that in me!
- Sir?
- Professor?
Get him!
Come on!
It's no use, Victor.
He's gone.
Let him go.
This shouldn't happen.
It need not happen!
To hell with you!
Whatever you say,
whatever you call it...
you doctors are killers!
You murder people!
Evil! You're evil!
You're the ones deserve to die!
God will punish you!
My God, you were so close.
Of course, the power!
The materials were wrong.
You needed auxiliary sources.
Yes, the experiment.
A failure? "Resulting reanimant...
malformed and hideous to behold.
This factor dependent
on the appropriate raw materials."
Raw materials.
- Come on, Henry.
- I can't help you.
- What are you frightened of?
- Everything.
- What if the authorities--
- We'll do this in secret.
I've got the raw materials.
I've got Waldman's journals.
- You stole Waldman's journals?
- We owe it to him to complete his work.
- He was one step away.
- He never wanted this.
- He couldn't face it.
- Even if it were possible...
and even if you had the right, which
you don't, to make this decision...
can you imagine for one second there
wouldn't be a terrible price to pay?
I think for the chance
to defeat death and disease--
to let everyone on this earth
have the chance of life--
sustained, healthy life--
to allow people to love each other,
to be together forever--
for all of that,
I think it's a risk worth taking.
Please, Justine, just leave me alone.
I won't talk about it.
All these letters.
You read them to us every week.
I wrote the letters!
He hasn't written to me in months.
Something horrific is happening to him.
I can feel it.
At first I wasn't sure, but I knew
I had to hide it from Father.
Now there are rumors of cholera.
I can look after Father and Willie.
You go to Ingolstadt.
That's not possible. He won't want me.
He's probably found someone else!
It he was mine,
I would have gone already!
But he isn't mine.
He's yours.
And you must go to him.
Raw materials,
that's all they are.
Tissue to be reused.
The very finest brain.
- But they all died of cholera, sir.
- No matter.
Thank you.
Now, the assembled organs must have
the appropriate nutrients and heat.
And crucially, more direct power.
More direct power.
Amniotic fluid is the chief
biogenic element.
The subject is injected with this.
The acupuncture needles pierce the flesh
at all key energy points.
After the removal of current,
a dead toad should retain animation...
but independently
of external power sources.
Yes!
That's it!
That's the combination!
Open the door!
- Victor, please!
- What do you want?
It's cholera.
It's an epidemic.
The city's been placed
under martial law.
- Are you listening to me?
- Yes. And?
The militia's arriving
to quarantine the city.
Most of us are getting out
while we still can.
Krempe knows you're here.
What if he tells the authorities?
Good-bye, Henry.
Victor, it's me! Elizabeth.
Can you hear me?
Victor, I have to see you.
- Go away!
- Please, Victor!
I won't leave here
until you see me!
Come in the side door.
Alone!
What's happened to you?
How can you live here like this?
And that stench!
Don't go in there!
- We have to leave. It isn't sate.
- No, I have to stay.
- Even if it means you will die?
- Yes.
Well, let me help you.
No, that's impossible.
We made a promise.
Victor, I beg you.
Look, I know that this is difficult
for you to understand...
but I cannot abandon
this work now.
It is too important.
Not just for me, but...
believe me, for everyone.
And it must come first.
Before us?
I love you so much.
But--
Good-bye.
Oh, God! Elizabeth!
Live! Live!
Yes!
It's alive.
What have I done?
Massive birth defects.
Greatly enhanced physical strength.
But resulting...
reanimant...
is malfunctional...
and pitiful...
and dead.
Tomorrow, this journal
and its secrets must be destroyed.
Forever.
Oh, God.
You tool, Victor Frankenstein
of Geneva!
How could you know
what you'd unleashed?
How is it pieced together?
With bits of thieves,
bits of murderers?
Evil stitched to evil
stitched to evil.
Do you really believe this thing
will thank you for its monstrous birth?
Evil will have its revenge.
God help your loved ones!
What do you think you're doing?
He's got cholera! He's the one
who's been spreading the plague!
Get him!
- Get him!
- Kill him!
Come here, you--
Keep away from him!
Kill him now!
He went this way!
There now. Easy.
Easy. Just a bit.
That's it.
There now. Rest easy.
- Henry, you're here.
- Of course I'm here.
It was touch and go with you, though.
Just a bit more.
I teared cholera.
Turned out to be pneumonia.
Yes, I'm becoming
something of a doctor.
Even Krempe seems pleased with me.
At this rate,
I might even pass anatomy.
- The-- The epidemic.
- Dreadful.
There's nothing we can do for them.
The vulnerable,
anyone who's without shelter or food--
the newborn especially will die.
Are you sure?
I'm certain of it.
Thank God.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
Well, then, that's my shift finished.
I'll see you later.
- Oh, please, forgive me.
- Of course I do.
Victor, I don't know
what you were working on.
I don't want to know,
but it nearly killed you!
It's over. It's finished.
It should never have started.
It's dead!
- Felix.
- Yes?
Don't forget the onion scraps.
- All right, I've got them.
- Make sure the shed door is shut.
Go on! Get!
Come on.
Get out!
- How are the pigs?
- They're happy. They've been fed.
- How're your hands?
- They're bleeding again.
Let me see them.
That's better.
There.
- Soup's ready.
- Come on, Grandpa. Sit down.
Thank you.
We'll never get through the winter
with this yield.
The ground's frozen hard.
- We'll sell another pig at market.
- We can't.
Not until they lift the quarantine.
Even then, it's one less for us.
And he'll be back
for last month's rent soon.
Come on!
We'll do this together.
You're right.
We've got to.
Before the snow comes.
Come on, then.
The ground's frozen solid.
We haven't the strength.
We'd need 20 men to work this field!
It's useless!
- We should stop. It's late.
- We don't have enough to eat!
We'll manage.
Let's go.
Look!
They must be gifts from
the good spirit of the forest!
Father, nothing in this life
comes tree of cost.
I'd like to know who and why.
Was it, Grandpa?
- Was it the good spirit?
- I believe it was.
Will you stop tilling their head
with nonsense?
Who's there?
Felix? Children?
Right.
What's this one?
"Frie--
nd."
Friend?
Well done!
That's very good.
You've got lots of friends,
haven't you?
Grandpa's your friend.
- Thomas is your friend.
- Friend.
Friend.
Family.
Father.
This is important. You must
travel with him the entire journey.
This equipment must not be
left unattended.
My father will personally take delivery
in Geneva. Understand?
- I do.
- Thank you.
- Going somewhere?
- Look at this locket Victor gave me.
- Isn't it beautiful?
- Lovely. Is this really you?
It's a bad likeness, but for now,
it'll serve instead of a ring.
Congratulations!
This is entirely expected!
- When?
- As soon as we get home!
I can't believe we'll be there
for New Year's eve.
- Victor's taking his father's practice.
- And expand it.
I'm going ahead, now that quarantine's
lifted. There's so much to do!
The practice needs a partner.
There's not much money.
But there is food and board
and some very good company.
And it's the ideal position for someone
who has finally passed anatomy.
So we were wondering if there was
anybody you could recommend?
- I don't know what to say.
- Please say yes.
And you can write that down
in your journal!
"This is the...
journal of...
Victor...
Frankenstein...
of Geneva."
Come on. Quickly!
Oft you go! Quickly now!
Merry Christmas!
Come on. Time for bed.
In you go.
"For the good spirit...
of the forest."
Are you the good spirit
of the forest?
Not exactly.
Where's your father?
I said, where's your father?
Who's there? Maggie?
Oh. It's you.
What have you done to Maggie?
Is he in there,
hiding behind a blind old man?
Get away!
Don't blame me.
Blame your son
for not paying his rent on time!
Oh, my God!
Thank you so much, my friend.
Won't you come sit by the tire?
Please. Don't be afraid.
Come.
Come in.
Have a rest. Sit down.
There. That's better.
That's better.
I'm glad you finally came in.
A man shouldn't have to hide
in the shadows.
Better that way.
For me.
Why?
People are afraid.
Except you.
It can't be as bad as that.
Worse.
I can see you with my hands.
It you'll trust me.
Papa! He hurt Grandpa!
- Who hurt Grandpa?
- What was that noise?
- Tell me what the noise was!
- What happened?
You poor man.
Have you no friends?
There are some people.
But they don't know me.
Why do you not go to them?
Because...
I am so very...
ugly.
And they are...
so very...
beautiful.
Father!
Get out of here!
You animal!
- You monster!
- Leave him alone!
It's all right.
We have to leave here.
I will have revenge!
Geneva.
Quickly!
She's here! We got your letter!
- Did you?
- It was the first one I could read!
- Congratulations! I'm happy for you.
- Thank you, Justine.
Is that the locket?
Look how handsome Victor is.
Elizabeth, can I take this
to show Peter?
- It's not a toy!
- Let him go. Don't dawdle, William!
Justine, you idiot!
Pay attention!
Anyone would think
you're the one getting married.
- Yes, Mother.
- What's wrong?
Nothing, really.
Just leave it!
You've ruined it now.
You! Quickly!
- Have you seen Willie?
- Isn't he back yet?
Claude went to see if he lost track
of time. They say he never arrived.
It's far too late
for him to still be out.
This isn't a game!
It's so late!
We're all so tired.
I'm so tired.
Father! I am so pleased to see you!
What's wrong?
We checked the east ridge.
There's nothing there.
Damn!
We found him!
I found him.
We did everything we could, sir.
You just rest easy now.
We did everything we could.
Sir, I'm terrified for my girl.
She's still out looking for William.
We parted badly.
I was cruel to her.
I didn't mean it!
I think she finds it very hard now
with your wedding.
She loves you dearly.
I couldn't bear it if anything happened
to her. She's all I've got.
Please help me!
We'll organize another search
now that it's light.
We'll find her, Mrs. Moritz.
I promise.
- How is Father?
- His heart is breaking.
Mr. Frankenstein, we've apprehended the
murderer, not five miles from here...
hiding in a barn.
We found this on her.
'Tis yours, I believe, sir.
Sir, you must come immediately.
The townspeople have gone mad.
- What are they doing?
- They must have broken into the jail!
- For God's sake! Can't you stop them?
- They've gone wild! It's a lynch mob!
Stop! This is unlawful!
Victor! Help me!
I was trying to find him!
I went to the lake!
But it was dark!
I wanted to bring him to you!
He must be there for the wedding!
I'm sorry! He's so tiny!
We managed to close the gates
on the mob, Claude.
What about Justine?
We cut her down, sir.
We can bury her in the morning.
Thank you, Claude. Get to bed.
The sea of ice.
I will meet you there.
On the sea of ice.
Oh, Justine, forgive me.
Victor, tell me.
Who is this man?
How do you know he's responsible?
-I'll tell you after I've destroyed him.
-This is a matter for the police!
They wouldn't understand.
Well, neither do I!
Then just accept it.
Get up.
You do speak.
Yes, I speak.
And read.
And think.
And know the ways of man.
How did you find me?
Your journal.
Then you mean to kill me.
You murdered my brother, didn't you?
I took him by the throat
with one hand...
and lifted him off the ground.
Slowly crushed his neck.
And as I killed him...
I saw your face.
You gave me these emotions...
but you didn't tell me
how to use them.
Now, two people are dead...
because of us.
Why?
There was something at work
in my soul...
which I do not understand.
What of my soul? Do I have one?
Or was that a part you left out?
Who were these people
of which I am comprised?
Good people?
Bad people?
- Materials, nothing more.
- You're wrong.
Did you know
I knew how to play this?
In which part of me
did this knowledge reside?
In these hands?
In this mind?
In this heart?
And reading.
And speaking.
Not things learned
so much as things...
remembered.
Trace memories in the brain, perhaps.
Did you ever consider
the consequences of your actions?
You gave me life.
But then you left me to die.
Who am I?
You--
I don't know.
And you think I am evil?
What can I do?
There is something I want.
A friend.
Companion.
A female.
Someone like me...
so she won't hate me.
Like you?
Oh, God.
You don't know what you're asking.
I do know that...
with the sympathy of one living being...
I would make peace with all.
I have love in me,
the likes of which...
you can scarcely imagine...
and rage...
the likes of which
you would not believe.
It I cannot satisfy the one...
I will indulge the other.
And...
if I consent...
how will you live?
We would travel north,
my bride and I...
to the furthest reaches of the pole...
where no man has ever set foot.
There...
we would live out our lives.
Together.
No human eye
would ever see us again.
This I vow.
You must help me.
Please.
If it is possible
to right this wrong...
then I will do it.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm all right.
I'm safe.
What happened?
Tell us.
Victor, you have to tell us
what happened!
One month! That's all I ask!
Then we can be married
and forget this whole business!
- I promise!
- Promise?
Don't dare use that word to me!
You promised to tell me who this man is.
You promised to abandon
this work for good!
Your promises don't mean anything.
I have to leave this house.
- Where will you go?
- Somewhere I can recover.
This is ridiculous!
I haven't got time to argue!
Isn't it convenient?
Doesn't it fit in with your plans?
Don't you ever think of anyone
or anything but yourself?
God forgive me.
Why her?
Materials, remember?
Nothing more.
Your words.
You will honor your promise to me.
I will not.
Go on. Kill me now.
That is mild compared to what will come.
If you deny me my wedding night,
I will be with you on yours.
Wait! Please wait!
I have to speak to you.
Please!
What do you want to say?
Don't go.
Please.
I'm frightened.
Of what?
I have done something...
so terrible...
so evil.
And I am frightened...
that if I tell you the truth...
that I will lose you.
You'll lose me if you don't.
I...
don't know...
what...
to do.
Will you marry me?
Marry me today.
Tomorrow...
tell me everything.
But you must tell me the truth.
And together we can face anything.
Whatever you've done...
whatever has happened...
I love you.
To share the truth...
the whole truth...
for good or ill.
To stand by each other...
in sickness and in health...
and in joy...
from this day forward...
till death do you part.
Who is this man?
How shall we know him?
- Believe me, you'll know him.
- He killed Master William.
And Justine Moritz died for it.
No hesitation, lads!
Shoot the bastard on sight!
- Henry.
- Don't worry about a thing.
You two look after each other.
I'll look after your father.
"Ferry"
I'm sorry, sir.
The last ferry's gone.
- There's nothing there till morning.
- Damn.
I'll ride on ahead
and secure you lodgings for the night.
- Thank you.
- Come on.
- Keep your pistols dry!
- They're dry enough.
It they fail, we've others. If those
fail, we can always cut the bastard.
- Go to your post.
- Yes, sir.
Don't worry, sir.
You're well guarded.
Now, why don't you go on upstairs
to your wife.
It's not often a man
has his wedding night.
You're soaking.
Brother and sister no more.
Now, husband and wife.
Lock the door.
I saw him in the lightning.
He vanished toward the lake!
You two stay here!
We lost him.
Don't bother to scream.
Please, sir.
Please don't hurt me.
You're lovelier than I ever...
could have imagined.
I keep my promises!
For God's sake.
Tell me what happened!
No point.
I know what I have to do.
God! No! You can't do this!
I won't let you!
She's gone. I love her.
What would you do?
- Leave her in peace!
- You call this peace?
Father would have
done this for mother.
Your father's dead!
Then there's nothing left to lose.
Nothing but your soul.
Live!
Say my name.
Please.
Remember?
You must remember.
That's it.
That's it. You remember.
Now stand.
Up. Yes!
Remember?
She's beautiful.
- She's not for you.
- Come.
Say my name.
You're beautiful.
Come to me.
Say my name.
That's right.
You're mine.
Leave her alone! No!
- Get away from her! She's mine!
- She said my name! She remembers!
She's mine!
All that I once loved...
lies in a shallow grave...
by my hand.
I followed the trail
he left for me.
North.
Always north.
For months now.
With one intent.
To kill him.
Now...
I'm tired.
I'm so...
very, very tired.
What did he say?
He's dead.
He died raving...
about some phantom.
What is it out there, Captain?
He told me a story that...
couldn't be true.
He was mad.
I think.
A warming breeze.
The ice will melt yet.
And what then, Captain?
- We head north.
- No.
Who are you?
He never gave me a name.
Why do you weep?
He was my father.
"And, yea, I gave my heart
to know wisdom...
and to know madness and folly.
And I perceived that all is vanity...
and vexation of spirit.
For in much wisdom
is much grief.
And he that increaseth knowledge...
increaseth sorrow.
For God shall bring every work...
and every secret thing
into judgement...
whether it be good...
or whether it be evil."
- Captain, we--
- He has a right to bear witness.
- Jesus! It's breaking up!
- The ice is giving way!
Help me!
Get back to the ship, Captain!
Leave the damn torch!
Come with us!
I am done with man.
Hang on! I've got you!
Help!
Here, Captain!
Take my hand!
Where to now, Captain?
Home.