- Move! Move it!
- Let´s go!
Jesus Christ!
Loomis!
I need you to come with me.
Just a minute.
It's Sophie.
Sophie thinks I have a mistress.
You´re worried about that?
lf you Iived with Sophie,
you'd understand.
Sometimes I yearn for our bacheIor days
in the army.
We were happy there, no?
WeII, l was happy! But you--
I wonder if you´ve ever been happy.
No. It´s not Sophie
that worries me today.
Then what?
- Who is he?
- l thought he was you.
EspecialIy when we couldn´t find you.
Then one of my men toId me
you were at Major Lescourt´s funeraI.
I thought it was a sick joke.
I aImost fired him.
- But who is he?
- A good question.
Come on.
We are taIking to witnesses.
ApparentIy he was being chased.
There´s evidence he had been tortured.
His death was not an easy one.
Here´s the bag, sir.
This was found
in the victim´s pockets.
These matches are from
the HoteI Chevre d´Or.
- Our men are there now.
- Let´s go.
AIain, wait.
This is not your case.
I'm not sure I want you invoIved
at this point.
I am invoIved!
Did you see his face?
Are you coming or what?
Monsieur Suverov, thank God!
This man toId me you were kilIed
in a car accident.
- Good morning, sir.
- You onIy had your hair cut!
Yes. MikhaiI Suverov.
Now if you want access
to his room...
why don´t you ask Monsieur Suverov?
Good idea.
May we search your room, sir?
But of course.
I trust my map to the street
you asked for was satisfactory?
It was. Thank you.
- Did I get any messages?
- Oh, yes. A teIephone message.
AIex Bohemia.
Did he leave a number?
Thank you.
You heard that woman. This Suverov
must have been Iooking for me.
A stranger with your exact face...
and according to the passport,
your exact birth date...
comes here and asks for directions
to the very street where you Iive.
A mystery, yes?
An airIine ticket
from Nice to New York...
and a New York driver's Iicense.
Some U.S. cash.
He was born five minutes after you.
I kept both of you for three months.
But I was sick.
I couIdn´t nurse.
There wasn´t even enough
for one of you.
I needed the money.
I had to do it.
TelI me now.
Why did you choose me?
I didn´t!
I didn´t have the courage.
Somebody eIse did it for me.
- Somebody else?
- A Iawyer from Paris.
He picked up your brother because...
you were crying.
He saw my distress
and offered me money.
He said it was a good famiIy.
Oh, God!
What have I done?
You survived.
Made a home for me.
You did what you had to do.
I don´t bIame you.
You should´ve toId me.
I know.
Can you remember his name, the Iawyer?
Why?
Somebody kiIIed him, Mother.
He was trying to come home.
They kiIIed him.
AIain, pIease.
Can you remember his name?
Etienne St. Denis.
He had an office
in PIace PigaIle in Paris.
Parents always Iie
to their chiIdren...
to prepare them for the way they´II
be treated later by the government.
Maybe I´m wasting my time.
But if I don´t go now,
I'Il regret it for the rest of my Iife.
What do you gain?
You onIy open old wounds.
The lawyer can´t bring him back.
My brother was adopted. If l can find
his famiIy, I can Iearn about him.
Kind of get to know him.
The Iawyer's office
is on the sixth fIoor.
Remember, I´lI do the taIking. Okay?
And then seafood.
Promise. Seafood before we go home.
Get out! Get out!
Go! Go!
The man in the eIevator!
Help!
PIease heIp!
Help me!
Don´t hurt me!
The adoption papers are here.
My boss made me hide them.
He wouId not give them to anybody.
Stay with me.
You´II be safe.
Come on, Iet´s go.
My God!
Let´s go.
Come on.
They´ve checked the entire fIoor.
There´s no one in there.
No body, nothing.
The secretary said a Russian guy showed
up, asked her boss a lot of questions.
Got upset with him.
Locked her in her room.
The next thing she knew,
the pIace was on fire.
Have you gone through
every piece of debris in the office?
- We´lI keep Iooking.
- Good.
He was adopted by a Russian famiIy.
The father was a Soviet dipIomat
who lived in Paris for five years...
and then immigrated
to America in 1968.
When´s the fIight?
- What fIight?
- Mikhail´s flight to New York.
- I want his passport.
- No! You´re a cop. That´s evidence.
You think it was a coincidence
that guy was Russian?
Who knows what MikhaiI
was invoIved in.
Sebastien...
what happened to my brother
couId´ve happened to me.
Thirty-two years ago it was onIy Iuck
that kept me in France.
He made a sacrifice
and never knew it.
I gotta go.
The kiIler did not know MikhaiI is dead.
You go to New York with that face and--
Maybe he isn´t.
WouId you Iike a vodka
before you sleep, Mr. Suverov?
- No, thank you.
- You´re weIcome.
What you see before you
is caIIed gridIock.
- Next exit.
- Yeah, yeah.
l´m writing the great American novel
here on the job.
Literary kind of stuff.
Knock the filIings outta your teeth.
Yeah. I see everything.
That´s what it is. It´s aII about
Iooking around, observing stuff.
Take you, for instance.
Like that accent of yours.
What´s that? Don't teII me.
That´s European or something?
Bet you got a story to teII.
This is Davis Hartley here.
I´m not some nickeI and dime
street mutt.
I'm not trying to rip you off
or anything.
It wouId be stupid. A guy Iike you?
Got a coupIe pounds of Iead in his eyes?
What´s that? Is that maybe grief
or something Iike that?
You want to taIk about it?
Maybe you think I´m trying to rip off
your experiences to put ´em in my noveI.
But that´s not true. Davis HartIey
is not some moraI cretin.
Not preciseIy.
I´m trying to make a point here.
I'm a professionaI New York City
cab driver. You know what that means?
I´m the greatest individuaI at being
abIe to find anything in the worId.
I couId find a penguin
in a sandstorm.
- l don´t know what a penguin would be--
- Stop taIking.
Please stop taIking!
HeIlo! Stop taIking!
You want to heIp? After l stop,
I'Il be busy for a whiIe.
Find a guy named...
AIex Bohemia.
Who do you think I am?
Do you think l´m a magician?
New York City is a big pIace.
How am I supposed to find AIex Bohemia?
Kind of Iike finding a penguin
in a sandstorm.
You sure you got the right address?
You boys think this is AtIantic City?
Jeremy, pick up your miIk money
and get inside!
I´m sorry. I´m Iooking for--
You´re in the wrong neighborhood, man!
I´m Iooking for a famiIy.
Maybe--
Wack accent!
You way out of your ´hood,
white boy.
You crazy or what?
Or maybe you´re a cop?
Hey! Get the heII out from my building,
you littIe shits!
Come on, oId man!
He's the chump.
- Thank you.
- Chump.
Thanks.
They´re not scared of you.
They don´t know who you are.
-They´re supposed to be scared?
-Everybody supposed to be scared of you.
- Why?
PIease! Big-time gangster Iike you!
Rich.
I thought you forgot about us.
I haven't seen you here
in a Iong time.
I´m not who you think I am.
WeII, when his famiIy disappeared...
there was a lot of rumors.
Some said they had gone back
to Russia.
Others said there was troubIe
with their grocery in LittIe Odessa.
Russian mob controls everything
in LittIe Odessa.
Maybe that´s why he joined them.
- How oId was he?
- Sixteen. Forced to live on the street.
You gotta be strong to be a white boy
growing up in this neighborhood.
Did he ever mention me?
Your brother´s.
He kept it here alI these years.
- Was he happy?
- Yeah.
The last l saw him, he had matured.
Got reaI serious.
- But he had choices.
- What choices?
- He was aIone.
- I´d have taken him in.
He was a strange boy.
You shouId go back to France.
What you find here couId be ugly.
Did he ever mention someone
named AIex Bohemia?
But there´s a nightcIub in LittIe Odessa
caIIed the Bohemia.
Your vodka, Mr. Suverov.
Excuse me, I´m Iooking--
Mr. Suverov, you have a phone caII.
FoIIow me.
MikhaiI.
Are you crazy? What the heII
are you thinking coming in here?
The key wasn´t in the maiIbox
'cause DarIene didn´t show up tonight...
so I don´t get a break
for another 20 minutes.
Here.
You might as weII take it now.
You shouIdn´t have come!
You shouId´ve Iooked for the key Iater.
What´s the matter?
You aII right?
- Excuse me.
- AIex.
You probabIy gave haIf of those
bent-nose guys up there a heart attack.
I´m surprised we weren´t trampIed
on the way to the phone.
You better get outta here.
I´II see you soon as I get off.
Don't even think about going to sIeep.
We got a lot of catching up to do.
Just teII me.
ls everything going to be okay?
Get outta here!
You need to go back inside.
Ivan wants to taIk to you.
We were famiIy!
You betrayed us.
Enough.
Enough!
This is your Iucky day.
Get in !
That was dynamite.
Any of those guys AIex Bohemia?
Good. I guess that wouId´ve been
structuraI Ietdown, huh?
You know this pIace?
Yeah. It's a fIeabag hoteI.
They say that Bret Easton EIIis,
he got drunk...
and he threw up in a fig tree.
The thing won´t stop growing.
They got to keep trimming it.
- Just relax.
- He´s a very good writer.
Just reIax. Thanks.
- I´Il wait here for you.
- Thank you for your heIp.
Wait. We´re not done yet.
We gotta find AIex.
My whoIe first chapter hangs on that.
Go home and use your imagination
for chapter one.
Hi. Last time I was here
I stayed in room 323.
Kind of a good Iuck thing.
It's avaiIabIe?
Nope. But I got 305
across the haII.
That´s fine.
Sign.
Good evening, Mr. Dzasokhov.
You´re a very pretty girI, AIex.
You know that?
Thank you.
WiII you do me a favor?
The band is too Ioud.
It's a birthday party.
Ten minutes, Yuri.
Ten minutes.
AlI l asked was that
you hoId MikhaiI...
for ten minutes.
Is that a Iong time?
No. That is a very short time.
How Iong can you hoId your breath?
I know a felIow in Odessa once
who couId hold his breath...
for five minutes, 33 seconds.
Did MikhaiI taIk to anyone
whiIe he was here?
NichoIas, pIease.
The man is trying to speak.
He was taIking...
to her.
So, what did you and Mikhail
taIk about?
l toId him he had a phone caII.
The caviar is fresh tonight.
Did l teII you
what a pretty girI you are?
Let me ask you something, sweetheart.
Do you have any idea what
wiII happen to you if you Iie to me?
I wilI never Iie to you.
Because if you Iie to me,
pretty girI...
you won´t be pretty anymore.
Get back to work.
AII she needs is a good f--
What are you doing over there?
Oh, MikhaiI, I missed you.
You´re so tense.
I'II heIp loosen you up.
What´s this?
You pIaying hard to get?
Is this a game?
Fine. Have it your way.
But no handcuffs this time.
You´ve gotten a Iot harder
since you´ve been away.
Ivan was alI over me
after you Ieft tonight.
He kept asking me stuff.
Did l taIk to you?
What did I say?
He´s Iike something
that crawIs out of an oId pipe.
It's okay.
ln a few days,
this wiII aII be behind us.
Uh, l can´t do it.
I´m not MikhaiI.
He´s dead.
Come here.
Shit!
Look, I´m positive the girI
went up to 323.
The room is empty.
I was just up there.
You saw her come in.
When did she Ieave?
I don´t--
Do you recognize this man?
Yeah. He checked in across the haII.
- Room 305.
- Room 305. Okay, good. Let's go.
Found this.
- Where did he go?
- I don´t know.
Where did he go?
TeII me!
I want them dead!
Down!
Come on !
HoId it!
What are you--
Get in, get in, get in!
Go!
Keep moving.
Come on.
What´s wrong?
Are you okay?
You were supposed to go home
and write.
Who needs home?
I´m aIways working anyway.
I guess we got
chapter one finished, huh?
Oh, my God!
- Is this AIex? Alex Bohemia?
- Yeah.
That's great.
Unexpected deveIopment.
The whoIe thing´s so scary.
We gotta go! Come on.
Come on !
Zanzibar Club. Police state that
a man and woman were being pursued--
He was in troubIe.
WouIdn´t admit it, though.
AIways said he had everything
under controI.
That he had a Iot of money put away.
Enough for a Iifetime.
Said he had a pIan
that wouId get him out of the mob.
I guess he was wrong.
They found him.
What did my brother mean to you?
Everything.
Take me to his pIace.
l want to get to know him.
Take you to his pIace?
Are you crazy?
You show up and start this mess
that aImost gets us kiIled.
You don´t have a cIue
who you´re deaIing with, do you?
If you wanna kiII yourseIf,
be my guest.
But who gave you the right
to risk my Iife?
l can't go home.
l can't go to work.
You painted a big red target
on my back.
Where´s the check?
MikhaiI used to say we could never stay
in one pIace too long.
We have to move aII the time.
It´s time for us to move.
- They´II find us here.
- The cabbie didn´t have to die.
This is just the beginning.
I've seen it before.
They won´t stop untiI you're dead, too.
You can´t go to the poIice.
You can't hide.
Ivan and his boss, Kirov,
are reIentless.
AII right, I´II bring you
to your brother´s home.
This expIains why MikhaiI
picked a bank in Nice.
HoIy shit.
Looks Iike we got another chance.
How did he manage to hide
a twin brother from us?
Sir, MikhaiI never communicated
with him. If he had, we´d have known.
AII right.
WelI, in Iess than 56 hours that bank
in Nice opens the safe deposit box...
and we aIl read about ourseIves
in the ''New York Times.´´
If that happens...
we'Il be spending the rest of our Iives
wondering how we screwed up so badIy.
Washington doesn´t
Iike federaI agents...
working for the Russian mob.
Our names are on that Iist.
Get the brother.
Convince him to work with us in Nice.
We don´t have any options.
We´II get him.
And, guys, keep this one alive.
I doubt if they were tripIets.
TripIets.
AIex, what are you doing?
Look at this mess.
Maybe if you toId me what you´re
Iooking for, I couId heIp you find it.
I wouIdn´t know what to teII you.
l´m just Iooking.
What´d you find?
He knew about me.
What´d you do in the war?
Sniper.
Why wait five years to find me?
Jimmy! You in there?
Open up, you shithead!
This stuff's hot!
This is not your Iucky day.
TeII your boss to Ieave me
the fuck aIone!
Ivan, you Iook Iike your parrot died.
- MikhaiI´s back.
- Bring him to me.
How can I bring him in when
l´ve got my hands tied behind my back?
Let me deaI with him my own way.
This is not a democracy.
You do what I say. You understand?
Mikhail has caused no troubIe.
If FBl had Iist, beIieve me...
we'd have major war with ItaIians,
with everyone.
If he is here,
then Iist is stiIl in France.
I wiII convince Mikhail
to take proper course of action.
So, bring him to me.
I meant no disrespect.
l´m just worried.
Remember when you toId me about Goradini
taIking to the FBI?
And Pietro? And Andrea?
I took care of them for you, Dimitri.
But MikhaiI is different.
I know you feeI Iike he´s your son.
Yes, Dimitri.
- ls fhis also Mikhail's place?
- No, my friend´s.
Mikhail and l used fo come here
to escape.
You Iooked comfortabIe with that gun
stuck in that guy's neck today.
That didn't scare me as much as when
you tried to drown him in the Jacuzzi.
I Iost it.
Sorry.
How Iong you been working
at the Bohemia?
About a year.
l used to dance.
NightcIubs.
I make Iess money now,
but it's a IittIe more respectabIe.
I doubt you´lI find anything here
of your brother´s.
It´s worth trying.
What'd he do to make alI these peopIe
want to kiIl him?
MikhaiI taIked about an insurance poIicy
or something that wouId keep him alive.
The FBl was folIowing him.
Pressuring him
to turn evidence on Kirov.
You think those aren't enough reasons
to kiII him?
The onIy time
my brother and I connected...
was when he died.
We both Iost something.
Rise and shine, boys and girIs.
SpeciaI Agent PelIman, Loomis.
FBI.
How are you?
Alex BartIett.
AIain Moreau.
I beIieve we share mutuaI concerns.
We know you´re not Mikhail. We know
you're not part of the Russian mob.
That´s a first.
What do you want?
We want to naiI the guys
that are trying to kiIl you.
- And?
- WeII, MikhaiI kept a list.
A detaiIed Iist...
of peopIe, pIaces, events...
which pretty much outIines
the entire Russian mob operation.
Mikhail was working with us.
He was heIping us with
our investigation of the Russian mob.
The fact is...
your brother wanted to set things right,
wanted to set things straight.
He wanted to heIp us.
He was gonna give us the Iist...
before he was kiIled.
The Iist is in a safe deposit box
in a bank in Nice.
What we want you to do
is come with us to the bank...
to Nice, and pretend--
- I´m MikhaiI.
- ExactIy.
Exactly.
We knew you´d want to heIp.
But I don't.
Can you protect her from being kilIed?
Can you protect me?
You sure didn´t protect my brother.
Hey, paI...
we´re your onIy hope.
I´II take my chances.
Why don´t we try another approach, okay?
Move.
l don´t understand. They´re the FBI.
They're supposed to heIp us.
At gunpoint, it´s not calIed heIp.
God, nothing makes sense. Who isn't
trying to kiII us at this point?
When the FBl toId you MikhaiI
was working with them...
you didn´t beIieve them, did you?
No way. He wouId´ve toId me.
I know he would´ve.
So they Iie!
They knew my brother was dead.
The Russians didn´t know about it.
The Russians were pissed at me...
but not surprised to see me alive.
- So if the Russians didn´t kiII him--
- FoIlow the Iist. Who eIse cares?
The FBI.
The FBl. Yeah.
- Where are you going?
- To see Kirov.
You can´t Ieave me here.
I'm coming with you.
It´s too dangerous.
I can't beIieve this is happening again.
First MikhaiI and now you?
AIain, you´ve got
to Iet me come with you.
We´re in this together, right?
AIex...
I promise you l´lI come back for you.
I promise.
Take me to Kirov.
Now.
Sit down.
Kirov asked me to bring him in.
I´m so sorry, Kirov!
Don´t do it.
Back off.
I came to taIk...
to Kirov.
Mikhail?
No, you´re not MikhaiI.
- Who are you?
- I´m his brother.
If you´re brother,
where is MikhaiI?
He´s dead.
I see I got your attention.
- How did he die?
- You teII me.
I had nothing to do with his death.
And you don´t need your gun.
- You´re safe here.
- Your peopIe tried to kilI me.
- They thought I was MikhaiI.
- lmpossibIe!
I wanted to speak to him,
not kiIl him!
To speak?
In what Ianguage?
They tried to kiII me
and aImost succeeded.
- Dimitri--
- Get out.
- l just want--
- Get out!
Look after Ivan.
MikhaiI.
l´m sorry.
What is your name?
AIain.
Come.
We need to taIk.
Ivan and MikhaiI...
they were Iike sons to me.
I need a favor.
I want to go back to Nice.
Back home.
Yes.
l can heIp you.
MikhaiI had Iist
in bank in Nice.
Get it for me.
We heIp each other, hmm?
Do it!
CaIl the poIice! Do it!
Go.
CaII an ambuIance.
Watch it, buddy!
The other side!
Get him!
- Don´t move!
- Okay, Peter Pan.
Spread ´em!
Get in the car!
Read him his rights.
Did you know
l had a contract out on him?
lf you weren´t protecting him,
he wouId be dead in his ceIl right now.
The probIem with you, Ivan,
is that you don't think. You kiII.
- You´re not Kirov.
- What did you say?
We need him to get the Iist, Ivan.
- Why wouId he get you the Iist?
- Because you're gonna help make sure...
he understands what happens
if he´s not a good boy in Nice.
Right?
And after?
We have 24 yours Ieft. Work with us
on this, and he´s aII yours.
I don't care what you do with him.
- Fine.
- Ivan, Iisten.
We know you have an aIibi
for Kirov´s death.
We aIso know
that you had him kiIled.
So after this, Iet´s start fresh.
No more trouble. Is that okay with you?
Listen to me.
l´m running things now, my way.
And that girI knows too much.
She´s mine now.
Step this way.
You have visitors.
So, I'm hoping a good night´s sleep
is aII you needed to see the Iight.
You win.
In a few hours, we go bankin'.
So try and get some rest.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Don´t worry about it. I checked it out.
Everything´s copacetic.
So what´s the pIan?
We gotta get out of here.
No pIan.
Nothing.
Alain, about tomorrow.
Tomorrow I reaIIy find out
who my brother was.
They´re not gonna Iet us go...
even when they get the Iist.
Monsieur Suverov.
WeIcome again.
If there´s anything I can do for you,
do not hesitate to make a request.
I think we´d Iike to go right in,
if that's okay.
I´m sorry.
Only Monsieur Suverov.
The vauIt is for customers onIy.
- My coIIeague and l wouId like to dis--
- I´m sorry, sir. Bank poIicy.
PIease, Monsieur Suverov,
come with me.
Please, make yourseIf comfortabIe
and stay as Iong as you desire.
Unfortunately, we must go through
the identity protocoI again.
Yeah, okay.
PIease identify yourseIf.
MikhaiI Suverov.
And the second name?
AIain Moreau.
- Your mother's Christian given name?
- ChantaI Moreau.
CIean and quiet.
Here, monsieur.
- Do you smoke?
- No, sir, I don´t.
- Can I get a cigarette?
- Of course, monsieur.
And some gum.
- CertainIy.
- Thank you.
I need access to my security box.
May I see your l.D.?
This is the one under the name
AIain Moreau.
Monsieur.
Only you could access this box.
Therefore, one of two things
has happened.
We are fogefher again
as we should have been, a family.
Or l´m dead,
and you shouldn´f trusf anyone.
l know you are a great marksman.
Therefore, l´m leaving you a gift.
Your favorite.
One of the boxes confains evidence
againsf governmenf agents...
and the Russian mob.
Hand it over to fhe American embassy.
Alain, when l found ouf about you,
it was luck.
A newspaper.
The moment l saw the picture,
l knew l had a brother in fhis world.
You, my brother, reminded me
that l had a chance...
and l decided to quit fhe mob.
l didn´t confact you because everything
l fouched in my world turned fo poison.
l´ve fried all fhese years
to leave my life behind, fo reunife us.
l´m sorry if that never happens.
Please forgive me.
l want you to fell our mother...
that l don´f blame her
for what she did.
The life l've lived
has taught me fhis.
l only hope thaf we are lisfening
to this tape together.
The money is for you and our mofher.
You are my only friend.
God bless.
Have everything in the small box
turned over to the American embassy.
- You understand?
- PerfectIy, sir.
What´s going on?
Sit down.
Just sit down.
Get the fuck out of here!
- We´re clearing the building.
- Can´t Ieave without our guy.
You can meet him outside. Everyone
is being cIeared to the street.
Don´t shoot.
I´m a cop.
We´II see about that.
Let's go. Come on.
Sorry, sir.
Let´s go.
Put your hands
where we can see them...
and step out of the van.
SlowIy.
Keep your hands
where we can see them...
and step out of the van.
Back it up!
Move!
Get out!
You move, you die.
Sebastien!
Come on. Come on!
Come on. Move!
Me first.
Get me out!
Take a number.
Come on.
Don´t Ieave me.
PIease.
I beg you!
Help me!
- You okay?
- Yeah. Thank you.
The two men,
they took the girI with them.
That way.
Don´t shoot.
- Where´d they go?
- Down there.
Need the car.
Sorry.
Here he comes.
Comin´ up.
- Look out! Look out!
- Shut up!
Watch that!
Try that again and you´re dead.
You hear me?
Come on.
I want you to Iisten to me now.
I know you don´t have the Iist.
But that doesn´t matter now. See?
´Cause I want the money.
I know you have Mikhail´s money,
and I want it.
Why don´t you give it to me?
And you waIk.
Do we have a deal?
I don´t think you get it, pal!
I wiII kiIl her.
You understand me?
The Americans are ecstatic
over MikhaiI´s evidence.
They´ve made dozens of arrests.
And thanks to his money,
you can afford to eat here.
HeIlo, AIain.
Are you nervous,
Alex meeting your mother?
l´m not nervous.
Okay, I´m nervous.
WeII, it's too late now.
Wish me Iuck, okay?
Do you feeI okay?
Because it´s no reason to be nervous.
l´m not nervous.
Good.
Let´s take a waIk.
It's nearby.
It´s reIaxing.
Okay, good. ´Cause I think one of us
needs to relax.
Do you know what you will say?
I´m not asking you to lie.
l don´t need to Iie, Alain.
I´Il teII your mother the truth
about MikhaiI.
That he was...
kind and generous.
Honest.
Just Iike his brother.
Thank you.