I can't stand the thought of people...
peering, whispering, pointing, at me.
We'll live in the forest.
Animals don't point and whisper.
But it's a dream, Merlin.
I want to make it real.
I've found a place here...
and prayer... and meditation.
It's a peace that I've never known before.
It passes my understanding.
To be honest, Nimue...
it passes my understanding, too.
Why do you shut yourself away here?
To be nearer my God...
The nearer you are to him...
the further you are from me.
Take off that veil...
Well... where was I?
Oh... yes... yes...
Arthur...
had just been born.
I fostered him with Sir Hector.
Do unto others... as you would
them do unto you.
I was his tutor.
I didn't teach him magic...
I taught him ethics...
and morals.
Arthur...
which is much more difficult...
believe me.
His real father... King Uther...
went mad...
Kill the prisoners...
and killed himself.
That brings us up to date... I think.
Arthur grew up to be a fine young man.
Perhaps, as usual...
I expected too much of him... but...
he was the vessel of all my hopes.
Arthur, don't charge around like that...
the horses don't like it.
And don't get off...
we're leaving right away.
Merlin, have you heard the news?
- Rupert...
- King Uther's dead!
Didn't you hear what I said?
The king is dead!
- I know...
- Know?
How could you know out here in the woods?
A little bird told me.
Where are we going?
To make you king!
Merlin... tell me...
how can I be king?
Because, you were born to it...
I've no royal blood in me!
Merlin...
Stand aside...
this is a job for a man!
That old windbag... look at him!
If he's not careful,
he'll do himself an injury!
Arthur kept asking me...
but I wasn't ready.
The truth about his father...
the death of Cornwall...
my part in the whole squalid plot.
No wonder I found it hard to tell him...
besides...
I was distracted.
Defense!
Thank-you...
I did nothing...
I wasn't talking to you.
What was that?
That... that was a message...
from an old friend.
Arthur wanted me to explain...
- Why won't you tell me?
He couldn't know...
that explaining everything...
settles nothing.
Yes, it's... it's time.
I hoped he'd understand my part of it.
Arthur...
you should know that...
Sir Hector isn't your real father.
Your father was King Uther...
and you...
are the true heir to the throne.
It turned out better than I'd hoped.
If I am Uther's only son...
I want what's mine.
I want to be king.
When you are king... what then?
Well... I...
Whoa... whoa...
What? What is it now?
He has the right-of-way.
You were saying... if you were king...
I'd...
do all the things that you taught me.
I'd... build a...
golden city...
devoted to peace...
and charity.
What the world needs is...
justice... compassion...
more than charity.
Still...
Camelot sounds like a dream...
worthy of a king!
Come on, Rupert...
Camelot!
Camelot...
Come on, Arthur!
All the knights in Britain...
have tried to take it.
But it is the sword of the true king.
It is yours, Arthur!
Merlin...
it seems you were here...
only a moment ago.
My lord...
this man claims Excaliber.
Who is it?
Arthur... only son of Uther...
and rightful king of Britain.
Why give him the sword?
He will betray the people...
just as his father did.
I don't know what I'll do...
or what I'll become...
only what I am.
A wise answer...
I had a wise teacher.
You're destroying the old ways.
You will be forgotten...
just like the rest of us.
That is your fear...
not mine, Mab.
I... cannot die.
I am a rock of ages.
I will live forever...
on the edge of dreams.
Take it now, Arthur.
NOW... ARTHUR!
The sword is yours!
Excaliber!
Excaliber...
Look at him... Merlin.
His reign begins in blood...
it will end the same way.
No, Mab... you're wrong...
Arthur will heal the land!
He has the sword...
he has Excalibur!
Long live the king!
Don't you ever tidy, Frik?
I try, your majesty...
but I'm terribly overworked.
I can't use imps, gnomes, or fairies...
they're utterly useless...
with anything practical.
I mean, I have so much to do!
And you'll have more...
I've totally given up on Merlin...
I thought... perhaps...
despite everything...
he might come 'round.
Well, I mean, he's a
stubborn creature, isn't he?
I wanted him to...
so I fooled myself.
I've never know you to do that before...
over anyone!
Enough!
Arthur's cursed...
I want everyone to know in good time.
And that will be your job... Frik!
Uther was my cousin...
I claim the throne by right!
You did not pull the sword...
Excalibur, from the rock!
You all failed.
My father is king by right of blood.
That's better... isn't it, my lords?
Now you can listen...
instead of fighting.
It should be a novel experience...
for most of you.
Uther had a son...
I give you... Arthur...
true king of Britain.
Uther had no son!
Everyone knows that...
He did...
Uther did have a son...
When Uther conquered Tintagel...
he took the lady, Igraine.
A son was born.
It's true...
I was there.
Arthur...?
is Uther's son?
If he is...
let him draw Excaliber from the stone.
I already have...
Well... prove it!
Prove that it is Excaliber.
You do have Excaliber!
You are Uther's son.
I acknowledge you...
my liege, lord, and king.
And so do I!
He has the sword...
Accept him... Lot.
Never!
I'll not bend my knee to a boy...
nor will my son.
I can speak for myself, Father.
He has Excaliber...
he is the king.
You'll go against your own father...
The cause is just.
And if it's not... and you're wrong?
Then you'll have to kill me in battle.
I'm the king's man, Father.
So be it!
My Lords...
hard as it may be for you...
think for a moment.
We have seen too many wars.
My mind's made up!
Hello... Morgan.
My... you've grown!
Who are you?
Don't you remember me
I used to visit you...
when you were very young.
I remember you...
I thought you were a dream.
I'm real!
You lied to me...
you told me you'd make me beautiful...
but you never did.
I told you I'd make you beautiful...
did I?
Then I will!
But first, it's time to put away...
childish things.
Why so sad?
It's just a toy.
Look at yourself...
I'm beautiful...
Very, very beautiful...
I think... clothes cut in the Roman style...
are the only gowns for...
a lady of fashion.
Oh... it's wonderful!
Now... get me the throne.
That's... beyond my powers.
I'll tell you from personal experience...
that elves are so short...
that when it rains...
they're the last to know.
Because of their size...
Frik...
stop enjoying yourself...
and get on with it!
I've been thinking... Morgan...
that there might be...
a way of giving you what you want.
Your son... could be king.
Well, how?
If Arthur defeats Lord Lot...
he'll be king, and I can't marry him.
You don't have to marry him...
to have his son.
We have the same mother...
and underneath this charming and...
devilishly handsome exterior...
I'm a crabby, old gnome.
Does it matter?
Not a bit!
You don't to have to seduce me...
to win me over...
like everyone else.
I want... the crown.
I like you, Morgan Le Fey.
You're a truthful young woman.
And I like you...
Stand aside!
The army is all it's ready size...
going to be a bloody fight!
Wait for my signal.
He'll be killed!
Merlin!
What the devil does he think he's doing?
There is no reason why men should...
die today, my lord.
The quarrel is between us.
It is...
This is Excalibur...
the sword of the true king.
If you believe you have a right to it...
take it...
and kill me.
Forgive me, Arthur...
I can feel it.
The sword is yours.
You are the true king!
The war is over!
Arthur is our true king...
by blood and right.
Here... in this circle...
let us give thanks to our savior...
for this deliverance.
And let this circle be a symbol...
of our purpose.
Each man in it...
is equal to the other.
Each has a voice...
and each will strive...
to fight for truth and honour.
Let us pray.
I thought I'd finally achieved...
one of my dreams.
At last, there was a good king...
on the throne.
Your Majesty...
may I present Lady Marie...
queen of the border Celts...
who comes to pay you homage.
You are most welcome, my Lady.
Lady... we are overwhelmed...
by your gifts.
Perhaps, I... and my servants...
can join you for the night.
We've had a long... tiring journey.
And we'd like to rest...
before we return home.
Of course...
we can spend some time together.
You can...
tell me about... your people.
It will be my pleasure...
your Majesty.
What are you showing me, Mab?
What have you done?
I rode fast that day...
but I knew I was already too late...
to stop something...
that could finish us all.
Out my Lords...
OUT!
And close the door behind you.
Merlin... what's the matter?
Tell me the truth, Arthur...
two nights ago you...
slept with a woman.
Yes... if you must know... I did.
'though I don't see why I
need to tell you about it.
That was Morgan Le Fey...
her mother was the Lady Igraine...
your mother!
I didn't know...
I swear I didn't know.
There will be a child.
Mab will see to that.
He'll be the future...
and he'll destroy us!
A mirror...
there are no mirrors in Avalon.
You see how it can change you?
You've changed me already...
you've scarred me.
I know... so unfair!
Unfair? That was evil.
With evil all around me...
I can do nothing but evil to survive.
Ohh, that's too easy!
You can fight it... like Merlin.
It's because of Merlin...
that all this came about.
That's not true!
Why are you here, Mab?
To make you an offer...
I will restore your beauty...
if you take Merlin...
to a place that I have created for you.
You can live with him there...
until the end of your days.
And be happy?
And be happy.
He has a destiny.
It would keep him from his purpose.
It would keep him from...
wasting his life.
He believes...
that fighting for what is right...
isn't a waste.
I wouldn't do that to him.
I love him.
- I love him...
- You hate him...
I hate him, too.
What's your answer?
No!
I'm... sorry...
If you change your mind...
just... call my name...
out loud.
I couldn't stay away for long.
Arthur was more to me...
than just a king.
And, I was curious
to see what was going on.
Merlin...
it's good to see you, old friend.
What's all this, Arthur?
A promise made flesh.
I'm building the city of Camelot.
It's a new beginning.
I made a mistake that night with Morgan.
But I can't believe that I will be
condemned for all eternity
for one mistake.
Well, not by me.
I'll never condemn you, Arthur.
I'm to marry Lord Leo's daughter.
Ah... do you love her?
She'll make a splendid queen...
and be a good wife.
We hope to get married here at Camelot.
It doesn't matter if it's not finished.
Will you be there with me?
I'd be honoured.
What's her name... your bride?
Guinevere.
I was going to Tintagel castle.
Perhaps, Arthur wouldn't
have been so eager...
to leave on his quest for the Holy Grail...
if he'd known what a terrible...
enemy he would leave behind...
in Morgan Le Fey.
Merlin...
is here to see you, my Lady.
Send him in...
You hear that Mordred?
There's a wizard come to see us.
Won't this be fun?
My Lady Morgan...
do you know why I'm here?
Say hello to my son, Mordred.
Master Mordred...
Hmm, that was rude, Mordred.
You can do anything you like... but
you must never be rude.
Rude is being weak.
You were saying, Merlin?
Do you know why I'm here?
Hmm, it's to do with my son.
Hasn't he grown?
Yes, he has...
and rather more than is natural...
I have to say.
Hmm, of course...
it's magic!
Morgan...
I beg you for the sake...
of the country...
you must not teach him the old ways.
Oh, this country means nothing to me.
A bastard sits on the throne...
that should be mine.
A bastard... begot in blood...
when his father, Uther...
seduced my mother... and killed my father.
It's the future, I'm thinking of, Morgan.
Oh, you would think of the future, Merlin.
because the past is too painful.
You choose Uther to be king.
You helped him seduce my mother...
and destroyed me.
In the end...
you...
begot Mordred.
Just as surely...
as Queen Mab, and Arthur.
I know that, but...
I can live with it.
Just as you have to live with the fact...
that Mordred will be king.
No... that can never be!
Mordred!
Merlin's a guest.
Don't be naughty.
He just wants attention.
You'll get all you want...
when you're king.
And he will be, Merlin...
he's Arthur's son.
What about the old ways, Morgan?
Well, you're in no position to
lecture me on what I can or can't do.
Besides... the old ways
have been good to me.
They gave me a son...
and made me beautiful.
Oh, poor Morgan...
it's only an illusion.
Beauty is always...
only an illusion, Merlin.
Didn't you know that?
We thought we'd come in...
the traditional way...
through the door.
It's traditional to open it, first.
Mordred! Look who's here!
Your Auntie Mab, and Uncle Frik!
It's been ages, Master Merlin...
Do you ever think of the old school...
where I tried to teach you the...
fundamentals of magic?
He could have been my star pupil, Morgan...
but he proved...
disappointing.
But you won't...
will you, Mordred?
Isn't he handsome?
Handsome is as handsome does.
What does that mean?
I've never really understood the phrase...
Toys... Mordred...
Auntie always brings you
lots of lovely toys.
You see, Merlin...
you took my family away from me...
now... I have a new one.
It won't last, Morgan...
Nothing does...
Can't you see it... feel it?
I'm winning, Merlin.
I have the precious gift of patience.
It'll be years before Mordred
can claim the throne...
but I can wait.
Time means nothing to me.
You'll be the death of Arthur...
and the end of all poor Merlin's dreams.
Won't you, my sweetie?
Oh! Look!
The big, bad wizard can't do a thing!
Run... run wizard!
Merlin... you're troubled again.
Still the same cry for help, Lady.
You're sister, Mab, grows more powerful.
And I grow weaker...
What can I do? I...
I have to find a man to guard the throne...
while Arthur goes questing...
for the Holy Grail.
The temptation will be to
seize the crown when he's gone.
You need a man pure in heart.
I've tried to find him before...
he doesn't exist.
The answer is at Joyous Guarde.
My ship will take you.
It was like a dream.
A dream of a dream...
the skies parted and I saw the dream
come alive, before my eyes.
That was...
someday, they'll describe me,
Arthur, Guinevere, and Camelot
as a dream.
Who are you?
I am Merlin, the wizard.
There aren't any wizards left.
I'm the last of them.
Who are you?
Galahad...
My mother is the Lady Elaine...
and my father is Sir Launcelot.
I've come here to find a man
to defend King Arthur, and his kingdom.
But he must be a good man...
pure in heart.
You've found him.
It was all... too easy.
You're sure this is what you want?
It's not what I want...
it's what you want.
I can't hold you back.
It's your chance for
one last great adventure.
I should have known.
Galahad...
protect your mother while I'm away.
My Lords, Ladies, Knights of the realm...
I shall leave soon, on a God-given
quest for the Holy Grail.
Now, I seek a champion...
to protect our country, and
the honour of our fair queen
while I'm gone.
I claim that honour, Sire.
Gawaine, I hope that you don't win...
you know I need you to come with me.
You should have let me compete
in the tourney, Sire.
You're too old, Sir Boris.
Of course, he's too old...
but I'm not.
Your Majesty...
I wish to vouch for
Sir Launcelot of the Lake.
He wants to enter the jousts.
So be it, Merlin.
Aha! Gawaine, or this Launcelot!
Launcelot of the Lake...
takes the honours...
He is the best...
and the noblest of the knights.
He's very handsome... isn't he?
Yes...
What did you say, my Lady?
Nothing...
Your Majesty?
I offer you my sword...
and my life.
It is an honour, brave knight.
As champion, Launcelot shall be
How is he?
Fair to middling, considering we haven't
taken the lance out, yet.
And why not?
There is a dispute... uh...
scholarly dispute...
as to whether we take it out
con or contra wise.
Which means, to the mere layman,
turning and pulling it to the left...
or to the right... contra.
Is there anything I can
do for you, Sir Launcelot?
Hold my hand, Lady.
No, Tannen, pull conwise...
the planets of Venus, and Uranus
will be the dominant influences.
You're physicians... instead of arguing...
about it... do it!
We must talk about it first.
Indeed... these are weighty matters...
fit only for experts.
Trust us...
if we treat a knight for a broken arm...
that is what he'll die of.
That's enough... enough!
Launcelot? Are you ready, Sir Knight?
Do it... Gawaine.
Goodbye, Merlin.
'Bye, Arthur... come back to us.
They left to chase dreams...
shadows...
but if I'd told them...
they wouldn't have listened.
And so, the years rolled on...
one year merging into another...
and another.
If you five gentlemen
don't stop trembling...
I might miss, and kill you all.
Less than perfect.
That's enough, Mordred.
You mustn’t get carried away, my sweet.
It shows lack of control.
Why fire at Auntie Mab, and Uncle Frik?
I do hope that the boy...
is just having fun,
and it's nothing personal.
It's not personal... he likes you.
I often wonder what he would do
if he didn't like me.
Stop fussing, Mother!
Auntie Mab understands...
don't you, Auntie Mab?
Of course, I understand...
you were testing yourself.
Now, come and sit by me.
You know you're my favourite, Mordred...
but you have to channel your aggression.
Against Arthur...
Yes... always Arthur...
and Merlin.
You're looking pale, Mordred.
You're not eating enough.
I already have the strength of ten men.
Listen to your aunt...
Please do something about your hair.
Very well, Mother.
There's a good boy.
The work is going much too slowly.
but you keep on changing
your mind,
Sir Launcelot.
First this, then that...
I'm giving it my best try!
Well, you've got to do better than that.
How can I do better than my best?
All alone, my Lady?
Merlin is my faithful shadow.
That's right, and proper.
Why not you?
You're my champion.
Because when I'm near you,
I can't control my heart.
You're near me now.
It's dangerous...
- My Lady...? My Lady...?
- Yes...
Perhaps, we should be
grateful for my shadow.
What's wrong, Merlin?
The walls are whispering, Guinevere.
Can't you hear them?
No...
What are they saying?
That you are too friendly
with Sir Launcelot.
Do you believe such whispers, Merlin?
Ah, but I've seen how you
two look at each other.
I don't care what others think.
I'm a queen!
That is why you must take special care...
I can't protect you in this matter.
You look... beautiful...
I should jump...
throw myself from the battlement.
Then I'll jump, too...
I can't live without you.
I don't believe it!
Launcelot wouldn't...
Auntie...
you're looking extraordinarily
pleased with yourself.
What have you done?
Is it terrible?
Do tell...
I'm sure it's perfect.
I've made sure...
Elaine knows that Launcelot...
and Guinevere are lovers.
How absolutely delicious!
Isn't that...
rather unworthy of us?
Unworthy?
Well, what does that mean, Mother?
Ohh, I've forgotten...
what does it mean?
Yes... it is unworthy...
but I don't like to be told, Frik.
Frik...
I warned you...
you didn't listen.
What's happened?
Elaine...
How did she die?
She died of a broken heart...
because of you.
I'm sorry...
I judged them too harshly.
The blame was mine, too.
I picked Launcelot, after all.
I wish I'd told them that.
It might have made it easier.
Oh, great news...
great news, Nimue!
Arthur's coming home!
Oh, thank God!
Did he find the Holy Grail?
No... but what of it?
He's coming home.
Holy Grail, or no Holy Grail...
he should never have left.
Merlin... he's free...
he can start living his own life again.
Yes... and it should be with you, my child.
Your true vocation is Merlin.
God doesn't want you when you love another.
Umm... I... I shouldn't really say this...
in these hallowed walls.
Faith is supreme, of course...
but love is even better.
Careful, my dear...
these steps are very slippery.
where are we going?
To my land...
the land of magic.
Can I create monsters?
Ohh, if you wish.
You're so good to me, Auntie.
It won't all be fun, and games...
Arthur's coming back.
There will be things I have to teach you...
Is Mother coming?
No, we don't need her, anymore.
Mab... where are you taking my son?
It's time...
without a word...?
without a by-your-leave?
I have to make him ready.
You're not taking him!
He's my son...
He's mine!
I gave him love...
you gave him toys!
I gave him life!
I'm never letting him go.
No!
That was very clever, Auntie.
My love...
Frik...?
My love...?
Am I still beautiful?
Beyond words, my love...
Am I?
Oh... yes...
beyond words.
You killed her!
Perhaps, she just slipped.
In any case, what does it matter?
You're holding us up, Frik.
We have a lot to do!
Mab! You evil, old crone!
May God have mercy on your soul!
He obviously didn't have
any on the rest of you!
Why is everybody suddenly against me?
Frik!
I'm leaving you...
with your misery, and pain...
but... with no more magic powers!
Now... you will wander through the world...
ugly and alone...
just as if you were human.
Goodbye, Frik... I'll miss you...
No, I won't!
Why didn’t you kill him, Auntie Mab?
Because, that's what he wanted me to do.
Camelot!
It's built!
Sir Launcelot has kept his word.
We have to ride in with
our banners held high, Sire.
You're right, Gawaine...
Raise your banners, and your hearts, men!
We're home!
Where is everyone?
Something's wrong, Sire.
What's wrong here?
Guinevere...
Where is Merlin?
Where's Launcelot?
I'll tell you...
Who the devil are you?
Elegantly put...
who the devil...
yes, indeed.
Who the devil...
Well, don't you recognize me?
No...
should I?
Ohh... I'm hurt!
here... in my heart...
not usually my most vulnerable spot.
I recognize you...
Father!
I'm your long lost son, Mordred.
Morgan Le Fey... is your mother.
Not is, Father... was...
she passed over into a better world.
And she sleeps alone, at last.
A great loss...
one day, she was laughing, smiling...
the next... gone!
like a summer's breeze.
In the midst of life, etc.
etc. and so on, and so forth.
It's why I'm here...
I don't understand...
to protect your interests, Father.
You see, your interests are my interests.
Whilst you were away on this
great spiritual quest...
to cleanse your soul...
How should I put it...?
you were being betrayed...
MORDRED!
- That's enough!
- It isn't!
So, come Merlin...
let's speak the truth, at last...
farces in the time...
Father... Launcelot
betrayed you with the queen.
- What?
- or should it be...?
the queen betrayed you with Launcelot?
No pretense... no point being pedantic...
You were betrayed!
Guinevere?
This isn't the place to discuss this matter.
Oh... I think it's the perfect place.
Is it true?
Arthur, you have just returned...
we must talk calmly.
- Guinevere, is it true?
- Yes, it's true!
Mordred, you have no right to be here.
I have every right to be here.
We all have. This isn't a private matter
it concerns us all.
How could you do that to me?
Didn't you think of me at all?
You left me alone for years...
did you not think of me?
What of my honour...
finding out my husband had a child...
by a woman named Morgan Le Fey?
Good one...
Oh, come, Father...
this is becoming distressingly personal.
When you're forgetting...
it's a matter of state.
Matter of state...!
We are talking treason here...
My Lords...
I don't see it as treason...
She betrayed me...
and only me.
That's enough.
- No!
- Sire, Mordred is right...
you are the king...
and that makes her adultery treason.
Then we must condemn her to death!
Do you really think we should do that?
- It's the law!
- It's harsh...
It's meant to be.
My Lords...
This is a time when we should...
temper justice with mercy.
After all...
your religion proclaims it.
Let he who is not guilty of sin...
cast the first stone.
Now... I know I have been guilty
in my time. and I suspect that...
you have been, too.
I must confess...
I have sinned a little.
So... we make excuses for
her, because she's a queen.
Because she is human.
No... because she is Arthur's wife!
Are we going back to one law for
the rulers, and one for the ruled?
Is that the way it is?
Arthur?
I thought Camelot was to be different.
It is...
Then, show the world you mean it!
Merlin...
What should I do?
In the end...
you must uphold the law.
Guinevere... will be tried for treason.
A splendid decision...
both fair, and just, eh, Father?
Now! Let's drink and enjoy ourselves
I want you out of Camelot!
But Father, I've only just arrived.
I thought we could reminisce about
old times, and play happy families.
Stop him talking!
You can't mean that, Father.
I'm your beloved son...
the crown prince,
your one and only heir.
I want you out of my sight.
- Embrace me, Father...
- Never!
or I'll take what's rightfully mine.
Guards! Seize him!
Don't get up...
I know my way out.
I'm sorry, Father...
but I'm going to destroy you.
And this time, you pet
wizard won't save you.
Mab...
I'm here, Nimue.
You made me a promise, years ago...
will you keep it?
Yes...
What made you change your mind?
The king is coming home...
Merlin is free to be with me.
I've discovered all I want is Merlin.
Will you agree to live with him...
in a place that I choose?
If you make me whole again.
I have to warn you, Nimue...
that if you go to this place...
you can never leave it.
Will he come to me there?
Yes... he will.
Then, do it, Mab!
I've got to watch?
The sin was mine... not hers.
It's too late!
Merlin...
Launcelot...
always left everything to the last moment.
But then, my memory of Launcelot is that...
he never got anything right.
Thank God!
And so Launcelot, and Guinevere...
rode out of my story...
and into legend.
What's the meaning of this?
You tricked us, Father...
you pretended to condemn
the queen to the stake...
then you had her rescued...
by your damned wizard!
You hadn't even the courage...
to set her free, yourself.
That's true...
I should have done it.
One law for you...
and another for the rest of us.
We can't live like that!
Do you hear?
They can't live like that!
I call upon all true-born Britains...
to rally to freedom's flag!
You caught me by surprise, Father.
I know how that is...
Nobles, the time for talking is over.
Those who value right, and justice...
follow me.
Who's there?
Father Abbot...
I rode all night to get here.
Nimue's gone!
- She's gone?
- Yes.
But she left you a message...
that she'll be waiting for you...
at the door of magic.
You're a liar!
How can you say such a thing?
I'm glad to see you haven't lost
all the skills I taught you.
I've lost none of them...
and it was Frik, who taught me.
Don't mention that ingrate!
He's left my employment...
without a reference!
Anyway...
Nimue has gone...
and she does want you to join her...
when you're ready.
Merlin!
My noblemen...
don't want you with us
against Mordred.
They say that if you come...
then they won't follow me.
Ah...
What will you do now?
Close my books...
break my wand...
and... retire.
I have a life to live, and... uh...
a chance to live it.
Nimue?
I'm going to meet her, now.
You'll be able to deal with Mordred?
It's just one more battle...
and right is on our side.
I'm proud of you, Arthur.
Don't worry about me, Merlin.
I've still got Excaliber.
Hello...
Nimue...
Merlin...
I am here...
Look!
Look where we are...
This is all Mab...
Oh... forget her...
we've wasted...
so much of our lives together...
we're ready.
Now, it's our turn.
Isn't it what you've always wanted?
Gawaine!
What a pleasant surprise!
Stop talking, Mordred... and fight!
I though you might enjoy a little light...
conversaton, before you die.
But... as you wish.
Mordred!
Clever boy!
Father!
So...
Mordred.
Hello...
Father.
It's time to... end it all.
Well...
we agree on that, at least.
You know, Father...
if you'd lived...
I don't think we'd have been very...
happy as a family.
What is it, Merlin?
I heard a scream.
I didn't hear anything.
It's the sound of battle.
Arthur and Mordred.
Oh... no...
It's nothing to do with us.
No...
I'm sorry... Mordred.
Don't tell me, Father...
another sin?
You've killed your own son.
Mordred...!
Arthur is dying.
I must go to him.
I'll be back very soon.
I'll be waiting for you...
always.
Very soon... I swear!
Why didn't you tell me?
Nimue...
I knew I would never see her again.
I cannot save you...
Don't die, Mordred.
Die here, Auntie Mab...
that's the last thing I shall do.
No...
Merlin... old friend...
I knew you would come.
How goes the day, Arthur?
I've seen better...
Merlin...
take the sword to the lake...
No one must have it.
Go, Merlin... now!
Rest easy, son...
You were the right man...
to hold Excaliber.
Take it back, Lady...
You lied to me...
I didn't lie to you, Merlin.
I told you the answer was at Joyous Guarde.
That's where I found Launcelot.
It wasn't Launcelot, was it?
It was the boy... Galahad.
It's human to make mistakes, Merlin.
and part of you is human...
the best part.
Goodbye, Merlin...
my sister, Mab, was right about one thing...
when we're forgotten...
we cease to exist.
What are you doing here, Frik?
Betraying my principles, I'm afraid.
Indeed, I've always believed...
that it was better to be a coward...
for a second...
than dead for a lifetime.
And yet...
here I am fighting...
fighting on the side of right...
which is worse.
And Mab?
As a matter of fact...
I gave in my notice.
If you're going after her, Master Merlin...
you'll need help.
I knew I'd find you here, Mab.
You've come to see my final triumph?
No, I've come to see your final defeat.
You always were a dreamer, Merlin.
Let me see...
you've lost Arthur...
the battle...
you're one, true love...
The battle isn't over yet, Mab.
You can't win...
Why are you consulting with that traitor?
Madam! After all my years of...
of faithful service... I mean that's...
rather harsh.
Not as harsh as I'm going to be...
Sorry! Can't stay!
Mordred's dead...
So, we both have nothing to lose.
The battle is just between you, and me, Mab.
I'll show you how weak I am...
My strength may be fading, Merlin...
but I can still deal with...
these poor humans.
What do you plan to do?
Use you puny sword... on me?
No, Mab...
we're just going to forget you.
Merlin?
What are you doing?
You can't fight us...
or frighten us...
you're just...
not important enough, anymore.
We forget you, Queen Mab.
Go join your sister, in the lake...
and be forgotten.
Look at me...
Look at me!
Frik!
Merlin!
Don't forget me, Merlin...
I... uh... love you...
as a son.
Merlin?
Merlin!
You failed!
I had won.
I was trying to smile...
but it was the smile...
of... desolation.
Inside I felt...
only the pity...
and the terror...
and the waste of it all.
Everyone I ever loved...
and who ever loved me...
all gone.
All gone, now.
And then... Galahad returned...
and brought with him... the Holy Grail...
and spring.
and the land became fertile, again.
And the cycle of death...
and darkness ended...
and so does my story.
Now...
if my story...
entertained, or enchanted...
you may show you appreciaton...
in any way you see fit...
but particularly...
with money.
Master Merlin...
did you ever find Nimue?
No, I never found Nimue...
or even the cave, again.
What about the magic?
Can you still do magic?
No...
I got out of the habit, and besides...
nobody believes in it anymore.
Thank-you...
it's all over, friend...
there is no more.
Is it all exactly...
the way I remember it...
Master Merlin?
Frik...
Is it you?
Yes... it's me.
I must say, you do...
tell a rather good tale...
terribly exciting and all.
But I was intrigued...
that you chose to omit certain...
Well, that's the way they like it...
and besides...
I didn't think they'd believe it...
if I told the way it really was.
And how are you doing...
in this world, Master Frik?
Well... I mean... there will
always be a need...
for the perfect gentleman's gentleman.
And I was, and always will be...
one of the best, you see.
Ohh... it can't be...
It 'tis...
Sir Rupert!
Yes, well I found him grazing in a field...
then, we got to reminising.
Dear old boy...
shouldn't you be dead by now?
No... no...
there's a little magic...
in me, too, Merlin.
Oh, I almost forgot...
Nimue...
What about her?
Oh, nothing really...
other than she was inquiring about you...
when I saw her... last month.
I don't understand...
what happened?
Sometime, after Mab disappeared...
her spells began to lose their power.
And, Nimue was set free!
Where is she, Frik?
Sir Rupert knows...
Thank-you, my old friend...
for everything.
Oh, no need to thank me...
I just... love happy endings.
Merlin...
Oh... my dearest...
Frik found you...
I never believed...
I would ever see you, again.
So many years... lost.
You've grown old...
You, too.
Does it matter?
No... not anymore.
What?
I think I have one, last trick...
There's no more...
That's the end of magic.