In Napoli
Where love is king
When boy meets girl
Here's what they say
When the moon hits your eye
Like a big pizza pie
That's amore
When the world seems to shine
like you've had too much wine
Bells will ring
Ting-a-ling-a-ling
Then you'll sing "Vita bella"
Hearts will play
Tippy-tippy-tay
Like a gay tarantella.
When the stars make you drool
Just like pasta fazool
When you dance down the street
with a cloud at your feet
You're in love
When you walk in a dream
But you know
you're not dreaming, signore
'Scusa me, but you see
back in old Napoli
That's amore
Lucky fella
He looks great.
That AI Conti is a genius.
I am a genius.
If you're such a genius, how come
you can't keep track of your receipts?
Al, how am I supposed to do
your income tax with this mess here?
Numbers, taxes, receipts--
I make them look better
than they did in real life.
I'm an artistic genius.
Then how come you got butter
on your tie?
Give it here. God.
You know what? I give you this.
You make good coffee.
You're a slob,
but you make good coffee.
Red roses.
Very romantic.
The guy that sends these
really knows what he's doing.
The guy who sends those
spends a lot of money...
on something that ends up
in the garbage.
I'm glad everybody
ain't like you, Loretta.
- I'd be out of business.
- What are you talking? I love flowers.
Thanks, Carmine.
- Are you ready?
- Hello, Bobo. How are you tonight?
- Very good, Mr. Johnny.
- We'll both have the Ticino salad.
- And I'll have special fish.
- Good.
You don't want the fish. It's the oily
fish tonight. Not before the plane ride.
Maybe you're right.
We'll have the manicotti.
That will be a base
for your stomach.
You eat that oily fish,
you go up in the air...
halfway to Sicily you'll be green
and your hands will be sweating.
You look after me.
- You're getting very upset.
- I'm bored with this.
- I don't understand.
- Don't ruin the whole evening.
- Patricia, please don't leave.
- Do you think I'm a talking doll?
I was just making a point
about the way you said...
-the way you stated your aspirations.
-You can kiss my aspirations, Professor!
Very clever.
The height of cleverness.
Waiter.
- Yes?
- Would you do away with her dinner...
and any evidence of her,
and bring me a big glass of vodka.
But absolutely.
A man who can't control his woman
is funny.
- She was too young for him.
- What's the matter, Uncle Bobo?
Tonight Mr. Johnny's going
to propose marriage.
- How do you know that?
- He arranged it with me.
When he asks her, he's gonna wave.
Then I serve the champagne.
Good bachelor customer
for 20 years.
- How's things?
- Fine, Bobo. We'll have the check.
No, l--
- I want to see the dessert cart.
- Very good.
- You never have dessert.
- Never is a long time.
What's the matter with you?
My scalp is not getting
enough blood sometimes.
- Have some dessert.
- I shouldn't.
- Will you marry me?
- What?
- Bobo, take the cart away.
- Very good, Miss Loretta.
- Are you proposing marriage to me?
- Yes.
All right, you know I was married
and that my husband died...
but what you don't know
is I think he and I had bad luck.
- What do you mean?
- We got married at City Hall.
-It gave bad luck to the whole marriage.
-I don't understand.
Right from the start,
we didn't do it right.
- Could you kneel down?
- On the floor?
Yeah.
- This is a good suit.
- I know that.
I helped you pick it out.
It came with two pairs of pants.
It's for luck. A man proposes marriage
to a woman, he should kneel down.
She's got him on his knees.
He's ruining his suit.
Is that man praying?
- So--
- Where's the ring?
The ring.
A ring. That's right.
I would have sprung for the ring
if it was me.
- You can use your pinkie ring.
- I like this ring.
You propose marriage to a woman,
you should offer her an engagement ring.
Loretta Castorini Clark...
on my knees,
in front of all these people...
will you marry me?
Yes, John Anthony Cammareri.
I will marry you.
I will be your wife.
- The check!
- Right away, Mr. Johnny.
What about the wedding?
My mother is dying.
When she's dead,
I'll come back and we'll get married.
How near death is she?
A week. Two weeks.
- No more.
- Let's set a date. How about a month?
Must it be so definite?
Can we just say
we'll be married when I get back?
Where?
At the City Hall? No.
My mother is dying.
I want a whole wedding
or we'll have bad luck.
For a whole wedding to be planned,
you gotta set a date.
All right. A month.
- A month from today.
- In a month.
- From today.
- I'll take care of the whole thing.
All you gotta do is show up.
Come on.
- Call me when you get in.
- I'll call you from Mama's house.
You make me very happy.
There's one thing about this wedding
I want you to do.
I want you to call this number.
It's a business number.
You ask for Ronny.
- Invite him to the wedding.
- Who is it?
- It's my younger brother.
- You got a brother?
We haven't spoken in five years.
There was some bad blood.
I want you to call him
and invite him to the wedding.
- Will you do it?
- Sure.
International Flight 604
for Rome...
with connections to Palermo
is now boarding at Gate 43.
I gotta go.
You got your ticket?
Here, I got you these:
gum and cough drops.
- Gum opens your ears when you chew it.
- Yeah.
I gotta go.
This is the last call
for lnternational Flight 604 for Rome.
- You have someone on that plane?
- Yeah, my fiance.
I put a curse on that plane.
My sister is on that plane.
I put a curse on that plane
that it's gonna explode...
burn on fire
and fall into the sea.
Fifty years ago,
she stole a man from me.
Today she tells me
that she never loved him...
that she took him
to be strong on me.
Now she's going back to Sicily.
I cursed her that the green
Atlantic water should swallow her up!
I don't believe in curses.
Neither do l.
- Mr. Johnny's, right?
- Yeah.
Good night.
The key's in it.
I've heard that song before.
What are you talking about?
I've seen the way you look at her.
- It isn't right.
- How do I look at her?
- Can I help you?
- A spumante.
- So how do I look at her?
- Like a wolf.
Never seen a wolf in your life.
That's $11.99.
I seen the wolf in everybody
I ever met...
and I see a wolf in you.
That makes 20.
Thanks.
- Have a nice night.
- You too.
- You know what I see in you?
- What?
- The girl I married.
- Come on.
Good night.
Hi, guys.
Sweethearts, how are you?
Guess what happened to me today.
Hey, how long must I wait?
Come here!
- Hi, Pop.
- Hi.
- Where's Ma?
- In bed.
- You're not sleeping?
- I can't sleep anymore.
It's too much like death.
Pop, I got news.
All right.
- Let's go into the kitchen.
- Once again I start to pray
Let it please be him
Oh, dear God, it must be him
It must be him
Or I shall die
You look tired, Pop.
What's your news?
I'm getting married.
- Again?
- Yeah.
You did this once before.
It didn't work out.
- The guy died.
- What killed him?
- He got hit by a bus.
- No. Bad luck.
Your mother and I were married
52 years. Nobody died.
You were married two years,
somebody's dead.
Don't get married again.
It don't work out for you.
- Who's the man?
- Johnny Cammareri.
He's a big baby. And why
isn't he here telling me this?
He's flying to Sicily.
His mother is dying.
More bad luck. I don't like his face.
I don't like his lips.
When he smiles, I can't see his teeth.
What is he hiding?
- When are you gonna do it?
- In a month.
- I won't come.
- You gotta give me away.
- I didn't give you away the first time.
- And I had bad luck!
Maybe if you gave me away...
and I got married in a church
in a wedding dress...
instead of down at the City Hall
with strangers outside the door...
then maybe I wouldn't have had
the bad luck I had.
Maybe.
I had no reception,
no wedding cake, no nothing.
Johnny got down on his knees
and proposed to me at the Grand Ticino.
- He did?
- Yeah.
- That don't sound like Johnny.
- Well--
- Where's the ring?
- Here.
It looks stupid.
It's a pinky ring.
- It's a man's ring.
- It's temporary!
Everything is temporary!
That don't excuse nothing!
You're coming?
Let's go tell your mother.
Rose.
Who's dead?
Nobody.
- Loretta's getting married.
- Again?
- Yeah.
- Johnny Cammareri.
- I don't like him.
- You're not gonna marry him, Cosmo.
- Do you love him?
- No.
Good. When you love them,
they drive you crazy...
'cause they know they can.
- But you like him?
- Yeah.
He's a sweet man, Ma.
This time I'm gonna get married
in a church and have a big reception.
- Who's gonna pay for that?
- Pop.
What?
Father of the bride pays.
I have no money.
- You're rich. You're just cheap.
- I don't want to pay for nothing.
It's your duty as my father
to pay for the wedding.
I won't pay for nothing.
He didn't used to be cheap.
He thinks if he holds onto his money,
he will never die.
What's done is done
And I tell myself
don't be a fool
Now he'll play that damn record
and won't touch me when he comes to bed.
Have a lot of fun
It's easy when you play it cool
Look at that old man.
How many dogs has he got?
- Keep your dogs off my lawn.
- Come on.
Don't do that.
She's asleep.
- She's asleep.
- Look all the flowers on Foncica.
My brother sent her a blue flower.
I can only see things in my house.
Things in my house are very bad.
I don't know what to advise my son.
I think he should pay
for the wedding...
but it's important
that he don't look ridiculous.
- Why don't you talk to him?
- I will.
But I must find the right moment.
See that bella luna last night?
The moon brings the woman
to the man.
Upstairs.
Everybody upstairs.
Come on.
- Will you live here?
- No.
- Why not?
- Pop don't like Johnny.
We'll sell the house.
I got married before,
you didn't sell.
Grandma was still alive.
Chiro was still home going to school.
Now he's married, gone to Florida.
If you and Johnny moved in
and had a baby--
Ma, I'm 37 years old.
What's 37?
I didn't have Chiro
till after I was 37.
It ain't over till it's over.
Johnny's got a big apartment.
We'll move in there.
So we'll sell the house.
You know-- What-- I want to live here.
I love the house.
Pop don't like Johnny.
No, he don't.
I'll get it.
Hello?
Yeah, this is Loretta Castorini.
Hello, operator?
- Yeah.
- Yes. Shh! It's me.
I'm calling from the death bed
of my mother.
Yeah, how was your plane ride?
The waitresses were very nice.
- My mother is slipping away.
- How long do I have to wait?
-I can't talk long.
-Did you tell her we're getting married?
No, not yet. I'm waiting
till a moment when she's peaceful.
Well, don't wait till she's dead.
Have you called my brother?
No. I'm sorry. Not yet.
I forgot.
- Will you do it today?
- Yes.
Make sure he comes to the wedding.
Five years is too long
for bad blood between brothers.
Nothing can replace the family.
I can see that now.
Loretta, are you there?
I'm sorry.
I'll do it today.
And listen, Johnny.
- Call me after you tell her.
- All right.
And don't stand directly under the sun.
You got a hat. Use your hat.
I got my hat.
All right. Bye.
All right. Bye-bye.
What did I do with that card?
How's the mother?
She's dying, but I could still
hear her big mouth.
He didn't tell her.
You know,
the woman makes him crazy.
Now who you calling?
Cammareri's.
Is Ronny Cammareri there, please?
Hold on.
Ronny, the phone!
Yeah, this is Ronny.
Yeah, I'm calling for your brother.
He's getting married,
and he would like it if you would come.
Why didn't he call himself?
- He's in Palermo.
- What's wrong can never be made right.
Look, just let me come
and talk--
Talk to you! Animal!
What an animal!
Thanks, Mrs. Fugocci.
Here you go.
Bye. See you tomorrow.
- Bye.
- Come on, honey.
- Is Ronny Cammareri here?
- He's down at the ovens.
- What do you want?
- I want to talk to him.
This way.
- What?
- Somebody here to see Ronny.
Somebody wants to see you!
- You come for my brother Johnny?
- Yeah.
Why?
We're gonna get married.
- You're gonna marry my brother Johnny?
- Yeah.
Would you like to go someplace
so we could talk--
- I have no life.
- Excuse me?
My brother Johnny
took my life from me.
I don't understand you.
And now he's getting married.
He has his.
He's getting his,
and he wants me to come.
What is life?
- I didn't come here to upset you.
- They say bread is life.
And I bake bread, bread, bread.
I sweat
and shovel this stinking dough...
in and out of this hot hole
in the wall...
and I should be so happy, huh, sweetie?
You want me to come to the wedding
of my brother Johnny?
Where's my wedding?
Chrissy, bring me the big knife
over by the wall.
I'm gonna cut my throat!
Maybe I should come back
another time.
No, I want you to see this.
I want you...
to watch me kill myself
so you can tell my brother Johnny...
on his wedding day, okay?
I won't do it!
She won't do it.
Do you know about me?
- Mr. Cammareri--
- What?
Okay.
Nothing is anybody's fault,
but things happen.
Look.
This wood is fake.
Five years ago,
I was engaged to be married...
and Johnny came in here
and ordered bread from me.
I said, "Okay, some bread."
And I put my hand in the slicer...
and it got caught
'cause I wasn't paying attention.
The slicer chewed off my hand.
It's funny, 'cause when my fiance
found out about it...
when she found out I had been maimed,
she left me for another man.
That's the bad blood
between you and Johnny?
Yes, that's it.
But that's not Johnny's fault.
I don't care!
I ain't no freaking monument to justice!
I lost my hand!
I lost my bride!
Johnny has his hand!
Johnny has his bride!
You want me to take my heartbreak,
put it away and forget it?
Is it just a matter of time...
before a man opens his eyes...
and gives up his one...
dream of happiness?
Maybe.
This is the most tormented man
I have ever known.
I'm in love with this man...
but he doesn't know that.
I never told him,
'cause he could never love anybody...
since he lost his hand
and his girl.
Where do you live?
Upstairs.
Can we just talk?
What are we painting here,
the Sistine Chapel?
We should have been plumbers
like Castorini.
What do you think?
Ten thousand eight hundred dollars.
That seems like a lot.
Look...
there are three kinds of pipe.
There's the kind of pipe you have,
which is garbage.
You can see
where that's gotten you.
Then there's bronze,
which is very good.
Unless something goes wrong...
and something always goes wrong.
Then there's copper,
which is the only pipe I use.
It costs money
because it saves money.
I think we should follow
Mr. Castorini's advice.
Yeah.
And then there's copper...
which is the only pipe I use.
It costs money.
It costs money because...
it saves money.
- What did they say?
- The man understood me.
The woman wanted to be cheap,
but the man saw I was right.
You have such a head for knowing.
You know everything.
I brought you something.
It's a present.
Oh, my God.
They're little birds and stars.
Birds fly to the stars I guess.
- What's that smell?
- I'm making you a steak.
- I don't want it.
- You'll eat it.
I like it well-done!
You'll eat this one bloody
to feed your blood.
This is good.
- Where'd Johnny find you?
- He knew my husband who died.
- How'd he die?
- A bus hit him.
- Fast?
- Instantaneous.
- When'd you get engaged?
- Yesterday.
So five years ago you got your hand
cut off and your woman left you.
- No woman since then?
- No.
- Stupid.
- When your husband get hit?
Seven years ago.
- How many men since then?
- Just Johnny.
- Stupid yourself.
- Unlucky.
- I've not been lucky.
- I don't care about luck.
You understand me?
It ain't that.
What's the matter with you? You think
you're the only one who shed a tear?
Why are you talking to me?
You got any whiskey? How about
you get me a glass of whiskey?
I'll call you later.
- She was right to leave me.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
- You really are stupid.
You don't know nothing about it.
Look, I was raised
that a girl gets married young.
I held out for love.
I got married when I was 28.
I met a man. I loved him.
I married him.
He wanted to have a baby right away.
I said we should wait.
Then he gets hit by a bus.
What do I got?
No man, no baby, no nothing.
How did I know that man
was a gift I couldn't keep.
My one chance at happiness.
You tell me the story, and you
act like you know what it means...
but I can see what
the true story is and you can't.
That woman didn't leave you, okay?
You can't see what you are,
and I see everything. You're a wolf.
- I'm a wolf?
- Yeah.
The big part of you has no words,
and it's a wolf.
That woman was a trap for you. She
caught you, and you couldn't get away...
so you chewed off your own foot.
That was the price
you had to pay for your freedom.
Johnny had nothing to do with it.
You did what you had to do
between you and you.
And now you're afraid...
because you know
the big part of you is a wolf...
that has the courage
to bite off its own hand...
to save itself from the trap
of the wrong love.
That's why there's been no woman
since that wrong woman. Okay?
You're scared to death
of what the wolf will do...
- if you make that mistake again.
- What are you doing?
- I'm telling you your life.
- Stop it.
Why are you marrying Johnny?
He's a fool!
Because I have no luck.
He made me look the wrong way,
and I cut off my hand!
He could make you look the wrong way.
You could lose your whole head!
I'm looking where I have to
to become a bride!
- A bride without a head!
- A wolf without a foot!
Wait a minute!
What are you doing?
Son of a bitch!
Where are you taking me?
To the bed.
Oh, God.
Okay, I don't care.
Take me to the bed.
- I don't care about anything.
- I don't believe this is happening.
- I was dead.
- Me too.
- What about Johnny?
- You're mad at him.
Take your revenge
out on me.
Leave nothing left
for him to marry.
Leave nothing
but the skin over my bones.
All right.
There will be nothing left.
Let's eat while it's hot.
Where's Loretta?
We're eating without her?
- She must be eating out.
- She don't know what she's missing.
It's not like her not to call.
She's got a lot on her mind.
We can talk about her, right?
- Everybody knows she's getting married.
- I don't want to talk about it.
I think it's a great idea
and about time.
What's she gonna do with the rest
of her life if she don't get married?
I don't want to talk about it!
My father needs another plate.
Many years ago,
when they told me...
you were marrying my sister...
I was happy.
When I told Rose...
that I was marrying Rita...
she was happy.
Marriage is happy news, right?
Rose, pass the wine.
I never seen anybody so in love...
Iike Cosmo was back then.
He'd stand outside the house all day
looking in the windows.
I never told you this
'cause it's not really a story...
but one time I woke up
in the middle of the night...
'cause of this bright light
in my face...
Iike a flashlight.
I couldn't think what it was.
I looked out the window,
and it was the moon...
as big as a house.
I never seen the moon
so big before or since.
I was almost scared,
like it was gonna crush the house.
Then I looked down...
and standing there in the street
was Cosmo...
Iooking up at the windows.
This is the funny part.
I got mad at you, Cosmo.
I thought you had brought
that big moon over to my house...
'cause you were so in love...
and woke me up with it.
I was half asleep I guess.
I didn't know any better.
You were altogether asleep.
You were dreaming.
You were there.
I don't want to talk about it.
What do you want to talk about?
Why are you drinking so much?
Old man, you give those dogs
another piece of my food...
I'll kick you
till you're dead.
You drank too much.
You'll sleep too hard, and later
you'll be up when you should be down.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing. I'm looking at the moon.
It's perfect.
I never seen a moon
like that before.
Makes you look like an angel.
Looks like a giant snowball.
- Rita.
- What?
Rita, dear, wake up.
Look.
It's Cosmo's moon.
What are you talking about?
Cosmo can't own the moon.
It's that moon
I was talking about at dinner.
Is he down there?
Is who down there?
- What would he be doing down there?
- I don't know.
You know something?
In that light...
with that expression
on your face...
you look about 25 years old.
What do you want?
Get out.