MY GIRL
English subtitles by Pippi Longstocking
January 1, 2009
I was born jaundiced.
Once I sat on a toilet seat
at a truck stop and caught hemorrhoids.
I've learned to live with a chicken bone
lodged in my throat for three years.
So I knew dad would be devastated
when he learned my latest affliction.
Dad, I don't want
to upset you...
but my left breast is developing
significantly faster than my right.
It can only mean one thing,
cancer. I'm dying.
Sweetie, hand me the mayonnaise
out of the fridge.
Who's in?
Raise your hand.
Are you coming or not,
Thomas J.?
- I don't think so.
- I knew he wouldn't come.
I have to go home.
To play with his dolls.
Leave him alone.
Come on. Let's go.
You didn't pay me.
How do I know
you'll show us one?
You're such a baby.
All right. Here.
Follow me
and don't say a word.
You ready?
You sure you want to see it?
Or are you yellow?
I'm not chicken.
Lean forward.
It's empty!
- You're so weird.
- I want my money back.
- I was afraid of this.
- Of what?
Sometimes
when we get them...
they're not
completely dead.
Like when they cut
a chicken's head off -
- and they still run around.
- You're full of shit.
I bet she's roaming
around this house somewhere.
There she is
in the rocking chair.
Hi, Gramoo.
Vada, would you bring down
my cigarettes?
See you later.
- Did you know he was my wood shop teacher?
- You took wood shop?
I made a tie rack.
- The fluid's mixed?
- Yes.
Put them on the stool.
Guess what?
I beat Thomas J. in Monopoly.
The rack holds six ties.
I still have mine.
- Arthur!
- Vada!
- I beat Thomas J. in Monopoly.
- Good for you.
Once you put hotels on Boardwalk
and Park Place, you're a shoo-in.
- I like to buy railroads.
- Vada, we're trying to work here.
Cruella De Vil
stole all the puppies.
Hand me the cannula.
There he was
just-a walkin' down the street
- Vada!
- Dad?
I'm embalming my high school teacher.
Don't sing.
All right, Arthur.
Slide him to me a little bit.
Alright, that's good.
CANCER OF PROSTATE
Let's put him in a nice model C-501
bronze stainless "Eternal Journey".
He'll look like a champion.
SULTENFUSS PARLOR
Is Mr. Harry Sultenfuss in?
Sure. Come on in.
Have you had the unfortunate experience
of recently losing a loved one?
Could I see your dad for a second?
Dad! Somebody's here!
He's downstairs working on Mr. Layton.
Prostate cancer.
Once it hits your prostate,
you're a goner.
- How may I help you?
- I'm Shelly DeVoto.
We spoke the other day
regarding the makeup artist job.
It's still available, I hope?
I think it's still available.
I'm a licensed cosmetologist.
I worked for two years
at the Dino Raphael Salon.
My customers cried
when I said I was leaving.
- Miss DeVoto...
- I have a wonderful disposition.
I put people at ease.
These people
are already at ease.
This is not a beauty parlor.
It's a funeral parlor.
- They're dead?
- They are.
Stiffs?
Deceased.
The ad just said
"makeup artist."
Excuse me a second,
will you?
Sure.
Hi, George.
This is a 1258.
I didn't want
the burnished handles.
- Is that your camper?
- Yes. It is.
That's really cool.
Hello.
She's shy.
Put it back
in the display room.
Daddy, how come
that coffin's so small?
They come in all sizes,
just like shoes.
- Is it for a child?
- Of course not.
- Then who's it for?
- Short people. Very short people.
Excuse me.
What about the job?
Pardon?
I need the job.
You still want it?
Even though...
Sure. It's no big deal.
You see, all my former clients
will eventually die -
- and all your clients
used to be alive.
So they have something
in common.
You'd do hair and makeup
and answer the phone.
OK, mr Sultenfuss.
You've got a deal..
You can start right away.
Call me Harry.
Is this what you'd normally
wear for work?
Don't get me wrong.
I like it very much.
I promise I'll take good
care of these people.
They deserve it.
They're dead.
All they've got left
is their looks.
Hey, look at this.
No feet.
Wow.
A real Evel Knievel.
ONLY PICK UP TRUCKS ALLOWED
NO BICYCLES
What are you doing in my garage?!
Get out of here!
Hi, Veda.
What's wrong today?
I'm very sick.
OK, take a seat.
I'll check if the doctor can see you.
Vada's here.
She says she's sick.
She looks all right.
OK, he'll see you.
Why don't you go in?
Well, what is it?
I can handle it.
You are perfectly healthy.
That can't be.
I have all the classic symptoms.
Did they bring
Mr. Layton to your house today?
Yes.
You've got to stop this. There's
absolutely nothing wrong with you.
I'll just have to get
a second opinion.
What did he say
is wrong with you?
The whole medical profession
is a crock.
Hey, wait up for me!
Look!
At what?
That's Mr. Bixler.
Let's go talk to him.
I don't want to talk
to no teacher, it's summer!
Hi, mr. Bixler!
Mademoiselle Sultenfuss
and the amazing Dr. J.
- How's the summer treating you?
- It's OK.
Mr. Bixler, I finished all the books
for summer reading.
Really? Already?
The summer's just begun.
Yes. Now I'm reading
"War and Peace" for fun.
No wonder you're
my prize pupil.
What about you, Thomas J.?
I haven't started.
Better get on his case, Vada.
How come you're painting
this house?
Well, I just bought it.
Now I'm fixing it up.
This is one big house
for one single person.
Well -
- you never can tell.
I might get a pet.
How are you going to pay
for this house if you're not working?
Well, I'm going to teach
creative writing this summer.
I'm doing some work.
- How much does it cost?
- 35 dollars.
What do you get for that?
Me. Two hours a week
talking about poetry.
Is this an interrogation, Vada?
No. Well, I guess I'll go home
and finish off "War and Peace."
It's summer.
You're kids. Go play.
Want to go to Gray's Orchard
and pick some peaches?
No. I'm going home.
Why? It's not dinner time yet.
You're just like a dog.
You just go home to eat.
Don't pee on the hydrant!
Bill
I love you so
I always will
I look at you
and see the passion
Oh, but am I ever gonna see my
wedding day?
Trooper Gwynn called.
There was a big accident on PA34.
They're bringing
in two tomorrow.
Excuse me, Harry. I finished
Mr. Layton's hair, I think...
What's wrong with her?
She's pretending.
Vada, get up and eat your broccoli.
I think it's my prostate.
How many removals did you say...?
We have to do a V section tomorrow,
will you give me a hand?
I guess so.
Now, this isn't gonna be a repeat of that
snooker accident a few years ago?
Don't knock that up, it's how
we got that new Cadillac.
I know that, except I had a body in my
bedroom, you had a body in your bedroom.
We were littered with people's bodies.
- Who's winning?
- I am.
Look! Vada and her
little boyfriend.
He's not my boyfriend.
I bet she kisses him
on the lips.
You think I'd kiss that ugly thing?
Yeah, anyway.
Come on. Let's go.
Judy's father
owns the Bijou theater.
We see all the movies
we want for free.
Maybe you can come sometime?
Eew, don't invite her.
She'll bring her boyfriend.
Vada and Thomas
Sittin' in a tree
K-I-S-S-I-N-G
First comes love
Then comes marriage
Then comes Thomas J.
in the baby carriage
You know Vada, you shouldn't
let those girls upset you.
I'm not upset.
I would never play with those girls.
I surround myself with people
I find intellectually stimulating.
Want a piece of chocolate?
- Thomas J.?
- I'm allergic to it.
- To chocolate?
- He's allergic to everything.
Chocolate?
To everything.
That's a pretty ring you're wearing.
It's a mood ring.
It doesn't work.
It's always black.
It's only black when you're around
because you put me in a bad mood.
Maybe black
means you're happy.
I don't think so.
Shelly,
how can I get $35?
She's crazy. She wants to go
to school over the summer.
It's not a real school.
It's a writing class.
I want to be a writer.
She only wants to go cause her
sweetie pie's the teacher.
Shut your
big, fat mouth!
I think you'd make
a fine writer.
Did you ask your dad?
He won't give it to me.
You don't know that.
Ask him.
Edith, what channel
is Cronkite on?
Channel two, Archie.
The one we don't watch
because you always say -
- Walter Cronkite
is a communist.
I never said that, Edith.
The man ain't all red.
What's wrong with this?
Nothing's coming on.
Daddy, can I have $35?
That's a lot
for a little girl.
It's for school.
A summer writing class.
Any more soda left?
Shelly thinks I'd be
a good writer.
Last month you wanted to play violin.
Then you wanted to be
a ventriloquist.
Dad?
I love this guy.
What?
The money?
Maybe next summer.
He forgot about the time
I wanted to be a magician.
I was really great
at making myself disappear.
Want to play?
No, I've got to go
to a cemetery.
Keep your head up.
Don't look at the ball,
look at me.
See? You were lookin'
at the ball.
All right?
Keep your head up.
Please!
Open the door, please!
Someone open the door!
Please!
Vada.
What happened?
My ball.
I lost my ball.
Come on.
Excuse me, Harry?
Could you take a look
at Mrs. Porter?
Didn't I give you a picture
of what she looked like?
You don't like it?
This was
the Reverend Porter's wife.
You have her looking
like a two-dollar hooker.
I think she looks nice.
Her lips are very thin.
I used the gloss
to give them a sensual quality.
And her eyes
just needed a little definition.
And her hair...
Nobody wears this hairdo in 1972.
She did.
This photo was taken a month ago
at the church food drive.
I wanted to get past
the schoolmarm image.
That wasn't an image.
She was an old schoolmarm.
Fix it.
Harry?
I was just wondering...
...if there's anything wrong with Vada.
What do you mean?
- The other night...
- Oh, that. She likes to play.
I don't think so.
I think she's confused
about death.
She was raised in a funeral home.
She knows a little about it.
But Harry, I really think...
She's a happy eleven-year-old girl.
Look...
...don't give me any advice
about my daughter, okay?
There's Shelly!
Hi!
Can we look around
in your camper?
Sure. I'll give you
the royal tour.
This is the coolest thing. You
can really eat and sleep here?
I'm going to drive us
to Liverpool.
Liverpool?
Big Ringo fan.
- Would you like a soda?
- I would.
- Thomas?
- Yes please.
What are you reading?
You shouldn't be looking at that.
It's too old for you.
Did you read all these books?
What are they about?
Mostly love
and romance.
Eew, gross!
They're just fun to read.
Here. Cheers.
Are you married?
No, I'm divorced.
Daddy says it's bad
when people get divorced.
I know. Sometimes married people find out
they can't live with each other.
The Meyers are divorced.
Shelly, can I have a cookie?
Hey, where are all the cookies?
Well, I guess you found
my secret hiding place.
What are you saving for?
Nothing in particular.
Just putting it away for a rainy day.
I'm supposed to be home at
noon for lunch. Thanks, Shelly!
Bye.
Well, miss Vada, what do you say we head back?
- Can I use your bathroom first?
- Sure.
You don't have to wait. Daddy will
be mad if you're late.
"The great way is not difficult
for those with no preferences.
With the absence of both love and hate,
everything becomes clear -
and undisguised."
That was written by a Chinese
philosopher in the year 600.
Why would I bring that up
in a creative writing class?
Because the absence of judgement
helps us to appreciate reality.
In other words -
- I want you to listen
to your classmates' writing -
- with a clear and open heart.
OK, so who's gonna go first?
I got one.
"I sang a song for you to hear -
I painted a picture for you to see -
I picked a rose for you to smell -
I planted grass for you to touch -
But you didn't hear my song.
You did not see my picture.
You did not smell my rose and
you did not touch my grass!"
Maybe she was outta town?
That's not funny!
His poem is about futility!
We toil in unrewarded obscurity.
Now, I hear judgement.
Don't forget the part about the
open heart! Vada?
Is there something I can do for you?
I paid the money.
For this class?
I wanna be a writer.
But Vada, this is an
adult writing class!
Hey, I think it's beautiful! She
wants to be a writer!
More power to you, little sister!
Vada?
You sure you wanna do this?
OK, welcome to the class!
Go find a seat.
OK, who's next?
I experienced something with my
boyfriend the other day -
- and I wrote a few words down.
The floor is yours, Ronda!
"He covers me like a blanket -
from the cold dark night.
As I look into his eyes I know it's right.
To touch, to feel.
I know he's real.
Flesh all a-mesh.
I can't fight it.
There's no point.
I wake up and light a joint."
I wrote a poem, too.
Please.
"Ode to Ice Cream"
by Vada Sultenfuss.
"I like ice cream a whole lot.
It tastes good when days are hot.
On a cone or in a dish,
this would be my only wish.
Vanilla, chocolate, rocky road,
even with pie a la mode.''
That's all I've got so far.
I hear that, Vada.
"Flesh all a-mesh" or "rocky road",
it's about desire.
Vada, that's very sweet and itrhymes,
and that's all good, but...
You're not expressing to
me what's in your soul.
I want you to show me how you see the world,
your fears or desires.
Your innermost secrets.
My fears and secrets?
I'm afraid I killed my mother.
Can not do without Harry's wild about me!
Excuse me, Harry?
I just wanted to let you know that flower's
were delievered.
And the room is all setup.
Thanks.
Listen, I want to apologize for the other day
downstairs about Vada.
I was a little harsh.
I shouldn't stick my nose in
other people's business.
It's just that I like
Vada very much.
After my wife died grandma moved in here
to help us take care of Vada.
They were very close.
But lately as her mind's been wandering...
Vada has been acting kinda crazy.
I'm sure she'll snap out of it though.
I'm sure she will.
Nothing's biting today.
Maybe they had a big breakfast.
I'm gonna be an acrobat
when I grow up.
Big deal, I can do that too!
Thomas J., you got something!
Hurry!
I'm trying.
Reel it in!
It's a sunny, throw it back.
I don't like touching fish. I'll
pull the hook out without touching it.
You're hurting him, don't kill him!
Darn hook.
I'm bleeding.
Did it get away?
Go look.
Yeah, it got away.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, we can become blood brothers!
No, I don't wanna.
You could pick that
scab on your arm.
It's a mosquito bite.
It'll bleed.
If I do it, can we go?
OK, rub them together.
Now we're blood brothers for life.
DEATH NOTICE
Hi.
Hi, what can I do for you?
Nothing, I was just wondering
what you were doing.
Nothing, I'm just typing
up a funeral notice.
When someone dies,
we put one in the paper.
It's a service
we provide for the family.
"Bader, Lorenzo. Died June 22, 1972.
Devoted husband to Nicolette.
Cherished father
of Fabrizio and Heidi.
In lieu of flowers, please send
donations to the Holy Name Society."
I wrote that.
No kidding?
It's good! "In lieu of."
I love that word, "lieu".
I prefer it to "instead", it
has  more dignity
"In lieu", "instead".
No contest.
It's no big deal
Harry...
You have to learn
how to take a compliment.
Movies! Movies...
"Love Story" at the drive-in! Cried
my eyes out! Did you see it?
I haven't been to the movies in ages!
I love to see movies.
Especially at the drive-in.
I don't think there's anything
more romantic than going to the drive-in.
I'll let you back to work.
I do enjoy playing bingo.
If you'd like to join me
tomorrow night, you're welcome to.
Hi Vada.
- Are you going out somewhere?
- No.
So how come you're
putting lipstick on?
A girl's always gotta look her best.
I think lipstick looks fake.
No one's lips are like that color.
- Have you ever tried any?
- No.
Come here, sit down.
Go like this.
A little less.
Now first we blot.
Take a look.
It looks real nice on you.
Shelly, do you think I'm pretty?
Yes Vada, I think you are very pretty.
You got these great, big -
sparkling eyes.
The cutest little nose.
And amazing mouth.
The boys at school
don't think I am.
They'll come around.
Close your eyes. I want to bring out
the gorgeous color in them.
Now, the first rule in
applying eye make-up -
- is you can never wear enough
blue eye shadow.
Do you like putting make-up on people?
I've been trying to get to Hollywood
to do make-up for the movie stars -
- but I haven't gotten there yet.
Open your eyes.
Shelly, I would definitely hold off
on that Hollywood thing.
Your lip bleeding?
What's wrong with your eyes?
A girl can never wear enough eye shadow!
Where's your bike?
In the garage. Walk me over.
It's only a garage, come on!
One of my streamers is gone.
It probably fell off in here.
Hey, look at this!
That was Gramoo's.
It's a phrenology chart.
They used to study the bones in your head
to see if you had a good personality or not.
Come here, I'll diagnose your head.
I don't wanna.
Come on, it's fun.
- Interesting.
- What?
You have no personality.
-Where does it say that?
-Never mind.
Is that your dad?
Yes.
Who's that with your dad?
It's my mother.
Do you remember her?
Gramoo said she's in heaven.
What do you think it's like?
- What?
- Heaven!
I think...
... everybody gets
their own white horse.
And all they do is ride them and
eat marshmallows all day.
And everybody's best friends
with everybody else.
When you play sports...
...there's no teams,
so nobody gets picked last.
But what if you're afraid
to ride horses?
Doesn't matter, cause
they're not regular horses.
They've got wings.
And it's no big deal if you fall.
You just land in a cloud.
That doesn't sound so bad!
Come on.
We're gonna find
that streamer.
Well well well, whats'
going on in here?
Nothing.
I'm dressing.
Oh, you're dressing, huh?
Don't you know it's not nice
to lie to your big brother?
Hey, watch the hair!
The shirt!
- Give!
- All right!
I'm going out with Shelly.
Oh yes, that's great!
I'm very nervous!
- Why?
- Last date I had was 20 years ago!
That's true.
Harry, sit down.
Let me fill you in
on today's women.
Since the last time you
dated something happened.
The sexual revolution.
Before, you had to hold a door
for a woman...
...pull her chair out,
pick up the check.
You wanna know what else is missing?
Bras.
Oh, come on!
Harry, I'm serious!
Trust me, Harry!
This women's lib thing is in!
You gotta treat her like
every Tom, Dick and Harry.
Are you sure about all this?
Did you not tell Vada
I'm a womanizer?
I'm running late.
Shelly will be here any minute.
She's picking you up, good!
You're on the right track!
No, she's just driving over here.
Then we're taking my car.
How do I look?
Like a Sultenfuss!
Go get her!
Night, Vada.
Dad?
Why are you dressed
up to play bingo?
I just wanna look nice.
You never cared before!
Well, Shelly's coming over,
we're gonna go together.
Why?
She likes to play bingo.
Can I go too?
No, I think you better stay
here and keep Gramoo company.
I've got to admit, I'd as soon
not have any more bounty prisoners -
coming through Dodge any time soon.
It's a bit wearin'
on the nerves.
This day was starting off just fine -
- and I'm gonna keep it that way.
Doc, you never
answered my question.
Vada?
- Where are you?
- Here!
Don't do that!
Sorry!
What do you want?
My mom will skin me alive
if she finds out I'm out here.
Let's go to the church.
They're playing bingo tonight.
I told you I'd get in trouble!
Pacifist!
Am not!
Bed wetter!
I stopped that!
N-38!
Under the "N"...
Don't laugh.
There's a strategy to bingo.
For instance, on a given night,
anybody can win. But I play the odds.
When choosing bingo cards I use
the laws of probabilities -
- to avoid duplicate number systems.
This way, you get much more activity.
Does it make it easier to win?
No. Just more activity.
I-17.
Under the "I", 1-7.
They won't let us in, Vada!
We're kids.
We're not going to bet.
We're just gonna watch.
Watch bingo? I don't even
like to play bingo!
Duck.
N-42.
- Under the "N", 4-2.
- Oh, great!
There's your dad
and Shelly!
I don't want them
to see me.
3-7.
B-4.
Under the "B", 4.
O-69.
Under the "O", 6-9.
I just had a terrible thought.
What's that?
I'm gonna be putting makeup
on some of these people very soon.
Why do you think
these seats were empty?
B-6.
Under the "B", 6.
Can we go yet?
Go!
You know, I'm not allowed
out by myself after dark.
O-67.
Under the "O", 6-7.
I'm just not lucky, Harry!
Look, it's not always luck.
Depending on the placement
of the numbers -
- a guy with 10 cards can win just
as easily as a guy with a 100.
Kinda like men.
How do you mean?
Well, you can be in a
room with a hundred men -
- and not like any of them.
Or you can be in a room
with just one man.
And he's exactly
the one you want.
Bingo!
We have a winner!
Will the winner raise their hand?
There was no bingo, it
came from outside!
How can someone outside get a bingo?
Someone outside
didn't get a bingo.
Someone outside yelled "bingo,"
you moron!
- Who you calling a moron?
- Put a lid on it, Vern!
Put a lid on it?
If you weren't 200 years old,
I'd kick your wrinkled ass!
Hey fellas, it's
just a bingo game!
We can go.
I had a good time tonight.
I haven't had a bingo partner in ages.
You'd like to come inside to see
my house? Just for a minute.
Sure.
Home, sweet home.
It's nice.
I did it myself.
I read a magazine article about
how to maximize small spaces.
Well, it certainly looks
bigger than it seems.
You can look in the
bathroom if you want.
People are always
curious about that.
Like what happens
when you flush.
Are you mad at me?
No, why?
I don't know, tonight you
just seemed a little cool.
Not opening car doors...
That was Phil, trying to give
me advice on dating 70s women.
Look, I'm so out of touch, I
haven't dated a woman in ages.
Not since my wife died.
What happened to her?
Complications during child birth.
She died two days
after Vada was born.
Did she ever see Vada?
I brought the baby into
the room a couple of times.
She opened her eyes.
Yeah, I think she saw Vada.
It was...
Did I ruin this?
Dance with me?
Here?
This is where we are.
Is there enough room?
- I haven't danced...
- ... in ages. I know. Me neither.
Bra?
See! You're not that
out of touch!
Phil, he's...
You're good.
At Woodman High, I was
considered a hot date.
I did a killer Trug.
What are you wearing?
"Old Spice". Phil says
it's a timeless classic.
So do you want to?
Want to what?
- Kiss me?
- Yes.
Good.
Good at kissing and dancing.
I'm very optimistic.
I better go...
It's only a clock.
Good night, Shelly.
Good night.
I guess it's official.
We had a date.
Maybe we can play bingo
again sometime?
I'm tired of bingo.
Maybe we should try
that drive-in of yours.
Good night.
Before class started -
- Ronda and Justin wanted to lead
the class in a group meditation.
That's really cool!
What we're going to do is
send our vibes out into the group.
Everybody hold hands
and close your eyes.
Relax your muscles
and take deep breaths.
Now, try to feel what the
other person is feeling -
- without speaking any words.
Send out your vibe and receive the
vibes from around you at the same time.
Can you feel it?
OK, open your eyes.
What did everybody feel?
I felt mrs. Hunsaker's strength.
I can feel that Ronda
is one with the earth.
She's so cosmically in tune!
So right on!
That's exactly what I sent out.
And I felt like you were full
of inner peace and harmony.
Vada, what did you feel?
I felt Justin's hangnail.
No Vada, that's not what
we're looking for.
A hangnail is insignificant.
What's in my soul?
Feel my aura.
I don't think I'm allowed to.
Tell you what, let's try
it again. Hold hands.
Gramoo once had a hangnail
on her big toe.
It got infected and traveled
to her vocal chords.
Ruined her singing voice.
I don't think Gramoo
thought it was insignificant.
And some lettuce.
Watch out for the rust
when you get lettuce.
Hey, I thought I
recognized you two.
- Hi Vada!
- Hi.
- We're just picking things up
for the barbecue.
- Me too.
Mind if I tag along?
Not at all.
Lot of potatoes!
It's for Shelly's
famouse potato sallad.
Looking forward to that!
Damn it!
Watch what you're doing, Vada!
Sorry.
This'll be my first July 4th
picnic in a long time.
Dad, didn't you say you
needed prunes real bad?
Vada, just put anything you
want in the cart. Anything at all.
I don't know what's
gotten in to her today.
I need olives.
I used to like to play
with my Ken and Barbie dolls.
Ken was my favorite.
Then one Christmas,
I got them a camper.
All they wanted to do
was hang out by themselves.
So I wasn't too upset when they took
that wrong turn and went over the cliff.
I told you, use fewer briquettes.
Now look what you've done.p
You've cremated them.
That's what I do.
Do you want to do it?
Why don't you pre-measure the briquettes
in little packages?
Put out a product.
Support me a while.
How's it going, chef?
I love your apron.
Thanks.
- Is it ready yet?
- No, sweetie. Not yet.
When?
Soon, honey, soon.
In a minute. Look, honey, it's hot.
You'll burn your nose. Look out.
Rub-a-dub-dub...
Thanks for the grub, Yeah, God.
I'll second that.
Shelly, you like seafood?
Aha, what?
"See food."
That's attractive.
Shit!
Excuse me.
Hey, who lives here?
The Addams family?
- Danny, what are you doing here?
- What am I doing here?
Hi, Ralph!
Danny, how'd you find me?
You told everybody where you were going.
I'm here for the motor home.
- No, I bought it. I paid for it.
- These two people do not have a good relationship.
I've been living in it.
The camper is mine!
Excuse me, "mutual asset."
That's what the lawyer said.
Not Shelly's recreational vehicle.
Keep your voice down!
My boss is watching us.
I'm impressed!
Oh God, I guess I have
to introduce you now.
This is Harry, Phil,
Gramoo and Vada Sultenfuss.
Vada Sultenfuss?
Tough break!
I like my name.
This is Danny and Ralph.
They own the Dino Raphael
Salon in Detroit.
We just to be married.
Are you here to take Shelly back?
It's nice to meet you.
We've got burgers and hot dogs
here if you'd like to join us.
Can't stay. I'm here because my wife...
Ex!
My ex-wife seems to have
ripped off my camper.
Honestly Harry, he got the Mustang.
I promise.
I don't think so, I've got a copy
of the property settlement here.
Shit! This is my lease.
Damn it. I keep forgetting
things. Getting senile.
What?
I know you've suffered
a terrible loss...
and there's nothing
anyone can do to comfort you.
I urge you to focus on the times
you had with the camper...
The trips you took,
the sights you saw...
Those days are gone, but they'll
live on in your heart forever.
Is he boinking you?
That's a real bonehead thing to say!
Look, you're not gonna
take Shelly's camper.
- Oh, no?
- It's her home. It's where she lives.
Oh really!
Really? Fine. Go cook.
Give me the goddamn keys!
- Come on!
- That hurts!
What you do that for?
- Who are you?
- I'm his brother.
Then you'll be visiting us quite often.
Why?
Because if he ever tries to take
Shelly's camper again -
- I'm gonna bury him in my front yard.
Your father's a savage!
Well, you were pretty great!
Is it really your camper?
Can we see them from the back yard?
You can get the general idea.
There they are.
They always look the same every year.
Look!
Did you -
- love him?
I would never marry anybody
I didn't love.
He must like Shelly.
I never saw him hit
anyone in his life.
He likes her.
Does he love her?
Probably.
Do you like her?
Yes I do -
- and I think she's very
good for your father.
Why?
After your mother died,
he was sad all the time.
But before that,
he was pretty funny.
Really?
Now when I see him with Shelly -
- sometimes he seems
like the old Harry.
My dad was funny?
He wasn't one of the Marx
Brothers but made me laugh.
My uncle fought in the Korean War.
He had a steel plate put in his head.
Daddy said he didn't come back the same.
One night, we picked up a radio
station from Oklahoma in his teeth.
It was really neat.
- Can't you see it?
- What?
Can't you see it?
It's there.
Vada there is no chicken
bone stuck in your throat.
Dr. Welty, are you
sure those are yours?
So you fill it with water, like
this. And you've got a water gun!
Cool! Can I get one for Vada?
Oh yes, yes.
Thomas, let me ask you a question.
Does Vada ever tell you why
she comes here so much?
She's dying.
Do you think she is?
No.
And why do you think she says that?
Because she gets scared of all
those dead people in her house.
You know that saying, " If you can't
beat them, join them''?
If she's one of them,
she won't be as scared.
You know what I think?
I think Vada's very lucky
to have a friend like you.
She's my best friend.
Miss Vada, how are you feeling?
As good as can be expected.
- Hey Vada, guess what we've got?
- What?
This!
Hey, you! I'm gonna get you!
I'll get you!
Give me that, you creep!
I just got you!
No, you didn't!
What?
- There's a bee hive.
- So?
Stand back.
Are you crazy?
You'll get stung!
You're right. Let's knock it down.
What do you want if for, anyway?
Cause they're neat.
Got it!
My mood ring fell off!
I gotta find it!
They're alive!
Run for your life!
Run faster! They're after us!
I am running faster.
- Hurry!
- Jump in the water!
I have my clothes on!
Do it!
Vada, is that you?
Yes.
Guess what? We're going
to the carnival tonight.
Be ready to go in 10 minutes.
Shelly's coming with us.
Vada, what's your favorite ride?
I like the freak show.
I know, I know.
I know. Let's go on the
"sit on the bench and rest ride."
I don't think that roller coaster
agreed with your dad's stomach.
You know Vada, you have to
watch what you eat here.
Once I went to a carnival
with my cousins, David and Frank.
They ate hot dogs -
- and the next day
came down with nephritis.
Nephritis is a kidney disease.
- You don't get it from hot dogs.
- I'm not a doctor!
All I know is, the next day
they had high fevers -
- and their faces got very fat.
It baffled medical science.
They were in a magazine.
They were! "Popular Mechanics"!
No, "Popular Science".
I don't know, it was "Popular".
They're trying to hit that poor thing!
Watch you don't knock out a fish.
Just arc it.
I don't know which ball's mine.
I won! I won!
Great!
We have a winner!
There you go, little girl.
See how easy it is, folks?
Oh Vada, that's a gorgeous goldfish.
Where'd you get that ring?
Did you win it?
Vada, we have something to tell you.
Vada, we have some good news.
Shelly and I are getting married.
Oh, my fish!
We're having the wedding sometime
near the end of the summer.
You'll be OK, little fish.
Vada, would you like us
to get another goldfish?
No, he's fine.
Fish are very resilient animals.
Don't worry, I won't
get another fish.
The bumper car! The bumper car!
For just 50 cents... a half dollar...
five dimes... ten nickels...
We have a ride guaranteed to rearrange
all of your internal organs.
Don't pass me by!
That's the bumper car ride!
Bumper cars! You can't go to a carnival
and not ride the bumper cars!
I fall asleep at the wheel!
I'll ride the bumper cars with you.
Great, Vada! Come on.
Two. I got the blue one!
I'm gonna come get you.
Vada, keep your
hands on the wheel!
Careful, Vada, careful!
Shelly, look out!
- Hi, Vada!
- Hi, is Thomas J. home?
Sure, come on in.
Hi, Vada.
- Hi, wanna ride bikes?
- Sure.
- Did you make your bed?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
- It's made.
Come here.
You've got a milk moustache.
Come on, let's go.
Bye, Mrs. Sennett.
- Bye, mum.
- Have fun, kids.
I'm running away!
Where are you running to?
To California. I'm going to Hollywood
to live with the Brady bunch.
I wanna live with them too!
You can't, they have enough kids.
You'll have to live with
the Partridge Family.
Really?
That's it.
- Get up!
- I'm tired of running away.
Besides, we passed this place
two times already.
We're not getting nowhere.
So why are you running away?
My dad gave Shelly a ring.
Wow, was it a decoder ring?
You're such a retard!
It was an engagement ring.
They're getting married?
So now you have a mother.
I don't like her.
I do. She's real funny.
She likes you better than me.
I'm hungry. I can't last any longer.
Then go home, baby!
I have to anyway, my
mum will be worried.
Leave then! Some friend you are!
You can come to my house for dinner.
No, I'm hiding out.
OK, see you.
Perhaps you didn't hear
what I said, Mr. Deeds.
The whole Circle
fortune goes to you.
I heard you, all right.
20 million, that's
quite a lot, isn't it?
It'll do in a pinch.
I wonder why he left me
all that money. I don't need it.
In social studies we learned some
people stole the Lindbergh baby -
- right out of his house.
I think I'll sleep
with my window open tonight.
Oh, my God!
Daddy!
Vada, what's the matter?
Where's daddy?
- He just left, what's wrong?
- I'm hemorrhaging.
What do you mean, you're hemorrhaging?
I don't want or need your help!
Vada, did this happen in the bathroom?
- How old are you?
- I'm eleven and a half.
It's okay. Come upstairs.
We have to have a little talk.
My mummy and daddy did that?
Actually, it's a very beautiful thing.
And look, there wouldn't have been a Vada!
I think it should be outlawed.
Believe me, some day you'll feel differently.
That's probably Thomas J.
I don't wanna see him.
It's not fair.
Nothing happens to boys!
Hi, Vada.
Can you come out?
I don't know...
Please, it's real hot.
Maybe we can go swimming?
No! Get out of here!
And don't come back for 5 to 7 days!
Gramoo, I'm going to the bathroom.
I'll be right back.
Stay here.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
It's quarter to three
There's no one in the place,
but just you and me.
So set them up, Joe
I've got a little story
you ought to know
We're coming, my friend
To the end of a brief episode.
I'm so sorry.
It's OK, ma.
So make it one for my baby.
And one more for the road.
Very very sorry.
What were you thinking?
It's your responsibility
to watch her!
Do you have any idea how
upset those people are in there?
Why do you think people
want to get married?
When you get older,
you just have to.
I'm going to marry Mr. Bixler.
You can't marry a teacher.
It's against the law.
- Is not!
- Yes, it is.
'Cause then he'll give you all A's,
and it won't be fair.
Not true.
Have you ever kissed anyone?
Like they do on TV?
Maybe we should, just to see
what's the big deal.
But, I don't know how!
Here, practice on your arm like this.
Like this?
OK, enough practice.
Close your eyes.
But then I won't be
able to see anything!
Just do it!
On the count of three.
One...
two... two and a half...
three!
Say something, it's too quiet!
Just hurry!
"I pledge allegiance
to the flag -"
- "of the United
States of America -"
- "and to the republic
for which it stands -"
- "one nation under God, indivisible
with liberty and justice for all."
You better not tell anyone!
You better not either.
Let's spit on it.
See you tomorrow.
Vada?
What?
Would you think of me?
If you don't marry Mr. Bixler.
I guess.
Yes!
God, no!
Get away!
What are you doing?
Feeding my fish.
- Is that the fish you won at the carnival?
- Yes.
He's getting big.
Vada, come here and
sit down for a minute.
Vada, something happened to
Thomas J. last night.
He stepped on a beehive.
I told him not to
tease those bees.
Did he get stung?
Maybe I should go over
and yell at him?
No, sweetheart,
you can't
Why not?
He was allergic to bees.
He's OK, isn't he?
There were just too many of them.
Dr. Welty!
Vada, what's wrong, sweety?
I can't breathe,
I'm suffocating!
Relax, let me look.
Come up here,
let me have a look.
It hurts, it hurts so bad!
What hurts Vada?
The bee stings!
I can't breathe!
I'll leave some food for you
at the door in case you get hungry.
Hi. Is Vada home?
Yes, but she's very upset
and she's not seeing anyone.
I'm Judy, I go to
school with her
I wanted to tell her
I'm sorry about Thomas J.
Maybe she'll feel better in
a couple of days.
Will you tell her
I came by?
Sure.
- Hi, Harry.
- Hi, reverend Moss.
The Sennetts want to thank you for
taking care of things so quickly.
Vada, I see you took
your tray in.
Maybe you should come
down to the funeral?
Sometimes it helps.
She won't come out.
It's been a whole day.
You'll have to
do something, Harry.
The funeral's starting.
Open your eyes,
she's 11 years old!
Her only friend in the
world is dead!
I know that but what do
you want from me?
Stop hiding, Harry!
You run Harry.
When I first came here -
- the idea of working with dead
people didn't exactly thrill me.
When I saw a family lived here -
- I thought -
- "If I'm living
without a family" -
- "at least I can work
with one." -
"And maybe once in while get
invited in for supper."
Yeah, but when those suppers
are disrupted -
- because there's a car crash or there's a
fire or a little boy steps on a beehive?
- I'm not asking you to stop
feeling for those people.
But life isn't just death, Harry.
Don't ignore the living -
- especially your daughter.
Excuse me Harry, Shelly, the
minister's about to begin.
Thank you, Arthur.
We are here to honour
Thomas J. Sennett.
He was born May 7, 1961,
in Madison, Pennsylvania.
He's survived by his loving parents
Charles and Susan Sennett, -
- his grandparents,
William and Gloria Sennett-
- and Gerald and Marjory Finn and
many relatives, friends and schoolmates.
The internment will follow
at Madison Memorial Park.
The family has asked me
to say a few words before we proceed.
No words I could say
would begin to express -
- the loss and grief.
One word that keeps
ringing in my ear -
- is "why?"
Why would God choose to take
this little boy from us?
Why? I cant give you an
answer to that question.
I can tell you -
God has chosen Thomas J.
for some very -
- special reason.
We must find solace in knowing
that Thomas J is in God's care.
In that place, there is
no sorrow or suffering.
The lion lies with the lamb.
The day is not divided.
I'd like to read a passage
from the Bible.
This is Matthew 19.
"At one point, children were
brought to Him -
- that He might lay his
hands on them in prayer.
Disciples began to chastise Him.
But Jesus said,
"Let the children come to me.
Do not hinder them.
The kingdom of God -
- belongs to such as these."
He laid his hands on their heads -
- before he left that place."
Let us pray in silence.
Wanna go tree climbing, Thomas J?
His face hurts!
And where are his glasses?
He can't see without his glasses!
Put his glasses on!
Put on his glasses!
He was going to be an acrobat.
He's gone, sweetheart.
Vada, wait!
Vada!
Vada, I was just on
my way to your house.
You all right?
I'm so sorry about Thomas J.
OK, we don't have to
talk about him!
It's okay.
We won't talk about him.
Justin and Ronda say that I should
tell people what I feel.
Come here.
Sit down over here.
Mr. Bixler...
I love you.
I love you like my dad loves Shelly.
And I wanna live here.
I think your dad would miss you.
No, he wouldn't.
I can't go home.
Hank, I'll be ready in a second.
I can't find my other earring.
Suzanne, this is Vada.
Vada, hi!
I'm really sorry!
Could you give us a minute?
Who's that?
That's Suzanne.
She and I are gonna be
married this fall.
I was gonna bring her to class
next week.
I want her to hear your poem.
Please, honey.
I cared for him too.
Get away from me!
Vada!
Vada, sweetheart, don't...
Why do you think people
want to get married?
When you get old,
you just have to.
Who's that with your dad?
That's my mother.
I'm gonna be an acrobat
when I grow up.
Vada?
Would you think of me?
If you don't get to marry
Mr. Bixler.
Now we're blood
brothers for life.
Shelly, I'm sorry but we
haven't found her yet.
She can't be alone in the dark!
- We'll keep looking.
- We've been looking since this morning.
- Her teacher called...
- I know. You told us.
Vada?
Are you OK?
Oh, God!.
I should have told Thomas J.
he was my best friend.
I'm sure he knew.
Shelly, I stole some money
from your cookie jar -
- to pay for the writing class.
- It's okay.
I'll pay you back. Besides, I don't
think I'll ever go to class again.
Tell you what. You dedicate
your first book to me, -
- I'll forget the whole thing.
I will. I promise.
OK, get into bed.
- Good night.
She's here.
Did I kill my mother?
What?
The bees killed Thomas J.,
and I killed my mother.
Sweety, that wasn't your fault.
Things like that aren't
anybody's fault.
It just happened.
I found this.
I forgot about that picture.
Where'd you find it?
In the garage.
That little Chevy was your
mother's favorite car.
What was my mama like?
She was pretty and kind.
She had your eyes.
Boy, did she love to laugh!
Sometimes when you laugh,
you sound just like her.
Really?
Know what she did when she found
out she was going to have you?
She came home and painted
this whole room pink.
She was so sure she was
going to have a little girl.
Do you miss her?
Yes, I did.
Very much, for a long time.
Even now, I get a little sad
when I think about a pretty flower -
- or a beautiful sunset
she would have liked.
I think every time I see a climbing
tree, I'll think of Thomas J.
That's good.
Memories are good, sweetheart.
Vada, I'm sorry.
I was trying to keep it from you.
I just couldn't.
You're a good girl.
I want you to be happy.
Don't be an old grump like me.
See you in the morning.
Daddy?
It's not so bad to be like you.
Mrs. Sennett, how are you doing?
Some days I think I'll be okay -
- others I have to force myself -
- even to get out of bed.
I know it's crazy, but sometimes
I think he's just away at summer camp.
How's Veda?
She's doing much better.
She's just inside.
Vada?
Mrs. Sennett.
Vada!
I've been wanting to
come over to you.
Thomas J. had this on him.
I thought you might
like to have it.
You were such a good friend to him.
I hope you'll still come by
and visit me.
I will.
I promise.
Mrs. Sennett?
Thomas J. will be all right.
My mother will take care of him.
Thank you, Vada.
"Encased in talent,
like a uniform -
- the rank of every poet
is well known.
They can amaze us
like a thunderstorm -
- or die so young
or live for years alone."
My advice to you
on our last class:
Be a thunderstorm!
What exactly do you mean by that?
I mean -
- be dangerous -
- and unpredictable.
And make a lot of noise.
Vada?
We missed you, man!
Give me a hug.
I was hoping you'd
stop by today.
Can't stay.
I just came to read my poem.
We'd love to hear it.
"Weeping willow with your tears
running down -
why do you always weep and frown?
Is it because he left you one day?
Is it because he could not stay?
On your branches he would swing.
Do you long for the happiness
that day would bring?
He found shelter in your shade.
You thought his laughter
would never fade.
Weeping willow, stop your tears.
There is something
to calm your fears.
You think death has ripped you
forever apart.
But I know he'll always
be in your heart."
- Hi, Judy.
- Vada.
Things are a little better these days.
I finally swallowed that chicken bone.
Judy and I are going to be
in the same homeroom.
And the Republican Party
just renominated Mr. Nixon.
The Temptations: My Girl