are you all right
- did you crush or something? -
- no, i was just resting -
- what's your name-
- Mona-
- You don't look like a "Mona"-
it's not my real name -
- It's cause of "me" brother -
- We're always playing when we're kids
and he started call me like a "mona" -
- as my real name is Lisa -
- Mona-Lisa
you get it? -
- Yeah, I've studied the original -
-I'm Tamsin -
- I like your bike -
- Ya?It's a Honda -
-It doesn't appear to have an engine
- it's rolling... -
- What's the point of a bike without
an engine?-
- Well. I'm getting one
next week
-Ok -
- This is where I live -
I've never seen you here
before -
- Yeah, this is cause I'm here only my
school hollidays -
-You've got in
a boarding school? -
-yeah, but i've just been
suspended
- Aparently, I'm under a bad influence
of people -
- Won't you come in? -
- Nah, I've got to go
Ok, but drop by if you could
-You've got invited
I'm here all summer..you know
- What are you doing? -
- A fair thing, don't I..-
- You are a bastard -
- This is what you are -
- And I want this place
back the way it was  -
- It can't be-
- I looked to the Pub and I thought
god..what I've been doing?  -
Thank you Lord
I now see what i can do
- Our room is not a Pub
our room is a spiritual center where
people can come and learn
about Jesus Christ -
because we will give
this valley back to Jesus Crist
-Because people live spiritual fullfilment -
They need to know that the
Lord is there for them
-they need an echo of it
- They need to know
their Lord -
- will you help me do this -
-How great is The Lord -
- We gonna bring love to this
valley
- We gonna bring the name of
Jesus Crist to the
lost people of this valley
-We would let them know
that He is there for them
Thank you -
- don't question the name of
lord
- come to me darling
come to me -
- more passion, more passion...
just give him strenght Lord-
-let' go out somewhere now -
-somewhere nice like a club
or something
- Look, I've have had enough of this -
- It's over between me and you now -
What? -
- Look,we've got good fun,
now it's finished
- Get in the car
i take you down now -
- You've could have told me that before
Oh yeah..like i'm gonna
in the car -
-No, fucking real, I'm not
suit yourself
- You are a pig -
- Hello-
- Is Tamsin in?-
- Yeah, she's in her room, as usual
Have fun
It was "This one" by Saint-Saens
- I live above "This one" -
- The Pub-
- You live in a Pub-
- yeah...boy, it's not like a Pub anymore
it's like my temple -
-You see Me brother
He found God -
- Our god found him
He's been born again -
- And Pub now is more like not so much like a
place to drink, it's a place to pray
- anyway
he love to be born again... -
-So it's just you and your brother
in the Pub -
-Yes, just me, me brother and God -
- Is he completely mad? -
- yeah -
- what happened to him
- he went inside and
he came out phoney-
he went to prison?-
-yeah
-what for? -
robbery, burgery
-
fighting people-
-What about your parents -
- i don't know me dad -
and me mom is dead -
-what she died of? -
- cancer-
- my sister died of anorexia -
-oh no-
- that's her there -
- that's Sadie -
- She's been beautiful -
-yeah, she was-
- do you think i look like her
yeah-
-have you read Nietzsche?
who?-
Nietzsche.
- This was great philosopher
and he just believed that -
- you know people, there are some people
that are put on this planet
you are made to succeed-
- or just made to blossom and
it doesn't matter how many things
they suffer-
- it doesn't matter
as long as they succeed
you know like Shakespeare and Wagner-
- And your borther with
all that crap, i mean Nietzsche would strangle him
up..
- with all that stuff about God -
- God's dead -
-God's dead
this is what is real,it's  here -
- here and now -
- Yeah, you should read him
I think you'd like him -
- Or Freud, you know -
- So, what are you gonna do
with your life? -
-I'm gonna be a lawyer -
- I'm gonna get a job ...-
-work really hard -
- get by famous like a bastard -
-and chillin out all this kids right -
- with mental problems -
- and then i'm gonna wait
for menopause -
- or cancer -
- God is dead -
-Good night brother -
- Ok,  -
- i  just go talk to her -
- what was all about Mona? -
- I don't know
it's just you and your friends
down there -
- you crack me all -
- sorry -
-i just imagine
with you being a room leader -
- i mean, you-
- why you're always trying to
hit in me? -
- because i think that you are
a fucking fake, that's why -
- what's wrong with you?-
- I just miss me brother
I'm here  -
that ain't you
did it?-
Mona, this is me-
- this is the real me -
- I want the old Phil -
-well, that old Phil didn't make me
very happy -
- he made me happy -
- i loved my brother -
- he used to be real-
- I've gotn't any family -
- me home-
- no one fancies me -
- come here -
- Oh Jesus watch over
this child -
- watch her always -
- back up -
- I'm lookin for Mona, is she there? -
- Yeah, she's here, she's
in there -
- Thank you -
- Could you wait me here?-
-On the left, inside -
- What's he making?
-A cross -
- He's putting it up to the top of the hill
to clean the valley off evil-
- Now.. these are nice -
- thanks -
- they're me mum's
when she used to be "this one" -
- are you done?yeah
- I've got a cab waiting outside
what for?-
- cause we're going
where? -
- you'll see -
-ok -
- what do you think of
this place
it's funny-
- and that one, that is special
-you see that house there?
yeah
- and the posh Jaguar parked
outside? -
- It's my dad's car -
and he comes here
quite a lot, i think -
- cause this is where his girlfriend
lives -
- and..his secretary..nice -
- and he is in there now
he must be in there now
with his car there -
- and you know
he is fucking her now
-
- and  he bend her over
and he is fucking her up in  her ass -
- oh man..you should to see her -
- she's just a dog  she's a fucking whore
-and she's also blond hair and
big tits and this high heels  -
- and she's got no fucking brains
she's got nothing -
- This is Edith Piaf -
-I just adore her -
- She was this marvelous parisien
woman -
- ...and she had such a wonderful
tragic life -
- and she was married three times-
- and each husband died
in misterious circumstances -
-and the last one was
a boxing champion -
- ..and she killed him
with a fork
- and she not even gone
to prison -
- because in France,
crimes of passion are
forgiven -
-so my mother is off somewhere
with some dodgy company  -
- pretending to be
an actress -
- while my father's busy
with his secretary -
- so, i'm practically an orphan -
- this is the main guest
bedroom -
- but it is dirty of dust
because we're not even
have many guests -
- excuse me -
- this my noon mother's
rehearsal room-
- this is my favorite bathroom -
- this is Sadie's room -
ohh
it's such a turn into
a bedroom of sanctuary
- because when she died
my mother wanted to keep everything-
- exactly as it was -
- you don't go in?-
- oh, and the whole house
is really creepy so you're
going to stay with me -
- common -
- if you're hear any strange noises
in the night, don't panic -
- it's just the furniture cricking
cause it's an old house -
- night
-night -
- wake up wake up -
-morning -
- morning -
- I didn't know what you wanted
so i just got you everything-
- what are your plans for today -
- manicure, pedicure
full body wax -
- get in the car... -
- what about you?
i'm gonna buy you an engine -
- this is me favorite rock -
- it's like a strange cathedral -
- I don't feel like in
me old town -
- What you mean -
- It don't feel the same
i like it.with you -
- which one do you
want -
- that one -
- which one?
this -
- try this one-
- you could have that
i don't want it -
- honest? -
- God, you're looking beautiful -
- It was Sadie's dress -
- I felt so useless -
- You know it was my only sister
my beautiful sister
and she started to turn into this monster -
- and all the bones
in that body...they started to
.....
-... like a death spell...
...like a warewolf -
- and she stopped smiling
she couldn't smiling anymore -
- because she was throwing up
all the time, and she vomit acid
and her teeth were going yellow -
- and she stoped smiling
she stoped living-
- i miss her so much
i miss her so much
-let it out -
- don't cry
don't cry "mia amica"
shhhh -
- who is it? -
- I think it's your brother
fuck -
- how does he know you are here? -
-I've told him -
- do you fucking a lot? -
- it give me kicks -
- who'd that be?.. -
- there's a guy -
- i've gone around with -
- what's he like?-
- ummm-
- he's like a man
you know... -
- not like a boy -
- not like a boy of school
he would... like a man-
-that's strong and overcome
and he used to go driving -
- He used to take me in places
....-
-wanna  know?
yeah..how did he shake you? -
- what you mean? -
- how would he do it? -
- horribly? -
- no -
-just normal
i mean..
i don't know
- show me -
- do you wanna see? -
-do you?-
- do you wanna be shaken
by Ricky?-
- do you?yes-
- are you ready?
yes -
- serious?
- no joking
no joking -
- ok
go -
- i'm on it -
- let me show you-
- oh Mona -
- no turn around -
- oh you so good mona -
- that's it -
that's it?
- is that it? -
- are you in love with him still?
no-
- were you ever? -
- I thought i were -
- then why did
you dump him? -
- he dumped me -
- why? -
- he said he couldn't be
bothered anymore-
anyway, he had wife and kids -
men like that should be
castrated
- you are clever-
- you should teach that Rick a lesson -
- That's Rick -
- You didn't mention
he is fat -
- he is not
he is all muscle
oh right... -
- all right
come on -
- hello
hi -
god, this is really hard
but this is my friend, Mona
and she just had to have an abortion
and what's that has to do
with me?
it was your husband's fetus
Basically, what he did
was completely to waste it...
and he took advantage of her
and now she is clinically depress
as you can see it
i mean she's just catatonic
she haven't said a word since
have you Mona?
I mean it could be....at the time
you not satisfied him enough at home
i mean...
we all know we have a certain age
we all get sad but you know...
..maybe you should keep your husband looked up
maybe you should castrate
your husband..
why won't you two just go out
and leave me and my family alone...?
It's just..you fully understand?
-get out of my face?
don't touch me!
leave my family alone!
hi there
Mona
would you be there tomorrow
won't you?
i have no absolutely any intention
to be part at your crucification
would you be there please,
for me...
can i come?
yeah
i need you there, Mona
We're going!
they go there...
Is he got a girlfriend?
As he thought of it...
he's got god
he's too busy with god
With god is like that
one long life orgasm
from you're born until you're dying
sin never goes down on him
if anything goes wrong we're slowly
bring it down again, ok?
ok,one,two,three,four..go.
fucking..how..
Ok again we deserve aplauze
if i can be saved
anybody can be saved,
anybody can be saved
the Lord Jesus started speaking to
me
he told me to build this cross
to claim this valley back,
in his name, for Him
because there's evil work in this valey
there's evil in this valley
and it manifests itself in
hundreds of ways
one person who's closer to god
today
for our actions
then that's a victory
it's a victory for everybody here
we don't pray for richies,
we pray for fullfilments in our souls
and in our hearts first before, most of all
but i have prayed for my sister,
who's there now
this is the power of prayer
cause i've prayed to Lord for
my sister
I've prayed that she'd be set free
because i know she's in turmoil
and so often
i can't reach out and tell her
but I've prayed for her Lord
I pray cause i love her
And I know that the Lord
is answering to my prayers
he answers all our prayers
...yes lord...
do you really think that
there is darkness in this valey?
oh absolutely ye
there's darkness everywhere
what about the devil?
yeah i know i was filled with Devil
at one point
what were you like?
i wasn't really a nice guy
i didn't think enough and
pour a glass in your face
pounching you in the
nose
and is it that Devil did that?
yeah, the Devil drove me
yeah
the Devil want you to do bad things
and he's got a grip of you
must be interesting to believe in something
yeah, but remember
there is Devil and there is God
and he is powerfull anywhere
I am the Devil and I have
come to kill you
I am possesed and I'll throw you..
I raise my hands on you..
you devil...as I am a child of
Jesus
..........leave your body...!!!
spirits say is anyone else
there?
do you push that?
you pushed it
I bloody did not
who is there?
s
a
d
sad
who the fuck is sad
i
e
sadie..i'm not moving it
i swear i'm not
sadie is that you?
yes
I don't think we should
carry on
are you in peace?
no
why are you not in peace?
d
a
dad
do you blame dad sadie?
do you blame dad?
yes
it's bollocks
no, it's not...
he didn't love her enough
that is why she died
it's still hair in it...
it's like she's still here
mushrooms?
we comunicate with sadie
open
Ricky
stop..-
thank you
good man
i love you all
bye
we must never be parted
do you hear me
yea
are you listening to me?
yeah
we're gonna spent the rest of
our lives together
i know
if you leave i'll kill you
and then i kill myself
i love you
tam
i've got the most blackcorns
for breakfast
ok, it doesn't matter how many you brought
Mona,
it's not enough for breakfast
i know
i'm fucking freezing, i've been
into shivers i wanna go home
i'm sick of this place
yeah
-yeah
let's go back
Luxor
It's in Egypt
why would you wanna go there?
O
m
sk
Omsk
It's in Siberia
It's your brother
Just ignore him
he'll go away
It's an attractive man
your brother
I'll seek some spiritual guidance from him
Yeah, go on... it would be funney...
Hello
Oh hi
-hi
is Mona here with you?
No, but she'll be back
in a moment
Oh right
why don't you wait here?
-would that be ok?
-yeah
-thanks
you can wait in the
sitting room
thanks
Actually, there is something
i wanna talk to you about
I have a real problem believing in anything
or anyone....
-and i can't stop thinking about
that day on the hill
when you made that speech
and...
and the way you spoke
and everything you said...
i just believed you
it was just god speaking thru me
The Lord is the truth
...and...
everything you were saying about the Devil
-...uhmm
and all the demons
you really believed that
oh yeah
i've already met the demons
and what did you do?
I've asked Jesus Christ to
come into my life
I've asked me to free me from
guilt,sin,fear
and He came and
He washed 'em away
I can do the same for you
But He never speaks to me
But you have to pray to Him
ask Him
- To come into your heart
and He will
he is a gentle God
He is a God of love
and he knows you
he knows every hair on your head
I can't feel Him
I can't feel anything
I just feel empty
-Lord can feel you
He's in this room now
He needs to be close to you
and He want you to ask Him
to come into your heart
he wants to reach out
and touch you
He want you to feel Him
He wants to come inside you
and overwhelm you with joy
I want him to
do not resist him
It's too easy
you're fucking fraude
Tam, Tam
Help me
Mona..
whoa..
come here..
I'm sorry I've got violent..ok?
is that it?
-no
there is something with that girl going on
inside her
this things that driving her
you saw what happened to me
didn't you?
we need you to promise me
you'd stay away from her
i love her
she loves me
we're going away together, forever
and we are never coming back
hey
Phil
what are you doing?
Phil, don't lock myself in
Phil,... please
Open!
Phil open the door..
...please
Philll...
-Don't leave me Lord
Father we just pray and you just
help us in our prayers
please you just don't leave us
helpless Father
we just pray, Father
you just reach into her life
.......
Father will you put words into his heart
into his mouth Father
that he will be able to deliver Jesus
to his sister, Father
that she will be saved, you're understanding Father...
You just shut up!
just shut up!
stupid girl
don't do this to me
I love you
I am the Antichrist and I am...
everything's ok man?
fucking not!
chill...
chill out
just fucking go
go
don't fucking touch me
get out
go!
you bunch of fakes
go,.. fuck off!
get out!
Fucking move!
move it!!!
get out
and take the fucking books with you
You..fuckers!!!
bye
Tammy??
What's going on Tam?
I'm going back to school..
Excuse me...
Can i have my top back, please?
You're Sadie..!!!
-yeah...
cand i have my top, please?
I've got to go back to school, Mona..
You've always known that...
Look..I couldn't be myself
back there..in front of my mother...
Anyway...I were just playing a part
Wasn't even me...
Common..you know me
you know me..
Don't be upset about Sadie..
Sadie was just..
Sadie was just a bit of poetic licence,
I mean I am a fantasist
You can't tell me we weren't have any fun..?!
I've never met anyone like you
Please don't be angry with me...
What the fuck are you doing?!!
You're a fucking crazy bitch!
Translated and syncronized by "dele" aka ditto___
<<sorry for all kind of mistakes:spell, type...etc. all because
hurry and... english pronunciation...>>>