We skipped the light fandango
Turnedcartwheels ´cross the floor
l wasfeeling kindofseasick
But the crowdcalledout formore
The room washummingharder
As the ceiling flewaway
How´s it going?
Had your lunch yet?
I heard these two kids
in a restaurant yesterday.
One said,
"What´s chocolate pudding?´´
The other said, "It´s good.
It´s a lot like chocolate mousse.´´
Why do I get this feeling
I´m not seeing any work today?
There´s nothin´ to see.
It´s "The Emperor´s New Clothes.´´
I´m gonna get slaughtered, man.
- Yeah, well, let me see what you got.
I´m sure it´s a lot--
-Just trust me on this. It´s shit.
I´m in here, all I want to do
is lay down. I´m takin´ a dive.
Well, ifyou can´t work, at least
you can eat. Come out with me.
I can´t. I have to pick up
my assistant at the airport.
I don´t know why she can´t
take a cab like everybody else.
- But, you know--
- Whatever.
So, uh, when would think would be
a good time for me to come back?
The show´s in three weeks,
you know.
Oh, Lionel, Lionel, you go
through this before every show.
I´m talking 20 years ofthis!
Now get to know yourself
a little better!
You can pull it off, Lionel.
You always do!
Andso it was
That later
As the millertoldhis tale
That herface at firstjustghostly
Turneda whitershade ofpale
Shit!
- Hi.
- What are you doing here?
I thought I´d pickyou up so you
don´t have to hassle with cabs.
- Didn´t you get my message?
- What?
I left it on the machine.
I said I´m not coming back.
What do you mean, you´re not
comin´ back? You´re right here.
I´d call that comin´ back.
- You should listen to
your machine now and then.
- "Listen to your machine´´?
Doesn´t that have a horrifying
ring to it, that expression,
to listen to your machine?
Look, I-- I didn´t go to Florida
with a girlfriend like I told you.
Oh, yeah?
I went with somebody else.
A guy?
- So? So what? Who´s the guy?
Did he come offthe plane with you?
- Why? You want to give him a lift home?
Well, I´d be lyin´ if I said
I wasn´t curious to see what
kind of man rings your bell.
- Look, he´s not here.
- What do you mean, he´s not here?
What´d he do? Take a goddam Greyhound?
We had a fiight. He left me. I spent most
ofthe time down there by myself, okay?
- He left me, okay?
- He left you?
He left you?
Who is he?
I mean, who in their right mind
would leave you? Who is this guy?
I know him, right?
Gregory Stark.
That kid?
The comedian?
- A performance artist.
- Performance artist.
What the hell is a performance artist?
A person´s an actor, a singer, a dancer.
I mean, do you call the guy that picks
up your garbage a sanitary engineer?
A performance artist.
And he left you?
- Now, you see through that, right?
- I don´t care. It´s over.
That´s all.
Look, I´m moving out.
That´s what
"I´m not coming back´´ means.
Where you gonna go?
What can you afford?
You gonna move into a dormitory?
You don´t want to sleep with me
any more? Hey, I´m a big boy.
You don´t have to go out on the street.
You had a fling. Big deal.
Welcome to the world. I mean, we´re
still employer and employee, right?
I´m leaving New York.
I wanna go home.
Ah, yeah, well...
that´s a whole
´nother ball o´ wax.
You want to split? Fine.
Come back, pack up and go.
Ifyou drag it out, I´ll die.
You know that.
Come on.
Let´s get it over with.
Shesaidthere isno reason
Andthe truth isplain to see
But l wanderedthrough
myplaying cards
And wouldnot let herbe
One of16 vestal virgins
Who were leaving forthe coast
Andalthough my eyes were open
Theymightjust as well
have been closed
Andso it was
That later
- You know, I can´t believe
I´ve never noticed that in here.
-Jesus!
Has this always been in here?
Incredibly handsome kid.
Beautiful boy.
I can understand the attraction.
Did you ever see him perform?
- Yeah.
How in the hell can you let somebody
like that drive you out of New York?
-I thought you had more spine than that.
-He´sjust some guy.
He´s not driving me out.
It´s not him.
- It´s me?
- It´s nobody. It´s things.
- Things? What things?
- Don´t you reason with me!
What about your painting?
Huh?
You gonna make a little studio
in your parents´ garage...
with rusty hedge clippers
hanging on a nail...
and pool stuff
laying in the corner...
and a broken sled and mice?
You work for Lionel Dobie.
You work for the lion, baby.
You stretch canvases.
You run a few errands.
You got your own room, studio,
life lessons that are priceless...
plus a salary.
And ifyou act now, you´ll also receive
a handsome sterling service for 24.
Look, I´m not kidding.
This kills me, you leaving.
It´s a suicide.
This is a time and a place.
At your age, you´re right in
the heart ofthe heart, Paulette.
I swear, you walk now, you´ll curse
yourselfthe rest ofyour days.
I don´t have to sleep
with you any more?
Baby, I´m your ally
against horse dung and fraud.
That´s as far as it goes
from now on.
We skippedthe light fandango
Turnedcartwheels ´cross the floor
l wasfeeling kindofseasick
- But the crowdcalledout formore
- God!
- The room washummingharder
- Ow! Lionel, for God´s sakes!
Sorry.
As the ceiling flewaway
When we calledout
foranotherdrink
The waiterbrought a tray
Andso it was
That later
Is the music too loud?
- Uh-uh.
-As the millertoldhis tale
- You should get some sleep.
- That herface at firstjustghostly
- I´m working on it.
Turneda whitershade ofpale
You´re gonna sleep like that,
you should shut this.
Otherwise, come 4:00 or 5:00
in the morning, you´ll be freezing.
Sorry.
Can I, uh, get you anything?
- Soup?
- "Soup´´?
Who are you talking to?
I don´t care.
He´s driving me crazy.
Heythere, now, baby
Get into mybigblack car
Heynow, baby
l wannajustshowyou
What mypoliticsare
- Don´t you knock?
- I did. I thought you said, "Come in.´´
I´m sorry, I--
I think I left my sable brush in here.
- Did you see it?
- What are you doing?
- I could´ve sworn that I left it--
- I´m not sleeping with you.
You promised.
What?
Jesus, you know what? This is crazy.
I just had this impulse.
I wanted to kiss your foot.
- You´re nuts.
- No, no, no. I´m just working too hard.
I´m just getting weird.
I´m under a lot of pressure, you know.
Phillip´s is hanging over my head
every day. "The show´s in three weeks.
Show´s in three weeks.
Show´s in three weeks.´´
Like a goddam mockingbird
in my ear!
I just wanted
to kiss your foot.
I´m sorry.
It´s nothin´ personal.
You want me to get you anything?
That herface at firstjustghostly
Turneda whitershade ofpale
So...
do you love me?
Love you?
I said I did, yes.
What would you do if I left?
What would I do?
I´d go up on the roof
and howl like a gut-shot dog.
Well, I don´t love you.
So what?
- Needme
- Night andday
- Oh, needme
- Oh, baby
- Night andday
- Take myhand
- Don´t need
- Night andday
- No otherman
- lsaid, baby
- Night andday
- Baby
- Whoa, baby, now
- Night andday
- Oh, come on, baby
- You knowl wantyou by myside
- Night andday
- l wantyou to keep
- Oh, keep mesatisfied, now
- Night andday
- lsaythe night time, now
- Whoa, Lord, is the right time
- Night andday
- Yeah, lookat the oneyou love now
Well, it´sso nice
It´s amazing how much more
interesting it´s getting.
- What do you mean, "interesting´´?
- It´s not boring.
You know, you got a nice
little irony working foryou.
- Irony?
- Yeah. Nice irony.
- How´s the tension? Last time--
- It´s nice.
- Nice?
- Yeah, nice.
-You´re full ofshit, you know that?
-You know, you´re the only person in the
world who could say that to me and live.
Look, could you just tell me ifyou
think I´m any good? How ´bout that?
Just tell me if-if-if...
I have any talent or ifyou
think I´m wasting my time.
Because sometimes I feel
I should just quit.
Because--
Just tell me what you think.
Come on.
What the hell difference
does it matter what I think?
It´s yours.
I mean, you make art
because you have to.
´Cause you got no choice.
It´s not about talent.
It´s about no choice
but to do it.
Now, are you any good?
Well, you´re 22, so who knows?
Who cares?
You wanna to give it up?
You give it up, you weren´t
a real artist to begin with.
Christ´s sake.
"You give it up, you weren´t
a real artist to begin with.´´
What a stupid thing to say.
Stupid!
Hi, Ma.
Not so good.
I´m not.
I can´t.
I want to go back to school.
I don´t know.
Can I come home
for a little while?
No.
I just hate it here.
- Nowhowdoes it feel
- Hey, Lionel.
- Lionel!
- Howdoes it feel
Turn the music down!
- To be without a home
- Lionel.
With no direction home
Like a complete unknown
Just like a rollingstone
Princess on thesteeple
andalltheprettypeople
They´re alldrinkin ´
thinkin´that theygot it made
Exchangingall
preciousgiftsandthings
Butyou´dbettertake
yourdiamondring down
Andpawn it, babe
You usedto beso amused
At Napoleon in rags
andthe language that he used
Go to him now, he callsya
Ya can´t refuse
Whenyou ain ´tgot nothin ´
yougot nothin´to lose
You´re invisible
Yougot no secrets
To conceal
Howdoes it feel
To be without a home
With no direction home
Like a complete unknown
Just like a rollingstone
I appreciate you coming with me tonight.
I hate these things with a passion.
You know this guy Wagner,
the party giver...
he´s in real estate, right?
Uh, he come down to
my studio one time.
He puts his arm around
my shoulder and he says...
"Lionel, do you understand
the importance ofJackson Pollock?´´
Then he points out all the condos and
loft co-op conversions out the window...
and he says, "If it wasn´t forJackson,
none ofthis would be happening.´´
Jackson, right?
His old pal.
His pal.
You know, I haven´t had any
knock-around friends since 1 968.
I´ve associates,
admirers, detractors...
ex-wives, rivals--
- I have lots offriends.
- That´s a very mean thing to say to me.
You have a string
in your hair.
You see right
through me, don´t you?
I was in the army.
Army intelligence.
You see, they had me draw
Russian couples screwing.
See, they fiigured this way,
come the next war...
they´d drop thousands ofthese drawings
behind enemy lines with the message...
"Hey, Ivan, while you´re
out here fiightin´ democracy...
ol´ Boris is back home
doing your wife.´´
- How could you tell
the couples were Russians?
- Oh, I had ´em wearin´ fur hats.
I mean, what´s the difference?
The next war was Vietnam anyhow.
- Paulette what?
-Just Paulette.
So, what´s it like to live
with the big man?
-I don´t live with him. I work for him.
-She´s an artist
in her own right, right?
- Ah, Pete, this is Paulette.
- Paulette what?
-Just Paulette.
- Oh, yeah, you live with Lionel Dobie.
- She works for him. She´s an artist.
- Yeah, I think it goes back, like,
to the Incas and the Aztecs, right?
- Really? Do you have visiting...
- in your studio?
- Don´t you feel that?
- Uh, well, um--
I, I, uh, collect
mainly ´50s stuff--
uh, Rothko, Kline, you know.
- But I like to keep
an ear to the rail.
- Excuse me a second.
Oh, I-I don´t have anything
in the studio right now. I--
- Do you have a show up somewhere?
- Uh, no, I-- I´m sort of
in between galleries.
- Where did you show?
- Excuse me. Um, may I
speak to you a moment?
I´ll bring her right back,
gentlemen. I promise.
I got real good at it, all these
different sexual positions...
and the expressions ofecstasy,
and the--
This captain gave me
a hundred bucks for a set ofsix.
Said it was an anniversary
present for his wife.
It´s the fiirst stuff
I ever sold.
- I´m sorry. I didn´t mean to be rude.
Are you an artist?
- Yes.
Guys who were in my unit
who were in combat used to say...
"Any day above ground´s
a good day.´´
Do you think that´s true?
-Who´s that short kid with the earring?
-Oh, the ladykiller? That´s Reuben Toro.
He shows at Bendix.
He´s not bad. Nice kid too.
- Hey, excuse me. Can I talk to you?
- Mr Lionel Dobie.
- You know, you, sir, are like
my Willie Mays. It´s a pleasure...
- Thankyou. Can I talk to you?
- Excuse me.
- ...to meet you.
- What?
- Shut up. Now, look now.
I-I don´t know how to say this. I mean,
I´m not your shepherd or anything.
- But people are laughin´
at ya out there.
- Why?
Well, you know that greasy-haired kid
you´re dancing with?
Well, he´s here to score and split.
I mean, he does this
everywhere he´s invited.
He likes to fiind some innocent kid,
and then he preys upon them.
I mean-- I mean, hey, you´re
a free agent. It´s your life.
But I´m tellin´ ya, ifthat
low-rent hound does anything
to hurt you or humiliate you, I´ll--
I thought you were gonna tell me
that they were laughing at me
because of my work.
Well, this is kinda worse,
don´t you think?
No. No, no, no, no.
Let me go out fiirst.
You stay in here a minute.
Because if people see us go out
together, then their minds
make these leaps, you know.
- So stay here.
- Creep!
- Lionel, there you are.
Lionel, I want you to meet Kurt Bloom.
Hejust bought the Rommel Gallery
in Berlin.
Lionel Dobie.
Lionel Dobie, nice to see you.
- Open the door!
- It is a great pleasure for me.
- Open!
- Is there a problem there?
- Lionel!
- No, just a couple of kids.
- Oh.
- Uh, Rommel Gallery?
- Yes, Rommel Gallery in Berlin.
- West Berlin?
- West Berlin, yes.
- Yes. Nice.
- Lionel!
- Kurt Bloom?
- Kurt Bloom, yes.
- I hate you!
- I´m really admiring your work.
- It´s very great to see you here.
- Lionel!
Happybirthdaytoyou
Happybirthday, dearGeorge
Conquistador, there isno time
lmustpay my respect
Andthough lcame tojeeratyou
lleave now with regret
Andas thegloom begins to fall
lsee there isno, onlyall
Andthoughyou came
with swordheldhigh
You didnot conquer, only die
Andthough lhopedfor
something to find
lcan see no maze to unwind
Andthough lhopedfor
something to find
lcan see no maze to unwind
Oh, man, could I get a cup ofthat?
I´m dead and buried.
Are you a graffiiti artist, Toro?
No, I wouldn´t say that.
It´s for theJapan House tonight.
Listen, I´m sorry what
I said to you at the party.
I-- I just get crazy.
It´s beautiful.
Look, I can´t go with you tonight.
I made other plans.
- Oh, yeah?
- I´m going to the Blind Alley
with some girlfriends.
Oh, yeah?
Who´s, uh, at the Blind Alley?
I just want to show him that I don´t
give a damn any more, you know?
I can go see him, see his stuff--
his stuff, like anybody else.
Does that sound like
total horseshit, or what?
No, absolutely not. I think, uh--
I think we should.
I think we should show him
that life goes on, that he´s
not even worth avoiding.
I-- I thinkyou have to go
right up in his face tonight.
- I mean, right up in his face.
- I think I´d rather work.
No, don´t use work as an excuse.
Your work´s sacred.
- Yeah, well, maybe yours is.
- No, yours too. Yours too.
Now, look, you go with your girlfriends,
you go with them...
that´s like a bunch of high school girls
with a crush on some boy.
But ify-you walk in with me,
you make an entrance with
fiirepower, with dignity.
- What aboutJapan House?
- Now, fiirst comes our house.
I don´t know. I think-- I think
you should go right up in his face.
See, I don´t look for trouble.
I mean, but some people do, right?
You know, they--
they, like, walk around, you know?
They-They-They--They´re, like,
lookin´ for a-- for a fiight.
Like, okay, I had this one guy one time.
He´s walkin´ down the street,
and he steps on my foot.
All right, it was an accident.
He didn´t mean it, right?
But he doesn´t say anything.
You know, so I said,
"Excuse me.´´ Yeah?
He turns around, he says,
"Yeah, what?´´
So okay, never mind. Forget about it.
Wha-- I mea-- Am I--
Am I supposed to get into a fiight with
the guy because he steps on my foot?
All right. What if I--
What if I do fiight with the guy...
and I get lucky and I kill him?
All right? Then, uh,
the cops come by and they say,
"Well, how come you killed this guy?´´
I say, "Well-- Well,
he, uh, stepped on my foot.´´
They´re gonna think I overreacted.
See, I don´t know what it is. I woke up
today. I mean, I wake up every day.
Today-- Today, I woke up and, uh,
I felt-- I felt really strange.
You know? I mean, really weird,
because I wasn´t depressed.
I wasn´t sad.
I wasn´t angry.
On the other hand, I mean,
I wasn´t happy or good-natured.
I just sort offelt...
I-I-I don´t know, kind ofeven.
Don´t get me wrong, okay?
I´m not content. I hate that.
You know, when you say to somebody,
"Well, how are you?´´ and they go,
"Well, I´m content.´´
I feel like saying, "Yeah, what would
you be if I smacked ya?´´ You know?
I´d rather feel
one way or the other.
But today, I-I-I just felt even.
And, uh, I don´t like it.
- Sex kick
- Ah! Lionel Dobie.
- Yeah, wow.
- lknow whatyou´re thinking
lknow whatyou´re wanting
Sex kick, sex kick
Se-- Oww
Hey, hey
Hey
- Go over and talk to him.
- No, I changed my mind. I´m tired.
- I just wanna go home.
- No, no, no, no, no, no.
Just go on over and talk to him.
Just tell him you liked the show.
I mean, now´s the time.
Yeah.
- Gregory, hi.
- Hey, Paulette.
- Listen, I-- I just wanted to tell
you, you know, it wasjust-- wow.
- Greg, hi. Excuse me.
- Peter! God.
- Yeah, wejust missed the show.
- You know, traffiic.
- Aw, man.
- But I have a friend here.
- I´d like you to meet Hank.
- How you doin´?
- Hey.
- Love your stuff.
- Creep.
- Paulette, don´t worry about it.
The guy is a jerk.
- Did you see Lionel Dobie?
- Where? Is he here?
He´s right there.
He´s got a blue shirt on.
- Hey! You feel better, right?
- Why´d you make me do that?
- He´s a bastard!
- Look, you´re the bastard!
I didn´t want to do that.
Why´d you make me do that?
Me? I love you.
I´ll do anything foryou.
You want me to go back in that tunnel
and pull him out by his hair?
Just say it!
Listen, you don´t want to sleep with me
or let me touch ya, I´ll live with that.
I will live with that, because
I love you. But you just tell me
what you want me to do. I´ll do it.
I´ll-I´ll kill him in front of
everybody! What?Just say it!
- Stop it! Stop! You´re such a fool!
- No-- Listen to me.
Listen to me.
I love you.
I´ll do anything foryou.
I´ll stretch canvas foryou.
Do you love me?
I said I did, yes.
You´d do anything for me?
What?Just name it.
See them?
Kiss the driver on the mouth.
Then we´ll talk.
What?
Come on.
Show me how much you love me.
- What if I do, huh?
- Then I´ll know your love is true.
And ifyou don´t, your name
is King Bullshit, and I pack.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
Check out Grizzly Adams here.
Has he got anything?
I don´t think so.
Just looks like he lost his llama.
What´s up?
Hey. Hey-Hey, oh-ho-ho-ho.
Back away from the car, pal.
You better back away from the car.
Why do I get these
all the time?
I love you too. Come on.
Take a walk, will ya?
Is that for me?
Is what foryou?
You walk around
like that in front of me...
what´s to stop me from losing control,
from just taking you?
Taking me?
I could do anything.
You know why?
Because I´m nothin´ to you,
so who cares?
I could rape you.
I could kill you.
- I could kill myself.
- Or rape yourselfeven.
I could do anything, because I´m
nothing. I´m the invisible man with you.
Night.
Anything. Anything.
- Hey, hear Heidi got a show?
- Her own show?
- Well, it´s a group show.
- Where?
In El Paso.
Is that Donald Dowd?
Yep.
- You see his show?
- I saw it with you.
Yeah, I-- Sorry.
Boy, I´m glad I make
such a strong impression.
Shit!
- Great.
- I heard he won some arts grant.
- Yeah, from his parents.
- Yeah!
- Hey.
- How you doing?
- I´m great. How are you?
- Good.
Oh, you know, I´m uh-- Got this new
piece running over at the Blind Alley.
- You should come see it.
- She did see it, you self-absorbed,
no-talent son ofa bitch!
- Shut up, Lionel.
- What´s your problem, man?
Who in the hell told you you
were a human being? What the hell
do you know about the human heart?
- You don´t even know her.
You don´t even see her.
- Lionel!
- Right.
- What was shejust she,
just some piece ofass to you?
- Okay, stop it!
- Shut your mouth, man!
Honey, don´t do that.
Hey! What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Are you punishing me?
Punishing you?
Listen, uh--
I got carried away. I´m sorry.
- I-I love you.
- Look, my brother´s
driving in to pick me up.
He´ll be here in two hours.
Stay out of my face till then!
Wha-- Who-- Wai--
What´re you doing?
I´m going home.
Stay out of my face!
Home? This is New York. It´s here
foryou. I´ll-I´ll do anything foryou.
All right, to hell with me. To hell
with me, okay? What about your painting?
Tell me what´s here.
Don´t give me the shit about
"real artists have no choice.´´
What´s here? Am I good?
Will I ever be good?
Come on. Right now! Come on!
I´m going home.
You´re young yet.
I love you.
Love me?
You just need me around to--
Sometimes I feel like a human sacrifiice.
I don´t know.
Maybe if I was as good as you, I
wouldn´t care about anybody else either.
But I´m not, so goodbye.
So I´m the monster, right? Well,
just what´s so hell great about you?
- I don´t know. Nothing.
- You know, you gotta start learnin´
to like yourselfa little more.
- Yeah, okay. I´ll try.
- But, see, you don´t think I love you,
because you don´t love yourself.
I´ll keep that in mind.
Okay, look, maybe it´s me.
It´s-- No, it´s me.
You know, I indulge.
I indulge in love.
I indulge in making my stuff,
and they feed offeach other, you know?
And they come together at times,
but this-- this is bad.
This is selfiish.
So maybe I--
I-I should try and be
a nice person forya.
Maybe the key to that
is to try and stop.
You know, just, uh, sh--
stop painting.
And, uh, maybe I sh-- Yeah,
and I should stop-- stop painting
and just be a nice person foryou.
Now, is-- is that what
you want me to do? Huh?
I don´t give a damn what you do.
My brother´s a United States Marine,
and I can´t take this any more!
Get out of here.
Get outta here!
I can´t take this any more!
Get out of my room!
Your room?
I own the damn building!
A complete unknown
Just like a rollingstone
You´vegone to the finestschool
Allright, MissLonely
- Butyou knowyou only
usedtogetjuicedin it
- You know something?
Ifjust once you came by my room
and said, "Gee, Paulette,
you´re a terrible painter.
- Why don´t you get a job and enjoy it?´´
- Let me tell you something.
You think I just use people,
just grind ´em up.
Well, you don´t know
anything about me.
You don´t know how involved I get
or how far down I go.
Hell, I was married four times since
before you were even born.
- So don´t you tell me!
- He´snotsellin´anyalibis
Asyoustare into the vacuum
ofhis eyes
-Andsays toyou wouldyou like to
- So don´t tell me.
Make a deal
Howdoes it feel
- To be without a home
- Chippies.
You know why they call ´em that? Because
they like to chip away at you, man.
Take a little chip. That´s your
art form. That´s your talent.
Just like a rollingstone
Oh, God.
Excuse me, Mr Dobie, uh,
I-I just wanna tell ya, man, like,
I´m kinda like an artist myself.
When I look at your stuff,
I just wanna divorce my wife.
- I mean, like, thankyou.
- Thankyou.
- Can I have a white wine, please?
- Sure.
- There you go.
- Thankyou.
- What was that?
- I wanted to touch you for good luck.
- For me?
- No, for me.
Maybe some of it´ll rub off, um--
Are you an artist?
You´re an artist.
I´m a painter.
I mean, I´m trying to--
- I´m not saying this right.
- Listen, are you making ends meet?
Um, it´s an expensive city.
Oh, it´s the only city.
What´s Fowler pay you?
Peanuts, right?
Yeah.
I need an assistant.
I pay room and board, give life lessons
that are priceless, plus a salary.
You wouldn´t know anybody
who needs a job, would ya?
Oh, God!
- What´s your name? I´m Lionel Dobie.
- Hi.
We skippedthe light fandango
Did you know that flute playing
was once banned by law?
Once upon a time it was.
It was banned because
it was so beautiful...
that all the virgins fell in love
and got themselves seduced.
My father told me that story.
He´s Claudio Montez...
and he´s the greatest
flute player in the world.
My mother is
Charlotte Montez...
and she´s usually travelling
in India or somewhere...
taking photographs
or maybe writing a book.
Her beautiful face
was the fiirst sight I ever saw.
When I was born, Claudio used
to play the baby music for me...
on his silver flute.
It was the fiirst sound
I ever heard.
They named me Zoe,
because Zoe means "life´´ in Greek.
Zoe, considerher
Zoe, deliverher
She´sso offbeat
So bittersweet
Zoe, considerher
Zoe, deliverher
Life wouldbe nothing without her
She´sgot thatsomethingabout her
Makesme weak
Zoe, considerher
Since Claudio and
Charlotte are rarely home...
I live alone in
the Sherry Netherlands Hotel...
where the old ladies in the elevator
wear too much perfume.
Hector is our family butler
and my guardian angel.
He takes care of me
when my parents are travelling...
which is most ofthe time.
- I´m not in.
- Good morning, Miss Montez!
Come on. Get up. You don´t
wanna be late for school again.
- Hi, Vegas.
- Smell that hot chocolate.
Come on. It´sjust like you like it--
sugar and Sweet´N Low.
- One and one.
- Yeah. Don´t wanna go to school.
- I don´t feel good.
- You don´t what?
You know, maybe you have the flu.
It´s going around.
Let me-- Ooh!
I burned my hand!
Quick, get the salve.
Ooh, please help! Please!
Tell you what.
We´ll look at your horoscope, okay?
See what that says
about going to school.
"Miss Zoe Montez, Aries.
Have a nice
continental breakfast...
then get up real quick
and get dressed for school.
Don´t dilly-dally.´´
What´s that mean, "dilly-dally´´?
It means you made it up.
How ´bout you wear this today?
This is nice.
My father gets the most unusual mail.
Brooklyn Academy of Music--
- Yes or no? Wanna wear this?
- No.
- No?
-Julio Iglesias tickets?
How ´bout this?
You could put this on real quick.
- Mm, okay.
- Okay.
You know, maybe you should
open the rest ofthe mail...
when you get home
from school tonight.
You´ll have more time then.
Hmm, the minister ofSharez
is having a big bash.
- Sharez. Do you know where is?
- Mm, no.
We could look it up in the atlas
tonight. But now you can´t be late.
- You know what your mother said.
- Oh, my mother.
Her life is always such a mess.
And before you know it, she tries
to organize mine long-distance.
- Listen, you´re gonna miss
the bus again. You know what time--
- It´s not right.
- Look, it´s 8:06, 8:07.
- It´sjust not fair.
- Right in that area. Hurry.
- Hot to trot.
Hey, you see? Your favourite.
Look, farm fresh.
And it´s donejust
like you like it.
Seven-and-a-half minutes.
I put a little salt on it,
no pepper.
Okay, now, chew it 20 times
like I showed you.
One-- Oh. Okay, just yolk?
I´ll give you some
ofthe white stuff later.
Remember her trying to teach me about my
credit cards and my damn bank balance?
Watch your language.
Don´t say "bank balance.´´
Once I was in debt,
I was in debt so much...
that with all the deductions
she took out of my allowance...
I didn´t even have enough
money to pay for taxis.
Thanks, Hector.Just don´t let
my mom long-distance harass you.
Whatever´s right.
- Oh, good. Thanks, Vegas.
- The bus is leaving. It does not wait.
- It´ll wait!
- Don´t miss the B-U-S!
- Don´t worry. Calm down.
Go, Zoe, go!
Hustle, Zoe.
Good morning, Mr Lilly.
What´s new?
I suppose you want cash, Zoe.
I wasjust saying hello.
Please, a twenty, two tens,
a fiive and fiive singles.
Charge it to my account, please.
Just in case I miss my bus.
And they´re off! Oh!
Here comes Zoe, running tired.
Running tired.
Zoe´s gonna be late for school again.
She´s gonna be late, folks.
She´s running slow.
She´s running tired.
She´s not gonna make it!
Come on, Zoe. Run. Run, Zoe!
Shit!
Cab, cab, cab, cab!
Taxi!
- You know, I have yet
to see you be on time.
- Thanks foryour concern.
- Who is that?
- Oh, that´s the new kid.
- Oh, that´s the new boy.
- New boy?
- Oh, my Lord, look!
- That´s a very, very nice suit.
Look at that thing
on that guy´s head.
It´s a turban.
Haven´t you ever seen one before?
Let´s get an interview
with that new boy!
Yeah! Andrea Melcher says he´s one
ofthe richest boys in the world.
- Oh, my God.
- Andrea said that?
- She knows him already?
- She works fast.
- The richest boy.
- Excuse me.
- Zoe, how are we gonna get
an interview with him?
- He has bodyguards.
- Yeah.
- Big bodyguards.
Rich people like
to be in the press.
Yeah, but what are you
gonna say to him?
We have champagne
and caviar, baby.
I show you my new BMW
and my red Ferarri.
We make beautiful music together.
He´s got a silver Maserati
with a 24-hour-a-day driver.
- Can you believe that?
- My Maseratigoes 185
Girls. Girls, girls.
Now, we need to get back to work.
- Sorry, Mrs Mendez.
- We have a magazine to put out.
- Who has his number?
How can we get his number?
- Andrea.
- Andrea´sjust like--
- Andrea!
- Are you talking to me?
- Can we have Abu´s phone number?
He´ll be on the cover
of Dingbat News.
I enjoy taking long walks.
He enjoys long walks.
I get really bored
with spending money.
Bored spending money.
I intend to inherit
my father´s wealth...
and after that,
create many times more...
so that I will be
the richest man in the world...
by the time I am 24.
Lately, people have been offering
me drugs, but I am not interested.
- I can satisfy myself
with a chocolate bar.
- Really?
I like going to parties.
Sometimes the Hewitt girls...
- invite me to their parties...
- Thankyou.
- at the Carlyle or the Concorde.
Last year, I was a straight guy.
I was very preppy--
into computers, video games
and a dirt bike.
- Now, I am into clothes
and music and art.
- Wow.
This is the Dingbat News,
not People magazine.
Well, we are supposed to
wear socks, but I do not.
Oh, good.
Doesn´t wear socks.
I have talked to Morgan Fairchild on
the telephone for an hour in my room.
Oh, I suppose you see right through me,
popular girls like you.
- See through you?
- Yes. Right through me, I think.
- Why?
- I have no friends, hardly.
Not any kids of my own age.
But I have plenty
ofadult friends...
but they´re easy to get
when you´re rich.
- No friends at all?
- Not one.
- Really?
- Gee, that´s too bad.
- Abu, I was a very lonely kid.
I used to travel with my father,
so I had no friends.
You? No friends? Really?
Then my mom told me the story
ofthe bunny rabbit.
"Bunny rabbit´´?
What is bunny rabbit?
Once upon a time there was
a bunny rabbit, a lonely one.
He had no friends at all.
So his mother put him in his backyard
with all his toys and carrots...
and vegetables and said,
"You play here with all your stuff.´´
- And what do you think happened?
- What happened?
Soon, lots of bunny rabbits were
peeking over the fence, saying...
"Can I play too?´´
My mom told me that story.
Whenever I´m lonely
and have no friends...
I just have a lot
offun by myself.
And people always peek over the fence
and say, "Can we play too?´´
I see. So be it.
Can I play too?
- Let´s go shopping.
- Okay.
Thankyou, Abu.
I had a wonderful time.
- So have I.
- But it´s extremely late.
- Will you be in trouble?
- I don´t think so. Bye-bye!
I´m sorry.
We don´t have a "Carter´´ on here.
Right here. Come on. Pull it.
- Come on. Move! Hey!
- Hey, I´m cool, buddy.
I´m not a real security guard.
- I´m just an out-of-work actor
tryin´ to pay the rent.
- Quiet! Quiet, fat man.
- We do this all the time.
- Leave me alone!Jimmy, please!
- Now you got something to
tell your grandchildren.
-Don´t hurt her!
-Lie down there. On your hands! Come on!
It´s all right. Come on.
Do what they say. It´s a robbery.
- Quiet! And don´t look!
- I´m scared.
- Be still and don´t look at them.
Stay here and don´t look.
Don´t look!
- Keep your eyes down.
- I don´t want to.
- Shut up, kid!
- Comfy?
- Leave her alone.
Kick me. Don´t kick her.
What do you have there?
- Pop it, pop it. Come on!
- Hey, that´s my father´s. Number 77!
- Clam up, kid, or I´ll make ya howl!
- They´ve got his security box!
I was gonna inherit
his cuff links someday.
- Will you keep quiet?
- Zoe, this is serious. Look at my eye.
- I´ve got an audition tomorrow.
-Just the big stuff.
- Blot that out with a little
Chanel Soft Bisque number three.
- Really?
- Hey, how you kids doin´ there, huh?
You need anything?
- All right.
- You comfy?
- Yeah.
- No.
- You want anything? A blanket?
Uh, how about a lobster roll,
or, uh, maybe a club sandwich?
How would you like that?
Ask me. Anything you want.
You just ask me. I´m your man, okay?
Come on, fellas. Let´s go!
Move it! Come on! Let´s go.
Don´t make any fuss for a while.
We might be right back.
Good foryou.
Big deal.
Boy, Zoe, if I could remember
this sense memory, I´d be
the hit of my acting class.
- Bravo,Jimmy.
- Thankyou, Mr Lilly.
- Are you all right, Zoe?
- Yeah.
You were very brave.
Lately, all these high-class New York
hotels have been getting robbed.
I´m glad the crook dropped the package
he stole from my father´s...
safe deposit box,
and I got it back.
Wow. Those crooks sure
didn´t know what they had.
I´d better tell Hector.
Hector!
Hector, wake up! Hector!
- What?
- There was a robbery downstairs!
- Yeah.
- Are you all right?
- Yes. Here, look.
Theyjust took it out of
my father´s safety deposit box.
Look, it´s a diamond,
and there´s a note.
"A Tear ofSharez for my tears when
I heard your flute. Princess Soroya.´´
- Sharez? Where´s that invitation
we opened this morning?
- In the garbage.
- What?
- Threw it in the garbage.
- Oh, gosh.
Come on.
Come on, Hector.
- How´d you get that thing?
- Those crooks dropped it.
- Vegas, drop-- Ahh!
- Ahh!
- Open your mouth.
- Drop it!
- Zoe, just--
- I am!
- Pull it, pull it, pull it.
- Wait! Got it!
- Got it? Okay.
I hope we have all the pieces.
I don´t know.
- Yeah.
- You think so?
Yeah, we-we got it all.
It´s all here.
- "Sheik Omar requests--´´
- "Sheek´´ Omar.
- It´s pronounced "shake´´.
Okay. "Sheik Omar requests the pleasure
ofthe company of Mr Claudio Montez...
at dinner and a party to follow.
Princess Soroya will wear
the famed Tears ofSharez earrings.
Black tie.´´
Well, black tie´s no problem,
but the earrings--
one earring, anyway,
is gonna be a problem.
- How can she wear it if it´s here?
- I know.
Claudio´s in big trouble,
and it´s not his fault.
I know what happened. She probably
heard him play the flute, and then she
took it off her ear and gave it to him.
- It happens all the time.
- And the sheik must think...
that he´s falling
in love with his wife.
- Oh, no.
- We gotta fiind this Princess Soroya.
Give her back the diamond.
That´s all.
Sheik Omar.
Maybe Abu´s heard of him.
Abu? Who´s Abu? Abu who?
Abu´s my new friend.
Hi, Abu? It´s Zoe.
Fine. And you?
I hope it´s not too late.
Say, Abu, do you know Sheik Omar?
"Shake´´ Omar.
Oh, he´s your uncle.
Oh, he´s the king!
So Princess Soroya is your aunt.
Abu? How would you
like to have a party?
- Play with all your
carrots and vegetables.
- Vegetables?
- Sorry, Hector.
- Hit me in the head with the hat. Abu?
- Yeah, like the bunny rabbit.
- Rabbits? What´s goin´ on?
Oh! Your parents are
out oftown. Perfect!
Yoo-hoo! Yoo-hoo!
It´s Tom Cruise,
and I´m wearing a tank top.
- Howdy,Jimmy. How´s tricks?
- Eh. Hey, Zoe, you think next time your
mom hasJoe Papp over for dinner...
she could use these for place mats?
- I think the plates might break.
- Ohh.
- Say,Jimmy, I like you in that colour.
- Thanks,Jimmy.
- Something about a man in uniform.
Oh, and, ladies, these pinky drinkies
are on Raoul.
- All right.
- Strawberry daiquiris.
- Who´s coming to Abu´s party?
Hey, the butler did it.
Zoe, I gotta talk to you for a minute.
- Zoe, your mother called and said--
- Yeah, I know.
My mother called to tell me that
she´s working on a new photojournal
of India, and my mother is home.
- My mother is home.
- Hello, Zoe darling.
So, is this what your father
calls "sophisticated´´?
Twelve-year-old girls drinking
strawberry daiquiris and reading
Paris Vogue.
- Mom, what are you doing here?
- Oh, my God, we gotta go.
That´s a warm welcome,
and I´m your mother...
this is my bedroom,
and these are my earrings.
- I´m sorry, Mrs Montez.
- Sorry.
- Bye, Zoe.
- That´s my hat.
- Watch that.
- Sorry.
- Bye, Mrs Montez.
- I´m sorry, girls. I was not
intending to be a snob. It was--
- So long, Zoe.
- You will forgive me, won´t you, girls?
- Bye, Zoe.
- Bye, Mrs Montez.
- Bye, girls.
- Move it, move it. Let´s go. Move it.
- Hello.
- Aw.
One, two, three--
Come on, Lundy.
Hurry up. Let´s go.
- Bye, Zoe.
- See you later, Bridget.
Uh, sorry, Mom,
but what´s going on?
Zoe, I know this is--
this is diffiicult, but...
your father and I
are trying a reconciliation.
What?
Oh, Zoe. Oh, sweetheart.
Most kids would be happy
to hear that.
Oh, whatever´s right.
- It´s your clothes, I think.
- My clothes?
Something´s wrong with my clothes?
The shoulders are really big.
Oh, Zoe, would yo--
Please don´t start on my shoulders.
A woman shouldn´t have
bigger shoulders than a man.
Besides, they slide around.
Face it, Mom, they´re passé.
We should have given me
a fair warning you were coming...
so I could have reserved
a room at the Plaza.
She´s a nut.
See? And you´re smoking again.
I tell you, Charlotte,
you shouldn´t be hanging out
with those art friends ofyours.
Lucy Montana and Aggie Zenobia?
You´re better than that, Mom.
You have real talent, and you´d see it
ifyou´d quit competing with Claudio.
I´m the daughter,
and you´re the mother! Oh.
I´m the mother,
and you´re the daughter.
Right.
Daddy, oh, Daddy!
- I was worried about you.
- How´s my principessa?
I love your scarf.
Can I wear it?
Ofcourse.
Can I have it?
Just kidding.
Look. You can use it
for a poster.
Ah. Wonderful. Good idea.
It´s a-- It´s a work ofart.
Look. I could use it
for an album cover.
- What do you think?
- Yeah. Sit down. Relax.
You must be tired.
- Can I get you a drink?
- Ah, sure.
Hey, Vegas.
How are you, Vegas?
Thankyou.
- My bambina.
- How´s everything?
Well...
in life there are always
a few problems.
But, uh, things are not too bad.
We were all surprised
you interrupted your tour.
- Well, you know how it is.
- How is it?
Uh, I´m a little bit in hot water.
- You know what that means?
- I can fiigure it out.
But nothing foryou
to worry about, my little signorina.
That´s for me, Vegas.
Hello?
Yes.
Still?
- What is it?
- Oh, my little charmer.
Did you know Mom
was coming home too?
Yes, your mother.
Zoe, did I ever tell you how once
playing the flute was banned by law?
A million times.
It was banned because the sound
was so beautiful...
so seductive.
- It oughta be against the law.
- It´s true.
Since when did you
start smoking again?
Mm. Occasional cigarette.
A flautist shouldn´t smoke.
I can help, Pops.
Believe me, Zoe,
there is no problem, though.
It wasjust a--
- Well, you see--
- Yes?
A very beautiful, mysterious woman.
- A princess, in fact.
- She heard you play the flute.
And she was so moved
that she gave me a jewel--
an earring.
She plucked from her ear and said...
"A Tear ofSharez
for my tears...
when I heard your flute.´´
I put it in my pocket.
- It´s nice, isn´t it?
- But-- But--
How? I thought it was stolen.
Her husband isj--
You see, Zoe, he doesn´t know it was
all an innocent misunderstanding.
- Neither will Mom.
- Exactly.
And this is the wrong time
for something to go wrong.
-Just give it back.
- He has a man watching me.
Maybe I can help, Pops.