subtitles by markyp
NEXT
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome the man that knows
what your going to do before you do it!
The amazing,
Frank Cadillac.
Good evening. Welcome to the
beautiful downtown Las Vegas.
How many people here
from the orient?
raise your hands.
You, sir...
where are you from?
No, wait... don't tell me.
You must have soul.
your a soul man.
Now tell everyone
where are you from?
- Korea.
- how about that, folks?
may I assume this charming young lady
- is your daughter.
- she is my wife!
Of course!
What happens in
Vegas stays in Vegas.
- what's your name?
- Yhun-Kihong.
would you be kind enough to join
me up on the stage please?
are you serious about
this guy? is this a joke?
coming around with some
minds and clowns while were at it
Yhun-Kihong.
what if I told you that that pretty
necklace your wearing
has a broken catch...
and on my count of three
, will fall in your drink.
wouldnt that be something?.
wouldnt that just blow your mind?
- Yes.
- wouldnt it blow all your minds!
Three, two, one
now.
Does anybody say that was spooky?
wait a minute, look at your glass.
where did it go?
Yhun-Kihong, why don't you
look inside my pocket?
reach in. dig deep
lets have a big hand for Yhun-Kihong.
Well... thats magic folks.
And thats why I'm here.
They probably seen a
lot of those shows.
Mentalists
magicians, illusionists...
you will be shocked to know
that sometimes
not often, but sometimes
its the real deal.
masquerding as an act
hidden behind
a few 50 dollar tricks
hiding in plain sight
Because if the magicians
doesnt do that,
the alternative is impossible
for others to live with
anyway Wednesday nights
the back page doesnt pay very well,
so I gamble.
But I don't play against other people,
only against the house.
so,no mega
Jack Pots,no wash outs
The idea is to go unnoticed.
that way I can keep coming back
I'm not a God.
I can't see everyone's future
only my own.
and only within
2 minutes,
except for when I saw her
but we will come back to that
there is no pattern to this guy.
he is all over the map.
well he's not counting not enough.
Wait a minute.
isnt it that two bit magic act from
Las Vegas. Whats his name?
Cadillac.
Yes, Frank Cadillac.
is he pulling tricks on us? is that legal?.
He cant trick the deck
I'm telling you. that little prick
knows whats coming
If he's really knocking a system
why's he not betting more
That will be my second question
look at him.
he is looking at us
Its like he can hear us.
- What table is that?
- 27.
Send security
to table 27!
here is a thing about the future...
every time you look at it,
It changes.
Because you look at it,
and that changes everything else.
Empty the drawer.
Move!
drop the gun, now!
drop the gun, step back.
Its his gun.
He was going to shoot your people.
step Back, now.
Whats he doing?
Check the doors, elevators, escalators
everywhere, under the staircases, now!
he is going to the Black Jack tables.
make it before he goes
hes right next to the ten dollar slot.
aisle 14.
there he is behind you!
your left. turn around!
He's right between you.
He's in the mensroom!
Where the hell is he?
Black shirt,straw hat
, heading towards the exit.
Let's go
Call vegas PD
He stole a silver sports car,
plates 5854AS.
this guy escaped from
the casino two months ago
what he does has nothing to do with luck
its an ability. look at him!
he knows exactly what to do.
Can it explain to me that?
I cannot explain, Kelly.
nor do I have the time.
The Russian Federation has a 10 kiloton
nuclear munition unaccounted for
I understand that
I'm not sure you do.
We need every
agent available beating the street.
that bomb was stolen
5 weeks ago ago.
We have just been informed of it now.
which means it could just be parked
under this truck for all we know
any actionable intelligence
Not paranormal
and bullshit magicians.
With all due respect
sir, this bullshit magician
advanced the way he did
its statiscally impossible.
let me bring him in
then get what you want.
5 days, Kelly.
thats it.
get me the head of casino security
You Roybal?
whatever.
- Who are you?
Cavanaugh, take a walk
hey roybal. this isnt
a picture contest. come on
What are you doing?
got a new car?
Its stolen.
See that.
20 minutes to walk, 20 steps.
thats what you get from two packs a day.
I got you two sandwiches
thats plenty grand
thank you... I love you.
how can I repay you
must be a big surprise
Jeff Roybal...
Special agent Ferris.
I don't need to say that
everything you say...
can be used
against you. Did we understand each other?
sure.
tell me about Cris Johnson.
- I don't know who that is.
how about Frank Cadillac, you
kicked him out of the casino tonight.
He stole a car from valet parking
Yes, yes I know Cadillac.
I thought he was cheating us at cards.
next thing I know hes tackling some
guy waving a gun -The gun wasnt his.
The man he tackled was one
of the two casino killers in reno.
he is in custody now
come on, I want to show you something.
you remember this?
Yes, of course yes.
we were saying that
he was looking right at us.
- how did you get this?
- now think carefully.
what were you talking
about when he looked up?
we were saying that if he had
a system why wasnt he bidding more
you sure you werent doing or saying
anything else?
mumbles...
and right then.
would that be very specific
thats what I said and
he looked up. really
so he doesnt have to be there to do it
is that to work the system.
Thank you.
Were finished.
done some good in there, Mr Roybal
as far as your concerned.
this person never existed
thats going to be difficult. considering
theres a hundred cameras at the casino
Don't worry,
the tapes have been destroyed.
You can have those cars
and things of that type...
but thats not a life.
but you kind of forget that girl.
that you Keep seeing in your head.
I am not going anywhere
until I meet her
And where do you think about going?
she already did.
Its a diner.
10 for the 8.
But youve got a couple of hours.
how about a game of pool?
Allright, Irv. We'll shoot some pool.
pretend Here hes at Black Jack.
And the 6 card 21
he want it so we know he can stay
at least a minute and a half ahead
i had a text from a radio
frequency detection analysis
he is not receiving any form
of electronic help
at one point there was a
2 minutes and 16 seconds delay
He never backed.
just got up and walked away.
maybe 2.16 is too long
and he cannot see that far
narrows the window
We got him
Vegas PD got a lo-jack hit
on the stolen vehicle.
Look.
about that girl.
about the clock.
Do you happen to see if its Canada?
Because...
Because its could be 10 years
Its gotta be soon.
I never see further ahead than two minutes
Except for her
And what do you think
the reason is for that?
I don't know.
Maybe she doesn't scare easy.
Maybe she is the one
when you get like this...
there is no talking to you.
she is on the street
This is somebody else. cop.
A cop?
you had better go.
Wait,I want to see how much she knows,what
she wants from me.
Mr. Johnson.
Still here huh?.
Where else would I be?
Special agent Ferris.
next time steal a car without lojack.
Can we speak privately?
its ok, Irv,you can go.
Thank you.
You know why im here.
Youre the man that knows what
im going to do before I do it. right?
Right?
The show, right?
Yes, I saw you there.
wonderful. Do you like magic?
Yes, I like yes.
Magic tricks, clairvoyance,
whatever you call it.
Lets see something hard.
stolen nucleur munitions being smuggled
into the US and may already be here.
I want you to look ahead and tell me
where it is going to be deployed
I think you got the wrong guy and...
Its a magic act.
you gonna stick with that story.
because millions of lives are at risk.
you could maybe prevent a major catastrophe
on a practical note. we are
standing in front of a stolen vehicle.
and you are wanted for assault
involving a weapon at a casino
that was an accident. he had a gun
and he was going to shoot two people
yes?
how did you know that
The deed goes unpunished does it?
I can fix your legal problems..
but you gotta step up
Or else your next
magic show...
will be in the state prison.
its ironic but...
people like you who try to help
end up torturing me
in the full sense of the word
since I was 3 years old.
what do they call it...
observed play therapy.
A marathon 36 hours...
can you guess the next flash card game?
so, please...
leave me alone.
Let me live some semblence of a normal life.
I would love to indulge
your feelings. But Im dealing...
with a slightly larger picture right now
now you can exercise your responsibility
to help your fellow men...
or I will exercise that
responsibility for you.
right, I gotta go.
he's gone, right?
this is my seconds tonight
excuse me honey, can you get off my car
- Yes.
- Thank you.
Sr. Roybal.
Can I help you?
I have a few
questions, is this a good time?
the Commission is after hours
you guys should be in a strip club come on
What can you tell us about Cris Johnson?
I don't know who your talking about
let me rephrase the question.
- The menu.
- Yes, thank you.
Excuse.
Hello!
unless your alone too.
do you mind if I join you?
actually I do
sorry to bother you. I have
a question about the coffee...
the bean they use
isnt that something you should
probably ask your waitress?
Yes, it is
excuse me, do you have a light?
I don't smoke.
Please. No.
did you follow me here or something?
No, I just thought we could talk
you know we got nothing to talk about.
I told you that 3 weeks ago.
Liz, come on. I had an off day
just give me another chance
its not going to happen,
so maybe you should just go
do you know how hard it was to find you?
I was at your apartment,
I tried the Starbox, in Lexington,
I was at the dry cleaners
All Im asking for is
a few minutes of your time.
My God! your stalking me
Don't say that,thats
a terrible thing to say...
let go of me.
I only want to talk,
maybe we can take a drive..
your hurting me.
Kendal.
I think your having another off day
who the hell are you?
I'm her future.
Really?
Hello, my name is Cris.
you okay, Kendal?
The thing is I feel connected...
and I don't know the reason why.
Now listen.
I think it would be at least fair
you pay for the ladies breakfast
what are you having?pecan pies are amizing
Excuse me. I can pay for my own breakfast
And you know what. you two are cleaned out
your hurting me.
Kendal?
I think your having another off day.
Who the hell are you?
Im her future.
really?
This is coming.
My God! Kendal!
what. dont point at me. this is your fault.
get out of here.
will somebody please call the cops.
I feel so sorry...
are you ok?
let me help you.
Come here,lets get
you cleaned up.
I see stars.
I am Liz.
I am Cris.
you must have a death wish
getting involved in that.
Hold it there.
to stanch.
well?
what well?
your luck,
its gonna change.
what are you? a leprauchaun
do leprachaun's get punched in the face?
or have their car stolen.
your car was stolen?
I'm hoping they find it today.
I think was in Flags Stags.
Hey, is this tooth loose here?
Don't I know?
I don't think so.
Hurt.
well listen, I guess I can give you a ride.
Im going that way.
That would really be helpful.
Thank you.
I do have to make a stop though.
Thats ok.
and it may take a few hours...
if that isnt a problem.
look if your uncomfortable with this...
I will take a bus.
No, no. Its fine,its fine
your not a psycho
right?
The first sign of a psycho
I kick you out of the car.
ok. Yes Ma'am
- Right.
deal
hey
and then
end up in a diner where you are and
both heading in the same direction.
I don't know if I can call
that amazing, but...
thats destiny.
Thats what it really is
your starting to get the psycho on.
Ah, no... you don't believe in destiny?
even if it does exist,
I just don't want to know
I mean if every move you make
is pre-ordained.
What is the point
life is supposed to a surprise
It would be nice.
hes came in twice a day for
a week at exactly 9 past 8?
Yes, he would stay a few minutes,
have a martini and then he'd go.
not today when he was with that lady.
Did you find anything strange about that?
not strange enough to call the police.
we got a regular who counts
the cornflakes in his bowel.
because it has to be an even number.
do you have any cameras?
Inside? No.
outside?
No.
do you know the kind of car
he was driving?
or maybe overhear
where they were going?
I don't know what car but they were leaving
for cascade.
thats what they said
Another regular. she's always on a diet.
brings in a scale with the salad dressing
Thank you.
You're welcome.
this guy knows we are after him.
he saw us coming here.
8 or 9. twice a day
he doesnt know if its day or night,
its the time he's waiting for her.
There is a traffic camera
over there. At the bank.
7-11 across the street. just run all
the tapes we will get lucky.
and catch them at the wide
Remember roybal. the casino chief?
he had his throat cut last night.
after getting a knee cap shot off.
your telling me this now?
we were just talking about Johnson?
hey I just found out.
alright.
got the weapon?
dead end
Forensic's came up emtpy.
Not a hair or a fibre.
Somebody wants information,
next time anything happens...
relevent to Johnson,
I want to know right away.
I dont care if its a paper clip.
ok boss.
The head of casino security.
What did you learn from him?
for a macho guy, he screams like a girl.
he was questioned by federal agents,
looking for Chris Jonhson.
Yes?
He said they
hadn't found him yet.
Do you believe this shit?
he see's things before they happen?
it makes no difference
what I believe.
look, we spent two
years setting this up.
And that man out there is worried
all this will be comprimised by Johnson
We are wasting our time with this.
for a magician.
we are being paid to secure
the operations room.
not to hunt down some
carnival party
really?
then why are the
same authorities that
are looking for us
so interested in him?
get rid of him.
do it now.
We have a super reservation.
I teach there once a week.
The conditions are pretty lousy.
Thats in the Great Canyon.
One of the eight wonders of the world.
Hello, Sam.
Hello, Liz.
A couple hundred years ago
this place was booming
plenty of food and thriving culture.
they should be better off.
I guess this is destiny then.
I would like to meet there shaman.
I read once, in the many
North American tribes.
That the shamans purpose
wasn't only healing.
And that they also claim
their power of the atmosphere.
To bring on and stop rain
even though future advance.
Do you think thats possible?
I believe any thing is possible.
Me too.
whose birthday?
only one of my students.
Hi.
Hows it going?
Hello, how this everybody?
good?
thats good.
only messed up in the last part.
Yes in the last part.
I thought you werent coming back
til next monday
well Im not, but its Jay's birthday.
and I couldnt miss that.
Who is that man with you?
- Is he your boyfriend?
- No, no not my boyfriend.
just my friend.
I think he likes you.
why do you say that?
Because he looks at you like
my brother looks at his girlfriend.
hey Jay.
Doe you want to see some magic?
I will show you something.
Come here.
I found this rock out
in the Canyon.
I want you to hold this
its a magic rock.
hold it really tight keep squeezing
It's magic.
it wont bite.
Happy birthday.
so your a magician?
Well.
I have a small magic act
back in Vegas.
Frank Cadillac show.
I thought your name was Chris.
It is.
Frank Cadillac is my stage name.
how did you come up with that?
I took two things I really like
and I put them together.
Frankenstein and Cadillac.
Your odd.
Charming.
But odd.
cease fire
get out of the range
Nice
It was close though?
ok.
you were right about the traffic camera
We got a positive ID
Chris?
its ok.
Did I snore?
snore?
- Yes.
- Ah, no.
As and that worsened
so much like this the climate?
Yes.
I like the rain.
I like rain too
do you know once...
I think was in Denmark,
it rained fish...
because the sun dehydrated the water.
took it out in the atmosphere.
rehydrated the fish eggs, and
it hatched and it..
and it rained fish.
That the truth?
Yes, in the clouds. true story.
happened 15 years ago.
felt like sharing that
with you.
The road's washed out ahead.
you can't cross until morning.
not even then its a sure shot
spin around and go back about two miles
take your second left
- there will be a hotel there called...
- The Cliff Hangar. Thank you.
Correct.
him right?
thats it
no front plate,
where is the other side?
I don't have it.
What was that at the front window?
go back
Back,back.
back, there!
Zoom in.
its a permit.
Track it and find it.
I will light a fire.
Chris, one little problem.
no, no, I will sleep in the car.
- Take it.
- Thank you.
sure.
you hear the joke about the zen master
who ordered a hot dog?
No.
He said that he would have
one with everything.
Good night.
What have we got?
They went to sleep in a motel
outside cascade.
We found an Arizona foreman
who remembers the land cruiser.
How did they do that?
The road was blocked and he was about to
suggest a place to stay.
But Johnson already know, right?
Exactly.
Callie, it just got worse
all right people,
we got a nuclear alert. code red.
In the southern California region.
LA to San Diego,
95% proven.
nuclear emergency search teams are on
there way. but until they get here...
somebody please tell me wht my
agency, the FBI are doing about it?
sir, two main suspects
have been interrogated.
cars and transmits have been checked
perimeter was revised and...
we have opened up surveillance on 2 or 3
suspects but nothing actionable yet.
Then what the hell are we doing?
waiting for something actionable...
we got 8 million lives
that are precaurious at best
so I say we widen this net
to slightly suspicious
and get some decent Intel
before this nuke blows up Los Angeles.
alright, Callie.
What do you propose we do next?
I believe that the
urgency of the situation...
compels the use of any and all resources to
obtain Cris Johnson.
We know where he is.
let my team pick him up
The FBI are mobilizing.
Continue watching.
- Did you listen?
- Yes.
He says they are mobilising.
standard procedure
tell them to wrap it up
They will lead us straight to Johnson.
- Don't lose sight of them
- Certainly, ok.
you hungry? there is
a coffee shop down the road
I'd rather eat here,
if thats ok.
fine.
What?
there is an Italian painter
named Calion.
he...
he defined beauty...
he said it was a summation of the parts...
working together in such a way
in such a way...
that nothing needed to added
taken away or altered
like you
your beautiful.
wow!
It was incredible
What was?
This.
Its good here, the best place to
view hotel.
We should cover different places,
that road and that turn off.
A team with a parabolic step right here.
thats fine, but I also
want mobile surveillance...
for case something skirt of the
control. I want to be flexible
Ferris?
call the local police in flagstaff.
have them patrol the outside perimeter
I want that area locked down.
A body turned up at an apartment,
in line of sight of my office...
with a slit throat,
like roybal.
The body trying to follow us to
Johnson.
Chris?
Yes.
Maybe destiny exists.
give 40 seconds.
Within two minutes,
he will start seeing whats going to happen
I hope so.
- Elizabeth Cooper?
- Yes.
Federal agent Ferris.
what is this about?
I only need a few minutes of your time
Yes,sure.
They are putting her in the car.
Back.
He will shoot in those people.
this was 3 days ago?
He used you to get away from Las Vegas.
Everything that he told you...
and lie and illusion.
He's a sociopath
My God.
Drugs.
Return to the hotel, have
a drink put one of these...
in his glass
It will take 5 minutes to put him to
sleep, then we will come in and get him
But this is important
you need to do it at least 2 minutes
after you get him out of the room.
that to enter in the room.
why do you need me?
why dont you just get him.
He seems to think that you work
for a pedagogic program...
for a reservation with bottoms
federal, is that true?
Yes, thats true
Good, we need you to help us,
we are on the same team.
go
- hey
- thanks for the
- sure
Did you have a nice walk?
Yes,I did. Its really beautiful here.
Ah! I have a present for you.
Ah, thanks
there was no need.
Yeah
Something wrong?
No, no... Why dont you go wash up
- I'll cook breakfast.
- ok.
45 seconds.
Minute 30.
next
everything ok?.
Thank you.
Don't drink that!
its drugged
God, I don't know what do!
I don't know what im doing
A federal agent came to me
and said that you were a sociopath.
Maybe you are
but I dont want to believe that.
I don't think is true.
they also said that if
you to escape they will kill you.
so I drug you instead
Even if is true what she said.
I don't want you to die.
Is this true?
Chris?
Remove that collapsed,
I'm not hearing that
Speak quietly.
how long does this drug take to have effect?
About 5 minutes.
- What is he doing?
- he's drinking.
give it a minute.
that a clean shot?
Not yet.
In the casino
I will kill two people.
It happened, it just hadnt happen yet
My God.
Then its true.
We will prepare pancakes for the kids
We will prepare pancakes for the kids.
Safe.
Who knows whats safe
no man dropped dead from looking at his wife
Safe.
Who knows what's safe
no man dropped dead from looking at his wife
You can't get lost in the woods
if you never go in to the woods
right sir your the only person
authorised to do so
- How does you do that?
- I have no idea.
I just know that I can,
I was born like that.
is that some kind of a trick?
We don't have time for that.
who said that anything is possible.
you see things
before they happen.
- Do you see the future?
- My future.
Only what affects me and only within
2 minute ahead...
except with you. For
some reason I saw you.
For some reason I saw you further
than anything ive ever seen before
I don't know why
what do you mean?you saw me?
Have you been doing that to me?
do you know. what im going to do
and what im going to say?
that your setting me up?
It was not like this.
I wanted you from the
first time I ever see you.
Because I...
It was not a setup.
What do they want from you?
They believe that I can be
useful in national security.
I don't understand. How can you help them.
why cant you do it?
Because I cant. I only can
only see two minutes into the future.
want you to read this
and wait exactly...
45 seconds before
you do what it says.
I will take Ferris with me.
I will be away a month...
but if you wait,
I find you.
something's wrong.
dont do it.
- I already did it.
get him!
alive!
Lets go!
Damn!
Johnson.
your not gonna shoot.
Will you let me die?
I need help!get him out of here.
I got you.
you ok? Open your eyes.
Look at me
no deed goes unpunished does it?
- They got him.
now what?
Did you see her?
you smoke?
Thank you for today.
you could have left me
to die. thanks
you really showed character.
I know that I seem
like a bad guy
its with the objective of
preserving our freedom.
there are larger issues at hand
what about my freedom?
freedom comes with
responsibility.
- I have rights
- It isnt about you.
It is about 8 million
other people.
If I do what you want,
you will keep me in this chair forever.
There is a nuclear bomb
somewhere in Los Angeles.
Every television station
in the world will broadcast...
the site details. so go on,
push that two minutes
as far as you can and find it
we have breaking news
from downtown las vegas.
The corporations is opposed the idea.
Members of the LAPD bombsquad
are searching in this area.
We have a reporter...
joining us at the scence
for the very latest
it all began when police received an
anonymous phone call...
saying that explosives would be detonated...
in this parking lot,at second
and Broadway at 6 o'clock tonight.
They have no idea of the motive
What?
What did you say?
they have secured a perimeter.
but now the bomb squad..
are making there way onto
the deck of this building
and are walking up
My God!
There was an explosion.
Ah, my God.
she has been identified as
Elizabeth jogle of Las vegas.
I feel
- What happened?
- I cant
I won't work like this.
get me out of this room and I will do
what you want
Please,
get me out of this room
Let him out.
- Wait.
- What?
The surgeon's report
forensic of Betty Peters.
the dead girl in the apartment
she died from blood loss
otherwise nothing
- How did it go with johnson?
- Something happened.
But he's not sharing. There
are traces of potassium and iodine.
Some medication that
Peters was taking.
they found an empty pill box
No. the only reason to take it is to
prevent radiation poisining
Wait. anyone gotta smoke
or something. I need to relax.
Thank you.
hey, could I have a light?
look at this
Air 1 to base.
I got visual...
running for the south in the 5th street
heading east onto Broadway.
here
- why did you come here?
- They killed her.
In two hours, they will kill Liz.
Tell me what saw.
I saw them execute her.
There.
It hasnt happened yet.
And I know who has her.
They are the same people
we are after.
They brought you here.
They are using Liz as bait.
As soon as you go out on that roof, they
are going to put a bullet in your brain
I know.
Right now, she is still alive.
she is, you are,we all are.
try to keep it that way.
you help me alright?
I want a two mile radius.
All the telephones, short waves,
- satellite tower, shut it down.
- What do you want me to do?
to stay here
You ok?
that looked pretty close
It was all in hand.
you didnt get him?
no.
He fired on the helicopter.
it doesn't matter,
he couldnt call in the hit.
As far as they are concerned,
your not here yet
We won some time.
everyway I try she still ends up dead.
If you do it earlier? They will have
to bring her here in a vehicle right?
- License plate.
- right
Do you see it?
It helps if you don't speak right now
California plate number:
50KF272.
California tag: 50KF272.
Where they are taking me?
What do you want from me?
Careful.
who the hell are you people
cavanaugh
SWAT has been deployed in the area
to back us up
listen.
The van carrying...
Elizabeth Cooper will arrive in
approximately 5 minutes.
4 minutes and 27 seconds.
Do you mind?
- No name.
you got a wrap of explosives...
wired to a cell phone.
Remote trigger. If something
goes wrong she dies
They will take this ramp
to the entrance door.
In this point, alpha Bravo...
if you can just be quiet.
and do exactly what I say...
I will save her life.
We needed to stop the vehicle
here before it gets into there.
Alpha and bravo they will
hold and contain here...
on Johnson's call. On his call
Are we clear?
shoot to kill. anything else
- The intelligence?
- We won't need it.
We have
him.
everybody. lets go.
Lets go!
back up!
go, go!
- Stop the van.
- not yet. your kill her.
Now!
Now! Now!
Back! Back!
They are in the
crane, northeast corner
Negative, no visual.
give Me that.
eight inches
above the guard rail.
lets go!
The girl escaped.
Right. Clear.
go!go!
shooting.
No!
Walking.
Here and Charlie 1, I exchange.
Thank you.
explosives there, there and there.
stay close.
- Sniper.
- Where?
Behind us.
Nobody moves.
I will find him
In the second floor.
The 6'o clock. the second floor.
I got him
We will have to repeat this deck by deck
You take this one.
I will do the rest.
Do what he said.
near the engine room.
let her go, man...
release the hostage.
You can't get out of here.
Don't patronise me
How good are you with the gun?
very good.
- You ok Liz.
- Back off!
I see every possible ending here
- And none of them are good for you.
I will take that chance
one more step fortuneteller, and it
doesnt look like it will be good for you
there is one way out of here.
It was not that.
Liz, look at me.
everythings ok Look at me.
its over
No, its not
The nucleur device has moved.
we need to find its exact location...
the significant explosions.
Of a glance.
Tell me what you see.
Something's wrong.
- I made a mistake.
- What?
I made a mistake.
Its happening.
- When?
- Now!
I have 4 teams in place
waiting for my orders.
Ferris.
Its me
I will do it, but
I have conditions.
I want her out of that.
sure.
we can work something out?
Liz.
come back to bed.
- I have to go.
- go where?
There is something that I have to do.
I cant put it off any longer
- are you coming back?
- Yes.
Maybe in one week or in one month.
But if you wait for
me, I will find you.
the thing about the future...
every time that you look at it. It changes.
Because you look at it. And that
changes everything else
You ok?
yeah