You kill your film
several times.
Mostly by talking about it.
A film is a dream.
You kill it writing it down,
you kill it with a camera,
Your film might come to life
for a moment or two when
your actors breathe
life back into it,
But then it dies again,
buried in film cans.
Mysteriously, sometimes,
in the editing room...
a miracle happens when you place
one image next to another
so that when finally an
audience sits in the dark
if you're lucky, very lucky,
and sometimes I've
been lucky
the dream flickers back
to life again.
That's why I'm secretive.
So, what's your favorite pasta?
Finally, a serious question.
"NINE"
Transcribed by:
anreith [inSanos]
Sync by:
lostmaniac [inSanos]
Cinecitta Film Studios
Rome 1965
Good luck, Maestro.
Maestro, maestro, maestro.
Maestro Contini
How do you begin?
How do you begin
this thing?
Page one, page one,
page one...
Page nothing.
- Guido, you're here.
- Buongiorno, Dante.
I've been looking for you
all over the place.
The set's coming along, eh?
- How are you?
- Bene, grazie, bene.
My God you look terrible.
Better go to makeup.
Forgot you've got a
press conference?
- He has no tie.
- Yes, makeup and wardrobe.
- Signor Contini, I’m Fausto.
- He's counting cost.
The bank wants him here.
- Signor Contini.
- Don’t speak to him, I speak to him.
Okay. I have some questions
for Signor Contini.
You all have questions for
Signor Contini.
Yes, but please.
I think it's customary for
there to be an approved
script and budget before
filming commence.
- Is he going to follow us?
- It's not my intention to be difficult,
I'm a huge admirer of
Maestro Contini's movies
your early films are...
everybody loves them.
And I consider it a great
honor for me to be here.
But nonetheless, I need
a script and a budget
- Where do you want your messages?
- On my desk.
- There's no room on your desk.
- Under my desk. In the trash. Non lo so.
Ciao, Paula.
Get me a cigarette.
We will never be ready
to shoot in ten days.
Jaconelli...
- What? Not ready?
- Ascolta me.
Be careful what you say.
He's a spy from the bank.
He's not exactly
from the bank.
You have actors waiting
for you in your office.
You have auditions
all morning.
You should see what I found.
I found two sisters...
I need a cigarette.
He needs a shirt
and a tie, Lilli.
Answer the question
and I will give you a coffee
Answer another, and I will
give you a cigarette.
- Actually need an Aspirin.
- Calm down.
Directing a movie is a very
overrated job, we all know it.
You just have to say yes
or no. What else? Nothing.
"Should this be Red?" Yes.
"Green?" No
"More extras?" Yes
"More lipstick?" No
Yes. No. Yes. No.
That's right: That's directing.
It doesn't seem to make any
difference what the answer is.
So, please, Guido, yes or no.
Do you want costumes
in this film?
- Yes.
- You see? Simple.
Might I know what period
the movie is in?
Soon.
You know I don’t allow
producers in here.
Two minutes Guido.
He’s gone.
Have you written
a word of the script?
No.
Are you in a panic?
Yes.
Is Luisa going with you
to the Press Conference?
No. Nobody.
Dante and his spy.
You need to shave.
You look terrible.
Why is there no
fire escape in here?
What if somebody
needed to escape?
I can't face these reporters.
I have nothing to say.
You'll be fine.
You’re a world class
liar, darling.
Go out there and
lie for Italy.
Lie for Italia.
What the hell is
wrong with me?
I can't sleep, I can't think,
I can't write.
I can't breathe.
My heart is racing.
Am I dying, Mamma?
I owe you flowers, I know.
I will come to the cemetery
at the weekend.
You should have let me
bury you in Roma, Mamma.
Could have visited you
every week.
Don't look at me like that.
Oh, Guido, Guido.
This is your Rome, Guido.
The world sees Rome the
way you invented it.
Your films did that.
- I miss you.
- I miss you too.
We are just waiting for the
arrival of Contini any moment now
Could this film put the
Maestro back on top?
And here he is!
Thank you for coming.
Silenzio, per favore.
Thank you, thank you.
Guido Contini's long time
producer, is about to speak
I just want to say a few
words from my heart.
I am humbled and thrilled to
announce that I'm producing
Guido Contini's next film:
"Italia"
which will star once again
Contini's longtime inspiration
the international film star,
Claudia Jenssen.
We start shooting in ten
days time in Cinecitta
That makes it one week
from Monday.
Thank you, Maestro,
thank you very much.
This is our ninth film
together. Guido Contini.
Thanks for coming, everybody.
- Maestro Contini.
- Yes?
Grazie. Your new film is
called Italia. Big title.
Actually it's my shortest
title yet.
- But hardly a modest one.
- Films are not modest.
They cost too much,
they take too long,
and they involve
too many people.
They should have
grand titles.
And might you tell the press
what the film is about?
Why?
I still don't know what my
last film was about.
That was the problem.
Nobody else did.
Of course I can tell you
what my film is about
I can tell you the story,
I can tell you....
who I am going to cast,
the music I want to use,
I can tell you everything.
But I won't.
I'm afraid that what I say
might leak to the press.
Our next film will be
exactly as it sounds.
Italia.
It's the very spirit of Italy.
Italy as a myth, as a woman,
Italy as a dream.
- Is this true?
- Sounds fantastic. Can't wait to see it.
Do you consider
pornography art?
- Signor Contini.
- Stephanie.
Could you tell the fashionable
women of America
who your favorite
designer is?
I'm less interested in wrapping
than what might be inside.
Signor Contini, you are a
man of the world, yes?
Educated in Britain,
a home in Biarritz.
With Italia is it fair to say that
you’ve come home for good?
It's been a long time since you
made a movie with your wife
Do you plan on casting her
in this new film?
I told Luisa that when we got
married I would never again
make love to
my leading lady.
But she hasn't worked at all
since working with you.
But why are you being so
tight-lipped about this film?
It’s a serious question.
What’s the big deal?
I would like to be here.
You want me to be serious
in a press conference?
I would like to be there.
I thought I was the
clown in this circus.
I would like to be
everywhere at once
I know that’s a
contradiction in terms
Artists do their best work
before they're famous.
Now you're famous.
Without wishing to be negative,
your last two films, they were...
Flops?
Your word, flops.
And it's a problem
especially when
My body's nearing fifty,
as my mind is nearing...
ten.
I'm just asking if you're nervous.
You seem nervous.
- Excuse me?
- What I'm asking, Maestro,
is have you run out
of things to say?
I can hardly stay up,
and I can't get to sleep.
And I don’t want to wake
tomorrow morning
at the bottom of some heap.
But why take it
so seriously?
After all, there's nothing
at stake here, only me.
I want to be young.
I want to be old.
I would like to be wise
before my time and yet
be foolish and brash
and bold.
I would like the universe to
get down on its knees and say:
"Guido, whatever you please.
It's okay even if it's impossible,
we'll arrange it."
That's all that I want.
I was wondering if you think
there's a limit to what
you can show in a movie.
What would you
like to see,
that I haven't already
shown you?
I am lusting for more
Should I settle for less?
I ask you: What's a
good thing for if not for
taking it to excess?
One limitation
I dearly regret.
There's one of me
I've ever met.
If you have any
questions about...
I would like to have another
me to travel along with myself
I would even like to be able
to sing a duet with myself
I would like to be here sing
along with myself in a song
To be there walking
down a lane now
Everywhere, everywhere,
everywhere
That's a contradiction
in terms.
I want to be here,
with a counter here
melody in the here, top
of the morning to you Guido.
Guido!
Guido. Me, me, me.
I want to be Proust
or the marquis de Sade.
I would like to be Christ,
Mohammed, Buddha
But not have to believe
in God, and you know
I mean it with
all of my heart.
It's the end if something
important doesn't start
I want to be young,
but I have to be old
What I want is a tale
of sound and fury,
that some idiot
went and told.
I would like the universe to
get down on its knees and say:
"Guido, whatever you please.
It's okay even if it’s ridiculous,
we'll arrange it."
So arrange it.
Arrange it.
That's all that I want.
Guido, Guido, Guido!
Contini, Contini, Contini
Guido!
Bellavista Spa Hotel
Anzio, Italy
- I need a room.
- Of course.
- A suite.
- Yes.
With a view of the sea,
balcony. Something with air.
All of our suites have air.
- Let me just look for you.
- I come from Milano.
- I understand.
- On business. I'm a business man.
Busy busy busy.
Would Maestro Contini prefer
to register under a pseudonym?
Please.
- Signor Milano?
- Why not.
Needless to say,
I love your films.
Guilty pleasure.
Those early films.
Not the flops.
I need to see a doctor. Do you
know one who's discreet?
I'd like to see him today in
my room, now, if possible.
Consider it done.
Please.
And I need to place
a call. To my wife.
Here.
You can take the call at
the lobby phone over there.
- Luisa? tesoro...
- There you are.
Is everybody mad at me?
Well I'm mad at you.
Where are you?
I had to escape from
the press conference.
Oh, I heard. Dramatic.
Don't tease me.
I'm sick, Luisa.
You're making a film.
You make a film, you get sick.
It's what happens.
No but this time
I'm really sick.
Are you by yourself?
Yes, of course
I'm by myself.
Then shall I come?
- Yes, that’s why I'm calling.
Please come, straight away.
That would be wonderful.
Okay.
Great. Marvelous.
I don't know
where you are.
I don't know. Some spa.
I just kept driving.
I can't come if I don’t
know where you are.
Actually, it’s hardly worth it.
I'll be back in a day or two.
Yeah...
Yes, it's hardly worth it.
I do wish you were here.
Get some rest.
Take the waters.
Sleep. Then come back here
and make a good movie.
I love you.
Get better.
Your doctor is
on his way.
This number. If a woman
answers, put it through
to my room.
- Otherwise...
- Wrong number.
What?
- Dottore.
- Si?
What is she whispering?
Is it about my blood pressure?
- Is it serious? Am I dying?
- Stress, exhaustion,
your liver, your heart,
your kidneys,
They are all very cross
with you, Signore.
- Open wide.
- Ahhhh.
But you've come
to the right place.
There are a dozen mineral
springs around the town.
The Roman emperors
came here for the waters.
Pronto.
I was lazing about my
bedroom when you called
and an idea occurred to me
I thought you might be...
wondering about.
Guido.
It's a very important call,
doctor. I have to take it.
- Private call.
- As you wish.
Who's not wearing
any clothes?
I’m not, my darling.
Whose afraid to
kiss your toes?
I'm not.
Your mama dear
is blowing into your ear
so you'll get it
loud and clear
I need you to
squeeze me
here
and here
Dottore, his pulse,
it's racing.
- Is something wrong?
- What?
Yes, yes, it's about my film.
It's from the Vatican.
Go ahead, Monsignore.
Of course I'm listening.
cootchie cootchie
cootchie coo
I've got a plan for
what I'm gonna
do to you
So hot
you're gonna steam
and scream,
and vibrate like a
string I'm plucking.
Kiss your fevered
little brow
pinch your cheeks
'til you say "Ow"
And I can hardly wait
to show you how,
Guido!
Who won't care if you
come to me tired
and overworked?
I won’t! Bambino.
Who knows the therapy
to beat what you can
get from me?
I don't!
But this will
have to be enough
for now
Guido!
Ciao.
I love you, Guido.
Guido!
Ciao!
- Carla
- I'm so happy to see you!
I missed you so much.
- Are you happy I'm here?
- Of course.
But very happy or
just a little happy?
Very happy!
What's wrong?
You look very tired!
Carla, all those bags
for one weekend?
Yes. Belavista is a very
fashionable place.
You know I stayed there
with my parents. During the war.
Carla, there's something
I have to tell you. Look.
They found out who
I am at the hotel.
- No.
- Yes, it's horrible.
Obviously we don't want to
be followed by the press,
I found the most charming
pensione for you,
right here, it's charming.
Here at the station?
Close the curtains,
it's too light in here.
- Perfect. Go to the corridor.
- What?
Yes. Count to ten,
turn back in,
pretend you're in
the wrong room
and I'm a
complete stranger.
I love your games.
- I'm here on business.
- Okay.
- Wait, wait, your face.
- What about it?
Get your makeup.
I had a nightmare
last night.
We went into that little
ally behind Piazza Navona
Where I bought you
that scarf, remember?
- The same your wife bought
- Don't move, Carla.
When you wear it I never
know if it's hers or mine.
So we were there on the
ground, naked, kissing.
We didn't care.
And then my husband
arrived and killed us both.
With a shovel.
Poor Luigi. He would
never do that.
He's so sweet.
He speaks Latin. He knows
all the roman emperors.
Good for him.
Perhaps there is a job
for him in the movie.
Why not?
You could work
well together.
Beautiful.
When you come in I want
you to be my little savage.
- Yes.
- Go, go.
You think I'm one of
your actresses?
Oh! Madonna!
I'll pretend to
be asleep.
What if I really found
the wrong room?
Would you be jealous?
Would you do
such a thing?
Who knows?
What happened?
It was the woman
from the hotel.
She wanted to
give me towels.
- Come here.
- Okay.
- What?
- You are a stranger.
- I don't know you.
- Just come here.
Be savage.
Show me.
Excuse me.
I've got the wrong room.
Yes you have.
And I don't have the
faintest idea who you are.
Page one.
Page one, page one,
page one.
The figure emerges from
the darkness, like a goddess.
She's Claudia, his muse.
She takes the man’s face
and kisses him.
And with that gesture he's
suddenly inspired to write
something... profound.
Mother of God,
give me a sign.
- Excuse me, father.
- Buongiorno.
- His Excellency, the Cardinal...
- Signor Contini!
I'm a big fan!
I would very much like
to speak to the cardinal
Is Claudia Jensen
with you?
- No.
- Pity.
His Excellency is a big admirer
of Signorina Jenssen.
I’m in need of some guidance,
some pointers...
Do you think you can
find a signed photograph
of Signorina Jenssen?
- For His Excellency?
- Si.
- I'm sure it would be possible.
- Truly? What a pleasure.
Arrivederci, Maestro.
Guido! Guidino!
I'm not going to ask
how you find me.
Please, it's my job. A producer
needs to know where his
director is at all times.
Even to know the pensione
where his mistress is staying.
- Oh my God.
- I understand, Guido.
Rome is absolutely unbearable.
The pressure.
- It's not good.
- Really, you understand?
Of course I understand.
Absolutely.
You're not going to
drag me back?
You're a genius and
genius must be served.
Thank you my old friend.
Where are we going?
You can't be in Rome?
Okay.
Rome will come to you.
It's a fantastic place
for you to focus.
Everyone is here
to help the movie.
Everyone is here because
they love you, Guido.
Look, with the flower
and the grass
and with the arches of
the empire. Roman empire.
You remember Donatella?
- Ciao.
- Donatella, you tested her.
- I was very nervous
He probably doesn't remember.
I was quite nervous.
No, I remember you. We all
enjoyed you, so to speak.
Maestro!
Claudia's agent.
Did she like the script?
No, no no no.
Impossibile.
Are you telling me she
didn't get the script?
Pierpaulo!
Claudia didn't get the script!
Send her another one, for
Christ sake. Send her two!
- Yes, I'm sorry.
- Cretino!
Right now.
Yes, that's what I say.
People just don't realize she's
an actress as well as a star.
I know Dante's dying to
talk to you. A dolpo. Ciao!
Lombardo.
What are we doing here?
I'm happy. I brought
my swimsuit.
It was Luisa's
birthday yesterday.
What? No!
Oh please God, no.
I spoke with her yesterday,
she didn't even mention it.
- Give me a cigarette.
- What's that?
- It's for Claudia.
For which scene?
I don't know which scene,
until I've seen the script.
But she always likes
something like this,
- Or you do.
- Looks like Folies Bergere,
It's wrong. Italian women
don't wear those things.
Don't knock the
Folies Bergere.
It brings back happy
memories, that's where I...
learned my art. All those
sequins, all those feathers.
And you're wrong.
You put Claudia in
one of these for that
nightclub scene in
"Natura Morta".
Why do people
love that film?
Oh, Guido.
Don't, that's death.
Every time we have to
start again.
I'm trying to find it.
You won’t find it with
your head jammed
halfway up your arse.
Ashtray.
You were saying my head
is jammed up my arse.
Halfway.
I don't know. Why not dream
up something entertaining?
Something with music.
With dancing.
God knows we could use
a little "joie de vivre".
Le Cinema today
is in a crisis.
The directors are so
existentialistes.
The movies are not worth
their entrance prices
If no one sings a love song
when he's kissed.
Love cannot be love
without "Le Singing",
A string, a clarinet
a saxophone.
Take a lesson from
this old Parisienne and
the finest entertainment
she has known.
Folies Bergere
What a showing of color,
costume and dancing.
Not a moment in life
could be more entrancing.
Than an evening you
spend aux Folies Bergere.
Folies Bergere.
Not a soul in the world
could be in despair
when he is glancing
at the fabulous stage
des Folies Bergere
FOLIES BERGERE
LA MUSIQUE, LA DANSE, LE
SON, LA LUMIERE!
LES PETITS JOLIES SEINS DES
BELLES BOUQUETIERES
SUR LA BELLE PASSARELLE DES
FOLIES BEREGERE,
PAS DE MYSTERE
LE SPECTACLE EST TOUT A
FAIT DECOUVERT.
"ET PAS TROP CHER"
VIENS CE SOIR AVEC MOI
AUX FOLIES BERGERE.
Bon soir, bon soir,
bon soir.
Je suis la vedette
des Folies Bergere.
Vedette, it means "star".
Let me tell you:
Last night I looked
down at this table
in the chairs you are
sitting in now
and what do I see?
A priest!
And next to him?
Mon Dieu. Guido?
Guido Contini?
What are you doing here
at the Folies Bergere?
You naughty boy!
You're only nine years old!
But I'm glad
you've come.
Would you like to
join me on stage?
Yes, come!
Come, come, come!
Feeling better?
There's no room for
hopelessness here,
is there, Guido?
We must explain something
to our young Guido.
What do we want?
Laughter!
Love!
What do we want?
Dreams!
Let us not forget,
Guido, mon cher,
that is our privilege:
To entertain!
Folies Bergere
The music, the lights
and the laughter.
The answer to what
you are after.
Each night at the
Folies Bergere.
Folies Bergere
By the heavens above
you will swear
there's nothing rarer.
Than the Folies Bergere.
Folies Bergere
The stage overflowing
and giving
a musical reason
for living
each night at the
Folies Bergere.
Folies Bergere
To your modern
ideas I compare
one derriere
at the Folies Bergere
The answer to what
you are after
The music, the lights
and the laughter
of the Follies Berger!
The Cardinal is
right this way.
Your Eminence,
Signor Contini is here.
I like Charlie Chaplin.
Me too.
A genius.
What can I do for you?
- Do you believe in God?
- Signor Contini, please.
No, no, it's an
honest question.
- Yes, I believe in God.
- So do I.
Are you a catholic?
Yes, very much so. Not as
much as I would like to be.
Not as much as you would
like me to be, I’m sure,
but certainly yes,
I'm trying.
- Try harder.
- Yes, I will.
Your Eminence...
I'm not happy,
I'm searching for something.
I feel a sense of misery,
of despair...
I saw your films. Not the flops,
the others, the good ones.
But you think people need
to see so much sex?
It's not necessary.
We can all imagine.
Excuse me. My films
are what I imagine.
Then your imagination
has no moral training.
How do you train
the imagination?
Imagination is
God's garden.
Don’t let the Devil
play in it.
Teach our Italian women
to be wives, not whores.
Don't make us look at
filth and debauchery.
Make us proud
to be Italian.
Pesaro
Italy 1926
Guido!
The money,
the money.
- Let's go.
- Guido, go!
Saraghina.
Saraghina!
So you little
Italian devils...
You want to know
about love?
Saraghina will tell you.
If you want to make
a woman happy
You rely on what
you were born with.
Because it is in
your blood.
Be Italian.
Take a chance and try
to steal a fiery kiss.
Be Italian.
When you hold me,
don't just hold me
but hold this!
Please be gentle,
sentimental,
go ahead and try to
give my cheek a pat.
But be daring
and uncaring.
When you pinch me
try to pinch me
where there's fat!
Be a singer,
be a lover.
Pick the flower now
before the chance is past.
Be Italian
Be Italian.
Live today as if it may
become your last!
Be a singer,
Be a lover.
Pick the flower now
before the chance is past.
Be Italian.
Live today as
if it may
become
your last.
Guido!
I'm ashamed
of you, Guido.
Mamma,
what did I do?
Bring him here.
That savage
is the devil.
God will punish you for
your sins now and forever.
What?
- What?
- I can't breathe.
Guido, don't die on me.
Can you imagine.
Poor Luigi!
It would kill him.
If I die it would
kill your husband?
No, that's not what
I meant, Guidino. No.
- Where are you going?
- I have to go to work.
Carla, I can't breathe!
- Let me come with you.
- It's impossible.
- Why?
- Because it's impossible!
- Please!
- Why is it impossible?
Look at your producer.
He's married, he brings
his girlfriend to work
and nobody cares.
Guido, everybody
knows about me.
Why, why won't you
let me near you?
For the very same reason
you don’t want me to
die on top of you. It's
not fair to your husband.
- It's not fair to my wife!
- You're playing with me.
You're twisting
everything.
Please let me
come with you.
I'll be here, waiting for
you, with my legs open.
DIMMI QUANDO
TU VERRAI
QUANDO QUANDO
Let's say there were
ten sequences,
each one set in a
different period,
but played by the
same cast.
Something light
and hectic,
like Mozart would
do it, like Figaro.
- Like the circus.
- Claudia will be amazing.
- Sounds like a masterpiece.
- He hasn't written a word.
A screenplay is first of
all a map. That's a map.
Let's try to dig for
something else.
Maybe a group of people
digging, in the desert.
Luisa?
Is that his wife?
I can't believe
you came.
The jungle drums said
it was an emergency.
The jungle drums
exaggerated just a tiny bit.
Not entirely.
You haven't
been sleeping.
I was dying,
until just now.
Come.
Don't think I forgot
your birthday.
When you get home, the
house will be full of flowers.
- Am I already going home?
- I hope not.
Happy Birthday,
my darling.
- Here she is. At last.
- Buona Sera.
Magnificent.
- You know Donatella?
- I do now.
- Thank you for calling.
- You're saving the movie.
Give him a good idea
for God's sake.
Let's drink a toast
to Luisa's birthday.
- Happy Birthday!
- It was Monday.
- Thank you.
Happy Birthday.
- Maestro.
- Ah, Don Mario.
Excuse me, darling,
this is Don Mario.
This is my wife, Luisa.
- A pleasure, Signora.
- Sit down, won't you?
- Please. Please.
- Thanks. Buona Sera.
I was telling your husband
how much I admire his movies.
Publicly, the church condemns
them. We have to.
But we all love them.
Last year we did our own
version of your "Il Vicolo"
at the Christmas Party.
- That I'd pay to see.
- Luisa was in that film.
She was the best
thing in the movie.
It's true. It was
your first part.
Of course. You are
Luisa Acari. Oh my Lord!
I was.
You can't stop
being somebody.
Can't you?
Well there's a good catholic
wife for you, Guido.
That's what they do:
Sacrifice.
Still, Signora Contini...
it must be a very
exciting life for you.
My husband makes movies
To make them he lives
a kind of dream.
In which his actions aren't
always what they seem.
He may be on to some
unique romantic theme.
Some men run banks.
Some rule the world.
Some earn their living
baking bread.
My husband he goes
a little crazy
making movies instead.
My husband spins fantasies.
He lives them then
gives them to you all.
Like Michelangelo he
paints his private dome.
But can't distinguish what's
his work and what's his home.
Some men sell stocks.
Some men punch clocks.
Some leap where others
fear to tread.
My husband as author
and director
makes up stories
in his head.
Guido Contini,
Luisa Contini,
Number one genius
and number one fan.
Guido Contini,
Luisa Contini,
Passionate woman
in love with this man.
Long ago.
Many years ago.
Once we two were
Guido Contini,
Luisa his lover,
actress with dreams
and a life of her own.
Then we had no end
of world to discover,
Singing together all
night on the phone.
Long ago.
Someone else ago.
Signorina Acari,
per favore.
Provino numero uno.
Luisa Acari.
Your name is Italian.
My father is Italian.
My mother is French.
What have you
done before?
I've waited.
Waited for this?
Waited tables.
And, of course, I studied
theater and mime in Paris.
But mostly
waited tables.