There is a little thread-like difference
between foolish and bastard person
On one side is foolish, other is of bastard
And if someone pulls the thread then
who is foolish and who is bastard is the
question of 10 million
Let's see the groom
You are a silly guy
But a man becomes foolish after marriage
And you marriage is impossible
No... it must
l said it is not possible
Your bride will be snatched by Omkara
Omi brother
You are my best friend, therefore
l am advising you
Now you've to fly like an arrow
And save the Dolly
Go
Hey your ...
Stop. you buddy liar
The dog wouldn’t be shoot if l am lying,
but your father if l shoot perfectly
You can’t proceed further for your bride
Hey... Run...  Run
Run to this side... Hurry up
You people can’t go further
Haven’t you listened?
Hey... snatch these people's cell phones
Give your cell phone and run away...
Go away... hurry
I am worry about those people;
they still not reached. Please inquire
Quickly
Hey brother where are those people?
l am trying to call on their cell phones, but in vain
please protect me from him
l don't want to marry
Hey... Hey... stop stop
Not red, but blue is final
Brother what happened?
Hey Langra brother...
l asked what happened?
Come with me
Hey Langra what happened?
Did Cheeri Patti's money order come?
Money order of your Mom!
My wife's brother
Am l stupid?
Sometime Red, sometime Blue, Yellow, etc.
Decide once that which ball l've to hit.
Ultimately you've to lose, l swear
Okay... Come on my friend
Now it is final that
you’ve to hit yellow ball
Come on
Agramb, Bagramb, Lambramb, Choo...
Yeah! Look there my brother-in-law
the yellow ball has been bit
l will certainly be the winner if a
tournament of ball-hitting is held
Is there any body who could play with me?
Where is Omi?
Where is he?
l don't know man
Hey you bastard English man
Even dog peas by leaving 10 houses
by his own Mr. Omi
Had you to chose just my daughter
in whole country?
Right
But that is my mistake
l forgot that you are the just half Brahman
Half of the blood in you is of that prostitute,
too you damn bastard
Sir, Mr. Lawyer... you've commendably
recognized my class
But you haven’t listened the voice of heart
of your daughter
Cruel father
Hey... You
Dear Brother on the line
Hi brother... me fine... Yes... yes
Omi and Lawyer, both are here
Yes... Mr. Lawyer
Lawyer brother is ready to shoot
Omi brother
Just waiting for trigger push
lf pushed the Omi is dead
Yes... just wait a second
What has been going on there?
Mr. Lawyer and Omi
Hello Lawyer brother
My dear the silence is useless...
You would've to speak
Dear brother he bastard kidnapped
my daughter from her wedding ceremony
Yes, l know
Now l am going to tell you a
latest news
Your that eyewitness, Mr. Jallal-ud-din,
has returned back from Muscat
The case hearing is on coming week
So don't kill each other
Let remain both of you alive
Meet him there in court
Okay brothers good bye
News has been confirmed brother
Indur Singh went to Muscat
And this Surinder captain
He is behind all of this
He has hidden him behind
that Pilkay's brickyard
And why this Indur Singh is purchasing
this wet wood
The posession of any metal good, cell phone,
SlM card, etc. is prohibited to keep
Any equipment, lighter, matchbox, or mobile
SIM cards are not allowed to take in
The visitors are informed that in prison...
Hey... l am taking in all such things.
What will you do?
You are lying
Hey you damn
Stamp my hand
l am seeing Omkara since my childhood
l have never heard his relationship
with any girl
Have you ever seen Dolly closely brother?
Do you think if she could run with
that bastard horrible criminal
as per her wish
No stove has been fired in my
house since yesterday
Furthermore, humiliation in family
And how l can offer my flower like
Daughter to that wicked person
There is a difference of caste, too
l need justice
Otherwise, you will see my dead face
Okay, tell to Captain
Omi brother, let's go
Dear brother, in my view the kidnappers are
I will present my cut tongue to you
if his daughter would tell me liar
You stay here I park the bike
Don't be afraid my daughter
And tell everything openly
That if anyone...
any person
has forced you or tried to kidnap you
Don't be afraid my daughter l am here
Just speak only truth
l am just bound of my will
Dad... Please forgive me
l can’t live without Omkara
* Don’t pay any attention to eyes
* Don’t listen to them
* Eyes will cheat you...
* They’ll mesmerize you
* while you’re awake
* while awake and destroy your sleep
* Eyes will cheat you...
l was plunged in love with Omkara
But until l could fully realize it...
It was too late
* Don’t pay any attention to eyes...
* Eyes don’t differentiate
* between good and bad,
* loved ones and strangers
* They just love to sting
l was burning day & night in Omkara's love
Like a drowning sparrow in dark well!
l had no way to come up with
* Their poison is intoxicating
Finally, l decided to suicide
But then l thought l should inform that person
at least in whose love l am dieing
* Eyes show you rainbows in clouds
* which rain till morning
* They’ll show you rainbows
* and drive you mad
Rajju will come to marry me,
but just with my dead body
You've no courage to tell me
But l've the courage to say you that
* Eyes will cheat you...
l only love you and will remain yours forever
include my name in your murder list, too
Okay now forget it what has happened
Stand up daughter
You both request for pardon from
your lawyer father
Now, You will've to wait it for marriage
until l am released
it doesn’t make any difference
for us to be in prison
But if witness records
his statement in court then
Our name will be excluded
in coming election member list
And if they don't understand in a gentle way
Then go ahead with your own method
Mr. Omkara, be careful of a woman's trick
Which girl can cheat her father
what one can expect better from her
OMKARA
Fill it as you want
Hey catch this damn up... it is flying
Hey Gijlo... You know that to earn from illegal
sources has been written in our fate
Just from illegal sources...
Am l right, OM brother?
What do want Mr. Captain? Just tell
A seat in National Assembly
Our lndur brother is trying vigorously
For that for last 5 years
Even if he keeps trying for his 5 lives,
he can’t defeat our Tewari brother
You're exactly right
But that is when if he stands in election
His pant, shirt cost will be higher than
the money given to beat him
Understand
Hey... Omi wouldn’t you eat food?
Your sister-in-law has made Saag for you
Oh... Shit
Damn it
How much phone you will break captain?
Our workers are on the gate
of every channel station
At least see it completely
Take and see it
Sorry Captain
Please take special care of Indur brother
See... Who was that girl?
Indur brother
In which meeting you were going yesterday?
Yes... we were raising funds in Ghaghre
Till today l had just seen in T.V. in
National Assembly members gathering
Hey... Great OMi brother great
You are a great man
The lights in this country
are open just because of you
But before you leave,
reveal a quiz
Khichlo and me have betted for one thing
Amounting a 100 Rs.
He says that you're in love
with Raghunath's daughter
Pour water
And it is of sure
that you must will marry her
But l said that our Omi is not a fool
He will enjoy with that girl for some
time and then will leave her
Hey... Kichlo give me 100 Rs.
I’ve won the bet!
Omi bhaya?
Mom... l help you
* Drums beat out...
* the biggest fighter in the land!
* Omkara, hey Omkara
Tell everybody in the village
That Captain has lost the bet
* Eyes like shapening steel,
* tongue like a snake’s hiss
Ask for your 100 Rs. from captain
* His swords sound like lightning striking
Captain
* Omkara, hey Omkara
* His forehead sports three lines
* like the mark of a trident
* His earrings clang
* like the sound of spears striking
* His forehead sports three lines
* like the mark of a trident
* His earrings clang
* like the sound of spears striking
* In every street...
* In every street is heard the cry…
* big brother is here!
* Hey Omkara!
Bet is always made on horses damn
Not on Lions
* Drums beat out...
* the biggest fighter in the land!
* Omkara, hey Omkara
* Drums beat out...
* the biggest fighter in the land!
* Hey Omkara, Omkara
* Eyes like shapening steel,
* tongue like a snake’s hiss
* His swords sound like lightning striking
* Hey Omkara, Omkara
The Storm of truth
has broken the prison wall
Yes, you've heard exactly right
As per instructions from high command,
l am going to enroll in coming
National Assembly election
And young social worker OMkara Shukla is
enrolling for local elections
Then Sir, public is interested in knowing
who will replace OMkara
Who will be the new caretaker of party?
Yes... Hello... Hello
Hello... l can’t hear properly
Dear brother
Yes... please repeat your question?
Oh... l think the line has dropped
Hey Langda brother
Langda brother... Langda brother...
Langda brother
Where are you feet?
l've sent them for shoes fabrication... bastard!
Hey... Kiss me your feet... please
Get away... you bastard
Brother new party's administrator is very strict
What?
Langda Tyagi, "new party administrator"
Langda Tyagi... Langda Tyagi
"new administrator" Langda Tyagi
Whole Janpat's college are in the fist of Kesu
lf Kesu is administrator
then the election will be one sided
And Langda?
He is our brother,
will realize it later
OMkara!
Kohlo Let's go
Hey... People get away from my way
Oh... My God
What pair God has made like...
Milk in dark black bowl
No... No...
Brother l did mistake
Like white sweet in Crow's mouth
No... No...
Brother forgive me
Forgive me brother
Okay Omi brother leave me now
l going to tell truly
Like a flute between the lips of Kahnaya
What are you looking aunt?
Looking whether if
she has been white coated
How can such white girls
be born in our country?
Ram Ram Uncle...
How are you?
l said good morning
Omi brother Rajju has come
Would you like to see him?
Send him in disarmed
Okay brother...
Don't worry
You can go
Sister...
Did'nt come Pandit?
You, my newly married sister,
will be a little patient
Hey... What a fragrance is this?
You seem to be a proficient cook
Hey...
Who taught you to make this sweet dish?
My Grand mom
She used to say that man's heart
can be explored through his stomach
But my grand mom used to say that path is
"just below the belly"
These have been sent by father for election
But the elections are too far away now
Yes, of course
Omi brother...
We did'nt make any mistake in that job
lf we could've known that you are
coming then before you come we had
stopped wedding
l am leaving
Hey... How will you go in such late evening
Just stay here, will go tomorrow after
celebrating Kohlo's birthday
Kohlo's birthday
How much old is now our Kohlo
Hey... Kohol...
Are you 8 or of 9 years?
l made a special sweet dish
Taste and tell how is it
ls it enough sweeter?
Once again rotate your finger in that dish
That will be much sweeter
Hey... My Devdas
Do mix some water in wine too,
Take it
See Friend l gave you a chance
But you don’t have brain
in you occipital region
No l have brain
That day my car was punctured, therefore,
l reached late
l can even give up my life for Dolly
Do you understand?
Don't drink more
you are already out of your senses
Can give his life... damn
Yes, l can give up my life
Give me back bottle first
l am not kidding...
l will jump into stream
Hey... You liar
No l will... truly
Then am l holding you, Bastard?
Go and jump
My dear Dolly
Hey...
Just jump instead of crying for Dolly
Oh my Dolly
Jump, you damn bastard
Hey... Can’t you swim?
You saw Langda brother that
l have brain in my occipital
But the matter is not of brain
The matter is of business
lf l do something irregular,
my father's business will be in danger
And you Langda brother
What you did of Omi?
When Omi made Kesu the administrator
of party before whole village
Don't l know that you were trying to be
on that seat for last 15 years with your one leg
Langda Tyagi...
"new administrator"
That damn, a teenager English man came
And taken all fruits before all people,
which you deserved for
Where was your brain at that time?
Company garden
You are saying exactly right Rajju
Actually, both of us have horrible luck
You damn bastard
Happy birthday to you
The water of stream was very cold...
You bastard
l am not feeling well
But because of it
you learned how to swim?
So from today
l will teach you how to fly?
Like a pigeon
Like this
And who will be with you...
Yours Dolly
You both would fly far
till the stars in sky
Yes, l understand
lf l would lie l will be like dog,
otherwise your father
Have you found time for me, damn?
Always talk to Administrator
with keeping eyes lower
Understand
OKay... My honey
Oh darling l will remove your tongue
l will not even allow you to taste my tongue
Oh my Chaman Bahar
Why?
Because you know,
you are very beautiful
And do you know
why l love you?
Because you say the same words
to every third girl
Hey you didn’t tell
What?
Will you marry me?
Hey... Leave me mad man?
There had been years when no child is
born after marriage in this house
And then my father fell in love
And l was born in that result of love
My Mom belonged to another caste
Therefore, l am called half of that class
Whether moon is half
Even so that is called moon
What happened?
l twisted my back incidentally this morning
Shukla is out of senses!
Where is this new Administrator?
l can’t see him
He is ringing music...
You start dancing
Hey you administrator
Come here, too
Please, take care
of poor people's problems, too
Take seat... Sir... Please
How are you talking...
Friend
What would like to drink?
No thanks l've already ordered for tea
Tea?
Will you not drink?
No friend No
This is the only thing,
which take me out of my senses
Okay, l understand
Hey... Mental
Go stat to City and take a Milk Bottle
For this Administrator
Along with its nipple
Dolly... Take it and wear around your back
Whose ornament is this?
This is not ornament,
but my family's tradition from centuries
Which always has been worn by
the ladies of our home
Today, l give it to you as deposit
Keep it in strict custody
First wear it
No first you close your eyes then
l will wear it
Hey... Billo
Yes?
We want to listen that "Beedi" song
l have forgotten that song
for which you are asking
No problem...
We start singing and you will recollect
* No sheet...
* Or even a blanket...
* No sheet or even a blanket
* When the cold wind blows against us
* It's so cold,
* borrow someone's blanket
* Go steal the fire
* from the neighbor's kitchen
* Light your cigarette
* with my heart, my love
* A great fire burns in it
* Light your cigarette
* with my heart, my love
* A great fire burns in it
* Don't blow smoke
* from those lips, my love
* This world is a cheat [smoky]
* Light the coal
* with my heart, my love
* In it burns a fire
* No sheet or even a blanket
* When the cold wind blows against us
* It's so cold,
* borrow someone's blanket
* Go steal the fire
* from the neighbor's kitchen
* Without fault...
* without tendency to crime...
* Without fault,
* without tendency to crime
* Without any crime,
* killed, killed
* Call me like this some afternoon
* Tie my anklets,
* bind me to the docket
* Call me, call me,
* in the afteroon
* Bind me, bind me,
* to the docket
* Light the coal burner
* with my heart, my love
* A great fire burns in it
* Not the slice of a knife
* or other cutting instruments
* Cut so deep that
* they left marks like a bite
* This knife even a farmer
* wouldn't use
* Such a tyrant,
* leave such a tyrant's home Billo
* leave such a tyrant's home
* Such a tyrant,
* such a tyrant
* Leave his home
* Not called...
* or told...
* Not called, or told
* He woke me from my bonded sleep
* With a sudden jolt
* inside my blanket
* He fed me an elaichi
* and came close to me
* Light the coal
* with my heart, my love
* In it burns a fire
* It's so cold,
* borrow someone's blanket
* Go steal the fire...
* from the neighbor's kitchen
Hey you bastard
Hey Langda brother...
Come and guard me
Hey... Have you drunken a lot?...
Leave it
Get lost you bastard
Hey wait...
l will ruin you
Omi brother...
Hey Omi brother
Hey... Don't you have tongue in your mouth?
Who did start the fight?
Langda
Now cool down Omi brother...
We will talk tomorrow morning
Don't talk fool
Answer me what l am asking?
Who is responsible of that?
Of wine
The guilty is only wine
And then of mine
This innocent guy told me that he can’t
keep his senses intact after drinking
l forced him and he drank
First you punish me Omi brother,
then to him
Hey Administrator...
The only fault is of mine,
but not yours or Langdla
That l chosen you for administrator
l don't want to see you again
for some days
Otherwise, l will cut your skin shreds
and dry them in sunshine
Hey... Omi's anger is just like,
as Pooja's Kapoor
Will disappear like this
Am l fool that l am baking breads for him
And this Administrator is still in that fight
Friend... What is wrong with food?
Eat it hurry up
Hey... Start eating
Hey... Look start eating otherwise l will be angry
The smile seems to be every expensive in this worl
Don't worry l will talk to Omi
Don't worry l will talk to Omi...
And he will listen to you, indeed
Omi will not listen to any one, now
Not me, not you, not him,
and not of anyone other
Omi's ears will be listening of one's voice only
Just Dolly's voice
And Dolly is your old friend
Right?
We all are going to City for some days to see
Big Boss for the planning of coming elections
Meanwhile, you talk to Dolly
Okay
Not just okay...
lt is best idea
Hey take it...
Open your mouth
ln your complete life you hav'nt give
me food in a such way
Okay... Really
Okay... Okay... Why are you worrying?
We're in the way, will handle as we reach
This Aunt is trying to hide something
even from us
According to ClD report
Our lives are in danger
lt will take me 2-3 days to satisfy her
What 2-3 days
Meanwhile,
We could start working on Bhandai Jee project
Yes.
He is absolutely right
Then
Pull the chain, my Son
What happened brother
Turn back and reverse the train to leave
them back from where they got into train
What?
Yes.
Kohlo, whenever you need the sugarcane
what do you do?
l request to Omi brother
And lndu Sister whenever you required
new ornament, What do you do?
Oh... l have had to press
the Omi's legs for a long time
So...
Your work will also be done
But you must will have to do
something for us against that
Mr. Kesu
No problem...
l will whatever you would say
Promise?
Promise
Now you sing
Everything is okay except
"bottom"
"Bottom"
l spoke correctly
Okay... No problem...
You keep saying this
What?
Omi brother
But Langda brother said that
they will come in 2-3 days
Oh... He will ruin me
Hey... Where are you going?
l talk to him before you
No... No...
He will put out my skin and will dry in sunshine
l am going
This was Kesu... Right
Kesu
You now leave that child
You and me,
both are out of village
and Dolly is alone at home
But that seemed to be his Motorbike
Oh... He is our Kesu, not a thief who will
run after seeing the owner of house
Just wait a minute...
l call on his cellphone
Hey... Hello... Hey Mental
Son... Give phone to Kesu for a momemnt
Okay
Okay... Then do me an SMS
What happened?
l don't know why it is not starting
Not Car, l am asking about Kesu
Kesu
Oh... lt has started now
Langda
Why are you hiding something?
Because l am still not believing
that he was Kesu
And l can't understand that what he was
doing with lonely Dolly in your house
Dolly
Why did Kesu come here?
And why he ran away as he saw me?
What happened?
Tell me what happened?
Tell me
Whenever l see you from deep of my heart,
soon one thing comes into my mind
What?
That whether you are very innocent,
otherwise a whore
* Oh, my lover
* hope the day never sets
* My veil will hold back the day
* and run after the sunlight
* Let the shade not touch us
* Oh, my lover
* hope the day never sets
* My veil will hold back the day
* and run after the sunlight
* Let the shade not touch us
* Oh, my lover
Hey...
lt seems that you've a terrible animal in you
What's that, a Tiger
No
Fox?
Snake?
No.
Girgat?
My Rabbit
Would'nt you eat food?
No
Will drink your blood
* Oh my queen,
* my doll,
* c'mon wake up now
* Wake up my little doll,
* my sweetie,
* your eyes are so sweet
* The morning's kiss
* is like a gentle reprimand
* Listen to it and wake up now
* Your nose will be
* bitten by a scorpion
* So get up! C'mon
* Ask whatever you want
* and it'll be granted
* (like King Dashrath, known for his word)
* Get rid of the night from your eyes
l have opened my eyes...
Now ask what you want?
Think carefully
Forgive Kesu
Hey... Are you listening?
What happened?
Have you forgiven him?
That can'nt be
Why?
lf l forgave him such quickly
then he may do this again mistake
So you will be angry with him
for his whole life
And for the next time don't promise to anyone
You promise breaker
Okay, will forgive him in wedding
Then Should l call the Pandit...
Crual person
Means 30th of next month
Hey... You listened
30th of next month is expected to
a fortunate day for wedding
Means, you must have to forgive Kesu
within the next 5 weeks
You've to forgive Kesu...
She is more happier on Kesu pardon
than the wedding, l guess
l think she likes Kesu very much
Do they already know each other?
They've studied in same college
Oh...
Therefore
So what?
No... No... No
My mind is filled with disgusting thoughts
Langda
What is in your heart?...
Tell me
No... not special
Actually, the Dolly is very beautiful
and we know Kesu
So sometimes l do think that
That may be they could have been
special friends in their college time
No... No... lt is not possible
Disgusting
But Kesu
He is a very handsome boy
But sometimes seems hypersexual
l suggest brother we should observe the Dolly
till the wedding ceremony
The world is very bitter sometime
And our Dolly Sis. is very innocent
Put all the substances in.
ls it original?
Run away... ..hurry up
CM... my son CM
You should wait at least till election
They will consider us to be dumb
if we kept quiet
lndur Singh's pitcher has been completly filled
Okay
But You will do nothing till your wedding
marriage
30th of next month is the fortunate day
How do you know?
l told him
You people ran so quickly that we just
kept crying to know what happened
Then we called Kesu
And have come straight here
Very good
First Kichlo, then lndur Singh
Langda will go to City
in attempt to depress Kichlo
And Mental you
With the help of Babu Ram will prepare the
timeable of lndur's bodyguards
And brother, Kesu?
He will distribute
the invitation cards of my wedding
l am on the phone wait for 2 min
lt is true
Whatever we say
Your postion will be your's only
Shit!
What ldea I have got
To kill Phichrou
You do it instead of me
And do it in that way
That Omi could see it
Phirchou is hiding somewhere
Ask how?
That Billo of your's
That prostitute
She does ClD in our bussiness
l bought it for lndu
you give it to Billo
Looks expensive Langda brother
For how much it will be?
Let it be
Langda borther
you are my true friend
Come, come
Come, come, don't be afraid
Kesu don't keep in heart
Talks on face to face
Kesu brother big or small Peg?
Are you mad?
That day beat have you forgotten
who will distriute these wedding cards?
This
This Rajju
He...
Yeah Rajju will do it
He has a passion for distribution
for Dolly's wedding no!
Sun will rise from west tommorw
Why?
First you took me to multiplex
Then you brought popcorn in
between the movie
Then Lunch, lce Cream,
a walk on mall road
The night is to end
But you are not talking about
taking me to bed
What is in your heart?
l am tired Billo
From me?
From my loneliness
You didn't tell me
What?
Will you marry me?
Are you gone mad, sick or what
going to marry me...
Hey Billo!
l am not kiddin
l have seen all the girls in the
world but could not live without you
See this
My heart is not accpeting it
And I am not accepting of my heart
Ok lair
Trusted you
Bastard!
Hey Bastard!
Now tell what is that you wanted from me
Let go brother
Lets go
Go go somewhere for 2-4 days
will see at the wedding in village
At night? 2 o'clock
yeah in the middle of night at 2
Tring Tring!
Tring Tring
l picked up my revolver
Then he woked up our bastard
and smiled with his teeth out
and said don't be afraid it must be
Billo
And really it was she our Billo
And she was in anger like Ramjee
l took my comfirt and got in to
bed again after seeing all this
Then what happend next
But in that comfirt there was a whole
And I am also human
And a little bastard as well
lt was winter night and Kesu was
on fire but Billo did not
let him touch her
Then Kesu took out jewellery from a box
A big briasllet for her waist
Sparklling one
That kind of beautiful thing
I have never seen before
lt was so sparkalling that it was shinnig
so much on her waist that one did not
need any electricity in the room
Then!
Then what? After this nothing was on top
of waist nor down and Kesu got started
You?
Where were you?
l have been waiting for you
Why were you not picking up the phone?
lt was on silent mode
Sorry
Shall I serve food?
No
l ll bring water
What happened?
Where is that waist braisllet
What?
That Braisllet
Should be here somewhere
Here or somewhere else
in the house only
Go and wear it
Now after marraige
l said go and wear it
Told you after marraige
lt seems that you have put it on
very safe place
Box eat it or cupbaord ate it
you lost it three days only which
l gave you
Did you give someone as a gift?
Whome I will give gift, Omkara?
Who else is there in my life?
For you I have left all the world
* A log burns and becomes coal
* Coal becomes dust
* But when the heart burns nothing happens
* There’s no smoke, no ashes
* Don’t let your heart burn
* Don’t give your heart away
Where it had gone?
This sun has also strated to come out late
Hey lt seems one did not sleep
the whole night in happiness
lf this is like on Mehndi what will
happen on the wedding day?
What happened?
Common tell?
lf you cray like that rain
will come in village
l Know now
you are missing you'r father right?
Stop it stupid! l am here with you
Baba, Mother, Sister
Let's go to my house
What happened?
Fell down?
Omi did something?
Wait...
ln love
Listen l will tell you for your
knowledge one thing
My grand Mother use to say
That you should let your man be a little
starvy and thrusty it is important
otherwise when they are over with you
will spit you like a chewing gum
Understand!
Smile is very precious in this world
Look the sun also rises
After the mehendi it is not god to go out
The railway has arrived at the
station lndu is in 4th compartment
Where is Kesu nowdays?
l don't know I called him but it
always says this no in unreachable
But Dolly must be knowing
he never forgets to call her
Langda
Yes Brother
Will you tell me one thing?
Truth!
Why not big brother
But only say yes or no
Why not big brother ask me
Kesu and Dolly has something going on?
My tongue does not support me
to say anything big brother
Yes or No
From my life you know better...
You are not doing this right with me
Langda Yes or No
Gone Bastard!
Let's go Brother
Yes or No
No
No you wanted to hear this only
To hear truth one has to have courage
What should l say now?
That When l stayed at Jaysu's house
l hear him saying in his sleep that
Dolly if we want to stay alive
we had to hide our love for life
Was anyone else there other than you
No
He dreams you were alone
You Listen you alone
lf I see in Dolly's eyes your whole
thing seems crap to me
Now bring Proof
Understand!
lf you could not bring any proof before
wedding l will hang you to death
Hey Band Master what are you doing
here Wedding house is ahead go there
Hey you!
What are you doing here?
Let's go home
there is lot do now
Whole day you sleep
All day you had so mush on your face
that you had now by Sir
Witch!
Horse is here
Get it ready then
When I got up this morning from my sleep
Stupid was written on my forhead
Big big
What l am saying to do you do that
otherwise tommorw morning there
will be something else written there
Big, Big
You want Dolly?
Huh!
Dolly?
He is still mad at me
today is marraige
You have to give me Hug today
Hey you! Hey, Don't put that there!
Move it from there that side is washroom
Hello! Kesu
Not Kesu who are you?
Me Billo!
Oho Billo jee
Kesu is busy right now
Give him the phone
No No we are not allowed to disturb him
Told you to give him the phone
Told you cant go in
Room is locked from inside
Who is with him?
l will tell you the truth but you
won't accept it
Hello
You stupid
Nothing will happen
This is all a play
Now Stop crying
We don't cry on the wedding day
Go now get ready
You are getting up or
shall I call Omkara?
l think you should
At least l should know what sin l have done
This is not that Omkara
For whom l have left all
My Omkara use to keep me like flower in hand
But what has happend?
l don't know!
All time he is angry with me
He slapped me one time as well
Why?
One small thing l kept and had forgotten
What thing?
Whatever thing
Why did he beat you?
You forgot Gorou in the festival
did l say something to you?
Now l will ask Omi Brother
you stop crying
you stupid girl clap noise are
made by both hands
if they or not toghether it
would not sound like
Smile is very precious in this world
On our 25th wedding aniversery
l took my Mrs to Timbuktoo
Timbuktoo!
Then what is the plan to go
on 50th Anniversery?
l will get her back from Timbuktoo
One Joke should l tell you
- Now he will also tell something
One time one man got married...
Then?
Finished
Lie to all the world but you
cannot lie to me
Your eyes are telling that you are sad
You say me that l am your sister
What is goin on in your head
All time his father's voice
comes to my years
Who can betray her father
how can be she someone elses
you suspect on her charachter rite!
our own sin have come in to our minds
lt is not your fault Omi Brother
We leave our houses, relations, love
and come in to your world with naked hands
Even if we walk through fire then
also we are called Betrayer's
You still have time Omi Brother
lf you have some sort of doubt on your mind
then do not come to our house for wedding
We will take care of Dolly
lf you could not find any proof then I will not let
anyone know where have you gone
Hello Kesu Brother
What Happened?
Billo is finding you in the village
At this time
Yes and she is in an angry mood
l have sent her to Langda brothers house
You should talk to Langda
Yes Kesu!
Yes she is here
But she is looking sad today
What happened?
l went to all this matter
What, what, what?
ln what matter?
She has done like this to me before
marriage after marriage what will happen?
Now you try to tell him why is
she making trouble
Today is the marraige
Hey Billo you
Here
Whom were you talking so late
in the middle of night
Why did you cut the line
You are taking it wrong come inside
Let me go!
l understood alright
You have got bad blood in your vains
lf you get chance you will take
your sister and mother on bed as well
Hey Billo that's it
What has happened?
From whose wife waist
did you took this off
Will you listen to me
Not in this life
Are you gone mad?
Shall l go now sir?
Let me go now please
You also was behind all this
now running away
Go now hit him 2, 4 from close
otherwise he will struggle for his life
the whole night
Go now
Your lover is gone
What?
Your Lover
Kesu!
Your Gift could not even take with him
Oh, Where did you find this?
Stop now your acting
You are been naked
lnnocent is looking very much on your face
From when you have been in bed with Kesu?
Tell me when did you
sleep with him the first time?
ls there any children abortion or not?
Listen don't deny now
l will forgive your life
Do not forgive me now
l don't want to live now!
Was something less between us?
Omi Brother!
Outside something bad has happend
How innocent she seems while sleeping
Nor she was her father's nor mine
Bad charachter!
l stole this braisllet
She is liying
l think she has also
some affair with someone
l worship you than God
Whatever you know
that's only you know
ln my truth and lies
will be no change
Pick up your gun
and relase me from this pain
You will get realsed from your body but...
you will never be relase from your soul
Not you neither me
* Wake up my little doll
* my sweetie
* your eyes are so sweet
* I'm the one who was residing in your eyes
* and still I am, am I not?
* Oh my queen
* my doll
* c'mon wake up now
* Wake up my little doll
* my sweetie
* your eyes are so sweet
* The morning’s kiss
* is like a gentle reprimand
* Listen to it and wake up
* The scorpion will bite your nose
* So get up soon
* Ask whatever you want
* and it’ll be granted
* (like King Dashrath known for his word)
* Get rid of the night in your eyes
* Oh my queen
* my doll
* c'mon wake up now
Was l that cheap in your eyes Omi Brother?
lf you said one more thing
then the story ends
ls there something else to be finished
Yes there is,
Remember how I killed Wajay in court?
On his brain
And lndhu Singh in his mouth
And remember Dhakur
ln his heart...