- You have a loan app? Wonderful.
- Yeah. Terrific.
My wife and I were having dinner
the other night... recently married.
- How can I help you, sir?
- Loretta...
see the man talking
to your bank manager has his case open?
Oh, that's Mr. Gwendon,
one of our assistant managers.
Our manager is Mr. Schoen,
but he's not in today.
- But you see the man with the briefcase.
- Yes.
That's my partner.
He has a gun in there.
If you don't do exactly
what I tell you or if you give me
any kind of problem at all...
I'm going to look at my partner
and he's going to shoot your
Mr. Gwendon between the eyes.
Okay.
All right, take one of those big
envelopes and put as many 100s,
50s and 20s as you can into it.
Nothing with bank straps
or rubber bands. I don't want
dye packs. I don't want bait money.
Start with the second drawer,
and then the one over there,
under the money counter.
Okay. It's okay. Come on, Loretta.
Key's right next to you.
There you go.
No bills off the bottom
of the drawer, please.
This your first time
being robbed?
You're doing great. Just smile so you
don't look like you're being held up.
You got a very pretty smile.
You got 20s? Give me the 20s.
I'll take those.
There you go.
I'll put those in my pocket.
I have to give my partner a sign.
Now, that's good.
He's gonna wait
until I'm out of the building,
make sure you haven't set off the alarm.
If you have, he's gonna shoot your
Mr. Gwendon between the eyes. Okay?
- Okay.
- I think that'll do it, Loretta.
Thank you.
Have a nice day.
You too.
Hey... she's cute, isn't she?
Yeah, she seems very nice.
Who was that?
No, no, no, no, no.
Son of a bitch!
Fuck! Fuck!
I think you flooded it.
Get out of the car, sir.
- Hey, you wanna hear a funny story?
- Shut up and get out of the car!
Yeah. Okay.
Go, go, go!
You want somethin', Foley?
Some fellas are goin' out of here.
What if I tell you where and when?
- How many?
- Expect you to look out for me,
let me run off work detail...
Okay, okay.
How many goin' out?
- I hear six.
- When?
- Tonight.
- You know who they are?
Yes, I do.
But I'm not gonna tell you just yet.
Meet me in the chapel,
just before lockdown. Okay?
- You all right?
- I love you, baby.
Tonight's the big night.
You excited?
- It's Super Bowl Sunday, okay?
- See you moved it up.
- Why you think that?
- I saw you runnin' this mornin'.
Stickin' to your routine
in case anybody happened to notice.
But you only did a couple of miles,
instead of your usual five.
Saving yourself for the big event. What
happened? Finish ahead of schedule?
Mira, you see those posts out there?
They're putting up another fence
15 feet back the fence that's
already there, you know?
So you figure, mira,
we wait till Super Bowl Sunday,
they have that fence built...
then, cono, we gotta dig what,
another nine, ten days, baby?
- Yeah.
- I don't think so.
So tonight, when it gets dark,
batta-bing, I'm outta here.
Come on, Foley. You could come.
I appreciate the offer,
and it's tempting.
It's a long run to civilization.
What's it? A hundred miles to Miami?
I'm too old to be tryin'
a stunt like that.
So, you send me a postcard
when you get out.
- Adele Delisi speaking.
- Will you accept a collect call
from Jack Foley?
Yeah, I'll accept.
- Hey, Adele, how you doin'?
- Hey, bank robber.
Want some advice? Next time,
keep the engine running.
- Huh-huh. That's funny!
- What do you want, Jack?
Adele, you know that Super Bowl party
that was for next Sunday?
They changed the date.
It's tonight at 6:30.
- Didn't you tell me one time
calls aren't monitored?
- I said, not as a rule.
So why don't you just come right out
and tell me what you're talkin' about?
- Listen to Miss Smarty Mouth,
out there in the free world.
- Oh, yeah, what's free about it?
I'm lookin' for work.
- What about Mandrake the Magician?
- Emil, The Amazing, huh?
He fired me.
Hired a younger girl... a redhead.
Adele, the reason I'm calling...
they changed the date.
It is tonight. It's 6:30.
That's like a few hours from now.
- You tell Buddy...
- Okay, all right, and the guy
driving the other car?
- What are you talking about?
- Well, seeing as you have
so much luck with cars...
Buddy thought it might be
better to bring two, you know?
He got this guy who says
you know him, from Lompoc...
- Uh, Glenn somebody...
- Glenn Michaels.
Uh-huh, that's him. Buddy said
Glenn thinks you guys are real cool.
- Adele?
- Yeah?
You tell Buddy I see Glenn wearing
his sunglasses, I'm gonna step on 'em.
- Might not even take 'em off first.
- Okay, honey. I'll do that.
Now, you try not to get shot. Bye.
Hey...
Here, ma'am.
Let me help you with these.
Beautiful young lady like you
shouldn't be carrying groceries.
Let a man do that for you.
Now, I didn't ask for your help,
so don't expect a tip.
Oh, that's okay, ma'am.
I'll just take your car.
Happy birthday.
Did you fit another
Chanel suit in here?
Something much better.
Go ahead, open it.
Oh, my God.
It's beautiful.
- It's a, um...
- Sig Sauer 380.
- Right.
- Oh, I love it!
Thanks, Dad.
Happy birthday.
- How 'bout some more coffee?
- You know, I can't.
I have to go out to Glades, and then
I'm meeting Ray Nicolet at 10:00.
Which one is that?
The A.T.F. Guy?
Actually, he's with the F.B.I. Now.
He switched over.
- He's still married, though.
- Technically. They're separated.
- Well, so he's moved out then.
- He's about to.
- Well, then they're
not separated, are they?
- Can we not talk about this?
- What are you doing at Glades?
- Serving process...
a summons and complaint.
Some con doing mandatory life
doesn't like macaroni and cheese.
So, he files suit. Says he doesn't have
any choice in what they serve...
and that violates
his civil rights.
- You can step in, work full-time
as one of my investigators.
- No, thanks.
- You used to like it.
- Dad.
You'd meet doctors, lawyers... nothing
wrong with them, if they're divorced.
Karen, why waste your time
on some cowboy cop...
who drinks too much
and cheats on his wife?
That's how those hot shots are...
all of 'em!
I really gotta go.
We don't talk much anymore.
How 'bout I come over Sunday
and we watch the Super Bowl together?
I'd like that.
Thanks for the gun, Dad.
They're right underneath you, Pup.
They dug a tunnel.
I don't hear anything.
Where's the tunnel come out?
Fourth post
from the guard tower.
I don't see nothin'.
You just keep watchin'.
Federal Bureau of Investigation,
how may I direct your call?
Yeah, this is Karen Sisco again
for Ray Nicolet.
Hold, please.
Yeah.
The line is busy.
Would you like his voice mail?
No, forget it.
I'll call back later.
- All right.
- Thanks.
Still don't see anything.
You will directly.
Wait a minute.
What the fuck?
Two men by the fence!
What the hell is she doin'?
Stop! Get your hands
in the air!
Tunnel's clear.
Seal up the north face.
- What happened?
- What the hell do you think,
jackass? Got a jail break!
Cubans out in the cane. Don't point
that thing at me. Hey, Buddy.
- It's okay, we're the good guys.
- What are you doing here?
All right. You're just a girl. What do
you do for a living you pack a shotgun?
- I'm a federal marshal
and you're under arrest.
- That's probably all the hacks.
Why don't we talk
about this later?
Watch your head.
I'm in. Let's go!
- Hey! You comfy?
- If I could have a little more room...
Well, there isn't any.
We got a lot of shit in here.
We got handcuffs in here.
What's in this can?
That's for your breath. You could
use it... squirt some in your mouth.
Yeah, well, that's mace, isn't it?
All right, you! Get...
Hey. Where's your gun... pistol?
In my bag, in the car.
Boy, it stunk in there.
I believe it. You're ruining
a $900 suit my dad gave me.
Yeah, it went great
with that 12-gauge too.
Why in the world would someone like you
become a federal marshal?
- The idea of going after
guys like you appealed to me.
- Sorry, what was that?
Guys like me?
Let me tell you something.
Even though I've been celibate lately,
I'm not going to force myself on you.
- I've never done that in my life.
- You wouldn't have time, anyway.
We come to a roadblock, they run the car
and find out who it belongs to.
That's if they get set up in time,
which I doubt. If they do...
they'll be lookin' for a bunch
of little Latin fellas, not
a big black guy drivin' a Ford.
He must be quite a pal,
to risk his own ass like this.
Buddy? Yeah, he's a good guy.
Back when we jailed together,
he used to call his sister
every week, without fail.
She's a born-again Christian. She does
bookkeeping for a televangelist.
He'd call her up,
confess his sins.
He'd tell her whatever bank
he happened to rob at the time.
Buddy... that
his given name?
The one I gave him, yeah.
So, what's your name?
Be in the paper
tomorrow, anyway.
Jack Foley.
You've probably heard of me.
- Why? Are you famous?
- The time I was convicted
in California...
the F.B.I. Told me that I'd robbed
more banks than anybody in the computer.
- How many was that?
- Tell you the truth,
I don't really know.
Started when I was 18 years old,
driving for my Uncle Cully,
and his partner, Gus.
So, basically you're saying
you spent half your life in prison.
Basically, yeah.
I go back, I do 30 years. No time off.
- You imagine lookin' at that?
- I don't have to. I don't rob banks.
You don't seem all that scared.
- Of course I am.
- You don't act like it.
What do you want me
to do, scream?
That wouldn't help much, anyway.
No, I'm just gonna sit here, take it
easy, and wait for you to screw up.
You sound like my ex-wife.
- You were married?
- Just for about a year,
give or take a few days.
It's not like we didn't get along...
we had fun. We just...
didn't have... that thing,
you know, that uh...
- That spark, you know?
Gotta have that.
- Mm-hmm.
- We still talk, though.
- Sure.
This is not gonna end well.
These things never do.
If it turns out I get shot like
a dog, it's gonna be in the street...
not off a goddamn fence.
You must really see yourself
as some kind of Clyde Barrow, huh?
- You mean, of Bonnie and Clyde?
- Yeah.
The part in the movie where they get
shot, when it's Warren Beatty and...
- Faye Dunaway.
- Faye Dunaway, yeah.
- I like her in that movie about TV.
- Network, yeah, she was good.
And that guy says he's not gonna
take any more shit from anybody.
- Peter Finch.
- Yeah! Peter Finch.
"I'm mad as hell, and I'm not
gonna take any more of your shit!"
In that part where they get shot,
I can remember thinkin' to myself...
thinkin', "Hey, that wouldn't be
such a bad way to go, if you had to."
You sure are easy to talk to.
I was thinkin', if we met
under different circumstances...
if you were in a bar and
I came up and we started talkin'...
- I wonder what would happen.
- Nothing.
- If you didn't know who I was.
- You'd probably tell me.
- Just saying if we met
under different circumstances...
- You have got to be kidding.
Yeah. Yeah.
Another movie I liked with Faye Dunaway
was Three Days of the Condor.
The one with Robert Redford
when he was young.
Yeah.
You know, I never thought
it made sense, though...
you know, the way
they got together so quick.
Why not?
- I mean, romantically.
- Mm-hmm.
Well, but it... if... uh.
All right.
Here we go. All right.
Where the hell are we?
At the turnpike. Glenn's right above us
with the other car.
- All right, c'mon. Hop on out.
- Turn around and get your hands up!
Shit!
We may as well leave her.
We're leavin' the car...
and we gotta leave her someplace,
anyway... what's the difference where?
- She's comin' with us.
- Jesus Christ, what were
you doing in there?
- Look for a name.
- I already looked.
Her name is Karen Sisco. Like
the Cisco Kid, only spelled different.
S-l-S-C-O.
Karen?
All right, Karen?
You be a good girl, now.
I'm gonna open up the trunk.
Hey, hey, hey, now!
Now, you're puttin' holes in your car!
I'm not leavin' you.
I'm gonna open the trunk enough
for you to drop your pistol out.
Now, if you shoot, Buddy's got
your shotgun, he's gonna shoot back.
There's nothin' I can do about it,
so it's up to you.
Hey. Don't!
It's Glenn! Whoa!
Fuck! Hey, hey, Jack.
Good to see you, man.
What the fuck
are you guys shooting at?
- Do we need 'im?
- The cop saw this car.
- He might tie it to the break
and turn around.
- All right.
- Hey, Studs. We didn't recognize ya.
- Hey, "Studs," man.
I haven't heard that since Lompoc, man.
So what's goin' on?
Aw, nothin'.
Karen. Are you comin' out?
- You hear that?
- Okay!
Okay.
You win, Jack.
Now, you get your clothes cleaned,
you send me the bill.
I'll send it to you at Glades.
What, did you crawl through
a sewer, man? Who're you?
- Take your sunglasses off.
- I see better with 'em on, man.
You don't take 'em off
I'm gonna throw them off
while they're still on your head.
- Go wait in the car.
- Um, we're in civilization now,
so you can ease up a little bit.
I'm sorry. I'd like you
to wait in the car, please.
Take her, put her in the back.
- Okay. In the trunk?
- In the backseat! In the backseat!
- Backseat. Okay, you gotta come now,
'cause I gotta do this...
- Gimme your jacket.
Somebody forgot
to bring the clean clothes.
I brought 'em. They're at Glades
in the back of the Cadillac.
You decided to jump
into the trunk of her car.
You can blame me if you want.
I don't mind.
- Here, sir.
- I'll tell you...
- What's your problem, Jack?
- I don't know why you got Glenn
involved in this.
- How 'bout the score was
his idea to begin with?
- Idea...
The guy's got a fuckin'
vacant lot for a head.
He thinks he can talk
to me like that? Shit.
"Gimme your jacket." I have been
sitting here for over a half-hour...
watchin' out for the Highway Patrol,
if you think that's fun.
God. You know, I hadda go
over there in the bushes...
to smoke a joint, just so I could like,
you know?
Yep. I got somethin'
big lined up, up north.
Yeah, these guys? Wouldn't even fuckin'
know about it if it wasn't for me.
- Every time he opens his mouth,
I wanna punch him out.
- He's not the problem, Jack.
You wanna pull your head
outta your ass, tell me why the hell
we're bringing her with us?
Glenn.
You don't remember me, do you?
Um, couldn't have been Glades
if that's what you're thinkin',
'cause I was never out there.
- No, that's not what I'm thinking.
- Oh, yeah?
But you're sure
we've met, huh?
Last fall.
I drove you from the Palm Beach County
Jail to the federal courthouse... twice.
You're Glenn Michaels.
I never forget anybody
I've cuffed and shackled.
Now let's think about this for a minute,
Glenn, see if we can't work it out.
Do we have a gun in the car?
Oh, shit!
I remember you! Hey!
Foley's not gonna make it,
and if he goes down, you go with him.
- Now, look. I can understand
if you guys are close, but...
- No, we're not.
- But, yeah. I'm helpin' him.
- Now wait a minute, Glenn.
Have you helped him?
I mean, technically,
at this point, I doubt you could be
charged with aiding a fugitive.
So you still have a choice.
You wanna take her to my place, get
cleaned up, come out of the bathroom...
with your aftershave on, and she goes,
"Oh. I had you all wrong."
No. I just wanna talk
to her again, that's all.
I just wanna see what it might have
been like under normal circumstances.
It's too late for that, Jack.
He wants to get out of here,
and I don't blame him.
Ref don't call it soon, Snoop's gonna
send this cat out in a body bag.
Anybody ever tell you
why they call him "Snoopy"?
He used to be
Maurice "Mad Dog" Miller...
back when he was a pro.
Now you pet him,
he goes down.
- I don't believe it!
- Oh, my!
Bullshit! Bullshit!
Yeah, you the man.
Guy's bragging he won
a thrown fight.
Fuckin' pathetic.
Dangerous is what it is.
- Who's the bald dude?
- Richard Ripley.
The Wall Street guy?
Call him Dick The Ripper on account
of all the guys he ripped off.
Oh, yeah. I didn't
recognize him without his rug.
- What's his bid?
- Three years.
You guys on the bench? Okay.
Three years, fined $50 million
and wrote 'em a fuckin' check.
Just like that.
Fifty mill, signed his name.
Didn't even... Didn't even...
Okay, a little help.
Okay, heavy!
Heavy! Come on!
All the bright glare out here,
you couldn't read the numbers
on the weights.
Oh. I had it. Jesus.
- How do you know he wrote a check?
- Uh, he told me.
We work laundry together.
Guy loves to fucking talk.
Yeah, he loves to talk.
He talked to the U.S. Attorney.
Rolled over on all the snitches
he was doing business with.
Hey! Any guy who can write
a fuckin' check for $50 million...
he says anything,
I'm all fuckin' ears.
Guy tells me he's got
all this money in foreign banks.
Plus, around, mmm...
five million in uncut diamonds
at his house.
He said, quote...
that I can get my hands on it
at any time.
- Where does he live?
- Detroit.
Snoopy Miller says that uncut diamonds
are as easy to move as cash.
Ever seen
an uncut diamond, Studs?
Looks just like
a plain, old rock.
Wait, you think this guy's lying?
What do you think, Studs? Use
your head. Some guy's got $5 million...
socked away in his house,
and he's gonna tell some motormouth
he just met in prison about it.
Oh, I see.
You guys are cynical. Right.
Here it comes.
Keep on walking. Keep walking.
You don't wanna be
answering any questions.
I'm just saying
she wasn't scared, that's all.
That's 'cause she had
her hand on her gun the whole time
waitin' to make her move.
You're just jealous 'cause
it was me in the trunk with her...
- and not you.
- You're right.
The first thing I'm gonna do...
is get this mud off me.
Hey.
Karen?
Karen, honey?
You were talking
in your sleep.
What'd I say?
"Hey, yourself."
Huh.
Hello, Daniel.
Daniel Burdon, F.B.I.
Marshall Sisco, Karen's dad.
- Hmm.
Umm...
Would you mind, please,
waiting outside?
We have some business
to do here.
Well, uh, I have
to use the john anyway.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
I wanna be
on the task force, Daniel.
Well...
That's nice of you
to offer, Karen, but...
I got all the help
I can use right now.
Instead, let's talk about
how you got that bump on your head.
Isn't that my file
you're holding on to?
Yes, but I want
to hear it from you...
starting... with when
you grabbed the wheel.
Where was this?
Coming to the Okeechobee exit.
- Sit back!
- Can you see with those glasses on?
I'm fine!
This is... stupid, man.
These guys are gonna be
so disappointed in me, man.
You know what?
If I wasn't stoned...
there is no way that you would have
talked me into this.
- Remember that.
- Get off at the exit
right after that bridge.
No, I am not fucking turning
myself in, so forget it!
- Get off at that exit!
- What exit?
- That exit right there. Take that exit!
- Sit back! No!
The next thing I knew...
the paramedics were
pulling me out of the car.
- You all right?
- There's a couple
of points I keep wondering about...
have to do with the two guys
that grabbed you.
Buddy, is it?
And this fella Jack Foley.
I swear, the man must have robbed
over 200 banks in his time.
- Really?
- Um-hmm.
He told me he didn't
remember how many he robbed.
Then you talked to him.
In the trunk, yeah.
What'd you talk about?
Different things.
Prison, movies.
This fella holds you hostage,
you talk about movies?
It was an unusual experience.
You know, Foley made me think
of that fella Carl Tillman.
The one that you were seeing,
it turns out, the same time
he was robbing banks.
- Do you recall that?
- And what happened to Carl?
The time came, you shot him. But you
didn't shoot Foley or the guy with him.
They're unarmed, you had a shotgun
and you let them throw you in the trunk.
Okay. Now you got
your Sig in your hand...
and you say in the report
that you couldn't turn around.
He had you pinned down.
But when the trunk opened...
how come you didn't
cap the two guys then?
What do you work on most of the time?
Fraud? Go after crooked bookkeepers?
Karen, I've been with the bureau
15 years on all kinds of investigations.
- Have you ever shot a man?
- No.
- When was the last time you were
primary through the door?
- I have to qualify?
You have to know
what you're talking about.
We'll talk another time.
All right, Karen?
I'd like to know why Foley
put you in that second car
when he didn't need you anymore.
You'll have to ask him that.
Rip, Rip.
- What the deal is, baby?
- Hi, Maurice.
- Oops. I don't know.
- Make a fist...
- There you go.
- Fuck it, man.
- Got your little fishies for you.
- Oh, good.
Not so fast. Starting out,
there's gonna be an across the board
cost of living increase.
- What?
- When I got put in here a year ago
on credit card fraud...
I didn't really get
no props for that.
But ever since I shanked
that loudmouth pussy in the yard...
it's like my Dun and Broadstreet around
this bitch done shot way the fuck up.
Actually, it's Dun and Bradstreet.
That's the, uh...
Well, I've heard it both ways.
Point is that the price
has gone up around this bitch too.
Get your little black book out.
We got some business to talk about.
For the little fishies...
What'd I say they was gonna be?
- Two thousand.
- Now they're gonna be three thousand.
- Come on. You...
That saltwater shit
you put in your eyes?
- What do you call that?
- Bausch & Lomb.
Yeah, that bushy lawn shit.
That's 300.
- I need it.
- Yeah, you do. And that extra pillow.
I'm gonna get that for you,
but that's gonna be like five C's.
- Five?
- Hey.
Sign says shut the fuck up,
or can't you fellas read?
Who the fuck
you talkin' to, man?
You got a problem
over there, Foley?
Yeah, this is
the dumbest fucking shakedown
in the history of dumb shakedowns.
- Five hundred bucks for a pillow?
- That's right.
- It does seem a little high,
doesn't it?
- Shut up, Dick.
- Must be a nice pillow.
- Full goose down.
- Look, you still...
- How much for your company at chow?
My company? Come on, man. You know
I'll watch this motherfucker's back.
- How much?
- That's a C-note.
If you're smart, Ripley,
you'll tell this guy to fuck off.
Really?
Well, l... l...
I don't know.
First of all, if he kills you,
then he's gonna get nothin'.
Well, uh, the man don't
just have to die, Foley.
He could accidentally hurt himself
falling down on something real hard.
Like a shiv or my dick.
I'll pay. I'll pay it.
Don't worry.
If he falls on anything, Snoop...
then they're gonna transfer
his ass outta here faster
than you can throw a fight...
and you're still
gonna get nothin'.
You know, last time I checked, man...
this shit over here ain't
got nothin' to do with you.
Why don't you go outside?
Smoke a cigarette or some shit.
I don't smoke.
You heard the man. Why don't
you get your punk ass up outta here?
- Uh-oh.
- You fucked up now, man. That's Himey.
Protege of mine. Ranked number 32
in the federal prison system.
- Thirty-two?
- That's right.
- Out of, what, 20.
- Kick this cracker's ass.
- What's going on here?
- Uh, nothin'.
Just "reading is fundamental" shit.
We got all excited and everything.
Clear outta here. Now.
- No problem.
- All of you. Let's go.
Uh, Snoopy.
I think we settled the fish thing.
Oh, the fish. Yeah.
That's how you
do the shake, partner.
Paper says there's ten grand each
on you, Chino and Lulu.
They say anything about Karen?
Just that she got away. Here.
- Hmm?
- Jack!
- Hey!
- That's all right. It's in the pool.
Did it say what happened to her
after she took off with Glenn?
I don't know.
You'll have to ask Glenn.
He's probably on his way to Detroit,
which is where we should be.
- Yeah.
- Do you realize what you're doing?
Worrying about a woman
who works for law enforcement?
You wanna sit down and have cocktails
with a woman who tried to shoot you.
- Do you hear what I'm saying?
- Do you think this old guy's
her boyfriend?
It's the only picture
she has in here.
Am I going to Detroit by myself?
The longer we stay here,
the better chance there is...
that either Glenn
is gonna screw up the score...
or we gonna get busted or both.
This is Foley?
- Karen?
- Hmm?
This is Foley?
Doesn't even look like that.
- Oh, no?
- Uh-uh. He looks a lot like...
Different.
Wyatt Earp is here.
- Hey.
- How you feelin'? Feel better?
- Good. Yeah.
- Is your dad taking good care of you?
- He took the week off...
to take care of me and he's worked on
his boat every day since.
- Dad, this is Ray Nicolet.
- Hi.
- Pleasure to meet you.
I heard a lot about you.
- Likewise.
Ray's working with the F.B.I.
Task force on the prison break.
I see that. Tell me, Ray, do you ever
wear one that says "undercover"?
- No.
- How's it going?
Sit down.
Okay. Good.
We caught one of them.
- Was it Foley?
- Was it off a tip?
Somebody spotted two of them
out in this hobo camp near the airport.
Called in the number.
That was it.
- I knew it as soon
as I as there was a reward.
- Was it Foley?
No, Linares,
one of the Cubans.
We went in there with full SWAT,
two choppers, that whole deal.
Linares goes nuts,
starts shooting, so we took him out.
I don't know how Chirino
got away, but he did.
- And Foley hadn't been there.
- No, this place was strictly Cuban.
Foley had a ride. He must have
his own agenda. You know what I mean?
He seems to be the only guy
who kinda knows what he's doing.
Uh-huh.
- Excuse me.
- Yeah.
Hello?
Yeah, she is.
Just a minute, please.
Karen.
- Hello?
- Hi.
You know who this is?
Yes.
Five minutes.
So. Ray.
- Yeah.
- There's something I'm wondering.
The headline reads, "I slept with
a murderer, says shaken Miami woman."
- Who is it that answered the phone?
- None of your business.
I'm just worried maybe
I'm not old enough for you.
- It was my dad.
- Really?
- He's got a cop's face.
- How do you know?
- Oh, wait. You have my wallet.
- And your gun.
- Think I can have 'em back?
- How do we do that?
You can come by my dad's place
and drop 'em off.
I could leave it with the SWAT guy
that answers the door.
There's a guy here
on the task force right now.
Maybe I should put him on the phone
and let the two of you work it out.
- You wouldn't do that.
- Why not?
Because you're having
too much fun.
She fixes him pork chops and rice.
The next thing you know,
they're making love on the sofa.
She says he was very gentle.
This guy, Chirino, shows up at the
house, says he misses his little girl.
She feels sorry for him.
Next thing you know... boom.
- On the couch.
- That's how you score now, huh?
I guess.
There's something
I've been wondering.
Whatever happened
to your Uncle Cully?
You think he's gonna
tell you where I am?
- Unless you wanna tell me.
- He's dead.
Did 27 years before he got out...
and he died a couple of years afterwards
in a charity hospital...
by trying to make up
for all the good times he missed.
That's not gonna be me.
What, one last score, retire
to some island? Is that the idea?
- Jack.
- I'm partial to mountains myself...
but if you like islands,
we'll make it an island.
- What do you mean,
"we'll make it an island"?
- You and I can make it...
- Jack, you better come
and check this out.
- Is that Buddy?
- What? No. Okay. Bye-bye.
- Who're you talking to?
- So she's a married woman.
- Right.
But she goes to bed
with a prison escapee because...
he tells her that
he misses his little girl.
She tells the world about it.
But you protect her.
You don't reveal her name.
That makes it sound like
what she was doing was okay...
as long as her husband
doesn't find out.
Like the guy who cheats
on his wife, saying what
she doesn't know won't bother her.
- Dad.
- What?
Ray, I wanna show you
something... in the living room.
- Yeah.
- Good talking to you, Ray.
Yeah, you too.
Federal law enforcement
agents raided a squatters camp...
north of Miami International
Airport this morning...
in the hopes of capturing
a fugitive from Tuesday's daring escape
from Glades prison.
F.B.I. Officials confirm that
one of the escapees, Arelio Linares...
- was killed...
- Chino's gonna
wanna talk to me.
Chino's runnin' for his life.
He don't give a shit about you.
He's gonna know by now
I gave him up back at Glades.
He's gonna wanna find me.
Maybe see Adele,
see what she knows.
He knows where she lives?
Jack!
We were talking once,
drinking rum...
and I may have
mentioned Adele.
How she worked for a magician.
Chino got all interested.
He said, "How do you saw
the woman in half?"
Maybe he wanted to meet her,
maybe see her if she came to visit.
Oh, okay, okay. So you call her up
and tell her don't talk to any Cubans.
- The phone's probably tapped by now.
- You're right.
And if the phone is tapped,
you know they have her place staked out.
Shit!
Adele Delisi speaking.
- Uh, uh, this is Adele?
- Yes, it is.
Oh... Uh, sorry.
Wrong number.
Nice disguise.
I'm a tourist.
All right. Here we go.
Coming up right here...
on the left.
- What about the guy with the clippers?
- I wonder what the F.B. I...
is charging to trim hedges
these days?
- Quite a checker game
they got goin' on too.
- Pull on up.
Oh, man.
Okay, you saw her.
That's all you get.
- Let's go to Detroit.
- Now you're talkin', brother.
I'll say one thing for Jack...
he's very considerate.
Lights on or off,
if you know what I mean.
- Really.
- Hmm.
Adele, listen...
I just want to find him
before he does something else
and makes it worse on himself.
No. Buddy'll take care of him.
Keep him out of trouble.
He's Jack's conscience, always has been.
They must have robbed
50 banks together.
- They were a really great team.
- Until they got busted.
Hmm. That wasn't Jack's fault,
no, that was on account of...
Buddy, for some reason, decided to call
his sister and confess to the job...
before they'd done it
instead of after.
Well, she called the F.B.I. They both
went down, and they ended up at Lompoc.
I think Buddy felt
kind of bad about that.
Adele, do you have any idea
where I could find Buddy?
Or Glenn?
Mira, Adele, you in there?
- Yes.
- Mira, I'd like to speak to you, please.
- Well, who is it?
- Emile, you know, the guy
you used to work for?
- Uh...
- He gave me your number
and where you live.
Mira, I'm looking for an assistant.
Can I speak to you, please?
- Oh. Uh, yeah.
- All right.
You did work for Emile, right?
Uh, yeah, I was Emile's box jumper
for four years, almost.
Cono! You were what, his box?
- Uh, his assistant.
- Oh, okay.
You say you perform
in the Miami area?
Oh, si. Here, there, you know.
I was a magician in Cuba. They used
to call me Manuelito the Magician.
Mira, can you please open?
- I'm not dressed.
- I'm a good friend of Jack Foley.
- You know Jack?
- Who are you?
Jose Chirino.
Or maybe you heard Jack call me Chino.
Bueno, I'm the same guy.
Tell him he has to wait in the hall.
You have to get dressed. Say it loud.
Wait in the hall.
You have to get dressed.
Mira, mira, you tell me
where I could find Jack
and I don't bother you no more.
Now, come on, please! Hello?
- I don't know where he is.
- I'm the guy that helped
Jack escape from prison.
- Mira, please open this fucking door...
- I'm gonna call the police.
Cono, why you gonna do that
to a friend, man? A partner to Jack?
That's it! That's it!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
Cono, mira, please!
- Adele! Adele!
- Give me your hand.
- You not Adele!
- I'm a federal marshal,
and you're under arrest.
- Get my bag, Adele.
- Oh.
Mira, please, please. I think
there's a misunderstanding here.
Can you...
you got nice bag.
Mira, let's say we just forget about it,
okay? We forget about this, I go home...
- Shut up.
- Owwww! Who the hell
taught you how to do that?
- Give me your other hand.
- Okay, okay. Ay, cono.
Ohhhh!
I gotta go make pee-pee.
Ohhhhh! Owww!
Wow! You are mean!
Look, I'm gonna call my lawyer.
This is... What do they call that?
Human rights violation.
- Ay, cono.
- Daniel Burdon, please. Karen Sisco.
Mira, Adele, Adele.
Can I ask you a question, please?
You know that trick you do?
Karen? Where are you?
I've been trying to reach you.
When you in the box
and they saw you in half?
- I'm at Adele Delisi's.
- It's magic.
We already talked to her.
That's a dead end.
I was just wondering,
if I brought in Chirino,
would you let me be on the task force?
- Yeah, sure, Karen.
- Then they put the saw through,
and they separate it.
- And that's it. Ta da.
- But how do you twinkle your toes?
I don't get that.
You bring Chirino in,
and you can be on the task force.
- That's all I wanted to know.
- Good.
Now, would you forget
about the ex-wife...
and get over to the Adams Hotel?
- You got it.
- Then they open it up...
- No! No!
- Come on.
- And then that's it.
- Fake legs.
- Mmm.
- Fake legs? How you gonna...
- Ay! Cono.
- Thanks, Adele.
How do they twinkle their toes,
then, if it's fake, mira?
First thing we do,
we get to Detroit, we find Glenn...
and we find a window
to throw him out of.
I was thinkin', if I was Glenn,
and I was up there...
to take down the Ripper,
where would I go?
'Cept that if you were Glenn,
you wouldn't be thinkin'.
Remember Snoopy Miller,
his old pal from the joint?
Snoop? I figured
he'd be brain-dead by now.
Nah, Snoop doesn't box anymore.
Glenn told me that he's managing
some fighters out at the Kronk.
- Did you get the key?
- They're in room 613.
All right. I want
two men outside, front and back.
Conroy, Jamison, go on up to six,
cover both ends of the hall.
You're primary.
You're secondary.
And you're point man.
- You gonna use a ram?
- Yeah. Why?
The manager's door is metal.
You know what I mean,
they might all be.
A ram on a metal door makes
a lot of noise for what good it does.
I got a shock lock round
for my shotgun that oughta do the trick.
Fine. Whatever.
Two, please.
You.
Fuck it.
Let's take the stairs. Karen...
Take the radio. Stay down here
in the lobby and watch the elevator.
- Daniel, I want to go upstairs.
- Well, you can wait
in the car if you want to.
Now, you see Foley and Bragg
coming behind us. What do you do?
- Call and tell you?
- And you let them come up.
You don't try to make
the bust yourself. You understand?
Is this your floor, ma'am?
Oh. Oh, yes.
Yes, it is. I'm sorry. Thank you.
Be advised we are
approaching the door.
going to blow the door.
Going up?
Shit, I thought I was going up.
She just looked right at me.
- Who?
- Karen.
- Karen Sisco?
- Yeah.
She's in the lobby.
- She's in the lobby?
- Yeah.
They know where I live,
no doubt they know what I drive.
We gotta dump this car.
She just sat there,
looking right at me.
Karen, they're
not up here. Keep your eyes open.
Karen? Karen, are you there?
He waved at you?