QUENTIN: The way I figure it,
everyone gets a miracle.
Like, maybe you hit
the Powerball jackpot.
Or a last-second jumper
in the NBA Finals. (CHUCKLES)
Maybe you make it to outer space...
or marry the Queen of England,
or something.
If you consider all the unlikely things
that happen in all the world...
you gotta think at least one of them
will happen to each of us.
Turns out, my miracle was different.
Of all the houses
in all the subdivisions
in all the state of Florida...
I wound up living across the street...
from Margo Roth Spiegelman.
Bring your own lampshade,
somewhere there's a party
Here it's never endin',
can't remember when it started
Pass around the lampshade,
There'll be plenty enough room in jail
QUENTIN: From the moment I saw her
I was hopelessly, madly in love.
If bein' wrong's a crime,
I'm serving forever
If bein' strong's your kind
Then I need help here with this feather
QUENTIN: Due to our close proximity
in both age and location...
and for no other reason
I could ever discern...
we soon became friends.
If bein' afraid is a crime
we hang side by side
At the swingin' party down the line
Look.
Quentin.
He's dead.
We should get out of here, Margo.
I thought you closed
your eyes when you died.
QUENTIN: The truth is...
at the time, it didn't feel like
that big a deal to me.
It's not like I knew the guy.
If I had a panic attack
every time someone I didn't know died...
I'd go insane.
(KNOCKING ON WINDOW)
It was a much bigger deal to Margo.
I figured it out.
His name is Robert Joyner.
He was 36.
Apparently he was getting divorced
and he was sad about it.
How do you know all this?
I'm doing an investigation. Are you in?
Sure.
- Great. Come on.
- Wait, what?
His wife works at SeaWorld.
I bet there's a clue.
Margo...
we can't go to SeaWorld.
It's almost 11:00.
I can get us in.
Come on!
I don't wanna get in trouble.
It's a shame, don't you think?
All those strings inside him broke.
QUENTIN: Margo always loved mysteries.
And in everything that came after,
I could never stop thinking...
maybe she loved them so much...
she became one.
But I'm getting ahead of myself.
A lot changed
in the years that followed.
Margo and I sort of... drifted apart.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
But I never stopped
thinking about her...
I'll get it! I'll get it.
...and hoping I'd get a second chance.
CHILDREN: Trick or treat!
QUENTIN: Yeah. Happy Halloween, guys.
- (HONKING)
- (ENGINE REVVING)
QUENTIN: It wasn't just me.
Pretty much everyone recognized...
Margo was different.
(LAUGHING)
Margo was...
special.
Her life had become a series
of unbelievably epic adventures.
Each one too insane to be true.
Like the time she spent three weeks
traveling with the circus.
Or the time she toured with the
Mallionaires up and down the East Coast.
Look, if you ask the bassist...
he's either gonna say I'm his girlfriend
or he wants me to be...
Either way I'm going back there...
so you might as well make it easier
for yourself and just let me in.
QUENTIN: And wherever she went...
she always left clues behind
for her little sister, Ruthie.
Or anyone else she deemed worthy.
(CREAKING)
I was never one of those people.
As senior year drew to a close,
Margo and I barely talked at all.
MRS. JACOBSEN: It's your senior prom.
I don't understand the objection.
QUENTIN: I have so many objections, Mom.
Like slow dancing.
And fast dancing. Any kind of dancing.
And wearing a rented tux.
You could take Suzie Chung.
No, we're not a thing anymore.
But she was such a nice girl.
What happened with you two?
I don't know, it just...
Just didn't work out.
Hi, Ben. Hi, Radar.
- Hi, Mrs. Jacobsen.
- Hey, Mrs. Jacobsen.
- I would hit that so hard.
- (GROANS)
I don't see it.
What? Q!
I'm not saying
I just wanna bang your mom.
- She should be respected.
- Stop.
Admired. You know, she's a real lady.
Yeah, she's my mom.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I wanna ride bikes with her.
What?
I'd feed her grapes, take her to Paris.
Treat her like the princess she is.
What, is that wrong?
It's weird.
It's always weird.
- I wanna give her a bath.
- (GROANS)
That's gonna be so...
(CHUCKLING)
Oh! Hold on.
(LOCKER DOOR RATTLING)
- Uh-oh.
- (SIGHS)
Hey, honey bunny.
How's prom looking for you?
Not a chance, Bloody Ben.
No.
No!
Freshmen know that story?
QUENTIN: When Ben was 12...
he got a kidney infection
- and started literally pissing blood.
- Oh, God.
QUENTIN: By the time he came
back from the hospital...
a rumor had spread through
the entire school...
that his condition was the result
of chronic masturbation.
I'm never gonna get a prom date, am I?
Don't worry about it.
Prom is a waste of time
and a waste of money.
Radar's going to prom.
Radar has a girlfriend,
so he has to go to prom.
Lame.
Radar, has she been to your house yet?
Oh, yeah. Has your girlfriend
come to your house yet?
- Stop.
- Isn't there a certain reason
why she doesn't come to your house?
Radar, what up with that?
You know very well "what up with that."
We just like to hear you say it.
- Could you tell us again?
- (MUMBLES)
- Because of what?
- I cannot hear you.
Can you project?
My parents own
the world's largest collection
of black Santas!
QUENTIN: Oh, yeah.
You heard that correctly.
Radar's parents were trying to get into
The Guinness Book of World Records...
for the largest collection
of black Santas in one house.
There were over a thousand.
And they were everywhere.
And not just at Christmas.
Even so, Radar was the first one of us
to get a serious girlfriend.
RADAR: You need a prom date.
Why don't you ask that girl
you slept with at summer camp?
Oh. She's made up.
No, she's not.
But you can ask the girl
from Saskatchewan.
Oh, yeah, you could ask...
Oh, no, she's also made up.
No, they are both real. Not made up.
- QUENTIN: Define "real."
- I don't know.
Gotta go.
- RADAR: Hi.
- Hey.
- Hey. Let's go.
- We have 10 minutes.
No, we're fine. Let's go.
BEN: Hi, Angela.
Bye, Angela.
It was nice talking to you, Angela.
Oh, God. She's great.
Glad we can have these chats.
QUENTIN: So most of my days
were exactly like this.
I threw myself into my classes...
SATs, extracurriculars.
By the end of high school...
I barely thought of her at all.
I just had to graduate,
go off to college,
find someone new.
And forget the miracle ever happened.
And it almost worked out that way.
Until this one night.
(APPROACHING FOOTSTEPS)
(WINDOW SLIDES)
Margo?
Shh.
Margo, hey.
I need to borrow your car.
- What?
- Your car.
I don't have a car.
I mean your mom's car.
Why can't you use your car?
My parents locked the keys in the safe
beneath their bed.
And while I'm sure I could go
in there and crack the combo...
it just so happens
that Myrna Mountweazel's in there
and that goddamn dog despises me.
Anyway, so like I said,
I need to borrow your car.
Mmm-mmm.
Also, I need you to drive the car...
because I have nine things
I need to do tonight...
and more than half of them
require a getaway driver.
What, are you committing felonies?
Ooh. Remind me, is breaking
and entering a felony?
Yes. What?
- MARGO: Well.
- MR. SPIEGELMAN: Margo!
Okay.
I gotta go, so are you in or out?
Why can't you just get one
of your underlings to help you out?
Like Jase, or Lacey, or Becca?
They're part of the problem, actually.
What problem?
There are nine problems.
And your boyfriend's one of them?
Ex-boyfriend.
(INHALES DEEPLY) Hmm.
Do you care to tell me
where we're going?
(CLICKING)
Uh, first, we are going to BJ's.
We're going shopping?
No, we're not going shopping.
We are righting wrongs.
Then after that...
we're gonna wrong some rights.
Basically, this is gonna be
the best night of your life.
Okay.
I really don't wanna get into trouble.
You're a very anxious person,
aren't you, Q?
I'm not an anxious person. I just...
I have plans and goals.
None of which involve jail or dying.
Pull in here.
- So, what plans?
- Huh?
You said you had plans.
Uh... I just meant I'm going
to Duke in the fall...
then go to med school
and become an oncologist...
and obviously...
get married and have kids by 30.
- And then you'll be happy?
- Huh?
When you're 30 in 12 years.
Married, kids, career.
Then you'll be happy.
Is that actually what you're saying?
Um...
Yeah. I guess. Yeah.
Isn't there something
that could make you happy now?
Like, that's the saddest
thing I've ever heard.
Bingo!
Nair? Wait, why do you need Nair?
All will be revealed shortly,
my young friend.
Six months older than you.
Remember that?
Oh, really? Are you?
- Margo, don't.
- (BLOWS AIR HORN)
(CHUCKLING) Stop, stop! Don't.
- It's really loud.
- Don't. Stop.
- What? Were you trying to say something?
- (BLOWS AIR HORN)
You can't do that. Shh.
- Stop, stop!
What else do we need?
QUENTIN: Interesting capitalization.
MARGO: I'm a big believer
in random capitalization.
The rules are so unfair
to the letters in the middle.
(RAPID BEEPING)
It's not as weird as it looks.
Still weird.
QUENTIN: So what happened?
With Jase and Lacey and Becca?
Apparently, my boyfriend
of lo, these many months...
has been cheating on me.
What?
With one of my best friends.
Seriously?
Why would he do that?
Oh, next left.
Wait, this is...
This is Becca's house.
Yeah.
And there is Jase's car.
Margo, this is a bad idea.
No, Quentin.
This is a tremendous idea.
Margo. Margo.
(MARGO CHUCKLES)
Idiot never locks his car.
- Are you sure we should be doing this?
- (SHUSHING)
The Margo Roth Spiegelman
revenge plot begins.
Do you wanna do the honors?
No.
Suit yourself.
I can't believe you just did that.
We bring the rain down on our enemies.
"We"?
You'll see.
(IN FAKE VOICE)
Hello, is this Mr. Arrington?
Do you know what time it is?
I'm so sorry, but I just thought
you'd like to know
that your daughter is having sex
in your basement right now.
Goodbye.
- What was that voice?
- Let me use your phone.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Quickly.
(SIGHING) Here.
Get in position.
What do you mean? What do I do?
MARGO: Four...
Three...
Two...
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Take the picture, now!
Go!
- (SHUTTER CLICKS)
- (GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
Watch this.
What?
(CHUCKLING)
Well, that was fun.
QUENTIN: He totally saw me.
What? So?
So, he could kick my ass.
He won't.
What makes you so sure?
Let me see.
(MARGO LAUGHS)
What?
The Rhode Island of penises.
It may have an illustrious history...
but it sure isn't big.
(CHUCKLING)
Okay. Now we go inside.
No. What? No, no.
This fish is for Becca
and it goes in her house.
No, no. Come on, Margo.
We're gonna get caught.
We can't go inside.
I'll be lookout.
You can do whatever you want, Q.
Damn it.
- MR. ARRINGTON: What the hell was that?
- BECCA: Dad, I'm sorry, okay?
MR. ARRINGTON: "I'm sorry"?
That's completely unacceptable.
- BECCA: I really like him, Dad!
- MR. ARRINGTON: He does not love you!
BECCA: Yes, he does!
(SHUSHING)
(INDISTINCT ARGUING CONTINUES)
(UNZIPPING)
- MR. ARRINGTON: Who's down there?
- MARGO: Go, go, go.
MR. ARRINGTON: I have a gun!
(COCKING SHOT GUN)
(GUNSHOT)
- MARGO: Shit!
- QUENTIN: Are you kidding?
MR. ARRINGTON: Yeah, run!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(QUENTIN BREATHING HEAVILY)
Couldn't you have just thrown it
through a window or something?
We bring the rain,
not the scattered showers.
That was fun. That was pretty fun.
Yeah.
You okay?
I don't know.
I just thought maybe it wasn't true.
Ah.
Anyway, moving on.
Lacey's?
QUENTIN: Has Lacey been naughty or nice?
MARGO: Lacey has been
distinctly naughty.
We've been best friends
since the 5th grade.
And then?
And then, she didn't tell me about Jase.
Ready?
Ta-da!
Nice.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Unsentimental
Traveling around
Oh, my God, it's so late.
If you're tired, we can go home.
I thought so.
In the aisles of the grocery
And the blocks uptown
Who lives here?
Chuck Parson. (CHUCKLES)
Chuck Parson?
You didn't think a scumbag like Chuck
Parson could emerge unscathed, did you?
He's Jase's best friend.
He's an accomplice.
Uh...
Don't worry.
(WHISPERING) He's a heavy sleeper.
(SNORING)
(SOFTLY) Don't, don't, don't.
(WHISPERING) The 6th-grade dance?
Hmm?
Chuck told all the girls not to dance
with you and we all went along with it.
All of us.
I'm really sorry, Quentin.
No, it's okay.
That was a...
That was a long time ago.
Here.
No, thanks.
There's gonna come a time
in your life...
where you're gonna look back
on this moment...
(SHUSHING)
and you're gonna think...
"What do I regret more?
"Removing Chuck's eyebrow...
"or not removing Chuck's eyebrow?"
All right, give it to me.
What the...?
(YELLS)
(GRUNTS)
(MARGO LAUGHING)
Look at us. We're ninjas!
Maybe you're a ninja. I'm not a ninja.
You're a ninja too.
Just a really awkward one.
I can feel my heart beating in my chest.
That's how you know you're having fun.
(ELECTRONIC MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay. So what's this about?
Come on.
Well, at the end of a grand adventure...
one must pause and reflect
on one's achievements.
And the best place
in Orlando to do that...
is the SunTrust building.
- Stop.
- What?
- Stop it.
You promised me
no breaking and entering.
We're not breaking and entering.
We're just entering.
Very clever.
I can't get arrested tonight. Or ever.
You won't!
(SIGHING) It's the SunTrust building.
There's gotta be a guard or something.
Well, of course there is.
His name's Gus.
- You know the name of the...
- MARGO: Yep.
Of course you do.
Yeah, you know the name of the guard.
(DOOR OPENS)
- Hey, Margo.
- MARGO: Hey, Gus.
Do you mind if we go upstairs for a bit?
- Mi casa es su casa.
- MARGO: Cool.
Who's the kid?
- It's Q.
- Me?
I'm six months older than her.
- (MACHINE GATES RATTLING)
- (BEEPING)
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
Welcome to my office.
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
QUENTIN: Nice music.
MARGO: Soothing sounds
of corporate America.
QUENTIN: Whoa!
Come here.
Okay, so, over there is Jefferson Park.
QUENTIN: Mmm-hmm.
MARGO: All the lights are off,
so that's good.
And over here is Chuck's house.
- No lights, no cops.
- (QUENTIN CHUCKLES)
MARGO: Seems quiet.
I think we're in the clear.
(LAUGHS)
It's beautiful.
You think so?
Uh...
From a distance, I mean.
Yeah.
Everything's uglier up close.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
Not you.
(SIGHS)
It's a paper town.
Hmm?
Look at it.
All those paper houses
and paper streets and...
And the people, too.
I've lived here 11 years...
and I've never come across anyone
that cares about anything that matters.
Okay, I'll try not
to take that personally.
Here's a tip, Quentin.
You're cute when you're confident.
Less when you're not.
(SLOW JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHUCKLES)
Hey.
May I have this dance?
You owe me one.
(CHUCKLES)
Maybe things
would have been different...
if I'd hung out with you
this whole time.
It's not too late.
Whoa!
Hey, Margo.
What happens now?
Will things be different...
tomorrow?
(SIGHING HEAVILY)
I really hope so.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Me, too.
Okay, you see this?
This is your comfort zone.
It's this big, Quentin.
All the things
that you want in the world...
are way out there.
The way you felt tonight...
that is the way you should feel
your whole life.
(CHUCKLES)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
All right.
See you.
(SIGHS)
MRS. JACOBSEN: Hey.
Hey!
Morning, sleepyhead.
Been trying to wake you for 20 minutes.
Some dream you must have been having.
Getting you a date to prom is so hard
that the hypothetical idea itself...
is used to cut diamonds.
BEN: (CHUCKLING) That's a good one.
Q.
BEN: What are you doing?
What?
Nothing.
That was so weird.
I know it was you!
- Relax, relax.
- Yo, don't tell me to relax!
I know it was you at Becca's!
I'm gonna kick your ass!
Are you sure you wanna do that?
I mean...
Even if I enlarge it...
Put that away.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Wow.
I'm sorry. This is the part
where I get confused.
You did not hook up
with Margo Roth Spiegelman?
No, we did not hook up.
What?
I'm so confused.
What is wrong with you?
Me? What's wrong with you, bro?
Margo Roth Spiegelman,
2:00 a.m., she's single...
she's dancing, it's dark.
And you don't make the move.
I don't understand that.
It's not even like that. It's like...
(SIGHING) I don't know.
We were connecting.
We were on a mission. It was different.
So now what?
(BELL RINGING)
- I don't know.
- (GRUNTS)
I'll let you know when I see her.
(TEACHER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
You need aglets.
You need aglets to exist.
BEN: I get that you need them.
But to exist?
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
QUENTIN: But Margo never
made it to school that day.
Or the next day.
Or the day after that.
Guy heard her singing
karaoke in the mall.
Next thing you know,
she's signed to his label.
She's in New York right now,
recording an album.
I know for a fact she's in Iceland,
saving the whales.
No, it wasn't Iceland. It was Greenland.
GIRL: Where did you hear that?
QUENTIN: Like everyone else,
I started to wonder...
"Where the hell was she?"
What was she doing?
Who was she with?
Why wasn't it me?
MRS. JACOBSEN: I know this is
a difficult situation for you.
Hey, Mr. and Mrs. Spiegelman.
Hello, Quentin.
This is Detective Warren.
Sounds like Margo's run away again.
MRS. SPIEGELMAN: For the fifth time.
- Deb.
- What?
Hank, I am tired of this.
She's 18. Let her do what she wants.
What do you know about it?
- Hmm? Me?
- Yeah.
When was the last time you saw Margo?
Uh...
It was Wednesday, I think.
Yeah, Wednesday night.
She came to my window and we talked
for a second and then she left.
You guys don't think...
something happened to her,
or anything, right?
MRS. SPIEGELMAN: We know
exactly what's happened.
She's bored.
She wants attention.
She'll come back
when she runs out of money...
or when people stop talking about her.
WARREN: So you don't wanna
file a missing persons report?
MRS. SPIEGELMAN:
She's not missing. She's gone.
There's a difference.
QUENTIN: Yeah. Not your top candidates
for parents of the year.
But they weren't wrong about one thing.
If she was gone...
she wouldn't be found
until she wanted to be.
BEN: Yeah, whatever, bro. She left town.
There's plenty other honey
bunnies in the sea.
QUENTIN: What, like Fattina?
RADAR: Uh... Ha-ha!
Not "Fattina." It's "Bettina."
- Doesn't even sound like a real name.
- Yeah.
QUENTIN: What was her last name?
- I don't know.
- Just say her last name.
Three, two, one.
It was a one hit, and a quit.
- It was a "hit it and quit it"?
- Yeah. I hit that honey bunny.
I've told you guys this so many times.
I don't wanna go over this again.
Tell us. I wanna hear it again.
Cousin's house.
Right, Bettina was
your cousin. I forgot.
No! Bettina was not my cousin!
- You slept with your cousin.
- Not my cousin.
It's so hard when you wanna sleep
with someone that's not in your family.
No!
- QUENTIN: "I slept with someone in my family."
- No, no, no.
I just feel if we're gonna validate the
story, could we get a couple details?
All right, I'll give it to you straight.
So, I'm in Saskatchewan.
My cousin Danny's like,
"Yo, Ben, I'm throwing a party."
I'm like, "Yo, what's up? Let's do it."
So, he throws a party.
Bettina comes over, looks at me.
She's like, (IN SHRILL VOICE)
"What?" We go upstairs...
So, she's making strange noises?
- No, she's making a call.
- (MIMICS BIRD CALL)
Like a bird makes to another bird.
QUENTIN: So you walked in,
and Bettina went... (MIMICS BIRD CALL)
Mating time, bro. Mating time.
Just say something true.
What do you mean, "Say something true"?
Just say anything true.
I'm saying all this is true.
I so don't believe you.
It's true!
What, you don't believe me?
No, no.
That's fine. Go poop.
Shut up! Shut up.
We're not even talking about me.
We're talking about you and Angela.
- Little honey bunny.
- Don't call her "honey bunny."
- You gonna tap that ass, son?
- Don't call me "son."
- When you gonna get up in it?
- Don't say "tap that ass."
- Do a little dance for her.
- Stop.
Show her what you're
working with. Come on.
If you must know, we're...
We're waiting till prom.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
Why?
Because we want it to be special.
BEN: Radar, that's
so beautiful. I think...
I think I wanna be with you.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Stop.
- QUENTIN: Hey, guys.
- Stop.
Hey, guys.
What?
There's something in Margo's window.
BEN: Has that thing always been there?
QUENTIN: I don't know.
The shade's never drawn.
RADAR: "Woody Guthrie, folk singer.
"Born 1912. Died 1967."
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Come and sit by my side, if you love me
It's looking right at you, Q.
Do not hasten to bid me adieu
I know.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
- Hey, Ruthie.
- Hey, Quentin.
Your parents aren't home, are they?
No, they went to the mall.
Would it be cool if we went up
to Margo's room for a sec?
Why?
Just wanted to check on something.
Margo doesn't like people in her room.
Okay, but we're her friends.
No, you're not. And, if you were...
you'd know she doesn't like
people in her room.
(SIGHS)
She has every album ever made,
except Woody Guthrie.
(BEN SIGHS)
Up.
Sorry.
Mind if I...
Don't even think about it.
What are you guys
even looking for anyway?
We don't really know.
BEN: Clues.
We're detectives.
Hey, look.
Holy shit-stickers.
BEN: What do we got?
QUENTIN: "Walt Whitman's
Niece," circled.
- What do you think it means?
- Oh! Wait.
What?
I think she's sending you a message.
RADAR: What message?
BEN: "Come find me."
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (CHUCKLING)
Last night or the night before that
I won't say which night
A seaman friend of mine
I'll not say which seaman
Walked up to a big old building
I won't say which building
And would not have walked up the stairs
Not to say which stairs
If there had not have been two girls
QUENTIN: It's a call to arms.
It's a way of her saying...
"Take a risk, asshole.
Stop playing it so safe."
Maybe that's what she's been trying
to tell me the whole time...
like with the paper towns thing.
She's like...
"I'm making a move, Q.
"I'm going after it. Come with me."
So, if you crack the code
and find out where she is...
Can I talk to you?
Hi, Lacey.
You were with her that night, right?
The night with the Saran Wrap?
Yeah.
Was she mad at me?
Nah, she was...
disappointed.
In what? What did I do?
That you knew about Becca and Jase.
No, see, that... That's the thing.
I had no idea. If I knew,
I would've said something.
Okay, Margo seemed to think that...
She's wrong.
Yeah, I believe you.
It's just, Chuck knew this whole time,
which is awesome.
So, now we're broken up...
and I don't have a date to prom
the week before prom...
and my best friend is off
doing God knows what...
thinking that I betrayed her,
which is something I would never do.
I'm sorry to tell all of that to you.
No, it's okay.
I'm sorry, what did you say about prom?
Something about a date?
If you hear from her, will you tell me?
Why would I hear from her?
You were with her that night.
Her last night.
It has to mean something.
See you, guys.
That was the greatest
30 seconds of my life.
QUENTIN: Walt Whitman's from New York.
Woody Guthrie
lived in New York for a while.
Maybe that's something.
- You think she's in New York?
- It's possible.
Did she ever mention New York or...
No, she didn't mention New York to me...
but I didn't talk to her
for nine years, so that's...
Yeah, that's true.
I'm taking Lacey to prom.
- What?
- You're what?
You guys didn't see it?
We had a moment back there.
Must've missed that.
"Unscrew the locks from the doors."
It's a metaphor.
But what if it isn't?
What if it's instructions?
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hmm.
I thought there'd be a...
Just put it back.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Gravity to the second power.
Yep.
Radar, what are you up to tonight?
RADAR: I promised Angela
I'd take her shoe shopping.
Shoe shopping?
Yeah, she decided today that she doesn't
like the prom shoes she bought...
so I'm taking her to the mall
while their Midnight Madness
sale is still going on.
It's a pretty good sale
they got going on.
Radar, Radar, Radar.
I found something.
What?
An address.
It wasn't in Margo's doorjamb,
it was in mine.
8328...
Bartlesville Avenue.
That's not a nice neighborhood.
Okay. Still, we have to go.
But not tonight, obviously.
Wait, what? Why not tonight?
Because you're a rational human being.
And because you weigh 130 pounds
and don't wanna die.
You can't go to a strange building
in the Detroit-iest part of Orlando...
in the middle of the night.
All right, fine.
We'll go tomorrow morning?
But we have school tomorrow.
Not if we don't show up.
- Angela's gonna kill me.
- No, she won't kill you.
Every day I walk her to calculus.
She'll survive.
What about Lacey?
What if she's looking for me?
Has Lacey ever been looking for you?
We might miss something important.
QUENTIN: You're missing gym class.
Guys, seriously,
if you don't wanna go...
It's not that. It's just,
I've never missed school before.
Neither have I.
Yeah, and it feels kind of wrong.
I give you that. It does feel
kind of wrong. But it also...
(WITH BRITISH ACCENT)
...feels kind of right.
Am I right?
Using that voice
doesn't change anything.
Aw, but doesn't it?
It changes a little.
I think it changes
something a little bit.
Doesn't change it a little bit?
(IN BRITISH ACCENT)
We got no time to waste!
Yeah, see? We gotta go right now!
(IN ITALIAN ACCENT) Let's go find Margo!
(CHUCKLING)
Start the car, let's go.
BEN: Was that Italian?
- BEN: A full right?
- RADAR: Yeah.
BEN: You're terrible at directions.
RADAR: Whatever. This is it.
BEN: This is it?
Why would she come here?
(GRUNTS) It's locked.
- (STRAINING)
- (DOOR RATTLING)
Now what?
BEN: Get a rock?
QUENTIN: Margo?
Anyone?
Guys?
(QUENTIN SIGHS)
BEN: I think the last time
I was this scared,
I had to sleep with the light on.
Last time I was this scared,
I had to sleep with a stuffed animal.
I had to sleep in my mom's bed.
Q, if I were you, I would get
that scared every single night.
(CHUCKLING)
So, we're in a souvenir store?
No Margo.
For some reason,
she wanted you to come here.
(GLASS SHATTERS)
RADAR: This stuff is old.
Guys?
QUENTIN: Did you find something?
QUENTIN: Paper towns.
(GLASS CLATTERS)
BEN: Bro, can we go?
What if it's Margo?
What if it's literally anything else?
(CLATTERING)
Goodbye.
TEACHER: In a thousand pages,
they talk about whale anatomy...
and in the last 50 pages
the dude kills the whale.
So, it's not about
a dude killing a whale.
Maybe it's about a guy
who actually believes...
that if he chases this whale down
and kills this whale...
it's gonna give his life
some meaning. That's Ahab.
- It's a common misconception that...
- (BELL RINGING)
...a lot of people...
Don't forget, final papers
are due next week.
Also, pick up your pop quizzes
from yesterday on your way out.
You're not gonna be too happy.
No circling two answers next time.
Like I'm just gonna let you get the one
that you didn't mean.
Not cool.
There was a quiz yesterday?
Pop quiz. You missed it.
Is there any way that I can
get a makeup test?
It's one quiz, Quentin. Relax.
You can still be a doctor.
(CHUCKLES)
All right, get out.
Yes.
Okay.
Hey.
Oh, hey.
Anything?
Did she ever say anything to you about
an abandoned building on the west side?
Like, an old souvenir shop?
No. You think she'd be there?
I don't know, but I think she was once
and it's connected somehow.
- See you tonight?
- Oh. I don't know. Probably.
GIRL: Let me know if you need a ride.
Okay.
Party at Jase's.
I thought you weren't talking to Jase.
I'm not.
But you can still
go to a party at his house?
Everyone's going.
Not everyone.
BEN: We should totally go!
- Wait, what? Jase Worthington's house?
- Yes!
- Are you crazy?
- It's just a party.
We've never been to one of those.
- We've been to plenty of parties.
- No.
If there's a tuba there,
it's not a party.
All right. I don't believe this, Radar.
What about Angela?
Angela is a mature, intelligent,
understanding woman...
who never has to know about this.
I don't wanna go to a party
at Jase Worthington's house.
You guys can go.
Q, are you seriously gonna spend
the rest of high school pining
for a girl that ran away?
I'm not pining for her, okay?
I'm trying to find her.
Stop being an asshole.
I'm not being an asshole.
I'm trying to be
a regular kid for a change.
- Have fun.
- What?
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
(SCRAPING)
Hello, Quentin.
Margo, where have you been?
Everywhere.
Nowhere.
You have to get lost
before you find yourself.
People were worried about you.
No, they weren't.
I was.
You're sweet, Quentin.
You've always been sweet.
(KISSES)
I'm glad you're back, Margo.
But I'm not.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Are you gonna answer that?
(GROANS SOFTLY)
- Hello?
- BEN: Q?
Q, yes! Yes!
Quentin Jacobsen is inside
of my phone, everybody!
Ben, give me the phone.
Stop it!
- RADAR: Stop. Go lie down.
- BEN: Stop it! Gonna go party.
Go, sit down.
Hey, how soon can you get here?
It's chaos. We need you. Ben needs you.
No. I told you I'm not going
to Worthington's.
Plus, Ben's, like...
Ben's a dick.
You know what your problem is, Quentin?
You keep expecting people
to not be themselves.
You are not Ben. Ben is not you.
We're all different people.
That's why we're best friends.
All right?
Get in your van and get over here.
Besides, Margo's been in this
house a million times.
You might even find something.
(LOUD ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
I think we might be here for a while.
I'm gonna be back.
(PANTING)
JASE: You're so much better than her.
- BECCA: Yeah, Jase?
- JASE: Yeah.
Becca.
(DOOR CREAKS SOFTLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(URINATING)
- Who's there?
- Whoa!
- Hi. Lacey.
- (CONTINUES URINATING)
What the hell are you doing in here?
I'm just peeing.
Well, stop.
- I can't just stop like that.
- Okay, fine.
Finish and then get out.
Okay.
(CHUCKLING) Sorry about that.
(WATER RUNNING)
You okay, Lacey?
I've been better.
You wanna get in the tub with me?
Not like that.
Not like that!
Um...
Yeah, sure.
LACEY: Look at me.
Huh?
What's the first word
that pops into your head?
I don't know. I can't...
Come on.
Beautiful.
See, no. No.
Okay.
QUENTIN: What?
That's the problem.
No one ever looks at me
and thinks that I'm smart...
or clever...
or interesting, you know?
I have a brain. I'm going to Dartmouth.
So, uh...
Is that what you're upset about?
(EXHALES)
Becca and I got in a fight.
She called me a bitch and a whore.
And then she stood on a couch
and shushed the entire party
and told them I have chlamydia.
- Oh, man.
- Yeah. Which, I don't.
- Yeah.
- Anymore.
But, I'm not a slut.
I don't think you're a slut.
Thanks.
Don't even... Becca's just jealous.
Why would Becca be jealous?
She's dating Jase.
She's gonna be prom queen.
She's basically the new Margo.
No one will ever be the new Margo.
(CHUCKLES)
You're right.
No one could ever be the new Margo.
(DOOR OPENS)
Really?
- I hate that guy.
- Me, too.
- He's the worst.
- The worst.
Here, let me help you up.
Thanks.
Hey, if anyone gives you any trouble...
- I can't fight, but...
- Thank you.
Hey. I'm gonna catch up with you.
- Okay.
BEN: Valar morghulis!
RADAR: Dude, put your shirt on.
Get down.
- Valar morghulis!
- How much did he drink?
I think it's stuck to my hand.
Hey, Ben?
Yes, Quentin, approach.
I pronounce thee a knight
of the Hefeweizen Order, all right?
Thanks, Ben. Hey, we gotta go.
No, I wanna party.
I think I know where Margo is.
- Wait, for real?
- Yeah.
BEN: Lacey!
Lacey!
I have to tell you something, okay?
It's not the beer talking, okay?
It's the me talking.
I just needed beer...
to get the words
from my brain to my mouth.
I wanted to say this
for a really long time.
(GASPS)
(VOMITS)
RADAR: Ben! Hey!
QUENTIN: Ben? You all right?
Let's get out of here.
BEN: I feel so much better.
QUENTIN: Let's go, buddy.
- BEN: God save the Queen!
- RADAR: Stop.
BEN: Radar, I love you.
RADAR: Don't kiss me.
- Where are we going?
- You'll see.
BEN: I love you.
RADAR: It's not that shady-ass
shopping center, is it?
QUENTIN: What?
RADAR: Q!
Oh, God.
Isn't this far enough?
No. Come on, guys.
Let's sing a song.
What?
You don't get as scared if you sing.
Okay. What should we sing?
I don't know, anything.
Maybe just sing the first song
that pops into your head.
I wanna be the very best
Like no one ever was
To catch them is my real test
To train them is my cause
That's the first song
that popped in your head?
It's working.
I will travel across the land
Searching far and wide
Each Pokémon to understand
The power that's inside
Pokémon! Gotta catch 'em
It's you and me
I know it's my destiny, Pokémon!
Oh, you're my best friend
In a world we must defend
Pokémon! Gotta catch 'em
A heart so true
Your courage will pull us through
You teach me and I'll teach you
Pokémon! Gotta catch 'em all
Gotta catch 'em all, gotta catch 'em all
- Gotta catch 'em all
- (SCRAPING)
(SCREAMS)
Hey!
Oh... Jesus Christ.
Lacey?
You scared the shit out of us.
(GRUNTS)
What are you guys doing here?
What are you doing here?
I followed you.
I don't know.
I thought maybe you found her.
No, she's not here...
but I think I know where she might be.
Guys, come on. This way.
I wasn't scared before, back there.
LACEY: Okay.
Just love me some Pikachu.
I'm more of a Charizard girl.
What is it?
Margo hung something here...
and I think it was a map.
Okay.
QUENTIN: This is Margo's map.
And this is where she used to hang it.
So where is she now?
QUENTIN: Let's see.
She is...
somewhere...
in upstate New York.
Can you be any less specific?
This... general area.
Is there a town?
Let me see.
BEN: Yeah, there's...
There's nothing there, bro.
There has to be something there.
Roscoe, Rockland, Beaverkill,
Agloe, Chatham, Wallaceberg.
These are all the towns
in that general vicinity.
Are any of them paper towns?
What's a paper town?
It's a fake city that map makers
would put on their maps...
so if they get copied
illegally, they'd know...
- ...that they're being copied.
- Whoa.
What?
Agloe, New York.
"Agloe, New York, population zero...
"is one of the most famous
paper towns in America."
Look at this.
RADAR: "The present day population
of Agloe, New York, is 1."
She's in Agloe.
What?
RADAR: Agloe.
Q, you gotta go.
What?
That's where Margo is.
You need to go right now.
Were you listening, Ben?
It's New York. I can't go to New York.
Why? You have a car.
What is stopping you?
Like, 1,200 miles.
Well, there you go.
That's 1,200 miles between you
and your love of your life.
Because you love her, right?
Yeah, I do.
(LACEY LAUGHS)
There you go. Your true love waits.
QUENTIN: You're right.
I'm gonna do it.
- Do it!
- Wait, I wanna go.
Wait, what?
She's my best friend.
I'm going with you.
Okay.
If she's going...
I'm definitely going.
Okay, yeah. All right.
QUENTIN: Radar?
I don't know, guys.
Come on, buddy!
If we're all going,
let's just make this a trip.
RADAR: What about your parents?
What about school?
- Parents, bro.
- What about prom?
Who cares about prom?
We're not missing prom!
Okay, fine, we'll get back by prom.
You're really doing this?
(IN BRITISH ACCENT)
And we're doing it now.
Doing it right this damn second!
We got no time to waste, Radar.
Okay.
- Yes!
- LACEY: Yay, Let's go!
We gotta make a stop, first.
You know how I told you I was
staying in to watch the Cosmos marathon?
I lied. I was at a party.
Not only that...
but I drank a beer.
I didn't drink it, but I held it.
Girls were talking to me.
And now the guys and I...
Correction. The guys and I
and Lacey Pemberton...
we're driving to New York.
Wait, you're what?
It's a really long story.
Are you breaking up with me?
Am I...? What?
No, no, no.
I wanted to be honest with you
and I don't want you to be mad at me.
Marcus,
why do I get the feeling that
you're afraid of me?
I'm not.
That is... That's... What?
You pretended to like
that Ed Sheeran song
when I know you didn't.
It was mixed well.
You've never once invited me
to hang out with your friends.
That's more about them than you.
You've never even had me
over to your house.
- Uh...
- Why is that?
Hmm?
It's a story for another time.
I promise, Angela,
one day I will answer that,
but not today.
I'm not afraid of you.
I'm afraid of losing you.
Aw.
Marcus.
Angela's gonna come with us.
- Okay.
- ANGELA: Hey!
- LACEY: Hi.
- Hello.
Don't say anything stupid.
When would we ever?
This is definitely the craziest thing
I will ever do in my life.
Not if I can help it.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Embedded in a magazine
Embedded in a drama queen
RADAR: According to my calculations,
our average cruising speed should be 72.
You're going 64.
QUENTIN: I don't wanna get pulled over.
- We're not gonna make it.
- We're gonna make it.
We have plenty of time.
We're gonna make it.
Excuse me, I hope you don't think that
we're gonna be back
with 20 minutes to spare.
I have a hair appointment.
Angela has to get her nails done.
Do you know how long it takes
to put on a prom dress?
The answer is all day.
Plus, my parents wanna take pictures.
We have a limo coming.
We have to be back
with 12 hours to spare
or prom is ruined.
Prom is very important.
Thank you.
(QUENTIN EXHALES)
I have to pee.
- Ben.
- BEN: Lacey!
Oh, shit! I really have to pee.
Pull over.
No, we can only stop four times...
if we're gonna get there, find Margo,
and be back in time for prom.
How long have we been driving?
35 minutes.
I'll hold it. Yep. I'm gonna hold it.
- Good.
- BEN: I'll hold it. Yep.
- Nope, we gotta stop.
- No, we're not stopping.
Bro! You don't... (GROANS)
Just think about something else.
- Yeah.
- Like what?
- Like rainstorms.
- Or waterfalls.
- (LAUGHING)
- An exploding bladder.
That is not helping, Radar. Not helping.
70% of my body is urine.
I'm going as fast as I can.
RADAR: Not exactly true.
QUENTIN: I'm going
as fast as I'm willing.
Oh, my God, I think I'm gonna cry.
I'm gonna cry pee.
Oh, my God.
- QUENTIN: No.
- Here, pee in this.
No, do not get pee in my car.
- No, Ben...
- ANGELA: Gross.
- Hey! Do you want me to die?
- (UNZIPPING)
- Do you want me to die?
- (URINATING)
RADAR: Why? Why are you doing this?
It's so gross.
Radar, it's so good.
- Don't say my name.
- (CHUCKLING)
Radar, it feels so good.
Oh, my God.
Uh...
I'm gonna need another can.
- RADAR: No!
- LACEY: Grab it!
- BEN: Guys, another can...
- Take it!
I'm switching, I'm switching.
ANGELA: Careful!
So gross!
LACEY: It's nasty.
Yes!
What's happening back there?
- I'm Ben Starling.
- Oh, my God.
JPHS marching band.
Oh, my God.
Keg stand record holder.
And now, I am pee-in-the-car champion!
Ben.
I'm the greatest! I shook up the world!
(EXCLAIMS)
- No!
- (ANGELA GASPS)
Perhaps we should make
one of those stops now.
All right. This is how
this is gonna work.
RADAR: If we're gonna keep on
schedule, we have six minutes.
I'm the gas man. I start the fill-up...
you guys run inside
while the pump is pumping.
LACEY: I take the credit card
to the guy behind the counter...
and hold our spot in line.
BEN: I pee.
- Jesus, dude.
- What? I had a lot to drink.
ANGELA: I've got liquids.
RADAR: Q?
QUENTIN: Tortilla chips,
beef jerky, pretzels,
peanuts, Milk Duds, Twizzlers. Got it.
LACEY: And definitely,
definitely get cleaning supplies.
It reeks in here.
Whoo!
You like dragons?
No.
One minute!
RADAR: Someone better get me a shirt.
BEN: Me, too.
RADAR: As soon as the tank is full,
I'm honking the horn...
and all of you guys have
10 seconds to hop back in...
or I'm leaving your asses.
Except you, baby.
Aw.
You guys need a bag?
- Uh...
- (HONKING)
No, thank you.
LACEY: Go, go, go!
RADAR: Six minutes flat!
BEN: Get in, get in, get in!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Yeah. Nice.
I'm gonna need one of those.
Thank you.
Really?
Dude, I just grabbed them
out of a bin. I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
RADAR: You kidding me?
Last time you're going
shopping for me, Q.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
BEN: Yeah, it's better that way.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Coming to your house
Knocking at your door
You mind a sip of wine?
You cool me, cool me down
Do you know me you know me, you know me
Do you know me now?
Oh
The kid you used to be
Well, I know that you're still there
I hope you had a great summer
QUENTIN: Mom, I'm sorry.
It was super last-minute.
We're not going to New York City.
We're going to New York State.
It's way safer.
Just two days. I love you,
Mom. Thank you. Bye.
I hope you had a great summer
A great summer away
I still can't believe she hasn't called.
They probably don't
have phones in Agloe.
She has a cell.
How do we know that she's
even still in Agloe?
I just do.
I bet she's in the middle
of the Atlantic somewhere.
On some billionaire's yacht.
Maybe she's been back in Orlando
watching us look for her.
Nope. She's in Agloe. I promise.
I admire your faith. It's very romantic.
Thank you. I'm on a mission.
I'm Captain Ahab.
You do realize Captain Ahab's
not the hero of that story?
Only because he didn't succeed.
ANGELA: I don't think that...
BEN: Q! Hey!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SNORTS)
(MOOING)
QUENTIN: Is everyone all right?
I'm okay. Are you okay?
- Oh, my God.
- You guys okay?
- Hey, Ben, you okay?
- (ALL PANTING)
QUENTIN: Hey.
Hey.
Your face is bleeding.
What?
QUENTIN: Ooh. It's not that bad,
- (TEARING)
- It's just...
QUENTIN: Thanks.
(ALL LAUGHING)
QUENTIN: Thank you. Okay, bye.
All right. It's gonna be
a couple of hours.
All right. It looks good, considering.
Considering we didn't die.
- Yeah.
What happened?
There was a cow
in the middle of the highway.
Cow? It was a land whale.
And Ben, at the last second,
grabbed the steering wheel...
spun us to safety, saves our lives.
You were a vehicular ballerina.
I didn't know what I was doing.
It was the best damn
passenger seat driving
- I've ever seen in my entire life.
- Thank you.
Yeah, it's what I'm here for, so...
All right, now what do we do?
We wait.
I think we could probably
all use some rest.
Seriously.
QUENTIN: How we doing on time?
RADAR: I'll miss my hair appointment...
but a few hours won't hurt us.
BEN: Guys, before this week...
I think the craziest thing that we did
was sneak into Snow Dogs without paying.
(LAUGHING) Snow Dogs.
BEN: I love that movie.
Remember the time that we
stole your dad's cigars...
then we all smoked them
behind the house?
- You couldn't stop coughing.
- Yeah. It was gross!
That was disgusting.
- I don't think you're supposed to inhale it.
- Good times.
RADAR: Remember that time
when we were all
definitely gonna die but then Ben grabbed
the steering wheel and we didn't die?
Pretty awesome.
Thank you. Thank you.
Yeah, I can't believe it's almost over.
QUENTIN: The road trip?
High school.
We hate high school.
RADAR: He's right, though.
I've been thinking
about it a lot lately.
The lastness of it all.
The last time we'll ever
be together in the band room.
Last time we'll ever eat pizza
and nasty tater tots in the cafeteria.
Last homeroom, last science lab.
These are all terrible, terrible things.
That we're never gonna get to do again.
And, like, this stuff.
Hmm?
Well, I'm going to UCF.
You're going to North Carolina,
you're going to Boston.
We've known each other
since we were fetuses.
And it's not gonna be like that anymore.
And that's gonna suck for me.
Me, too.
Stop. You guys are bumming me out.
We can't sleep.
ANGELA: You wanna take a walk?
Sure.
- LACEY: Hey.
- BEN: Hey.
You cold?
Yeah.
Actually...
I'm feeling like I'm gonna probably
get some sleep, too.
Yeah.
BEN: All right, see you.
LACEY: Bye.
What was it you wanted to tell me...
back at Jase's house,
before you puked yourself?
(LAUGHS)
Nah.
It was something stupid, probably.
I don't know.
I didn't really know you then.
You're not kind of what I had thought.
What'd you think?
You know...
(CHUCKLING) What?
That you were hot...
and your face...
and torso.
I'm sorry.
Listen, you are all those
things, obviously.
But, um...
You're also pretty cool.
Drive all this way for your friend,
I don't know.
If you ask me, someone like Margo
doesn't really deserve you.
You know?
Would you wanna go to prom with me?
Yes.
(CHUCKLES)
Okay.
Yes.
(LAUGHING) Wait, say that again?
You're really gonna
make me say it again?
Black Santas?
I know. I know.
I know it sounds weird.
It's actually 20 times
weirder in person.
No, I think it's progressive.
(LAUGHING) No, you don't!
I do! Santa is a construct.
It doesn't make sense
that he's always an old white guy.
I think that it's cool
that your parents are willing
to embrace the complexity of that idea.
Yeah, I think about that
every morning...
when I eat my Lucky Charms
with a little black Santa spoon.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
You don't have to speak
Just keep me company
Be mine
QUENTIN: Cool. Thank you.
MAN: So long.
Hey.
What's that look on your face?
What? What look?
You look like...
You're acting very strange.
(SCOFFS) You are.
You got a weird little
grin on your face.
What is that about?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Scoot! Scoot.
Ben, did you notice something about him?
He looks kinda strange, like he's...
You're grinning or something.
What happened?
I have news.
What?
I'm going to prom with Lacey Pemberton.
- Holy shit! Really?
- Yeah.
- Congratulations, man.
- I know, dude.
Bloody Ben and Lacey Pemberton.
Angela and I had sex.
Dude!
- BEN: What?
- What?
You just had sex with Angela?
Bro, are you serious?
Yeah. Don't tell her I told you.
What are you guys talking about?
- Books.
- (CHUCKLES)
- Books?
I told them.
Bro.
I thought you could make it to Scranton.
I really did.
- Shotgun!
- Move!
All right, Radar, big man,
what's the ETA?
If we continue at yesterday's pace,
we should be there in four hours.
All right.
Dude, awesome. That leaves
an hour to find Margo...
tell her you love her.
Back in time for an amazing prom.
Agloe, here we come.
(ENGINE STARTS)
BEN: Hey! Check it out,
ladies and gentlemen.
RADAR: This is insane.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
On a drive I'm taking backroads
High against where
the rivers are flowing
I didn't think that our love had grown
Cross the bridge
To redefine your pain
Wide awake
I rearrange the way I listen in the dark
Dreaming of starting up again
RADAR: According to Omnictionary,
this should be it.
Margo?
(INHALES DEEPLY)
BEN: No?
QUENTIN: Let's look around.
Okay.
Yeah, all right.
(SIGHS)
How are we doing on time?
If we wanna make it back for prom,
we should probably...
go.
She'll be here. I know it.
- Q...
- She'll be here. I know it.
I know it.
It's time to go, Q.
He's right.
Guys, we can't give up yet. It's Margo.
She's probably sitting,
watching right now, laughing.
This is our final test.
You promised we'd be back for prom.
Not that again. Seriously?
I don't wanna miss prom, either.
Five seconds ago, you couldn't get a date
to prom if your life depended on it.
And now, suddenly, it's the end
of the world if you're not there.
Just because you don't give a shit about
prom it doesn't mean that nobody else does.
Prom is more important
than your best friend?
That's what you're saying?
No. That's not what I'm saying.
Why did you even come
if you're not gonna see this through?
Because I thought it would be fun...
because I wanted to spend time
with my two best friends...
before we leave for college
and probably never see each other again.
Yeah, wasn't this fun for you?
Not if I don't find Margo.
Don't you get it?
If I don't find Margo, it's not fun.
It's all for nothing.
(SIGHS)
Wow, okay.
What about you, Lacey?
Don't you wanna find her?
LACEY: I thought I did...
but you know what, Quentin?
I came all this way because
I was worried about her.
Do you think she'd do the same for me?
Would she do it for you?
Come on.
I'm gonna stay.
I'm gonna find a bus back to Orlando.
Have a great prom, everybody.
- Q.
- QUENTIN: No.
Go. Go.
Are you serious?
Q, let's go.
I'm not going! Okay? I'm not going!
All right, great. Good luck!
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
I'm trying to get home to Orlando.
- WOMAN: Here you go.
- Okay.
(EXHALES)
Margo?
Quentin.
Hi!
I knew I'd find you. I knew it.
I can't believe you're here.
How are you?
Wait, what? What do you mean
you can't believe I'm here?
I'm just a little surprised.
Wait, what are you surprised about?
I followed the clues...
I found that note
that you left in my door...
and then I saw the "You will
go to the paper towns..."
I read the whole Walt Whitman...
and, you know...
You left those clues for me, right?
Yeah, I always leave clues...
Yeah.
...so you'd know I was fine.
That I was okay.
I didn't think you would
come all this way.
Wait, what did you think?
Quentin, what are you doing here?
I'm in love with you.
You're in love with me.
Yes.
Quentin...
come on.
I've loved you since we were kids.
And I've never stopped loving you
every single day since.
You're not in love with me.
Don't say that.
You don't even know me.
Yeah, I do. Don't say that I don't...
I don't even know me.
Q, I have no idea who I am.
Why do you think I'm here?
I...
I thought...
Why are you here?
Can I buy you a drink?
Thank you.
I'd been planning to leave
for a while, actually.
I would graduate,
do the whole cap and gown thing...
and then, the next morning... Poof.
Into thin air.
And then I found out about
the whole Jase thing, and that was it.
I couldn't take another
second of that place.
It was really that bad?
You know what it's like.
Yeah, but...
I don't know. You had everything.
You were Margo Roth Spiegelman.
That's it. That's the problem, Q.
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
People have always looked at me
and seen what they wanted to see.
And yes, I know...
I cultivated it a little.
"The myth of Margo Roth Spiegelman."
But it's just a fantasy.
And there we were...
at the top of the SunTrust building,
looking down on the city.
And all I could think about...
was how I felt just as paper
as everything else.
Hmm.
So then you came here?
A paper town for a paper girl.
Not a lot to do, but it's a great place
to read and think.
Can I ask you something?
Of course.
Where do I fit in to all this?
You were my first partner in crime.
I wanted you to be my last.
And you surprised me that night.
You really did.
You're a way better ninja
than I expected.
You know, Q, I'm really sorry.
For what?
For all of it.
The clues.
Not being a better friend.
Ruining your last few weeks
of high school.
You didn't.
What?
You didn't ruin my last
few weeks of high school.
In fact...
I think they were
the best weeks of my life.
First party.
First road trip.
My first time cutting class.
Everybody else is doing things
for the last time...
but I was doing them
for the first. So...
don't apologize.
Because...
none of that would have
happened without you.
Are you sure you don't
want to come back?
College, job, husband.
The allure of a life rightly lived.
That's not me. You know it isn't.
So, what's the plan?
I have absolutely no idea...
but I'm excited to find out.
You know, you...
you may not be the myth
we made you out to be...
but you're still pretty something.
You're pretty something yourself.
You could come with me, you know.
You can't imagine how many times
I dreamed you would say those words.
But I have to go.
Hey.
Do you want to call your sister?
She misses you.
We talk every day.
(SIGHS)
I'll see you.
What a treacherous thing it is
to believe that a person
is more than a person.
Margo was not a miracle.
She was not an adventurer.
She was not some fine, precious thing.
She was a girl.
It took me a long time
to realize how wrong I was.
And not just about Margo.
I was wrong about a lot of things.
I used to believe
everyone gets a miracle.
And I still do.
But as it turns out...
my miracle...
was this.
Don't stop, no, I'll never give up
And I'll never look back
just hold your head up
And if it gets rough
it's time to get rough
They keep saying
Don't stop, no, it's never enough
I'll never look back never give up
And if it gets rough
it's time to get rough
But now I'm falling, falling
Falling, falling, falling
Falling, falling, falling, falling, oh
Now we're going down
And I can feel the eyes
are watching us so closely
I'm trying not to make a sound
'Cause I'll be found out somehow
Don't stop, no, I'll never give up
And I'll never look back
just hold your head up
And if it gets rough
it's time to get rough
Don't stop no it's never enough
I'll never look back never give up
And if it gets rough
it's time to get rough
So maybe we won't all win the lottery.
Or marry royalty.
Or make that last-second shot.
But that doesn't mean we won't
have amazing adventures...
Aw...
I want one.
...meet exceptional people...
(ALL LAUGHING)
and make indelible memories.
The trick is...
to notice.
Before it's too late.
Oh, and Margo?
Someone said they saw her in New York,
starring in a revival
of The Fantasticks.
Someone else said
she's on the West Coast
teaching surf lessons in Malibu.
I don't listen to those rumors anymore.
Wherever she is...
whatever she's up to...
I'm sure it's pretty something.
But, hey...
that's her story to tell.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I know it's not the right time tonight
But I won't move until this stops
Go back to the top
Back to the top
I'm not scared if you run to me
Lost like when you were mine
You can take what you want from me
Just don't offer me your time
Stay, life can be long
Wanna know, wanna know,
wanna know, wanna know it's true
When you say I want you around
Gotta make me believe you
I know it's not the right time tonight
But I won't move until this stops
Go back to the top
Back to the top
I know it's not the right time tonight
But I won't move until this stops
Go back to the top
Back to the top