Here, Charlie. More fortune cookies.
- Good luck!
- Thanks! What?
Next week, we'll be selling
Sanyo remote control VCRs for $299!
- Look, it's Dad!
- Oh, no! I'll go broke!
To give away Mitsubishi
giant-screen television sets for $1,299!
Oh, no!
We won't be undersold on microwaves,
videorecorders, ovens...
- Mom, you're not looking.
- Please turn that off.
Mom, when are you going to stop
being mad at Dad?
I mean, how do you think
that makes me feel?
I have certain unresolved feelings
about your father.
I don't trust him.
- And I hate those commercials.
- All right, forget it.
We don't have time
for another heart-to-heart.
Come on. You have to get dressed.
- I want you to understand it's insulting...
- Watch your hair.
...for him to go from me to that bimbo.
Do you think he really loves Janet?
Maybe he's just smashed
too many fortune cookies!
Mom, give me a break!
He's missing the reunion because of you.
You know he's dying to go.
At least we won't both have
a miserable time.
Let me see.
What do you think?
You are a very hip chick!
God, you look like you've stepped
right out of Life magazine!
I don't know.
What if nobody else there
is dressed like this?
So?
- I don't think I wanna go.
- Mom.
Everybody's just gonna say,
"Well, hey, where's Crazy Charlie?"
Lots of people are separated and divorced.
Not from the guy
with the lowest prices in town.
I feel ridiculous in this dress!
I'd like to change.
Why are you so nervous?
What's the matter?
Reunions do funny things
to people at this age.
- Hi, Peggy Sue! Beth!
- Hi.
Hi, Maddy.
How are you?
You two look
just like that soap commercial.
- "Which one's the mother?"
- "And which one's the daughter?"
You took this seriously.
You're a real blast from the past!
It was Beth's idea.
I wish I had the nerve. And the figure.
- Hi.
- Hi! Peggy Sue Bodell?
- All right.
- Mom?
Beth's boyfriend is with the band.
- Must run in the family.
- What does?
You and your mother.
You both seem to fall for musicians.
Mom, look!
Oh, God!
It's okay. Come on. Look!
Why don't you find a table?
We'll see you in a little while.
Sure.
God, Mom, that picture's great!
Come on, let's get a table.
- Is this good?
- Fine.
- I'll be right back. You be all right?
- Sure.
Thank you. We're gonna do
a little medley for you now.
- Come on, pose like your picture.
- What?
Hi, do you like it?
I figured as everyone has a gold Rolex,
I'd have one made in platinum.
- What a wonderful idea!
- How are you?
I'm fine. How many children do you have?
- I don't have any.
- You don't? I thought you did.
- No. How many do you have?
- I have four.
- Four?
- Four, yeah.
I'm so happy for you.
- I love them so much.
- How's Peggy Sue doing?
She was a mess,
right after they separated.
But I think she's coming out of it.
Seems to be friendly now.
I'm so glad.
Sometimes it's easier when you hate them.
- How about a little dance, princess?
- Walter!
- How are you?
- Good.
- Nice to see you. I'll see you later.
- Yeah.
Aren't you Peggy Sue Kelcher?
I was once. Richard Norvik?
I didn't recognise you!
You look terrific.
You look exactly the same.
I feel ridiculous!
I only did this for tonight, you know.
- It's adorable.
- Thank you.
Peggy Sue Kelcher, this is my wife, Sharon.
- How nice to meet you. Why don't you sit?
- Thank you.
But call me Peggy. Peggy Bodell now.
So, where's Charlie?
I was in town about a year ago
and I turn on the television...
...and I see Crazy Charlie.
It really made me laugh.
Charlie won't be here tonight.
- We're getting divorced, actually.
- I'm sorry to hear that.
Mr. Norvik!
Richard. Doug Snell, Merrill Lynch.
I read about that Codex deal
in Business Week. Congratulations!
Thank you very much.
Peggy, how are you? How's Charlie?
Hey, Terry!
- Thank you, Doug, thank you very much.
- Call me.
Madeline Hutton and Arthur Nagle
were high school sweethearts.
Married right after graduation,
they're still together.
Maddy. Arthur. How does it feel
to have missed the sexual revolution?
What? What kind of question is that?
That doesn't have anything to do
with the reunion, Delores!
Take it easy, kitten.
- Welcome to the singles scene.
- I don't know how you do it.
I've never even dated anybody but Charlie.
It's not that bad, really.
You just have to think of men like houses,
and trade upward.
I always thought that you and Charlie
had a really great marriage.
I think we did.
We just got married too young...
...and ended up blaming each other
for all the things we missed.
So he started having affairs
and you started getting depressed?
You just should have left here years ago,
like I did.
It's not so bad.
I've got two great kids.
I've got my own business.
Still, if I knew then what I know now...
...l'd do a lot of things differently.
Your damn computers
put me out of business.
You're right. He's drunk.
You're a billionaire
and I'm a goddamn failure.
No, the bakery's doing very well.
- Do you manage it?
- I own it.
I remember that dress.
Rosalie?
Oh, no. I remember that locket, too.
You were so excited!
I think you showed it to the whole school.
You have an incredible memory.
- It's beautiful. Does it open?
- Yes.
- These are my children.
- They're so cute!
Of course, they're not babies anymore!
But you were married
when you were three, right?
God bless you!
The best thing about being a dentist.
Pure pharmaceutical grade.
A couple of lines of this,
I could drill my own teeth.
Hi.
- Who's the guy with the eyes?
- Michael Fitzsimmons.
I used to have
such a crush on him in school.
- Peggy.
- Hi!
God, that Walter Getz can still dance!
Your first boyfriend!
Come on, tell me. Any sparks left?
Well, who knows?
I mean, remember,
whatever Walter wants...
...Walter gets!
I'm sorry. Sharon Norvik.
This is Carol Heath and Maddy Nagle,
my oldest and my dearest friends.
- Nice to meet you.
- Sharon is married to Richard.
- Lucky lady!
- Thank you.
Michael Fitzsimmons. Is he here?
No. No, I asked Rosalie.
She couldn't track him down.
- That's too bad.
- He must have been quite a guy.
Yeah.
You know, he is the only boy in high school
I wish I'd gone to bed with!
Only one?
Well, besides Charlie.
I hope the sales of your book go very well.
Anything anecdotal
you'd like to leave us with?
Yeah, every dog has its day.
Meaning what?
Peggy, would you please rescue Richard?
Ask him to dance.
Richard. Would you like to dance?
Of course I would.
So, are we through now?
- No.
- Good.
From snivelling runt
to pompous ass in 25 years.
That's quite an accomplishment.
I really cannot get over this.
The only time people like Delores Dodge
used to pay any attention to me...
...was to laugh at me or insult me.
- You know that guy Doug Snell?
- Yeah.
He shook my hand
when we walked in here?
He used to call me, "Four-eyed worm."
You showed them all.
You're rich and famous and successful...
...and you have a beautiful wife.
You were always friendly to me.
I appreciated that.
It's Crazy Charlie, the appliance king!
Hey, Charlie!
Look at you! You're putting on
a little weight, man!
You look great. Great.
So, this is the reunion? It's wonderful.
Like, wonderful!
Are you and Peggy still talking?
I mean, is it amicable?
She hasn't changed at all, Charlie.
- Your daughter's a real doll.
- "Why, I oughta..."
Hello.
Hello!
Can I have your attention, please?
Listen up! Can I have your attention?
I know everybody's having a great time...
... but now, you have to get ready for
that moment you've all been waiting for.
Dad? Hi.
The Reunion Committee has selected
a king and a queen.
Let's get back to business.
The Reunion Committee
has given this a lot of thought...
... and decided on two people
who best represent the spirit...
... of Buchanan High's Class of '60!
What are you doing?
The king is someone who,
in more ways than one...
... has come a long way since he left here...
... and we are especially proud
to welcome him back.
Richard Norvik!
Come on up here, King Richard!
I demand a recount!
That's gotta be Getz!
First you gotta learn how to count.
Hold me back!
Well, I just want to say thank you.
Sharon and I feel real welcome.
We're having a great time.
Boy, our high school
looks really good from up here.
And I just wanna say, it's good to be back.
Thanks a lot.
- Now, every king deserves a queen.
- Over here!
Not you, Getz!
Life of the party!
But when we sent out the invitations...
... we didn't mention anything about
this being a costume party...
... and perhaps we should've...
... because just looking at her
brings it all back!
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you our queen...
... Peggy Sue Kelcher Bodell!
Come on up here, Peggy Sue!
I can't. I can't do it.
Yes, you can.
Go on, you can do it. Go on.
You can do it.
Congratulations.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Mom!
Now, hold your arm up.
Would you like your Twinkie now?
Charlie?
I want to suck your blood!
I also want to suck your Twinkie!
- Am I dead?
- No. You are the undead.
Let's have it. You hate them, anyway.
Young man! You stop that!
Hey, I just made a deposit in your bank.
Now I want to make a withdrawal.
I think it's time for your next class.
- Go on! All of you!
- I'm a little worried about the side effects.
Now, you lie back down.
What am I doing here?
You passed out for a minute, that's all.
Nothing to worry about.
- But how did I get here?
- Why don't you let your friends help you?
Take her into the washroom
and splash some cold water on her face...
...and that should perk her up.
- Yes, ma'am.
How are you doing?
Blood drive? 1960?
Wanna smoke?
No, Carol. That's the worst thing for her.
I gave them up years ago.
- Where is it?
- Where's what?
Maddy, what did you do to your hair?
I'm taking you back to the nurse.
- Delores, why aren't you giving blood?
- I can't. I'm too anaemic.
Maybe you should drink
some of that nail polish.
It might give you strength.
Why don't you come back
and show me how?
We're going to take you home now.
That's okay.
I'm sure I can remember the way.
Steady now.
People get weak when they give blood.
It's wonderful Spring Radio.
At 1280 on your AM dial,
here's more from our golden survey.
And now from The Champs,
let's party with a little Tequila.
- I'll call you later.
- Yes! Let's keep in touch.
Who is it?
Peggy. Peggy Sue.
Come on in. I left the door open for you.
The nurse called
and said you'd be coming home.
I have a note.
- How do you feel?
- I was excused.
Why don't you go upstairs
and lie down for a while?
Oh, Mom!
Chanel No. 5.
It always reminds me of home.
Of course, dear. You're home now.
- You sure you're going to be all right?
- Yeah.
What is going on?
Nancy?
It's Nancy!
My baby sister!
- I'm so happy to see you!
- What are you doing?
Mom said you were sick.
You're never happy to see me.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry about that.
I want us to be closer.
I have too many unresolved relationships
in my life.
Teenagers are weird.
And you're the weirdest.
You wanna play a game?
Come here.
How about Monopoly?
Or Parcheesi. Or Chutes and Ladders?
I have a question.
Let me turn the tables on you.
Maybe you, down here, don't know.
Is there anybody in the house knows
where Dion and the Belmonts are?
I don't believe it.
Look at that man. He never ages.
Isn't Kenny Rossi dreamy?
I wish he'd break up with Arlene.
She thinks she's so great.
- Don't eat any of the red ones.
- Why not?
They're bad for you.
They give you red lips.
What the hell? I'm probably dead anyway.
Peggy Sue, get in here!
Dion's almost over.
I left your laundry on your beds, girls.
Don't forget to put it away, okay?
What's for dinner?
Creamed chipped beef on toast
with rutabagas.
Your father's favourite.
Not again!
Evelyn! Girls?
What is this out on the street?
Come and take a look!
Who left this out here?
- What is it, dear?
- Come on out and see for yourself!
Don't yell. Stop shouting.
It's cool!
- Dad!
- Wait until I tell Diane.
She's always bragging
about her dad's Cadillac.
What do you think, Peggy Sue?
Oh, Dad! You were always doing
stuff like that! It's funny.
It's really funny. You bought an Edsel.
Young lady, what's the matter with you?
Are you drunk?
Just a little. I had a tough day.
No, don't wear it out, Nancy!
We can't afford a new car.
Do we have to take it back?
I fail to see the humour of this!
Go to your room, you're grounded!
- Grounded?
- Put that down!
That's the story of my life! I'm an adult.
I'm going to go to Liverpool
and discover The Beatles.
Jack, take it easy!
She gave blood at school today.
- She's a little lightheaded.
- This is not giving blood! This is drunk!
Dad, I never knew you had
a sense of humour.
- Evelyn, put her to bed!
- Come on, Mom!
You're making a mountain
out of a molehill.
A tempest in a teapot!
My little baby.
Don't try to grow up so fast.
Mom, I forgot you were ever this young.
Sleep, baby.
Good morning.
What happened to your hair, Peggy?
You have such a pretty face.
- Why are you always trying to cover it up?
- I forgot.
- 'Morning.
Excuse me.
Nancy, put your homework down
and sit down.
You're looking bright and chipper
this morning.
I'm still here.
I thought I might as well enjoy myself.
I think I'll go to school today.
You know, Dad, I'm sorry about yesterday.
The Edsel is a classic.
Use it in the best of health.
Well, thank you.
But don't ever let anything
like that happen again.
You're far too young
to start acquiring bad habits.
I agree. You know, Mom and Dad...
...you are the best parents
a girl could ever have.
I'm really gonna try and behave myself.
Sure you will!
Come on, Momma, sit down.
You want me to sit?
I mean, isn't this great?
Just all of us here together!
Can I tell Charlie
Peggy Sue got drunk last night?
Young lady!
I forgot about him. What am I gonna do?
- Did you two have a fight?
- Sort of.
- About what?
- House payments.
Baby!
How do you feel?
Pretty strange.
Come on. Get in. I can take care of that.
I have a headache.
Headache?
You drive like a maniac!
It's not that I'm glad you were sick...
...but it just gave me a chance
to do some thinking last night.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. About what we said on Tuesday.
I think it makes a lot of sense.
- Refresh my memory.
- How could you forget?
We talk about seeing other people
and you forget.
I must have blocked it out.
Yeah. I guess I can understand that.
But, please, don't start crying again.
It's not gonna be forever.
I figure three years is long enough
for the music to pan out, which it will.
I know it.
So right after graduation we should...
...one: Start to see other people
so that we can...
...two: We can comparison-shop.
And then, three:
Settle down and get married.
Why wait? Why not break up now?
Because we got the prom coming up
and all these parties.
- We don't want to upset our parents.
- They'll learn to live with it.
Peggy Sue!
Peggy Sue, come here.
Peggy Sue.
Did you study for the test?
- Test? There's a test?
- Yeah.
All right, class. Time's up.
And what's the meaning of this,
Peggy Sue?
Mr. Snelgrove...
...I happen to know that in the future
I will have no use for algebra.
And I speak from experience.
- Who said that?
- I'm sorry.
Sit down!
The result of his struggle is
that Santiago comes back with honour.
Santiago comes back with nothing!
There's no meat on the bone.
It's Hemingway's ego
trying to defend itself again.
Trying to prove he can still perform.
What Hemingway's saying, Michael,
is that we are alone.
That when we go out too far,
we're vulnerable.
The irony that Santiago
is beaten by the sharks...
...doesn't make him less of a hero.
Who is the victim and who is the predator?
We'll finish this discussion next week.
And don't forget, first four chapters
of The Great Gatsby by Monday.
Hope you enjoy it.
Why does your father take inventory
on Sunday nights?
Hi, Peggy.
It's poker night.
You always got out of it before.
I just gotta string him along for a while.
It's for his own good.
You're not going into his business.
When are you gonna tell him?
Soon.
Walter!
I can't tell everybody everything
all at once.
Strange rumours
are sweeping the school about you.
Hi, Peggy.
What do you mean?
- I hear you gave it to old Smellygrove.
- I was there! She told him off to his face!
Attagirl, Peg!
Arthur, please don't call me Peg.
"Why, I oughta..."
I don't get it.
That's 'cause you're not
a total moron like they are.
It's a stupid movie thing they started.
That's enough outta you, little lady!
"Why, I oughta..."
I'll be right back.
Hi, Richard.
I wanted to congratulate you
on winning the math contest.
It really wasn't that difficult.
What are you doing?
You fishing for four-eyed worms?
Get lost, you macho schmuck!
I wanted to talk to you.
It's really important.
I'm not doing any tutoring this year.
I'm too busy.
No, it's not about that.
Would you meet me after school, please?
All right. I'll be in the physics lab.
Make it 4:30.
I have to go to a Rocket Club meeting.
Sure.
She's not wasting any time.
- Peggy Sue and Mr. Square Root.
- He's a nice guy. He's writing a book.
A book? Excuse me for a second.
Why is she punishing herself?
Come on, Peggy Sue. Try it again.
You haven't been practising.
Sorry.
What a girl, what a twirl.
Peg "Leggy" Sue Kelcher.
A brief but glorious career as a majorette.
Baby!
Looking good out there!
Thanks.
I love it when you twirl your baton.
I noticed you were giving me
the silent treatment at lunch.
I guess I deserved it.
I've been thinking
about my three-year plan.
I think it's totally unworkable.
I must have been delirious.
I don't know.
I thought it made some sense.
Well, in the abstract, maybe.
Get a good grip on yourself.
When I think about you going out
with other guys, I feel...
Rejected? Worthless? Miserable?
Yeah.
Good.
Boy, that's some kite!
I'm writing a book on kite construction.
So what do you wanna talk about?
I just wanted to ask you a question.
Do you think time travel is possible?
- Are you doing a science project?
- Sort of.
Well, that's a very interesting question.
Well, now, let's see.
If we look at this
in a Newtonian framework...
...the possibilities of time travel
were limited.
With the advent of the relativity theory,
that's Einstein's relativity theory...
...the idea of absolute time
cannot be reasonably affirmed.
Well, then we have Richard's burrito.
What's that?
That's my own theory,
based on a Mexican food called the burrito.
- I had one at Disneyland.
- I know what a burrito is!
You see, I think that time is like a burrito...
...in the sense that one part of itself
will fold over...
...and it will just touch the other part.
- What's inside?
- You can fill it with whatever you want.
You can fill it with memories,
with experiences, trigonometry. Anything.
Then you think
that time travel is possible for people?
Yes, it is. It is possible.
It's absolutely possible for people,
dogs, elephants, cancan girls.
Then I'm not crazy!
I really don't know if you're crazy.
I know most people think I am.
- Come here, Richard.
- What?
- Come on.
- What are you doing?
Wait a minute, what are you...
Now, I want to tell you something.
You have to promise not to tell anyone!
- Okay. I won't.
- No, I'm serious. No one else can know.
I won't.
I promise, I'm not gonna tell anybody.
I have come here from the future,
from 25 years ahead.
I think that you're probably crazy.
I don't have time for this.
I don't have time for jokes.
- I know what you people think about me.
- No!
And I don't appreciate it!
You're just the smartest guy I knew to ask.
I know it sounds unbelievable,
but I can prove it.
Well, proof is an excellent concept. How?
You have a blind grandfather.
You're gonna invent this machine
that reads books for the blind.
You're gonna invent a lot of things.
You're gonna be really famous.
Wait a minute.
How did you know about my grandfather?
Because I'm telling you the truth.
I read about your invention in a magazine.
I know a lot of things
that are gonna happen.
There's gonna be test-tube babies
and heart transplants.
An American...
...named Neil Armstrong
will be the first man to walk on the moon.
July 20, 1969.
1969?
That's six years ahead of schedule.
I would be very careful about this
if I were you.
What if you fall into the hands
of some madman...
...with plans to manipulate your brain?
- Well, that's why I was getting a divorce.
You know what I really think happened?
I think I had a heart attack
at the reunion and died.
- You look great for a corpse.
- I'm serious.
- You're giving me the creeps.
- Well, am I dead or not?
There's one way to find out.
- Give me this.
- What are you doing?
Confucians say, "If you want a way out,
go through a door."
There's a fire truck.
If you're dead, it'll pass right through you.
Now just stay there. You're dead.
Young lady!
No, I don't wanna die!
It's all right.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
I had it made into a cocktail ring, though.
This is good.
Well, there's not a whole heck
of a lot here.
- Very nice pieces.
- So, thank you.
I'll take them to the shop
and have the appraisal ready next week.
- Good day, Mrs. Kelcher.
- Good-bye.
- Who was that man?
- That was nobody, Peggy.
I'm voting for the Democrats this year.
You know how your father feels
about Democrats.
That was a polltaker.
I wouldn't mention it, if I were you.
How was school today, darling?
It was nice to see everybody again.
I don't know.
Everything they teach is so useless.
And the lunch! God, that was the worst!
Get that, Peggy.
- Hello?
- Peggy Sue? This is Grandma.
- Grandma?
- How's my little girl been?
- Grandpa and I are very concerned.
- What's the matter?
What's up?
- It's Grandma. I can't talk. I'm sorry.
- What's wrong?
Mom, I'll call you back. It's Peggy.
It's okay. I'll call you back.
Peggy Sue, what is it?
What happened to you just now?
What is this all about?
I dreamed that Grandma died.
Oh, baby. No wonder you're so upset.
She's getting on, it's true, but she's fine.
I told her
you weren't feeling well yesterday.
She called to find out how you are.
I love her so much
and I haven't seen her in so long.
- Grandpa Barney, is he all right?
- He's perfectly fine.
You saw them at Easter.
What's this all about, Peggy?
I don't know. I forgot.
- I'll call her tomorrow. I'll apologise.
- Good girl. I hate to see you so upset.
You're my angel.
Peggy, I don't mean to be intrusive.
But are you having problems with Charlie?
You mentioned something this morning.
A lot of things are confusing right now.
Charlie's just one of them.
Is Charlie pressuring you to do things
you don't think you should be doing?
What do you mean?
Peggy, you know what a penis is.
Stay away from it.
You're the best.
Make her love me, okay?
Feed me. Charge me.
Go get her, tiger.
Get the door, Jack!
Just a moment!
Hello, Charlie.
- Hello, Mr. Kelcher.
- Come on in.
- How are things at the hat store?
- Very good.
Charlie, could I have a word with you?
- Something wrong, sir?
- No, not a thing.
I'd just like to talk to you.
Hi, Mrs. Kelcher!
- How do you do today?
- Good.
- You look wonderful. Snap, crackle, pop.
- They're delicious.
Sit down, Charlie.
Nancy.
That sounded really great, Nancy.
Charlie, you may have noticed that...
...Peggy Sue has been acting
a little bit strange lately?
- Indeed.
- She's distorted!
Nancy, please.
She seems to be
a little bit nervous and confused.
Over-emotional and even a little bit
irresponsible at times.
Of course, her mother says,
"That's the way girls act sometimes."
She's almost a juvenile delinquent.
- No!
- Out!
"Why, I oughta..."
Oh, God!
Yes, sir, but I think that's what I like
about Peggy, Mr. Kelcher.
She's not like all the other girls at school.
Charlie, in spite of your adolescent
infatuation with music...
...we've always regarded you
as a very fine young man.
- Thank you, sir.
- And we've trusted you with our daughter.
Well, trust is a two-way street.
In the past two years...
...l've been pleased to note
that you and Mrs. Kelcher...
...have provided your sacred trust
with upbringing the woman...
...that I plan to take off your hands.
Charlie's downstairs.
Why aren't you ready?
- For what?
- For Maddy's party, that's for what!
Mom, I don't feel like going to a party.
Feel or not feel, you accepted the invite.
Maddy's one of your best friends.
I baked the Rice Krispie squares.
You're supposed to be doing
your homework.
I need to talk to your sister.
Baby.
Try and enjoy yourself.
This is the best time of your whole life.
The sooner you learn to handle Charlie,
the better.
Stand up to Charlie.
Be a good girl.
Wear something cheerful. Perky.
We think this party might cheer her up.
As long as you understand
what's expected of you.
What would that be?
Show her a good time,
but for heaven's sake, restrain yourself!
Of course!
- Hi.
Charlie?
Your sweater!
- It's great, isn't it?
- It's really '50s!
It's like you clash with the whole world.
What's the fun of being a teenager
if you can't dress weird?
- Good night, Dad.
- Good night!
- Good night, Mom.
- Be good, dear.
- Good night, Mr. And Mrs. Kelcher.
- Good-bye.
Have a good time, youngsters!
Nancy.
You look really beautiful.
Thank you.
- I cleaned the car. Do you like it?
- Yeah, looks better at night.
I got tickets for Fabian on your birthday.
You like him, right? Yeah, he's cool.
I was thinking of four ushers
and four bridesmaids.
The Yankees have the pitching,
but the White Sox have defence.
What will your colours be?
Kubek and Richardson any day
over Fox and Aparicio.
Pink and green.
- Look, Carol!
- What?
Look at Delores. What a tramp.
My God!
I think that pitching wins pennants.
The Tigers have got four
twenty-game potential winners.
You'd be surprised
at how many girls in school aren't virgins.
Like who?
Don Mossi, Frank Lary,
Jim Bunning and Paul Foytack.
- Hello?
- Hello!
And now, direct from four weeks
of rehearsal in Walter's garage...
... four guys who have prided themselves
on becoming the best group in the world.
Walter, Leon, Terry and Charlie,
The Definitions!
Charlie can really sing!
Maybe they'll be
the next Dion and the Belmonts!
I wouldn't count on it.
Come on! Where's your enthusiasm?
He really is kind of cute, isn't he?
Yeah!
He really loves you, too. You're so lucky!
He's always telling Walter
how wonderful you are.
- He is?
- Yeah!
Carol and I saw you
with that creep Richard Norvik today.
First of all, he's not a creep.
He's exceptional.
You'd know that if you took any time.
You just pity him since he has no friends.
If you weren't so neurotic and insecure...
...maybe you could shut up
and show some compassion.
Are you for real?
I don't know what you said to her,
but I wish I'd said it.
Hi, fellas.
Walter!
- What do you think about Richard Norvik?
- He's a nice guy.
Is he going to help you
with all that physics stuff?
He's trying.
Who needs physics
when we've got chemistry?
Put on some make-out music
and turn out the lights!
There's not a girl in school
that can hold a candle to you.
You're pretty charming
when you want to be.
I know. But I don't have to flatter you.
It just feels right.
You're the perfect girl for me...
...as in: Is, was...
...and always will be.
I'm glad dancing was invented.
You know, the first dances were rituals.
Like fertility rites.
I always loved the way you kissed.
I missed you.
Your eyes look like silver pools
of moonlight.
And the tide rushes in.
You really love me, don't you?
You know I do.
I even wrote you into my will.
Charlie, let's make love.
What? You mean sex?
Intercourse.
You want to have intercourse?
Last weekend you said... What time is it?
Holy cow, it's late!
A lot of things have happened
since last weekend.
You were the one who said we should wait
and you were right.
We should wait till we get married.
I know I must have believed that...
...when I said it, but...
...doesn't Lucky Chucky want to come out?
- Who?
You know, your love machine.
Your throbbing thrill hammer. Your thing.
You mean my wang?
Listen, it's running real late!
Come on! What is this?
What the hell is going on, Peggy Sue?
One week you say,
"If you love me, you won't."
The next week you say,
"If you love me, you will."
That's a guy's line!
Forget about it. I made a mistake.
You're damn right!
Jesus, Peggy,
you sure know how to spoil a mood.
I'm sorry.
Save it, woman! Humiliator!
I was very impressed with what you said
in English class today.
Gilford's okay, except that he thinks
that Hemingway's great literature.
And you don't?
He's a fisherman.
The most overrated writer of the century.
I mean, man,
he is the perfect American author:
Fat, violent, drunk.
Maybe you're confusing his life
with his work.
A writer's life is his work.
Jack Kerouac doesn't have to kill a bull
to have something to write about!
I mean, man, he's out there burning,
feeling, grooving on life!
"The young man leaned back in his chair.
"No bulls would die today."
What are you doing here, anyway?
Coffee, donuts.
I thought chicks like you travelled in packs.
Man, I'm a hip chick.
- Come on, Delores.
- Terry, slow down!
What?
Look, there's Peggy Sue
with Michael Fitzsimmons!
- That Commie beatnik?
- First a geek and now a weirdo!
This is great.
This is great reefer.
It must belong to Beth.
I found it in my dress. It's really old.
It travels well.
Well, the world sure looks better up here.
The world is fantastic.
It's the ultimate absurd circus.
And I am shot from a cannon
into the energy.
What are you shooting for?
Maximum intensity.
I'm going to get out of here.
I'm going to write.
I'm checking out of this bourgeois motel.
Push myself away from the dinner table
and say:
"No more Jell-O for me, Mom!"
Don't you get along with your parents?
All my father digs is money.
All my mother cares about
is her standing at the country club.
Come on! They care about you.
- They're just a different generation.
- What's with you?
I thought you were cool.
You rode my bike. You blew some pot.
What's your scene, Miss Majorette?
You going to marry Mr. Blue lmpala...
...and graze around with the other sheep
for the rest of your life?
No. I already did that.
I want to be a dancer.
That's what I want to do.
I'm going to dance and dance.
Come here.
You know, I had you pegged all wrong.
"Ray of oneness piercing the solitude
"Falling bodies in the ecstasy of flesh"
Is that one of your poems?
No, I just made that up.
- Do you want to hear one?
- Yeah.
It's called Tenderness.
"I couldn't sleep so I thought I'd scream
"Betrayed by a kiss
Sucking pods of bitterness
"In the madhouse of Doctor Dread
Razor shreds of rat puke
"Fall on my bare arms"
I'm sorry. I was trying to impress you.
Michael. You're as good as you looked.
"How many loved your moments
of glad grace
"And loved your beauty
with love false or true
"But one man loved the pilgrim soul in you
"And loved the sorrows
of your changing face"
I didn't write that. That's Yeats.
I envy you.
You have your whole life ahead of you
and you know exactly what you want.
But no more rat puke, okay?
Try and write something beautiful.
I'll respect you for eternity.
You know, this really isn't happening.
- And one Shostakovich.
- Shostakovich?
Charlie, I'm just taking Ravel!
Listen. Take the Shostakovich home.
Listen to it. Let it grow on you.
If you don't like it
I will give you your money back.
I did like the Dvork one you suggested.
I liked that a lot.
And, young man, you talked me into it.
It's the most definitive Dvork!
You'll like it. I kid you not.
- What do you know about classical music?
- Nothing. But selling is selling.
Charlie, about last night...
Hush, baby, hush. I've been thinking.
Girls must go through that stuff, too.
Sometimes when I look at you
I feel like an animal.
I don't know. Maybe my dad's right.
Teenagers are nuts.
But I'm not.
I'm a grown woman with a lifetime
of experiences you can't understand.
Girls mature faster than guys.
But last night,
I was the one who put on the brakes.
- And do you know why?
- Why?
Because nothing else matters.
That's the great thing about love.
Every time we argue...
...every time something goes wrong,
and I know I'm not perfect either...
...things just work out better in the end.
Because you're my baby. And I love you.
Charlie, what am I going to do with you?
Boy! Just cherish me.
You have an opportunity
to be the richest woman in the world...
...and I'm going to be your partner.
I'll tell you where the fortune is:
Running shoes...
...tennis and jogging shoes,
all that kind of stuff.
I mean, I'm talking $50, $100, $200 a pair.
- Wait, you got to be kidding.
- No!
You're talking about exercise stuff?
Like gym stuff?
Not your style.
These are the choices, okay?
Microwave ovens, pocket calculators...
...Walkmans, digital watches...
...and miniature television sets.
And huge radios.
For some reason everything else gets tiny,
but portable radios get enormous.
Huge, enormous radios?
- Portable enormous radios.
- Wait a minute, I got an idea. Come on!
- What?
- Come on!
Come here!
Here.
- Excuse me, miss.
- Yes.
- Do you have pantyhose?
- I'm sorry, what?
Pantyhose. You know...
"Pantyhose"?
Why, Richard!
This is lingerie.
Mrs. Woodhouse, I am studying the fabric
for the aerodynamic principles for kites.
They don't have it!
They've never heard of it.
Isn't it wonderful?
- What?
- I'm talking about the wave of the future.
I've decided on our first fortune.
- I'll see you later.
- Okay.
You just keep thinking high tech.
"High tech"? That's nice.
I like the sound of that. High tech.
- All right, what is the scoop?
- What?
How come we're your friends
and we find out about...
...you and Michael Fitzsimmons
from Delores?
Who needs satellites
when I've got Delores' mouth?
I hear she does more than talk
with her mouth.
That's disgusting!
Maddy, would you grow up?
It says in Love Without Fear
the tongue kiss is a means...
...of genital stimulation, is widely practised
and has much to commend it!
Did you memorise the book
or just the good parts?
No. Just what you underlined.
You did!
You know, Carol, you have great hair.
Peggy Sue, come on!
What's with you and Michael?
Yeah, come on!
He's so cool and mysterious.
Well, he's interesting.
Underneath that rough exterior
lurks the heart of a true poet.
A poet?
I bet Delores told Charlie!
- That loudmouthed little bitch!
- Peggy Sue!
Watch out for her, Peggy Sue.
She's after Charlie.
Just cool it, girls.
Charlie's free to go out
with whoever he wants to.
What?
But I always thought
you were going to marry Charlie.
Carol would marry Walter
and I'd marry Arthur.
We'd all live on the same street and...
...take our kids to the park together
and have barbecues every Sunday.
It's going to spoil everything
if you and Charlie break up.
That Michael Fitzsimmons
doesn't look like the barbecue type.
Come on! I just had one date with him.
I'm not going to marry him!
You promise?
Come on, let's go to the movies.
Peggy Sue, I mean, don't be silly.
It's Saturday night. It's date night.
I got to go. Arthur's picking me up soon.
Wait a minute. No, I mean just the girls.
Like a slumber party.
- Aren't we too old for that?
- Sometimes you're so immature.
Well, we...
'Bye!
I'm immature?
Charlie? Charlie, I had such a dream.
Peggy Sue, I have to talk to you.
Charlie, what are you doing here?
Let's go down to the basement.
Okay.
I want to know what's going on.
Delores told me about you
and that scuzzball Michael Fitzsimmons.
When you dropped me off last night
I didn't feel like going to bed.
- And I ran into Michael and went for a ride.
- Then it's true, damn it!
I had a miserable time tonight
because of you.
When the Monotones did Book of Love:
"Chapter four, you break up
Won't you give it one more chance?"
I'm thinking, "Did we break up?"
Did we break up?
Because if we did
I don't even know about it.
Did that Maynard G. Beatnik
give you what you wanted?
You know, I hate your sarcasm.
You're going to blow it, Peggy Sue.
No one treats Charlie Bodell like this.
Why do you talk about yourself in the third
person like you were Napoleon?
- Why is everything an argument with you?
- Look! I've got the hair.
I've got the teeth. I've got the eyes.
Peggy, look outside that window.
I've got the car. I'm the lead singer.
I'm the man.
Why are you arguing with me?
It's over, Charlie. I don't want to hurt you.
I want you to be happy.
But, no. I will be happy if I have you.
I love you.
No! That doesn't make any difference.
We just can't live together.
And you went off with that bimbo Janet.
What are you talking about?
Who is Janet?
- I don't know any Janet.
- I just can't trust you!
But what about everything
I said to you this afternoon?
That's exactly what I'm talking about.
I have this window in my heart
and anytime you want, you can crawl in.
I got to close it
or nothing's going to be different.
- What has to be different?
- Everything!
You know it's not going to work like this.
You have to go to college and finish.
What about the group
and my singing career?
What about me?
I am trying to save you years of frustration
of waiting for...
...that big break. No.
That big disappointment so you can
blame me for the rest of your life.
You don't know zip.
You think I'm going to spend
the rest of my life selling appliances?
Chasing women around the store
like my father?
I've got to give it a shot.
What the hell has changed, Peggy Sue?
Until yesterday you loved me
and you loved us.
For two years,
I've done nothing but love you.
All right, I'll prove it to you. I'll show you.
I'm going to be just like Fabian.
Let's sit there.
Sure.
This is great.
Okay, here we go.
- Suds for you.
- Thank you.
And a whiskey for you.
Five more weeks of school.
Ten minutes past graduation, I'm gone!
To freedom!
For everyone.
Now, this is the plan.
As soon as school is finished,
we move to Utah.
Utah?
I thought you'd be going to Paris
or New York.
What's in Utah?
Rita. I met her last summer. She's cool.
You'll really dig her.
She's got this little cabin outside the hills
of Provo where she raises chickens.
I'll write, and you two can take care
of the chickens to support us.
- I can't do that.
- Why not?
Polygamy's legal in Utah.
I'm allergic to chickens.
Wait. What about the other night?
We were like two stars
in the same constellation.
Michael, you and I are light-years apart.
You should go, but not with me.
But we had heat, baby. Passion! Fire!
We owe it to ourselves to fuse together.
At least one more time.
That's a great line.
You are going to be a terrific writer.
- You think so?
- Yeah.
Michael,
we had one glorious night together.
Someday you'll remember
and write about it.
Yeah.
I can dig that.
Bittersweet perfection.
Dogs of lust on leashes of memory. Yes!
It's Charlie.
What a treat.
Now I get it.
It's great.
Peggy Sue's still stuck on
"Treble Without a Cause."
Come on, I want to dance.
I thought I knew everything about him.
Can we split now?
Thank you.
So, Mr. Wilkins, new client?
I'm sorry, Charlie.
I don't think so, you know.
It happens, but not with you.
Believe me when I tell you.
Maybe it's the material.
But it can't happen.
Good morning.
Charlie?
What are you doing here?
I wanted to talk to you.
I've got one last thing
I have to do at school and then...
Elvis. Hi. How are you? Hi, guy.
Elvis is dead. That's Ajax.
I guess I always liked Elvis.
- Can I have a ride to school?
- No.
- Why?
- The tiger's out of commission for a while.
Come on.
- How about a walk, Charlie Bell?
- How did you know about that?
I was at Lena's last night.
I heard you sing.
I thought you were terrific.
Not terrific enough.
What were you doing there?
- Who were you with?
- Well, what were you doing there?
You never told me you sang
with an R & B group.
There's not a whole heck of a lot
we know about each other, Peggy.
- I forgot how much music meant to you.
- That's real big of you.
Stop being so defensive. Here.
I wrote a song for you.
- Why did you write me a song?
- Because I want to help you.
- It'll be a hit. I promise.
- Come on! Stop being sarcastic.
Lee Wilkins came to hear me last night.
He told me to forget it.
Would you just take a look at it?
Come on. I wrote it for you.
Well, if you wrote it I guess I'll look at it.
Listen, about the other night,
I feel so stupid.
I'm beginning to think that maybe
there is more to life than just music.
Do you think the world would still like me
if I stopped being Mr. Excitement?
Yeah.
Do you want to walk to school?
Okay, I'll just put the dog inside.
Come on, Ajax.
What's the matter, princess?
Lost your prince?
Delores, there are a lot of things
I could say to you...
...but you're just not worth the effort.
- I'm so sorry. These pens are so tricky, I...
- You did that on purpose!
I hate you! Go stuff your bra!
- I beg your pardon?
- Take a long walk on a short pier.
Have a nice day.
You know, Peggy, there are so many things
to look forward to in the future.
I came to say good-bye, Richard.
Good-bye? Wait a minute. Sit down.
Good-bye? Where are you going?
Peggy, we have a partnership here.
- I'm making progress on that microchip.
- Well, you were meant to.
You're one of the people
good things happen to.
So are you.
- You have a vision, Peggy.
- A vision?
I am a walking anachronism!
I've upset my parents. I miss my kids.
I could be trapped here forever.
And poor Charlie.
I got pregnant when I was 18.
That was why we had to get married.
Tomorrow's my birthday.
- I have to get out of here.
- You broke up with Charlie?
Yeah. I know it's a gamble.
I've loved him for a long, long time.
Okay. Then let's do something
really visionary.
Change your destiny, Peggy Sue.
Change your destiny and marry me.
No! Peggy Sue got married.
Case closed.
I don't want to marry anyone, Richard.
Good-bye.
Wait! Peggy, please. Can I go with you?
No! You have to be valedictorian.
Peggy Sue, wait a minute!
Listen, I cut shop
and I did some work on your song.
You know, it's not half bad
for your first try.
I changed all the "yeahs" to "oohs,"
but listen to this:
"She loves you, ooh, ooh, ooh
You love me, ooh, ooh, ooh"
I got to go.
About your birthday.
I made reservations at Chez Trev.
I thought it would be great to eat
at a nice restaurant.
I won't be here.
- Why?
- I want to go see my grandparents.
Good-bye, Charlie.
I cancelled the tickets for Fabian.
Close that.
- There you are.
- Thank you.
Look! Oh, it's so beautiful.
What's the matter, Peggy?
Someone jump on your grave?
You know, Peggy, your mother said
you had a dream that I died.
I wish she hadn't have told you that.
I'm not afraid.
I know exactly when I'm going to die.
What's it going to be, Lizzy?
Seventy-five or eighty?
I'm not telling!
I've been trying to drag
that out of her for years.
You know,
dreams are a fascinating business.
- Especially when you see the future.
- Do you believe all this?
Well, I like to speculate.
Like this book I'm reading right now.
It's about a woman in Colorado who says
she lived in Ireland 150 years ago.
She gives names,
dates and where she lived.
Grandma. Grandpa.
I want to tell you something.
If you believe it, darling, then I believe.
Being young is just as confusing
as being old.
The things that happened to me
50 years ago...
...are more on my mind
than the things that happen today.
But I'm remembering the future.
A chilling wind tonight.
It's really picking up.
Right now,
you're just browsing through time.
Choose the things you'll be proud of.
Things that last.
I'm proud of my children.
I miss them so much.
Scott and Beth.
I named my daughter after you.
Sweetheart, thank you.
Grandpa.
When you and Grandma are gone,
the family's gone.
And I'll never see the cousins anymore.
It's your grandma's strudel
that's kept this family together.
If you could do it all again, Grandpa,
what would you do different?
I'd have taken better care of my teeth.
Now what's Peggy Sue going to do
at your lodge meeting?
It's her 18th birthday
and I want to show her off.
It was my idea, Grandma.
I wondered about those lodge meetings.
He won't tell me.
But I have my suspicions.
I don't want to know.
Have a good time, darling.
All right.
- Good-bye.
- Good-bye, darling.
Grandpa?
What does Grandma think you do
at these meetings?
Stag movies and poker.
I may be an old fool,
but I think I can help you.
At least I got to see you
and Grandma again.
Has this ever worked before?
The last time was 600 years ago.
And it's about time for another one.
Welcome, Peggy Sue!
Peggy Sue! Welcome, Peggy Sue!
- It's so wonderful to have you here with us.
- Thank you.
You've come to the right place.
Our lodge was founded by a time traveller.
- We're going to send you back home.
- That's right!
You know, this is very exciting for all of us.
You know, we've waited a long time
to find a girl like you.
Yes!
Grandpa! Do you have to wear that hat?
Wouldn't be a lodge without hats.
"Lord of the universe.
"Vast and mighty one.
"Ruler of light.
"King of the sun.
"This girl is lost amid your mysteries...
"...and wishes to return to her own time.
"We adore thee and invoke thee!
"Grant thine aid.
"Look with favour upon us
as we witness the regeneration of spirit.
"We ask thy intervention...
"...that this girl may return to thee
on the wings of thy love."
"Womb of the mother,
reclaim thy child of light."
"The name of your love is rebirth."
- This is never going to work.
- It's going to work!
"Reclaim thy child of light."
"We offer up this girl
that her soul may find its home."
It's nothing to worry about.
Somebody get the lights.
Somebody get the lights!
She's gone!
What the hell do you think you're doing?
I'm saving you!
They were going to vaporise you!
Don't be ridiculous! They're harmless
old men! My grandfather was in there!
- Get in the car!
- I'm not getting in this monstrosity!
Well, the girl's gone.
Let's play cards.
I've got good news.
Now sit down right here.
You've got two minutes!
I told my father
that I'm going to quit singing.
And he gave me 10 percent
of the business right now!
- What are you talking about?
- I know what you've been going through.
You were just scared.
But you don't have to be scared anymore.
I can support you now.
- Shit!
- Peggy Sue?
Will you marry me?
How can you know
what I've been going through?
Of course I'm scared!
I can't change anything.
- I can't help anybody.
- You're not listening to me.
- I'm proposing to you now.
- You betrayed me.
You were never there for me
and the children.
I'll be there for the children.
I'll forget Walter.
Forget the group. I want to marry you!
Don't be crazy.
I may be crazy, but I'm not crazy enough
to marry you twice.
Christ.
Peggy.
I'm sorry.
I thought I was what you wanted me to be.
It's all my fault.
Here.
It's a birthday present.
I'm tired of being the romantic fool.
I'm going to go save my car.
Charlie?
It opens, too.
Look inside.
Scott and Beth. Where did you get this?
Who are Scott and Beth?
Your mother gave me those.
It's you and me.
You know that.
So are they.
I do love you.
I love you.
This is right, Peggy Sue.
I want this to be forever.
Mom, can you hear me?
Please, Mom, can you hear me?
They call what happened a near-death...
... but we figured out
exactly what the problem is...
You are a very lucky young lady!
What happened to you, Peggy Sue,
was a very rare problem...
... with the rhythm of your heart.
Mom, do you remember anything?
In fact, at the party,
they had to do CPR on you...
... before the paramedics arrived
to give your heart a shock and restart it.
Dad's been here every day.
"'Cause I love you, Peggy Sue
"I love you, girl, and I need you, Peggy"
Charlie?
- Was I dead?
- I thought you were for a while.
You look awful.
You look like you haven't slept in days.
- You look so old.
- But happy.
Very happy, Peggy.
I thought I knew everything about you.
I'm sorry.
I wanted to tell you that I...
- I wanted to...
- I'm sorry.
I can't live without you.
What about Janet?
That's over.
I got tired of translating everything to her.
She thought the Big Bopper
was a hamburger.
- Who are all the flowers from?
- Everyone.
Maddy and Arthur, Carol and Walter...
...Richard Norvik.
And here's a book by that guy
in high school, Michael Fitzsimmons.
He dedicated it to you.
It couldn't be me. I hardly knew him.
I'll just set this right here.
I had a strange experience.
I went back to high school
and I spent a lot of time with you.
You and Walter and Leon were singing
I Wonder Why.
God! Dion!
You were terrific.
And I kept trying to push you away.
- But you wouldn't give up.
- I'll never give up.
Would you hold me?
I don't expect that all our problems
can just vanish.
Christ, I would cut my right arm off
for another chance.
No, please, I need some time.
Well, I'll let you get some rest.
I'd like to invite you over to our house
for dinner on Sunday.
With your kids.
I'll make a strudel.