The second star to the right
Shines in the night for you
To tell you that the dreams you plan
Really can come true
The second star to the right
Shines with a light so rare
And if it's Never Land you need
Its light will lead you there
Twinkle, twinkle little star
So we'll know where you are
Gleaming in the skies above
Lead us to the land
We dream of
And when ourjourney is through
Each time we say
Good night
We'll thank the little star
that shines
The second from
The right
All this has happened before.
And it will all happen again.
But this time
it happened in London.
It happened on a quiet street
in Bloomsbury.
That corner house over there is
the home of the Darling family.
And Peter Pan chose
this particular house...
because there were people
here who believed in him.
There was Mrs Darling.
George, dear, do hurry. We mustn't
be late for the party, you know.
Mrs Darling believed that Peter Pan
was the spirit of youth.
- But Mr Darling...
- Mary, unless I find my cuff links...
we don't go to the party.
And if we don't go to the party, I can
never show my face in the office again.
And if I can never... Ouch!
Well, Mr Darling
was a practical man.
The boys, however,
John and Michael...
believed Peter Pan
was a real person...
and made him the hero
of all their nursery games.
Blast you, Peter Pan!
Take that! Give up,
Captain Hook? Give up?
Never! I'll teach you
to cut off me hand!
Oh, no, John.
It was the left hand.
Oh, yes.
Thank you, Wendy.
Wendy, the eldest,
not only believed...
she was the supreme authority
on Peter Pan...
and all his
marvellous adventures.
Oh, Nana, must we always
take that nasty tonic?
Nana, the nursemaid,
being a dog...
kept her opinions to herself...
and viewed the whole affair
with a certain tolerance.
Take that!
Insolent boy!
I'll slash you to ribbons!
And I'll cut you to pieces.
- Aha!
- Ouch!
- Careful, Michael, my glasses.
- I'm sorry, John.
You'll never leave
this ship alive!
Oh, yes, I will.
Take that!
Scuttle me bones, boy,
I'll slit your gizzard.
Oh, no, you won't.
Back, back, back, you villain!
- Insolent pup!
- Wicked pirate!
- Aha, I got ya.
- You didn't either.
You never touched me.
Take that and that!
And that!
Boys, boys,
less noise, please.
- Oh, hello, Father.
- You old bilge rat.
Wh-Wh-What?
Now, see here, Michael...
Oh, not you, Father.
You see, he's Peter Pan.
- And John's Captain Hook.
- Yes, yes, of course.
Uh, have you seen my cuff...
Oh, Nana,
for goodness sake!
Where are those cuff links?
- Cuff links, Father?
- Yes, the gold ones.
Michael, the buried treasure.
Where is it?
- I don't know.
- The map then.
- Where's the treasure map?
- It got lost.
- Good heavens, my shirt front!
- Hurray! You found it!
- You found it!
- Yes, so I have.
And hereafter...
Don't paw me, Michael.
This is my last clean...
No! No!
George, dear, we really must
hurry or we'll be late...
- Mary, look!
- George.
- It's only chalk, Father.
- Why, Michael.
It's not his fault.
It's in the story.
- And Wendy says...
- Wendy? Story?
I might have known. Wendy!
- Wendy!
- Yes, Father?
- Would you kindly ex...
- Oh, Mother!
- You look simply lovely.
- Thank you, dear.
- Wendy.
- Just my old gown made over.
- But it did turn out
rather nicely, didn't...
- Mary, if you don't mind.
- I'd like...
- Why, Father, what have
you done to your shirt?
What have l... Oh!
- Now, George, really.
It comes right off.
- That's no excuse.
Wendy, haven't I warned you?
Stuffing the boys' heads
with a lot of silly stories.
- Oh, but they aren't.
- I say they are.
Captain Crook!
Peter Pirate!
- Peter Pan, Father.
- Pan! Pirate! Poppycock!
- Oh, no, Father. Father, have you...
- Oh, you don't understand.
Absolute poppycock!
And let me tell you, this ridiculous...
- Now, George.
- "Now, George."
"Now, George"!
Well, "Now, George,"
will have his say!
- Please, dear.
- Mary, the child's growing up.
It's high time she had
a room of her own.
- Father!
- George!
- What?
- No!
- I mean it!
Young lady, this is your
last night in the nursery.
And that's my last word
on the matter...
No!
Oh!
Poor Nana.
"Poor Nana"?
This is the last straw!
Out! Out, I say!
- No, Father, no!
- Yes!
There'll be no more dogs
for nursemaids in this house!
Goodbye, Nana.
"Poor Nana."
Oh, yes, "Poor Nana."
But "Poor Father"?
Oh, no!
Blast it!
Where is that rope?
Oh, thank you.
Dash it all, Nana,
don't look at me like that.
It's nothing personal.
It's just that...
Well, you're not really
a nurse at all.
You're, well, a dog.
And the children aren't puppies.
They're people.
And sooner or later, Nana,
people have to grow up.
But, Mother,
I don't want to grow up.
Now, dear, don't worry
about it any more tonight.
He called Peter Pan
"absolute poppycock."
I'm sure he didn't mean it, John.
Father was just upset.
Poor Nana,
out there all alone.
No more tears, Michael.
It's a warm night.
She'll be all right.
- Mother.
- What is it, dear?
- Buried treasure.
- Now, children.
Don't judge your father
too harshly.
After all, he really
loves you very much.
Oh, don't lock it, Mother.
He might come back.
- "He"?
- Yes, uh, Peter Pan.
You see, I found something
that belongs to him.
- Oh? And what's that?
- His shadow.
- "Shadow"?
- Mmm, Nana had it.
But l...
I took it away.
Oh? Yes, of course.
Good night, dear.
But, George, do you think the children
will be safe without Nana?
Safe? Of course
they'll be safe. Why not?
Well, Wendy said something
about a shadow, and l...
- Shadow? Whose shadow?
- Peter Pan's.
Oh, Peter Pan...
Peter Pan!
You don't say. Goodness gracious,
whatever shall we do?
- But, George... Really, l...
- Sound the alarm!
- Call Scotland Yard!
- There must have been someone.
Oh, Mary, of all the impossible,
childish fiddle-faddle.
Peter Pan indeed. How can we expect the
children to grow up and be practical...
- George, dear.
- When you're as bad as they are.
- Please.
- No wonder Wendy gets
these idiotic ideas.
Over there, Tink,
in its den.
Is it there?
Must be here somewhere.
Tink! Shh!
Stop playing
and help me find my shadow.
Shadow. Oh, shadow.
Huh?
Aha!
Peter Pan! Oh, Peter!
I knew you'd come back.
I saved your shadow for you.
Oh, I do hope it isn't rumpled.
You know, you look exactly
the way I thought you would.
Oh, a little taller perhaps.
But then...
Oh, you can't stick it
on with soap, Peter.
It needs sewing.
That's the proper way to do it.
Although, come to think of it,
I've never thought about it before.
Uh, sewing shadows, I mean.
Of course, I knew it was
your shadow the minute I saw it.
And I said to myself, I said, "I'll
put it away for him until he comes back.
Oh, he's sure to come back."
And you did, didn't you, Peter?
After all, one can't
leave his shadow lying about
and not miss it sooner or later.
Uh, don't you agree? But what
I still don't understand is how
Nana got it in the first place.
She really isn't... Oh, sit down.
It won't take long.
She really isn't vicious, you know.
She's a wonderful nurse.
- Although Father says...
- Girls talk too much.
Yes, girls talk too...
Hmm? Oh.
- Well, get on with it, girl.
- Uh, my name is Wendy.
- Uh, Wendy Moira Angela Darl...
- Wendy's enough.
Oh, uh, but how did
Nana get your shadow, Peter?
Jumped at me the other night
at the window.
Well, what were
you doing there?
- I came to listen to the stories.
- My stories?
- But they're all about you.
- Of course.
That's why I like 'em.
I tell 'em to the Lost Boys.
The Lost Boys...
Oh, I remember.
- They're your men.
- Uh-huh.
I'm so glad you came back tonight.
I might never have seen you.
- Why?
- Because I have to grow up tomorrow.
- Grow up!
- Tonight's my last night
in the nursery.
But that means
no more stories.
- Mm-hmm.
- No!
I won't have it.
Come on!
Bu-Bu-But
where are we going?
To Never Land.
- Never Land!
- You'll never grow up there.
Oh, Peter,
it will be so wonderful.
But wait.
What would Mother say?
Mother? What's Mother?
Why, Peter, a mother is someone who...
who loves and cares for you.
- And... And tells you stories...
- Good! You can be our mother.
- Come on.
- Now, just a minute, l...
Let me see now.
L-I have to pack.
Oh, and I must leave
a note when I'll be back.
Of course, I couldn't stay too long.
And then I'll have to...
Oh, but Never Land.
Oh, l...
l-I'm so happy l...
I think I'll give you a... a kiss.
What's a... a kiss?
Oh, well, uh,
l-I'll show you.
- Oh!
- Stop! Stop it, Tink!
John, John, wake up!
He's here.
Huh? Jiminy!
Ooh, what in the world was that?
Tinker Bell.
Don't know what got into her.
Hello, Peter Pan.
I'm Michael.
And my name is John.
How do you do?
- Hello.
- Oh, look, a firefly.
- A pixie.
- Amazing!
- What's the pixie doing?
- Talking.
- What did she say?
- She says you're a big, ugly girl.
Oh. Well, I think
she's lovely.
- Well, come on, Wendy, let's go.
- Where are we going?
- To Never Land.
- Never Land!
- Peter's taking us.
- "Us"?
Well, of course. L-I couldn't
go without Michael and John.
Oh, I should like very much to cross
swords with some real buccaneers.
Yes, and fight pirates too.
Well, all right,
but ya gotta take orders.
- Aye, aye, sir.
- Me too.
But, Peter, how do
we get to Never Land?
- Fly, of course.
- "Fly"?
It's easy. All you
have to do is to... is to...
Is to...
- Ha! That's funny.
- What's the matter?
- Don't you know?
- Oh, sure.
It's... It's just that
I never thought about it before.
Say, that's it!
You think of a wonderful thought.
- Any happy, little thought?
- Uh-huh.
- Like toys at Christmas?
- Sleigh bells, snow?
Yep! Watch me now.
Here I go!
It's easier than pie.
- He can fly!
He flewed!
- Now you try.
- I'll think of a mermaid lagoon...
underneath a magic moon.
I'll think I'm
in a pirate's cave.
I think I'll be
an Indian brave.
Now everybody try.
One, two, three!
We can fly! We can fly!
We can fly!
This won't do.
What's the matter with you?
All it takes
is faith and trust.
Oh! And something
I forgot. Dust!
- Dust?
Yep, just a little bit
of pixie dust.
Now, think of
the happiest things.
- It's the same as having wings.
- Let's all try it just once more.
Look! We're rising off the floor.
- Jiminy!
- Oh, my! We can fly!
- You can fly!
- We can fly!
Come on, everybody.
Here we go!
Off to Never Land!
Think of a wonderful thought
Any merry little thought
Think of Christmas
Think of snow
Think of sleigh bells
Off you go like reindeer in the sky
You can fly, you can fly
You can fly
Think of the happiest things
It's the same as having wings
Take the path that moonbeams make
If the moon is still awake
you'll see him wink his eye
You can fly, you can fly
You can fly
Up you go with a heigh and ho
To the stars beyond the blue
There's a Never Land
waiting for you
Where all your
happy dreams come true
Every dream that you dream
will come true
Come on, Nana!
When there's a smile
in your heart
There's no better time to start
Think of all thejoy you'll find
When you leave the world behind
and bid your cares goodbye
You can fly, you can fly
You can fly
There it is, Wendy. Second star to
the right and straight on till morning.
When there's
a smile in your heart
There's no better time to start
Think of all thejoy you'll find
when you leave the world behind
And bid your cares goodbye
You can fly, you can fly
You can fly
Oh, a pirate's life
is a wonderful life
A- rovin'over the sea
Give me a career as a buccaneer
It's the life
of a pirate for me, oh
The life of a pirate for me
Oh, a pirate's life
is a wonderful life
They never bury your bones
For when it's all over a jolly sea rover
drops in on his friend, Davy Jones
Oh, my good friend
Davy Jones
- Good morning, shipmates.
- And what's good about it, Mr Smee?
Here we are, collecting barnacles
on this miserable island.
While his nibs plays
ring-around-the-rosy with Peter Pan.
Look out. It might go off.
We ought to be tending to
the business of looting ships.
Why, I've almost forgotten
how to slit a throat.
- Better hop it.
- And tell the captain...
we wants to put to sea, see?
Peter Pan...
Blast that Peter Pan!
If I could only find his hideout,
I'd trap him in his lair.
But where is it?
Mermaid Lagoon?
No, we've searched that.
We've combed Cannibal Cove.
H-Here! No. No, no, no!
That's Indian terri...
But wait.
Those redskins know this island
better than I do me own ship.
Ah...
I wonder.
- Good morning, Captain.
- I've got it!
Tiger Lily, Smee!
T-Tiger Lily, Captain?
The Chief's daughter.
She'll know where Pan is hiding.
B-B-But, but will she talk, Captain?
Oh, a little persuasion
might be in order.
Now let me see.
Boiling in oil?
Keelhauling? Marooning?
A pirate's life
is a wonderful l-life
You'll find adventure and sport
But live every minute
for all that is in it
The life of a pirate is short
Oh, the life...
Now let me see, where was I?
Oh, dear, dear,
dear Captain Hook.
Shooting a man in
the middle of his cadenza?
It ain't good form, you know.
"Good form," Mr Smee?
Blast good form!
Did Pan show good form
when he did this to me?
Why, Captain, cutting your hand off was
only a childish prank, you might say.
Aye! But throwing it
to the crocodile!
That cursed beast liked
the taste of me so well...
he's followed me ever since,
licking his chops...
for the rest of me.
And he'd have had
you by now, Captain...
if he hadn't swallowed
that alarm clock.
But now when he's about, he warns ya
as ya might say with his tick-tock...
tick-tock, tick-tock.
Smee? Smee!
Oh, save me, Smee!
Please, don't let him get me, Smee!
Please, don't let him
get me, Smee! Smee!
Here now, shame on ya.
Upsettin' the poor Captain.
There'll be no handouts today.
Shoo now, shoo!
Go on, go on, off it. Off with ya,
I say, go away, go away, out of here.
- Is he gone, Smee?
- Aye, Captain, all clear.
- Nothin' to worry about.
- Oh, Smee, Smee.
I can't stand it any longer.
I tell you, I can't.
Now, now, now, now, Captain.
Just relax.
What you need is a shave.
A nice soothing shave.
There now.
Oh, a pirate's life
is a wonderful life
A- sailing over the sea
Give me a career as a...
Captain, you know,
I can't help noticin'...
you just ain't been
your usual jolly self of late.
Give me a career as a buccaneer
And the crew's gettin'
a might uneasy, Captain.
That is,
what's left of it.
Now, why don't we put
to sea, see? Leave Never Land.
Forget Peter Pan.
There now!
Give me a career as a buccaneer
We'd all be a lot happier,
not to mention a lot healthier.
Captain? Oh, dear! I never
shaved him this close before.
Now, don't worry, Captain.
L-It must be somewhere about.
Get up, you idiot!
Aye, aye, sir.
Ooh! I found it, Captain.
- Good as new.
- Why, you blithering blockhead!
- Peter Pan ahoy!
- What? What? Where away?
Three points off
the starboard bow!
Swoggle me eyes!
It is Pan!
Headed this way with
some more of those scurvy brats!
Mr Smee, pipe up the crew!
A-Aye, aye, sir. Uh, pipe up
the crew. Uh, pipe up the crew.
All hands on deck!
Look alive, you swabs!
- We've got him this time, Mr Smee.
- That we have, Captain.
Man the Long Tom,
you bilge rats!
- I've waited years for this.
- That's not countin'
the holidays either.
Double the powder
and shorten the fuse!
Shorten the powder
and double the fuse!
A pretty sight, Mr Smee.
We'll pot 'em
like sitting ducks.
- All right, men! Range 42.
- "Range 42."
- Elevation 65.
- "Elevation 65."
- Three degrees west.
- "Three degrees west."
Steady now! Steady!
Oh, Peter, it's just as
I've always dreamed it would be.
Oh, look, John,
there's Mermaid Lagoon.
By Jove!
And the Indian encampment!
Oh, look, there's
Captain Hook and the pirates.
Look out!
Quick, Tink, take Wendy
and the boys to the island.
I'll stay here
and draw Hook's fire.
Hook! Hook!
You codfish! Here!
Tinker Bell? Not so fast.
Please, Tinker Bell.
We can't keep up with you.
Tinker Bell! Wait!
Ouch!
So!
- Who ya shovin'?
- You! That's who!
I'll show you!
Huh? Orders from Pan?
- Hold it, men!
- What's the orders, Tink?
- A terrible what?
- Wendy Bird.
- "Wendy Bird"?
- Flying this way?
- Uh, Pan's orders are...
What? Smash it?
- Kick it?
- Stomp it?
- Oh! Shoot it down!
- Shoot it down!
- Yeah!
- Yeah, shoot it down!
- Come on, follow Tink!
- Follow Tink!
- Let's go!
- Yeah, come on. Let's go then!
- We're gonna get 'er!
- I see it!
- Me too!
Ready, aim...
fire!
Oh, Peter, you saved my life.
- Are you hurted, Wendy?
- No, Michael.
Good heavens, Wendy,
you might have been killed.
- Hey! Hey! Pan!
- We followed your orders, Pan!
- Hey, Pan, I got it
with my skull buster!
- Ya did not! We did!
- I did it, Pan! I did it!
- No, I did!
Attention! Well...
I'm certainly proud of you,
you blockheads!
- I bring ya a mother
to tell ya stories...
- A mother?
- And you shoot her down.
- Well, Tink said it was a bird!
- Tink said what?
- Well, she said you said
to shoot it down!
Tinker Bell. Tink!
Come here. You're charged
with high treason, Tink.
Are you guilty or not guilty?
Guilty? But don't ya know
ya might have killed her?
Tinker Bell!
I hereby banish you forever.
Please, not forever.
Well, for a week then. Come on, Wendy,
I'll show you the island.
Oh, Peter, uh, the mermaids?
- Aw, let's go huntin'!
- Tigers?
- Naw, bears.
Personally, I should prefer
to see the aborigines.
- And the Indians too.
- All right, men!
Go out and capture
a few Indians.
- John, you be the leader.
- I shall try to be worthy of my post.
Forward! March!
- Come on, bear.
- Oh, Michael, do be careful.
Come on, Wendy.
I'll show you the mermaids.
Following the leader
The leader, the leader
We're following the leader
wherever he may go
Tee dum, tee dee
A teedle ee do tee day
It's part of the game we play
Tee dum, tee dee
The words are easy to say
Just a teedle ee dum
a teedle ee do tee day
Tee dum, tee dee
A teedle ee do tee dum
We're one for all
and all of us out for fun
We march in line
and follow the other one
With a teedle ee do
A teedle ee di tee dum
Following the leader
The leader, the leader
We're following the leader
wherever he may go
We're out to fight the Injuns
The Injuns, the Injuns
because he told us so
Tee dum, tee dee
A teedle ee do tee day
We march along and
these are the words we say
Tee dum, tee dee
A teedle ee do tee day
Oh, a teedle dee dum
Oh, a teedle ee dum
A teedle ee do tee day
Indians!
Oh, Blackfoot tribe.
Belongs to the Algonquin group.
- Quite savage, you know.
- Uh, let's go get 'em.
- Come on! We'll get 'em!
- Gentlemen, gentlemen.
- First, we must plan our strategy.
- Uh, what's strategy?
A plan of attack. The initial phase
is an encircling manoeuvre, thus!
John! Indians! Indians!
Let me in!
Now remember,
the Indian is cunning...
- Hey...
- but not intelligent.
Therefore, we simply surround them
and take them by surprise...
I'm frightfully sorry, old chaps.
It's all my fault.
- Aw, that's all right, Wildcat.
- Oh, we don't mind.
That's okay.
- How!
- Uh, h-how, Chief!
For many moons red man
fight paleface Lost Boys.
- Ugh.
- Ugh, ugh.
- Sometime you win.
- Sometime we win.
- Okay, Chief.
Uh, you win this time.
Now, turn us loose.
"Turn us loose"?
You mean this is only a game?
Sure! When we win,
we turn them loose.
- When they win, they turn us loose.
- They turn us loose.
This time, no turn 'em loose.
- Huh?
- The Chief's a great spoofer.
- Me no spoof'em.
Where you hide
Princess Tiger Lily?
- Uh, Tiger Lily?
- We ain't got your old princess.
- I've certainly never seen her.
- Me neither.
- Honest we don't.
- Heap big lie.
If Tiger Lily
not back by sunset...
burn 'em at stake.
Just imagine,
real live mermaids.
- Would you like to meet 'em?
- Oh, Peter, I'd love to.
All right, come on.
- It's Peter.
- Oh!
- Hello, Peter!
- Hello!
Hello, Peter!
- Hello, girls.
- I'm so glad to see you.
Why did you stay away so long?
Did you miss me?
- Tell us one of your adventures.
- Something exciting.
Want to hear about the time
I cut off Hook's hand
and threw it to the crocodile?
- Oh, I've always liked that one.
- Me too.
Well, there I was on
Marooner's Rock surrounded...
- Oh, Peter!
- By 40 or 50 pirates.
- Who's she?
Huh? Her?
Oh, that's Wendy.
- A girl?
- What's she doing here?
And in her nightdress too.
Come on, dearie.
Join us for a swim.
- Oh, please, I'm not dressed for it.
- Oh, but you must!
- We insist!
- No, no, please!
- Too good for us, eh?
- Peter!
- If you dare to come near me again...
- Wendy! Wendy!
They were just having a little fun,
weren't you, girls?
- That's all.
- We were only trying to drown her.
- Ya see?
- Well, if you think for one minute...
- that I'm going to put up with a...
- Shh. Hold it, Wendy.
- Yep, it's Hook, all right.
- Hook!
Hook! Oh!
Quick, Wendy.
They've captured Tiger Lily.
Looks like they're
headin' for Skull Rock.
Come on, Wendy.
Let's see what they're up to.
Now, me dear Princess,
this is me proposition.
You tell me the hiding place
of Peter Pan...
and I shall set you free.
- You dog.
- Poor Tiger Lily.
Am I not a man of me word, Mr Smee?
Oh, yes, always, Captain.
You'd better talk, me dear,
for soon the tide will be in...
and then it will be too late.
- I'll show the old codfish.
Stay here, Wendy, and watch the fun.
- "Fun"?
Remember...
there is no path
through water...
to the happy hunting ground.
This is your last chance,
Tiger Lily!
Manatoa, great spirit
of mighty seawater, speak!
Beware, Captain Hook!
Beware! Beware!
- Did you hear that, Smee?
- It's an evil spirit, Captain.
Stand by, Smee,
while I take a look around.
Spirit of the great seawater, is it?
Psst! Wendy. Watch this.
- Mr Smee!
- Uh, yes, Captain?
Release the princess
and take her back to her people.
Aye, aye, sir.
Release the princess...
- But... But, Captain...
- Those are me orders, Mr Smee!
Aye, aye, sir.
- Well, at last Captain Hook's
comin' to his senses.
- Odd's fish!
I told him all along you Indians
wouldn't betray Peter Pan.
And just what do you think
you are doing, Mr Smee?
Just what you told me, Captain.
Carryin' out your orders.
- My orders?
- Why, yes, Captain.
Didn't you just say to go...
Put her back!
You blithering idiot!
- My orders. Of all the bumbling...
- Mr Smee!
Just exactly what do you
think you are doing?
Putting her back
like you said, Captain.
I said nothing of the sort!
Oh, but, C-Captain, d-d-didn't you?
I thought that...
For the last time, Mr Smee.
Take the princess
back to her people.
Understand? Understand?
- Uh, aye, aye, sir.
- Oh, and one more thing.
When you return to the ship,
tell the whole crew...
to help themselves
to me best rum.
- Peter!
- Here's your spirit, Smee!
Why, it's Peter Pan.
- Scurvy brat!
- Thank you, Captain.
Come down, boy,
if you've a taste for cold steel.
- Watch this, Wendy.
- Oh, Peter, do be careful.
- Try your luck, Mr Smee?
- Let him have it!
Well, come on, you idiot!
Blast him!
Right here, Mr Smee.
Hold it, you fool!
No! No!
Captain?
Oh, how dreadful.
What a pity, Mr Smee.
I'm afraid we've lost the dear Captain.
Captain!
In the back, Captain?
Give it to him, Captain!
Cleave him to the brisket.
I've got you this time, Pan.
Well, well, a codfish on a hook.
I'll get you for this, Pan,
if it's the last thing I do!
I say, Captain,
do you hear something?
No.
No!
Mr Crocodile,
do you like codfish?
- You do?
- Oh, Peter, no!
No!
- Smee!
- D-Don't go away, Captain!
Uh, stay right there now, sir.
I'll save ya, sir.
Smee!
Ow!
Captain! Captain!
Smee! Smee!
- Give him back!
- Smee...
Row for the ship!
Row for the ship...
Whoa!
Smee!
Peter, what about Tiger Lily?
Tiger Lily?
Oh, Tiger Lily.
Help...
Peter. Wait for me.
That cursed Peter Pan.
Making a fool out of me.
Oh, my head.
Oh, a pirate's life
is a wonderful life
- Your hot water, Mr Smee.
- Shh!
The poor Captain
has a splitting headache.
We mustn't annoy him.
Well, Captain, it's nice
to see you smiling again.
Brings back the good old days when
we was leadin' a healthy, normal life.
Scuttlin' ships, cuttin' throats.
Oh, Captain...
why don't we put to sea again?
You know, there's trouble
brewin' on the island.
Women trouble.
I wouldn't want this
to go any farther, but...
the cook told me that
the first mate told him...
that he heard that Pan
has banished Tinker Bell.
Whoa!
Why, you doddering imbecile, l...
Did you say Pan...
has banished Tinker Bell?
Aye, aye, Captain.
That he has.
- But why?
- Well, on account of Wendy, Captain.
Tink tried to do her in, she did.
Tink's terrible jealous.
- Well, well.
- That's why we ought to leave, Captain.
This ain't no place
for a respectable pirate.
That's it, Smee!
That's it!
I'm glad you agrees, Captain.
Quick, me coat.
Me best dress coat.
Aye, aye, sir. The sooner
we get going, the better.
Ah, yes, a jealous female
can be tricked into anything.
- My case of hooks!
- Aye, aye, sir.
Here you are, sir.
Your Sunday set, sir.
If we impress the pixie, convince her
we're eager to help her...
the wench may chart
our course to a...
certain hiding place.
Our best hiding place
is the Spanish main, sir.
I'll set our course...
And where do you think
you are going?
T-To tell the boys
we sails with the tide, sir.
You will go ashore,
pick up Tinker Bell...
and bring her to me.
Understand?
Aye, aye, s-s-s-sir.
- How!
What's the Chief doing, John?
He's delivering an oration
in sign language.
- What's he saying?
- He says...
"Peter Pan, mighty warrior.
"Save Tiger Lily.
Make big Chief heap glad."
Well, he certainly
doesn't look "heap glad."
Make Peter Pan heap big chief.
You now Little Flying Eagle.
- Hurray for Flying Eagle! Flying Eagle!
- Hurray!
Hurray!
- Oh, how wonderful!
- Hurray!
Teach 'em paleface brother
all about red man.
Good, this should be
most enlightening.
Uh, what makes the red man red?
- When did he first say, "Ugh"?
- First say, "Ugh"?
Why does he ask you, "How"?
"Why does he ask you, 'How'?"
Hana mana ganda
Why does he ask you, how
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
Once the Injun didn't know all
the things that he know now
But the Injun
He sure learn a lot
And it's all from asking how
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
We translate for you
Hana means what mana means
and ganda means that too
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
- Hana mana ganda
- Squaw, no dance.
Squaw, get 'em firewood.
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
When did he first say, "Ugh''
Hana mana ganda
In the Injun book, it say
when first brave married squaw
He gave out with heap big "ugh''
when he saw his mother-in-law
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
Hana mana ganda
What made the red man red
Let's go back a million years
to the very first Injun prince
He kissed a maid and start to blush
and we've all been blushin'since
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
Hana mana ganda
Now you've got it right
from the head man
The real true story
of the red man
No matter what's been
written or said, no matter what
Now you know why
the red man's red
- Wa-hoo!
- John!
Squaw take 'em papoose.
Wa-hoo!
- Michael!
- Squaw, get 'em firewood.
Squaw no get 'em firewood!
Squaw go home.
Beggin' your pardon, Miss Bell...
but Captain Hook
would like a word with ya.
Yes, Miss Bell,
Captain Hook admits defeat.
Tomorrow I leave the island,
never to return.
I'm glad to hear that, Captain.
I'll tell the crew and...
And that's why I asked
you over, me dear...
to tell Peter
I bear him no ill will.
Oh, Pan has his faults,
to be sure.
Uh, bringing that Wendy
to the island, for instance.
Dangerous business, that.
Why, rumour has it that already
she has come between you and Peter.
But what's this?
Tears?
Then it is true.
Oh, Smee.
The way of a man with a maid.
Taking the best years
of her life and then...
casting her aside
like an old glove!
Ain't it a bloomin' shame?
But we mustn't judge
Peter too harshly, me dear.
It's that Wendy who's to blame.
Mr Smee, we must
save the lad from himself.
But how?
We've so little time.
We sail in the morning.
Sail! That's it, Smee!
- We'll shanghai Wendy.
- "Shanghai Wendy," Captain?
Take her to sea with us.
With her gone, Peter will soon
forget this mad infatuation.
Come, Smee, we must leave immediately.
Surround Peter's home...
But, Captain, we...
we don't know where Peter Pan lives!
Great Scott,
you're right, Smee!
What's that, my dear?
You could show us the way?
Why, I never thought of that.
- Take this down, Smee.
- "Take this down, Smee."
Aye, aye, Captain.
- Start at Pegleg Point.
- "Start at Pegleg Point."
- Forty paces west of Blindman's Bluff.
- "Blindman's Bluff."
Yes, yes. Hop, skip and
a jump across Crocodile Creek.
Then north by northeast,
one, two, three.
Well, get on with it...
Continue, my dear.
I mustn't harm Peter?
Madam, Captain Hook
gives his word...
not to lay a finger...
or a hook on Peter Pan.
Ah, Hangman's Tree.
So that's the entrance
to his hiding place.
Thank you, me dear.
You've been most helpful.
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
- Hana mana ganda, Hana mana ganda
- Hana mana ganda
- What makes red men red
Hana mana ganda, hana mana ganda
Hana mana ganda
Big Chief Flying Eagle
greets his braves.
- How!
- Uh, how, Chief.
- How, Chief! How!
- How.
Big Chief greets Little Mother.
- How!
- Ugh!
Aw, Wendy, is that
all you have to say?
- Everyone else thinks I'm wonderful.
- Especially Tiger Lily.
- Tiger Lily?
- John! Michael!
Take off that war paint
and get ready for bed.
- Bed?
- Brave no sleep.
Go for days without sleep.
- But, boys, we're going
home in the morning.
- Home!
- And...
- Oh, Wendy, we don't want to go home.
No go home. Stay many moons.
Have heap big time.
Now, Peter, let's stop
pretending and be practical.
Chief Flying Eagle has spoken.
Oh, for goodness sake.
Please, boys.
Do you want to stay here
and grow up like... like savages?
- Of course.
- But you can't.
You need a mother.
We all do.
Aren't you our mother, Wendy?
Why, Michael, of course not!
Surely you haven't forgotten
our real mother!
Did she have silky ears
and wear a fur coat?
Oh, no, Michael.
That was Nana.
I think I had a mother once.
- What was she like?
- I forget.
- I had a white rat!
- That's no mother!
Hey, who ya shovin'?
No, no, boys! Please.
I'll tell you what a mother is.
- Yeah, tell us.
- Please, Wendy.
Well, a mother,
a real mother...
is the most wonderful person
in the world.
She's the angel voice...
that bids you good night...
kisses your cheek...
whispers, "Sleep tight."
Your mother
And mine
The helping hand
that guides you along
Whether you're right
Whether you're wrong
Your mother
And mine
What makes mothers
all that they are
Might as well ask
what makes a star
Ask your heart
to tell you her worth
Your heart will say
Heaven on earth
- Another word
- Shh.
For divine
Your mother
And mine
- I wanna see my mother.
- Yes, Michael.
I propose we leave
for home at once.
- Could I go too? Huh, Wendy?
- Me too, Wendy!
- Come on! Let me go!
All right, boys. All right. I'm sure
Mother would be glad to have you.
Uh, that is,
if Peter doesn't mind.
Go on!
Go back and grow up!
But I'm warning ya.
Once you're grown up...
you can never come back!
- Never!
- Dear.
- Well, then, shall we be off?
- Yeah, come on. Let's go!
- Yeah!
- See ya, Peter.
They'll be back.
Peter.
Goodbye, Peter.
All right, men.
Take them away.
And now, Smee, to take care
of Master Peter Pan.
But, Captain, wouldn't it
be more humane-like to slit his throat?
Aye, that it would, Mr Smee.
But I have given me word
not to lay a finger...
or a hook on Peter Pan.
And Captain Hook
never breaks a promise.
Yo ho, yo ho
Yo ho, yo ho, yo ho
So try the life of a thief
Just sample the life of a crook
There isn't a boy
who won't enjoy
A- workin'for Captain Hook
The world's most famous crook
Crook, crook, crickety
crockety, crickety, crick
the croc is after Captain...
A special offer for today
I'll tell you what I'll do
All those who sign without delay
Will get a free tattoo
Why, it's like money in the bank
Come on
Join up and I'll be frank
Unless you do
you'll walk the plank
The choice is up to you
Yo ho, yo ho
Yo ho, yo ho, yo ho
You'll love the life of a thief
You'll relish the life
of a crook
There's barrels
of fun for everyone
And you'll get treasures
by the ton
So come and sign the book
Join up with Captain Hook
- Hey, I wanna join!
- Please! Oh, boy!
- I wanna be a pirate!
- Oh, boy! A pirate!
Boys! Aren't you
ashamed of yourselves?
But Captain Hook is
most insistent, Wendy.
Yeah! He says we'll walk
the plank if we don't.
Oh, no, we won't.
Peter Pan will save us.
Peter Pan will save them, Smee.
Peter Pan will save them.
Oh, Captain, you did it.
But a thousand pardons, my dear.
I don't believe you are
in on our little joke.
You see, we left
a present for Peter.
Sort of a surprise package,
you might say.
Why, I can see our little
friend at this very moment...
reading the tender inscription.
"To Peter, with love
from Wendy.
Do not open till 6 o'clock."
Huh. I wonder what's in it.
Could he but see
within the package...
he would find an ingenious
little device.
Set, so that when
the clock is like this...
Peter Pan will be blasted...
out of Never Land forever.
No!
But time grows short.
We have but 18 seconds.
Fifteen seconds.
Thirteen seconds.
Twelve seconds.
Well, I guess
I can open it now.
Hey, Tink.
Look what Wendy left.
Hey, stop that! Stop it!
What's the matter with you?
Hook? A bomb?
Don't be ridiculous!
And so passeth a worthy opponent.
Amen.
Hook! It was a bomb!
Why, if it hadn't been
for Tink... Tinker Bell!
Tink? Tinker Bell?
Where are you, Tink?
Tink? Tinker Bell!
Tink. Are you all right?
Wendy? The boys?
But I've gotta save you first.
Hold on, Tink! Hold on!
Don't go out.
Don't you understand, Tink?
You mean more to me than
anything in this whole world!
And now, which will it be?
The pen or the plank?
Captain Hook, we will
never join your crew.
As you wish.
Ladies first, my dear.
- Goodbye, boys.
- Goodbye, Wendy.
- Be brave, John.
- I shall strive to, Wendy.
- Goodbye, Michael.
- Goodbye, Wendy.
- Come on!
- Get along over there!
- Get going, miss. Get going!
Don't give us no trouble!
Go on! Go on!
Get it over with!
- Move along!
- The Captain's waitin'!
Wendy! Wendy!
- Captain, n-no splash.
- Not a sound.
- Not a bloomin' ripple.
- It's a jinx, that's what it is.
- No splash.
- No sign of the wench.
- Did you hear a splash?
- I'm telling you, mates,
it's a black day.
Mark me words.
We'll all pay for this.
The ship is bewitched.
No splash, Captain.
So, you want a splash, Mr Starkey.
I'll give you a splash!
- Who's next?
- You're next, Hook!
- This time you've gone too far!
- It's Pan! Peter Pan!
- And Wendy!
- It can't be!
It's his blinkin' ghost
what's talkin'!
Say your prayers, Hook.
I'll show you this ghost
has blood in his veins.
I'll run him through! Ooh!
Take that!
Curse this hook!
Come on, everybody!
Hurry, Michael! Hurry!
Don't stand there,
you bilge rats!
Get those scurvy brats!
After the brats, men!
This is no mere boy.
'Tis some fiend fighting me.
A flying devil!
- Hold your fire.
- Get 'em!
Steady, men. Steady.
- Club 'em with the marline.
- Fire!
- I'll crack their bloomin' skulls!
- Let me at 'em!
Down, you blackguard!
Hurray!
- Right through, Michael.
- Yea, Bear Killer!
- Yea for Bear Killer!
Fly! Fly! Fly! You coward!
Coward? Me?
Ha-ha-ha! You wouldn't dare fight
old Hook man-to-man!
You'd fly away like
a cowardly sparrow!
Nobody calls Pan
a coward and lives!
I'll fight you man-to-man,
with one hand behind my back.
- You mean you won't fly?
- No, don't, Peter! It's a trick!
- I give my word, Hook.
- Good, then let's have at it!
Now! Insolent youth,
prepare to die!
Fly! Fly, Peter! Fly!
No! I gave my word.
You're mine, Hook!
Cleave him to the brisket!
You wouldn't do old Hook
in now, would you, lad?
I'll go away forever.
I'll do anything you say.
Well, all right.
If ya say you're a codfish.
- I'm a codfish.
- Louder!
- I'm a codfish!
- Hurray!
Hook is a codfish
A codfish, a codfish
- Hook is a codfish, a codfish, a codfish
- All right, Hook...
you're free to go,
and never return.
Peter!
Smee! Smee!
Smee!
Smee-ee-ee-ee-ee-ee-ee-ee!
Captain!
Captain! Captain!
Hurray!
Hurray for Captain Pan!
All right, ya swabs,
aloft with ya!
We're castin' off!
Heave those halyards!
But, but, Peter...
Oh, that is, Captain Pan.
- At your service, madam.
- Could you tell me, sir,
where we're sailing?
- To London, madam.
- Oh, Peter.
Michael! John!
We're going home!
Man the capstan!
Hoist anchor!
Pixie dust!
George, I am so glad you
changed your mind about Wendy.
After all, she's still a child.
Oh, pshaw, Mary.
You know I never mean those things.
Do I, Nana?
Oh! Wendy!
Wendy, what on earth
are you doing there?
Mmm. Hmm?
- Oh, Mother, we're back!
- Back?
All except the Lost Boys.
They weren't quite ready.
- Lost Bo... Ready?
- To grow up.
That's why they went
back to Never Land.
- Never Land?
- Yes, but I am.
- Uh, "am"?
- Uh, ready to grow up.
Oh! Oh! Uh...
Well, my dear,
all in good time.
- After all, perhaps we were too...
- Oh, but, Mother...
it was such a wonderful adventure.
Tinker Bell and the mermaids
and Peter Pan.
Oh, he was the most
wonderful of all.
- Why, why, even when
we were kidnapped, l...
- Kidnapped!
Mm-hmm. I knew Peter Pan
would save us, and he did.
And we all called him a codfish!
Uh, Captain Hook, I mean.
And then we sailed away
on a ship in the sky.
Hmm. Mary, I'm going to bed.
Oh, Mother.
He really is wonderful, isn't he?
See how well he sails the ship.
- George. George!
- Now what, Mary?
Nana, d-did you see...
You know, I have
the strangest feeling...
that I've seen that ship before.
A long time ago...
when I was very young.
- George, dear.
- Father.
When there's a smile in your heart
There's no better time to start
Think of all thejoy you'll find
When you leave the world behind
And bid your cares goodbye
You can fly