Excuse me...
Come here, honey.
So how did it go?
Very well. We went towards
the dam, and then...
How did it go?
Very well. We went towards the dam,
and then to the old town.
You don't like
the old town, do you?
So did you have fun
with your friends?
Did you have fun
And were you a good boy?
You were a good boy.
You were mommy's good boy.
So... how did it go?
Very well.
Impeccably.
We went towards the dam...
But did he feel good?
Excuse me?
Did he feel good?
Fulfilled?
He's somewhat of a loner.
He's anxious.
He doesn't like the
company of other animals.
No...
It went impeccably.
He was with other dogs.
They ran.
And...
they talked to each other.
That's good.
Very good.
Wonderful.
Thank you.
Thank you, madam.
PRICELESS
Honey?
Jacques, I can't believe it.
Get up.
Come on.
Get on the bed.
Do you feel well?
Very well.
And you?
You're completely drunk.
It took you 3 hours to get ready.
Look how much you've drunk.
Don't worry.
These are little bottles.
You could have made an effort today.
Don't argue with me, honey.
I hate it when people
tell me the truth.
Right.
Don't move.
I'll give you a second pillow.
Thank you.
In 2 minutes I'll
be at your disposal.
Dammit.
Jean?
I'm sorry.
You look awful.
- Did you walk the dogs again?
- Yes.
And today morning
I took care of supplies.
Why do you accept this work?
They're so used to me accepting,
that I don't dare refuse.
Besides, I have the time.
Do as you like.
It's not my problem.
But don't fall asleep in the bar.
Sure.
Of course.
I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
I'm leaving now.
- Can you close up?
- Yes, of course.
He'll leave if
you turn down the lights.
Excuse me.
I'd like another one.
It's good you turned
down the lights.
It's nicer this way.
Thank you, sir.
Can you turn on the TV?
There's a live broadcast on Eurosport.
Yes, sir.
Sit down.
I'm not allowed to
leave the bar, sir.
Really?
Really. Except to serve drinks and...
in case of a fire.
Yes, sir.
Sit down.
Have a cigar.
The leaves grow in
the middle of cocoa fields.
That's what gives them
their particular aroma.
Do you smell it?
Yes, sir.
Because of the embargo against Cuba,
I fly them in by private jet.
One cigar costs about...
120 euros.
Good evening.
I'm sorry.
This is the first time
I've fallen asleep like this.
Considering the mood here,
I don't see anything better to do.
This place is dead.
No. It was brimming with life earlier.
But now it's a bit late.
It's not normal, that there isn't
anyone at the bar at this hour.
Normally, they aren't
allowed to leave before 3 a.m.
It's forbidden.
Unless there isn't anyone.
But you're here.
Yes.
And I'm here, right?
Indeed.
Something like this wouldn't
happen at the Carlton.
You know, the Carlton...
Do you think their
service has worsened as well?
Do you think he'll come back?
Who?
The barman.
I don't know.
Will you wait with me for him?
Yes.
Of course, miss.
That's nice of you.
Your cigar smells nice.
Normally I can't stand the smell,
but in this case...
Yes...
It's because of the leaves,
which grow in the
middle of cocoa fields.
Really?
They're flown in from Cuba
by private jet because of the...
Because of the embargo?
That's it.
Are you alright?
Today is my birthday.
Happy birthday, miss.
It's off to a bad start.
I wanted so much
to have fun tonight.
I'd give anything for
a cocktail and some music.
What are you doing?
Cocktails are my specialty.
Isn't this too risky?
In the worst case,
I'll just say I work here.
So what would you like?
I don't know.
Something that gives a feeling of joy.
For your birthday I suggest
something with champagne.
And that gets you drunk fast.
Gets you drunk fast...
Then...
A cocktail with champagne.
Excellent.
Wonderful.
I love to watch someone work.
I'm always impressed by
people who can do something.
I can't do anything.
Actually I can.
I can make conversation.
And you?
Right.
I'll have another one.
Which floor are you staying at?
Me?
Yes, you.
The fifth...
The fifth floor.
The imperial suite.
I only know the royal one.
- Will you give me a tour?
- Sure.
The dressing room.
Here we have the living room.
The living room.
The first bathroom.
Here we have the study, with
a wireless internet connection.
And a fax.
The bedroom.
This way, please.
You must be very rich.
Why do you say that?
Must I do everything for you?
What?
Happy... birthday... to... you...
Did they leave the royal suite?
They left this morning.
They stole a bathrobe.
ONE YEAR LATER...
The coffee, ladies and gentlemen.
Who'll be having the decaf?
Excuse me.
Is everything alright?
Jean, but...
What are you doing?
Jean, are you alright?
Thank you very much, sir.
I'm not hungry.
What will you have?
What you picked.
Good idea.
With pleasure.
- Irene?
- Yes?
Happy birthday.
Thank you, Jacques.
Are you alone?
For the moment.
And your...
uncle?
You're talking about my great-uncle?
He's growing old.
Will you have a cocktail?
Just one?
What the...
Older people get up early.
You should know that by now.
I couldn't sleep at all.
I went to the beach
to get some fresh air.
I also couldn't sleep.
And I saw you at the bar
with that guy.
You were tenderly getting
some fresh air on the sofa.
I'm sorry, Jacques.
I don't know what came over me.
That was the first time.
I swear.
In a few months I'll see
you at the same place
where I picked you up.
At the hotel bar,
wearing a mini,
with the same fake
expression of indifference.
I'm not worried.
You'll be so drunk
you'll ask me my name.
You'll offer me a drink.
Dammit.
I can't believe it.
I'm so stupid.
Dammit.
I left him.
I left it all for you.
Did you forget something?
I forgot you.
Excuse me?
But... weren't you supposed
to leave today?
Jean?
Yes?
I left him.
I left it all for you.
Really?
Yes.
Tell me I did the right thing.
You did the right thing.
I want to spend every
hour with you.
- Do you know what would make me happy?
- I don't.
A trip to the Maldives.
Where?
The Maldive Islands.
You don't know them?
I do.
But not all of them.
But first we'll order
a big breakfast.
When I'm happy
I'm also very hungry.
And this time we'll
spend the morning in bed.
You're not the type of person
who works all the time?
That depends.
Do something.
Damn, what are you doing here?
Everyone downstairs is looking for you.
Dammit.
I can't believe it.
Get out of here.
In 2 minutes I'm sending
Martine to clean the room.
Damn, I can't believe it.
I can't believe it's you.
You've arrived in Nice.
This is the last stop.
We ask all passengers to
get off the train.
We ask that you make sure you
haven't left anything on the train.
The next train will
arrive at 2 o'clock.
Henri?
It's Irene.
Irene Mercier.
We met at that social gathering.
At the casino in Cannes.
Last year.
I'm sorry.
Yes, of course.
Maybe some other time?
My number is...
Bye.
Asshole.
Dominique?
It's Irene.
We met at the VIP club last year.
You spilled your
glass on my dress.
Irene.
That's right.
Very well.
For how long?
Too bad.
Baire?
It's Irene.
Ivan?
Single, small but well-proportioned.
Yes, Irene, that's right.
Benoit?
Asshole.
Philippe?
It's Irene.
Don't you remember the meeting
in Dauville last year?
I'm sorry.
My condolences.
Are you his son?
Grandson?
So we must be the same age.
What are you doing here?
Reception told me you asked for
the schedule of trains to Nice.
I'm going around from
one bar to the next.
I wanted to say I'm sorry.
Fine, alright.
Good bye.
I didn't get the chance this morning.
So I came by train.
No kidding?
You didn't fly in by jet?
I really wanted to say I'm sorry.
I wanted to say it to you.
I'm sorry for what I did.
Fine.
You've said it now.
So good bye.
I thought we could go
have dinner together.
Are you nuts?
I won't eat dinner with you.
I want you to go away.
I feel bad...
I don't care how you feel.
Do you understand? I don't care.
I have a date.
So good bye.
How about tomorrow?
Do you know who that
was back at the hotel?
We were going to get
married in 3 months.
3 months.
He adored me.
I even had an engagement ring.
I'd be done with the bars,
the mini and the smiles.
Do you understand?
I'd be set until the end of my life.
I'm sorry.
So am I.
You don't know how badly.
And now I have to start all over.
So if you want to do me a favor,
then just leave me alone.
You don't have the
time for a drink?
Dammit.
It's probably the second to your left.
You go out and it's
the second to your left.
Going out, the second to your left.
Going out.
François?
Yes.
- Irene?
- Yes.
- Good evening.
- Thank you.
I love Italian food,
because it's never pretentious.
And we never expect
anything out of the ordinary,
so we're never disappointed.
Right?
Indeed.
It depends.
But when in Italy, I don't like
to eat in the local restaurants.
It's less amusing.
Maybe because they don't make
the effort to act like Italians.
Maybe.
Listen...
That guy next to the
cars is watching us.
And I feel funny.
But I don't know him.
He was with you at
the bar when I arrived.
And now he's here and
I think he's waiting for us.
And I feel uneasy.
I'm sorry.
This is ridiculous, François.
You seem to love pasta,
so you can eat mine.
Can I leave you my number?
Is your invitation to
dinner still open?
Yes, of course.
I found a really nice pizza
shop in the old town.
No. I don't eat at nice pizza shops.
Alright.
As you wish.
120 EUROS
115 EUROS
230 EUROS
180 EUROS
I'd like some caviar.
The crawfish.
And some champagne.
And you?
What will you have?
I don't know.
I need to think it over.
Available at next delivery.
What?
The crawfish. It will be
available at next delivery.
The delivery has just arrived.
Good.
I feel relieved.
So?
I need to leave you for a moment.
Good evening, Mr. Molluquet.
This is a message from Mr. Simon.
Can you wire my bonus
to my current account?
My whole bonus.
Tomorrow morning.
I'd appreciate it.
I'll confirm it later in writing.
Thank you.
Good bye, Mr. Molluquet.
We'll order a second one.
It's sad with just one bottle.
It's boring.
I didn't want to lie
to you at the Biarritz.
I just didn't want to oppose you.
You seemed so happy.
And I was in heaven.
I don't really like caviar.
I force myself to eat it.
And with time I'll
start to like it.
I'm sure that when
I start to like it,
it will taste great.
It's nice here, isn't it?
I like this place a lot
because it's not pretentious.
It's calm and grand
at the same time.
We have the impression
that we're unique.
The handle is made from shark bone.
Amazing, isn't it?
The bones are dried for 2 years.
It takes one shark to
make one set of cutlery.
Here you go.
I'm bushed.
I want to go to bed.
At which hotel are you staying?
I found a small, very nice
hotel in the town's suburbs.
Very good.
So go get your stuff
and we'll meet back here.
Here?
It's more simple that way, right?
Yes.
- Is there a problem?
- No.
No. Not at all.
See you later.
Mr. Simon?
Yes, that's right.
Ms. Mercier is waiting
for you in room 304.
Thank you.
Did you enjoy your dinner?
Yes, very much.
May I ask for your credit card?
Excuse me?
Your credit card.
To cover the bill.
Right.
Of course.
Thank you.
Please take Mrs. Pontini's
baggage to her room.
- We're sorry.
- It's alright.
I have exactly the same.
They're the same color?
That's right.
Yes?
Mr. Molluquet.
How are you?
Excuse me?
No.
No one stole my card.
That much?
Please wire the money from my
PEL account to my current account.
And my PEP account?
And my PEA account?
Go ahead.
No problem.
Please do tell me.
Do I have the right to the CEL?
Well that too then.
How much money is in it?
I assumed there's more.
160 EUROS
Well?
Do you really want to go to town?
Yes.
Are you sure?
Yes, why do you ask?
620 EUROS
Why do you ask?
What do you think?
300 EUROS
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Good.
Can we go?
You can't continue doing this.
This is my business.
I'm paying, right?
Indeed.
And that's what counts, right?
So what's wrong?
Nothing.
So let's go for a walk.
I don't want to go for a walk.
What do you want?
I want a handbag.
What is it?
I feel good, because I'm
not working this afternoon.
I feel like I'm skipping class.
Me too.
On top of that I'm drunk.
Better to be drunk in the
afternoon than in the evening.
It's much better this way.
We have the impression
we're keeping a secret.
Would you like anything else?
Maybe some ice cream?
I want a dress.
Have mercy.
OPERATION CAN'T BE PERFORMED
THANK YOU FOR YOUR VISIT
This one is gorgeous.
Castelles cake!
I love it!
Here you go.
I got you a place in first class.
Thank you.
So, good bye.
Good bye.
Wait.
Another 10 seconds.
The 10 seconds are up.
Fine.
Fine, thank you.
Ask Jeff to come here.
You're not looking for a barman?
I have very good credentials.
No, sir.
I'm sorry sir, but I'm
forced to call the police.
Can't we work something out?
Pool man, room service,
porter, driver?
No, sir.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Can someone give me
a hand with my bag?
I'll send over Benoit.
Don't trouble yourself.
My friend will be delighted
to give me a hand.
You were very eager to
help me last time.
Add the bill of room 304
to the account of room 429.
- Shall we get out?
- Yes, of course.
And?
Will you close the door?
Yes.
Good evening.
Which floor?
The third floor.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Is everything alright?
Impossible.
You'll never go away.
This isn't about you.
Yesterday I had a
problem with paying...
You have to leave me alone,
do you understand?
I have to work, Jean.
Calm down.
Do you think you can
go around having a crush?
It's not about that.
I met this woman and
she made me an offer...
Stop it.
I know why you're here.
I'm telling the truth.
You think I don't know
what's going on?
That I don't know that look?
Since I was 12 I've seen that look.
Good morning, Madeleine.
Did you sleep well?
Very well, thank you.
Have you picked something?
Excuse me?
Have you been served?
No, but everything is fine.
Won't you sit down?
Excuse me.
Shall I bring you something?
Not now.
That's nice of you, thank you.
What's going on?
You had a bad dream.
But that's good because
now you're awake.
I know what your color is.
You need something that's blue.
We'll keep the indigo shirt
and the lavender one,
the blue one and
the navy-blue one.
But certainly not those
two remaining ones.
Gilles?
Can you bring me that pink dress?
Yes.
And this one, Jean?
It's gorgeous, isn't it?
Yes, I'm trying it on.
So... doing a little shopping?
A little.
And?
It's very nice.
She's the friend I told you about.
She's accepted to help
me for a while.
You don't call me miss anymore?
We have to pick something.
We can't buy 36 shirts.
And I've had enough.
I have to go.
My friend is in a hurry.
Can you spare me 10 seconds?
You look very nice in that shirt.
Thank you.
I'm coming.
I took two. I didn't know
which one you want.
Both.
Of course.
Finally you're smiling.
It's nice to be
well-dressed, isn't it?
Yes.
We're leaving.
Come in, the door is open.
4 days.
What did you get?
Shirts.
Those 4 shirts?
And a pair of jeans.
That's it?
Today morning I had
a wonderful breakfast,
with room service.
And an extra serving of pancakes.
Jean, I can't believe it.
We haven't gone out much.
She's shafted you.
I'll wait a bit.
Wait for what?
That she'll marry you?
Take. Take as much as you can.
A new suit, glasses, shoes.
Take, Jean.
Otherwise what's it for?
Do you have 5 minutes?
I'm free until noon.
No, in half an hour I'm
going to a garden party.
I love such parties.
I'll look around and
maybe pick someone up.
The guy you're with now is no good?
I'm with him for the time being.
Why is that?
He's been divorced 4 times
and pays 4 ex-wives alimony.
He doesn't have much left.
Believe me, you can
find someone better.
- Is she married?
- She's a widow.
You're lucky.
When will you be back?
I don't know.
Will we see each other later?
Of course.
- We're neighbors, aren't we?
- Indeed.
Wombats and other koala bears,
who don't know what fear is,
always find out too late that
they can't defend themselves.
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
How was it?
Very good.
I have a gift for you.
What is it?
Guess.
Excellent, thank you.
I don't know...
A suit?
Glasses?
Shoes?
A bar of gold?
They're beautiful, aren't they?
Yes.
Very beautiful.
She can't treat you like that.
This can't go on.
She has the money.
So what?
You have a soul.
Youth.
Charm.
Make use of it.
Do you think I have charm?
You say that to someone
you don't find attractive.
But charm is more
valuable than beauty.
You can resist beauty,
but you can't resist charm.
Show me how you...
seduce someone.
How I seduce someone?
You must have a trick you practiced
in front of the mirror when you were 15.
No, I don't.
Improvise something.
Come on, start seducing me.
No...
Come on, do it by staring at me.
I can't do it just like that.
Go ahead.
Come on.
I just started.
I'm sorry.
Show me how you do it.
- Show me.
- Alright.
What's wrong Irene?
Nothing.
I...
I had...
I want to...
I'd like to...
What do you want?
What would you like?
This is what makes the
other person go crazy.
Not finishing your sentences.
As if the rest is too painful to say.
Not finishing your sentences
is very effective.
That and looking ahead and afar.
That'll get her.
Look.
I'm here...
and I'm gone.
And you have nice arms.
You should show them.
And you have nice hands.
What is that?
Damn... my watch's alarm.
She finished her meeting.
She set an alarm?
I have to go.
I can't believe it!
You aren't listening to me!
I am.
And?
I can't change everything right away.
I have to go slowly.
Dammit...
Give me that.
I know what to do.
You have to press...
There we go.
Why did you do that?
Because.
That was the end of our lesson
about the secret of womanhood.
Go.
Go or you'll be late.
PLASTIC SURGEON
This is ridiculous.
You don't need this.
You look very good.
You have no business being here.
Thank you, Jean.
That's nice of you.
I have no business being here,
because I come here regularly.
Hello.
Is everything alright
since your last visit?
Better and better.
Thanks.
Thank you.
I'm really happy with the result.
Me too.
Good.
So what's the matter with that ear?
That guy is the best.
Do you know what I had to do
to set up this appointment?
Do you know how long you have
to wait sometimes for breast surgery?
No. Is that the next procedure
you're planning for me?
Oh come on.
That was nothing.
A single stitch and 20 minutes.
Do you know what you
have to go through sometimes?
I can imagine.
Jean, stop it.
Say something.
This silence makes me anxious.
I want to...
I'd like to...
What do you want?
What?
What would you like?
What do you want?
It's...
It's just...
Jean, look at your watch.
It's broken.
Driver take us to number 63.
The handle is made from shark bone.
Amazing, isn't it?
The bones are dried for 2 years.
It takes one shark to
make one set of cutlery.
Once I'm dead I'll donate
my body to them.
Excuse me.
- Do you have a light?
- Yes.
Thank you.
Do you think they sell it
at the hotel's boutique?
The watch?
No.
The cutlery.
Yes.
Of course.
I'm sorry.
I'll be right back.
Show me it.
Oh my goodness.
A Jaeger-LeCoultre watch.
Do know how much it's worth?
I can't even pronounce
such an amount.
You had a slow start,
but now you're rolling.
All this is white gold.
With diamonds all around.
And there's a diamond
on each number.
And inside there are rubies
and other stuff.
This isn't a watch.
It's a treasure chest.
What did you do to her?
I gave her the silent treatment.
You look nice.
Every rich guy looks nice to you.
You're not rich.
You've barely begun to be rich.
I never could have
expected any of this.
Go first.
I'll follow you.
- Jean?
- Yes?
What time is it?
A quarter to 9.
- It's nice here, isn't it?
- Yes.
I like this place because
it's not pretentious.
It's calm and grand
at the same time.
We have the impression
we're unique, don't we?
Yes.
The handle is made from shark bone.
Amazing, isn't it?
The bones are dried for 2 years.
It takes one shark to
make one set of cutlery.
Good evening, sir.
This is François from room service.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
We're unsure of something.
I need to clarify something
concerning your breakfast.
The juice that you ordered.
Should it be orange
or grapefruit?
Orange.
- Orange?
- Yes.
Maltaise, Navelle or Sanguine?
What?
Do you prefer a certain brand?
A what?
The brand of the juice.
- Maltaise.
- Excellent choice, sir.
We also have apple juice.
A very popular apple juice.
It's very much in demand.
It has a delicate flavor,
but has character.
Thank you very much.
Very well.
Sir, this is François again
from room service.
I'm sorry to be bothering you again.
Regarding the eggs.
Should they be soft-cooked, hard-cooked,
fried or boiled?
Soft-cooked.
Very well.
A very good choice.
- Anything else?
- No.
Are you sure, sir?
Fine.
Starting from a certain age,
a little ginseng added to your tea
improves blood circulation.
And I've also heard of
spectacular erections.
Is this room service?
Yes, this is room service.
Is this a joke?
Yes.. I mean, no.
No, this is not a joke, sir.
This is room service.
Have you been told about
the food for seniors?
No.
The food for seniors
is specially prepared
for our older clients.
There's nothing to chew.
The food is mechanically
chewed prior to serving,
so that you may enjoy
every kind of food,
in spite of a disability
of the jaw.
I can offer you soup,
purée and yogurt.
And stewed fruit for dessert.
Where were you?
I went to the bathroom.
Two visits to the bathroom
during a meal at your age?
I'm sorry... I...
What were you doing?
Were you talking to someone?
No.
You can tell me.
You weren't talking to anyone
or you don't want to tell me?
I'm not jealous just curious.
I...
What's wrong, Jean?
Nothing... I...
I want to...
I'd like to...
Enough of this.
What do you think you're doing?
That you can play games with me
like with a young virgin?
Listen to me carefully, my boy.
If I want to I can
throw you out of here
with one snap of my fingers.
So if you want to continue
to enjoy the pool and the boutiques,
then you better show
some more concentration.
Do you understand?
I'm sorry I'm late.
We visited the boutiques.
- She bought you a scooter?
- Yes.
It has a luggage box.
And a full tank.
We can go for a swim.
I know this nice place by the sea.
I've been wanting to go
there since arriving here.
We'll go there now.
Order me a glass and
I'll be right back.
We made a good choice
by picking this suit.
It's very nice.
- Good night.
You were right.
It's good to go to bed early.
It was nice of you to cancel
our dinner at the restaurant.
Really?
Yes. It's as if you gave me a gift.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
You're really not hungry this evening?
No I'm not.
That's something rare, isn't it?
That's true.
Do you want some candy?
No, thank you.
I own some of the producer's stock.
It makes me good money.
Where are you from?
Excuse me?
I'm from Saint-Brieux.
Saint-Brieux?
Is it nice there?
It rains all the time.
Do you know that I haven't
seen the rain in 4 years?
It's always summer here.
I miss the smell of rain.
Do you have any siblings?
No.
I have 2 brothers and 3 sisters.
And my oldest sister
would always tease me.
I mean that...
You haven't said anything.
It's very nice here.
I lack the words to describe it.
Behind us is an abandoned vineyard.
I find grapes there in September.
And up there, to your left...
There's an old sheep house.
Do you see it?
I can barely see my sandwich.
Dammit.
Impossible.
Jean, excuse me.
It would be lovely if you could
bring me my book from our room.
Irene?
Is everything alright?
I wanted to tell you that
I spent a wonderful night.
Me too.
When can we do it again?
I didn't want to
fall asleep, you know.
So that I could savor each minute.
What's wrong?
I'm leaving.
I came to say good bye.
Where to?
I'm going to Venice.
With Gilles.
And then to the Maldives.
When?
This evening.
When are you coming back?
I'm not coming back.
When I was a kid I went to
Venice once with my parents.
I remember the bread rolls
they had there. I adored them.
I don't remember their name.
Do you know which ones?
Yes.
I also don't remember their name.
And I also adore them.
So... good bye.
Jean, are you here?
Here you are.
Is everything alright?
Yes.
The book was here.
Thank you.
Madeleine, what's the name of
those Italian bread rolls?
Oh no...
Oh no, this can't be true...
That bastard...
Not again...
Dammit...
The bread rolls are called panettones.
That idiot dumped me.
He dumped you?
He left me here.
And took everything.
But why?
And what do you think?
Do you think he saw us?
Of course he saw us.
I can't believe it.
I'm so stupid.
You have to go to the train station.
I keep my things there
in a luggage box.
Dammit... I have nothing.
I only have this cover
and the swimming suit.
Miss?
This is for you.
The room has been paid
for the whole week.
Are you alright?
Yes.
I'm fine.
You look a little nervous.
No, I'm not nervous.
What will you have?
I'll have a vodka.
We'll have a scotch
whisky and a vodka.
Where's your watch?
I sold it.
That's not true.
It's in our room.
No, I sold it at the same boutique.
But...
It was mine, wasn't it?
Yes.
I wanted to believe
you're a little different.
Not like the others.
But you're only more
clever than they are.
I don't know what came over me.
I wanted to buy you a gift,
but I had no money.
So... here you go.
They're gorgeous.
This is charming, Jean.
That watch was the
only thing you had.
I'm sure I gave you the invitation.
No. The invitation was
on your nightstand.
Most likely the cleaning
lady took it.
It doesn't matter.
Excuse me.
Do you have a light?
Can I bring you some champagne?
That would be charming.
5 glasses, please.
Thank you.
You're a prince.
I will be needing your help, Jean.
Of course. How can I help?
I saw Jacques.
You need to help me.
In what way?
I want you to help me...
seduce him.
Things can't go on like this, Jean.
That situation at the
pool was just too hard.
I don't want to find myself
without anything again.
I prefer to...
What do you want me to do?
Tell me.
Excuse me.
A glass of champagne, please.
One for you?
Yes.
One more glass, please.
Thank you.
Getting some champagne is real madness.
When did you arrive?
About 10 minutes ago.
Are you alone?
Yes, for now.
- And you?
- No.
Here's to our health.
- Irene.
- Agnes.
Impossible...
What?
This is my lucky day.
What is it?
- The Prince von Hoffenberg.
- Who?
The Prince von Hoffenberg.
There, near the roses.
Who is he?
A mover and shaker of this world.
He's a Dutch nobleman.
And he's an industrial tycoon.
He must have just arrived.
He's very rich
and very lonely.
He lost his wife in
a car accident 2 years ago.
And since then he's
in such a poor shape.
I'll go to him
and take my chances.
Excuse me.
Is it at her you're looking?
Yes.
Is she looking at you?
Yes. She's taking shy
glances at me.
She wants to get married.
Here you go.
I noticed you hadn't any left.
Thank you.
Good evening.
This is Agnes, my friend.
- Prince Michel...
- ...von Hoffenberg.
Of course.
- Good evening.
I'm rarely recognized.
But you have a face
that's impossible to forget.
Have you just arrived?
I don't intend to
stay here too long.
- I think this is a little...
- Yes, that's true.
You think the same?
I couldn't help myself from
looking at you all evening.
I'm sorry.
No need to be sorry.
You remind me of someone.
The Princess of Edinburgh.
- Excuse me, Ines.
- Irene.
I'm sorry.
Don't mention it.
Maybe we can see each other later?
I have her portrait, painted by
Rembrandt, at my country house.
I hung it in the guest room.
I'd like to show it to you.
The resemblance is striking.
She was executed during the revolution.
Oh my God...
I'm so sorry.
The pain has passed.
Excuse me for a moment.
You're behaving like a rude bastard.
For the past hour you've been
going from one woman to the next.
What are you doing?
Who do you think you are?
Do you think a little
jewel is enough?
I'm sorry, Madeleine.
I don't give a damn
that you're sorry.
You told my friends you'll
bring us some champagne, so do it.
You have 2 minutes to bring it.
I'd be happy to help, but I can't.
What do you mean you can't?
I need to go to the hotel and
spend a few hours with this girl.
What are you talking about?
I need to do a favor.
I can't do otherwise.
Are you kidding me?
I'm warning you.
If you leave with that girl,
don't count on me, understand?
I'll leave the scooter at the
parking lot and the keys at reception.
There's nothing I can
do to stop you?
No.
I'm sorry.
Stop being so nice.
It's unbearable.
It seems that a man
like you can't be bought.
Even by me.
I'll be fine, don't worry.
You're not the first.
Thank you for approaching
things this way.
Do I have a choice?
You can keep the scooter.
You deserve it.
I'm sorry...
That was my ex mother-in-law.
The Baroness von Bosten.
She can't stand that
I talk to other women since...
Yes.
I know.
Don't hold it against her.
She's suffering because of it.
But I have to live on, right?
Yes, of course.
One must live on.
Life goes on.
Are you alright?
No...
Yes.
I want to...
I'd like to...
Well well.
Good evening, Jacques.
Good evening, Irene.
You see. I still
remember your name.
Are you alone?
As you can see.
What have you been doing?
I've been signing checks.
When did you arrive?
I arrived this morning.
I was dumped this evening.
Not all is lost.
It seems so.
I think I've already
forgotten her name.
Excuse me.
What did you say?
That I've already
forgotten her name.
Agnes.
You know her?
Small world.
Are you alright?
Yes. I'm fine.
Do you have any plans
for the coming days?
Do you have any plans?
Excuse me?
I have this impression
your thoughts are elsewhere.
And I don't like it.
Excuse me.
Pardon me.
It's the alcohol and the fatigue.
I'm falling asleep.
What were you saying?
I asked if you had any plans.
What are you plans
for the coming days?
Love.
I plan to make love.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, Jacques.
I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
I'm really sorry.
Prince?
What's going on?
What are you doing here?
I'm doing you a favor.
He's not a prince.
I can't believe it.
Excuse me.
Well...
It took you a while.
I did what I could.
I want to...
I'd like to...
Kiss you.
TOLL: 1 EURO