Just like we need to breathe..
..to live, all I want is a sweetheart..
When you're on the verge of dying..
..you'll realise some important facts of life.
And, one of them would be..
..that, girls and rockets can take you any limits.
Look, that's me.
'They completely rearranged my face.'
'30 minutes ago, I was standing on my own two feet.'
'Just 20 minutes ago, they 11 bones..'
..and cracked my skull.
'Murari was right.'
'This mess was created by me.'
'But someone's love had become the bane of my life.'
'But my story doesn't start here.'
'My story starts at Beneras.'
'All hail Lord Shiva. - All hail Lord Shiva.'
'All hail Lord Shiva.'
'I was a free soul.'
It was not just difficult but impossible to catch me.'
'All hail Lord Shiva. All hail Lord Shiva.'
'All hail, sir.'
Uncle Rameshwar, out with some money.
This time we'll burn Ravana's effigy in a way..
..that no one would dare to burn Ravana's effigy again.
But why are you dressed like Lord Shiva to ask..
..for donation for Dussehra?
You should have dressed up like Rama, right?
Would Rama himself have come to ask for donation..
..to save his own wife?
Would he have liked that?
That's why he sent me.
After all, I am His special friend. Am I not?
Here you go.
All hail Lord Shiva.
Bindiya. Brother, did you see Bindiya?
No.  That Kundan will spoil her.
Hide, hide. - Bindiya.
Seems like your father has come, Bindiya.
Go. Or else all of us would get beaten up because of you.
You are scared because my father is a policeman, isn't it?
I am scared of nobody.
Your father has messed up my life.
Okay. Hold on. I'll call him.
Papa.
Please. Quiet. Quiet.
I shall be doomed if I don't rip off your father's clothes one day.
Come on.
All hail Lord Shiva.
Uncle, we've come from the third lane of Hanuman Phatak.
For donation. As we have to burn Ravana's effigy.
Hope you won't burn down someone else.
Uncle, if you think this is a lie. You can come there and check.
Give it. Give him the receipt.
Here. 100 rupees.
Okay. Junaid. Get 100 rupees. - Yes.
Murari, we...
'That day, that very moment, that very second..'
'..it felt as if Lord Shiva had answered all my prayers. '
'200 years ago the king of Banaras had brought..'
'..my forefathers from a village in Tamil Nadu.'
'To be his personal priests.'
'But it felt as if Banaras had accepted me today.'
'This was Banaras's first gift to me.'
'She was the one offering prayers..'
'..but it felt as if my prayers had been answered.'
'I was still a kid.'
'But all of a sudden it felt as if I was an adult.'
'Old enough to marry.'
'Old enough to live and die in that girl's love.'
All I demand is you.
All my immaturity is limited to you.
All my eyes look for are you.
You give me joy as well sorrow.
Only you. Only you. Sweetheart.
All I want is you. But it's all up to you.
All my hardships are limited to you.
All my intelligence is limited to you.
All I prepare for is you. Only you.
Only you.
I am smitten by you and you only.
You dare tease the girl of our territory.
Dogs have territories. - Lions have guts.
Darn you.
Hey...don't beat me. Okay.
I will beat you to an inch of your life.
Murrari. Don't let them get away. Catch him.
Look aunt, these scoundrels have been beaten up again.
They were teasing with girls.
Aunty, we only fell down, She's lying.
Delicate. And shy. Delicate. My heart lets out a tune.
Your eyes are mesmeric.
Don't give me those mesmeric looks.
To you. All the roads lead to you.
I'm drawn to you. All I want is to meet you.
I'll meet you. Only you. Only you.
Fiery face. And the dark eyes.
We fight and squabble.
You seem to be mine. And sometimes you seem like a dream.
When you look at me.
Your eyes pierce straight through my heart.
You control my destiny.
How do I get out of this dilemma?
Only you. Only you. Only you, sweetheart.
All I want is you. But it's all up to you.
All my hardships are limited to you.
All my intelligence is limited to you.
All I prepare for is you. Only you.
Only you.
I am smitten by you and you only.
Only you. Only you.
Someone will take your girl away.
And you will be left licking your wounds.
What do you mean?
I mean if you don't express it now..
..you'll be seen eating sweets in the girl's wedding.
Only you.
Sanju!
Only you. Only you.
My smartness is limited to you.
My youth is all for you.
My story ends on you.
My story ends only on you.
Only you. Only you.
I love you.
Did he scare you? Go.
I'll slap you and you'll stop flirting around.
I am prepared for that. Here.
Tell me your name at least.
Come tomorrow again to get slapped and I'll tell you.
I'm in love. Someone come and check on me.
I locked eyes with her smack in the middle of the market.
I have locked eyes at a tender age.
It's my last board paper tomorrow. - Very nice.
Come and meet me at the fort at Ganga's banks.
At 5.
And listen. I'm meeting you because of your consistency.
Not out of love.
No matter the reason. Just meet me.
Leave the rest to destiny.
You have slapped me 15 times. Tell me your name at least now.
Zoya. - Zoya.
And yours? - Rizwan.
Rizwan.
Oh my! You look cool.
Why? Can't I?
No. You can. Why not?
But mister, I know whom you are pursuing.
Heard that you're going to the fort today to show that witch the moon.
You are a witch. Get lost.
Great. Great. Love her and beat me. - Lay off.
You are looking nice, mister.
If that witch casts an evil eye on you..
..then you'll have to marry me.
Why don't you ever show me the moon?
Go count the stars, Bindiya.
Go to hell.
Your heartbeat is saying something.
It says something...
What happened?
What is this?
I bought the I love you card in haste. Thought you would take offence.
So I bought this. - You are a bumpkin.
Is this any way to propose to a girl?
Listen to your heart first. Then let your eyes take control.
Your heartbeat is saying something.
I suggest you should listen to your heart.
Your eyes are glistening in the sun.
The sun...
Sorry, I forgot.
If this is you...then I have been smitten by you.
What is your name? - Rizwan.
And your father's?
Mirza Galib.
You didn't think? Did you?
'This was the sixteenth slap.'
'But I was happy to have kissed her.'
'Rather than be sad about the slap.'
I hate liars.
'What could be better than a wife of sound character?'
'But I was a Banerasi priest. Dark at that.'
How could I accept defeat?
In U.P. girls are cajoled in two ways.
First is dedication. Follow her around all day.
Write love letters, and ask her friend to deliver it.
But, every boy in U.P was doing that.
'But I wasn't a handsome hunk.'
'To have passed by doing all this.'
'So I failed.'
Now, the second way.
Scaring the girl.
What are you doing?
If you stop the vehicle you'll not be able to drive it from tomorrow.
What's the problem? - You're the problem.
Don't chase me around. - So whom should I chase?
I don't know. But don't chase me.
Say that you don't love me.
I don't love you.
Just because I am a Hindu.
If you say I'll read out the Kalma(holy book).
You are a liar.
Say that you don't love me. Or I'll slit the wrist.
Mine.
I don't love you.
What are you doing?
I've suffered enough humiliation.
You'll leave for Aligarh tomorrow itself.
Go to your aunt's place. And study there.
Just think, sir. The boy is Hindu.
We'll be disgraced in society.
What about your daughter who flirts around with the entire neighbourhood?
How dare you come here to complain about me?
Get lost. - Keep quiet.
Keep quiet.
Is this the age to be doing all this?
And from where did you learn to misbehave?
You'll be leaving for Aligarh tomorrow itself.
Kundan, your father-in-law's sending..
..your wife away to Aligarh, forcefully.
Hurry up, or you will miss her.
Find another Ram, he's gone for good.
Your papa and I love you a lot.
But what you've done will not be tolerated.
Study hard, Zoya.
And remember what we said.
And don't get down at any station.
Zoya!
Are you blind?
Zoya, don't worry. I'll wait for you. - Stop.
You bet. By the time you return everything would've changed.
Waiting for you. Always.
'That day I realised that heart is neither on the left or right.'
'It is in the centre.'
'Because there is where I felt the pain.'
'But I wasn't dead yet.'
'Because this wasn't the end of the story by any means.'
'I was yet to reach my prime.'
Hail Mahadev!
No, Kundan.
Let papa go.
Kundan! This isn't right.
I'll punish both of you in jail.
I'm ready to go to jail. Just let me colour you once.
Beware, Murari. I'll kill you. - Catch him.
Tear his clothes off.
Kundan, the arms of law are very long.
And so are the legs of criminals.
Careful, papa.
Kundan. - Floor him, Kundan.
Kundan, no.
Hail Mahadev!
You're always doing as you want.
Papa was on duty.
You think you're funny. I'll show you.
You are a rascal.
Will you rip off just my father's clothes?
Kundan is not that easy to get, Bindiya.
If you think you can entice me with your beauty then you are so wrong.
Your competition is returning.
Rascal. Darn you and that witch.
Even after 8 years, you're still in love with her, isn't it?
Go to hell, Kundan. - Murari.
You are great.
She'll die a torturous death. I swear.
Vultures will feast on her, and you too.
What news you've given me!
Come. Come back to your love.
Someone's waiting for you.
My luck will change. My luck will change.
For the better.
There is chaos and music everywhere.
You've left to come to me.
Love is in the air. Sweetheart, please show up.
I am madly in love with you.
You are the only one I have.
You light up my life.
You are my world.
You are the only one I have.
My body is grooving. My heart's thumping.
In waiting for you.
The entire world knows what's in my heart.
Only I know what's in your heart.
Let me feel a little more love.
Show me a little more love.
I'm madly in love with you.
You are the only one I have.
I see vibrancy all around. Everything seems to have come to life.
I'm so proud of myself. I have lost control.
Come and whisk me away.
Come and take me away with a smile.
There is chaos and music everywhere.
You've left to come to me.
Love is in the air. Sweetheart, please show up.
Seems like sir's car has broken down.
To hell with the sir.
Are you going to meet her in front of him?
Hold the wrench. - Yes.
Lord Shiva is on our side.
Not just Lord Shiva. Even the spark plug of the sir's car..
..is on our side.
Murari, you are genius.
Run, quickly. I'll handle here.
Is there a problem? - No.
Don't be so unfair. Let's carry one bag at least.
We talked to him for two hours.
Let him do work worth 200 bucks at least.
Shall I give him the books as well? - Sure. Go ahead.
What? She just didn't recognise you?
Right. She just passed by.
But Murari, she is really beautiful.
Even Katrina Kaif pales in comparison to her.
Yes, she is your Katrina Kaif.
And both, she and Katrina don't recognise you.
How is it going, Kundan? - Hello, aunty.
But Kundan, we haven't run out of gas yet?
Aunty, it's the festive season. - Yes.
You will not get it later. - That's right.
Come. Keep it here.
Okay, Kundan. Look, the sink pipe has started leaking again.
Please change it.
Okay. I'll check.
And the servicing of the Fiat was not up to the mark.
We had to go pick up Zoya this morning.
And it just wouldn't start.
I need to check the spark plug. - Yes.
So brother...did she recognise you?
Did she recognise you?
It means that this girl has lost her memory.
Take her to some doctor.
She will refuse to come. But still, take her to a doctor.
Come on. Get lost. Go.
Okay. All hail Lord Shiva.
How are you?
I am good now.
That is what I was wondering. What's wrong with Banaras?
Even the delivery guys are flirting with girls.
I felt that I have seen you somewhere.
How is the wrist?
This one.
Okay. See you. - When?
Soon. Bye.
From a small school to JNU.
How did you get there?
Have you stopped eating Gol Gappas(snacks)?
This is my friend. Rashmi.
Rashmi, this is...
Myself Shankar. Kundan Shankar.
Are the Gol Gappas good? - They are excellent.
Zoya, how are we going to go? - Where?
We have to elope, right?
Why are we going to elope?
Okay. So I'll convert into a Muslim.
Why would you convert into a Muslim?
Then how will we get married?
Whose marriage?
Yours and mine.
Hold on, brother.
Why would I and you get married?
Because we love each other. - Since when?
Are five done? - There is one left.
So give. And some more for madam.
One minute.
What were you saying? - Talk decently.
Okay. Let's make this a little decent.
When did we fall in love?
Give this to me.
What do you mean when did we fall in love?
We have been in love since the last 8 years.
In your dreams, Kundan. There is nothing of that sort.
I was in the 9th grade back then.
Yes. As if I was pursuing law.
I was also in the 10th grade.
Kundan, we were immature then.
So now we are mature. Do it now.
You're mad, Kundan. There is nothing of that sort.
Rashmi, let's go. Come on.
Who is he?
He was my friend when I was small. He is mad.
Listen you rickshaw driver, don't take money from madam.
She is your sister-in-law.
Which one, brother?
The tall one who is angry.
What are you looking at? Look in front.
You're mad. There is nothing of that sort.
Forget me. - You forget me.
Forget me means goodbye.
The 10 year investment has gone down the drain.
Murari, I have come at the right time.
Here's some sweet.
I heard that the priest's son has become a widower.
Oh Lord!
What are you going to do now, mister?
Your sweetheart has lost her memory.
Hide.
Murari, shut her up. Or I'll beat her up.
Bindiya, stop deriving pleasure from this.
The boy is serious.
Kundan, your Lord cannot be such a liar.
I have been fasting on Mondays for the last 15 years.
You are not marrying Zoya.
Do you want a beating?
I had told you. I had told you. You'll get beaten up.
Okay. Okay. Leave her.
Don't push her down and hit her on the back.
Don't throw her out.
Don't throw her out the house. - Rascal!
Threw her out of the house.
You moron! I curse you.
What happened, Bindiya?
Aunty, he is drunk in the afternoon. That dog.
Banaras will rejoice the day you marry me, Kundan.
I would rather marry a witch than marry you.
Why you..
You are the witch. - Yes. Break the sandal as well.
Kundan. - Shut up.
You monkey. - You're the monkey.
Since you have a tail.
Zoya. - Oh no. - Curses.
It's stuck.
Kundan, thank God I found you. - Tell me.
I was looking for you in the university as well.
We have a small function at home tomorrow.
We are expecting around 50-60 guests.
Well, I have told Sunder to do the decoration.
You also get some of your boys to work on it.
Will come handy.
What's happening tomorrow night?
Nothing as such. You have come after so long.
And nothing has happened in the house all this while.
Great. - Not bad.
Kundan, what are you doing here?
Well... - He has come to wear bangles.
Listen. Why does she laugh when she sees you?
Because she feels shy.
Now would she stare her eyes out at her future husband?
A little shyness. A little shame.
This is the mark of a woman, Murari.
No. I think you'll have a slit wrist again.
Darn you.
Get lost.
Everyone's looking so decent.
Pal, where is your madam?
And nor is her intelligent friend to be seen.
No problem. Both of them must be having a bath.
Shut up.
So Kundan. Is everything under control?
Yes, uncle. - Handle everything.
A match is coming to see Zoya.
He is a doctor.
We'll get her married to him if he likes her.
I will also be retiring in two years.
Where is Zoya?
What did father-in-law say?
Stop.
You are fooling me?
What nonsense, Kundan.
Let go of my hand. It hurts.
I am also hurting. I have slit my wrist once.
Mind you, this time I'll slit yours.
What's wrong, Kundan?
Why are you acting crazy? - Okay.
Don't you know that a boy is coming to see you this evening?
That is why your father is having this celebration.
Mummy, is some boy coming to see me this evening.
Yes. - Why didn't you tell me?
What should I have told you?
Your father has fixed everything.
Mummy, I am not a kid anymore that you can do as you please.
I don't want to marry.
Zoya, don't create a scene.
Meet the boy and then let's see.
Look, he is only coming to see you.
You're not getting married in the evening.
I have lots on my plate. Let me go.
Listen. - Sister-in-law. Zoya. Ms. Zoya.
Kundan will attend the evening's party, right?
How can he not come?
The guru has given him the job of serving sherbets.
Here, take all of it.
When will you people stop acting silly?
Drink one at least first. Keep it. Go.
Kundan, Zoya is calling you. - Why?
Why don't you ask her?
I didn't know of all this, Kundan.
I don't want to marry that boy.
I see. So then?
Save me from all of this, Kundan?
Otherwise I'll slit my wrist before you do.
Don't say so, Zoya. Wait and watch.
Move. - These days you are rarely seen.
My marriage has been fixed. - Here.
What a shame. - Get lost.
Aren't you ashamed to be a waiter?
Why should I be ashamed?
Your prince Charles is himself serving sherbet to these rascals.
Oh God! Why?
What do you mean why? It's sister-in-law's party.
She is your sister-in-law. And me?
You are also sister-in-law.
And her? - She's sister-in-law too.
As if your Kundan is a superstar..
..that every girl would marry him.
Isn't he? Turn around.
Someone's come before me. And my heart's pounding.
Just a glimpse of hers has driven me crazy.
She will chat and meet me also.
She'll be friends with me sooner or later.
Someone's come before me. And my heart's pounding.
Just a glimpse of hers has driven me crazy.
Ordinary boys of lose their love to a doctor or a engineer.
Don't be disheartened.
Murari, this is Banaras.
And if the ordinary boy loses here as well, then he'll never win.
Is that so?
Mother. Please tell me. Zoya will die, right?
Kundan will marry me, right?
Bindiya.
I will not do anything for you. Spare me.
Listen, Bindiya. - No!
You act so sweet when you need a favour.
Otherwise you keep abusing me.
You're getting mad for no reason.
Aren't you my friend?
Wait. Let me see. Hold on.
Mother, she should do things for us, right?
Look, she's saying yes. -See. - What do you want from me?
Come here. - Tell her the idea.
Yuck. Gross. Not at all.
Bindiya, try to understand.
I'm not doing anything for that wretch. - Murari!
Not at all. - Murari, come on.
Catch her. - I'll never do it.
Banarasi guy. Banarasi guy.
Banarasi guy.
Is there is a mess up or are things messed up?
Banarasi guy. Banarasi guy.
Are we fighting together? Or are we fighting because we are together.
Banarasi guy.
Trickery is in the blood of every man and woman here.
But they are innocent at heart.
They spend their lives at the banks of Ganga.
Residents of the bank.
But Banarasi people have an attitude all their own.
Is there is a mess up or are things messed up.
Are we fighting together? Or are we fighting because we are together.
They are capable of anything when it comes to them.
They chomp on some betel nut leaf..
..and walk around proudly.
Proud Banarasi.
No. This is not possible.
I...I mean we're over and done with this.
That's it. Okay. Yes.
Proud Banarasi.
Is there is a mess up or are things messed up?
Are we fighting together? Or are we fighting because we are together.
Banarasi guy. Banarasi guy.
Great. Now that you don't need me anymore..
..you even don't recognise me.
I do. Of course.
Since I got you of this pickle, won't I get a reward?
Absolutely. Tell me. What do you want?
Marry me, Zoya.
Are you mad? No. Never.
Okay. Look, I bought this scooter for you.
But you never sat on it.
You'll have to be my pillion.
You will have to hold me by my waist.
Not the stepney.
When I put on the breaks, you'll have to fall on me.
You will have to laugh at things I say.
You will have to sing with me.
You can do this at least, right?
At least let me feel it. So be it if not as my girlfriend.
That day for the first time I saw you so upset.
I was so scared.
Yes, I stepped over the line.
Okay, I swear. I'll never ever get mad at you again.
Okay. I have something to say.
Go ahead.
Thank you. You saved my life.
I would've been dead otherwise.
Me too.
Come what may. I would've never married that boy.
I love someone else.
I know. But you've never said it.
I am telling now. There is a boy.
He studies with me in Delhi JNU.
I'll give up my life if I don't marry him.
I love him a lot.
'Three years in Aligarh had left me really weak, Kundan.'
'My confidence was at an all time low.'
'Leave the house meekly. And come back meekly.'
'Every girl was trained to be the ideal wife.'
'Aunt was running a coaching institute and not a house.'
'I was good at studies. So teachers told..'
'..me that I should study in Delhi.'
Vote for Aisha. Vote for Aisha.
'So, after a lot of struggle..'
'..I came to JNU, after completing my 12th.'
'I had to repeat 9th again..'
'..due to which, there was a gap year.'
'I was having trouble getting admission.'
'I had adequate marks, but couldn't get admission.'
'When I arrived at JNU, it was election time.'
Parveen, go from here. Wait there.
I wish to see Mr. Anand. - I had asked you to do that.
Yes.
Look, my marks are up to the mark. But I am not getting admission.
Why? - Because I took a year's break.
Do this. Be there outside VC's office tomorrow at 11.
Tomorrow at 11. - Okay. Please.
Did you call him or not?
'That day I saw him for the first time.'
'An ordinary guy in a pant and shirt.'
'He had innocence in his eyes. But he was fearless.'
'He came across like a born leader.'
'When I saw him I felt something which..'
'..I had never felt in 21-22 years.'
'During the conversation, he lost his cool a number of times.'
'He banged on the table. Threw things around.'
'But he never raised his voice. Nor did he threaten.'
'And nor was he disrespectful.' - I'm talking to you.
'And the VC had to relent.' - Calm down.
'And they got up, and left just quietly.'
He wasn't as tough as he looked.
He readily agreed to all our demands.
Excuse me. - Listen, come here.
Thank you. - Aunty, that's great.
Could've said that with a smile.
'That was my first meeting with him.'
'After that, I saw on the day of the election results.'
Catch. Stop there.
I said stop.
Catch him.
Catch him from that side.
Hi!
We won!
So, we can stop running now.
Uncle, 3 cups of tea.
You can drink with the President today.
Enjoy.
Consider that, a farmer has four children.
And, there's a bowl of porridge prepared in his home.
But, I say why not make two bowls of porridge?
They'll say We've material enough for just one.
I believe, the rest of it is at the minister's home.
There's one thing I would like to say.
When the poor won't have anything to eat..
..they'll start eating the rich.
War. War. American war.
American war.
America...
All of you sing really well.
You should quit social work and start a band.
And madam, you're so beautiful that you should..
..quit college and become an actress.
No. Don't say that.
Ever since this girl has come to the university..
..it seems more likeable, right?
You are right.
Escapism is the easiest thing in this world.
I am dying to see Disneyland and statue of liberty.
Choose between Coca Cola and Pepsi.
I heard your speech at the seminar.
Do you actually think that everyone in this world is equal?
I mean in a country like India can you seriously overlook caste..
..culture, creed, community, social and economic position..
..of every individual and speak about equality.
But I seriously think you are over-romanticizing a situation..
..which needs a much more logical approach.
What is your name? - Zoya.
Zoya.
Even If I was a nobody, you would still be wincing like this.
Every man in this country is different.
On caste, creed, class....blah...blah...
This is the fact.
And I don't fight for facts, madam.
I fight for what's right.
Sorry. - Go to hell.
'This was happening to me for the first time, Kundan.'
'Right from Banaras to Aligarh to Delhi..'
'..this was the first man who had treated me like that.'
'For him, I was like anyone else.'
'Actually he proved what he said.'
I get scared in the examination hall. - What else can happen?
How were the exams?
Madam, I had apologized to you.
What will you get by failing me?
Equality. You had chits to cheat.
The rest didn't.
Either come prepared next time..
..or distribute the chits in the entire examination hall.
This is a fact and also justified.
Now have I proved my point? - No.
I haven't kissed anybody else in this college.
This proves that you are privileged.
This proves that not everyone in this world is equal.
It was like I had regained my lost courage, Kundan.
This was college. A new world.
New people. New courage.
And, new love!
I'm only for you, I'm your world.
You're so sweet, while I'm bitter.
I'm all yours, I'm your world.
The color red's so pure.
It's pure, it's filled with life.' 	3132833	3137791	5375
in my heart now.
I've found my beloved.
Let no one cast an evil eye on you.
Curses to anyone who does.
My heart now belongs to you.
Let no one cast an evil eye on you.
I'm only for you, I'm your world.
You're so sweet, while I'm bitter.
I'm all yours, I'm your world.
I'm all yours.
Kundan!
What are you doing, Kundan?
Kundan. Kundan.
There will be no electricity for three days.
Yeah, that's common with us too.
What happened? How did you get wet?
Did someone throw water on you?
There's a boy here to see you. Go inside and change.
I'm serving food, get changed.
You just sat down.
Get married. That's all we want.
I don't want to. - What do you mean you don't want to?
He was such a nice, well educated boy.
Well educated? They are freaking half educated people.
What did you say? - What do you want, mother?
Either you shouldn't have sent me out of town..
..or given me such good education.
And since you have done so much..
..the boy should be of my choice, right?
Or should I marry an uncouth boy like Kundan?
This boy...was like Kundan?
He has a big house. Big cars.
What else does one need?
I want a boy like me.
What do you mean by that?
I love someone else. - What?
You call this cleaning? Sweep here. - Yes.
Murari, what's wrong with Kundan? He is not talking to anyone.
Forget him. Ask what is wrong the scooter.
He drove my brand new scooter into the Ganges.
I just took it to the mechanic. - Don't know what happened?
He says the entire engine needs overhauling.
Kundan. What have you done!
Kundan. Get up. Get up.
Get up.
You think love is a joke?
You slit your wrist as when you feel like.
This seems more like UPSC examination and not love.
You just can't pass it.
Zoya loves someone else.
To hell with your love. To hell with Zoya.
Don't you cry like a sissy who has lost his love in front of me.
And don't go to sleep.
Beloved. My beloved.
Tell me what the doctors said,
Aunt, what do I know? I was busy settling things with Ramesh.
This is not the solution.
Listen, Mr. Psychiatrist, are you done?
So leave. - Okay.
Don't use your brains too much.
Eat it. - He's calling it suicide.
As he said... He just... crazy.
He won't say that.
I had been to your house.
From there I came to know that you are here.
Yes. You will find him here if you don't find him at home.
He is in the hospital if he is not at home.
Murari. - I want to talk to you.
In private.
Come, aunt. Let's go meet the doctor.
Ask him what you were asking me.
Bindiya, come on. Come on.
Come with me.
Apples are 180 rupees a kilo.
You get vitamins from me. But you love them.
What a stubborn boy!
What a loser!
Explain to your friend. She is a curse to us.
Keep quiet.
Zoya tried your number many times.
She said that she wants to meet you.
Zoya.
I will give up my life if these people force me, Kundan.
How did this happen? - Nothing.
You slit your wrist again?
How stupid can one be?
There is a limit to tolerance.
Is this all you know to do?
I made a mistake when I was small.
So are you going to ruin my life for that?
Come on.
You want to marry, right? This is all you want, right?
Let the world go to hell.
What happened? Come on.
Come on.
Don't you understand, Kundan?
You are a Hindu and I am Muslim.
We are poles apart.
You come to deliver gas cylinder to our house.
Father likes you. So he gives the car for servicing.
You carry mother's bag of grocery.
You get flour for us.
This doesn't mean they'll get their daughter married to you.
I had imagined that you would help me if not anyone else.
But you turned out to be my biggest enemy.
I have shed blood. You shed tears.
This seems more like a violent story than a love story.
Go. Go home. Have food. Go to sleep.
I'll come up with something. Go.
What is your boyfriend's name?
Should I call him Amitabh Bachchan?
Akram. Akram Zaidi.
Kundan! At this hour?
Sir, the Hindu boy Zoya fell in love with 8 years ago..
..was me.
Because of whom you distanced Zoya from yourself.
It was me, sir.
I kept coming to your house so that I get close to you.
I kept working for you like a servant hoping you would..
..consider me family.
Only to elope with Zoya when she returns one day.
What happened, Mr. Haider?
But your daughter loves you a lot, sir.
She cares a great deal about your honour.
She had forgotten me 8 years ago.
But the boy she loves so much.
She wants to marry him with your consent only.
She could've eloped, sir.
And no one could've done a thing.
You wouldn't have found anyone's collar to grab.
And what problem do you have?
He is a Muslim boy from a good family.
He is well educated. Not an uncouth like me.
What happened, pal?
I am jacked up. Now do you want to help me?
Get lost, moron.
One by one. - Yes, I am giving. Hold on.
Now I won't give. Back up. Back up.
She is here. Go.
I think this has been going for a bit too long.
I think you should end it.
Yes, I'm giving. Don't get desperate.
No. I am not. I've run out of it.
If you couldn't find sweets you could've ordered something else.
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Otherwise papa would've never understood.
You made a fool out of me, Zoya.
What do you think, Zoya?
You are some damsel.
Loving you was my talent, Zoya.
You don't deserve any credit for it.
Even if it had been anyone else instead of you..
.. I would've loved her just as much.
What do you think, Zoya?
You are the only one in the whole of Banaras for Kundan?
I will marry the day you marry. Be it with a witch.
I'll marry on that very day. As far as your marriage goes..
..and I will do everything I can in it.
I would rather die.
But, I'll never utter your name again..
..or, I'm a deadman.
Look, forcing women is a crime.
Why don't you listen to me.
Her father's a police officer, we'll be jailed.
Don't create a scene. You'll have to get a nose ring.
This crazy girl's troubling me - Mummy.
Bindiya. - What is it?
You were really fond of marrying me, right?
Tell your father. To call the confectioner and the priest.
You're getting married to me.
On the 21st.
Tell me. Tell me. What is this, my friend?
Tell me. Tell me. What is this mystery?
What is this mystery? Am I the mystery?
Everything changes in a flash.
I have life long bond with her.
At times it seems populated. And at times deserted.
There can be no marriage without friends.
He can plunge me into darkness.
Or light up my life.
I cherish weird dreams.
There is no season without your beloved.
He makes torments me when he is with me.
He is nowhere to be seen even though he is near me.
When he is near me, he jinxes me.
My desires always stay with him.
I do everything in my power for him.
And there are no friends without mates.
What happened, pal?
A lover doesn't get petrified when his love is about to get married.
He gets petrified when he is about to get married.
Let him cry. It is his doing.
Enough. Stop. Stop.
Why is this happening with me, Murari?
One minute. One minute, Kundan.
What the..
Yes, I am fine. - Take a look.
Kundan. Kundan, you are mad. Listen to me.
Kundan, where are you going?
Kundan, where are you going? Are you mad?
I won't be able to eat all that.
Kundan. What happened?
Complete it.
Kundan, what happened?
I learnt at least that in your love.
You should've taught him something.
What's happening?
What happened?
He is Hindu.
'And with that incident..'
'..this beautiful chapter came to an end.'
'It was time to wage war.'
'All hail Lord Ram.'
No one's a kin..
Kundan, what are you doing?
Zoya has slit her wrist.
There was blood all over the house.
She's been taken to a hospital. Let's go.
Which hospital has she been taken too? - The one at Hanuman Fatak.
And, the boy Akram? - Hey
He was badly beaten up. They smashed his head.
And, these boys dumped him somewhere.
Don't try to act smart with us.
It wasn't me.
It was Nawaz and Guddu.
I left from the Kent Railway Station.
They were still beating him up.
Stay in your senses.
Kundan!
He was my brother.
Akram! -Akram!
Jasjeet!
Jasjeet! -Jasjeet!
Murari..-Jasjeet!
Jasjeet!
Oh no!
Jasjeet! Jasjeet! - They really thrashed me up.
Lift him up. - Jasjeet.
Move. Move. - Get aside.
Move. - Move.
Doctor!
He's fine now.
I'll be back soon.
She's better now.
But, she's lost lot of blood.
Weren't you getting married today as well?
Oh no! Darn it!
You go alone, Pal.
I cannot face this.
He's here.
The groom's here. - He's here.
I was trying to sleep, but couldn't. Start playing.
He's here.
Why did you do such a terrible thing with this girl?
Move.
Get out of this house. Don't ever show me your face again.
I knew it all the time.
But, it was too late.
Wouldn't have made a difference.
The Delhi government couldn't lay a finger on me.
But, a girl got me messed up.
Same with me.
Like a fool, I did as she said.
You should never pay heed to a girl's suggestions.
There's lot of work I still got to do.
If I don't get well soon..
..who's going to raise his voice in the Parliament.
What line had we thought of telling to this champ here?
What was it? - My, my, your principals..
My, my. Your principals. - These ideologies.
These ideologies.
You can't get one time meal..
These things can't get you even one time meal.
And the rallies you have on streets and the slogans and all.
This is not going to be of any use. Got it?
Join our party. True happiness is in being in power.
You hail from Jalandhar, right?
I'll get a ticket from Jalandhar area.
Anand, what had we thought of replying to Mr. Gupta?
First go and get the sign of the man...
Yes.
First go and get the sign of the man whom you have been fooling..
..for the last 60 years.
And then I'm ready to sign any paper you give me, Mr. Gupta.
Why will we fight the elections from Jalandhar..
..when we can win from Delhi.
We'll fight. And create our own party.
Thank you for the offer, sir.
And sir, you are right.
Real happiness is in being in power.
The rest is rubbish.
Did you saw that? - Yes.
We're boys of free will.
We can ride the winds as well.
The path of love, is a difficult one.
Be brave...give me your heart without a care.
Learn to be faithful from us.
Get some fresh air from us.
The stories of the heart. The days in our share.
Can only be spent from the heart.
Get rid of all the fears.
Forget the worries. Destroy the fears.
Sweetheart, come with me.
Come, the world of dreams awaits you.
The one who is alive in the true sense can conquer the world.
He will breathe freely.
Learn to be faithful from us.
Get some fresh air from us.
Join the path of truth.
Let's go everyone, to the big house. - How's everything? All okay?
Mr. Salim, how are you? - Great.
You came here personally.
You've done such a thing that we have to come time and again.
Aunt?
Good to see you, Seema. I'm coming back tomorrow.
We've such immense pressure from our seniors to arrest you.
We have been sent to arrest you.
How is everyone at home? - Great.
Officer, you too are here. - Yes.
Where are you going, sir?
Come. Let me show you the jail.
No. No. Good for you, sir.
What can I do if I'm destined to marry a criminal?
Excuse me.
What criminal, madam?
I am about to be the CM.
And if lady luck shines on me, then I'll be the PM some day.
This is the chance you have.
If you marry me, your life will be risk free.
Or carry on with your street plays in Dariaganj.
I see. And who'll ask my parents?
Parents? If you say, I can ask the entire nation.
I will announce it from Red Fort on 15th August.
Let's go, sir.
Injustice won't be tolerated. Injustice won't be tolerated.
Let's see if your jail's can hold us.
Let's see if you really got the guts.
After that, Zoya left for Beneras.
She called few days ago.
Are you insane?
Who's going to put up this act?
Just spare a week for me, please.
Everything will be fine.
Zoya, this is nonsense. I've too much left to do.
Everything was fine.
Everything under control.
And now...
Everything's shattered.
Father, this is Kundan.
He saved brother.
Otherwise, brother wouldn't have made it alive..
..from the accident.
Thank you son, you've been a big help.
But, we don't understand a thing here,
We're taking him back to Punjab.
He's lost a lot of blood.
But, there's nothing to worry about.
I'll need a tempo.
What's cooking in your mind now?
And, two train tickets to Punjab.
Tickets?
What for?
Elope! With Zoya.
Tonight.
Have you lost it, Pal?
You think Zoya will come with you.
I'll just take her to Jasjeet.
You'll get yourself killed. She'll never take a favor from you.
I don't have a choice.
Kundan, there's a limit to..
Just do as I'm saying..
Jasjeet's fine.
He's hurt, but fine.
His parents took him back home.
I made a big mistake.
But, I swear..
I'll take you to Jasjeet.
What?
The one you're searching for, dwells in your heart.
There's a sea inside you, stop looking for droplets.
Clear all your doubts.
Lift the veil.
Beloved.
You will see your beloved.
The one you're searching for, dwells in your heart.
There's a sea inside you, stop looking for droplets.
Clear all your doubts.
Lift the veil.
You will see your beloved.
No point in seeing what others do.
Try to see what the others can.
You can't see with the naked eye.
Close your eyes, and you can see it.
You will see your beloved.
You don't always get what you want.
My companion is only my shadow.
You robbed me of my heart.
Yet you whisper softly.
You will see your beloved.
The one you're searching for, dwells in your heart.
There's a sea inside you, stop looking for droplets.
Clear all your doubts.
Lift the veil.
Beloved.
You will see your beloved.
Go away.
The one you're searching for, dwells in your heart.
There's a sea inside you, stop looking for droplets.
Bring it, dear. Baba will bless you.
Hey. Priest. Leave.
Go on. Go.
You know, many of the sages here are cheats.
Castouts.
Bloody criminals.
Murderer, rapists.
They just dawn the saffron color..
..and mingle along with the real ones.
Whom did you kill?
I can see it on your face.
No faith in this world can pardon a murderer.
Go. Do something.
Don't know what?
But, you won't get salvation at the banks of Ganges.
Hello. - Murari.
Where are you?
I've been thinking about you.
Is Zoya in Beneras? - In Beneras? Is she?
That's exactly what I'm asking. Is she?
Rascal, you eloped with her.
Do you know the chaos it led to?
What are you doing? Where are you?
And, where's Zoya?
Seeking him. Feeling him.
Either its you, or its him.
Without him, everything's vain.
You will see your beloved.
People look, stare at you.
Humiliate you with their stare. Disrobe you.
And say We're just looking.
They whistle, sing songs..
..and tell their friends about it, show-off that they're men.
And say, We were just looking, it's not a crime.
Are you alive?
Is everyone here?
Zoya, let's go. - Yes, drive this vehicle.
What's wrong? - Just a second.
Hey!
What are you doing?
Hey. - Hey.
We had to wrestle the management..
..to install that pipe.
Don't break it.
Who are you? What're you doing?
And, why are you climbing up the pipe?
I...am a thief.
I was here to steal.
Why don't we turn him in?
That will mean we believe in this administration system.
I know, it's a completely ruthless..
..and a politically aggressive system.
Correct. And, we should be against it.
He's a victim of this system as well.
Samosa (Fritters). - Huh!
Two Samosas.
Samosa?
Chotu. Samosas.
Two.
So, we need to understand..
..why would anyone become a thief.
Why did you become one?
Because...I'm poor.
Water.. - Huh!
Tea...
Poverty is a result of over-population.
Don't simplify things.
Over-population is a result of lack of education.
But, lower-classes don't have resources..
..to educate their children.
No, no. One minute.
Even the educated youth in this country..
..are suffering from unemployment
I agree. - No. I am sorry.
Becoming a thief cannot be justified. - She is also right.
He's asleep.
Bro. Bro.
We know why you became a thief. - Why?
Because you're poor. - And you don't have a job. Right?
Yes.
I'm poor, and I don't have a job.
Kundan, get a cup of tea.
Give me a cold drink.
Go ahead, I'll be right with you.
What now?
I'd rather work myself to death here, than die of guilt.
And, I don't know why I'm here.
Let me stay here. Please.
Nothing's changed.
Jasjeet's 'All India Citizen's Party'..
..will still run in the upcoming elections.
His hard work can't go to waste.
I nominate Zoya as the new leader.
Those who agree, raise your hands.
So, we need to decide what's next.
We should do something..
..about the 'Bhatta Parsal' scam.
Around 4000 farmers are losing their lands.
Only to put up a factory.
The media must be present as well.
We can gain a lot of political mileage.
Fine. Let's meet here tomorrow at 11am.
The girl's got the spark.
We'll teach her the rest.
These are the basic things in politics.
Zoya. - I don't care a damn if he lives or dies.
There's nothing to discuss about him, Rashmi.
There's much left to do, and he doesn't exist for me
Come on, give the tea.
Don't look at me...like that.
Like you never saw me before.
He'll never learn. Where are you going? Stop Kundan.
Don't look at me...like that.
Load all the flags.
Anand.
Take me along. - What will you possibly do, Kundan?
Lend a helping hand.
Or, serve you all tea. - Climb on.
Come on. Who else?
Stand straight.
Don't let anyone come this side.
Be ready.
Shoot anyone you see. Get that.
No one.. Stand straight.
We're ready to talk.
Let us talk to your headman.
The government will talk to you. - You stay here.
Who are you? - What about th extra forces?
We want to meet the farmers?
Farmers? Who are you?
Get lost! - You cannot stop us.
Our party's running for elections this year.
We're here to meet the people of our constituency.
Ma'am. They've kidnapped a PSE soldier.
And, they shot at the DM's leg yesterday.
If they don't return that soldier, they'll be shot.
You've an excuse to shoot them.
It's a golden opportunity for this corrupt government..
..to take away their lands.
You're raising your voice at the wrong place.
Get that. SP sir has arrived.
Come on. Get lost.
What's the position? - The position's really bad.
Sir, we've seized the entire area.
Look. I give you five minutes..
The farmers were wrong.
They just gave the government..
..an excuse to shoot them.
They'll just target the main leaders and kill them.
And the government will say..
..We were only trying to save the PSE soldier.
The people will blame the farmers.
We'll have to talk to the SP.
Anant. - Yeah!
Talk to the media. Tell them about the situation going on here.
..we'll have to take harsh action.
Sir, we know what you're trying to do here.
We tried talking to them sir, but they aren't listening, sir.
Sir, excuse me sir!
I know you must be following your seniors orders..
..but, you cannot do this.
Actually, I can do anything I want.
I can have you all arrested.
Don't do this. Behave yourself. - Move back.
Please don't do this. - Let us talk to them
This is the last warning for you. - Move aside.
Sir, sir!
Let us go inside. - Sir!
Please, sir.
Okay. Stop! Stop!
Hey, quiet!
Thank you.
Kundan, be careful.
Bravo
Bro, What?
What did you tell the farmers?
Nothing.
I said So you shot the DM, that's alright.
But this soldier's a poor man.
His father's a farmer like you.
If he dies, his mother will curse all of you.
And, you'll be ruined.
Your rivers will run dry.
Then you can keep your lands.
That's all.
That scared them, and they let him go.
How do you come up with such things?
I'm a Pandit!
This is how I've been living in Beneras for years.
You're a rascal. - Top class.
Yes.
We will win! - AICP will win!
Vote for.. - AICP!
Vote for.. - AICP! - Hello uncle, aunty.
Vote for.. - AICP! - We're here.
Come along, sister-in-law
Stop hitting us.
Have you lost your mind? Why are you hurling slippers at us.
Are you guys mad? - Don't set foot in here.
Get lost.
We just want to talk.
We're against this government as well.
We've formed a new party.
New or old, you're just a bunch of thieves.
After the elections, no one will even take a peek here.
I'll be damned if anyone does.
We just want to help.
Mother Teresa. We don't want your help. Get out!
These rascals are here to help.
Hey! Keep that spade down.
Pick it up again and I'll beat you to a pulp.
Better get going, or else I'll start throwing slippers at you.
And humiliate you to death.
Kundan, where are you going? - Just forget it.
Hey, what's this? - Hey.
Don't create a scene.
Or else I'll beat you.
You're such pathetic rascals, to show this anger so late.
Thirty years ago, if your father had shown the same anger..
..you wouldn't have been living in this shit.
Yes, we're here to ask for your vote.
So what's wrong in that?
You've been giving your vote for the last 60 years, aren't you?
So, this time give your vote to us.
What's going to happen?
At the most, you'll be the fool.
But, that you still are.
So, shall we leave..
..or pick up the shovel and help you.
The AICP members...
'The media had made us heroes, so did fate.'
'This is when I realised..'
'..there's a huge dearth of leaders in our country.'
'If they were listening to a uncouth like me..'
'..they would listen to anyone.'
'But, I wasn't concerned about the country.'
'All I cared about was me.'
'I was thinking, if I can impress these AICP kids..'
'..then someday, she'll see the light as well.'
'But, Zoya didn't like me one bit.'
'I was walking ahead.'
'I was getting on her nerves.'
'But, I didn't realise..'
'..when my success posed a threat to the government.'
AICP party members nearly escaped from being badly beaten.
After the Bhatta Parsol incident, this is another victory..
..for AICP's youth party in Sheelampur area.
There's less than a month for the elections.
They're gaining good mileage.
They'll certainly win 10-12 seats.
Put up tents all around this place.
And, all the tents..
You don't need to put up the tent, pal.
Work on your speech.
People only listen to you.
I will speak.
What's going on here?
Get out!
Take these out. - Why?
We've official permission. - What permission?
We're the official.
You don't have our permission.
They can't just take it off? - Take these out!
Look, sir, we.. - Has the government stooped so low?
Don't touch me, or I'll have to take action.
Go ahead. Take action! - Zoya.
Beat us! - Zoya.
Stop, Zoya. - Move back.
Sir, please try to understand.
Sir! Sir! Sir!
You shouldn't raise your hand on women!
Did you record that? - Yes.
Do you want me to upload it?
That's okay. I'll handle it.
And, sir.
Even if we win 2 seats in the elections..
..you'll definitely get transferred.
Sir. We get orders too.
We've no personal enmity with you.
Sorry.
Whose orders?
Vinod Gupta.
We could've talked to the inspector calmly.
Only 10 more days of campaning.
It's not a good idea to get in a tiff with the police.
Come on, dear. Go home.
Study. Exams are close.
Him. He'll be the leader of the masses!
Don't try to catch the snake by the hood, Gupta..
..if it stings, you'll be in deep trouble.
Let's go.
Where are you going, Mr. Gupta?
Let me tell you a joke.
Everything he does is right, and what I do is wrong.
He's the undisputed leader of the party.
We'll need his permission for everything, right?
He'll give the speech. Help us win the elections!
Let me congratulate you Kundan!
You must be really happy, you dog!
What else do you need?
Now, you've the position of the man you killed.
And, now you want his girlfriend to sleep with, right?
What else do you want?
I never cried over Jasjeet's death.
I wanted to dedicate my life to fulfil his last dream.
That's all.
But, you can snatch that too.
Yes! He killed Jasjeet. And you're cheering him!
Anant Srivastav! This man killed him!
Go ahead, lick him!
You didn't just lose Jasjeet..
..or, you didn't lose just a friend.
I lost my brother.
That means I get to kill him first.
This man is our last hope.
You can choose power, politics, position..
..over your brother's death.
Can you all forget the man that formed this party?
His agenda wasn't just winning the elections.
He had principles, he believed him.
And he died because of this man.
Honestly son, my son passed because of you.
You made it possible.
Police? - Why are they here?
Come on, son. Apoligise.
Apologise, or we'll break your bones.
Mr. Gupta. I never even apologised to my father..
..when I made a mistake.
And now, it's not my mistake, neither are you my father.
Beat him!
Stop. - Don't beat him.
Kundan, let him go.
Let Kundan go.
What are you thinking?
Say it
Thankfully Zoya said everything.
I couldn't have.
I should leave.
Look.
There are two types of leaders.
One, that likes to dissolve the government.
And the other, who like to make a government.
I knew Jasjeet better than these two women!
He was the second type.
Stay.
But, this time you've got to do something.
Madam. That's a really nice gift for Kapil.
But, think Gupta.
If he bites us only for his ego.
Pees over the 2015 budget.
And bites every minister and official?
Sorry, madam. It was a mistake.
You've turned this into a chaos..
..and say it's a mistake.
Don't worry, I'll handle it.
The next five years..
..you will be handling that dog, Gupta.
You've enjoyed too many privileges for too long.
Santram, take me to St. George's Hospital.
Will you tell me what this is all about?
Start from the very beginning.
It's the first time police has entered JNU Campus.
And, your reaction?
Who said it's the first time? It's happened before.
Madam, yours is a political party.
So, how can you operate from a government institute.
The administration doesn't have a problem..
..so, why do you?
Ms. Zoya, what was the reason behind the scuffle.
Look. We are the victims here.
My friends are hurt.
Many have suffered broken bones!
Why don't you go to Mr. Gupta's office?
Why not raise this question outside the Parliament?
We'll give a reply. But, not like this.
Not when we're beaten.
We'll do it on a stage.
And, on the top of our voice.
We're organizing a rally. You're all invited.
Thank you. - Ma'am, please..
May I have a word with you, Zoya?
Alone?
Sad about Jasjeet.
I often heard about him.
I met him once. At the ISC Conference.
He was an intelligent boy. - He did tell me.
He said you're quite intelligent as well.
So, how can you be so stupid?
She has come.
Excuse me!
Hey, the CM's here.
Name your price for giving us Kundan.
Ask him to join our party.
I'm telling you because you're close to him.
The party is Jasjeet's.
Kundan's the leader.
And, what about you? Nothing.
The reason your party made it this far..
..was only because of Kundan.
Are you done?
Thank you.
Why did you feel hurt?
Did I say something wrong?
Zoya, Jasjeet would've been really sad..
..to see you in this condition.
Come on in.
Let's talk.
Just think about it, Zoya.
Think. No pressure.
You know my house. Office too.
My secretary will be in touch with you.
Let me know if you change your mood.
Everyone likes you, Kundan.
You're their hero.
Stay back.
They all need you.
I don't want anything from you.
No consolation, or faith.
No applauds, or sympathy.
No dreams, no comfort.
Sorry!
Don't look at me like this.
Where's your husband? - He's dead.
Dead? There he is.
I am the song...you don't want to listen.
The first leaf...fallen in Autumn.
A drop of tear...in the desert.
I'm the moment that's passed.
No way I can come back.
That's true.
Don't look at me...like you never saw me before.
Like you never saw me before.
Don't look at me..
Load these as well. - No!
Who is calling now?
Kundan, answer the phone.
Talk to them once.
Anant.
Kundan and I are taking a rickshaw.
You guys take the bus. - Okay.
Hurry up everyone. If you're finished then sit in your places.
Take him along.
These are Jasjeet's clothes.
This Nehru jacket looked really nice on him.
I couldn't see him make it this far.
So, why not you.
I couldn't help him prepare for the battle.
The first day I saw you in Delhi..
..I wanted to hug you.
And ask...won't you do anything..
..for the same Zoya you slit your wrist.
The world will spit on me if I love you.
But look, I'm in love now.
You're looking nice.
Go on, Kundan.
Everyone's waiting for you.
Kundan, go!
You're doing everything so well..
..why did falter here now?
Zoya, you're trying to prove a Muslim, Hindu again.
Control yourself.
No need to love me.
They're crazy, but you're smart.
I don't know what you're trying to do..
..or, where you're asking me to go.
But, I'll go anywhere you ask me to.
And I swear, I will win.
And, if you still say you don't love me..
..then you can slap me 17 times.
Otherwise..
..I will take my 17 kisses.
'Everything can still be fixed.'
'You've to keep Kundan until the last day of the campaign.'
'You just announced a big rally.'
'Your job is to bring Kundan to that rally.'
'And according to the situation..'
'..you might win a few seats.'
'But, that's possible only when Kundan's with you.'
'So, that face will help you win.'
'On the last day of the campaign, finish him.'
'The police will pose no threat.'
'An small explosion can scatter such gatherings.'
'Doesn't take long to start a pandemonium.'
Hello madam, look.
'Doesn't take long to shoot a bullet in such places.'
'And what's left behind? Seats.'
'You just need to extend your support..'
'..to our party, after Kundan's dead.'
'Who'll be the leader of your party..'
'..of course, only you will decide.'
'That will take care of your job, and ours too.'
'Scores settled.'
How can they stoop that low?
Some people believe that Kundan's been shot..
..while others believe he's been badly beaten up.
Only time will tell us the truth.
Come. Come.
Calm down! Please calm down!
You all want to know..
..whether we're involved in the India Gate incident?
Well, the answer's right before you.
Can we hurt those we want to make an alliance with?
Well, no leader can be that stupid.
Come, Zoya.
Come, share the big news.
The big news isn't what the CM just announced.
The big news is that..
..she's involved in the India Gate incident that occurred today.
And, me too.
Her reasons obvious.
And, it'll take all night to know mine.
By the way, I'm ready to go myself.
You can levy an inquiry on her.
And in 10-15 years, when it's proven..
..you can send her to me.
Now the scores are settled.
You're lying, right?
How could Kundan go to that rally?
Because, I had informed him in the morning..
..that, there's going to be an uproar.
Can you take me there?
Move back!
You'll die, pal.
Why endure all that..
Die.
Is your party under anyone's pressure?
Ms. Zoya, answer us.
He's yours.
My Kundan never spat blood.
'That's it.'
'That was my story.'
'A girl sitting besides me.'
'Few doctors, who were hoping to save me.'
'A friend, who was insane.'
'Another girl, who dedicated her life to me.'
'My mom, dad, and the lanes of Beneras.'
'And my body, that had left me.'
'And my chest, where the fire was still raging.'
'I could've got up, but for whom?'
'I could've screamed, but for whom?'
'My love, Zoya, Beneras, Bindiya, Murari..'
'..they were all slipping away.'
'But, why would I have stayed back for?'
'The fire inside me could've kept me alive, or kill me.'
'But, why get up now.'
'Who's got the courage to fall in love again..'
'..suffer a heart-break.'
'Somebody stop me.'
'This girl besides me with the blank stare..'
'..I can still get up for her.'
'But no. I'm not in the mood anymore.'
'It's better to close my eyes. To get into deep slumber.'
'But, I will get up again some day.'
'To ring the tabor on the banks of Ganges.'
'To run in those lanes.'
'To fall for some Zoya again.'