555-01-36.
If you check in, I'm heading for
the airport early. Meet me for coffee.
They're gonna mark you tardy.
I've got court today.
You working late?
I can if you are.
Thought I'd take you to The Palm.
I wanna get my dad
one of those weather radios.
The nothing-but-weather ones.
Now that he's on the water.
Get him a book.
Let him dope it out. He'd like that.
You'd like that.
He doesn't think the weatherman
will lie to him.
He wants to know
if a hurricane's coming.
What's wrong with The Palm?
It's Friday night. It'll be crowded.
You like it crowded.
Okay, let's go to The Palm.
If you're just killing time...
Help!
Did he talk about God?
Ask him if God said anything bad.
If we get him to say
God speaks to him, then--
That thing's cordless.
What else did he say?
Oh, baloney.
She's on the phone.
She'll be right down.
What's he know about
the democratic process?
I gotta go.
Got any cash?
Sure.
I need about a half a million.
Harold Cornelius is gonna run
against me as a write-in.
He's a nutcase.
With a chain of drugstores
and a lot of money.
- Where are you going?
- New York.
New Hampshire won't stand for him
buying a seat in Congress.
He's Elmer Fudd.
Yeah, sure.
Jessie's birthday's Wednesday.
I said we'd both be home.
Sure.
Attention.
Convective Sigma 3 Echo in effect
for Washington-Baltimore area.
A line of thunderstorms
approximately 60 miles wide...
...moving from 260 degrees at 15 knots
with tops to flight level 350.
Wind gusts to 60 knots and possible
cloud-to-cloud lightning.
Visibility occasionally one mile...
I said I wouldn't take PAC money.
- That's when we didn't need it.
- What do I say now?
Do you swear to tell the truth?
I do.
Name and occupation for the jury.
William Van Den Broeck.
Sergeant in Internal Affairs...
...of the District of Columbia
Police Department.
And what's your job, sergeant?
Internal Affairs investigates incidents
or allegations of misconduct...
... involving sworn officers and
employees of the District of Columbia.
Miami boarding at gate 33.
He thinks we'll let him
get away with that?
Depose Henry.
Sure.
I'll see you.
Sergeant...
...Van Den Broeck...
...you had to take a test
to make sergeant, didn't you?
It was a written exam.
If I put into evidence
records showing...
...56 officers took
the test same time as you...
...and you did better than 54 of them,
would that be about right?
- We could look it up.
- The point is...
...you're a smart guy.
Number two on the written,
11 years a sergeant.
How come you're not a lieutenant?
Where are we going with this?
Is it because you're white?
She cannot do that! Your Honour!
From 1 1 News,
this is a special report.
May I help you?
I'm looking for a gift for my wife.
Is there a radio just for weather?
It's for my father-in-law in Florida.
I got a couple back here.
I'll show you.
A normal crew is two pilots
and three attendants.
The aircraft involved was a 7 3 7...
... which normally is configured
for seats for 96 to 1 38 passengers.
- Where's this?
- Down in the bay.
National Safety Board officials
were en route to the site...
--over Chesapeake Bay,
20 miles south...
... of the city limits,
where Southern Airlines flight...
...43 7 to Miami went down
about an hour ago...
... with 1 03 passengers...
Anything happening?
School cops took a nine
out of this girl's locker.
Same gun got logged into evidence
six weeks ago. Drive-by weapon.
--8000 feet when it veered off-course
and began a steep descent--
The only thing he isn't short on
is cash.
He'll buy a million dollars
worth of TV time...
...and hide behind the best advertising
money can buy.
I can beat him if I can get
on television myself.
The issue here is whether someone
totally unsuited for public office...
...can buy his way into
the United States Congress.
I hope your answer's no.
I said "buy" too many times, right?
Let's eat.
You got no lunchroom here?
Here's what we got.
We got a gun that was used
in a homicide. Killed someone.
It got stolen out of the property room.
Maybe some cop sold it right out.
Then we got you
in possession of that gun.
We ain't got no lunchroom.
Some school fool say he found
some gun in my locker.
I wouldn't know. I wasn't there.
I ain't possessing nothing.
How did it get in your locker, Shyla?
Don't use my Christian name
like we'll be friends.
It's my impression you weren't
in the market for corporate support.
I hate making these calls.
I thought I wouldn't have to.
But now I need the money.
We had good relations with your dad.
He understood the communications
business. We appreciated that.
Who was doing your media?
I guess I was.
Never needed much till Cornelius
came out of left field.
Make that right field.
What do you think of Carl Broman?
--offshore breeze and clearing.
Low tonight in the mid-70s.
Juvenile's got her brother
for knocking over gas stations.
I guess she's holding for him...
...but she won't talk to us.
We can get her detention.
Oh, yeah? How?
I'll lose her paperwork.
You'd do that?
Hold her without a charge?
For a week. If she wants
to go home, maybe we get a name.
Dutch, line three.
Van Den Broeck.
Clayton? And George Beaufort?
Well, Friday's payday, I guess.
Stick with him till we catch up.
I want this son of a bitch.
Alcee, we're on the roll.
Janice...
I didn't do anything.
We were just talking.
Don't even think that way.
Shit like that makes people hate cops.
Grab a radio.
Cassie?
You got a car for me?
Not the pimpmobile.
It's surveillance, not narcotics.
This is it.
Your wife called.
She said things came up at work.
She can't eat with you
and you should call.
You can see the tail
is sticking out of the water.
You can hear choppers above me.
News choppers are getting
a better look.
Search and rescue operations--
--about an hour ago, with a reported
1 03 passengers onboard...
That aeroplane, a 12-year-old 737...
There's Clayton.
What the hell's he doing?
- What's this clown doing?
- I don't know.
And where's George?
- Wait a minute.
- Get Elton and Tommy back here quick.
Tommy, we need you guys back here.
Something's going down.
Clayton?
How you doing? What's going on?
Where's George, your partner?
In the basement.
The basement?
What's he doing in there?
A guy named Marvin is pouring booze
without a license.
We're getting ready to write him.
He comes up with a shotgun.
He says he wants money.
He tells me to get it.
He's got George.
Somebody's holding
George Beaufort hostage.
Can he send us an ear?
What's the plan, officer?
We could call police.
Is that what you're
getting ready to do?
Call the police?
There's a lot here already.
He's got a gun on George.
We gotta do something.
See, we're Internal Affairs.
You got a policeman that screws up.
You got a policeman
that abuses his position, steals.
That's us.
What do you think is going on?
You think we just happened by?
We've been on you all day. All week.
We've been on you all month.
You know what I think?
Somebody got sick
and tired of paying you off.
You wanna corroborate that,
gives us a reason...
...to drag George's ass
out of the basement.
Or we'll talk to the guy
with the gun, hear his version.
You're asking me to turn George in?
Just push me and push me...
Marvin?
I'm Sergeant Van Den Broeck.
Hello, asshole. You're under arrest.
Who is the real Kay Chandler?
What's she stand for?
Do you know?
What's she doing in Congress anyway?
Harold Cornelius for Congress.
Shirley Magnuson did it.
- Pretty good.
- You think so?
She knows you're running
as Arthur Spencer's daughter.
Poor guy's dead, and when he wasn't,
he got a lot of votes.
So all she does is ask
a couple of questions.
The subtext is "She only
got elected because of her daddy."
She didn't earn it.
This is America. That ain't fair.
I'm not running
as Arthur Spencer's daughter.
What will you run as? Nice person?
I have my own record.
City attorney?
"National committeewoman"?
A record's when somebody
remembers what you did.
I beat Harvey Galin five to three.
My, my.
Five to three.
How'd those three vote Democratic
in a district that hadn't...
...voted for a Democrat since
Roosevelt? They're sending a message.
This won't be a nice election.
Folks talking about
the amber waves of grain.
It's about the man's money
against the woman's name.
Can't beat you on your record.
You have none.
He won't beat you on the issues.
On the issues, I'll kick his ass.
The question is,
can you beat Shirley Magnuson?
I'm not running against
Shirley Magnuson.
What you don't want in the papers...
...what you haven't told your husband,
she'll find it.
Shirley's wasting her time.
How's your marriage?
Swell. How's yours?
If I was running for office,
I'd be in trouble.
You fool around, Mrs. Chandler?
A little slap and tickle?
Any special friends?
Not at the moment,
but I'll keep you posted.
What's the worst thing
you've done?
You need a life, Mr. Broman.
For a moment, I thought we wouldn't
have any fun at all.
I didn't take a dime from you,
you bastard.
Marvin...
We don't come up soon,
they'll come and get us.
What you think they'd do about me?
You'll pay a fine for pouring liquor
without a license...
...but I need you to testify
against George.
You got some leverage.
Wanna make your situation worse?
Just keep thinking
what you're thinking.
You pay a little fine,
plead to disorderly.
But you gotta promise
you'll show up against George.
I gotta have that shotgun.
Now.
Good man. Go on up.
Alcee, Marvin's coming up.
Get him downtown.
Take real good care of him, okay?
Were you really gonna shoot him?
He had that shotgun
pointed right at me.
What would you do about me?
I figured he'd shoot you.
And I'd shoot him, get myself a medal.
You'd be dead, of course.
You got a right
to remain silent, officer.
Use it.
--95 passengers and crew members
are now feared lost.
Navy divers were expected
to work throughout the night.
Will Thomas, are you there?
They already have a crane trying
to hoist the plane out of the water.
We've got divers.
Where's Peyton?
Working late.
You gonna eat?
We've got bay scallops.
See if I can find her.
--the plane struck the surface
at an angle...
...and bounced at least one time before
plowing into the water nose first.
I'm at Billy's. I'll call you at home.
If we don't catch up, I'll eat here.
He's got scallops.
Love you. Bye.
It's the Van Den Broecks.
Leave a message. We'll call you back.
To play back your messages, press one.
Hi, I'm at the airport.
I send a catalogue to Miami without me,
and it's falling apart.:
A new stylist, locations don't work,
bugs biting the girls...
...and you don't wanna know what else.
Therefore, I'm on the plane
to kill critters and counsel careers.
I'll try to get back tomorrow,
but it may not be till Sunday.
God knows where I'll sleep.
They're in the Keys.
I'll call you when I can.
I had fun this morning.
I love you.
You find her?
No. That plane was going to Miami,
wasn't it?
Give me some quarters.
I once got laid in Miami.
My name's Van Den Broeck.
I'm a police officer,
if that makes any difference.
I know you get a lot of crazies
when something like this happens.
I think it's possible my wife
may have been on your plane.
Peyton Van Den Broeck.
Great. Boy. She must be on another
flight. Boy, that'll wake you up.
What are the other flights to Miami?
Check the 1 : 1 5,
but it doesn't make sense.
She left for the airport after 9.
Excuse me. I'm Bill Van Den Broeck,
Peyton's husband.
She went to Miami today.
I need to know what plane she was on.
I can be with you in just one moment.
We don't have this in a six,
but I can order it.
I'm Bill Van Den Broeck,
Peyton's husband.
She went to Miami.
I need to know what plane she was on.
- You're the policeman?
- Right.
Mary Claire Clark books the travel,
but she goes home at 5:30.
Can you reach her at home?
Oh, my God! The plane that crashed.
She was going to Miami,
but they don't have her listed.
How do we get ahold
of Mary Claire Clark?
Do we have to shout?
Peyton went to Miami.
She might be on the plane that crashed.
We have to find out
what flight she was on.
Does anyone know what
Mary Claire Clark was doing tonight?
Call the switchboard.
Get her number.
The airline won't tell you?
She's not listed,
but she's not listed on any flight.
I know she was going.
She left messages at work and home.
They can't give out home numbers.
This is Molly Roll. Who's this?
I need your help. I'm the supervisor
in Designer Wear...
...and you'll confirm that when you
call me back at extension 293, okay?
I need the home telephone number
of Mary Claire Clark.
She's the department secretary.
We are managing an emergency.
Do you understand?
Thank you.
You must be Dutch. I'm Molly.
What was she doing in Miami?
It sounded like some kind of crisis.
You're shooting a catalogue in the Keys
that was falling apart?
What would we be shooting in the Keys?
Did she say which catalogue?
Molly Roll.
Thank you.
Sarah, would you get her for me?
I'll get my boss.
What catalogue are we shooting?
I didn't know we were doing a catalogue.
Susan, are you working?
- Peyton didn't know she was going.
- There's no answer.
Somebody must've called her.
Would she call Mary Claire
for a reservation or would she...
...use a travel agent?
This is Mr. Driker, vice president
of Designer Wear. He's our boss.
- Would you excuse us, please?
- Sure.
Molly says Peyton may be
on the plane that crashed.
- Is Peyton on that plane?
- We don't know.
- Either way, she's toast.
- Can you zip it?
We don't have a catalogue shooting
in Florida or anywhere else.
The next catalogue's not till Christmas.
Maybe it's not a catalogue.
Something with models.
The girls were bit by bugs.
No, there's nothing like that.
If Peyton's travelling,
I don't think it's for the store.
I know when people are out of town.
I approve it, and we're stingy on travel.
Are you saying she lied to me?
I'm saying I don't know where she is.
I'm thinking of something I can do.
I'd like to be helpful.
There was this judge who had...
...two whole entire families, kids,
dogs, everything. A judge.
We think we know. We don't know.
Nobody knows. You just don't know.
Oh, my God.
Maybe she travelled as someone's wife.
If anyone knows what his name is...
...I could check that way.
I don't know. Honestly.
Beats me. She seemed...
I mean, she never looked
like she was looking.
Like girls look
if they're looking, okay?
Mr. Van Den Broeck...
...I think I know Peyton
as well as anyone here.
I've got no idea.
Are you surprised?
The important thing is we don't know
if she was on the plane.
I think she was on the plane.
Jessie, tell me the truth.
Are kids drinking at these parties?
I invented some of the excuses
you're giving me.
I've been 15. You've never been 35.
Okay, okay, 37.
I'll see for myself Wednesday.
5'6."
1 20.
Blue eyes.
A wedding band, just plain.
A diamond ring, emerald-cut,
about a carat.
I'm telling you, she was on your plane.
If I'm wrong, great!
If I'm right, you know
who to call, okay?
Got some empty boxes?
Ask the guy out back.
Excuse me.
Are you Mr. Van Den Broeck?
I'm David Dotson. This is
Phyllis Bonaparte. Southern Airlines.
- Do you have a minute to talk to us?
- Sure.
Mr. Van Den Broeck...
...we don't show your wife as anybody's
passenger on any flight to Miami.
Hi, I'm at the airport.
I send a catalogue to Miami without me,
and it's falling apart.:
A new stylist, locations don't work,
bugs biting the girls...
...and you don't wanna know what else.
Therefore, I'm on the plane to kill--
No one named Van Den Broeck reserved
or bought a ticket to Miami.
There is no catalogue shoot.
She works for Saks.
They don't know where she is.
I think she was gonna spend the weekend
in Miami with another guy.
If she was, would she tell
the truth about her destination?
Trick is not to lie more than you
have to. Got a passenger list?
I can't let you see it.
I figure he bought the tickets
"Mr. and Mrs."
I think he's married. Be interesting
when you call his house.
- I'm not allowed--
- Let him see the list.
- I need that back.
- They'll give you another one.
A Royal Regency Hotel is
near where the plane went down.
We have rooms there
for family members.
Why don't you drive down with us?
You'll have to identify--
To make the identification.
Sit around with the next of kin?
I got a lot of things to do.
I don't think you should be
alone right now.
I was alone before you got here.
Everybody, listen up. Listen up.
A guy thinks his wife was on 43 7...
...travelling with a man
on Mr.-and-Mrs. tickets.
He's a cop, so as far as we know,
he's not nuts.
Who the wife's boyfriend is,
he hasn't got a clue.
We got nine M-and-Ms. Another two pair
sitting together, same last name.
Married, cousins, who knows?
Be careful.
Don't assume a deceased Mrs.
is for real.
We don't wanna be the ones telling
some widow her husband died happy.
And we don't wanna tell kids that Mom's
gone when Mom's asleep in Bethesda.
What does your sex life have to do
with saving social security?
Tell me that.
According to
Shirley Magnuson, everything.
What is the worst thing
you've ever done?
If I've already done it,
it'll be a dull life.
You're gonna be a big disappointment
to old Shirley.
You think Cullen's the last man
you'll ever sleep with?
College was best.
All that stuff going on.
"When's he gonna call?
When's he gonna kiss me?"
At night, when I bring it back...
...I get that ache all over again.
I'll tell Richard to host
the fundraiser. Come over.
Both of you.
We'll make a guest list.
He's in New York.
What are you doing here on Saturday?
George and Clayton made bond.
You know this ain't the best case
we ever made.
We got Clayton's statement.
Did you read him his rights?
He'll say I didn't.
We got Marvin.
Something wrong with you?
What's wrong, Dutch?
Dick? Sorry.
Three A and B,
Mr. and Mrs. Cullen Chandler.
No one's called.
There's an unlisted number for
a Cullen Chandler at the Metropolitan.
Doorman says Mrs. Chandler
is a congresswoman.
And he saw her today.
She was going jogging.
When I was small,
I knew my father was in politics.
I didn't know what that was,
or why he went to Washington.
Let's make it "dad." "My dad."
Instead of "father."
Warms it up a little.
"Dad." All right.
Kay Chandler, take three.
Hello. I'm Kay Chandler
and I'm running for Congress.
When I was small,
I knew my dad was in politics--
Maybe it should be "kid."
"When I was a kid"...
"When I was just a kid."
How about that?
"When I was a kid."
Help you?
We need to speak to Mrs. Chandler.
- We're taping.
- It's all right. What is it?
Mrs. Chandler, I'm Dick Montoya.
This is Phyllis Bonaparte.
We're with Southern Airlines.
Is there somewhere we can talk?
Well, about what?
I'm very sorry to have to tell you.
Your husband was on our flight...
...to Miami yesterday.
What?
The one that--
No, no, no. Cullen's in New York.
I wish that were so, ma'am.
You do fly to New York, don't you?
Not from Washington, no, ma'am. No.
The identification is correct.
I'm awfully sorry.
He said he was going to New York.
Why would he go to Miami?
The identification is correct.
We have his wallet.
I'm very sorry.
If something happened to him
it'll lead the news tonight.
Where's your daughter?
We have a daughter. She's 1 5.
We won't release the casualty list
till all families are notified.
But we need your help
identifying your husband.
Where is he?
Patuxent Naval Air Station.
- I have to get home.
- I understand. Let us help.
Call Dick Taradisian at the White House.
Tell him what the deal is.
Ask him if he can get a plane
to meet us at Patuxent.
If the Air Force can't do it,
call GM or anybody with a jet.
He did say Miami.
Usually it's New York,
but this time he said Miami.
Mr. Van Den Broeck,
we have a car for you.
Ma, what are you doing home?
Where's Dad?
"Thou anointest my head with oil.
My cup runneth over.
Surely goodness and mercy
shall follow me...
...all the days of my life...
...and I will dwell in the house
of the Lord forever."
Let us pray.
Almighty God, Father of mercies
and giver of all comfort...
I met this guy because he was
smart enough to get out of the rain.
I was too.
So we waited under the arch
in the Law quad till it was over.
And then he asked me...
...if I knew where the bookstore was.
And I said...
...I happened to be going there myself,
which was a lie, of course.
We had so many great days.
Just not enough years.
But we had his love.
Maybe I'll call you.
Let's go.
Excuse me.
Are you Mary Claire Clark?
Yes. I am so sorry.
The name Cullen Chandler
mean anything?
No.
If I'd called my wife that morning,
what would you have said?
That she called in and said
she was taking the day off.
But you wouldn't have gotten me.
She sent me to Tyson's Corners...
...and said I could go home.
So I'd have gotten her voice mail?
Thank you.
Mr. Van Den Broeck...
...I have some of her...
...personal things.
I could drop them off--
I'll take them now.
I know.
I gotta get out of here.
I'll take Jess.
Kay, it's gonna look like--
I don't care.
Just get us back to Washington.
I can't see these people.
It's like going--
Don't make a mistake now.
Everybody's watching.
Just one more day.
How can I find out if a guy
was on a flight to Miami in May?
My name is Bill Van Den Broeck.
- They said you're a policeman.
- I am.
But I'm not working right now.
Then what is this about?
My wife was on that plane
that your husband was on.
I'm sorry.
- I wonder if I could have a few minutes.
- I just got home.
This isn't a good time for me.
For me either.
So you're visiting survivors.
You're the only one.
I'd ask you to sit--
I don't understand.
My daughter's due back any minute.
Do you have kids?
Jessica. She's 1 5.
Is there something
you wanna know, Mr...?
I'm sorry, I forgot your name.
It's Van Den Broeck.
I just thought that...
I'm so sorry.
It's really...
It's unspeakable.
Unspeakable.
But you seem okay.
Do I?
Paper said your husband was a lawyer
in New Hampshire.
He has an office here.
Most of his work was here.
I'm in Congress.
Yeah, I know.
So why was he going to Miami?
Business.
He had business there.
Are you investigating something?
They were sitting together on the plane.
Your husband.
My wife.
Do you know that?
Three A and B.
First class.
First class isn't what it used to be.
It's not worth the money.
Is there anything else?
You mad at me?
I don't know you, lieutenant.
Why would I be mad?
I'm a sergeant.
What are you? A sophisticator?
That's my daughter.
Sorry. An airline guy left
Dad's things downstairs...
...so I brought them up.
This is my daughter, Jessica.
This is Sergeant--
Van Den Broeck. They call me Dutch.
It's easier.
He lost his wife on the plane.
I'm sorry.
Never been to New Hampshire.
You go to school there or here?
I go to Andover. It's a prep school.
I won't take any more of your time.
- I'm sorry about your dad.
- Thanks.
Nice to meet you.
I need an hour.
It's not a lot to ask.
Don't come around here again.
They must've cleaned them.
It must--
I'm sure it's for your birthday.
Dad said he was gonna
get you something great.
Expensive.
He knew I'd say no.
I know you're worried about me...
...but I still want you to run.
I'll be fine.
I don't want us to sit around here
all day and be depressed.
I'm gonna go back to school tomorrow.
All my friends are there.
And it's only 40 miles.
I can come home on weekends if I want.
Somebody popped Marvin.
Jesus Christ!
Shit!
George Beaufort did this.
What else did you
find in here? Anything?
Is this a bad time?
I don't need to go
through all that garbage.
My case'll get kicked because
somebody killed my only witness.
- You get in there and do it!
- Easy, easy.
The last pickup was a week ago.
It hasn't been that long.
It sure smells long.
Sheila, what are you doing here?
That ain't even my name.
Let's talk to people.
Take that side. I'll take this side.
It's Homicide's.
- We're off it.
- The hell we are.
- I will not allow you to--
- I have no choice. I need your help.
Before you told me my husband
was screwing your wife...
...did it occur to you that
that might be hurtful?
You knew already.
Suppose I didn't.
How did you know?
He told me he was going to New York.
He's on the wrong plane,
so it must be another woman?
Well, it could've been amnesia.
My wife was in Miami
in February and in May.
- Do you think your husband was?
- What difference does it make?
It's over. It's entirely over.
They're through with each other!
We are through with them!
We can't even get a divorce!
You can do that.
I have a child.
I try and go back...
...in my head.
What's the last thing
you remember...
...about you and your husband
that you know is true?
I gotta find out how far back
I have to go to do that.
This is where they were gonna stay.
I've got work to do.
Don't you wanna know how it started?
How long it was going on?
You don't wanna know their plans?
You don't wanna know anything?
What she thought
when she thought about me.
I'd like to know that.
I thought you might like to know
what she looked like.
You leave me alone.
I mean it.
Thirty.
Take a number and have a seat.
Alice Beaufort? George Beaufort's wife?
Is he all right?
He's fine.
I'm Sergeant Van Den Broeck.
I'd like to ask a few questions.
He was with me.
What time was that?
Any time you're talking about.
Thirty-one.
You've got an envelope.
February was swimsuits
and May was fall fashion.
And you saw those catalogues?
I saw the catalogues. I told you twice.
I'll get them for you.
How do we know she shot them in Miami?
What if--?
There were palm trees.
There was a beach
and a very big ocean.
If she doesn't run, she's crazy.
It's a sympathy bounce, but she's
up 1 4 points since the funeral.
I think she'll stay in,
but she'll need some time.
She's this brave widow with this kid.
They're eating it up.
You're hard.
She knows. I know she knows.
Maybe he was buying a boat.
Maybe it was drugs
or government work.
Why are you so determined
it's another woman?
Why are you protecting him?
If you know who it is, I swear--
You think I lied the first five times,
but now I'll cave?
Why is this so important to you?
I caught Sam with a woman once.
I spilled a milkshake on my skirt,
so I ran home from lunch.
I heard them in the shower.
And at first, I thought
it was the radio.
But what she was saying
you don't hear on the radio.
I ran.
I couldn't go back to work.
For hours, literally...
...I didn't remember...
...that I was involved
with someone else.
I had been for months.
And I liked my life with Sam.
Things were fine.
What'd you do?
I kept my mouth shut.
And I never went home again
without calling first.
To say that involvement...
...and I don't mean casual sex,
I mean romance.
To say that that whole part
of life...
...half the fun of life has to end...
If you told me that had to be over...
...I'd feel old.
If you had known about Peyton...
...would you tell me?
Now, I mean.
No.
I'm gonna run to the ladies' room.
Get me another one.
Broman's over there dreaming up
ways to remind you of my loss.
A detective came by
the office today...
...asking about Cullen.
I wasn't there. Barry said he asked
how much Cullen travelled.
He seemed particularly
interested in Miami.
Asked who our Miami clients were.
Said he was going there tomorrow.
Is this anything I should know about?
I have no idea.
I'm sorry. It's too soon.
- I'm sorry.
- I wanna go home.
- Wait for Wendy.
- I'll get a cab. Tell Wendy I'm sorry.
Leave a message. I'll call you back.
Mr. Van Den Broeck? Hi.
I'm so sorry about Peyton.
Come. Have a coffee.
February, we shoot in the studios...
...May, the Keys,
to get away from tourists.
Why come to Miami twice in a row?
Why not go somewhere else?
I would like to think
it was my work...
...but I suspect so she can
walk the city and sketch.
She loved the streets, the markets...
...the Latin music.
Was there a man?
I don't think there is a man, no.
What did she do after work?
More walking.
But sometimes the clubs,
for music and to watch the dancing.
You know who she went with?
If I can say...
If you wanna be with a woman,
these shoots are not so good for that.
Did you ever sleep with Peyton?
Your situation is very difficult.
I excuse the question.
Could I talk to somebody
in your security department?
It looks like she did.
Can we talk someplace?
Stoli, please, on the rocks.
I'm from a little town
in a little state.
Unfortunately, I'm in Congress.
So when you interview people,
it's easy to start talk.
They might stumble on the truth.
You can't possibly want that.
- You're the only one I wanna talk to.
- I don't know anything!
What do you wanna know?
- How long it went on.
- So we know how stupid to feel?
How they met, their plans.
I can't help you.
At least you tried.
You trying to be funny?
No. Not anymore.
Don't you fuck with me!
If you don't like that word,
don't use it.
Do you know what happens when a member
of Congress accuses you of harassment?
We'd get our names in the newspapers.
That's close to blackmail.
I'm not a lawyer.
I'm not some investigation.
You can't rummage through my life.
Who's next on your list?
My neighbours, staff, friends?
- Then talk to me.
- So you can paw through my marriage?
Make me confess to something?
My life is mine to judge, not yours.
You're not the only one involved.
Look, if they find out about your wife,
it's gossip.
If they find out about my husband,
it's in the papers.
I have a daughter who adores
her father, who doesn't know.
What do I tell her?
I don't know.
Come on.
I wanna show you something.
Nice, huh?
I figure they would've
had drinks here.
Wanna see their room?
- They never got here.
- Not this time.
She stayed here February 1 9th.
Also May 1 4th, on business.
If he was with her,
he didn't register.
Did your husband like Latin stuff?
Music, dancing?
Why?
The concierge booked them a table
at a place called La Roca.
Cullen liked classical music.
You sure?
What?
Do you know what I do for a living?
I get paid to notice stuff.
I get paid to know who's lying.
I didn't have a clue.
I missed it.
I thought we were happy.
Not giddy...
...not ecstatic.
We weren't unhappy.
I wasn't.
I was pretty happy.
I don't wanna be here.
That's Kay Chandler.
Peter Suchet. East Concord.
Voted for your dad.
Do you mind?
Honey, take another picture.
- They took our picture.
- You know them?
They're from Concord.
They took our picture.
I bury my husband
and go nightclubbing in Miami.
- Stay here.
- Where are you going?
To get the film.
God, no! You can't just mug some guy.
It'll just make things worse.
You are a cop.
Is that gonna be trouble for you?
What'd we look like?
Looked like--
You had your hand on my shoulder.
You don't care who knows, do you?
About her and him, I mean.
I care.
They know anyway.
Sooner or later,
everybody knows everything.
What time is it? My plane's at 9:30.
A little after 8.
Sure you don't wanna stay over?
Yes.
Maybe we should split up.
We should've stayed.
I'm in restricted parking.
I took the metro.
It's not running now.
I'll get a cab.
Where do you live?
- Northwest. It's out of your way.
- Want me to drop you or not?
You know where we're going.
Why?
Stayed? Why? Why?
Because they were going to?
Easy!
Goddamn it. Stop it!
Stop it now.
Well, that was fun.
Don't.
Just drive.
Unbelievable.
- You want to come in, or--?
- Don't be ridiculous.
Pick up the phone,
you son of a bitch.
You like scaring women?
You come around my wife
one more time and--
No, no. You come and try to scare me,
asshole. Chickenshit.
1 0.:52 p.m. End of messages.
Last number called.: 555-44 21.
Press one to connect.
Parkway Lanes.
Is George Beaufort still there?
Dutch, hold on, man.
Take it outside!
Son of a bitch! Get off me!
Get off me!
Back off.
Son of a bitch!
Come on!
Somebody call the police.
I have your badge now, baby.
You'd better get a lawyer.
George killed that man.
Goddamn it.
You can't go around
beating up suspects.
You're suspended.
There will be a trial board.
You assaulted a man.
You can lose your job.
What if somebody swore they saw
George at that dumpster?
How tough would that be?
I was thinking.
If you went to see the shrink...
Wouldn't cost nothing.
Talk about Peyton. It could help.
I don't need to talk about Peyton.
I could tell them you got stressed out
on the job. It wouldn't be a lie.
Honk if you're screwing him.
Save a plane ticket.
Where'd you get that?
Shirley Magnuson.
Says she thinks it's phony.
Says I'm setting her up.
Setting her up?
I take the picture,
get it slipped to her. She uses it.
I provide a perfectly
innocent explanation.
- Her candidate's a mudslinger.
- My God, you people.
Pretty good idea.
I wish I'd had it.
If you have to explain that picture,
can you do it?
Yes.
- Where's your bracelet?
- It's around.
You didn't lose it?
It's around.
What's the matter?
It's not my bracelet.
What?
Dad didn't have any clients
in Miami, did he?
He was with that cop's wife, huh?
What was going on?
Something.
I'm not sure what.
Were they serious?
That'd be my guess.
Do a lot of people know?
Leave a message. I'll call you back.
It's me.
Remember? From restricted parking?
So you picked Peyton.
And Cullen picked Peyton.
That's two-zip against the home team.
"Have we been introduced?"...
...she says, straightening her clothes.
I thought I should introduce myself
and fill you in on my plans.
I'm packing it in.
No. That sounds like suicide.
All I mean is, like you said,
sooner or later...
...everybody knows everything...
...and this'll be in the papers...
...and I can't handle that.
I can't let Jessica be mowed down...
...by gossip she had
nothing to do with.
But if I'm not in Congress,
if I'm out...
...it's not news anymore.
She's safe.
You know?
You do know, don't you?
You're the only one who does.
And I miss that.
Do me a favour.
Erase this.
God, I'm glad you're not there.
She's getting a lot of points
for showing up.
How are you guys doing?
Excuse me for just a minute.
My contribution.
If you quit, they win.
And the crash got us all.
Don't let them do that.
I'm not the only one involved.
She should know her mom's no quitter.
Wanna say how impressed I am
that you're staying in.
I have to say a few things.
The name of this group is
"Friends of Kay Chandler."
I'm sorry about that phone call.
We're not getting much sleep.
- I'm afraid of what's playing.
- Me too.
Might give it a try.
Turn in around 3.
Cullen would be proud of you.
I know you know.
I don't know how many times
I've introduced Kay Chandler.
Miss a lot between 3 and 5.
Australian football.
May I present your friend...
...your congresswoman...
Don't go away.
...your next representative for
the 2nd district of New Hampshire...
...Kay Spencer-Chandler!
Thank you.
Thank you, Richard. Thank you, all.
It's good to be home.
I wanted to say just a word.
Just a few words.
You're all being very nice to me.
I don't wanna disappoint you.
But I just don't wanna talk
politics tonight.
I'm just glad to be home.
Richard and Wendy, thank you so much.
Thanks, all of you, for your friendship,
for your support...
...for showing up here tonight.
Thanks.
I mean it.
Don't leave without me getting
a chance to talk to you.
We love you, Kay!
Be back first thing.
- Do you have the number?
- You told me 1 5 times already.
Sorry.
I wish I could get out of the party.
No way, missy.
Some of these are $1 000 folks.
I just wish I didn't have to go.
It was good of you to come.
It was our party. Kind of had to.
I appreciate it, that's all.
Thank you.
You get a ticket?
It's a road map.
Maybe someone thought
it fell out of my car.
Listen, Kay.
Time to commit.
All the way in or not.
If you're not running, we need to return
that fundraiser money quick.
Maybe I'll take a day.
Do some thinking.
I'll be around.
I wondered if you'd come.
Guy like you, girl like me.
What reason could there be not to?
Sorry I'm late. I had to change
a few times and pack. I thought...
...if I packed light, it'd look
like I knew what I was doing.
But I didn't know what I was doing,
so I didn't know what to pack.
Where are we exactly?
Chesapeake Bay's
a couple miles that way.
I won't make small talk. I don't want
there to be any junk between us.
No littering.
There's so many reasons
I might be doing this.
I kept thinking,
I'll go one more mile...
...then I'll turn around and...
I was thinking about your mouth.
Nobody knows who I am anymore.
Nobody knows how easily I can do this.
I know who you are.
I have to know something.
Are you a Democrat?
What if I am?
We talk.
I give you books to read.
I like it when there's
just the two of us.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry.
No TV?
Is there a phone?
Not so far.
What's that like?
Quiet.
What is this? Do you know?
Heineken.
The start of something?
That's what I thought.
I want to know who is this woman
who's wearing my clothes...
...and using my body?
Is she permanent?
Or is she only around when you are?
Let's hide out here for a few years
and run for the border.
I always thought
when I had my time in...
...I'd like to live down here.
Start a little security service.
The raccoons are knocking over
the garbage cans?
A lot of Washington, Baltimore people
have places here.
They think they'll get robbed.
You had plans.
I don't think we had any plans.
I always wanted a boat.
One you could sleep on.
We've got a boat.
Defence Rests. Get it?
I've got a boat.
I'll give it to you.
I don't trust this
any more than you do.
You're the only thing that's real.
Let me ask you something tough.
Are you sorry the plane went down?
What are you doing?
Just think about it.
You can have it all back
the way it was.
But you gotta take it all.
He's lying.
He's screwing another woman.
They laugh at how easy we are to fool.
Stop. Don't do that.
I'm done with them.
Done with them.
- The thing is...
- Stop.
Come on.
Let's go home.
You know those kits that tell you
when you're pregnant?
They should have one that tells you
when you're sane.
I think they had a place they'd meet.
An apartment just makes sense.
How could it make sense?
No driving, no motels.
If they did, they did.
They're on their own.
This was in her desk at work.
Is that why you drew the map?
- Is that why you came to Concord?
- I didn't want you to quit.
- People have keys.
- Did you see one like this?
In his luggage maybe?
So they had a place.
They're not there anymore.
And I don't care.
I just don't care.
Maybe you didn't lose that much.
Or you're lying to yourself.
The sun's going down.
It's time to go.
When will you be back?
Roof's got a leak and I got some time.
I thought I'd make it worse.
Maybe we'll never get clear of how
we met. Maybe we'll never be alone.
But I don't want us to lose
this chance because...
...if it's just gonna be about them,
if it'll always be four of us--
You be careful driving home.
Thanks for driving
all the way to Concord.
And for the contribution.
And I don't even live
in your district.
You have one message.
It's me, Wendy.
Where've you been?
I have $50, 000 from your friends
and neighbours, and nobody to give it to.
What do you wanna do?
Lunch tomorrow? Give me a call.
Come on, Alcee.
Just get me a picture of him.
Headshot's okay.
Give me the photo from his I.D.
I'll call you when I get back.
I want Jessica out there, smiling like
Chelsea and keeping her mouth shut.
Her job is good kid. No opinions.
She can wear jeans.
No short shorts, no bra tops.
No Jessica.
She's in school.
School? We're trying
to win an election here.
No Jessica. I don't want her--
I think I may be losing
what it takes to lie.
- This may become a problem.
- Let's take a break.
- I don't like this.
- Just asking.
We're telling the whole southeast side
an officer's a murder suspect.
You think George won't hear about this?
You're not supposed to be working.
That's why you're here.
Shyla? You in there?
Anybody home?
We need to talk. Can we come in?
No, you can't come in.
You wanna come out?
Folks see me talk to you,
get my ass in trouble.
Goddamn it, Dutch!
Come on, man! Come on!
- You got no right in here!
- I won't hurt you.
Let's go. You got no warrant.
She said "no."
If my brother faced 1 5 months
in detention...
...it wouldn't hurt to look at
one picture. You seen this man?
That's Big George.
I see him all over.
Did you see him
when we found the body?
You didn't maybe see him dump
that man in the dumpster?
Take another look.
How's your brother?
Any chance he'll get out?
Okay, that's it! You didn't see him.
Sorry to have disturbed you.
I want you out right now!
Out now!
What's the matter with you?
Look, Dutch, I'm sorry about your wife.
You want George to come after you?
Is that it? So you can shoot him?
You got tired of working cheap?
You know he's guilty.
Why are you protecting him?
Is he paying you now?
Oh, man.
Here.
I feel like a bagman.
There's cash in there, so be careful.
Well, guess what?
Cullen was having an affair.
Tru says Ahi tuna's
incredible here.
That's why he went to Miami.
How long?
What's the difference?
You think being deaf, dumb and blind
is a liability for a congresswoman?
I think he kept an apartment
I don't know about.
- Would you like to hear our specials?
- Give us a minute.
And I thought maybe...
...Cullen had told Richard...
...and Richard had said something.
Come on. It's only adultery.
Nobody gives a damn
except the people it happens to.
It's not happening to--
My God.
Please give me a chance to explain.
Shut up.
Kay, it didn't mean...
I was gonna tell you.
Where is it?
It's been over a year.
I haven't been there--
Where is it?
The Colton Building on Rhode Island.
It was just stupid.
I'm not hungry.
If you could get the check, please.
Stop, please, Kay.
Just listen to me, okay, because...
...if we don't see you,
Richard'll know.
I can't keep seeing you so your husband
won't know you've been screwing mine.
Kay, please.
I need to tell you...
...how rotten I feel.
Let me go, punkin.
Hello. It's me.
Bad time?
How's the roof?
Lousy.
Something wrong?
Wanna get something to eat?
Sure. I'm not that hungry,
but I wanna see you.
Everything all right?
Weren't you ever tempted
to cheat on Peyton?
Tempted? Yeah.
Sure.
Why didn't you?
Maybe I did.
I don't think so.
I wonder how they got their
laundry done, if they had a place.
You think this...
...everything that happened...
You think it's...
...made you different?
Different how?
More suspicious.
Maybe.
But here I am.
I'm leaving you tomorrow.
I knew we should've gone
to McDonald's.
I have to try to get elected.
I lost a friend today...
...being suspicious.
What if you don't get elected?
Country goes to hell...
...and I go home.
For keeps.
But you're gonna beat this guy, right?
When I get back...
I'll be here.
I'll nail his ass.
Here you go, Clara.
Back Friday.
Wait up a second.
You got some dry cleaning.
Sorry.
Saks Fifth Avenue.
Employees' entrance.
I'll get him.
Sorry, Dutch.
Ladies' room.
Mary Claire.
You wouldn't believe
all the keys I've got.
I got a key to the Vic Tanny's
in Rochester.
I've got keys to the ones
in Westchester.
I don't think there was an apartment.
She was always here.
There wasn't time.
No, wait.
You know, she gave me
a phone number once.
She was on her way to a meeting--
Just a minute.
This is it.
In the bottom, in pencil.
Go right ahead.
Can I have the 911 supervisor?
Sergeant Van Den Broeck.
D.C. Internal Affairs, 9114.
I need an address
for a telephone number.
How long did you know?
Did you know when you came to Miami?
How could you think--?
When you came to my cabin,
did you know?
I found out yesterday.
So you knew last night.
When were you gonna tell me?
I thought...
I thought maybe...
...years from now...
...when it's behind us.
What did you find?
Nothing.
Dutch, you weren't...
We had a pact.
Then why are you here?
I wanna finish it. I want it over.
That your purse? What'd you find?
What did you find?
There's nothing here.
Oh, Christ.
I can smell her perfume.
Stop it, Dutch.
There's nothing here.
There's gotta be something left...
...some sign of--
Stop it!
You'll never find
what you're looking for. Never.
You wanna know why.
And there is no why.
Don't.
If you check in, I'm heading for
the airport early. Meet me for coffee.
Hi, it's me. I'm running late.
There was something I needed to do.
Go without me. I'll get the next
plane and meet you at the hotel.
What are we doing? Do you know?
We made love that morning.
That's why she was late.
Get an ambulance!
I'm okay.
Get out of the car! Get out!
Help!
Kay Chandler, congresswoman.
Police report said her husband got it on
with Van Den Broeck's wife.
He kept a love shack in the building.
You all right?
The press is out there
and they know you're here.
They could get hungry
and go somewhere for a hamburger.
How we gonna handle this?
"Handle it" is when you got a client
who'll tell you what's going on.
They'll wanna know just how well
the congresswoman knows the cop.
- How will we handle this?
- I don't know.
If we can get back to New Hampshire
and let this age a day...
We'll leave through the basement.
He's right, Kay.
What time is it?
- It's almost midnight.
- Somebody stole my watch.
Where's Alcee?
He said he'd come by tomorrow.
I was trying to catch up with you.
What were you going to say?
I don't know what I was gonna say.
I just...
I just didn't want you to leave.
Not like that, anyway.
Welcome back. Hungry?
Where's my watch?
They need you in X-ray.
Listen...
...I probably never would've told you
about the place either.
All I wanted...
What I want, really...
...is just to find some way...
...to let her go...
...and move on.
I don't know how you do that.
Neither do I.
It's not a crime, Dutch.
You loved your wife.
And you still do.
All set. Let me see
if I can find some orderlies.
Will you hang around?
I can't.
You're supposed to be nice.
I've been shot.
We did okay, Dutch.
We did the best we could...
...under the circumstances.
We ready, sergeant?
It's time for you to go. Me too.
Will that be all right?
So long, Kay.
Here she comes.
Can you tell us what you were doing...?
What's the sergeant's condition?
I've gotta catch a plane,
but if you can make it short...
We're told your husband had an affair
with Van Den Broeck's wife.
They had an apartment, and that's
where you were. Is that correct?
Yes, it is.
Characterize your relationship
with the sergeant.
The sergeant's wife was killed on the
plane that went down with my husband.
I met the sergeant
a few days after that day.
He was a friend when I needed a friend.
I hope he feels the same way.
So you're just friends?
Just friends.
We are surely friends.
We've seen each other
through something...
We're more than friends.
We're survivors.
You'll have to excuse me.
I have to get home.
Can you tell us more
about the sergeant's condition?
- See you Friday, sweetie.
- Bye, Mom.
Bye, Mrs. Chandler.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas. Do I know you?
I'm Tad Baker.
I work for Mr. Cornelius.
You said we could...
Yeah, sure. Make yourselves at home.
Hello, Kay.
Hi, sergeant.
Lieutenant.
They made me a lieutenant.
All I had to do was get shot.
Can I get you something?
Stoli on the rocks.
I haven't had one of those in a while.
I got a plane.
I don't have time.
What's with those New Hampshire voters?
Are they crazy?
They could tell
I didn't want the job.
Or I wanted it. I just didn't
wanna do what you have to do to get it.
So you're out of work.
Guess I am.
Are you as well as you look?
Leg's a little stiff.
But I think I'm gonna be okay.
You?
How's football in Australia?
I tune in once in a while.
Not like before.
I was a real fan.
I gotta tell you,
I thought I might run into you here.
Where are you going?
That's the thing. Nowhere.
I called your office,
and they said that you were...
...headed home, so...
My flight's overbooked and I--
Go later.
Take another plane.
It's my Christmas present,
running into you.
What'd you get me?
How about...
...I call you up sometime
in New Hampshire?
And say what?
Say...
..."You wanna go to a movie?"
What do you say?
Wouldn't that be something?
Ripped by Alex Raynor with SubRip 1.17.1.
November 17, 2004. 25 FPS.