I'm hungry.
You want some?
Don't.
Stop it.
Sam?
This one has better image quality.
Nikon is good.
These are professional cameras.
I'll show you something.
Sir!
Take one yourself.
Tired?
- No.
Are you Ali? Hop in.
Finally, I'd say.
- I drove around for an hour.
Slide through.
- I meant to call Anna already.
Nice van I have, huh?
You find it really nice, huh?
Because God forbid someone
doesn't like my van.
Do you want it?
Nice chap.
Eight drivers on the road.
After some conversations with Anna ...
I thought: I'm going on my own.
Then I bought this van.
What's that for?
- To eat outside when it's hot.
There is plenty of sun.
- I'm still holding.
Look, look.
You see the dogs?
Those are Aunt Anna's.
Whose car parts are those?
- Neighbor Che's
who moonlights with this.
Very handy.
Say when.
From this you become a big boy.
How long haven't you seen Anna?
A year, or five.
That long?
Where does she work?
- In a supermarket.
As a cashier?
- Yes, exactly.
No, from the top stack.
Those are the furthest past date.
They are on date,
from top to bottom.
I grab one here? You too?
Anna takes them home from work.
In the shop they are discarded.
But they are still good for a week.
Do you earn well?
- What can I say ...
We can get by.
- What exactly do you do?
I deliver frozen products.
Mainly fish, but also other things.
That depends on the offer.
More coffee?
Tasty, yes.
He looks like you.
Is that all?
Doesn't your brother get a kiss?
All is well?
Are those all his things?
She thought of his passport.
No, that was still in there accidentally.
In his bag they smuggled
dope back from Amsterdam.
She told me that.
How will you take care of him?
Because Richard and I don't have time.
Did he do well at school?
Don't you know that
your son went to school?
Sam, you went to school at your mom's?
- Yes.
I'll try to register him nearby.
He needs new clothes.
I'll just drop in on the neighbors.
Shall I wake you in an hour? Door closed?
- Don't.
Want some cake? Okay.
Here, help yourself.
You watch them? I'll be right back.
Careful with them.
He licked me.
- They can't run away.
Won't you eat?
They are beautiful, huh?
I got them from a breeder.
In a month he takes them.
So we earn a little.
Everything alright with you?
- I'm exhausted.
He doesn't remember.
- Wait.
Looks can be deceiving sometimes.
To go to your work.
Are you shitting me?
- No.
Che?
Where is the toolbox?
- In the garage.
Would you like some help?
Stop it, you idiot.
When is Mommy coming?
- Soon.
Soon ...
When is Mommy coming?
- Soon, I told you.
When is that?
- I don't know.
Where did you work last?
- In a slaughterhouse. That was closed down.
But never in security?
- Yes, half a year in a stadium.
As a night watchman.
And in a parking garage.
Have you done martial arts?
- Six years and two years Thai boxing.
Can you prove that?
With photos or a license?
I was regional champion in Belgium.
I have a belt.
Have you stopped?
- No, my trainer has stopped.
Why?
- He's dead.
You don't smoke?
- No.
And you don't drink?
I didn't hear anything.
- No, I don't drink.
Drugs?
- No.
Why should I hire you?
Trust me.
Right. And what is this?
Hello.
And?
- In a week he'll hear from me.
Is that his son?
- Yes.
You didn't say you had a child?
- I didn't ask either.
Did you hear from that customer yet?
- You have cold hands.
Good evening.
Okay, you win.
For four girls, I am no match.
Good night.
It's that easy.
You just chat with them ...
If you're lucky, they are drunk or frustrated.
Then you say something nice ...
Does that work?
- You bet.
Get out, you guys. Buzz off.
Are you OK? Keep your head back.
Good. Breathe slowly.
The bastard.
Breathe slowly.
I have to go home.
- Are there any of your friends inside?
No, and I'm here by car.
You can't drive like this.
I'll call you a cab.
No, I need my car.
Nice of you, thanks.
What a slut you are.
- What did you do?
Shut up.
Crap.
Still bleeding?
- Not anymore.
Damn
Did you hurt yourself?
- Yes, it is swollen. Look.
You come to the Annexe often?
Why do you come alone?
To dance?
To pick up a guy?
- You think?
You don't dress like that
just to dance.
What am I dressed like?
- I don't know ...
You see ...
- What?
You look like a whore.
I'm sorry?
How do you call that?
- That's enough.
It doesn't surprise me that guys ...
- Shut up.
How do you get back?
- Will see.
Never mind.
- For a taxi.
Don't. Here ...
Goodbye.
- Do you have ice in the house?
Why?
- Ice cubes.
Wait here. I'll check.
I can come along.
- No.
There is someone upstairs.
- So what?
Wait here. I'll be right back.
Alright.
Come in.
Steph?
- Here are ice cubes.
What happened to you?
There was a slugfest.
- Are you okay?
Hello.
- Who is that?
The bouncer at the Annexe.
He brought me home.
What did you do at the Annexe?
What are you doing?
I'm packing ice.
- He has a sore hand.
Can I talk to you for a moment?
No, you should see how you get home.
Mind your own business.
Is it better?
- Yes.
Is that you in the photos with the orcas?
Is that your work?
I wouldn't have thought that.
- Can't whores train orcas?
You're nuts.
Aren't you gone yet?
Are you talking to me?
Please go.
Here is my number, just in case.
Are you OK?
- Yes.
You are angry.
No.
I saw your face just now though.
- Just now?
With that guy from the Annexe.
I saw how small you were.
- I was small?
For sure.
You aren't commanding me anymore, Simon.
What do you mean?
- That you don't give me commands any more. Period.
Careful, Steph.
Sam, come away from that pen.
Come out, that's disgusting.
Come out.
Come out. Shit, you're filthy.
Do not touch me. Walk.
Anna?
Off those pants.
You smell like shit.
Up those arms.
Come here.
Stay like this.
What are you doing?
- Did you watch him?
Yeah, I just hung the laundry.
- Hold on.
Don't cry, you.
- Act normal.
Where is my sister?
- The van had a breakdown.
Look at that.
- Come, I'll wash you.
You stay out of that doghouse.
Is somebody there?
Steph ...
Wait ...
What happened to my legs?
I had your brothers on the phone.
They wanted to talk to you,
but that seemed a little too early.
Hugo is coming the next holiday.
She is devastated.
They don't dare to come.
Give me that.
Let go.
Please.
What do you want with it?
I'll take you.
You need to get out of here.
No, there is no point.
Right.
Very good. Now left.
Left, right.
Stay in the middle. Not too much ...
Your cover.
You are too static.
How are you?
- And you, Foued?
Hello.
- Ali.
See you soon!
Hi!
Wait a moment.
You forgot Sam.
- I'm still at the gym.
I'm going already.
I'm telling you I'm going.
Mister van Versch, can I talk to you for a moment?
Sorry, ma'am.
I was still at work.
This is the third time in two weeks.
The next time
I'll have to call the police.
Sam, come here.
Hop through, stupid beast.
Don't you like dogs?
- No.
Great, he does not like acorns.
- Move it. What is with that creature?
And it stinks too.
Am I speaking with Ali?
- Yes. Who is this?
Stephanie.
Do you remember?
The Annexe, the brawl, the ice ...
Yes, of course. How are you?
You know what happened?
- I saw it on TV, yes.
So how would I be, what do you think?
I don’t know.
And you, all good?
- Yes, the usual.
Are you still a bouncer?
- No, watchman, four times a week.
I'm here.
Come in.
Have you been here long?
- I just arrived.
Didn't you ring?
- No.
Sit down.
Want something to drink? Coffee?
I only got Nescafe.
- That's fine. Shall I help?
No.
Have you lived here long?
- Since ...
A month or two, three, four, I think.
Nice place.
It is temporary, because ...
Let me.
Give it to me.
The insurance pays.
Do you have anyone to help you?
With what? Walking?
No, the household and all that.
Yes, all kinds of people come along.
Are you OK?
Do you think it stinks?
- A little bit.
I think I stink.
Come outside.
Yes, put this on.
- No.
Yeah, let's go outside.
Be careful!
No, don't push. I feel sick.
I do it myself.
I feel like swimming.
Don't you?
Don't you have a bathing suit?
Do you realize what you're saying?
- There's nobody here.
I'm going in.
I'm going in too.
Can you give me that towel?
Ready.
And now?
- You have to carry me.
Hold on.
Don't let me go suddenly.
Are you OK?
Ho ...
Shit, that was nice.
Thank you.
I don't wear that any more.
Garbage.
Garbage, garbage.
- You are throwing good things away.
You can wear that dress with pants just fine.
You find this so beautiful?
You find this dress so beautiful?
You can have it.
I like this one.
Holy shit. See those hulks?
- Fuck, I say.
Against him I fought matches.
Twice. He was not bad.
Knee, right, right.
More right, like that ...
What do you want?
- To come inside.
Who's this?
Are you Martial?
- I know him. He's a colleague.
He goes down.
- It's not over yet.
Right, right. He is an executioner.
How much does he weigh? 80, 90 pounds?
No, not 90.
- Surely 85. Look ...
He's demolishing him!
Why don't they stop?
He's coming back.
- Look, a knee thrust. And another one.
Do you like it?
- What?
Fighting.
- Yes.
Can you fight?
- Reasonably, yes.
Did you fight matches?
- Long ago, boxing and Thai boxing.
Would you like to earn money?
Are you shitting me?
- I know someone who organizes fights.
A gypsy. With gambling and everything.
How do you know him?
I had cameras installed
in a garage where he stole cars.
He wanted the tapes from me.
What kind of boxing?
Thai boxing with your legs?
No, you can use anything:
Elbows, knees.
You really finish each other.
Who remains last, wins.
You are almost choking me.
Are you going first?
- Yes.
Aren't you afraid?
- Of what?
How much does it pay?
- I don't know.
Five hundred, one thousand.
Depends on whether I win.
Will you do it for 500 euros?
- Yes.
Put your health at risk
for 500 euros?
Don't exaggerate.
You get 500 euros from me
tomorrow if you don't do it.
If you have too much money ...
But I have agreed already.
You don't do it for the money?
- I wouldn't say that.
Well then.
- Don't bother.
I do it for the fighting, for fun.
Just like you with your fish.
You did that for fun too.
And for the money.
You see how it ends.
- Stop it.
Where is your cart?
When you are fighting, can I come?
Yes, sure.
I make two prints for prosthetics
so at least you can walk.
Later we will look at what you get as
knee joint, pneumatic or electronic.
What is an electronic hinge?
- It fixates itself.
Can the feet move?
- No, not the feet.
They are flexible carbon fiber,
but not moving.
Then I walk like a robot.
- Of course not.
There are Swedish feet
that are not reimbursed ...
but with those you can wear
heels from 10 to 50 mm.
That is important for women.
Oh shoot
Stop. Good.
Go. I'll take a cab.
Of course not.
Keep an eye on Sam.
The breeder is there.
Hello? Watch your son?
- Yeah, yeah.
He should not be in the garden.
Stay with Daddy.
Sit here.
- You have cold hands.
Don't touch it.
Did you see that?
See how strong he is?
- Who?
The black pants.
Wait. Sit here.
What did he say?
Why, 'others'?
How many are there?
That was not the intention.
Then you fight yourself.
Where do the dogs go?
Go inside.
That I don't give a fuck about.
What did I ask you for?
- I'm on the phone.
Watch your fucking kid.
Come back here, you.
What is this shit?
I'll call you back.
Watch your fucking kid.
Quiet, you.
Now you calm down.
I hate you. Do you know that?
Come.
He has nothing.
- Get out, you.
Hands off and get lost.
- He has nothing.
Don't touch him and get lost.
It's over.
Martial, careful.
- Put her belt on then.
Fasten your belt.
Who is she?
- His girlfriend.
Okay. Go ahead.
That guy is imitating the TV.
Who are those guys?
Dealers, figures with money.
Are you OK?
- Yes, fine.
In case of problems lie down.
- How much are the bets?
Over 2000. In the finale it gets more.
And what do I do?
- No women, you stay in the car.
Are you ready? Ali?
That was quick.
Do you have to go again?
- What?
Yes, soon.
I'll run a bit.
Damn ...
Stop right there. I want to tidy up.
What is that?
- For whom is that?
For the little one.
You have a child?
- Yes.
So drive.
And if you're there, he gets hit.
- Don't exaggerate.
But you beat him lately?
- Accidentally. He's not dead.
I don't understand why you have taken
him with you. He was better off there.
For you.
For what?
- For the past and the future.
How did you get that?
- I won a fight.
What fight?
Is that your work? Get beaten up?
- Do you take it or not?
Don't look like that, damn.
I cheated.
Do you like it?
- Yes, Ali.
Shall we go swimming?
Give daddy a kiss.
- No point.
- No.
No, I don't want to.
Shut up.
Damn.
Put it there.
Yes, and now come back.
Come.
This is not for watching the customers,
but the staff.
As a manager of a supermarket ...
you have too many staff around.
What do you do?
I fire them.
- You need a reason for that.
So find out who pauses or is on the toilet
too long or smokes in the corner.
When you know, build up pressure.
Those who don't quit on their own, you fire.
That's what my cameras are for.
I work for the managers, for
bosses in their three-piece suits.
It's overwhelming. There is no big
supermarket without my cameras.
Is that legal?
Legal? Who determines that?
But if a manager gets caught,
he has a trial on his ass.
And I go to jail.
Left, on your left.
Wait, I'll wave.
Shit, that's brilliant.
How long?
- Two days.
Can I see it?
We go swimming?
I don't know.
It's different now.
I don't know if I want to undress.
Do you have a girlfriend, a fiancée?
- No.
No love life at all?
- Yes, but no fiancée.
Only girls to fuck?
Do you have many flings?
- No.
Does it annoy you to talk about it?
- No, I don't care.
And did you have many lovers?
Before?
- Yes.
I was with Simon.
Is that all?
No, there have been other men.
But not many.
I was very ...
I liked it when men looked at me ...
when they found me tempting.
That they got excited by me.
But I quickly became bored.
And now?
Nothing.
I can't imagine being together any more.
I'm not even sure if it still works.
Don't you feel any more?
I never said that.
Of course I still feel something.
Different subject.
Never mind, I'll do it.
- I don't have my legs for nothing.
Do you want to fuck?
Huh?
You want to know if it still works?
Then you fuck.
Just like that?
- Yes.
I don't know if I can do it
just like that.
I hear you.
Wait ...
Come.
Don't you want to kiss me on the mouth?
Ok
Your breasts too?
Careful, you are heavy.
- Now no more talking.
Ok
Gently.
Are you OK?
Was it good?
Does it still work?
Yes. No. I don't know.
It's different. After a while ...
- I'm out of time. I have to go.
No, that's not what I mean.
It's new.
- But was it good?
Yes, it was good.
If you like, call me. If I'm OP, I'll come.
How do you mean 'OP'?
- Operational. When I can.
So if you are OP ...
- Yes.
What?
Nothing. Awesome.
I'm going. Ciao.
Thank you. I had missed it.
OP?
Shit, get dressed.
What is it?
- My sister.
You scared me to death.
- I want to introduce you to a friend.
Do you take all girls back home?
- Stephanie, this is my sister.
It's the girl from Marineland.
The poor child.
- Anna ... Stephanie.
Four times.
That's enough.
Is it him?
Hello.
How old is he?
- Five.
The grapefruit juice is out.
I've got multivitamine juice.
Pour some for you?
Or do you prefer tea?
I'll make tea.
- Really, you don't need to.
Anna, sit down.
- This is fine.
Shall we leave?
- Why?
That whining about tea.
- She's very nice.
Yes, very nice ...
She feels inferior as a cashier.
Please.
Thank you.
Do you sleep here?
Nice room.
Why are you looking like that?
Do you find it scary?
Want to see it?
- Yes.
Does it hurt?
No.
Feel it.
With this hand,
I try to disable your arm.
Same movement.
Good, yes.
Are you OK?
- No, that guy will kill me.
Ready?
Do you want to move?
To dance?
I'll go.
I move along. I'll call you tomorrow, OK?
- What, are you leaving?
Yes, I'm going.
Guys, until next time.
Thank you.
See you soon!
Want something to drink?
Will you take a drink from me?
Yes, champagne.
Two champagne Mika.
My name is Pierre. And yours?
- My name is Marie.
Do you come here often?
Occasionally.
Sorry, not tonight. I don't feel like it.
I'm going. Thanks for the drink.
Sorry, I ...
- Sorry for what?
I didn't know ...
- What didn't you know?
I didn't know you ...
no ...
- Bastard.
Everything alright?
Did you guys stay long?
- No idea.
How was it?
- As usual.
You think this is a normal conversation?
I ask how it was with the girl
and you say 'as usual'.
What should I say?
Nothing.
Do think it's 'usual' to chat up
someone when I'm with you?
What would you say if I did that?
- Nothing.
Would you be that cold?
- Stop it. What is your problem?
What am I to you?
A friend? A little girlfriend?
A pal, like the others?
Do you fuck your pals?
To continue, we should do it well.
Then we behave.
I'm talking about tactfulness.
You know what that is.
You've always been very tactful with me.
Do we call it off?
We go on, but not like animals.
What?
I'm OP.
Usually, I am OP.
Why do you look at me like that?
You feel it, yes?
Why not?
Calm down or I'll have the store evacuated.
Don't bother.
- We'll call the police ourselves.
Remove the stuff.
- You are spying on your own staff.
Don't you dare even looking at us.
Don't touch me.
He does a criminal offense
and calls the police himself. Bravo.
What are you doing?
- I'm taking everything.
Are these things yours?
- No.
No photos.
- Do you work for them?
No pictures, I said.
- Did you film us yet?
Want a blow to your head?
Come on, now.
We got you.
- Shut up.
I need a month away or three or four.
Ali wants to continue fighting.
Would you like to replace me?
But does he agree?
- He said it himself.
Why me?
- He trusts you, I suppose.
I don't know that world at all.
Do you see me deal with those barbarians?
- Yes.
Really?
Everything is in here.
If you have questions, let me know.
And the bets?
- You have fingers to count.
You mean this Clio? That one?
I noticed that you have a problem ...
I want an automatic.
- This is an automatic.
But it's ugly.
RIGHT
What's up, Robocop?
- A circus!
How much is it?
- 3400.
Are you ready?
I'm here.
Don't look like that.
- What are you doing?
I go pee.
Give me my T-shirt.
- What time is it?
Six o'clock.
Shit, I've fallen asleep.
I don't want you to see me like this.
Hold me. Come.
Good like this?
What's the matter?
Do it now?
You need to come to the supervisor.
The management.
Wait here.
- Here?
You too?
And?
I got fired.
- Calm down. You should see something.
Here he packs up the stuff.
And here he stands up to beat me.
Then he takes off.
But beautiful that I've caught him.
Hi
What are you doing?
- I'm hungry.
Close that refrigerator.
You don't eat here.
- What's the matter?
I got fired this morning.
What does that have to do with
whether I eat here?
That has to do with the cameras
hanging in the warehouse.
They know we took things
that were expired.
Because of you, your sister was fired.
What does that do with you?
How much did it pay?
Was it per camera or per job?
You don't say anything?
I give you shelter and I care for
your child, but you say nothing.
Great.
I couldn't know.
- No. But I don't get you.
How could you do something like that?
Whose side are you on? On their side?
Do you have sawdust in your head?
What didn't you know?
That you'd bring us into shit?
Can't you think?
Calm down, you.
You calm down.
Get your stuff and get out.
You can fuck off. Get out of here.
This is the mess he left behind.
He has recorded that he is in Strasbourg.
Perhaps no longer. Didn't he call you?
Have you been to the gym?
- They too know nothing.
If I hear anything, I'll pass it on.
He will have pulled something stupid.
You believe me, do you?
Yes.
He just leaves his child here.
He has shit on everywhere.
You don't know him.
- Oh, no? What did you expect from him?
I don't know. But not this.
Keep moving. Hands up.
Is there any coffee left?
Everything alright?
- Yes. And you?
I don't want to get stuck.
Got a new truck?
- A new boss.
I'm going to get exploited.
Put your jacket on, Sam.
- Everything okay at home?
Yes.
And Anna?
- Good.
She works part time in a school canteen.
She likes it.
Does she know this?
- Of course.
Are you saying that I cannot help?
But once I have money ...
It's OK. When will you fight?
- Next month, the 9th.
Keep us informed?
- Yes.
Come on, Sam. Here Mr. Sam.
My mittens.
- Kiss.
Handover.
I will deliver in Colmar
and get him at 7 o'clock.
Ali, I count on that: Seven o'clock.
I have to get back before eleven.
Alright.
- Have a nice day, you guys.
Sam, listen, make a snowman.
Have a good day.
- I'll bring fries for you.
I also want to skate.
That is called skiing.
- No, skating.
No really, skiing.
- Skating.
Skiing.
- You are annoying.
Faster?
I'll let you go. Then you can do it yourself.
Put it on.
Crap.
Careful. Grab the sled.
Sit on it.
One, two, three ... departure.
Crap.
Again.
We are going back in ten minutes. Okay?
Help
Now we look after you.
Come.
Can you do that?
- Yes, thank you.
Hello?
Yes, it's better.
Here he comes himself.
She wants to talk to you.
Anna?
- No.
She's with me.
Do you mind me calling?
No.
How is he?
He came to an hour ago.
Is he injured?
- No, I don't think so.
And you?
I got my hands broken
on the ice.
Severely?
They are broken.
And how are you?
Good.
What are you doing?
- At this moment? In life?
Or in general?
- I wanted to say ...
I ask for nothing. I'm hanging up.
I'll call you to ask about Sam.
Give him a kiss.
Don't hang up.
- Okay.
For three hours he's been ...
in a coma.
He was dead for three hours.
I was so afraid I would lose him.
Don't let me down.
- I won't.
I love you.
In a human hand there are 27 bones.
Some apes have more.
A gorilla 32, five per finger.
A human has 27.
If you break an arm or a leg ...
the bone grows back together
by calcification.
Your arm or leg can therefore
become even stronger.
But with a hand fracture
it will never get quite right.
In every battle and with
each slap you will think of it.
You'll be careful.
But once in a while the pain will come back.
Like needles.
Like glass splinters.