(PANTING)
(DOG BARKING NEARBY)
(WHIMPERING, SOBBING)
Open the door! Open the door!
Oh, my gosh, what is the matter?
- I don't know what happened.
- Are you OK? Erin...
(SIRENS WAILING IN DISTANCE)
- All right.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER PA)
There you go, miss.
Thank you.
(SIRENS WAILING OUTSIDE)
Oh, sorry. Ma'am, I'm so sorry.
Are you all right?
Wait, they're not boarding
in there yet.
(CARS SCREECHING OUTSIDE)
Come on!
Excuse me, I'm sorry.
Have you seen this woman?
- I don't think so.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, pretty sure.
- No?
- Dino.
- Yes, sir.
Guys, have you seen this woman?
- Isn't she blonde, with short hair maybe?
- Thank you.
Stop the bus! Boston PD.
Excuse me.
Hey! Stop the bus! Open up!
(MID-TEMPO POP SONG PLAYS)
(GULLS CRYING)
DRIVER: Folks, we'll be stopping
for 15 minutes here in Southport.
WOMAN: Do you have
any fresh coffee?
It's so thick,
it tastes like lukewarm mud.
- I don't know what to tell you, ma'am.
- You're gonna have to throw it out.
- It's a fresh Ethiopian blend.
- It's not...
I've never tasted Ethiopian
that tasted like that in my life.
- It's Ethiopian. Yeah.
- It's Ethiopian?
Just the mud for you then?
That'll be 97 cents.
Out of one.
- Thank you.
(GULLS CRYING)
(WOMAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
And I wish they would, you know,
take us to places that...
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(BUOY BELL CLANGING)
(BUS BRAKES HISSING)
- Here you go, Kevin.
- Thank you.
Hey, you catch the game?
Patriots killing 'em.
Hey, we got security footage
from the bus station.
- Want me to take a look at them?
- No, I got it.
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
(TAPPING KEYS)
(KIDS CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
All right. Have a good one, buddy.
See ya.
OK, how many in your party, three? OK.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
Is your owner available?
I'm the owner.
How can I help you?
Uh, do you guys have any job openings?
Uh, well, we've been awfully busy lately.
I might can work you in.
I'm not sure.
Do you have any experience?
(LOUD HISSING)
(LAUGHING) So sorry. Frankie!
Yes, I have experience.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(MOUSE CLICKING)
(SIGHS)
(TAPPING KEYS)
I'll be damned.
Don't hover at the tables.
Make sure their glasses are always filled.
Hi, Mary Ann.
And ask 'em if they need something,
but don't ask more than once.
- When you hear this ding...
(DINGS)
...try to beat me up here
more times than I beat you.
WOMAN: Perfect size for you.
It's got hardwood floors,
some wainscoting.
It's a great location to town.
(FLOORBOARDS CREAKING)
A little bit of a fixer-upper,
but it's got a lot of potential.
(INSECTS CHIRRING)
What do you think?
I'll take it.
(WOMAN AND MAN GRUNTING
WITH EFFORT)
(WOMAN WHIMPERS)
(GASPS)
(COYOTE BARKS IN DISTANCE)
(COYOTES BARKING,
HOWLING DISTANTLY)
(WOOD SPLINTERING)
(SHRIEKS)
(POSSUM GROWLS)
(GASPS)
(GULLS SCREECHING)
(DOOR BELL JINGLING)
MAN: Josh!
Two feet on the dock,
I'm not gonna tell you again.
- Hi.
- Um, are your mom and dad around?
- Um, no, but I can help you.
You looking for anything?
Well, now that you ask...
do you have any paint?
Um, we have this book that's...
...with all different kinds
of colors that you can get.
- Oh, really? Oh, that would be great.
- What are you painting?
I'm painting my kitchen floor.
(GIGGLES)
- The floor?
- Why is that funny?
'Cause you usually don't paint floors.
You usually put a rug on them.
Well, I'm thinking that I
want to brighten the place up, so...
- What's a happy color? What could I do?
- Hm... there's yellow.
- Yellow?
- Yeah. The color of the sun.
OK, that is happy. I think you
just sold me on that. All right.
I can go get some samples of it.
I'm Lexie.
- OK, I'm Katie.
- Hi, Katie.
Thank you.
Lower on three. One, two, three.
(INDISTINCT SPORTS
BROADCAST ON TV)
I'll just... I'll grab the rest.
- What, you're still here?
- Mm-hm.
Let me, uh... let me check you out.
It's just that usually people
are just passing through, you know?
It's kind of a pit stop. Ten minutes
is usually enough. All right.
- I like it.
- Yeah?
LEXIE: Found it!
- Thank you.
- No, no, that's not for...
You're painting something?
Yeah, she needs to paint
her floors in her kitchen.
Ah, OK.
- Yeah, I can take them home?
- Yeah, yeah, take it home.
Pick out your color and we'll...
we'll order it up for you.
- Thank you.
- All right.
- Thanks, Lexie.
- All right, there you go.
- Rice. Ah, basmati, the king of rices.
- Yum.
Good catch.
- Light bulb, ding!
- Tuna.
LEXIE: - Tuna.
- Soap.
LEXIE: - Soap.
- And that'll be 18 even.
OK, thank you.
- All right, out of 20.
- Bag.
Two dollars is your change. We have
some books down here. They're free.
People just leave them
on vacation, so...
Yeah.
You can take a book.
All right. Well, thank you, Lexie.
- Thank you.
- Bye!
Grab a book.
- Yeah, they're really good books.
- How do you know?
- You didn't read any of them.
(GIGGLES)
(BELL JINGLING)
- Bye.
- You want me to go get Josh?
- Yeah, go grab Josh, will you?
LEXIE: - Josh!
- "The king of rices"? (LAUGHS)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(DINGING)
MAN: - Hey, Maddie.
MADDIE: - Hey, Rhett.
RHETT: - How are we doing?
MADDIE: - Hey, Bass.
Hey, are you OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
MADDIE: - Y'all looking for somebody?
RHETT: Yeah, I sure am.
Got a white Honda Civic
parked in a handicapped space outside.
You wouldn't happen to know the owner,
would you?
I sure don't. Can't help you there.
You got our lunch?
MADDIE:
Katie! You got the chief's order?
- Sorry it took so long.
RHETT: - Oh, no problem at all.
- Can I help you?
- Oh! Ooh.
Oh! Uh... You scared me.
Uh... I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be snooping. Um...
I wish I had a good excuse,
but it's just idle curiosity.
You're the first neighbor
I've had out here in ages.
Yeah, my Realtor said
I didn't have close neighbors.
Oh, well, I'm not close by city standards.
I'm Jo, by the way.
- Katie.
- Nice to meet you. Um...
Look, I moved out here
same reason as you, I think.
To get some peace and quiet,
so I get it if you just...
Yeah, I like the fact
that I can hear myself think.
Yes, thank you.
I mean, isn't it so nice to be away
from all that noise and that chatter?
(CHUCKLES) I mean, it can be a little bit
deafening sometimes, so it is...
...it is nice to meet somebody
as rustically inclined as I am.
- Yeah. OK.
- All right, well, it was nice to meet you.
- Yeah, you too.
- I'm down the road if you need anything.
I'm stronger than I look.
So, if you get in any trouble...
- OK.
- OK, I'm sorry again.
- It's OK.
- OK.
- Walk safe.
- Thank you.
All right.
How many stops are on your route
from here to Atlanta?
- To Atlanta? Um...
- Yeah.
- Quite a few. I wouldn't know offhand.
- You got a ballpark?
Um...
Come on, buddy.
You gonna buy a ticket or what?
Uh, no, I'm not gonna buy a ticket,
but I can help you. I can help you out.
Uh... Can we open another window
for my friend here?
Beautiful. Thank you.
- OK, so...
MAN: - The whole Eastern Seaboard.
Yeah. Down to Atlanta.
What happens in Atlanta?
Well, where do you want to go?
- Where can you go from Atlanta?
- Anywhere.
Atlanta's our southern hub.
There are routes to every city
in America from there.
(TAPPING KEYS)
- Hey, everything OK?
(SIGHS) - Shit.
Job just got a little harder, that's all.
LEXIE: - Hey.
KATIE: - Hey, Lexie.
- Haven't seen those kids in ages.
KATIE: - How are you?
- They're growing up so fast.
LEXIE: - Good.
- Whatcha doing?
- I'm drawing.
Yeah? Drawing, what are you drawing?
I don't know yet.
Hm. It looks sorta like a... carrot.
- No.
- No?
You need to bring 'em by
and let me see 'em all, I miss 'em.
- Maybe this weekend, all right?
- All right.
KATIE: Is it a dragonfly?
LEXIE: No, it's a flying fish.
- Need a bag?
- No, no, thanks.
MAN: OK.
KATIE: - A flying fish. Now I see it.
- Well, hi, Katie.
Hey.
See ya.
- Thanks.
- Bye-bye.
KATIE: I see you're a true artist.
You got blue all over your hands.
- That stupid door. Use the other one.
- I'll just go out this one.
- OK. See ya. Come see me.
MAN: - OK. I'll see ya.
Hi.
Oh, hey.
So, I picked out a color from
these samples and I'm thinking
I might go with lemon twist.
OK. You're gonna paint
the floors yellow?
- Yeah, why not?
- You sure about that?
- Yeah, of course, it's happy.
- No, it's a good idea. OK.
- Um...
- How much?
- Uh, probably a gallon.
- A gallon?
- Yeah, a gallon.
- OK, that should be...
You know, I'll put the order in now.
Hopefully, we can get it back by Monday.
- Great. Thanks.
- All right. Lemon twist.
Lemon twist. All right.
I'm gonna need a name and a number
so that I can call you
when the order comes in.
My name's Katie and no number.
I'll just stop by Monday.
OK. I'm Alex, so you know
who to ask for when you come back.
This is Roger,
we're usually around here.
Hi.
- All right.
- Is that it?
That's it.
OK, great, bye.
When did we start
selling paint?
Today.
Ooh, the drawing looks good.
Thank you. Would you like it?
- Really?
- Yeah, I can just make another.
Aw, you're so sweet.
Thank you. I love it.
Give me a hug. All right.
- Thanks. Have a good day.
LEXIE: - You, too.
JO: Katie! Wait up.
- Hey.
- Hi.
Hi. You might not want the company,
but I'm headed home.
I thought we might walk together.
- Yeah, sure.
- Yeah? Oh, good.
Good, it'll keep me from
peeking into stranger's windows.
It's a habit I'm trying to break.
That and snapping my gum.
It's a horrible habit.
I started in middle school and...
What you got there?
Oh, the little girl from the general store,
she drew it for me.
- I think it's the store owner's daughter.
- Oh.
It's a flying fish, right?
Yeah, that's what she said.
What a beautiful day, huh?
I love how the light
comes through the trees.
I always dreamed
of going overseas to Europe
and learning different languages,
meeting new people.
Eating my way through Italy.
I've never even made it
over the Atlantic.
I'm sure you will.
You still have plenty of time.
Yeah.
OK, well. Thanks for the walk.
- Of course. See ya.
- Bye.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
Detective Tierney, Boston PD.
Do you know this woman?
I'm sorry, Detective...
KEVIN: Have you seen this woman?
No. Sorry.
(KNOCKING)
(DOOR OPENING)
- Hi.
- Hello.
Do you know this woman?
- No, I don't know this woman.
- No?
- She's new to the neighborhood.
- Is she?
- To the beach? I don't think so.
(WATER SPLASHING)
I saw you got to spend some time
with Alex and his kids.
Yeah.
I guess by now you heard
about what happened to his wife?
It was cancer.
A few years ago.
And it nearly broke Alex in half.
This storm's gonna
blow over here pretty soon
and all the people are gonna
be coming in from the beach
and we're gonna get really busy.
(BELL JINGLING)
- Katie!
Your paint's here.
I had this extra can of primer in the back.
I thought maybe you might want
to put that down before
you put the paint down.
Oh, yeah, right.
I didn't even think about that.
Let me grab my keys.
I'll give you a lift.
- No, I'll be... I'm fine.
- You're gonna walk
- all the way back with the cans?
- Yeah.
- Are you...?
- Yep. I'm good.
(CHUCKLES)
(DOOR RATTLING)
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
WOMAN: (ON STEREO)
What you been doing in there?
BOY: Nothing.
WOMAN: Nothing? Look at your hands
and look at your mouth.
- What is that truck?
BOY: - I don't know, Aunt.
ALEX: - It's Mark Twain.
WOMAN: - Well, I know.
The kids love it.
I can't complain.
You know, it could be worse.
It could be Slayer.
I got Slayer in here.
Why don't we listen to that instead?
- No, this is good.
- OK.
MAN: The switch hovered in the air.
The peril was desperate.
ALEX: All right.
- You can just leave it there.
- No, I can run it up to...
No, no, no, really, it's fine.
- Thank you. Just...
- OK. I'll just leave it right there.
- See ya.
- Bye.
Yeah.
Oh, wait, wait, I got...
...some other stuff
you might need just in case.
Some tape, sandpaper, scrapers,
things like that.
Just tape around, sand it down before
you put the primer... you know what to do.
- All right.
KATIE: - Thanks.
Yep.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(SIGHS)
MAN: (ON STEREO) He surveyed
the fence, and all gladness left him.
And a deep melancholy
settled down upon his spirit.
(MID-TEMPO GUITAR SONG PLAYS)
(INAUDIBLE CHATTER)
JO: I like this color.
It's brightening up the place.
KATIE: Yeah, I like it.
So, you think you're
gonna stay in town for a while?
Yeah, we'll see.
(CRICKETS CHIRRING)
(GASPING)
(WHIMPERING)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
(GASPING)
(VEHICLE DOOR OPENS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH)
(QUIET RATTLING)
(PANTING)
(FOOTSTEPS OUTSIDE)
(VEHICLE DOOR CLOSES)
(VEHICLE DRIVING AWAY)
ALEX: - All right, have a good one.
MAN: - Thank you, Alex.
Well, what you got there?
Did you leave this
outside my house last night?
Maybe.
I can't take it.
(STAMMERS)
Well, it was just sitting in my shed.
It's OK, I don't have any use for it.
You know what? I just...
I don't appreciate you coming
in the middle of the night to my house.
And I know this is a nice gesture,
but I just... I can't accept it.
- So, um...
- I don't understand.
- It's not a big deal. It's just a bike.
- I know.
- I see you walking back and forth...
- I didn't ask for it
and I don't want it. So...
(STAMMERS) Wait, I'm sorry.
You know, normally when somebody
does something nice for you,
you just say thank you.
JO: - I like the curtains.
- I mean...
...I barely know this guy and he comes
to my house in the middle of the night,
- and just leaves something...?
- Oh, Katie... Katie.
Look, I know you found a place as
far away from people as you could,
but you're gonna have to learn that
if you're gonna live south of the
Mason-Dixon line, people give you stuff.
That means stuff you don't want,
stuff you don't even need.
- Trust me, there is no hidden agenda.
- No, because when you put it...
And sometimes we just leave
that stuff in the front yard.
I just don't want to owe him anything.
It's a bike, not a kidney.
So, you're saying that
I overreacted a little?
Yeah. Yeah, maybe a little bit.
- All right, maybe I did overreact.
- Thank you.
- A little.
(JO CHUCKLES)
Look, Katie, the great thing is
life is full of second chances.
Hey, Alex.
So... you were right.
I was right? About what?
I should have just said thank you.
For the bike.
- I'm sorry, I was really rude and...
- No, no, no, it was my fault.
I should have asked you
before I did it. (SIGHS)
- Bus is here!
(DOOR BELL JINGLING)
Don't worry, it won't happen again.
- Hi.
- Hi, how are you?
- Where's your bathroom?
- Uh, straight back there.
- Oh, thanks.
- Hi, Katie.
- Hi.
BOY: - Can I have some popcorn?
- Popcorn anywhere?
- Popcorn... is right over here.
(TOILET FLUSHING)
- No!
- Josh!
(GASPING)
Josh!
(JOSH GASPING)
- I hit my head!
- I know, I know!
MAN: Alex, is he OK?
- Get him around to the ladder.
KATIE: - Lexie.
You OK?
It's OK, it's OK.
- It's OK.
- I hit my head!
Here we go.
You OK?
Just stand back.
How you doing? You OK?
You're OK. You're OK.
Come on.
Stop. Stop it.
I'm fine.
- Katie!
DRIVER: - Watch your step.
Thank you.
DRIVER: Watch your step.
- Of course.
(BUS BRAKES HISSING)
Did you forget something?
(BUS ENGINE REVVING)
(ALEX WHISPERS INDISTINCTLY)
- You forgot your bike!
JO: Katie!
See? It's not so hard.
(KATIE LAUGHS)
Hi, Jo!
(MOUSE CLICKING)
Hey, so listen, I've been
looking over this Lumpkin case and...
I didn't ask you to do that.
Who asked you to do that?
You know what it looks like? It looks like
his alibi might actually check out.
OK, right.
Lieutenant signed off on it,
the DA's office signed off on it.
The case is closed.
I've got open cases to work now.
I mean, the guy has three
little kids and, you know,
even if there's a slight chance
he's innocent...
Oh, God, don't you have like a wife
or something that you
can go home and irritate?
Look... no one's innocent.
No one.
I don't care if he killed her himself.
He was there. He knows what happened.
I'm not his judge, I'm not his jury...
I'm not his maker.
The job is to bring him in,
the other guys sort him out.
RHETT: Alex, the crowds are
gonna be huge, we gotta go bigger.
Every year the crowds get bigger
and every year you call me
freaking out that we need
to make the show bigger.
I don't know how much bigger
we can make it, man.
I am not freaking out.
City council called and said
they're expecting 100,000 people.
Now those are big city numbers,
so we need to put on a big city show.
I got this new brochure I want you to see.
ALEX: No, no, no,
I've seen the brochure. All right?
No, you haven't seen the new one.
But that's not the point. The point is...
- Daddy, when are we going?
- Hold on. In a minute, sweetheart.
Hey, Mulligan, you boys born stupid
or you had to work at it?
Zip it, Luther.
ALEX: - I'll stop in in the next week.
- Great, fine. When?
ALEX: - No, no, no...
- Katie!
- Hey.
ALEX: - Hey, hold on one second.
- What's up?
- Can you go to the beach with us?
- Lexie. She's not...
- I don't know.
- We're going to the beach.
- Yeah, I see that.
- I need her to come right now!
(ALEX AND KATIE LAUGH)
Lexie, she's not coming with us.
- I want her to come!
- Actually, that sounds really nice.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- What do you say?
- Yes!
(ALEX CHUCKLES) - OK. All right, OK.
RHETT: - Alex.
- I gotta go. You're breaking up.
- No, Alex, don't hang up on me.
Wait...
He hung up.
- Look at Roxy. (GIGGLES)
- Roxy.
I think this one's Roxy.
Do you like this one?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Should we do it?
KATIE: - You're a good shopper.
- Are you cool with this?
- With what?
- Katie coming to the beach with us.
Uh...
Yeah. Yeah, I guess so.
How about you?
- It's a little awkward.
(CHUCKLES)
(GULLS CRYING)
(MID-TEMPO GUITAR SONG PLAYS)
Line it up.
- Oh!
- All right, let's get a photo.
Look up. Josh, look up.
All right, you two.
Come on, let's get a photo.
(GRUNTING)
- All right.
ALEX:
All right, let's take a photo here.
One, two...
Thank you.
OK, one, two, three.
- Come on, give it back!
- No, you're done.
(LAUGHING)
- Caught one. He caught one!
- Oh, my gosh!
ALEX: What do you got?
Aah! My battery's dead,
hold on one second.
- I lost my battery power.
- Oh, no.
What happened to the fish?
I don't know.
What do you mean, you don't know?
Just one time, could I get
a picture of you with your fish?
Why do you always
have to take pictures?
I don't know, Josh, because I want to be
able to remember this stuff, that's why.
Try to remember without the camera.
ALEX: What do I do about Josh?
He's testing me.
Do you think it's just a phase?
I hope so. (SIGHS)
No, I see the way he pushes your buttons.
Josh was young,
but he remembers her, you know?
Lexie remembers
the idea of her and...
It's just... there's a difference.
You know?
KATIE: Have you talked to him?
ALEX: At this point, I don't
really know what to say to him.
Oh!
You did a good job with this.
ALEX: So, why Southport?
Um... Because it looks like this.
Just a clean, empty canvas.
You're starting over.
You know, sort of.
I kinda was just...
- ...looking for a change and...
- Hm.
I always wanted to live
in small town, so...
Well, you found one.
- It is pretty small.
(CHUCKLING)
Yeah, a little too sleepy sometimes,
if you ask me.
- Well, the grass is always greener, so...
- Yeah, but it's nice. You'll like it.
Are you staying or... you just passing
through, or what's your story?
So many questions.
Just curious.
What about you?
- Are you from here?
- I'm from Wilmington.
We used to come here quite a bit
when I was a kid.
Stayed for a few weeks, I loved it.
My Uncle Roger,
the guy that I work with at the store...
- Yeah.
- ...worked with him for a few weeks
out of the summer...
...then when we got pregnant
it just seemed like...
...it seemed like the right place to stay.
LEXIE:
Mighty Josh is crushing my castle!
(KIDS MIMIC EXPLOSION SOUNDS)
LEXIE: - No!
One, two, three!
Now let's all do Josh's face.
ALEX: - Ready?
- You ready?
One, two, three.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
Well, here we are.
- Thanks for coming.
- I had a great time.
- It was fun.
- Thank you.
- All right.
- Well, have a good night.
- You, too.
Oh, hey, I forgot to ask you,
how'd your floors turn out?
You want to see?
All right.
ALEX: Wow, look at that.
I wasn't too sure about the yellow,
but it looks pretty good.
Yeah, thank you.
Thanks to your primer
and Lexie's keen eye...
- Yeah.
- ...I think it worked out.
Looks like your walls need a little...
- Jeez!
- Oh, my God.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
- Are you OK?
Sorry I'm laughing.
Are you OK?
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
ALEX: What the hell just happened here?
- I'm sorry, I should've told you about that.
- I just made a giant hole in your floor.
- The hole was there. So you're OK.
- I can fix this.
- I have...
- You're OK, right?
I have a hammer
and some nails in my truck.
- You're fine, you're fine.
- It would take me two minutes to...
- Alex, it's...
- You don't want to leave a giant hole...
- OK. Here.
- So...
(LAUGHING)
- All right.
- I'm fine. I promise.
- I'm gonna go.
Bye, Josh.
- Bye.
- I had fun.
ALEX: That's it?
- How about some manners?
- He's fine. He's fine.
He's tired.
Thank you, again.
I had fun.
Hey, anytime.
I think they had more fun
with you than me.
KATIE: Drive safe.
Bye.
Careful up there.
You know, if you fall, it's not gonna
be anybody's fault but your own.
That's enough, honey.
You've got enough of those already.
- Come on in.
- Excuse me, ma'am. Ma'am.
It's me again.
Mind if I come in for a moment?
Actually, this is a very bad time.
It's time for my husband's nap.
Dan, come on in for your nap.
I understand,
I'm so sorry to bother you.
I just needed to ask you
a few more questions.
I answered all of your questions
about her last time.
I really don't know
what you want me to say.
- It's just a moment of your time...
- You wanna bring some cherries home?
- No, dear, he doesn't. No.
- No, sir. Thank you.
Have a good day.
(DOOR LOCKING)
(BOAT HORN BLOWS IN DISTANCE)
Here's one.
Hey, Katie! Come here and you try.
No, I don't really know
what I'm doing, so...
MADDIE: - Come on, you can do it.
- Come on, it's easy.
- It's tradition.
- OK. All right. What do I do?
You just see a fish and you stab it.
- I... I stab a fish. OK, easy.
- Yeah.
FRANKIE: - I'm your eyes.
- How do I...?
FRANKIE: Here's one right here.
- Get him!
- You see it? OK, you just stab it, OK?
OK, OK, I got it, I got it.
Whoo!
Oh, shit, I got it!
ALEX: What's this?
This is a gift.
- This is to say thank you.
- Wha...?
- Did you actually catch this?
- I speared it.
You gigged it.
- I gigged it? I gigged it.
- You gigged it.
Josh, look at this.
- She gigged it.
JOSH: - Cool.
- That is disgusting.
- That is...
But you know what?
I can't accept it.
You're gonna have to stop
doing nice things for me.
Ah... Well...
...you could just say thank you.
OK, well, thank you,
for thank you flounder.
(GIGGLES)
- I'm gonna put it in the fridge.
- Yeah.
- All right.
(DOOR BELL JINGLING)
Did Josh leave already?
Yeah, I'll take you to soccer, sweetheart.
Go get your backpack.
- OK.
- Hey, Lexie.
LEXIE: Hi.
- What about my snack?
- Uh...
- I'll get you some oranges, all right?
- OK.
All right, well, you'll have
to let me know how the fish is.
Oh, I'm sure it'll be great.
We'll probably grill that up tonight.
- Yeah? Well, good.
- Mm-hm.
I don't know how to grill flounder,
but I'm sure you do.
- Oh, it's pretty simple.
- Yeah?
I like to go fishing in my canoe.
You ever go canoeing?
- Canoeing, you ever been?
MAN: - Canoeing?
- Uh... no.
- I like canoeing.
Where do you go?
Dutchman's Creek.
Dutchman's Creek, lot of gators there.
I like Walden Creek better.
- Just got a new canoe.
ALEX: - Hm.
Anyway, there's, uh...
It's not the most exciting thing in
the world, but it's beautiful out there.
- You know?
- Yeah.
Hey, I think I got everything I need here.
Spit it out.
Get it over with, will you?
- You wanna go canoeing with me?
- No price tag on it. How much is it?
Yes. Yes, I would.
- You would?
- Yes.
- Tomorrow?
- That'd be great.
OK.
We should be back around six or seven.
There's plenty of food in the fridge.
As you know, the kids won't be shy
about telling you what they don't like.
- Well, it's gonna rain, you know?
- What?
It's not gonna rain.
I checked the weather report.
It said a five percent chance of rain.
Yeah, well,
the weather report's wrong.
They have instruments for this.
Doppler, Super Doppler,
all kinds of other crap.
You have an arthritic knee.
It tightens up, it's gonna rain.
- Don't need a Doppler or Super Doppler...
- It's not gonna rain.
...to figure that out.
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(INSECTS CHIRRING)
KATIE: - It's so beautiful.
ALEX: - Yeah.
This is probably my favorite place
in the whole world.
Did you used to, um...
come here with your wife?
Yeah.
Does it get better? With time?
(SIGHS)
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, at first, I tried to avoid
any place that we went together.
I tried to forget, I tried
to put it all behind me.
I tried to, you know...
just look forward.
But it just didn't work.
And I realized that if...
...if I'm not thinking about her, who is?
You know? And she didn't deserve that.
She was an amazing woman
and I loved her
and I want my kids to know that.
I want them to know her.
So... I don't know, I just...
We're just keeping our heads down.
Getting to play mom and dad
which is interesting.
Just trying to keep it all together, really.
But today with you, this is probably
the first time that I've looked up.
It's a perfect day.
Did you feel that?
No.
All right.
It's just a little light shower.
It'll pass in a bit.
- Yeah, just a little...
- Let's go over here.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
It's off in the distance.
We'll be all right.
- Did you hear that? (LAUGHS)
- We're all right under here.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
- OK! Uh...
You know what?
I have a better idea.
You hungry?
- Yeah. OK.
- OK. All right.
Come on.
Oh, my gosh! (LAUGHING)
(SCREAMS, LAUGHS)
Come on.
(SQUEALING)
Hello. How's it going?
- Want to just sit here?
- Can we seat ourselves?
(LAUGHING)
I have a friend who's
coming back from Charlotte.
He should be able to pick us up
on his way back through,
but he isn't picking up his phone, so...
Well, no rush.
I mean, I'm happy here.
- So...
- Yeah?
Yeah.
It's a big study. That's
what this whole book is about.
What I always wondered was gorillas,
maybe the strongest animals on the planet.
- Primates, anyway.
- Yeah. Mm-hm.
- Don't eat meat.
- Fruits and vegetables.
They eat mostly kale.
Yes, kale is fantastic for your body.
Is there protein in kale
or is that just...?
- I'm sure there is.
- Where does the strength come from?
- They have to... it has to be genetic.
- It's genetic, but...
Except what are you gonna eat?
Fruit, vegetables, nuts...
I'm guessing Rhett will be here soon.
I should probably settle the...
It sure cleared out.
- Let me see if I can find someone.
- Thank you, by the way.
You're welcome.
Hello?
(SLOW-TEMPO SONG PLAYING)
- Hello?
This song is nice.
(VOLUME INCREASES)
(CHUCKLING)
(LAUGHING)
Let's go this way.
What's this?
- Well, thank you.
- Oh, you're welcome.
- How's my hat?
- Very pretty.
Thank you.
(LAUGHING)
(POLICE SIREN CHIRPING)
RHETT: (OVER SPEAKER)
Step away from the girl!
ALEX:
All right, all right. It's just Rhett.
(RHETT LAUGHING)
- Come on.
(SIREN CHIRPING)
It's just my friend.
RHETT:
We're in for a nasty rainy season.
I don't know what we're gonna do on
the Fourth if it keeps going like this.
ALEX: What does that mean,
the fireworks are a wash?
Not a chance, buddy-boy.
The show goes on.
We've been running the fireworks show
here for as long as we can remember.
Biggest extravaganza
on the Eastern Seaboard.
- What?
- Yeah.
- That's a slight exaggeration.
- Oh, I don't think so.
Maybe the lower third of North Carolina.
- Oh, bullshit.
- God.
Bullshit. Who does it better
than we do? Come on.
- That's the answer. Thank you.
- Nobody does it better than we do, officer.
- Nobody. We do it best.
- Yep.
End of the line, everybody out.
Pretty isolated out here.
- I got neighbors. They're not too far.
- Hm.
Oh.
Pleasure as always, ma'am.
- All right.
- OK.
- Good night. Thank you.
- Oh...
Come here.
(CHUCKLING)
Shut up.
(STARTS ENGINE)
ALEX: - Thank you.
RHETT: - You got it, buddy.
ALEX: - All right. I'll see you tomorrow.
RHETT: - You bet.
ALEX: - We'll talk fireworks.
RHETT: - Yes, we will.
I guess your arthritis
is smarter than the both of us.
Dad? Where have you been?
JOSH: Out having fun.
Why are they still up?
Probably too much candy.
Hey, guys.
Where have you been?
I'm sorry I'm late, honey.
I just... I got caught in a rainstorm
and I wasn't expecting
to be out this late, OK?
But you weren't here to tuck me in.
I know.
But I'm here now.
I can tuck you in now.
Yeah. I just missed you a lot.
You did? I missed you, too.
I missed you more.
No way. Not possible.
- It is possible.
(CHUCKLES)
Good night.
Dad!
What are you doing up there?
It's Mom's place!
I'll be right there. Hold on.
You're not supposed to be up there.
I know. I know.
Look, I know that it's Mom's place.
And it's always gonna be her place.
Not like you care.
Hey. Hey... Come on, bud,
I'm doing the best I can, all right?
- It's Mom's place.
- I know that it's Mom's place.
(DOOR SQUEAKING)
KATIE: Thank you for everything.
Oh, kiddo, you're welcome.
Just call me when you
land somewhere safe, OK?
Do you promise? You take this.
Be careful.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPING)
Hey, it's me.
I know I should have
called a long time ago...
...but I just wanted
to let you know that...
...I've ended up somewhere safe.
(SIGHS)
(SCREEN DOOR CLOSES)
(GASPS)
- That's your handwriting.
Now you lied to me, Mrs. Feldman.
You told me you didn't know her,
but that's not the case, is it?
So, open the door,
we're gonna have that little talk now.
When you get a warrant,
I'll open the door.
Well, don't go away,
I'll get that warrant.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYS)
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
I'm here for a pick up.
(LAUGHING)
- I don't want you to get in trouble.
I just came by to see you because...
(GIGGLING)
I gotta go. All right,
quit messing around and get back to work.
- See you tonight!
- Bye!
KATIE: We spent hours
talking at dinner last night.
I haven't had that
much fun in a long time.
Hm, to think it all started with a bike.
I thought you said that
was him just being Southern.
Ah, yeah, I was lying.
He was making a move.
- What?
(JO LAUGHS)
You know, some people
just need a little nudge.
I could tell you weren't
gonna get there on your own.
- Yeah, well, you're lucky it worked out.
- Yep.
- You want anything?
- Oh, no, I'm good.
(SLOW-TEMPO SONG PLAYS)
(INAUDIBLE CHATTER)
So, um... I fixed the floor.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Hm.
If you wanna check it out.
Yes.
OK.
- OK.
(GULLS CRYING)
(BUOY BELL CLANGING)
(ALEX LAUGHING)
- Angel Cake's the fireworks.
- Oh.
No, they're elegant,
they don't cost as much.
They come in red, white and blue,
you're really gonna love these.
I think we should go with these this year.
Take a look.
Highway Patrol just faxed these docs
for you to sign, boss, if you don't mind.
RHETT: All right. That's fine.
Anyway... Oh, you know what?
We could go with the, uh...
What's the other one?
Black Cat Aerial Phenomenons
or the Whistling Dixies.
The Whistling Dixies. I mean, they really
whistle "Dixie." How cool is that?
No, it really is.
Where did I leave that?
- In the can.
- Shit, you're right.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Alex, let me get this for you.
RHETT: - Bass, where did you put it?
BASS: - In the can.
Rhett, I gotta... I forgot something
back at the house.
RHETT: - What?
- I'll be back in a minute.
(ALARM BEEPING)
- Hey, hey...
I know, I know, I know.
Kevin, can I see you in my office?
- Yeah, I'm in the middle of something...
- Now!
KATIE: Oh... (CHUCKLES)
- All right, I'll see ya later, Katie.
- All right. I'll see you tomorrow, Frankie.
ALEX: Erin?
(SCOFFS)
What is this, some kind of a joke?
What is this?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
"Special bulletin, person of interest,
suspect murder, first degree.
Erin Tierney"?
- Who did you kill?
- No, it's not what you think.
Why don't you tell me
what I'm supposed to think then?
Because I see your picture on a wanted
sign saying you're a suspect for murder.
Your name is Erin.
Erin.
- Please, Alex, let me explain.
- I trusted you.
I let you into our lives,
for Godsakes, my kids.
My kids trusted you. What the hell
am I supposed to tell my kids?
That I was stupid,
I was a stupid young girl
that got into a relationship
with the wrong man.
- How am I supposed to believe that?
- Who hurt me.
How am I supposed to believe anything
that comes out of your mouth?
I don't even know your first name,
for Chrissakes.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
The last thing that I wanted to do
is hurt anybody.
- You should go.
- Especially you.
You should go. You should
probably go before Rhett sees that.
(SIGHING)
What's up, boss?
You tell me.
What's this?
That's... that's not what you think.
Tell me what it is.
What's in your water bottle?
Your water bottle, you carry it with you
everywhere you go. What's in it?
- Water.
- Yeah? Give it to me.
Why?
(SNIFFS)
As of now, you are suspended without pay,
pending internal review.
I need you to hand over
your badge and your gun.
Don't take the badge, boss.
MAN: Do you have any idea
how many rules you've broken?
LEXIE: Hey, Miss Katie!
You know, I knew you were crazy,
but I didn't think you were stupid.
- I need to find her.
- You don't do it like this.
You know that. You know that!
I need your badge and your gun.
KEVIN: I need to find her, Jim.
Kevin, you sent out a nationwide APB.
She's not a murderer for Chrissakes,
she's your goddamn wife.
KEVIN: Something smells amazing.
Hey, you're home early.
Oh, you're killing me.
(BIKE CHAIN SPINNING)
(GASPING)
- How was your day?
- Tiring, sweaty, hot, horrible.
KATIE: Lovely. What's this for?
KEVIN: What's it for?
I need an excuse to give my wife a gift?
KATIE: - It's beautiful. Thank you.
KEVIN: - You like it?
KATIE: Yeah. It's really gorgeous.
KEVIN: - May I?
KATIE: - Of course.
KEVIN:
This is the best pie I've ever tasted.
Yeah? It's a new recipe.
It's so good. So good.
Thank you.
Are you done with this?
Yeah.
You think I'm done with that?
No, I was just...
coming to pour you some more.
You want to say something, you say it.
I don't have anything to say.
You got that look.
I don't have any look.
What do you want from me?
Nothing. I don't want anything.
KEVIN: How many times do you
have to hear me say I'm sorry?
You won't let it rest.
Every moment of every day you
want me to apologize. You make me...
No, it's fine, I promise. It's fine.
I'm just gonna go put on some coffee.
- You think you can walk away from me?
- No.
(GLASS BREAKING)
- Huh?
- Kevin! (GRUNTING)
- What do you want from me, baby?
- I give you everything! Everything!
(YELLING)
Stop, please. Kevin, stop, please!
- What do you want from me, huh?
(SOBS) - Please. Please, please...
No! (GASPS)
(KNIFE CLATTERS ON FLOOR)
Stop! Please.
No!
- Listen to me. You listen to me.
(COUGHING)
- You know that I love you.
- Stop!
I gave you the necklace for a reason, baby!
Why did you make me do this?
- Stop fighting, stop fighting.
- Kevin!
I love you so much,
and you want to walk away from me?
(GASPING)
(KEVIN SHOUTS)
(PANTING, SOBBING)
JO: - Katie, what's going on?
- I've gotta get out of here.
I've been here for too long.
Whoa, what are you talking about?
You just got here.
It's exactly what I was afraid of, Jo.
The things I've done... I can't stay.
OK, Katie, let's just calm down, OK?
We can figure this out. All right?
Wait, does Alex
know that you're leaving?
Who do you think was
the one who told me to go?
Alex wants nothing
to do with me anymore.
And frankly, I don't blame him.
Look, Katie, if you run now,
you're taking the easy way out.
The easy way?
You think this is easy for me?
You obviously don't know me.
Katie, you have people here
who care about you.
I think that you should stay here
and face whatever this is.
Face things the way you face things?
Excuse me?
Come on, Jo. You know you're
stuck here and for no good reason.
At least I know when
it's time for me to leave.
Yeah, you're right, Katie.
But some of us don't have that choice.
Good luck, Katie.
(GULLS CRYING)
(BUOY BELL CLANGING)
Katie!
(FERRY HORN BLOWING)
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Katie!
Katie! Hey.
- Alex.
- Look...
- I can't.
- ...I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry. Please, just...
...just stay.
No. You were right.
- I have to go.
(HORN HONKING)
- He's gonna find me. He's gonna find us.
- Whoa, wait. Just tell me the truth.
Just tell me what happened,
and if you're in trouble,
we can get the police involved.
I can talk to Rhett.
You don't understand, Alex,
he is the police.
My husband's a cop in Boston.
That's why he could do all that.
I don't care, all right?
I'm not gonna let him hurt you anymore.
It doesn't even matter.
I can't put you through that.
I can't put your family through that.
He's always gonna be there.
- He doesn't quit.
- Katie. Listen to me.
I'm in love with you.
And if you stay, I promise...
...there's no safer place in the world
than right here with me.
God, I'm so scared.
I know you are,
but you don't have to be.
You don't have to be scared.
I love you.
Please stay.
(CRICKETS CHIRRING)
COMPUTERIZED VOICE:
Saturday, 2:03 p.m.
MAN 1:
Hey, Ma, it's Andy. Give me a call.
Sunday, 9:00 p.m.
MAN 2: Hi, this is Ernie
calling from Buffalo...
Monday, 11:47 a.m.
KATIE: Hey, it's me.
I know I should have
called a long time ago...
...but I just wanted
to let you know that...
(WATER RUNNING)
KATIE: ...I've ended up somewhere safe.
(LINE RINGING)
MADDIE: Hello, you've reached
Ivan's Fish Shack,
Southport's finest waterfront café.
We're open Tuesday through Sunday
from ten to ten,
and we're located at 631 Yacht Basin,
just past the Frying Pan.
If you need to leave a message
for Maddie, just wait for the beep.
Thank y'all.
You just become dark, like there's...
...the life is just sucked out of you.
You just felt worthless,
like there's no point.
And I just stuck up for him
all the time. (SNIFFLING)
'Cause it wasn't his fault. It was mine.
And you're completely alone.
It's OK.
- It's OK.
(SNIFFLING)
You're OK now.
I've never really talked about it.
I'm so glad you're here.
And I am, too. (SNIFFLING)
Everything's gonna be OK.
Yeah.
- Whoa!
(LEXIE GIGGLES)
You're gonna help me carry these in?
Thank you, buddy.
I appreciate it.
(HORN HONKING)
Listen...
...if there's a problem
with her being here,
- I want you...
- No, it's cool.
Seriously. I'm fine.
I like her.
- You like her?
- Yeah.
Well, I like her, too.
I know she likes you.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
(GRUNTING)
Do you need any help?
Is that all?
You're a little small
to be running a store. (SNIFFS)
- My daddy runs it. I'm just helping.
- Yeah?
- Where's your daddy?
- Not around.
- Yeah, what's your name?
- Lexie.
Lexie, I'm a policeman. OK?
And I've just driven a very long way
to be here today
and I would like to speak
with someone a little taller.
OK?
Where's your uniform?
- My uniform?
- Yeah.
Hm. (CHUCKLES)
I'm a detective.
You know what a detective is, Lexie?
- No.
- No?
Well, detectives catch the bad guys.
That's what I do.
Now, also, I look for missing people.
(SNIFFS)
That's what I'm doing here, Lexie.
I'm looking for a missing person.
Now...
...have you seen this woman?
No.
- You sure?
- I'm sure.
You wouldn't lie to a policeman,
would you?
No.
OK. OK. (SNIFFS)
- How much is that?
- $1.50.
$1.50.
Two dollars.
LEXIE: - Thank you.
KEVIN: - You keep it.
Bye.
You ready?
ALEX: Oh! You're getting big!
LEXIE:
Do policemen always wear uniforms?
ALEX: Uh... I'm sure they take them off
when they get home from work.
GIRL: - Hey, guys.
ALEX: - Hey!
- Happy Fourth.
ALEX: - Look who we have here!
- Hey, Lexie!
ALEX: - Go get her!
(MARCHING BAND PLAYS
PATRIOTIC MUSIC)
MAN: The Southport High School
Marching Band!
The Southport Fire and Rescue!
(ANNOUNCER CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY)
Here comes the Kitty Hawk!
First in flight, that's us, North Carolina!
And sponsored by the Daughters
of the American Revolution...
(ANNOUNCER CONTINUES
INDISTINCTLY)
(MID-TEMPO SONG PLAYS)
(OVERLAPPING CHATTER)
The fireworks start at 9:00,
I should be home shortly after that.
- All right?
JOSH: - Can I come with you?
- You wanna come with?
- Yeah, I wanna come with.
- OK, yeah. Go grab your shoes.
- OK.
Wow.
Hey, and if Lexie's stomach keeps hurting,
chamomile tea usually does the trick.
- We have some over at the store.
- Got it.
- All right. You sure you're OK?
- We are good.
- You got it?
- Alex.
- All right, all right. Come on, kid.
- Be safe, have fun.
Wanna race?
ALEX: Hey, look who showed up.
Hey, Josh, man. We got plenty of room.
All right, hold on, buddy.
Let me get in here first.
All right.
RHETT: - All right!
ALEX: - Put that on.
You ready for a big night?
Want to blow some stuff up and be men?
ALEX:
All right, we're gonna do this, boys.
RHETT: Josh, no drinking, no smoking.
You got that?
MAN: Bow clear.
RHETT: You're not gonna go climbing
around on this thing, are you?
- Feeling better?
- Mm-hm.
- All right, here we go!
- Ready?
- All right, we're hot!
- Fire in the hole!
(ALL CHEERING)
(CROWD CHEERING, APPLAUDING)
- Oh, there's your precious Angel Cake.
- What did I tell you, buddy?
- Angel Cake!
- Your precious Angel Cake! (LAUGHS)
Katie?
Hey.
Look, I just want to apologize
- for what I said earlier.
- He's here.
- Who's here?
- You know who.
(FIREWORKS EXPLODING
IN DISTANCE)
You cut your hair.
(WHISPERS) Kevin.
- It looks good.
It looks really good.
Thank you.
I found you.
I found you. I missed you, baby.
What are you doing here?
I just want to talk, you know?
I just...
I want to talk like we used to talk.
We used to talk about everything,
you know? (SNIFFLING)
Or nothing, it didn't matter.
We just... we just talked.
- I miss you so much, baby.
- OK, let's talk.
- Out here.
- OK.
(FIREWORKS CONTINUE CRACKLING)
What do you want to talk about?
You wanna go home?
I am home.
What? Here?
With him?
Huh?
I saw you today.
He doesn't know you like I know you.
- He doesn't love you like I love you.
- No, he doesn't.
You want me to walk away.
Is that it?
Yes. Go.
No, see, you don't tell me what to do.
You hurt me.
- I know.
- You kept hurting me.
- You need to go right now.
Now.
You're making a mistake.
No, I'm not.
(EXHALING)
(LEXIE GASPS)
- You scared me to death, Lex.
- But I wanted to see the fireworks.
I know, but we're gonna
watch them up here, OK?
I don't wanna.
All right. This is safer.
I need you to stay here for me,
OK, Lexie?
OK.
Here.
- Everything's OK. OK?
- OK.
I'll be right downstairs.
(PANTING)
(DIAL TONE)
(LINE RINGING)
(WHISPERS)
Come on, Alex, come on.
(LINE RINGING)
(LIQUID SPLASHING)
Oh, my God.
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
I'm so glad you found me.
Take me home. Take me home.
What are you doing?
I want you to take me home.
Take me home.
(GRUNTING)
(FIRE ROARING)
(GASPING) No, Lexie! Lexie!
(LAUGHING)
Watch Josh!
Lexie! Lexie!
Katie!
Lexie! (GASPING)
(KATIE YELLING)
- Dad!
- Lexie!
Hold on! Hold on!
(GRUNTING)
Hold on, Lexie!
(GASPING)
Baby, I'm here. I'm here.
Back up for me, back up for me, honey.
(GRUNTING)
- I gave you everything!
(SOBBING)
All right. Hold on.
All right, you sit right here,
- sit right here.
(KATIE SCREAMING)
Katie!
(GRUNTING)
- No!
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
Lexie!
Come on. I need you to jump.
I need you to jump.
You can do it! Come on.
Come on, honey. Come on.
Come on, baby.
One, two... three, come on!
(SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
Please... (GASPING)
I saw you.
- I'm so sorry, baby.
(GASPING)
(GUNSHOT)
No. No! No!
(GASPING)
(PANTING)
(LEXIE CRYING)
KATIE: Lexie...
Lexie.
- Are you OK?
- I'm so sorry.
Are you OK?
Are you OK? Are you OK?
She's OK, she's OK.
You're OK.
OK.
(SIRENS APPROACHING)
(BUOY BELL CLANGING)
Come on.
(JOSH SOBBING)
Hey, bud.
Hey, hey, hey, hey...
- It's gone.
- I know it's gone.
I know it's gone, but we're gonna rebuild it
just like it was before, all right?
I miss her.
I miss Mom. (SNIFFLING)
(SNIFFLING)
I miss her, too, buddy.
I'm always gonna miss her.
(SOBBING)
It's all right. It's OK.
(GULLS CRYING)
(BUOY BELL CLANGING)
So you're really leaving then, huh?
Yeah. I think that we both know it's...
it's time for me to go.
Well, when you get a chance, call me.
When you're settled,
so I know you're OK.
God... will you look at that sunlight.
(SIGHS) It's incandescent today.
Oh, God, it'd make a great photo.
- Promise me something, Katie.
- Yeah.
That you'll take a lot of pictures.
You'll only regret the ones
that you didn't take.
Thank you.
For being such a good friend.
You deserve this, Katie.
You belong here.
Hi.
So, there's a letter here.
It's for you.
- Oh, yeah? What is it?
- Mm-hm.
I'll be over with the kids.
ALEX: How's it going?
WOMAN:
To the woman my husband loves.
If you're reading this
then it must be true.
He loves you.
Beyond a shadow of a doubt, or else...
...he wouldn't have given this to you.
I can only hope that you feel the same
way about him as he does about you.
But I wanted to write you a letter
because I wanted you to know
one very, very important thing.
I'm so glad he's found you.
I only wish I could be there...
...somehow... to meet you.
Maybe in some ways, I am.
Outside of my husband
and my two beautiful children...
...you are the most
important person in the world to me.
Because I'm gone
and they're yours now.
- Hey, basmati rice. The king of rices.
(LEXIE GIGGLING)
It's OK. It's OK.
JO: You need to... take care of them.
Make them laugh.
Hold them when they cry.
Stand up for them and...
...teach them wrong from right.
The thought of you... it gives me hope.
Hope that Alex remembers
what it feels like
to be young and in love.
Hope that Josh finds somebody
to fish with again.
(NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE)
- Hope that Lexie has somebody there
to help her on her wedding day.
I hope that one day
my family is whole again.
But most of all, hope that...
...somehow, I'm there with all of you.
Watching over all of you.
(SLOW-TEMPO SONG PLAYS)
(English - US - PSDH)