Mrs. Larson?
It, uh...
It won't be much longer, Mrs. Larson.
Well, is he in a lot of pain?
No. No, no. There will be
No more pain for your husband.
He's heavily sedated.
OK. I think I'm gonna go
send little Hal in now.
No. No, no. I don't think
that's such a good idea.
With all the pain killers, uh...
the reverend's not exactly himself.
Look, I think my boy has a right
to say goodbye to his father.
I mean, the man means
everything in the world to him.
Well... your call.
Nurse?
Yes, Reverend Larson?
- Did you see the cowboy?
- The cowboy?
The cowboy who gave me
the singing nickel in Pudding Town?
OK. I think it's time
to turn down the morphine drip.
Reverend Larson, your son is here.
OK, sure. Send her in.
Ladies? A little privacy.
(wheezy coughing)
Dad?
It's me, Dad. Hal.
Oh.
Glad you're here, kiddo.
Got a few things to tell ya.
First, I want you to promise
that no matter what you do in life,
you will never ever settle for average.
Yes, sir.
Second, don't be satisfied
with routine poontang.
Huh?
Don't do what I did.
I married for love, and your mother
Betty has been a nightmare.
But, Dad, Mom's name is Marian.
Listen to me. I'm giving you pearls here.
And third, find yourself...
a classic beauty...
with a perfect can... and great totties.
That will put you in good stead
with the Lord. It's all in here.
Yes, sir.
Hot young tail's what it's all about.
Hot... young... tail.
I'll make you proud, Papa.
(* "Members Only" by Sheryl Crow)
* Uncle Larry's hooked on ice again
* He seems to be stuck in the '80s
* He wears his Members Only jacket
* Cos he thinks it turns on all the ladies
* And all the white folks shake their asses
* Looking for the two and four
* I'll have mine in martini glasses
* Cos I can't take it any more
* These are the days of empty kitchens
* The rise and fall of Mary Ellen's hair do...
Jackass, can you not hear me down there?
I don't want anything to do with you,
you little warthog.
You had me at "Get lost".
- What's up, Mauricio?
- Hey, Hal.
- How's the crowd tonight?
- Good. I got a few bites.
- Can I get you a drink?
- I won't say no to that.
Two beers.
- Two Buds?
- Two Buds.
So, I didn't expect to see you here.
Where's your new girl Loni?
- Lindy.
- She's, uh...
- (bartender) There you go.
Actually, I didn't tell her
I was goin' out tonight.
Why not? Things OK with you guys?
Yeah, a little too OK,
if you know what I'm talkin' about.
- What does that mean?
- Things are going in the shitter real quick.
Jeez, I'm sorry to hear that.
Why is she dumping you?
- She's not. I'm dumping her.
- You're dumping Loni?
- Lindy.
- What, are you crazy? Lindy's gorgeous.
On the surface, but when you get to know her
better, there's a whole other story goin' on.
Yeah? How goes that?
We're sitting there, you know, and
she's got her bare... feet up on the couch,
and I notice that her second toe is, like,
half an inch longer than her big toe.
- That's it? You're breaking up over that?
- Hey, I don't need that circus shit.
Well, couldn't she get the toe
filed down or something?
What, then I'm dating a nub?
I'm starting to think we're jinxed here.
- Speak for yourself, my friend.
- What, you got the promotion?
I don't hear till tomorrow, but guess who
is now officially going out with Jill.
Jill?! Your neighbour Jill?
You're going out with Jill, your neighbour?
And she doesn't exactly hate me.
Get out!
You are the luckiest man on the planet.
So what are you doing here?
She's hostessing until 11. I better get going.
I'm gonna try to catch her on the way home,
see if she wants to get a drink.
If I know you, that's not all she'll be gettin'.
See you later.
- I said no.
- No? Why not?
I don't wanna have a drink with you. I wanna
go home. Is that so hard to understand?
- What's goin' on? Are you mad?
- No, I'm not mad. I just...
Go on, say it. You know what?
No matter what it is, we're gonna work it out.
Hal, I'm not attracted to you.
So what? You think everyone who goes out
is attracted to each other? Get real.
They're attracted to each other
in the beginning.
Oh, come on. That sounds
like a bunch of New Age hooey.
Maybe for some people
there's a little spark in the beginning,
but for most, the attraction part
happens way later. Whoa!
What? That's it?
Just like that, we're breaking up?
Well, we were never going out.
We just had one date.
Come on. Hey, let's stay together five days.
That's all I need.
- Why do you need five days?
- Tomorrow I'm finally getting my promotion.
There's gonna be parties, dinners,
this, that. I need you now.
Hal, you're gonna be so busy,
you won't even think about me.
How am I not gonna think about you?
You live right across the hall.
I don't know, Hal. Maybe...
maybe you should think about moving.
Hal, we've made a decision
regarding that wholesaler position.
Yes! It's about time, Dave.
We decided to go with the gal from Merrill.
She's a proven entity. A big producer.
- I'm sorry, man.
- No, it's...
The gal's a proven entity.
What the heck you gonna do?
- Hal, I'm so sorry.
- Yeah, thanks.
- You should have gotten it. You deserved it.
- No, I didn't.
I didn't put them in a position
where they had to promote me or lose me.
It's a good lesson.
Make yourself indispensable, that's the key.
And to make matters worse,
Jill dumped me last night.
Dumped you? Don't you have to be
going out to get dumped?
- What does that mean?
- Well, I just thought it was more of a...
Anyway, why do you care so much?
Jill wasn't right for you and you know it.
How can you say that? She was perfect.
When are you gonna get it?
They're just well-formed molecules.
And by the way, her tits weren't even real.
Well, I could squeeze 'em.
That's real enough for me.
Hal, I don't understand how a guy
who's as nice and loyal and generous as you
could have such a huge flaw.
What are you talking about?
It never occurred to you that picking girls
on their looks may not be the best way?
Am I supposed to apologise
for having high standards?
High standards? ln the five years
I've known you, every woman -
I should say girl - you've gone after
has been completely out of your league.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- She doesn't mean anything by it.
She's just saying
you're not that good-looking.
Oh! I thought she was implying
something really mean.
No.
Hey, it's you. You're the TV guru guy.
- Yes, Tony Robbins. Pleased to meet you.
- Yeah! Oh, man!
So, wow! You gave advice
to what chama call it.
- President Clinton? Mandela?
- No, no, no.
- Gorbachev?
- No, no. Pamela Anderson.
Right? Yeah! Give me another handshake.
Wow! Man, look at those mitts!
It's like grabbing a bunch of bananas.
And those dogs. How big are those?
- Size 16, buddy.
- Holy cannoli.
- So you must do pretty good with the ladies.
- Just one.
- Really?
- Yeah.
(chuckles)
She sounds hot!
- She is an amazing lady.
- I bet.
- So, what are you doin' in my town?
- We're doing a seminar here.
I help people to deal with the challenges
in life with more dignity and courage.
That's my deal, is the courage. I try to...
Hang on a second. Buddy, hang on.
The elevator just stopped. That's weird.
- Man, yeah. So what do we...?
- Hang on.
- Are you OK? I'm fine.
- You OK?
Yeah, yeah. It's just I feel a little light-headed.
Then she dumped me. Flat out. Without
even the courtesy of a severance pop.
- A severance pop?
- You know, one last...
To ease the pain. The nice ones'll
sometimes throw you that.
It sounds like you've had
some odd relationships.
Yeah. See, the problem is I'm kinda picky.
- What do you mean, "picky"?
- Well, for instance, I like 'em real young.
Like, did you ever see Paulina
in her first Sports Illustrated layout?
- You're looking for a young Paulina type?
- That face, but with better headlights.
You know how hers
have kind of dimmed lately?
Heidi Klum's beams would do. And her teeth.
Or that Britney Spears girl.
She's got great knockers.
But she's a tad muscular.
Actually, you know what? Her ass would do,
too, if she had a better grille.
Like Michelle Pfeiffer
back when she did Grease 2.
But she'd have to be
a little smilier than Michelle.
Like Rebecca Romijn-Stamos,
before she got Stamosed.
But not as skinny. Someone meatier,
like Heidi, but without the accent.
You know those accents: yah-yah-yah-yah.
They really get old fast. You know
what I'm saying. Someone like that.
Don't you think you're being a little bit
shallow in the way you look at women?
Well, no. I mean, you know,
I'd like her to be into culture and shit, too.
OK, hypothetical situation.
Which do you prefer, a girlfriend
missing one breast or half a brain?
Ooh, toughie. That's a toughie.
How's the remaining breast? ls it big?
- How's your relationship with your parents?
- Excellent. I mean, my mom's hilarious.
She golfs every afternoon.
Actually, I don't really remember my dad.
He died when I was nine, so...
If you were nine, you should remember a lot.
Yeah, but I don't.
My mom thinks I might have been
a little traumatised by the whole thing.
Anyway, all I remember is, he was great.
He was a great guy,
and I really loved him, but...
I'm sorry you lost him.
Hey, listen, I know you got a great heart.
You're just fixated on
the outside appearances of people.
- Hal Larson, I'm gonna do you a great favour.
- Really?
This is how it'll work. From this moment on,
whenever you meet someone in the future,
you're only gonna see what's inside them.
So you'll respond to that, because that,
my friend, is where the true beauty lies.
OK, Tony, I think
you're getting a little cabin fever.
Hold on. What if I told you by doing this,
you could have the most beautiful women
in the world and they'd want you?
- Is this like what you do in your seminars?
- No, no, this is very special.
This is just between you and me.
Let's get up and I'll show you what to do.
Now, you got a pattern of looking at women
and judging them by the exterior.
We gotta break that pattern.
So has there been a time
when you were especially shallow with a
woman, where you thought you were better?
- All the time.
Is there one specific time
where you were really shallow?
- Oh, yeah, I got one.
- Think about that.
Devils, come out!
- What the hell are you doin', banana hands?
- Just hang on.
- We gotta jolt your nervous system.
- Oh, yeah. I'm sorry.
It's not just talking about it. Here's what
I want you to do. Just relax for a moment.
- I won't do that again.
- I didn't mean the "banana hands" thing.
Close your eyes. Just relax. And I want you
to imagine that you're on a beach.
It's a warm day and the sun
is just starting to set.
And you're looking in the eyes of a woman,
and you're feeling her heart.
You're seeing her soul.
You're feeling her spirit.
That's it. That's it.
Excellent. Excellent.
Taxi!
Oh.
I'm sorry. I... I thought that...
No, it's my fault. I didn't see you.
This is your cab. I'm gonna get the next cab.
- OK.
- All right.
Look, I'm just... I'm just
headed over to the East Side.
- Do you wanna share, or...?
- Yeah!
Yeah, let's take this one.
So, awesome. Thank you. Terrific.
- Where to?
- East Side Plaza for me, please.
Likewise.
- What?
- Oh. Huh? Sorry. I just...
I mean, yeah, you're... you're really pretty.
Yeah, right. Jeez,
is everybody in this city so flattering?
I figured you weren't from around here.
Where you from?
- Boston.
- Bean Town.
The musical fruit.
The more you eat, the more you... toot.
So, are you here on a shoot or something?
- A shoot?
- I mean, you must be a model, right?
My grandmother's not doing so well, so I
took a year off from school to help her out.
Oh. Helping granny. Cool.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Bye.
So, nice catchin' up.
Listen, um... I know you'll probably think
I'm some kind of wacko for asking, but, um...
What?
Well, while you're here in town,
I mean, you know...
If you ever feel like taking a break from
hangin' out with your old sick granny,
you know, we could...
- Sure. I mean...
- Really?
Are you kidding? Yeah! That'd be...
I would absolutely love to, if...
OK, yeah. I should get your number, then.
No, no. I'll get yours, because it would...
- With my luck, you'll lose mine, so...
- Oh. I get it.
Very funny. You got me.
That was... No, that was good.
You could've just said no,
but you went the extra mile. That was harsh.
- I don't need this shit.
- Uh...
What?
- I... I do want your number.
- Oh, I'm sorry!
I don't know what... That was dumb.
I was saying something...
I thought you meant... Never mind. Yes. Yes.
Here's my phone number,
and here's my email.
- Email. That's...
- Yeah. That's funny.
- (Mauricio) Hello?
- Mudwhistle, get dressed. We're goin' out.
(* "Roy's Toy" byJeffBeck)
This Robbins guy gave you free therapy
while you were in the elevator?
Yeah. And then - check this out -
he does this thing to me where he makes it
so I can score better with the ladies.
At the time I thought it was a joke.
But this afternoon, the first
beautiful woman I saw went for me.
- Could be coincidence.
- Yeah, but no. This was different.
It was like she went crazy
for me or something.
I think maybe talking to him helped my
confidence, cos I do feel more confident.
Shit. Look who's here.
What's the matter?
You have a problem with Walt?
- You don't?
- No. Why would l?
- Don't you just get sick of it sometimes?
- Sick of what?
The whole "I walk on all fours
so I own the world" thing.
Plus all that phoney self-deprecating crap.
Jeez... Give the guy a break!
He's got spina bifida!
- He's just playing the hand he was dealt.
- Yeah. Here he comes.
- There's a couple of belt buckles I recognise.
- Hey, Walt. How you doin'?
Do I look like I have
anything to complain about?
Not if you don't mind
bunions on your knuckles.
I gotta go to the can.
- Hey, man, good to see ya.
- Good to see you.
- How you been?
- Good.
There's a pair of panties I recognise.
How ya doing, Deb?
OK, wise guy, what's it gonna be?
- How about a bottle of Dom for my buddy?
- Another? OK, you got it.
- And keep 'em coming.
- What's the occasion?
- You don't read the business section?
- What did I miss?
- I sold my company to Microsoft.
- Yeah? And you cleaned up?
Well, if I had an ass, I'd wipe it with twenties.
All right! Congratulations!
I'm officially retired and on the prowl.
- Hey, Walt.
- Hey, Sally.
I got a leash. Would you like
to take me for a walk?
Come on, boy.
Catch ya later.
Hi.
- Hal.
- I'm Bella.
- So, what's up?
- Nothing.
- My friends are all out on the dance floor.
- Yeah?
- How come you're not spanking the planks?
- Spanking the planks! (snorts)
Are they your roommates, or...?
No, we work together
at the Foundation Fighting Blindness.
- Cool. I used to know a deaf guy.
- (snorts)
- Do you wanna dance?
- Yes!
All right.
(* "Too Young" byPhoenix)
* Baby, when I saw you
turning at the end of the street
* I knew a time was gone
and it took me like ages
* Just to understand that
I was afraid to be a simple guy
* I tried my best to smile
* But deep inside my heart
* I felt it was shouting like a crowd dancing
* I guess I couldn't live without the things
* That made my life what it is
* Can't you hear me calling?
* Ooh, yeah
* Everybody's dancing
* Tonight everything is over
What in the name of all that is holy...?
* I can't lie on my bed
without thinking I was wrong
* But when that feeling calls...
- Do you need help?
- What? Come on!
* Night-time won't hold me in your arms again
* I got a very good friend who says
* He can't believe the love I give
* ls not enough to end your fears
* I guess I couldn't live without the things
* That made my life what it is
Hal?
It's ten o'clock. We gotta go.
- What are you talking about?
- Hal, we gotta go... do that thing.
- You know, at the place.
- What thing?
Hey, sorry, ladies.
I gotta steal your dance partner here.
- What are you doing?!
- I am rescuing you.
- From what?
- From what?!
From a pack of stampeding buffalo,
that's from what!
Come join us. I'm goin' after the redhead.
You can have your pick of the other two.
You mean you get the hyena, and I choose
between the hippo and the giraffe?
Don't be intimidated, man. They don't bite.
Let's go! I'm gettin' back in there.
Hey... go nuts.
* Tonight everything is over
* I feel too young
Hey, Jill.
* Everybody's shaking...
Mauricio, it's Hal. Pick it up.
Look, man, I don't know what the hell
was the matter with you last night.
First you wouldn't dance with the hotties,
and then we go to the IHOP, and those hotties
are even hotter, and you disappear!
Oh, my...
I gotta call you back. Something came up.
(* "Toxic Girl" by Kings of Convenience)
* ln the sky the birds are pulling rain
* ln your life a curse has gota name
Building a parachute?
- Excuse me?
- They're a little big, aren't they?
Oh, I get it. You ripped the spinnaker
on your sailboat, right?
Sorry. It seemed so funny seeing someone
like you holding up a pair of old-lady trou.
Someone like me?
Yeah. You know, someone so fit.
You are a jackass.
Miss, please. I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to offend you.
Hey, unibrow, why don't you double
your dosage and leave me alone?
Whoa, whoa. Let's start over.
Look, that was really dumb of me.
You were probably buying 'em for
someone close to you, and I insulted them.
However you took it, I want you to know
I didn't mean to piss you off.
I wanted to meet you, and I guess...
I guess I'm not real smooth sometimes.
Let me make it up to you.
Excuse me, Miss. Is everything all right?
So, um... what do you do
for a living, Rosemary?
I'm actually volunteering
at the hospital right now,
cos I'm waiting for this...
re-up thing to come through.
Re-up? What, are you in the army?
- Peace Corps.
- Peace Corps. Wow.
That's very... altrudocious of you.
"Altrudocious"? That's not a word.
Oh! You mean humanidocious, right?
(chuckles)
- Yeah. That's the one.
- All right. Ready to order?
Yeah. Um...
Can I get a double pizza burger, chilli fries
with cheese and a large chocolate milkshake?
Nicely done. I'll have the exact same thing.
You got it.
I am impressed.
It's nice to see a girl order a real meal.
I hate it when you guys order
a glass of water and a crouton.
It ruins the whole point of goin' out.
That's probably what I should be ordering.
But, I don't know, no matter what I eat,
my weight just seems to stay the same.
So I figure, what the hell?
I'm gonna eat what I want.
Totally. If you can get away with it,
more power to ya.
- Don't be a smart ass.
- What are you...? What?
No, I'm just saying, you know.
I feel bad for people who count calories.
It's no way to live.
Yeah. But in return they get to be
a lot thinner than I am.
Are you out of your mind?
What do you weigh? 110, 115 pounds?
Which one of my butt cheeks
are you talking about?
OK.
Cuckoo! Cuckoo!
Trust me, whatever you're doin',
it's working. It is working.
Go on.
Oh, my God! Are you OK?
Oops.
- Goddang it.
- Don't move. Is your back all right?
- Yeah.
- Is she all right?
Yeah. You gotta get
some decent chairs in here, man.
What's this shit made out of, anyway?
Steel.
Yeah? Well, you should...
get it welded better in the corners!
- All right.
- Rosemary, you sure you're OK?
Yeah. I'm a little embarrassed but...
it's happened before, it'll happen again.
Oh, man. I...
Don't be embarrassed.
Listen, I beef it. Everybody beefs it.
Looks like we're too late.
The food's probably all gone.
- Listen, can you wait here one second?
- Hal, just let it go.
Nah. Nah.
Hal.
(mock laughter)
You guys are so funny, making fun of me
cos I'm a little pudgy, right?
- No, I wasn't making fun of you. I was...
- Do me a favour. Take a look out the window.
You see that little fox out there?
You see that little number? She's with me.
If you took all the women you two have ever
gone out with, they wouldn't equal one of her.
- We're not arguing that.
- No.
That's right. Laugh it up, fellas.
And tonight, when you're hugging
your pillow, remember, I'm with her.
All right? That's it.
What happened?
Well, let's just say the score's
Hal two, mall rats zero.
Let me walk you to your car.
- Well, thanks for lunch, Hal.
- My pleasure, Rosie.
- My mother calls me Rosie.
- Really?
Yeah.
Gentlemen, can I interest you
in some chilli fries and half a burger?
There's a lot left cos the little guy
couldn't finish his meal.
- Hey, hey.
- Pussy.
- That was nice of you.
- Well, you're all right in my book, too, Hal.
- Can I have your number?
- What number?
Your PIN number. I want your money(!)
Your phone number. What do you think?
Why?
You know, to... go out. Maybe, like, tomorrow.
Uh...
Well, yeah.
I mean, sure. It's in the book
under Rosemary Shanahan.
- I can write it down. It's S-h-a...
- No, I'll remember it.
- My boss's name is Steve Shanahan.
- That's my father's name.
Not JPS Steve Shanahan?
Yeah. Yeah.
Your father is my boss. I mean,
not my boss, but he's my boss's boss.
I mean, I don't know him,
but I see him around the office.
Well, then you won't forget my name.
- Hal?
- Yeah?
If I don't hear from you...
I appreciate everything anyway.
Cuckoo!
You sure you don't want a dog?
Yeah, yeah. I'm tryin' to lose a couple of LBs.
- Since when do you care about your gut?
- I don't really, but...
I am a little nervous because of
this girl who's coming to meet me.
- She's incredible.
- Uh-huh?
Like the ones on the dance floor?
Even better, buddy. I'm telling ya,
it's almost beyond belief.
She's funny, she's smart,
she teaches self-esteem to sick kids...
I would never believe a girl as beautiful
could have such a great personality.
- Ugly-duckling syndrome.
- What?
She probably wasn't pretty till high school.
The personality developed out of necessity.
You know what? I bet you're right.
She's way too pretty to be so nice.
Sometimes they're ugly so long,
when they turn pretty, they don't realise it.
The ugly self-image is so well ingrained.
That's a real find.
- Hey!
I've been looking for you.
Oh, shit. Oh, it's Lindy. The girl with the toe.
- Hey.
- How ya doing?
Good. Did you get my message?
No, no. My phone machine's
not really working there. Did you call?
- I got tickets for that Beatles reunion.
- The Beatles?
Yeah. Well, not the real Beatles,
but Paul, George and Ringo will be there.
But Eric Clapton is filling in for John.
It's an invitation-only acoustic set.
- Only about 70 people, tops.
- Oh, man.
- So you're in?
- Uh...
No. Not a Clapton fan.
I think I'll pass.
OK. Well, I guess I'll see ya.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Bye, Lindy.
- Did you see the toe?
- Mauricio, I gotta tell you, you got issues.
- Don't even get me started.
- Oh, my God. There she is.
There's Rosemary.
- Where?
- Right there.
- Right where?
- Straight ahead. Across the field.
- Is she behind the rhino?
- She's right there!
Mauricio, I want you to meet someone.
This is Rosemary Shanahan.
Rosemary, Mauricio Wilson.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Holy cow. I mean, uh... hi.
- Is that a Members Only jacket?
- Yes. Yes, it is.
So, what are you, like, the last member?
Oh, man.
- One-nothing Rosemary.
- (mobile phone)
Excuse me for just one second. Hello?
Oh, hi, Mom. Yeah, hold on.
- Will you guys excuse me?
- Want something from the snack bar?
Yeah, get me a beer
and nachos with all the stuff on it.
You got it.
- Does she take the cake or what?
- She takes the whole bakery, Hal.
- I told you.
- Yes, you did. And yet I wasn't prepared.
- So, what are you up for?
- I don't know. I like the track.
Ah, so she's a gambler.
Yeah, well, just the dogs.
I hate the ponies. There's too much
human involvement, you know?
You can't trust people
lf you're looking for a fair deal.
- What about you? Do you gamble?
- No, not really.
I bet on pro football now and then,
But just to make the games more exciting.
- I don't really care if I win.
- Huh.
- I've never read that book.
- What book?
Things Losers Say.
(Rosemary chuckles)
Hey, why don't we forget the track, and I'll
introduce you to some good friends of mine?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- All right.
- What do you say?
- I say OK.
- You say OK?
Hi, guys. I want you to meet
a very good friend of mine. OK?
This guy here is Hal. And he's really funny.
Hi.
How ya doing? Good to meet ya.
Hey. Wow. Oh, my God. Look at that face.
She should be doing Keebler commercials.
You're the cutest thing I've ever seen.
- What's your name, beautiful?
- Cadence.
Cadence. That's a pretty name.
You know, my uncle's name is Cadence.
Well, I got news for you, Cadence.
I'm not putting you down
until the cows come home.
Put her down.
The cow came home.
What is he doing here?
These aren't visiting hours.
Oh, Nurse Peeler, we were just
coming by to say hi to the kids.
Fine. Pack it up.
And get these patients back in their beds.
(pager beeps)
- Should we get going?
- Don't pay any attention to Nurse Sourpuss.
Sourpuss.
Hey! I got an idea. Do you guys
wanna play the kissing game?
- Yeah?
- You want me to go get a bottle?
This is how we play. Wanna get the lipstick?
- Get lipstick.
- Yeah, OK.
What we do is, we put on the lipstick...
and then the kisser kisses as many times
as they can until the lipstick comes off.
Cool! I wanna go first.
- Then I'm going last.
- Jesse.
- Hey, they don't have anything I can catch?
- They don't have anything you can catch.
I didn't think so.
You guys don't even look sick.
You're just a bunch of phoneys
like my Uncle Cadence.
I bet you're here just so you can
get out of school. Is that right?
- Yeah.
- Give me some of that lipstick.
You were incredible in there.
You were. You were so amazing.
I'm serious. A lot of people get
really squeamish in that situation...
- Rosemary? ls that you?
- Dr Sayed! How's it going?
- Good. Who's this?
- This is my friend Hal.
- Good to meet you.
- Be nice to her. She's a good girl.
- All right.
- Bye, Rosemary.
That's what these kids need -
a stranger who isn't afraid to just
be with them and play with them.
- That's what builds their self-confidence.
- Why would anybody be afraid of 'em?
You are off-the-charts adorable.
Do you know that?
Come on.
- This is a nice street you live on.
- Yeah, this is my street.
- You wanna come up?
- Yeah. But I don't think I should.
Why not? It's only 9 o'clock.
- I know. I just don't think it's a good idea.
- Oh, no. Did I do something?
No. You've been really cool.
- Hi, Hal.
- Oh, hey, Jill.
- Rosemary, this is my neighbour Jill.
- Hi. Nice...
- Sorry.
- Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too, Jill.
I gotta go and meet some friends,
so I'll see you guys later.
- Bye.
Come up.
- No.
- What?
I thought we were having a good time.
We were. It's just, you know,
Hal, I'm not used to all this.
Used to what?
Hal, you've been really nice to me today.
I really appreciate it, but...
What, your other boyfriends
aren't nice to you?
- I don't have other boyfriends.
- Bullshit.
Well, I had one boyfriend.
It was kind of recently,
actually, but it didn't work out.
- You've been burnt, huh?
- No.
That's just it. I, um... I've never been
close enough to anybody to get burnt.
Please! With a mug like that?
You must be fighting 'em off daily.
Right(!) I mean, I saw the way
your friend Mauricio looked at me.
I thought he was gonna shoot me
with a tranquilliser gun and tag my ear.
Don't worry. He's been acting really weird
lately, especially around really pretty girls.
Hal... do me a favour and stop saying
that I'm pretty and that I'm not fat, OK?
Cos it makes me uncomfortable.
OK. You have a problem with compliments?
Look... I know what I am
and I know what I'm not.
I'm the girl who gets really good grades
and is not afraid to be funny.
And I'm the girl who has a lot of friends
who are boys, and no boyfriends.
I'm not beautiful, OK? And I never will be.
And I'm fine with that. You know?
But when you go around saying
that I'm something that I'm not,
it's just... it's not nice.
Whoa, Rosemary.
You're starting to scare me.
I mean, I really like you,
but I have to assume you're a little nutty
if you really believe you're not beautiful.
Grow up, Hal.
Rosie. Wait a second.
Well, it was too good to be true.
Hm?
Rosemary. Turned out to be a total psycho.
Her self-image is so far off, it's scary.
Well, maybe you had a little
something to do with that.
What are you talking about? All I ever did
was tell her how perfect she was.
Really?
Yeah. Then she got all huffy
and told me to grow up.
Well, that's probably good advice.
You are kind of immature.
You're not serious. You actually
think you're more mature than me?
You're right. I'm probably more immature
than you, but at least I have a bigger willie.
Yeah, bigger than a mouse's.
- What the hell was that?
- I said your willie's...
I heard what you said,
but it took you, like, eight seconds.
You can't come back with a comeback after
eight seconds. You got three. Five, tops.
That's why they call it a quip. Not a "slowp".
All right, you got anything better to read?
I gotta fire off a missile.
(knock at door)
Hi.
- Is this a bad time, or...?
- No.
I just wanted to apologise for last night.
- You don't have to apologise.
- Yeah, I do.
I called you, like, immature or sophomoric
or something like that. I know you're not...
(Mauricio) Oh, my God, Hal!
You gotta get in here and look at this turd!
It looks just like Klinger from M*A*S*H.
- Why don't we get outta here?
- OK.
Coffee?
(* "Baby, Now That I've Found You"
by The Foundations)
Excuse me. Are you ready to order?
Yes. Two double cheeseburgers with bacon,
one with relish. Thank you.
(slurping)
Ow.
- Are you OK?
- Brain freeze.
* Baby, now that I've found you
I can't let you go
* I'll build my world around you
* I need you so, baby, even though...
Excuse me, sweetie. Professional.
Hey, Billy, stay over near the ladder.
Weak. So weak.
You wanna see a splash?
I'm gonna show you a splash. Ready?
* Spent a lifetime looking for somebody
* To give me love like you
* Baby, now that I've found you
I can't let you go...
- That was good?
- Bialy?
Bialy? Bialy? Billy!
Daddy!
Sorry.
- What's the matter?
- I should have changed at the beach.
What? Are you crazy? You look great.
I don't normally dress like this
around my parents.
Hey, hey, come on. I'm the one
who should be nervous here, not you.
Hey, you know, I've been meaning to ask you.
Were you adopted?
No. Why?
Cos your dad has that weird accent.
And I've seen him around the office. I gotta
say, I don't see the slightest resemblance.
Really? Everybody says lf you put
a wig on him, he'd look just like me.
(lrish accent) Look at who's here now.
Come here, my darlin'.
Hi, Daddy.
- Rosie, honey.
- Mom.
Good to see ya.
This is Hal Larson,
the guy I was telling you about.
- Great to meet you, sir.
- Likewise.
- Nice to meet you, Hal.
- The pleasure is mine, Mrs Shanahan.
Wow. I can see where
Rosemary gets her figure.
What the hell... What the hell
is that you've got on?
We were at the beach.
Won't you be putting
something else on, darlin'?
Oh, come on. She doesn't have to
do that for me. Let's just keep it casual.
Casual.
Hey, Dad, Hal's one of your great
untapped resources down at the company.
- Why don't you tell him some of your ideas?
- Oh, so you've got a few ideas, do ya?
It is risky, but the rewards are greater, too.
Only a company with a solid reputation
like JPS could ever market this product.
- Hal, let me take your plate.
- Thank you. It was delicious.
- Can I get you boys some coffee?
- I'd love a cup of tea, darlin'.
Maybe just a drop of the hard stuff.
Yeah, I'll just have a cup of joe.
That'd be great. Thanks.
I have to say, Hal,
I'm impressed with a lot of your ideas.
Some of them are dog shit, but for the most
part you seem to have done your homework.
- So I'd like you to do something for me.
- OK.
I'm meeting with me executive committee
Monday morning,
and I'd like you to make a presentation.
- Seriously?
- Well, nothing fancy, you understand.
Just talk about the same things
that you talked about here tonight.
Great. I'd love to.
Oh, and by the way,
you can cut out the act now.
Excuse me?
You think I got as far as I did
in me life by bein' a fool?
Now, you've got ambition,
Hal, and I admire that.
Hell, I wish I had a hundred
more like yourself.
We'd be the number one firm in the country.
And me daughter would get
a hell of a lot more dates.
I'm sure Rosemary doesn't have
any problem getting dates.
I told you to cut the shit out, all right?
Look, Rosemary's me daughter,
and God knows I love her dearly.
But I think we both know that we won't
soon be seeing her twirlin' the baton,
marching along with the Dallas cheerleaders.
Uh...
I don't understand.
I'm telling the truth, Hal.
And the truth is I haven't been able to bounce
me daughter on me knee since she was two.
You know, I've read about people like you.
- People like me?
- Super achievers with impossible standards.
Nothing's ever good enough.
Nothing ever measures up.
It never occurs to you that your kids
are people, with their own feelings.
You think they're an extension of you,
like your company,
or your $20-million Learjet
and your Picasso out in the front hall.
Everything reflects on you, so nothing
and no one is ever good enough.
Go on.
When I first met Rosemary, she told me
she knew she wasn't that good-looking.
I could not believe my ears.
I thought how can a person this beautiful
possibly interpret what she sees in the mirror
to be anything other than that?
Well, now I know.
Is everything OK?
Yeah, everything is fine. Just fine.
What?
Nothin'.
I just can't believe how lucky I am.
(* "This ls My World" by Darius Rucker)
You swear to God you're not gonna laugh?
Come on, I'm not gonna laugh.
(whimpers)
Oh.
Daddy like.
* The look on your face
* It could never explain your heart
* And the touch of my lips
* It could never tell you my thoughts
* And you want me to change
* I can't get used to...
What in the...? How did...?
Get over here, Houdini.
* Cos it's not really me
* This is my world, this is who I am