[ Disco ]
[ Crowd Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
- [ Man ]
Richard, say, kudos.
- Oh, thank you.
Wow, that was--
y ou found some essential truth
in that staging.
- y eah?
- absolutely.
Clearly it's about Vietnam.
He suffers from
suburban existential--
[ Richard ]
lt's about whatever
you want it to be about.
- [ Woman ]
Richard, we loved the play.
- Thank you.
- y ou could understand it?
- Perfeectly well.
[ Richard ]
l'll talk to you later.
[ Chattering Continues ]
y ou aced it.
This is, uh-- I'm sorry.
I don't know your name.
Pam. Pam.
Pam? This is Shelley,
my girlfriend.
Hi, Shelley. Hi.
Hi. How are you?
I'm Richard,
and I'm thirsty.
So we'll talk to you later.
Bye-bye.
Oh, boy, look at--
Hi, Dan. How are you?
Kudos. That was
a fine, fine play, really.
Absolutely.
I'm afraid I don't know--
Mike Neeley,
Chicago alternative.
[ Richard ]
Hey, Shelley, l gotta go talk
to this guy, okay ?
What is happening?
This is for you,
from all of us.
Hey, Shelley !
Oh, thank you.
Shelley, look at this.
Wait a minute.
Did everybody sign this?
- [ Woman ]
y eah, everybody signed.
- Oh, fabulous. Thank you.
- [ Richard ]
Where'd you sign this?
- lnside.
[ Richard ]
Good, l got some news.
There was an agent
in the house tonight,
and he says he thinks
this play might be
good enough for Broadway.
[ Cheering ]
Yeah, I know.
Let's keep our fingers crossed.
Let's all have some cake.
[ Richard ]
Penelope, great !
Okay. Now, l think this thing
that we ought to do here is--
Here you go.
Let me trade you that.
I think
we shouldn't cut the mask.
We save those for later.
[ Chattering Stops ]
[ Whispers ]
Come back to me.
[ Shelley ]
Who was she?
I never saw her in my life.
What'd she give you?
[ Gasping ]
Oh, my God.
[ Man ]
ls this a party or what?
Let's have some cake.
How was the play?
Did you enjoy it?
Are you all right?
[ Classical ]
[ Skipped item nr. 45 ]
[ Skipped item nr. 46 ]
[ Stops ]
[ Elevator Humming ]
Aha !
Aha, what?
Aha, where ya goin' ?
I'm going on a trip.
Where?
I have no idea.
What about the play?
Well,
it isn't done.
Okay.
When will it be done?
I don't know.
Oh, my God.
Richard, there are people
waiting for that play.
Shell going with you?
No, I don't think so.
We broke up.
[ Jazz ]
[ Radio announcer ]
The White Sox are
at home tonight...
for a Comiskey Park game
against the y ankees.
The Cubs are just beginning
a West Coast swing--
How long will you be
with us?
Just tonight.
Fine. If you'll sign
in here, sir.
Sure.
[ Clears Throat ]
Arthur, 313, please.
Have a pleasant stay.
Thank you.
Okay, thanks a lot.
Uh, this your first time
here, Mister, uh--
Collier. Yeah.
For some reason, I never
got around to coming here.
I always heard
how nice it was though.
Oh, when was that?
Oh, about eight years ago.
See, I used to be a student
up at Millfield College.
Yeah. The students
come here now and then
to enjoy the restaurant...
and the rooms.
[ Chuckles ]
It seems to me,
I remember they had
a graduation prom here...
back in, uh, '47,
was it?
Oh, really?
You been here that long?
Why, I've been here
since 19 10.
19 10?
Uh-huh.
Came here with my parents
when I was five years old.
My father was a desk clerk.
I used to drive him crazy
playing ball in the lobby.
He got so mad at me sometimes,
I'm lucky I lived to be six.
Three, George.
Got yourself
a nice view here.
Let me see.
Oh, great.
Okay, let's see now.
Here you go.
Thank you, Mr. Collier.
If there's anything
I can do for you,
just let me know.
My name's Arthur,
and I live in the bungalow
behind the hotel.
Okay. Thanks a lot.
See ya around, Arthur.
Have we ever met before?
Have we ever me--
No, no, I don't think so.
No. No, I'm sure we haven't.
Have a nice stay, Mr. Collier.
Okay, thanks a lot.
Sir ?
Uh, yeah.
When do you open?
In about 40 minutes, sir.
Forty minutes?
Yes, sir.
Arthur ! Hi.
y es, Mr. Collier.
Arthur, you know,
in the Hall of History,
there's a photograph,
a young woman.
There's no nameplate.
Yes, that's Elise McKenna.
She was a famous actress
in her day.
Starred in a play
in the hotel theater.
I-I'm sorry. D-Did you say
there was a theater here?
Down by the lake.
Really?
When was this play done?
Oh, uh, 19 12.
19 12?
Hey, Arthur !
Arthur, hi, listen.
Could you take my luggage
and put it back in my suite?
Great. Thanks a lot.
And can you tell me
where the nearest library is?
In town, right past the church.
Great. Look out.
Thanks. Terrific !
Thanks a lot.
See you around, Arthur.
Yeah.
Yes.
[ Whispers ]
Oh, my God.
[ Richard ] "One of
the most revered actresses
on the american stage,
for many years, she was
the theater's greatest
box office draw. "
"Under the guidance
of her manager,
William Fawcett Robinson,
Elise McKenna was the first
american actress to create
a mystique in the public's eye. "
"Never seen in public
in her later years,
"apparently without
an offstage life,
the absolute quintessence
of seclusion. "
Excuse me, do you have
any theater biographies...
that aren't in the racks
under the rare books
or magazines?
Well, we do have
some magazines,
but they're in the back,
and I'd have to find them.
And--
Oh, could you do that
for me, please?
Well, all right.
Thanks.
I'm in the back.
Okay.
Great !
Here you are.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Yes?
Uh, hello, yes,
M-Miss Roberts?
Yes.
Hi, uh, my name's
Richard Collier,
and I just read your book
on famous American actresses,
and I really enjoyed it a lot.
What is it you want?
Information
about Elise McKenna.
What sort
of information?
Well, I'm a playwright,
and I was thinking about
doing a play based on her life.
And, of course,
I'd have to talk--
I'm sorry.
Ma'am, please.
Please, don't.
This is not for a play,
Miss Roberts.
This is something
very personal.
I don't understand.
Where did you get that?
She gave it to me, ma'am,
at the opening night
of a play that I wrote...
at Millfield College
about eight years ago.
That watch was
very precious to her.
She never, never left it
out of her possession.
It disappeared
the night she died.
She died that night?
Won't you come in,
please?
Thank you.
I have some things
I've been saving
for the theater collection.
That was a costume
from one of the plays
she was in.
Miss Roberts,
what was she like?
When I knew her,
she was kind and thoughtful,
but she was just
too much within herself.
She, she seemed
empty somehow.
Well, she wasn't always
that way, was she?
Oh, no, not at all.
People who knew her
when she was young said...
that she was quick and bright
and full of fun,
strong, willful,
not at all the way
she was later.
What made her change?
l don't know,
but the change seems to have
taken place about 19 12,
after she perfeormed
in a play
at the Grand Hotel.
That was her manager,
William Robinson.
Was he really as strange
as you seemed to indicate
in the book?
There was something strange
about their relationship.
Oh, wow, look at this.
Hey. May I ?
This is incredible.
Of course.
This guy, Finney,
he was my philosophy teacher
at Millfield.
Really ?
Yeah.
She read that book
over and over.
She had that made.
[ Classical ]
What is it?
That's my favorite music
in the whole world.
I don't understand
what's happening.
Doctor Finney?
You'll have to walk
with me, young man.
I have another class.
What's your name?
Collier, sir. Richard Collier.
Student?
Uh, yes I was,
nine years ago.
Well, I try to make
my classes interesting,
but nine years?
What can I do for you?
I have a question
for you, sir.
Shoot.
Is time travel possible?
That is a question.
Let me tell you something,
Richard, is it?
Yes, sir.
I was in Venice
in 1971 .
I was staying in
a very old hotel.
But I mean, very old:
the structure,
the furnishings,
everything.
The atmosphere was aged,
if you follow me,
and my room, I felt
as though it was...
a century or more
earlier than 1971 .
You understand?
Yes, sir.
So, in other words, then,
the location is very important.
Not all important,
but essential.
Mm-hmm.
The rest is here.
One afternoon, I--
I was lying down
in that room,
all the sights around me...
a part of the past,
even the sounds
l heard,
and l conceived a notion.
What, l asked myself,
if l attempt
to hypnotize my mind?
Suggest to it
that it isn't 1971,
but 1571.
l closed my eyes...
and fed a suggestion
into my brain.
It's August, 1571 .
I am in
the Hotel Del Vecchio.
I spelled out the details
for myself...
and did it
over and over...
and again and again
and again--
and?
Well, I'll never
really know, Richard.
l've never done it since.
And I'm not sure
I'd want to do it again.
I felt exhausted afterwards,
completely washed out.
And if it really
did happen,
I was only there a fraction
of an instant, remember.
- A flicker.
- Yes, sir, I understand that,
but you were there.
I thought so.
Oh, it wasn't perfeect, granted.
How would it be otherwise?
There were objects around me
that were clearly
from the present,
and l knew they were there.
Oh, if l were going to
try it again--
Mind you,
I have no such intention.
But if I did,
l would disassociate myself
entirely from the present.
Move everything out of sight
that could possibly
remind me of it.
Then, who knows?
Whoops.
Sorry. Hey.
Hi.
Hi, how do you do?
Listen, do you have 19 12 money?
I mean, very specifically, 19 12.
[ Scissors Clipping ]
Aha. That's it.
All right--
[ Murmuring ]
Yeah, not too bad.
Yup, yup, yup, yup.
It's looking all right.
[ Clears Throat ]
Ah, good evening, Miss McKenna.
You don't know me, but you will.
Evening, Miss McKenna.
You don't know me,
but you will.
Okay.
It is June 27, 19 12.
Oh, boy.
You are lying on your bed
in the Grand Hotel,
and it is 6:00 p.m.
in the evening
of June 27, 19 12.
Your mind
accepts this absolutely.
lt is 6.:00 p.m.
on June 27, 1912.
Elise McKenna is in this hotel
at this very moment.
Her manager,
William Fawcett Robinson,
is in this hotel
at this very moment.
Now, this moment, here,
Elise McKenna and you...
[ Whispering ]
God, how stupid.
That's not very bright.
both in the Grand Hotel
on this early evening,
on June 27, 19 12,
6:00 p.m.,
on June 27, 19 12.
Elise McKenna and you.
Good-bye.
Elise McKenna, now,
in this hotel.
She and her company,
who are in this hotel
at this very moment,
even as you lie here
on your bed in the Grand Hotel
on June 27, 1912,
6:00 p.m., June 27, 19 12.
[ Murmuring ]
The stage is being set...
for their perfeormance
tomorrow night.
[ Murmuring ]
y our mind accepts this
absolutely.
It is 6:00 p.m.
on June 27, 19 12.
y ou have traveled
back in time.
Soon you will open
your eyes,
and you will walk
into the corridor,
and you will go downstairs
and find Elise McKenna.
She is in the hotel
at this very moment.
[ Yells ]
Damn it !
There's no question
in your mind.
Now, now, now, now.
lt is 6.:00 p.m.
on June 27, 1912.
That which you think
becomes your world.
y our mind accepts this
absolutely.
lt is June 27, 1912.
It has to happen !
[ Murmuring ]
y ou know that now !
y ou know it.
It has to happen.
There is no question.
You know it.
It has to happen.
Relax. accept.
Relax and accept.
[ Screams ]
Shut up !
[ Man ]
Yeah, not bad.
Great.
Hey, look at
these pictures.
Oh.
I'll bet they're
a hundred years old,
if they're a day, huh?
[ Woman ]
Oh, look at this furniture.
lsn't that nice?
[ Man ]
What a place, huh?
Mm-hmm.
y eah? y ou like those?
Oh, it's beautiful.
They're yours.
l'll bet
this is all crystal.
[ Man ]
y ou suppose it is?
y eah, it must be.
Look at the rest of the place.
lt has to be.
Look at here,
the original picture, huh?
y eah, but look how much
they've been--
lt's beautiful.
[ Yells ]
Arthur !
Arthur ? Arthur ?
Arthur ?
Arthur !
Come on. Wake up.
Arthur, I'm really sorry
to wake you up,
but you're the only one
who can help me.
You know those things
in the Hall of History
display cases.
Where do they
come from?
I-Is there a storeroom
or something?
Arthur, please.
Where do those things
come from?
The, uh, attic,
Mr. Collier.
[ Richard ]
Whew.
Oh, shit.
Come on.
Here we go.
Twelve !
[ Murmuring ]
McKenna.
[ Whispers ]
Yes.
I was there.
It is 6:00 p.m.,
June 27, 19 12.
There is no question
in your mind.
Wait a minute.
It is 6:00 p.m.--
Of course.
[ Whispers ]
Room 4 16, room 4 16,
9: 19, tomorrow morning,
9: 19, 9: 19,
tomorrow morning.
[ Murmuring ]
Believe.
[ Whispers ]
19 12, 19 12, 19 12,
19 12, 19 12.
[ Hoofbeats ]
[ Horse Whinnying ]
[ Hoofbeats Continue ]
[ Groans ]
[ Whispers ]
I made it.
Oh, brother.
[ Laughs ]
l made it.
I made it.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Woman Humming
"y ou Made Me Love y ou"]
[ Humming Continues ]
Maude !
[ Humming Stops ]
I'm back.
Are you ready yet?
No.
I don't know why you act
in such a manner.
Indeed, I suspect
you do not.
And what am I to make
of that remark?
What you will, Rollo.
What you will.
Are we to have
this maddening exchange...
each and every time
I notice the existence of
a female other than yourself?
Notice her existence?
Oh, that scarcely describes
your rapt appraisal
of her every inch.
""Rapt appraisal of her--""
You just don't
love me anymore.
Oh, Maude.
Oh, Christ.
- l want to lie down a while.
- That's a good idea.
- Great idea.
I warn you, I've had enough
of this constant bickering.
That's what you
always say to everything.:
"l will not discuss it. "
That's your answer
to everything.
Unless you come
to your senses,
I shall leave
without you.
Excuse me,
did you see someone
just trying to get in here?
Yes, some young chap,
ran that way.
I'll be damned.
I'd better report that.
Indeed,
you'd better, sir.
I'd have reported it myself
if I'd known that there was--
Good afternoon, Miss McKenna.
You don't know me.
[ Murmuring ]
Good afternoon,
Miss McKenna.
Good afternoon, Miss McKenna.
I've just come 69 years.
May I please speak to you?
Yes?
Yes, monsieur ?
Uh, is Miss McKenna here?
No, I'm afraid, she's not.
Could you tell me
where she is?
I'm sorry.
I have no idea, monsieur.
Strike one.
[ Chattering ]
Oh, I beg your pardon.
Getting out?
Not inside, arthur.
Are you Arthur ?
Yes, sir.
Here you go.
arthur,
not inside.
[ actors Shouting Lines,
lndistinct ]
[ Piano ]
Oh, I'm sorry.
[ Man ]
l say, l shall have her !
[ Woman ]
Not in my life,
you shall not !
[ actors Continue,
lndistinct ]
[ Man ]
Whatever you desire,
l guarantee you...
satisfaction !
[ Woman Shouting Lines ]
Be out of here
within two hours
after the show's over ?
That's impossible.
The man's insane.
That's what he wants.
You know Robinson.
I wish to God
I didn't.
If he's that anxious to get us
out of here, let him help us
tear down the set.
[ Yelling ]
What?
Sorry.
Uh, have you seen
Miss McKenna?
You have a message for her ?
Give it to me,
and I'll see it reaches her.
As for our precious
Mr. Robinson--
[ Actors Continue,
Indistinct ]
Madam, I do not
so regard her.
Yes, you do.
and you shall not
marry her.
And I say, I shall have her.
Not in my life,
you shall not.
Give in, Cecily.
It's not your place to say.
Desist !
Good people,
this is a comedy,
not King Lear.
Let's not bury
the playwright
before his time.
Excuse me !
I'm terribly sorry
to bother you.
I wonder if you know
where Miss McKenna might be.
Very well, very well.
Let us take it again.
From the beginning.
"a yearly stipend, shall we say,
paid for by the month. "
""Whatever you desire.""
Hello.
- Take it again, Madeline.
- "Why not put her on the scale
and sell her by the pound. "
May I speak to you, please,
Miss McKenna? May I--
May I please speak to--
Miss McKenna, uh, no, no.
Elise, may I--
Whoo, boy.
Miss McKenna.
Good afternoon, Miss McKenna.
[ Grunts ]
Uh, I'm, uh--
Flustered, my sweet?
Qu'est-ce que c'est?
Never seen an actress
en dishabille before?
Uh, I'm, I'm looking
for Miss McKenna, please.
Most likely walking
by the lake, my dear.
Thank you.
Oh ! Sorry.
Excuse me.
Watch it, sonny.
Is it you?
Is it?
Yes.
Are you all right?
Yes, yes,
quite all right.
I'm sorry
if I startled you.
You didn't.
I think I did.
l'll take you in
to dinner now.
May I speak
to you, please?
Anything the matter ?
Who was that young man?
I've no idea.
He gave no name?
There was hardly time.
You were conversing,
McKenna.
No.
Well, not really.
No, no need to look back.
He's following us.
Uh, keep on walking.
I'll be right along.
Are you a guest here, sir ?
You're Robinson.
Are you a guest
of the hotel ?
Uh, yes.
Yes, I am.
Then I must ask you
to stop annoying Miss McKenna
any further.
If you do not,
I shall see
that you're put out.
What did you say to him?
Oh, what I've always said
to men of his sort.
That gown of yours
in act two,
I'm not crazy about it,
you know.
It'll have to be redone.
I shall discuss it
with Marie later.
[ Man #1 ]
Good evening. Reservations
for four under Woods.
[ Man # 2 ] Woods. y es.
Monsieur, what time
was the reservation for ?
Monsieur,
may I help you, please?
I'm dining with Miss McKenna.
Uh, good evening.
How are you, sir ?
[ Maude ]
l told you, we should have gone
to "Poughpeepskie. "
Poughkeepsie.
""Poughpeepskie.""
And I just won't
discuss it any further.
It isn't the lines at all.
If only these actors would--
Isn't he the nincompoop
who thought he could do
Hamlet last season?
Oh, mon cheri,
we meet again.
Yes, hello.
I so admire a man not hidebound
by the dictates of fashion.
Ma'am?
That suit.
I haven't seen one
like it for a decade.
A decade?
Yes.
Oh, still looking
for Miss McKenna?
Yes, in fact--
Over there.
[ Orchestra Playing
"Oh ! y ou Beautiful Doll"]
- Thank you.
- a bien tot.
What do you think
you're doing?
Dancing with you.
But we don't
even know each other.
I know everything
about you.
Yes, I'm sure you do.
What do you mean?
If you will excuse me--
N-N-N-No,
you don't understand.
I think I do.
No, no, please,
don't leave.
You have no idea
how far I've come
to be with you.
There's no need
to be afraid of me,
you know.
The man's an intruder.
Will you kindly see to it
that he is escorted
from the premises?
If you will, sir.
One moment.
I shall go with him.
McKenna.
Are you sure
you want to do this?
Don't worry, William.
I shall return momentarily.
Thank you so much.
I was so embarrassed--
Your name, please?
Uh, Richard Collier.
Your place
of residence?
Chicago.
Your occupation?
I'm a playwright.
A playwright.
[ Stuttering ] Yes,
but I'm not here because--
And you say that you know
everything about me.
Well, yes--
Which is patently absurd.
You couldn't possibly know
everything about me.
We've never met.
You're a complete
stranger to me.
But, then, why did you say,
""Is it you"" ?
I don't
have to answer that.
I know you don't.
I wish you would, though.
What is the matter
with him?
He's just looking out for me
as he has always done.
Why?
Do I look dangerous?
Wait, wait.
When can I see you
again?
I don't know.
[ Orchestra
Continues ]
Guardez la ligne, Marie.
And have it ready
by tomorrow morning.
I'll do my best.
[ Knocking ]
Smiling, McKenna?
Seems appropriate.
Rather handsome young man,
if ill-mannered.
I'll keep
an eye on him.
I'm sure you will.
Is he the one, William?
Is he?
Only you can tell
for certain.
Now, tomorrow night's
performance.
Remember,
stay ahead of them.
Keep the mystery,
always the mystery.
[ Together ]
""Excess within control.""
Sleep well,
McKenna.
[ Door Shuts ]
[ Grunts ]
All right.
[ Yawning ]
[ Clears Throat ]
[ Knocking ]
[ McKenna Whispering ]
Who is it?
Richard Collier.
Good morning.
Um, you sleep all right?
Wonderfully.
Oh, l'm sorry.
I didn't sleep too well either.
Uh, but I was on a porch chair.
So, you know--
Don't you
even have a room?
Uh, yes, I will at 9: 19.
Room 4 16.
I mean, w-would you like
to go to breakfast?
At 6:00 a.m.?
Oh. Well, later ?
I don't eat breakfast
on performance days.
Oh, no. Of course not.
Um, lunch?
Mr. Collier !
No, no, no.
It's not Mr. Collier.
Isn't that your name?
Yes, that's
my name, but--
Shh ! Shh !
What?
Marie. She's sleeping
in the other room.
Marie?
My maid.
Ooh. I'm sorry.
[ Whispering ]
Well, of course my name
is Mr. Collier.
But I was hoping
you'd call me
by my first name, Richard.
Why should I ?
I don't know.
Just hoped you would.
[ Laughs ]
When can I
see you today?
I shall be rehearsing
all day.
All day !
That's crazy !
You can't--
Shh ! Don't wake her up.
Will you walk with me?
Can you do that much?
I can't.
[ Sighs ]
Young woman, if you do not walk
with me, I shall go mad,
positively insane, and do
crazed things to myself.
Shh ! Shh !
[ Sighs ]
Walk with me. Please.
Say, ""Richard--"" That's me.
""Thank you.
""I would love to walk
with you, talk with you,
get to know you...
not be afraid of you
and resolve everything.""
Say ""Yes.""
Yes.
One o'clock.
Mm-hmm.
Outside the hotel.
She's crazy about me.
[ People Chattering,
Laughing ]
Can I persuade you
to join me?
Where are you from,
Collier ?
Chicago. Where
are you from, sir ?
I'm given to understand
that you're a playwright.
You understand correctly.
No doubt you dream of
seeing Miss McKenna...
in one of your opera.
That's plural for opus.
I presume you've written
more than one?
Mmm.
And seen them produced.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I'm not
entirely unacquainted
with the achievements...
of the American stage
in the past decade.
Perhaps
I've seen one?
No, I doubt it.
I also doubt very much...
that I shall ever see one
graced by Miss McKenna.
You don't really believe
that's why I'm here, do you?
Why are you here?
Is it money?
I don't think you really
believe that either.
There is a law, Collier.
I warn you,
I will not hesitate
to make avail of it.
Oh, yes?
On what charge?
The matter's
concluded, sir.
No.
Oh, yes.
You may depend on it.
[ Rhythmic Thumping ]
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Uh, excuse me.
Arthur !
[ Clerk ]
Forgive me again, sir.
[ Grunts ]
[ Laughs ]
I'm very sorry, sir.
Ah, that's
quite all right.
I'd like a room, please.
Oh. Uh,
don't you have one?
Well, I was rather ill
when I arrived last night,
so I stayed with a friend.
Ah, I see.
Mm-hmm.
You do have a room, sir ?
Oh, yes, yes.
Thank you.
One single,
$3.00 a day.
Bathroom privileges extra.
Would you care to sign
the register now, sir ?
Um, e-excuse me.
I-I'm sorry. Are you sure
this is the right room?
The right room, sir ?
I-I don't understand.
I'm sorry, Mr. Biehl.
That room is reserved.
Forgot to put a notice
in the slot.
[ Biehl ]
l'm very sorry.
[ Sighs ]
Right.
Shall I sign?
Uh, would you, please?
Mm-hmm.
Mm-hmm. Excuse me.
Let me just
finish that for you.
[ Bell Buzzes ]
[ Woman ]
Grand Hotel.
Uh, 9: 19. Mm-hmm.
[ Woman ]
l'm sorry--
Thank you, sir.
[ Whispers ]
Bingo.
I beg your pardon?
Oh, nothing.
Uh, w-which room is
your luggage in, sir ?
Um, it's no problem.
I can get it later myself.
Thank you very much.
See you around, Arthur.
[ Richard Humming ]
Morning.
[ Man ]
Astonishing.
Hello.
You look lovely.
Thank you.
Shall we?
Certainly.
Sorry I'm late.
Complications.
What did you do
to your face?
Shaved.
New blade wasn't
quite sharp enough.
I shudder to think
what you'd look like if
the blade were any sharper.
Oh, no. I don't
believe it.
Gotta give him credit.
He's like a bulldog.
Would you like me
to speak to him?
Wouldn't do a bit of good.
[ Horse Whinnying ]
I think I know
what would, though.
[ Horse Snorts ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
Whoa !
Wait for me !
[ Both Laughing ]
Mr. Collier,
it isn't easy being
a successful actress.
Over the years, I--
I found it necessary
to protect myself.
So understand,
please understand...
that I'm even
with you today, when--
[ Sighs ]
when we only met
last night.
Why did you say,
""Is it you?""
I was expecting--
Me?
Someone.
Who?
Tell me.
I think you'll laugh.
Why? Is it funny?
In a way.
William told me
you were coming.
Robinson?
Yes.
He knows, somehow.
He really does.
He knew a lot of things
before they happened:
my career, my--
He told me that...
one day I would
meet a man who'd...
change my life.
Did he tell you
that man would be someone
to be afraid of?
Yes.
And what
do you think now?
Do you--
Do you believe that?
No.
You're obviously not.
[ Humming ]
That's
beautiful.
Hmm?
What is it?
That's Rachmaninoff,
from the Rhapsody.
Hmm. I saw him with
the philharmonic once.
I love his music,
but I've never heard
this piece.
Really?
Well, I'll introduce you
to it sometime.
[ Richard ]
Sorry we had the carriage
so long. Thank you.
See that guy's face?
[ Laughs ]
They're gonna hang us
for horse-napping.
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
Stick out
your tongue.
Huh?
Stick out
your tongue.
Why? Oh, no.
The most peculiar moment
in my life, Mr. Collier.
I think you'll survive it,
Miss McKenna.
What time
is it now?
Um,
4:30.
Well, I must be
getting back.
You have to?
Can't you stay
a little longer ?
No, I have to rest awhile.
The play.
[ Laughs ]
It's lovely.
Where did you get it?
It-It was given to me.
Well, shall we?
So... when's
the company leave?
Tonight.
Where are you going?
Denver.
Oh.
Well--
Well, thank you for
a most pleasant afternoon.
Could we talk
just a little longer ?
I really should
rest awhile. I--
Please.
Very well, then.
Just for a moment or so.
What did you want
to talk about?
No.
Oh, my God.
What's happening?
[ Knocking At Door ]
[ Robinson ]
McKenna?
[ Knocking ]
Come in.
I think you'd better go.
Have you been waiting
all this time for our return?
This is
hardly the time--
Have you?
Yes. Does that
surprise you?
Our relationship
is strictly business.
Strictly business?
I'm involved with you
as an actress, Mr. Robinson,
not a doormat.
Do not attempt
to wipe your boots on me.
Richard.
I shall leave a ticket for you
at the theater door.
""Excess within control,""
McKenna?
au revoir.
[ Door Slams ]
[ Crowd Murmuring ]
[ Waltz ]
[ applause ]
[ applause Stops ]
Good evening, miss.
Not good at all.
Particularly bad.
I'll not go
downstairs again.
Oh, what is it, miss?
[ Sighs ]
I've just been dining...
with the man my father
is determined that I wed.
Ooh, banker Harwell.
Banker Harwell--
yes, all 67 years...
and five-foot-four of height
and several hundred pounds
of him !
[ Laughter ]
He does have money,
though, miss.
And never lets
a soul forget it.
I'm amazed he has
the least desire
to marry.
- He's so happily wedded
to his gold.
- [ Laughter ]
[ Maid ]
He won't be
that bad, miss.
There must be something
you like about 'im.
Yes, his absence.
The man of my dreams
has almost faded now.
And what man
is that, miss?
The one I have created
in my mind.
The sort of man...
each woman dreams of
in the deepest...
and most secret reaches
of her heart.
I can almost
see him now before me.
What would I say to him...
if he were really here?
"Forgive me. "
I've never known
this feeling.
I've lived without it
all my life.
Is it any wonder, then,
I failed to recognize you?
y ou've...
brought it to me
for the first time.
Is there any way that--
that I can tell you
how my life has changed?
Any way at all
to let you know...
what sweetness
you have given me?
There is
so much to say, I--
I cannot find the words,
except for these.:
I love you.
And such
would I say to him,
if he were really here.
[ applause ]
[ Applause, Cheering ]
[ Applause Continues ]
What, in God's name,
were you doing?
[ Murmuring ]
Nothing.
Nothing? Rewriting
the entire first scene?
I got it back
on course.
Elise, hold a moment.
We've just got to take
that photograph.
Oh !
Very well. Just a moment,
I have to change.
Quickly !
A-And
a little flourish.
Yes, yes.
Yes, very pretty.
Very pretty.
Just one moment.
Here we go.
I'm just going to focus
on that lovely--
Oh, yes, yes, yes !
I'm just going to
put in the plate.
One moment.
There we go.
A little smile, please.
Uh, not-not quite.
Uh, perhaps if you think of
something happy or bright.
y es, that's it.
That's it. Hold it.
[ Shutter Clicks ]
Perfeect !
absolutely perfeect.
[ actor ]
l say l shall have her !
[ Laughter ]
[ actress ]
Not in my life,
you shall not.
[ Man ]
Mr. Collier ?
l am the one who loves her !
For you.
[ actress ]
Neither do you.
[ actor #1 ]
l can provide her
with life's enrichments,
rather than
the riches of life.
[ Laughter ]
[ actor #2 ]
are you sure?
[ actor #1 ]
an old song says it best.
[ Laughter, applause ]
Do you have any notion
how many years...
I have been
with Miss McKenna?
Since March of 1903.
March, 1903.
That's correct.
She was 16
at the time.
There she was
on that dingy stage...
in that pathetic play.
Total radiance.
It only took seconds
for me to realize...
exactly what
she had to be.
Mrs. Robinson?
Do you actually believe...
that I have nurtured her,
cared for her,
molded, taught,
developed her
for all these years,
merely to groom
a wife?
What, then?
A star.
Only someone with...
the limited awareness
of your age...
could possibly conceive
that my entire passion
for this woman...
is no more than physical !
are you incapable
of understanding that...
she has it within herself
to be one of the greatest,
if not the greatest...
actress
of her generation?
I owe you an apology.
What?
I understand you now.
You have nothing but the best
motives in mind for her.
- And you--
- But so do I.
Of course,
she'll continue to act,
she will continue to grow...
and she will become
everything you want her to be.
With you at her side?
y es.
With me at her side.
Never.
My God.
You really think
you own her, don't you?
Collier, I know
who you are.
Ever since
you came here,
I've known
from the start.
You came
to destroy her.
God, you're
out of your mind.
[ Orchestra ]
[ applause ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Orchestra Finishes ]
[ applause Continues ]
No more.
No more?
One curtain call ?
The audience
will be furious.
Marie, did you
find him?
No, Miss McKenna.
Did you try his room?
He wasn't there.
Oh !
What did they say
at the desk?
They have not seen him.
He left no message?
No, I'm sorry.
[ Sighs ]
This makes
no sense at all.
What could have happened
to him?
Marie !
Marie, help me
change. Quickly.
[ Knocking at Door ]
Wait, Marie.
Thank you, Marie.
Your performance
in act one, I--
I must say,
was somewhat eccentric.
Where is he?
What have you done to him?
I've done nothing, McKenna.
Mr. Collier has left.
That's all.
What do you mean?
Gone... from the hotel...
and your life.
I don't believe you.
I must admit,
he was somewhat
more charming...
than others that
we've encountered in the past,
you and l.
a trifle more sincere,
perhaps. Still--
Then he was not
the one you spoke of?
No.
Then you were wrong
about him, weren't you?
You were wrong.
I love him,
and he's going
to make me very happy.
Do you understand?
I love him.
What difference...
can that make now?
He's gone.
I'll find him, William.
Don't you dare
try to stop me.
Now, if you will excuse me
while I change.
Of course.
May I remind you...
that we leave
within the hour ?
[ Door Opens,
Footsteps Recede ]
[ Door Closes ]
Thank you.
[ Horse Snorts ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Moans ]
[ Horse Snorts ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunting, Panting ]
[ Glass Shatters ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
Yah !
Elise !
Elise?
[ Sighs ]
Sir ?
are you all right?
The company--
Are they gone?
Company?
The ones who did
the play last night.
Are they gone?
They left as soon
as they were packed, sir.
Oh, come along, Arthur.
We'll be late.
Richard !
[ Laughing ]
You all right?
Yes.
I thought
I lost you.
Oh, never.
Never, never, never !
Mm-mmm.
You will marry me,
won't you?
[ Splutters ]
[ Laughing ]
Sorry.
You won't?
[ Murmurs ]
Sure.
I was just laughing
at the way you asked,
that's all.
For one moment
there...
What?
I thought you had
a wife and children
back home somewhere.
[ Laughing ]
Oh, Elise.
I want to be
everything to you.
You are.
Tell me more
about yourself, my love.
Well--
What sort of plays
do you write?
Um--
Are there
parts for me?
I could--
I would love to act
in one of your plays,
assuming that I ever want
to act again after tonight.
You will.
Oh, Richard.
[ Clears Throat ]
Good plays.
What?
I write good plays.
[ Laughs ]
I never let you answer,
did I ?
No.
Sorry.
What time
do you think it is?
I don't know.
I don't care.
I love you.
Oh, don't look--
Fine.
It's 5:00.
Really?
I don't feel
sleepy somehow, do you?
No.
The first thing
I intend to do for you--
You've already done.
Well, the second thing,
then.
What?
Buy you a new suit.
I don't understand.
Nobody seems to like my suit.
Can you blame them?
Wait a minute.
I think my suit's terrific.
What's wrong with this?
So what if it's
ten years old?
Oh, at least 15.
Fifteen?
Mm-hmm.
Well, I think
it's fabulous.
[ Laughing ]
Let me show you.
lt's a really great suit.
It's in first-class condition.
The sleeves fit.
That's pretty good for me.
My arms are
about nine feet long.
And it's got pockets everywhere.
I can pull rabbits outta here.
The best part, this is a special
coin compartment for emerg--
Richard?
Richard !
Richard ! Richard !
[ Screaming ]
Richard !
[ announcer On Radio,
Faint ]
[ Gasping ]
[ announcer Continues,
Faint ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Traffic Noises ]
[ Radio ]
WJjjT
[ announcer On Radio ]
How's traffic?
[ announcer Continues,
Faint ]
[ Woman On Radio ]
The road conditions
are pretty good today.
[ Gasping, Sobbing ]
at the inbound Kennedy
at Jackson, there's a three-car
accident with injuries...
right at the center
of the roadway.
Traffic is backed up
from Ohio to Jackson--
No. No, no !
No !
[ Panting ]
[ Mumbling ]
June 29, 19 12.
It's June 29, 19 12.
It's J-- Oh, God.
[ Sobbing ]
Please.
June 29. I'm back.
I'm back. Oh, God--
[ Mumbling ]
June 29, 19 12.
[ Exhales ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
No !
[ Sobbing ]
[ Knocking At Door ]
[ arthur ]
Mr. Collier ?
[ Knocking Continues ]
[ Man ]
are you sure he's in there?
Well, the maid says
he's been in there for days.
[ arthur ]
are you all right, sir ?
[ Man ]
Use the passkey.
[ Keys Rattling ]
Mr. Collier ?
Oh, my God !
Let's get him
on the bed.
All right, easy.
Careful,
careful !
I got him.
Better take
his legs.
All right.
all right,
over here.
Okay.
Easy.
[ Phone Dialing ]
Operator ? Get Dr. Paul
up to Suite 313 right away.
Looks like
he hasn't eaten in a week.
Send for
an ambulance.
I'll call one.
- What a shame.
If I'd only known.
- Operator ? Get an ambulance.
[ arthur ]
He is gonna make it, isn't he?
I don't know.
[ Man ]
They're on their way.
How is he?
We're gonna need oxygen.
We've got some.
I'll get it.
[ arthur ]
Keep him warm
with this blanket.
Such a fine man.
What a shame.
I wonder what happened.
Gotta keep him goin'
until they get here.
[ arthur ]
Gladys, this is arthur again
in Mr. Collier's suite.
We've got to--
[ Murmuring ]