You can operate here,
but remember to pay dues to us.
Show some respect.
I'm not a "yakuza".
I'm not paying you anything.
But you act like a yakuza.
So, the police can arrest me.
But I needn't put up with your bullshit.
Then you're as good as dead!
Don't be an idiot.
You're the idiot.
Waiting for your date?
He's not coming.
I'll finish work soon, we could go to a club.
Boss, Kitajima called you a little while ago.
He said he'd call you back.
How did it go?
Let's sort him out.
I'll get it.
It's the old man.
Hello...
...yes...
Today?
Okay.
How are you, sir?
I thought you'd decided to go back home?
The cafe needed a waiter so,
I thought I'd stay a bit longer.
Act like a waiter then.
Okay, sir.
If you muck me about, you'll pay for it.
Sorry, sir.
Murakawa Productions.
Kashimoto for you, sir.
Katagiri speaking.
- Tanaka can drive can't he?
- Yes.
You know that mah-jong parlour?
Yes.
- Go there and wait for me.
- Okay.
You can't?
Don't bullshit me!
People like us don't lend money for nothing!
Don't dare try it on with us!
Ken...
...I'd like to quit the Yakuza.
We've led the tough life for too long.
I'm worn out.
Maybe you're too rich for this trade now...
They're here.
I hear they're doing well.
His patch is booming, thanks to
the new underground line.
Our business is lousy.
This trip may change our fortunes.
So handle it carefully.
The Nakamatsu clan of Okinawa,
is at war with the Anan clan.
They're begging us for help.
So we must send some soldiers down there.
Would you fly down there with some men?
Three of my men were killed on our last sortie.
I didn't like that.
That's how you earned your patch.
Isn't business booming?
Show the boss some appreciation.
Only if you go with me, Takahashi.
You know that I must...
...take care of the boss and the syndicate.
I can't go, even if I wanted to.
Who'll look after my patch?
Katagiri will be your lieutenant.
Don't worry.
It's an operation to restore peace,
there shouldn't be any bloodshed.
You may smoke.
Nakamatsu may be my sworn brother,
but he's never done anything for me.
He's only a distant family relative.
But you boys are my immediate family.
We've sworn allegiance,
and put our lives in your hands, boss.
You're putting my life in his hands.
A call for you, Mr. Murakawa.
- I'm going.
- Goodbye.
You may join us now.
Well...?
What...?
What's going on?
Over there...
Aren't we naughty ?
Mr. Murakawa, please, listen...
Shut up, punk!
Let's be reasonable...
...how much do you want?
Too late.
How long can he stay under?
Two or three minutes, I imagine.
So let's try two minutes.
Go ahead!
Mr. Murawaka...
...please don't kill me !
Please, don't!
Check him.
Hey, pull him up.
Still breathing?
Please, stop.
Try three minutes.
Go ahead.
No, please...
Mr. Murakawa, please!
There's something fishy about the Okinawa trip.
The old man says both sides are
waiting for us to restore peace.
It's a sticky situation....
We lost three men on the Hokkaido job.
Isn't it over three minutes?
Oh, yes.
Oh, we've killed him...
...but never mind. Deal with it!
My name is Sakai, sir.
Okumura.
Hirose.
ltoh.
My men will join you guys.
You'd like to see me dead?
Sure. I'd feel safer having a piss.
Introduce yourselves.
Maeda, sir.
Ohno.
Tsuda.
Why are you here?
Mr. Takahashi says...
...you can take me to Okinawa.
They look green!
This isn't a school outing!
What? Bastard!
What you doing?
I told you to give that up.
Welcolme to Okinawa.
We'll take you to your office.
Rest before the boss takes you out to dinner.
Hi,
I'm Ryoji.
If anyone wants a drink or an ice-cream, then...
...Let's go, Shiraishi.
Something to drink?
My belly still hurts from when you stabbed me.
I don't believe my eyes.
It's quite some time since we used this office.
You won't be here long so,
I hope you don't mind the disorder.
The toilet's over there...
Ryoji, bring the tools.
In case you might become lonely, take your pick.
We took these off some Americans.
What's that mean?
Just a friendly welcolme!
Or perhaps...
...the end of the war.
Well, what now?
The boss talked to the Anan clan a little while ago.
A few of them got worked up
about you guys coming...
Taking a tea-break?
I guess we must say hello to them?
I'll try it now...
Nothing happened, idiot!
It was an American grenade,
you can't rely on them.
Now what?
It all started when my one of my idiots
shot at an Anan man...
Nothing serious...
...nobody was killed or anything...
...and I didn't need any help.
But, your old man insisted on
sending some soldiers.
And, I do appreciate you coming all this way.
We were told that you begged for some help.
News to me...
As I said, it was your man who insisted.
Nothing serious here...
...just the sort of little problem
we encounter everyday.
What are you doing tonight, sir?
Mr. Uyeji is taking us out.
Which part of Tokyo you from?
Nakano.
Then you know 'Tommy's, by the station?
Never heard of it.
- It's a popular place.
- Do you listen?
Smoke?
What's that?
Marijuana.
No. I'm not into that.
- You all right?
- Fine.
...Got any cigarettes?
We'll reassemble and split into smaller units.
Whoever wants to go home
can go back to Tokyo.
This is war.
Hello.
- You can relax in a booth.
- No.
- What would you like?
- Beer.
I'll call some hostesses, shall I?
It's Tomiko.
Send some girls, we're getting busy.
You know my friend Kinjo, of Nakano?
He robbed a supermarket and
barricaded himself inside.
I don't know him.
What about Nanbara, a gang leader?
Haven't you any decent friends?
Someone famous, in baseball or something?
Another beer.
- Hi, good evening.
- Good evening.
All clear.
It's my brothers house.
He's in Osaka now. No one will bother us.
I'll call Tokyo.
About what?
Just lie low and keep a check on things out here.
- Nothing but beer and sake?
- No.
You better aim straight. At the can.
You almost hit me, idiot! I saw it fly past.
Give it to me.
Let's play.
- What, sir?
- Stone, paper, scissors.
You playing?
You're first.
What game?
- You could've killed me!
- Let's continue.
Stone, paper, scissors...
- You again!
- Just hang on...
- Again.
- It's the last chamber....
Stone, paper, scissors...
You lost that time.
No! Don't!
I don't believe it...
...It was empty.
Your boss is a weirdo.
Watch your mouth!
And you were shit scared.
Don't just sit there, dance with me.
No, some other time.
You've watched it all?
Are you a pervert?
You enjoyed it?
Answer me!
You're a dead man. I'll slit your throat!
...What are you doing?
You sure the girl killed him?
Two shots in the stomach.
Shall we dump him?
What about the car?
We'll use it.
Drive slowly...asshole.
It's my friend.
How's the boss?
Still talking about the truce.
I just can't work him out.
Well, some clothes for you. Nothing fancy.
Thanks.
Call whenever you need me.
Just a minute!
Give these to Marimo at
'Bar Chez-Nous', will you ?
What is it?
A present.
- I'm not your errand boy.
- Please, do me a favour.
There's plenty more over here...
I won.
Let's fight with this.
- What's that?
- Mai-no-umi.
So, you like flashy shirts then?
- Doesn't it suit me?
- You look ridiculous!
Can I visit you again sometime?
Wouldn't bother.
Why must I drive you home?
I'm an awful driver.
- Does it matter?
- Yes.
This is my husbands car.
Do I have to know!?
When was the first time you killed anyone?
When I was at high school.
Who did you kill?
My Dad.
Why?
He wouldn't let me screw girls!
Get in the front.
How could you run off such a wide road?
A snake was crossing.
You've no driving license, have you?
- She was driving.
- I wasn't.
Push.
Sure you'll make it back in one piece?
Go.
You must pay for the petrol.
Watch out for holes.
They're coming...
Over here, quick!
- Can we get across?
- Yes! Hurry up!
Let's have a drink.
Boss, isn't all this rather childish?
What else can I do?
Still wearing that shirt? It's terrible!
- There's no more traps.
- You sure?
Water!
No more now,
or else we can't have a bath.
You can wait 'till it rains.
Where's boss?
Gone fishing, with that girl.
She's here again?
Guess she's in love...
Don't you like the shirt anymore?
None of your business, idiot!
It's great to be not afraid of shooting people.
That must mean...
...you're not afraid of killing yourself, right?
You're tough. I love tough men.
If I were tough, would I carry a gun?
But you shoot with ease...
Because I scare with ease.
But, you're not afraid of dying...
If you're afraid of death for too long,
it become's a death wish.
I don't get it...
What's your plan from now?
There's no word from Tokyo.
We better go home in a couple of days.
"Screw me, darling".
Screw yourself!
"You're pestering my girl".
"Want a fight"?
Will you just piss off!?
''Smack''!
...It's raining!
Quick! Grab the shampoo...
...It's great not to be afraid of showing your tits!
Is that it? What the hell!
Ready? Action!
Enter slowly...
Start again.
Ready...Action!
Call that dancing?
You must enjoy yourself.
I'll dance with you.
Is Takahashi there?
He's always "out".
He better be in next time.
What about the change?
Did you put money in?
What do you take me for !
Of course I put money in.
Is it a telephone or piggy-bank?
I can kill you for this!
Not fair, you're using a gun!
This isn't playing!
Not fair!
Mr. Murakawa, stop!
- Where's Murakawa ?
- Maybe out on a date.
- My boss wants to see him.
- What about?
Proposing a truce.
I'd better come along.
Your boss's aide, Takahashi,
came to see me yesterday.
He's been concluding
the truce with the Anan clan.
That's good news.
They accept on one condition.
Anan wants us to disband.
What's your response?
I can't do that. I'll fight to the end.
Uyeji...
...I will retire.
She's expecting a baby, and I'm getting old.
You take over my patch and the affairs.
Choose whether to fight or disband.
Do as you must.
Did Takahashi say anything about us?
For the time being...
...the Murakawa clan will be expelled.
Goodbye, sir...
Ha! Missed!
Impossible! How can I hit it?
It's not some Western. Here, try it.
When I say, okay?
Throw it that way...
Okay? Throw!
- Shit, it's empty!
- See, you can't hit it either!
We'll put the heat on Takahashi.
The boss wants to go all the way.
Here.
Yes?
Mr. Takahashi here?
I'am Takahashi.
Must be a mistake.
He wouldn't register under his own name.
Takahashi!
I swear I know nothing.
The boss always wanted Anan
to become his partner.
But before that, he had to
get rid of Nakamatsu.
The squabble was the ideal excuse...
...to eliminate Nakamatsu.
So, why expel me ?
Your patch is booming,
he's greedy and wanted a part.
Listen, Murakawa.
The boss is coming to see Anan.
You can take over Nakamatsu's patch...
...I can arrange it.
Your turn.
Not that.
Now we must walk back.
Sorry.
Who are you?
I'm lost.
Are you coming back?
Maybe.
Will you wait for me?
Can I shoot it?
Okay.
Shall I go with you?
Stupid question.
You've had enough, haven't you?
...Shit.
The lights will go out in ten minutes.
Fill her up on the way back.