To Dean of Admissions,
Princeton University.
The most influential person in my life...
... is Mother Teresa, whose example
helped me overcome the arrogance...
which threatened after my 1,600 SAT score
and National Merit Scholarship.
My influential person taught me
the most important word I've learned.
Aloha, which I...
To the Dean of Admissions,
Princeton University...
from Cristina Moreno.
Most influential person: My mother.
No contest.
I think I have been pointing
toward this essay...
ever since the day, 12 years ago in Mexico,
when my father left.
Such was my mother's need to protect me...
that she would not let me see her cry.
The trick was...
get over it as quickly
and privately as possible.
Such was my need to protect her...
that I never let on that I could hear her.
My mother kept us in Mexico
as long as possible...
to root me in all things Latin.
Finally, she sensed
our last opportunity for change.
We would leave for America.
"One tear."
"Just one."
"So make it a good one," she said.
She would be my Mexico.
Because this admissions essay
is open record...
let me just say that our transportation
into the United States was...
economy class.
In order to raise me properly...
my mother needed as much of the security
of her own culture as possible.
So we rolled through Texas...
just 34% Hispanic...
to Los Angeles...
48% Hispanic.
...look at the Detroit Pistons.
And your mother's saying, "Get up!"
But, no, what of it?
You can't see them. Why?
'Cause you're being killed...
you're being strangled
by the psychotic Raider fans.
What do you have in Oakland?
You got a bunch of psychotic...
A few minutes adrift
in an alien environment...
then we turned a corner,
and we were right back home.
My mother's favorite cousin,
Monica, gave us shelter.
For the next six years...
neither of us ventured outside
our new community.
Mom worked two jobs,
paying a total of $450 a week...
each of us doing everything we could
to make things work.
We were safe and happy.
If only I could have stayed six.
But I was blossoming.
And during my very first dance...
in the time it took a boy's hand...
to go from my back to my bottom...
it was evident that
she would have to leave her night job...
to keep a watchful eye on me.
Within days, she was
on her way to a job interview.
She needed $450 from one job.
And that meant,
after all her time in America...
finally entering a foreign land.
Hello?
Yeah, hi. We're here for
the interview with Mrs. Clasky?
Oh, great. You made it.
Come on in. The front door's open
and we're out back. Okay?
And call me Deborah.
Holding out had helped though.
She was no longer intimidated.
Working for Anglos
now posed no problems.
It would just be a job.
White America beckoned.
She stepped across the cultural divide.
Gee whiz in heaven, are you okay?
No. Don't worry, I'm not mad.
I've been looking for decoration to put up
on the glass so people wouldn't walk into it.
Instead of taking what was in stock,
which was awful, I special ordered...
but I'll design something myself,
which I should've done...
What does that matter
when your nose is bleeding?
- Shut up, Deborah.
- Now you got it, Mom.
- There's no ice pack, Bern!
- So get anything frozen.
Pressure! Just pressure!
Take this.
Is it strange that I just gave you money?
I just felt really badly.
It's okay.
Chum, knock it off!
I'm sorry about the way the place looks.
I'm hosting a fundraiser
for the school tonight.
It's just a mess. Come sit right here.
Here you go.
Yeah, just... That's great.
Just toss it.
She's my cousin.
She's been here for a while and
she understands some, but doesn't really...
speak English, but, anyway...
She lives in the apartment I manage and...
- So who am I interviewing?
- Her.
You're gorgeous.
She didn't mean it as a compliment.
It's more of an accusation.
- Mother!
- Go ahead.
I'm sorry. This is my daughter, Bernie...
- and my mother, Evelyn Wright.
- Evelyn.
- Do you want to come in out of the sun?
- No, we're fine.
You need some sunscreen? I got a 70 here.
She loves the sun.
Look, we're wearing the same sweater.
That's good booga-booga.
You want some lemonade, maybe?
Lemonade, please?
Would you like to take some? Both of you?
Okay, let's just talk.
I have two children. My husband is
a top chef. Like that makes me something.
- Anyway, he works nights, so...
- Do you work?
Yes. No. Not right now. Why?
How do you know to ask that?
It's okay. I can talk about it. I just...
I ran a commercial design company
until four months ago...
when it was downsized to zip.
- Now I'm a full-time mom. Gulp!
- Double gulp.
I have two children.
My son Georgie is nine, Bernie you know...
and I like the house to be like me,
you know...
I'm very loose and meticulous
at the same time.
It's all about first names
and closeness here.
Let her know, absolutely.
But I do care about the place.
I'm so sorry,
I'm not leaving you time to translate.
What's your name?
Llamo. It's one of my five Spanish words.
Flor Moreno.
Floor?
Flor.
- Floor?
- No, Flor.
Floor.
Flor.
- It means "flower," right?
- Flower, yes.
- Floor! What I walk on, right?
- Flor.
- Flor!
Is there some school of the ear
I'm flunking out off right now?
What'd she say?
She says if you curl your tongue,
then let it be loose, you'll get it...
and that it's really hard for Americans...
and that it's great you try so hard.
Because most people wouldn't bother.
She gets me.
Flor.
Dense, but stubborn, right?
Now, see what you just did for me?
That is just what the kids need.
Patience and encouragement.
All right, money.
- Goodbye. Look forward to seeing you.
- Love you.
The job is six days a week.
Seven, eight, 12 hours, it depends.
All the housekeeping, driving the kids.
How much a week do you want?
- Whatever you say.
- No!
No. This is a very important question...
because if you ask for too little,
it means you don't value yourself.
You ask for too much,
it means you're taking advantage. So?
$1,000.
She's kidding!
$650!
Welcome to the family.
Come on. I want to show you around.
Come on!
I had never known that my mother
had been chronically worried about money...
until the first glimpse of her
as financially unburdened.
Can we have a table for two, please?
- We're celebrating.
- Okay, right this way.
Is this good?
- Gracias.
- You're welcome.
Here you go.
Enjoy.
- Gracias.
- You're welcome.
Whoa, expensive.
Excuse me.
Those men would like to buy you a drink.
Thank you.
- No, gracias.
- Okay.
Sorry.
This is so embarrassing.
My mother said to tell them,
"Who do you think you are?
"Can't you see I'm with my daughter,
for God's sake?"
Good.
She said, "Who do you think you are?"
She's with her daughter, for God's sake.
Her young daughter.
Passing on the left!
Left!
Morning, Flor. See you up there.
Hey! Will you try this?
Isn't that good?
Okay, think seriously about getting up.
You don't have to get up yet,
but are you thinking seriously about it?
- Yes.
- Okay.
My God. This is amazing!
A simple "it's good" will do.
I'm glad you like it.
But you could do without this.
No!
Flor, never do fetch to Chum! Never!
I'm not mad. I'm thinking of you.
This is me being nice.
Okay. It's just...
no taking the ball from the dog.
Just don't. No fetch.
No. Never do fetch with this dog.
Okay? Never.
Here, can you make us
some coffee, maybe? Yeah?
Okay. Right. Thank you.
- Now?
- Yes, actual up.
Hey, Dad!
Are you as mad at me as Mom
'cause of what happened?
No, Georgie, I'm not.
Are you mad at me?
- No.
- Good.
Let's hope.
When it comes to the kids, John,
we got to stay on the same page!
United. Doing consistent parenting.
Do you know how many books
on parenting I've read?
Deb, since high school we've been able
to read each other. Take advantage of it.
Word for word, what did you say
to Georgie exactly?
"No, I'm not mad."
Good guy...
bad guy.
Come on.
What the hell are you doing?
Everything's okay.
- John.
- Yes.
Do you really think that cupping my breast...
- is going to solve the issue here?
- It's worked before.
Now it's infuriating me.
- Wrong breast.
- Oh, my God!
No, I know what you mean.
Oh, my God. Don't do the calm thing.
Just don't go there. Don't do that thing.
This is very important to you. Us.
I just like to level with Georgie.
That's why I answered him this way.
This is not an argument, honey.
Yes, it is!
We're having a fight, John.
A big fight, at last.
So could you stop
being so stark raving calm?
Great God in heaven, save me.
Hi.
I didn't know Deb found somebody.
You work here?
You're gonna help out
with the house and kids?
You work here
and you don't speak any English at all?
All she has to do is dial 911
and press two for Spanish.
This is...
Flor, this is Georgie and this is John.
John, this is Flor.
Flor.
Great. I'll take Georgie to school.
No, I'm doing it.
I'm gonna show Flor the ropes.
Flor, will you come with me, please?
Come. Thank you.
- She's mad.
- You're fine. Deb?
- What?
- You love me.
- Not the best place to stand, fella.
- No, it's me. I'm bugged.
I'm sorry.
Not a problem.
You're the new helper, Alex, right?
Okay, welcome. First day.
John, I have something very important
to tell you.
- Damn.
- What?
Victor recognized a food critic
over the phone.
- From?
- The Times.
I'll bet they sent her
across the country just for us.
- Lf you're nervous, take a walk.
- I don't need a walk.
I'll walk with you. I know a breathing thing.
What do you think I'm worried about?
How I'm gonna cook?
That's not the thing. That's not the problem.
I worked at a restaurant in New York
that had four stars.
It was like a line formed
to become an asshole.
People's accents changed.
The heart went out of the place.
You understand?
- No.
- I agree with everything you just said.
I admire you for your feelings.
I hope to adopt them as my own.
Here we are, ladies.
I don't know what to root for.
The thought of one star gets me nauseous...
but with four, there's no place to go but,
"My God, they took away one of my stars!"
- The Times liked the first course.
- You know what you want?
Three and a quarter stars.
Yes, that would be perfect.
It'd mean you're good,
but not good enough to feel disappointed...
you just missed out on excellence.
You still get enough respect.
Good people wanna work with you.
Business is good, not crazy.
You're right below the radar,
where you get to mind your own business.
That's a good, solid life.
Big wipe.
I'm in the vitamin section
and this little hip-hop girl, what's her name?
Nice surprise, thank you. You want some?
This little hip-hop girl, what's her name?
Grammys.
She's famous. You kids know her. Oh, darn.
God bless the language barrier.
It keeps you from being bored with me.
Anyway, she said:
- "Aren't you Evelyn Wright?"
- Oh, my God!
First of all, that she remembered me
from the old covers.
- Yeah.
- And then she...
- Oh, please. Her name.
- Stop it.
- It makes the story so much better.
- It's still a good story.
She said:
"Whenever I think everything's"...
Pardon my French, pardon her French.
"A mother-hm-hm...
"I put on one of your records."
Oh, my God.
That is so sweet.
Well, you think your life is embarrassing,
and then...
somebody finds encouragement in it.
- You understand?
- I think I do.
Mom, it's not even noon.
- This is going to work.
- I don't know anything.
Free your mind.
"The president whose policies...
"many consider responsible
for the Great Depression."
I don't know.
- Name a vacuum cleaner.
- What?
- Okay, I got it.
- Hoover.
- I said I had it. You don't trust me?
- Okay.
I no longer know nothing.
And Hoover was followed in office by...
I'm just drawing blanks. I'm embarrassed.
It's my own fault.
I spent all my time on math,
which I'm lucky if I don't flunk, anyway.
Stop it.
The man you're looking for is not a ruse.
- What does "ruse" mean?
- Phony.
Roosevelt!
If I'd ever heard of that word before,
that would lock it in.
- Surprise! New clothes.
- What?
- What did I do right?
- It was a warehouse sale.
I went nuts. I got so much stuff.
Great! She needed a boost.
That came together.
I wouldn't wear it together, it's a little much.
Eight?
What?
- Eight.
- What?
- Bernie, come on. Listen.
- What's going on?
You're gonna do it,
and you're gonna look beautiful.
Honey, I just...
You are going to lose that weight, and...
You know...
I'm glad you didn't get here earlier,
because...
then I wouldn't be able to tell you that...
your gift to me...
is a ruse.
- Honey, I...
- Please, just excuse me.
- Hey, Bernie...
- I just...
I just need to be alone right now, okay?
I'm sorry. It's okay.
We have to be able to endure this, John,
if we're gonna help her.
I'll just gonna hang out here
and wait for you, okay?
Her pediatrician intervened on
his own daughter's weight, and she is an 8.
Dad, don't.
Didn't you ever just need a minute?
Yes.
This is the same page
that I'm talking about, John.
We gotta be on the same page.
That's the most important thing.
I don't know why it has to be so hard.
I need a minute.
She's right between the two sizes.
I thought about it.
What am I supposed to do?
Encourage her denial...
or motivate her to get herself in shape?
Flor?
Me go.
- Okay.
- I'll take you to the bus stop.
Sorry, I didn't even help you with the door.
No, what I meant was...
My mother did not understand
her male boss.
He seemed as upset as she was
over what had been done to Bernice...
Shit!
... and yet had done nothing.
I am running out of excuses
for the lady of the house!
But, man, Bernice's final is tomorrow.
She didn't need this one.
And just the look on her face
when she got the gifts!
Like for one second she thought...
all her problems with her mother
had been solved!
He appeared to be a good man...
but to someone with first-hand knowledge
of Latin macho...
he seemed to have
the emotions of a Mexican woman.
She had no idea of how to react,
except to flee.
What're you doing? We're still moving.
I'll take you all the way to the bus stop.
You got to let me take you all the way.
I'll take you.
All the way.
How weird was this ride?
Sorry. I'm sorry.
Yes, you are released. Yes.
Bye-bye.
A simple request from my mother
startled me.
Her rules were bending.
She was losing her battle
to remain uninvolved with the Claskys.
"Try it on."
Try...
Just. "Just try it on."
Just try on.
Just.
There is one particular cultural difference...
which I wish to explore academically
at Princeton.
American women, I believe...
actually feel the same as Hispanic women
about weight.
A desire for the comfort of fullness.
And when that desire
is suppressed for style...
and deprivation allowed to rule...
dieting, exercising American women...
Left!
... become afraid of everything
associated with being curvaceous...
such as wantonness, lustfulness...
Left!
... sex, food...
motherhood.
All that is best in life.
Wow!
Taste, she has.
Just try it on.
When did you learn to speak English?
It's too tight. It doesn't fit.
Bernice, just try it on.
It's too small. I'm too big.
- Just try it on!
- Okay.
I'll show you.
Thanks.
Lovely way to start the day.
The world's most trim Mexican
learns her first sentence...
and uses it to watch me grunt my way...
into a...
- It fits!
- Okay.
No.
Thanks.
Whatever happened to Frère Jacques
or Itsy-Bitsy Spider?
- Make room.
- I know.
But every time he has a nightmare,
I teach him one of my old songs.
That way, his nightmares have a purpose.
But I don't have to sing it for anyone.
Right, you're clear on that.
How many did you sell of this song,
Grandma?
He likes to know that stuff.
She was huge.
Here goes.
76,000, which is great for a jazz album.
Jesus.
Fuck you.
Dad!
For Christ's sake, why are you screaming?
Why, crazy father,
why aren't you screaming?
I'm working on it.
The stunned thing has to get dealt with.
"John Clasky..."
- No.
- Yes.
"John Clasky, who, at 25...
"made his mark
on the New York restaurant scene...
"has re-emerged
as a young and confident veteran...
"taking chances with his combinations..."
- Dad.
- Your sister's talking.
"...beginning with a succession
of appetizers...
"is constantly yet casually daring."
Dad, this is so great.
Oh, my God.
I think, here it is.
"Eating at this perfect, smaller,
passionate restaurant...
"inspires one's own abandonment
of caution.
"To wit...
"John Clasky is the best chef
in the United States."
- Look how great you read it.
- Perfect, Dad.
John, four stars. Oh, my God.
You even look different to me.
I wonder what Mom will do?
I read it!
All right. What is this?
I don't know.
I'm just so happy for you
and all your hard work.
Oh, my goodness.
All right.
Don't worry. I'll wait for you.
Nice move.
We are so smooth. Right on.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the mother of two children! Look at that.
You look good.
You're too beautiful. It's ridiculous.
- I like you.
- Okay, I love you.
Go.
You don't even need me, do you?
Just go. Now she's on.
It's all you!
No.
Don't get sad. You had fun, I swear.
Deb, cheer up!
What am I going to do about me?
No, not yet!
Great sex.
It's John Clasky.
"I read your good review."
I read your good review.
They read me your good review.
- Nice.
- Not so far.
I'm sorry. How are you doing?
I do fine.
Be happy.
Yeah. Absolutely.
Congratulations. Good job.
- I need to talk to you.
- Oh, man. Okay.
- You deserved it.
- You were terrific.
Congratulations. You guys worked hard.
Way to go.
- Pietro, what's wrong?
- I got a fantastic offer for my own place.
Everyone wants to back me
since the paper came out.
I can't lose you
and keep the hours I'm keeping.
I can't do my life unless I hold onto you.
I think I just gave you
an incredible bargaining position.
So you gave away 20% of the restaurant...
without even talking to me about it?
I had to, right then,
or I would have lost him.
Then I wouldn't have enough time
with the family.
- I don't exist.
- Sure you do.
I was all worried, just trying to
figure out the timing to talk to you...
about renting a place for the summer.
I think you have your timing.
- Mom, the realtor's here. You coming?
- Go on.
All right, I'll be back later.
- Hi.
- Hi there.
- I'm Mike.
- Deborah. Hi.
There's a great rental that just came
on the market, so we're starting at the top.
- Okay.
- Good.
I'm never gonna be one of those girls
whose hair...
flows perfectly in a convertible.
Move your seat forward.
I just...
A little more. Good.
You must be trouble.
Look at this.
Isn't it gorgeous?
It's beautiful. It's fabulous. Perfect.
What word is the same in Spanish?
Thank you.
So, this will be your room, okay?
Don't worry.
I'm gonna put lots of nice stuff in here, too.
Did you ask her if she could live in?
Come on.
There are no buses from her to here.
There's no question. Double come on.
The barrio, Carbon Beach.
What to do?
Come on, it's going to be so great.
I'm gonna get someone
to explain everything to you. Come on.
You must learn English.
Why won't she learn English?
Be careful.
I'm gonna have to learn
"you must learn English" in Spanish.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me, do you speak English?
- Yes, I do.
Would you please help me?
Will you translate for me with her?
Sure.
Sure. Forever.
He's gonna...
Give me a minute.
Okay. Hi.
I've rented a house for the summer...
and she needs to sleep at the house
because of the bus schedule.
No, sorry.
What? Why?
She can't, because her daughter.
You have a daughter?
A whole daughter you've never mentioned?
This is a little crazy that I don't know this.
No, don't translate asides.
She said she can't live here.
- Because her daughter...
- I got that.
Her daughter can also live here
for the summer. Go, tell her that.
Deborah, if she didn't tell us
about her child...
she has to have a deep sense of privacy.
We can figure out
how she can still live at home.
Hell, I don't mind driving her at night.
Let's spare the world
you on the roads, okay?
What am I gonna do?
I'm sorry, my friend, but this is what I need.
It's just for the summer.
I don't want to lose you, but...
She said she live here with you.
Hey, Cristina!
Malibu. Malibu.
The first time one sees natural beauty
which is privately owned...
oceans as people's backyards
confounds the senses.
Oh, my gosh.
I didn't know God had a toy store
for the rich.
The beaches are so clean. It's beautiful.
Three months?
We're gonna be staying here
for three months.
We're gonna be staying at this beach
for three months! This is amazing!
You want to go swimming?
Look at this child.
Oh, God, you could make a fortune
at surrogate pregnancy.
How you doing? I'm John.
- Hello.
- Great.
Come on out and meet everybody.
I'm Deborah
and this is my daughter, Bernice.
Here's Georgie...
and my mother, Evelyn Wright.
So glad to meet you.
No comparisons, please.
I'm not even gonna respond to that.
Come here.
My mom says it's best if we go, get
out of your way, and put our things away.
Yes, go get settled.
Thank you so much. I'm thrilled to be here.
Okay, here's the idea.
I need to make a serving platter
for serving fish out of sea glass like this.
Just bits of broken glass
that the ocean sand...
blasts over the years.
So here's the deal.
You guys go hunting for it.
I'll give you 50 cents for any piece you find.
A dollar for any piece
that's bigger than that sucker right there.
All right, $5 for any piece
that isn't brown, clear, or green.
- Do we really have to do this?
- What?
- Come on.
- Let's go. Let's do this. Have fun.
- Come on, Chum.
- Go get them, kid.
- Me, too?
- Yes, of course.
Thank you.
Oh, my God, Georgie.
Cristina! Up here. Over here.
What's wrong?
She's wild-eyed over this.
Flor.
I'm sorry.
Very sorry.
Listen, she'll be back shortly.
No, you don't have to work. Give me that.
Here.
Thanks.
Deb made a mistake.
I understand how you feel.
Do you understand what I'm saying
right now, at all?
- No.
- Good. Is simpático the word?
Uno momento. That's Italian.
I really am sorry that this is happening.
I wanted you to know that.
I really. So sorry. Truly.
I didn't mean like...
I meant just a normal sorry.
So, I'm going to go to work.
Thank you so much.
- Thank you so much for taking me there.
- Stop thanking me.
I really enjoyed having the company.
The flea market was just...
I don't know what to say. It was just...
so many things.
And you.
You knew so much about all of them.
The way you made those people
lower the prices, though.
I just think that you're...
- Never mind.
- No, go ahead. I can take it.
I just think that you're...
the most amazing white woman
that I've ever met.
That is so nice to hear.
Absurd, but deeply appreciated, Cristina.
Oh, my gosh.
Thank you so much. That was so fun.
- This was the best day ever.
- What?
Did something bad happen?
Cristina, tell your mother those wash
right out. It's no big deal.
Not right now.
What?
You can't just take someone else's kid
and then make them over.
Don't go there. Or I'll go there,
and you know where "there" is.
Can you believe what a big deal
Flor is making this into?
Please, shoot me
if I ever become that hard to deal with.
- What's this?
- For you.
From?
Look, you are not yourself.
This was written in anger. Will you hold on?
Sleep on it.
You still want me to have it, that's fine.
Take the letter.
I don't think that you will,
once calm and rational thought returns.
- Take the letter, Deborah.
- Just sleep on it.
She didn't even want us to know
she had a daughter...
and on the first day you take her kid away
without even asking?
- I think that's a little...
- What?
Insensitive? Elitist?
Narcissistic? Irresponsible? Perverse?
Dizzy? What?
Stupid.
When is anyone in this damn house...
in this damn life
gonna consider my feelings?
I tried to make a lovely kid feel welcome.
There is no reason to rake this over.
I let it go and gave Flor the room to let it go,
which I'm sure she has.
It's over, so just get on board, pal.
I slept.
Well, I'm broke.
No, please. Don't worry about it.
You really don't have to pay me.
- Please, don't worry about it.
- I'm just kidding.
- When you count it up, give me a holler.
- I did count.
Many times. I didn't sleep. I counted.
All right, what do I owe you? Give it to me.
$640.
- Really?
- Yes.
- I'm really sorry.
- No.
All right. I don't know.
How about
we figure this out tomorrow, okay?
You even told me, you said that $5...
I know, I promised.
It's all coming back to me now.
Let me just go deal with this.