The National Film Archive
presents
Sunrise.
Based on The Journey to Tilsit,
a novel by Hermann Sudermann.
Directed by
Production design
Photography
CHARACTERS:
THE MAN - THE WIFE
THE WOMAN FROM THE CITY
THE MAID - THE PHOTOGRAPHER
This song of the man and his wife
might be heard anywhere at any time...
...a young lighthearted city person
also stayed here for several weeks...
‘‘... they used to be so happy... "
‘‘... and now he neglects the farm
for that woman from the city... "
‘‘Do you truly love me?"
‘‘Sell your farm...
and come with me to the city!"
‘‘And my wife?"
‘‘... she could drown... "
‘‘... say that the boat capsized...
and that she drowned... "
‘‘Come with me to the city!"
‘‘After the boat has capsized,
save yourself with these bulrushes!"
‘‘The rushes will hold you up...
when you are tired... "
‘‘We are going to the city!"
‘‘Don't be afraid of me!"
‘‘Protect your wife from evil!"
‘‘Wilt thou love her?"
‘‘Forgive me!"
‘‘Manicure?"
‘‘You'd look grand with a high polish!"
Farming homesteads, we pay cash!
More information - Alexandr 12705
‘‘Come again!"
‘‘Thank you- and you must come
and see us some time!"
‘‘Congratulations!
What a pretty bride!"
‘‘... I couldn't give up hope and... "
THE END