Sometimes this thought
enters my heart
So loudly that you soil your pants
Sometimes this thought
enters my heart
So what enters your mind?
Tell me
Shut up. Quiet. Silence.
Sometimes this thought
enters my heart
Who am I?
- I know
You go to work and come home
every day
The boss yells at you.
You tell no one
You're one of hundreds,
packed in a crowded bus
Warning. The audience has arrived
Go. Go.
How can I go without you?
We're connected.
Inseparable, eternally
Live and die together
Two bodies, one soul
SOS SOS Charlie come
in Charlie Security
Forgive the poor chap
A nice guy like you.
But what to do?
He's stuck between the heart
and the world. Like you
There's more to come
You see I am here
His heart's voice
The heart skips a beat
What is a heart?
The heart! The heart!
Disruptive technology
A B theeta beeta gaama
Five hundred and seventy-five
methods, fester.
He's prepared a play for you
Straight from the heart
Clap if you like it
So? Are you sitting comfortably?
Shall we start?
He did so badly,
got the lowest marks
He can't solve the simplest problem
I understand that
Ask him what's wrong
Stories obsess him
Got the money?
Let's go
Half an hour
Many years ago
A million miles away, there was
a unique land
Made famous, not by the King,
but by the Prince
A rare Prince
The heartbeat of all
The apple of all eyes
Ayodhya sang His praises
But He chose exile over throne
He who slayed the evil Ravaan...
...the one they call...
Hail shri Ram!
The forest is strewn with thorns,
my Queen
You're delicate, a Princess
The forest is not a place for you
All the world's comforts...
...mean nothing without you,
my Lord
With your hand in mine...
...thorns are flowers to me
Beware, Princess
The forest is as dangerous
as it is beautiful
Lakshman will protect you
I shall now hunt that deer
That's all
Half an hour. Go
What happens next?
End of story...money over Scoot!
A little more. Please
5 minutes
Are you done?
Grandma
"I shall now hunt that deer"
Where was I?
The evil Ravaan abducts Sita
When the noble king returned,
the Princess was gone
The evil king had taken her...
...across the seas to Troy
The King called all the Greek kings
Brothers!
Set sail a thousand ships
Fight the great Trojan war
Bring back my honour, my Helen
Wait!
Something's wrong
- What?
You told me a different story
the last time
The demon king Ravaan carried
Sita away to Lanka
So what's the problem?
A story is a stow
Same everywhere
In Ayodhya or in Greece
Laila- Majnu. Romeo- Juliet.
Alexander's Victory
The Battle of Lanka
Your story too is like all stories
It's always the same story
Ignore the why, the where
and the what
Take pleasure in the story
Are you comfortable?
Shall we begin?
The story begins with a rhythm
Starting from Time itself
Running free through words
A story within a love stow
An age- old story
The story of our new love
Who knows from where the story
flows or where it goes
Like the river Chenaab,
flowing with love
Sohni goes to Mahiwal
Her name was Sohni
And she belonged to Mahiwal
Scared of King
Vasudev crosses
the river with Krishana
Pharoah's sister picks
Moses from the river
So the day had come when...
...Sanyunkta had to get married.
Several rulers from
all over the world..
...had come to her palace,
to get married to her.
But she only liked
Prithvi Raj Chauhan.
And so the story flows on
Who does she go to?
Who calls her from beyond
society's confines?
With garland in hand...
...Sanjunkta comes out of the palace
Sayunkta!
Yamuna or Jamuna?
Joseph or Yusuf?
Jesus or Isa?
Moses or Musa?
Tell me
Brahma or Abraham?
Or Ibrahim?
A Hindu river or Indus?
Hind or India?
It's Sanjukta
And so the story flows on
The story begins with a rhythm
From the start of Time itself
Running free through words
A story within a love stow
An age- old story
The story of our new love
Who knows from where the story
flows or where it goes
Why suffer the pain of separation?
When it is you I see in my heart
I count each passing moment
Years have gone since
I gave myself to you
My eyes have been
shedding tears since morning
It's hard to describe
my love in words
Should I end my life or end
this distance?
Or fill this distance with
sweet memories of you?
"My heart's wrenching."
"I will explain you how."
"Sita."
There's the flag of
rebellion soaring high
The Emperor feared...
...the Prince would fall in love
Bring shame to his name
Helen belonged to Troy
The undefeatable Raavan
A fierce battle cry
Ranjha belongs to you
The genie appeared before Aladdin
"Your wish is
my command, Master"
You are not listening to me...
I am not asking for money,
lam asking to make a call...
A phone call...
No no phone, go...
It'll be one second, okay?
I'll just call and quickly
ask them to call back.
No, no!
Please one phone call, please...
No no no money go
- Okay fine
Bloody miser! Swine.
Die, you rascal
Thank you
- Thank you
Go, go
Please...please...
No money go
Fine
Bloody miser! Swine.
Die, you rascal
Thank you.. Go, go
Excuse me.
You said bloody miser?
I was just telling that..
- Swine..
To make one call,
it was just going to take one second.
Here.
I have to call India.
It's OK, go ahead
My bag's gone
Passport, phone, wallet
That bag one should never lose
Or someone stole it
I went back. I looked everywhere.
No one speaks English
Bloody Asterix in Corsica
Sorry.
I mean the Asterix comics
That's the reason actually.
"Asterix in Corsica,"
my favorite comic
I always thought I'd come here
one day
Phone first. ok?
Hi.
- Hi.
They'll call back, OK?
Absolutely
Five minutes
I'll just...
- Yeah, sure.
By the way, thank you.
- Please, you don't have to do that.
No, I have to do it.
I was in a state
If you weren't there...
By the way, my name is..
- Stop.
One sec.
Pause.
You'll tell me your name,
I'll tell you mine
We become friends
Where we live, what we do Say:
"Wow! Small world!"
Mutual friends
I'll tell you old jokes.
Try impressing you
I'll behave decently
Behave decently? In Corsica?
Tough finding a place...
...where no one knows me.
I can be anyone, do anything
I'm Don!
The police from 12 countries
are looking for me and I wait here...
...for Teja's gold
And you?
Me?
Yes, you
You must have a name
lam Mona
Mona Darling
I work with Teja
Should I call you Mona or...
...Darling?
Mr Don
I like it
But how can I be sure that
you have the gold?
How can I be sure that you're Don?
Proof is the law's thing
And Don doesn't play by those rules
May I ask why Teja isn't here?
Mr Teja has a dentist
appointment, sir
He's having root canal
treatment miles away
Interpol!
I'll handle it
Hello...
Yeah... dad...
Madam...hey...
Hello..
I'm a Son of a B***-
Correct. You look like one
lam a son of a hm
Again
Don?
Yes.
Bon appétit
Hello..
Name... name what?
Antoniya...
- Antoniya
Feeding the hungry was a
good move. But drinks too?
I don't know
Why? What do you plan to do?
I also don't know.
What is this place?
Where are we?
Shall I tell you?
At once upon a time...
A story begins
Will the story be good?
Always the same
Boy meets girl,
starts hitting on her
Like it's his duty
Tries to impress her
Makes some excuse...
touch, feel, hug, kiss
lam a boy, I'll play my role
I'll plot, create situations
To hell with Corsica!
Figure out how to touch you,
get physical
Oh no! Then I'll have to play
Miss Touch-me-not
Keep a safe distance from you
Then I'll have to behave
No.
Hold myself back
No, no
Hold back? In Corsica?
What to do?
Shame is a woman's wealth
I won't...
What?
...be a rascal
Move.
Don't hold back. I'll be good
You'll see
I give you my word
Understand?
"As long as I breath, honey"
My passport arrives in 7 days
I'm here for a week
I'll soon have cash
I'll be broke by then
No introductions
We could be anyone,
I don't know
No talking?
No talking the truth
Let's promise
We lie about our lives
Speak nothing but lies
And after Corsica,
we'll disappear. Magic!
Never meet again
A twist in the story.
A story like no other
So whatever happens,
happens here
And what happens in Corsica...
Stays in Corsica!
Strolling down the open road
Showing off big-time
Hail rained down on me
No umbrella to my rescue
Can't decide
Shall I run or get drenched?
And then I thought,
dry up what's soaked
Be it female or male
Attention
She played a new ruse
And tricked me again
Trapped me for no reason
Curse you, O life
She played a new ruse
And tricked me again
Trapped me for no reason
Curse you, O life
You know...
You're the one
I played tag with
You're Laila, Shirin, Sohni, Juliet
Don't seek me in the forest
I am on WhatsApp
This is not your era or my era
Not female or male
Take the bait
She played a new ruse
And tricked me again
Trapped me for no reason
Curse you, O life
You're the one who...
...tugged at my dhoti
Where do you seek me?
I'm not in Kaaba or Kashi
I am on Twitter
Listen, O beloved
My heart betrayed me
When I set eyes on you
I lost all senses
My weeping heart whispered
My eyes now speak for me
I see a new dream every day
My restless heart cries out
Don't hide behind that veil
A devoted lover...
...can only talk of love
The heart may lament
So...
Baby, I have news
The gold will be hidden
behind the lighthouse
And handed over to Don
Gorgeous Mona Darling
is handling the transfer
I'm sure you know the name
Where's Teja?
Still at his dentist's
On behalf of Interpol,
I'll arrest the lot
Unarmed
The time is right, baby
If you trust me, then follow me
I wonder what secrets
are hidden in the case
It's so heavy
A little burden scares you?
I'm from Interpol.
It's my duty to tell you
Your beautiful valley is visible
So now what?
Meaning?
Why did you call me here?
For sex, no?
What utter nonsense!
I'm an Interpol officer
Don't Interpol officers have a pole?
Disgusting!
Hear this
Extras cost extra.
No whining later
Extra for ***
And I don-t ***
How wonderful!
Welcome to Corsica.
Say it
What is it? Why so sad?
You're usually so cheerful
Obviously, I know
I see!
A tunnel in my jail?
Drop it
Not here
Home is OK
Packed like sardines
Do your own thing
- I'm all yours
- Hand is God
- Sister by day, wife by night
- Wife by night?
- This bikini will slip off
- All B Grade
Yes!
I see you..
Excuse me... hi... Me parle-vous no French...
Can you help me please...?
Yeah.
And how you say;
Are you free this evening?
Yes, correct.
Come here!
Hurry UP!
Come on.
Buy me a drink?
- Come on.
And how do you say
"Will you take me out this evening".
Excuse me.
Welcome to India, Sambar-vada,
Medu-vada, Pav-vada
Very, very nice. Namaste
What must I do?
Beg on the streets?
Beg for alms?
You should've thought about
that before betting
Look. Can you see an expensive
restaurant nearby?
God, if only
You had made me a girl...
...l would've sold my honour
to feed this glutton
What do I do?
Are you listening, God?
You're too cool, God
Come on.
What's the plan?
- Don't know
Padre. Padre.
She's a movie star
Madhubala making a picture
in Corsica
Welcome. Please come.
Please come.
Come, come, enjoy.
Welcome.
What a lovely dinner.
Merci! Merci!
But I will only be happy
if he cast me in his next movie.
Mousier Director, why don't
you tell them about your latest story?
You will..
Bravo. Big Indian movie director
will tell you his latest story.
Bravo. Bravo.
And then he put the gun to his head.
And he said I'm going to kill you,
prepare to die.
And she said, Merci..
Thank you God for
answering my prayers.
For one year I tried to kill myself.
I shoot myself 'Bang'...
and the chandelier fell.
I miss..
Then I take poison to die.
Next morning
I wake up with hangover.
Mama mia...then I cut my vein.
I still no die.
I get infection,
doctor give me seven injections.
My ass is soar.
Now God send you...
Hurry up, kill me. Shoot me now.
But wait...l have to pi-pi..
First I pi-pi then you kill me.
What does it matter?
Once I die I have no pi-pi,
shoot me now.
What if you kill me 'Boom'..
...and I pee on your shoe.
Ooh la-la...what a lovely shoe.
What brand shoe?
Jimmy-chu.
Armani?
I am tired of talking.
Pardon me, where's the wine?
Where?
Salute.
Pretty, pretty girls...
I've a message for you.
This Madhubala,
she and me no together.
No, no, no girlfriend.
Yes...Madhubala...free.
Madhubala available.
And in my heart...
there is lot of love, amore.
I want to give you love, come...
Take it.
Praise the Lord.
He has come to redeem us
He has come to save us
from our foes
Show mercy to our ancestors,
remember his Holy covenant
Thank you very much
What?
Just looking
That's allowed.
Remember our vow
Why?
See?
That's all you get
You upset?
Your carnal desires
are weakening our oath
What to do?
Once we make a commitment
Don't be disheartened, Princess
Why just 'ting?
We can 'tong' too
What a fun
Fun has just begun, baby.
There's more we can do
For example
ls this allowed?
- Why not?
And even...
...this is allowed
Sure it's allowed?
Why not? Why not?
No crossing the line
So can I do this?
And this too
The line is drawing close
But we won't cross it
Sure?
I gave you my word
I gave you my heart. And all
you gave me was your word
This heart will mean nothing
in the next world, Zohra Bai
Alas!
Rules and regulations are
so different there
What do we do?
Shall we run away?
Run! Run!
Why does this always happen?
Good times pass so quickly
What if Sohni just never
returns home?
Can she stay?
A day early?
There were a few phone-calls
from the ministry in New Delhi.
You can tell me when
you want to fly out.
There is a flight tomorrow.
What time's the flight?
Good bye.
The airport is an hour away
We'll never meet again
Heer is very sad
She's so upset these days
Doesn't eat or drink
Can't even complain
The embers of love
have singed her
How to face these embers again?
Heer's state,
I swear by God
ls a very bad state
Heer is very sad
She's so upset these days
Love is a matchstick,
the heart is diesel
Best to keep them apart
Thorns piercing vision
Shattering all dreams
Heer's song is broken
Who can enjoy the melody?
She once spoke so freely
Now utters not a word
People say she's senile
So utterly mad
Heer is very sad
She's so upset these days
Her heart plays
a tuneless tune
She looks pale
Her mind is like
a pressure cooker
To hell with life
She sleeps to kill Time
She blames Time
Keeps punching it in the face
Even her Dad is so worried now
Mom is sad too
Heer is really very mad
Yes, she's very mad
And none too glad too
Doesn't eat or drink
Can't even complain
The embers of love have singed her
How to face these embers again?
Heer's state, I swear by God
ls a very bad state
Heer is very sad
She's so upset these days
If you look at point
no.3 in the presentation..
...you'll see that
for this strategy to work,
we'll probably need
to get some expertise..
...and hire some technical people.
So I mean we should go back..
Excuse me, please.
- Sure.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Hi.
Remember?
Corsica! Oh my, God.
You? Here?
I come here often.
You're from Delhi
We decided never to meet again
What now?
What shall we do?
Ved
Ved?
Like Rig Ved?
Tara Maheshwari
Ved Vardhan Sahni
Your real name?
The real me
Product Manager,
MGM Tech
Listen
This is no coincidence.
I was pretending
I've often come here
because I know you do
I came to Delhi from Kolkata
on an assignment
I couldn't stop myself
Listen...don't. It's fine
Really?
- Yeah, really.
There's more
Okay-
Can we...
- Yeah.
After you.
You know since
I came back from Corsica...
...l thought it'd be OK, usually is
I don't know what it is
All this love and all
I thought how stupid I am
Why do I always behave
like this with you?
Your friends are waiting
Give me 5 minutes?
- Sure
Okay..
Listen..
Don't psych yourself out.
I'm not a crazy stalker
I promise you, I won't pile on
I know you have a life.
Probably a girlfriend too
I don't have a girlfriend
Oh, okay.
Five minutes
You did well
Be right back
Hi.
- Hi.
Looking great?
- Really?
Of course.
- Thank you.
I'll put this at the back
Thank you.
Thanks.
Would you like regular
or mineral water, ma'am?
Room temperature or cold, sir.
Bisleri or aviola.
So...here we are.
- Yeah.
Place is fine?
Yeah... Very nice...
I'm glad...
For the last two years...
...it's won Timeout's Best
Oriental Restaurant title
Yeah.
Japanese cuisine is so popular, no?
What a brand. Japan!
Countries are the latest companies,
and Companies are the latest Countries.
Have some.
So...
I'll call you tomorrow
Great
At s?
You OK?
Yeah! Why?
No, just asking.
Would you like to come up?
Let me.
Nice place.
- Thank you.
There are four apartments like this?
SQ?
Sony, did it hurt?
One sec...
I am sorry.
I put it on silent
Okay-
Shah Rukh Khan!
Please...please...
Thank you..
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning, sir!
The CSB focus
of the recent tradewinds..
...rests in the lateral
shift of consumer behavior..
...which may appear bi-polar, but it
does not take an Einstein to co-relate..
Granted that we cannot
un-google ourselves..
...from the geometrical
growth of social-media.
Why do you get nervous?
Next time don't get nervous.
- Okay, sir.
You can do it, boy.
- Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Hello.
Hi.
Good.
My plan?
You'll decide that
Okay-
So this is it, huh!
This is what they say...
love and all.
I love you too.
Why are we standing?
Everyone's waiting...
Come, $0..
Hero, nothing today?
Good morning, sir.
I would say Glo-cal.
Global, yet local.
This out-of-the-box strategy..
...follows a bottom-upward approach.
Yet has a 360 perspective...
So, how was it, sir?
Good, could be better.
Always a pleasure to have you.
Please come back soon.
Please tell the driver
to come by in half an hour.
Sir.
- Yes, boy.
Tara
I won't say meet my "boss."
I'd say meet my "guru"
Hello.
- Hello.
Everything MCMTech Telecom is today,
is thanks to this man
One man army.
His vision, his philosophy has
changed the face of Indian telecom.
Totally.
Good human in today times
Keep it up, boy)!
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday Dear Ved.
Guys, she's coming.
One sec, Ved.
Can we step out for a minute?
What's wrong?
Just come out, please.
Excuse us...
Yeah.
Ved, since I've returned
from Corsica...
It's like..
It's like you're with me
You understand?
I don't know your name
No hope we'd meet again.
But I am with you
ls it possible? To feel like this?
I never knew
Then you found me
No
I found a product manager
who lives in a city
Who is very well behaved.
Polite, decent
But...
Tara, I am a product manager.
I do live in a city
I am not Don, Tara
Nor a movie director
That was play-acting.
Role playing
This is the real me
No
Meaning?
You're Don,
and the Interpol officer
You're acting here
Now you're playing the role of
a regular guy
Who follows a set pattern
Who does things as he ought to.
It's not you, Ved
All fake
You stick your face in the
river and drink like a beast
You talk to the mountains.
That's you, Ved
What's with you?
What's with you, Tara?
Who is that? He's no one.
It's all in your head
Maybe you have imagined
that's me
This is me, Tara
Standing here before you
This is all I am
Sure?
Tara.
Yes, I am sure, Tara
Then I'm with someone else, Ved
I am looking for something else
I already have this
I don't want this
It's a mess now
Everything is ruined
But it's happened
Hi... So I am back...
There are things we must sort out
It's like this...
It's fine, okay...?
Please... let's relax...
It's okay...
Let's order the main course
Excuse me...
Look, boss, you've two options
Become Majnu
Rip your clothes off and scream
Or stay cool
You know what...I'll stay cool
Yeah... It's all good.
It wasn't going to work
What had to happen -
happens now
It's fine
No tension now
Good.
Set.
Hey Raj-U...
Good Morning... good morning...
Good Morning...
How are things?
We're going to the movies tonight
Coming?
We'll have a beer later
Where?
At the same pub we went to
after your breakup?
Why not why not...?
My girl dumped me.
Something good must happen
Keep me amused!
That's right.
I was waiting for you to feel better
But you look perfectly fine
So here
You forgot this at the restaurant
Saved me thousands
Never seen him this happy
Someone help me break up too
No problem
- And me!
Sony, it's very late
It's okay..
But I was just...
Come in
- No
I won't take time. I was thinking...
I mean...you...instead of...
Ved, look at me
What is it?
Tell me Ved...
It's not what you think
Nothing important
- Then say it
Okay
You see it was different in Corsica
We promised we'd lie.
Here you didn't have to
What?
- The truth!
You could've told me the truth
Ved, come inside
- I'm not here to come inside
You should've said I was not
on your level
Ved...
I don't know what you thought
of me in Corsica. But here?
You know what I am
A normal person. Ordinary
Ved, one second
I'm ordinary
- That's the issue, Ved
I am average. Like them all
Walking on the street, with briefcase
Ved...
- Mediocre
That's what I said, Ved.
You're not that
I know who you are
B*! You know, but no one else does
My family, friends.
Don't know myself, but you...
7 days in Corsica,
you've sussed me
No it's not fine Tara...
How could I?
It's good to let it out
What's there to let out?
Ved, just come.
- I am very sorry
I'm really really sorry.
Let it go Ved... It's fine...
Come inside
I shouldn't come inside
I didn't come here to patch up
No sense standing out here
It's late. People must be asleep
I'll wake them because I'm nuts.
I'll scream, make a racket
Make a scene
Take me inside. Hide me
Anything to control this beast
You're my life
You're my ivy
Hairstyle is terrific, boss
Hairstyle
Joining the movies?
- I wanted to
Sure, I did
Do it. What's the problem?
Only one problem
Circumstances
Parents did their duty,
got me married
I did the needful, had two kids
The wheel of time turns
Food, children's education,
wife's demands
The traffic, this rickshaw
You wanted to act?
To sing
You couldn't guess from my looks
But when I sang on stage
in Allahabad...
...the audience went crazy
They wouldn't let me stop
So you're a hero
No, sir
I'm just a rickshaw driver
Not a damn soul knows me
Inside, I am another man.
Outside, I'm powerless
Maths
I don't get Maths
Can't get the hang of it
Go on
I don't want to study
engineering, actually
It's not me, Papa
I am not interested. So...
When your grandpa came
here after the Partition...
...he had zero
No roof over his head
And a family of 8 to feed
If he had said: "I'm not
interested in working in a factory
"lt's not me,
actually, I want to play the flute"
Could the family have survived?
Would you have the chance
of doing engineering?
After two years of training...
...you couldn't even pass the
entrance exam
You wasted a year at home
You're getting admission now
thanks to my donation
You should be grateful.
Work harder out of shame
But what interests you?
Sitting under trees, telling stories
at 10- rupees an hour
Want to be a movie star?
What is your career plan?
Speak up!
Locking eyes
with dazzling damsels
Trying to lure lovely chicks
Locking eyes
with dazzling damsels
Trying to lure lovely chicks
O beauty...
Doing my duty, hitting on you
I've left decency behind
Inviting trouble on myself
I'm in hot water, thanks to you
Locking eyes
with dazzling damsels
Trying to lure lovely chicks
Spending time talking
about you to myself
Laughing to myself,
crying to myself
Torturing myself
They all mock me because
of you
Me? Who strutted about proudly
What next? The usual
The same old story.
Majnu rips off his clothes
Makes a scene in public
Thinking to himself:
"Why...where...sunny...money"
Without money, how would it be?
Just think! Forget boring facts
Be happy, eat well
Lock horns, walk the gallows.
Tear your clothes, untie knots
Whip the cream, tell the tale
Entertain them all.
Make noise, shake hips
Pour out the silver and gold
of your heart. I surrender to you
Just for you
Your slave, master, wearing a tie.
In the lift, coming to you
Doing again what I do
every day
Doing it again and again
and again
Sometimes it's your story.
Sometimes another's
What's in your heart?
The color of your heart?
What does it seek?
Tell me
Answer me
Sorry, Papa
- No, son, my donation
You realise, that's enough
lam proud of you my son...
I know you'll do well in college
All the best...
The flowers in your hair have
robbed the very life from me
Your every move has ensnared me
Tell me where are you
leading me
Slowly but surely
you've done me in
Locking eyes
with dazzling damsels
Trying to lure lovely chicks
Locking eyes
with dazzling damsels
I pray you get your dream girl
Thank you
Good morning
Morning
Good morning sir
Where's your tie?
Forgot it?
Tiwari
It's okay boss...
It's okay...?
We're hardly selling the tie
Put it on!
Gone nuts, all for a girl
Hurry up...---
...it is finally our core values
that will harness the seismic shift
because technology epiphanies
are not a result of a packed like sardines
Eureka Moment they
are systematically produced
and the Devil is in the detail
what difference does it mane
plus the Blue Ocean Strategy
is call it what you want IP driven
and favors the backward
integration process
Why, sir? I wasn't nervous today
Not the point
The client looks happy
You were talking crazy stuff
Crazy stuff?
Anyway...
- Okay sir
and sector agnostic though
it looks from the outside,
from the inside it
is not only hello hello Charlie
consistent to our corporate
DNA but also organic to the
new drivers of economy
Patparganj and since...
all points of convergence
are known to us-
Very amused, right?
Yes!
You know you'll get sc
Badly
You'll get sc*
Bastard
It's come to this
Went nuts over a girl
Ved..
Hi, Tara
Sorry, I saw your missed calls
How are you?
- Absolutely fine. You?
Can we meet?
Why?
I want to see you
That's not why I called
I just wanted to apologise
I want to see you, Ved
What is it? I'm fine
Where are you now, Ved?
Can I come over?
I'll wait, if you're busy
OK
Hi
Oh, hi
Dicey, eh?
Should we? Yes, no?
Better
Hello, how are you?
I won't do anything crazy
What did I do the other day?
Ved...
I came here to tell you
it's my fault
HOW?
Because you rejected me?
Because I said something...
...acting too smart
It disturbed you
I think I touched a raw nerve
in you
I want to say sorry
Then say it
Say $0")!
Go on, say it
What are you?
A psychiatrist?
Am I your patient?
I'm concerned
That's mighty helpful
Wow!
I'm feeling well these days
Great, thanks
Ved, I'm sorry
I take back everything I said
to you the other day
Where's the ring? I want it
Everyone can see how happy I am
Ved.
Don't get physical
Leave it, Tara
- Please, Ved, sit down
You're in love, crazy girl
Yes, Ved
But with someone else
You belong to someone else,
O muse of poetry
Tara, listen
I can't predict my reactions
So I'll go
- What have I done wrong?
Sorry
You're so great, Tara
I could worship you
See...
...what I become
when I'm around you?
Your negativity
Ved, it's a passing phase
It'll be fine
- Stay away from me
I might do something
That's the problem
I can't stay away from you
Betraying your true love?
Ved seriously...
No, seriously, Tara
You're compromising. Right?
Wait. Don will return
He'll come back some day
Wait for him
Ved
- Tara
I promise I'll make things right
Don't you get it? Let me go
I won't let you go
Stay still, let the moment pass
Let the heart settle
But how do I stop you?
My sorrows would slip away
If you let me fill my eyes
with you
Talk to you without words
If you were by my side
Flowing as one
Like a lake and river
Your world makes my world
I will mould myself in your image
If you were by my side
Your eyes hold your dreams
Dreams full of disappointment
You believe that feelings
of the heart...
are merely deceitful words
If you were or not by my side
Doesn't matter
Life was cruel
And still is
If you were by my side
Let the heart settle
Every sorrow would slip-away
If you were by my side
These days would pass
ls it all right, boss?
Okay sir.
Shyamji Jewellers?
I'm returning the diamond ring
It can't lose value
Charge the next buyer
You have no heart
Good morning
- Good morning sir
Hi
- Hi
- Hello...
Good morning
What's wrong with him?
Give me something!
Hey hero!
God bless you...
such a kind man...
...in the current socio-political
climate where consumer is king
and companies are the new
countries night show Priya Cinema
MCM Tech Telecom continues
to remain mission driven, not money
driven as it rejects
block and tackle zaalim lotion
five hundred and seventy-five
methods, fester.
Organic growth avoid disruptive
technology A B theta beta Gama
measure success square root 74.7
to the power n by the impact
on Lado Sarai, Malkagunj,
Teriyaki, King Kong, Mon Amor...
What's happening to me?
Something's wrong
Sure, something's wrong
But sir, this job is all I have
I don't want to lose it, sir
Listen, boy, your behavior is
always A- 1
Your work is average.
Yet you survived all these years
Only on good behaviour
You're decent,
polite, nice...everyone likes you
And you're doing this?
All for that girl
What is there so much in
that girl?
Everyone has a weak moment
Even I do
I have a weak moment.
So what do I do?
I put in more effort
More focus, focus!
And you've a bright future
Just improve your work
You could be the Company's
VP in five years
Wow!
And if things go well...
...you may have my seat
in 10 years
Yes, why not?
In 15 years you could be like me
Oh, s* No!
It is possible
Impossible! Tell me it's a lie
No!
You're going to yell again
Now go for it, boy
Send security
I was very wrong.
Can you forgive me?
Tell me. Say it
Please sir!
Will you forgive me or not?
Go on, forgive me
Raw
Won't you forgive me?
Security! Throw this man
out of the office
I'll ruin you, ruin you
The beauty is here to face
punishment for loving him
May no one throw a stone...
at my crazed one
What's happening, boss?
Please I beg you
"Please I beg you"
Drama
Hello... How are you Ved buddy?
Fine...
So wonderful to see you.
You're fine...? Hmm...?
Are you OK? All good?
Actually, no, I'm not fine
In a bad way. I've been fired
Security threw me out.
So I sit at home all day
I wake up at nights, anxious,
in a sweat
I had my appendix operated
It's been leaking ever since
And fungus is growing
inside my body
The scrotum? In Hindi it's...?
- I don't know
Algae in my scrotum
I know it doesn't happen,
it's all psychological
What are you doing?
- He asked
Four times
Everyone says:
"How are you?"
Why? They don't want to know
Very funny
I'll tell you
I swear I tell you today
Let me go...
He's mad...
He assaulted me...
He is dangerous... He can't
be walking around like this...
You are someone else
You know it
The world...
...sees only a mask
You are someone else
Be who you truly are
Why aren't you what you really are
Don't forget your true self
for the sake of the world
Do not torment yourself
Remove the shackles you have tied
Tell the world you are another
Tara!
Which star?
Heading where?
Where does my heart lead me?
Without my walking
The princess of my dreams
stands far away
Unreal. A mirage
Looks like water but is sand
Why make the effort?
She's worthless. Why bother?
Sacrifice everything for nothing?
Who wants gold and pearls
of the heart? Who cares...
...what's inside
Looks like water but is sand
Speak to him calmly
- Of course I will
What do you mean?
Come...
Come, son
How long will you stay?
A day or two
That's all? Only for a day or two?
Can't you extend your leave?
What's wrong?
Nothing
I am not working
- You quit your job?
Working elsewhere?
How long has it been?
It's been...
A few days
Two days, a month?
- Six months
Papa, don't worry
Six months
Doing what for six months?
What's wrong with you, Ved?
Ma, don't make a scene
- She's making a scene?
Idle for six months
Look at your face! You look like
a drug addict
I'll leave today
I'll go back, Papa
You'll repeat the same things
Remind me of my duty.
When will I be responsible?
Think it pleases me?
Repeating the same things
over and over
You're on the wrong path.
I have to drag you back
OK, Papa. I'll pack my bags
Am I your enemy?
No need for that
I'm my own enemy.
Ruining myself
That's true
Now you've said it
People without problems,
create problems
Never faced bad times
Cool...
Super...
I'll pack my stuff
Done? What now?
I am going beyond the mountains
Today I'll find out if the gypsies
found water
Get out of the world of stories,
you idiot
Think of yourself. What will
become of your life?
Who knows? Only the storyteller
knows what will happen
He'll tell me
An old man used to sit here years ago
Tell me a story
A story
I have money. Loads of it
The girl says to the boy:
"You're not whom I thought you were
"I thought you were free, but
you're stuck." She goes
The boy is shaken.
He starts behaving oddly
He's fired. He's all alone.
What happens next?
He's bound to his fate
The boy leaves the city for the
forest, lives among the beasts
He talks to the trees, laughs loudly
Seeks Laila in all things.
In every speck
This is not Majnu's story.
It's Ved's story
who?
Ved. Me
This boy lives in the city.
Not the forest
He finds everything disagreeable
Correct
People around him
are suspicious of him
They get mad at him.
Call him useless and crazy
He calls them crazy.
They are nasty to him
He cries out: "lt's my right."
Stop!
They bury him alive between
two walls
The Emperor says:
"Take the wretch away
"Throw him off the highest tower
"So Heer shan't see him again"
- Listen!
Heer cries loudly
Where is my Lord Ram?
Ravaan, standing among
the crowd of devotees...
What are you blabbering?
I asked something
What are you asking?
About my story
Who are you?
Why are you here?
What happens in my story?
You're a thief. Throw him out
Calm down, Baba
What happens next?
- What did you come to steal?
We have no diamonds or
cures or God
Calm down, Baba
He's senile
- What happens next?
You're scared.
You ask me for your story. Coward!
Who do you fear? Who is here?
You tell me what happens next
Tell your story
What's in your heart?
What do you want?
What do I want?
Heer is in your heart but you
seek her in the wilderness
imposter. Cheat!
Get out!
I said get out
Call the police
He's an imposter, a thief
He's gone.
- Call the police.
The story of this journey
Replete with questions
It starts with you
It ends with you
The story of this journey
The one I sought...
...sought everywhere
was deep within me
The story of this journey.
Replete with answers
A step taken towards you.
Soon we shall meet
Hi
Hello
What happened?
Nothing
You said you were leaving
I didn't. This is my father's house
Papa, can I tell you a story?
Yes, go ahead
Many years ago when India
was Partitioned
There was a man who lived
in Lahore
His name was the Hero
The fire of Partition
spread ferociously
The Hero had to bring
his family to India
He left his riches behind
In one night,
our hero became a zero
Sorry, mistake. He didn't become
a zero, he's the hero
He worked in a wood mill
He worked hard.
Started his own business,
built a beautiful house
Next came his son,
the new hero
Worked hard too,
grew the business
He got a job. Educated
his children well
Added rooms to the old house
And then came his son
Now this is our hero
He tried management,
engineering, office work
Say yes, look down,
happy and sad
One day many miles away,
between the heart and world
Our hero found a companion
Who said: "Hi"
Our hero said: "Hello"
The companion asked:
How are you?
Our hero said: Fine, thank you.
The companion asked:
Why are you talking like this?
HOW?
You sound like a machine
Meaning?
Wait. Where are you going?
I cannot stop. If I stop, I will die
Die?
Iam running a race
What race do you run?
- I don't know
You don't know,
so why are you running?
Everyone is running.
So that's why I am running
Why is everyone running?
Does no one stop to ask?
What? Why?
"What's that?"
What's that?
Why?
Our very own "Why?"
You don't know why
You seem to have
dialed the wrong number,
Forget it
What difference which race
As long as you're winning
I'm sure you always win
Come second?
No
Third?
- No
Fourth, fifth, sixth,
seventh, eighth?
Ninth?
'You seemed to have
dialed the wrong number.'
Train no. 721...
Stop. Forget password.
Insurance is a subject
matter of solicitation.
Please read the offer document
carefully before investing.
You're somewhere in the middle
The middle-man
Yes, I'm mediocre
You're so proud to be mediocre
Can I say something?
I don't think you're ordinary
When I'm with you I feel special
Imagine how special you are
I've never met anyone like you
Don't you think you're special?
Sorry, wrong number.
What? Did no one tell you?
That reminds the hero of something
He says:
"There was someone
who said I was special"
That's right
Who was it?
He was a snake
- A snake?
Yes! He talked rot
You're full of wonder!
A mine of diamonds
Damn imposter
Know his name?
His name was...
Childhood
My childhood
Childhood? Meaning, brother?
Are you mad?
Childhood was a poisonous snake
Slithering in the garden
Hiding behind bushes
Hood raised, ready to strike
Destroyed him when I grew up
Crushed him underfoot
I put my foot on his damn neck
and pressed hard
Destroyed
Now it's OK. Now no one says
I am special
I can live my life comfortably now
Walk, stop, smile please, mediocre...
Nonsense! A mistake
Choose your race. See if you
come first or not
You'll come first
Guaranteed. Stop!
- I cannot stop
Look at yourself
Know who you are
One day the world will know you.
Open your eyes
I won't open my eyes, I won't stop
I'll keep running the race.
I'll keep running
I'll stay mediocre
Average. Work, stop, smile please.
So our hero ran the race for
the rest of his life
And one day he died
Story over
Why?
- What's "why?"
So how was the story?
Papa?
The end's bad?
Bad ending
It's my story. We'll change the end
This is who I am, papa.
This is who I am.
I am no good at Maths. I'm sorry
The last hero is the best.
My favourite
I'll come first in this race. I know
I know you will, son
Will you keep hugging each other?
Tell us the new end
What happens next?
No one has ever given me
such a big gift
I was so happy
But what will I do with it?
The ring will fulfill
all your heart's desires
You'll see
When souls unite,
how long can bodies stay apart?
Ranjha, wander in forest or mountain.
Befriend the wilderness
You'll find your path.
Your feet will start moving
And one day Ranjha will reach
Heer's abode
Looking forward,
to the second part of your speech.
Thank you.
The discussion on the bipolar behavior
of the metropolitan consumer..
Stay cool, be normal.
They're watching us.
Keep walking
So you got the diamond consignment?
Oh, by the way.
Don 2!
The police from 12 countries
are looking for me...
...and I am at a corporate's,
settling an old score
And you?
Me
- Yes, you
You must be someone
Me?
Mata Hari
Must have heard the name
So should I call you Mata...or Hari?
Don't call me anything,
just listen
Indeed. I have much to hear
How are you? Where were you?
Actually, I was in China, training
What training?
- Chinese torture training
In exchange for the diamond,
I'll teach you
How exciting!
- No need for that
There's need.
I know unique ways of torturing
I have changed, Tara
- You'll change again
No, I was born as Don,
got corrupted later
Let me start at the beginning
The masks you're wearing
are not yours
Step forward,
tell us what lies in your heart
The path of your dreams...
...will lead you where you must go
Embrace those dreams
Tell us who you really are
Untie those shackles
You're someone else
You without boundary
Sky without limit
Be who you wish to be
You're the waves
You're the grandeur
Ladies and Gentlemen
Present...
The story teller...
Ved Vardhan Sahani.
I am convinced now
What?
You do have Teja's gold
For sure
So...
And then I thought,
dry up what's soaked
Be it female or male
Take the bait
She played a new ruse
And tricked me again
Trapped me for no reason
Curse you, O life
Listen, O beloved
My heart betrayed me
When I set eyes on you
I lost all senses
My weeping heart whispered
My eyes now speak for me
I see a new dream every day
My restless heart cries out
Don't hide behind that veil
A devoted lover...
...can only talk of love
The heart may lament
So...
'A Digital Desi Releasers Presentation...'