Launch control is having trouble
verifying mass acceleration.
Team Banzai rotational supervisor,
please confirm.
l want an electromagnetic
fuel reading from the launch.
We are T minus seven zero and holding.
Antigravity inertia reversal crosscheck.
Can we have a photographic
printout to the bunker?
T minus six zero three and holding.
Phaser positive. Latch compressor.
Multistage
axial compressor... latched.
Fuel pressure... 1800 torrs.
Commence pullback to
the launch sequence. Clear the launch.
Specific density is 2.5. Over.
You're kidding. He's still at the hospital?
Banzai hasn't showed yet, Mr Secretary.
Looks like he's got cold feet.
Well, better go see what's
keeping the boss, Reno.
Why me?
Cos l'm busy.
May l have the curved Yasargil, please?
lt's not here, Dr Banzai.
Ah, let me have the straight one then.
See, this is the part where for me
it started looking like a problem.
I mean, l wanted to sacrifice the precentral
vein in order to get some exposure.
But because of this guy's normal variation,
l got excited and all the sudden I didn't know
whether I was looking at the precentral vein or one
of the internal cerebro veins or the Vein of Galen
or the Basilar vein of Rosenthal, so one my own me at
this point l was ready to say ''That's it, let's get out''.
See, you can check
your anatomy all you want,
and even though there may be normal
variation, if you get right down to it,
this far inside the head,
it all looks the same.
No, no, no. Don't tug on that.
You never know what it might be attached to.
This is control.
02 vents are closed. Looks good.
Dr Banzai is using the laser
to vaporise a pineal tumour
without damaging
the quadrigeminal plate.
Subcutaneous microphone gonna
allow the patient to transmit
verbal instructions to his own brain.
- Like ''Raise my left arm''?
- Or ''Throw the harpoon''.
People are gonna come from all over.
This boy's an Eskimo.
You ever thought about
joining me full time?
What do you mean? You serious?
Do you have an opening?
Uh-huh. Can you sing?
A little. Yeah. l can dance.
Hey, it's Buckaroo.
We have Buckaroo descending.
We have him on the launch parameter.
lnertial control positive.
T minus five four five. Resume counting.
Hey, hey, Rawhide!
All systems righteous.
Professor Hikita says we have a go.
l'm teeing off in an hour and a half.
What's this jalopy supposed to do anyway?
- 500 miles an hour, General.
- Oh, Senator, you're so gullible.
Please clear the launch grid.
HB 88, this is control.
Driver's door check secure.
- ..B, C, D, E...
- Clear the area!
Control, this is HB 88.
Commander's voice check. Over.
Roger, HB 88. Read you. Out.
Control, this is HB 88.
Event timer started. Over.
HB 88, this is control.
APU start is go.
You are on your
on-board computer. Over.
Roger, l copy.
- Altimeters? Compasses?
- Set and crosschecked.
- Reserve brake system two?
- Closed and guarded.
- Gear handle?
- Down and in.
- Throttles and start levers?
- Closed, off.
- Number four electric hydraulic pump and press?
- On and checked.
- Parking brake?
- Set. Press checked.
- Radios, radar and transponder?
- Set and stand by.
HB 88, this is control.
lMU alignment in progress.
We show 28 degrees, 36 minutes.
30.32 seconds north...
by 80 degrees, 36 minutes.
- 14.8 seconds west.
- Synchro is aligned.
HB 88, this is control.
Ground crew secure. Over.
- lNS ram coordinates.
- Form one, fuel ticket?
- On board.
- Circuit breakers?
Point of no return. Five, four, three...
- We have main engine start.
- ..two, one.
Electronuclear carburation seems fine.
He's fast. l'll give Banzai that. But one
heat-seeking missile and he's history.
This is control. APU start is go.
You're on your on-board computer. Over.
They are reading you on the localiser
downrange. Looks good. Over.
HB 88, this is control.
Speed steady at 317 nautical.
400 and accelerating!
Horizontal velocity is expanding. Over.
- Four... three...
- Here he comes.
..two... one.
- Where's he going?
- Yeah!
He is off course.
This is Chase One. Over.
He has broken trajectory...
50 cylinder. There is an immediate
fire hazard. Do you read?
- Roger.
- Do you read?
Advise you abort. Over.
Repeat: advise you cancel phase two!
- What the hell's phase two?
- That's a big no-can-do.
Buckaroo, are you decompressing? Over.
- He's broken the sound barrier!
- Mach 1.3.
Buckaroo, do you read?
Commence braking procedure. Over.
Just be cool. She'll hold.
Axis negative.
Pneumatic pressure negative.
We are looking at 500 degrees...
We are in pursuit.
He is gaining. Over.
He's headed for the mountains!
Eject, Buckaroo! Eject!
HB 88, do you read? Do you read? Over.
This is control. Do you read?
Unsafe levels of...
Standby recirculation has been activated.
HB 88, this is control. Do you...
Hotel Brava 88 do you read?
Do you read? Over.
- What is going on?
- lt's off my scope.
This is Chase One. We got his tracks.
They go right up to a wall of rock.
Holy shit!
This is Chase Two. Chase Two.
We see him. We see him.
We have him. Chase Two reports
a visual 100 miles off course.
Banzai!
He's gone through it.
He's gone through the mountain.
lt has deployed there.
There is a minimal disturbance
in the electromagnetic field.
Antigravity inertia is normal.
Mass acceleration is diminishing. Over.
He is OK.
The vehicle is hot, but we are
showing no radioactivity. Over.
HB 88, this is control. We see you.
Welcome home. Over.
We show electrical-field aberrations
on the windshield.
We are getting a localised vibration
of the drive train and a minor oil leak.
Buckaroo, can you verify
operational capability?
HB 88, this is control.
We are reading an electrical
field aberration of 993
on your windshield, static and fracture.
Can you confirm? Over.
HB 88, this is control.
Do you hear me? Over.
We are getting localised vibration on
your drive shaft. Can you verify? Over.
HB 88, a retrieval vehicle
will rendezvous in ten minutes. Over.
Well, there it is,
tyre tracks right up to a wall of rock.
Perfect Tommy, Rawhide, Reno -
cute guys of the Hong Kong Cavaliers,
Buckaroo's most trusted inner circle.
Could you elaborate on that device,
l believe, dubbed the ''oscillator''...
- Oscillation overthruster.
- Hikita!
- Thank you, Allison.
- That dirty little Asian critter!
Tranquillisers are being dispensed
to all patients between 10 and 11 am,
Tuesday, Friday and Wednesday.
The sound barrier crumbles,
and then the dimension barrier.
lt was, Buckaroo Banzai said, exactly like
Professor Hikita had glimpsed in 1938
through the overthruster he and Dr Emilio
Lizardo put together from spare parts
in a laboratory at Princeton.
1938. Can you imagine what it
must have been like then?
Molto grazie, Dr Lizardo.
Almost ready, Dr Lizardo! Almost.
Electromagnets, they are charging.
Catapult, she's wired!
No. Not yet. No!
Whoo!
No, not yet! Not yet! l'm not ready!
- He did not go through the wall.
Holy Toledo!
Facile. Sotto, dottor.
Emilio?
..asked what he saw,
asked where he went,
Dr Banzai replied ''Vast chasms
of hissing swamp, spurts of flame,
huge thunderclaps
and gurgling rock formations.''
Lithium is no longer
available on credit.
G-sub-E...
Gesù Cristo, make the ganglia twitch.
We're home free.
Home... home is where
you wear your hat.
l feel so break up, l want to go home!
Hello, Doc. Who are we today?
Albert Einstein?
No. Lord John Whorfin.
lf there's one thing l hate,
it's to be mistaken for somebody else.
Cheer up, Lizardo. lt's Friday. l got
a care package from your yo-yo friends.
Hey, Signore...
grazie tanto.
Thanks, Doc.
l come for your TV.
You've been using too much juice.
Another 10,000 kilowatts
again this month.
lt beats me how an old homicidal
loony can use that much power.
Go on, take it! l don't need it!
Tomorrow l'm goin' home
with my overthruster.
That's terrific, Doc.
l'll make sure you get
an early wake-up call.
Laugh while you can, monkey boy.
Buckaroo, l've done
a spectrographic analysis
on the specimen you pulled
off the jet car drive shaft.
Rawhide, what do you think?
l don't care if you walked
through a mountain in Texas.
This is New Jersey, and when you
play my joint, you're just another act.
- l want some music out of you.
- You want it, Artie? You got it.
Let's rock and roll!
Ladies and gentlemen, Artie's Artery
is proud to present for a single night only,
New Brunswick's own,
the one, the only, the amazing...
Buckaroo Banzai and
the Hong Kong Cavaliers!
Excuse me.
Excuse me, is someone out there
not having a good time?
ls somebody...
is somebody crying...
out there in the darkness?
Somebody crying?
Over here. l'm sorry.
Um, could we get... could we
get her a mike and a spotlight?
Tommy, could we run her a mike?
- What, are you serious?
- Yeah, run her over a mike.
What's your name?
- Who cares?
- Right.
Well, l care. What's your name?
- Penny.
- Did you say Peggy?
No. My name's Penny. Penny Priddy.
That doesn't matter.
lt's not important.
l just... l just sponged up
a little too much Vat 69, that's all.
l'm down to my last nickel
in this lousy town,
and they wouldn't take
my luggage in hock.
l lost my room at the Y this morning.
But it's cool.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey, now.
Don't be mean.
We don't have to be mean,
cos, remember...
no matter where you go...
there you are.
- l'm gonna sing this song for you, Peggy.
- No, Penny! Who cares?
l don't have plans and schemes..
And l..
Don't have hopes and dreams..
l don't have anything..
- This is weird.
- Sure is.
Since l don't have you..
-  Yeah, l..
- Who's the girl?
Don't have fond desires..
l don't have happy hours..
l don't have anything..
- Get her outta here now! Let's go!
- Let me go! Let me go, you freaks!
- Wait. Wait a minute. Wait.
- Kill that spot. Kill it!
..festive briefing by the
Banzai lnstitute. Tomorrow...
Where you think you're going, Doc? The moon?
- No, no. Planet Ten.
- Planet Ten. Why, pray tell?
- Operator?
- Doc, put down the phone.
Operator? l wanna make a call
to a Mr John Bigbooty
at Yoyodyne Propulsion Systems
over in Grover's Mill.
And you tell him that
it's John Whorfin calling.
That's W-H-O-R-F-l-N.
You got that, honey?
- John. J-O-H-N.
- This better be collect, Doc.
Bigbooty? Of course it's me, you fool!
Who do you think?
The time has come, Bigbooty.
Prepare for my return.
Well, haven't you heard?
Don't you watch TV?
Banzai and Hikita have done it.
They have opened the window!
Si. Si. So meet me at the factory.
And get their overthruster.
And Hikita, too.
Sure. Alive.
No, no, don't worry about me.
l'll get my own ride.
Evil will not prevail. That was...
Arrivederci, Jersey.
Goodbye, goodbye to her..
- lt's the spittin' image.
- Doesn't look anything like her.
Pictures don't lie.
Hell they don't. Met my first wife that way.
lt's Peggy to these eyes. lt's the
same nose. It's the same hair.
Plus, Buckaroo has to think so too
or else he wouldn't be ready
to make a fool of himself.
Just hot off the World Watch Wire, Buckaroo.
Thought you'd wanna be notified.
Remember that old ltalian pal
of the professor's?
- Emilio Lizardo.
- Yeah.
Last night he kills a guard, breaks out of
Trenton Home for the Criminally lnsane.
Ten minutes later, he cops a Maserati
Bora. Totalled it a block away.
Holy moly.
- Maserati Bora.
- Mm-hm. That ain't all.
He's vanished. Thin air.
- Dr Lizardo. Wasn't he on TV once?
- You're thinking of Mr Wizard.
This guy is a
top scientist, dummkopf.
- So was Mr Wizard.
- Dr Emilio Lizardo is a raving lunatic, Perfect Tommy.
A vicious psychopath.
Just as soon kill you as go fishin'.
Buckaroo, look at this.
Grossly-abnormal high-altitude
electrostatic disturbance
- moving down over Connecticut.
- From the jet car, do you think?
No, not from the jet car.
Check with NORAD Command.
lt could be above-ground atomic testing
in China. Maybe sunspot activity.
Man, that's strange.
Scientists at Strategious Space Command have detected
a mysterious radioactive cloudlike
mass over southern New England.
Sources close to the National Security
Consortium have refused to comment.
Let's get on back to three
great modern country hits in a row.
- Sidney!
- Buckaroo!
- How's the patient?
- Fine, thanks to you.
- But more importantly: Congratulations!
- Thank you.
You drove right through
a mountain the other day.
You did it right after you left me at the operation.
You haven't even said anything about it.
- Didn't mention it.
- Sidney, these are my friends.
This is my colleague Dr Sidney Zwibel, old
medical friend from Columbia P and S.
- Howdy. How you're doing?
- Listen, Sidney, l'm glad you could make it.
Cos it looks like we may need an
extra hand sooner than l thought.
Aha, I see. That's what l was wondering about.
l got your message about rendezvousing
at this address. Barely had time to pack.
- Then l came here...
- l can see that.
l'm gonna snoop around.
Make yourself at home.
You know, l thought we were gonna
rehearse or something.
l'm a big fan of all you guys. l love
the comic books and the records.
l know you. You're Pecos.
- Perfect Tommy.
- Perfect Tommy. l'm sorry.
- You're Pecos.
- Pecos is in Tibet. Name's Reno.
- Reno! lt's an honour.
- Where do you hail from, Doc?
- Uh, New Jersey. Fort Lee.
- Where are your spurs at?
ls he making fun of me?
Third cell to the left. Pink dress.
Arigato.
What do you want? Huh?
What are you doin' here?
What are you doing here?
Why don't you just go away
and let me rot?
Who were you really trying
to annihilate last night?
You. Just like the papers all say.
Come over here.
Come on.
Oh, my God! Perfect Tommy!
What do you want from me?
Oh, you remind me of someone
l once knew long ago.
Was she very beautiful?
She was... queen of the Netherlands.
That's a long way
from where l come from.
Wyoming? Cody, Wyoming?
No, l'm from Laramie.
Except that l was born in Cody,
but nobody...
Do you have family?
Back in Cody, l mean?
l don't know.
See, l always felt that there was
another part of me somewhere.
Another part of you?
Somewhere, yeah.
l'm adopted.
Of course!
lf it was a snake, it'd have bit me!
- Another you.
- Anything's possible.
- Let her out!
- Hey, me too.
- Let her out?
- Yeah, let her out. l'll be responsible.
- She's a killer!
- No, she's not. And give her your coat.
Why me?
Because you're perfect.
You have a point there.
l'd like to move this thing along.
Perhaps some of you noticed we have
a motorcycle convention rolling in here.
We're a little short of time.
Besides, l don't imagine you
came here to listen to me talk.
You're right.
Without further ado, l'd like
to introduce a young man
who yesterday took our notions
of reality and turned them inside out.
Dr Buckaroo Banzai,
perhaps you can explain yourself.
Ooh.
Secretary, Senator Cunningham...
members of the world press.
30 years ago, almost to this day, my mother and
father, Doctors Sandra and Masado Banzai
gave their lives for what was then
considered to be a very insane notion...
the possibility of contacting alien life.
However, not on another planet. But here.
Maybe right inside this table...
living on a simultaneous plane
of existence with our own.
Perhaps within a mountain.
See this rock? lt's solid matter, right?
But the solid parts of this rock - the
neutrons, quarks, protons and electrons -
comprise only about
one quadrillionth of its total volume.
- How many zeros is that?
- Quite a few.
The rest of this rock
is actually empty space.
So, back in 1937, Professor Hikita here
and Dr Emilio Lizardo
figured that if solid matter
were mostly just empty space,
a person should be able to discover
a way to travel inside things.
We at the Banzai lnstitute
have at last found that way.
We have created a device
called an oscillation overthruster,
which systematically reorders matter
by annihilating electrons, positrons...
I get it. What you're saying is that
oppositely-charged particles collide,
and blow each other up in a burst of energy.
Like a tiny big bang, like a... baby bang.
l'm probably just stating the very obvious.
Shut up, Penny. Shut up.
Oh, no. lt's not obvious at all. lf it was obvious,
everybody would be doing it every day.
See, by all accounts, it appears as though
l literally went right through a mountain.
But you could take that mountain
and pulverise it...
and sift through it like breadcrumbs
for the rest of your natural life...
and you would never ever find... this.
And yet this living organism came out
of that mountain in Texas with me.
Even though l was never
inside that mountain.
The president's calling.
- The president of what?
- The president of the United States.
Oh. Here.
Later.
- ls he still delirious?
- l can't tell. It's real fuzzy. I patched him
through to a payphone down the hall.
- Do your thing.
- Buckaroo, you forgot your thruster.
Why don't you hold onto it for a while?
Any time.
Do we have the first slide, please?
What about the Pentagon?
The possibility of war
in the Eighth Dimension, Mr Secretary?
What?
lt seemed like a strange connection
even back at the bus.
Mr President?
Some kind of interference.
Hello, Mr President?
Mr President? Mr President, hello?
- What's going on?
- Maybe it's a prankster, some computer whiz kid.
Not with Elephant Bravo.
- Not with an alpha clearance.
- Alpha clearance? Hello? Mr...
Ed, go back to the bus and reroute this call to
the president's suite at Walter Reed Hospital.
Yeah, and make sure this is on the level.
We're busy people here.
Does the President call him a lot?
Pencil! Pen! Quick! Anything!
Don't touch him!
What's he writing?
Conference room!
Conference room! Let's go!
Launch thermopod.
- There they are.
- Dr Banzai.
- Don't you see 'em?
- What do you mean? Who?
Evil! Pure and simple from the
Eighth Dimension! Grab 'em!
- Lectroids! Grab 'em!
- Lectroids? He's got a gun.
OK, wise guy!
Let those gun belts hit the floor!
Nobody follows or the Prof is history!
- Where's Buckaroo?
- Get him.
- Where's the overthruster?
- Get an ambulance.
- Come on, will you just ignore them?
- lsn't that...?
Hey, wait a minute! You can't ride that!
lt's Buckaroo Banzai!
- Hold it!
- Freeze!
- l had my eyes open all day long, Burt.
- lt may not be a total loss.
- l'm about ready to go home.
- We might see something.
l hit it! It is wounded.
What'd it look like to you?
- Like a big black flying dinosaur.
- Dinosaur? lt was purple.
- That's what it looked like. lt was black.
- lt was purple. lt'll be dark before we even find it.
We get Professor Hikita
to cough up the crucial missing circuit
and then we finally get our butts off this rock!
Oh, yeah? Listen to this!
Well, what is it? What is it?
Black thermopod emergency beacon!
Here? On Earth?
- Why? John Bigbooté, why?
- Coordinates established.
Electromagnetic energy
back on route three.
- The whole top of the tree's squashed!
- Do you think it up there?
Let's wait for the cops, Burt.
What for? Are you scared?
- There's gotta be something there.
- Come on, Burt. There's nothing up there.
Well, how do you know?
Here, hold this. Hold this!
Where you going? Where you going?!
Christmas shopping.
- What's that?
- lt's a stick. What's it look like?
- Gimme some light, will ya?
- l got two guns in my hands.
- Put one of them down.
- l ain't putting the guns down!
- lt's just a tree.
- Then leave it alone!
Aagh! See, l told you!
l told you! Leave it alone!
Run! Run! Run!
- Shoot it, Bubba. Shoot it!
- l can't! lt's jammed! lt's jammed!
There's something.
There's something coming out!
- Where?
- Out of the top.
Oh, my soul!
Throw me my gun, Bubba. Throw it.
Sorry.
ls he dead?
Yeah, I think so. But look
at his face. It's changing.
And his hair...
his hair is all disappeared.
- What's that smell? You smell electricity?
- He's crackling. We're standing in water.
What is he, Burt?
ls he radioactive?
How the hell do l know?
Do l look like a nuclear genius?
He's probably from Mars.
Or Jupiter.
Jupiter? I hope he's alone.
- There's somethin' over there.
- Where?
Right there.
What is it?
Buckaroo Banzai. lt's the latest issue.
Rawhide, come in. Rawhide.
Rawhide.
Buckaroo, what's up? Where in Hades
are you? l'm gettin' a lot of static.
Yeah. That's me.
l've been ionised, but l'm OK now.
Listen, l'm switching
on the homing beacon.
Mark two minute intervals... now.
Look, we got the overthruster. But someone
shanghaied the professor right from the conference.
- Oh, the deuce you say.
- What do you think?
- Dr Lizardo, maybe?
- Yeah, l'd put money on it.
- That crate.
- What crate?
The crate they shoved in that van.
You and the guys...
go back to the house and dig up
everything you can on an outfit called
Yoyodyne Propulsion Systems.
- You got that?
- Right. Yoyodyne. We're on it.
Hand me that tarp, will ya?
Let's cover this guy up.
- Guy? What guy?
- He's got paws.
- Now what?
- Who are they?
Cover it up.
John Bigbooté, Officer.
Head of Operations,
Yoyodyne Propulsion Systems.
- There's one of our birds.
- That fella over there one of your birds, too?
The droid, you mean?
Doesn't look like anything l've seen
before. I mean, l've seen droids...
Nice night, huh?
That big thing over there attacked me.
lmpossible. No, no, no, no, no, no.
Yeah! lt's some kinda creature.
There's part of it still stuck in the tree.
No, it's a machine with 30-foot
leather wings. l think it's radioactive.
Three minutes since he last moved.
This is a fix. Something is happening.
Let's get somebody over there.
Al, you set up the grid
and get the last known coordinates.
Tommy, hop on the Marconi
and see if we got Blue Blazes
in a ten-minute radius.
But no strike teams, Tommy, understand?
l'm headed downstairs.
Keep everybody calm.
- Hikita-san.
- Buckaroo!
Repeating: intrastate outward band five.
Coded. Calling all Blue Blaze
irregulars in the Garden State.
Buckaroo... in trouble.
Will repeat coordinates.
This is Scooter Lindley, Junior Blue Blaze
irregular 41 and a half. Hang on.
- Dad! Dad! Buckaroo's in trouble!
- Say what?
Aliens from the Eighth Dimension.
l'm seeing them now.
You can see them now? Here?
Yeah, the three jerks driving this van.
Look at this. What is this?
lt's your hand, Buckaroo.
No, no, no, no, it's a formula.
lt's an antidote of some kind.
Whatever that was in that phoney call
from the president gave me information,
some electrochemical message that
allows me to see what they really are.
- What are they?
- Lectroids from Planet Ten
by way of the Eighth Dimension.
Mr Gomez?
- l got a truck on the way to help mop things up.
- ldentification?
Or else this place'll become a zoo,
not to mention a haven for gawkers.
Wait a minute. Now just a second.
- Stay put. All of ya.
- Sure thing.
We'll go ahead and start breaking it down.
Don't touch it!
l got my own help on the way.
Now, that's an order.
Go find something to crack it open.
There's a Harley in those bushes.
l want you to get out and go to the laboratory,
start working on this formula.
- l want you to synthesise it.
- Buckaroo! Give me the formula.
Oh, wow!
Peggy!
She's not Peggy, Mrs Johnson.
Sois sage, mon amie.
No. Of course not. How could she be?
- Any word from Buckaroo?
- No, l thought he was with you guys.
No, he's not. Ah, Dr Zwibel,
Penny Priddy... Mrs Johnson.
Nice to meet you.
The fellas call me New Jersey.
- Well, where are they all going?
- Bunk house. Off limits.
Again, John Gomez!
John O'Connor,
there's a crowbar in the truck.
l'll get it.
Destroy yourself, John Gant.
Set detonator.
Detonator set.
My most profuse apologies
to my homeland and loved ones.
John Valuk is dead. He fell on his head.
Perhaps John Parker will get through
with our message to Buckaroo Banzai.
l said back off! Now, dammit, l mean it!
Hey! Hey, leave him alone! Ugh!
Easy, friend. Ha, Buckaroo Banzai!
Hey!
lt's Buckaroo Banzai! Get him!
Hustle up!
Scooter Lindley, Blue Blaze Irregular.
- It is! lt is Professor Hikita.
- We're closing the gate. Please, step back!
- Where's Buckaroo?
We gotta have something for him.
Try a new cipher.
- Try a G-cipher.
- G-cipher.
There...
That's more like it.
Looks like we've accessed their restricted
data file. Could be highly revealing.
No sign of Buckaroo. The professor
just rode up saying something
about space monsters and where's the
overthruster. Went straight to the lab.
Space monsters, my ass.
Hey, man, nice jacket.
What's in the big pink box?
Hey, buddy. May l help you?
Hello! Buckaroo Banzai!?
You a messenger? What you got here?
No, no, wait a minute.
l need see Buckaroo Banzai in person.
My name is John Parker.
ldentify yourself, no?
Blue Blaze irregular Pinky Carruthers.
Sorry, John, everybody
needs see Buckaroo. Later.