WOMAN: For as long as I could remember,
the four of us shared everything.
Stories...
... secrets...
... laughter...
... broken hearts.
So when we found a pair of pants that,
by some miracle, fit each of us perfectly...
... we took it on faith they'd come
into our lives for a reason.
That summer and the two that followed...
... the pants had the magic
of keeping us together.
No matter where they found us.
[BLOWS WHISTLE]
BRIDGET:
Bring it in!
CARMEN:
They saw us through times of love...
... times of loss...
MAN: Congratulations.
- ... and times of change.
And those moments where you
feel your life just lift up...
... and take off.
Let go!
That fall when we left for college, I watched
each of my friends settle into a new life.
- Cut!
- Tibby was at NYU.
Bridget made the soccer team at Brown.
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[CROWD CHEERING]
And Lena? She was on scholarship
at Rhode Island School of Design.
They made it look so easy,
fitting right in and making new friends...
... while I was at Yale just waiting
for something to feel real or familiar.
I was lost without them, especially when
it felt like my mom was moving on too.
I believed that the Sisterhood
could survive anything.
But maybe the pants had done
just about all a pair of pants could do...
... and the rest
we had to learn on our own.
How to become ourselves
without losing each other.
[MAN SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
LENA:
Kostos?
I'm so sorry, Lena.
I know how much Bapi meant to you.
It's good to see you.
- These past few months have just...
- Lena.
I've missed you.
I only broke up with you because...
[SPEAKING IN GREEK]
Lena...
...this is Melia.
My wife.
WOMAN:
And treachery in me, your queen.
Wait, Kostos got married?
Yep. Apparently
there's a B-A-B-Y on the way.
Oh, my God!
I didn't get the whole story.
You have to Heimlich it out of Lena.
Well, she must be devastated.
Wait, why didn't she call me?
I hardly hear from her, or any of you.
She was probably planning on
telling you when school's out.
Listen, I gotta go.
I think I just found bliss.
- Love you.
- Okay, l... Love you too.
[ROCK MUSIC PLAYS
O VER SPEAKERS]
CARMEN:
Here you go.
- Hold this.
- How was it?
It was great. One of your best.
Excuse me! Out of the way!
My God, there is nothing more
invigorating than a full house.
Here, take it down.
I just want to get this dress off.
I can barely breathe. Perfect. Thank you.
You're welcome.
- These came for you during intermission.
- Oh. Great.
She's consistent. My mother sends
two dozen yellow roses...
...every time she doesn't show up.
Let's see.
"Sorry I couldn't be there, darling.
See you in Vermont." Of course.
Have you ever been to Vermont?
- Vermont?
- Yeah.
I'm doing an acting internship at the
Village Theater Arts Festival this summer.
My mom will have to go to that.
A lot of her friends will be in it.
Professional actors.
We actually get to work with them.
Hey, Carmen, they're always
looking for people backstage.
I could pull a few strings
if you're interested.
Oh, wow. That's really nice of you...
...but I made plans to go home,
because my mom's pregnant...
...and we're moving, and my friends
would kill me if I wasn't home.
- But thank you.
- Yeah, I understand.
Dad, I'm home.
Dad?
FATHER:
Bridget.
Hey, honey. I didn't expect you
home so soon.
I know, me either.
You hungry? Want a slice?
Favorite recipe.
No, it's okay, I ate on the road.
So how's school?
Good. Yeah.
How's everything with you?
Good. You know, same.
Yeah.
Okay. Great.
Um, I guess I'll go unpack.
Get some rest.
Mom!
CHRISTINA:
What is it?
CARMEN:
Where's my stuff?
We just wanted to get a jump-start
on all the packing. It's gonna be fine.
- Here are your towels.
- Thanks.
CHRISTINA:
David, is this the box you wanted?
DAVID:
Let me see it, honey.
Welcome home.
I'm sorry I'm late, I'm sorry!
I didn't pack the boom box!
But I'm here!
And it's so good to see you!
It's been too long.
Your piercing closed up!
I know, right? Cool in Bethesda,
passé in the Village.
Here, hold this.
- Why are these open?
CARMEN: I got hungry.
- Hi, Bee.
- Carma.
- Wow, you came prepared.
- Well, it's all that theater work.
- Theater work? Acting?
- I always said you were a drama queen.
Thank you, but no.
It's behind-the-scenes.
Does this mean you're gonna be able to help
me with my screenplay for summer school?
Summer school?
Well, yeah, I got an incomplete.
I was supposed to write a romantic
comedy, but my characters broke up.
- You're gonna be in New York the summer?
- Yeah, it sucks.
Brian will come visit you every weekend.
Because the guy worships
the ground you walk on.
Don't you just hate that in a guy?
BRIDGET: Take these.
- Bee, be careful.
If you fall, I'll laugh.
LENA: It always makes me nervous
when she does this.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh!
Piece of cake.
CARMEN:
We'll be like 85 climbing up these stairs.
You not gonna be able to do that again.
Okay, Tib, please come out
of downward dog.
TIBBY: Okay.
- Pants.
Check. Junk food.
LENA: Oh, wow.
CARMEN: Check.
Have some chips.
Cheesy '80s music, check.
[C YNDI LAUPER'S "GIRLS JUST
WANNA HAVE FUN" PLAYS ON STEREO]
- I forgot. What do we do first?
- Carmen goes next and she does the:
"Blah, blah, blah, rules one, two,
and three of the pants. Blah, blah, blah."
Prayer, and we hold hands.
And then we all sit around and pray.
That's very sentimental, Tibby.
I'm just saying. We've been doing this
for a couple summers now.
- We don't need the ritual every single time.
- Why not? It's not any less important.
Okay, you guys, let's just keep
the same rotation. Okay?
So, what, now you guys
don't care about it either?
We care.
Carmen, we've done this a million times.
It's not that big of a deal anymore.
So if we just keep going as usual, you have
them for a week and you pass them on.
TIBBY: Bee's next.
LENA: Don't take them on your digs...
...with those corroded bones
and corpses.
I'm sorry I'm not painting
in a studio all summer.
Wait, what are you guys talking about?
Bones and studios, what is that?
I got accepted into this
archaeological camp in Turkey...
...so I'm gonna go there for the summer.
- Didn't you get my e-mail?
- No.
I'm taking a figure drawing class.
Cool.
What are your plans for the summer?
Um...
I'm going to Vermont.
Really?
Yep.
Vermont.
Can't you take me with you to RISD?
I'll die of boredom here, I swear.
Come on, I'm your sister.
- I thought you were going back to Greece.
- Not until August.
Oh, God. Okay, that reminds me.
What should I do about Kostos?
What do you mean?
You know, if I see him, what do I say?
Or do I not say anything?
God, what if I see him with her and
she's, like, all out to here and everything?
I don't know.
We agreed to see other people,
so I knew there was a possibility he'd...
That he'd date someone, not get her
pregnant and have to marry her.
God, whatever. Just talk to him,
don't talk to him, I don't care.
WOMAN:
Effie Kaligaris, we have to go!
Yeah, coming!
Hey, Mom, can we pick up Ashley
on the way?
Why didn't you tell me
she'd been writing all these years?
Where did you get these?
Where you hid them.
Your mother and I weren't on
speaking terms with Greta.
- It was in your best interest...
- My best interest?
What, to make me think
my own grandmother didn't love me?
You had no right to do that to me!
I had a right, Bridget.
I'm your father.
It's my job to protect you.
Protect me? From what?
I can take care of myself, Dad.
In case you hadn't noticed,
I've been doing it for years.
- Over there is the Ford Theater.
- Oh, cool.
- I'm so glad you changed your mind.
CARMEN: Me too.
JULIA:
Thank God for summer theater, huh?
Julia, Julia, Julia, darling.
How nice to have you
back with us this season.
JULIA: Thanks.
- How's your mother? Working?
Of course. But she sends her love.
Tell her love should not be sent.
Carmen, this is Bill Kerr,
our brilliant director.
KERR:
Uh-uh-uh-uh.
My actors are brilliant,
I merely facilitate.
JULIA:
Carmen is one of my friends from Yale.
Yale. Well, I shall try not
to hold that against you.
- Welcome to the theater.
- Thanks.
KERR:
Charming.
JULIA:
He's like family. God, I love this place.
As you may have heard,
this season on the main stage...
...we will be mounting The Winter's Tale.
And, as is tradition...
...acting interns will be
assigned roles in the ensemble...
...with the exception...
...of one sacrificial lamb...
Is he drunk?
[JULIA LAUGHS]
Ladies.
Sorry.
- Who will be cast in a leading role...
...and have the great good fortune
of working very closely with me.
Margaret.
Auditions begin tomorrow at...
...9 a. M?
By my troth, an hour I know not well.
[LAUGHING]
I would like everyone to prepare...
...a monologue or
a scene from the play.
Oh, God, I could vomit, I'm so nervous.
Are you kidding? You're gonna be fine.
I'll run lines with you.
Thanks.
Hello and welcome.
I am Professor Nasrin Mehani,
director of the university program.
Let me show you
where you will be working.
Shall we?
I'm guessing you're a virgin.
Pardon me?
To figure drawing, I mean.
You look a little nervous.
Nervous? No.
Oh, God, no.
I've never officially
taken a class before...
...but I've been sketching people
my whole life. It's a model, right?
It's not like I know the woman.
Talk that much
when you're not nervous?
Actually, I don't normally
talk this much, like, ever.
Good morning, everyone.
Please grab an easel and let's get started.
Leo. We're ready whenever you are.
Have fun.
Relax your strokes, Lena.
Find the areas of tension
within the pose, and then...
...feel the contours
as you move through them.
Okay.
ANNIKA:
Okay, that's it for today.
Thanks, Leo.
He's a nude model,
Lena, not a porn star.
Hey, Tibby? The return box is so jammed,
nothing'll fit through the slot, do you mind?
Yes, I absolutely mind.
It's inconsiderate of the customers...
...and interferes
with the timely collection of late fees.
I'm gonna call you back.
- But, Tibby...
- Just send the sketch.
- Hey.
- Should I have called?
- No, I love surprises.
- Good, because...
MAN: Tibby!
I'm with a customer!
Hi.
Happy anniversary.
It's 10 months today. And I thought...
...we should celebrate.
You have a good memory.
I'm a romantic guy.
And I have a calendar on my cell phone.
[PLASTIC CLATTERING]
MAN: Tibby!
- Oh, God.
[HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYS ON STEREO]
You convinced your boss
to give you the weekend off?
I told them the creators
of "Dragon's Lair"...
...were giving me a lifetime
achievement award.
- No, seriously.
- I told them the truth.
That I had to see
my favorite person in the world.
Oh, and you too.
Well, your favorite person in the
whole wide world is clearly incompetent.
Help.
You have to... Well...
[LAUGHS]
Okay, that was way too simple.
How's everything so simple for you?
Everything's simple.
I mean, you don't play games...
...you don't take three days
to call a girl back.
Would you like me to give you
a simple answer?
Go on.
Because... I love you.
- That simple, huh?
- Yep.
- It's that simple.
So you just use the L word
and I'm supposed to...
...swoon?
Get a little emotional?
That'd be nice.
Okay.
I'm not gonna fight you here.
I know you really want me to, but I can't.
- You sure?
- I think so. Okay.
TIBBY: So now that we have
a new anniversary to celebrate...
...I just want you to know
that even though I am a feminist...
...I still do enjoy a nice box
of chocolates.
And I don't hate all poetry.
You okay in there?
What's wrong?
Uh... I think, um...
I think we had a malfunction.
It's not a computer. What do you mean?
It broke.
I don't understand.
Those things last forever in landfills.
- When did it break?
- I don't know.
Look, I mean,
I was a little preoccupied, you know.
- Are you sure that it was a real one?
- Of course it was real.
My uncle gave it to me for graduation,
you know. I was saving it.
For two years?
Brian...
God.
What was I, just like the first girl
to say yes?
Of course not.
I wasn't the first girl?
No, I mean, of course you are.
Bathroom.
[DOOR OPENS]
Tibby...
...Iook, I understand that you're worried.
I'm not worried.
I just have to work on my script,
you know, because it's due soon.
It's okay.
You sure? Okay.
MAN: It's gotta come down at least
six inches. It's gotta clear it.
Can we hold the work, please?
And the rest is silence.
Lan, it's your time.
What you do still betters what is done.
When you speak, sweet,
I would have you do it ever.
[CLICKS]
And for the ordering your affairs,
to sing them too...
KERR:
Lan?
CARMEN:
Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
I'm sorry.
Are you okay? I don't know what
happened. Are you okay?
As long as it wasn't
a comment on my acting.
No, I wasn't even watching you.
- Now, that hurts.
- No, that's not what I meant.
KERR:
Where the hell is the technical director?
- Okay, you're fine.
- I'm fine.
- Okay.
KERR: Go around. Go around. Please.
Okay. Sorry.
KERR: Lan?
- I'm okay, Bill.
MAN:
I think it's a jaw.
BRIDGET:
Oh, awesome.
See? Should've brushed more.
Hey, guys. Cheese!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[LAUGHING]
Have a seat. Good day in the dirt?
Great, I almost have Hector
all the way out.
Hector. Very heroic name.
What makes you think it's a he?
The size of the skull.
We found a female skull last week.
And what did you name her?
Cleo.
I've been searching for the last few bits of
her because her skeleton's almost complete.
It really doesn't get to you, does it?
No, why would it? I mean,
these people are way long gone.
And what is "way long"?
How do you calculate the moment
when a person's death becomes scientific...
...rather than emotional?
I don't know. I guess when the last person
they knew died.
Then you, my friend, have a thing
or two to learn from the Greeks.
Well...
Come on! Bridget, come on!
- Go, go.
- No, only if you come.
- No, I'm tired.
- Come on. No, you're not tired!
BRIAN [ON RECORDING]:
Tib, it's me, again.
Look, I really just... I just want to talk
to you. Can you call me, please?
CARMEN [ON RECORDING]: Hey, it's
Carmen. What rock are you hiding under?
Haven't heard from you in a while.
Call me back.
BRIAN:
Tib.
It's Brian.
Oh!
Okay.
BRIDGET: Lenny, I enclosed with the pants
a little bit of ancient dirt...
... and a picture of me
with my new boyfriend, Hector.
Not exactly the lively type,
but he's got the wisdom of the ages.
LEO:
Aren't you a little early?
Oh.
Pretty sure class doesn't start
for like 12 hours or so.
Yeah. I just thought I'd come by
and get in some extra studio time.
What are you doing here? Is this yours?
In exchange for the modeling,
they let me use the studio at night.
- It's okay if you don't like it.
- No, I like it. I like it.
I really wish I were brave enough
to try something like that.
I'm sure you have your own style.
I'm Leo, by the way.
We didn't formally meet.
I mean, I was at the, I saw...
- The class.
- Yeah. I'm Lena.
Lena. Interesting jeans, Lena.
Oh, yeah.
It's a long story.
I like long stories.
Who knows? Maybe you could
tell me one over dinner sometime.
I like dinner.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Great.
IAN:
Are you stalking me?
Oh, God, it's you.
Shouldn't that be my line?
Oh, no, mine would be,
"Oh, bollocks, it's her."
I'm British, you know.
Really? And here I was thinking,
"He does a really good accent."
Gets them every time.
May I?
Sure.
So did I screw up your audition?
Yes. I didn't get the part.
- Really?
- No, not really.
Ha-ha.
It was more of a formality.
I played Mercutio in Bill's
Romeo and Juliet last year.
That's very impressive.
Did you make a good death?
- Excellent.
- There aren't street fights in A Winter's Tale.
Just your basic poisoning,
child abandonment, obsessive jealousy.
Yeah, a more sensitive side
of Shakespeare.
Have you thought about auditioning?
No.
No. I'm pretty sure
I'm right where I belong.
Belong? According to?
Right. Um, okay, bye.
Sorry, I don't even know your name.
Carmen.
That's definitely not a backstage name.
MAN:
Goal!
I'll get it.
[YELLS]
[COUGHING]
Bee! Bee! Are you okay?
Jesus, Bee,
what the hell were you thinking?
WOMAN 1: I hope she's okay.
WOMAN 2: She looks okay.
We have rules for a reason, young lady.
Okay, okay, sorry.
Won't happen again.
So any idea
what the room was used for?
I'm guessing it was the gynaikônitis.
Gynaikônitis means
"women's quarter" in Greek.
It is where the women
spent most of their time:
Weaving, entertaining visitors...
...seeing to the care
and education of the children.
It is likely where your friend
Cleo raised hers.
Cleo had children? You can tell that?
You can tell a lot from a skeleton.
Look. Here.
We know that she stood
at just over 5 feet...
...and that she died around the age of 35.
The shape of the pelvic bones
rules out childbirth as the cause...
...so it was most likely due
to an illness of some kind.
Wow. Uh...
I just never imagined her that young.
My mother died at the same age,
four years ago.
I'm sorry.
I can imagine how difficult
that must have been.
So are we done here?
All set. Stay out of trouble.
Yeah.
Will't please you, sir, be gone?
I told you what would come of this.
This dream of mine.
Being now awake...
...I shall queen it no inch farther...
...but milk my ewes and weep.
Excellent, Julia.
Thank you.
KERR: Excellent.
JULIA: Thanks.
Trippingly on the tongue.
All right, thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Carmen.
What do you want?
- Bill?
- No, no, no.
IAN:
Do you have time for one more?
- Are you crazy?
IAN: You won't be disappointed.
KERR:
Yes, fine.
Shock me, thrill me.
Come on. What have you got to lose?
This is Carmen.
Hi! Wow, those lights are bright.
Yes.
- You're Julia's friend.
CARMEN: Yes.
I'm Carmen Lowell.
You don't have to write that down.
I'm not here to act,
I'm just doing some backstage work.
I'm not an actor.
Not that I don't love the play.
I love the play.
KERR:
What do you love about it?
Well, I guess mostly
the character of Perdita...
...and how she doesn't really have
a true identity...
...but she knows what she believes in
and she sticks to that.
I guess.
I don't know.
KERR:
Why don't you give it a shot?
Perdita.
Page 62.
Lan, would you be a love
and read Florizel with her?
Begin with "No shepherdess."
Ready?
I hate you.
No shepherdess, but Flora...
...this your sheep-shearing,
is as a meeting of the petty gods...
...and you the queen on't.
Sir, my gracious lord...
...your high self, the gracious mark
o' the land, you have obscured...
...with a swain's wearing, and me...
...poor lowly maid,
most goddess-like prank'd up...
...but our feasts in every mess have folly
and feeders digest it with a custom...
...I should blush to see you so attired...
...swoon, I think,
to show myself a glass.
Thank you, Carmen.
Okay. Sorry.
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
BO Y: I want a DS now! Give me it!
WOMAN: No. No. No.
I said no. No, no, no, period!
- Give me it!
WOMAN: I said no!
[BABY CRYING]
[HOT HOT HEAT'S "5 TIMES OUT OF 100"
PLAYS O VER SPEAKERS]
Hi, Phil.
Morning, sunshine.
A guy named Brian called for you twice.
Thank you.
Could you check the return date on these
for me? I think I might be a little late.
What'd you just say?
I said I think I'm late.
Is that supposed to be funny?
Hey, honey. Sorry I'm late.
Okay, I'm just going to waive
the late fee for these.
- Cool.
TIBBY: Don't worry about it.
Thank you.
LENA:
So how can I help?
- Can you throw a couple onions in there?
- Yeah.
What do your folks
think about art school?
I think they probably wish I was still going
just on Saturdays after school, but...
They just want what's best for me.
What's that, two-car garage,
house in the suburbs?
Yeah, I mean, they've worked so hard
for what they have...
...and it makes me feel guilty
for not wanting the same thing.
It doesn't make you ungrateful.
Just for wanting to find out for yourself.
Wow, everything looks so beautiful.
You cook with so many colors.
Only another artist
would even notice that.
Can I taste something?
Yeah. Okay, let's try this.
Ooh.
- You like mushrooms?
- Yeah. Looks good.
Mm. Wow.
- It's good?
- That's so good.
- You have to give me the recipe.
- Recipe? No, no recipe.
- You don't use recipes.
- No recipes.
It's like painting inside the lines,
you know?
The downside is you never know
how it'll turn out...
...but it's kind of the upside.
Okay, so how can I help?
Yeah, try the saffron. Just try not to knock
anything over tonight. All right?
LENA:
Yeah, yeah.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Beckwith, Beckwith, Beckwith.
Dorcas.
Well, at least I have a line, right?
That's good.
- Hey, congratulations.
- Oh, thank you.
I was actually talking to Carmen.
What?
Carmen.
Perdita.
No. No, no, no.
No, no, that's not right.
No, this has to be a mistake.
Did you audition?
No.
Actually, yes.
I did, but it wasn't for real.
I was just standing there.
I was watching you and...
Congratulations.
Thanks.
It's gotta be a mistake.
It's okay. I'll be happy to help you
in any way that I can.
Thanks.
Congratulations. This is a big deal.
Come on, let's go celebrate.
- Okay.
- This is great. I promise.
Hi.
You okay?
I'm fine.
Because you haven't answered your phone
or returned my phone calls.
I know. I've just been busy with the script,
you know.
I'm worried too, Tib.
I am. But until we know if this is real...
Real?
I don't mean that.
- I could get a job, right?
- Yeah?
Yes, I could get a job, I could come
to New York. We have options.
What about my options? Huh?
What if I wanted to take it all back...
...the whole night, everything?
Where's my option?
What are you saying?
I think I'm just a little weird and...
...busy, and I think
it's a bad combination.
What does that mean, like, what,
do you need space?
Oh, God.
I hate when people say that.
Yeah, because they usually mean
something else.
Like, I don't know,
you want to break up with me?
I can't finish that sentence.
Well, then why don't you call me
when you can?
CHRISTINA:
The movers are coming tomorrow.
CARMEN [O VER PHONE]:
I thought we weren't moving till August.
Oh, I know, but David felt
that we should move sooner.
Mom, guess what. I got cast in a play.
Nena, that's wonderful!
- It was an accident, but still...
- Did you tell your friends?
- Well, Julia knows.
- No, I mean your other friends.
Yeah. No. Well, they're kind of busy.
I have to go. I'm gonna be late
for rehearsal. Can I call you back?
- Yeah, yeah, sure.
- I love you.
Love you too.
Dear Carmabelle, these might have had
a miracle left in them after all.
I'll e-mail you! Love, Lena.
Hey. You ready? The read-through
starts in 10 minutes.
CARMEN:
Yep, all ready.
Wow.
- What are these?
- Oh, nothing.
- They're just an old pair of pants.
- Oh.
CARMEN:
Let's go.
Hey, Margaret. Where would you like us?
We changed the call to principals only.
We just need Carmen.
The rest of you can have the day off.
Oh.
Wow, well, good luck.
Thanks.
MARGARET:
Carmen, your seat's next to lan.
WOMAN:
Hello, dear.
Hi.
You're welcome.
Oh, I'm sorry,
did I forget to say thank you?
Thank you.
How do you feel?
Like a fake.
Please. You had them at, "Um, hi."
Morning, Nigel. Nigel, this is
Carmen Lowell. She's playing Perdita.
Hi. It's nice to meet you.
I'm a big fan. Huge, actually.
Yes, our young apprentice
on the main stage.
Was that a compliment?
With Nigel, you'll never know.
KERR:
Margaret.
The Winter's Tale by William Shakespeare.
Act one, scene one.
Hey. How is it going in the new room?
Well, apparently these women
never vacuumed.
[BOTH LAUGH]
I was wondering,
how's it going in the mortuary?
Have they found any more
graves near Cleo's?
Not yet.
Um...
I was thinking, maybe I should transfer
there, just in case they need more help.
Bridget...
...archaeology is more than just
finding bones.
These people, they painted their pots,
made their sanctuaries...
...told their stories
on every surface they had.
It is what I love most about them...
...that they left so much of themselves
for us to find.
Yeah, but...
Like you, I have lost family...
...and my home.
To a bloody war.
I'm just fascinated by what is left.
What endures.
"Tib, here are the pants.
Nothing happened. Carmen."
Great.
Give me a miracle. Give me a miracle.
And feel the miracle.
Pants, please give me a miracle.
Ohm.
And stretch the miracle back.
[GRUNTS]
I just want a miracle, please!
[MUTE MATH'S "YOU ARE MINE"
PLAYS ON STEREO]
[PHONE BUZZING]
- Hello.
- Tibby!
What's going on? You haven't answered
any of my e-mails. Are you okay?
- No.
- Well...
...I'm getting in the car right now.
Hang on. Can I bring you anything?
Pregnancy test?
Lift up your countenance,
as it were the day of celebration...
...of that nuptial which we two
have sworn shall come.
Oh, Lady Fortune,
stand you auspicious!
God, why don't people
talk like this anymore?
We've gotten so lazy.
We don't say, "Oh, Lady Fortune,
stand you auspicious."
We say, "Dear God, help me."
Or instead of, "Enjoy the honey-heavy dew
of slumber," "Yo, get some Z's."
It's not the same.
It's just, it sounds so good
and it feels so good to say.
It's rich and luscious and...
See how she lays her cheek
upon her hand?
Oh, that I were a glove upon that
hand, that I might touch that cheek.
See what I mean?
Yep.
Give me those flowers there, Dorcas.
Here's flowers for you.
Hot lavender, mint, savory.
Now...
...my fairest friend...
...I would I had some flowers of the spring
that might become your time of day...
...but these I lack to make you garlands
of, and, my sweet friend...
...to strew you o'er and o'er.
What, like a corpse?
No. Like a bank for love,
to lie and play on...
...not like a corpse, or if, not to be buried,
but quick, and in mine arms.
Uh...
Um, sorry, Bill.
I forgot my line.
Take a break.
We'll pick it up where we left off.
Do not go to drama school.
It'll ruin you.
Well, thank you, Nigel.
I'm enjoying your work too. Ah!
Carmen?
JULIA:
Let me help you.
Did anybody see that?
- No, you're fine.
- Okay.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Guess what got here
just before you did?
TIBBY:
So I thought it'd be easier that way.
Wait. You told him
you weren't pregnant in an e-mail?
If I had called him
or told him in person...
...he might've thought things could just
go back the way they were, but they can't.
Well, why not? I mean, if you're not
pregnant, then what's the problem?
I suck at relationships.
Should've been a guy.
No, a guy wouldn't worry about
sucking at relationships.
[TIBBY LAUGHS]
You know what the problem is?
Every time I try to
get close to somebody...
...it's like there's something
out there that just says, "Oh!
Tibby's about to be happy.
Better get her."
I'm not really sure what to say,
you know?
Well, maybe you're just scared.
Yeah, maybe.
Hey, I should really get back.
And leave me in the middle of my life?
God.
I'll have another breakdown if you stay.
Tempting. But I have an early class.
- Right-o.
- Come on.
I'll walk you back.
[WOMAN SPEAKS
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[NASRIN SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Look at you!
Hello.
Hi, hon.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
WOMAN: Dear Honey Bee,
how is my sweetie doing?
The summer breeze blows the sweet
perfume from our garden into my kitchen...
... and I think of you.
How you love flowers!
I'm sorry I can't visit you now.
But you should know I always love you.
Dear Honey Bee:
Sometimes I want to help your mom...
... but she thinks it is best
if I leave her alone.
I hope that she will get well
and let us visit again real soon.
Love always, Grandma.
BRIDGET: Dear Nasrin,
you deserve more than a letter...
... but as you probably guessed,
I suck at goodbyes.
You said archaeology
is more than finding bones.
And you were right.
People do have a power over us,
even after they're gone.
When my mother took her own life,
I tried to forget the past.
I ran away from the pain because...
Well, I guess I was afraid.
But the past is always with us,
and it's time I stop running.
Thank you for the lesson. Bridget.
Alas, Florizel, I know not
'tween the turkey club sandwich...
...or the Hamlet and cheese omelet.
What say you?
Well, I come not to bury Caesar,
but to have a caesar salad.
- Ooh.
- Now tell me about you.
Only child? Brothers and sisters?
Only child.
Oh, no. Well, not for long.
My mom is gonna have a baby.
It's kind of a long story.
Or not that long of a story.
- Hey. Am I interrupting?
- No, not at all.
- Great. Can we take this chair? Thanks.
- Sure.
Sit down.
Do you know Julia? Lan.
Yeah, we've met once or twice.
Lan's family are in the theater,
just like mine.
- You went to RADA with 20 of my friends.
- RADA?
Royal Academy of Dramatic Art,
it's in London.
Oh.
- Did you hear about Patrick O'Houlihan?
- Lucky bastard.
I'm hoping to catch the show
when I go to New York.
We should get a whole group of
people together and surprise him.
Sounds fun.
- Jam, on your lip.
- Oh.
You know, we really should order.
We've got a rehearsal to get back to.
Caesar salad, please.
[JAMES OTTO'S "SUNSET MAN"
PLAYING ON STEREO]
BRIDGET:
Hello?
Excuse me, sir?
Hi. Greta?
Um, I'm really sorry.
I should have called first, but I'm...
I think I know my own granddaughter.
You're not running away from home,
are you?
No, actually, I'm coming home,
from Turkey.
That's an interesting sense of direction.
So you fix your own car?
Cars are easy.
It's people you need a manual for.
Come on in. You must be exhausted.
BRIDGET:
Yep. You don't even know.
GRETA: Why don't you go right up
and get some rest?
- Hello!
- Hey.
Hey. Wow, you look great.
You think? Thanks.
So, what's the occasion?
Um, lan asked me to dinner.
I mean, I can be so dense sometimes.
I didn't even know
that he liked me that way.
- Did you?
- No.
But, then again,
I can be pretty dense too so...
I just thought he
might have said something to you...
...because you guys have become
such good friends. You know men.
So you're going, then?
You're going on a date?
Yeah. I mean, he's gorgeous,
and he's really nice, and...
...he's really real. For an actor, anyway.
I just thought, why not give it a chance?
We have so much in common anyway,
and it might really work.
I know you need sleep
before rehearsal tomorrow.
I'll be really quiet when I come home,
but don't wait up.
- I won't.
- Okay. Well, have a good night.
Thanks, Greta.
Grandma.
I'm sorry, I don't know which...
I haven't heard from you in...
...10 or 12 years.
I know.
Look, my dad,
he hid your letters from me.
I just found them this summer.
I see.
So I guess we can skip...
...junior high and high school.
How's college?
It's good. I haven't declared
a major yet, but...
Got a fella?
No, not at the moment.
Listen, you ought to kick up
some trouble now...
...because in 40 years,
they'll all tell you you're old.
You made that the summer you visited.
You must have been about
6 or 7 years old.
I've been here before?
Well, that was a long time ago.
TIBBY:
"Return to sender."
Super.
O, the fates. How would he look to see
his work, so noble, vilely bound up?
KERR:
Stop.
Again.
O, the fates. How would he look to
see his work, so noble...
KERR:
Stop. Again.
O, the fates.
How would he look to see his...
Stop right there.
Carmen, is there a problem?
No. I don't know.
Did I say the wrong line?
No.
You're supposed to sound like
a woman in love.
You sound like a woman
who's about to have a root canal.
Again.
O, the fates. How would he look to s...
I hear the drill.
Again!
Carmen, wait.
I'm sorry. I don't mean to be
screwing everything up like this.
You've got great instincts.
You just need to trust them.
Why don't we work on it together,
tonight?
No. It's okay.
I should just work on it alone. Thanks.
- Oh, my God, that was torture.
- Hey.
- All I could think about was drawing you.
- Sorry to interfere with your concentration.
That's okay. I don't mind.
Okay.
Well, I guess you have to get back
to class, huh?
Yes.
I guess.
I'll see you later.
I'll see you.
KOSTOS:
Lena!
There was no choice but to be married.
My grandfather, I think he could see
I did not love her.
And then that day at the funeral,
she saw it too.
That my heart would always belong
to someone else.
And that is when
she told me...
...there never was a baby.
We had the marriage annulled.
I wanted to tell you right away.
But I was afraid. I didn't think
I had the right to ask your forgiveness.
- Maybe it's too much to hope you could...
- Forgive you?
I forgive you.
- Lena, I thought...
- That I'd be waiting for you to come here?
No. I didn't expect anything.
I just wanted you to know the truth.
Well...
...thank you.
The truth is we loved each other
a long time ago.
And my life is so different now.
Lena, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
No, it's okay. It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
I have to get to class.
[REGINA SPEKTOR'S "BETTER"
PLAYS O VER SPEAKERS]
New York is so cool.
Mom and I, we came up to see Hairspray
and do a little shopping.
WAITRESS: Can I get you guys anything?
- Just give us a minute.
WAITRESS:
Okay.
So you and Brian broke up, huh?
I guess.
Do you think you're over it yet?
Over him, I mean?
Like you wouldn't be upset or anything if
you found out he was dating someone else?
Effie, what's this about?
I guess it's about wanting to know if...
If you'd be okay with me dating Brian?
Of course I said I didn't mind.
I just think it's a little weird, you know?
She's not even his type.
And she's really young, which is gross.
I can't believe he would actually ask her
out. Do you think he would ask her out?
Whatever. It doesn't matter.
I don't really care.
I'm just curious, you know.
It kind of sounds like you care, Tibby.
Otherwise you wouldn't be here freaking out.
Like you're the poster girl
for even tempers?
I'm just saying
you can't have it both ways.
If you didn't want Brian dating other girls,
then you shouldn't have broken up with him.
Pretty simple.
You don't have a clue
why Brian and I broke up.
Well, do you?
Carmen, I was just kind of hoping
for some support.
Not a lecture and some psychobabble.
I didn't drive all the way up here in rush hour
traffic just so you could read your book!
I'm studying my lines, Tibby. What do you
want me to do, just stop my life?
It's not like I was exactly expecting you!
I haven't heard from you in what, a month?
Where the hell is this coming from?
The fact that you even have to ask that
question pretty much says everything.
Carmen! Hey, I brought you a scone. Hi.
Thank you. Julia, this is Tibby.
Tibby, this is Julia.
You're the video-store girl.
The video-store girl.
I have to go. I have to work on my script.
Wow. So you're a writer too?
[SPEAKS IN ITALIAN]
LENA:
Nice restaurant.
You know, it's not too crowded either,
which is nice.
LENA:
It's great.
- How are you?
- Good.
LENA:
I can't believe you did all this.
Well, nothing's too good for my muse.
What? Is that what I am?
Well, I've been feeling
really inspired lately, so...
Why do I get the feeling like
something's not right? You okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
I'm sorry, I'm just thinking.
About what exactly?
What's going on?
Nothing.
This idea of a muse,
it's romantic, isn't it?
Yeah. Yeah, it's a little romantic, I guess.
I've heard worse.
Have you ever been in love?
I love being in love.
Yeah, but...
...do you think that there's one person
that we're each meant to be with?
One person? No, not really.
I know that's not the answer
you wanted to hear.
No, it's the way you feel.
I like that you're honest.
But...
...you may not be into it?
No, I am.
I wanna be.
That's two different things, right?
But, I mean, Lena, you don't need to
apologize for what you want.
But I don't even know what I want.
I'm sorry.
And I'm sorry I keep saying
I'm sorry so much.
Then stop saying you're sorry.
You don't need to apologize.
Unless you don't like the food.
Then you should definitely apologize.
Food's great.
TIBBY:
Uh-huh. Yeah, I'm gonna wear black.
Excuse me?
TIBBY:
Hold on, Mom.
Yes, I will be at the anniversary party.
Call you later.
Do you know if this movie's any good?
Well, that depends.
I mean, yes, if you like nauseatingly
smarmy love stories...
...that have absolutely
no basis in reality.
Oh. Well, what if you're in the mood for,
you know, something romantic?
I would go with
Texas Chainsaw Massacre, the remake.
- It works for me.
- Thank you! Tibby, thank you.
[PHIL CHUCKLING]
I apologize.
Is there something I can help you find?
Just forget about it, man.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Okay.
Freaking the customers out, not one of
the sales techniques we discussed.
I'm sorry.
Why don't you take
the rest of the month off?
What? No, but...
Yeah, things around here
have been slow anyway.
Though with you gone,
they might just pick up again.
Yeah.
Oh, please. Please, take anything you want.
Take it all.
- Really?
- I'm lightening my load.
Thank you.
I didn't know she went to prom.
What?
Oh, yeah.
She sure did. She was so excited.
She bought five dresses.
Took them all back,
she bought five more.
But after that, she went into
a downward spiral, got so depressed.
Slept right through her graduation.
Yep, well, that was Marly.
Two speeds, high or very low.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[BRIDGET SOBBING]
Mom!
Honey.
Bee. What, honey?
What is it? What is it?
I remember it now.
There was a storm, just like this one,
and she left me.
Even then she didn't care about me.
No, that's not true.
Why didn't you stop her from leaving me?
Why didn't you try harder?
It was complicated. I tried to help her,
she wouldn't let me.
But I was always trying.
- Listen to me, she loved you.
- Then why didn't she stay alive for me?
Because she was sick...
...and there was nothing that you
could've done to make her better.
You hear me?
That summer,
your father brought you to me.
Things had gotten bad with your mom...
...and he wanted you to be here
while he tried to get her into a hospital.
She wouldn't let us in her life unless
we pretended that she wasn't sick.
Your father had to pretend.
I couldn't.
She wasn't strong like you are.
You're different.
The only reason she hung on as long
as she did is because she loved you.
She loved you. You hear me?
Brian's on his way to pick me up and
I can't find my hoops. Can I steal yours?
Wait, Effie, you're going to Tibby's parents'
anniversary party with Brian?
Yeah, she said she was over him.
Effie! That's not the point.
You don't date your friend's exes.
Well, they're your friends, not mine.
You've shut me out of your little group
my whole life...
...so that rule doesn't really apply to me.
[CRAIG DAVID'S "FRIDAY NIGHT"
PLAYS O VER SPEAKERS]
GIRL: Brian!
BO Y: Effie!
- Brian.
- Hey. How are you?
- So, what'd you think?
- I thought it was great. Everyone was good.
WOMAN 1:
Hey, Effie.
WOMAN 2:
Happy anniversary, Mrs. Rollins.
- Hey.
- Hello.
You know, I didn't know
if you'd be here, so...
How's the script?
Good.
It's a romantic comedy.
Which is an oxymoron.
Right.
- What's...?
- Uh...
- I should pr... Huh?
- L...
- No, go ahead.
- What? No, l...
Jinx.
Back at you.
Effie's waiting for you.
What?
Effie.
I'm gonna get more quiche.
CARMEN [O VER PHONE]: Hello?
- Carmen?
Are you okay? What's wrong?
I'm at the hospital, honey,
the baby's coming early.
Now? Well, where's David?
He's flying back from a business trip.
Okay, okay, I'm coming.
Mom, I'm about to start
a dress rehearsal.
I'll figure something out.
I'll be there. I'm coming.
You do what you have to do. I'll be okay.
I just wanted to let you know.
Okay, I love you! Oh, God.
[PHONE CHIMING]
What? Yes.
Tibby, it's me. I'm sorry to call you like
this, but I don't know who else to call.
What is it, Carmen? What's going on?
It's my mom. She just went into labor early,
and I can't be at the hospital.
- I'll be there in five minutes.
- Okay, thank you.
I'm coming!
[SCREAMING]
Again? Oh, boy, you're having
another one of those, huh?
How's it going in here?
Those ice chips are not doing squat!
Look at her. You have to
give her one of those, the needle.
She elected to do...
...natural childbirth.
Are you crazy?
Lady, dear Queen,
who ended when I but began...
"Give me that hand of yours."
- Give me that hand of yours...
- "To kiss."
...to kiss.
KERR: Stop.
Okay, Christina,
I'm told you are ready to push.
No, no, no. I have to wait for David.
She's gonna wait for David.
She should wait for David.
Do you have something to help her wait?
DOCTOR: You need to stop fighting
and let go. Push.
CHRISTINA:
I can't!
Christina, listen to me, you can!
You can do this.
I'm here, okay? I'm here for you.
Okay? Just start pushing.
I'm not gonna leave you.
We're gonna do this together.
Okay, you and me, we're gonna do this.
Okay. Okay. You ready?
All right, you're gonna push.
Beseech you of your own state take care.
This dream of mine, being now awake...
Um...
I'll queen it no inch further, but...
[BABY CRYING]
DOCTOR:
There he is.
My beautiful baby boy.
TIBBY:
He's really tiny.
And purple... Perfect!
Oh, my God, he looks like marble.
Carmen would be so proud of you.
She would've been proud of both of us.
I couldn't have done it without you,
Tibby.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for being there, Tib.
She was so lucky to have you.
No, no, no, don't wake her up.
Just give her a kiss.
And give the baby a kiss too.
Okay. I'll see you soon.
IAN:
Good news?
Yeah, I have a baby brother.
Congratulations!
Thank you. I'm sorry,
I don't know why I'm crying.
God. I just...
I can't believe I wasn't there.
You know, my whole life it's been me
and my mom...
...Iooking after each other.
And I don't know, I just...
I recently feel so far away from her...
...and my friends.
Not unlike Perdita.
Who lost her mother for 16 years?
I guess.
I don't even know
why I'm telling you all of this.
It's bad enough I single-handedly
am ruining our show.
Everyone knows you're upset.
But dress rehearsals are supposed to suck.
Let me take you out to dinner
and we can talk about it.
I'm okay. Besides, you probably
have plans with Julia.
Julia?
I barely know the girl. We had dinner
once because she fairly begged me.
What, she asked you?
Carmen, if there's anyone I've been
wanting to go out with, it's you.
I understand this isn't the right time.
I'll see you tomorrow.
JULIA:
Wow, that was just awful.
KERR:
I am simply flummoxed.
My instincts about actors
are never wrong:
Bill, you can't beat yourself up.
I probably should have
said something from the beginning.
I love Carmen, but she's very insecure.
At the end of the day, maybe she just
doesn't have what it takes.
Dad?
Oh, I must have dozed off.
How was your trip?
- Good.
Both of them, actually.
I went to visit Greta.
- Bridget, I was only trying to...
- Dad, it's okay.
She helped me so much...
...to understand these things that you
and I were never able to talk about.
And what are these things
you think you understand now?
That you loved Mom
more than I ever knew.
And you couldn't have saved her.
No one could have.
It's just who she was.
If we're gonna get through this, Dad...
...we have to start
taking care of each other, okay?
Don't you think that
that's what she would have wanted?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think that's what
she would've wanted.
I love you, Daddy.
I love you.
I'm really sorry.
That night...
...I think I felt a little more
than I bargained for.
Maybe I thought I was being punished...
...for feeling too much.
Why didn't you just talk to me, Tib?
Because I can't lie to you
as well as I can lie to myself.
You need to have a little faith, Tib.
Not everyone you love
is going to leave you.
I know that now.
So wanna get some breakfast?
Yeah. Breakfast sounds great.
CHRISTINA: This is your baby brother,
Nena. Ryan Christopher Sands.
I tried to get him to wait a little longer,
but this one's got a mind of his own.
Just like somebody else I know.
He reminds me so much of you, Nena.
When they put you in my arms
for the first time...
... I never saw anything so beautiful
in my whole life.
And I knew that from then on,
my heart would be full.
So you go out on that stage now...
... and you show them
how beautiful you are.
We'll be waiting for you...
... at home.
I love you.
Say goodbye. Bye, Carmen.
Hi. So I just want to say...
... break a leg, and...
... you deserve your day in the sun, so...
Your night in the sun.
You deserve your night in the sun.
Bye.
Jesus, Carmen, where the hell
have you been? You're on in 30 seconds.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God,
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
These your unusual weeds...
...to each part of you do give a life.
This your sheep-shearing is as a meeting
of the petty gods, and you the queen on't.
Sir, my gracious lord...
...your high self,
the gracious mark o' the land...
...you have obscured
with a swain's wearing...
...and me, poor lowly maid,
most goddess-like prank'd up.
O, the Fates.
How should he look, to see his work,
so noble, vilely bound up?
What would he say?
See, your guests approach.
Address yourself to entertain them
sprightly, and let's be red with mirth.
[CROWD APPLAUDING]
- Great job.
- You too.
Carmen, that was incredible.
Sometimes words fail.
[EFFIE SOBBING]
Effie?
Effie, what's wrong?
What happened?
EFFIE:
Brian's going back to Tibby.
Can't he see that she doesn't love him?
Well, you don't know that, Effie.
You don't treat someone
like that if you love them!
Well, it's not that simple.
You're actually taking
her side on this, aren't you?
No, I'm not taking sides.
Even though I'm your sister,
you've always chosen them over me.
Effie, that's not...
I wish I was on my way to Greece...
...so I could be out of this house
and away from you.
You know, you've barely said
two words to me all week.
You get a couple good reviews and suddenly
I'm not good enough to be your friend?
Actually, I didn't read the reviews.
Were they any good?
That's not the point, Carmen.
In case you forgot, I brought you here.
So you wouldn't have any of this
if it weren't for me.
But you didn't really give me anything.
I am who I've always been, and, sure,
maybe for a minute, I was a little insecure.
I know you did what you could
to keep me that way.
Right?
Look, Julia, I'm very sorry
if my tiny bit of success...
...feels like I've taken something
from you.
But if there's one thing
I've learned this summer...
...it's that no one can diminish you
but yourself.
And you taught me that.
So thank you.
EFFIE:
Lena.
- Lena, I am so sorry.
- What's wrong?
I did something really terrible.
What did you do?
Well, I was mad at you
and at Tibby and everyone...
...and I took them.
Took what?
The pants.
You took them? You have the pa...
You have them over there in Greece?
That's the terrible part.
You see, I wore them on the ferry
and they got wet...
...so when I got to Yia Yia's,
I hung them on the clothesline.
- I never thought that...
- That what?
Well, I don't know if the wind
blew them away or what, but they're gone.
Look, they're not lost. She'll find them.
How big is Santorini?
They're lost.
Are you sure she even really looked?
This is Effie we're talking about. No offense.
I hate to say this,
but this never would've happened...
...if the rotation wasn't screwed up.
You were supposed to send them to me.
I didn't get the press release
you were in Ala-fricking-bama.
- Yeah, me neither.
- It must have been lost...
...along with
"Tibby has a pregnancy scare."
Excuse me?
What pregnancy scare?
I didn't want to worry you.
- You didn't have a problem telling Lena.
- I was here!
I tried to tell you, when I came up
to your place, you know.
- I wanted to tell you, we got in that fight...
- I e-mailed everybody.
It's not my fault I have a lame server.
Oh, well, thank God for e-mail!
You can have an entire relationship
and not even look at somebody.
E-mails, guys, really? That's lame.
Can we just focus on the pants?
No, maybe this is a sign, you know.
That we should just forget about it.
What are you talking about, Tibby?
The pants, okay?
"The pants"! They're supposed to
bring us together, and look, look at us!
Look at us.
All the more reason to try and find them.
My sister lost them.
I'll go to Greece and find them.
[SPEAKING IN GREEK]
My beautiful granddaughter!
Is Effie inside?
Effie? That girl.
She left for Athens this morning.
She was too afraid to face you.
Not very Greek of her, of course.
Naturally.
- Come, your room is ready. Come here.
- Thank you.
CHRISTINA: It's Effie.
- Effie?
Here, take him.
Come on.
Yes.
Effie, what's up? Did she find the pants?
I don't know, I'm in Athens.
Listen, I would've
never taken the pants...
...if I knew what she was going
through, but she never said a word.
- So Kostos isn't married.
- Nope.
And he went all the way to RISD
to tell Lena that?
Two weeks ago. Effie ran into him
in Greece, and he told her the story.
He came out here and Lena
won't even give him a second chance?
- Gee, imagine that.
- Shut up.
I just wish Lena
had said something to us.
I know.
Well, she shouldn't have to.
Yia Yia. How do you say "lost pants"
in Greek?
[SPEAKS IN GREEK]
Greek girls do not lose their pants.
[CHATTERING]
TIBBY: Sure this guy knows
where we're going?
CARMEN: Yep, he says
we just stay on this main path...
...then we take a left at the third bend.
TIBBY: Oh, so you speak Greek now?
BRIDGET:
Come on, we've got bigger problems.
One of your donkeys
just did something way nasty.
Shit!
Oh, that's gonna leave a mark.
- Opa! Lena!
- Bridget!
What are you guys doing here?
- You think we'd let you do this alone?
- Oh, my God! Hi!
It turns out my stepdad had
a million frequent flier miles...
...and they were about to expire,
so he gave them to us.
LENA:
Hi, Tibby!
I just fell off a donkey!
Are you okay?
Are we having fun yet?
Okay, about 500 more.
There.
Excuse me. Do you know somebody
named Kostos or Kostas?
- Tibs, everybody here is named Kostos.
- Bridget, please!
Kostos Dunas.
Kostos? Yes. Nice boy.
You miss him by 10 minutes.
Naturally.
He go to sell his fish, to restaurant.
BRIDGET:
Carmen!
We got a lead.
This guy over here just told us...
...He Who Must Not Be Named's
at the restaurant.
Excuse me! There is a tourist!
What?
With the pants,
that I found that has the pants...
...and he's at the restaurant.
So if we go to the restaurant, we'll
find this particular tourist with the jeans...
...who might be there,
will probably be there. He'll be there.
Are you guys okay?
- What?
- We're fine.
- Let's go to the restaurant.
Hey, you guys, look, green hat.
Is that him?
CARMEN:
Oh, my God.
I've only seen pictures,
but it totally looks like him.
- He's hot.
- Everyone, be calm, okay?
I'll do the talking.
- No!
- What?
- We'll go and do the talking.
- Where are we going?
We're going to you to warn you that
Kostos is standing right over there.
Oh.
Well, that's okay.
We'll just calmly and quietly
turn around and just go right back...
- No. He's already seen you. Go.
BRIDGET: Good luck.
Effie told me you were coming.
I kept hoping I see you before
I have to leave tomorrow.
I almost called to ask you to meet me
at my boat.
But I wasn't sure you remember
which one it was.
I remember.
So you said you were leaving tomorrow.
Yes.
I got into the graduate program
at the London School of Economics.
Oh, really?
That's great.
Anyway, I should go.
It's good to see you, Lena.
I really hope you'll be happy.
You too.
Lena?
There's a full moon tonight.
It's called a "sailor's moon."
Maybe it will bring you good luck, eh?
Help you find
what you are really looking for.
- Hey.
Um... Well, that's that.
Let's just go.
That's that? That's that?
[SPEAKS IN GREEK]
Okay, Lena, will you say something,
please? What happened?
Nothing happened.
Nothing happened? Do you have any idea
how long we've been looking for this guy...?
Slick.
Wait. That's why you guys
were acting so weird?
You've been planning this
this whole time?
- No.
- Yes.
- Yes?
- We didn't come to Greece just for the pants.
Wait, I don't believe this!
Why would you guys lie to me?
Because, Lena, we knew you
couldn't do it on your own.
And why didn't you tell us that
Kostos wasn't married, Lena?
- Because it doesn't matter.
- Yes, it does matter.
No, it doesn't matter. He's... It's over.
- Well, it didn't look over to me.
- Me neither.
Nope.
You don't know what you're talking about.
No way you could understand.
What's to understand?
Why can't you just stop
thinking about it...
...and follow your heart?
- Because he broke my heart! He...
It hurts. I don't ever want to feel
this way again.
I don't think I could
go through this again.
Lena, this just happens once
in a lifetime, you know.
I think that you owe it to yourself
to at least try.
Lena Kaligaris.
We are terrible at not loving each other.
I tried to stop, but I couldn't.
I tried too.
So, what do we do?
We figure it out.
[LAUGHING]
Well, now that Kostos is taken care of...
- Oh, shut up.
- Kostos!
- Stop.
- What are we gonna do about the pants?
I don't know. We've been here for
five days. What if we don't find them?
BRIDGET:
I hate the idea of leaving without them.
TIBBY:
God, I hate the idea of leaving at all.
CARMEN:
Oh, my...
What an idiot.
- Bridget?
- Bridge, don't.
- Bridget.
CARMEN: Hey.
- Are you crazy?
TIBBY: Don't! No, Bridget.
LENA: Don't do this! It's not funny.
TIBBY: Stop!
I'm not the only one that's going in.
- I'm not the only one that's going in.
- What are you doing?
- Come on, we're all gonna go.
- Jump.
No, I'm not doing this. I'll dip my toes
in the water or something.
TIBBY:
Oh, my God, be careful.
One, two, three!
[BOTH SCREAM]
CARMEN:
Oh, my God, I can't do that!
Come on, Carmen, jump! Hurry!
CARMEN: Sometimes I like to think that
the pants got lost on purpose...
... that this was their final gift to us...
... bringing us back together...
... back to a place
of forgiveness and love...
... and an understanding that what we shared
was all the magic we could ever need.
And as we spent those
last few moments of summer...
... looking out at the blending
of sea and sky...
... I realized it was a color
I knew very well:
The softly faded essential blue...
... of a well-worn pair of pants.
The pants had brought us together again.
The rest...
... was in our hands.
[ENGLISH SDH]