Transcript made by rogard,
with a little help from lyliakar
[The Caribbean, 1970]
[The Bank Job]
[Based on a true story]
[East London, 1971]
Another "Terry Leather
Low Mileage" done.
Good you're glad, but have you all
sorted out for your wedding tomorrow?
Yeah, of course, Terry.
New suit, two buttons,
9 inch pump flaps.
Nice.
Ingrid will like that.
So, you're getting
married tomorrow, Ingrid?
I hope so.
Go on, get off now.
Go make yoursef more beautiful
than you already are.
If that's possible.
Terry.
Promise you won't get Eddie
too legless tonight, will you?
At his stag do?
(bachelor party)
We're just going round the pub,
couple of pints and a sing song.
Oh, fuck...
Fuck it, what are you
trying to do to me, eh?
I've got Jessul's money.
The Problem is,
it's tied up in these cars,
and you wankers want to
trash the lot of 'em.
Mr. Jessul doesn't care about
your inventory.
Mr. Jessul wants to know
that he's getting paid.
Any day, I swear, Perky.
What did you call me?
I called you Perky, Perky!
Everyone calls you Perky,
and him Pinkey.
- Pinkey and Perky?
- Yeah.
They're fucking cartoon pigs
on the telly,
what, people call us
that behind our backs?
Well, I'm not gonna say it to your face,
aren't I?
Well, you just bloody did!
Yeah well, you got me rolled.
I'm very intimidated.
Don't make us come back again.
Not every customer is
a satisfied customer.
What are you doing
here, my dear Martine?
What are you doing tonight?
Tonight?
Tonight is Eddie's stag do.
Taking him out for a drink.
Why?
I've got a proposition for you, Terry.
A proposition?
Can you meet me at the Player's Club
before you see the boys?
And I'll fill you in on the details.
Make it 9 o'clock.
[3 weeks earlier]
- Morning, Gale.
- Good morning, Tim.
Top floor?
Summoned by the gods?
Something like that.
Got up to your new
mistress this weekend?
I don't know what you're talking about,
I'm a married man.
What do you think,
am I presentable?
Not sure about the tie, darling.
What's this?
"Peace and Love"?
Too much of that nonsense
and we're both out of our job.
Michael Abdul Malik.
Calls himself Michael X,
in homage to Malcolm X,
his American counterpart.
The Pinko (socialist) press would
have us believe this Michael X
is a crusading champion
of the poor and oppressed.
And the black Robin Hood
of Notting Hill.
The richer, whiter and more famous,
they will all fall over him
The truth is, he's a slum landlord,
a drug dealer
and a vicious pimp who should have
been in prison years ago.
Are you not charging outrageous rents
to my brothers and sisters, Mr. Brown?
I'm charging the same as your
slum-lord friend Lew Vogel.
Ten quids a week is too
much for these shitholes.
You know,
I always wanted to meet
a white man by the name of Brown.
You know what this is?
It's a slave collar.
And a white man made my mothers
and fathers wear this
to bend them to his will.
Can I bend you to my will,
Mr. Brown?
You sure got a faithful
dog now, Michael.
Michael, I don't think we
should get our hopes up here.
Kidnappning, extortion,
assault on this man Brown here,
as well as your previous problems
with the law, I mean...
You could be looking
at 10 to 20 years, I'd say.
I don't think so. I am smarter
and better protected than whitey thinks.
All rise.
It seems Michael X has managed
to keep himself out of jail
by threatening to release
damning photographs of a
certain...royal personage.
Until we get our hands on these snaps,
the police can't move.
The public prosecutor won't move...
and the home office
doesn't want to know.
Has anyone actually
seen these photographs?
Yes, but at the minute
I'm not at liberty...
to say who that person is.
We've had Michael X under surveillance
for quite a while.
He keeps a safe deposit
box at the Lloyd's Bank...
in Marylebone.
We believe that's were
the photos are located.
Seems straightforward enough.
I'll send a team into this bank
and take whatever he's got
in this safe deposit box.
That would have to be sanctioned
at the highest level,
and that's not going to happen.
Do you see our problem?
There can be no connection to 5 or 6.
So you want me to come up with something
devoid any accountability for anyone.
We'd welcome suggestions, Tim.
And if it all goes pear-shaped (wrong),
I assume it's my arse on the line?
You're young and ambitions, Tim.
A chance to make a name for yourself.
Thank you, Sir.
Excuse me, madam, miss.
Can I have a word?
Yes.
- Where have you been?
- Morocco.
- I'll have to check your underwear.
- Be my guest.
- We found what we're looking for.
- Found what?
What were you looking for?
Oh Tim, thank God!
I'm in a spot of bother.
(I've got problems)
- What have you been up to?
- Nothing much. You?
I was in Morocco recently.
- Business or pleasure?
- Bit of both.
Drinks are on me.
So, we're gonna sit here all night,
making small-talk?
I know you, Terry,
and I know your mates (friends).
You've always been looking for
the big score,
the one that makes sense of everything.
- I have it for you.
- What?
- A bank.
- A bank...as in robber?
What would you know about a bank?
I've been seeing this guy
who runs his own business.
Security systems.
Next month, they're installing
new alarms in a bank at Marylebone.
Seems like the trains have been...
setting off the trembler
alarms in the vault
and they've had to turn them off.
So for a week or so,
they won't have any.
Now why would he tell you all this?
We were having a laugh about it.
Imagine if half the villains in
in London knew about this, he said.
And I thought, I know half
the villains in London.
I grew up with some of them.
Look, me and my mates have been
involved in the odd bit of
skullduggery (criminal acts).
Can you see us tooled up,
taking on a bank like
the (Jesse) James gang?
This isn't about waving a
waterpistol at a cashier's head.
This is about getting into the basement
where the deposit boxes are.
Hidden, secret wealth.
Money and jewels, they're safe to steal,
- 'cause people won't report it.
- Oh, no no no.
You can't talk about this here.
It's a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity, Terry.
We can't pass it up.
I didn't expect this
from you tonight, Martine.
What did you expect?
I'll have to think about it.
You better get off to your stag party.
Thanks for the drink.
Eddie tells me his brother invited you
to the wedding.
- Are you going?
- I'll see you there.
Can I get a Campari and Soda, no ice?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Well, Tim sweety,
what do you think?
- Is he offering?
- Maybe.
Cheers, gorgeous.
- So you're coming in?
- I don't know, it's late.
Do you need to run home
like a good little boy?
I guess I've got time.
- What exactly do you do?
- Bit of this, bit of that.
How did you and Hakim meet?
I met Hakim in Los Angeles
last spring.
He was rasing money for a black
Montessori school
and writing his life's story.
And what an extraordinary
life it has been.
The book is called "From the Dead Level,
Malcolm X and Me."
I've read the manuscript.
Hakim is a poet.
The voice of the black soul.
A friend is throwing a thing next week
to celebrate the launch of
Brother Hakim's book,
and you are all invited.
Hakim, tell us more about your book.
It's about being born black
in America.
Can any of you imagine what it is like
to be born a black man in this world?
Can any of you white women
imagine what it would be like
to bring a black baby into this world?
Good evening, sir.
What, you freakhead? Why are we
even having this conversation?
We're not--
Here's your beer.
We are not bankrobbers.
Maybe that's why we
could get away with it.
It's a bit daunting, isn't it?
You know what scares me more?
Living and dying with
nothing to show for it.
You know how old Mozart was
when he composed his first minuet?
- No.
- Five. Five! A fucking minuet!
And how would you know that fact, Terry?
Because it's tattooed on
that stripper's arse, Kevin.
What the fuck's it matter how I know?
It's a fact and you're
missing the point, Kev.
What I'm trying to say is,
we stop fucking about and stop...
picking the shit from
under our fingernails.
Shtum (quiet), lads.
Coppers at 12 o'clock.
Damn...
What are you two doing here,
personally?
I thought you were way past
being a bagman, Jerry.
Your associate Sonia Bern has raised
prices at that knocking shop of hers.
- £120 quid up from a £100.
- And your point?
A rising tide lifts all ships, mate.
I think we are owed some money.
- Cause even Sonia's can be raided.
- Yeah, you would do that, wouldn't you?
You'd kill the goose that
lays you golden eggs.
Wouldn't that be dumb, would it?
But then again,
everyone knows coppers are dumb.
Now you can do one thing for me.
You stop your collegues from
having their boys night out in my clubs.
They're loud, they're lewd (horny)
and they expect free oral sex.
You know what, that's disgusting.
My, most of them have families.
We'll pass the word along.
Lew, you tell your
greedy little bobbies (cops)...
to find their
perks (extra income) elsewhere.
No one is going to bother me.
My patrons could have a lot of these
wank-cockers cut out of pasture.
Well, I'd say, spread the wealth around
and keep the peace.
Five quid a week extra.
- It's all it's worth.
- I'll pass it on.
- Drysdale.
- Urquhart.
Lord Drysdale, can I offer you a drink
before your session?
Very kind of you, Sonia.
- Good to see you.
- As well, Urquhart, as well.
Good girl.
Tighter!
Yes, that's a good girl.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
[Congratulations
Eddie & Ingrid]
Louder.
Louder!
Come on.
We want a kiss,
what's wrong with you?
- I just can't.
- Come on...
Give her a snogging (kiss), babe.
Hello.
So you were in a magazine the other day?
The Campari ad on the beach.
Nice.
Must have been an old one,
I'm not modeling any more.
I don't know why.
You're still a knockout.
- What are you doing these days, Dave?
- Me?
A bit of film work.
Extra, you know.
And you, Kevin?
You're still snapping, I see.
The wedding photos?
No no, these are just
photos for the family.
Fashion is my game.
Fashion and passports.
- And the odd snap of a wayward husband.
- Thank you, Dave.
So, what's the verdict, boys?
We're interested.
First thing we should do
is take a look at the place,
suss (check) it out.
- Maybe open a box of our own.
- I've already done that.
We can go and have a look tomorrow.
Tomorrow it is.
Heads up, lads.
- She's adorable, your little one.
- She is off.
And what a gorgeous flower girl
your eldest made.
Thanks. Catherine.
I do envy you.
- Kev, you want to dance?
- Yeah, come on.
It was lovely to see you all.
- Ciao.
- All right, mate.
- All right.
She envies me...
She's being sarcastic?
I suppose what she meant was,
money can't by what we have.
Didn't you use to go out with her?
No love, that was Kevin.
He had this big thing for her.
- And you didn't?
- No.
I love me and you,
love at first sight.
Oh yeah...
I remember that night, you were
with your mate Audrey at that disco.
I saw this gorgeous little bum
in a pencil skirt
and I thought:
"Oh, I've gotta have that."
But Audrey surely already had blows,
so I pulled you.
Cheeky sod.
Daddy, daddy, come and dance with me.
Come on, dad.
Hands off me.
Good morning.
I'd like to access my
safe deposit box, please.
- Martine Love. L-O-V-E.
- Certainly, madam.
- You're an actor, right?
- That's right.
I did a couple of films
for you, Mr. Vogel.
Yeah, right.
So what are these films you're in?
Forget about it.
Go on.
Technically, it's what you'd call...
pornography.
- You're joking?
- No.
So you've been going around town with a
12 inch mutton dagger
hanging down your pants?
That's nothing to be ashamed of.
Nice.
Fake.
For the posh party at the weekend.
This is the one.
The lease is available.
Finally.
- How do I look? Good?
- Not your best, Dave.
Here we go.
So how come you've got the inside
note on this place, Martine?
She knows this bloke,
runs a security company.
Bloke? Is it serious?
Are you getting married?
He is married.
All the best ones are.
Here we go.
Marylebone Road and Baker Street,
on the corner here is the bank,
next door is the Chicken Inn,
and at 189, Le Sac.
In the back is an underground
car park
with direct access to
the shops' basements.
We can pull in here from
Glentworth Street...
into the car park
for dropoffs and pickups
without being seen from the street.
We'll dig a tunnel from the basement
of the shop
under the Chicken Inn and pop up
in the safe deposit vault.
I've got a question.
What do ourselves know
about digging tunnels?
Nothing.
But I know a man who does.
- So what do you reckon, Bambas?
- What do I reckon?
I reckon I know you guys,
but I don't know her.
Don't worry about Martine,
she's solid.
We go way back.
Terry, you have been up to
some mischief in your time
but this, this is serious shit,
my friend.
Don't you think it's a little
out of your league?
Maybe it's time to step up
to the first division.
There's going to be reinforced concrete
under the vault.
We're going to need a thermic lance,
a jackhammer, a generator,
lights, ropes, cables, the works.
It's about 40 feet (13m) of digging
before we're under the bank.
We can hire some Micks (Irishmen) from
Camden Town to do the digging
That's brilliant, Dave.
Why don't we just pay their
national ensurance contributions?
And then you have to get on
your Tommy Nutter suit.
- This way, Michael. One more shot.
- This way.
Thank you, that was great.
- What are your plans?
- I am returning to Trinidad...
to liberate my brothers and sisters
from the enslavement of
the British colonialists.
What about the charges you are facing?
How can you leave England?
They are liars and cowards.
If they had anything against me
but their fear of me,
I'd be tried and jailed.
See you later, Bambas.
But we gonna need a front man
on this,
someone who can sign the lease on
the shop and looks the business.
I know someone, Guy Singer.
Calls himself "The Major".
But that's a lot of bollocks,
He has got this white posh accent
if anyone comes nosing about.
A bit tight under the
arms, dont you think?
Traditional fit, sir.
One can't raise ones
arms above one's head.
It tends to inhibit any
impulsive acts of surrender.
I'll be right back, sir.
What on earth are you doing here?
Got a bit of business for you here, Guy.
You'll be tempted.
Sit down, luv.
What do you think you're doing?
Taking the E (Jaguar E-Type)
for a test drive.
Tell your boss, he can
have his inventory back
when he settles Mr. Jessul's debt.
And it'd better be soon
or we'll be back to tap
through his kneecaps.
If I was you two,
I was looking for another job.
Lovely.
- Cheers.
So, come on then, what don't I know?
Romantic dinner on a Monday night?
Look honey,
I'm going to be working some strange
hours over the next week or two, so...
don't ask me what I'm doing,
because I don't want to lie to you.
What are you doing?
Look...
All llife I've caused us a few problems
with all these cars aren't selling
All I was trying to do
is get ahead of the game.
- This thing's gonna put us there.
- Wicked.
- Yeah.
And a better place.
It's for all of us.
For you and the kids.
And how afraid do I have to be, Terry?
It'd be the best smart thing if you
wanted to stay with your aunt,
in case things turn out cursed, that is.
So, we are settled. 25% to run
my girls till I return from Trinidad.
It's all right,
you don't have to worry.
I'll look after your little flock
of birds like they were my own.
As long as you remember
they are not your own.
Lew, while I'm back in Trinidad,
I can arrange for shipment of some
high grade gunja (weed, marihuana).
Not interested.
You want my opinion?
All these drugs are responsible for...
the moral decay of
this countries' young.
Smut, smut and more smut.
(pornography, dirt)
That's my special area of interest.
You should think about it.
With these goodies you can make
a lot of dough (money),
especially the police in your pocket.
I am paying enough pung as it is,
(weed, here: money)
but probably not as much
as you're donating
to be permitted to leave our
fair shores (the country).
Not a shilling! I have something
so special, I don't need to pay anyone.
And what would that be, Michael?
Sorry, Lew.
Well.
Whatever it is, you can't be buggered.
I hope you're keeping it safe.
Yes, as safe as it can be.
In a place that you recommended.
transcript by r o g a r d
- You're late.
- Sorry.
This is the Major.
Major Guy Singer.
Final member of our team.
I don't know this man.
Who are you?
None of your business.
No secrets around here.
The Major is a con artist.
Usually elderly widows.
There's no need to bring that up.
Now he's the official
new owner of Le Sac.
Handbags and leather accesories
for the discerning lady.
Nice.
I told the district planner's
office about the remodelling.
They gave me the specs for the
sewage, drainage, gas and power lines.
Lifted our take
to miss that lot (a pipe).
What's this for?
That is the thermic lance.
It cuts through concrete and metal.
We're doing this, right?
I mean, we're bloody going for it.
Let's see what this thing can do.
Good idea, Kev.
Give us a demonstration, Bambas.
Ok, hold this.
Hold it. Here.
Kevin, go stand over there
by the oxygene.
Here we go.
Turn it off!
Off! Off! Off!
Not good.
They know what they're doing,
these people, do they?
Absolutely.
Professional criminals.
What's the worst case scenario?
They get caught and go to jail.
No possible connection to us.
What about this model you're screwing?
What promises have you made
to keep her in line?
None that can't be broken.
Look, she's already tied
to the bank operation.
If things do go belly up (go wrong)
it'll only take one
cut to sever the knot.
What's Gale Benson up to?
I believe she's working her way
into Michael X's inner sanctum.
Could you sign that book, please?
I've got them finally together.
Daddy!
I am so glad you decided to come.
This is my father, Sir Leonard Plugge.
Always happy to meet Gale's new friends.
Her new name is Halekimga.
It's an anagram
of the letters of our names:
Hakim and Gale.
- And your name is?
- Hakim. Hakim Jamal.
Right.
Excuse me...
Hello, gorgeous.
So, where's the author?
He's over there,
signing his masterpiece.
Why don't you both drop by
the house this weekend
and introduce Mr. Jamal to mother?
Sorry daddy, can't do that.
We're popping (going) on time
for the islands for a while.
- Let me get you a drink.
- Good luck with your book.
- So you've read this book of his?
- You must be joking.
Right.
You're probably undercover,
spying on Black Power's insidious
threat to the British way of life.
Oh, that's very funny.
Tell me, is that little enterprise
still shipshape (going well)?
We're currently on schedule, Tim.
We're taking over the shop
on Friday afternoon.
I know if this stuffs up
I'm in poo poo land.
(I know that I'm in serious trouble
if this goes wrong)
We have a blue Transit van
that's just pulled up.
"Clacy Builders" on the side.
And we have one man entering the shop.
Construction crew, for Le Sac.
[Under new management.
Reopening soon]
I've got a question.
What do we do with all the dirt
we're gonna dig out of the hole?
That's all been worked out, Dave.
We'll dig another hole over there
and put in in that. Over.
If we're to get the job done
before the bank opens on Monday morning,
we better get a wriggle (move) on.
Want to do the honours, Martine?
This is it,
here we go.
Watch your nails, Martine.
Yeah, yeah.
Let's get this store to rock.
- Some racket (noise) there is.
- Bloody hell! What's going on?
Dave, come on, mate.
Dave, you need a break.
I'll take over.
Cheers (thanks), Major.
Heads up!
- Where's Dave?
- No idea.
Where did you get to?
Just checking the door was locked.
Of course it's locked, Dave.
I locked it.
Hang on.
Look what we got here.
This is a copper.
Christ, he's not going in there, is he?
- I'll go.
- Shit! Dave, Dave, get back.
- I only wanted--
- Stop! Hold it down!
Someone is knocking.
Someone is at the door.
Stop, Stop! There's somebody
at the door of the shop.
Bambas!
Hold on!
There's somebody at the door.
- Look, I don't want to go in.
- It's my job.
Coppers.
It's the old bill (police).
Good evening.
You're working late?
Around the clock, officer.
Expanding our storage.
Trying to complete renovations
for the grand reopening--
If you don't mind, sir.
Excuse me?
You use a jackhammer down there?
Yeah. You heard some
complaints, officer?
Yeah, from some of your neighbours.
We'll try to keep it down, all right?
Right.
How the hell did they
talk their way out of that one?
Tim, Quinn here.
We just had a copper
going into the shop.
Not sure why, but he's gone now.
All clear.
We need a lookout,
someone on a roof somewhere.
- We've got the walkie-talkies.
- What about Eddie?
He's a good lad,
we can trust him.
No. Look, we're not cutting
anyone else in.
We won't cut him in on the loot.
We'll give him the car lot.
Hopefully I won't need
that headache anymore.
- My God, not again.
- Get up there, Major.
Cover that up!
It's not the coppers.
- Yes, can I help you?
- Delivery for Dave Shilling.
- And what is it?
- Chicken and chips.
I see...
- Takeaway for Mr. Shilling.
- Thanks.
- You can't be serious.
- I was starving.
Radio is in the bag,
binoculars as well.
There's a pension on the
top floor of this building,
paid for the week.
There's a ladder that'll
get you to the roof.
You're in from Liverpool,
looking for work.
I don't have a Liverpool accent.
Then don't talk to anyone, Eddie.
I'm up on the roof, and...
I've got a good view
of all directions, over.
Are you in position, Nightjar?
Command HQ here. Acknowledge.
Yeah, I'm in position.
I can see the front of the bank,
Marylebone Road,
Baker Street, I can see
everything really well.
All clear on the Western front, Guy.
Over.
- No names, Eddie.
- Sorry, Dave.
Aye, you delinquents.
What have I told you?
No idle chitchat.
Sorry, T--
Over.
Fuckin' hell...
Wakey wakey, gentlemen.
I'll keep an eye on
the shop from here on.
You two go down to Glentworth Street.
Guard the parking garage exit.
Okay.
Nightjar here, there's some fellow
looking through the window.
Hang on.
Wait, hang on. He's going.
He's going.
Yeah, he's gone.
Over.
Roger, Nightjar.
Over and out.
I want to go to the pub,
grab some more smokes.
Do you want anything?
A pack of Seniors.
There you go, sir.
Two packets of Rothmans,
2 Senior Service and 8 bags of crisps.
Okay.
Hello, gorgeous.
Are we still on track?
We had a scare last night.
The cops came round.
Can't you pull rank and make
sure it doesn't happen again?
No, we can't show our hand.
We're invisible, remember?
- I wish I was.
- How about your friend Terry?
Where is he planning to
carve up the proceeds?
Shit.
- A pint of ale, chief.
- What's wrong?
I needed to take a break.
Who's that you've been talking to?
I wasn't.
He was trying to chat me up.
Does happen, you know.
- Right.
- Here you are.
- Cheers. Keep the change.
- Thank you.
Now, what are you doing here?
Are you following me?
No.
- I just wanted a pint.
- Then enjoy it.
- Hello, Gale.
- Where have you been?
You're rather impressed with our
friend Hakim, aren't you?
I know rule #1:
"Don't get emotionally involved"
That doesn't mean I can't
enjoy my work.
You certainly do.
What does your father think of your
consorting with these radicals anyway?
We are not amused.
Of course, if he knew
what I was really up to,
he would have a heart attack.
Here you are.
Credit cards and cash.
If he does have copies of the
photos and negatives there,
they will be hidden.
Find them.
Destroy them.
And then get out.
Michael X thinks he's safe,
tucked away in Trinidad.
That will all change if
we're successful here.
Just remember, Gale:
He's a nasty piece of work.
He's a crazy dope-smoking lunatic
pimp extortionist, that's what he is.
Everything okay, Nightjar?
Anything I need to know?
Yeah, everything's all right, mate.
Listen, what if I want to go
for a pee up here?
I don't know.
Use your imagination.
Stay off the radio unless you
see any old bill (police), all right?
Yeah, all right. If I see any
old bill, I'll let you know.
I'll speak to you in a bit.
Over.
Hey Bambas.
What's all this brickwork?
I don't know,
it wasn't on the plans.
Fuck!
Terry?
Fucking hell!
Terry!
Bambas!
Terry, talk to me!
Terry!
Oh fuck..
Terry, talk to me!
- Are you all right?
- I think so, yeah.
What happened?
The floor just caved in.
Bloody hell, Terry.
Don't do that to me.
- I thought you was a goner (dead).
- Yeah.
Give us a light, Dave.
What's down there?
- It's a pile of skeletons.
- You're joking.
Let's hope they're not the last gang
who tried to take this bank.
Latin.
Roughly translated:
Lamb of God,
forgive us our sins.
- You actually know Latin?
- Catholic school.
The Bleeding Heart sisters
of eternal misery.
Interesting date.
1665.
You all know what year
that was, don't you?
The last time West Ham
won the (F.A.) cup?
It was the great plague of London.
This must be a
burial chamber.
A crypt where they dumped the bodies.
Well, if these poor
bastards had the plague,
then they could be infectious.
I don't think so, Dave.
This crypt goes all
the way under the bank.
It'll put us in the vault quicker.
Well, then we'll gonna do that.
Concrete.
Floor of the vault.
Time to get paid for all our work.
Right.
If we hit the restaurant by mistake,
we'll be knee-deep in fried chicken.
I'll be happy if we don't
hit the sewage.
When are you guys
going to hit the vault?
I'm freezing my tits off up here.
Over.
In the army, soldiers would pull on
their puds (penises) to keep their blood flowing.
How's that?
What regiment were you in,
the Royal Corps of Wankers?
Over.
Yes, we welcome new members.
Roger, over and out.
Emergency operator.
Which service do you require?
- The police, please.
- Putting you through.
Police here.
Can I help you?
Yes.
I'm a HAM radio operator
and I think I may be overhearing
a robbery in progress.
We're in!
Dave, get the ladder.
We're gonna move into the vault
after we take a break.
Later when the fume's cleared out.
You're having a laugh, ain't you?
Let's go in now.
Dave. Nothing's going nowhere.
I can hardly breathe in there.
- Nightjar, are you there? Over.
- Nightjar here, over.
We're in.
Over.
What, in the actual vault?
Yes, in the actual vault. Over.
Great, great.
That's great news. Over.
We're taking a break.
We're knackered (tired).
I need to get some sleep.
Getting a shut-eye (a nap). I want
the fumes cleared out. Over.
Lucky you. My eyes are like
**** stops. Over.
We can smell the money now.
Over.
Look, money may be your god,
but it ain't mine, all right?
I want a warm bath and a cup of tea.
Over.
You'll get your cup of tea.
Just your odd time.
Lucky you.
My eyes are like **** stops.
We can smell the money now.
I rang 4 other police
stations before you,
but nobody took me sriously.
They said it was probably a hoax.
How strong was the signal, Mr. Addey?
I'd say they were within
a 10 mile radius.
There must be a ton of
banks in that area.
And when was the last time
you picked them up?
They've been quiet for about an hour.
What about releasing the tapes
to the radio and TV?
Maybe somebody can recognize the voices?
No, no.
If they hear themselves,
they'll stop transmitting.
No, we should keep listening.
Maybe they'll reveal where they are.
Alfie, you stay here with Mr. Addey.
I am going back to the station.
You call me if you hear anything.
Hi.
You scared the piss out of me.
- What are you doing here?
- I couldn't sleep.
Yeah, I'm a bit tingly
(nervous) myself..
I just had to come and have a look.
Our future is in those boxes.
So, what are you going to do
with your share?
Vanish.
Martine Love will cease to exist.
Why, do you think if you
vanish you'll become someone else?
At least no one will know
who I was.
Why did you pick Kevin and me?
You could have found better thieves.
For old times' sake.
Must be old times
you spent with Kevin,
not me.
Kevin has it in his mind that
we had this passionate affair.
The truth is, it came down
to 4 chinese meals and
a roll in the hay.
And that was a long time ago.
All right,
let's make some money.
Look at this!
Look at all this cash.
Fantastic!
Guys? Gold bars.
Diamonds. Diamonds!
Guys, what's going on?
How would your wife fancy a tiara?
Too bloody right.
Get the gas.
The gas.
Look at it.
Hold it.
- Emerald.
- It's like winning the lottery.
Dave.
Give us a hand with this one.
- What's so special about this box?
- It's my lucky number.
All yours, me lovely.
- There you are.
- Cheers.
Holy shit.
You know who that is?
It's Princess Margaret.
Terry, anything for the
widows and auctions funds?
- Will that do?
- God bless you, you're very generous.
Look, we have to have
some sort of system.
You don't know what you are throwing
or what you are keeping.
Yeah, but we know what money looks like.
We're not throwing that away, are we?
How long does it take
to rob a bank?
We're just about to get
this job done, okay?
More cash.
Have a look at this.
No, nothing.
Still nothing.
Sergeant, what we need is something
that will motivate the
robbers to go on air,
- give away their location.
- Right..
Bait to lure the fish.
No, they are not there,
not transmitting.
They are not there, sir.
Move to the next bank,
unit #2.