NewYorkCity.
&nbsp
Hewantstosee
what'sthere.
&nbsp
I can tell him
what's there.
&nbsp
I don't know how...
when you've never been.
&nbsp
¢Ü Think of it, 'ey ¢Ü
¢Ü The world's in the palm
of my hand ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Run a comb through my hair ¢Ü
¢Ü Headin' out for
some new foreign land ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü And all this could seem
like a dream out the door ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü With everyday people
face down on the floor ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I always said I could make it
and be who I am ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü There's a new look
in sight ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü What a change
for the new modern man ¢Ü
&nbsp
Well, Toto, I guess
we're not in Kansas anymore.
&nbsp
I can't figure out why he'd want to go
to New York when we got everything here.
&nbsp
Somethin' I have to do, Dad.
[ Mom ] Did you pack an iron
like I told you to?
&nbsp
Mom.
You're gonna walk around
wrinkled in New York if you don't.
&nbsp
[ Dad ] Elmer Whitfield's cousin Carlton
went off to New York a normal boy.
&nbsp
Came back with his head shaved
and an earring stuck in his cheek.
&nbsp
¢Ü With all this it seems
like I'm dyin' for more ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü The streets are on fire
Never seen it before ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü It's like the sound
of electric guitars ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Worlds collide
and hearts will be broken ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Over and over
it's the same every day ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü How can I say
what has never concerned me ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü The secret of my success ¢Ü
¢Ü Is I'm livin' ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Twenty-five hours a day ¢Ü
Mom, there's
a whole world out there.
&nbsp
- I mean, big, exciting.
- [ Horse Whinnies ]
&nbsp
I got a nice, small
apartment lined up.
&nbsp
I got a great job.
I wanna make
lots of money.
&nbsp
I want to have a meaningful experience
with an incredibly beautiful woman.
&nbsp
I can't even take a woman like that
to a small apartment.
&nbsp
- I gotta get a penthouse.
- A penthouse?
&nbsp
With a Jacuzzi in it.
Doin' this for you
as much for me, Mom.
&nbsp
All those years of college,
they're gonna start payin' off.
&nbsp
[ Sighs ]
¢Ü Ooh, ooh, yeah ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Worlds collide
and hearts will be broken ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Over and over
it's the same every day ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü How can I say
what has never concerned me ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü The secret of my success
is I'm livin' ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Twenty-five hours a day ¢Ü
¢Ü It's amazing to me ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü What a fool will believe
to get by ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Changing your life ¢Ü
¢Ü I can live, I can fly ¢Ü
&nbsp
- Back!
- ¢Ü The harder they come ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü The harder they fall ¢Ü
¢Ü I never say maybe
and I go for it all ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Just like the sound
of electric guitars ¢Ü
&nbsp
[ Rodents Squeaking ]
All right, listen up.
&nbsp
If there are any bugs in here or rats or
anything that has more legs than I do,
&nbsp
you just stay on your side
of the room, okay?
&nbsp
I'll stay on mine.
I should warn you.
I'm packing an iron.
&nbsp
- [ Squeaks ]
- You weren't listening.
&nbsp
¢Ü Twenty-five hours a day ¢Ü
¢Ü The secret of my success
is I'm livin' ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Twenty-five hours a day ¢Ü¢Ü
Darling, please pack it
as fast as you can.
&nbsp
- Mr. Forbush?
- Not me! He's two doors down the hall.
&nbsp
Into the shredder
as fast as possible.
&nbsp
- Mr. Forbush.
- [ Man ] Yep.
&nbsp
Hi, I'm Brantley Foster
from Kansas.
&nbsp
- You hired me. I start work here today.
- You're fired, kid. Sorry.
&nbsp
We all saw it coming, but we
looked for some kind of miracle.
&nbsp
Miracle never happened.
- What did happen?
- Hostile takeover.
&nbsp
Ninety percent of the people
in this building are out on the street.
&nbsp
You are one of those 90%.
Tough break.
&nbsp
Mr. Forbush, I was counting on this job.
What do I do now?
&nbsp
Punt!
Okay, New York,
&nbsp
if this is the way
you want it, okay.
&nbsp
- I'm sorry, Mister--
- Foster.
&nbsp
I'm sorry, Mr. Foster.
We need someone with experience.
&nbsp
How can I get experience until I get
a job that gives me experience?
&nbsp
If we gave you a job
just to give you experience,
&nbsp
you'd take that experience
and get a better job.
&nbsp
Then that experience
would benefit someone else.
&nbsp
But I was trained in college
to handle a job like this.
&nbsp
So in a sense,
I already have experience.
&nbsp
What you've got is
college experience,
&nbsp
not the practical, hard-nosed business
experience we're looking for.
&nbsp
If you'd joined our training program out
of high school, you'd be qualified now.
&nbsp
- Then why'd I go to college?
- Had fun, didn't you?
&nbsp
What impresses me most...
is the amount of experience you picked
up while still attending college.
&nbsp
Well, ma'am, I knew all
those years of college...
&nbsp
would be worthless without practical,
hard-nosed business experience.
&nbsp
"Assistant personnel manager,
J. Hall Communications.
&nbsp
"Junior purchasing agent,
Midland Furniture.
&nbsp
Vice President in Charge of
Production, Central Manufacturing."
&nbsp
Outstanding.
You're not gonna tell me I have
too much experience, are ya?
&nbsp
Certainly not, you're
perfect for the job.
&nbsp
- Great!
- Except--
&nbsp
No. No exceptions.
I want this job.
I need it. I can do it.
&nbsp
Everywhere I've been today
there's always been something wrong.
&nbsp
Too young, too old,
too short, too tall.
&nbsp
Whatever the exception is,
I can fix it.
&nbsp
I can be older. I can be taller.
I can be anything.
&nbsp
Can you be
a minority woman?
&nbsp
- Mom, I'm doin' great.
- Is it dirty? Are the people rude?
&nbsp
No, this town is terrific.
The people are really nice.
&nbsp
- That's good. What about your job?
- Job? Hey!
&nbsp
I got a fantastic office,
got a gorgeous secretary. The works.
&nbsp
- We don't care if she's gorgeous.
Is she any good?
- What?
&nbsp
- You heard me. Can she type?
- Ma, of course she can type.
&nbsp
Some can't, you know. Is it safe there?
You haven't been robbed?
&nbsp
Ma, will you quit worryin'.
There is no danger.
&nbsp
- But New York is--
- New York is like Kansas intensified.
&nbsp
- [ Alarm Ringing ]
- i Policia!
&nbsp
- What?
- What's that? Something the matter?
&nbsp
Oh, no, Mom,
that's just the TV.
&nbsp
- It sounds so real.
- It's Miami Vice.
&nbsp
[ Mom ] Turn the sound down.
It's too loud.
&nbsp
Uh, Ma, it's broken.
The knob came off in my hand.
&nbsp
Goodness. Well, what about
Uncle Howard? Did you call him?
&nbsp
Uncle Howard!
Uh, yeah, the phone number.
&nbsp
Well, you still have
the number, don't you?
&nbsp
Oh, yeah.
I got it right here.
&nbsp
[ Mom ] Are you all right?
You seem distracted?
&nbsp
- They just totaled a Ferrari.
- But Uncle Howard?
&nbsp
- Did you call him?
- No, I haven't had a chance yet.
&nbsp
- Will you try to see him?
- I'll probably bump into him
at the Country Club.
&nbsp
Get the TV fixed, dear.
- Y eah. Listen, I gotta go. Okay?
- Okay.
&nbsp
- Give Dad my love.
- I will, dear. I love you, Brantley.
&nbsp
- I love you too, Mom. Bye-bye.
- Bye!
&nbsp
[ Man ]
They got 'em.
&nbsp
¢Ü The light is in my eyes ¢Ü
¢Ü How can I see through ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü What do I hold on to ¢Ü
Well, at least let me
buy you an airline ticket.
&nbsp
Dad, I'm gonna do this
on my own.
&nbsp
But you did make it
a round-trip ticket?
&nbsp
Y eah. I'm not
gonna need it.
&nbsp
No, when I come back to Kansas,
I'm comin' back in my own jet.
&nbsp
¢Ü It seems like the world
is upside down ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Don't know where
I'm goin' to ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü But you know I'd turn it
all around ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü It's just something
I've got to do ¢Ü ¢Ü
&nbsp
Take this. It's Uncle Howard's
phone number in New York.
&nbsp
I got an uncle
in New York?
&nbsp
My cousin Ellen married
his half-sister's nephew...
&nbsp
before she got bit
by that dog and died.
&nbsp
But he's still kin,
and kin is kin.
&nbsp
Hi.
I'd like to see
Mr. Prescott, please.
&nbsp
Do you have
an appointment?
&nbsp
I tried to get one, but I couldn't,
so I thought I'd surprise him.
&nbsp
Mr. Prescott
doesn't like surprises.
&nbsp
- Everybody likes surprises.
- Not Mr. Prescott.
&nbsp
- You can leave your name.
- Uh, Brantley Foster.
&nbsp
- Of?
- S-T-E-R. Of, uh, Kansas.
&nbsp
Of what company?
What do you wanna see
Mr. Prescott about?
&nbsp
About being his nephew.
Oh. Well, why don't you
have a seat?
&nbsp
I'll see if I can work you
into Mr. Prescott's schedule.
&nbsp
Thank you.
[ lndistinct Noise ]
&nbsp
Give Uncle Howard my card.
Are you really
Mr. Prescott's nephew?
&nbsp
In a roundabout
sort of way.
&nbsp
[ Man ] You sons of bitches don't
have a half a brain between you!
&nbsp
I'm looking at
a $300 million deficit here...
&nbsp
because you idiots didn't anticipate
the needs of a changing market!
&nbsp
- Uncle Howard?
- Now, get out, all of you!
&nbsp
And bring me back some
new ideas that'll work!
&nbsp
Or I'll have your heads
mounted on my wall!
&nbsp
- Geez, he's gonna burst a blood vessel.
- Y eah, wishful thinking.
&nbsp
I'll see if I can
get you in now.
&nbsp
Thank you.
It can't be good for his heart
to shout that way.
&nbsp
- He doesn't have a heart.
- [ Group Laughing ]
&nbsp
- What, Maureen, what?
- Brantley Foster is here to see you.
&nbsp
I don't know any Brantley Foster.
- Your nephew from Kansas.
- Who?
&nbsp
- He says he's your nephew from Kansas.
- Kansas?
&nbsp
- [ Maureen, lndistinct ]
- l-- But, Maureen--
&nbsp
Mr. Prescott
will see you now.
&nbsp
Clever. So you're one
of the Kansas Fosters, huh?
&nbsp
Shirttail relative,
to say the least.
&nbsp
I know you probably told your secretary
to get me outta here in five minutes.
&nbsp
- Two.
- Right.
&nbsp
So I'll get
right to the point.
&nbsp
I need a job, Uncle Howard.
Around here,
I'm Mr. Prescott.
&nbsp
Do you have any idea
what we do here?
&nbsp
Yes, sir.
Pemrose is a multinational conglomerate
with 27 different divisions.
&nbsp
Products ranging from dog food
to guided missile systems.
&nbsp
There are 30,000 people
working in this building alone.
&nbsp
Their accumulated salary is higher
than the gross national product...
&nbsp
of half the nations
on the Common Market.
&nbsp
Last year we borrowed more money
from banks than Mexico did.
&nbsp
It's a great company, Uncle--
Mr. Prescott. That's why I'm here.
&nbsp
What can you do for us, Brantley?
What experience have you had?
&nbsp
Practically none.
But I believe in myself.
Doesn't that count for something?
&nbsp
Deep inside, I know I can do anything
if I just get a chance.
&nbsp
[ Sighs ]
Think back to when
you were my age.
&nbsp
Remember how you felt when
you went after that first job.
&nbsp
Remember how you wanted it
so badly you couldn't sleep
the night before the interview.
&nbsp
Remember how crushed you were
when the guy said, "What kind
of experience have you got?"
&nbsp
You wanted to shake
your fists and say,
&nbsp
I can do anything
if I can just get a chance.
&nbsp
They're ready for you
in the boardroom, Mr. Prescott.
&nbsp
Call Bates in Personnel.
Tell him I'm sending somebody up.
&nbsp
Well, you're
in the front door, kid.
&nbsp
What you do on this side of it
is up to you.
&nbsp
Congratulations. He really
must have taken a shine to you.
&nbsp
Thanks. He's a warm guy.
May l?
&nbsp
You can't come in here, Bozo.
Take your crap to the mail slot.
&nbsp
I work here. Just started.
What do you want, an engraved
invitation? Come on, come on.
&nbsp
- Brantley, huh?
- Yeah.
&nbsp
Somebody gave you
that name?
&nbsp
Aw, Jesus, a college puke.
This really makes my day.
&nbsp
- Well, you're welcome.
- Melrose, get over here!
&nbsp
¢Ü¢Ü [ Rock, lndistinct ]
- Listen to what he says,
then do what he does.
- Right.
&nbsp
Stay out of my way. Don't use
the stamp machine for personal letters.
&nbsp
Take off that
stupid-looking tie.
&nbsp
- You got any questions?
- Y eah. What do I call you?
&nbsp
Call me God.
Got a problem, Boss?
I'm your man.
&nbsp
Show the college puke the ropes
and keep him outta my face.
&nbsp
His name is... Brantley.
All right, kid.
Follow me.
&nbsp
Brantley, stick with me
and everything's gonna be copacetic.
&nbsp
Twice a day you deliver. Like a mailman,
you pick up whatever's goin' out.
&nbsp
I can do it in 30 minutes.
Rattigan thinks it takes me two hours.
&nbsp
What's this department?
What do they do here?
&nbsp
Who knows? This place is a zoo.
Nobody knows what anybody else is doin'.
&nbsp
Can you get promoted
out of the mail room?
&nbsp
You can't even get paroled
out of the mail room. Excuse me, dear.
&nbsp
- [ Chattering ]
- Good morning.
&nbsp
- Nix.
- What?
&nbsp
- Good morning.
- Look, not the suits.
&nbsp
- What do you mean?
- [ Melrose ] Excuse me, sir.
&nbsp
- Good morning.
- Look, not the suits, man.
&nbsp
You never consort with the suits,
unless they consort with you first.
&nbsp
That's ridiculous. He's a person.
I'm a person. I can't say hello?
&nbsp
He's not a person,
he's a suit.
&nbsp
You're mail room.
No consorting. Come on.
&nbsp
We're entering
a sensitive zone.
&nbsp
This guy in that office
just got canned.
&nbsp
Mail room knew about it on Friday.
He just found out today.
&nbsp
No kidding.
Is his job still open?
&nbsp
No, man, an economic cutback.
His job was dissolved.
&nbsp
About two dozen suits
got the ax.
&nbsp
- [ Sniffling ]
- Quit trying to consort. Come on.
&nbsp
[ Sniffling ]
[ Melrose ] All right,
the yellow ones go to Purchasing.
&nbsp
All the white ones are a bunch
of suits talkin' to themselves.
&nbsp
You're supposed
to deliver 'em, not read 'em.
&nbsp
Some of this stuff
doesn't make any sense.
&nbsp
They send requisitions
through two departments...
&nbsp
to get procurements
for a third.
&nbsp
- What kind of thinking is that?
- That's suit thinking.
&nbsp
Something happens to a man
when he puts on a necktie.
&nbsp
Cuts off all the oxygen
to his brain.
&nbsp
You crazy? You're not supposed to
take the memos out of the mail room.
&nbsp
I can't follow a chain
of command in this company.
&nbsp
They got the right title, but their job
assignments and objectives are screwed--
&nbsp
- Look at this. Jesus. Purchasing.
- What?
&nbsp
It's a joke. They've got two people
doin' basically the same job.
&nbsp
Neither one of them
is doin' it right.
&nbsp
I'll bring it up at
the next stockholders meeting.
&nbsp
- Would you put these things away?
- Whoa, Melrose.
&nbsp
How ya doin'? We've been gettin'
a lot of requests in the mail room...
&nbsp
for stockholder information,
company assets, expenditures.
&nbsp
- Anything you can give us.
- You're kidding?
&nbsp
Any of this research you want,
you can have.
&nbsp
- Take it all.
- Thanks very much.
&nbsp
¢Ü Feelin' all right
It's the same with me too ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü There's something
that's taken a hold of us all ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü What we say and we do ¢Ü
¢Ü Just look at our lives ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü We run through the day
We stare at the night ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü As you head for the noises ¢Ü
¢Ü For me, well, it's just
like the Fourth of July ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Maybe it's change
or the time of the year ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Or is it the way
that you hold me so near ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Oh, I swear
it's the price of love ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I swear
it's the price of love ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Now I gaze at the lights
Our hearts show the way ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü For a moment I swear
it was heaven right there ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I'm at war on this day ¢Ü
She's the most incredible-looking woman
I've ever seen in my life.
&nbsp
[ Melrose ] She's a Rolls-Royce,
but she's also a suit.
&nbsp
What's she like?
What do you know about her?
&nbsp
I know enough never to
consort with the suits, pal.
&nbsp
- Even when they do have legs like hers.
- You know more than that.
&nbsp
Her name is Christy Wills.
She's supposed to be some
sort of financial wizard.
&nbsp
Harvard, all that crap.
And forget it.
&nbsp
¢Ü I swear
it's the price of love ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Price of love ¢Ü
¢Ü I swear
it's the price of love ¢Ü¢Ü
&nbsp
No, no, no, no.
That's Transportation's problem.
&nbsp
No, we do not supply drivers
for executives' wives.
&nbsp
We are a messenger service.
I don't care if the
other drivers are all busy.
&nbsp
Yeah, well, the same
to you, sweetheart.
&nbsp
Hey, Dartmouth,
get over here.
&nbsp
Executive's wife wants
a ride at the Litchfield.
&nbsp
Check out a car
and drive her.
&nbsp
- Oh, where's Litchfield?
- You'll find it.
Follow the smell of money.
&nbsp
Excuse me, ma'am.
I'm not quite sure which way--
&nbsp
[ Woman ] Turn the key, start the car,
put it in drive and step on the gas.
&nbsp
Any idiot can do that,
even my husband.
&nbsp
Excuse me, ma'am.
- I know I'm not supposed to consort--
- Then don't.
&nbsp
[ Sighs ]
You seem kind of upset. I was wonderin'
if there was anything I could do.
&nbsp
I don't know.
My cook quit this morning.
&nbsp
My analyst is away on vacation.
My Mercedes broke down.
&nbsp
I split my nail, and my husband
is screwing somebody at the office.
&nbsp
What did you have in mind?
Stick of gum?
&nbsp
Ha, ha, ha!
This is the third weekend he's found
an excuse not to come to the country.
&nbsp
No, I don't know. But knowing him
it's probably some teenage airhead...
&nbsp
from the steno pool.
The last one I caught him with
was so dumb...
&nbsp
she thought dictation
was some kind of S and M trip.
&nbsp
Do you know my husband?
I'm sorry. I can't hear you.
&nbsp
Never mind.
- Didn't hear a thing.
- I'm gonna have to call you back.
&nbsp
[ Woman Sighs ]
I'm so mad, I could spit.
&nbsp
He looks twice as good as the day we
were married. I just look twice as old.
&nbsp
Are you kiddin'?
You look-- I just hope that when I'm
his age, I can wake up every morning...
&nbsp
and find a woman as beautiful
as you are... Iying next to me.
&nbsp
Thank you.
¢Ü Oh, yeah ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Beautiful ¢Ü
¢Ü Oh, yeah ¢Ü
&nbsp
[ Voice Echoing ]
¢Ü Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ¢Ü
&nbsp
Turn in here.
Please.
&nbsp
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughing Continues ]
&nbsp
[ Woman ]
Bring those inside. Charles.
&nbsp
- May I help you with those, sir?
- Yeah. Thanks.
&nbsp
- What are you drinking?
- I can't really. I have to get back.
&nbsp
God, I hate the country.
Y eah, I can see how you'd
be real miserable here.
&nbsp
Who can live
with so many trees?
&nbsp
They suck up
all the oxygen.
&nbsp
No, actually,
trees produce oxygen.
&nbsp
Who are you? Mr. Wizard?
What did you say your name was?
&nbsp
Brantley.
No, no, no.
I mean your first name.
&nbsp
That's it:
Brantley.
&nbsp
Well, Brantley, I don't know what
you want out of Pemrose Corporation,
&nbsp
but I'll tell you
what you do not want.
&nbsp
You don't ever, ever
wanna become a corporate wife.
&nbsp
I'll watch my step.
- Have another.
- Mm.
&nbsp
Thanks.
I've run 8,000 miles
on that tennis court...
&nbsp
chasing a fuzzy, little yellow ball
with an oversized racket.
&nbsp
Do my legs
look heavy to you?
&nbsp
No.
I've swum laps from here
to the moon in that pool.
&nbsp
Do you see anything
in this body that isn't firm?
&nbsp
Tennis, swimming,
aerobics, jogging, massage.
&nbsp
Anything and everything
to stay in shape,
&nbsp
not that he'd ever notice.
So, Brantley, do you know
why I stay in shape?
&nbsp
- How 'bout a dip in the pool?
- No, wait!
&nbsp
- Are you serious? Listen, uh--
- [ Laughing ]
&nbsp
I have to get back. This is a
tempting diversion, but I got a job.
&nbsp
- I don't know if this is a good idea.
- Transportation, please.
&nbsp
Y es. The young man from
the mail room who drove me home?
&nbsp
He's going to stay here
and do a little work in my garden.
&nbsp
See that he gets full credit
on his time card.
&nbsp
Thank you.
- Help me out of this, will you, dear?
- Whew!
&nbsp
[ Yells ]
- [ Giggling ]
- That was great.
&nbsp
Thanks. I swim
five miles a day.
&nbsp
- Supposed to tone my ass.
- Yeah, it works. Oh!
&nbsp
Just when I thought it was safe
to go back in the water.
&nbsp
[ Screaming ]
Ohh!
&nbsp
Whoa! You sure
this is a good idea?
&nbsp
It's okay. I know the owner.
[ Laughing ]
&nbsp
Last one out of the--
- Sure your husband's not coming home?
- Who knows?
&nbsp
He could be home any minute
or several hours from now.
&nbsp
Oh, my God. Oh!
I'm going to see that
my husband gives you a leg up.
&nbsp
I think we've done pretty well
so far by ourselves.
&nbsp
[ Both Chuckling ]
I mean Pemrose.
&nbsp
Uh... no.
No, thanks.
&nbsp
No, I'm gonna make it
to the top by myself.
&nbsp
Oh! God, you're adorable.
Mmm!
&nbsp
I could spend a week
inside those sweet, unwrinkled eyes.
&nbsp
- Can I make a personal observation?
- Anything but the thighs.
&nbsp
Somebody sold you a bill of goods and
convinced you you had to be 21 forever.
&nbsp
That's bullshit!
I think you're terrific.
&nbsp
The only thing wrong with you
is your husband is a jerk.
&nbsp
You're beautiful.
You're intelligent.
&nbsp
You're sensuous.
Say that again!
&nbsp
Which part?
All of it!
&nbsp
- [ Car Horn Honking ]
- Oh, no!
&nbsp
- What? What is it?
- It's the jerk.
&nbsp
[ Car Door Closes ]
My husband.
&nbsp
- My uncle.
- Your what?
&nbsp
- Oh, God! That makes you--
- Auntie Vera?
&nbsp
Oh, G-- Oh!
Oh, God!
Ow! God! Oh, God.
&nbsp
What's my mother going to say?
I've disgraced my whole family.
&nbsp
Oh, the hell you did!
Not funny! Okay?
This is not a funny moment in my life.
&nbsp
Oh, relax.
Who's going to find out?
&nbsp
I'm home!
He's gonna find out.
That's who's gonna find out.
&nbsp
Don't worry!
He won't fire you.
&nbsp
There's no way I'm gonna
get a raise out of this.
&nbsp
Vera, what's the company car
doing in the driveway?
&nbsp
It broke down, darling. The driver
had to take the train back to town.
&nbsp
No, he didn't, darling. He's in here
having trouble with his fly.
&nbsp
- Get back! Do you ever stop?
- No!
&nbsp
How am I gonna get home?
Maybe we'll just have to
keep you here and adopt you.
&nbsp
You're a riot, Vera.
[ Yells ]
&nbsp
[ Grunts ] Please, Lord,
get me out of this.
&nbsp
I'll go all over the world telling
people not to screw the boss's wife.
&nbsp
What are you doing
in here?
&nbsp
- Feeling romantic.
- Oh.
&nbsp
What's for dinner?
Oh, Howard! You really know how to
sweep a girl back onto her feet.
&nbsp
[ Rustling ]
[ Barking ]
&nbsp
Go back!
- [ Barking ]
- [ Yells, Grunts ]
&nbsp
[ Snarling, Barking ]
Sit! Sit down!
&nbsp
You look like death on a cracker, man.
What happened to you?
&nbsp
I was chased by a 200-pound dog
with a mouth as big as my head.
&nbsp
- And that was the best thing
that happened last night.
- What was the worst thing?
&nbsp
- I got laid.
- I'm not sure you got
your priorities straight.
&nbsp
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
Oh! Hold the elevator.
Good morning.
&nbsp
- Hi.
- ¢Ü The light ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Is in my eyes ¢Ü
¢Ü How can I see through ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü What do I hold on to ¢Ü
¢Ü This time ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I've got to find ¢Ü
¢Ü Everything and more ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü 'Cause that's
what I'm fighting for ¢Ü
&nbsp
[ Melrose's Voice ]
We're entering a sensitive zone.
&nbsp
The guy in that office
just got canned.
&nbsp
The mail room knew about it on Friday.
He just found out today.
&nbsp
¢Ü Seems like the world
is upside down ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Don't know
where I'm going to ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü But you know
I'm turning it all around ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü It's just something
I've got to do ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü No one knows
what I feel inside ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Don't you know
that I just can't hide ¢Ü
&nbsp
[ Vera's Voice ] I'm gonna see
that my husband gives you a leg up.
&nbsp
No, thanks.
No.
&nbsp
No, I'm gonna make it
to the top on my own.
&nbsp
¢Ü And if rules have to break ¢Ü
¢Ü Whatever it takes
I know that it's my time ¢Ü
&nbsp
- ¢Ü It seems like the world
is upside down ¢Ü
- [ Phone Ringing ]
&nbsp
¢Ü I might have to break
some rules ¢Ü
&nbsp
- ¢Ü You know you've got to try ¢Ü
- [ Ringing ]
&nbsp
¢Ü You know I'll turn it
all around ¢Ü
&nbsp
- ¢Ü It's just something I've got to do ¢Ü
- [ Ringing ]
&nbsp
- ¢Ü It's something I've got to do ¢Ü
- [ Ringing ]
&nbsp
- Um... hello.
- Tucker, where the hell have you been?
&nbsp
We got a problem
in Midwest Distribution.
&nbsp
What are you gonna do about it?
What's, uh--
What's the problem?
&nbsp
Our stock is down
another quarter-point this morning.
&nbsp
Whose fault is that,
Thomas?
&nbsp
Nobody's fault, sir.
It's a momentary lapse in the market.
&nbsp
- Whose fault is it, Thomas?
- Uh, it's Davis's fault, sir.
&nbsp
His department hasn't been
pulling its weight.
&nbsp
- What do you have to say for yourself?
- I've been having troubles at home.
&nbsp
My wife ran over
the children's dog with her car,
&nbsp
then we had to buy
a new dog.
&nbsp
Then the new dog chewed up this
entire report that I'd been working on.
&nbsp
Are you suggesting
that your dog ate your homework?
&nbsp
- In a way, yes, sir.
- This is not grade school, Davis!
&nbsp
- Run at the back of the line.
Consider yourself on warning.
- Uh, yes, sir.
&nbsp
Everybody, check your pulse. Make sure
you're exercising at the optimum level.
&nbsp
I'm a bit above my level.
I better stop running... maybe.
&nbsp
- I'm above too.
- I really don't care. Everybody, run!
&nbsp
[ Man ] I can't get anybody's approval
for the extra two trucks!
&nbsp
- Tucker, what're you gonna do about it?
- [ Sighs ]
&nbsp
All right, look.
What does a boxcar cost?
&nbsp
The transfer sheet
shows that somebody...
&nbsp
is accumulating
an enormous block of our stock.
&nbsp
- What do you think about that, Thomas?
- I think it's very encouraging.
&nbsp
- Oh, you do, do you?
- Y es, sir.
&nbsp
When a stock takes a dive
and somebody buys a ton of it--
&nbsp
It means that stock is on
its way to a quick rebound.
&nbsp
It means that the company
is ripe for a hostile takeover!
&nbsp
- That's what I meant!
- A hostile takeover, sir?
&nbsp
Y es. I'm afraid that's
what we're looking at.
&nbsp
I want each of you to examine
your department and see
where you can cut costs.
&nbsp
Cut! Cut them
to the core!
&nbsp
We need to raise capital quickly
so we can boost stock support.
&nbsp
Boost it!
Boost it to the moon!
&nbsp
You gonna put that
in writin'?
&nbsp
Y eah! You tell the trucking company
that we have to service our customers.
&nbsp
If they're not going to help us,
we're going to find somebody who will.
&nbsp
Well, all right!
[ Chuckling ]
&nbsp
That's what we need, some gutsy
decisions! I'll get back to you.
&nbsp
Okay. Bye.
[ Whispers ]
Y es!
&nbsp
I have got to get that report
by the end of the day, Art,
or you're in the doghouse!
&nbsp
[ Art ] I don't know.
Mr. Prescott?
&nbsp
- I'm sorry this came in so late,
but it just arrived.
- It's about time!
&nbsp
Uh--
[ Panting ]
&nbsp
- This isn't the men's room.
- No.
&nbsp
They took the urinals out last week.
I didn't like them.
&nbsp
How about a paper cup?
- What?
- I'm sorry.
&nbsp
I'm just about the only
woman executive at Pemrose.
&nbsp
Some days, I have a chip
about the men's room.
&nbsp
Sorry.
[ Panting ]
&nbsp
Hey, nice office. Nice furniture.
It goes with your hair.
&nbsp
Thank you. I like your suit.
It goes nicely with your nose.
&nbsp
Well.
[ Panting ]
&nbsp
This conversation
isn't going very well.
&nbsp
Thank you. There's enough talk
in the world already. Good morning.
&nbsp
That meant good-bye.
I have work.
&nbsp
Oh, yeah.
Sorry. I have, uh,
a lot of work myself.
&nbsp
[ Tapping At
Computer Keyboard ]
&nbsp
Good morning.
[ Tapping Continues ]
&nbsp
I really swept her
off her feet.
&nbsp
[ Sighs ]
All right, Foster.
Let's do it!
&nbsp
Hello. This is
Carlton Whitfield, 4319.
&nbsp
That's right. I'm still waiting for
that secretary I requested last week.
&nbsp
I realize you're
busy down there,
&nbsp
but I'm typing my own letters
and answering my own calls,
&nbsp
and it's getting
to be a pain.
&nbsp
Empty?
[ Chuckles ]
&nbsp
Well, I've been here a week,
got my name on the door,
&nbsp
got a desk full of supplies and got
a geranium on my window ledge.
&nbsp
What I don't have
is a secretary.
&nbsp
Okay, I'll tell you what.
I'll have Personnel
send a boy up from the mail room
with the requisitions you need.
&nbsp
Just send me my secretary, okay?
Thank you very much.
&nbsp
Whew!
[ Secretaries Chattering ]
&nbsp
Got a memo here. Big cheese in 4319
wants his new secretary pronto.
&nbsp
I got a memo here that's
burning up my fingers.
&nbsp
New suit in 4319 wants his personalized
memos and stationery immediately.
&nbsp
- This guy is hot.
- Who?
&nbsp
I don't know.
Name's on the memo.
&nbsp
He wants nameplates for his door,
and he wants it by noon. Okay?
&nbsp
- Mm-hmm.
- Smile.
&nbsp
[ Phone Ringing ]
- You're late.
- I already done my rounds.
&nbsp
You didn't punch in.
Well, I couldn't wait to get to it.
Boy, I love my work.
&nbsp
Punch in, then run this up to Personnel
and wait for an answer.
&nbsp
Right.
[ Phone Ringing ]
&nbsp
[ Gasping ]
I-- I'm Jean,
your secretary.
&nbsp
I'm not wearing anything.
I see that.
&nbsp
It was warm.
Seems cooler now.
I'll get dressed.
&nbsp
Yes, sir.
I'll move my stuff in.
&nbsp
Great, Jean.
Good idea.
&nbsp
¢Ü Ow ¢Ü
Jean? I have
some notes here.
&nbsp
I also have some charts,
some graphs, some tapes.
&nbsp
They're all sorted
into different departments.
Can you read my handwriting?
&nbsp
- Sort of.
- Do your best.
&nbsp
I need some poster boards,
colored pencils, colored push pins,
&nbsp
T-square, drawing table, lots of
pencils, and my lunch. Chinese?
&nbsp
¢Ü I just can't wait 'til the day
when you knock on my door ¢Ü
&nbsp
- Hey, 4319?
- Uh, yeah.
&nbsp
¢Ü Now every time
I go for the mailbox ¢Ü
&nbsp
- ¢Ü Gotta hold myself down ¢Ü
- [ Brantley ] Great.
&nbsp
- Good morning.
¢Ü You're coming around ¢Ü
&nbsp
- Good morning.
- Hi.
&nbsp
¢Ü Now I'm walking
on sunshine, whoa-oh ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I'm walking on sunshine ¢Ü
¢Ü Whoa-oh ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I'm walking on sunshine
Whoa-oh ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü And don't it feel good ¢Ü
¢Ü Hey, all right now ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü And don't it feel good ¢Ü
¢Ü Hey, yeah ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I used to think
maybe you loved me ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Now I know that it's true ¢Ü
¢Ü And I don't want to spend
my whole life ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Just a-waiting for you ¢Ü
¢Ü Now, I don't want you
back for the weekend ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Not back for a day ¢Ü
¢Ü No, no, no ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I said, baby
I just want you back ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü And I want you to stay ¢Ü
¢Ü Oh, yeah, now
I'm walking on sunshine ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Whoa-oh ¢Ü
¢Ü I'm walking on sunshine
Whoa-oh ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü I'm walking on sunshine
Whoa-oh ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü And don't it feel good
Hey ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü All right now
And don't it feel good ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü Y eah
Oh, yeah ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü And don't it feel good ¢Ü
Hello again.
Small world.
&nbsp
Hello.
¢Ü Walking on sunshine ¢Ü
&nbsp
¢Ü¢Ü [ Whistling ]
Are you standing still
for some purpose?
&nbsp
Hey, I'm just soaking up
the atmosphere.
&nbsp
Whoa!
Executive Lounge, huh?
&nbsp
- Care to do a little lounging?
- No, I'm busy.
&nbsp
Ron, did you get those figures
on transfer costs and insurance?
&nbsp
Not yet.
Big delay in Chicago.
&nbsp
- Damn! I really need them!
- Blame Chicago.
&nbsp
- Maybe I can help.
- I'm sorry?
&nbsp
Transfer costs
and insurance for what?
&nbsp
By the time I explained,
I could find out myself.
&nbsp
Ron. Big weenie.
Why don't you explain it
to me over lunch?
&nbsp
- I'll have the answer by dessert.
- I don't eat lunch.
&nbsp
Why don't we start this again?
Carlton Whitfield. And you're?
&nbsp
Annoyed. Shit.
You know, I'm just
trying to be friendly.
&nbsp
You picked a bad time. I was counting
on those figures from Ron.
&nbsp
- Christy Wills. How do you do?
- Good.
&nbsp
Terrible news.
Just awful!
&nbsp
Conference room, everybody.
Come on, on the double.
&nbsp
[ All Murmuring ]
-You don't eat lunch. Do you eat dinner?
-Occasionally.
&nbsp
- Tonight?
- Booked.
&nbsp
- Tomorrow night?
- Booked.
&nbsp
All right, but don't beg, okay?
It's embarrassing.
&nbsp
[ Executives Murmuring ]
Do you know
what this is about?
&nbsp
Who are you?
Carlton Whitfield.
New employee.
&nbsp
I didn't get a memo
on that.
&nbsp
Oh, you will.
All right.
As long as I get the memo.
&nbsp
The absolute worst has happened.
We are the target of a corporate raid.
&nbsp
- Donald Davenport has filed a 13-D.
- [ Gasping ]
&nbsp
- A 13-D?
- [ Executives Murmuring ]
&nbsp
He's acquired five percent
of the stock,
&nbsp
and this is definitely the beginning of
a hostile takeover of our corporation.
&nbsp
I think we all know what happened the
last time Davenport took over a company.
&nbsp
Everyone was canned!
Mr. Prescott has sent down word
of what he wants us to do.
&nbsp
We are to recommend cuts
in every department.
&nbsp
Our job is to slash
the red ink...
&nbsp
in every nook and cranny,
because our company needs
the cash for its defense.
&nbsp
Anybody wanna fire
the first shot?
&nbsp
[ Christy ]
Kill Toledo.
&nbsp
That's a good idea.
If we close down
our distribution centers...
&nbsp
in Toledo, Joplin,
Jacksonville,
&nbsp
we'll slash the red ink
completely off the books.
&nbsp
[ Executives Applauding,
Murmuring In Agreement ]
&nbsp
Whitfield, you don't have to
raise your hand. Just speak.
&nbsp
Thank you. Well...
I know I'm new here
and everything.
&nbsp
- On the surface, these cuts
seem like a good idea--
- "Seem like a good idea"?
&nbsp
But closing down those distribution
centers would be a big mistake.
&nbsp
It so happens that those closings
are exactly what Mr. Prescott wants.
&nbsp
Well, then Mr. Prescott hasn't
thought things through very well.
&nbsp
- [ All Gasping ]
- I'm going to tell him you said that.
&nbsp
Good. Closing down
those centers...
&nbsp
will put a strain on
this company's cash position.
&nbsp
In the long run, those cuts are going
to hurt this company's innate value.
&nbsp
Innate value?
What is he talking about?
&nbsp
Davidson here will back me up
on this. Davidson?
&nbsp
I'm Proctor. He's Davidson.
Well, damn it,
Davidson, tell him!
&nbsp
You wrote a memo to Mr. Thomas
explaining what I'm talking about.
&nbsp
Well, how do you know
I wrote that memo?
&nbsp
How did I know
you wrote that memo?
&nbsp
Who else could write
that memo, Davidson?
&nbsp
That memo was famous.
That memo
was a masterpiece.
&nbsp
Clear, concise, to the point.
That was the best damn memo I ever read!
&nbsp
In fact, that memo wasn't even a memo.
That memo was literature.
&nbsp
- Well, thank you.
- You're welcome.
&nbsp
If you have finished your book report,
could you explain what your point is?
&nbsp
- The point is, we gotta be bold.
- That's my point.
&nbsp
- We gotta build. We gotta expand.
- [ Davidson ] Absolutely!
&nbsp
Expanding is the only way
to help the situation.
&nbsp
We gotta make
this company so strong,
&nbsp
Davenport won't be able to find anyone
willing to give up Pemrose stock.
&nbsp
It'll be too damn valuable.
Then we'll buy his ass out!
&nbsp
- Absolutely!
- [ Executives Laughing, Agreeing ]
&nbsp
- How old are you, Mister, uh, Mister--
- Whitfield.
&nbsp
- Yes.
- Twenty-four.
&nbsp
I think you should keep quiet
until you're at least 25.
&nbsp
If I may, I don't think Whitfield's age
should be an issue here.
&nbsp
No one is interested
in your opinion, Davis.
&nbsp
We gotta block
that takeover.
&nbsp
I'm too old to look for a job.
Nobody would hire me.
&nbsp
[ Executives Arguing ]
- This meeting is going nowhere!
- [ Arguing Stops ]
&nbsp
Mr. Prescott's
command stands!
&nbsp
We are to find those cuts!
Meeting adjourned.
&nbsp
[ Executives Chattering ]
You'll pick up the coats.
That looks like one only a lot smaller.
&nbsp
Hey! Harvard!
Where the helI've you been?
&nbsp
Personnel. You said to wait for
an answer. They are real slow up there.
&nbsp
- ¢Ü¢Ü [ Headphones: Rock ]
- There's something going
on around here, Foster.
&nbsp
I'm gonna be on you like a rash.
You got that? Like a rash.
&nbsp
Ooh, won't the other guys get jealous?
Whoa, heads!
&nbsp
[ Woman, Man Groaning,
Grunting ]
&nbsp
- [ Man Chuckles ]
- [ Woman ] Down, boy.
&nbsp
¢Ü¢Ü [ Salsa ]
[ Groaning,
Grunting Continue ]
&nbsp
[ High-Pitched Squealing ]
[ Banging Wall ]
&nbsp
[ Woman Moaning ]
[ Moaning Stops ]
&nbsp
[ Loud Moans ]
- [ Moaning In Unison ]
- Come on.