- Fluffy, why are you there?
- Put your cat away.
The alarm is off.
Heat the sauna, dear.
Right away.
I'm incredibly thirsty.
Mom, look!
What's that?
The stereo is gone.
My porcelain soldiers!
Mom, your soldiers!
Don't touch anything!
- Call the police.
- At once.
Laura, don't touch!
There is a letter.
The stereo is in the fridge.
Readme!
Your Days of Plenty are Numbered.
They work 14-hours days for peanuts!
7 days a week!
We buy the shoes for 100 Euros.
But they only cost 5 Euros to make!
Do you know who really makes those shoes?
No
Children in Indonesia, the Philippines...
Please leave the store.
In Indonesia, Philippines...
This isn't allowed.
That's enough. Get out!
I'm just handing out flyers.
Don't touch me!
They’re made by children
between the ages of 12 and 16!
Capitalist pigs!
Pigs!
The state supports capitalism!
Let go of him!
The demonstration is legal!
,
There's Miss Lindner!
Eviction papers for you.
Two weeks to vacate.
Leave it in tip-top shape
or loose deposit.
But I paid the rent back.
Yes, but 6 months too late.
Have a nice day!
Ticket control!
Tickets please.
Young man, did you hear me?
You, there. Ticket please!
What a stench!
He stinks up the entire car
Let's see you ticket.
- Stop drinking.
- ¡Leave me alone!
Take it easy or else!
Show me your ticket.
Ticket, please.
Do you have a ticket?
Take your hands off!
No drinking in here!
That's enough!
What's going on?
Mind your own business.
He is a total wreck.
Leave him alone.
What's it to you?
End of the line for you.
Here, you dropped this.
Hold on.
Jule, what's wrong?
Everything, nothing...
Move in with us for now.
A cosy little commune.
Sure.
Taste this. It's raspberry.
Choose the bright colors,
not always the depressing ones.
Shit!
Jan!
What a pain!
Bastard!
Do you think it was a good
idea to move in with Jan?
Jan is totally alright.
You just have to know him better.
I dunno.
Sometimes he gives me
this really aggressive look.
Really scary.
Jule, I've known Jan for 15 years.
He's a little unpredictable.
But he's a loyal soul.
And he's got a backbone.
Not many people do.
I dunno. He's kind of weird.
What's that?
Oxygen concentrator...
He bought it "used" the other day.
Really?
Are you excited
about going to Barcelona?
Sure!
Are you excited?
It's just that my debts
are out of control.
Baby, it's my treat. Completely.
We'll have a great time.
You just don't get it.
I have to straighten this out.
Beating yourself up
wont make things better.
Try to relax!
Just forget it.
Hello.
Man, we have to find
a new approach.
Take it to another level.
Everything is fine.
Bullshit!
We need to see things...
in a larger context.
What are you talking about?
Forget it!
- Got a light?
- Check in my bag.
No.
Look in the small one.
Open your eyes!
What is this?
Looks like a watch to me.
Won it at poker?
I think so, yeah.
- Peter, are you nuts?
- No, I won it.
Put it back where you found it.
- Yeah, I'll do that.
- OK. Thanks.
- Man, are you crazy?
- What?
You just threw 5000 Euros
out of the window!
So what?
Yeah, so what?
It's a principle!
You and your damn morals!
What morals?
What's it worth if we
are seen as common burglars?
If we can't agree,
then let's just drop it.
OK, man. I got it.
But in Kreuzberg,
I know this Turk...
He would have given me 2500 for it.
We could have split 50/50.
You don't get it
and you don't want to!
But it was just sitting there...
So shiny, calling out to me.
It's green.
Change the station.
So far, so far away from home...
Shit it won't get any louder.
No hellos, no hearts, no kisses
No sorrow.
Everything so far, so far away.
The best of times
You asshole!
...where flowers bloom,
where my sweetheart lives...
One more time!
Fucking awesome!
Miss!
We ordered Williams pear brandy.
That's William pear brandy.
But never in these glasses!
These are liqueur glasses.
So?
Can't beverages be served
in their proper glasses?
I simply cannot drink
from this glass.
Thank you.
- Just a moment, please.
- By the way...
Don't use the same brandy.
It's lost its flavor, understand?
Yes, by all means.
Table 47 prefers brandy glasses.
You have more customers.
At table 22.
Dream on your own time!
Be careful getting home!
- Sweet dreams.
- You too.
Can't you do something else?
Putting up those posters
doesn't pay much.
Plus, you're out all night.
Yeah, I'm sick of it too.
But there's nothing else
Good night.
What?
You can't go?
I have to turn over the apartment.
That asshole! I can't believe it.
It's only 3 days.
I don't get it.
Shit!
Then I'm staying too.
No, this is your big break.
You have to go alone.
I'll find someone to help you, OK?
Sorry, I overslept.
You can use this one.
- Here?
- Maybe over there.
How about some music?
Is that Jeff Cole?
I saw him in concert.
At the Columbia?
I was there.
Funny, I didn't see you!
This is a great place.
Why move?
I can't afford it.
Your debts?
Peter told you?
He mentioned it.
That idiot.
It's not a big deal.
We all have debts.
But not like me.
I probably can't compeed but...
How much?
1000 Euros? 10000 Euros?
More? 20000?
- 30000?
- Jan, please...
Don't ruin my day.
94500.
Euros?
What did you do? Burn down a factory?
If only.
A year ago, on the highway...
I was in my old Golf.
Ahead of me, this executive
driving his Mercedes S-Class.
He brakes. I don't.
His car is totaled.
My registration had expired.
I hadn't paid my insurance.
That fucking Mercedes
cost 100000 Euros.
But I'm now down to 94500.
You work your butt off
so that some big shot
can drive a Mercedes?
For executives like him...
That car is petty cash.
But it was my fault.
He was in the right
In the right? Is that justice?
You are paying for
some jerk's lifestyle.
A 100000-Euro car?
Why not gold-plated pipes?
It makes me sick too!
I should never have reached
for the glove compartment.
I screwed up.
Now I pay the price.
Who says that?
The cops?
The prosecutors, the news rags?
Fucking petty bourgeois ethic!
Decency, honesty, family values...
Get to work on time,
pay your taxes...
All hammered into us.
First in school, then on TV.
For what?
So guys like that can
buy expensive cars?
To hell with those morals!
Ruining a young woman's
life is immoral.
Think that guy ever thought
he was wrong?
You are right.
But I missed a payment once...
They were knocking on my door.
Step 1: Recognizing injustice.
Step 2: Action.
But how?
Take the first step alone.
Find allies for the second.
From where?
Take the first step, then call me.
I calculated how much of my life...
I'm giving to that asshole...
Just for fun.
And?
About 8 years.
But only once I'm a teacher.
That's what you want to do?
Better than waitressing.
And before the accident?
Concretely...
I guess I wanted...
This might sound stupid.
I guess I just wanted
to live wild an free.
That's not stupid.
It's OK.
That's what half of us want.
Then come the compromises.
That's how it goes.
Not necessarily.
Sometimes not.
Some people make it.
Anyhow...
If you keep working
for that asshole,
you'll loose faith
in everything.
I go this way.
I go that way.
Thanks again.
If you still need help,
I can come again.
Great!
Sure.
- So where are you headed?
- Sleeping at a girlfriend's.
How about you?
I think I'll cook something.
Want to join me?
Gladly.
DAYS OF PLENTY.
All washed up?
Shall we cook?
Jan, it was great.
Guys who can cook
must get all the girls.
Not really.
Other things count more.
You join me for a smoke?
I don't know.
It's dessert.
Dope chokes young people's
revolutionary energy.
Grass too?
No, grass is OK.
The drugs the body produces
aren't bad either.
Actually, they're greats.
Like adrenalin?
For example.
There are thousands. Endorphins...
Happiness hormones
when you are in love...
Now you're talking hard drugs.
Watch out for those.
Don't fall into a life of crime!
Fear is an awesome drug.
Don't let fear take control.
Use it as a motor.
It takes practice.
Put yourself into a situation
where you're scared stiff.
First there's panic.
But after a while,
the body's self-protection
system kicks in.
You do things you never dared.
You overcome you limitations.
You believe you can do anything.
Really!
Do you know it or think it?
I know it.
Done it a thousand times.
¨A thousand times gone bad...¨
Run a check on-that plate.
It's OK.
It works if you smear it.
It's not good wallpaper.
- How come?
- The glue isn't right.
But i followed the instructions.
Shit!
You know what?
Fuck the deposit!
We should have done this before.
It works.
Hope they'll like it.
Look.
Every heart is a revolutionary cell.
Smile!
Excuse me...
Your hair!
Yes, I'll fix it.
Roast beef with potatoes
and summer vegetables.
We should smoke downstairs
in the storeroom.
Why not tell him too?
That way he can say
all we do is smoke.
You're right.
There you are!
The place is packed.
Just fixing my hair.
I can tell.
Are you crazy?
In the kitchen?
- I'm truly sorry, .
- What were you thinking?
Know what?
I've had it with you.
That's enough. You're fired.
No, boss. I need this job.
It's my fault. I smoked first.
I said it was OK.
Then you are fired too.
- What?
- Pack it up!
Wait, Jule. Let me.
Boss, wait!
Why can't I shut up?
What for?
It's great that you defended him.
Yeah sure.
But I need that job, you see.
No, I don't see.
You go to all those protests...
against exploitation and oppression...
but you're still
some bastard's slave.
Those protests are totally useless.
The rebellion is difficult now.
Before, all it took was
dope and long hair.
And the establishment
was automatically against you.
What was considered subversive then
you can buy in shops today.
Che Guevara t-shirts
or anarchy stickers.
That's why there aren't any more
youth movements.
Everyone has the feeling
it's all be done before.
Others tried and failed.
Why should it work for us?
For all revolutions,
one thing is clear...
Even if some didn’t work,
the most important thing is...
that the best ideas survived.
The same goes for personal revolts.
What turns out good...
what survives in you...
that makes you stronger.
What do you think?
How many people down there
are thinking about revolution?
In this moment, not many.
At 10:45, they are watching TV.
Probably.
Europeans spend 4 hours a day
in front of the boob tube.
4 hours!
Terrible!
Doesn't leave much time
for revolutionary thoughts.
You know...
Not being part of all that...
that's not the problem.
The problem is...
I can't find anything
I really want to believe in.
Got any ideas for me?
Follow me.
Now what?
Who lives here?
You never wondered why
Peter and I stay out all night?
To put up posters. What else?
Then...
What do you do?
We are driving around looking for villas.
When we find one we like...
we take a closer look.
Then what? You take pretty photos
and put them in an album?
Is this a joke?
We break into them.
Just one catch.
We don't steal anything.
We re-arrange the furniture.
And we leave a message.
"Your Days of Plenty are Numbered"
or "You Have Too Much Money"...
signed "The Edukators"
You and Peter are the Edukators?
Why?
So they feel less safe...
in their high security neighborhoods.
It's a creepy feeling...
Someone has been in your home.
They have been watching you.
And they will keep watching you.
Why not empty the villas
and give everything to the poor?
They expect burglars.
We want to really scare them.
Standing in the bank,
they'll hear faint whispers:
"You have too much money..."
They'll feel completely alone.
Nothing can help them.
Not money, not a spouse,
not any damn cop.
Are you serious?
I'll show you.
Guess where the camera is?
Behind the grill.
Skeleton key...
Look at this.
Peter found this list.
The x's mark our hits.
This is real.
No way... This is insane.
How did it start?
Not a clue.
Peter installed alarm systems.
I once asked him...
if he knew how
to disable an alarm system.
He said no problem.
So we did it
You two...
Isn't this Zehelendorf?
Which street?
Finkenbachstrasse.
No way! Wait...
Shit!
Jan, shit!
Take a left down there, OK?
Now I'll show you!
That must be it, there!
Stop, pull over there.
I think that asshole...
I owe money to lives there.
What are you doing?
He really lives here.
The mailbox is full.
They must be away.
Let's take a look.
Down at the lake we can get in.
Don't be a drag!
Let's just take a peek.
Wait up!
See?
Check out this place!
With boat and private dock...
The blinds are down.
They must be on vacation.
Don't be so sure.
How would you break in?
Maybe through a cellar window.
Let's go closer!
Doesn't that look like
the ideal point of entry?
Totally hidden.
It could work.
Let's break.
You're insane. No way!
I have to see how
that asshole lives. Please!
This is too spontaneous.
It's too risky
But you're a pro.
I just want a peek!
Jule, I'm not a pro.
We have to monitor the house first.
You can see no one's home.
Please!
We can come back a few times.
Then do it with Peter.
They'll be back then.
But only if the house
is on file, which I really doubt.
Agreed.
Shit!
What?
- Bingo!
- What?
- We've got his alarm system.
- We are going in?
I'll only have 30 seconds
to find the main console.
- We do it Edukators style.
- Agreed.
Once I open the window,
I'll have only 30 seconds.
When the alarm is off,
I'll come for you.
- So I wait here?
- Yes.
Jan, check out the pool.
Come on!
Let's make sure no one's home.
It's OK.
I told you...
petty cash.
- What are you doing?
- Don't panic.
Less conspicuous than a flashlight.
You can take off you mask.
No one's home.
This is him.
He needs cooling off.
And vertically?
Got it?
Awesome!
Looks much better now!
You have too much money.
The Edukators.
OK, let's go.
Come on, Jan.
Let's do something extreme.
I need to work off some aggression.
Please!
You're crazy.
We have been here to long.
Let's throw the couch in the pool.
It's a great idea. Come on!
Let's do it!
Then we'll go.
- Will it pass?
- It's hot here.
First things first!
One...
two...
Three!
Come on
Help me.
¡Idiot!
¿What's that?
It's me!
Where from?
Jule, give it back.
Come and get it..
Wait here. I'll be right back.
Don't do this, man.
Jan, let's go now!
Pack our things.
I'll be right back.
Got everything?
- Shit!
- What's wrong?
Cops!
That was so awesome!
I'd love to see Hardenberg's face!
when he comes home
and finds his couch in the pool.
It was the best, I tell you.
38 degrees...
the whole city is one big party.
But what was really the best...
I found this in Barcelona.
Look.
"Strange Edukators...
Nasty surprise for Berlin family,
upon return from vacation,
Perpetrators
had broken into their villa.
But nothing was stolen.
Only furniture
and valuables were moved.
Responsibility claimed
in a note signed: The Edukators.
Police still have no solid leads
to their identities".
Which paper?
The Tagesanzeiger.
Super.
I got this for Jule.
Think she'll like it?
It's perfect for her.
Wake up, man.
You seem out of it.
That must be Jule.
How are you?
And you? Everything OK?
I have to tell you something.
Wait... I brought you something.
We have to talk.
I left my phone at the villa.
What? Really?
I'm pretty sure.
I know I had it in the car before.
- It's not in my bag anymore.
- Don't tell Peter.
Why not?
Just don't tell him anything.
Look.
Isn't it nice?
Try it on.
He really needs a chick.
I'm sure that would help.
Really.
Jan, see her?
She's been checking you out.
Isn't she sweet?
Is she sweet or what?
So ask her to dance.
Leave him alone.
Want me to ask for you?
I'll ask her.
Sleep well.
- You, too.
- Bye.
I'm going for a walk.
I need some air.
Come in, man. Let's have a drink.
Put your oxygen on.
Not today.
I'll stay out for a while.
I'm off to bed.
Let's get out here.
I have a bad feeling.
We need to find your phone.
But maybe they already saw
the hole in the window.
What would you tell the cops?
Hardenberg know you.
Jan, please.
No. We have to go back in.
Want to go to jail?
It’s not here.
Where was the jacket?
- And?
- No.
Let's try calling it.
It's on voice mail.
I should've known.
I'll go upstairs.
I have to get rid of fingerprints.
- Hurry!
- I'll be right back.
I just arrived.
Where? Home, of course!
Rita, I didn't drive 700 km
at night to...
I already told you.
Gerling says he needs me.
What could I do?
Like I told you,
in 3 days if all goes well.
Shit!
Theresa left the bathroom light
on again.
Me too.
Say hi to the kids.
Take care, bye.
Found it!
What are you doing here?
I know you...
Hold on!
Fucking shit!
Is he alive?
Should we call the medics?
- No.
- Let's just go.
Did he see you?
Yes.
Did he recognize you?
Of course.
Then we can't go.
- Come on.
- We can't just go!
Think hard!
- What are we going to do?
- Fucking shit!
Not a clue!
Not a clue, man!
I don't know what to do!
I don't either!
Call Peter.
No.
Why not?
Because, no.
But why not?
You call him. I can't.
- What?
- Just call him!
It can't be...
This is Jule.
Jan and I are in big shit.
We need your help.
Please come right away.
Is this necessary?
Just run away.
The police don't have to know.
I won't say anything.
Maybe he won't talk.
Let's just go.
Are you crazy?
That guy lies all day long!
Shit! He dialed the cops.
Did the call go through?
We have to go.
- But we...
- We're out of time, OK?
He is coming with us.
Can't we come to a solution?
Shut up!
I won't be a kidnapper!
You can't pull out now!
The cops are coming.
We'll take him and decide later.
End of discussion.
This is crazy!
Open the door.