Very good.
Exquisitely worked.
You've crafted a jewel, my boy.
Perfect for a courtesan or priest...
to pluck after supper, or polish...
...Sundays after mass.
In other words...
...this violin will never bear my name.
Put your anger into your work, my boy.
Stay with me and learn.
Madame?
Cesca, can you still see the future?
Are you all right?
Sit down.
Did you call me? I was in the garden.
- I can come here, can't I?
- Of course.
This is part of my house.
Of course, madame.
I have some new amulets and bones for you.
If your husband spits on them it will help.
Are you hungry?
Don't eat that, it's fish.
So?
Your child will be slow to learn.
I also have some stones for you...
and a key to wear around your neck.
My husband's tired of spitting.
Spitting's what men are good for.
A father's saliva, the best thing he can give.
Cesca... Tell me my child's future.
I can't do that.
Don't worry about my husband.
It's not your husband.
I'm simply not able to do it.
I see.
Until the baby is born your humors are one.
However... I can read your future.
No, I told you, I'm scared.
Come on, madame.
Five cards.
It's only the future.
What if it's bad?
I'll pretend not to see it.
Tell me everything.
The Moon.
You'll live a long life, full and rich.
There's... There's travel ahead.
I see... a long journey.
Niccolo?
Leave us.
Close the door.
What is it?
Why do you come here in your condition?
- I know I'll find you here.
- What is it?
- I talked to Cesca.
- And...?
She read my future.
Cesca! Dear God!
And the birth, she said,
will be very difficult, and painful.
They always are.
This is no prediction!
We're talking about me!
Why do you listen to Cesca?
She is our servant.
I have an excellent midwife,
an astrologer, a doctor.
They'll all be there. It will be perfect.
I know.
How do you know?
I'm so old to be having a baby.
This is a violin.
It's different.
I still have to varnish it.
But there's something...
It's perfect.
Everything else here is junk...
worthy of a peddlar, or the trash heap.
But this is my masterpiece.
I made it for our son, Anna.
Our son will be a musician.
He'll live for music.
He'll bring us pride and
beauty to the world, my love.
I wanted to surprise you, but you see...
I can also make predictions.
It's too big for a baby.
He'll grow.
My child will come when this moon is full.
Come to bed.
You're jealous of our relationship.
Me and the moon.
No, I'm not jealous.
I know you'll come back.
Master, a boy is asking for you.
Tell him to go away.
He won't, sir. The doctor sent him.
I think you'd better come.
Your wife, sir. The doctor...
What is it? She's not well.
Having the baby.
Get out.
Get out! Leave me alone, for God's sake!
You must clean the violin every day.
Care for it well.
This is your violin for as long
as you're with us at the orphanage.
A curse hangs over you, madame.
Danger to those who come under your thrall.
And there will be many... many.
It is a powerful card, the Hanged Man.
I see, I see danger... infirmity and disease.
I'm sorry, but what kind, I can't say.
There are many kinds of sickness.
These roads, Brother Christoph!
You've no idea what I've endured.
And why such haste?
What is so urgent that it couldn't
wait until my next visit?
We have a boy, sir.
You have many boys!
This boy is a miracle, you'll see.
Vienna swarms with miracles.
Not like him.
We felt you should see him at once.
Does he speak French?
No, sir. Unfortunately.
All your students should learn French.
It's the language of music.
It hones the ear and elevates the mind!
Monsieur Poussin... This is Kaspar Weiss.
What violin is this?
I haven't seen it before.
We've had it for 100 years.
Far too big for him.
Look at his hands.
He should play on a child's violin.
Even Mozart... God rest his soul,
played in Versailles on a child's violin.
No shame in that.
Wouldn't you like a smaller... instrument?
He seems to manage.
Let him try.
Play, my boy. Play.
I see.
Monsieur Poussin?
We're prepared to offer a small sum...
to help him in his study.
They say you're a good boy,
well-mannered and clean.
Glad to hear it.
But you don't like vegetables. Is that so?
Yes, sir.
What don't you like?
Carrots, sir... and beans and cabbage...
These monks can't cook.
They also write you've a weak heart.
Is that so?
You must have a strong heart to play a violin.
Believe me.
And stronger still to live in Vienna.
You shall see, Vienna is an infuriating city...
infuriating, but magnificent.
Magnificent... this city!
Antoinette!
May I present to you Kaspar Weiss.
One of the most gifted children on Earth.
But, Georges, we can't.
My wife, Antoinette Poussin.
Good afternoon, Kaspar.
How nice to meet you.
Go on in, I'll show you your room in a minute.
Georges, please. We can't afford to keep him!
We can't afford not to.
There's something about
your playing that eludes me.
I've decided to analyze it
systematically with a scientific method.
First, your bowing and your left hand phrasing.
Your detache, ornamentation and your taste.
And theory! Theory, too, is important.
You need a lot more than inspiration
to play the violin.
You need method. You must think. And work.
Won't you eat?
You must eat!
Do you want something else?
Try this cheese. I think you'll like it.
It's French!
Try some.
Taste it.
You'll see, a little different from
the monks' crumbly cheese!
Go on. Kaspar... if you play well...
you'll enjoy the finest fare.
We can't afford coal, let alone food!
Sell your jewelry! Sell your David!
Besides he voted...
to behead the king, the monster!
My boy play well, and there will be cheese.
Violin, cheese.
May I go to my room now?
Go ahead. And sleep well.
Madame will assist you in your prayers.
Why speak French? He doesn't understand.
So he'll learn!
I want them to know who taught him!
Good morning, Poussin.
I pride myself on visiting the
Taufer Orphanage three times a year...
to offer my services as a teacher...
as a gesture of support for
those good men of the cloth.
This year, they called early.
I was sceptical,
but when this child raised his bow...
when he played his first note,
well, Baron von Spielmann...
I knew my prayers had been answered.
You've unearthed another wunderkind.
I've no money for you, Poussin.
I have no concerts to offer you.
It isn't for the money.
I suggest you find another patron.
Must I beg?
Isn't that what you're doing?
Yes... I am.
In 3 weeks...
I'm holding a private audition at my salon.
Prince Mannsfeld is leaving for Prussia...
and seeks a prodigy to accompany him.
He must hear this boy.
Three weeks. Can you be ready? Truthfully!
I could be ready tomorrow.
Be very certain, Poussin.
If you embarrass me again...
I've charmed the crowned heads of France.
Where are those heads now?
Rolling in the gutters of the new Republic!
The first phrase, the entire section,
must be played staccato.
A modern style, well and good,
but let's not be crude.
You liked it, didn't you?
I'm delighted.
You're going to play it again and
again and again.
See this? It's a clockwork chronometer,
of my invention.
It's called the Poussin-meter.
You will heed it with the same
deference you would me.
What you just played corresponds to
a tempo like this.
Each day, as we progress
we shall push down this little ball one notch.
Until finally, in 3 weeks,
you'll be playing like this.
The world will be yours.
You see, Antoinette,
there's something I still don't understand.
His violin has a wonderful sound,
and a lovely form.
Of course, it's Italian.
Is it very valuable?
Why do you ask?
Well, it could pay the rent, if ever...
He will play divinely, my dear.
Can't you trust me?
Yes, of course I can.
But must he sleep with it?
He could roll over on it.
What?
He sleeps with it?
Straight, proud. Lift your chin. There.
Perfect, your bow. You're clutching.
Your body's stiff, your elbow's locked.
I knew something was holding you back.
Something, but I didn't know what.
Now it's totally clear.
You're oppressed by your violin.
It has you completely
enslaved. Look at you. There, very good.
If you want to advance, Kaspar Weiss,
you must let go.
What do you mean, sir? I don't understand.
Antoinette tells me you sleep with your violin.
Tonight you'll sleep by yourself.
Without the violin.
Without your violin.
Thank you for coming so quickly.
Thank you so much, Doctor. Goodnight.
Feeling better?
Yes, thank you.
The doctor says your heart must have
stopped for a minute.
I'm sorry.
It's alright,
but we don't want it to happen again.
Were you worried?
Were you nervous about the audition?
It will be... just fine.
You know that, don't you?
Georges!
I know, I know.
Kaspar, we want to tell you...
you don't have to do it if you don't want to.
You don't have to play.
I don't?
We can cancel the audition.
We'll manage, somehow.
It's better than making you sick, do you see?
You don't have to be famous.
No? Yes.
Sorry. Malade.
I want to be famous.
Sir, I really do.
That's my boy.
I'm very proud of you.
I want you to rest, relax.
Madame Poussin will bring
a visitor you like very much.
Good!
There you go!
We better sleep now.
Tomorrow's going to be a busy day.
Perfect.
And now, backwards. Are you ready?
Rejected! The shame!
Kaspar Weiss, violin!
Play the best you can.
Play your best.
Master Poussin and his protege, Kaspar Weiss.
Closer. Come closer.
So you're the wild child...
I've heard all about.
An orphan raised by monks.
If you prefer, we can call in the next...
There's the son of...
How charming to think a monastery has
actually produced something worthwhile.
That's a lovely instrument you have.
May I see it? May I see it, my boy?
Is it for sale?
I'd give you a good price for it.
He's very attached to his instrument.
So I see.
Perhaps after he's played...
Of course, let him play. I might take him too.
Come, play for me.
Won't you play something for me? Please.
Poussin!
Just play for him, son. Play.
Monsieur Poussin?
On behalf of the brothers I thank you...
for the generosity you showed Kaspar.
He takes with him the many gifts you gave him.
I did what I could.
Would you honor us by sharing
our modest supper?
It's very kind of you, but...
my wife awaits me,
all of Vienna awaits me.
Of course, we understand.
I do have one question.
The violin...
what will become of it?
I'm sorry, I thought you knew.
Naturally you were foremost in our thoughts.
After all the time and energy you invested...
it would be wrong to give it to another child.
Yes, of course.
So we buried it with the boy.
He can play it in heaven.
Yes, quite right.
And then I see a time of life...
a time of lust of energy...
Ioosed across mountains and oceans, and time.
Confusing, madame, I know.
But I see it.
I'm certain.
Yours is a Lazarus soul.
We're on hold.
You'd tell her our story, explain its past.
Brother, please, she doesn't care.
She's doing her job.
But if you convince her...
I feel helpless.
Isn't there something we can do?
Yes... we can pray.
And then... a man comes into your life...
a handsome man, and intelligent.
He'll seduce you with his talent and worse.
In short, he's the Devil.
It's there, Duval's.