Ripped by thewildbunch22
(Celebratory lndian music)
(Sings joyous song)
(Sings joyously in response)
(Upbeat rock 'n' roll music)
I got chills
They're multiplyin'
And I'm losin' control
'Ca.use the power you're supplyin'
It's electrifyin'
-You're the one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
Oo-oo-oo, honey
-The one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
Oo-oo-oo, honey
-The one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
Oo-oo-oo
(Upbeat dance music)
-You can all dance like that.
-No. Impossible.
You can.
Dance is like love.
Just move your feet
to the beat of your heart.
Go, yes!
Come on, follow your inner beat!
RAMU: Come on, ladies.
Move your feet to the beat of your heart.
(Women giggle and laugh)
(Music stops)
I told you you could do it.
Ladies, I have an announcement.
I'm sad to say
that today will be my last day here...
at Shanti Dance and Modern Movement.
-What?
-No.
Next week, my classes will be taken over
by Sister Munju Murthi, a nun from Kerala.
-But why? Where are you going?
-To America.
-You're going to drive a cab there?
-A cab? No way.
I'm going to be a star.
-You can do that?
-Well, of course you can.
Anything's possible in America.
Look at my friend, Vijay Rao.
-The one with the red Mercedes?
-And the penthouse?
He went there with nothing.
No job, no money, no visa...
and he's a big success.
I don't want to dance with a nun.
(Slow lndian backbeat)
GIRL 1 : 'Bye, Ramu.
'Bye. Take care.
GIRL 2: 'Bye. We'll miss you.
(Upbeat instrumental lndian music)
(Engines and motors revving)
(Upbeat lndian song)
MRS. GUPTA: I wanted a spring wedding.
I was going to bake a mango cake.
-You'll end up working in some restaurant.
-With bad food.
Soon you'll be back,
begging me for a decent life.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe I'm better off staying here...
-and becoming a salaried man.
-Don't even say that.
But I tell my students,
"Move your feet to the beat of your heart."
And my heart is telling me to go to America.
I dreamt of it my whole life.
RAMU: Don't worry.
I'll be fine.
You'll not only be fine. You'll be famous.
Like Ricky Martin.
Mira, be careful!
Your bike!
Hey, man, can I get your autograph?
-So your flight was good?
-Yeah, it was good.
-And your sister. How's your sister?
-Okay.
Is the Mercedes in the shop or something?
Or something.
This is the penthouse.
It's the top floor.
RAMU: It's the only floor.
RAMU: You're a real bastard, you know that?
VIJAY: Come on, ya.a.r.
If I told you the truth,
you never would've come.
Immigration!
Open up!
SANJIV: Oh, shit.
VIJAY: INS!
VIJAY: This is Amit. He's a nerd.
AMIT: What's up, ya.a.r?
That's Sanjiv. He's illegal.
VIJAY: And an idiot!
Bhen ki lohdi! Yeah, I was reading, Vij.
Hey, Ramu.
Kya. ka.r ra.he ho, ba.ba.? Welcome.
SANJIV: Good to meet you.
Now the rent goes down.
Now welcome my boy Ram to America.
Peera.h! Peera.h!
To America!
NEIGHBOUR: Shut the fuck up!
RAMU: I know it's been a while, but....
The penthouse is beautiful.
Vijay's doing really well.
No, New York is great.
Cook says your samosas are getting cold.
That was the butler.
My samosas are getting cold.
I better go, Na.nima.. Na.ma.ste.
(Restaurant chatter)
(Slow sitar strumming)
PATRON: The guy's totally lame.
How long can that guy go
for the "working late" crap?
What is this?
I ordered the chicken tikka masala.
That is chicken tikka masala, sir.
(Mimicking accent)
That is not chicken tikka masala, sir.
That is definitely chicken tikka masala.
Dude, I know chicken fucking tikka masala,
and that's not it.
So how about taking your skinny brown ass
back to the kitchen and get me some?
Yes, sir. I'm sorry, dude.
WOMAN: Oh, my God.
(Shocked gasps from other patrons)
No chance.
I even told him you got 10 kids
and your wife's in a wheelchair.
I don't care.
I don't want that stupid job back.
Come on, man.
You got a roof over your head...
and food in your belly.
What more do you want?
I want what you promised me in your letters.
So did you, Vij.
The penthouse, the Mercedes.
So what happened to your business empire?
RAMU: Huh?
VIJAY: It's not that easy.
I don't want it to be easy.
I just want my chance.
Maybe I'm not good enough.
Maybe all I can do is be a waiter,
but I want my chance to find out.
-Isn't that the American dream?
-You're a fool.
Do you know why they call it
the American dream?
Because it only happens
when you're asleep.
(Upbeat lndian instrumental music)
DWAIN: Next!
I'm here for the audition. Ramu Gupta.
Tell me something I don't know.
My mother comes from Hyderabad.
My father wanted to marry a Muslim girl,
but his family wouldn't let him.
Everybody's a comedian.
DWAIN: What'd you say your name was?
RAMU: Ram Chandra Gupta.
Actor.
Dancer.
Okay, Rammy, what would you say
your specialty is?
Well, I move smooth.
I take instruction easily.
I'm not afraid to try new things.
Good. We like that.
How big are you hard?
Yes, I work very hard.
No. Your johnson.
How big is your johnson?
RAMU: Johnson?
DWAIN: Your wand.
Your pork-sword. Your baloney pony.
Would you like to see my Macarena?
Is that what you call it
in your part of the world?
Let me see your Macarena.
(Ramu hums melody)
Hey, Ma.ca.rena.!
All right, you wanna lose the pants?
Is that part of the movie?
Could be.
I get it.
Like Tom Cruise in Risky Business?
(Piano rock 'n' roll intro)
(Rock 'n' roll music in Hindi)
DWAIN: All right!
You know you could be big.
Oh, yes, sir, very big.
I can see that.
I must say, most guys come in here,
they wax the dolphin.
That's it. It's over.
You dance. I like that.
Thank you.
Plus you got this really interesting look.
It's kind of an Oriental cabana boy thing.
You're unique, Rammy.
You could be a big star.
Yes, sir. I know.
I'm telling you.
I'm the star, like John Travolta.
"Pulp Fiction" Travolta
or "Urba.n Cowboy" Travolta?
"Grea.se" Travolta.
-How many lines do you have?
-I haven't seen the script yet.
I know your lines,
just like your lines in the restaurant.
"Would you like chutney with your chapatis
or poppadums with your paneer?"
-"Do you want nachos with your Big Gulp?"
-Piss off, man.
Oh, I'm sorry. Good for you, ya.a.r.
Come on, so tell us about it.
What role are you playing?
SANJIV: Man in turban
working in gas station.
You guys joke all you want,
but this is a real movie and I am the star.
(lndian sitar music)
CAMERAMAN: Clock's ticking. Come on.
DWAIN: Okey-dokey pokey.
Actors on the set.
DWAIN: Walk away. Okay? Grab that.
For a starring role,
I don't have a lot of lines.
-What are you doing?
-Giving Mr. Happy a shine.
He gets more screen time
than your face does.
RAMU: What?
DWAIN: Any sign of our Mr. Rammy?
Okay, now, no time for nerves.
You gotta get out there.
Don't you want to be in the movie?
But a real movie, not...
-pornography.
-Sugar, please.
PEACHES:
Everybody has to start somewhere.
DWAIN: So it's one, two,
and the inserts and we're done.
There's my Ja.ne. Now where's my Ta.rza.n?
Hey, there's the Ra.m.
Everyone meet Rammy.
DWAIN: Meet your co-star Sharrona.
Hello.
All right, let's rock. Come on.
DWAIN: Welcome to Fantasy lsland.
Okay, Rammy, you live
on this desert island, obviously.
And you've basically been in the bushes
beating your meat your whole life.
One day you're skipping along the beach,
you see this...
hot power-suited mama,
and you just wanna...
-teach her your native tongue.
-Hindi.
You're the junior senator from Wisconsin.
You're investigating a nuclear dump site
that's contaminating the marine life.
DWAIN: Okay, roll camera.
CAMERAMAN: We are rolling.
DWAIN: Action!
Hello, I'm Senator Snatch.
I'm here on official government business.
Are the natives here friendly?
The natives here are restless, Senator.
You look hot in that power suit.
I didn't realise
the tropics would be so warm.
RAMU: The temperature
isn't the only thing here that's up.
(Drums beating with increasing tempo)
DWAIN: Cut!
SOUNDMAN: Just tape it up. It'll be fine.
Brilliant.
Nice moment, Rammy,
but we're not doing this for Lifetime. Okay?
You see her, you screw her, we go home.
Also, you're happy
skipping along the beach. Life is good.
Skip. Screw. Happy. Got it.
Guess Who's Coming a.t Dinner, take two.
Hello, I'm Senator Snatch.
I'm here on a--
(Wild drums beating)
Rough stuff.
DWAIN: Problem?
SHARRONA: We don't have wood.
Stand by. Holding on wood.
Standing by for wood.
(Shouting) We are holding on wood!
Do you have an erection problem?
-No, sir. Ask the makeup girl.
-She's a guy.
I'm more woman
than you'll ever have, pencil dick.
Sorry, dude.
DWAIN: Get hard or get going.
(Motivating himself in Hindi)
It's just sex, silly.
CAMERAMAN: Where'd you find this guy?
DWAIN: He found me.
You know, we could've had Waldo.
No, Waldo's too hairy for this.
The natives don't have a lot of back hair.
It's just the idea of being naked
in front of all these people.
Well, the trick is not to be naked up here.
It's like other actors get costumes,
but we don't, or at least not for very long.
So your naked body
is really just your costume.
I promise, in lndia I'm a real stud.
If you and I could just go somewhere
by ourselves...
without people watching.
There's always someone watching.
-Dwain?
-God, silly.
-God is watching us?
-Yeah, but not for kicks.
I mean, the universe isn't run
by some big old perv.
What do you mean?
I mean, the same God
who made the rose and the ocean...
he made me.
And my body is made to have sex...
just like the rosebud is made to open.
Wow.
We're in. Places, please.
DWAIN: Short five. Sorry.
The most powerful sexual organ
God gave us is our brain.
Think about it.
Action!
Okey-dokey pokey.
(Sharrona moaning excitedly)
DWAIN: Cut!
Wha.t now?
I can't stop thinking about God.
And therefore I cannot achieve wood.
DWAIN: I see.
Sharrona,
you gotta help me out here, please?
Forget it, Dwain.
If I'm late again meeting Rusty...
-he's gonna get suspicious.
-Doesn't this guy ever go to a video store?
Hey, that's good.
This'd be a great character for you.
We haven't done a schoolteacher number
in a while. Not since...
The Prime of Miss Jea.n's Booty.
SHARRONA: See you.
DWAIN: Please.
SHARRONA: Taxi! Taxi!
Broa.dwa.y a.nd 86th. I'm in a. hurry.
RAMU: Sharrona!
(Upbeat instrumental music)
RUSTY: Guys, you seen Miss Lynell around?
BOY: Who?
I'm telling you, bro, she's definitely
two-timing you with the librarian.
Why don't we go to O'Neill's?
We drown out your sorrows.
-Hey.
Thanks, guys.
I'll catch you in the a.m., Randy.
Not if I catch you first, firebug.
Where you been, princess?
One of the foreign students had a problem
straightening out his grammar.
'Bye, guys.
Not a very friendly group.
They're never nice to substitutes.
(Upbeat instrumental music)
GREETER: Nice to see you,
Mr. and Mrs. de Borman.
Service entrance is downstairs.
Okay.
EDWIN: Good evening, Lloyd.
EDWIN: Lars, your sister's locked herself
in the bathroom again.
Please, get her now.
(Upbeat instrumental music)
(Laughter and party chatter)
(Conversing in Hindi)
So, Swami, you really see the future?
A couple more of these and I do.
As many of you know, our birthday girl...
is on a little quest for spirituality.
Om.
LARS: Lex?
One more "Om"
and then you have to come to your party.
It always has to be what she wants,
even on my birthday.
I wanted a Tibetan gathering
with a Rinpoche...
but no, she does an lndian feast with a....
...world-famous swami.
SWAMI BU: All those people care about
is sex and money.
If they have money, they care about sex.
SWAMI BU: lf they have sex,
they care about money.
If they have both, they feel guilty
and raise money for the opera.
More tandoori in the library.
Swami, you're on.
CHANTAL: Alexandra searched
for so many years.
In the shoe department at Bergdorf's.
She has searched for the perfect diet,
the perfect rock star boyfriend.
It seems Lexi will search for anything
except steady employment.
So, dear Lexi, in honour of
your current fixation...
I give you Swami Bu.
VIJAY: Swami Bu has gone
to another dimension.
I swear she was 16.
Mrs. Von Austerberg is going to kill me!
She paid a lot of money for a swami,
and now we have no swami.
We have jack shit!
Or we don't have jack shit.
I don't know which one it is!
What we do have is a drunk bastard. You....
Didn't I fire you?
Rasphal, I was just wondering about my job.
You really want your job back?
RASPHAL: Mr. Ramu "Tom Cruise" Gupta?
CHANTAL: Swami Bu!
Swami Bu!
I'm conjuring up a swami.
CHANTAL: Here he is.
Ladies and gentlemen, Swami Bu.
Not long ago...
a wise man told me that
all people care about is sex and money...
and opera.
Now, myself, I don't have any money...
well, because I'm a swami, and...
swamis don't like opera, because...
well, you can't dance to it.
So I will talk to you about sex.
What'd you pay for this?
God, is it hot in here.
God.
God wants us to have sex.
And if God wants us to have sex,
then, well, it can't be bad...
because the universe
isn't run by a big old perv.
Glad he cleared that up.
Your naked body...
is like a costume that you wear
to be yourself.
Be comfortable...
in your nakedness.
The most powerful sexual organ
God gave you...
is your brain.
RAMU: Think about it.
Are you thinking?
My whole body is about to think.
And like roses are made to open,
so must you.
You must open your rosebud.
Dance is like love.
(Electronic backbeat)
Join me.
Follow your inner beat.
(Quickening electronic backbeat)
-Is he doing the Macarena?
-Looks like it.
Wait, isn't that the....
I think it's one of those
dervish, spiritual, trance-dance things.
(Sings joyous Hindi song)
(Upbeat Hindi dance music)
(Whistles of approval)
VIJAY: Excellent. Come on.
(Sings joyous Hindi song)
I thought we were just going to do
some light chanting.
(Whistles of approval)
(Silence)
ALL: Bravo.
The Macarena, man.
Shut up.
Swami Bu!
We're going clubbing. You want to come?
Unless it's against your religion
or something.
No, my religion believes in clubbing.
LEXl: Swami Bu.
RAMU: Call me Ramu.
Candles. We need candles.
You can't have spiritual sex
without candles.
You must use a lot of candles in lndia.
When the electricity goes out.
Undress me slowly, spiritually...
Iike a goddess.
Pretend I'm Vishnu.
Vishnu is a man.
Kali?
Kali is the goddess
of death and destruction.
LEXl: Okay. Death and destruction.
Music.
LEXl: We need music.
Not really, no.
This is perfect.
It's the Guatemalan Boys Choir.
They're deaf.
I'm having sex with a guru.
Cha.kh le.
It's so powerful.
I can stand alone.
It feels like we're doing it. Right now.
From there, it's like....
It feels like we're doing it.
Right now, from there,
it's like you're pulsating through me.
It's better from here. Trust me.
Oh, Guru, what is the most sacred position?
(Chanting)
You may find this hard to believe,
but in lndia guru sex is very fast.
What about the slow chanting
200 position sex?
That's Tibet.
Where I come from, we do it very fast.
Like wild monkeys at sundown.
And if we don't,
the evil spirits might grab our tails...
and throw us into the next jungle.
(Drums beating slowly)
(Makes monkey sounds)
You know what? Don't get me started.
You know what Father Flanagan says:
"How you gonna teach kids values
if you haven't lived them yourself?"
RUSTY: Will you hate me if I make you wait?
SHARRONA: No, I love you.
I'm proud to save myself for you.
You know what? You're the best.
RUSTY: Honey, can I ask you a question?
How does a nice,
Catholic schoolgirl like you...
Iearn how to make
all those sexy little sounds?
Well, me and my friends
used to practice kissing.
On our hands.
That's silly. The second half is starting.
(Mystical lndian music)
LEXl: Remember when I had that thing
with my African drumming teacher?
I don't know. He just got really needy.
But this one is the real thing.
Not a lot of people know about him yet.
It's up to me to get his message out there.
LEXl: Anyway, he's gonna be
bigger than Deepak Chopra.
Ramu is the guru of sex.
(Sensual hip-hop music)
VIJAY: The guru of sex.
She really thinks
you can be as famous as Deepak Chopra?
Who is he? Does he dance?
No, he tells Americans
how to get rich and be happy.
I thought they knew.
-Have you even tried the Kama Sutra?
-No, have you?
A little.
By myself.
But, Vijay, I don't want to be a guru.
I want to be an actor.
Then act like a guru.
It's better than acting like a waiter.
So, who writes the lines for Deepak Chopra?
They're not lines.
He has a philosophy and shit.
These guru-types don't just
put on turbans and screw chicks.
They say profound things
they've been thinking about for centuries.
The point is the guy's made
a gazillion dollars.
A gazillion dollars?
What's that in rupees?
I don't think they have that many.
VIJAY: Sex guru. Why didn't I think of that?
(Loud dance music)
LEXl: I want the suede, not the leather.
I want every colour.
LEXl: No, I'm staying in town,
so have them sent to New York.
Okay. I gotta go.
Guru Ramu.
Thank you for gracing me
with your presence.
Champagne?
I hope you don't mind.
I invited Amy to join us.
She's a journalist.
A journalist? No.
So, as the son of the Maharajah,
when did you have your epiphany?
When I was 15.
Tell us everything.
It was: I'll touch yours, you touch mine.
No big deal.
Do you know who or what you were
in any of your previous incarnations?
Dessert?
AMY: That's me.
I wa.s hoping to schedule a. scrub.
It seems like you're holding back,
just a little.
What you said at my party was
so much more powerful.
God, rosebud, the naked costume,
and all that.
Right.
You know, Lexi,
maybe I'm not the one to do all this.
Wow.
Alexandra, hi.
-How's your mother?
-Remarkably lifelike.
Guru Ramu, Kitty.
Guru?
-Does he do privates?
-Does he ever.
-Tuesday?
-Perfect.
-Heaven.
-Cia.o.
You do privates, right?
You'll get a call-back. Adios, Waldo.
-Great job today.
-Thanks.
-Hi. It's me. Rammy.
-Hello.
I just wanted to apologise
for what happened on the set.
I got paid.
RAMU: Excuse me, sir.
MAN: Watch it, pal.
RAMU: I'm so sorry.
RAMU: I'm so sorry. Pardon me.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Hello, again.
So now you're stalking me?
No, I was hoping perhaps
I could buy you a cup of tea?
I don't do that.
Perhaps coffee then.
Look, Rammy,
I'm engaged to a nice, normal guy.
Do you know how hard it is
to find a nice, normal guy in the city?
Right?
I just want your help
with a professional problem.
Would you stop worrying about it?
A lot of guys can't get it up.
You don't understand.
People are telling me
I could be the next Deepak Chopra.
Well, I'm not familiar with Deep-Pack.
I don't watch dirty movies
because my fiancé's kinda religious.
No, I have an opportunity
to make a lot of money.
Duh! Why do you think I got into
this business, 'cause it was interesting?
In three years I saved enough
to buy a house in Throg's Neck...
and pay for my whole wedding.
Mulberry Street.
Do you want to see the cake?
Gra.zie, cia.o.
SHARRONA: Hi, I'm Sherri, I called earlier.
Are you Tony?
Yeah, I got everything over there.
SHARRONA: That's--
TONY: Expensive.
TONY: It's $800.
You see this one?
This is more in your price range.
-That's very nice, too.
-Yeah.
Actually, sir, we will order this one.
-I want my lovely bride to be happy.
-Rammy, no.
TONY: Now, you two kids
discuss it amongst yourselves, okay?
Rammy, $800 is too much.
I can't accept that.
Look, it's not a gift.
I want you to be my teacher
and I'm happy to pay for this privilege.
(Mandolin strumming wedding song)
Okay.
(Upbeat instrumental music)
(Doorbell rings)
Yeah, come on in.
If this is a bad time I could come back later.
What am I doing here?
-Isn't this your apartment?
-What?
Yes, this is my apartment.
I mean, what am I doing
letting you into my apartment?
-The other day--
-Rusty, my boyfriend...
doesn't know about my X-rated job
in the real world.
He thinks that I'm a PG-13 girl.
That I'm a nice, normal girl.
-Well, you are.
-What?
A nice, normal girl.
You think so?
Wait a second. Do not flirt with me.
Do not. That is rule number one.
Okay? And no little gifts either.
SHARRONA: Rule number two:
You don't try to hit on me
or take advantage of any situation...
that you might find a turn-on.
Do you understand? This is just a lesson.
-I am a teacher and you are the student.
-Of course.
So, no touchy-feely.
If you touchy-feely me, I will hurt you.
I will cause you pain.
I know the art of karate.
Okay.
Okay, rule number three: lf we're gonna
do this, you have to promise me...
that everything I say stays in this room.
You can't tell anyone.
-Not a single soul.
-No, you see, you don't understand--
Then you can leave right now.
But of course.
Okay. Let's get started.
So the other day, what happened?
Why did you lose it?
I was afraid.
There were 20 people around,
many drinking coffee, watching me.
Exactly. Fear.
Fear is cold. It freezes us up.
Fear of performance.
Fear of doing something bad,
something dirty.
SHARRONA: What would our parents think?
What do we think?
Do you know where we hold our fears?
Up here.
Further south.
That's why sex is such a release.
When we come, we let go of our fears.
And when we let go of our fears,
we touch our soul.
So the way I look at it is...
my pussy is the door to my soul.
(Mystical sitar music)
Why are you afraid, Kitty?
Well, what makes you think I'm afraid?
I feel it.
RAMU: Please, close your eyes.
We have so many fears.
"Fear of performance.
"Fear of doing something bad."
Fear of what people will think.
Yes.
Do you know where we hold our fears?
Between our eyebrows
where we get those yucky little lines?
In our genitals.
That is why sex is such a release.
When we come, we let go of our fears...
and when you let go of your fears,
you touch your soul.
Your pussy is the door to your soul.
KITTY: So, if I touch myself here...
Kitty?
...l won't be afraid?
Excuse me. How much do I owe you?
What you wish.
I'm sorry. I need to be by myself.
Lexi, he is beyond insightful.
KITTY: I have to go.
KITTY: Thank you.
RAMU: You're welcome. Nice to meet you.
RAMU: Wow. She paid me.
You're incredible.
Kitty's such an unhappy person
and you helped her so much.
Just think, there are so many
unhappy people out there.
I know most of them.
LEXl: But we can help them together.
I really want to do that. I've never...
really done anything, you know.
Can we do that? Can we...
help mankind?
I really want to help mankind.
Cool.
VIJAY: $2,000!
It's bloody incredible.
But it's not my wisdom, it's Sharrona's.
She thinks she gives me lessons
to be in porno movies...
and she made me promise
not to tell anyone.
-Great.
-Vij, be serious.
I am, ya.a.r.
Get her wisdom and use it.
-Don't you want to be a star?
-Well, yes--
How do you think that's going to happen
if you're not a guru?
Name one lndian star in America.
Name one.
That guy from The Simpsons.
He's a cartoon.
Don't you guys have to be at the restaurant?
Ramu's got a new job.
You gonna be a cab driver?
No, I'm going to be a guru.
Cheers, Guruji.
(Upbeat soul music)
Vij!
Come on, you want to get comfortable
in your naked costume, don't you?
You need to be comfortable
with your own body.
Okey-dokey pokey.
Great.
Your nakedness.
SHARRONA: Sa.y tha.t five times.
I'm a good lover.
-And again.
-I'm a good lover.
I deserve pleasure.
Budweiser: The Ma.ha.ra.j of beer.
Next.
You two are gonna have
a wonderful weekend.
CLIENT: I'm a good lover.
RAMU: Thank you. That was very good.
That was very good. Stop.
Guru, my brother golfs
with the maharajah of Jaipur, Bubbles.
And he says he's never heard of you.
Well, it's a big country.
LEXl: Gurus shun the life of wealth
and materialism.
Swami Muktananda said
everything in the universe...
is made of divine consciousness...
and its innermost form dwells
in the centre of us all.
Wow, that's good.
Lexi, can I see you in the kitchen?
Do you know where it is?
So, Guru...
what would you tell a couple
that has hit a wall?
"Are you all right?
"Can I get you a doctor?"
CHANTAL: What in heaven's name
are you doing?
Being happy for a change.
Freely expressing my sexuality.
You are sucking face
with your yoga instructor.
He's not my yoga instructor.
And so what if I am?
Darling...
we don't date the help.
Remember what happened
with Aunt Eujanie and that U.P.S. man?
News flash, Mother,
all people of colour aren't here to serve you.
How dare you say that!
I have served meals to the homeless.
Good meals. Things I'd eat myself,
if I still ate carbs.
At any rate, you are making our guests
feel very uncomfortable.
They'll get over it.
MALE GUEST: You're drinking too much.
Darling, come join.
Hi.
MALE GUEST: Yes.
RAMU: Thank you very much.
SHARRONA: Can you feel it in your mouth?
Can you taste it?
The taste is sweet.
The taste is....
Mint chocolate chip.
Okay, you can open your eyes now.
I got that from an acting class.
It helps when you don't click with someone.
Remember tha.t we ha.ve five senses...
and using them can make anything sexy.
So, why do you do these movies?
If you're having doubts about the business
then you should quit now. Trust me.
You like to cook.
In lndia, we call that a homely girl.
You know, a girl who likes
to do things in the home.
Yeah, that's me, homely girl.
Can I taste?
Cinnamon? Hey, that's lamb stew.
Yeah, so? It has no flavour.
Come on...
taste.
Are you flirting with me?
No. No.
Got you.
Don't take everything so seriously.
-All right, that's it for today.
-Okay.
And, Rammy...
I use mint chocolate chip, too.
Edwin, is that you?
What's wrong? You haven't been up here
since the Reagan administration.
It's Bush time.
(Edwin growls)
And tell Josh that a lot of agents
want to sign him.
Lexi.
We met at Dr. Sid's retreat
for neurotic compulsives.
I'm not supposed to say that.
Lexi who wouldn't go
to the Oscars with him. Don't say that.
Just tell him Lexi, okay?
He'll know who I am. Cia.o.
-Get up, we have the trainer at 10:00 a.m.
-10:00 a.m.?
I have to go. I have an appointment.
But I planned my day around you.
I was going to buy you sweaters.
I'm sorry, Lexi, but I have my own life, too.
You can't do this to me.
You can't just go and not tell me where.
Guru!
LEXI (Shouts): I have abandonment issues!
Okay, now I'm going to tell you something
I've never told anyone...
but it's helped me more than anything.
I can't even believe I'm telling you this.
-You don't have to tell me if you don't want.
-No, I want to.
Okay, one of the biggest problems...
is making something mechanical
look romantic.
So music can help.
-I love music.
-Me, too.
What I do is, I hear and I feel the music...
in my body.
What music?
Songs, romantic songs. Like, I let it sing...
and then the rest of me follows.
I'll show you. Name a song.
La. Ba.mba..
(Sharrona sings softly)
That doesn't work. It has to be romantic.
It has to send love through your loins.
Don't go cha.nging
to try a.nd plea.se me
You never let me down before
(Sharrona humming melody and moaning)
Did you see what I was doing?
Yeah.
It's like, on certain words
the passion comes through my body.
It's like I can actually feel
Billy Joel between my legs.
Not Billy Joel the person...
but the romance, the sweetness,
the intention of his words.
Now you try it.
Don't go cha.nging
to try a.nd plea.se me
Don't try to make a point,
try to touch your soul.
I'll do it with you.
You never let me down before
(Sing in unison)
I don't ima.gine
you're too fa.milia.r
Why don't you get on top of me?
It's the only way you'll learn.
What?
(Soft instrumental melody)
Sorry.
Don't go trying
some new fa.shion
Don't cha.nge the colour ofyour ha.ir
(Upbeat instrumental music)
I don't wa.nt clever
conversa.tion
I never wa.nt to work tha.t ha.rd
Ijust wa.nt someone
I ca.n ta.Ik to
I wa.nt youjust the wa.y you a.re
(Upbeat instrumental music)
(Knock at the door)
RUSTY: Shar?
SHARRONA: Oh, my God, that's Rusty. Hide.
Shar, open up.
Shit.
-Hey.
-What a surprise.
I got off early.
Randy and I were going to the gym,
but he had O.T. I gotta take a leak.
SHARRONA: Don't! I mean, are you sure?
RUSTY: Oh, God.
Do you want something to eat, or a beer?
What the....
Ma'am, that leak shouldn't cause
any more trouble.
I've readjusted the pipe connection,
and hooked it up to the main artery.
-I'm the plumber.
-I should hope so.
You are the big, strong
American boyfriend, huh?
I guess I am, yeah.
But you couldn't fix
the pipe connection now, could you?
-How come he didn't have any tools?
-He's a holistic plumber.
SHARRONA: Ca.Iculus isn't my only
a.dva.nced skill, Professor Wa.nk.
How do you like them a.pples?
-What are you watching?
-My Sha.rona..
-You bastards! Turn it off!
-What? You've seen Good Will Humping?
We also have Sta.r Whores.: Episode 69,
and Cha.rlie's Anus.
(Moaning from TV)
SHARRONA: It's not my fa.ult.
It's not my fa.ult.
You couldn't get it up for her?
-You try having sex with 20 people around.
-I've never had sex without 20 people.
Now, I don't want you to watch that again.
She's a real person, and my friend,
and she's a lot smarter than you guys.
Oh, I see a young man. He is in love.
-He's in love with a buxom schoolgirl.
-Piss off, man!
All right.
All right, what's got your turban in a twist?
I don't know.
Desi Fantasy Hotline.
For Hindi hotties, press one.
SANJIV: For Punjabi poontang, press two--
SHARRONA: ls Ra.mmy there? It's Sha.rrona..
Sharrona.
Hi.
RAMU: Give it to me.
I talked to a real live porn star.
I think she sounded naked.
RAMU: Hey, how's it going?
SHARRONA: I got you a.job.
Dwain said that you could be an extra
on the gladiator movie tomorrow.
What? I mean, what?
SHARRONA: You wa.nt to be in films, right?
I do.
Well, this is what we've been working for.
SHARRONA: Ra.mmy?
RAMU: I don't have to do it, do l?
SANJIV: I'll do it.
I'll do it!
SHARRONA: You don't ha.ve to do a.nything.
It's extra. work. Remember, fea.r freezes.
See you.
SANJIV: Did you tell her I'll do it? Did you?
DWAIN: All right, gladiator love slaves...
a little more thrashing.
I want to feel your pain.
Gla.d He Ate Her...
scene 21, take six.
And, action.
Which one of you worthless love slaves
will dare--
DWAIN: Cut!
Can we get some oil for these guys?
I'm seeing chalky legs here.
-How are you hanging in there, Rammy?
-From a chain.
(Cell phone ringing)
Hello.
Guru, where are you?
I'm here at Josh Goldstein's office.
Right, the agent.
I've been detained out here.
Where's "out here"?
ANNOUNCER:
Puerto Rica.n Lea.ther Queens to sta.ge two.
Queens.
LEXl: Queens?
Do you know how important this is?
The access Josh Goldstein has?
He can help us get our message out there.
-I'll be right there, I promise. Don't worry.
-Hurry up!
Lying to your girlfriend?
Who said that was my girlfriend?
Is she pretty?
CAMERAMAN: Places, please.
-Your guy's not here?
-He's coming. He had a thing, got tied up.
He got tied up? You--
Which one of you worthless love slaves
will dare to enter my love ring?
Cut!
All right, good work.
Grea.t work.
-It was a lot to memorise.
-Yeah, well, not so much talk this time.
Excuse me, I have to get my clothes and go.
No one leaves till we wrap.
What's up?
-"Ramew Gouda."
-Hey, you made it. I'm so psyched for this.
-Josh, Ramu.
-It's nice to meet you.
-May I take your coat?
-No, I'm fine.
Oh, no, please, I'll just hang it....
I was at a past life workshop.
Really? Did you see me?
I worked in the mailroom.
Just kidding. Why don't you have a seat?
Lexi tells me you have quite the following.
I'm just gonna jump right in, okay?
The goal here is to separate you
from all the other self-help spiritual types...
so you're not just another lndian,
or, excuse me, Native American.
What you've got going for you is God.
And by the way, God is big.
You mention God, people pay attention.
God demands attention, and....
What can I say?
We want to be in bed with God.
But what do people want to pay attention to
more than anything else?
Sex. You let people think about both,
which is brilliant.
Josh is one of the smartest agents in town.
We can handle your book deals in London,
website in Munich...
-your television in New York.
-Television?
-That's right. Movie deals in Hollywood.
-Hollywood?
JOSH: Sure.
Step one, you gotta expand
your core audience. How do we do that?
I think we do a big show,
a couple thousand people.
-Maybe we book a Broadway house.
-Broadway?
That's right:
"The Guru of Sex." One night only.
You gotta keep them wanting more.
Hey, Ari, get me the Playhouse.
And, by the way,
I'm not into micromanaging...
but you're not going to wear that....
What is it you're wearing, anyway?
-I really like Josh.
-What's going on?
-What do you mean?
-You run to secret appointments...
-to past life workshops with costumes.
-I'm sorry--
You don't invite me,
when you know how much I love that stuff.
I couldn't, l--
You'll be the Mother Teresa of sex.
I want to help you, and you leave me out.
I don't understand that.
No one can give you what you want.
It's too much.
What are you saying?
I'm saying live your own life, not mine.
Follow your own dreams, not mine.
There are many different paths.
You can go this way, or that way.
But you must choose your own path.
It's your own damn journey.
I'm going to meditate on that!
Yeah.
(Upbeat pop music)
SANJIV: Hello. Thank you.
'Bye. Ramu.
What more could a swami ask for?
RAMU: Hey!
-Hey.
-I got an idea for today's lesson, but--
-No.
It's such a beautiful day. Let's take a walk.
Okay.
After you.
-So, I miss my na.nima. the most.
-Does your family like it you're in America?
No, they'd rather I be married off with kids...
holding down a nine-to-five salary.
But they're getting used to it.
They want me to be happy.
You're lucky, 'cause the only family
I have right now is Dwain and Peaches.
They're quite a family.
No, really, they saved my life.
I don't even want to tell you
what I was doing before I met them.
They treat me right. I'm safe with them.
Look, Sharrona...
I have to tell you something.
Go on.
This is really difficult.
Let me tell you something first.
I really like teaching you.
It makes me feel good to help someone.
But I don't think you should do it.
You don't know what it's like. It's porn....
I just don't think you should do it.
You're so pure and good and....
You don't know what it's really like.
That's why I made up all those ways
to get through it.
Because I wanted to make it seem
like I was doing something else.
-Something important and respectable.
-You are respectable.
How can you say that?
Rusty doesn't even know what I do.
If he did, he wouldn't marry me.
But I'd marry you...
(Tender instrumental music)
...for 50 cows.
SHARRONA: Only 50?
RAMU: Well, they're sacred you know.
Okay, 100 sacred cows, and...
Iet's see, a field full of buffalos...
a dozen peacocks...
and a herd of the most beautiful creatures
in all the world:
A herd full of blue elephants.
Blue?
Blue.
-I have to go.
-No, you don't have to do anything.
Of course I do, silly. See you.
(Melancholy instrumental music)
RUSTY: But, hey, that's Randy for you.
MRS. MCGEE: He's so funny.
RUSTY: You always say that.
To Sherri and Rusty.
Russell tells me
you'll help teach the catechism class.
Catechism. Neat.
FATHER: It's a blessing to have
a professional in charge at last.
Hi, baby.
MR. MCGEE:
Father feels you're an amateur.
Leave Mum alone.
MR. MCGEE: I said no such thing.
Tuesdays is knitting circle, and you will be
the first member of the millennium.
I had to use all my influence.
If it doesn't interfere
with couples' bowling, right, honey?
You ever bowl with Rusty? It's a good thing.
Throws the ball like a ballet dancer.
RUSTY: Don't start, Dad.
Tell me, my dear, have we not met before?
Sweetie, have you met
Father Flanagan before?
No, Father, I would have
remembered meeting you.
Your lovely face looks so familiar to me.
You don't believe me?
Watch and learn, tough guy.
You're the chick from Sta.r Whores, right?
Episode 69?
-Excuse me?
-No, that's not me.
DRUNK GUY: No, it's you.
I saw that forwards and backwards.
You're out of line. Sit down.
You're making a mistake.
DRUNK GUY: It's her. Baby.
MRS. MCGEE: What's he doing?
You know what? I'm sick of this.
There must be some cheap porn star
out there that looks just like Sherri.
-I'm sorry, honey.
-I'm feeling a bit sick--
-Sweetheart, wait--
-I have to go home.
Honey?
RUSTY: What did I say?
MRS. MCGEE: Pre-wedding jitters.
SHARRONA: Hello, is Rammy there?
AMIT: Ra.mu? No.
SHARRONA: Can you tell me where he is?
AMIT: The Broa.dwa.y Pla.yhouse.
Thank you.
Now that you have an agent,
I think you need a manager.
What do managers do?
Take 15 percent.
LEXl: Guru Ramu and friend.
Hey, Lex.
Well, hello. Vijay Rao, manager.
Guru, I've been meditating
on what you said...
and I think I understand
why you pulled back from our relationship.
I don't.
The reason you ignited
my kundalini energy in the first place...
was so I could move that sex force
into other chakras...
my heart, my mind,
maybe even some day, my third eye.
Exactly.
Yes, I knew it. I knew giving up the stuff
would help me focus.
-What stuff?
-Everything.
I'm moving to a studio apartment in Queens.
Will you be subleasing your penthouse?
CROWD (Singing): Don't go cha.nging
RAMU: Tha.t's right. Feel it.
CROWD: to try a.nd plea.se me
RAMU: Yes, let it sing.
CROWD: You never let me down before
RAMU: Feel Billy Joel between your legs.
RAMU: And then,
feel your genita.Is come a.Iive.
CROWD (Singing): Don't ima.gine
RAMU: Some wa.nt to sing in ha.rmony.
CROWD (Singing): you're too fa.milia.r
RAMU: Tha.t is oka.y.
CROWD (Singing):
And I don't see you a.nymore
CROWD (Singing): Don't go trying
some new fa.shion
Don't cha.nge the colour ofyour ha.ir
RAMU: Tha.t's right.
Send tha.t love through your loins.
CROWD (Singing): You a.Iwa.ys ha.ve my
RAMU: Feel it. Tha.t's it.
CROWD: unspoken pa.ssion
RAMU: Genita.Is a.re the ga.tewa.y
to your soul.
RAMU: Let them sing.
CROWD: Although I might not seem to ca.re
RAMU: Let go ofyour fea.rs.
Fea.r is cold.
CROWD (Singing): I don't wa.nt clever
RAMU: Cold freezes.
RAMU: When we ma.ke love...
CROWD: conversa.tion
RAMU: ...we relea.se our fea.rs a.nd we...
CROWD: I never wa.nt to work tha.t ha.rd
CROWD: ljust wa.nt someone
RAMU: ...touch our souls.
CROWD: tha.t I ca.n ta.Ik to
I wa.nt youjust the wa.y you a.re
RAMU: Sharrona, wait!
Carry on,
the Guru's just gone to the restroom.
CROWD: I need to know
tha.t you will a.Iwa.ys be
VIJAY: Remember, sex is good for you.
CROWD: The sa.me old someone tha.t I knew
VIJAY: Love your loins.
-I meant to tell you.
-You certainly had a deal, didn't you?
You pay me, steal my private thoughts,
and sell them to the world.
-I told you things I have never told anyone.
-I tried to tell you, I did.
And then I wanted your philosophy,
and then I wanted to see you.
That is why. I just wanted to see you.
You're sick, you know. And mean.
How could you lie like that?
You tell me, Mrs. Schoolteacher.
What about Rusty?
-You're lying to him and to yourself.
-That's not true!
You think no one will love you for you,
so you pretend to be someone else.
Don't you see? That is not real.
-What is that? Guru-speak?
-It's true.
Maybe I'm a bad person
who deserves to be stabbed in the heart...
but I know you deserve more.
You're just a stupid con man.
Go steal those people's money...
before they realise
that you're just a big dumb fake!
I'm a fake? Well, then you're a super fake.
A porno star saying you're a teacher,
for a house in Frog's Neck!
Throg's Neck. I plan to be very happy there.
You better go steal those people's money
before your visa expires!
-Okay, I will!
-Taxi!
I'll be rich, and famous,
and very, very happy!
-Fine!
SHARRONA: Taxi!
VIJAY: Hello, girls, come on.
Rea.dy for some fun?
This is Amit and Sanjiv.
This is Candy, Mindy,
Sandy, Daisy and Tasha.
I just....
(Speaking in Hindi)
SANJIV: Beautiful jungle top.
SANJIV: You are a heartbreaker, baby.
The great thing about this place is
we never have to move.
They can carry us out of here in a box.
WOMAN: Anthony, I'm waiting for you!
VIJAY: All right! We got it.
Ten cents for every Guru of Sex T-shirt sold.
Maybe we could donate the proceeds.
Maybe. Not.
You know,
I'm sick of your fucking materialism!
I'm sick of your fucking scented oils.
You smell like a Bombay hooker.
Ramu, we've got the Cher party tonight.
Sa.Ily Jessy Ra.pha.el tomorrow.
Hey, man, did you hear me?
Did it ever occur to you
he might be meditating?
No.
(Rap music plays)
FAN: Guru.
VIJAY: Vijay Rao, the Guru's manager.
Hello, girls, a.Il right there.
Ra.mu's coming in there.
All right, then. Vija.y Ra.o, ma.na.ger.
RAMU: Hey, man.
SANJIV: Tony called.
-Tony who?
-I don't know.
I don't have all the answers like you, Guruji.
He said your wedding cake will be ready
tomorrow 9:00 a.m.
Are you getting married tomorrow?
No, I'm not getting married tomorrow.
I never know with you, ya.a.r.
(lndian song and dance music)
You better sha.pe up
'Ca.use I need a. ma.n
(Sing rock 'n' roll song)
-And my hea.rt is set on you
I better sha.pe up
-If I'm gonna. prove
-You better prove
Tha.t my fa.ith isjustified
-Are you sure?
-Yes I'm sure down deep inside
-You're the one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
Oo-oo-oo, honey
-The one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
Oo-oo-oo, honey
-The one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
Oo-oo-oo
-The one I need
-Oh, yes indeed
-Yes indeed
-You're the one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
Oo-oo-oo, honey
-The one tha.t I wa.nt
-You a.re the one I wa.nt
(Melancholy instrumental music)
(Doorbell rings)
MRS. MCGEE: I'll get it.
No, you go get your things together.
I'm double-parked.
Why did they send the cake here?
It's supposed to go to the reception hall.
I'm so sorry.
Just leave it right there.
She's just a nervous bride.
I'll get my purse. I won't be a jiffy.
It's terrible what I did to you. I know that.
But what you're about to do....
Don't go through with this.
You don't have to.
-You and me--
-There is no you and me. You used me.
And I used you, too.
And I did it for the cake.
Here you are, sir. Good-bye. And thank you.
All righty, then.
(Both doors slam shut)
-Vij, I can't go in there.
-What the fuck you talking about?
I know you love it.
The clothes and everything...
but it's not real. I can't do this anymore.
You're serious.
But, Ram, you've made it. You're a star.
-I don't care.
-Of course you do.
Remember, ya.a.r, we came here with nothing.
And look at us now.
You've made it for all of us.
Think about your family,
how proud they'll be.
Come on, ya.a.r.
MAN: Hey, is that him?
WOMAN 1 : Oh, it's him.
WOMAN 2: It's Guru.
VIJAY: Right this way.
Okay, I'm your cousin Kimberly.
I'm a librarian, and I have five children,
all boys. I like that part.
And, I live in Utica.
Ithaca. You live in lthaca.
-And you run a Head Start program there.
-Okay. Head.
-Head, I can remember that.
-I'm cutting the cake, not jumping out of it.
Okay.
(Sharrona starts sobbing)
Honey, what's wrong? Why are you crying?
(Sobs) I don't know.
Oh, honey.
SHARRONA (Sobs): They're just tears
of joy or something.
Honey, no. No, the makeup.
Waldo Hernandez.
Waldo. And what do you do?
I'm in the meat-packing industry.
Hi.
Pretend I'm not here.
Marsha!
And now I'm happy to introduce
a true phenomenon...
the Guru of Sex, Ramu Gupta.
(Applause)
Ramu Gupta will be taking calls,
and he will be talking about...
well, what he talks about,
sexual intercourse.
Mama! Ramu's on Sa.Ily Jessy Ra.pha.el.
Well, first I'djust like to sa.y hi to my fa.mily.
Hi, Nanima.
He said hi to me.
What's he doing?
He's talking about sexual intercourse.
What?
EDWIN: Candy, make sure everything
is in tiptop shape.
Oh, yes. Mrs. Von Austerberg
is very demanding.
Yes, I know. So am l.
SALLY: Welcome ba.ck. The Guru of Sex...
-Ra.mu Gupta..
-Look, it's our guru.
SALLY: Our next question is from....
MAN: John.
Guru, my problem is
that the only way I've been...
able to get a woman is on the computer.
Well, John, don't limit yourself.
Maybe sometimes on the computer,
other times on the bed.
Don't be afraid to try new things, huh?
Next, we have a caller from Alaska.
Go ahead, caller.
RUSTY:
Yes, hi. I'm supposed to get ma.rried.
Congratulations.
RUSTY: Yeah, but the problem is
the girl I'm marrying.
She's awesome, but I don't really love her.
Does your fia.ncée know how you feel?
No, she has no idea.
And I know it would kill her.
Well, Ala.ska....
MR. MCGEE: Come on!
...the best a.dvice I ca.n give you is...
to move your feet to the bea.t ofyour hea.rt.
But my heart beats
for the second hoseman on my truck.
Then you must go to the hoseman, Alaska.
You must go to the hoseman.
He doesn't seem himself.
I feel sorry for the girl marrying the homo.
It's quite a responsibility
being a spiritual guru, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
But there is something I have to say.
I am not a guru.
AUDIENCE: What?
There goes the book deal.
All I've ever done is...
is to teach dance.
SALLY: What?
RAMU: I tried to act.
I came to America to be in movies...
well, to be on TV.
RAMU: But I'm a. fa.ke.
(Tender instrumental music)
I have betrayed you all and...
I am sorry, l....
I have to go.
-All your wisdom....
-It was just an act.
But, I gave up all my stuff.
I am sorry. I'm a fake.
What does that make me?
I now have all these ideas,
and they came from me...
not from Va.nity Fa.ir or my mother.
-How can you say that's fake?
-It's not.
No, I didn't change you.
The guru you saw in me
was the guru in you.
In your lie I found my truth.
(Tender instrumental music)
RAMU: Come on, Vij.
(Uplifting instrumental music)
That's our Lexi.
(Studio audience applauds)
-What are we doing? Where are we going?
-To get the woman I love.
(Adventurous instrumental music)
Hey, can you get to the Bronx
in 15 minutes?
I'm a cab driver.
I can get to Bombay in 15 minutes.
(Rock 'n' roll song)
(Organ plays wedding song)
I'm so proud of you.
This whole thing has made me
want to go back to documentaries.
(Rock 'n' roll song)
She's marrying someone else.
You can't interrupt a wedding and
take the bride.
Sure I can.
Haven't you seen any American movies?
It happens here all the time.
About fucking time, man.
Don't speak to me like that.
Come on.
Just don't forget,
I'm the one doing you a favour.
Right.
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here
in the sight of God...
to witness the sacrament of marriage.
-It was your stupid idea.
-Vij, you're a real bastard.
Rammy.
Is that your plumber?
Carry on.
Thank you.
...should not be joined together
in holy matrimony speak now...
or forever hold your peace.
I do.
Randy.
Who are they? The new Village People?
-You first.
-No, you first.
I insist.
Come on, man.
If you please, I am trying to conduct
a wedding ceremony here.
But I thought you said we could speak now.
It was merely an expression
as in "get lost." Please leave.
I can't leave.
Because if I leave...
I leave everything that matters to me.
Sharrona, you have taught me
so much about so many things...
but right now I know something you don't.
(Tender instrumental music)
RAMU: This is just a dream.
Ma.ybe you've ha.d it for so long
you think it ha.s to become rea.I...
but it doesn't.
We live, and life brings us new dreams.
Better ones.
Ones that come from the heart,
and not from the mind.
Dreams that you cannot predict...
Iike you.
That is why I cannot leave...
because my heart beats
for that lady up there.
And I am not leaving here until
I find out if her heart beats for me.
Well, Sherri?
Yes, my heart beats for you.
That's the lndian fella couldn't get it up.
I thought you said he was Native American.
Yeah.
And you, young man.
Why a.re you here?
I agree with him.
Well, proceed. I'm not paid by the hour.
Rusty.
My heart beats for Rusty.
(Mrs. McGee gasps)
-That's good. Get that.
-I'm on it.
DWAIN: Good angle for her.
Russell, we always knew
you swam upstream.
Amen.
Come here, baby.
(Joyous instrumental music)
-There's a market for this.
-Yeah.
My little firebug.
GUEST: There you go, ma'am.
Peg, get over it.
Well, enough of this swapping of spit.
FATHER: Let's celebrate!
CONGREGATION: Yeah!
(Joyous electronic music)
(Joyous Hindi dance song)
Ripped by thewildbunch22