Taken...
Do I?
To us.
Us.
Do you know what
you're gonna name her?
Allie.
Her name is Allie.
ERIC: I want you to join me
in the program, Mary.
You're grandfather found this
in Pine Lodge, New Mexico.
Found it at a crash site.
So it's all true.
This is something that shouldn't
go outside the family.
What's this, Allie?
That's my journal.
I write down things I think of and stuff.
We need your help, gentlemen.
You'll stop playing games
and tell us everything you know
about whoever it is who's out there
and what the hell they want.
Mr. Miller has an implant.
We're monitoring it.
The implants broadcast
on a spread spectrum.
We block those frequencies,
the implant doesn't register.
ERIC: Will this work on Allie?
We can block her frequency, too.
And they can't find her.
ERIC: Let's pick her up.
She can manipulate time.
That therapy group her mother's in?
We have someone in that group.
Put your gun away, Ray!
You don't want to do this.
Put the gun away!
You know who's in there, right,
besides the little girl?
Her mother and her father... Charlie.
That means he knows, and that's
two people with a lot of information
that have had some pretty bad
experiences with us over the years.
They have to go.
Dr. Penzler, too.
What are you doing, Allie?
Look at me, Dad.
(gasps)
Get away!
Take the little girl and... it's a trick!
Run!
Come on!
I'll take care of you. Come on.
CHET: Where did they go?
ALLIE: Miss Crawford...
I'm ready to go with you now.
ALLIE: I guess I always knew
that there was
something different about me.
But when all of this
began to happen,
when I started
to be able to do things,
it was kind of scary...
like in a dream
where you start falling
and it feels kind of good,
until you begin to wonder
if you'll ever be able to stop.
That was a good trick.
You're a very complicated little girl.
What do you mean?
I mean, with what you can do,
you could have walked out
of that building.
Why did you let us take you?
I wanted you to leave my mom
and all the other people alone.
I was afraid you might hurt someone.
I thought if I went with you,
they'd be all right.
Allie?
It's 12:17. We've lost two hours.
What?
We've lost two hours.
Are you all right?
Look, what I did... I'm sorry.
It's okay. I'm alive. We're all alive.
Everyone get out of here.
Don't go home.
Find places where
you're gonna be safe.
- Allie?
- Just get out of here! Go!
LISA: Allie!
CHARLIE: Go!
LISA: Allie?
Allie!
Lisa, she's gone. She's not here.
Where did she go?
Where did they take her?
Allie!
I've got to find my daughter, please!
I know.
Allie did this...
the time... all of it.
Allie gave us missing time?
Y-Y-Yes.
She... she stopped time.
She stopped us,
she stopped us
and let time keep moving.
She wanted to keep us safe,
and she did that.
She needed the missing time
so that she could go with them
without us trying to stop her.
She was trying to keep us safe.
(radio plays)
(knock on door)
I'm coming!
Oh, thank God.
I've been worried sick!
I went by your apartment
four times.
I kept calling. What happened?
Are you all right?
(voice breaking) Allie's gone.
Do you know who I am?
Not exactly.
Well... um...
our families go way back...
mine and your mom's
and your dad's.
I kind of think that you and I
might be the end of all this.
We might just be
the beginning.
Your grandfather wasn't
a very happy man.
Why are you trying so hard
to be like him?
We're almost to the airstrip.
We better get this thing in place.
(moans)
Lisa.
Lisa, it's all right.
Lisa. Baby. Lisa!
Lisa! Lisa!
N-N-N-Nina?
I'm right here.
I'm right in front of you.
I can't see anything!
I can't see anything at all!
NINA: Lisa.
Lisa!
(Lisa moans loudly)
All right? Can you see me now?
What happened to you?
I don't know.
I was... somewhere else.
I was somewhere else, and...
wherever it was,
I couldn't see a thing.
She's always been a...
she was a real good-Iooking baby
right from the start.
And really smart.
At seven months' old, she was
already playing peek-a-boo.
I've got a video at home of her
taking her first steps.
You should see that.
I'd like to.
We've always had this link,
you know, a connection.
I've always known
exactly where she was,
what she was thinking,
how she was feeling.
I'd go to pick her up at school,
I'd stop off to get Tylenol...
she'd walk out the building with
a runny nose and a headache.
Sounds silly, doesn't it?
I mean,
every mother has that.
No, they don't.
Man, I'm really, truly sorry.
This is because Allie's blessed, right?
These people that took her
want to know what she's all about.
Yeah, pretty much.
We'll do whatever we can
to help you get her back.
I've got a couple of shirts
around that'll fit you.
Over the years, a girl winds up
with a souvenir or two.
Allie left this in the park
when she ran away
at soccer practice.
12 hours ago, there was
a bullet in my lung.
I should be dead.
Why doesn't it surprise me
that you're not?
She's just a kid.
She didn't ask for any of this.
She shouldn't
have to do any of this.
It's not fair! It's not fair at all!
We'll get her back.
How?
ALLIE: When you've done something
that you can't take back,
something that
you don't understand,
you start to hold tightly
to the things
you do understand,
and you try to make sense
out of everything you can.
Because if you believed
that all you had to do
to make things right
was to find a reason,
but what happens
when you find the reasons
and they are not your own?
How do you find any comfort
or any sense in that?
They're on their way.
We haven't had a chance to talk.
What do you mean?
About your father.
There's nothing to say.
You did what you had to do
for the project.
Ha Ha. "For the project."
When I was a kid,
every time he went out of town,
I used to imagine a car wreck,
something like that,
just how much better our lives
would have been if he were gone.
You've been inside a craft.
Many times, yeah...
that one at Groom Lake.
That was beautiful...
wasn't it?
Yeah.
That was my family legacy.
The craft, the bodies.
My grandfather's legacy.
My father squandered all that.
He had it right there in his hand,
and he let it all slip away.
He couldn't stop them.
He could have tried.
You don't feel any remorse, do you?
Do you think that
makes me a bad person?
You did what you had to do.
I heard about your father.
I'm sorry for your loss.
It was a terribly
unfortunate mistake.
Mistake?
You've got the girl?
She's inside.
So you really believe
that thing you put on her head
is blocking her signal?
Right now, they're in their ship,
scratching their little gray heads,
going, "Where's our girl?"
Then, when we take that shield off,
here they come.
You're confident
we can take them down?
Wherever they come from...
the most distant star,
the furthest reaches of time...
the moment they enter
our time and space, our reality,
they're confronted by
the laws of our physics.
You're sure of that?
In 1947,
in Roswell, New Mexico,
a ship came down when it collided
with a Mogul spy balloon... a balloon.
Yeah, I'm pretty damn sure.
You done a fine job.
We're indebted to you.
What is this?
SOLDIER:
Charlie company, move out!
I'd like to thank you
on behalf of your country
for your contribution to this effort.
You've done your part,
Miss Crawford.
The little girl's a part of
a military operation now.
We'll take it from here.
For three generations, my family's
been preparing for this.
I've dedicated my career...
my life... to this.
And don't think we don't appreciate it.
In a matter of days,
we may be able to set foot
inside one of their craft,
to meet these beings,
to find out what this
has all been about.
If you think I'm gonna stand by
while you take that opportunity away
from me, you're out of your mind.
You don't really have a choice.
You've been benched.
Go sit down. Grab some pine.
What I'd like you to do now...
I'd like you to clean up
the mess you made in Seattle.
The doctor... she's a liability.
Marginalize her.
And the girl's parents... put them
somewhere until this is over.
Don't want them stirring the pot.
We have people for that.
You mentioned your father's
death was a mistake.
People spend the rest of their lives
in prison for mistakes like that.
Stay out of my way.
You can ride with me, doctor.
Brief me on the way.
E-E-Excuse me?
We need your expertise.
I'm not giving you
a choice here, doctor.
Come on, let's go. Now.
Uh...
Milo and I,
we drove everywhere.
We'd ask people in diners
and in gas stations,
and we got guys
from every band we know
doing the same thing.
Nothing.
What about taking this public?
They're not gonna come after you
with the whole world watching.
I called Channel 4 news.
I said my daughter was kidnapped
by a super-secret government agency.
They... they said I should
call the police.
I told them I didn't think
it would do any good,
and they gave me another number...
for Highline West
Psychiatric Hospital.
We put an ad
in the New York Times.
That's how Lisa gets
in touch with her uncle.
Tom will be calling us soon.
I'm cold.
Shouldn't be much longer.
Thank you.
Lisa.
(Allie's voice)
I'm scared, Charlie.
I'm very, very scared.
Just how powerful is this
little girl, doctor?
She's demonstrated powers
beyond anything we imagined.
She can manipulate time,
she has amazing abilities to screen,
to project images from our minds.
Just how powerful is she?
The question
you should be asking is,
why is she letting us
take her anywhere at all?
You've reached the voice mail
for Dr. Chet Wakeman.
Dr. Wakeman is out of range
of this cellular device.
Please leave a message.
General Beers' office.
This is Mary Crawford.
Can you reach
the general for me?
I'm sorry, Miss Crawford.
He's not available.
Tell him I have new information
he'll want to hear about.
ALLIE: We had come to the time
I had always known was coming.
I had always had
this feeling that, one day,
I would have to do
something very hard.
I just hoped that I could
find a way to do it
without anyone getting hurt.
Sorry, sir. There's been a toxic spill.
You need to turn your vehicle around.
No one's allowed to go through.
Let's get the gate.
How you doin' in there?
I'm all right.
Can I ask you something?
I heard that you let them take you,
that you came right up to them
and said you'd go with them.
Uh-huh.
I also heard that you can do things,
kind of like magic or something.
Is that true?
Yes.
So you've got all of that power,
why didn't you just stop them?
I was afraid
they'd hurt other people.
You're one brave little girl.
I don't feel very brave right now.
Hey...
maybe later, I could come back
with a book or something.
Did you ever read
Huckleberry Finn?
No, I never have.
Well, I've got my copy
in my duffle.
I always carry it with me.
It was my mom's favorite book.
She'd bake us Toll House cookies,
and we'd share the whole plate
of them while she read.
If it wouldn't make you
too sad to remember her...
I'd like to hear the story.
No, it wouldn't make me sad at all.
It would be nice to remember her.
We're calling the operation
"Dropping the Dishes."
The three Humvees
equipped with the missiles
will be here, here, and here,
camo nets above 'em.
The target, gentlemen,
will be in the air.
It will be big.
Observation posts here
on the mountains for early warning.
Two men to each O.P.
We're gonna try to take
this thing down intact, sir?
That's the plan.
Once we get it down, sir,
how do we find these guys?
Y'all have seen the S-2 briefing video.
You know as much as I do.
All right, they can do some
pretty incredible things.
They've taken people through walls.
They can make you see things
that are not there.
But no problem, right? We're the best.
Y'all are about to fight an enemy
the likes of which
no soldier has ever seen.
I can't tell you how it will go,
but I can tell you this...
you're about to earn
a place in history.
She's completely normal.
No fluctuation
in brain-wave pattern,
nothing in her blood chemistry.
Her biology is human.
Of course it is.
We won't find anything.
The part of her that isn't human
is capable of perfect mimicry.
Then what are we looking for?
I don't know.
SOLDIER: Any questions?
Is there anything we can do to
maximize our cone of fire, sir?
I'd aim for the center
of the damn thing and pray.
Any other questions?
Uh, General?
General.
I need to talk to you
about the little girl... Allie.
Something wrong?
Her powers are just
beginning to manifest.
We need to protect her
for further study.
So you're uncomfortable with
the notion of using her for bait.
Let's not think of this,
then, in terms of fishing.
In fishing, you put a worm on a hook,
fish bites the worm, takes the hook,
the worm's toast.
But this is hunting country,
so think of her
more as a... a salt lick.
A buck comes up to the salt,
boom, you shoot the buck.
No harm at all to the salt lick.
General, I, uh...
I think there's been
a miscommunication here.
A miscommunication. Really?
Yeah. See, um,
my understanding of the plan...
and I did design the plan...
an explosion is to be
detonated above the craft.
The effect is to bring
the ship down intact.
We're not trying to, uh, bag a buck,
as you so elegantly put it.
We're trying to collect
specimens for the zoo.
My orders are
to take down their craft
and to replace the craft
and the bodies you people lost
and, if possible,
to take the occupants
of the craft alive,
and if not, well, we'll have
more bodies to study.
This is an opportunity
to communicate with beings
from another world.
We're on the brink of the single
most important moment
in human history.
As far as I'm concerned,
we're at war.
These beings have taken
our citizens against their will,
they've invaded our air space,
our lives, even our gene pool.
These are unparalleled
acts of aggression.
We're at war here, fighting an enemy
we don't understand at all,
so I'll do whatever I have to do.
You guys think
these things will do the job?
You men are outclassed,
out-equipped,
and probably outnumbered.
Plan A, then, would be for
the missiles to do their job
and take these things
out of the sky.
Plan B would be for you
to stick your head
between your legs
and kiss your asses good-bye.
There is no plan C, gentlemen.
(laughter)
You know about
all the things they do?
The probes and stuff, man?
I hear they show you stuff
that'll rip your brain apart.
I heard one of these came down
in Nebraska two years ago...
took a squad
and wiped them off
the face of the earth.
I think this is some sort
of training exercise
in psychological warfare,
to see how we do with
an impossible situation.
- You saying there aren't any aliens?
- That's what I'm saying.
You've all seen
the S-2 briefing videos.
I saw the alien autopsy video, too.
Dude, that was awesome.
That looked more real
than any of our stuff.
I met this guy once, special ops,
had to debrief these two marines
that were taken right through
their barracks walls.
Showed up a couple hours later
with scars all over their bodies.
They were never right again.
See, it's drug tests.
Chemical warfare,
something like that.
We're not fighting any aliens.
We're like lab rats being tested.
You don't think we're gonna
storm a flying saucer?
Tried to get
my head around it, but, no.
I think this is some very deep,
weird zone of "don't ask."
Either way, we're toast.
Ah! Get it off!
Get it off! Get it off!
(all chuckle)
I've got this thing
about roaches, all right?
(laughter)
And this is the man
who's going to save the world
from the alien menace.
(laughter)
Back to work.
"They judged it was him, anyway.
"Said this drowned man
was just his size
"and was ragged
and had uncommon long hair,
"which was all like pap.
"But they couldn't make nothin'
out of the face,
"because it had been
in the water so long.
"Weren't much like a face at all.
"They said he was floating
on his back in the water.
"They took him
and buried him on the bank.
"But I weren't comfortable long
"because I happened
to think of somethin'.
"I knowed mighty well
that a drowned man
"don't float on his back,
but on his face.
So I knowed then
that this weren't pap."
This isn't getting too scary, is it?
It's good. I like it.
I remember
I would picture that river.
When I imagined it,
it was all kind of dark and mossy,
trees hanging down and stuff.
Not like those pictures you see
of Tom and Huck fishing.
Oh, I'd get so scared, but I liked it, too.
And my mom would
get under the covers with me
and read these parts.
She was nice, your mom.
Yeah, she was.
My mom, too.
My mom's great.
You want me to go on?
Yes, please.
"We played robber
now and then about a month,
"and I resigned.
"All the boys did.
"We hadn't robbed nobody,
hadn't killed any people,
"but only just pretended.
"We used to
hop out of the woods
"and go charging down
on hog drovers.
"Women in carts taking
garden stuff to market...
we never hogged any of 'em."
(chuckling)
I appreciate that, Colonel.
I thought with the history our families
have shared over the years,
you could give me
an off-the-record location.
Yeah, I understand what
"need-to-know basis" means,
you jackass.
We need your help.
Come in.
Please, come in. Sit down.
Close the curtains.
You don't have to worry.
No one's coming here.
What do you mean?
I work for them, Charlie.
I was the one who called them.
You told them about Allie.
Lisa...
Just tell me where she is.
Please, Harriet, tell me
where they took Allie.
I don't know. I tried to call them.
All the numbers I've been given
are disconnected.
I have no way of finding them.
We trusted you,
everyone in the group.
We put our trust in you,
and you betrayed it.
They told me I was helping.
They told me they had proof
that people who had been taken
were in greater danger
than they knew. I thought...
You thought you were helping?!
You told them Charlie was here,
you told them Allie was with us,
and now they have her!
Lisa, I am so sorry.
I want you to put me back under.
Allie and I, we have this link.
Yes, I believe that's real.
In regression,
I've had those moments
where I feel Allie,
where I get that sense
of knowing where she is.
Yes.
I've been experiencing
things like that again
since they took Allie.
I keep getting this sense of knowing
where she is and what she's doing.
It's very strong. l...
I want you to help me find her.
We'd have to go pretty deep.
We've gone there before,
but frankly, Lisa,
I'm a little over my head here.
Can you help me get there?
We're dealing with something
that I don't fully understand.
Even if I am able
to access it...
hypnosis of this sort
can be very dangerous.
Are you sure
you're ready for that?
I'll go wherever I have to
if I can get my daughter back.
You have to do this for me.
You owe me that much.
ALLIE: Most of
the fights people have
are about something simple...
you want something
the other person has,
or maybe they're afraid
you're going to want it,
and they go after you first.
People always think that if they win,
then that's the end,
everything will be all right
from then on.
But everything changes,
and tomorrow, the thing
you were fighting for
will just be a memory.
Like everything else,
it's already happened.
They're ready to take
the shield off, doctor.
What we're going to do
is extremely delicate.
It would be easier for
Lisa and me to find a way in
if there wasn't
anyone else in the room.
It's all right.
And a third deep breath...
Now I want you to go to that place
where you and Allie find each other.
Can you find it for me?
(inhales deeply)
Yes.
SOLDIER: "And so we would lay
in ambuscade,
"as he called it,
"and kill the lot
and scoop the things.
"He said we must
slick up our swords and guns
and get ready."
Okay, I'm going to take
this thing off your head
in just a moment.
Now, it's not very bright in here,
but it may hurt your eyes
at first, okay?
Okay.
Now what do you see?
Darkness.
All I see is darkness.
l... I can make out something.
LISA: There are people watching.
It doesn't feel good.
There are all these people.
They're waiting
for something to happen.
They want something.
They're waiting for something.
Do you know where you are?
It looks like a hospital...
but it's not.
It smells kind of moldy...
it's like an attic.
DR PENZLER: Now what do you see?
Ugh!
But I don't know if it'll happen.
There's a lot of anger here
and a lot of fear.
Lisa... Lisa.
Charlie?
I don't know if they're
gonna get what they want,
but I know they're
going to keep her.
They're going to keep her
until they get what they want.
So what happens now?
We wait.
How long should we wait?
I don't know.
You believe they'll come?
Absolutely.
But then again,
I believe a lot of things.
He threatens to become
a major pain in the ass.
NINA: If they went for Dr. Penzler,
they'll be coming for you next.
I don't care about that.
All I care about is finding Allie.
Where is she?
I was with her in this room. It's...
it's a room.
Uh... Bare walls,
peeling wallpaper,
like a... farm.
Why a farm?
The way the room
looks and... feels.
(sighs)
Something on the wall...
license plates...
old, rusted license plates
and a calendar with a picture
of a tractor on it.
There were all these people.
A man I saw the time
they tried to pick me up,
but there was someone
in uniform...
You said there were
license plates on the wall?
Yeah, old ones.
What state?
Let me think.
North...
North Dakota! North Dakota!
That's a start.
North Dakota and a farmhouse
doesn't exactly
narrow it down that much.
Wallington's Feed and Grain.
Wallington's Feed and Grain!
The calendar on the wall!
That was the name of the place!
North Dakota.
I don't know what city.
The listing's for
Wallington's Feed and Grain.
You're sure?
Nothing.
In the whole state
of North Dakota, there's nothing.
Ask yourselves,
what would Maddie Hayes
and David Addison do?
And they say that watching
five hours of TV a day
for 26 years is a bad thing.
This intelligence is of
an other-than-human form.
They let us see what they
want us to see, nothing more.
Your govemment knows this.
Gulf Breeze, Exeter, Dayton...
I love this guy.
He believes in everything.
The scary part is how often
he comes close to the truth.
... our govemment has been
involved in a massive conspiracy
to cover this up.
Call me and tell me your story.
This is William Jeffries.
Talk to me, and I'll talk to you.
Oh, hi. This is Theresa,
from Pocatello, Idaho,
and I just have to tell you,
I'm so glad you're here,
because I was abducted
last September...
Snack time.
I tried to talk to everybody about this.
I tried the govemment...
I live on bad coffee
and stale Oreos
from the vending machine.
THERESA: Thank God
you're on the air.
(telephone rings)
Yes?
Little girl's light just came back on.
North Dakota, Benson County,
just outside of Brinsmade.
- Program worked.
- Thank you.
ALLIE: My mother used
to sing to me a lot,
folk songs mostly,
and things she liked
when she was a little girl.
There was this one song
called Further Along
that always made me
feel better when I was sad.
"Further along,
we'll know more about it.
we'll understand why.
"Cheer up, my brother,
live in the sunshine.
We'll understand it all,
by and by."
When you get to wondering
too much about things,
a song like that can really help a lot.
When we find her,
she's gonna want that.
She'll be glad you brought it.
Thanks for the book.
Well, I figured now that you
had that thing off,
you could read it for yourself
if you wanted.
I was kind of hoping you would
keep reading it to me.
Sure. I mean, I'd like that.
Me, too.
Can I ask you something?
Sure.
Are they really
gonna come and get you?
I don't know.
Probably something like that.
That sure will be something to see.
"Well, three or four months
run along,
"and it was well
into the winter now.
"I'd been to school
most of all the time
"and could spell and read
and write just a little
"and could say
the multiplication table...
Just before it gets dark
When the light
still hangs in the sky
The day's not quite come
All its promises
still in your own eyes
Between the time
your mother calls
Thanks.
And the time
you put the ball away
SOLDIER: "But before the cold
weather, I used to slide out...
There's a lifetime to be lived
And a world where every dream
is here to stay
Just before the night comes
And you run back
to the safety of your world
You're sure you've never heard of it...
Wallington Feed and Grain?
No, I'm sorry.
Just before it gets time
Are you folks asking about Wallington?
Yeah.
Harry Wallington, he went bust in '75.
'75?
Had a place up in Brinsmade.
I used to stop in on my way
back from fishing with my boys.
Good prices, quality products.
What's a couple of young folks
doing asking about a store
that went under when
you were still in diapers?
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
Well, nothin' lasts forever
But those moments
keep forever far away
You didn't mention
that it was an old calendar.
Sorry, my super-vision's
a little rusty.
We're gonna find her, Lisa.
We're going to Brinsmade.
Are you from there?
No. We're visiting a sick cousin.
Brinsmade's been evacuated.
You'll find your family member
at the high-school gym in Leeds.
Evacuated? Why?
Toxic spill. A truck collided with a train.
What kind of spill?
They don't tell me. They just tell me
to keep the cars out.
You're not afraid you're
standing downwind of something?
You folks turn around
and do like I said.
You'll find your
family member in Leeds.
Move along. Let's go.
Hold on tight
And I promise you, baby
It'll all be all right
I promise you, baby
Okay, so where are they?
I mean, they took that thing
off the little girl's head last night,
so where are they?
When I was in Afghanistan last year.
This was all we did... sit and wait.
Come out and kill me already.
I don't care.
Don't make me sit here
and think about what might happen.
You would have been lost
at the Alamo, my friend.
Day one of that siege,
I'd have been the first one
over that wall.
So what's the deal
with the little girl, Pierce?
I mean, you been with her.
She's special.
Well, what's so special about her?
You have to be in the room with her.
You guys are gonna think
this is really weird...
We're in a field waiting for
a flying saucer to land.
How weird could anything
you tell us be?
I've told you guys about my mom,
what a good cook she was,
the cookies she used to bake.
We have heard the tales.
My mom died in 1998.
And you start to lose 'em
after they die...
your loved ones.
I mean, their memories just...
start to fade in your head.
I don't mean events...
I remember birthdays,
picnics, everything like that.
I mean, your actual
mental picture of the person.
I'm reading to Allie,
just helping her pass the time.
She's just a scared little kid,
and she misses her mom,
just like I miss mine.
The book I'm reading,
it's something my mom
used to read to me.
It's just like
my mom's there with us,
that's all I'm trying to say.
And you attribute this
somehow to the little girl?
I'm just saying,
you have to be there with her.
You can't put it into words,
but if you spend some time
with her, you'll get it.
I can promise you that.
Thank you.
Sorry about how
all this worked out.
If you guys want to go
hunting in a couple of weeks,
they should have
the spill cleaned up.
There was no toxic spill.
I can tell you that.
How the hell you know that?
Because I worked
that railroad 19 years.
You know what they haul
on those lines?
Lumber and steel.
Nothing but lumber and steel.
Now, I'm up there
at Cranberry Lake
with Michael and Tony,
and I'm trying to explain
a little of my philosophy
of life in the woods.
A couple of fellas
up from Grand Forks
desperate to kill something
before the weekend is over,
and I'm trying to explain that
that's not really what
hunting's all about.
Is this a story
that goes someplace,
or is this "Dewey's
Meaning of Life, Part 7"?
The point is, the three of us
are sitting around the campfire
and I'm explaining my philosophy,
and this Humvee pulls up,
a bunch of soldiers get out
and tell us to head on
back to civilization.
On account of the spill.
A toxic spill...
if there had been one...
they might have told us
to evacuate the area
and then gone on
about their business.
Not this bunch.
They just stood there
the whole time
it took us to strike camp,
and then they damn near
followed us
all the way out of the woods.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for a Mr. Clayton.
- Over there.
- That's him?
Thanks.
You're Mr. Clayton?
(laughs)
That would be my dad.
I'm Dewey.
We'd like to hire your services.
Oh, you lookin' for a guide?
We were told
that you're the best.
And you two want to go huntin'?
In a way, yes.
Well, you're out of luck.
We're shut down.
Damn government's locked us
out of our own woods.
We know that.
But you've got some reason
you want to go up in there, anyway?
Why don't you step
into my office?
Now what have we got
out in those woods
that you two are so anxious
to go huntin' for?
Our daughter.
She's lost in the woods?
No. She...
The army has her.
Would this have anything to do
with that toxic spill
that didn't happen?
Yeah.
And your daughter, you say?
That gear back there belongs
to a couple of young killers
I had out this morning.
I promised to ship it to 'em
so they could put it in storage.
I sure don't think they'll be back.
It'll just sit in the garage
with the exercycle
and the cross-country skis
and the racquetball rackets.
Might as well put it
to some use before then.
It'll get down pretty low tonight,
but you get in them
sleeping bags right away,
you'll survive.
There's only one farm
out this way.
Nobody's lived there
for 25 years,
so if they're keepin' her
anywhere around here,
that'll be the place.
Now...
I take out all kinds of folks...
hunters, what have you.
There's a lot
of different game up here.
But if I'm lookin' at grouse,
then I have to go in
with a whole different set-up
than if I'm lookin' at deer or elk.
Now, you don't have to be
in a rush to tell me anything,
but at some point, you're
gonna have to let me know
just exactly what it is
that I'm gonna be lookin' at.
Oh...
just bend these
and give 'em a shake.
Good night.
I guess we'd better
get in our bags.
They're not gonna
do anything to her, Lisa.
She's too important to them.
Just before it gets dark
Before you grow
Before you're
too old to pretend
Just before it gets dark
And you know your dreams
will not come back again
Hold on
Hold on tight
And I promise you, baby
It'll all be all right
I promise you, baby
(crying)
Williams.
Williams, you asleep?
Not anymore.
Keel's got the night watch
on the little girl.
He's gonna let us in
to take a look. You in?
Yeah.
All right.
Let's go.
This is really dumb.
This is a court-martial.
We'll be in and out
in ten minutes.
- No one's gonna get court-martialed.
- Is that right?
This kid's gonna bring these guys
down from outer space.
The least we can do
is look her in the eye.
Hi.
We were just
kind of wondering...
What the big deal was.
Yeah, pretty much.
I'm not quite sure.
I'm important to the...
do you guys
call them aliens?
Yeah, usually.
Okay, the aliens.
And your general figures
they'll come get me.
We kind of know that already.
How come you're
so special to them?
They're my other family.
What do you mean?
I'm part them.
For real?
But you just look like a little kid.
Maybe they're not
as different as you think.
ALLIE: Can I ask you something?
Sure.
Are you mad at them?
But you'll fight with them
just the same?
That's our job.
Grownups are weird.
36 hours... nothing from
Cheyenne Mountain,
nothing from NORAD,
nothing in the sky.
Damn it!
I knew this whole thing
was a bust.
I'm a four-star general.
I've been serving my country
for 30 years,
now I'm sitting in the middle
of Old McDonaldland
with a 9-year-old girl?
I'll tell you one thing...
I'm gonna have that
squirrelly-ass Dr. Wakeman
served up on a platter for this.
I'm not gonna be
the only one taking this fall.
You want to tell me
what the hell went wrong?
Oh, you got a theory, don't you?
They're up in their craft
worried about this girl,
and as soon as you take
that thing off her head,
they're gonna come swooping down.
Well, we could have
been mistaken.
Well, that's big of you
to admit it.
General, we're talking
about aliens here.
By definition, their motives,
their behavior,
everything about them
would be... alien.
So how much longer
do we wait?
That's entirely up to you.
What's a five-letter word
for "idiot"?
This whole culture is built
on a fear of death.
No one wants to talk about it,
everyone wants to pretend
it's not gonna happen.
That's how come you get
those vegetarians
springing up all over the place.
"If I don't eat the little darlings,
then they're never gonna die."
Nonsense.
Neither one of you has ever
been hunting, am I right?
I went out with some guys once
when I was maybe 14.
We were living in Wisconsin.
I didn't like it.
It made me feel terrible.
Well, you're supposed
to feel terrible.
That's a part of it...
understanding what it costs
for you to stay alive.
Well, we better keep moving.
As it is, it'll be dark before
we get to where I think we...
(rustling)
That little girl of yours
must be something special.
- How are you?
- I'm all right, ma'am.
What you got up there?
Some sort of toxic spill, ma'am.
Ah, is that what they told you?
Yes, ma'am.
You'll have to let me through.
I need to see General Beers.
Do you have clearance?
Do you have any idea
what spilled up there?
No, ma'am, I don't.
You need to let me through.
I have important information
that General Beers is expecting.
You're not gonna
let me through, are you?
No, ma'am.
I didn't think so.
Next time, I'm just gonna
run through the roadblock,
so why don't you arrest me?
What?
Arrest me and have someone
take me to General Beers.
No one goes in.
We detain people here.
Okay, well, then detain me
and get General Beers
on the phone and let him know
that Mary Crawford has important
new information about the project.
I can't do that
without provocation, ma'am.
(sighs) I see.
(clears throat)
How's this?
They're not coming, are they?
Maybe they're not
that worried about her,
maybe they think she can
fight her own battles.
You don't know
when to quit, do you?
At the roadblock,
you told one of my soldiers
you had information for me.
I lied.
You son of a bitch.
Did you think I was just going
to let you take the project
away from me,
you and the general here?
You bastard.
You sold me out
the first chance you got.
Worthless bastard!
At the roadblock. Trunk.
Put her somewhere
where she can't hurt anyone.
MARY: Creep.
It's a woman thing, right?
They know how to hold a grudge.
My father had this idea that
he could do dangerous things
because they needed him,
that they'd keep him safe.
Well, they took care of me
more than once.
Because they needed us to, uh...
to get together.
Because they needed Allie.
Exactly.
So they're not gonna
let anything happen to her.
We don't know that.
They're not gods, Charlie.
No. We're outclassed enough,
so they can act like gods.
We don't know what they want
with Allie or why they did this.
The odds are they didn't
go through all this trouble
just so they could hand her
over to these people.
I think she's gonna be all right.
I'm going to find Allie
and do whatever I can to help her.
I'm not going to rely on them
for anything.
Hey!
Okay.
I need to speak to Miss Crawford.
This is for
Miss Crawford's ears only.
You can wait over there.
SOLDIER: Yes, sir.
You peeked, didn't you?
My grandfather
found it at Pine Lodge.
At the crash site.
I never thought your dad
was all that bright.
It can be very effective
when a stupid person lies to you.
I found some papers
with these images on them
when we moved out
of Groom Lake.
I asked your dad about them,
he gave me nothing.
I stood there with your father
and told him I was wrong
about the body
from the Roswell wreckage
being the transmitter.
I told him there had
to be something else.
He just looked at me
like he didn't have a clue.
(chuckling)
You got to admire that.
Mary...
I had to go with them.
I couldn't let all this
happen without me.
You understand?
Please. I would have done
exactly the same thing.
I know.
Subtitle
CEDO FILM - by Lucifer