(SIGHS)
Last tour of the day.
I wonder why
nobody wants them.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(GIRL LAUGHS)
(GROANS)
Bull's-eye.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Ugh.
Hi, super old guy!
A museum? Again?
(WHIMPERING)
(SCOFFS) I hate stuff.
Oh, boy.
BETH: It's okay, Thomas.
I'll take them.
Uh... Are you sure?
I think these are the "detention" kids.
(GRUNTS)
(ALL CHEERING)
Don't you worry.
I can handle them.
You go take your break.
Thanks.
(GRUNTS)
Follow me, kids.
ALL: Huh?
Yo, lady! The museum
door is that way.
Yes, it is, but you aren't
like the other kids.
Oh, no, no, no.
You need to see
something special.
(LAUGHS)
Right through that door.
ALL: Huh?
You're seeing things, lady.
Am I?
Or are you
not seeing things?
ALL: Whoa.
Come on.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Now, today is
November 2nd.
Does anyone here know why
that date is important?
Taco Tuesday!
(ALL LAUGH)
No.
"Gorge Yourself on
Halloween Candy" Day?
(MARBLE CLINKING)
Nope. Today is
the Day of the Dead.
Wait. Is that National
Zombie Day or something?
(ALL LAUGHING)
(MAN SHOUTS)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
You can't go this way!
You will get us both in trouble.
Ancient rules of the, uh...
museum administration.
Huh.
Well, I suppose I could
turn a blind eye, my...
(CHUCKLES)
dear.
(SHOUTS)
(SCREAMS)
(CHUCKLING)
Behold, children,
the glorious beauty...
of Mexico!
Huh?
(INDISTINCT CHEERING)
Whoa!
This place is loco.
So many skulls!
At least that part
isn't lame.
(GRUNTING)
SASHA: Whoa!
What is this book?
That is the Book of Life.
All the world is
made of stories...
and all of those
stories are right here.
This book
holds many truths.
Some are actually true.
(YELLING)
"The battle of
Cinco de Mayo"?
Mayo! I love mayo.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
BETH: And some,
not so much.
GOTH KID: El Chupacabras,
the legendary goat sucker?
I have to get one.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Now, although you may doubt
some of these stories...
there is one thing
that we know for certain.
Mexico is
the center of the universe.
And long ago,
in the center of Mexico...
was the quaint
little town of San Angel.
Churros! Churros!
Frosted churros!
BETH: Now, naturally,
since San Angel
was the center
of the universe...
directly below it lay...
the Land of the Remembered.
A festive and magical place
for those who live on...
in the memories of their loved ones.
Whoa.
BETH: And below that..
Lies the Land
of the Forgotten.
MAN: Ay ay av!
BETH: The sad and lonely destination
for those poor souls...
who are no longer remembered.
(CHILDREN GROANING)
But before I can properly
begin our story...
you need to meet the two magical
rulers of these realms.
Who is that?
That is La Muerte.
She is made out of
sweet sugar candy.
She's so pretty.
She is, isn't she?
She loves all mankind...
and believes that their hearts
are pure and true.
And that is Xibalba.
That charming rascal thinks mankind
is not so pure, just like him.
He looks spooky.
BETH: Yes, he's made out of tar and
everything icky in the whole world.
He's so... pretty.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Uh, what about
the weirdo with the beard-o?
(BETH CHUCKLES)
BETH:
That is the Candle Maker.
He keeps
everything in balance.
He's made out of wax and has
a beard full of clouds.
(GIGGLING)
Clouds?
All right. Let me show
you something else.
All of these
wooden figures here...
represent real people in our
story, just like you and me.
ALL: Whoa.
And so, our tale begins...
on the day
the people of Mexico call...
the Day of the Dead.
No retreat.
No surrender!
(ALL CHEERING)
BETH: On this festive,
enchanted day...
families bring
food and offerings...
to the altars
of their beloved.
SASHA: It's like
a hundred birthday parties.
BETH: Yes, it is.
And on this particular
Day of the Dead...
after centuries of
being banished...
Xibalba had had enough.
Really, my dear...
you have no idea
how cold and vile
the Land of
the Forgotten has become.
(GIGGLES)
Just like your heart,
Xibalba.
Just like your heart.
(XIBALBA GRUNTS)
(GASPS)
(LA MUERTE LAUGHING)
Why must I rule
a bleak wasteland...
while you enjoy
the endless fiesta
in the Land
of the Remembered?
It's simply unfair.
Xibalba!
What? It's his time.
More or less.
Uh-uh.
Not today, my love.
Come on, my dear.
Trade lands with me.
I beg you!
Oh. You're so cute
when you beg.
I'm serious.
I hate it down there.
Hey. You're there
because you cheated!
You made your bed
with that wager.
You're not the man
I fell in love with...
all those centuries ago.
Let's not dwell
in the past, mi amor.
(GRUNTING)
Anyway, I was thinking...
how about
another little wager?
You think you can calm the flames
of my anger with another bet?
What exactly did
you have in mind?
(XIBALBA LAUGHING)
Let's check out the menu
for the evening.
Hmm...
Ah, look there, my love.
Classic mortal dilemma.
Two boys.
Best friends, no less.
LA MUERTE: Oh, in love
with the same girl.
(SIGHS)
Fear not, senorita.
Your hero has arrived!
Is that so?
How dare you
interrupt a guitarrista?
(GRUNTING)
(MARIA POSADA LAUGHING)
Ha!
(LAUGHING)
MANOLO: The girl is mine.
JOAQUIN: Never!
She is mine.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
I belong...
to no one.
BOTH: Whoa.
(SIGHS) I believe we have our wager.
Which boy will marry her?
Very well.
We will each choose one of
these boys as our champion.
Let's go wish them luck.
Maria,
weren't you grounded?
(SCOFFS)
My father is overreacting.
How was I supposed to know that
chickens don't like baths?
(CHICKEN CLUCKING)
Don't worry. He knows a real
man is protecting you tonight.
You're not even close.
But I have a moustache.
Yeah, just like
your grandma.
(ALL LAUGHING)
GENERAL POSADA: Maria.
CARLOS: Manolo!
(INDISTINCT TALK)
(SIGHS)
Come, mijo.
Your mother would
be so proud of you.
You think she'll
come back tonight?
Carmen is here.
But it's...
But it's more like...
a warm feeling you get
when loved ones are with you.
All of these
families have lost someone.
But as long as we
remember them...
we can feel their
presence with us...
for one night each year.
I just thought I might
see her one more time.
She always
smelled like flowers.
(WOMAN SINGING SOFTLY)
I remember her singing.
She was a good woman,
that one.
I miss her so much.
Just be still,
and you can feel it.
Your mother is here,
along with all our ancestors.
As long as we remember them,
they are with us.
The moment we forget them,
they are truly gone.
I can feel them.
Kind people...
may I please have
a bit of your bread?
I am so hungry.
I'm sure Mama would
want you to have it.
Right, Papa?
Thank you, my dear.
In return,
you have my blessing.
May your heart be
always pure and courageous.
What do we say, Manolo?
Thank you, senora.
Thank you.
Ah, Manolo.
Always giving away
stuff for free.
Right, Dad?
BETH: Joaquin's father,
Captain Mondragon...
had passed away fighting
the fearsome bandit...
known as Chakal.
(XIBALBA LAUGHING EVILLY)
(JOAQUIN GASPS)
(GRUNTING) Who's in there?
(GASPS)
Young sir, may I please
have some of your bread?
I'm so hungry.
This bread is
for my father.
And it's delicious.
Well, perhaps
you would consider a trade?
An old medal? Please.
Mmm-mmm-mmm.
Oh, this is no
ordinary medal, my boy.
As long as you wear it,
you cannot be hurt.
And it will give you
immeasurable courage.
Really?
Deal.
(LAUGHING)
But keep it hidden.
There is a bandit king...
who would stop at nothing
to get it back.
Bandit king? (GASPS)
You mean Chakal?
Where did he go?
(XIBALBA LAUGHING EVILLY)
So, then,
if my boy marries the girl...
I will finally rule
the Land of the Remembered.
And if my boy marries
the girl, you will...
You will stop interfering
with the affairs of man!
What?
I can't do that!
Come on. It's the
only fun I ever get!
Then the bet is off.
(SCOFFS)
Very well, my dear.
By the ancient rules...
the wager is set.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
BETH: And, so, the greatest
wager in history began.
Manolo versus Joaquin
for the hand of Maria.
Wait. So these ancient gods
picked three little kids to...
Represent the whole world?
Yeah. Pretty crazy, right?
GOTH KID: Yeah!
Keep going, lady.
Yay!
Whoo!
Yeah!
Yeah! (GRUNTS)
(MANOLO LAUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(PIG BLEATING)
(GASPS)
You're so cute.
(KNIVES SCRAPING)
(GASPS)
(MARIA POSADA GASPS)
Oh, no.
(BLEATS)
Not on my watch.
We have to
free the animals!
BOTH: Huh?
Come on, you guys!
Let's do this!
Yeah!
Hold on, Maria.
Don't!
(INDISTINCT CHATTING)
People of San Angel,
please!
I beg you.
After the Revolution...
we need more volunteers
to join this mighty brigade!
(SNEEZES)
(DOG BARKS)
(GRUNTING)
Whoo-hoo!
A heroic brigade
to protect us from Chakal.
(ALL GASP)
(RUMBLING)
IGNACIO: Chakal is here!
(GASPS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(BLEATS)
(ALL SIGHING)
Freedom!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING)
Maria, what have
you done now?
Freedom is coming through!
(GASPS)
Stop!
(GRUNTS)
(MANOLO GRUNTING)
(LAUGHING)
(BOAR SNORTING)
(GASPS)
Oh, no!
(ALL WHIMPERING)
(ALL GASP)
Whoa.
Oh, dear.
No retreat.
No surrender.
(GRUNTS) Toro, toro.
(ALL GASP)
Ha!
He has the gift.
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
Oh.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Hmm.
Ha!
Great form, mijo.
(MANOLO GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Ha!
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
(ALL CHEERING)
That's my son!
Oh, thank you, Manolo.
(ALL SING) Gracias
Oh, my.
What did I miss?
JOAQUIN: You okay, sir?
You have saved my life.
And I--
Shh.
Quiet, boy. I'm talking.
But I--
Quiet.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(EXCLAIMS)
That girl is in
so much trouble!
Uh-oh.
Maria!
(CLUCKING)
I'm sorry, Papa.
It's just that I--
(GASPS)
Manolo's guitar.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Maria!
This rebellious
nonsense ends now!
You are going to
become a proper lady.
Why?
Because I said so!
I'm sending you to Spain.
The sisters at the Convent of the
Perpetual Flame of Purity...
will straighten you out.
BOTH: What?
But, Papa!
No. it is decided.
Now go home!
(SOBBING)
Joaquin, you are so much
like your father.
This town could
use a new hero.
Come.
You are like
the son I never had.
My boy, your father
was like a brother to me.
(GRUNTING)
(URINATING)
(PIG BLEATS)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Where do you
think you're going?
He can't send Maria away.
Well, fathers do what's
best for their children.
Come along.
Mijo. I saw how you
fought that beast.
You made our
ancestors proud.
Do you think
Maria was impressed?
Maria and every girl in town.
People said I was the greatest
bullfighter in our family's history...
but it is you, my son, who will
be the greatest Sanchez ever!
They will write
songs about you!
And I will sing them!
Wait, what?
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
I will sing them.
(SIGHS) Son, music is not work
fit for a Sanchez bullfighter.
But I want to
be a musician.
No. You must focus.
Your training
begins at once.
Your grandpa, Luis, taught me
when I was about your age.
Wait, isn't that when that
bull put you in a coma?
Ah, memories.
My only son fighting angry,
thousand-pound beasts.
The family
tradition continues.
Yay.
(BLEATS)
BETH: And so, the day came when
Maria would leave to study abroad.
The three amigos
would be no more.
(WOMEN SINGING) Adios, Maria
Adios, Maria. Write soon.
(TEARFULLY)
I'm going to go over there.
(MARIA POSADA SIGHS)
I'm gonna miss you guys.
We'll be here, waiting.
For as long as it takes.
Don't ever
stop playing, okay?
And you.
Don't you ever stop
fighting for what's right.
I got you a present. You
should probably open it now.
Wait a second. We were
supposed to bring gifts?
(LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
(BLEATS)
MANOLO: I named him Chuy.
He'll look after you.
Oh!
I remember you.
I figured you needed a little
part of town to go with you.
Thank you.
Seriously, no one told me
about bringing gifts.
Can you hold Chuy for me?
(BLEATING)
This is to make up for breaking your guitar.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(GASPS) Hmm.
MAN: All aboard!
(SNIFFLING)
I gotta go.
Don't forget me!
JOAQUIN: Maria!
Your bonnet!
(GASPS)
(TRAIN ENGINE STARTS)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(SOBS)
MANOLO: Maria!
(GASPS)
When you come back...
I will sing for you!
And I will fight for you!
BETH: It would be years before
they would see Maria again.
I will wait for you.
(MANOLO SINGING)
I'll be bold
As well as strong
One, two, three.
And use my head
Alongside my heart
(SIGHS)
So tame my flesh
And fix my eyes
Whoa!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
One, two, three!
A tethered mind
(GRUNTS)
Freed from the lies
(WHIMPERING)
And I'll kneel down
Wait for now
Hey, Manny!
I kneel down
(GROANS)
Know my ground
Yes! Just like your father!
'Cause I will wait
I will wait for you
And that's how
you finish a bull!
And I Will wait
I will wait for you
And I will wait
I Will wait, I Will--
CARLOS:
I will not wait for you!
Papa, I was on my way.
BETH: After years of training, Manolo's
father organized his first bullfight
which,
as luck would have it...
was on the day
that Maria returned.
MANOLO: Wait, Papa!
CARLOS: Playing all night
with those mariachis brothers!
You want to end up
like those bozos?
Oh! Okay, Manny,
we'll wait outside.
I don't think
Mr. Sanchez likes us.
You think?
Quiet, you lazy bums!
Ahh!
You live under my roof...
you live under my rules.
You will be a matador!
Papa, this is my life.
All the Sanchezes
are bullfighters!
Every single one of us.
I was a beast in the arena.
A beast!
It's in your blood.
It's your destiny.
How many times do
I have to say it?
(LAUGHS) This is not me.
This is you.
(SIGHS) My son, Joaquin may
be the hero of the town...
but today, you will be
the hero of the ring.
If, for once, you
actually finish the bull.
But he finished the bull
the other day in practice!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(LIGHTNING CRACKLING)
Ugh.
That did no count.
No. Killing the bull
is wrong.
Here we go again.
Ay! Kids today, with their long
hair and their no killing stuff.
(SIGHS) I'm out of here.
Don't you love your family?
Then go get that bull, mijo.
Don't dishonor our name.
Just be a Sanchez!
GRANDMA: Mijo...
he no gonna do it.
JOAQUIN: Hey, Manolo!
Huh?
No retreat.
(SIGHS) No surrender.
The hero of
San Angel returns!
Oh, come on.
You didn't think
I was gonna miss
your first little
bullfight, did you?
And Maria's here, too!
(SQUEALS)
Have you seen her? I cannot
wait to show her these babies.
Oh, so, she's back
only to see you?
Come on. That's not--
You have your medals, but I
have the bullring. (CHUCKLES)
We'll see which
Maria prefers.
It's a good thing you're finally
taking bullfighting seriously.
(SCOFFS) You should see me
in the bullring.
That's where I
really do my thing now.
A true Sanchez man.
Those are some big shadows
we live under, huh, buddy?
Huge.
(TRUMPETS PLAYING FAN FARE)
Hey, brother,
may the best man win Maria.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Joaquin!
BETH: In honor of Maria's
return from Europe...
the town received a rare visit
from its most noble son...
who was now a decorated hero.
They say Joaquin goes from town
to town saving them from bandits!
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
(LAUGHING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(ALL WHIMPERING)
(GRUNTING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
Yes!
That's my boy.
Afternoon, my general.
That is a mighty
moustache you have.
(MEN EXCLAIMING)
Huh?
BETH". As expected...
everyone in town was curious to see
how the young Maria had grown.
The jewel of
the town has returned.
And she's going to be
helping at the orphanage.
And I hear she reads books,
like, for fun.
No way!
Senorita Posada.
Hola, Joaquin.
(WHISPERING) It's really
nice to see you.
WOMAN: Oh!
And she's so natural!
(ALL GASPING)
OW! What?
(BAND PLAYING)
(LAUGHING)
And they say Manolo...
might be the greatest
Sanchez ever!
Yeah! That's my boy!
(CLEARS THROAT)
What?
(GRUNTS)
I would like to
dedicate this corrida...
to Miss Maria Posada.
(GRUNTING)
Welcome home, senorita.
(BULL SNORTING)
(SCREAMS)
I'm allergic to dying!
Especially in the face!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(ALL GRUNTING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Now, that's a Sanchez!
Manolo!
(GRUNTING)
(CHEERING)
Wow. (LAUGHS)
That's my son!
(ALL CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GASPS)
(LAUGHING)
Huh?
ALL: (CHANTING)
Manolo! Manolo!
Come on, mijo.
For me.
For our family.
Be a Sanchez!
(GASPING)
No.
Killing the bull is wrong!
Huh?
(GASPS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(SIGHS)
GRANDMA: See?
I told you he no do it.
(ALL BOOING)
MARIA POSADA: Bravo!
Bravo!
We don't have
to kill the bull!
Oh, no. Manolo.
(GENERAL POSADA GRUNTS)
Adios, Maria. Ow!
CARLOS: Manolo.
Manolo. Get up!
(GROANING)
I'm sorry, Papa.
Do not make it worse
by apologizing!
A Sanchez man never
apologizes! Never!
Even
If being
a bullfighter means...
killing the bull...
Well, then,
I'm no bullfighter.
No. You are no Sanchez.
(BULL GRUNTING)
Victory! (LAUGHING)
That poor kid never had
a chance, my dear.
Good game, though.
It's not over.
Ay, Maria.
(SINGING)
When you were here before
Couldn't look you in the eye
You're just like an angel
Your skin makes me cry
But I'm a creep
I'm a weirdo
What am I doing here?
I don't belong here
I don't belong
Oi. Manolo.
GENERAL POSADA: Maria!
(GASPS)
What just happened?
You don't know women,
my love.
BETH: That night,
General Posada
threw a grand party
to welcome Maria back.
But, you see,
he had bigger plans.
(LAUGHTER)
ALL: To Joaquin!
GENERAL POSADA: A great hero!
(LAUGHING)
Too bad you're just
in town for a few days.
If only there were something
that would make you stay...
like a special girl.
Eh, Maria?
Papa!
What? What I say?
On! (LAUGHS)
Oh, my father.
It's so wonderful to see
you again, Joaquin.
Look at that mustache.
(GASPS) And all those medals.
What's this one for?
(SCREAMS)
Nothing! Nothing, nothing.
What? I didn't--
(STAMMERING)
Why don't you tell me
a little more about Europa?
I loved it.
Such beautiful music and art and books.
It was wonderful.
Ugh.
Books, art, wonderfulness.
You sound like you've
learned so much, Maria.
I'm sure one day...
you are going to make a man
very, very, very happy.
And I hope that man's
mustache, or his medals...
makes you very,
very, very, very happy.
Oh, is that so?
(CHUCKLES) Well, yes.
Behind every man with an amazing
mustache is a beautiful woman.
(GASPS)
Oh, yes.
And I'll cook
and clean for him...
and be at his beck and call.
Mmm-hmm.
That sounds... That sounds so good.
That just sounds so good.
And you sound...
You're just so pretty.
Are you kidding me?
Oh, boy.
Is that how
you see a woman?
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY) Um...
We're only here
to make men happy?
(MEN LAUGHING)
Yeah.
(MARIA POSADA CLEARS THROAT)
So, I don't know.
I believe I have
lost my appetite.
No, please, please,
stay seated.
Now, if you will just excuse
me, I must go check on Chuy.
That's my pig-
I need to spend time
with someone civilized.
Buenas noches. You've picked
yourself a feisty one.
(CRASHING)
Good one, Joaquin! Very witty.
(SIGHS)
PEPE: I can't believe the
general invited the whole town!
Except for you, Manolo.
Sorry, bro.
He even invited us.
And he hates us.
(SCOFFS) It's hopeless.
I've lost her to Joaquin.
Okay, listen. All we got to
do is play the right song...
and trust me, everything will turn
around in the space of four bars.
We've already
been to four bars!
Twice! (GRUNTS)
Hold it. I know exactly what to play.
(WHISTLES)
PANCHO:
it has to be romantic...
and classy...
but with tons of dignity.
(PABLO YELLING)
(BLEATS)
(SINGING)
You, you got what I need
But you say
he's just a friend
Oh, baby, you--
(CHOKING)
(COUGHING)
(BLEATS)
Wow, that totally
captivated her.
I don't get it.
That one always works.
Even on my wife.
Mmm?
Wait. You're married?
Ooh! I got it!
Follow my lead.
(SINGING) If you want my body
and you think I'm sexy
Mami vamos, let me know
(VOCALIZING)
Oh!
Very romantic, Pepe.
(LAUGHING)
(BLEATING)
That's all I got, mang.
Okay. my turn!
One, two,
one, two, tres, cuatro!
That girl is way out
of your league, bro.
PABLO: Hey, let's eat!
(ALL CHEERING)
(DOGS BARKING)
(TUNING)
(SIGHS)
(MANOLO PLAYING GUITAR)
(MANOLO SINGING)
I love you too much
To live without
you loving me back
I love you too much
Heaven's my witness
And this is a fact
I know I belong
When I sing this song
There's love above love
and it's ours
'Cause I love you too much
I live for your touch
I whisper your name
night after night
I love you too much
There's only one feeling
And I know it's right
I know I belong
When I sing this song
There's love above love and it's
ours 'Cause I love you too much
Heaven knows your name
I've been praying
To have you
come here by my side
Without you
a part of me's missing
Just to make you my own
I will fight
I love you too much
(GRUNTING)
Heaven's my witness
and this is a fact
You live in my soul
Your heart is my goal
There's love above love
And it's mine
'Cause I love you
There's love above love and
it's yours 'Cause I love you
There's love above love
and it's ours
If you love me as much
(LAUGHS)
Huh?
Did you think it was
gonna be that easy?
(SCREAMS)
Ow! (GRUNTING)
I... I kind of did.
(MARIA POSADA GASPS)
Manolo! (LAUGHS)
Hold on, I'm coming.
(LAUGHING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
Joaquin.
Eh?
What are you doing?
Maria...
uh, will you...
Will you marry me?
Um...
ALL: Yes.
(CHUCKLES) Don't worry, your
father already said you could.
He did-- (STAMMERING) What?
Oh.
Who else could
protect us from Chakal?
(PEOPLE AGREEING)
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
(GASPS)
(ALL GASP)
Huh?
Uh-oh.
(GROANING)
(LAUGHING) What did I miss?
Huh.
Wait... Wait a sec.
Did he propose, too?
(MARIA POSADA LAUGHS)
No.
Were you going to?
What?
Well, I proposed first.
So, go fight
a bull or something.
(GRUNTS)
You two are
acting like fools!
Wait, me too?
Ooh.
You're so strong, Joaquin.
Thanks, I work out a lot.
Huzzah!
I love you,
you know that.
But how are you
going to protect Maria...
if you can't even
finish a bull?
(GASPS)
(ALL EXCLAIM)
Good one, Joaquin!
Oh, yeah?
Well, you will never be
as great a hero
as your father!
(ALL GASP)
(CHEERING)
Now, that's just
uncalled for.
You better get your
finger out of my face.
You don't point at me!
I'm the best pointer
you've ever seen!
That's so stupid,
so childish.
Joaquin!
Ha-ha!
Come at me, bro!
Manolo!
Huh?
PEPE: What?
You wanted a banjo?
JOAQUIN: Look at him!
He got his guitar.
What are you gonna do?
La musical
I'm so scared!
I'm gonna teach
you some manners.
Joaquin!
(GRUNTING)
(CROWD GASPS)
Huh?
Did I mention
I also studied fencing?
Fine.
We'll settle this later.
Any time. Any place.
On. Really, guys?
No!
Don't go, Joaquin!
What if the bandidos come?
(RUMBLING)
(PEOPLE GASP)
The bandidos are coming!
And Joaquin is gone!
(SINGING) All is lost
(BANDITS SHOUTING)
Tremble in fear before the
might of Chakal's army!
Women and children,
go to the church!
Men, we are going to drive
Chakal's bandits off!
Who is with me?
(SCREAMS)
Ay. This is not good.
Listen up, you cowards!
These are Chakal's demands!
"Hand over your chickens...
"monies... bacon...
"jars... mustache wax."
(SCREAMING)
This looks like "jelly"
but I think it's "jewelry."
Yeah, jewelry.
Anyways,
if you give all this to us...
then maybe we won't burn...
your town down.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh.
You want the town?
You're gonna have to go through me!
(GRUNTS)
(LAUGHING)
JOAQUIN: Hey, ugh
Huh?
Why don't you
fight a real man?
With a really
awesome mustache!
Joaquin!
Thank goodness
you are here!
(LAUGHING)
Here, hold this.
Hmm?
And this. And this.
Oh, and if
that's too heavy,
maybe you can just
hand it to Maria.
My name is Joaquin,
son of Captain Mondragon!
(BANDITS MURMURING) Tonight,
the town of San Angel...
is under my protection.
(BANDITS LAUGHING)
Prepare to be beaten.
(ALL GASP)
Get him, Plomo!
(BANDITS SHOUTING)
Joaquin!
CHILDREN: Joaquin!
(SINGING)
Who wants some more?
Get him!
Hey, girl.
(LAUGHING) You goofball.
(GRUNTING)
(BANDITS GRUNTING)
Ow. Ooh. Oh.
All right, that's just
not hurting at all.
CHATO: The beautiful hero!
He has the Medal
of Everlasting Life!
Joaquin!
(BANDITS GRUNTING)
(BANDIT COUGHING)
Retreat!
(BANDITS YELLING)
JOAQUIN: And don't ever
come back!
Yeah!
You better run away!
That was incredible.
Yeah, you really are a hero.
Hmm.
Perhaps now...
we possibly could continue our
conversation, Senorita Posada?
Uh...
Maria, please,
do it for the town.
Without Joaquin...
we are at
the mercy of Chakal.
(INDISTINCT CHATTING)
So, why don't you tell me
about some of your medals?
Oh! Well, I got this one for
delivering a baby with one hand...
while arm wrestling a bear with the other.
That's nothing, really.
Duh. Of course she's
gonna go with Joaquin.
And did you see
that mustache?
Are you crazy?
Maria is doing this
to protect the town.
Putting her duty before her heart.
BETH: Yes.
Life can be really
tough for the living.
CARLOS: Failing in
and out of the ring.
The whole Sanchez family
would be so...
disappointed in you.
Please, don't say that.
Listen. You love Maria?
Then fight for her,
like a man!
(SIGHS)
It's too late. Joaquin
proposed to her already.
Now, that's a real man.
GRANDMA: Quiet, Carlos!
Manolo...
if Maria didn't
say yes to Joaquin...
then she said no.
So, what are you
gonna do about it, son?
BETH: After stealing Xibalba's
magic medal in a battle...
Chakal had risen to become
the king of the bandits.
But when Xibalba stole it
back, Chakal had come undone.
We found... We found the medal!
The Medal of Everlasting Life!
It's in the town
of San Angel.
(ROARING)
Are you certain?
I swear! I swear!
A beautiful hero wears it
to protect the town!
It looked just like that.
CHAKAL: Gather my men.
We ride for San Angel.
(GRUNTING)
You've come back
to me, medal.
JOAQUIN: I got this one for saving
some orphans from a fire...
and then going back
in for their cribs,
in for their toys.
And then I also saved
a little puppy one time
that had a little
thorn in its paw.
And this medal is for
having the most medals.
Well, here we are.
Thank you for this most
informative talk about you.
Uh, I have something
for you, Maria.
That is so nice of--
Wow.
I'm speechless.
I know. Right?
I get that a lot.
(LAUGHING)
Good night, Joaquin.
Wait. Maria.
Yes?
Um... MARIA POSADA:
(GASPS) My bonnet.
Aw.
You kept it
all this time?
It's... Well,
it's what's kept me going.
About my proposal, will you
at least just think about it?
Good night, Joaquin.
Yes! Yes, yes, yes!
Joaquin, you're awesome!
Yes!
(MARIA POSADA LAUGHING)
(SIGHING)
(WINDOW RATTLING)
(GROWLING)
(WHISPERING) Meet me
at the bridge at dawn.
I can't.
My father won't--
Please, Maria.
I beg you.
If she meets him alone...
I will lose the wager.
Fix this for me,
old friend.
(SNAKE HISSING)
(GASPS)
(MANOLO PLAYING GUITAR)
Manolo.
MANOLO: (SINGING)
Wise men say...
only fools rush in
But I can't help...
falling in love with you
falling in love...
with you
This is what I
wanted to show you.
MARIA POSADA: It's so beautiful.
What you're feeling...
that's how I feel
every time I'm with you.
(GASPS)
I can't offer you a ring.
I have nothing
to give but my love.
Oh, Manolo.
I may not be
the town hero, Maria...
but I swear
with all my heart...
I will never,
ever stop loving you.
And I will never
stop loving the man...
who plays from the heart.
(HISSING)
(GASPS)
Snake!
No!
Ahh!
Maria!
No.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Help!
(FRANTIC MURMURING)
(GASPS)
What did you do, Manolo?
There was a snake and...
She's gone.
(ALL GASPING)
Why didn't you protect her?
Maria!
Oh, no. Oh, no!
This is all your doing!
Leave!
Or so help me, I'll--
(SOBBING) My little girl.
What have you done, boy?
What have you done?
It should have been me.
Yes. It should have.
SASHA: No!
Maria died?
That can't be right!
What kind of story is this?
We're just kids!
As the sky
cried with rain...
Manolo went back to
retrieve his guitar.
I will never see her again.
Are you certain?
You want to see
Maria again?
With all my heart.
Think about what you say...
boy.
With all my heart.
Done.
(HISSING)
(GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Maria...
SANJAY: No!
Manolo, too?
What is it with
Mexicans and death?
But it can't end like this.
Can it?
Oh, my sweet child,
this is not the end.
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
(DISTANT SCREAMING)
Huh?
(GASPS)
(LAUGHS)
Welcome to the Land of the Remembered!
(NEIGHING)
I made it.
And on the Day of the Dead,
no less.
Where is...
You're going to be a little
disoriented at first.
Don't try to
take it all in at once.
Let's start with your name.
Maria Posada!
Really?
Parents and their
crazy baby names.
And there's no
Maria Posada on my list.
No, no.
I'm looking for Maria Posada.
Oh.
My name is Manolo Sanchez.
(GASPS) Another Sanchez?
Man, that family
just keeps growing.
My family!
They'll help me find Maria!
Can you take me to them?
I would love nothing more than
to reunite a young couple.
Just hold on!
(YELLING)
(LAUGHING)
You know, I've been
down here for years...
awaiting my
beloved honey bunny.
Hi, honey!
(SCREAMS) Too soon! Go!
BETH: The Land of the Remembered
was vibrant and joyous!
Everything was
like the land above...
but it was more colorful...
it was more beautiful,
it was more festive!
And, on the Day of the Dead...
that place was bursting with endless
parties and spectacular parades.
There, your family
is in that one.
Wow.
Get in there!
(SCREAMING)
Oh. yeah!
Another Sanchez bullfighter.
You are...
the amazing
Carmelo Sanchez!
Yes! I was famous...
for fighting bulls without a cape!
(BULL MOOING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GRUNTS)
Capes are for cowards!
(SPITS)
Can you help me
find Maria Posada?
La Muerte can help you.
She helps everyone. Hold on.
Ow! (LAUGHING)
Oh. The great
Jorge Sanchez!
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
At your service!
I was famous for
fighting bulls...
with only one arm
and one leg.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Arms and legs
are for cowards!
You are Manolo,
the one who plays the guitar.
Yeah, that's me.
You know, when I was younger, I always
dreamt of singing in the opera.
You did?
(LAUGHS) But as you know...
BOTH: Music is not work
fit for a Sanchez bullfighter.
(LAUGHS) The same story.
(CHUCKLES) They crushed
our dreams. Hilarious.
(MANOLO SCREAMING)
He's new.
He reminds me of me.
But less handsome.
(CONTINUES SCREAMING)
Eh? Huh?
(SCREAMING)
(GASPS)
Of course!
It's Luis
"El Super Macho" Sanchez!
I was famous...
for fighting
three bulls at once!
(CROWD CHEERING)
One bull is for cowards!
MANOLO: Grandpa!
It's me, Manolo.
Manolo?
I'm so happy to see you.
Why you disgrace the family name?
Playing the guitar!
You couldn't finish one bull?
You were a clown.
(HORN BLOWS)
Sorry, cousin Chucho.
Welcome home, mijo.
Your mother will be
very happy to see you.
Mama?
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(GASPS)
Manolo.
Mama.
Manolo! (LAUGHING)
I missed you so much.
Ay, mijo, it's been like
a hole in my heart.
I've waited
so long for you.
But not long enough!
What are you doing here?
I'm here to be reunited
with the love of my life.
You're going to
love Maria, Mama.
I'm sure I will.
Manolo, you look
just like your father.
So handsome,
you turned out.
And I became a bullfighter,
just like you wanted.
Me? Are you crazy?
Haven't you learned anything
from your family's history?
What? But Dad said that--
Ay, that Carlos.
Wait until he
gets down here.
Now, come on, mijo!
Oh.
Everyone,
this is my son, Manolo!
(ALL GREETING)
And these are
your Adelita cousins.
They fought
in the Revolution.
BOTH: And we won.
No way!
BOTH: Hey, primo.
Being with
the whole Sanchez family...
and you, Mama.
This is incredible.
This is La Muerte's castle.
ALL: Aw!
Huh? I don't see it.
Oh.
Savage.
Come, she will help you find
my new daughter-in-law.
ALL: Whoa!
It's so pretty!
Now, this is a castle!
JORGE: We were always
La Muerte's favorites.
You know how bullfighters
flirt with death, eh?
And that's why there are
so many of you down here.
(CHUCKLES)
La Muerte's throwing a big Day
of the Dead fiesta for everyone!
Ooh. Ahh.
Savage.
Ask her, mijo.
My lady, could you help
me find Maria Posada?
XIBALBA: No one here
can help you, bullfighter.
(LAUGHING)
The Land of the Remembered
has a new ruler!
(ALL GASPING)
(INDISTINCT MURMURING)
Who, you ask?
Lil' old me.
You again?
But La Muerte would never
hand her domain over to you.
(BURPS) She lost a bet.
Ah. She would do that.
This land is finally mine!
All thanks to you, Manolo.
What?
La Muerte bet that
Maria would marry you.
I bet that Maria
would marry Joaquin.
And since you're
not around anymore...
Maria is going to
marry Joaquin just to,
you know,
protect her beloved town.
So, I win.
No, but Maria passed away.
I saw her.
Oh, no.
Oh, yes.
(GASPS)
Mijo, what is it?
One snake bite
merely put her in a trance.
My champion easily woke...
the sleeping beauty.
(GASPS)
Oh, my goodness.
It's a miracle!
(SINGING) Thank you
I'm... I'm...
Alive.
(ALL GASPING)
Cheers.
One bite? Your snake!
It bit me twice!
You cheated!
You will pay for this!
In all my years,
no one, in any realm...
has ever talked
to me like that...
and survived.
So, I ask you...
are you
threatening me, boy?
I will expose you
to La Muerte.
And then you and me
can settle things!
(ALL GASPING)
You'll never reach her
in her new realm.
I should know.
I rotted there for eons.
(MANOLO SCREAMING)
Now, if you'd all excuse me,
I have a wedding to plan.
Ciao! (LAUGHING)
MARIA POSADA: What happened?
Wait, where's Manolo?
I'm sorry, Maria.
Manolo...
Manolo passed away.
(GASPS)
No. It can't be.
I'm sorry, dear.
(SOBBING)
Maria, we are all
sorry Manolo is gone...
but Joaquin just
saved your life.
You see?
He will always protect you.
General,
this is not the time.
Shh.
Please,
for everyone's sake, mija.
Make him stay.
Will you stay in San Angel
if I marry you?
Yes, but you don't--
I accept Joaquin's proposal.
Ah, young love.
MANOLO: I have to
find La Muerte! Please.
Please, help me.
Mijo, stay here with us.
No more worries.
Epic fiestas every day.
BOTH: With the whole
Sanchez family.
And all-you-can-eat churros.
(LAUGHS) Thank you, guys.
But, no.
I need to be with Maria.
(ALL GASP)
It's all I ever wanted.
How's Manolo
gonna get back?
He's...
He's stuck there forever!
And Maria is gonna marry Joaquin!
(SCREAMS)
All right,
do you want me to continue?
So, one thing
was for sure...
Manolo needed help
from his family.
If La Muerte is where
Xibalba rotted away...
BOTH: Then she's in
the Land of the Forgotten.
No,no,no.
Quiet, you!
Manolo, there's only one way to
get to the Land of the Forgotten.
(SINGING)
Through the Cave of Souls
Going there
would be certain doom!
Well...
it's a good day for doom.
(ALL CHEERING)
He's a Sanchez,
I tell you!
A Sanchez!
(SINGING)
This is impossible!
Hey! Good luck,
little Sanchez!
BETH:
The legendary Cave of Souls...
was rumored to be at the edge
of the Land of the Remembered.
Now, many had tried to reach it,
but none had ever returned.
At least, not in one piece.
Caramba, it hurts
just looking at it.
Why couldn't this be
the Elevator of Souls?
My arthritis
is killing me!
Are we there yet?
(ALL GRUNTING)
We made it, mijo.
Come on! What are
you guys waiting for?
(SCREAMING)
You are not worthy!
Hey! My arthritis is gone!
Grandpa! (GASPS)
Mama!
Ow!
Manolo!
CAVE GUARDIAN:
Face the labyrinth...
and earn the right
to be judged.
(GASPS)
(PANTING)
I can't see him!
Lift me up!
I see him!
(SCREAMING)
Where did he go?
(GRUNTING)
Uh-oh.
What? What's happening?
It's okay, honey.
He's totally okay.
Run for your life!
(GASPS)
That was so beautiful.
(LUIS SOBBING)
You have earned...
the right to be judged.
But be warned.
No mortal has ever passed.
Ay ay ay!
For Maria.
Manolo!
Manolo Sanchez...
your heart is
pure and courageous.
You and yours may enter.
Ay, mijo.
Don't do that again!
This is the Cave of Souls?
Shh, Grandpa!
Show some respect.
CANDLE MAKER: That...
was...
awesome, man!
Look, the giant
boulders were like...
"boom, boom, boom!"
And then, you were, like...
(MAKING SWISHING NOISES)
And then, the Cave Guardian
came in, and he was like...
"I'm going to judge you
with this giant sword."
Um, excuse me? Sir!
And then, you...
you got through.
I have to find La Muerte.
La Muerte? (SIGHS)
Sorry, you missed her,
Manolo.
Wait! You know me?
Yeah, man.
We know everybody.
We know Luis,
Carmen, and puddle.
How are you doing, puddle?
Huh? Hello, puddle.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
It's all here
in the Book of Life.
Wait, where are my manners?
Come on in, y'all!
BETH: Manolo and his
family were the first
to ever see
the magic waterfalls...
that linked all the realms.
CANDLE MAKER: Welcome to the Cave of Souls!
Mi casa es su casa.
(BOTH GASPING)
Now, this is a cave!
You see all these candles?
Each one is a life.
And I'm your humble,
yet strikingly handsome...
Candle Maker!
I don't get it.
Wait! I didn't do the thing.
I got to do the thing.
Watch this.
LUIS: Wow!
Amazing, huh?
This is our work!
This is what we do!
Look! That group,
that's your town.
And there, that's Maria.
And next to her, Manolo.
One aflame with life,
the other...
kaput
You see...
as long as someone alive
remembers you...
you get to live in
the Land of the Remembered.
Santa Gordita!
What is it?
Chakal is on the march.
With him comes
the end of your town.
And there will be no one
left to remember you.
We would all
be forgotten.
Please, Candle Maker.
Come on, help me go back.
I can't do that, Manolo.
Hmm'?
Santa Chihuahua!
Okay, Okay-
Look, guys, the Book of Life
holds everyone's story.
But the pages
on Manolo's life...
they're blank!
(GASPS)
You didn't live the life
that was written for you.
You are writing
your own story!
(MIMICS EXPLOSION)
That's good?
So this means you'll
help me find La Muerte?
Well, I'm not
supposed to interfere,
but I may be able
to bend the rules.
Just a little.
After all,
it is the Day of the Dead.
Right, book?
(ALL GASPING)
Come on,
let's do this.
I'll take you to La Muerte.
I'm going alone.
Alone?
Hold on, now.
Fine.
I'm going alone, too...
Can I get a word in?
...right next to you.
Actually--
We should go.
"We"? No! It's much too
dangerous for a lady!
No retreat!
Hold on!
No surrender!
I tried to warn them.
(ALL SCREAMING)
I immediately
regret this decision!
(SCREAMING)
Are you sure we're
in the right place?
(CANDLE MAKER LAUGHS)
You Sanchezes
need to look
before you go jumping
into magic waterfalls.
What if you jump
into the wrong one?
You might end up in Tijuana.
I think I died there.
Welcome to
the Land of the Forgotten.
Sad,huh?
(GROANING) Ay ay ay-
You poor things.
And that's gonna happen
to us if we don't hurry.
Come on.
There it is,
Xibalba's castle.
La Muerte!
I need a word
with you, my lady!
(GASPS) Manolo?
But how did you get here?
I had some help.
(LAUGHING) Hey, there.
Candle Maker. Carmen!
And the head of Luis?
Ah. Great,
my arthritis is back.
I know about the wager.
Xibalba cheated.
He did what?
Yeah!
With a two-headed snake!
You might want
to cover your ears right now.
Xibalba!
Yes, my dear? (GASPS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Oh.
You misbegotten son
of a leprous donkey!
You cheated!
Again!
I did no such thing.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Oh, that.
It has a mind of its own.
Or two.
That is unforgivable!
Oh, please!
I never sent
that snake to Maria,
and I never gave
that medal to Joaquin! Oh.
What medal?
The,uh,one
I never gave him.
Ever. At all. Never.
Who is this Joaquin?
You gave Joaquin the Medal
of Everlasting Life?
Yes.
"Medal of Everlasting Life"?
Whoever wears the medal
cannot die or be injured.
(LAUGHS) Ah!
Please, can you help me up?
(GRUNTS)
Thank you.
Uh, can I get a slap, too?
My son did not
deserve this.
Come on,
I have to go back.
(SIGHS)
It's only fair.
(GRUNTS)
Please, Balby?
ALL: "Balby"?
No. Never.
You better do this!
No.
Hey, what about a wager?
BOTH: A wager?
If I win...
you give me my life back.
You have nothing I want.
But I do.
If you win, Xibalba,
you can rule both realms.
You name the task, anything you
want, and I will beat you.
Hmm.
What? Are you
afraid you might lose?
What you doing, kid?
Do we have a deal?
We have a deal.
Now, tell me, boy, what
keeps you up at night?
What eats at you
from the inside?
What, do tell,
is your worst fear?
Got it.
Manolo Sanchez!
You will have to
defeat every bull...
the Sanchez family
ever finished!
That would be thousands!
(ALL GASP)
All...
at...
once!
If you complete this task...
you will live again.
And if you fail,
you will be forgotten.
Forever.
This is impossible.
It can't be done!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GRUNTING)
You can do it!
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
Are you two
all right?
Chakal is coming! With a
whole army behind him!
You boys warn General Posada.
(BOYS PANTING)
I will buy you some time.
Who wants to go first?
(LAUGHING)
(BANDITS GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
I hate...
bullfighters.
Then come and get some.
(YELLING)
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Manolo!
Get out of there!
(GRUNTING)
What is happening?
Carlos!
Carmen!
Manolo!
Your father is here!
Papa?
Chakal and his men are at
the gates of San Angel!
(ROARING)
(ALL GASP)
Man, this is
a whole lot of bull.
(SNORTING)
Maria Posada...
do you take Joaquin
to be your husband?
Yes.
For San Angel, I do.
And Joaquin...
do you take Maria
to be your wife?
GIRLS: Uh-uh.
I...
(RUMBLING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Chakal is here!
My medal.
It's on my other suit.
I gotta go.
But Joaquin
is the only one
who can defeat Chakal.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
(SIGHS)
We can fight them
together, Papa.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(GRUNTING)
Get up and fight
like a Sanchez!
Mama? What are you
doing here?
Eh. Cholesterol.
(BANDITS GRUMBLING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
MARIA POSADA: Everyone!
Listen up!
(SCREAMS)
(LAUGHING)
I know you're scared,
but look around you.
Do you know what I see?
SOLDIERS: No.
I see proud people ready to
fight for their beloved town.
And I see that
inside each of you
is a strength that
cannot be measured.
(BABBLING)
Yes...
even in you, Pepe.
This Day of the Dead
will never be forgotten!
We will teach Chakal...
that he's messing with the wrong town.
(GROWLING)
San Angel...
I swear by those
before us,
we will not fall!
Not today.
(BANDITS GRUMBLING)
Medal!
Not ever!
Now, who's with me?
(ALL CHEERING)
You are like the son
l never had!
But much prettier!
(LAUGHING)
Hey,Chakal! Why don't you pick
on someone your own size?
BANDIT: Because no one's that big, man.
(BANDITS LAUGHING)
Where have you been?
Thank goodness
you're--
Hey! Soldier boy.
(SPITS)
You give me that medal.
Right now!
All this is about
a stupid medal?
Are you kidding me?
Not now, Maria.
It's Joaquin time.
Joaquin!
(GRUNTING)
(BANDITS SHOUTING)
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Hey, buddy,
let's talk about this.
(GROWLING)
(PUNCHES LANDING)
JOAQUIN:
(SCREAMING) Joaquin!
Joaquin?
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(GASPS)
(CATCHING BREATH)
The beast is out!
Time to finish this.
Yeah!
Finish him! Finish him!
(CHEERING)
(ALL GASP)
What is he doing?
(EXCLAIMS)
(ROARING)
(GROANS)
(SINGING) Toro, lam humbled
For tonight, I understand
Your royal blood was never
meant To decorate this sand
You've suffered
great injustice
So have thousands before you
I offer an apology
And one long overdue
I am sorry
Toro, I am sorry
Hear my song
And know I sing the truth
Although we were
bred to fight
I reach for kindness
in your heart tonight
And if you can forgive
Love can truly live
Love
Love will truly live
He did it!
Yes, he did.
(ALL CHEERING)
Yeah. I'll give him that.
But how did
Manolo do this?
He's a Sanchez.
BETH".
Xibalba had been wrong.
Manolo's fear was
never bullfighting.
I told you,
a Sanchez man
never apologizes.
Papa, I--
But you just changed that.
I should have been
a better father.
I am very sorry.
No.
You only wanted
what was best for me.
I'm so proud of you, son.
Hove you, Papa.
Ay, mijo.
BETH".
And at that moment,
Manolo conquered
his greatest fear...
being himself.
In accordance with
the ancient rules...
ALL: we give you life.
Be careful
up there, mijo.
JOAQUIN: Please, Chakal...
just don't hurt them.
Yes. Yes!
The medal is mine!
(RUMBLING)
Huh?
(YELLING)
(MARIA POSADA GASPS)
(MANOLO YELLING)
(GRUNTS)
What?
Huh?
(BLEATS)
Manolo?
(GRUNTS)
Hold this for me, amigo.
So, my father tells me
you hate bullfighters.
I hate everybody.
(BANDITS LAUGHING)
Yeah. Yeah, mang.
Okay. Let's do this.
(LAUGHING)
You and what army?
(BANDITS LAUGHING)
Huh?
(YELLING)
(BLOWS HORN)
(ALL CHEERING)
It's the Day of the Dead,
Manolo.
And on our day,
we have a certain
amount of...
Leeway.
Good luck!
Thank you!
(BANDITS GRUMBLING)
No retreat.
BOTH: No surrender!
He gonna do it now!
Familia Sanchez!
(ALL YELLING)
(SINGING CIELITO LINDO)
Huh?
We should get that guy for the band, eh?
(LAUGHING)
(SINGING) Now, is your turn!
Okay, I sing good, too.
(SINGING OUT OF TUNE)
ADELITA: I was like, "I think you look good.
I like your hair."
And he was like,
"I like your hair."
Are you wearing
my boots?
They look better on me.
Come here, lover boy!
(LAUGHING)
Huh?
(GRUNTING)
(GIGGLING)
Huh?
Medal!
(GRUNTS)
(SINGING) Thank you
(YELLING)
(GROWLING)
(GRUNTING)
Ah. (SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERING) Hold me!
Huh?
Chakal!
We found the medal!
(BLEATING)
MY COMRADES.
UNLEASH THE FURY!
?????
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
I'm done playing!
I got it. I got this.
No, no, no! I got this!
Yam!
Did I tell you I also
studied kung fu? Wow.
CHAKAL: Enough!
Look out!
MARIA POSADA: Ah!
Let go of me!
Get me my medal,
or your woman will pay!
Men. Typical!
(CHAKAL LAUGHING)
Go find the medal.
But Maria...
Find the medal.
I'll handle this.
Got it. Joaquin!
(BANDITS SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
I save you,
little Sanchez!
Good luck, Manolo!
Kick his butt, grandson.
(LUIS GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS)
Epa! Where do you
think you're going?
I have to get up there!
I was right!
You have become
the greatest Sanchez ever!
Hey!
Whoo!
(GRUNTS)
(GROWLING)
Ha!
Whoo!
Care to dance, senorita?
I thought you'd never ask.
(CHAKAL GROWLING)
(MARIA POSADA LAUGHING)
(YELLING)
MARIA POSADA: Whoo!
(GRUNTS AND YELLS)
(MARIA POSADA LAUGHS)
(LAUGHING)
Pretty good, guitarrista.
Now it's your turn!
(GRUNTS)
Watch out, sisters!
Save yourselves!
(MARIA POSADA SCREAMS)
Huh?
ALL: Hi, Maria!
Hi!
(CHAKAL YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
I'm taking this
whole town with me!
(ALL GASPING)
No more shadows, Dad.
No retreat?
No surrender.
(BOTH YELLING)
Manolo, the column!
I got it.
No. No!
Hey!
Don't stop fighting
for what's right.
Wait, what?
Manolo!
Adios, brother.
What is he doing?
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
Don't forget me.
No!
(EXPLOSION)
(JOAQUIN GROANS)
Chakal is defeated!
Retreat!
(GASPS)
(MARIA POSADA SOBBING)
(ALL GASPING)
Manolo?
(GASPS)
It's me, mi amor.
But how did you survive?
Don't look at me.
(GASPS) Joaquin.
You gave me the medal.
You were going to
sacrifice yourself...
for me.
I thought
it might be time...
to be a true hero.
Like you, Manolo.
Are you all right?
I have never seen
more clearly.
It's time to cast
our own shadows.
(MANOLO LAUGHS)
And write our own stories.
And so, Joaquin learned
that to be a true hero...
You have to be
selfless.
Uh-uh-uh.
There is one more
thing we need to do...
Son.
Do you take Manolo
as your husband?
I do.
By the power vested in us
by the Book of Life...
We now pronounce
you husband and wife.
You may kiss...
the groom?
(CHUY HOWLING)
She is gonna be
a great Sanchez.
And today was a good day...
of the dead.
Oh, yeah-yeah!
Ah, well... I believe you've
won the wager, mi amor.
Along with my heart,
all over again.
Ay, Balby
I'm so sorry,
my love.
You deserve better than me.
I know that now.
Will you ever
forgive me?
I do.
(FIREWORKS BURSTING)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Husband, how about a song?
(MANOLO LAUGHS) As you
wish, Mrs. Sanchez.
(MARIA POSADA LAUGHS) (SINGING)
I will stay by you...
even when we fall
I will be the rock that holds
you up and lifts you high...
so you stand tall
Oh.
And I won't let you fall
I won't let you...
No matter where you are
I'll be there
(ALL CHEERING)
So tear apart
these giant hearts
That beat inside us now
Let's give ourselves
our promises
Of our unending...
love
And I won't let you fall
I won't let you fall
I won't let you go
(GIGGLING)
No matter where you are
I'll be there
I will be there
Hey!
No matter where you are
I'll be there
I will be there
No matter where you are
I'll be there
BETH: And the world
keeps spinning...
and the tales keep turning...
and people come,
and people go...
but they are never forgotten.
And the one truth we know,
it held true one more time...
that love, true love...
the really, really
good kind of love...
never dies.
Caramba, it gets me
every time.
Okay, kids,
closing time.
ALL: Aww.
Your bus should be
outside waiting for you.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Adios, pretty lady!
Adios, Sasha!
La Muerte?
(LAUGHING)
La Muerte!
(WHIMPERS)
You never cease
to amaze me...
mi amor. Such passion.
Anyone can die.
These kids, they will
have the courage to live.
I'll wager you are
right, my love.
(LA MUERTE
AND XIBALBA LAUGHING)
Hey, write your own story.
And I won't let you fall
I won't let you go
No matter where you are
I'll be there
Oh, whoa
No matter where you are
I'll be there
If you listen
To the rhythm
Calling out in the dark
Can you hear it?
That's your spirit
Just follow your heart
So if you're feeling
like dancing frequently
Just tune in
the magic frequency
Don't worry about it
'cause we're gonna burn up
Live life like it's a song
So turn it on and sing along
It's all right
if it goes wrong
Just keep calm and carry on
On a single note
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Whoo!
Live life like it's a song
So turn it on and sing along
It's all right
if it goes wrong
Just keep calm and carry on
On a single note
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Live life
(SPANISH GUITAR PLAYING)
Toro, I am humbled
For tonight I understand
Your royal blood was never
meant to decorate the sand
You've suffered
great injustice
So have thousands before you
I offer an apology
And one long overdue
lam sorry (CHORUS
SINGING) Toro, I am sorry
Hear my song
And know I sing the truth
Although you were
bred to fight
I reach for kindness
in your heart tonight
And if you can forgive
Love can truly live
Toro, I am frightened
but I'll use my final breath
To tell you that I'm sorry
Let us end this
dance of death
Two centuries of agony
that to your heart we sent
Here and now with my amor
This senseless killing ends
lam sorry (CHORUS
SINGING) Toro, I'm sorry
Hear my song
And know I sing the truth
Although you were
bred to fight
I reach for kindness
in your heart tonight
And if you can forgive
Love can truly live
Love