Presented by IMPICTURES
Distributed by SHOWBOX MEDIAPLEX
Produced by SIDUS
Produce Investment by CHOI Wan
Lady!
Chief Investor by KIM Min Ki
OriginaI Author by GUI Yeo Ni
ScreenpIay by KIM Tae- gyun
Cinematography by JIN Young Hwan
Gaffer by PARK Kun Woo
Sound Mixer by LEE Sang Jun(WaveLab)
Editor by KO Im Pyo
Music by LEE Hun Seok, PAE Jung Eun
FractaI KIM Han Nyun
Art by KIM Hyun Ok
Fashion by KIM Kyung Mi
Make- up by KANG Kyung Hwa
Park Sun Sook(OZ Make- up)
Sound Supervisor by LEE Seng ChuI
(WaveLab)
VisuaI Effect Supervisor by
Chang Sung Ho(MoPac)
Stunt by LEE Eung Jun(Fighters)
SpeciaI Effect by KIM Pyung Ki
LEE Hyun Woo(Future Vision)
Assistant Director by KANG Kun Hyang
Chief Producer by CHOI Sun Mi
Producer by LEE Jung Hak
Co- Producer by LIM Chung LyuI
Producer by CHA Seung Jae
NO Chong Yun
Stop following me, will ya?
lf l had the crap beat out of me
l'd be hiding in shame
Screw it!
Why don't you stop running away, huh?
JO Han-sun
KANG Dong-won
LEE Chung-ah
Director by KIM Tae-gyun
Temptation Of The Wolves
- Hi, kid
- Who are you, lady?
- l'm not a la-dy... l'm... Um...
- Mom, the pot lady's back again
l don't sell pots...
Oh! Han-kyung, you're here
My, you've grown
Hello
So, did auntie's wedding go well?
l heard grandma came from Australia?
Yes...
mind your step-dad and don't fight
with your sister and brother
Okay
You don't mind sharing a room
with Da-reum, do you?
Dad, mom's a total city lady
She's like those sleek ladies on TV
Nah, don't worry
l'll be just fine...
Why?
Because Dae-han's in Seoul!
- Hello? Yes...
- Don't worry, dad
Phone for you!
Why, you're just the same...
You haven't changed a bit
Really? You've gotten so pretty
lt's so good to see you
How long has it been?
l transferred in junior high so...
4 years, it's been 4 years
l was so happy when l heard
you were transferring to Seoul
l really wanted to tell you something
What?
- l... have a boyfriend
- A boyfriend?
Yes
You remember him?
My Dae-han...
Congrats, congrats!
You guys look really good together
Good going, buddy!
l knew you'd be happy for us
Han-kyung, Let's never let
our friendship change
Of course! That's a no brainer!
Um, the bus is here
l gotta go, See you later
Honey, shall we go?
l like you too...
Yo, why you so cold to her?
- Look, it's him! lt's Hae-won Bahn!
- She looked fine to me...
- Then you take her
- Huh? Really? Yeah?
- He is so cool!
- Really?
This is why l hate taking the bus
Hey, hey Hae-won
no changing your mind later!
- Yeah, yeah
- Yes!
- Yahoo! Hyori...
- Move that away, it stinks
- Wait for me
- Dude, it stinks!
- You okay?
- Yes
- Are you really?
- l... l'm okay
You don't look okay...
l said l was okay!
l'm okay, Why do you keep... Keep...
- What's the name?
- Han-kyung Jung
No, not your name, the jerk...
Dae-han Kim...
Who are you saying got dumped!
Never mind then
And do you even know me?
Oh! My stop! Wait!
- Who said l was dumped...
- slippers!
You still have my shoe!
Sis, Sis, Sis
You've been crying?
You've been crying!
Just meet with him once
Forget it
He's a sure thing!
Girls are backed up
3 months to meet
with him, 3 months!
Then l'll meet him in 3 months
Are you still hung up
on that Dae-han or whatever?
You are! Stupid, stupid...
Do you have any pride?
That's right, l have no pride
- Da-reum, long time no see...
- Han-kyung Jung!
Han-kyung!
l hate boys now
More so if they're younger
Haven't we met before?
- What?
- Why? You know me, right?
No... Today's the first time
- Your hand...
- Ah! You go to Dong-won High, right?
- No
- Then... Sung-kwon High?
No
That's strange
Where have l seen you?
l moved here from Kong-joo
yesterday
What? Kong-joo?
Assholes, what a damn show!
They gotta come and
rumble every day?
Hey! There's Da-reum!
Why are you alone?
Have you guys seen 'Hottie?'
Hottie? Nah, it's just them
Sung-kwon High assholes...
... and Tae-sung Jung!
l know someone in Kong-joo too
Oh? Who? l know everyone there
Do you really?
- Then do you know Han...
- Han-kyung Jung!
Han-kyung Jung!
What are doing with this jerk?
Tae-sung Jung!
Your buddies have all run away
What are you still doing here?
Your name is...
Han-kyung Jung?
Yes...
Nuna, don't you remember?
lt's me, Tae-sung!
You really don't know me?
You don't remember?
- You really don't?
- Put on a show, why don't you?
You hitting on my sister right now?
Your sister?
Sorry to break this to you, bud
But she's gonna be my girl
Tae-sung! Run! Run!
Man, my head's spinning...
Ah, mm, mm
Hey
Hey, stop right there!
Nuna, you really run well
Hey!
- Sis!
- Hey Tae-sung Jung, Hey!
Nuna, my name is Tae-sung
You have to remember this time
Promise!
Sis, are you okay?
Crazy bastard, what the hell?
Nuna!
Tae-sung Jung?
Ooh, it's hot!
Nuna, how do you know
that jerk, Tae-sung?
- Huh?
- You know nothing
Here's some advice
Don't get too excited that
Tae-sung seems to like you
You'll get hurt in the end
l'm not excited
No...
Sure you are...
So you got dumped
You start hanging with that idiot
you crap on your whole life, got it?
l told you l wasn't dumped!
l told you l wasn't dumped...
Of course not!
Who got dumped?
- lt's just a new start! A new start!
- l'm telling you, she was dumped!
Yeah, drink up! Drink!
Let's drink and die!
l... told... you...
l, l...
l wasn't dumped...
And you...
YOU!
You're younger than me but
Dae-han
- Dae-han
- lt's Hae-won!
Dae-han
l'm Hae-won!
Man, you're heavy
Are kidding me, Da-reum?
l really... missed you
After you moved
every day, l went up to the roof
looked up at the stars and l'd wish...
... that we'd meet again...
You think wishing
on the roof actually works?
l'm really happy...
Happy to see you again...
Daddy died...
But l met mom again
So l'm really happy
Dae-han...
But why am l so sad?
l'm glad to see you happy...
Hey! What happened?
- Here... you keep it
- Where are we?
Look around! Figure it out!
lt's cold...
What is this smell?
lt's booze!
lt's only the smell of chung- guk stew!
Don't be a smartass!
Don't be a tattletale
little bro
- Does your school uniform fit?
- Yes
Don't stay out so late
Hae-won, get Hae-won...
Nuna!
Nuna, it's me, Tae-sung
You didn't forget me already, did you?
- Are you here to see someone?
- Yes. l'm here to see you
Me?
- lt's Tae-sung Jung of Sung- kwon High
- lt's really Tae-sung
Wow, he's so cool!
But why is he here?
And with the biggest loser in our class?
l know, right?
You, repeat what you just said
He's talking to me...
Huh? Me?
- Who are you calling a loser?
- Um, l...
Watch your mouth or else l'll... !
- l'll smash you up
- Please smash me up...
- Me, too!
Hey, Tae-sung
bring yourself out
- Come out, you jerk
- Nuna, enjoy the pizza...
Take a slice and you die!
Nuna, l'll see you next time
Tae-sung Jung, you dick!
l'm gonna kick your ass!
Hey, Hae-won
Hae-won Bahn! Try to keep
your eyes open in class! See you!
Why that! Does he know where this is?
How dare you come here! Hey!
Da-reum, the bastard's
completely flipped for your sis
Hae-won, the idiot's got
some weird taste, huh?
Hey, hey
Going somewhere?
- Yeah, home
- Whose? Tae-sung's?
No l don't even know where he lives
Nuna!
This is just great
Just transfer here
why don't you?
Hey, Tae-sung!
The dumbass is still here
l'll just go my way with nuna
so you guys go
your own way, okay?
You mean, Han-kyung?
She's coming over to my house
Hey! Why would l go there?
l'm not going...
See, she doesn't want to
And what, 'Han-kyung?'
- Show some respect, she's older!
- l told you
She's my girl
- Uh, uh, hey!
- Try and take her
Wait Stop! Time- out!
- What are you doing? Move
- No! Don't hit him
He knew this'd happen
when he came, Move
No!
lt's unfair, all of you against him
Don't hit Tae-sung!
Hey, Hae-won...
What was l thinking? Whew...
Thanks for taking my side, nuna
But am l really your senior?
Yes, You are
Okay, Then l'll act accordingly
- Okay, nuna
- Okay, Tae-sung...
But why did you wait for me?
- Because l like you
- Hmph, that's not even a funny joke
lt's true
You, you shouldn't make fun!
And, and, look at you
A student should dress like one
and study hard
Don't laugh
Nuna, buy me dinner
- Why should l?
- Cause you're older
- l don't have any money
- Even so
- l really don't
- Buy me dinner!
l better go home
Your hand...
is warm
Yes?
Joo-ho's asleep and...
Da-reum isn't yet...
Don't worry l'll make sure
the door is locked
Goodbye
Sorry, bud She's gonna
be my girl
Han-kyung? She's my girl
This is bugging me
The phone is turned off now
Connecting to voicemail
Tae-sung, it's Han-kyung
You're not picking up...
We're supposed to
meet at 7, right?
l'm here at the phone booth, waiting
Was it 9?
Han-kyung Jung
Don't smile at me
- Huh?
- Don't speak to me
don't stand in front of me
Then...
l should go...
What am l going to do?
l... l like you
must like you
Hey! Hey!
- Nuna
- Yeah?
- Get out
- Why?
- Hey! Hey!
Jae-hee!
Jae-hee...
Hae-won!
Han-kyung! What's going on!
Why don't you tell me?
Hey! Open this door! Get out of!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
HEY!!
lt takes exactly 5 minutes
to get to your home
So answer in that time
You wanna go out with me or not?
You don't answer in 5minutes
l'm going straight to the east coast
The east coast?
W, wait...
What's your relationship
with Jae-hee?
We went out
For a short time in junior high
- That's all Why? You jealous?
- Don't meet with her!
She has a boyfriend
And he's really cool actually
Should l make it the west coast?
4 minutes 18 seconds!
4minutes 15seconds
5, 4, 3, 2
You don't even have a license!
Drive carefully l'm going in...
Did you...
just say yes?
l said to drive carefully
Doesn't that mean yes?
Well, that's how l heard it
Miss my text messages
you're dead
Miss my calls
you're really dead
See you
mm, l...
Sis, congrats!
Be happy with Hae-won!
But why'd you play
so hard to get?
What?
Hae-won called me
said you two were going out
What? You think l'm crazy?
Go out with him?
No way
l see
Yeah... lt is a little crazy
to go out with Hae-won
Right? You think so too, right?
Sis, you gotta be careful
from now on
Why, would he hit me?
When people find out about you
all those girls around Hae-won...
Last year, a girl Hae-won liked got hit by
a rock and ended up in the hospital
Bam!
That probably hurt
Why are you all leaving me...
Mom... Dad...
Now even grandma
grandma
Why are you all leaving me alone...
The phone is off right now
after the connection...
Sis!
Sis, if Hae-won tries to kiss you
pretend to give in and...
His chin line is really awesome!
What am l thinking?
When l see him today l'll return
his phone and set him straight
Han-kyung! Are you sick?
- No
- What happened yesterday?
You're the first girl
who didn't answer my phone
l know nothing of forgive or mercy
so remember that
- Wait, l...
- Let's go eat!
- Hae-won...
- Watcha looking at!
Tae-sung...?
Follow me, follow me
Bastard! Come here!
Your turn
Tae-sung, you bastard
Bastard, got some respect
for us now?
Oh no, Hae-won...
Tae-sung... What do we do?
- Got money for a cab?
- what?
l'll block them
you take him and run
Hae-won...
- What's this?
- Hey, hey...
Now this isn't fair, to 4 to 1
- Here, take him...
- You wanna die?!
Hurry and take him, Han-kyung!
- Hae-won... what do l do?
- Nuna
Nuna... you came...
You're only in the way! Go!
Look at your face...
My God...
- Nuna
- Look at you!
- What do l do?
- Can you get me some water?
Yes, water
Big baby...
This is a nice house
You live alone?
Lucky...
l lived with my grandmother
But she died recently...
You didn't eat yet, right?
That's why you got so beat up
l'll make some porridge
Don't be surprised at how good it is
Tae-sung, Tae-sung
Are you asleep?
Tae-sung... l'm going now
l made some porridge
have some later
lf it's bright then dark
you can't see anything
But if it's dark from the start
you get used to it
and can see
l'm okay, dad
Hey! Stop pretending and get up!
You don't even come to school?
- Hi
- Hey...
Who beat you up, huh?
l can't believe it, really l can't
Sis! What were you doing
while he got beat up, huh?
Your sis ran away while l got beat
ln a cab, no less
Really?
Really, sis?
Stupid, you believe that?
What kind of wife would
leave her husband and run away?
Yeah, right
Your face is like a monster's
- Go and study or something
- Huh?
Right... l gotta go study
- Where are you going?
- Um, l'm a little busy
ls Tae-sung alright?
Um, yeah, he is now
Hae-won, you hate me, don't you?
Even if l did
what can l do?
l see you and all l can do is smile
Man, l'm an idiot
Sorry l'll be good to you from now
- How are you gonna be good to me?
- Well
call me when you
get beat up
l'll take the beating instead
Another way?
Still... this isn't right
Get it , Get the phone
- Hello?
- Nuna! Where are you?
- Come meet me
- l...
- really can't right now
- Then l'll go to you Are you home?
- l'm at a home but...
- Tell him to come!
- Hello
- Or are you gonna?
- You want me to tell him?
- Nuna, nuna
You're going out with Hae-won?
Why? Can't you believe it?
She says she likes you like a brother
What can l do? l hate you but
my girl thinks of you like a brother
You can't, nuna, This jerk's
relationships have always been messy
That's right
l've been pretty popular
Han-kyung, did you know this?
Seniors chased after Tae-sung
even in junior high
Oh, so you were popular then too...
That's right...
But the thing is they were boys
Calm down
Hearing you guys talk
you were friends back then, huh?
Never
Hae-won, l won't give you my nuna
You can beat me to death but l won't
give her to you. So don't even try
Your nuna?
Since when is Han-kyung your sister?
She's not your nuna
she's my girlfriend
Before she's your girlfriend
she's my nuna
You two related or something?
Tell me, are you?
Nuna, is it Hae-won or me?
- What?
- Han-kyung, is it him? Or me?
Um, well, that's...
Stop...
l got it so don't say anything
- But l...
- Don't say anything!
l know what
you're gonna say so don't
You afraid she's gonna say my name?
Nuna likes me a lot
She took care of me all night
and made me porridge
Have you had some?
Porridge?
Tae-sung, stop
Where are you going?
Seeing you two now
you fit with him more than me
Hae-won...
- Tae-sung...
- l'm sorry for going too far
Sorry...
Hae-won!
Hey!
Hae-won...
What are you doing here?
Why'd you come out?
To grab you
Where's your shoe?
huh?
l'll do it
Stay still
Thanks...
Tae-sung
Remember what grandma told you?
What?
Yes? l know
Don't call him daddy in front of her
Mister, call him mister, right?
But will she...
Will my sister like me?
Hi
[Can't get through to you, boo-hoo]
More than 3 questions of this subject will come out
in the next university entrance exam
[Send me a text so I won't worry...]
So if you listen to me carefully
you will at least get 3 points
Hey! Listen! Listen up!
Western religious beliefs brought
the end of traditional society and...
Han-kyung, what'd you do yesterday?
You meet with Hae-won? Or Tae-sung?
- Hae-won...
- Hae-won!
- And Tae-sung...
- Tae-sung! You're so lucky!
What, Tae-sung?
Sorry
- Hello?
- lt's me, Jae-hee
Uh, hi Jae-hee
lt's been a while
Yeah How are you?
So you gotta come today...
To what?
Didn't Hae-won say?
We're all meeting up today
Who are?
l thought as well, l'm glad l called
- Why didn't you tell me?
- lt's not for you to come
- What?
- You'll just end up crying again...
l didn't give you that phone for you
to take those calls, Give it back
No What are you doing with Jae-hee?
Oh, alright
Then l'm gonna meet with Tae-sung
You still talk with him! My phone!
So- so- sorry
Hae-won, let's dance
Are you waiting for Han-kyung?
He must really be dating the bumpkin!
Dae-han doesn't mind
you coming to these places?
l broke up with him ages ago
- l only have eyes for you, Hae-won
- Oh, is that so, nuna?
l told you not to call me that
Hae-won She's here! She's here!
Go and change!
lt took me 4 hours
Do l look that strange?
No, you're too pretty That's why
Well, l want to dress like this too!
Dress like this only for me
lt doesn't suit you!
Look
lt's for girls like that
What's with you?
She's looks great!
You really do, nuna!
Yeah, you do
Don't listen to Hae-won
Jae-hee, you win
What bar does she work at?
l said, shut up!
Han-kyung...
Go change, please
No!
Do l look that strange?
Hot...
Mister, what are you doing?
Dammit... not mister, honey!
H- honey... what are you doing?!
Stay still
What?
Hae- Hae- Hae- Hae- wo...
Do it? Here?
Sure, baby!
Mister, what are you saying?
Dammit, l'm in the middle of...
lt was dead wrong of me
Should l die right here?
lt's all over so let's go
What do you mean it's over...
So why go and dress like this?
So l'd look good next to Jae-hee
Hey! Watch closely...
Wow, Cool!
Was it that good?
Bet that's hubby now
must miss you already
Hae-won, did you get in okay?
- Hello?
- lt's... Tae-sung...
- Oh, Tae-sung...
- You met with Hae-won?
Do you like him that much?
And l'm suffering like this...
Nuna... You're bad
Tae-sung... Tae-sung...
l want to see you, nuna
l really wanted to see you
Tae-sung
Daddy...
No...
- l don't know him...
- Mom...
You're hiding something, aren't you?
Your father...
loved someone else
Nuna, it's Tae-sung
Don't you remember me?
My name is Tae-sung, Tae-sung Jung
You have to remember this time
Sis, get up and eat!
Get up and eat breakfast!
- Tae-sung!
- You surprised me!
You must've missed me
Tae-sung! What happened?
Where are you? Did you eat?
Nuna, breathe while you talk
l like that you worry about me
Sorry about last night...
tell you the truth
l was dumped by someone l love
That's why l had a little tantrum
- You're not mad, are you?
- Yesterday... l went to your house...
Tae-sung's motorcyle accident
Tae-sung, What do l do
Tae-sung
Wake up, Tae-sung
l'm a dumb sister
l didn't recognize my own brother
A stupid sister who didn't
even know her own brother
Tae-sung, what do l do?
l'm so sorry... Tae-sung
Get up, Tae-sung Get up...
Tae-sung, your phone's ringing...
- Get up, Tae-sung Get up...
- Nuna
Why didn't you tell me?
You should've told me we're family
You looked so...
so happy
Dummy! lf l knew you were my brother
l'd be even happier!
Nuna... That hurts!
Now that l know...
Now that l finally know
l'll take care of you
- l don't care
- Da-reum
Tae-sung's also your brother
what, brother
You wish... ls there anyone in your family
who's had cardiac disorder?
My mother and grandmother...
ls it really bad?
lt's aorta valvular disease
lt's not that good
Still, how can you get malnutrition?
- By not eating, that's how...
- Hurry up!
You go first!
- Hae-won!
- l thought you were only good at hitting on girls
But you'd be good at kidnapping too
You coming to a hospital
empty-handed?
Don't pick a fight with me
l'm not here cause l wanna be
Your sister whined until l came
How long is it gonna last this time?
The longest you went out with a girl
was what? 2 weeks?
3weeks
Don't be like this
Shake hands now
Then l'm going Joo-ho, let's go
Okay, we'll shake
You've now made up
See how nice this is?
Nuna!
Watcha looking at, huh?
Look away!
Kid, what are you doing here?
Right, Joo-ho's tooth...
- Let's go, let's go
- l don't wanna
- lt'll be okay
- l don't want to
Grandma!
Dad...
lt's me
Daddy...
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
No, l won't go
Don't be stubborn
Come with me to Australia
Yes There's no one left here for you
Go with grandma to...
l'm not going anywhere
l'm staying here with nuna
- Right, nuna?
- Huh? Yeah...
Nuna! Open wide!
Hey! Just do the dishes
Han-kyung!
Let's go
l gotta at least finish
Hey! You still here?
l'll hurry Okay?
- Let's do the dishes, okay? Stop
- Okay Okay
Hello
Wait, dishes
- dishes
- One sec...
Hey, Han-kyung
l'll be outside so hurry up
- Okay
- Yo! See ya
Nuna and l are gonna play some more
Hey
l told you to do the dishes, dishes
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, watch your back
Man, damn thugs...
Why'd you piss the pervert off
in the bathroom?
He was being the pervert!
Dammit!
Something wrong? Don't worry
lt'll be okay
Hae-won, chin up!
You have me...
What do we do about your brother?
- That was Tae-sung?
- Yeah
Oh no...
What's the problem?
You're not his girlfriend
Let's go
Hi...
- Are you Han-kyung?
- Yes, and you are...
Oh, l just...
l want to be friends with you
- With me?
- Yes, Here!
- What's this?
- Well...
l made this chocolate to give to you
- l'm Bo-jung Lee, Happy to meet you
- l'm Han-kyung Jung
Han-kyung!
Keep clear of this bitch!
l don't know what she's up to
- but she has a dirty reputation
- Hey, why are you...
Looks a bit naive like someone
so she's probably nice
Right! She's probably nice
Dammit! She and l went to the
same junior high Hey, Bo-jung! You...
S- sorry, Han-kyung
l shouldn't have come...
She's trouble, l tell you
Hey, Tae-sung!
You don't even answer your phone...
Oh! A kitten...
Where'd you get it?
You hungry?
Want some milk?
Why are you staring at me like that?
You'll bore a hole in my face
Am l... like a brother to you?
Of course, my adorable brother
You really think of me as your brother?
You're taking a stand cause
l didn't make you dinner, right?
Well, l'm making it now
so wait just a little
- When l'm suffer
- Why did you come by yourself
do you suffer too?
Sure, Here, kitty Let's eat
When l'm smiling with another girl
do you get so mad
you can't...
- do anything?
- Um, yeah...
- Then do you...
- Look at all the shit
- Were you cold?
- that l'm your real brother?
hate to death...
right?
- Tae-sung...
- l...
l really hate that you're my sister!
l hate that l call you 'nuna' and
that you're standing in front of me!
Every day...
l curse heaven thousands of times
for letting us meet like this!
What's wrong, Tae-sung?
Because l love you
Because l love...
Han-kyung Jung
Hey!
Where'd you go?
You left school early
You were with Tae-sung, right?
Why don't you answer the phone
when you're with him?
- Give it a rest
- Give it a rest?
l haven't even started!
Are you mad cause l was with Tae-sung?
He's my brother!
You're mad cause
l spend time with my brother?
What are you thinking?
l just... you didn't answer your phone
D- don't cry
l'm, l'm sorry
lt's time Tae-sung got a beating
- Hae-won, that's not it...
- Right
making his own sister cry...
Dammit!
- don't cry and let's go
- Why are you doing this, Let me go
Hey! You Sung- kwon High jerks
make all the girls l know cry for fun?
- Sorry Sorry
- Gotta death wish or something?
- Hey, 'Silly'...
- Hae-won!
Yo, you're getting my uniform wet!
lt's okay now so go on
By myself? l'm scared
Hae-won, can't you take me home?
Yeah! Grab her a cab at least
What a pain...
Get us a pizza
- Thanks, Han-kyung
- Be careful
What's up with Silly back there?
Why?
See this?
She kept holding me and crying
That's cause you let her
Han-kyung, are you jealous right now?
- No, l'm not
- Nah, you are, You're jealous
- l am not!
- Why wouldn't you be mad?
Let's eat!
Han-kyung You got a text message
[Tae-sung! Hae-won's wavering]
- Who is it?
[- l did good, right?]
A classmate
You're acting strange
Nothing
Who's this?
Hey, Tae-sung!
You gotta freakin' get in the way
every time we date?
Why you...
Wait a minute...
You're here!
Hmm? You've lost weight
Right? You have!
Wow, You're even prettier now
- Tae-sung...
- lt's cause of...
the stupid things
l said last time, right?
lt was a joke, a joke
Lighten up, A brother's joke
Jerk, calling us here and there
You guys here for the picture too?
lt's so nice to see!
No, he's my sister's boyfriend...
Quiet, you little pup
The girl in the back
get a little closer
Nice! Kimchi!
Kimchi!
I feIt it from the start
I feII for you right then
I feII in Iove with you
Every time I saw you
it was hard to hide my heart
I wanted so to express it
It that too much to ask?
My Iove for you
is it so hard for you?
I am aIways
wanting to be with you
Can't our Iove be?
It wiII be hard
but I wiII hoId back for you
I wiII aIways Iove onIy you
I wiII aIways Iove onIy you...
Nuna! My singing rocks, right?
That jerk...
- Hae-won
- We had dinner, isn't that enough?
Hey!
Huh? Tae-sung...
What are you doing right now?
This is Han-kyung's friend
That's right l'm her friend
Don't get the wrong idea
You're her friend?
Then why is she
looking at you like that?
- You wanna move that hand?
- What's it to you?
- What?
- What's it to you!
l got my hand on my sister's shoulder
What of it?
What does this look to you?
- Move your hand! You bastard!
- l can't give you my sister!
No, l won't!
lt's better l take her
What? Say that again
Nuna... Let's go
No!
Tae-sung, this isn't part of the plan!
- Who are you? Do you know me?
- Huh? Right...
No, l don't know you
S-sorry
Bastards, mind your own business!
You guys have the wrong idea
Sorry, Han-kyung
l just...ran into him
l'm going
Han-kyung, even you don't believe me?
Let's talk tomorrow
Hey, l'm not finished talking!
Han-kyung!
This... Didn't you send this by mistake?
Forgive me, Han-kyung! Sorry!
Tae-sung asked me to break you two up
l never thought it'd get so big...
Don't lie! Tae-sung wouldn't
Who are you?
Tae-sung, he's your brother, right?
He asked me to do it
Tae-sung and l are old friends
Boy, he could sure act yesterday
Why the hell are you doing this to me?
Why? You'd have to ask him
To love your own sister
What kind of cruel joke is that?
Don't you feel sorry for him?
lt's all lies, isn't it?
You! Why... Why...
Han-kyung!
What are you doing?
l said, what are you doing!
- Hae-won, look at this
- Bo-jung, are you okay?
- Bo-jung Lee!
- Enough! Didn't you see
her fall and hit her head!
Yo-won, take her to the infirmary
Tae-sung, that bastard
l knew this would happen!
She's acting right now!
Why don't you believe me?
Believe you? Believe you
after you left yesterday like that?
Bo-jung's tricking you right now!
Whatever kind of girl she is
whatever her game is with me
l don't care about people
l have no interest in
What makes me mad is you!
Han-kyung, you!
Are you still suspicious
of me and Tae-sung?
You still don't know
who l really like?
Me?! To be honest, it's hard for me
to watch you two
ls that how little you trust me?
You really can't trust me?
Go be with the person you really like!
lt'd be easier for both you and me
Alright
l'm also really tired of you
thinking of Tae-sung and me that way
Go to Bo-jung who likes you...
Bo-jung Lee!
You dare make my sister cry!
Are you really okay?
Should we go to the hospital?
Tae-sung...
You really don't know a Bo-jung Lee?
don't know?
No... Why?
Tae-sung, it's Bo-jung!
Who are you?
Tae-sung, it's me, Bo-jung
Han-kyung and Hae-won finally broke up
l did good so buy me a dinner
like you promised, See you later!
What the hell are you talking about?
Hey, hey
[l got beat up cause of you
so you owe me lots of drinks! Bo-jung]
You
Are you really the Tae-sung l know?
How can you do this to me?
What's this about you and Hae-won
breaking up? And this text...?
Even if you liked me
more than a sister...
This is wrong
l don't know what's going on!
l'm going now
Nuna!
Nuna! Nuna!
You think l broke you two up?
l trusted you l really did
lt wasn't me! You're wrong!
Why don't you believe me?
Let's talk later
Guess you are young
Soaking in the rain
Hey! Where's this Hae-won jerk?
- Go ask someone else
- Come here...
These youngsters, they never learn
Man, you got a temper...
Cheer up
Wanna hear some good news?
Tae-sung, he got totally beat up
and they're dragging him away
Those thugs beat him like a wet dog
Hey
Yo, Hae-won, welcome!
We were waiting for you
Chicken shit...
Watcha doing beating on a kid?
Hey
How'd you get here?
Heard you got the crap
beat outta ya, stupid!
You guys here to fight?
Or chat?
That bastard's mine
Tae-sung!
You okay, Tae-sung?
Tae-sung, you alright?
You okay?
Bo-jung Lee...
Who the hell is she?
That's cool
When are you coming back?
Well...
Maybe l won't?
Please don't!
Exactly what l was hoping
Hae-won, l have a favor to ask
What?
While l'm gone...
Take good care of my sister
You don't need to ask, idiot...
Go running to her when she calls,
buy her lots of food
and call her often...
and call her nuna!
Well, that might be a problem
And also...
Man, we'll see each other again
Why are you asking all at once?
And also what?
And...
Han-kyung Jung!
Ooh, that must hurt
l told you to stay away from Hae-won
She can't trust her boyfriend
she can't trust her brother...
How can a guy love his sister?
Right? That's really whacked...
- l can't forgive you, l can't
- So you won't forgive, so what!
- Ooh! Bo-jung's really mad
- Why do you think l'm here?
- See this?
- Hey! You bitches!
Damnit
You bitch! You wanna die, huh!
l just did what Jae-hee told me to!
Ha! You said it'd be fun!
Just kill him
Hey, you told me to
You all same kinds
Hae-won, leave them to me
You two are dead!
Tae-sung asked me not to tell you
but you'd probably hate me forever
when you found out
You can't go like this, Tae-sung
Nuna
l didn't think l could
get on that plane if l saw you
Nuna... ln our next life
don't be my sister
You can be really, really ugly
just please don't be my sister
Tae-sung
l had it all wrong, l was bad
Come back, Tae-sung
Tae-sung...
Nuna, are you well?
Miss your cool bro?
Oh, well l don't miss you much...
This is Monster Monster, say hi
Hi
Dummy This way, this way
Hello Nice to meet you
enough
Good Remember l told you?
Lives next door, bugs me a lot
She can't see so you understand...
l wonder if Hae-won's
treating you right
He's so pigheaded
and his relationships are a mess...
Hi
Hey, say hi to my sister!
Nuna, l'm a little busy See you!
Hi, Nuna, Are you well?
Oh, cool bro
Aren't you tired of that yet?
lf you have time to watch that
study up Like me
He hadn't written in so long
He looks okay, right?
You've watched like 30times can't you tell?
No wonder you're retaking the entrance exam
What!
Hello?
Hey! Tae-sung
- What? lt's Tae-sung?
- Wait, wait!
How are you? ls something wrong?
Sorry, l've been busy
l can't help being so popular
So did you graduate high school?
l was really worried for you
Of course
School going well for you?
l'm so tired of going to school
The girls here got such high standards
they can't get enough of me
Nuna... Hae-won treating you well?
Uh- huh He calls every night
and sings me to sleep
ya ya ya
- Hae-won Bahn sings?
- l did not
Tae-sung! Your sis has gotta make
dinner for her hubby so bye now
Tae-sung, don't hang up!
lf anything happens to sis
l'll fly over and
kick your ass, huh?
Ooh, scary l just hit her, fly over!
Stop fooling around
Tae-sung, l'm fine so don't worry
Are you coming back to visit soon?
huh? Mm
No... l'm going on a trip soon
A trip? Where?
Here in Australia, There are
so many places l wanna see
l've run out of change Bye, nuna
Already?
Take care of yourself
And call more often! Okay?
Hey! Are the girls pretty over there?
What! You have a girlfriend!
Hello?
Han-kyung Jung! Han-kyung Jung!
Han-kyung Jung!
Why am l here?
Tae-sung Jung, you idiot!
What are you doing here?
Tae-sung?
Where did you go?
Why are you here again?
Where's grandma?
She went looking for you again...
Are you okay?
Your surgery's coming up soon
You should stay put
l told you, right?
My sister, who l love so much
Look, look, she's pretty, right?
l can't see
Neither can l
You can see
No...
l can't see her
What are you going to make?
What did she just say?
Don't lie! What kind of trick is this?
Then what about these postcards?
l... sent them all
He said she can't know...
This can't be
Tae-sung's on a trip right now...
Grandma... lf
lf l... don't get up...
lf l don't wake up, don't tell sis
Keep it a secret till she dies
Whether she be in her 30s or 40s
let her think
l'm living happily in Australia...
He just wanted to see you from a far
To see if you were smiling or crying...
With these two eyes he gave me
he wanted to see you just once...
just once
Nuna...
My trip... might turn into a long one...
No! Tae-sung...
Tae-sung...
Tae-sung, you can't go like this...
Tae-sung, can you see?
lt's the ocean you wanted
to go to with your sister
Tae-sung... l'm so sorry
l didn't know this time either...
l didn't know again...
Sorry, Tae-sung...
Nuna, it's Tae-sung...
Duh, of course she knows it's you...
The days... l spent with you
were the happiest of my whole life
When l was young
l hated dad most of all
But now, l'm so thankful
to dad in heaven
l'm thankful he
left me
l really want to see you today
When l see you
the first thing l'm gonna do...
Huh? lt's off...
Man, nothing l do is right...