Anne.
Mary.
Wait.
Wait for me.
I received a request
for marriage today...
... for Anne from the Carey family.
William, their eldest son.
Oh, that's wonderful.
I turned it down.
Offered them Mary instead.
Mary.
Everyone improves the standing
of their family with their daughters.
I think Anne can do a lot better
than a merchant's son.
And Mary can't?
- I think you underestimate her.
- No, no, that's not true.
I think she's the kinder of the two,
quite possibly the fairer.
To get ahead in this world,
you need more than fair looks...
...and a kind heart.
I'll beat you, I'll beat you.
Hey.
Well done, Anne.
Well done, children.
You look... You look adequate.
Not too adequate, I hope.
This is our sister's day.
One wouldn't want to outshine her.
Mary, may we come in?
Look at you.
Younger than me.
More beautiful than me.
Married before me. I'm eclipsed.
I'm the other Boleyn girl.
Hardly.
So is this it, Mrs. Carey?
Do we...?
Do we lose you now, forever?
No, never. I'll be married, that's all.
Apart from that,
it won't change a thing.
Come, George, let's leave our sister.
She needs to make herself pretty.
Was it a boy?
Stillborn, Your Majesty.
No brother for you
to make this country safe.
I'm sorry.
Tell His Majesty.
Your Majesty.
I'm so sorry.
Are you happy?
I am.
You don't wish you'd married
someone grander? With a title?
I want a husband who loves me.
Who thinks it first thing every morning
and last thing at night.
Then you have found the right man.
He continues to stare.
- Who?
- Henry Percy.
Well, why ever
would he interest you?
What could you want
with the sole heir...
...to the richest landowner
in England?
Oh, I had no knowledge of that.
I simply like his face.
Oh, really?
- Well, he's betrothed.
- Betrothed is not married.
It's a long journey
from bended knee to the altar.
- Sister.
- Hello, brother.
Thomas.
- A proud day for you.
- Yes.
How is His Majesty?
These are difficult times, Thomas.
The king and queen,
once happily married...
...now barely speak.
The failure to provide a male heir
has consumed them.
The queen has lost yet another child,
a boy.
I imagine it won't be long before
he seeks solace with a mistress.
I've given it some thought
and wondered...
...which Howard girl
I can place under his nose.
You imagine the riches and influence
that would give us?
If we could help the king
with this delicate matter?
What about Anne?
I realize, as a Boleyn,
she's not officially a Howard...
...but as your sister's daughter.
But, Thomas, she's your first born,
and your favorite.
Wouldn't you prefer her to have
a simple, uncomplicated marriage?
Like Mary?
If Anne were a simple,
uncomplicated girl like Mary...
...l'd say yes. But she's not.
She's anything but.
Are you afraid?
A little.
I should be able to tell you
how it will be tonight.
Give you advice on what to do.
I've failed you as an elder sister.
No one could wish
for a better sister.
And tell me everything
in the morning.
- I promise.
- No details spared.
Lie back.
- Anne.
- Father.
Uncle.
You asked to see me.
An opportunity has arisen.
An opportunity in which,
were you to succeed...
...you could secure for yourself
and for this family...
...incalculable wealth and position.
There is a strain
on the king's marriage.
In such circumstances, a man
sometimes seeks comfort elsewhere.
Because of your uncle's friendship
with His Majesty...
...we're alone in knowing this.
It won't be long...
...before the other families
discover the truth...
...and parade their daughters
under his nose.
Before watching somebody else profit,
we would sooner have...
What?
- Have me bed him instead?
- No, that... That's not...
Yes.
Exactly.
The favor he would bestow upon us...
I mean upon you, if he liked you.
To be mistress of the king of England
is by no means to diminish yourself.
And after he's finished with me?
My reputation and prospects
will be ruined.
On the contrary.
Under such circumstances,
when the time came...
...to find you a husband, it would
be a marquis or a duke at least.
Will you accept the challenge?
Don't resist this.
The king and his retinue
will spend two nights here next month.
Your brother has arranged it.
It's done.
Well, I don't like it.
It'll cost a fortune to get this house...
...ready for a royal visit.
It's money we can't afford.
And what if he doesn't like her?
And what if you were to look
on the bright side, just once?
Risk nothing, you gain nothing.
Anne understands that.
Anne understands nothing.
She's just a child.
Tell me, when was it that people
stopped thinking of ambition as a sin...
...and started thinking of it
as a virtue?
That's easy for you to say.
You've had position
and wealth all your life.
Until I married you, Thomas.
And I was happy to give it up for love.
So how was it, the wedding night?
It was very satisfactory.
Really? William Carey,
a good lover.
Yes.
Oh, God. He was in rather a hurry.
- And he snores.
- No.
He got up in the middle of the night
and used a pisspot...
...by the side of the bed.
It was awful.
No.
I also have something to tell you.
Last night,
our father put his trust in me...
...and gave me a commission.
Tell, tell.
To divert the king.
The king of England himself,
on his visit.
Divert him?
Divert him. Beguile him.
Enchant him.
He has a wife.
I know.
But who knows what could happen?
If he liked me,
I'd be married off to a duke.
I could be a happy duchess.
The king.
The king will be here betimes.
- The king.
- Look alive.
The king.
To your places.
Come on, set to, everyone.
The king.
Take the horses to the yard
and prepare.
Where's the spit boy?
Where is he?
Get over here.
Do you think he'll like me?
Course he will, sister.
How could he not?
Sir Thomas.
Your Majesty.
You're most welcome.
Lady Elizabeth.
May I present my daughter, Anne.
A daughter?
No one said anything of a daughter.
Had we known,
we might have come sooner.
Your Majesty.
Anne, Anne.
Go to bed, get a good night's rest.
Tomorrow there's the hunt.
You must excel at that.
Everything depends upon it.
Good morning, Anne.
Good morning, Your Grace.
- Who will you ride with?
- On my own, Your Grace.
On your own?
There's a new saddle now
which allows this.
But with no man to hold on to...
...how do you propose
to stay on the horse?
As you do, Your Grace.
With my thighs.
Away.
What's keeping them?
Where are they?
Is someone hurt?
My God, it's the king.
The king? What? What happened?
The stag went into the woods
and led us to the deep ravine.
Everyone was prepared to concede
defeat and let the animal go.
Except Anne.
Oh, no. What?
She knows that ravine.
She must have ridden it
a thousand times.
What, and the king followed,
and then he fell?
Oh, Lord.
- What happened?
- He fell.
He's in some pain.
Although I suspect
his pride is hurting rather more.
It was my fault.
- Anne.
- How could I?
Fetch Mary to me, would you?
And who are you?
Mary, Your Grace.
Anne's sister.
You've been here all the time?
How could I have overlooked you?
Next to Anne, it's easy to do.
And you're married.
Yes, Your Grace, to William Carey.
Then why haven't I seen you at court?
Because I've persuaded him
to spend a year or two here first.
We have a small manor.
Nothing much,
but enough to start a family.
Charmed life in the country,
away from it all.
Yes.
You don't think he'll miss court?
A young ambitious man.
He says not, Your Majesty.
But if he ever changed his mind...
...as his wife, of course,
I would do his bidding.
Lady Elizabeth, thank you.
Sir Thomas.
You will take care of that matter?
Yes, of course.
Of course, Your Majesty, thank you.
Mary, you've obviously made
a deep impression on the king.
He's requested that you come to court
with immediate effect.
The king has secured for you,
a position in the queen's household.
But I don't want to go to court.
Nor does my husband.
The king has also
offered me a position...
...as a gentleman
of the Privy Council.
Do you hear that, Mary?
Privy Council.
Attending upon His Majesty himself.
The inner sanctum.
What about our future
in the country?
Oh, you must put that
out of your mind.
From now on, your future is at court.
William, please.
Don't you understand
what this means? They'll separate us.
Put me in different accommodation,
where the king can always find me.
Happily, your husband understands
the value of such an opportunity.
For us all.
What about Anne?
Couldn't she go instead?
Anne?
The way Anne has behaved,
she's fortunate to be coming at all.
Mother, please, speak to Father.
Do something. I don't want to go.
This is not a request.
We have been summoned.
Please don't be angry with me.
You think I desire to go
for this purpose?
All I know is that a man
that didn't know who you were...
...was with you in that room
for half an hour...
...and came out besotted.
I don't know what you said or did.
Nothing, sister.
Except sing your praises
and talk about my husband.
Really? Well, you must show me
how you did that some time.
- Mary Carey, Your Majesty.
- Who?
Your new lady-in-waiting
and her sister Anne.
Really?
I wasn't aware I was expecting one.
Appointed by His Majesty the king.
By my husband? Really?
Well...
...then she must be some kind of
gift or surprise.
He must have seen in her some talent
he knew would please me.
Tell me.
What special talent is it
that you have...
...apart from your
obvious youth and beauty?
I...
- Poetry, perhaps?
- No.
- Or dressmaking?
- Singing then, surely?
- No, Your Majesty.
Come, you're too modest.
Sing for us.
- Really, I beg you.
- Sing.
Bravo.
A nightingale.
Welcome at court.
Mary? Stop.
That can't have been easy for you.
But put yourself in the queen's shoes.
She knows the only reason...
...the king has asked you here
is because he desires you.
She's a good woman, trust me.
Jane Parker.
It's embarrassing.
Look, she has her eye on you.
Sweet Jane Parker would be a match
to please our father.
Oh, vile girl.
She's the most ambitious little serpent
at court.
She can't stop watching.
How are you, Stafford?
I'm well, thank you.
I'm not sure I'm one for court life.
I'm a little homesick.
Well, you and I both.
Now, in my view it...
It changes people.
And not necessarily for the better.
Your sister, though, is thriving.
She's truly caught the eye
of Henry Percy.
Why does she do this?
He's already taken.
Tonight.
My little sister.
My little golden sister.
My milk-and-honey sister.
It should be you in my place.
Don't concern yourself with me.
I'll make my own way.
Shall I walk with you?
No need.
Try to please him. If you can.
Your Grace.
Come in.
Can I bring you something?
No.
Anything to ease your comfort
or well-being?
Perhaps you might ask your servants
to bring me some water.
Please.
There. There are no servants.
So this is it?
Where the king of England sleeps.
And reads and writes.
Finds a few moments each day
for himself.
And yet you invite me here?
Because I like you and trust you.
You hardly know me.
I'm lied to a hundred times a day.
Petitioned, lobbied.
One learns how to decipher a face.
And yours is as the sun.
One shouldn't gaze too long.
My flattery,
it makes you uncomfortable.
Because compliments in your family
are usually for someone else.
The elder sister.
That's something I understand.
What it is to be the second child.
Forever in the shadows.
I'm making you uncomfortable
again.
- Morning.
- Stafford.
Morning.
I have orders
to bring you to your father.
Better not keep him waiting.
Well?
Did he have you?
Yes.
More than once?
You better get used
to talking about it.
When you sleep with the king,
it ceases to be a private matter.
Yes, more than once.
And was he satisfied?
- I believe so.
- Did he say so?
He did not need to, uncle.
Well, you may go.
Good.
Now our work begins.
It's one thing to catch a king,
quite another to keep him.
She must be well-read,
know her music, excel in company...
...and she must be clean.
- Anne will see to it.
- See to what?
Mary is already all of these things.
Thanks to the education
I have given her.
And for what?
That she may be traded like cattle...
...for the advancement
and amusement of men?
Sister, you may leave us also.
Katherine of Aragon
will never give Henry Tudor a son.
But if Mary could give him a child,
and that child could be a boy...
If I gave your husband an assignment
that took him away from court...
...would you object?
I would not presume
to interfere in affairs of state.
- Amen.
"My heart and I surrender themselves
into your hands."
It's Anne.
She's married Henry Percy.
Wedded and bedded
without telling anyone.
You... You don't look pleased.
Why would I be pleased?
Well, it will make her the future
Duchess of Northumberland.
- Our sister.
- George, they'll never allow it.
He's already precontracted
to Mary Talbot.
If this gets out, it will damage her.
Her reputation will be ruined.
I have to tell Father.
For her own protection.
What were you thinking?
The marriage of a senior noble
is a matter of the state.
Something only the king can decide.
Who else knows about this?
- No one.
- Good.
Well, that's how it will remain.
Forever.
But you cannot undo
what has been done before God.
And consummated too.
There have been
improper intimacies?
I have lain with my husband.
- There's nothing improper about it.
- By God, if you were my daughter.
The boy will return
to Northumberland...
...where he will marry the Talbot girl,
as arranged.
You will be sent to France
and stay there...
...until you have learned your lesson.
- What?
No.
Father, please.
How can you have done this?
You knew full well...
...Mary's friendship with the king
is at an extremely delicate stage.
Any scandal, any mark upon her name
could be fatal.
You will join the court
of the French queen...
...and stay there
until your father has forgiven you.
You told them, didn't you?
It was for your own good.
You never would have got away with it.
It would have ruined your
prospects forever.
For my good?
Well, I'll try to remind myself of that
while I'm in exile.
And you're here in the king's bed...
...not challenged
for our father's affection...
...that is was for my good
and not yours.
Anne.
You would be wise
to regard this as an opportunity.
You are educated.
It's a chance I never had.
Now go to France.
The queen of France is sophisticated.
Be useful to her, amuse her.
She'll admire your spirit.
Learn from her.
Observe the ladies of the court.
See how they achieve...
...what they want from their men,
not by stamping their little feet...
...but by allowing the men to believe
that they, indeed, are in charge.
That is the art of being a woman.
Still shut, keep them shut.
Careful, careful.
All right, now open.
I am to become an earl,
your brother a viscount.
In addition, we have received
a number of new grants and estates.
So our debts are paid, and more.
George, the king will arrange a match
between you and Jane Parker.
I beg you, Father, no.
I thought you had ambitions
for this family?
The girl's well connected.
Her father is cousin to the king.
Must I actually marry her?
Of course you must marry her.
Have you no pride?
Or would you rather
leave everything to Mary?
No, sir.
It'll be a wedding
attended by the king of England...
...with all the greatest
lords of the land.
Would a smile be too much to ask?
What's there to smile about?
I'm a mother with one child
ordered to marry a girl he hates...
...another banished abroad
in disgrace...
...and a third,
whoring in public with an adulterer.
You say you're concerned
for her happiness.
Will Mary be happy
when he leaves her?
Because you know
that will happen in the end.
Only God knows
how anything will end.
God? He turned his back
on all this a long time ago.
And these rooms, our new position?
Does none of my work please you?
These gifts, this favor
will go as swiftly as it came.
These rooms once belonged
to the duke of Buckingham...
...the king's closest friend.
His head now rots on a spike.
He committed treason.
Treason? What is treason?
Anything the king or his lawyers
decide it to be.
On a whim.
The baby lives.
She's not miscarried.
But for the sake of the child...
...she must begin her lying-in,
immediately.
Now that Mary is lying-in,
the king will no longer bed her.
Out of compassion, he'll visit her
every day for, what, a week?
The queen
will have his head spinning...
...with pretty little Spanish things.
Not to mention the Seymours
and that milky-faced girl of theirs.
We must influence him in our favor
with whatever means we have.
Yes?
Well, l...
- I was going to suggest Anne.
- You couldn't control that girl last time.
What makes you think
a couple months...
...in France
have made any difference?
I receive regular reports
from the dowager queen.
It seems that she's quite changed.
And so you must return
as your uncle bids.
You are to entertain the king...
... and keep his mind on Mary
at all times.
That is your task and no more.
What's the noise?
It's Mistress Boleyn, Your Grace.
Her stories of life at the French court.
I'm aware of one Boleyn girl.
But she's lying-in
with a certain child in her belly.
Well, Boleyn girl...
...show your face.
What's so amusing?
I was merely offering my thoughts
on the new French king.
Who has such great power,
yet such meager authority as a man.
- Continue.
- His pettiness is astounding.
He will bear a mortal grudge
over the mildest of slights.
Spoiled cub with a spike in its paw.
Riven with resentment.
Unable to forgive or forget.
A great king...
...a great man,
rises above such things.
And what would you know
of great men?
I've read enough books
and heard enough talk...
...to believe I'd know one
if he were before me.
Then look about you.
I'm curious. Do you see one here?
Looking, my lord.
Still looking, my lord.
There. Found one.
So forgiveness, you say,
makes a man great. What else?
Generosity.
Humility.
The ability to recognize
his match in others...
...and not be threatened by it.
- His match in other men?
- Women too.
You believe that?
That women can be
the match of men?
It's a question women have asked
themselves for some time.
But we concede
men do have some value.
So we accept them as equal.
I find you much changed,
Mistress Anne.
Then my prayers
have been answered.
Welcome back at court.
My lord.
What?
I suppose he felt that
she'd been banished long enough.
But in whose interest
do they imagine she'll act?
Certainly not mine.
Why do they make this room
such a dungeon?
Does it have to be this dark?
- Where were you?
- Just visiting Mary.
As ever.
Well, now that Anne's back,
you can be doubly jealous.
I'm your wife.
You never lie with me.
Yes, it has.
I hope you know what you're doing.
These are vagabonds who'll stop
at nothing to take your money.
We're not gambling, Your Grace.
Mistress Boleyn
is reading our fortunes.
Read mine.
Another talent picked up in France?
The queen offers her ladies
a broad education.
Last I heard, she was entertaining
Lutherans and heretics.
Scholars and philosophers, my lord,
escaping persecution.
- I hope you kept your ears shut.
- I did.
And a cross close to my heart
at all times.