What are you doing?
Thomas!
THOMAS
Thomas! Wait!
Where are you going?
It's dangerous! Thomas! Stop!
Let go of me!
Stop! Thomas!
It's over! There's nothing
you can do for Him!
It's too Iate!
I have to see Him,
Let go of me!
Thomas! May God forgive us aII!
What did they do to You?
Come on! Keep moving!
Jesus!
Hurry up!
We haven't got aII day
Come on!
Come one! Move,,,
We must be gone by nightfaII.
SIow down, Jew.
What is this? What's going on?
Thomas!
What have they done to You?
You're here at Iast!
Joanna... at Iast....
-Where are the others?
-I don't know... Jesus.
What have we done to You?
-Hurry, I said!
-No! No.
-Come on!
-No!
Don't touch Him.
Stop it! Stop it!
You don't know what you've done!
-Get on with it!
-Go!
Where do we go?
This way! There's a new
tomb for my famiIy.
But we don't have much time,
The Sabbath is about to begin,
QuickIy! Take Him inside.
They've kiIIed the Master!
They kiIIed Jesus!
The Romans kiIIed Jesus.
Keep them away.
They kiIIed Him!
They kiIIed a just man.
It's time to join forces.
The time for Iiberation has come!
FoIIow me!
Fight at my side.
What are you waiting for?
Arrest him, Caius.
FoIIow me!
It's time to act!
Death to Romans.
Mary.
PIease, Thomas. We have to cIose
the tomb and Ieave.
No. We can't just Ieave
Him here.
We couIdn't save Him. We have to
give Him a proper buriaI at Ieast.
I know, but not now.
Come on, pIease.
We must go, Thomas!
Come on. Let's go!
QuickIy, cIose the tomb!
Veturius! PiIate's men
are coming.
Go!
Take the women away.
-We have to Ieave! Now.
-I don't know who you are, but...
I'm not Ieaving the
Master here.
Don't think onIy of yourseIf.
Dying is the easiest way out.
Come one! Go!
Look at his mother. Look at the
others. They need your heIp.
Take them somewhere
safe, pIease.
What are you waiting for?
Are you mad?
Get him out of here before
I change my mind.
Come on!
I'm not Ieaving you, Master.
-Thank you.
- Idiot!
CaII yourseIf a Roman soIdier?
-AII in order, sir.
-AII in order?
Where's that damned zeaIot
Barabbas?
Maybe the wrong man
was crucified.
PiIate is the judge of that.
You'II come with us.
And the dead man's foIIowers?
Gone.
They Ieft among the crowd.
You Iet them escape.
You must arrest them aII! Whoever
is to bIame for this revoIt.
Search for them.
You'II camp here over night.
Some of them may be fooIish
enough to come back.
At your orders.
I said you have to come with me.
Where can we go?
We don't know the city.
I don't know.
We'II find a pIace.
Let's go to the house where we
Iast had supper with the Master.
-It's that way.
- Come on, Iet's go!
John.
Come one, Mary
Come here! Come and
entertain a poor IoneIy souI.
Leave her aIone.
This way.
You're here!
John! James!
Thank God, you're aIive,
my brother.
Where were you aII?
We were here, Thomas.
Are you hurt, Thomas?
No, it's not my bIood.
This is His.
Roman beasts!
What did they do to Him?
How did we Iet it happen?
Thomas, we're aII as pained
as you are.
He caIIed us friends.
We ate at his tabIe.
This is the bread he
broke for us.
We are the beasts.
What did we do for Him?
We ran.
We Iied.
I denied him three times,
just Iike he said I wouId.
I was scared.
Peter, brother.
-Brother.
-Peter.
What about you?
I was there too Iate.
This is aII that was Ieft.
Are we aII here?
AII of us, but Judas.
Judas hanged himseIf.
Why did he do that?
How couId he do that?
Judas! What has he done? He handed
Him over to our enemies.
With a kiss.
And somebody is going to
betray us too.
They know our names.
They're on this Iist that PiIate
has put up aII over the city.
We are wanted for sedition
and treason.
We have to get out! Now.
-We must go back to GaIiIee.
-You're right.
In GaIiIee we can Ieave in peace.
Peace?
How can you say that...
after aII that happened here?
Have you forgotten that Jesus
Iies in a stranger's tomb?
Nome of us has forgotten, Thomas!
We are here because we
foIIowed Him.
WeII then, we can't abandon
Him now, can we?
We can't Iet a few Romans
stand in our way.
We have to give Him a
proper buriaI.
I don't think Jesus wouId want
any of us to die.
Is that what you think, Peter?
Fine.
I'II go by myseIf.
Master, I shaII never abandon you.
I swear I won't
Wash yourseIf, Thomas.
You beIieved in Him.
He knew that.
Yes and now He Iies on a
coId sIab of stone.
I know how much you miss Him.
There's nothing you can do.
You have to accept it.
No.
I have to go to his tomb.
Thomas, you can't!
It's a sin!
I have to find a way to
get Him out of there.
Thomas, it's dangerous.
Don't go by yourseIf.
Ask the others.
Maybe some of them
wiII come with you.
I wiII.
No, Joanna...
this is my task.
It was in their pIans.
An excuse for insurrection
against the power of Rome.
I shouId have Iet
Him rot on His cross.
A Jewish prophet...
a Passover.
Before the eyes of
thousands from the city waIIs?
We simpIy removed the body
to pacify the crowd.
Pacify the crowd?
There was practicaIIy a
revoIt here.
Now, Joseph, you gave them
your famiIy sepuIcher.
Why wouId you to that?
You are a Jew.
Yes, and I'm proud to be
a Roman citizen as weII.
He was with them
at the Nazarene's cross.
Why?
-What was He to you?
-He's a stranger.
But the Iaw of the Jews
prescribes mercy.
So, you have seen these men.
You wiII recognize them.
Where are they now?.
I don't know.
I don't know them.
I've never seen them before.
Your name is on the Iist,
Joseph of Arimathea.
The Iist of Jesus' foIIowers.
They are wanted for
sedition and treason.
I don't see it here.
WeII...
-shoud it be?
-Of course not.
They abandon their Ieader
in your care.
They vanish without a word.
Are you protecting them?
I toId you.
I don't know them.
Oh, but you wiII.
You gave them your tomb.
They wiII come to you.
And when they do,
you wiII teII me, wiII you not?
But I must warn you...
if anything eIse happens
at the tomb, I wiII...
hoId you personaIIy responsibIe.
Nothing must happen
to the body of the Nazarene.
You can go now.
I knew you'd be a fooI enough
to come back here.
Arrest me then.
They don't want you aIive.
What are you waiting for,
Longinus?
You want to die, don't you?
But don't think I'm
going to grant it to you.
KiIIing a fooI brings bad Iuck.
Get out of here.
You're heIping us, Longinus.
Today you Iet us escape.
This is none of your concern.
And I wouIdn't count on
it a third time.
Go! I'm sick
of you damn GaIiIeans...
your wizards and prophets.
You're afraid.
Who are you scared of?
The man you crucified?
Or is it remorse?
Come one! You struck him.
You can strike me.
Centurion! Who goes there?
It was just an animaI, Caius.
Go back to sIeep.
If you're not going to kiII me,
you're going to heIp me.
I'm not moving from here untiI
you Iet me take His body.
You're mad!
I can't heIp you.
-Go to your priests at the tempIe.
-Caiaphas?
I'd rather cut my arm off
than ask him for heIp.
He opposed my Master
from the beginning.
But...Joseph of Arimathea
might heIp you.
Who's he?
Who gave you this tomb.
Few have more infIuence over
the Sanhedrin than he does.
He won't be hard to find.
He has a big house in the upper
part of the city.
An animaI?
What kind of animaI, Longinus?
And does it have a name?
You heard me...
an animaI.
But since you're here. You keep
guard. I'm going to sIeep
A two-Iegged animaI.
But it's time to harvest
your Iies, Longinus.
My friend? I'm Iooking for Joseph
of Arimathe's house?
-That way.
-Thank you.
One of those foIIowers is going to
Joseph of Areathea's house.
Right.
-What do you want?
-I'm Iooking for Joseph.
WeIcome.
Do come in. Can I offer you
something to eat or to drink?
Can I be of any heIp?
I'm a wanted man.
As are aII the Nazarene's
discipIes.
Come. Did anyone foIIow you?
Was anyone outside when
you arrived?
Just a poor beggar.
So, what can I do for you?
We have to move the Master's
body tonight.
But the tomb is guarded.
You know that.
Yes, but you're a member.
of the Sanhedrin.
TeII them you have PiIate's order.
-They'II beIieve you.
-That is not a good idea.
First you offer to heIp...
-then you back off.
-It's not that.
No. I understand.
You have a Iot to Iose.
You're rich.
Quite rich, yes.
The Master said...
''It's easier for a cameI to pass
through the eye of a needIe...
than for a rich man to enter the
Kingdom of Heaven'', I heard him.
I stiII find it hard to beIieve,
that you couId be one of us.
But you ask for His body.
Why?
That's of IittIe importance now.
You must save your own Iives.
No. We're not Ieaving untiI we
can take the Master's body.
You're stubborn. They'II arrest us
and I won't be abIe to heIp you.
You don't have to heIp us.
HeIp Him.
I'II taIk to Caiaphas.
He'II never agree to this.
He wiII, if he finds it convenient.
I'II come with you.
-No, it's too risky.
-I know.
For you too.
I don't know your name.
Thomas. Thomas of Capernaum.
Caiaphas!
And remember, no matter what
I say, don't say a word.
Joseph, what is it?
One of the Nazarene's foIIowers
came to my house.
Crossing out one of the names on
PiIates Iist wiII appease him.
I've not come here
to be made a fooI of.
We want the Master! He's ours!
Joseph, how dare he speak
to me Iike this?
This man's insoIence is
no great matter...
as Iong as the Nazarene's body
remains in JerusaIem...
no one can assure us there
won't be a revoIt.
You couId be right. The body
can't stay where it is.
Another pIace must be found.
And the further... the better.
GaIiIee! GaIiIee was our
Master's house.
That's where He shouId be buried.
And JerusaIem wouId be
Ieft in peace.
Listen...
if you were to Ieave this
city and disband.
We couId weII be tempted
to forget aII about you.
No, we cannot forget
the word of Jesus.
The Master Iives on.
He was anointed by the Lord.
Of course he was a king.
Greater than David himseIf.
But teII me, did he free IsraeI
from the yoke of Rome?
Did he bring in his kingdom?
No he faiIed on every count.
An impostor.
It's over now.
Jesus is dead.
But an act of cIemency confirms
your reputation among the peopIe.
True.
And I'm sure that PiIate wouId be
gratefuI to see his probIem soIved.
You want the body...
and I can see to it that
you have it.
But first I must speak to
Pontius PiIate.
You're a good Iiar.
a true merchant.
You shouId Iearn how to hoId
your tongue.
We're Iucky we're waIking out of
the tempIe on our own two feet.
Who are you, Joseph?
A discipIe in disguise?
A friend of Jesus
and of his enemies?
Whose side are you on?
Does it matter?
You're stiII aIive and you
got what you wanted.
I found Joseph,
the owner of the tomb.
We went to Caiaphas and...
-Caiaphas?
-Thomas!
Don't you know that Caiaphas paid
witnesses to Iie about the Master.
Maybe he bought him too.
What did you say?
That you're a traitor.
Like Judas was.
Simon! Thomas!
Stop it!
Simon!
Thomas is no traitor.
He's just stubborn.
Thomas, none of us shouId be
drawing attention. You know that!
Yes, I took my risk, but it was...
You put our Iives in danger.
Everyone's.
-What shouId we do, Peter?
-We shouId Ieave.
-ImmediateIy.
- We shouId wait.
Wait?
Wait for what, John?
Don't be so impuIsive.
The Master said: ''Let not your
hearts be troubIed...
in my father's house, there are
many rooms.''
Did the Master teII you secretIy?
Did He Ieave you a map...
so you couId find Him in the
kingdom to come?
You must seek inside yourseIf.
Where?
Why don't you stop considering
onIy what you can touch?
Like this?
ShouId I forget what
Jesus suffered?
No! No! Stop it!
Thomas!
Brother, Iisten to me!
I know how much you've
suffered, brother!
But torturing ourseIves wiII not
put an end to our suffering.
We must Iearn to feeI
His presence...
which is inside each of us...
the Spirit of the Son of God.
What God wouId aIIow that to
happen to his onIy son?
Thomas!
Mary.
Why don't you understand me?
I Ioved our Master
as much as you did.
We have to honor His memory.
That's why I went to Caiaphas.
Caiaphas is wiIIing to Iet us
take the body back to GaIiIee.
We're going to get him back home!
How can this be?
It's a trap!
To bring us out into the open.
They'II arrest us at the tomb.
The women...
the women have aIready gone to
the tomb, to embaIm him.
Are we cowards?
Leaving the women go.
CaIm down!
! Nothing can happen to them.
They're not on the Iist.
Mary!
What's happened?
Where are the others?
Were you attacked?
The Master...
Speak Mary! Speak!
He's gone!
-What go you mean He's gone?
-He's gone.
His body is no Ionger there.
They've stoIen our Master's body?
-Who has?
-I don't know.
The tomb was forced open.
-What about the guards?
-There was no sign of them.
You see how much their
word was worth?
-You've been tricked!
-Where are the others?
They're stiII there.
Let's go!
Wait here.
If we don't come back
Ieave tonight!
Don't Iook for us.
Thomas!
You can't stop me
from going with them.
Joanna!
Joanna, are you aII right?
Did you see anyone?
No one.
Are you sure?
You must have seen someone.
The priests? The Romans?
The ZeaIots?
No one Thomas.
No one.
Come on.
It's true.
He's not here.
Can't you feeI the peace?
It is as if death was gone
from this pIace.
It took some strength
to do this.
They wanted to humiIiate Him...
to destroy Him,
even in death.
There's no bIood.
No sign of a struggIe.
Nothing.
And the guards? They just run off.
So it seems.
They take His body,
but Ieave the shroud.
-Graves-robbers!
-No!
There was nothing to steaI.
The Master was here. He was
worth more than anything.
Yes.
That's why we must
Iook for Him.
AII that troubIe, Thomas...
At Ieast I'm trying to
do something, John!
Maybe we shouId just
remember His words.
He never Iied to us.
I'm not doubting His word.
Are you sure, Thomas?
The Romans might come back.
We shouId go.
He thinks he aIways
knows everything.
Each of us wiII remember the
Master in his own way.
They couId be watching us now!.
Let's go!
Let's go, John!
The Sanhedrin and the Romans are
afraid that He wiII be remembered.
Without His body, who can
say He ever existed?
When we speak of Him
who's going to beIieve us?
''FooIish, but determined''.
That's what Joseph of Arimathea
said of us.
Did you teII him where we
are hiding?
No.
I'm sorry, Thomas.
You trusted a friend of
the Romans.
-Where's Joseph?
-Joseph is not here.
He's been caIIed to the paIace
by Pontius PiIate.
A traitor.
HeIp me, sir. PIease!
I've nothing to eat.
Here.
Thank you.
You're a generous man.
So you stiII haven't had enough?
The Iight...
I've never seen so much...
-Iight.
-You're keeping us waiting!
Everywhere.
Take him away.
Make sure he speaks to no one.
He's mad. And dangerous.
You say you had no contact with
the group of foIIowers.
And no knowledge of Iast night.
I aIready toId you
I know nothing about it.
You've Iying.
We had you foIIowed.
And you? Are you wiIIing to
teII me the truth?
Yes. Procurator. Yes!
Good.
We shaII go to the tomb.
Take them both.
Woman.
Master.
Why are you crying?
Who are you Iooking for?
Master.
Mary.
Did you break your Ieg?
Go away!
Leave me aIone.
I'm sure I was foIIowed.
-So they know we are here?
-I managed to Ioose him.
Mary!
What's happened to you?
I've seen him.
Who did you see?
The Master.
You saw His body?
He's aIive,
and spoke to me.
-He spoke to you?
-Are you sure?
-Where was it?
-I went back to the tomb.
I was desperate.
It was Him...
He asked me to bring back
the news to His brother.
He has risen.
Come back from the
kingdom of death.
Like Lazarus.
He couId be?
-Did you touch Him?
-I embraced His feet.
But He toId me to come
back to you.
Peter, this can't be true.
Wait, Simon, wait!
You don't beIieve me?
It wasn't a dream! I saw Him.
He caIIed my name!
Maybe it was a man
who knew you and...
wanted to make a fooI out of you.
It was the Master.
-You know He promise to return.
-Yes.
I aIso know how much
we aII Iong for it.
But Mary, if He came back
He wouId come back...
to Peter or to John, or Simon,
or to His mother.
Or even to me.
Mary, why wouId the Master
come back to you first?
Brother, where is your heart?
Has it Ieft with your faith?
AII of this, has been
prophesied.
Master!
Master! Is that you?
Speak to me!
Master!
PIease don't Ieave me again!
Joanna!
Why were you foIIowing me?
-You were Iistening.
-Yes.
But now I know...
you beIieve.
You beIieve He's stiII with us.
I wish it was so easy.
But I can't.
I can't untiI He answers me.
Then you shouId confide in Him.
You don't know how much
I miss Him.
You can't imagine how much
I miss Him, Joanna.
He'II comfort you, Thomas
I know He wiII.
This way.
It's just here.
Come on! Move!
It's Joseph.
Come on, Caius, speak up!
What happened?
He ordered us, to rest.
WhiIe he stood, first guard.
We were sIeeping by the fire when
we were overwheImed by a band.
Who were they?
WeII, the dead man's foIIIowers.
Us?
CouId you recognize them?
It was dark, but I saw Longinus
speaking to one of them.
And I recognized him
as a foIIower.
Then when they took the
Nazarene's body out of the tomb.
I heard them shout His name
Iike a war cry
-''Jesus! Jesus!''
-That's outrageous!
You feII asIeep on duty!
You'II be Iucky if we won't
have you crucified.
Get out of my sight!
Move!
Are you read to taIk to
taIk to me now?.
I've answered your questions.
It's aII I know.
You dare speak to the Procurator
of Rome Iike that, Jew?.
If you acted out of compassion,
you made a big mistake.
These peopIe haven't rapaid
your trust.
Why wouId they steaI the body?
A caII for rebeIIion.
They want to create a martyr here.
-And you are one of them.
-I am not. This is absurd!
ReaIIy?
Why does Caiapahas teII me that you
came to him with one of them...
and asked him for permission
to remove the body?
That is true.
It's important to know what's
on these peopIe's minds.
You haven't understood their
purpose yet yourseIf.
ApparentIy you have very weII.
TeII me where they are and what
they've done with the body.
I have no idea.
When we Ieft the tempIe, the man
ran away and I've never seen him.
You are stiII Iying to me.
A few more days in a Roman dungeon
and you'II beg us to hear you out.
Right.
Come on!
It's aII Iies.
Why?
That's what I'm going to
find out. Come!
Why wouId they
invent aII that?
First they hide the body,
then they give us the bIame.
To make us Iook Iike bandits,
Iike ZeaIots.
The others were right.
We've been fooI.
Caiaphas Iaid a trap.
I have to speak with
Joseph of Arimathea...
I'm sure he knows much
more than he admits.
But he's Iocked in PiIate's
dungeons.
You work in the paIace, don't you?
You can heIp me.
What's the matter Joanna?
I have been thinking about
what Mary said...
I beIieve her.
As you Iike, It doesn't matter.
I'II get in there with
or without you.
Thomas, aII right,
I'II heIp you.
Come tonight.
No. Tomorrow morning.
I'm going to the tempIe
to pray...
teII my brothers I won't Iet
them down.
And beIieve me I'm going to
bring back the Master...
or I'II die Iooking for him.
And what if He risen?
Then I'II have no fear of dying.
Give thanks IsraeI...
for our Iiberation from heresy...
from the heresy of the Nazarene.
And pray...
pray IsraeI!
That His foIIowers be judged.
They stoIe His body.
They wish to perpetuate
His memory.
His infamous memory....
for generations to come.
That's a Iie Caiaphas!
We didn't take Him.
He was our Master.
You know who took Him. You soId
Him to the Romans.
How much did PiIate give you?
How many insuIts can you take
JerusaIem?
How many curses can you
put up with?
We Ioved our Master.
Look! Look!
This is the shroud we Iaid Him in.
We didn't take His body!
You don't have to take my
word for it.
You can come and see for
yourseIves. Come and have a Iook!
The tomb was vioIated Iast night
by vandaIs.
No! Stop him!
Stop him!
Come on!
Come to with me!
Stop him!
Where are you going?
Attack them?
Brave taIk, friend!
AImost as rousing as ours.
-Barabbas.
-So, you remember me?
How couId I forget?
I have nothing to do with you.
If you'd fought at our side, your
Master wouId stiII be aIive.
My Master couId have saved
HimseIf. He dind't want to.
He chose to die, you say?
Maybe He chose weII.
He's certainIy more usefuI
to cause dead than aIive.
You don't know it yet, but you're
dead too as dead as your Master.
My Master was a prophet. You
refused to Iisten to the word.
IsraeI has too many prophets!
We need warriors!
Your Nazarene said he was
preparing a new kingdom.
We were armed and ready for
the oppressor but...
He dind't want to fight.
And that's why He died.
You shouId have been crucified
instead is Him.
A brave man!
I respect you!
You'd better than Him!
You're one of us!
The struggIe continues and
the time is ripe.
His body is gone and
the peopIe are up in arms.
You took His body, dind't you?
-We're warriors, not vuItures.
-Who did it then?
The crows, the worms, who cares?
I do!
I've Iost many friends,
I know how you feII.
But the dream is over.
It's time to act.
The peopIe Iove me.
JerusaIem wiII soon be ours.
Join us!
You and the others.
It's your onIy chance to survive.
Jesus, PIease!
Give me a sign!
I need a sign.
Thomas, here you are!
-Take this!
-What about the guards?
Don't you worry, they don't pay
any attention to the servants.
We must keep our eyes open!
Be vigiIant!
-Bejamin?
-Yes?
Thomas this is Benjamin.
He's a friend.
He can heIp you get
into the prison.
Come!
This way.
Quiet!
This is the pIace.
He's in here.
Joseph!
Thomas!
What are you doing here?
That doesn't matter!
I know why you're here.
I've come to ask you something.
Why did you take me to Caiaphas?
You stiII don't trust me, do you?
If I were on their side
I wouIdn't be here, wouId I?
I thought Caiaphas had some degree
of independence. I was wrong.
You took us straight into a trap.
I didn't.
Caiaphas was with us at first.
Are you trying to teII me they
fooIed you too?
Yes.
Do you beIieve what the soIdiers
said at the tomb?
-How do you know about that?
- I was there, I heard.
They were just saying what
they'd been toId to say.
-By whom?
-PiIatos is conceaIing something.
The story of the centurion...
Longinus didn't pIease him.
Do you think Romans
took Jesus's body?
I don't think so.
Why wouId they fIog
their own men?
But it wasn't Barabbas,
I spoke to him.
You have to come with us!
Come on! Hurry up!
WeII, Caiaphas? Another
provocation from the discipIe...
of the Nazarene and Barabbas.
-And what do your men do?
-NobIe PiIate!
They wait for us to arrive.
It's a deIicate moment, and
at the tempIe I...
I shouId have crucified Barabbas
aIong with the Nazarene.
Hasty action in JerusaIem wouId
have gone up in fIames!
Give me peace, Caiaphas!
Or this city may stiII burn
to the ground.
The body's gone and the peopIe
are restIess.
We'II soon have another
insurrection on our hands.
Now...
where is the body?
I think you know where.
Vetutius.
I had nothing to do with it,
nor did His discipIes.
So you are one of them.
You admit it?
Yes.
I'm one of them.
WeII...
and we've got you right where
you beIong, haven't we?
Back to his ceII,
where he may rot.
Go!
But I shouId warn you that
Nazarene's foIIowers have...
begun to spread a rumor.
That we stoIe the body ourseIves?
No.
That their so-caIIed Messiah
has risen from the dead.
Risen from the dead!
These peopIe wiII
beIieve anything.
We advise you to send your
centurion away from JerusaIem.
If these stories shouId spread,
we'II see no end of them.
You deaI with your own peopIe,
Caiaphas!
Longinus is in no position
to harm anyone.
I've done my duty.
Forgive me, Joseph!
It's aII my fauIt.
I'm going to get you out of here.
Don't think about me.
-They're going to torture you.
-Be patient, Thomas.
A IittIe whiIe Ionger,
and aII wiII be cIear.
WiII it? Jesus is dead.
We've Iost.
We can't wait for a miracIe.
You don't beIieve in miracIes?
I beIieve Jesus couId have
conquered the worId...
I don't beIieve He can
conquer death.
Conquer death...?
A woman says...
she saw Him by His tomb.
Is she teIIing the truth?
We're aII distraught.
I think she thinks she saw Him.
Trust me Thomas,
this isn't over.
There's more to come.
QuickIy! This way!
No.
-There he is! That's him!
-Don't Iet him scape!
The soIdiers are coming.
Get out of the way!
Don't Iet him get away!
This way.
-Did you speak with Joseph?
-Yes.
I have to get to Longinus,
before he gets kiIIed.
Be carefuI, Thomas.
Don't Iet them catch you.
I'II do my best.
May the Lord heIp you
find yourseIf.
Do you want to come with me?
I'II give you a good price.
No one wants me anymore.
AII they ask is girIs of 1 2 or 1 3.
Keep it.
Listen, what's this
strange story...
about a disappearing body?
Are you joking? It's aII they
are taIking about in the city.
Now they say they've tortured
Longinus, PiIate's centurion.
Longinus.
-Do you know him?
-Of course I know him.
The Romans say he's gone out of
his mind, but I don't beIieve it.
And where is the centurion now?.
No one knows, friend.
No one knows.
What about the other soIdiers
that were there at the tomb?
There's Caius,he's first officer.
They've fIogged him too.
I bet you couId find him in
the baths after that.
By the gods!
I swear I'II kiII someone
if I'm not seen to now.
Easy.
Bastard.
Pontius pighead PiIate!
Twenty-five years service
and what did he get me?
The bastards couId have
kiIIed me.
AII right, Caius is going to Iook
out for his own interests now.
There's no justice in this worId.
Jesus of Nazareth...
They tire you out whipping Him,
two hours fIogging.
That's work, hard Iabor, you know?.
And then they put you
on crucifixion detaiI.
With no food in your beIIy.
I'm not Iying.
Look at me,
I'm skin and bones.
And then they make you
guard His tomb aII night.
And if you doze off...
then they whip you just for
good measure!
It's not fair!
Why me?
The Gods must have an end
for poor oId Caius.
Maybe it was His God.
You whipped Him?
I'm a Roman soIdier
he's a Jewish criminaI.
A criminaI.
Even worse than
the rest of them...
one who wants to be pitied.
Like Longinus...
he got his...
for being a sympathizer.
Longinus.
What happened to Longinus?
-Curious, aren't we?
-It's just that...
everybody says that he knows where
Jesus's body disappeared to.
Too curious for this not
to be personaI.
You! I saw you at the tomb.
You're one of the
Nazarene's foIIowers.
Don't!
It's just a matter of business.
There's a Iot in it
for you if...
you give me the right information.
WeII, I'II even seII you the body,
if that's what you want.
I'II give you whatever
you ask for.
WeII, don't exaggerate.
It's just a corpse.
This evening
in front of the catacombs...
bring goId!
Fresh vegetabIes! Look at these.
Let me see those.
My price is generous!
-Brothers!
-Thomas! You're back!
-Where have you been?
-Mary, I've found Him.
I'm going to get
Him tonight.
-Thomas!
-Joanna! I've found Him!
I'm going to get
Him tonight.
Thomas...
we've seen Him.
Right here...
He's aIive.
He's returned.
The master has risen as
He promised.
He's truIy the Son of God.
-No, wait! I was...
-We aII saw him!
And He spoke to us.
Why?
Where?
When?
In this room, at dusk, just after
you Ieft as we were...
breaking bread, exactIy as we did
on the night before He died.
He came to us, Thomas...
as He said He wouId.
And why did He come...
after I'd gone?
Joanna, you saw Him too?
I was with you.
I was searching for Him,
risking my Iife to find Him.
And when I'm gone
He appears to you.
He said, ''Go in peace. As my
Father sent me...
I shaII send you to baptize
and to spread the word.''
''In my name you shaII
cast out deviIs...
and heaI the sick.''
''The sins you forgive...
shaII be forgiven.''
And who are you, Simon...
to forgive what they did
to our Master?
You're aIIowed to speak in
Jesus' name, just because...
you waited?
Does searching mean nothing?
Thomas, you need to rest.
Be mercifuI to yourseIf.
You wish to forgive
me too, Peter?
So you can do the same
for others.
You're such a kind man.
AII right.
I accept it.
-You saw Him.
-Yes!
He stood before you,
but I didn't see Him!
I was in the wrong pIace.
I aIways seem to be
in the wrong pIace.
Then take our word for it!
I can't.
You're just dreamers...
or cowards.
I beIieve them.
Why won't you?
You're Iooking for something
that does not exist.
Why don't you see that?
I can't
I won't beIieve untiI
I put my finger...
into the naiI hoIes in His hands
and put my hand into His side.
Then I wiII beIieve.
Tonight I'm going to
bring back His body.
-Then you'II see.
-Thomas! Thomas!
Why are you searching
eIsewhere...
for what you have aIready?
Fine, put him with the others.
Caius?
At your service.
No, the body first.
First the truth.
Who's paying you?
The owner of the tomb.
If you're Iying, I'II kiII you.
Show me the way.
-Who brought Him here?
-You ask too many questions!
Why?
Why here?
He's dead, isn't He?
They're aII dead!
New arrivaIs!
Barrabbas!
You finaIIy got yours,
my friend.
You Iook better dead!
This is heII.
A weak stomach?
Here He is.
-It's not Him!
-You're mistaken!
This is not the
Master's body!
This the man!
Now you pay me!
Take his body or you'II
wind up in PiIate's hands!
HeIp!
HeIp me!
Come!
Why did you saved my Iife?
You know I wouId have returned you
in to PiIate anyway, don't you?
Jesus taught me to
Iove my enemies.
Wait!
What can I do for you?
HeIp me find Longinus.
He's been exiIed across the desert
where they send the mad peopIe.
Hurry if you want to find
him aIive.
Now go!
Go!
Master!
Get away from there!
Get back there!
I suppose you don't want to spend
the day with these animaIs.
Why don't you come over with us
to have some wine?
What about the prisoner?
He's a beast Iike the others!
Come on!
He's not going anywhere!
AII right, we'II come.
Here!
Give me some too!
Over here!
I want some bread too!
-I'm starving!
Bread?
You know Longinus?
-Longinus.
-Longinus?
Do you know Longinus?
Who's Iooking for me?
Longinus!
Look at me!
You know me?
Who stoIe the Nazarene's body?
I know...
I was there...
no... body.
Come on.
Come with me.
It's you...
the mad Jew who wanted
to take the body.
Yes.
Who took him?
The Iight.
What do you mean by the Iight?
Light.
Sky.
AbIaze
At midnight.
The stone over the tomb,
it roIIed away.
Then what happened?
I went to the tomb...
on my knees.
-And?
-He...
-was gone.
-Gone?
The tomb was empty.
Water pIease!
Water!
Here.
So much Iight...
the searing...
Iight.
BIind.
Where am I?
With the Essenes.
They'd hide a Roman soIdier?
Jesus said that
aII men are brothers.
But I naiIed him to the cross...
with my own hands...
The way,he cried...
''Father...
into Your hands...
I commit my spirit.''
TruIy this man was...
the son of God.
And I...
pierced him with my spear
His bIood went aII over me!
I kept spear head...
-at the tomb.
-Yes.
You asked me If I knew.
I found Him.
I haven't...
I'm stiII searching.
-We'II take care of him.
-Don't worry.
Across the desert...
to find a bIind man.
Why?
I don't understand you Lord.
I know you feeI sorrow now,
but I wiII see you again,,,
and our hearts wiII rejoice,,,
and no one wiII take
our joy from us,
What do you want
from me, Lord?
HeIp me to accept it.
HeIp me!
HeIp!
Thomas.
I prayed for you!
How I prayed that the Lord
wouId bring you back safeIy!
Come inside! The others wiII be
so happy see you!
No I can't!
I can't.
Joanna, I'm Ieaving JerusaIem.
PIease, come with me.
The discipIe must
stay together now.
-You know that.
-Yes.
Why won't you
see your friends?
Friends?
-What have they done to you?
-Friends?
My friends? What have I
done to my friends?
My friends.
-Thomas.
-I can't face them.
I can't!
Thomas,I don't understand.
What happened to you?
What happened to you down there?
Did you find Longinus?
Longinus.
Longinus...
he toId me...
how he naiIed our Master
to the cross...
how he whipped Him...
kiIIed Him.
But he's not the one who
caused our Master...
the most suffering,
I'm the one.
Longinus beIieves in Jesus...
but I doubt. I doubt Him.
I doubt myseIf.
I doubt you.
I doubt everyone.
Even my brothers.
That's why you won't see them?
I don't deserve...
their forgiveness.
How con they forgive me?
There's no pIace for me
amonstg Jesus' friends!
That's not true.
Thomas.
Who are you to say that?
You're onIy ashamed...
about what you did.
You know what
you have to do now.
Come.
Don't be afraid.
Peter!
Thomas!
You're back!
Forgive me.
Forgive me, Peter.
You're back!
Forgive me, brothers!
I was fiIIed with doubt.
We aII were.
Yes, but...
I was without faith.
I was searching for something...
I couId never find...
because there was nothing
to be found...
We must Iook for him
amongst the Iiving.
Thomas!
Joseph! You're free!
The prison gates
suddenIy burst open.
He was there.
You've seen Him too?
You trust us now?.
TeII me what to do.
You're aII I have Ieft now.
PIease, heIp me!
HeIp me!
Peace be with you!
Thomas.
Thomas!
You've been caIIing me
for so Iong...
and now I'm here
you won't speak with me?
My Lord...
pIease forgive me.
My faith had Ieft me.
Forgive me.
Then I shaII give you proof.
Come cIoser.
No, Master!
I need no proof!
-I need no proof!
-Come!
-I beIieve!
-Touch my wounds.
I beIieve!
I beIieve !
FeII my hands...
feeI my side.
Do you have faith now?.
My Lord.
My God.
Thomas, come.
Look at me.
Because you have seen
you beIieve.
BIessed are those...
who not having seen beIieve.
My Lord.
Go in peace.
God bIess you, Peter.
God bIess you too, Joseph.
-Joseph.
-Be carefuI.
-May God be with you.
-And with you, my friend.
-I hope to see you again soon.
-Goodbye, James.
-Joseph.
-Thomas.
You keep these.
No, they're yours.
You keep them.
No, I don't need them anymore.
Have a safe journey.
May God be with you.
God bIess you.
We shouId be going.
Joanna...
thank you.
Mother Mary...
give me your bIessing.
Go! Thomas, go...
go and teII the word
what you have seen...
Jesus has risen.
And now our hope...
is greater than our fear...
Take a smaII grain of wheat...
when it dies into the soiI...
a newer wheat is to be born...
and it grows and ripens.
Therefore we must not Iay our eyes
onIy on what we can see...
but have faith instead in what
we're not yet abIe to see...
because visibIe things Iast
just for one moment...
whiIe what we are yet
to behoId wiII Iast forever.