Subtitles translated ♪♪by
AsifAkheirESL@teachers.org
We're almost there.*[POL]
The doctors are looking at us.
Try to hold on.
You're nervous.
That's what makes you cough.
Plug your ears and pray to
The Mother of God.
Alright.
We'll soon be at aunt Edyta's
and
we'll be safe together.
We'll start our families
and have plenty of children.*
What are they saying?*
- No.
- Ewa, it's fine.*
Go without me.*
Magda, I promise I'll get you out!*
Muy caliente !*(very hot)
Who is it?*
- Auntie
- Wojtek ! Ewa !
They told me you weren't there,
but I found you, auntie!
Thank God.
Come in. We looked for you
a long time.
It's a miracle.
Edyta, who is it?
Wojtek! Wojtek, my niece is here!
Ewa found us!
We haven't seen each other
since the wedding.
But I remember you.
Give her something to eat and drink.
Yes, of course.
Come, I'll make you some tea.
They said you weren't there, on the boat.
Your uncle went to Ellis Island and
they said you hadn't come.
No, WE were there.
they said YOU weren't there.
They said your adress wasn't valid.
But I knew it wasn't so.
That you wouldn't have forgotten us.
Of course we'd never forget you!
Never.
Where's Magda ?
She had to stay in the hospital.
She's sick.
But she sent me a letter.
With your help we can get her out.
Magda was very brave.
Without her, I wouldn't be here.
I'm very tired...
But I'm well.
Tomorrow we'll go to church
to give thanks.
Let her rest.
Of course. Yes.
Dear, you're safe now.
You'll be very happy in this country.
You'll see.
We live well, here.
You'll find a nice man and
you'll get married.
Sleep, now.
You'll feel better.
Don't lose hope, dear.
The nightingale's song is
always sweetest
at the darkest hour.
Sleep.
Magda.
I was dreaming.*
Why?*
I have a good reputation, a business...
I don't want to be dishonored.
I didn't do anything.
They told me what you did
on the boat!
- You're shameful.
- No.
A whore!
Be grateful we let you
sleep here last night!
No! It's a lie!
Aunt Edyta! It's not true!
That's enough.
- Don't speak to her!
- What about Magda?
I pray for her.
She's sick, you poisoned her!
Where are you taking her?
Shut up!
- Tell me where they're taking her!
- It's MY house!*
Are you Polish?*
We're from Lodz.
It's terrible, how they treat us here.
As if we were nothing.
I'm NOT nothing.
Mary, mother of God,
in this hour of great need,
help me
and help me find Magda tonight.*
Che cosa? (What?)[ITAL]
God, you're beautiful!*
♪ Ma come puoi lasciarmi*
(How can you leave me)[ITAL]
♪ se mi struggo in pianto,
(when I'm melting into tears)
♪ se disperatamente io m’aggrappo a te!
(and desperately clinging to you)
♪ O mia divina amante,
(O, my heavenly lover)
♪ o vita di mia vita,
(O, life of my life)
♪ non spezzare il mio cuor!*
(Don't break my heart)
♪ [LA RONDINE G. Puccini]
I don't need him.*
You don't need him?
Really?
You know all the men in New York?
You know how to tell the rich ones
from the ones who beat you?*
In momine patris...[LAT]
et filii, et spiritus sancti, amen
Oremus. (Let us pray)
Lord, forgive me.[POL]
Mary, mother of God,
protect the souls of my mother
and my father.
Mary, mother of God,
please, protect my sister.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
In English.
I'm only Polish by descent.*
Oh, God. Oh, God.*
Wojtek is home. He's sleeping.*
We need to talk.
I need your help.
Please, auntie. I beg you.
It's so hard to say it...
Last Sunday I went to church.
First time in a long while.
I prayed to the Holy Virgin.
I've gone through so many trials.
Is it a sin to try to survive?
Auntie...
Is it a sin to want to survive
when I've done so many bad things?
Your uncle is a proud man.
I can't change him.
I know.
I know he's rejected me.
But I'm asking you
to believe I can be saved.
God sent me
to someone who's really lost,
someone who turned my life into a sin.
And now,
this person is suffering for me.
So I'm learning the power of forgiveness.
Auntie...
I need money...
for Magda.
A lot.
But we won't come back, ever.
Will you help me?
Can't you forgive me?*
Subtitles translated ♪♪by
AsifAkheirESL@teachers.org