Berlin, Germany
You didn’t wake me.
You were sleeping.
You let me sleep because you can’t
bear to have breakfast with me.
Nothing could be further from the
truth. I boiled you an egg. See?
I’d hardly have boiled you an egg
if I didn’t want to see you.
Tea or coffee?
Does any woman ever stay long
enough to find out
what the hell
goes on in your head?
What are you doing tonight?
I’m seeing my daughter.
Your daughter? You’ve kept very
quiet about her.
Have I?
She’s been abroad for a year.
Did you say tea?
I’m going.
Give my love to your daughter.
Tickets please.
Neustadt, West Germany, 1958
Hey, you!
Your feets!
Hey, kid.
Up.
It’s alright
Where do you live?
It’s here.
I’ll be fine now.
Thank you.
Goodbye
Look after yourself.
I’m worried about him.
He looks terrible.
The boy’s saying he doesn’t need a doctor.
- He does.
- I don’t need a doctor.
Good then.
- Peter!
We’re not going to argue about this.
Remind me, how old are you now?
Michael’s fifteen.
It’s scarlet fever.
He’ll be in bed
for several months. At least.
In completely isolation.
Emily, keep away. He’s contagious.
Emily?
How are you feeling?
Better.
I meant to tell you..
the day I got ill...
a woman helped me.
She helped you?
Yes. She brought me home.
Do you have her address?
Yes?
I brought you these flowers.
To say thank you.
Put them over there.
I would have come earlier, but I’ve
been in bed for three months.
You’re better now?
Yes, thank you.
Have you always been weak?
Oh no. I’d never been ill before.
It’s incredibly boring.
There’s nothing to do.
I couldn’t even be
bothered to read.
Well, thank you again.
Wait.
I’ll walk with you.
I have to go to work.
Wait in the hall while I change.
There are two more buckets downstairs.
You can fill them and bring them up.
You look ridiculous, look at you, kid.
You can’t go home like that.
Take off your clothes.
I’ll run you a bath.
Do you always take a bath in
your trousers?
It’s all right, I won’t look.
I'll get you a towel.
That’s why you came back.
You’re so beautiful
What are you talking about?
Look at me kid.
Slowly.
You’ve inconvenienced your mother.
How many more times?
I’ve said I’m sorry.
You scared her.
- I got lost, that’s all.
That’s why I was late.
Can I have some more?
How can anyone get lost in their
own home town?
I meant to head for the castle, I
ended up at the sports-field.
They’re in opposite directions.
- It’s none of your business.
He’s lying.
He’s not lying.
Michael never lies.
Dad, I’ve decided, I want to go
back to school tomorrow.
The doctor says you need another
three weeks.
Well I’m going.
Peter!
Like this?
That's right!
Not so fast.
It's alright!
Do it again.
What's your name?
What?
Your name?
Why do you want to know?
I’ve been here three times.
I want to know your name.
What's wrong was that?
Nothing, kid...
There's nothing wrong with that
It's Hanna.
It looks so suspicious
What’s yours, kid?
Michael.
So I'm with Michael.
Hanna.
The notion of secrecy is central to
Western literature.
You may say the
whole idea of character
in fiction is defined by people holding
specific information
which for various reasons.
- Sometimes perverse... Sometimes noble
They are determined not to disclose.
You never tell me what you’ve been
studying.
Studying?
At school.
Do you learn languages?
Yes.
What languages?
Latin.
Say something in Latin.
Quo, quo scelesti ruitis? Aut cur
dexteris aptantur enses conditi?
Aut cur dexteris aptantur
enses conditi?
It’s Horace.
It’s wonderful.
Do you want some Greek?
Oi men ippeon stroton oi de pesedon
oi da naon phais epi gan malainan
emmenai kalliston, ego de ken otto
tis eratai.
It’s beautiful.
How can you tell?
How do you know
when you’ve no idea what it means?
What are you studying in German?
I'm studying a play
Well, I’m writing a play.
By a writer called Gotthold Ephraim Lessing.
You’ve heard of him?
The play’s called Emilia Galotti.
You can read it.
I’d rather listen to you.
Allright.
Act One.
Scene One.
The setting:
one of the prince’s chambers.
The Prince:
I'm not very good.
Go On!
"Complaints, nothing but complaints."
For goodness’ sake, is there anything,
live for work?"
just imagine that people actually envy us.”
You’re good at it, aren’t you?
Good at what?
Reading.
What's funny?
I didn’t think I was good
at anything.
What are you doing?
What is it?
Why did you treat me like if you didn't know me?
You didn’t want to know me!
You can see I was in the first carriage.
So why did you sit in the second?
What did you think I was doing?
Why the hell do you think I was there?
How should I know.
I need a bath.
You know I've been working.
I'd like to be by myself
Could you please, leave?
I... I didn’t mean to upset you.
You don’t have the power to upset me.
You don’t matter enough to upset me.
I don’t know what to say.
I’ve never been with a woman before.
We’ve been together four weeks
and I can’t live without you.
I can’t!
Even the thought of it kills me.
Kid, you thought we could make love
in a tram?
kid, myœla the eœ that we will
kochaæ is the tram?
Is it true what you said?
That I don’t matter to you?
Do you forgive me?
Do you love me?
Do you have a book?
Yes, I have.
I took something
with me this morning.
What is it?
"The Odyssey" by Homer.
It's my homework.
We’re changing the order we do things.
Read to me first, kid.
Then we make love.
"The Odyssey" by Homer.
What’s an odyssey?
It’s a journey.
He sets out on a journey.
Good.
“Sing to me of the Man, Muse, the
man of twists and turns...
Driven time and again off course,
once he had plundered
The hallowed heights of Troy.
Come here!
"You press your hand
to his lips."
"She was dead"
"Pass all hed."
"I poked into the place aways and
encountered a little open patch
as big as a bedroom.
All hung around with vines.
and found a man lying there asleep,
and by Jinks,
it was my old Jim..."
"- When you learn it. I'll rec catch up land with shout you...
“Lady Chatterley felt his naked
flesh against her as he came into
flesh against her as he came into her.
For a moment he was still
inside her...
This is disgusting.
Where did you get this?
I borrowed it from someone at school.
You should be ashamed.
Go on.
‘Blistering Barnacles and a
thundering typhoon. It is water.'
‘But what on earth did you expect
it to be?’
Whisky.
Whisky! By thunder, whisky.
‘Whisky?
Come now captain, you
can’t be serious.’
That’s enough for today, kid.
I was wondering...
Do you think you could get some time off?
Maybe we could go for a trip.
What sort of trip?
Bicycling holiday.
Just for two days.
I’ve got a guide-book.
I’ve worked out the route.
Look!
What do you think?
I think you like planning, don’t you?
“I’m not frightened.
I’m not frightened of anything.
The more suffering,
the more I love.
“Danger will only increase my love,
it will sharpen it,
it will give it spice.
I’ll be the only angel you need.
You will leave life even more beautiful
than you entered it.
Heaven will take
you back and look at you and say
‘Only one thing can make a soul
complete,
and that thing is love.’
Excuse me.
Do you know what would you like?
What are you having?
You order.
I’ll have what you have.
Two a skip the potato...
Thank you.
I hope your mother was happy.
She enjoyed her meal very much.
Here, let me show you where we’re going.
It’s OK, kid.
I don’t want to know.
- What are you doing?
- I’m writing a poem. About you.
About you.
Can I hear it?
It’s not ready.
I’ll read it to you one day.
- Morning Henry.
- Good morning, Mr. Berg.
- Room 306
- Thank you.
- You all right, Michael?
- I’m fine.
You’d better hurry.
You know what she’s like.
- For now!
- Good luck.
Please, Stand!
Please, sit down.
The defender, please!
- Hello
- Hello.
Good morning, ladies.
Gentlemen, please welcome your new fellow-students,
treat them with courtesy.
Sit down!
Hello!
My name is Sophie.
I’m Michael.
"The Odyssey"
Take off your books.
Everyone believes that Homer’s
subject is homecoming. In fact,
The Odyssey is a book about a journey.
Home is a place you dream of...
Berg, I don’t mean to distract you,
but we’re meant to studying Homer,
not studying Sophia.
It’s wonderful, isn’t it?
Wonderful.
It’s going to be a great summer.
Why do you leave early?
He always leaves early.
Do you have large for a job?
See you tomorrow.
I’m sorry I’m late.
I was held up at school.
I have a new book.
"The Lady with the Little Dog."
By Anton Chekhov.
“The talk was that a new face had
appeared on the promenade,
a lady with a little dog.”
Schmitz!
One moment, please!
I read the reports on you
Every single word.
Excelent!
To work with me in the office.
We’re going to promote you.
Congratulations.
Let's get out of here...
Come on! Michael, We're leaving.
Let's Go!
This is a surprise to
your birthday.
What is it?
I'm sorry, really...
We thought you’d like it.
We have a beer, will dances.
I promised something.
Michael? Please!
"Here and elsewhere the glint y
and the world is a reflection of stars."
Oh kid, kid. Stop.
What?
Stop.
What’s wrong now?
Nothing’s wrong.
It’s nothing.
You know?
You never ask,
You never bother to
ask how I am.
You never say.
It just happens to be my birthday.
It’s my birthday, that’s all.
In fact, you’ve never even asked when it is.
Look if you want a fight, kid?...
No, I don’t want a fight.
What’s wrong with you?
What business is it of yours?
It’s always on your terms.
Everything!
We do what you want.
It’s always what you want.
My friends were giving me a party!
Well then why are you here?
Go back to your party.
Isn’t that what you want?
And it’s always me that has to apologize.
You don’t have to apologize.
No-one
has to apologize.
War and Peace, kid.
Now you must go back to your friends.
Michael. You all right?
It's him
Good.
Get the boy something to eat.
I think we all knew you’d come back
to us eventually.
Mr Berg. It is eight o’clock.
Your daughter.
Thank you.
Julia.
I'll not kept you waiting
I was early.
Welcome back.
So how will you decide?
I don’t know.
I’m happy back in Berlin, I suppose.
You’ve seen your mother?
I wanted to get away, that's all
It was Paris,
but it could have been anywhere.
Away from your parents?
I’m aware I was difficult.
I wasn’t
always open with you.
I’m not open with anyone.
I knew you were distant.
You know?
I’d always assumed it was my fault.
Julia.
How wrong can you be?
- See you soon.
- I’ll see you soon.
- Good night, Dad.
- Good night, Julia.
Those of you for the special seminar group.
Please stay on in this room.
Professor Rohl will be here in a moment.
Well...
we seem to be quite a small group.
A small group and a select one.
Clearly, this is going to be a
unique seminar.
We're going to start reading this, gentlemen.
- Karl Jaspers.
- And ladies...
"The question of German guilt."
So this is where you are.
Yes.
Come in.
You take work seriously.
Oh I don’t know.
You’re rather a serious boy.
It’s how I was brought up.
What about you?
Are you serious?
You’re sure you want to work tonight?
But I won’t work every night.
See you tomorrow.
We need help.
Why all the police?
They’re worried about demonstrators.
For or against?
both.
Is a circus.
All photographers are now asked to leave.
The defendants, please..
Please sit down!
The first thing I’m going to do is hear motions
from each of the defendants’ lawyers.
They’re going to be arguing that
there’s no reason
to keep the defendants in jail until the
outcome of the forthcoming trial.
Do you want a pen?
I’ve got a pen.
Hanna Schmitz.
Your name is Hanna Schmitz?
Yes.
Can you speak louder please?
My name is Hanna Schmitz.
Thank you.
You were born on October 21st, 1922?
Yes.
At Hermannstadt.
And you’re now 43 years old?
Yes.
You joined the SS in 1943?
What was your reason for joining?
You were working at the Siemens
factory at the time?
Yes.
You’d recently been offered a promotion.
Why did you prefer to join the SS?
Objection
I’ll re-phrase my question.
I’m trying to ascertain if she joined the SS freely.
Of her own free will.
I heard there were jobs
Go on...
I was working at Siemens when I
heard the SS was recruitin
Did you know the kind of work you’d
be expected to do?
They were looking for guards.
I applied for a job.
And you worked first at Auschwitz?
Yes.
Until 1944. Then you were moved to
a smaller camp near Cracow?
- Yes.
- Are you OK?
I’m fine.
... You then helped move the prisoners west
in the winter of 1944 in the so-called death marches?
- So what did you think?
- I do not know.
It wasn’t quite what I expecting.
Wasn’t it?
In what way?
What were you expecting?
I thought it was exciting.
Exciting?
Why? Why did you think it exciting?
Because it’s justice.
Societies think they operate by
something called morality
But they don’t.
They operate by something called law.
You’re not guilty of anything merely
by working at Auschwitz.
8,000 people worked at Auschwitz.
Precisely 19 have been
convicted, and only 6 for murder.
To prove murder you have to prove intent.
That’s the law.
The question is never ‘Was it wrong?’
but ‘Was it legal?’
And not by our laws.
No.
by the laws at the time.
with the law of the times.
But isn’t that...
What?
Narrow?
Oh, Yes. The law is narrow.
On the other hand, I suspect people
who kill other people
tend to be aware that it’s wrong.
Miss Schmitz, you’re familiar with this book..
Yes.
Parts of it have already been read
out in court.
It’s by a survivor,
a prisoner who survived
Ilana Mather...
She was in the camp, wasn’t she,
when she was a child?
She was with her mother.
Yes.
In the book, she describes a
selection process.
At the end of the month’s labour, every month,
sixty inmates were selected.
They were picked out to be sent from the
satellite camp back to Auschwitz.
That’s right, isn’t it?
Yes.
It’s right.
And so far, each of your fellow defendants
has specifically denied
being part of that process.
Now I’m going to ask you.
Were you part of it?
Yes.
So you helped make the selection?
You admit that?
Then...
tell me, how did that selection happen?
There were six guards,
So we decided we’d choose ten people each.
That’s how we did it - every month.
We’d all choose 10.
Are you saying your fellow
defendants took part in the process?
We all did.
Even though they’ve denied it?
You’re saying you
took part in the process.
than the "I", true
Ms Schmitz?
Did you not realise...
you were sending these women to their deaths?
Yes, but...
there were new arrivals,
new women were arriving all the time. So...
of course we had to move
some of the old ones on.
I’m not sure you understand...
We couldn’t keep everyone.
There wasn’t room.
No, but what I’m saying
let me rephrase: to make room,
you were picking women out and saying
‘You you and you have to be sent back to be killed?’
Well, what would you have done?
Should I never have signed up at Siemens?
Ms. Mather, they’re ready for you now.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Where's Michael?
- I do not know.
In your book you describe the
process of selection...
Yes.
You were made to work and then,
when you were no longer any
use to them,
then they sent you
back to Auschwitz to be killed.
Are there people here today who
made that selection?
Yes.
I need you to identify them
Can you please point them out?
Her
And her.
her.
Thank You!
Please continue.
Each of the guards would choose a
certain number of women.
Hanna Schmitz chose differently.
In what way differently?
She had favourites.
Girls, mostly young.
We all remarked on it,
she gave them food and places to sleep.
In the evening,
she asked them to join her.
We all thought
Well, you can imagine what we thought
And then we found out...