[Bell Tolling]
[Pigeons Cooing]
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Oh...
Ha! Ha ha ha ha!
[Whispers]
Take off your clothes.
What?
l said, take off
your clothes.
But you saw everything
last night.
Mm, but l need
to check something.
Shh.
Only for three seconds.
The bastard.
How does he
do it?
l've got to go.
Don't you ever spend the night
at the woman's place?
Never.
What about when a woman's
at your place?
l tell her
l get insomnia...
anything.
Besides, l have
a very narrow bed.
Are you afraid
of women, Doctor?
Of course.
l really like you,
Tomas.
You are the complete
opposite of kitsch.
ln the kingdom
of kitsch,
you would be...
a monster.
No, wait.
Sabina, l've got to go.
Ah!
Ha ha ha!
Oh...
Oh...oh...
No, wait. Wait.
Ha ha!
Now. What am l?
Ha ha ha ha!
Grrr...a monster.
Ha ha ha!
Room 6.
[Humming With Band]
Here we go.
[Drilling]
[Humming]
[Whistling]
[Splash!]
[Speaking Czech]
Oh! Oh...
Ah...
[Groaning]
Oh...
Oh!
[Coughing]
Oh, cognac.
Can you charge it
to my room?
Yes, of course.
Oh, that's funny.
You're in Room 6.
So?
And my shift
finishes at 6:00.
And at 6:00,
l have to be
back in Prague.
Well...
around 6:00.
[Bell Tolls]
Oh, l'll be back.
Wait.
[Singing]
Lo lo lo
Lo lo lo lo lo...
You know,
this is my bench.
Your bench?
Yes, l come here
every day to read,
to this same bench.
lsn't that funny?
Yes.
What are you
reading?
Anna Karenina,
by Tolstoy.
Oh, yes,
that Anna Karenina.
Yeah.
l would have come
earlier,
but...my mother...
You live
with your mother?
Well, l've checked out
of my room.
Are you leaving?
Yes, it's getting late.
l just came
for an operation.
A colleague of mine
was supposed to come,
but he injured
himself, so...
Well...
maybe l'll
come back sometime.
Why would you
come back here?
lt's so boring.
Nobody here reads.
Nobody here
discusses anything.
You know what l mean?
Yes.
Yes, l do.
Well.
[Starts Engine]
Nice to meet you.
Good-bye.
[Bells Tolling]
Tomas.
Are you only
searching for pleasure?
Or is every woman
a new land
whose secrets
you want to discover?
You want to know what
she's going to say
when she makes love?
Or how she will smile?
How she will whisper?
Groan...scream?
Maybe the very smallest...
unimaginable details...
Tiny things
that make one woman
totally unlike
any other.
What's my detail,
Doctor?
Your hat, Sabina.
The hat...
comes from
my grandfather's...
grandfather.
He lived
a long, long time ago.
A long time ago.
Tomas.
What are you
looking at?
Your eyes.
[Knock On Door]
Hello.
So...
you are in Prague.
l just arrived.
l have friends to see.
l'm here
on some business.
Mm-hmm.
l'm looking
for another job.
Ha...
Why don't you come in?
Are you alone?
Yeah.
Take off your clothes.
Achoo!
Excuse me.
l must have caught a cold
on the train.
Perhaps l better
take a look at you.
Come here.
My hands cold?
l'm very ticklish.
Does it hurt there?
Look up.
Down.
Left.
Right.
Ha ha...
Don't worry.
l'm a doctor.
A bit higher.
That's it.
Breathe.
[Breathes Deeply]
Again.
Cough.
That's fine.
Up we go.
Everything looks fine.
Fine.
Open your mouth.
Tongue.
Ah! Mmm...
Ooh!
Mmm! Mm!
Ah!
Aah!
[Ring]
Hi.
Tomas?
They called
from Geneva.
They are still
offering you that job.
Why should l go
to Geneva?
Everything's
fine here.
Well...l hope so.
You think the Russians
won't interfere?
Think about what
happened in Hungary.
They couldn't.
The world wouldn't allow it.
Besides, we have socialism
with a human face.
Who could be
against it?
Ah, my patient is here.
Which one?
Pigs are not allowed.
l told him to wait
in the truck.
But we will make
an exception.
Hello, Doctor.
You are not angry with me
because l brought
Mephisto?
Look, Doctor,
a gift for you.
Wonderful.
Oh, thank you!
Hmm.
So...Pavel.
Ha ha!
We operated
a month ago.
Yeah.
Any pains?
No.
Dizziness? Headaches?
Good. You can get
back to your farm.
We just need
a small procedure
to replace
the bone flap.
What time shall l expect
your visit tonight?
Ah...
l'm sorry,
l can't make it tonight.
Too bad.
Um...how about
tomorrow afternoon?
Tomorrow night.
So what l heard
was right.
Somebody has moved
into your place.
No.
l have my spies.
Good-bye, Doctor.
Ah...
[Tick-Tick-Tick...]
Ah!
Ah...
lt's not here.
You must have come
without your sock.
How could l have
come without it?
l wouldn't wear
only one sock.
You've been absent-minded lately,
always in a hurry.
Always looking
at your watch.
l'll lend you one
of my stockings.
You want me
to put this on?
lt's cold out,
Doctor.
Mm-hmm.
You think l'm doing
something silly.
Maybe.
How can l know?
What are we
talking about?
Tereza.
lf l had two lives...
with one, l'd have her
stay at my place.
With the other,
l'd kick her out.
Then l'd compare
and see which was best.
But we only live once.
Life's so light...
like an outline
we can't ever...
fill in...
or correct...
make any better.
lt's frightening.
She's looking for something
to do here in Prague, and l...
Now...
you want me
to help her?
She is not
qualified for anything,
but she takes
beautiful pictures.
l was wondering
if you might...
You mean...
you want me
to help you.
Come on in, Tereza.
Let's have some tea.
Yes. Why don't
you fix it?
Yeah, sure.
Hee hee!
lt's very messy
around here.
l always try not to get
too attached to a place,
to objects.
Or to people.
Hmm.
Tereza, come over here.
l want to show you
some pictures.
You know Man Ray?
No.
l like...
l like this one very much.
Mmm.
This is Lee Miller.
She's so...
She's so beautiful.
Tomas says
you're a photographer.
Well, l like to
take pictures, but...
Take pictures of what's
going on in the streets.
l'll help get
them published.
Thanks, Sabina.
l love
those pictures.
They were trying
something different.
Searching for
a new beauty.
Yes.
Something higher.
Here's the tea l made.
Aaah. Aaah.
What is it?
Tereza?
Oh, l had a dream.
l was at her place.
Sabina's.
ln her studio...
and you were
making love to her.
ln that
big bed of hers.
You made me
stand by a wall
and not move at all.
You made me watch.
And l had such pain
from seeing you
that l started to pierce needles
under my fingernails
to stop the pain
in my heart.
lt hurt so much.
Why did you
do it to me?
lt was just a dream.
Try to sleep.
l can't sleep.
Yes, you can. Come here.
l can't fall asleep.
You can sleep.
Sleep in my arms.
Like a baby bird.
Like a broom...
among brooms...
in a broom closet.
Like a tiny parrot.
Like a whistle.
Like a little song.
A song sung by a forest...
within a forest...
a thousand years ago.
[Hey Jude Sung ln Czech]
Oh!
[Announcer Talking ln Czech]
[Band Plays
That'll Be The Day]
Look! They are here!
Tereza's pictures!
Two full pages!
Thanks, Sabina!
Congratulations!
They're really great!
Tereza, this is
my colleague Jiri,
and this is the chief.
- l'm pleased.
- Hello.
Wonderful! You've really
captured a new spirit here.
You can see how
everything is changing.
Not everything.
Look over there.
Our comrades
with the Russians.
Some people
never change.
Some people are
always scoundrels.
How can you tell?
Does it show
in a man's face?
Can we judge
by a man's face
if he is
a scoundrel or not?
Let's look
at them and see.
Scoundrel.
- Scoundrel.
- Definitely.
- No doubt.
We know you.
Scoundrels.
What would you say
about Tomas?
Hmmm.
He's definitely
scoundrel.
Why?
ls it the mouth?
The sly eyes?
No, it's carefully hidden...
in the brain.
Such things are hidden
in all of our brains.
So what makes
the difference?
Maybe only
one millionth part.
Maybe there is
no difference.
These men don't even know
if they're scoundrels or not.
Are you serious?
More than 100,000 people
were imprisoned, tortured,
executed in their regime.
And now,
these men cry out
that they didn't
know anything...
that they were
misled or manipulated.
That they were...innocent.
Not innocent,
but, um...
unaware, perhaps.
They had to know
what they were doing.
Otherwise,
it's unthinkable.
lt doesn't matter
whether they knew or not.
- Boo!
[Singing ln Russian]
l've been thinking
about Oedipus.
Good King Oedipus.
ls sleeping with your mother
the same sort of crime?
When Oedipus realized that
he had killed his father--
unknowingly...
unknowingly killed his father...
and was sleeping
with his mother...
and that because of his crimes
plagues were
ravaging his city,
he couldn't bear
the sight of what he'd done.
He plucked out
his own eyes and left.
He did not feel innocent.
He felt he had to
punish himself.
But...
our leaders, unlike Oedipus,
they felt
they were innocent.
And when the atrocities
of the Stalinist period became known,
they cried,
''We didn't know!
We weren't aware
of what was going on.
Our conscience is clear.''
But the important
difference is...
they stayed in power.
And they should have
plucked their eyes out.
All l'm saying is that
morality has changed
since Oedipus.
[Music Becomes Jazzier]
Come on.
Yes!
Why don't you
write it down?
l'm not a writer.
lt will be published.
Our politics are in it.
l don't really care
about politics.
What do you
care about?
ls something
bothering you?
No, why?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
No...
When l watched you
dancing with another man...
l thought to myself,
''He could be her lover.''
You are jealous.
No, l'm not jealous.
You are.
l'm not.
l'm not jealous, Tereza.
He's jealous.
No, he isn't.
Who's he?
He's jealous
l'm not jealous.
He's jealous,
he's jealous
Whatever you say, Tereza.
You're jealous.
l'm not.
Yes, you are.
You're jealous.
l'm not jealous.
Doo be doo
be doo be doo
No!
You are!
l'm not.
Let go!
l won't let go!
You're jealous!
You are!
l'm not!
No! No! No!
Ha ha ha ha!
Will you marry me?
What? No!
Yes!
No!
- Yes.
- No.
Yes? Ha!
Be my witness?
Of course!
l'll have to buy
Mephisto a black tie.
Did you hear, Mephisto?
A black tie.
My dear fiances,
l am welcoming you
from the deep bottom
of my heart
on this very special day
when you freely decided
to be legally man and wife.
l suppose that
both of you know your duties
in supporting each other,
and l am sure
both of you know
your own medical records?
l have to
tell you this.
Don't think a life is
a walk on a sunny meadow.
Life isn't a walk
on a sunny meadow,
and life isn't a walk
on a rose garden.
Our socialist country
has done much for you.
Now it's up to you.
[Squealing]
Shh.
Shh!
l make you laugh?
No...no.
[Squealing]
Shh!
You are laughing at me?
l'm sorry. l'm sorry.
[Squealing]
l refuse to go on.
ln this country,
is nothing sacred anymore?
lf you can't be serious,
you don't deserve
to be married!
[Singing ln Czech]
Mmm!
Let's take one, Tomas.
lt will make us happy.
Choose one.
This one.
Hey!
My nephew from
the country's here!
Uncle!
Hey!
[Speaking ln Czech]
Let's call him Tolstoy.
When l first met you,
you were
reading Tolstoy.
lt can't be Tolstoy.
lt's a girl.
lt's a girl!
How about Anna Karenina?
lt doesn't look at all
like Anna Karenina.
Look.
lt's a man's face.
lt looks more
like Anna's husband.
Let's call her Karenin.
Karenin.
Come on, Karenin.
Let's go home.
Heh heh heh...
l like it very much.
King Oedipus.
lt's a very good idea.
And with those changes,
we can publish next week.
Eva, will you
type this, please?
Now we can publish
a piece like this.
lt's fantastic.
Think about it.
Complete rehabilitation of
the people who were prosecuted.
Complete freedom of speech,
of the press,
emancipation
from the Russians.
That's all we wanted.
And you think the Russians
will let us emancipate?
What can they do?
Nothing, Doctor.
Nothing, nothing, nothing!
Keep on writing.
Thanks, but surgery's easier.
[Dog Cries]
Take me to them.
Oh, you're awake.
To whom?
To the other women.
Take me to them
when you make love to them.
l'll undress them for you.
l'd like to.
Really.
l'll give them a bath
and bring them to you.
l'll do anything you like.
Other women's bodies
will be our playthings.
Tereza, what are
you talking about?
l know you see
other women.
l know it!
You can't hide it from me.
Every day,
l try to tell myself,
''Well, it's nothing.
lt's not important.
He's just playing around.
He can't resist it.
But he loves me.
l'm sure about that.
He loves me.''
''He loves me!''
But l can't stand it.
l tried hard.
l just can't.
Take me to them.
Don't leave me alone!
Tereza, calm down.
Stop talking.
Try to sleep.
You need
some sleep now.
l don't
want to sleep.
You're tired of me.
l know that.
[Ring Ring]
l can see it
in your eyes.
[Ring Ring]
Arf! Arf! Arf!
Hello.
Yes.
What?
Tereza!
[Engine Roars]
Here they come!
Arf arf!
Tereza, stay there.
Karenin!
Tomas.
l'm going to Switzerland.
What?
To Geneva.
Good luck.
Be careful.
[Machine Gun Fire]
- Aah!
[Singing ln Foreign Language]
[Bells Tolling]
[Violin Playing]
[Singing ln Foreign Language]
[Crash]
[Sirens]
[Explosion]
[Explosions]
What country
are you from?
The Netherlands.
Good. Take these.
Have them
published, please.
Tereza!
ldi!
Have you gone mad?
Don't you realize
that we love you?
That we always
loved you?
That we came
to protect you?
To protect?
To protect us
from what?
Did you give your pictures
to foreigners?
Yes, l did.
You could be shot
for that!
They are identifying people
from our photographs.
[Speaking Czech]
ls it your camera?
No.
l'm sure it's yours.
Who is this man?
Never seen him before.
lt's you!
No.
lt's you.
[Crowd Chanting]
No!
No! No!
Good luck.
You, too.
The invasion
of our country
constitutes a clear act
of aggression
against
an independent country.
Our Czech people
had the right and the duty
to fight against
the aggressor.
People who don't have
the courage to fight
with arms
in their hands
do not deserve freedom.
So why did you
emigrate?
Go back and fight.
lt's easy to tell
other people to fight.
[Sigh]
One day, everybody
will be asked,
''What did you do against
the communist regime?''
Excuse me.
l wanted to ask
you something.
Well, what do you
want to ask?
Why did you do
that back there?
Why do you want to know?
Who are you?
My name is Franz.
l came to that meeting
to listen.
No, no, l'm not
from the police.
l'm a professor
at the university.
l have nothing in common
with these people.
The only things holding
them together are defeats
and the reproaches
they address to one another.
lt's hard to be
in exile.
People feel
abandoned.
They feel a lack
of understanding.
They feel
at a loss, lonely.
Your country's occupied.
Are you indifferent to that?
l can't stand pointing fingers
and raised fists.
So what do you
want to do?
l want to go to lunch.
l'm hungry.
[Music Plays Faintly]
Ha ha ha!
When l was
a student in Paris,
l liked
the demonstrations,
the marches,
the crowds, the shouting.
l liked to be
part of it.
The whole world looked
like a grand march--
ever onward
to a better world.
Me, too. l marched
every year.
Really?
Yes, but l was
forced to march.
Everybody was.
The May Day parade--
the girls dressed the same.
Everybody smiling,
everybody throwing flowers.
Mmm.
l could never keep
in step.
The girls behind me
would step on my heels.
Ha ha ha!
What happened to your country
is a tragedy.
You think so?
Of course.
There was hope.
They killed it.
You're not going to
become boring, are you?
Waiter?
Can you stop
that noise?
Noise?
Yes--what
you call music.
l'll have to ask
the manager.
Everywhere music's
turning into noise.
Look.
These plastic flowers...
they even put them
in water.
Ha ha ha!
And look out there.
Those buildings--
the uglification
of the world.
The only place
we can find beauty
is if its persecutors
have overlooked it.
lt's a planetary process...
and l can't stand it.
ls anything wrong?
Wrong? No.
Everything is fine.
Well, it's
just that noise.
Could you stop it?
lt sounds like
dirty water.
l'm sorry, sir.
The other customers
do like this noise.
How can they eat food
and listen to shit?
Well, in that case,
we'll look for a place
with better taste.
Thank you.
Well...
l hope you didn't
mind leaving that place.
Just the opposite.
l like to
leave places.
l like to leave.
Ha ha ha!
So...
l hope you're
not having a bad time.
Oh, not at all, no.
l have a train
to catch in an hour.
You travel by train?
Always.
l love trains.
They are so erotic.
By the way, my wife
owns an art gallery.
Maybe she could
help you.
Oh, you are married?
Yes.
Watch out!
Be careful.
Mmm.
Ha ha ha!
Uhh.
Oh. Oh.
[Whimpers]
Ahem.
Well, welcome to Geneva.
Well, that's good work,
but it's too late.
Russians in Prague--
We've seen these
everywhere.
The events are
too remote now.
lt's over.
But there,
nothing is over.
Everybody--Everybody still demands
that the Russians leave.
There are strikes all over
the country, and protests,
but here, nobody
seems to care anymore.
Here's the story
about the nudists
in France.
Oh, thank you.
Wait. Just have
a look--
superb photographs
of Prague.
lt's a pity
we're just getting them now.
[Telephone Rings]
Have a look
at mine.
They have nothing
to do with yours.
Not at all.
They are the same.
Nothing's wrong
with the body.
lt's normal...
and everything normal
is beautiful.
You have a terrific sense
of the female body.
These provocative poses.
You'd be a topnotch
fashion photographer.
You ought to
get a model,
make a portfolio
for agencies.
l'll introduce you to the editor
of our garden section.
Yeah, sure.
They always need shots
of cactuses and roses.
Cactuses?
No.
You're too kind,
really,
but l'd rather be
a waitress or stay home.
But will you be fulfilled
sitting at home?
[Growling]
Arf arf!
What am l
going to do,
take pictures
of naked women?
Why does everybody want
to see pictures of naked women?
Are they
that interesting?
Hmm?
Blah!
See you later.
Are you working
this afternoon?
Yes, l'll be back late.
Will you be all right?
Yes, l suppose so.
Good.
Come with me
to Amsterdam in two days.
l've seen
Amsterdam.
You have?
A friend of mine
sent me
a post card
from there.
lt's taped up
over my toilet.
Haven't you noticed?
Tell me, Franz...
why do you always
take me to another city?
Why won't you make love
to me in Geneva?
l told you.
Tell me again.
Because l couldn't go to bed
with my wife.
You couldn't go
from one bed to another?
That's right.
Why?
l feel it would be
humiliating to my wife,
to me,
and to you.
lt might seem
ridiculous,
but that's
the way it is.
l have to go.
Um-hmm.
Say you'll
come with me.
l'll come with you.
lt's good to see you.
How are you?
Fine.
l'm fine.
Did Tereza come
with you?
Of course.
Good. How is she?
She's...so-so.
She's ok.
She's looking
for a job.
Good. l'd like to
see her sometime.
Of course.
What about you?
Fine.
l'm fine.
Good.
l met another man.
Uh-huh.
He's the best man
l've ever met.
Ha ha ha!
Oh.
He's bright,
handsome, good...
And he's crazy about me.
Good.
And he's married.
There's only one thing.
He doesn't like
my hat.
Your hat.
Your hat makes me
want to cry, Sabina.
Ha ha ha!
So...
l'll call you.
l'll see you soon.
Ha ha ha ha!
Oh...
Ah...
[Camera Shutter
Clicks]
Naked women.
[Ring]
Yes?
Oh, it's you!
Yes.
What?
Some woman said
that l should do some...
some nude shots.
Nude shots?
Yeah, nude shots.
For that,
we'd better have
a drink first.
Take a glass.
[Gulping]
How is Tomas?
Fine.
Haven't you
seen him?
No.
[Click...Click...
Click...]
Look at me.
Look up.
[Thunder]
[Rain Pattering]
[Camera Clicking]
Take off your clothes.
What?
Now it's my turn.
l don't like
to be naked.
l...
Take off your clothes.
Wait.
Ah! Oh!
Ha...
Ah!
Ha ha ha...
No! No!
[Click]
Look at me, Tereza.
[Breathing Deeply]
Ha ha ha ha...
Ha ha ha ha!
[Door Opens]
Ah!
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Tereza, meet Franz.
Ah!
She's a friend
from Prague,
another crazy chick.
Ha ha!
She's modeling for me.
Or l am for her,
or something.
l've left her.
What?
l've left my wife.
What did she say?
''Don't forget your tuxedo.''
She even helped me pack.
We're still friends,
l think.
l have to go home
to get some more things--
my books, my tuxedo...
and l want to make sure
she's all right.
We didn't argue.
l know you agree.
We have to live
in a glass house with no secrets.
We couldn't live
in lies anymore.
We have to live in truth.
Sabina, would you mind
if l stayed here
for a while?
lf it's no imposition.
Until l get my bearings.
lf it's all right, l'll...
l'll come back tomorrow...
and, uh...
Oh...
Oh, God.
Ha ha ha...
Ha ha...
Good-bye, Tereza.
See you again,
l'm sure.
Listen, Tereza...
l want you
to leave now.
l have things
l must do.
Sabina?
Maybe l should have stayed.
Stop running.
Stop leaving.
Franz was such a good man.
So...
what are you
going to do now?
Leave.
Ha ha ha ha...
Ah, Sabina.
l don't know.
l'll go to...
Paris, maybe.
Or to America.
Come to me.
You want to see
America?
Hmm?
Sometime.
Maybe l'm seeing you
for the last time.
Maybe.
Karenin.
[Whistles]
[Tereza's Voice]
''Tomas, l know
l'm supposed to help you,
but l can't.
lnstead of being
your support,
l'm your weight.
Life is very heavy to me,
and it is so light
to you.''
''l can't bear
this lightness, this freedom.
l'm not strong enough.
ln Prague,
l only needed you
for love.
ln Switzerland,
l was dependent on you
for everything.
What would happen
if you abandoned me?
l'm weak.
l'm going back
to the country of the weak.
Good-bye.''
''l'm sorry,
but l've taken Karenin.''
[Knock On Door]
And your camera.
Ha ha ha!
Ah, cognac?
[Pounds On Hood]
[Helicopter]
[Trumpets Play Dolefully]
[Knock On Door]
[Whimpering]
Are you all right?
Yes, fine.
And Karenin?
Fine, too.
What are you
going to do here?
l'll find something.
Oh, Tomas.
Tomas.
Oh...
Oh!
l really
don't like to do this.
l shouldn't
have to do this.
You remember the article you wrote
about King Oedipus?
How communist leaders
should have put out their eyes?
Yes, l'd almost forgotten.
Well, they haven't.
They've prepared
this little letter...
sort of retraction.
Say you got it wrong,
you really
didn't understand...
You sign. That's all.
Don't misunderstand.
They're not asking for
a public declaration.
They're just
prudent bureaucrats.
They've given me
their word.
They won't
publish anything.
l need you, Tomas.
l hope l can keep you.
You're not a writer,
savior of the country.
You're a doctor.
A scientist.
This article's so terribly
important to you?
lt couldn't be
less important.
Hi, Tomas.
Hi.
Tomas.
Hello, Jiri!
lt's nice to
see you back.
How are you?
Thanks, fine.
So...are you going to sign
the...thing?
What thing?
Mmm...your, um...
retraction.
What do you know
about my retraction?
Have you read it?
No.
But you know
how things work.
Who told you l had agreed
to go along with it?
See you.
Ha ha ha ha...
l suppose
a lot of them
have signed
these letters.
They're kept
on file.
They know they can be published
at any moment,
so they
keep quiet, see?
They can't say
anything anymore.
They accept
everything.
Cowardice slowly becomes
a rule of life.
Yes, l have
the feeling
that everyone would be
very happy to see me sign.
Everyone...
everyone but me.
So...what can
l do for you?
There is nothing you can do
for me, Doctor.
l represent
the Ministry of the lnterior.
Everybody at the Ministry
regrets seeing you here.
You are one of our best
brain specialists.
Just between us--
maybe l shouldn't
say it--
we don't all agree
with the drastic tactics
that are removing our top specialists
from their posts.
One can only be sorry
about all this.
May l?
Please.
You had a very good
position in Geneva,
and you came back
to our country.
We very much appreciate
your having returned,
but your place is at
the operating table.
l couldn't agree more.
Everybody agrees.
Then...
tell me, Doctor...
do you really think
that communists should pluck out
their own eyes?
You, who have healed
so many people?
That wasn't what l meant.
But that's how everyone
understood it.
And we can
only regret it.
How can you
let people think
that you,
a doctor,
want to deprive human beings
of their right to see?
Maybe someone
inspired this article?
No, no one.
Did you know
the publishers?
No.
You never spoke?
Once, they asked me over
to discuss the article.
Who was it
you talked to?
One of the editors.
What was his name?
l don't remember.
l've no idea.
What did he look like?
l can't remember.
Tell me
the truth, Doctor.
He was tall...
with...short, blond hair.
A little stooped, hmm?
Perhaps.
And how did he react?
What did
he say exactly?
He asked me
to make some changes.
So...
you might have been
manipulated, Doctor.
Used.
Whether you
meant to or not,
your article
contributed to
the anti-communist
hysteria.
Nobody requires a doctor
to understand politics.
Of course, we can't allow
a politically suspicious man
to operate on brains.
We have here
another declaration.
l would
advise you to sign.
''This temporary error...
due to bad influences from
so-called intellectuals...
doesn't in any way
put in doubt
my faithfulness to
the Communist party
or my admiration
for the Soviet Union.''
Of course, Doctor,
it's only a proposition,
a first draft.
lf there is something
you want to change...
after all,
it's your statement.
Just a paper
to keep in their files.
lt's nothing.
Just in case
someone reproaches them
for letting you
work here.
Good evening,
Excellency.
Why do they call him
Excellency?
He was an ambassador
in Vienna...before.
Oh.
Give me a cognac.
Ah. Ha.
Are you 18?
Yes.
May l see
your identification card?
Haaa.
Ugh! Drunk.
Give me a drink.
All right.
You have
beautiful legs!
l watched you
in the street.
Ugh.
Ow!
Stay here.
l want to look at you.
l love you!
Ohhh!
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
Madame.
You have no right
to serve alcohol to minors.
That was lemonade.
Do you think
l did not see
what else you put
into his lemonade?
What are you
talking about?
l've been watching you
for some time now.
Then be grateful
you're watching a beauty,
and keep your mouth shut.
You stay
out of this.
What business
is it of yours?
And what business
is it of yours, my friend?
Well...
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
That man comes here
all the time.
He's...
He's terribly unpleasant.
Promise me you won't
think about him anymore.
l promise.
l like hearing you
make me promises.
What is a beautiful
girl like you
doing in this
terrible part of Prague?
What are you doing here?
l'm living here.
l'm an engineer.
l just stopped here
by chance.
l live very near here.
[Tapping]
You're a doctor,
aren't you?
Yes.
May l see you
for a moment?
l have
windows to do.
Oh, don't worry about it.
Come.
Come in.
Don't worry
about the window.
l'll tell them
all the work has been done.
A glass of wine?
Thank you.
That would be very nice.
Sit down.
l've heard
so much about you.
When l saw you,
l said to myself,
''What a coincidence.
He's the one
who can help me.''
Of course, l'll pay
for the consultation.
l've had a pain
in my back
for a few months,
and l would
like to get
your opinion
about it.
Take off your clothes.
Everything?
Everything.
lt's, uh...
here.
[Sniffing]
[Sobbing]
What's the matter?
Tell me what's wrong.
What's wrong?
You forgot
to wash your hair.
What are you
talking about, Tereza?
Your hair
smells of a--
What?
Of another
woman's sex!
l thought you had
come back here for me.
l did come back here
for you, Tereza.
Then why do you keep
seeing other women?
l don't know
what to say to you.
l know, l know.
You've explained it
a thousand times.
A thousand times.
There is love
and there is sex,
and sex is entertainment,
like football.
l know it's light.
l wish l could
believe you, but...
How can someone make love
without being in love?
l just don't know.
Let me try.
Oh, no.
You'd reject me
if l tried.
l wish l could
be like you...
insensitive...
strong...
Strong.
[Voices Arguing ln Czech]
Oh, hello.
l just tried--
Come in.
lt's a very
simple place.
l hope you
don't mind.
No, not at all.
All these books
are yours?
Yes.
What do you
want to drink?
Anything.
Wine?
No. Coffee?
Ok.
l'll go fix some.
Shall l take your coat?
Yes.
Sit down.
Thank you.
l'm very glad
you came here.
l didn't want
to come here.
Of course not.
[Creaking]
There is somebody here,
behind that curtain.
You're being silly.
Draw aside
the curtain.
l told you--
you're being silly.
So why don't you draw aside
the curtain, please?
Look. Nothing.
And over here.
l can feel
that you want it.
What are you
looking at?
But be careful.
lt was very well
set up--
a young,
provocative drunkard,
then the other one,
the one who
attacked you.
Then the third one,
who gained your confidence
just because
he took your side.
The engineer?
The so-called engineer.
Why do you look afraid?
You have nothing
to be afraid of.
But l went
to see him,
at his place,
with my dog
and a friend.
He offered us
some...some coffee.
How do you know
it was his place?
They have a lot
of places they can use.
Pretty cheap place
for an engineer.
You know what they do
with foreign diplomats?
A beautiful girl,
an apartment,
a hidden camera.
Then they blackmail
the poor man.
And he does what
he is told to do.
That's Vienna in '61.
That's me there,
just behind Kennedy
and Khruschev.
l'm in the back.
You can hardly see me.
Are you sure
he was from the police?
l'm not sure of anything.
Anybody can be
from the police.
[Laughter]
Maybe your engineer
is a real engineer.
Ah!
Who knows?
They know.
And now they have
what they wanted.
Now you are afraid.
[Crying Softly]
Tomas.
l don't want
to stay here.
l want to go away,
to leave.
To leave?
Again?
We left here once.
We were in Switzerland.
Then we left Switzerland.
Now you want
to leave again. Why?
l don't understand.
Prague has grown
so ugly.
[Crying]
No.
l know there's
another reason.
[Footsteps]
Oh...
Please tell me.
l want to leave.
They've taken our passports.
There's nowhere
we can go.
We can't go anywhere.
Maybe we can.
[Humming]
Ha ha ha!
[Snorts]
Mephisto is big now.
Huh? Look, look.
Look, Karenin.
Mephisto's here.
Ah!
Phooey.
Ha ha ha ha ha!
[Cow Mooing]
Karenin prefers
Mephisto to dogs.
She thinks other dogs
are silly.
[Snort]
Ha ha...
Do you know why
l love Mephisto?
Because he's
very bright,
but at the same time,
he doesn't know anything.
After all,
he doesn't know
that life is
impossible here now.
Nothing left here.
The church is gone.
No place to drink
beer now.
lt's good...
very good.
[Slurp]
lf you two
ever change your mind...
it won't be easy to leave.
We'll never leave.
Arf! Arf! Arf!
Moo!
Yah!
Ha ha ha!
Can l help you?
Uh!
Ha ha ha!
Aah!
Ah!
[Mooing]
[Cowbells Ringing]
Look at Karenin.
l don't like
the way she's running.
Yes, you're right.
[Whistles]
Karenin, come on.
Come on.
Come on, girl.
Let's have
a look at her.
[Whimpering]
What is that?
lt's from the vet.
lt's the result
of the tests.
What did they say?
Cancer.
Oh, look at that.
Look at it.
Oh, it smells
so good. Look.
Come on, Karenin.
Look, Tereza
loves it, too.
Oh, look at that.
Oh, oh...
Grr.
Mm...mmm...
mmm...
Oh, she's smiling.
Oh, Karenin,
it's so good
to see you eat again.
l was forced
to love my mother.
But not to love
this dog.
You know, Tomas...
maybe...maybe l
love her more
than l love you.
Not more.
l mean
in a better way.
l'm not jealous
of her.
l don't want her
to be different.
l don't ask her
for anything back.
l don't think
we should wait.
[Dog Whimpers]
lf we do, she'll have to
go through terrible pain.
Yeah.
You should do it
yourself.
Yeah.
Look.
She's smiling.
Just hold her
and talk to her.
Don't be scared.
Don't be scared,
Karenin.
You won't feel
any pain there.
lt'll be
beautiful there.
You'll have
cows to chase.
[Dog Whimpers]
And Mephisto
will be there.
Mephisto will
be there.
Don't be scared.
Aaah!
[Speaking Czech]
Tomas!
Aah...
What happened?
Shoulder.
Now, lie down.
Lie down.
Arrrr...
Not this way. Come on!
Turn around.
All right, let go.
Let go!
Hold that arm.
Errr...
You've dislocated
your shoulder,
and l'm going to
put it back for you.
lt's going to hurt.
Yaaah!
You ready?
Aaggghh!
And again.
Oorrrhh!
One more time.
Come on.
Ah!
Whew.
Do you feel better?
Your wife is
damn beautiful today.
You dumb idiot.
Tereza is always pretty.
Yes, l know,
but especially today.
Seeing you
in this dress
makes me want
to dance with you.
Yes! Let's all
go and dance!
Sure, but where?
l know where.
We can go
to Milos' Tavern.
lt's 40 kilometers
away.
l'll drive.
l'll drink.
And we'll take you
and Mephisto,
the dancing pig.
[Snorts]
And all the women
will faint
when they get an eyeful
of those two pigs
walking in together.
Ha ha ha!
Yai!
Let's go!
[Thunder]
[Singing ln Czech]
[Pianist And Violinist Play
Sentimental Journey]
[Pig Squeals]
Ha ha ha ha!
[Yelling ln Czech]
Shh!
No pigs allowed.
Ah, come on!
He's wearing a tie!
No. Everyone who comes here
must order a drink.
Only one?
Did you hear that,
Mephisto?
Ha ha ha ha!
Wine for everybody
and beer for him...
[Snorts]
A large one.
Make it a pilsner.
When Mephisto
drink wine,
he goes crazy.
Ha ha ha ha!
Ha ha ha!
[Applause
As Song Ends]
There's no girls
for me...
except you,
Tereza.
[Musicians Play]
Tomas...
No, no,
l can't drink.
Ah...
l must not.
l'm driving.
Ho ho ho! Driving.
Listen.
Why not spend the night here,
you and Tereza.
You take the truck tomorrow.
Ah.
[Mephisto Squeals]
Hey!
[Speaking Czech]
Ha ha ha!
[Burping]
Ya-ha!
[Seagulls Calling]
Nice.
[Whistling]
Excuse me.
Hey, Sam.
l got a special delivery
here for you,
from Europe.
l'll see you, Sabina.
See you.
[Bell Rings
ln Distance]
What is it?
Bad news?
Some friends died.
They were coming back
from spending the night
in some small hotel
there,
gone there to dance,
and they...
lt was raining, and...
the brakes on their truck
didn't work.
They were killed instantly.
l was...
l was their closest friend.
Sorry. Damn shame.
Come to our place
for dinner tonight,
if you feel
up to it.
[Musicians Play Tango]
Tomas...
what are you thinking?
l'm thinking
how happy l am.