(CROWD CHEERING)
Come on, come on, come on.
All right, here we go.
MAN: Take a seat, buddy!
Come on.
It was a good play.
Are you gonna be
like this all day?
I don't know. Is it gonna
be like this all day?
I don't know.
It's up to you.
I have no room to sit.
I got no room to sit.
I'm sitting next to
a guy who's sitting
like he's at home
on the toilet
with his legs spread.
Please don't crowd people.
Relax, please. Look at me.
I am relaxed.
Look how I'm sitting.
Why are you
sitting like that?
Because... What do you think?
Why'd you wake me up
for this shit?
Because I'm trying to relax
and have a nice day.
Sweating in the sun
like a Tijuana whore.
VENDOR: Ice-cold soda!
Get your soda here!
VENDOR: On the right.
Coming down there.
Pass that on down there.
Hey, hot dog guy,
can I get six hot dogs
down here, please?
Right away.
GARY: And make it right,
please.
You know, with the mustard
and the ketchup
and the relish.
Don't make me
hit you up for more.
I thought we were going
to Wiener Circle after this.
We will.
Then why are you
getting hot dogs?
Pass this down, please.
You can keep the change.
Do you want
one of the hot dogs?
GARY: You can have a hot...
You want a hot dog?
Do you want a hot dog, miss?
No. Thank you.
You can have one.
That's okay.
Go ahead.
You can have a hot dog.
No, I don't want one.
Excuse me, sir?
Would you mind
passing the lady
one of the hot dogs?
I'm good, thanks.
You don't have to share.
You can have your own.
Thanks. That's really
nice of you.
Just have one, please.
Okay, give me a hot dog.
Somebody give her a hot dog.
I got... The big guy can't
eat all of them. Have one.
Have you ever had one before?
A hot dog?
At the ballpark?
I have. I believe I have.
Okay, good.
Thank you.
Well, enjoy this one.
Thanks.
Do you like mustard?
No, I'm okay.
It's much better
with a topping. Here.
I'm just kidding,
I'll give you two.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Cheers!
Thanks.
We'll share it.
It's a good dog.
I like the hot dog. I know.
That's nice.
You have a problem
with me eating a hot dog,
guy?
I'm trying to watch the game
and have a hot dog.
I'll smack him
in his head.
No, just leave him alone.
Hey, you want
to go get a drink?
No.
I'm with somebody, sorry.
Who? The guy with
the tucked-in shirt
and the visor?
What, is that like a brother?
The guy was not
your brother, then.
Who is this guy?
He's not my brother.
Who's this...
I'm getting mad now.
I'm jealous. Who is this guy?
Who are you?
I don't know.
I'm kidding with you.
Who's the guy with
the tucked-in stuff?
Is that a boyfriend?
Uh, it's...
I'm going.
Do you think
you'll marry him?
What?
'Cause I know
you've thought about it.
The first time
you laid eyes on him,
you probably thought,
"I wonder if I could marry
this guy in plaid shorts who
tucks his shirt in. No way."
Then when you kissed him,
you said, "I can't believe it.
"I had a lot to drink
tonight. I'm kissing
the tucked-in guy."
My point is, if you're
not gonna marry him...
Yeah.
...and if it's not forever,
then you really don't have
anything to lose in
taking me up on my offer.
Uh-huh. Well, I'm gonna go.
Okay. Me, too.
Okay.
To where? On an
ice-breaking first date?
Well, no, I don't think...
Listen.
If you want to stay
off the market
while you're with
I'm-not-the-one-
but-I'm-comfortable,
then you can do that.
But for all you know,
I just offered you
a get-out-of-bored-Iove-
for-free card
with no strings attached.
God, you're crazy.
No, I'm not crazy.
And a lot of times people go,
"Oh, that's crazy,"
and then they go,
"It's genius."
That's what happened
when the person invented fire.
They burned that witch.
And guess what, then they got
warm and they ate good stuff.
Now, where are we headed to?
Let's not make this weird,
'cause I'm not good on dates.
No. You know what?
I'm better just to kind of
hang out and,
if we don't have fun,
I might go my separate way.
Okay.
I'm not committing
to anything. I'll go hang out
with you for a little bit.
That's not gonna happen.
But I can't say for sure.
(YOU'RE MY BEST FRIEND
PLAYING)
GARY: All right, all right,
everybody. Welcome to
Three Brothers Bus Tours.
I'm brother number two.
It's good to have you here.
That's right, there's plenty
of seats here up front.
I promise I won't bite.
I'm not a biter.
I'm psyched to have you here.
Okay, a couple quick
ground rules. Please
don't jump off the bus.
Weird. Not fun for anybody.
Also, no throwing objects
at pedestrians,
unless, of course,
they deserve it. Okay?
We are not at work today.
We are on vacation today.
And if you can't blow it
out here on the big funny bus,
where the hell can you?
I do split the tips
with my driver, Shondra.
We don't want her back out
turning tricks.
That was a weird time
for everyone.
Seriously. Honest to God.
And I was a customer.
Long time ago.
Come on, everybody,
let's get loose!
I'm gonna ask you once.
Show me that you mean it.
Don't make me ask you twice.
Are you ready to see Chicago?
That's what I'm talking about.
Shondra, put this baby
in the air.
Let's get the blood flowing.
Let's get everyone up
and let's loosen it up.
Coming up here,
you're gonna notice
one of the only buildings
to survive the fire of 1871.
That is the original
Chicago Water Tower
and Pumping Station.
(PHONE RINGING)
CHRISTOPHER: Happy Holidays.
Marilyn Dean Gallery.
The artist was inspired
by the neoclassical movement.
CHRISTOPHER: No, she doesn't.
But wanted to reflect it
with an abstract bent.
CHRISTOPHER: Okay, bye-bye.
And how much is it?
$35,000.
Happy Holidays.
Marilyn Dean Gallery.
Hold, please.
Will you excuse me
for a moment?
Sure. Go ahead.
Christopher?
Yes, sweetie.
Hi, honey.
Hi.
Christmas was months ago.
Don't remind me.
I miss it so much.
Yeah, I know.
But today is not a holiday.
I know for a fact
that people like
my spirit on the phone
and they dig the energy
that I give them.
Okay. I'm just saying,
I don't think Marilyn Dean
will "dig" the energy.
Oh, no.
She's the one that told me
to be creative. So...
I know. It's just... Okay.
What is the next holiday
coming?
The Fourth of July,
is that what's next?
Well, if you want
to get technical,
there's Memorial Day,
there's Flag Day.
Some people recognize
Father's Day as a holiday.
I don't.
I get it. I get it.
Well, on those days
you can say, "Happy Holidays."
Every other day,
"Good morning, good afternoon,
"good evening,
Marilyn Dean Gallery."
Okay?
Okay.
I'm so sorry about that.
Oh, no.
So, now this is a new piece
by Zakrzewska.
What do you think of this?
Can I be honest with you?
Please.
Other than taking
an art history class
in college,
which I pretty much
slept through, I don't have
the first clue about art
or how to go about buying it.
I mean, like that painting.
I mean, I don't see the point
in buying something that
I could have done myself.
Yeah. I completely agree
with you.
You know, an art teacher
of mine once said,
"Never buy a piece of art
that you don't have to have."
You know, don't worry
about who the artist is
or how much it's worth.
I mean, you have to live
with it every day. You have
to walk by it every day.
You know, you have to
really love it. You have
to really appreciate it.
It's kind of like
picking a mate.
(EXCLAIMING)
GARY: Hey, honey!
Hi.
How's it going?
BROOKE: It's good.
Oh, wow. You got
a lot happening.
I know.
Very exciting.
I am starving.
Oh, careful. That's really...
That's very hot.
Oh, that's hot, hot, hot.
Yep.
Jesus.
Hey, honey,
you've got to really...
You should get ready, okay?
Oh, you look great.
Thank you.
Got a lot of nice stuff.
Got a pizza.
All kinds of stuff.
Terrific.
I just need you
to decide what to...
You know, I did everything.
(TV CLICKS)
(COMMENTATOR CHATTERING)
Gary?
Yeah?
Oh, come on! Really?
You got three lemons.
What my baby wants,
my baby gets. You know that.
Yeah, but I wanted 12.
Baby wanted 12.
Why would you want 12 lemons?
Because I'm making
a 12-lemon centerpiece.
So, no one's actually
even eating them?
They're just show lemons?
Yeah. They're just
show lemons. Shown in
the center of the table.
I'm glad you find that
amusing,
but I cannot fill a vase
with only three lemons.
Well,
can't you just use, like,
maybe a drinking glass?
I'm not gonna use
a drinking...
We could have
a smaller version
of a centerpiece.
I'm not gonna use
a drinking glass
for our centerpiece.
You know what?
I've got an idea.
Why don't we go ahead and
scratch the centerpiece idea
altogether,
because the chicken
that burnt my mouth
could maybe use
a little bit of lemon
on top of it.
Guess what? Now we've made
a better meal versus something
visually nice to look at.
What are you do...
What's happening here?
What are you doing?
(STAMMERING) Oh, I had
such a long day on the bus.
I need a little bit
of down time.
My feet are killing me.
Gary, come on,
my feet are killing me, too.
I'm exhausted.
I worked all day.
Went to the market.
I cleaned this entire condo
and then I've been cooking
for the last three hours.
Come on. Help set the table.
GARY: Sweetheart.
What?
You've done such a great job
already. Don't you want
to finish it yourself
and have that personal power
of that accomplishment?
Set the table.
Listen to me.
Do you think that
when Michelangelo, right,
was painting
the Sixteenth Chapel,
that he said,
"Hey, guys, you know,
I did pretty good
on the first 15 chapels,
"but why don't you help me
design this one?
"And maybe
you could help me...
Give me a brush
"and you guys can
grab brushes, and we can all
make a great chapel." Uh-uh.
No, he didn't.
And you wanna know
what the results were?
A masterpiece.
Okay. It's the Sistine Chapel,
not the Sixteenth,
and I bet when Michelangelo
asked for 12 brushes,
they didn't bring him three.
Yeah. Okay, all the talking
is really starting
to drain me,
and now I'm gonna have to
watch the highlights later
to see what I missed here.
Honey, look, Gary, just...
Down time's important.
Gary, please just
take a shower, okay?
Down time's important.
'Cause this is what
I don't want to have happen.
I don't want the doorbell
to ring. I'm then forced
to answer the door,
entertain people,
and I'm still cooking dinner.
Yeah.
Okay?
You're absolutely right.
Let's do that. The second
that this inning's over...
Gary.
There's one out all ready.
They're gonna be here
in 20 minutes.
Baby, have you ever seen
a shower of mine take
more than four minutes?
Yes, I have. Come on.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Oh, great!
They're here. Okay.
Table's not set.
Dinner's not ready.
Would you please
just let my parents in?
I gotta jump in the shower.
What?
(DOORBELL RINGING)
I gotta go.
Gary. Gary.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
GARY: Well, seeing how
our families haven't
had many opportunities
to get to know one another,
we figured, what better way
than to break some bread?
So, everyone,
thank you for coming
and enjoy the meal.
ALL: Cheers.
Cheers, honey.
Mrs. Grobowski.
Nice to meet you.
Thank you.
DENNIS: Cheer with the sons.
GARY: Sweetheart,
cheers to you.
Darling, I see that you put
those Feng Shui books
that I sent to you
to good use.
This place is
so well balanced.
Thanks, Mom.
Yeah, the energy in this place
is just amazing.
WENDY: Yes.
Well, the energy in the condo
might be a little more amazing
if we had a pool table.
Gary, we've already
discussed that.
We're gonna get a pool table
when we get a bigger place.
The place is plenty big now,
if you wanted a pool table
because...
Gary.
Yeah. You could take
the dining room table,
go ahead and move her
in the living room.
BROOKE: Really?
GARY: Plenty of room.
And put a dining room table
in the living room? Okay.
How do you...
I mean, what do you do
with a dining room table?
Eat on it.
We'd have no furniture
in the living...
Where's the furniture go?
All I'm saying is,
it would be nice
to be able to shoot some pool.
Well, this isn't a dorm.
Look, baby,
I completely understand.
There's halls and stuff.
I mean, you can go...
We will wait
and get a pool table
when we have a bigger place.
Thank you.
The food is outstanding.
It is delicious food.
DENNIS: It's outstanding.
LUPUS:
Yeah, it really is nice.
Okay, everybody.
Time for the joke of the day.
Knock, knock.
Dad. Dad, come on.
Who's there?
Norma Lee.
Norma Lee, who?
Normally, I don't go around
knocking on doors,
but would you like to buy
an encyclopedia?
LUPUS: I got a joke.
I got a joke.
(ALL CHUCKLING)
How's it going?
I got a joke for you.
What do you get when you cross
a gay Eskimo and a black guy?
All right, look,
I think we've had enough
with the jokes for tonight.
Thank you, though.
Let's just talk
with each other.
All right.
I saw that Three Brothers
article in the Trib this week.
Sounds like you guys are up
to some pretty exciting stuff.
Basically, our big goal is to
try to take Chicago tourism
by air, land and sea.
We're still in the ground
phase with the buses.
But as soon as we get
our infantry established,
then we'll take it
to the squids.
Yeah.
Boats. Boats.
Oh, boats.
As soon as we control
the waterway, then we'll
bring in air supports
and then we'll pretty much
control everything.
You know, Dennis,
the way your face lights up
when you describe
your ambitions,
it's really inspiring.
Oh, thanks.
Because I understand
how you feel that passion.
RICHARD: And sharing it
with other people, I think
that's what life's about.
I don't feel that about
boats and squibs... Squids?
ALL: Squids.
Sorry.
CAROL: Yeah.
But I do feel it
about singing.
With my a cappella group,
The Tone Rangers.
Although it's not
as aggressive as your dream,
it's really
more of a brotherhood.
It's like a musical team.
It's like a symphony of guys.
Guy symphony.
And it's very hard
to describe the true magic
of a group of guys
singing in perfect harmony.
It's transcendent.
But it's still very real.
I guess the best way
to put it in words is just...
(SINGING SINGLE NOTE)
Even that doesn't do it.
That doesn't do it
because that's just
one person.
And what I'm talking about is
the pulse of the collective.
Oh, heck. Let me just
show you how it's done.
Dad, how about
a little percussion?
RICHARD: Tap-tap-tappy.
Tap-tap-tappy.
And, Mom, high-hat.
(HISSING)
RICHARD: Good, Mom.
Excellent. And Gary!
(RHYTHMICALLY)
On the kick drum! Come, come!
That's Gary! Come, come
with the kick drum. Come!
Come, come with the kick drum.
Gary, on the kick drum.
Come, come.
That's Gary on the kick drum.
Go! And Gary. In the house.
Come, come.
I'm not with you.
With the kick drum.
Come, come.
I'm just not really
the kick drum kind of guy.
I'd rather be just a listener
and enjoy all the banging
that he's doing and the...
You know, Gary,
that's your prerogative.
That's your right, to listen.
Meantime, I've gotta talk
to Brooke about something.
It's called the bass line.
Excuse me.
Okay.
(PITCH PIPE PLAYING)
(HUMMING RHYTHMICALLY)
(SCATTING)
(HISSING)
Good, Carol.
Good, Brooke.
(ALL SINGING)
RICHARD: Yes, Dennis.
(WHISPERING) Be nice.
RICHARD: Totally awesome.
(MIMICKING METALLIC CLANGING)
Move yourself
You always live your life
Never thinking of the future
Prove yourself
You are the move you make
Take your chances
win or loser
See yourself
You're every step you take
You and you
and that's the only way
Shake
WENDY: Shake!
Shake yourself
You're every move you make
So the story goes
CAROL: Thank you so much.
BROOKE: Okay, bye.
WENDY: Thank you so much.
CAROL: It was great
to see you.
Okay. Come on.
Have a good night.
It was really nice, Gary.
Nice to see you. You, too.
Good to see you guys.
Thanks, Brookie.
Oh, honey.
Thank you, sweetie.
You're still
my favorite singer.
Stop it.
Love you, sis.
And I'd love for you
to come to a live performance
of The Tone Rangers
singing live. That's
something you'd really enjoy.
It was good seeing you.
Okay.
Thank you.
All right.
Bye, darling.
Thank you for such a...
Okay. Okay, Mom.
We'll see you soon.
Bye, dear. Thanks, darling.
See you later.
Okay, buddy.
Oh, now, are you sure
that we can't help you
clean up?
No, no. I think we're
gonna be great. We'II...
Yes?
So nice of you to offer,
but we got it. Thank you.
Oh, it was such fun.
Great.
I love you.
Great to see you.
Good night, sweetie.
Thank you so much.
I appreciate it.
All right, guys.
WENDY: Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Thanks for coming.
Love you, too.
MAN ON TV: Are you blind?
(HORN TOOTING)
Oh, no, no! My demos!
(MAN ON TV SCREAMING)
Well, I'm gonna
go do the dishes.
Cool.
It'd be nice if you helped me.
Damn it.
MAN: Way to go!
No problem. I'll get them
a little bit later.
I'm just gonna
hit the streets here
for a little bit.
Gary, come on,
I don't want to do them later.
Let's just do them now.
It'll take 15 minutes.
Honey, I am so exhausted.
I just honestly want
to relax for a little bit.
If I could just sit here,
let my food digest,
and just try to enjoy
the quiet for a little bit.
Get some! Get some! Get some!
That's what happens.
And we will...
You know, we can clean
the dishes tomorrow.
Gary, you know I don't like
waking up to a dirty kitchen.
Who cares?
I care! All right? I care!
I busted my ass all day
cleaning this house
and then cooking that meal.
And I worked today.
It would be nice
if you said thank you
and helped me with the dishes.
Fine. I'll help you
do the damn dishes.
Oh, come on. You know what?
No. See?
That's not what I want.
You just said that you want me
to help you do the dishes.
I want you to want
to do the dishes.
Why would I want to do dishes?
Why?
See, that's my whole point.
Let me see if I'm
following this, okay? Are you
telling me that you're upset
because I don't have
a strong desire
to clean dishes?
No. I'm upset because
you don't have a strong desire
to offer to do the dishes.
I just did.
After I asked you!
Jesus, Brooke,
you're acting crazy again.
Don't you call me crazy.
I am not crazy.
I didn't call you crazy.
You just did.
I didn't call you...
No, I didn't.
I said you're acting crazy.
You know what, Gary?
I asked you to do
one thing today,
one very simple thing,
to bring me 12 lemons
and you brought me three.
God damn it. If I knew
that it was gonna be
this much trouble,
I would have brought home
24 lemons. Even 100 lemons.
You know what I wish?
I wish everyone that was
at that goddamn table
had their own little private
bag of lemons.
Honest to God!
Gary, it's not
about the lemons.
Well, that's all
you're talking about.
I'm just saying
it'd be nice if you did
things that I asked.
It would be even nicer
if you did things without
me having to ask you!
Well, I do seem to remember
doing something for you
this morning
without you asking.
Gary, come on.
What? I'm serious. Come here.
You know what? I'm serious.
I really am.
I am, too.
Come on.
You knew I was working today
and I made that meal.
And you could have thought
to yourself, you know,
you could have said,
"Yeah, I think I'm gonna
get Brooke some flowers."
You said
on our very first date
that you don't like flowers,
that they're a waste of money.
Every girl likes flowers,
Gary.
You said that you
don't like flowers.
I'm supposed
to take that to mean
that you do like flowers?
No. This is not about...
You're not...
God, you're not getting it.
You're not getting this,
Gary, okay?
It's not about the lemons.
It's not about the flowers.
It's not about the dishes.
It's just about...
How many times do I have to
drop hints about the ballet?
You know I can't stand...
Brooke, come here.
We've talked about
the damn ballet.
I hate the goddamn ballet!
You got a bunch of dudes
in tights flopping around
for three hours.
It's like a medieval
techno show. It's a nightmare.
I sit there in a sweat.
The whole thing, I do,
wondering when the hell's
the goddamn nightmare
gonna end.
Go to a damn ballet.
It's not about you
loving the ballet, Gary.
It's about the
person that you love
loves the ballet
and you wanting to spend time
with that person.
Not when they're
at the ballet.
Okay. Forget the ballet!
Forget the ballet!
I will.
We don't go anywhere together.
We just went
to Ann Arbor together.
To Ann Arbor.
To the
Michigan-Notre Dame game.
You think screaming,
drunk kids and leprechauns
doing backflips, that's fun.
That's fun for me.
Come on, man.
I did that for you.
What do you...
How do you show up for me?
I'm up on the bus
every goddamn day for you!
Come on. You...
I'm busting my ass
to be the best tour guide
in the damn city,
so I can make enough money
to support both of us
and hopefully you won't
have to work one day.
I want to work.
All I ask, Brooke,
is that you show a little bit
of appreciation.
That I just get 20 minutes
to relax when I come home,
instead of being attacked
with questions and nagged
the whole damn time.
You think that I nag you?
That's all you do!
All you do is nag me!
"The bathroom's a mess."
"Your belt doesn't match."
"Hey, Gary, you should
probably go work out."
Nothing I ever do
is ever good enough!
I just want to be left
the hell alone!
Really? Is that
what you want, Gary?
Is that what you want?
Yeah.
That's what you want?
Fine. Great.
Do whatever the hell you want.
You leave your socks
all over this house,
dress like a pig,
play your stupid-ass
video game.
I don't care, I'm done.
What?
I'm done!
I don't deserve this.
I really do not deserve this.
I deserve somebody
who gives a shit.
I'm not spending one more
second of this life
with some inconsiderate prick!
You're a prick!
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(DOOR SHUTS)
Addie, it just became
so clear tonight
how much he takes me
for granted.
What happened?
BROOKE:
Just the same old shit.
I asked him to do one thing
and he didn't do it.
Then he complained
that he had to do anything,
and I just felt like
I had no choice.
No, sweetie,
you did have a choice, okay?
And it sounds like you
made the right one.
You respected yourself.
But it's just not what I want.
I don't want to break up
with him.
I don't. I just want him
to say thank you. I want him
to want to do the dishes.
I just want him to want
to take me to the ballet.
I want him to get me
12 lemons! You know...
I just want him to care
enough about this relationship
to want to work on it.
Okay, you know what?
I'm putting on my shoes
and I'm gonna be there
in 15 minutes.
No, Ad. Don't.
Please, I really don't
want to see anybody.
I really don't.
But, look, I'm worried
about you, okay?
And I can hear you in there
banging around your dishes.
And I don't want you
getting out your Clorox
and your rubber gloves,
and taking this out
on the kitchen.
Look, look, look.
Okay. Tonight just...
It just got a little
out of hand,
and hopefully
he's just gonna realize
that he's got some changes
to make and he's gonna...
He's gonna come home
and apologize.
Okay?
That's what's gonna happen.
GARY: I feel like, I don't...
You know, like, you dress
however you want to dress.
You know,
do whatever you want to do.
I'm done with
the relationship.
Whatever.
So, it's just kind of,
"You're done
with the relationship?"
Well, you're obviously
hurt about it.
She got to you. You're hurt.
I'm not.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
She hurt you.
Will you look at me?
I'm not heartbroken.
I'm a little shocked.
I'm a little surprised.
Gary, you're devastated.
Now, what's the name
of the guy she's doing?
I'm gonna solve your problem.
What's his name?
What are you talking about?
Have you checked her e-mail?
I don't check e-mails.
I don't...
You can get a program
that records keystrokes.
It costs, like, 20 bucks.
Very easy to use. Okay?
You get a password, you check
her e-mail. You find out
everything about her.
That's how I found out
about the Puerto Rican
that Stacy was
running around with.
Okay.
You are reading
a little too much
into this situation.
There is no one she's
running around with, okay?
We had a fight
over the groceries
I brought home.
You're probably right.
She's probably not
sleeping with anybody.
No. Not what it's about.
Okay.
Maybe she's with
another guy, maybe not.
She's not.
I don't know.
I'm not Columbo. Okay?
But what we do know
is that she doesn't want
to be with you anymore.
I mean, I hate to be shitty
about it, and so cut and dry,
but let's face it.
She says she doesn't
want to be with you,
and I believe her.
Now, we gotta figure it out.
And you're gonna
need a place to go
and lick your wounds
while you get your head
right over this thing.
I don't need a place to go
and lick my wounds.
You're gonna stay with me.
I'm not gonna hear it.
Look it...
I'm not moving
out of the place.
Oh, you're not moving out.
No. I put money in the place.
I put half my money
in the place.
You're obviously not
the one calling the shots
in this case.
Yeah, but I own the place.
With her.
Yeah.
But it's not up to her
who gets to keep
the goddamn place.
If you find out
who she's sleeping with,
maybe we could leverage it.
I want you to listen to me.
You listen to me.
I'm gonna leave you a key.
I don't need a key.
Why?
'Cause she's gonna put...
She's gonna move out
of the place, Johnny.
Did she say
she was moving out?
She will.
She's gonna move out.
Oh, she's...
I'm gonna keep the place.
I'm not moving
out of the place.
I'll leave you a key.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR SHUTTING)
(TOOL WHIRRING)
Hey, how's it going?
LUPUS: I almost got it.
Yeah.
You know, I was thinking.
You know what you should do,
is you should find somebody
who looks like Brooke,
but even hotter and, you know,
bang the shit out of her.
What the hell's
wrong with you?
What?
Logs.
Just fix the damn engine.
I am fixing
the goddamn engine.
I need your tour logs.
I'm off the clock, okay?
Well, I cannot
file the quarterlies
until I have your log.
I'm going through
a little bit of a
life change here, Dennis.
I would really appreciate
a little bit of sensitivity,
please.
CHRISTOPHER: I know they're
both French, but that has
nothing to do with it.
Because Manet was earlier
and... No. Monet and Manet
are very different things.
I'm sorry, I beg to differ.
Excuse me, sir, can I have her
call you back personally?
Yes. Okay, thank you.
Sorry. Brooke?
I am so sorry.
What?
Come here.
Oh, honey, your mom called
and told me everything.
Oh, Jesus.
Good morning, Marilyn.
Morning.
I'll go water the plants.
I understand
you had a long night.
Tell me everything.
BROOKE: "Everything."
I couldn't possibly...
Then don't.
My time is pressing.
What I want is for you
to take the rest
of the day off.
Oh, no.
No, that's not necessary.
Who am I?
Marilyn Dean.
And where are we?
The Marilyn Dean Gallery.
And of whom is that portrait?
That is Marilyn Dean.
Yeah.
You know, your personal life
is your personal life.
But you look like shit.
And when you look like shit,
Marilyn Dean looks like shit,
and now it is my business.
And when it comes to my
business, I don't like
anything that's distracting.
So, I want you to take
the rest of the day off
to be sad
and then come back
to work tomorrow ready
to take care of business.
Got it?
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
(ROCK MUSIC BLARING)
(POOL BALLS CLACKING)
Oh, hey, Brooke. How are you?
What the hell are you doing?
Well, my whole life,
I always wanted my own place
with my own pool table.
I finally got my own place,
but you would not allow me
to have a pool table.
I just kind of figured
I'd rectify that today.
And it does feel good.
I'm gonna go ahead
and put the four ball
in the corner pocket.
Nice.
I'm sorry, can I...
A little room for the
shooter, please?
It's hard to shoot
with someone standing...
Thank you.
(POOL BALLS CLACKING)
Wow.
Well, I guess he feels
threatened that you broke up
with him and he's acting out.
Okay, look, Brooke,
men are like children.
You know? And they...
(WHISPERING) Sweetie, it's a
figure of speech. It's Brooke.
And I love you so much.
And you're my man
and you know that.
You're amazing. I love you.
Listen, and they're gonna
test boundaries to see
what they can get away with.
I think there's three things
that Gary needs to know.
One, this type of behavior
is not unnoticed.
Two, it's not acceptable.
And three, you know,
you're definitely not gonna
tolerate it. Right?
Yes.
And Brooke, remember,
we're always owning
our actions, right?
And we're always
healthy with it, yes?
Yes.
I don't wanna finish the game.
I got showings, okay?
I gotta buy the cookie spray.
I gotta clean up the dog.
(YOU OUGHTA KNOW PLAYING)
And now I'm really leaving
'cause I don't want
to hear that. Okay?
Thank you for the pool.
Thank you for the snacks.
I'm going to get a cab.
I'll split it with you.
What are you, 12?
Brooke, that is not healthy.
I'm trying to make a point.
And what is that point?
My point's your point.
Your three points.
That it's not unnoticed,
that it was not acceptable,
and that it would definitely
not be tolerated.
Not exactly what I meant.
Unbelievable.
I knew it!
Hey, gang.
Found my shirt on the floor.
Thanks for laying it out.
Gary, are you here
for couples bowling?
Yeah.
Well, don't you think
you and I should discuss
something first?
Like what? How your
47 average is killing us?
Okay. Great. No.
Gary, this is couples bowling.
And since you and I
are no longer a couple,
because you have chosen
not to participate
constructively
in our relationship,
we're now singles.
So, there's not room
for two singles on the team.
Why do you look confused?
I don't have any idea
what's happening.
I've come to play on the team.
Look, Gary, I just don't think
it's a good idea
for you and I to be around
each other any more
than we have to right now.
I completely agree.
Maybe you should go
play some pinball.
No, I think you should leave.
Okay.
Brooke, when a man makes
a commitment to a team,
he honors that commitment.
He doesn't let emotions
or personal issues
get in the way of victory.
And I've made a commitment
to this team.
They don't want you here
either, Gary.
Yeah. Sure, they don't.
They don't.
They're my friends.
But you're not
a strong bowler.
That's not the point.
You know what? Let's just...
Why don't we let them decide?
Gary, don't. No.
Don't involve them, okay?
That's unnecessary.
What's wrong, Castro?
Castro?
Well, Castro doesn't
let people vote as a team.
Okay. Ask them.
Thank you.
Okay, everyone.
Team vote here.
By a show of hands,
just put it up when you
make a decision,
who here agrees with Brooke
and thinks I should leave
the bowling team?
Shocker.
Band of Brothers.
You should rent it sometime.
Good luck, everyone.
Riding Miss Gutter Ball
to the finals.
Hey, Gary.
Yeah.
I'm gonna need
your shirt back.
What?
Well, we're gonna have to
replace you, and you know
we get docked 10 pins
if everyone's not in matching
Pin Shakers uniforms.
My shirt says "Gary" on it.
Granted.
But actually,
we know a guy named Gary.
And he's not as tall as you,
but he's a pretty good bowler.
I'm gonna have to request
that I have my wrist guard
back then.
I'm sorry. That's mine.
Just give me
the goddamn wrist guard,
please. Thank you.
I hope your wrist snaps.
Wow. Okay? You see that?
You know what I mean?
Yeah. That was awesome.
You just had your
ex-boyfriend, who you wish
you were still dating,
voted off the bowling team.
Well, I had to do that
to get him right
where I want him.
Where's that?
Shirtless in the parking lot?
Addie,
you're not getting this.
Gary loves this bowling team.
He's hurt right now.
He's feeling pretty bad.
He's gonna go out there
and he's gonna get drunk.
He's gonna make
a complete fool of himself.
And he will be sitting there
feeling pretty Ionely
and pretty pathetic,
and then it's just
gonna hit him.
What's gonna hit him?
That not only is he
out a girlfriend,
but his life is just
falling apart piece by piece
and maybe that life
was pretty great.
And maybe I was the glue
that was holding it all
together.
And if he wants
that life back,
he's gonna have no choice
but to change.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
How about this, huh?
I feel like
we just found hell.
When did you start
coming to knobby joints
like this?
I might be the greatest
you've ever seen, pal.
I'm conquering new frontiers.
Hello, babe.
Yeah, you've got to put up
with the bad music
and the $15 drinks,
but this place is stacked
with top-shelf, young,
dumb ass.
All you gotta do is just
separate the weaker ones
from the herd.
Come on,
I'll get you into the VIP.
Can I get a couple drinks
from you?
Okay, L.G.
Lupus, I got to be totally...
I got to be honest with you.
I'm not feeling it here.
You're gonna like it in here.
You're gonna love it.
I don't like it out here.
Look, listen to me,
will you, please?
How you doing, Buzz?
While you were
on the inside locked up
for the past two years,
the game has changed.
(WOMEN CHEERING)
Do you remember
when you were an outdoor cat
and you used to have to hunt
and kill for your food?
Well, you've become
an indoor cat.
You've been getting your milk
brought to you
in a silver bowl,
and guess what?
Now, you've been
tossed back outside
and the alley has changed.
For example,
your MTV generation,
your technology,
your text message,
your TiVo. You name it.
People want their
information faster.
People e-mail each other
because they want to
exchange information, Gar.
They don't want to connect,
they want results.
Okay.
You gotta get to
the message quicker.
Now, I want you to watch.
It's real simple. Okay?
How you doing, ladies?
Now, here's what I'd like
to do to you.
First, I'd like to
get you naked.
And then I'm gonna take
some Saran Wrap
and I'm gonna wrap you
up in it, head to toe.
Then I'm gonna
cut out two holes.
One for your mouth,
so you can breathe,
obviously.
And the other one...
Asshole.
It could be a gorgeous
evening for us, babe.
The pink is gorgeous.
Jesus, God.
Come here.
Lupus, listen to me.
I want you to listen to me.
There are our drinks.
You want your drink?
No, I'm fine.
Thank you.
The L.G. thanks you.
Will you listen to me,
please? You're my brother
and I love you very much,
and maybe you do
get laid tonight,
but maybe you get arrested.
Arrested for what, babe?
Being awesome?
Come on, babe, listen.
You want to tell your jokes,
tell your jokes.
But sooner or later
you're gonna get hungry
and you're gonna wanna eat.
And jokes might
make you feel better,
but they don't get you fed.
I'm gonna go take a lap.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR SHUTTING)
What are you doing?
I'm sketching.
And where are you sketching?
In the living room.
No, in my bedroom.
And I didn't say anything
to you, Brooke,
when you so arrogantly
claimed the bed
without asking me,
but you can't just waltz
into my room and turn it
into a damn art fair.
Gary, I've only taken up
a little bit of space, so...
I don't care if you only
took an inch.
There might not be
a door here, but this
is my domain. Okay?
I don't go into your bedroom
and set up a goddamn sawhorse.
Well, then what the hell
is that pool table
doing in the dining room?
Because that's a common area.
And that's where this belongs.
Not in my room.
Hey, what are you doing?
It belongs in another
common area.
Gary.
People want to come home
and they want to relax
in their room.
Gary, it is 2:00
in the morning!
Don't you drop my things.
I don't know
what to tell you, kid.
This is how I am
when I'm single.
My hours start to get
pretty strange.
Might be time for you
to think about moving out.
Why would I...
No, I'm not moving anywhere.
Gary, just please
turn the volume down.
Yeah, but I don't tell you
what the hell to do
in your room.
You can doodle. You can dance.
You can bake
a goddamn gingerbread house.
I don't give a shit.
But in my room,
I want to relax
and watch my highlights
in complete surround-sound
experience.
What the hell are you doing?
You're not even gonna
watch it!
Don't tell me what I am
or aren't not doing.
Oh, what you are not,
not doing?
Go learn some English.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't have a grandfather
on the board of
some fancy college.
Key word being "was."
Did he touch the Filipino
exchange student?
Did he not touch
the exchange student?
I don't know, Brooke.
I wasn't there.
Okay.
No, don't start
with the family stuff.
Like your family's so perfect?
Your brother's a pervert!
Don't talk to me about
the sexual habits
of family members.
What about your sister?
My sister's
been through a lot.
Of dick.
There are some problems, Gary,
but can we please
just leave it...
Problems? She slept with
the entire Arizona Cardinals
offensive line.
That's not problems.
That's she's the problem!
She was on vacation!
She was on vacation.
Don't even get me started,
by the way, on your brother.
If I have to hear
that guy sing
just one more time,
I'd hang myself
with wax dental floss.
Could the guy just
come out of the closet,
please?
Richard is not gay.
Okay, lassie,
I want you to listen to me
and listen good.
I'm not saying
he won't get married.
he won't even have kids.
But then one day
his wife will come home,
and then she'll find him
with a guy named Majulio,
wearing leather helmets
and clubbing each other
to Yanni's greatest hits.
Yeah. Right. Whatever.
You're an infant.
Yeah, I'm an infant.
Go enjoy your room, Brooke,
'cause I'm gonna enjoy mine!
Okay.
You know what?
I might enjoy
some pay-per-view
options tonight.
It's gonna be a long one,
sweetheart,
and I got nothing to do maana
but sleep in.
(DOOR SLAMMING)
(BOOGIE NIGHTS PLAYING)
(SINGING) Boogie nights
Ain't no doubt
we are here to party
What are you doing?
Boogie nights
Come on now,
got to get it started
Ricky, you and
the Get Along Gang leave
or I'm gonna
throw you out of here
personally, you understand?
Actually, Gary,
this is Brooke's bedroom.
So, technically,
you don't have
jurisdiction here,
but I think it'd be really fun
if you sang with us.
Come on, Gary.
I think you'll like it.
You got 10 seconds
to get out of here
or I'm gonna break
your damn magic whistle.
You understand
what I'm saying to you?
Move this group
out of my house, now!
(EXCLAIMING)
(GRUNTING)
(ALL SINGING)
Gary, you can't take
a pitch pipe
out of a guy's hand
when he's in the middle
of a very funky groove.
You can get hurt
doing something like that.
I'm tapping out,
I'm tapping out!
Here we go. From the bridge.
(SINGING) Party night
Get on down
with the sound of the music
Boogie nights
Do it, do it
What kind of bullshit move
was that?
I'm sorry. What?
What happened?
Oh, don't be coy with me.
You sent that animal over here
to attack me when I was
hung over and weak.
Oh, no. Look, all I know
is The Tone Rangers,
they needed someplace
to rehearse,
so I very clearly
told Richard,
"Stay in my room,"
which you explained to me
was my space to do
with what I want.
Is that how
you want to play it?
'Cause I'll play it like that.
I'll play it like
Lionel Richie.
All night long, lady.
Oh, yeah.
I'll call some guys
from my neck of the woods.
And we're not talking, Brooke,
about a couple of queens
who know a few grapples.
We're talking about Polacks
that don't have
a goddamn future.
Right.
That's right!
We can make shit
real uncomfortable
around here,
and that's what
we're gonna do.
Please. Come on.
You know what?
You're just embarrassed
because Richard
kicked your ass.
Richard did not kick my ass.
What Richard did was attack me
when I was half asleep.
Really?
Is that how you see it?
There's a really big gap
between getting
your ass kicked
and having
a dancing, singing sprite
fool you with trickery
and then strike your throat
before you know that
you're even in a fight.
And I wouldn't expect
someone like you
to understand that,
because all you ever do
is make moves from
up in your ivy tower.
Wow. You have officially
gone off the reservation.
I'm an adult.
I talk through shit.
He ran out of ideas.
God. Listen, by the way,
there's messages
on the voice mail
regarding game night,
which is obviously
not gonna happen,
so you might want to
call people and tell them
that it's canceled.
Why would I cancel game night?
Well, I mean...
If it's our turn to host game,
I'm gonna host
goddamn game night.
You want to host game night?
I'm fine, Brooke.
I don't have any strangeness
over what happened here today.
Okay.
If there's anyone
that should feel weird
about seeing people,
that's you, Tonya Harding.
Me? I'm gonna honor
my commitments.
Great.
Fine.
Let's do that.
Let's honor the commitment.
(WATER RUNNING)
Hey, there's no food in there!
BROOKE: So?
Well, people are gonna
be here in an hour.
What are they supposed to eat?
You're a big boy.
Figure it out.
Oh, great.
Well, that's what we got.
We have only tap water
because, you know,
Gary didn't shop.
BROOKE: And we don't have
any ice either 'cause
he didn't fill the trays.
That's trash. It's your shot.
What is your name again?
Diane.
GARY: Did you call?
JOHNNY O: I called the five.
Well, yeah,
but you didn't call
the second ball,
so that's trash,
so it's your shot.
GARY: You got to play
by the rules. It's your shot.
Hi.
Andrew.
BROOKE: Oh, hi.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hey, hey, hey!
These two Benedict Arnolds
aren't welcome in my condo.
Who sent an invite to them?
I'm sorry.
These are very loyal friends
and they are always welcome
in my condo.
Oh, really? Why don't we
take it to a vote and see
who has the numbers this time?
GARY: All right.
Show of hands here.
Who thinks that these two
traitors should leave and
not be a part of game night?
And maybe take their shirts
off when they leave.
Raise your hand.
I know I feel that way.
Who else?
GARY: Come on, Johnny O,
put your hand up, please.
Come on. Thank you.
You, Miss? New girl.
Who's the girl?
What's her name?
The girl you're with.
Her name's Diane.
Oh, I'm sorry.
You might want to go ahead
and touch some sky.
Thank you. Come on,
Riggleman, please?
What are you doing?
No. We need the eight
to count towards
a running tally.
You know that. Come on.
Show her whose side
that you're on.
Put your hand in the air.
You know whose side I'm on.
You know we need eight,
though. Come on.
Put your hand down.
Please don't touch
my Ruffles.
GARY: Put that one back.
Those are my Ruffles.
Don't eat them, please.
Thank you.
Oh, Gary.
They're mine.
Come on.
Here we go. All right.
RIGGLEMAN: Eyes front. Ready?
Hold on. Get the
timer going, please.
Ready?
GARY: Now I gotta do it. Go.
ANDREW: Okay.
It's a brick.
ADDIE: Square. Square.
Box. Box.
Corner. Corner.
A dot in the corner.
A house.
Home plate!
JEN: Football! Baseball!
Sports. A house.
ADDIE: A triangle.
It's algebra.
Okay, it's a house.
ADDIE: It's a house.
JEN: It's a house.
ANDREW: Two words.
JEN: Banana?
ADDIE: Chimney,
chimney, chimney!
A fruit. House. Fruit.
Oh, restaurant. Or...
ANDREW: No, chimney, chimney.
ADDIE: Smoke...
JEN: Oh, a house call.
House call!
(TIMER RINGING)
Oh! House call!
Yeah, well, I thought
it was a house call.
Like a hotel, then it hit me
it was a house.
ADDIE: Yeah!
You're terrific.
Absolutely terrific.
All right, beat that.
Okay, guys, listen.
The next one wins, okay?
So let's stay focused.
Let's stay calm.
We can do this. High fives.
Let's go. Come on. Let's go.
Let's get a mind-meld.
Let's try and get a mind-meld,
okay?
GARY: Here we go.
Let's go. Mind-meld.
I heard you!
Don't over-think it.
Mind meld.
ANDREW: Ready?
I heard you!
Well, just keep it simple.
Shush.
Ready? Wait. Go!
Here we go!
We're mind-melding.
Draw faster.
It doesn't have
to be beautiful,
just has to be
something we can get.
Shoe, shoe...
Shoe! Shoe, shoe, shoe.
Shoeless Joe Jackson.
Draw something different.
No one's getting it.
Shoe. What, is that
a smaller shoe?
JOHNNY O: Baby shoe.
Smaller shoe. Baby shoes.
JOHNNY O: Shoes.
Baby shoes.
Smaller shoe. Gumshoe.
GARY: Smaller shoes.
DIANE: Gumshoe? Gumshoe?
Running Olympics.
JOHNNY O: Inside the shoe.
Inside a shoe. A bubble...
JOHNNY O: Lining.
Stop pointing at the shoe.
We're not...
No one's guessing shoe.
Stop pointing at the shoe
and draw something different.
(TIMER RINGING)
Draw something different.
You...
Goddamn it!
No one's guessing shoe!
You drew a big shoe,
then a small shoe,
and no one got it.
You gotta draw something
different. Everyone said
"shoe" seven times.
It's a sock, asshole.
You call yourself an artist?
Yes!
A three-year-old with
a box of crayons could
do a better job than this.
I'm sorry, I don't have
the great talent of standing
on top of a big red bus
and pointing out architecture
that other great men
have built!
I'm the one who should
be sorry, Brooke.
I shouldn't sit here
and pick on your art.
No.
Because you got
the nuts part down,
Picasso.
GARY: All you have
to do is
cut off your frigging ear.
BROOKE: That's Van Gogh,
you idiot!
And your insults
are much more effective
when they're accurate.
Don't talk to me about
being goddamn accurate!
I can talk to you
about anything that I want.
'Cause you couldn't even
draw a sock.
You don't do anything right!
You're a lazy...
Everyone said,
"Shoe, shoe, shoe!"
At first,
I figured that the split
was just something temporary,
something that you two
would work out and get past,
but after tonight
I think it's pretty clear
that you two genuinely
do not want to
get back together.
There's not a shot in hell.
Gary.
I'm just...
I got you.
As your friend
and as your realtor,
I'm not gonna
leave here tonight
until we decide
what to do about this condo,
because this living situation
is obviously not working out.
Gary?
Well, the only logical thing
that I can think of
is for her to move out
of the condo,
and then to pay me some
sort of a penalty
as compensation for
the labor that I did
all around the condo.
What? What?
What? Pay you compensation
for your labor?
We fixed this place up
together.
Are you nuts?
Stop calling me nuts,
I swear to God.
I fixed the...
You went around with a sponge,
and you went in the bathroom
and you dotted foofy shit.
That's what you're saying
that I did?
GARY: There's no...
BROOKE: That was...
That's called aesthetics.
It warmed this place up
so it didn't look like
an army barracks,
which it was about to.
I'll tell you what
it's called in his language,
depreciated.
That's what it's called.
You don't even know
what that means.
Unless the next buyer
happens to have your same
Zulu-voodoo-land taste.
All right.
Let me tell you
something else.
It's gonna cost money
to cover up the holes
in the wall.
The holes that you drilled
in the wall there to hang up
whatever that thing is called.
Oh, please. Gary.
GARY: You're gonna have
to cost money to fix that.
What I did, Brooke,
has concrete value
to the condo.
I added concrete...
Well, let's just go on record.
We're dealing with facts here.
I did the tiling
in the bathroom.
Have you seen...
I did the new track lighting.
That tile is the
shittiest tile job.
GARY: I did the plumbing!
The plumbing!
That's realty terms.
Okay. Let's talk
about your plumbing.
This is his plumbing.
We have two temperatures
in our bathroom.
We get either scalding hot
or we get frostbite.
That's it. That's all we get.
It's my problem
that she doesn't know how
to pace a shower?
GARY: Now all of a sudden
that's my fault.
I get a minute
to take a shower.
One minute?
BROOKE: One minute of warmth?
Oh, Jesus. One minute.
That's it. That's correct.
Thank God you're not
in charge of keeping all the
clocks in Chicago on time.
This is basic logic.
You are out of your mind.
You have lost it.
Let me explain this to you
in plain chapter and verse.
Cheese and rice,
you guys are gonna kill
each other. Now, let's just...
Realistically speaking,
neither one of you
can afford this mortgage
on your own, okay?
And that's a shame,
because this building will
continue to increase in value.
I get nothing but
phone calls about it,
all right?
Waiting for a unit to open up.
So, as your realtor,
the last thing I would suggest
is selling.
But as your friend,
I just, I don't see
any other solution.
You take your halves,
you go your separate ways,
and you get on
with your lives.
I know that selling is not
the easiest thing, but
I do think that it's the best.
And to be honest,
this is a situation
where I would just as soon
not take a commission.
That's great. Thank you.
That's great.
Thank you for that.
I wish I didn't have to,
you know,
but company policy says
I cannot waive that.
But I was just...
You know, I'm saying
in theory, you know.
In this situation,
'cause we're friends,
I wish I could waive it.
No can do, though.
As soon as you can,
I would love to get
a set of keys from you guys.
You just drop them off.
Okay. Great. There they are.
I'll be bringing by
people all week.
You won't even know I'm here.
The good news is,
should move quickly.
All right.
Okay to leave you two
alone now?
Got to get back to Jen.
Very excited about
the win tonight.
Okay.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
BROOKE: Addie,
if the condo sells,
I think I'm gonna lose him.
ADDIE ON PHONE:
Yeah, but game night
was so light and fun,
I'm really surprised
to be hearing this.
Okay. You know what?
That's not constructive.
Really.
I just... Yeah, I need
a new plan, Addie. I don't...
(SNICKERING)
I'm just kidding. It's me.
I'm gonna have to
call you back.
Whenever one of my friends
is down, we all go on,
like, happy patrol.
I was actually having
a very serious conversation.
(SINGING)
Christopher, do not sing.
(SINGING) If you're happy
and you know it
Clap your hands
If you're happy
and you know it
Clap your hands
If you're happy
and you know it
You're going to smile to...
(DOOR SLAMS)
Pack up your shit and go home.
Okay. You know what?
This is not his fault.
He was just really trying
to cheer me up and it...
Did I or did I not give you
the day off to be sad?
Yes. But I...
Well, today's not that day,
and unfortunately for you,
I can't afford to look weak.
No, please.
You have warned me
so many times
and you have yet to fire me.
I think you and I both know
that to find and train
somebody new,
it's gonna cost you time,
and it's gonna cost you money,
and I don't think you want
to spend either one of those.
Now, look, I'm just gonna
take a wild guess here,
but you don't become
Marilyn Dean
without knowing
how to handle men.
Okay? Now, just listen
to my problem,
tell me how to fix it,
and then we'll all
go back to work.
Okay. What is this problem
so severe
that has caused you to
blaspheme in the synagogue
of Marilyn Dean?
Well, it's Gary.
I broke up with him
in hopes that losing me
would make him
want to change,
and that's, you know...
And I've just ended up
pushing him, you know,
farther and farther away.
That's it?
Yeah.
Honey, this is not
surrealism or cubism,
it's paint-by-numbers.
Go see Mischa,
my personal waxer at the spa.
Ask her for the Telly Savalas.
The Telly Savalas.
Compliments of M. Dean.
Then go show Gary
your immaculate canvas
and let him see another man
eager to paint it. Got it?
Got it?
Uh-huh.
Ow!
Who loves you, baby?
ANNOUNCER ON TV:
Wow, impressive.
Three sharp hands landed.
What an amazing display
of punching technique.
The crowd jumps.
That punch rocked him.
They sense he's on the verge
of hitting the canvas.
The roaring for anticipation
of a knockout.
We are witnessing
a great fight.
He's displaying incredible
rhythm with his hands.
Bulldog terrorizing
his opponent. Down he goes!
Hard punch slams him
to the canvas.
(WHO LOVES YA BABY PLAYING)
REFEREE: One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight,
(BELL CLANGING)
nine, ten. It's over.
(DOORBELL RINGS)
(STAMMERING)
Is... Did... Is Brooke here?
I don't know.
(VIDEO GAME PLAYING)
Brooke?
BROOKE: I'll be right there.
(EXPLOSIONS ON TV)
MAN: Cool, baby, cool.
(SCREAMING)
So, how do you and Brooke
know each other?
Well, how don't we
know each other,
you know what I mean?
BROOKE: Hi, Paul.
Oh, hey. Wow, you look great.
Thank you.
BROOKE: Are you ready to go?
Yeah. All set.
So, it was great meeting you.
Apple martinis.
All right, come on.
That normally does the trick.
Just ignore him.
But just two.
Three, she'll get sloppy.
You'll become a babysitter.
Oh, and fantasy role playing.
She's got a real thing
for lifeguards.
Put some zinc oxide
on your nose
and she'll lose her mind.
It'll all be over with.
(DOOR CLOSES)
MAN: Y'all want me
to stop running?
I mean, the most challenging
part of what I do
is between February
and April 15th.
That's what we in the biz
like to call crunch time.
That sounds fascinating.
Good evening.
Hi.
Can I start you two off
with something to drink?
Yeah, you know, we're gonna
start with a couple
of apple martinis, please.
No, you know what?
I'm gonna... I'm just
gonna start with a water.
Well, you can just
bring those, just in case.
What was I saying?
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So, you know,
it's not like it's
all work and no play.
You know, I mean,
after April 15th,
that's what we in the biz
like to call party time.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Excuse me.
Oh, I have to get this.
I'm so sorry.
Hello.
ADDIE: Okay, is this when
I'm supposed to call?
What?
What do you mean? What?
Where? What happened?
Okay, that's great.
Wait. What? Oh, all right.
Listen, where...
Just don't move.
Where are you?
I'm sitting in my kitchen.
Sitting? Okay.
(STAMMERING) Don't move.
Don't... I'm gonna be
right there, honey. I'm gonna
be right there, okay?
Is everything okay?
Oh, my gosh.
That was my best friend.
She just had an accident
and she...
She has this knee thing
and she's just very fragile,
and I have to go.
What?
I can give you a ride.
No. No. That's okay.
I'm gonna grab a cab, so...
I'm so sorry.
I like your dress.
I think he's fascinating.
He's obviously
read a lot of books.
Yeah. Yeah, I bet he has.
He reads a lot of books
because nobody
wants to talk to him.
He's a friend of Andrew's
who's always been polite.
It's the best I could do
on such short notice, okay?
Well, you know what?
Polite is not gonna do it.
We've got to find somebody
who is really gonna
make Gary jealous.
LUPUS:
Can I just say something?
You sound a little jealous,
Gary.
GARY: Why would I be
jealous of some guy
with computer skills?
Let's say he doesn't have
computer skills, but he's got
a big old elephant hog on him?
Would that bother you
or would you be
okay with that?
Not nearly as much as the way
that your mind works.
LUPUS: My mind works great.
So, what's this bullshit
I hear about you
selling the condo?
Selling that condo
is ludicrous.
I was waiting for
when I was gonna get
the how-Gary-always-
screws-his-life-up
speech again.
This must be the right time.
Look, you tell me,
you just tell me, tell me.
Is it happening now?
Yeah. Okay.
Tell me how
losing that asset
is gonna get us
on the river?
Go ahead, just tell me.
Tell me. Somebody tell me.
What is this?
What is this? What is it?
What is it? Hey!
Don't patronize me.
Helicopters.
Helicopters. Exactly!
How does losing the asset
give us helicopters?
Dennis, I'm being totally
serious with you. I don't
need this shit right now.
Hey, you want to cry,
cry to Mom.
Nobody's crying.
I'm not crying.
I just don't feel
like hearing it.
There's no feelings here.
This is about money
and business.
Fine, you broke up.
You broke up. Fine.
You know, sad.
Sad is, instead of putting
$1,000 into your mortgage
every month,
you waste it on rent.
That's what sad is.
Oh, you're broke up.
You're confused,
brokenhearted.
Heartbreak is not
having that money
as part of your net worth
and then not saving the money,
so that after taxes
you can invest!
You know, you're confused.
Are you finished?
Look, I need
the damn tour logs.
Yeah.
Well, I really,
really appreciate
the heart to heart.
It was a great talk, Dennis.
Thank you.
Oh, well, you're behind
three months. You're still
behind three months.
And those logs are imperative
to insuring that our books
are straight!
I'll tell you what those
logs are. Those logs are
bullshit is what they are!
You got the receipts.
Tally the goddamn
things yourself!
I do, I do!
And I don't appreciate it,
because it cuts into
my time with my family.
I could be spending that time
with my family instead of
doing your books.
I already do the taxes.
I do the billing.
I do the hiring, the firing.
I do the maintenance.
Come on, what do you do?
What is it that you do?
You do the tours!
I am the talent, Dennis!
They sign up a month
in advance to see me.
They'll wait in line
for the next bus
to see me! All right?
So don't drain me
with all this bullshit
about the goddamn tour logs!
GARY: How big's your TV?
BOY: Oh, shut up!
How big's your TV,
'cause I wanna know if you
can see what's happening.
Oh, wow.
You beat a 12-year-old.
I don't care if you're
12 years old. You have
more time in the day to play.
I live in the real world,
my man,
(DOORBELL RINGING)
with bills
and responsibilities.
GARY: That's right.
You can't have a handle
called Mad Dog Killer
if you complain every time...
Brooke?
Hi, Mike.
Hi.
Come on in.
Hold on, Mom. I'm coming.
Is your mom
in the room with you?
'Cause I hope she can't see
what's happening.
I hope she can't see
I'm gonna be just
a few more seconds.
So, just sit down and relax.
Oh, yeah, no problem.
GARY: I'm sorry?
Yeah, why'd you do that?
You take the fun
out of beating you, because
you have an excuse to lose.
Get a life, dude.
Do you think it's possible
that your mom won't
love you anymore
if she sees how bad
you're losing in the game.
Shut up!
Okay.
All right.
GARY:
That's great. You're gonna
stay man-to-man with me.
What happens
when I make a play?
(MIKE GROANING)
Making plays, making plays!
Making plays!
Well, you know,
that's how my people
like to handle their business.
While your guys
are out partying,
mine are running routes.
Try to make a difference.
Mike? I'm ready to go.
Oh, hey,
do you mind if we finish
the game? We got
a real nail-biter going here.
Yeah, sure. Of course. Great.
Awesome, all right?
Touchdown.
Oh, God, is that pretty.
God, is that pretty.
Yeah, I'm a gentleman.
I like to be humble.
I'm old school.
I don't like to talk a lot.
But at the same time,
am I talented?
Tell me how you felt about
what just happened there.
That's him going deep.
That's him going...
Work ethic. Work ethic.
I could play this game
forever.
Oh, I could, too.
I love it, yeah.
I love it, don't you?
I mean, it's the kind of thing
where literally
I play the game and it's like,
four hours go by.
Fate has me highly skilled
and loaded with talent.
Oh...
'Cause I think I'm
good enough to figure out
how to beat myself.
GARY: You push yourself.
You push yourself
trying to achieve
the impossible,
because you know
that when that moment comes
that everything you've done
up to that moment
has prepared you for victory!
I can't take credit
for it, Mike.
I got to thank
these little digital guys
with the big hearts.
Does it feel good to be
a champion? Yeah.
Yeah, it feels good
to be a champion.
Good game.
Hey, Brooke,
are you ready to go now?
Oh, yeah, yeah. Sure.
MIKE: Great.
Hey, Gary, thanks a lot, man.
It was great to meet you.
Absolutely, man.
Come on, Mike. I know
a great little martini bar.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
LUPUS: Yo.
Hey, man, saddle up.
It's time to rope in
some talent.
What's up? What do you got?
My place. Tonight. Poker.
Call some girls up.
Your roommate is awesome.
Mmm.
Yeah, he's something.
So, where did you go
to law school?
Oh, Northwestern.
God, Gary's hilarious.
Yeah, he's okay.
Okay? I mean,
the guy's all time.
But he's gonna take
Chicago tourism
by air, land and sea.
And he asked me to join
his new bowling team.
I mean, how cool is that?
Mmm-hmm.
You know what?
I can't do this.
I'm so sorry.
Excuse me,
would you please pull over?
Can you pull over, please?
Hey, wait.
Tell Gary to call me.
GARY: Welcome, everyone,
to the first annual
Texas Hold'em No-Limit
Strip Poker Tournament.
(GIRLS WHOOPING)
Now, per the e-mail
that Lupus sent, we each have
eight articles of clothing.
Now, if you want to bet,
you take off an article
of clothing,
you put it in the center.
If you win,
you take back the clothes,
you put back on what you bet.
The extras that
other people bet
will stay in front of you,
much the same as chips would.
You can go all in
at any point,
but as I outlined,
you must take off
all your clothes to do so.
The game shall last an hour,
maybe two,
at which point we will begin
the dance portion
of the evening.
(ALL CHEERING)
GARY: Let's get going here.
I need to see the blinds.
Small blind. Big blind.
The blinds are one and one.
LUPUS: Come on, ladies.
GARY: All right.
Oh, yeah.
Let's get going here.
Shuffle up and deal.
All right.
I mean, just because
they were playing
video games,
that doesn't mean
it didn't bother him, right?
Honestly, Brooke,
I wish I could tell you,
but I wasn't there.
All right, Sally,
get the soap
out of your mouth.
We're gonna save that
for when you're 12.
Mike was really,
really good-Iooking.
I mean,
he's a little bit of a goof,
but Gary doesn't know that.
I mean, for all he knows,
a sophisticated,
really good-Iooking guy
took me out on a date tonight.
I could be in bed
with this guy right now
for all he knows.
You know?
I'm telling you,
if you saw the look
on his face,
Mike got to him.
(CRAZY LITTLE THING
CALLED LOVE PLAYING ON STEREO)
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
Hey, it's Riggleman.
Great news.
(GARY SNIFFING)
So, how does this work?
I'll bring the car
around front
and you wrap them up to go?
Oh, no, no.
We take care of everything.
We deliver it. We hang it.
We check the light
and the sun exposure.
Oh. Perfect.
Yeah.
Listen, I don't want to be
too forward,
but would you like to have
some dinner with me sometime?
I'm sorry. I have a boyfriend.
Of course.
So...
Well, he's a lucky man.
BROOKE: Oh, thank you.
I guess I will just have
to keep it to home deliveries
and gallery purchases.
Thank you, though. See you.
Have a good day, Brooke.
You, too.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
Okay, are you
out of your mind?
Gary's throwing Greek orgies
in your living room
and you're telling
hot rich guys
you have a boyfriend?
Are you nuts?
Hey, look.
I'm not exactly innocent here.
Brooke, as an outsider
with some perspective,
I really think you...
Christopher, stop. Stop it.
I don't want to hear it.
This has already gotten
way out of hand.
I know what I have
to do now, all right?
I know what I have to do.
(COMMENTATOR CHATTERING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR SHUTTING)
Hi.
Did you get my note?
Yeah.
Two weeks.
Yep.
I brought some boxes
from work,
so, you know,
if you need any
just help yourself.
Great. Thanks.
Oh.
Listen, a while ago
I got these tickets
for the Old 97's tonight,
and I completely forgot
about it, so I...
You know, if you want to go.
Well, how many tickets
did you get?
I got two.
How much do you want for them?
Oh, no, I'm going. I'm going.
So, then it would just be
the two of us?
Well, yes,
and 2,000 other people.
I mean, it's not a big deal,
but, you know, look, you know,
I was going to invite Addie,
but I just figured
I'd gotten them for you, so...
Sure. Why not?
Are you sure? I mean,
if you don't want them,
I can definitely give them
to somebody.
No. No, I'll be there.
That sounds...
It sounds great.
Okay. All right.
It's at the Riv.
So, I'll just leave
your ticket at Will Call.
Good?
Okay.
Yeah, so, there.
I'll just leave that for him.
Okay, great.
Okay, so.
Gary Grobowski?
Grobowski, yeah.
He should be here in a minute.
He's really...
He's oddly tall, so.
Oh, okay. Great.
You won't miss him. Thanks.
All right, have a good night.
(ALL CHATTERING)
Hi. Can I get a beer, please?
Sure.
Actually, make that two beers.
It's gonna be $8.
Excuse me. Sorry.
(CROWD CHEERING)
MILLER: Hello, everybody!
Good evening, Chicago.
We're the Old 97's.
(BAND PLAYING TIMEBOMB)
(BAND PLAYING SALOME)
(MELT SHOW PLAYING)
(LOCK CLICKING)
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR SHUTTING)
(KNOCKING)
Brooke?
Are you up?
Yeah.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Are you sure?
What's up? What do you want?
I just want to say
I'm sorry that I missed
the concert,
and let me know
what that ticket cost,
I'll pay you back for it.
Just leave me alone, Gary.
I planned on going
to the concert.
It's just, I stopped by
Johnny O's and we...
It doesn't fucking matter,
okay?
Would you just leave my room
and shut the door?
Jesus.
Please.
I didn't really know
that the concert mattered
all that much to you.
Exactly.
Hold on a second here.
Let me talk for a second.
Gary...
Brooke. You broke up with me.
Then you have guys
coming over here for dates,
and all of a sudden
you ask me to go
to some concert.
I mean, I just figured that,
you know.
Gary.
(SNIFFS)
I just... I don't know
how we got here.
Our entire relationship
I've gone above
and beyond for you, for us.
And I mean, I've cooked.
I've picked your shit up
off the floor.
I've laid your clothes
out for you like you were
a four-year-old.
I support you.
I supported you, your work.
If we ever had dinner
or anything,
I make the plans.
I take care of everything and
I just don't feel like you
appreciate any of it.
I don't feel
you appreciate me.
And all I want is to...
Is for you to just show me
that you care.
Why didn't you just
say that to me?
Gary, I've tried. I've tried.
Yeah, but never like that.
You might've said
some things that you meant
to imply that, Brooke,
but I'm not a mind reader.
I doubt it would matter.
You are who you are.
Just leave me alone, okay?
Right now. Just shut my door.
Listen.
All right, Gary, just, please.
Just leave the room.
Listen to me.
Gary, just...
I don't want to be
near you right now.
Listen to me.
I just want to...
Please, just shut the door.
Please.
(SOBBING)
JOHNNY O: I know. Look, I know
you feel bad, but, you know,
what are you gonna do?
I mean, what does she expect,
for me to want to go with
the girl who dumped me?
I don't know. She probably
just wanted you, you know,
to show her the respect
of not standing her up
or some shit, who knows?
Well, damn it.
I should have just said
no in the first place.
I don't know why I called...
You know what?
It's her fault she got hurt.
You shouldn't even feel bad
about it. She should have
expected it from you.
You're a fun guy, okay?
Everybody likes you.
You're the quickest guy
I know. Anytime we go out,
I have a blast.
All right? But, you know,
everybody who knows you
knows you're gonna do
what you want to do.
And if it's not what the
other person wants to do,
well, that's their problem.
That's bullshit.
It's not bullshit.
There's plenty of times
I do shit that
I don't want to do.
That's ridiculous. No.
Like when?
That's bullshit to say
about me.
When have we ever
done something
you didn't want to do?
You know, I don't know,
off the top of my head.
I don't keep score...
When's the last time
we went to a Sox game?
The Sox.
Not when they're playing
the Cubs, either.
We always do what you want
to do and she always did
what you want to do.
It's who you are.
Everybody thinks
that you're their friend,
okay?
But the fact of the matter is
that there's not one person
that I know that
you trust enough
to let close enough
that they could hurt you.
And her big problem
is that you really liked her.
I mean, she is the one girl
you really liked.
And no matter what she did
and how hard she tried,
you were never gonna
let your guard down.
That poor girl
never stood a chance.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(AY COSITA LINDA
PLAYING ON STEREO)
Marilyn?
MARILYN: Yeah.
I'm sorry. I just...
MARILYN: Oh, just get in here.
Oh, okay.
I'm sorry, excuse me.
Marilyn, I just...
I just wanted to let you know
that today is gonna be
my last day.
I'm gonna be traveling
for a bit.
Here's a blank check.
Write down a number, I don't
want to know what it is,
and go back to work.
No, no. It's not about that.
I can't accept that.
Brooke.
Travis, get your gorgeous
tuckus out of here.
(SIGHS)
(STEREO STOPS PLAYING)
If you make it to Rome,
search out an establishment
called the Padre Negro.
Ask for a strapping young
fellow named Alberto.
Compliments of M. Dean.
Well, thank you.
I appreciate that.
Yeah. And, honey,
take as long as you want,
because when you're done,
your job will be right here
waiting for you.
And if you discover a path
that doesn't lead back here...
Well, I hope you'll text.
I will.
(CHUCKLES)
And, like I said,
the apartment's a mess,
but I'm moving, so...
It's okay. Relax about
the place. I don't care.
Okay. This'll just take
a second.
Okay.
(LA VEM A BAIANA
PLAYING ON STEREO)
BROOKE: Hello?
GARY: Hey. I'm in here.
Don't say anything. I...
How're you doing?
Could I talk to you in private
for a second?
You know what?
This is really
not a good time,
and obviously you have
something happening here,
so we'll just be in...
No, no, I don't have
anything going on.
This is actually for you.
I'm just gonna wait outside.
No, no. Wait.
No, no. Really. It's okay.
I really can't do this
right now.
Brooke, this whole thing
has been really tough on me
and I've tried to act
like it hasn't been
that tough on me,
but the first Sunday
after me and you broke up,
it all kind of really hit me.
And I think
it partially hit me
because Sunday was sort of
always our day that we
would do stuff together.
But I didn't have any idea
you still cared so much.
And, you know,
when I saw you crying
the other night,
that was honestly
the worst moment of my life.
Gary.
Let me just try to say
some of these things here.
It's just...
Look,
I know that I've caused you
a lot of pain.
And the funny thing is,
all I really want to do
is make you happy.
I just want to make you smile.
Now, I've had a lot of time
to think about
some of the things
that went on, and I know,
Brooke, that I don't always
do the right thing
or always say
the right things,
but I am willing to try
to do things differently.
And I'd be happy to go
take a dance class.
Well, I would. Honestly.
I would like to go do that.
Or go travel.
I mean, I'd even be willing
to go to the ballet.
Although I would much rather
do the dance class
or take a trip somewhere.
But I realize
that's not the point.
I realize that the point
isn't that at all,
because it's not really
about doing things
that you love to do always,
but it is about doing things
with the person that you love.
And I love you.
Gary.
Just give me one second here.
I've missed you so much.
(SOBBING)
I promise you, Brooke,
I will do whatever it is
that I have to do
to never hurt you again.
I love you and I'm sorry.
Okay, that's it.
That's all I...
Oh, God.
That's all I wanted to say,
so you can go ahead now
with anything that
you're feeling to say.
I don't know what to say.
Just say whatever
you feel inside.
I don't feel the same way.
I don't. I just...
I don't know.
Oh, God.
I just, I think...
I don't know,
but I don't think I have
anything left to give.
I'm sorry.
I was hoping for...
It doesn't matter.
Oh, this is now
beyond awkward.
There's some new guy
standing out in the hallway
and I think I'm gonna go.
Okay.
Thank you.
I made a dinner,
and I don't know if
it's any good or not,
but you're welcome to have it.
Okay.
Gary, that's really...
That's not what
you think that it is.
It's okay.
I'm gonna go take a walk.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
I'm sorry about that.
No.
I'm sorry I imposed.
No, that's fine. Please.
So, what do you think?
I think you're right.
I think it's great.
Good.
Okay.
So,
I will have that wrapped up.
Packed up, sorry,
and delivered.
Thank you for taking the time
to show it to me, okay?
Sure.
Yeah. I'm gonna run.
Okay, I'll walk you out.
No, no, no.
I can... It's okay.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
GARY: So, the thing that
I was most afraid
of happening happened
and I don't regret it at all,
because now she knows
how I feel.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
I think,
what you got to do now
is really think hard,
because you have
to find somebody
that can't be traced back
to either of us
to visit this guy.
What are you talking about?
I don't...
The guy who came with her.
I don't need anything
to happen to the guy.
But if they could trace him
back to either one of us...
It's not about him.
I don't care about that.
...it's a problem.
The guy, he's not a...
They're not dumb.
Cops are smart, trust me.
Okay, but he's not
a problem to me.
Right.
Listen to me.
Promise me that you're
not gonna do anything.
I got you.
It's better if nobody...
You don't know anything.
What are you talking about?
I'll take care of it.
I don't want you
to take care of anything.
John, do me a favor.
I'm being serious with you.
I know, I know.
Smart. You're smart.
No, I'm not.
I'm being honest with you.
I don't want anything
to happen to him.
Me, either.
Promise me you're not
gonna have anyone
do anything to this guy.
But you've gotta
tell me exactly
what you're gonna tell them,
if the cops come to you.
Because if we tell
a different story...
Nothing.
Promise me one thing.
We don't care...
John, I'm gonna go home.
I can't do this.
I'm exhausted.
Right, go home. Just make sure
your neighbors know
you're going home.
Do me a favor.
They got phone records. Make
a couple phone calls tonight.
Especially around 10:00.
Okay. Please don't
do anything. All right.
I don't mean it like...
I mean, honestly.
No, no, I got it.
For all you know,
nothing's happening.
I don't want anything
to happen.
Right.
Say it louder.
What are you doing here
so early?
Hey.
Everything okay
with you and...
Yeah, everything's
gonna be great.
I just wanna get
my day started,
but I just wanted to say that
I'm sorry it took
so long for me to...
I love you, Dennis.
(GASPING)
It's all right. It's okay.
I'm sorry. I'm gonna go
do the stuff.
So, that's it
for all my stuff.
If you want, you could give me
your key and I'll drop it off
at Riggleman's.
All right.
Thanks.
Gary.
You know, there's
a thousand things I...
I would have done differently.
Me, too.
Sort of, actually,
when I see this space, I
realize that if we didn't have
such a big coffee table
and that oversized couch
a pool table
would have fit nicely.
Yeah.
Although the oversized couch
did come in very useful the
last couple of weeks, so...
Yes, it... I guess.
Have a good trip.
Thanks.
GARY: Chicago is called
the Second City
because after the
Great Chicago Fire of 1871,
Chicago was rebuilt
on its ruins.
The city came back
even bigger and stronger
than it originally was.
So it's not really an insult,
it's more of a badge of honor
to be called...
The Second City!
Okay. People, you might
be able to get away
with that reaction at work,
but you are on vacation here.
If you can't blow it out here,
then where the hell
can you blow it out?
Ladies and gentlemen,
show me that you mean it.
Do not make me ask you twice.
Are you ready to see Chicago?
ALL: Yes!
I said, are you ready
to see Chicago?
ALL: Yes!
Are you ready to see Chicago?
Shondra, put this babe
in the air.
Let's go!
There is a bar downstairs.
Please enjoy yourself.
I know it's early
in the morning, but it is
Chicago in the summer.
Who are we kidding? It's fine.
Go get hopped up,
make some bad decisions.
My jokes get better.
The buildings look bigger.
It's not so important
that everything is finished.
It's important that
everything is right.
Well, what time's
the presentation?
All right, I'll pick up
the rest of the stuff
and I'll see you at 6:45.
Great. Bye.
GARY: Brooke!
Hi.
Wow.
(CHUCKLES)
It's good to see you.
I'd give you a hug,
but my hands are kind of
full with all the bags here.
How've you been?
I've been really good.
How have you been?
I've been good.
Yeah.
You look great.
Thank you.
The hair's a little different.
Looks nice.
Yeah? Oh, yeah.
You've lost some weight.
Well, it's very
deceiving, actually.
I've managed to become thin
without having any real muscle
on me whatsoever.
Very tough thing to
accomplish, by the way.
I'm proud of myself.
Well, you look terrific.
Thanks.
I heard your trip
went really well.
It did. It went really well.
Oh, good.
It was fun. It was amazing.
I saw so many amazing places.
It was just...
But, you know,
you do realize
how much you love home.
It's good to have you back.
Yeah. It's good to be back.
And the boat.
Congratulations on the boat.
Thanks.
I'm waiting for it
to get warm, and I'm gonna
come by and take a ride.
Well, anytime you want.
It'll be on the house.
Come on by.
Well, I will, then.
I hope you do.
Definitely.
Well, I got to...
I'm going to a meeting, so...
I got to drop these bags
off anyway, but it's really
good to see you, Brooke.
Really good to see you.
Shouldn't...
Sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm just saying we shouldn't
wait so long the next time
before we...
Yeah.
...catch up.
We have a lot more
to talk about.
Yeah.
So.
Be good.
Okay.
Bye.
(I CAN SEE CLEARLY NOW
PLAYING)
(RAINBOW CONNECTION PLAYING)