THE PAINTED VEIL
CHINA 1925
LONDON TWO YEARS EARLIER
Hello.
Say, I was wondering...
What?
Sorry. I was wondering if
you'd like to dance?
Why not?
Kitty, who was the young man you were
dancing with last night?
Which one?
The quiet, serious-looking one.
Oh, him.
I suppose you invited him, Mother.
I don't know who you're talking about.
I invited him.
His name is Fane and he's a doctor.
He manages a government laboratory
in Shanghai.
A civil servant?
In any case.
He called 'round last Sunday,
we had a long chat.
I told him to come back anytime.
It's not often that you like
any of my young men.
Well, do you like him?
Not really.
- What's wrong with him?
- Is he in love with you?
I don't know.
I should have thought by now
you'd know when a
young man was in love with you.
The point is whether or not I'm in love
with him. And I'm not.
You'd better be careful, young lady.
Time can run out, you know.
Oh, stop it, Mother. Honestly.
The very idea that a woman
should marry
any Tom, Dick, or Harry...
...regardless of her own feelings is
simply prehistoric.
How much longer do you expect your
father to go on supporting you?
Oh.
Hello.
Hello. I...
I was just coming...
Your father invited me.
I'm going out.
May I join you?
Right on time.
What is it exactly that you do?
I'm a bacteriologist.
That must be fascinating.
You have no idea what that is, do you?
No. I'm afraid not.
No, there's no reason you should.
I study the microorganisms
that carry disease.
Charming.
No, it's not actually. It's the opposite.
Shall we step inside?
Do you like flowers?
Not particularly, no.
Well, I mean, yes.
But we don't really have
them around the house.
Mother says,
"Why purchase something you can
grow for free?"
But then we don't really grow them
either.
It does seem silly, really.
To put all that effort into something
that's just going to die.
I'd like to say something to you.
I came to see you to ask you
if you'll marry me.
You could knock me down
with a feather.
Could you not tell that I'm in love
with you?
You never showed it.
Oh, I'd...
Well, I wanted to. It's difficult. I...
But there it is.
Right.
I'm not sure that's very well put.
No, it's not.
Do you see how clumsy I am? I...
I'm terrible at these sorts of things.
But the thing is
I've got to get back to China very soon.
I don't have time to be cautious.
I've never thought of you in that way.
I think I improve greatly
upon acquaintance.
Oh, I'm sure you do...
I'd do anything in my power to
make you happy.
Anything at all.
I think you'd like Shanghai.
It's quite exciting, it is.
Lots of dancing.
Surely you're not expecting me to
answer this second?
I don't know you at all.
Yes! Well,
we had the highest of hopes, but...
...no expectation that he'd ask her
so soon.
Yes. A lovely late autumn wedding.
She's done very well for her herself,
has my Doris.
At least one of them's made a success.
No, I gave up on Kitty ages ago.
Yes.
Well, I know you understand. Yes.
Well?
Is it smaller than you imagined?
I'm not sure what I imagined.
Don't you have a piano?
No, I don't play the piano.
Who is it?
It's I.
Come in.
Just wanted to see
So, then, you're comfortable, then?
Do you need anything?
No.
I'm fine.
Thank you.
Good. Good.
I'm so happy you're here.
Shall I shut the lamp?
What for?
I'll shut the lamp.
It's raining cats and dogs.
I said, it's raining cats and dogs.
Yes, I heard you.
You might have answered.
I'm sorry.
I've gotten used to not speaking...
...unless I have something to say.
If nobody spoke unless
they had something to say...
...the human race would soon
lose the power of speech.
Walter.
I'm sorry.
You're right.
What shall we do? Shall we...
...shall we play a game?
You don't like the games I play.
They bore you.
Nonsense.
Let's play cards.
Do you think you'd enjoy a night out?
We have an invitation for
Saturday night.
From whom?
The Townsends.
Dorothy Townsend.
Do you not like her?
Well, I've only met her once,
but there's no reason for her
to put on such airs.
Does she?
Yes. I have no idea why.
She was what?
Married to a vice consul?
Honestly, they're absurd,
this Shanghai set.
Mother wouldn't dream of asking
half of them to dinner.
I'm taking that black five.
Well, it's all right.
I thought you might enjoy it,
but we certainly don't have to go.
I don't care either way.
Go where?
- Kitty Fane?
- Hello, Dorothy.
I'm so glad you could come.
This is Walter.
I'm pleased to meet you.
This is my husband.
Charlie, stop talking and
greet our guests.
- You know Mr. Fane.
- Charlie.
It's Dr. Fane, darling.
Oh, dear. I do beg your pardon,
Dr. Fane.
Not at all.
And this is Dr. Fane's wife, Kitty.
Mrs. Fane.
Mr. Townsend.
I do apologize, Dr. Fane.
I assumed you worked with Charlie
at the consulate.
Oh, no. Nothing so glamorous.
I'm at the Civil Laboratory.
The government lab? How fascinating.
Are you enjoying it?
I've never seen anything like it.
Every gesture has a meaning.
See how she covers her face
with the cloth?
She is mourning her misfortune.
What happened to her?
She was sold into slavery.
Condemned to a life of drudgery
and despair...
...in a strange land far from home.
See the chains?
They represent the heavy bondage
of her poor trapped soul...
...from which there is no escape.
And so she weeps.
She weeps for the lively,
vivacious girl she once was...
...for the lonely woman she has become.
And most of all...
...she weeps for the love
she'll never feel...
...for the love she'll never give.
Is that really what she's saying?
Actually, I haven't a clue what
she's on about.
I don't speak Chinese.
What was that?
Perhaps it was the amah,
or one of the...
They've gone.
He heard us.
Who?
Walter.
Walter. What if it was?
For all he knows you were taking a nap.
With my doors locked?
Kitty, dear, you need a drink.
Even if it was,
my impression is he'll do nothing.
That's flattering.
He knows as well as anyone...
...there's nothing to be gained by
making a scandal.
Has it occurred to you that my husband
is in love with me?
I have a feeling you're about to say
something awful.
It's just that women are often under
the impression that...
...men are much more in love with them
than they really are.
I wouldn't delude myself for a second
that you were in love with me.
Now there you're wrong.
Do you like your present?
It's good enough.
Charlie?
Do I make you as happy as
you make me?
Of course you do, darling.
(Miss you Father)
- Hassan?
- Yes?
- Who brought this package 'round?
- Dr. Fane.
When?
While you sleeping.
It's nearly midday.
We could stop up here under the trees...
...but I'd like to press on if
it's all right with you.
Certainly, my comfort's of no concern
to you.
Right. Then we'll continue.
Charlie Townsend, please.
Charles Townsend.
I need to see you.
Kitty, I can't possibly see you.
I've got a meeting in an hour at the club.
What is it?
I have to go.
What are you doing home?
I'm sorry. There's something I need
to speak with you about.
Actually, I was just about to
take my bath.
I'm afraid it's rather important, darling.
Can't wait.
Sit down.
Do you know a place called
Mei-Tan-Fu?
No.
Well, it was in the papers the other day.
It's a small town on a tributary
of the Yangtze River,
in the interior.
They've had an outbreak of
cholera there.
It's the worst epidemic anyone's seen
in a long time.
The Chinese medical officer has died.
There's a convent of French nuns and
they're trying to run the hospital...
...and they're doing the best
that they can,
but people are dropping like flies.
I have volunteered to go and
to take charge.
Why?
Because they need a doctor.
But you're not a doctor.
You're a bacteriologist.
I'm an M.D.
The fact that I'm foremost a scientist...
...is actually all to the good in this case.
Won't it be awfully dangerous?
I suppose it might, yes.
Now, Mei-Tan-Fu is a ten-day journey.
You can go by rail for the first part of it,
but after that it's carriage...
...and then we'll have to take a
sedan chair.
Who's we?
Why, you and I, of course.
You're not expecting me to come too?
I hoped that if I was going
you would want to go.
Surely it's no place for a woman.
It would be madness for me to go.
Why should I?
To cheer and comfort me?
No.
No, I won't go.
In fact, it's monstrous of you
to even ask me.
Fine. Then I shall file my petition
for divorce tomorrow.
I'm afraid that you have thought me
a bigger fool than I am.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't you?
I am divorcing you for adultery.
I am naming Charles Townsend
as your lover.
I'm sorry, Walter.
I realize this is very unpleasant, but,
please, let's not make this uglier
than it needs to be.
By all means. What is it that you
propose that we should do?
You could let me divorce you quietly.
You divorce me?
- On what grounds, may I ask?
- That's what a gentleman would do.
Can you give me one reason I should...
...put myself to the smallest
inconvenience on your account?
Please, Walter, don't be so hateful.
We didn't mean to hurt anyone. But...
...Charlie and I have fallen in love.
He wants to marry me.
Really?
I knew that you weren't the cleverest girl
in the world...
...but I didn't know that you were
actually a fool.
Yes. Well, if it makes you feel better
to hurt me,
then go ahead.
But you might as well get used to it.
We love each other.
And we're sick to death of the secrecy...
...and compromise and all the rest of it.
And now you curse the day
that you ever met me.
Stop mocking me.
There's no other response...
...for such pathetic behavior!
It's comic.
When I think about how hard I've tried
to make you happy.
Debasing myself!
Acting as though I was as thrilled
as you...
...by the latest gossip
and as vulgar and as ignorant...
- ...of the world as you are!
- Shut up!
If you interrupt me again,
I'll strangle you.
Sit down.
I knew when I married you that
you were selfish and spoiled.
But I loved you.
I knew that you married me...
...only to get as far away from
your mother as possible...
...and I hoped that one day...
...there'd be something more.
I was wrong.
You don't have it in you.
If a man hasn't what's necessary
to make a woman love him,
then it's his fault...
...not hers.
Either way.
Tomorrow morning we are to leave for
Mei-Tan-Fu,
or I shall file my petition.
Walter, you can't be serious about
taking me...
...into the middle of a cholera epidemic.
Do you think that I'm not?
My God.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Do you really think Charlie
will let you do this?
I don't think Charlie has very much
to say about it.
Everything you said is true.
Everything.
I married you even though
I didn't love you.
But you knew that.
Aren't you as much to blame for
what's happened as I?
All right.
Here's what I'll do.
Gentlemen, we all have assets
to protect here.
Unfortunately, Mr. Nagata's actions...
...have created a rather urgent situation.
It was an unfortunate,
but unavoidable incident.
Your foreman shot a worker.
He was an agitator.
He was a Chinese.
You may have suppressed a
very small strike...
...but in doing so you have started...
...a very large demonstration.
I need to use your pen, please.
Here you are, miss.
What about support from
Chiang Kai-shek?
Where does he stand on this?
He's a Nationalist. He will stand
on the side of the Chinese.
That's why they call themselves
Nationalists.
Excuse me.
Mr. Townsend.
I think you underestimated the situation.
I have three of my mills shut down
because of walk-outs.
There is talk about boycotts.
So, what do you propose?
A handful of municipal soldiers is
hardly a show of force.
If you'll excuse me.
Mrs. Fane. What a pleasant surprise.
You've rescued me from
a pack of wild bores.
I wouldn't have come if
it wasn't necessary.
Are you all right?
I needed to see you. I'm sorry.
Kitty, this is not the most opportune
time for me to...
He knows.
Right.
After you, Mrs. Fane.
Hello, Charlie.
Hello, George.
Hello, Townsend.
Adam.
He wants a divorce.
You didn't commit yourself, did you?
Acknowledge anything?
No.
Are you sure?
Quite sure.
Well.
This is a bloody scrape we're in.
He says he has proof.
We deny it.
He can't prove anything.
Besides, it wouldn't do Walter
any good to create a scandal.
But there isn't going to be a scandal.
Walter's agreed to let me
divorce him quietly.
That's not so terrible, is it?
Will you hold me?
Of course I will.
Oh, God.
Charlie?
His offer comes with a condition.
I'm not a rich man.
He doesn't want your money.
He's agreed to let me divorce him...
...if Dorothy will agree to divorce you.
And if...
What?
If you'll promise to marry me.
You know, darling, whatever happens,
we must try to keep Dorothy out of it.
What do you mean?
We can't only think of ourselves.
I know Dorothy.
Nothing in the world will induce her
to divorce me.
You don't want to divorce her.
It's not just a question of my marriage...
Then what is it?
Do you have any idea of the importance
of my station here?
If I were...
Why are you laughing?
I don't think Walter intended for
one minute to divorce me.
He knew you'd let me down.
Try to understand.
I understand, all right.
Kitty! Kitty, please.
We'll work this out, I promise. D...
I'm coming with you.
Good. I thought you might.
I suppose I needn't take more than
a few summer things?
And a shroud?
I've told Hassan what you will need.
She's packing already.
I wouldn't touch that if I was you.
They may have died in that bed.
This can be your room.
You must be the doctor's wife.
I've just met your husband...
...and invited myself to dinner.
I've kept the Watsons' cook for you.
She's not bad.
She'll have to do as your amah as well.
We're a little short-handed here.
Sorry, my name is Waddington.
Oh, yes, of course. Kitty Fane.
I'm the Deputy Commissioner.
Please.
I believe you're one of our neighbors.
Only neighbor, I'm afraid.
Last one standing.
And Watson was the missionary
living here?
Yes. Nice fellow.
American. Lovely family.
I'll show you their graves tomorrow,
if you like.
How kind of you.
I hope your journey wasn't too arduous?
We've been traveling for two weeks.
Two weeks? What did you do, swim?
No, we didn't come up river.
Came overland.
Whatever for?
Well, we wanted to take in a bit
of the countryside.
Get a bit of sun. Didn't we, darling?
Anyone for a cocktail?
Here's luck.
I was told I might get some help from
the local army officer.
Colonel Yu, is it?
Good luck with him. He's not fond
of us British.
Listen, I'll warn you,
things are pretty dicey even out here.
I'm afraid that if the cholera
doesn't get us,
the Nationalists might.
Tried to get those nuns to go,
but they refused.
They all want to be martyrs,
damn them.
And why have you stayed?
I was posted here. Simple as that.
I was shocked to hear you'd volunteered.
Opportunity for research.
I couldn't pass it up.
Yes. And you?
I don't suppose you've come to
Mei-Tan-Fu for the research.
My husband's the scientist.
Indeed.
Did you have any reaction to the
inoculation?
You have been inoculated?
Yes, of course.
No guarantee.
The Watsons were inoculated,
it didn't do them much good.
Have you brought any gramophone
records?
No, unfortunately not.
Pity. I'm sick of all mine.
Listen.
What's all that?
Across the river.
Trying to frighten off the spirit of death.
I'm going to town in the morning.
Have a look around.
I expect you'll want to rest.
I can inoculate you in the evening.
Will you be doing yourself?
No, I don't think so.
You needn't bother with me then.
Suit yourself.
Tell me, Walter.
Is it a long, drawn-out affair,
dying of cholera?
No. All of the fluid goes out of you...
...in the first 36 hours.
You die of dehydration, actually.
So, it's messy and very painful.
But it is relatively quick.
Good night.
It's rather unfortunate.
I thought perhaps that you and
your wife...
...you'd like to take precautions in case
you have to leave this place.
Do you think all this is really necessary?
You can see the picture.
I thought you'd like to put
your wife's mind...
...at rest from this situation.
This is Colonel Yu.
He's the KMT's man.
He's posting one of his men here
at the house.
Am I a prisoner?
No. It was Mr. Waddington's
idea actually.
He feels we should take precautions.
Precautions against what?
A few days ago,
British troops opened fire...
...on a group of Chinese workers who
were demonstrating in Shanghai.
Eleven were killed.
We've only just heard.
Those were plastered around
the town last night.
(Death to foreign murderers!)
I shouldn't worry too much.
Even the Nationalists are afraid
of cholera.
Do they take that water from the well?
Colonel, can I see where they get
their drinking water?
(Imperialist pig!)
For starters,
we've got to stop people from...
...using this well until I can test it.
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand, Dr. Fane.
I received my military training
in Moscow.
If you don't like English,
we can speak Russian.
English will be fine. Thank you.
Here.
You have seen cholera before,
yes, Doctor?
At the laboratory, of course.
No, I mean in a patient.
No. No, I haven't had the chance
Well, I'm not a clinician.
Did they not tell you?
I'm an infectious disease specialist.
Shall we?
After you, Doctor.
(Charlie)
(without you it is intolerable)
I don't need you.
Go back!
Mr. Waddington?
I'm looking for Mr. Waddington.
Wait here. All right?
Hello?
Mr. Waddington?
Mrs. Fane?
Good morning.
What can I do for you, Mrs. Fane?
I found a record for you.
Stravinsky.
Very modern. Thank you.
Was there something else?
I was wondering if you could tell me...
...when the post comes through.
It's for Shanghai.
Unfortunately, since the cholera,
the cowards won't venture
past the river port...
...but leave it with me.
A local trader I know is making the trip
on Friday.
Townsend.
Charlie Townsend?
Yes. He's an acquaintance
of my husband.
Do you know him?
Years ago. We were both assigned
to the consulate in Shanghai.
Charming wife?
Yes. They're very popular, aren't they?
He'd made a science of popularity.
So, you know his family?
Well, well enough. I like Dorothy.
Yes, I understand they're quite
the devoted couple.
Oh, he had his little flirtations.
Nothing serious.
I once heard her say that she found it
most unflattering...
...that the women who fell
for her husband...
...were so consistently second-rate.
Well, enjoy the record.
Mrs. Fane?
The letter.
Right.
Yes, it suddenly occurred to me that
Friday's much too late.
Thanks all the same.
Can you pass the salt, please?
I'm sorry. Did you say something?
Could you pass the salt?
Thank you.
So, this is how it's going to be?
Passing her evenings in silence.
Walter.
Walter!
I wonder if you haven't gone insane.
- She's not cooking it.
- Leave it.
Leave it.
Thank you.
Are you looking to kill yourself?
Town well's contaminated.
This is dirty. It's dirty.
What?
Mr. Waddington?
Mrs. Fane?
Mrs. Fane!
Come away. Come away.
What's the matter with Te-Ming?
You have the dead man on you.
They're very superstitious, aren't they?
She's lost three children and a husband
to the cholera.
So, you can hardly blame her.
You know,
this is no place for a woman.
When they telegraphed me
that you were
coming out, I was astonished.
I imagined you might be a grim-visaged
old nurse...
...with thick legs and a mustache.
I came into the bungalow
and there you were...
...frail and tired...
...and very unhappy.
It was a long journey.
But you're unhappy now.
And it occurred to me that you and your
husband might be madly in love...
...and that you'd simply refused
to stay behind.
That's a reasonable explanation.
Yes. But it's not the right one.
Do you know what I find strange?
That your husband should never look
at you.
He looks at the walls, the floor,
his shoes.
He has a great deal on his mind.
Yes, I'm sure of it.
Dr. Fane!
Oh, God.
All right.
What are you doing?
Martini?
Yes?
I'm the bearer of a message from the
Mother Superior.
Who?
The nun who supervises the orphanage
and the hospital.
I didn't know she was aware of
my existence.
Well, apparently Mr. Waddington
has spoken of you.
She would very much like to meet
the loving...
...loyal wife of the compassionate
Dr. Fane.
Right. Then I must prepare myself
for the charade.
She does understand if you...
...don't want to venture into the center
of the epidemic.
If you're not afraid, why should I be?
I forgot.
Walter!
Oh, my God!
Oh, you're drunk.
(Foreigner!)
(Go home!)
Don't expect anything grand.
They're miserably poor.
Hello.
It's a great pleasure to make
the acquaintance
of the wife of our good and brave doctor.
Lovely to meet you, too.
Mr. Waddington.
You must eat the madeleines.
Sister St. Joseph made them for you
herself this morning.
So, tell me, Mrs. Fane.
To which faith do you subscribe?
Excuse me.
We attended services,
not religiously regularly.
You could say I'm a member of the
Church of England.
Which is an inoffensive way
of saying you
don't quite believe in anything much.
You're very pretty.
And very young.
I assure you I'm not. I feel ancient.
If Mrs. Fane would like to see
over the convent...
...and orphanage. I shall be glad
to show her.
Alone.
We keep the older girls busy
with sewing.
It keeps them occupied.
And earns money for the convent.
That one won't allow us to baptize her.
Our music room.
Sister Maryse.
Sister Dominique was our pianist.
She died last week. Cholera.
Through there is the infirmary.
It is not a sight one would wish to see.
Shall I call Dr. Fane out to see you?
No. You needn't disturb him.
Now, with the epidemic...
...we have even more to care for.
This baby was brought in this morning.
Another orphan.
She says Dr. Fane loves babies.
He spends as much time as he can
in the nursery.
Mrs. Fane?
You all right?
Yes.
It's nothing...
...only foolishness.