(CROWD CHEERING)
ANNOUNCER: This is the one
and only PBR World Final!
Luke Collins is young,
easy on the eyes,
and a magician on a bull.
(BULL GRUNTS)
But right now,
he's about to face his ultimate demon.
He is about to ride a bull
who needs no introduction.
This bull has 74
consecutive buck-offs.
Las Vegas,
you know who I'm talking about.
This is Rango!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(BULL GRUNTING)
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(BULL GRUNTING)
(ALL CHEERING LOUDLY)
And he is ready
to rock and roll!
(BULL GRUNTING)
Let go!
ANNOUNCER: Wait a minute!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Luke Collins is down.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING
OVER SPEAKER)
Hey, do you guys
know where Sophia is?
No, sorry.
MARCIA: Tell them
to save our seats.
Did you see Sophia?
She's in her room studying.
But you're not
gonna get her to go.
Hi, Marcia.
Thanks for not disturbing.
I have a present for you.
Wait. You were serious?
Do I look serious?
No, you look ridiculous.
Oh, come on, Soph.
They're so much fun.
I can't.
I have work to do.
It's second
semester senior year.
Your grades are stellar.
You already have a job
lined up in New York.
An internship.
All of the work and none of the pay.
Half the house is going.
I don't see myself
as a rodeo gal.
Fine. It's not the rodeo,
it's bull riding.
There's a difference.
You're missing the point.
Hot guys, I know.
No, not "hot guys."
The hottest guys
you have ever seen.
Please.
Fine.
(GASPS EXCITEDLY)
But I'm not wearing
those cowboy boots.
So, this is it, huh?
Yeah, this is it.
"The toughest spost on dirt"!
GIRL: Yeah,
I need a hot cowboy.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
Whoa!
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(WHISTLES)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GASPS)
Oh, my God!
Whoa!
What was that?
Look at that guy
in the chute.
ANNOUNCER: Fans, we're gonna go now to
the Ridin' Dirty bucking chute...
where we have got
local hero Luke Collins
from Walkertown,
North Carolina!
Go, Luke!
(ALL CHEERING)
He's a three-time
PBR World Finals champion.
For over a year,
an injury has sidelined him.
But he's back.
Currently ranked
52nd in the world.
He has a long way to go.
LUIZ: You ready for this?
We'll see.
(LUKE BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
ANNOUNCER: And today,
he will be riding Sweet Thang.
(BULL GRUNTS)
(ALL EXCLAIM)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Let's go!
(GRUNTING)
Yeah, go!
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
Whoo! Yeah!
(EXCLAIMS)
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have ourselves a champion.
Yeah! That's my boy!
I feel like I should stand!
ANNOUNCER: Luke Collins
now moves up...
to 48th in
the world standings.
(CLANGING)
(MAN WHISTLING)
Hey!
Keep it.
(GIRLS EXCLAIMING)
Oh!
Work it, girl.
It's so big on you.
I know.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SINGING) Lay me down
by the old oak tree
Don't cut my hair
when they bury me
Light me up
and send me out to sea
One, two, three
In the backwoods company...
(SIGHS)
Nice riding, cowboy.
Of course,
my grandma could have made
the eight on Sweet Thang.
It's good to
have you back, Luke.
It was getting too
easy without you.
LARRY: Jared!
Hey, buddy.
I'll be right back.
Hey, Larry.
Good to see you.
Good to see you here.
Luke, hey, man.
How are you doing?
Congratulations, man.
I know it feels good to get a
win under your belt, doesn't it?
Sure does.
Yeah.
Let me ask you.
You need to come visit us.
I wanna introduce you
to some good folks from PBR.
Important folk.
Come get a beer.
JARED: You got it.
I'll be right behind you.
Yes. Okay.
Hey, um...
You had a good night.
But it's a long
way back to the top.
I got a hat just like that.
Yeah. Sorry.
No, you hold on to it.
Looks better on you.
Like this?
May I?
Sure.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Luke.
Sophia.
Nice to meet you, Sophia.
I'm gonna... Can I...
Can I get you a drink?
You were the big
winner tonight, right?
I think I should be the one
buying you a beer.
Oh, no.
Doesn't work like
that where I'm from.
Okay.
You're buying.
MARCIA: Sophia!
(GASPS)
Hi! Whoa.
There you are.
I've been looking
all over for you.
Um, this is Marcia.
She's my...
Sister.
Sorority sister.
BFFs, if we're
speaking technically.
You are gorgeous.
(SOPHIA LAUGHS)
Time to put you in a cab.
What?
I just need everything
to stop spinning for a sec.
I'm gonna be sick.
What?
I think I'm gonna be sick.
How sure?
High 90s.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa!
Yeah. We got her.
Okay.
I should take her home.
Yeah. Probably a good idea.
I would say that
I'd call you...
but I have a feeling,
where you come from...
it just doesn't
work like that.
That's right.
I'll call you?
You're telling me
that he has called you,
and you haven't called him back?
I'm moving to New York
in two months.
What's the point?
Have you gotten
a good look at him?
Those shoulders, those eyes.
That's the point.
Okay, look.
I am starting a new
chapter of my life.
I do not need
any distractions.
(CHUCKLES) Sophia,
you are literally the only girl I know...
who wouldn't have
a fling with a cowboy.
(SIGHS)
(CLEARS T HROAT)
Okay.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(LINE RINGING)
Straight to voice-mail.
LUKE: Hello?
Hey, Luke. It's Sophia.
I was wondering if maybe
you wanted to hang out sometime...
or grab coffee
or something.
No, I'm okay.
Okay.
Uh, well, I guess I should
just let you go, then.
I'm just messing
with you, Sophia.
How about dinner?
You mean, like a date?
Yeah, like a date.
Wow!
Most guys, they just say,
"What are you doing later?"
Or they text late at night,
"Hey, come over."
Yeah, well,
call me old-school.
Should I meet you somewhere?
No. I'll pick you
up at your place.
Does 6:00 work for you?
Okay.
(SINGING)
I feel a sin comin' on
Please Jesus don't
hold me back
I know it ain't mine
but I want it so bad
The smoke in the whiskey's
got me feeling easy
And after I'll fade
in the glass
And you can see it
All over my face
LUKE: Ladies.
Sweet temptation
All over the place
(GIRLS GIGGLING)
(SIGHS)
Give me tall dark
and handsome
Mix it up with
something strong
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
I feel a sin comin' on
Hi.
I know you.
Marcia, right?
Mmm-hmm.
The last time
I saw you...
you were a little blurry.
Yeah.
You can come in.
Thank you.
She's upstairs getting ready.
Hi.
Um...
Thank you.
So sweet.
(GIRL SIGHS)
GIRL: He's even
bought her flowers.
Shall we?
Yeah.
Good night, ladies.
GIRL: Good night, you guys.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
MARCIA: Oh, my God!
I want a cowboy!
GIRL 2: He is so hot!
You never said you lived
in a sorority house.
Uh... Yeah, well,
it's the cheapest rent on campus.
Is it like
I would imagine?
How would you imagine?
Eh...
Pillow fights in your underwear.
(LAUGHS) No. Come on!
We don't wear underwear.
(LAUGHING)
(CLEARS THROAT)
I got you, a little.
Uh-huh. You did.
Okay. So where are we going?
That's a surprise.
(GROANS)
It's breathtaking.
Yeah.
Well, aren't you
full of surprises?
I can't believe
you made dinner for me.
Well, Amy made dinner.
Who is Amy?
Smokin' Amy's.
Best barbecue
in North Carolina.
I kind of got into that and classical,
which is so strange.
I know. It's weird.
It's totally like...
How did a girl from Rutherford,
New Jersey end up
in the middle
of North Carolina?
LUKE: Yeah,
something like that.
I ended up getting
a scholarship down here,
so I couldn't pass it up.
Scholarship?
Pretty fancy.
I kind of knew that
tips from my dad's diner...
weren't really going to cut it.
I just...
I love art.
I love everything about it.
I love studying it.
I love the culture
that it brings...
and the whole
human experience...
just all wrapped up into one.
Anger, sadness...
love, passion,
acceptance...
history.
Never mind. I don't know.
What about you?
Tell me about you.
What's your story?
No, mine's, uh...
Mine's pretty simple.
Just keep winning events.
Make it to the top 35.
Go to Vegas.
Make it to the finals.
I got some
making up to do.
I got hurt last year.
What do you mean
you got hurt?
All bull riders get hurt.
It's not "if."
It's "when."
And how bad.
How bad was yours?
Serious?
I've got a few
more years to ride...
before I'm just
a washed-up bull rider.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm going to be the best.
It's just all about winning?
No, it's not all
about winning.
Well, not entirely.
I've got a family ranch.
It's been a tough couple years.
My mom is kind of
all on her own.
I just gotta
keep making money.
Mmm.
Are you cold?
You're cold.
A little.
Where are you going?
What do they call
this nail polish color?
This would be "clear."
Clear.
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
Right. Clear.
That makes sense.
It's good.
You are pretty smooth
for a country boy.
Me?
Yeah, you.
Come on, I saw the way
those girls stared at you.
You think
I'm that type of guy?
No.
No one has ever done
anything like this for me before.
So, uh, do you like
North Carolina?
Yeah, I do.
It's beautiful.
Yeah.
Um...
I'm actually moving to New York
at the end of next month.
I got this job.
Well, it's an internship,
actually.
But it's a pretty big deal.
It's at a gallery in Manhattan.
Okay.
Uh...
That's why it took me so long
to call you back.
I just didn't think that
this would even be a good idea.
I'm glad you did.
Yeah?
Yeah.
This is just bad timing.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Oh, I probably
should take you home.
Gonna rain.
Did you see that?
What?
(BRAKES SQUEAL)
Luke!
What is it?
Call 911!
Hey! Wake up!
Is he alive?
Here, hold this.
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Box.
What did he say? "Box"?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(GROANING WEAKLY)
(PANTING)
I think you just
saved that guy's life.
(EXHALES) We both did.
Oh, come on,
I held the flashlight.
You were amazing.
I just hope
that he's okay.
I'll take you home.
I think I'm going
to stay.
Really?
Yeah, at least until he gets
out of the emergency room.
Then I'll wait with you.
No, it's fine.
Really.
And thank you for tonight.
Yeah, it was a...
it was a great night.
Kind of.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(SIGHS)
Good luck with
everything in New York.
Mmm-hmm.
"April 10th, 1940.
"My dearest Ruth...
IRA: "Today started out
like any other day.
"But when you walked in
to my father's store...
"so beautiful, so vibrant...
(DOOR BELLS JINGLING)
"I knew my life would
forever be changed."
You are the new family
the Rabbi has told us about.
From Vienna?
MRS. PFEFFER: Uh, yes.
I am Hannah...
and this is my daughter,
Ruth.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Sarah...
and this is my son, Ira.
Ira?
(RABBI SPEAKING HEBREW)
Good Shabbes.
ALL: Good Shabbes.
Good Sha...
IRA: The following
days were consumed...
with plotting ways in which
I could talk to you...
now that you had found
a home in my small community.
(INDISTINCT)
IRA: But I wasn't the only
one seeking your attention.
This would take
some more time.
(SIREN WAILING)
He's awake,
if you'd like to see him.
NURSE WILSON:
You have to eat something,
Mr. Levinson.
It's the only way you're
going to get better.
I'm old.
I've had a heart attack...
a hip replacement...
Surgery in both knees.
How much better
am I going to get?
Who are you?
I, uh...
I came to drop this off.
How'd you get that?
SOPHIA: From your car.
You asked me
to get it for you.
Oh, you...
You pulled me out?
No, my friend Luke
pulled you out...
but you asked me to
go back and get this box.
You don't remember?
Hmm.
Well, thank you.
Very much.
He seems to like you,
which is a first for him.
See if you can get him
to eat something,
would you?
She has the coldest hands
I've ever felt.
I think she soaks
them in ice water...
before she comes by.
You really
should eat something.
I'm done.
Is that what
Ruth would want?
How do you know about Ruth?
Did you read my letters?
What do you care?
You're done.
They're beautiful.
She was a beautiful woman.
In every way.
I can see why they
were so precious to you.
I haven't been able
to read them for years.
Even with my glasses.
Do you want me
to read them to you?
But you have to eat first.
"May 25th, 1940.
"For the first
time in my life...
"I was hoping the service at the
synagogue would be longer."
(ALL SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
Excuse me.
(CHUCKLES)
Are you ever
going to talk to me?
Excuse me?
I always see you there,
lurking around.
(SCOFFS)
I don't lurk.
You do lurk.
But then you never talk to me.
Am I so frightening?
No, I...
(CHUCKLES)
What you did to that poor
rose was unforgiveable.
You saw that?
(CHUCKLES)
Don't be embarrassed.
It was a lovely gesture.
MRS. PFEFFER: Ruthie?
Want to walk me home?
Oh...
What about David Stein?
He can walk my mother home.
(CHUCKLES)
Vienna is beautiful
and so cultured.
It has more
artists than Paris.
At least it did
before the war.
It must have been
hard for you to leave.
Yeah.
Especially for my parents.
But it would have been worse
if we had stayed.
Everyone thought
we were being foolish...
that my father
was overreacting.
Now we can't even contact
our relatives anymore.
Sometimes I think...
what right do I have
to be happy
when there's so much
suffering in the world?
I guess you could say,
what right do you have to be unhappy?
True.
For a country pumpkin,
you're quite philosophical.
(CHUCKLES)
What?
It's a "country bumpkin"
not a "country pumpkin."
What?
I think I prefer
the way you said it.
RUTH: Well.
Thank you
for walking me home.
Oh, you're welcome.
It was a pleasure.
(INHALES)
(SIGHS)
Ruth...
Do you want to go
out with me sometime?
I'm free after Shabbat.
Wait. You want
to go out tonight?
We're not getting
any younger, Levinson.
You can wait there
if you want.
(SIGHS)
SOPHIA: "Forever yours...
"Ira."
You want me to
read you another one?
(LETTER RUSTLES)
Mmm.
But...
Could you maybe...
Could you maybe come back?
(CROWD CHEERING)
Carolina Thunder's
a good draw.
Sure you can handle him?
ANNOUNCER 1:
Savannah, Georgia fans,
put your hands together..
For the one,
the only, Rango!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(BANGING)
(GRUNTS)
We will move our attention down
to the Cooper Tires bucking chute...
where Evan Matthews from Summerville,
Georgia is set to go.
ANNOUNCER 2:
He is about to face a bull
that needs no introduction.
85 consecutive buck-offs...
(GRUNTING)
ANNOUNCER 1: He is going
for the Gold Buckle.
(GRUNTING)
(RIDER EXCLAIMING)
That looks familiar.
(MAN WHISTLING)
ANNOUNCER: Let's go
to Luke Collins.
If he makes a qualified ride
on Carolina Thunder...
he will crack the top 35 and
punch his ticket to Vegas!
Let's go!
He comes down too early
in a costly mistake.
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
A mistake that could cost
him a trip to the World Finals...
and ultimately,
a World Title.
You really gotta wonder...
where this guy
is mentally right now.
The incident with
Rango before he rode...
Good ride, Luke.
...has affected
his mental focus.
(GROANS)
(EXHALES)
Damn it!
(SIGHS)
(SINGING) What I've got
I don't want
All it does is hover
and taunt
Reminding me
what I used to be
What I may never be again
Learn it all again tomorrow
Nothing I have you can
borrow or steal
KATE: Return of
the conquering hero.
Hey, Mom.
You want eggs?
No.
So, how did it go?
Well, you left the ring
on your own two feet.
So, it's a victory for me.
When are you gonna
stop the bull riding, Luke?
Mom, I told you, I can't.
Really? So you forgot
about your head injury?
I'm a grown man.
I just want you to get
to be an old man.
Thanks.
You're scaring
the hell out of me, Luke.
Please just give it up.
Don't worry.
(LUKE SIGHS)
So, what's going on?
Nothing.
I met a girl.
You meet girls all the time.
No.
This one's different.
(SIGHS)
I can't stop
thinking about her.
So?
She moves to New York
in two months.
So, I guess
that's that, right?
IRA: You soak
your hand in ice water.
NURSE WILSON:
I do no such thing.
I'm the only person at
the hospital who still talks to you.
Am I interrupting?
I was just about
to strangle him! But...
Strangle me before dinner...
so I don't have to eat
another hospital meal.
The sooner the better.
Enjoy his letters.
You look good.
Shall we?
Yeah.
"July 12th, 1941
Oh.
(SOPHIA CHUCKLES)
That was a good day.
"Dearest Ruth,
the memories of our adventure...
"are always
dancing in my mind."
IRA: Seems like yesterday...
you helped me see the world
in a whole different way.
I don't know why
you insist we get
all dressed up
just to go to a movie.
In Vienna,
everyone always dresses up.
Even just to stroll
in the park. It's elegant.
It is also July
in North Carolina.
Oh, let me show you something.
I have to show you something!
What?
Ruth, we're going to be late.
(BAND PLAYING SWING MUSIC)
(SIGHS)
It's by an artist
in Black Mountain.
What's Black Mountain?
It's an arts college.
A whole movement,
right here in North Carolina.
And isn't it wonderful?
Such a personal landscape.
It's so direct and frank.
Simplified and distorted.
All at the same time.
(SIGHS)
Don't you love it?
I love how much
you love it.
(BAND PLAYING LIVELY MUSIC)
Come on.
RUTH: What? No, no, no.
Excuse me.
All right.
You want to dance?
Let's dance.
Oh! (GIGGLES)
Wow.
RUTH: Whoo!
IRA: That kiss,
our first kiss...
it was a promise
of everything to come.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON CAR RADIO)
IRA: The days became months.
We ventured on
weekends to new places.
Never once had I been
on vacation.
Had I, though...
it could never have been
as memorable as these.
What?
It's the first time North Carolina
has felt like home.
(GIGGLES)
But yet,
with my most important student...
I am a total failure.
(SIGHS)
Ruth has fallen in love
with contemporary art.
Father thinks that art stopped
with Matisse and Picasso.
I don't think it stopped.
But it's taken a long nap.
You try and raise
your children right, Ira...
and they grow up
and think for themselves.
Very good. Very good.
It's tragedy!
(ALL LAUGHING)
IRA: It was nice seeing you talk like that.
(RUTH GIGGLES)
IRA: Nothing would make me happier
than a lifetime of days like this.
Hey, Ruth. I need to ask
you something.
Wait.
(SIGHS)
I want a big family.
A really big family.
(CHUCKLES)
I've always wanted one
since I was a little girl.
With everything
that's going on now...
I feel this need,
this responsibility,
to bring life back
into the world.
Sounds perfect.
(CHUCKLES)
You can ask me now.
Ruth...
I know I'm not a rich man.
Don't know
the last thing about art.
All I can do is promise
to love you...
every second of every day
for the rest of my life.
Really?
Will you marry me?
Yes!
Yes, yes, yes!
What took you so long?
(ALL TOASTING IN HEBREW)
Welcome to the family.
Thank you.
So good to have you.
"With love, Ira."
(SOFTLY)
I'll come back tomorrow.
(POP SONG PLAYING ON RADIO)
(CHANGES STATION)
MAN: (SINGING) I'm gonna
set aside my pride
Not gonna be the one
to say "goodbye"
WOMAN: Neither am I
BOTH: Oh, tonight
Mr. Levinson?
Do I know you?
Luke Collins.
Remember, off 119...
when you decided to
bust open that guard rail?
(STAMMERS)
Oh, you saved my life.
Thank you.
Hi.
Is this your Luke?
This is my friend Luke.
Yes.
Your friend. Hmm.
Mmm-hmm.
What are you doing here?
I found this on
the floor of my truck.
Figured you might wanna
hang on to that one.
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT:
December 7th, 1941.
IRA:Nothing made me happier than knowing
we were going to be married.
But the world you and
your family had fled...
finally caught up to us.
PRESIDENT ROOSEVELT:
The United States of America...
Was suddenly
and deliberately attacked...
by Naval and Air Forces...
of the Empire of Japan.
Promise me you'll come back.
I will.
Promise me, Ira!
I promise.
(SIGHS)
Look at me. I promise.
Come back to me!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
SOLDIER: Help!
(GUNS FIRING)
(EXPLOSION)
We can't just
leave him out there.
SOLDIER: Help! Help me!
Somebody help me!
IRA: I gotta save him.
Are you crazy?
Those Panzers are 200 yards away.
You'll never make it back.
I'll make it back.
I made a promise
I have to keep.
You getting killed ain't gonna
help anyone but the Germans.
(GUNS FIRING)
SOLDIER: Help me! Please!
Oh, my God!
Can somebody help me?
Oh, shit.
Put your arms around my neck.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
I gotta get back.
I gotta get back to Ruth.
(GROANS)
That was goddamn crazy,
Levinson.
Do you know that?
(GROANS)
Shit!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SOFTLY) I'm very sorry.
(INDISTINCT)
IRA: When I came back from the war,
I wasn't the same.
I was fighting
a bigger battle now.
And I couldn't honor the
promise I had made to you.
Your mother says you've
been home since Monday.
I can't pretend to know
what you've been through...
but I want to help.
Don't you think
I deserve an explanation?
Well...
I do.
You don't understand.
It wasn't the injury itself.
The wound got infected.
I ran a high fever
for almost two weeks.
You need to see more doctors.
Get a second opinion.
Don't you think
I've already done that?
There's nothing
they can do.
(SIGHS) This is my life,
I have to accept it.
But I don't want it
to be yours.
But there is still a chance.
I want to marry you.
If you marry me,
you may never have a family.
Are you honestly willing
to give that up?
(ALL CHEERING)
IRA: The war was over...
and as far as I
was concerned...
so was my life.
(DOOR BELL JINGLES)
We're closed!
I know what you're doing!
You cannot tell me
what I'm willing to give up!
When you went to war...
I was here,
clinging to the hope...
that you would come home
and we would get married.
Yes, and have kids.
But that's a dream, Ira.
You're real.
I don't know what
the future holds...
but I know there's
no future without you.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Unless you don't
love me anymore.
IRA: And in that moment...
we both knew...
a chance at life together was
greater than the risk of being apart.
It was really nice of you
to bring that photo.
He sure has been
through a lot.
Yeah.
Uh...
Well, you take it easy.
Luke.
It was really good
to see you.
(CHUCKLES)
What are you doing
right now?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
SOPHIA: That looks good.
LUKE: Yeah.
SOPHIA: I'm ready.
LUKE: All right.
I'm so ready.
I'll give you
the little stick.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Ladies first.
I'm still getting used to
your Southern gentlemanly ways.
I'm still trying
to impress you.
It's kind of working.
A little.
Mmm...
Just don't let me win.
I enjoy good,
healthy competition.
Noted.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(CHUCKLES)
What are you doing?
You told me not
to let you win.
So I'm going with plan B.
Distraction.
Hmm.
Mmm-hmm.
Yes!
Yes! Sorry!
SOPHIA: Oh, thank you.
LUKE: Thank you very much.
Oh, I love mac and cheese.
(CHUCKLES)
Comfort food?
Yeah.
What's your comfort food?
(SIGHS)
Kolduny.
Kol-what?
They're these super,
super delicious...
Polish meat dumplings
that my mom makes.
We serve them
at the diner...
and I promise you,
with one bite of those...
it would put your mac
and cheese to shame.
Is that an invitation?
Maybe.
Oh. No, no.
Help yourself.
No!
Yeah.
Just a bite.
(CHUCKLES)
When did your parents
come to the States?
Uh, before I was born.
That's crazy.
I couldn't have done that.
Really?
No.
You ride bulls for a living.
You could do anything.
Riding bulls has got nothing
on moving clear across the world.
What?
Yeah.
Your parents had to
adjust their whole life.
No, they didn't
adjust anything.
Growing up with
immigrant parents,
my life was always
really different.
Everyone was always
screaming in weird languages...
I brought smelly,
strange snacks to school.
My pants were
too short always.
Pants still are too short.
Growing up on a cattle ranch,
everybody I knew was the same.
Everybody you know is fourth
generation cattle ranchers.
(SIGHS) I'm jealous.
Why?
I wanted to be like everyone
else when I was little.
The reason I like you is because
you're nothing like everyone else.
You're not so bad yourself.
I think before I met you,
the closest thing I came
to cattle was...
steak.
Steak? Time to get you
on a bull, then.
A bull?
Yeah.
No way! (CHUCKLES)
One bull, one time.
No! How about one horse,
one time?
We could do that.
Next week.
Okay.
Ooh. I've got an idea.
Uh-oh.
It's so good.
What?
So good! Come on!
LUKE: What?
Where am I going?
Where are we going?
You'll see.
After you.
Wow. Thank you.
(GIGGLES)
Ready?
Crazy face.
Yeah.
Yeah, that looks good.
Thank you.
(SINGING) Two hearts fading
Like a flower
Okay.
And all this waiting
There you go.
Whoa.
For the power
Put your feet in.
Grab the reins.
For some answer
To this fire
Sinking slowly
You ready?
Yeah.
Pull back on those reins.
Come on.
Hey, there we go!
Oh, whoa,
we're going backwards!
This is awesome!
Yeah, there you go,
just like that.
Lay your hands down.
Okay.
With no secrets
No obsession
How are you doing that?
Why am I bouncing so much?
Ease up on those
reins a little bit.
All right.
Without a reason
What is this fire?
Burning slowly
My one and only
LUKE: Atta girl!
(GIGGLES)
I don't think you
can keep up with me!
(LAUGHING)
Desire
You know,
I have to admit
you're pretty good
on a horse.
Well, thank you.
(CHUCKLES)
But I don't know...
I bet you couldn't
beat me to the barn.
Oh, I wouldn't go that way!
Whoa!
(SPLASHING)
Oh!
(GASPING)
Oh, my God!
(CHUCKUNG)
Come here.
I tried to tell you.
I know you did.
Well, this is, um...
This is home.
Wow. This is nice.
Really nice.
Yeah.
Oh, the shower's
right in there,
and there should be towels
and everything.
Okay.
Hey, uh, Sophia?
Did you want soup?
Oh, you make soup, too?
Kind of.
Soup, soup, soup...
(SIGHS)
(CLEARS THROAT)
Oh, my God.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on.
(GRUNTS)
There you go.
Put your hands right here.
The goal's pretty simple.
All you gotta do
is hang on for eight seconds.
Wow!
There's nothing to it.
Yeah, some bulls
are nice like that.
This is...
Yeah, okay.
Excuse us, sorry.
Sorry.
So how do you know
which one you're gonna get?
You don't.
You pick from a bowl.
And the fan favorite from Walkertown,
North Carolina...
Luke Collins!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Number four is the chip
you selected...
and that is Gunpowder
and Lead, Luke.
Jared Middleton reaching in...
and pulling out chip
number two.
You have Asteroid.
Whoa... Whoa!
That's impossible!
Yeah!
You can only touch
with your riding hand.
All other touching's
against the rules.
Okay. I got it.
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(CHEERING)
Let's go!
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
If you are off balance even a little,
you lose points.
But if you control the bull,
you get style points.
SOPHIA: Is that how you do
the hand? That?
More or less.
(GIGGLES)
The bull is judged too,
on speed, agility and power.
Whether it bucks or blows out,
turns back around on you.
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
Some bulls are just
plain mean.
And others...
(BULL GRUNTING)
Others are monsters.
(RAIN PATTERING)
Let's brave the storm.
Let's do it.
(LUKE CHUCKLES)
(INDISTINCT)
This is certainly better
than the hospital, isn't it?
(SOPHIA CHUCKLES)
How are you feeling?
The better question is,
how do I look?
Very handsome.
All I care about.
(CHUCKLES)
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Hold on one second.
Hello?
Hi, Sophia. This is Adrienne.
Hi, Ms. Francis.
My client has an exhibit
in Charlotte next weekend.
Can you be there?
Yeah, I'd love to.
That sounds great.
This could be
a real opportunity for us.
Okay.
I'll email you the details.
Okay. All right,
I'll talk to you soon.
Bye, Sophia.
Thanks, bye.
Good news?
Yeah.
Um...
The woman I'm working for
this summer...
she has a client with an
art exhibit in Charlotte...
and wants me
to help her out.
I didn't know you had
an interest in art.
Only since I was,
like, five.
Ruth also loved art.
Yeah.
Yeah, I remember the story
with the painting in the hotel lobby.
You've heard of
Black Mountain College?
(CHUCKLES) I'm doing my senior
thesis on it right now.
That's where
I was headed...
when I got in that fight
with the guardrail.
Are you sure this is how
you want to spend your honeymoon?
Oh, I promise you're going
to love it, I promise!
(IRA CHUCKLES)
I'd rather we'd just
stayed in bed.
(CHUCKLES)
(RUTH SIGHS)
IRA: You weren't able to engage
your passion for contemporary art...
In our little town...
so Black Mountain College
was a godsend.
It's so amazing!
ALBERS: Really look at your
work to understand it.
But I want to be able to
control the accidents...
and not leave them to fate...
or the Lord or chance,
whatever you want to call it.
I teach you to see.
Then even an accident
will have purpose...
and direction.
(SIGHS)
Oh, I love it!
For over 500 years,
artists have been reproducing...
quite literally what
they see in front of them.
Then Kandinsky came
and broke all the rules,
all of them!
Sorry.
I love it!
(GASPS)
RUTH: I can't believe we met
Josef Albers today.
IRA: It's just a bit further.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
You all right?
(SHRIEKS)
Oh! (CHUCKLES)
You ready?
Yeah.
You like it?
(BOTH LAUGHING)
IRA: From one happy day
to the next...
You said you
love the house, right?
We began the process
of creating a life together.
Doesn't look like
anyone's home.
No, I don't think
you should go in.
Ira!
What?
Well, let's just
use the key.
(CHUCKLES)
No! Oh, my God!
You wonderful person!
Wait, wait, wait.
Come here.
(GIGGLING)
(GRUNTS)
Yeah, there.
No.
There.
There! First thing you see
when you come in!
IRA: Life was busy
and happy for us.
I took over my dad's
booming business...
and you found a job
teaching at the local school.
Who understands this, huh?
Oh! Look at this!
You're all on your way
to becoming math geniuses.
Solve the problems
on the board.
If you have any questions,
please ask.
Wow, it sounds like
you made her very happy.
I did.
For a while.
KATE: His first cowboy hat.
(SOPHIA GASPS)
SOPHIA: That is so cute!
Never took it off.
He ate in it.
He slept in it.
He even tried to glue it
to his head so it
wouldn't come off!
Mom!
What?
He broke his arm riding
a calf when he was seven.
I found him sneaking into
the barn at night to practice...
hanging on with his
non-cast arm.
Even then, I couldn't get him
to stop riding
when he shouldn't.
Hey. There you go.
Thank you.
Sweet.
KATE: That's Luke's dad, Jack.
He was a great man.
SOPHIA: Mmm-hmm.
Great rider, too.
Even if you stop now,
you'd still have a
better career than he had.
What happened?
He died of a heart attack.
Yeah, almost five years
ago now.
How about a little dessert?
Luke, wait till you see
what I made for you.
Sophia, it's worth
the calories.
No.
(CHUCKLES)
How come your mom keeps
talking about you giving up riding?
She's just being
an overprotective mom.
How bad did you get hurt?
Sophia...
No.
I know all riders
are bound to get hurt.
It's not a matter of
"if" but "when."
That's right.
They say all bull riders
are either stupid or crazy.
Yeah, and which one
are you?
(GROANS)
I don't know.
I guess a little of both.
What are you doing?
SOPHIA: This is a new painting by an
artist that Adrienne Francis represents.
You know, the woman
I'm interning for?
$80 grand, really?
(SCOFFS)
SOPHIA: A lot of people
think he's a genius.
Yeah,
he most certainly is...
getting people to fork
over $80 grand for that.
Are you sure that you wanna
go to this gallery showing in Charlotte?
You want me to, right?
Of course.
Then I'll be there.
Yeah, but you're riding
that afternoon.
I'll be there.
(CHUCKLES)
(INDISTINCT)
Wow! Don't you
look nice!
Never seen you in a
coat and tie before.
Yeah, doesn't happen
too often.
Oh, that's my boss,
Adrienne Francis.
I gotta go. Okay?
Yeah. Go.
Hi. Sophia.
Nice to meet you.
Hopefully, Sophia will be
joining me in New York,
and my team.
You usually find these sort of things
in process art or lenticular prints...
but it's very rare
in brushwork.
That is what makes
this piece so special.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(INDISTINCT)
If you have any questions,
let me know. Thank you.
Excuse me.
Just one second.
WOMAN: It'll be worth
twice that a year from now.
MAN: At $20,000, it's a steal.
Sure.
MAN: Good.
Do you wanna get it?
Let's do it.
Okay.
I'll fly you to New York.
See the space, meet the team.
Yes!
These are some
very important people.
So if you can't do it,
don't say yes.
No...
I know you have finals
and other commitments.
I'd love to.
This is the most important
thing to me.
Oh! Uh, Luke, hi.
This is Adrienne Francis.
Adrienne, this is
my boyfriend, Luke.
Nice to meet you,
Ms. Francis.
Nice to meet you, Luke.
Are you in college
with Sophia?
No, never made it
to college.
Luke's a professional
bull rider.
I've never met a professional
bull rider before.
Probably not too many
in Manhattan.
Are you an art lover,
like Sophia?
No, I can't say that I am.
What did you think
of tonight?
Honestly?
Of course.
I think there's more bullshit
here than where I work.
(LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLES AWKWARDLY)
I like him. Keep this one.
How could you
say that to her?
It was a joke.
To the woman
who's gonna be my boss?
To the woman who I hope
is gonna launch my career?
That lady? Come on.
No, you come on.
You know how hard I have
just tried to fit into your world.
Why can't you try to
fit into mine?
I do!
It was a joke, okay?
She thought it was funny.
She laughed.
You don't know that.
What if she was just trying
to be polite?
Does this make sense?
(SCOFFS) What?
How are we gonna
make this work, huh?
Do you really see yourself
living on a ranch?
Working a ranch
the rest of your life?
And what am I gonna do?
Move to Manhattan?
Go out with your artist friends?
Go to brunch?
Talk about squiggly lines
on a white canvas...
like they're more than squiggly
lineson a white canvas?
I know all of that,
I do. I get it.
I just...
I just don't know
how to make this work.
I don't know either.
But I know that I want to.
Are we just crazy?
Do you think it could
work between us?
We just come from
such different worlds.
But I've never felt this way
about anybody before.
(CHUCKLES)
Not everybody gets that.
You did.
It wasn't that simple.
IRA: As the years went by...
I could see how much
she wanted to start a family.
We tried to adopt.
But it wasn't so easy
back then.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Now, today we're
going to learn...
about my favorite...
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
book.
It's called Pippi Longstocking.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
If anyone
teases him about this,
they'll have me to deal with.
Good morning.
RUTH: Hello.
My name is Ruth Levinson.
I'm Daniel's teacher.
I came here because
I'm slightly concerned.
He's falling asleep in class.
IRA: We were
surprised to learn...
that Daniel McDonald was being
raised by a half-brother and his wife.
Neither seemed to care
if he ate or starved.
He's a very bright boy.
Infinite potential.
Maybe I could tutor him
after class?
MAN: All right.
RUTH: Yes?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CHEWING NOISILY)
Are you a wolf?
No, ma'am.
Are you a bear?
Oh.
Are you a boy?
Yes, ma'am.
Boys use knives and forks.
RUTH: Oh. Almost.
Yeah. Okay.
What star is that?
The North Star, Polaris.
Good. Look.
"That was because
she didn't want to
"turn around to get home.
"When she reached
Tommy's and Annika's gate,
she stopped.
(CONTINUES READING)
IRA: Pretty soon,
the tutoring was every day.
And sometimes he
stayed for dinner.
(BURPS)
(LAUGHING)
We never said he was the child
we could never have...
but even so...
What do you think?
She's making her son dinner.
Right?
RUTH: Yeah.
I hate taking him back there.
Why can't we adopt him?
Because they're his
legal guardians.
There's nothing we can do.
Did you speak
to the lawyer?
I did, and
that's what he said.
They don't care about him.
They don't!
They're his next of kin
and they're proud people.
They're not gonna let us
take Daniel away.
There must be
something more we can do.
IRA: Ruth?
We better go.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(CHICKENS CLUCKING)
You be good.
Okay, pal?
Okay.
Maybe I'll raise chickens...
or work at the factory.
RUTH: If that's what you want.
You can be anything you want,
Daniel McDonald.
Anything at all.
A farmer, a lawyer,
an astronomer.
You're a very clever boy.
You really think so?
Yeah!
I know so.
All right, come on.
Okay.
RUTH: I'm just saying goodbye.
You can't stop me!
I'm just saying goodbye!
I know you are, sweetheart.
Let's go back to the car.
There's nothing we can do.
Please reconsider.
Please reconsider!
There's nothing we can do.
RUTH: He deserves
better than this.
Sweetheart,
get in the car.
They don't care about him.
I know they don't.
(ECHOING)
They don't care about him!
(INAUDIBLE)
Ruth.
(SIGHS)
What was I supposed to do?
Fight for custody.
From a half-brother
in small-town North Carolina?
Come on. We wouldn't have
had a chance!
And who knows what they
would've done to Daniel.
We were a family.
We are a family.
Ruth, you are my family.
(DISH CLATTERS)
I wanted kids too, you know.
We never saw Daniel again.
(SOFTLY) Oh, my God.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GATE RATTLING)
(BULL GRUNTS)
(INDISTINCT)
(BULL GRUNTING)
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
Oh, shit.
(MAN WHISTLING)
(SNORTING)
ANNOUNCER: Luke Collins
is trying to come around.
The bull fighter's taking the
bull away in the other direction.
I think he's gonna be okay.
He's trying to get up. He is!
Let me get him something to make
him feel a little bit better.
92 points!
264 on three bulls!
Luke Collins is
your clear-cut winner.
He's awesome.
...number nine spot
in the world.
(CROWD CHEERING)
(ECHOING) Are you okay, Luke?
I'm fine.
SOPHIA: All right.
Have an amazing time in New York.
Yes, I will.
You impressed Adrienne,
you'll impress her team.
Okay. Gotta go.
This is what you've always wanted!
I know!
Bye! See you on Monday.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hey, babe.
I'm walking to the taxi right now.
Sophia, it's Luiz.
Hi, Luiz.
Something's happened to Luke.
Hi, can I help you?
Um, I need to see
my boyfriend, Luke Collins.
He came in an ambulance earlier.
I need to see him.
I'm sorry.
Only family can visit.
Okay. Can I at least know
how he is?
His condition is stable,
but he's getting an MRI.
He took a pretty hard fall.
If you wanna take a seat,
I'll check with the doctor.
I'll let you know.
Thank you.
(SIGHS)
(EXHALES)
So, are you light-headed,
dizzy?
Nausea?
I'd like you to stay
overnight for observation.
Sweetie. What are you
doing here?
I came as soon as I heard.
Aren't you supposed to
be in New York?
No, no.
I should be here.
Thank God you're okay.
I'm fine.
You're lucky to be alive,
is what you are.
What?
I just got a little dizzy,
that's all.
DOCTOR: Luke, (SIGHS)
you need to stop downplaying
the severity of your condition.
If you care about your friend,
you need to make him understand...
that his riding days
are over.
What is he talking about?
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm tired, okay?
Can we just talk
about it tomorrow?
Ms. Francis,
I am so sorry about all of this.
ADRIENNE: Please, Sophia.
I understand you can't meet
the team this weekend,
given the circumstances.
And I do hope Luke is okay.
Yeah, me, too.
I don't know when
I'm gonna be able to come to New York.
Oh, really?
Wait a minute.
You're not rethinking
the internship, are you?
Look, Sophia.
I think you have a bright
future ahead of you...
but you're going to have to figure
out for yourself what that's going to be.
I know.
ANNOUNCER 1: World Finals
qualifier from Walkertown,
North Carolina.
Luke Collins!
And he is ready
to rock and roll!
Let's go!
Luke Collins outside
in the middle, rocked over!
He is just... Wow!
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
A double flip somersault
face-plant into the dirt.
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
You've gotta get him
out of there!
ANNOUNCER 2: Yeah,
no doubt about it.
He took a devastating shot
right there...
by one of the PBR's best.
Our sports medicine team
are coming in right now...
to take care of the young man
from North Carolina.
ANNOUNCER 1:
Talk about your scary moments.
The degree of difficulty here
is impossible to calculate.
The official buck-off time,
4.7 seconds.
Right now,
our medical staff is attending.
That's fine, right here.
No. It's fine, please.
Thanks.
Thank you.
NURSE: You're welcome.
I'll take the bag.
No, I got it.
Thank you.
Luke...
I'm really sorry.
I know how hard it must be to
give up that whole part of your life.
You're kidding, right?
Sophia...
You heard the doctors.
Doctors don't know
everything.
Are you crazy?
I watched what happened
to you on YouTube.
You were in a coma
for 10 days.
I told you, every time
a rider gets in that chute,
he could die.
That's bullshit!
Your situation is different!
You have to quit!
You have to!
I can't!
I can't be with someone if every
time they walk out the door...
I don't know if I'm gonna
see them again!
Then that's your choice.
Yeah, I chose you!
I chose you over New York!
Over my internship.
I chose you over everything.
I didn't ask you
to change your life.
You can't expect me
to change mine.
This is what I do.
It's all I know.
This is my life.
I thought this was
our life.
I can't watch you ruin it.
(ENGINE STARTS)
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Hi.
Right upstairs.
Thanks.
How was... (COUGHING)
How was New York?
I never made it.
And I broke up
with Luke anyway.
I'm really sorry.
Come here.
(SIGHS)
How can I help?
Take my mind off of it.
What happened
after that fight over Daniel?
Are you sure you don't wanna
talk about you and Luke?
Mmm.
Yeah, I'm sure.
It's a scary thing.
How the people
you're closest to...
can so quickly become...
strangers.
(DOOR CREAKING)
(DOOR OPENS)
I can't do this anymore.
I'm going crazy.
I know it's not your fault.
I have to go.
(DOOR OPENS)
No, please don't!
I just need to say something.
I need to say something.
(CHUCKLES)
I fell in love with you
the first time I saw you.
You're just the most amazing,
beautiful girl I ever met...
and somehow...
I don't know,
somehow you chose me.
But howl loved you then...
it's nothing compared to
how I love you now.
Now, I love you with
everything inside of me.
I think you should go.
I love you so much,
I just want you to be happy.
Even if that happiness
no longer includes me.
(SIGHS)
Love requires sacrifice.
Always.
(GRUNTING)
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
(CRYING)
IRA: And from that day on,
Sophia,
it wasn't exactly happily ever after,
but it was pretty close.
We focused on celebrating all the
wonderful things we had...
rather than regretting
the things we didn't.
Every anniversary,
we would drive to Black Mountain.
I still wrote Ruth letters...
even though I saw her
every day.
(ALARM BEEPING)
Ruthie.
Ruth.
(SOBBING)
So many wonderful years.
But, of course,
not nearly enough.
The paintings
Ruth and I had collected...
only served as a reminder
of what I had lost.
So I packed them away.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Can I help you?
My name is
Andrea McDonald.
I believe you knew
my husband...
Daniel McDonald?
He collapsed in his classroom
early one morning before school.
A brain aneurysm.
That was six years ago.
I'm very sorry to hear that.
Thank you.
He was a teacher?
A professor.
Physics and astronomy
at the University College London.
Astronomy.
I moved back to the States
a few years ago.
When I saw your wife's
obituary in the paper...
I knew I had to
bring you this.
It meant a lot to him.
You did everything you could
with Luke, Sophia.
You sacrificed.
I have loved
spending time with you.
You've made me very happy.
(CHUCKLES)
What are you doing up
so late?
I won tonight.
Puts me fifth in the world.
Are you really gonna
start on me now?
No.
The mistakes you make
are your own.
Mistake? Jesus, Mom!
These risks you're taking...
I don't know why.
I'm just trying to keep
this ranch in the family.
For you.
For me?
Yeah.
This isn't about me.
Where are you gonna live?
If we don't have this place,
where are you gonna go?
Do you honestly think
I give a damn?
You're doing this
for yourself.
It's eight seconds.
That's all it is.
That girl could be
the rest of your life.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
MAN ON PHONE: Sophia Danko?
Uh, yes. This is she.
My name is Howie Sanders.
I'm the attorney for Ira Levinson.
I've been trying to reach you.
Uh, yeah. What is it?
Is he okay?
I'm sorry, Ms. Danko.
He passed away
late last night.
Ms. Danko?
Are you all right?
(STAMMERS) Yeah.
Mr. Levinson's art collection is
being auctioned off next week.
This is a private auction,
and is by invitation only.
And Ira asked
if you would attend.
Yeah, of course.
I know this is short notice.
But it's important to know...
he was very fond of you.
I was very fond of him, too.
Well, I'll send
all the information along.
It was nice
to finally talk with you.
Thank you.
ANNOUNCER:
Tonight we're gonna be watching
the top bull riders in the world.
Aces.
(MEN LAUGHING)
(SIGHS)
ANNOUNCER:
This is the one and only PBR!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Time to meet
your top 15 contenders!
Being led out by the
number-one-ranked
bull rider in the world...
from Oklahoma,
Jared Middleton!
Boy, what a fight
it has been...
between him and the man
from North Carolina...
Luke Collins!
It has been an epic battle
between those two...
for this title!
But don't count out men
atop that leaderboard!
We will now go
atop the shark cage...
for our
championship-round draft.
Ryan Dirteater,
you will have Smackdown.
We will see you soon.
Now over to Billy Robinson,
the talent from Virginia.
Billy, let's find out
what bull you will face.
You are going to face
Bushwacker! Congratulations!
Now to the fan favorite
from North Carolina,
Luke Collins!
Luke, your fate
is in that cup.
It is time for you to reach in
and pull out your bull...
for this championship round.
Let's see what it will be.
Luke, you will have
the number-one contender...
for this year's
World Champion Bucking Bull...
Rango!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(EXHALES)
ANNOUNCER 1: Okay, Nashville.
You know
who I'm talking about.
With 99
consecutive buck-offs...
and staring down number 100...
this is the number-one-ranked
bucking bull in the world!
(SNORTING)
ANNOUNCER 2:
He is doing one of the most
difficult things in sports...
and that is
mounting a comeback.
Yeah, but Luke Collins,
he is on PBR fire!
(BULL GRUNTING)
(SNORTING)
(GROWLING)
MAN: Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(SNORTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GROWLING)
You got it! Keep riding!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Yeah! Yeah!
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY)
We have just seen
David slay Goliath!
(SIGHS)
Hey, Luke, you made
the eight on Rango.
I knew you were a cowboy.
(LAUGHS) One hell of a ride,
son, I tell you!
Luke, we gotta get together
now and talk some business.
Luke?
Luke, where you going?
AUCTIONEER:
The Levinson artwork
is the largest
and most valuable
private collection.
Not only are these pieces sourced
from local Black Mountain College...
but the world.
We'll look at contemporary
modern artists...
such as Andy Warhol,
Pat Passlof,
and Willem de Kooning.
These are
amazing works of art...
and incredibly diverse,
as you already know.
Never been seen in one place
like this before.
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen
for attending this
remarkable auction.
If everyone could
take their seats, please.
I know we are all eager
to get started.
Before we begin,
a personal note.
Welcome. I'm Howard Sanders.
I was Ruth and Ira
Levinson's attorney...
for more than 25 years.
Now, Ira's will
is very detailed...
on how he wants to
proceed today.
So, let me start by reading
you a letter he wrote...
specifically for the occasion.
"My name is Ira Levinson.
"I'm an ordinary man who fell in
love with an extraordinary woman.
"Around this room you will see some
beautiful and priceless works of art.
"Ruth had an incredible eye
for talent...
"while I only had
eyes for her.
(CROWD CHUCKLES)
"For me...
"the great joy of collecting
wasn't in the art itself..."
IRA: ...but in the person
I collected it with.
My beloved Ruth.
The happiness these paintings
brought her was immeasurable.
And sharing that happiness...
was the great privilege
of my life.
We celebrated, we achieved.
We endured, we compromised.
And above all...
we loved.
The true work of art...
was the longest ride
Ruth and I shared.
This thing called life.
There's not a painting here
I wouldn't trade in a heartbeat...
to hear her voice.
Or see her smile.
Just one more time.
HOWIE: Signed, Ira Levinson.
Thank you all for coming.
(APPLAUSE)
Thank you, Mr. Sanders.
First up, a painting located
on page 34 of your catalogues...
titled Portrait of Ruth.
Composed by American Daniel McDonald,
born 1954, died 2001.
The work is circa 1963.
We'll start the bidding at $1,000 for
Portrait of Ruth.
Do I hear $1,000?
Who has $1,000 for me?
How about $800?
Who can give me $800?
Just $800, folks.
$600.
Do I hear $600?
Who has $600 for Portrait of Ruth,
the first work of the evening?
$600.
I have $600.
I have $600, here.
Going once.
I have $600. Going twice.
Fair warning.
(GAVEL BANGING)
Sold to the young man
right there for $600.
(APPLAUSE)
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're going to take a short pause.
We can take this time
to look at the next item...
which will be a
Jackson Pollock.
That's located on page 124.
There we go.
What are you doing here?
Ira invited me.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm done bull riding, Sophia.
I'm done.
Look, I drew Rango
this afternoon.
I thought if I could just
ride that son of a bitch...
if I could just
make the eight...
I'd have everything
I ever wanted.
Well, I did. I rode him.
So, you're the best.
No. Not even close.
You see, the whole time
I was thinking about you.
I realized that what I want is
standing right in front of me.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
What made you buy
that painting?
Ira.
Excuse me, sir.
We need you in the other room.
Sir?
Not now.
BOTH: Not now.
Mr. Sanders needs you.
(CLAMORING)
(GAVEL BANGING)
HOWIE: Quiet! Quiet, please!
What is your name, son?
Luke Collins.
And did you just close your
purchase of Portrait of Ruth?
Yes.
Mr. Collins,
I have a stipulation...
in Ira Levinson's will
I need to read to you.
"Portrait of Ruth may not be the most
valuable painting in my collection...
"but it was the most
precious to me...
"because it reminded me daily
of my beloved Ruth.
"And so, the terms
of my will are simple.
"Whoever purchases
the portrait...
"will receive the collection
in its entirety."
(PEOPLE GASPING)
Ladies and gentlemen,
this auction is over.
LUKE: What?
This is worth millions.
Millions of dollars.
How much do you want
for the Warhols?
What are your plans
for the Jackson Pollocks?
MAN: I have a client who wants to
buy both of the Picassos.
I'll write you a check.
(ALL CLAMORING)
Sorry.
I'm gonna guess that your
head is spinning right about now.
Yeah. That's a good guess.
(CHUCKLES)
When your feet
hit the ground, call me.
You are now
a very wealthy man.
(HONKING)
You think you know all about
it then it seems you are wrong
She hit it out of the park
before it had even begun
I needed sunshine in the
darkness burning now
Well, now I know that I'm
the fuel and she's the spark
We are bound to
each other's hearts
Cold, torn and pulled apart
Hey.
Hi.
How was the museum?
Great.
How was the ranch?
(ENGINE STARTS)
Like wildfire
These feelings arrange
deep down inside
Try describing a love
you can't design
More and more every
inch of me is holding on
This is it All the flames
are burning strong
LUKE: "Dearest Ruth..."
IRA: When a North Carolina boy meets
a beautiful girl from far away..
He should do everything he can
to win her over.
And if he does...
his life will be
a portrait of happiness.
You think you know all about it
then it seems you are wrong
What?
Come on!
Where are you going?
We are bound
to each other's hearts
Cold, torn and pulled apart
This love is like wildfire
(SHRIEKING)
(LAUGHS)
And to my word now
I'll be true
I can't stop this
breaking loose
This love is like wildfire
What took you so long?
Like wildfire