THE HOUSE OF THE SPIRITS
that good to be of turn.
come, dad.
Our memory is weak.
The life is very brief.
everything is so fast
that there is no time to understand the relationship among events.
this wrote my mother in their diaries
to be attentive at the time.
what was, dad?
do want to lie down?
feel Clara's lack.
dad...
... I think the mammy he/she is connosco at this time.
come to lie down.
My mother always referred to the love as a miracle.
from child registava everything
to see the things in their owed dimens
were the first time that she saw my father.
although he had come to ask the oldest sister's hand, the Rose,
my mother noticed that it was passionate for him.
wanted, we didn't get to talk.
Esteban, if it is that also the will of the Rose...
for us the important...
... it is not only that the Rose is happy,
but also... - I am decided...
to work arduously everyday.
are convinced...
that to work always arduously,
one day I will be sufficiently rich for...
no, Clara.
that one day will be sufficiently rich to take the Rose to the altar.
Clara, not!
two years later,
discovered the gold that would take him of turn Pink
The love made him to go down bottom in the mine,
but the arduous work and the wait turned his desire still larger.
finally, he had success and soon it would go back to marry the Rose.
vein people to celebrate the candidacy of my av
my grandparents tried to hide my mother's supernatural powers,
but all knew them.
secretly, the people came to advise with her.
only wanted to know Clara it was able to me to say...
got into an enormous debt.
for a politician that is an escãndalo.
don't know what to do.
My family... - "Black Devil" will expire Sunday.
The something? - In the third race.
thank him/her immense.
promise that never again I will ask for him/her help. Thank you.
thank you.
It is that my fiancé...
are so unhappy...
thought that Clara maybe I could help myself.
could feel a hunch for him love again.
His/her fiancé doesn't support the lavender smell.
if he/she leaves of using lavender oil,
maybe he wants her again.
what happens?
Clara?!
should be embarrassed for upsetting Clara!
He/she is a delicate child.
rose, what is she to say her?
say that soon there will be a death in our family,
but that will be by accident.
Partido Conservador has state always in the power.
are greedy, corrupt, intolerant and outdated.
us, of Partido Liberal, we have that combatting.
thank you, dear friends for your support. Thank you.
should drink.
who it carves the pig, drink. It is the tradition. Go.
Clara? 74
nun meows...
The brandy has enough poison to kill an ox.
but...
to have the certainty of the cause of the death, I have of the autopsiar.
have that to examine.
mean... what will have he/she that to shred?
Clara...
... the fault was not yours.
you don't provoke the events...
wanted...
only foresee them a little before they happen.
It is soon the Rose had to die in my place.
don't feel need of revenge.
The revenge doesn't do well to anybody.
The revenge...
... he/she won't bring us the Rose of turn.
because I wrapped up in politics in this country?
don't pass of murderers and thieves!
My mother thought the Rose he/she had died for fault of her.
that if he/she spoke again, he/she could cause new accidents.
tormented for the displeasure and fault, maintained the silence.
never again decided to pronounce word.
Is it even true, Clara?
could not have waited for me, Pink?
for why didn't wait for me you?
if he/she knew that you would live so a little,
would have stolen to marry with you.
would have done you happy.
after leaving of speaking,
the mother started to live in an own world,
wrapped up in their fantasies,
in a world that escaped logical ã and laws of the physics.
enclosed for spirits of the air, of the water and of the earth...
becoming unnecessary for her to speak for many years.
don't go back to the mine.
have to do any thing.
the mother's medicines they are expensive.
already ended.
how many years of my life do know passed to take care of the mother?
The road for God is through of the devotion and of the suffering.
were what taught me.
will leave. I hate this city.
because you don't say before what do hate this house?
that also.
would like to be man... for also to leave.
And I am happy for not being woman.
bought an old farm with the money of the mine.
will feel your lack.
write me if the mother worsens.
do favor!
can take me even ã "Three Marias?"
how you call?
second.
now are the patrón here now.
who doesn't like, it can leave.
the ones that be...
won't lack them food, if they work a lot and well.
understand?
understood, patrón. We don't have to go where.
force, force.
care, they can break the wheel.
go, I count. A, two, three!
in the 20 following years, the father rebuilt Three Marias,
turning her/it in an of the farms more productive of the country.
worked very in the morning even ã night,
and he/she had many conflicts with unhappy workers.
do you want him to pay them orderly? Is it like this that you/they thank me?
are demanding, but I am always exactly.
in spite of all of the problems, my father was happy
and conscious that everything was fruit of his/her arduous work.
how much want?
preferred that he/she lent me some money.
are very shameless. - 50 weights, patrón.
He/she is the most powerful man and rich of this city.
would not ask for this the more nobody.
for something so much money?
for a convoy ticket for the city, a red dress,
a pair of shoes of high jump, a perfume bottle...
and a permanent one. I want to come to be rich and famous.
as I know that I return you to see? - We will see each other again.
I know.
trust me.
how you call?
I closed business,
I taste of ambitious people.
- Is everything? - Yes.
telegram for itself, patrón.
remember of when were we children?
cook for you...
and to order you to the school.
take care of you, do you know?
will make what the mother asked me.
accepted me as son-in-law once...
her no, Esteban. - They can make him/it again.
she is not normal.
His/her sister, the Rose, was special.
at least, it was healthy and normal,
but Clara is so strange. You will never be happy with her.
are with jealousies. You were never passionate.
only remain you a home for old spinsters.
she will never be able to love you as necessary of being loved.
Clara is too strange.
necessary of a woman that he/she takes care of you,
that he/she adores you and obey. - It already arrives, Ferula!
seem to live in another world, since the Rose died.
I know.
are not that she cannot speak. He/she never wanted.
since it can feel healthy children, it is enough.
maybe had her protected too much.
It is impossible to give afecto too much to somebody.
can see her now?
don't take decis
know her first.
later have to know what does Clara want, doesn't you agree?
dad! Dad!
came to ask me in marriage.
Clara! Be not impertinent!
want to know. I don't want to lose time.
me also taste of being directo.
yes, Clara. - She told any thing.
were for that that I came. - She spoke!
she told any thing. - You told any thing!
she spoke!
she speaks!
thank you, Clara. You did me very happy.
good-bye.
everything is well?
good afternoon, Ferula.
excuse the delay.
suddenly...I didn't remember if it was today.
owe you an explanation...
for having request that you came.
wait for not having made you to wait a long time.
not.
are so happy that you have come.
used to frequent places like this.
in fact, it had never here come.
Clara, he/she would like to talk about you...
don't worry.
come to live with me and with Esteban when we marry.
will be as sisters.
And our friendship... the rest of our lives will last.
don't worry. I will speak to him.
nor we will tell him/her that in the encontrámos.
are well?
excuse me. Used to cry.
are not habituated that you/they play me. Excuse.
are not accustomed the one that is kind to me.
never nobody showed me affection.
excuse me...
are so confused... and so diminished.
thank you, dear Clara.
Ferula, dear sister.
accept...
... Esteban Trueba...
... Clara del Valle...
.... as your legitimate wife...
.... to love and to respect...
... in the disease and in the health...
... in the wealth and in the poverty...
... until that the death separates you?
accept.
And you, Clara del Valle...
... you accept Esteban Trueba...
... as your legitimate husband...
... to love and to respect...
... in the disease and in the health...
... in the wealth and in the poverty...
... until that the death separates you?
accept.
yes, I accept.
It is beautiful.
oh! It is beautiful!
welcome ãs Three Marias. Congratulations.
remember of my sister Ferula?
should be tired.
will make you a chocolate.
are not tired.
did take good trip? 257
she is not any child. You should not treat her as such.
oh! My dear Esteban!
walk!
forgive me Priest, because I sinned. I don't admit there am me one week.
leaning that committed a terrible sin. - Of the meat?
My meat is weakened, but my spirit is not.
The demónio torments me.
The mercy of God is infinite.
don't imagine the thoughts that a lonely woman has.
a virgin that he/she never had a man,
not for opportunity lack but because...
God gave me a sick mother of who had to take care.
that sacrifice it is recorded in the sky, daughter.
same that I have sin in thoughts, Priest?
well, that depends of the thoughts.
per times...
... ã night...
... I don't get to sleep.
feel to suffocate.
to calm down, I wander for the house.
are going to my sister-in-law's room and I listen ã carries.
per times,
enter in beaks of feet and I observe her/it to sleep.
that she was stupid and incompetent.
now know that she doesn't belong to this world.
maybe his/her life in the earth be a small part of her.
maybe are more close to God than us, Priest.
seem the Angel of the Light.
please to enter me in his/her bed...
... and to feel...
... the heat of his/her skin...
... and his/her soft breathing.
prayer, my daughter.
the oraç
wait, I still didn't finish.
when my brother, per times, sleeps with her...
... it is still worse.
my oraç 296
don't get to sleep.
sweat and all my body shakes.
rise and I wander for the house in the darkness.
cross the corridor...
carefully,for the ground not to do noise...
... and I listen to them...
... ã carries of his/her room.
once, until I saw them...
... because the door was open.
What saw...
... I cannot tell him/her, Priest. It is a great sin.
The fault doesn't belong to Clara.
she is innocent. My brother takes her/it to that.
he wants much more of the one that his/her body.
want what exists inside of her of more secret.
he is eternally cursed.
only God can judge and to curse, my daughter.
but...
what made them?
be good narrator.
didn't get to see very well,
but the one that I felt was incredible.
the movements trementes,
the abundãncia of fluids,
the whispered words to his/her ear,
the strangers and secret odors,
a true miracle.
He/she is a girl...
... and Blanca will be called.
are not beautiful, Esteban?
who he/she had felt that the mother could be present.
would be proud of you. And only think...
... a girl. Badly I can wait.
don't like the form like her he/she always walks thereabout.
The doctor ordered to rest her a lot.
And he/she said that should not continue to sleep together.
The something?
said that it would not be good for Clara to sleep together during the pregnancy.
To me didn't tell me anything.
are only to repeat what he said.
leaning that he wanted to say...
that you are weighed for the bebé or for Clara, that is fragile.
leaning that a lot of excitement he/she won't make ã well Clara.
are to enter in subjects that you/they don't tell you respect.
good morning, Clara.
Is it necessary kiss each other?
are, yes.
sit down how he/she gives kicks.
think he/she wants to leave to greet the grandparents.
grandparents? - Do they arrive today,do you remember?
will treat of your bath.
will know myself well.
The doctor gave me almond oil for your belly.
Evita that you are with grooves.
lament a lot.
should have come from convoy but the dad insisted on coming...
... in that old car.
have something to communicate him/her.
It is terrible. - Tell me.
due ã collision with the convoy...
their parents they were spit of the car...
His/her mother's head it was separate from the body...
And the most terrible is that...
but I know where she is!
stop with that.
know where she is!
The police sought her/it on the whole side.
My wife is a little... It is of the pregnancy.
Ferula, my sister,do you help me?
- It is here. - Clear?
but we are very far of the place of the accident.
are here. I know.
could do me the favor of going there...
to look for me a head of woman that will find?
are dispatched, señor.
think my hour he/she is to arrive.
are dispatched, senor.
everything well. I relaxed you.
force.
everything well. - Force!
are to come.
well arrival to this world, small Blanca.
hold her/it with firmness.
concentrate you, Blanca. - You are a champion.
throw her/it for the aunt Ferula!
go, Ferula, with force!
do you have to play with hat?
will win.
don't throw her outside.
don't throw her/it for so far!
leave you of stupidities.
go there, Ferula!
almost that it picked her!
should teach Clara to play.
think ganhámos. Blanca is the champion.
if the mother was alive it ordered you for his/her foot.
will take a refreshment. Only us the two.
do you come to play with me?
please, it comes to play with me...
here have.
who are those?
what make here? Out of here!
needed money for food.
then will win him/it!
P
don't remember of me, Esteban?
to the foot of the river?
this is your son.
look at him.
have your name.
what that talks is?
take and it is going you away!
if I return you to see here, I loosen you the dogs.
will never get rid of us, Esteban!
will never get rid of your son!
did stop playing? Were you to win?
who are you? - Esteban Garcia.
my parents are not.
I know.
what want?
to see your house. - You cannot be here.
the strangers are not authorized to enter here.
I know.
then are going you away.
already go.
arrive here.
walk. - Reason?
want to smell you.
smell well.
It is perfume. My mother he/she gives me everyday bath.
have a beautiful dress.
seat you to the foot of me for the power to touch.
were my aunt Ferula that made him/it.
imagine.We are of the same blood.
don't understand you.
Blanca, your chocolate is ready.
last, he/she wanted to ask to Pedro
that it told us the history of the chickens and of the fox.
once there was a capoeira...
and all of them night was visited for a fox...
to steal the eggs and to eat the chicks.
this irritated the chickens.
the people are happy with their liç
Pedro! - Blanca!
Blanca!
Clara, why don't use your powers well, to vary,
and don't you tell me where they are?
cannot contact who doesn't want to be found.
if you didn't have the school, nothing of this would have happened.
The Second found them close to the river.
are well?
The fault is yours, Second!
never again want to see your son with Blanca! Did you hear?
heard yes, patrón.
will close the school tomorrow and to order Blanca for an internal school.
cannot do a thing of those!
can, yes!
don't want to see my daughter turn in a native one.
It is my duty to give him/her a life enter people of his/her class.
Esteban, it is not necessary... - It silences you, Ferula!
It is interfere never again in subjects of my family!
Pedro! - Blanca!
The school had finishing.
What turned bearable my life in the school...
were the wonderful vacations of Summer that approached.
congratulations for your exam. - There is so much time.
are very proud of you.
the school finished! - Thanks to God!
are so happy that you are home.
me and your mother we felt your lack.
I and Pedro saw each other always hidden ãs, to the foot of the river.
now that he/she had finishing the school, we could be together forever.
missed.
thought that he/she would die at the school. Now never again I return.
of here for the future only both of us will count.
what happens? - You know...
... that it is not well like this. - It is, yes.
don't want to know of the opinion of my family.
I love you and you love me. That is that it matters.
told me that you began to do political speeches.
Your father represses the farmers.
are afraid of him.
all hate him/it. - Pedro...
promise me that you are careful. Don't run danger.
love you.
I also love you.
well coming, Mr. Trueba!
the Conservatives want to do him a proposal.
are not political. - He/she is a powerful man, Esteban.
He/she is a honest man, as we needed for Senator.
The country is to change.
unhappily,the things are not what were.
are with crazy ideas. The farmers of his/her district
and the workers of the cities speak in uniting.
if we don't take a position now...
will think.
you are a family man, which has to be protected.
have to protect our values.
who is that?
He/she is Conde Jean of Satigny, there is very absentee of the country.
for the that I know are very rich and it continues single.
His/her daughter could use a coat of arms in their cart
later tell me that decided on Party.
excuse me.
can make him/her company?
have ear to speak a lot of itself, "Monsieur" Trueba.
say that his farm it is the more beautiful woman of the roundness.
And the most efficient, as it consists.
wait one day to know her. To study their methods.
will be very well coming the...
leave!
a terramoto!
Clara!
did feel him/it here? Did some happen thing?
are everything well, patrón.
Clara?
Clara asked me to be to his/her foot to fall asleep.
were panicky with the terramoto. It was alone for that.
finished.
already destroyed too much my life family time.
want you to leave of this house.
never again want to see you...
... and you proíbo-te of you contact with my wife...
or with my daughter.
will send you money all of the months for Priest António.
will live honestly, while I live.
if it picks you to importune my family again,
kill you.
interest...
... for our mother's soul...
... that I kill you.
damned you are, Esteban.
had been alone forever...
... your body and your soul mirrarão...
... you will die with fear...
... and with the heavy conscience.
- He/she leaves.
in consideration to Clara...
tell you that there was never anything of what you imagine, among us.
never!
Clara...
would like to speak with you, Clara.
as you could do a thing of those?
as you could order her away?
now already more nobody exists among us.
she was never among us.
love you, Clara.
want to do you happy!
want us to have a happy family!
but she is also part of our family. He/she is your sister.
don't want to know of Ferula.
want to know of us and of our love.
display that you love me.
show me that I am your husband.
love me.
are you hear? He/she loves me!
help me, Clara.
tell me that should do...
for us to be happy, as husband and woman.
give me a time, Esteban.
give me a time.
a long time passed,
are with good aspect.
as it is that he/she discovered me, patrón?
asked for the best house of the city.
now can pay him/her the 5O weights...
... with interests.
prefer that you are me to owe that favor.
wait a little
I display...
... some tenderness.
fake that you like me.
It is alone of that that I need. - But I like you...
a lot.
come.
come for here.
I feel so well with you.
It is as returning to the home.
are the best, Esteban.
are a strong man.
very strong.
a man of the earth.
"to your health."
there is a thing that I don't understand, Monsieur Tassigny.
Satigny.
And it is...
... what does you in our barbaric country?
well...
... my felizarda position allows not to need me of working.
only have the time to pass. A luxury life is upset.
turned in the restless ones.
my vineyards in Liechtenstein and in Riviera.
but...
... this country...
... it is a challenge for me.
but Monsieur Tassigny...
Satigny.
even so are very strange.
sought again and I don't find him/it in my letters.
nor his/her family, nor his/her age...
nor from where came.
maybe your letters don't see for besides the Atlãntico.
Is it for me? - Oui.
thank you.
It is beautiful.
tons a year, in two crops.
have the advantage on the countries to north of the equator,
of we get ripe fruit in another time of the year.
God gives to all the right of struggling for the justice.
don't want us to await only for the reward in the Sky.
Own Jesus Cristo it was a revolutionary.
are entitled to a wage.
that is revolutionary?
of course is!
are entitled of not working on Sunday.
are entitled to the vote.
are entitled...
arrive. Return to the work!
return to the work, he/she already said!
tell them that you/they return to the work.
please, return to the work.
come here.
didn't teach your son to not to look the patrón in the eyes?
take off the shirt.
... Tassigny doesn't he/she eat connosco?
Satigny.
Conde Satigny.
he continues outside to see the crop of the corn.
have a great interest for the agriculture.
And in to know that possess.
today had to dismiss Pedro Segundo.
never again want to see him/it for here. - Reason?
picked him/it to try to return the workers against me,
to do revolutionary speeches.
only in consideration to his/her father, I didn't give him/her a shot.
my God!
all my life tried...
to help this people.
gave them everything...
and now that crooked one he/she speaks to them in their rights!
I know them, they need to be guided.
need justice and not of charity, dad.
are as children.
need a firm hand.
only notice like this. - You cannot avoid that the world changes.
but I can try.
decided to run for office to Senator for the Conservatives.
what leaning of this?
the politicians don't pass of thieves and criminals.
cannot close one of the windows?
aunt Ferula?