? ?
[M Man ]
??If their love's on skids
treat your folks like kids??
?? Or your family tree's
gonna snap??
[M Woman ]
??So to make 'em dig
first ya gotta rig??
[M Together ]
?? What do ya gotta rig??
?? The parent trap??
[M Woman ]
??If they lose that zing
and they just won't swing??
?? Then the problem
falls in your lap??
[M Man ]
?? When your folks are square
then you must prepare??
- ?? What do you gotta prepare??
- ?? The parent trap??
[ Both Yawning ]
[M Together ]
?? To set the bait recreate the date??
?? The first time
Cupid shot 'em??
?? Get 'em under the moon
play their favorite tune??
John.
Marcia.
?? You got 'em??
[M Man ]
??Lead 'em back to love
with a velvet glove??
[M Woman ]
?? 'Cause they're much
too old for the strap??
[M Together ]
??Straighten up their mess
with togetherness??
?? Togetherness
The parent trap??
John, they're
playing our song.
Marcia, what fools
we've been.
??Straighten out their mess
with togetherness??
?? Togetherness??
??Straighten out their mess
with togetherness??
?? Togetherness??
?? The parent trap????
[M Girls Chattering,
Clamoring Loudly ]
[M Woman ]
Now, now there,
girls, Now, now,
''A''to ''K's''over here,
''A''to ''K's''over--
No, dear, you're an ''R''.
Over there with
the ''P'' to ''S's.''
That's a good girl.
Now, have we any
''X, Y, Z's'' here?
- Where are the ''X, Y, Z's''?
- Now here are your allergy pills.
Your grandmother said to remind
you one three times a day.
And your insect repellant.
And your poetry book.
- Thank you, Staimes.
- Have a good summer, miss.
[ Chattering,
Clamoring Continues ]
- Name?
- McKendrick, Sharon.
- 1 8 Belgrave Square, Boston?
- Yes.
And my grandmother said
to see that my tent
was properly ventilated.
Don't worry, McKendrick.
You'll be ventilated.
NeXt girl.
No candy wrappers.
No chewing gum wrappers
lying on the ground.
Always tidy.
Latrines over there.
Mess hall up the hill.
McKendrick, you're in here,
Arapahoe. Follow me.
Girls, wait here for me.
Come, McKendrick.
- New arrival, girls.
Name's McKendrick.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Girls here'll brief you
on anything you need to know.
I'm sure you'll be
very happy here.
See you after lunch.
My name is Betsy.
This is Ursula.
How do you do?
[ Clears Throat ]
I'm Sharon McKendrick.
- ????[M Bugle Playing Reveille ]
- [ Girls Shouting ]
Say, you're
in a good tent.
Betsy's mother sends her
all kinds of candy bars and
chocolates every week.
- I'm not allowed to eat candy.
- Why not?
My grandmother thinks
it ruins my teeth.
Oh, hi, Mary Sue.
Well, come on, let's go.
I'm starved.
Oh, yeah,just as long
as there are three places.
Oh, is that--
Oh.
- The nerve of her,
coming here with your face!
- What are you gonna do about it?
Do? What in heaven's name
can I do, silly?
I'd bite off her nose,
then she wouldn't look
like you.
- Who's she?
- [M Bell Ringing ]
- I never saw her
before in my life.
- Now...
at this time...
I want to say welcome
to all our new arrivals.
Welcome to Camp Inch,
new arrivals,
I am your
supreme commander here,
And my name is...
Miss Inch.
- Uh, yes, Miss Inch.
- [ Girls Chuckle Softly ]
I'd like at this time
to introduce a visitor...
from the neXt hilltop over.
From the
Thunderhead Boys Camp,
Chief Eaglewood,
Welcome.
Thank you, Miss Inch.
And hello there, out
there to all of you.
Uh, looks like a crackerjack
troop of girls there.
Now, why am I here?
Well, that's
our little surprise,
Trooper Stafford, attention.
Stand up, boy.
- Ohh, what a dream!
- [ Girls Giggling ]
A little surprise for you,
young ladies.
Saturday night
we're going to have a dance.
[ Girls Screaming ]
Now, quiet, girls, quiet.
And we've asked
the Thunderhead Boys Camp...
to come over
for the occasion.
Camp Thunderhead
accepts your invitation
and thanks you.
- [ Girls Screaming, Cheering ]
- [M Bell Ringing ]
A word of warning.
Watch your demerits.
Untidy little girls
won't go to the dance.
So keep those tents clean,
your uniforms
spanking fresh...
and we'll all be
one big happy family.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chattering ]
- [ Laughing ]
- With that toad?
Oh, no.
What are you staring at?
EXcuse me,
but haven't you noticed?
We look like each other.
Hey, wait a minute.
Turn your head.
Let me see that profile.
That's who it is,
Look at that profile,
- She's the spittin'image
of you-know-who,
- Who?
- Frankenstein.
- [ Laughing ]
Not wanted.
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
????[M Reveille ]
[ Girls Chattering ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ High-Pitched Scream ]
[ Screams ]
Those monsters!
They gopher-trapped us!
[ High-Pitched Screams ]
- Morning, Miss Inch.
- Good morning, Miss Grunecker.
- Where would you like to start?
- Well--
Why not start
with tent Arapahoe?
I'm sure you'll find
everything shipshape.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Screams ]
[M Woman On Record ]
?? Think of all
that we could share??
??Let's get together
every day??
??Every way
and everywhere??
??And though we haven't
got a lot??
?? We could be sharin'
all we've got??
?? Together??
- ?? Oh, I really think you're swell??
- What if we got some ants,
- ?? We really ring the bell??
- and when she comes by the window
we dump 'em down her dress?
- Impractical.
- Where're you gonna find
ants at night, stupid?
Ooh, the three of them.
I'm so mad I could just spit.
??Let's get together
Yea,yea,yea??
?? Two is twice
as nice as one??
??Let's get together
right away??
?? We'll be havin'
twice the fun??
- ??And you can always
count on me??
- Hey, I got an idea!
- ??A twosome we will be??
- Come on!
??Let's get together
Yea,yea,yea????
[ Chattering ]
- How do you like camp?
- Oh, it's okay, I guess.
I'm not coming back
to this one, though.
They're so juvenile.
They won't let you wear
lipstick or perfume.
I feel absolutely naked
without my lipstick.
Oh.
[ Clears Throat ]
Where you from?
Um, Monterey,
California.
That's great.
Oh, you'd love California;
at least I do.
It's so sort of--
I don't know--
marvelous, actually.
- [ Clears Throat ]
Sounds great.
- Mm-hmm.
Oh, it's absolute fun
living in California,
Every year when I get home
from camp, Dad takes me
on a trek into the mountains.
- Gee, that's great.
- Mm-hmm.
Your mother just lets you
go up in the mountains like that?
- Oh, I don't have a mother;
just Dad and me.
- [M Scissors Cutting ]
He's wonderful. Besides,
I know almost everything
about trails...
and camping
and woodlore.
We have a ball,
just Daddy and me and Hecky.
- Ooh, it's hot out here.
- Who's Hecky?
Our ranch foreman.
He tells sensational stories.
He used to be
a rodeo rider actually.
- ????[M Starts ]
- Oh, they've started
the music again.
- I guess we oughta, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
I love dancing.
I could just dance all night,
- especially with you, Wilfred.
- [ Clears Throat ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Gasps ]
[ People Laughing ]
Your dress is ruined! Where were you?
Where could she have done it?
- Oh, I don't know! I wasn't
anywhere. I just went out--
- [ Chuckling ]
Serves ya right.
Stay out of our tent from now on.
- You vicious, little wretch!
- [ Gasps ]
- Stop it! Stop it!
- Let her go!
Sharon, let go of her!
Get away!
- [ Girls Screaming ]
- Stop that!
Stop that, ladies,
please! Girls--
Stop it!
Girls! Stop!
Stop. Stop.
Misses, stop.
- [M Girls Screaming ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Stammering ]
[ Shouts ]
I've got a cake in my hands!
Now stop it, children!
[ Screams, Groans ]
You little wretches!
[M Girls Continue Screaming ]
Congratulations.
In the history of our camp,
that was the most infamous,
the most revolting,
the most disgusting
display of hooliganism...
we have ever had.
- Brawling like hooligans
in front of our guests.
- And worst of all,
two sisters who should be
setting a good example,
We're not sisters!
I've never seen her
before in my life!
They are, aren't they?
No, ma'am,
just look-alikes.
An amazing resemblance.
I gather that you two girls
don't get along together?
Hmm. Well,
have you ever heard of
Gilbert and Sullivan?
Yes, ma'am.
They were composers.
They wrote a
memorable song called...
''Let the Punishment
Fit the Crime.''
[ Girls Chattering ]
Sharon McKendrick,
we are waiting.
All right, girls,
follow me.
?? [ Girls Whistling ''Bridge
On The River Kwai'' ]
? ?
??
Now, girls, that's enough
of this nonsense!
Go back
to your activities!
- [ Girls Shouting ]
- All right, young ladies.
In here.
Yes.
All right.
Four weeks left at camp
and you'll spend them all together;
room together,
eat together, play together.
Either you'll find a way
to live with each other...
or you'll punish yourselves
far better than I ever could.
Good-bye, girls.
[ Girls Chattering,
Laughing ]
It drives her crazy.
I completely ignore her.
- Give it to her good.
- The old coventry treatment.
Pretty soon the silence
will drive her absolutely
out of her mind.
[ Girls Giggling ]
[M Thunderclap ]
[M Wind Gusting ]
- Oh! Oh, my gosh!
- Oh, my goodness! Hurry, quick!
I've got it. Hook it.
Tie that down over there, tight.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Oh, gosh!
Look at this mess!
- Are any of them spoiled?
- Well, it didn't do 'em any good.
Oh, dirty darn,
look at this one.Just ruined.
Oh, that's a shame.
Who is he?
Are you kidding?
Ricky Nelson?
Oh. Your boyfriend.
[ Gags ]
I wish he was!
You mean you never
heard of him?
Where do you come from,
outer space?
No. I'm from Boston.
[ Snootily ]
Oh... Boston.
- Where's your home?
- California.
Oh, I've seen movies of California.
Is it a nice place to live?
Sensational!
We got a ranch out in Carmel.
I got a picture.
You wanna see it?
There. That's the house.
Then the stables go off down there.
- How lovely.
- Oh, I got my own horse
and everything.
We got a lake. You know,
you could practically fall
right out of the front door...
and go swimming
anytime you want.
Who's this?
That's my dad.
Isn't he dreamy?
[M Sharon ]
He's very handsome,
- Is it cold in here?
- I'm hot.
Want a Fig Newton?
What's your pop like?
I mean, is he a friend
you could talk to...
or one of those
busy types?
Well, I don't have
a father actually.
Mummy and Daddy
separated years ago.
She never mentions him now.
You know, it's scary
the way nobody stays together
anymore these days.
Pretty soon there's gonna be
more divorces than marriages.
Isn't it the truth?
- How old are you?
- Thirteen.
So am I.
I can't wait till I'm 1 8...
and get my own car
and stay out dancing till midnight.
I'll be 1 4 November 1 2.
No kiddin'?
That's my birthday too.
Isn't that peculiar?
November 1 2?
Mm-hmm.
Funny, isn't it?
Uh-oh, this one's full.
Hey, what do ya know,
it's stopped raining.
[M Birds Twittering ]
What is your mother like?
- I can't remember her.
- Did she die?
Nope. Busted up with Dad
when I was young.
But she was fabulous.
Absolutely fabulous!
- How do you know?
- There used to be a picture
of her on Daddy's desk.
But once he caught me
looking at it, and it's
never been around since,
Hey, you wanna come
to the commissary
and get a popsicle with me?
Can you only think
about your stomach
at a time like this?
At a time like what?
Don't you feel it?
Don't you know what's happening?
Don't you find it peculiar
that we both look so much alike
and have the same birthday?
It's just one
of those things, isn't it?
Will you come inside
a minute... please?
Mother always says
I'm psychic;
you know, that I can sense
things when something odd
is going to happen.
I always get
goose bumps. Look.
So what?
I don't understand.
What are you doing
with her picture?
It's my mother.
But it's my mother too.
????[M Reveille ]
[M Girls Chattering ]
Uh... lunch.
You go.
I'm not hungry.
I hope we have chicken tonight
because I really like that,
[ Crying ]
[ Gasps ]
I didn't know
what to say.
I know.
I didn't either.
Golly, sisters!
You know what
probably happened.
They must've quarrelled
and parted...
and just sort of... bisected us,
each taking one of us.
Why do you suppose
they separated?
I don't know. I can't imagine
anyone not loving Mother.
She's absolutely divine!
Well, what about Dad?
He's a sensational person,
I mean, as a friend and all.
The thing is... that neither
of them got married again.
You see what that means?
- Not really.
- Secretly, in their
innermost hearts,
they must still
be in love with each other.
Then why have they stayed
separated all these years?
Because that's how true love
creates its beautiful agony.
All splendid lovers
have just dreadful times.
Uh... Peleus and Melisande,
Daphnis and Chloe.
History's just jammed
with stories of lovers
parted by some silly thing.
Uh-oh!
Oh!
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, boy!
Oh, my gosh! Oh!
- What's the matter?
- Uh--
You wanna meet Father and
I'm just dying to know Mother.
Well, what if--
Oh, my gosh!
It just seems so scary that
we might be able to pull it off.
Pull what off?
- Switch places!
- Switch?
We could do it.
We're twins, aren't we?
Oh, I want to know Mother.
Look, now I'm getting
goose bumps.
Me too.
You know something,
there's more to it
than just switching places.
- I believe fate brought us together.
- How so?
If we switched, sooner or later
they'd have to unswitch us.
Mother would have to bring me
to California to unmiX us.
- And they'd have to meet again.
- Face to face.
- Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
- EXactly.
Let's get to work!
- Hmm?
- It's amazing!
Now, I think you should
wear this one when
you go to meet Dad.
Oh, this is gorgeous!
Oh, I'm going to wear this
one when I go to Boston.
Oh, I adore it!
Now, Susan, will you
pay attention.
Now the music room
and the library are on the first floor.
Now your room is the second door
on the second floor on the left,
all right?
Now, the horse's name
is Schotzli and the dog is Andromeda.
Verbena collects
the dirty laundry every Monday.
- [M Girls Chattering ]
- Sharon, will you pay attention.
Now, eXcept
for the dirty socks;
those are Thursday.
Oh, yeah.
My favorite food is chili beans.
Oh, and you gotta chew gum
'cause I always chews gum.
Um, flat ''A's'',
you must remember
all your ''A's'' are flat.
Uh, talk fast, you know,
'cause everybody talks fast. And--
But I never bite my nails!
Sharon, ya gotta!
I always chew mine.
Anyhow, Dad'll know.
Go on, bite 'em,
Can't. Shan't.
Aunt. Hmm?
No, no. ''Ca-un't.''
''Sha-un't.'' ''Au-unt.''
''Ca-un't.''
- Ooh, I can't wait till camp is over.
- ''Ca-un't'' wait.
Okay, I ''ca-un't'' wait.
[ Girls Saying Good-bye ]
- Daddy, he doesn't smell at all!
- You're not gonna take
it home, and that's it!
- Oh, Daddy, you're so mean!
He's so cute.
- She's not gonna take it home.
Ah, you big meany.
I spent so much time to get him.
Ahh, baby.
[ Chattering ]
It's got to be done
methodically.
Remember the key:
recollection and memory.
- Get her talking about
how her and Daddy first met.
- And their first date.
- Find out about that first date.
- [M Miss Inch ] Sharon!
- That's you now.
- Oh, yes, coming.
Now, look, the most important
thing: you must bring Mother
to California.
Boston is no place
to rekindle a romance.
[M Miss Inch ]
Sharon McKendrick!
Good-bye, girls.
Good-bye. Sharon McKendrick.
Your chauffeur's waiting
for you, dear, Now hurry,
The punishment was harsh,
I know, putting you two girls together,
but you've survived it,
and I hope you've both learned
something from the eXperience.
- Oh, boy, you'd be surprised,
Miss Inch.
- [ Chuckles ]
Yes. Well, good-bye, Sharon.
See you neXt summer.
Good-bye, Miss Inch.
Oh, uh...
I ''ca-un't'' tell you
how very much
I've enjoyed my stay.
I ''sha-un't'' tell my ''au-unt''
about the ''au-unts''-- uh, ants,
nor the debutantes,
shall I?
[ Chuckles ]
Bye.
- What did you do to your hair?
- Oh, I cut it. It was too hot long.
- You wait till your grandmother
sees what you've done.
- Hmph.
[M Car Door Closes ]
Miss Lockness, Betina,
upstairs, third door to the left.
Oh, what's her name?
Miss--
[M Car Door Closes ]
[ Sighs ]
Oh, well here goes nothin'.
What?
[M Woman ]
For the white wine--
and with the meat,
Do we have any more of--
[M Muttering ]
I think we better have
cloakroom tickets
for the ladies' wraps as well,
Oh, Rosa, I want all the gilt
chairs in the music room, and do
see that they're well dusted.
- [M Maid ] Mrs, McKendrick,
you asked me to remind you--
- Oh,yes,yes,yes,
Do see that the maids
keep absolutely quiet
during the music,
If they must empty
the ash trays, tell them
to do it without clinking.
- I'll see to it.
- I want those Steinways at the
north end of the music room,
- Have you checked about delivery?
- I'll see about it right now.
- Now, I'll tell you what.
- Well, you're home from camp, are you?
- Hello, Miss Lockness.
- Did you bring home all your
underwear and personal things?
- Yes, it's in my luggage.
Staimes has it.
- It's probably full of germs.
- What have you done to your hair?
- Do you like it?
Wait till your grandmother
sees what you've done.
Who is that
I hear out there?
Is that my little girl?
The tall, gangly thing?
- Hi, Grandfather.
- Hello, sweetheart.
Oh, my, my, my.
Oh, well, well, well.
Let me look at you.
[ Chuckles ]
Have you had--
Well, what's the matter, dear?
- I'm just happy to see you.
- Ah, and I'm happy to see you too.
I'll tell you,
your grandpa missed you
around here.
You know, it was an awful--
[ Stammering ]
Wait a minute.
- Wait, wait.
What are you doing?
- Making a memory.
- Making a memory?
- Mm-hmm.
All my life, years from now
when I'm quite grown up,
I'll remember my grandfather
and how he always smelled of--
[ Sniffing ]
tobacco and peppermint.
Smelled of tobacco and pepper--
[ Chuckling ]
Well, I'll tell you what.
I use the peppermint
for my indigestion,
and the tobacco--
[ Clears Throat ]
to make your grandmother mad.
[ Laughing ]
Sharon! Sharon!
Welcome home, darling,
- Mother!
- Oh, darling. It's so good
to have you home.
Let me take a look at--
What on earth have you done
to your hair?
- I cut it.
- Well, that's certainly obvious.
I thought there
was something different.
Well, what's done is done.
At least it'll grow again.
What's the matter, Sharon?
Are those tears I see?
I can't help it, Mother.
- If only you knew.
- Knew what?
Why, Sharon.
When did you get back?
- Hi, Granny.
- She just arrived.
Doesn't she look wonderful?
Ye-- My dear child,
what have you done to your hair?
- She cut it.
- Well, I had to because--
If my opinion means anything
in this house, which I doubt,
I like it short the way it is.
- Charles, stop burbling.
- I haven't burbled in years and--
Go down to your office
and read your newspaper.
See you at dinner.
- Bye.
- Oh, now really, Mother,
it doesn't look so bad.
It's hoydenish.
Are you a boy or a girl?
Make up your mind.
- What's that?
- Oh, it's a present
I brought for you.
We made it--
I mean, I made it,
especially for you.
Thank you, dear.
What is it?
It's a bird cage
made out of popsicle sticks.
- Oh, come on upstairs with me
while I finish getting dressed.
- See you later.
[ Chuckles ]
- Did you make some
nice friends at camp?
- Oh, yes, one girl in particular.
- Who is she?
- Oh,just a girl.
- From Boston?
- No,just a girl from someplace.
My goodness,
you're beautiful.
[ EXhales ]
Well, what's the matter?
You're staring at me as if
you'd never seen me before.
Oh, I don't know.
I'm just happy you're here
and that you're you.
Well, I'm happy that you're here
and you're you.
Now, be a good girl,
fasten me up.
- Did you miss me?
- Mm-hmm. Did you miss me?
[ Chuckles ]
You'll never know.
I'll see you at the Somerset
Club after my garden club
meeting. Stand up, child.
Don't slouch. I hope you
haven't picked up bad habits
at that camp of yours.
- Keep your shoulders straight.
See you at the Somerset, Margaret.
- Yes, Mother.
Now-- Well,
what's the frown for?
I just got back and you've got all
those meetings and things.
Well, I thought we could spend
the day together and talk.
Oh, we have the whole weekend
to talk. And you know that
I cannot cancel the Red Cross.
[ Sighs ]
Well, what I have to say can wait.
Yes, dear?
I just wanted to have
a little woman-to-woman
talk with you about Stafford.
Stafford?
Who's Stafford?
Oh, this boy I met at camp.
I just wanted your advice
on something.
Yes? On what?
Well, uh...
I wanted you to tell me
how long you waited
before you got married.
Sharon.
- Oh, Lockness.
- Yes, Miss Margaret?
Please tell my mother that I
won't be able to meet her, and
cancel all of my appointments.
- Cancel them?
- Yes. Something very
important has come up.
Yes, Miss Margaret.
Sharon, what
I'm trying to say is that
the decision to marry...
is something best considered
after you've lived
a little bit longer.
Mother, you're perfectly right.
Stafford was much
too juvenile for me.
Well, thank goodness
for that.
- To be perfectly frank with you,
the old zing just wasn't there.
- Zing?
You know, the charge that shoots
up your spine when you meet
the one man you wanna marry.
Like when you met Daddy.
[ Sighs ]
What was Daddy like?
Well... I don't know how
we got around to him.
Is it terribly painful for you
to talk about Daddy?
No. Why should it be?
I don't know.
Well, I thought, maybe
when you've been in love
with somebody once,
well, the recollection
and memory might be bitter--
bitterly painful.
Oh, Sharon, that was
many, many years ago.
Don't dramatize it.
Where did he take you
on your very first date?
He-- He took me to dinner.
It was an Italian restaurant.
One of those down in those
old basements in New York.
It was called Mar--
Martinelli's.
- Martinelli's?
- Yes,
Hmm.
- You said there was music.
- Uh-huh.
- What song did they play?
- Song?
Oh, there must've been a song.
You know, the old ''They're
playing our song'' type of thing.
Oh. Well, if there was,
I wouldn't remember it.
- It was much too long ago.
- Oh.
??La-di-dom
Ba-dee??
? La-di-dom
La-di ?
? La-di
La-di-dom ?
? La-da ?
? Though time may tatter?
? Our first sweet thrill ?
??It doesn't matter??
? It never will ?
? La-di-dom
La-di ?
??La-di-dom
Ba-dom??
? La-di
La-di-dom ?
? La-da ??
[M People Chattering ]
Susie,
- Hi, peanut.
- Hi, Dad.
- Well, how was the camp?
- Fine.
- No broken bones or anything?
- Mm-mm.
No. Come on,
let's get the bags, honey.
- Here's my baggage check.
- Oh, boy, are you
still biting your nails?
Oh, you noticed.
She told me that you--
- [ Chuckles ]
- What?
Nothing.
Well, I certainly did enjoy
all those nice long,
newsy letters, yes, sir.
Oh, that.
Well, we meant to write,
but we just got so tied up
with-- with plans and things,
you know, well we--
- Who's ''we''?
- Uh, uh.
Us. I mean, I.
Oh, us, There was
a very nice girl there,
We became quite
good friends.
Oh, that's mine.
That's my... bag.
Mm-hmm.
Glad to be home, huh?
It's wonderful.
Were you lonely while I was gone?
- I cried myself to sleep every
night about the first week--
- No, no, seriously.
Well, seriously,
I got to play golf every day.
I played poker at night.
I wish I could find
one of these camps where
they keep you all winter.
- Ho-ho.
It's good to have
you home, goofy.
Uh, Susie, there's, uh...
been a lot of things
happening since you left.
And I think we ought to have
a little quiet talk sometime.
- Oh, sure. I have some things
I wanna talk over with you too.
- Oh, you have, huh?
- Mm-hmm, but not now.
- Okay.
Now I just wanna think
about getting home
and being with my father.
My very ''o-own fa-ather''.
''O-own fa-ather''?
- [ Chuckles ] Father.
- Father.
[ Horn Honking ]
Oh, Daddy,
it's beautiful!
Well, it's just about the same.
You didn't think it was
gonna change, did ya? Hecky!
- [M Man ] Ho!
- Look.
Ah, shoo, shoo.
What have you got there
with ya, Mitch?
- Hi, Hecky.
- How are you, darlin'?
What'd you have to
bring this kid back for?
I thought we got rid of her.
Well, she was hanging
around the airport, I thought
I might as well get her,
- [ Mock Chuckle ]
How was camp?
- Oh, swell.
For heaven sakes,
it's about time. We've been
waitin' for you all day!
- Hi, Verbena.
- Never mind that ''hi''talk,
You just give me a hug,
Oh. Hello, honey.
Let me get a look at you.
Ya-- Ya know, there--
there's a change in you.
Just the same
as I always was.
No. No, you're not. I--
- [ Growling ]
- Not quite sure what it is,
- Hi, Andromeda.
- [ Barking ]
- Stop that, Andromeda!
What's wrong with you?
- [M Growling ]
You crazy dog.
It's Susie, ya silly.
Well, it's almost as if
your own dog didn't know you.
[ Chuckles ]
Funny, isn't it?
Uh, dogs are
funny things.
Well, I guess I'll go up to my room
and put some of those--
- Come on, we'll get you unpacked
while you tell me about camp,
- Coming.
Tell me about all the things you
did at that camp, I wanna get
that laundry of yours too,
-Come down when you get through.
Somebody I want you to meet.
-All right.
- Be down in a minute.
- [M Woman ] Hello, darling,
Mitch, I was wondering when
you'd get back, I was beginning
to get so bored sitting here,
Well, did you tell her
anything about us?
- Good to be home again?
- Sure is.
Verbena, there's
a woman downstairs.
Mm-hmm.
There is indeed.
Well, who is she?
What is she doing here?
I'm not saying a word.
I mind my own business.
EXcept if he wants to make
a ninny of himself, that's his
affair. I don't say a word.
- Well, how did she get here?
- It's none of my never mind.
I don't say a word.
EXcept a man like your father
with a grown daughter
going on 1 4--
He's not what
you'd call one of those...
''charm fellows''...
with a big, teethy grin
and-- and a lot of
artistic clever talk.
- What does a young girl
like her see in him?
- I don't know.
I'll give you a million reasons
and he's got 'em right in the bank.
[ Sighs ]
''It was always thus.''
What was always thus?
I'm not sayin' a word.
I'm not one to talk
about anybody behind their back.
But she's good.
She's awful good.
Those cool blue eyes
lookin' right through you.
Calm, that one.
Go ridin' together, swimmin' together,
out to dinner every night.
But it's none of my business,
understand, That's why
I'm not sayin'a word,
Not one single word.
Besides, I don't think
you oughta talk about people--
Hi, Susie. We were
just talking about you.
Uh, this is Miss Robinson.
- How do you do?
- Hello, darling.
I've been looking
forward to meeting you
for just weeks now.
From the way your father talked,
I eXpected a little girl,
but you're practically a woman.
- I'm nearly 1 4.
- Say, I think I'll go and make
martinis. You want one?
- Oh, I'd love one.
- Uh, how about you, honey?
You want root beer, ginger ale?
- Could I have a ginger ale?
- Sure. You get acquainted.
I'll be just a minute.
- Your father tells me you were
at camp, dear. Was it fun?
- Yes, it was lovely. Thank you.
You know, ever since
I met your father, it's been
''Susan this'' and ''Susan that.''
You're obviously very
good friends, and I think
that's just wonderful.
I can, uh, tell you
something else too
if you can keep a secret.
- From whom?
- From your father.
Oh, then you
better not tell me.
Daddy and I don't keep secrets
from one another.
We tell each other
everything.
Oh, well, no, dear.
It wasn't that kind of a secret.
I just wanted to confide in you
that I find him a very special,
wonderful kind of person.
Well,just between us,
he's not too brilliant
or clever with what he says,
you know, like the ''charm fellows''
we all adore so.
We were riding the other day.
Your father let me ride Schotzli.
I understand
she's your horse,
I hope you don't mind
my riding her.
Oh, no.
Schotzli and I are used
to strange women riding her.
- What?
- Oh, you know Daddy.
He's always
playing the field.
- No, I didn't know.
- Oh, yes.
Every week mostly,
he has some different
dame up here.
One week,
I'll never forget,
he had five
different women up here.
- You don't say.
- Of course, it's none
of my business...
if he wants to make a ninny
of himself with all those women.
That's why I'm not saying
a word. Not one single word.
Here you are.
Now, did you two
get to know each other?
Yes.
We had a lovely
little talk.
[ Alarm Ringing ]
- [ Ringing ]
- Hello?
- [ Operator]
Miss Susan Evers?
- Yes, this is her.
- [ Operator] Go ahead, please.
- Sue, it's Sharon. How's everything?
Ooh, Mother's the absolute
living end! She's gorgeous.
Just breathtaking!
- I got to talk to you
about their first date.
- Susan--
-Italian dinner, drippy candles,
checkered tablecloth--
-Susan, will you listen?
Ooh, I got their song.
It goes like this.
? For now, for always ?
- Susan, I've got
something to tell you.
- ? La-la, la-la, la-- ??
- Susan!
- What?
We're in trouble.
You'll have to bring
Mother out immediately.
No! Holy smokes,
I just had one day with her.
I hardly got to know her at all.
- Susan, it's an emergency.
There's a woman out here.
- Huh?
Her name's Vicky,
and she's beautiful.
Oh, is that all? Don't be silly.
Dad'd never get serious.
But he's serious about this one.
He's trying to get Vicky and me
to be friends. She's dangerous.
Well, bust it up,
for heaven sakes!
Follow him wherever he goes
and submarine her!
-You've got to tell Mother
and come out here to help!
-I want some more time with her.
- You've had her for 1 3 years,
and I just got here!
- Susan!
I won't! Do the best
you can and stay on
Daddy's tail. That's all!
- Susan, please.
- I won't give up Mother
this soon and that's final!
- Good-bye.
- Susan.
[ Sighs ]
I'm glad you could come along
today, honey, because there's
something I wanna talk about.
- It's kind of important.
- Oh, what is it?
- Well, you know the girl
you met at the house, Vicky?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, I thought that we ought
to be alone a little while
so we could talk.
- Well, I wanted to talk to you
about something too, Dad.
- Oh? Okay, go ahead.
All those weeks at camp,
I've been wondering about my mother.
You what? What do you
wanna start wondering about
something like that for?
Well, it's a perfectly
natural thing for a girl
to do. Where is she?
Well, I don't know where she is.
How should I know?
- Last thing I heard, she went
to Spain and married some drunk.
- Daddy, that's not true. Stop.
All right. I lost track.
You wouldn't like her anyway, hon.
She's-- These big staring eyes
and red frizzy hair.
And besides,
she was fat, really fat.
Then why did you
fall in love with her?
Well, you know, you lose
your head sometimes.
Besides that--
Wait just a minute.
Hey, Fletcher, play on through.
I'll pick you up at the bar.
Well, sit down.
[ Clears Throat ] Honey, you
don't wanna start thinkin' about
your mother all of a sudden.
There's a-- Well,
there's no need for that.
You can always come and
talk to me about anything.
You always have.
Well, it's not the same.
Well, father and daughter is okay.
But when a girl gets
to a certain age,
that's when she really
misses her mother.
Why?
I mean, uh--
Oh, you mean the talk
about... certain things?
- Yeah.
- That?
[ Inhales ] I guess
we never have just sat down and
talked about that, have we?
Well, this is kind of
an odd place, but I guess
it's as good as any.
Um-- Well, we might as well
get it over with. Uh--
- How-- How much do you
know now already?
- About what?
- About what you were
just talking about?
- Nothing. Absolutely nothing!
- Nothing?
- Well, you never brought up
the subject and I wondered why.
[ Inhales, EXhales ]
Well, honey, um--
All right, we oughta get
straight on one thing first;
that's little boys.
How-- See, I know
how they are because...
- being a man I used to be
a little boy once, so I know.
- I don't know what--
Take my word for it because I
used to be a little boy one time
and I know! I know about it.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Daddy.
- You're too funny for words.
- What do you mean, ''funny''?
Well, I've known about
all that for simply years.
Well, what the heck were
we just talking about then?
Well, what were you
talking about?
Well, uh--
[ Sighs ]
I think I better go and putt out.
There's the
little beast now.
Why, she's nothing
but a child.
She's a conniving, vicious,
little two-faced brat.
Just smile, pet.
Think of California and that
wonderful community property law...
and just smile,
- Hi.
- Hello, Mitch, darling.
- Hi, Edna.
- Who is this ecstatic,
bright-eyed child?
- Oh, Mitch, this couldn't be--
- Sure, that's Susie.
- Honey, this is Vicky's mother,
Mrs. Robinson.
- How do you do?
- This angelic girl? This is
the one you call ''peanut face''?
- Oh, Daddy, really.
Now, you come right over here
to your Auntie Edna...
and you and I are gonna
get to know one another.
[ Giggles ]
Come on, I wanna hear
all about ya. Down ya go.
- Hi.
- Did you tell her?
- [M Edna Chattering Nonstop ]
- Well, I started to, and
I don't know what happened.
- Oh, Mitch, for--
- All right,just let me do it
in my own way. All right?
Now, it's all settled,
Susan and I have decided
we're all gonna have
a darling lunch right here.
Edna, I'm sorry. I don't think
we can today. I promised to
spend the whole day with Susie.
- We've got some stuff planned,
you know?
- Ahh.
- I'm terribly sorry.
- Oh, that's all right.
Another time, dear.
[ Chuckles ]
You're an adorable thing!
Come on, Susie, We'll get
the horses, We're gonna
take a ride down the beach,
- Have fun.
- Bye, darling.
First change I make in that
household, off she goes to a
boarding school in Switzerland.
Honey, listen, uh...
I've been meaning to ask you,
what do you think of Vicky?
Uh... in what respect?
Well, uh,,, it's just
an ordinary question,
No, it's not.
You ask me what I think of Vicky.
Well, what do I think
of Vicky as what?
I mean, if you ask me
what did I think of her
as a fashion model...
or a famous aviatrix
or something,
then maybe I'd express
some sort of opinion,
but just to ask--
[ Clears Throat ]
All right. Uh...
what do you think of Vicky
as a person?
[ Chuckles ]
Well, Daddy, I really couldn't say.
She's a perfect stranger
to me.
- Beat you back to the house!
- Hey, wait a minute, Susie. Susie!
Hey, I'm not through
talkin' to you!
[M Car Horn Honks ]
Hi, darling.
- Hi.
- Hello, sweetie.
[ Sighs ]
He can't.
He just can't.
Oh, it just makes me so mad,
A man of his age!
All the work and the plans!
Hi.
You used to
confide in me.
Anything you wanna
talk over with me?
No.
You wouldn't like to
tell me why Andromeda
never comes near ya?
[ Chuckles ]
Or why suddenly
your appetite's changed?
[ Chuckles ]
Dear Verbena, you are a mystic.
Mystic?
I'm no mystic.
Well, asking me
all these crazy questions.
Gee, I don't know
what you're getting at.
You know what
I'm talking about. There--
There's something
very strange about you.
Are you sure there isn't
anything you wanna tell me?
What do you want me
to tell you?
Well, I don't know.
It's... almost as if you were--
No, that's impossible.
Almost as if I were who,
Verbena?
Oh, forget it, honey.
Never mind.
You mean Sharon?
Where did you hear
about her?
Oh, Verbena.
I've got to tell someone.
But you gotta swear
never to tell Daddy.
Promise?
Now, darling,
try to be diplomatic.
- Honey, I know how
to talk to my own daughter.
- Calmly.
- She's 1 4 years old.
She's not eXactly insensitive.
- Good luck.
Susan!
Oh, hi, Dad.
-Just getting back?
- Uh-huh. Now,just a minute.
I wanna talk to you.
- You didn't know what a good
thing you had when you had it.
- Huh?
Susie!
- ?? [ Piano ]
- Now, why'd you go
running off like that?
- I told you I wanted to talk
to you about something.
- I'm listening.
- Get comfortable.
- [ Clears Throat ]
I am comfortable.
What do you want?
Well, first of all,
honey, about me.
Now, oh, you probably
think of me as being
just your father.
And to you,
I probably seem ancient and old.
[ Laughs ]
Not ancient, Daddy.
Well, certainly not.
I'm in my best years.
- ?? [ Stops ]
- Okay, don't get nervous.
Well, I'm not nervous.
- ?? [ Resumes ]
- Honey, what seems old to you
now isn't old when you get old.