I can't believe that I
didn't get a pedicure for this.
How embarrassing.
Look at that.
If I were with a real guy doing this
I would have gotten a pedicure,
and a wax.
Oh shit, that one’s worse!
- Sorry I didn't get a pedicure.
- What?
Uh, my toes.
I am Sorry.
I'm not looking at your toes,
- I'm looking at your cervix.
- Right.
Now I kind of wish you were
looking at my toes.
- All done.
- That's it?
We'll, uh, elevate your legs for 10 minutes
and you'll be good to go.
This is the first I hear the ticking
clock sound and I'm not freaking out.
Good. Just relax.
I can't, I'm totally freaking out!
Oh, come on, everything is going to be great.
I have a feeling that you
and, um, CRM-1014
are going to make beautiful babies together.
Thank you.
Oh God, I hope this works.
I wanted this for so long.
Maybe this isn't how I pictured it...
exactly,
thought I would have a little
more support.
No, you don't want kids!
Trust me.
Well that’s easy for you to say,
you have four.
And it's awful.
They've ruined my life!
What?!
No, go away!
Have you seen my vagina?
I mean have you?
But I wouldn't show it to you,
I will show it to you
just to prove you do not want to have kids.
I will show you, my vagina!
I don't want to see that,
I want to have a baby.
I just think you're tired
of being alone,
you haven't met the right guy ...
It's not about a guy,
this isn't about a guy
I've dated hundreds of guys
over the past five years
not one of them is close
to being the one.
It's just not happening for me.
Yeah, but that does not mean
that it won't.
- Doesn't mean that it will.
- Is that my chicken?!
What are you doing?!
That is your dinner, not a toy!
I hate them.
Do you smell pee?
So I had to figure it out on my own.
I examined every possibility
and arrived at the most logical conclusion.
Would you be my baby daddy?
What?!
No, I can't be the father,
Are you out of your mind?!
What are you talking...
No, no!
I'm in my sexual prime, alright!
I have countless more women to bed before
I do something idiotic as having a baby.
Clyde, you're my friend.
Don't you want to help me?
I mean, we don't have to have sex.
You don't have to be involved at all.
Alright? Just... give me your sperm.
Oh, oh. Ok. Ok.
You're... you're feeling lonely, alright? Maybe a little...
a little dead down there. I get it, I get it.
Long time since you had uh... you know...
- J..Just shut up! Ok! Just forget it! Forget the whole thing.
- What?
Well that was a bust.
So I took life by the, uh... horns?
and I... I did what I had to do.
Yeah.
It's going to be ok.
I have a plan.
- Whoa, You don't have to walk like that!
- Well, oh... ok.
Uh, by the way, I know a
excellent support group
for single moms,
if you're interested.
Great! Great.
Maybe we should hug? We might have
just made a baby together.
- Good luck.
- Okay. Alright.
- Hi.
- Hi!
- Get away from me!
Taxi!
Excuse me,
this is my cab.
- What, you own it?
- No, but I'm about to rent it.
If you see someone hail a cab
and a cab pulls up
you can't just jump in the cab
and say it yours?
- I didn't see you.
- I saw you see me.
Sir? sir... excuse me
Who saw you first?
Look, maybe you're not from around here
but there is a code, you know
there are certain rules we try to follow ...
Fine!
Forget it, I get out!
But not because your right
but because I am in a terrific mood
and you're ruining it.
No, I'll get out.
- Now what?
- I don't know, you tell me?
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Where's it going?
Come back!
Well, that was stupid!
Why did you get out?!
You stupid head!
You said you were in a good
mood and I was ruining it.
I felt bad.
I'm sorry, did you tell me a
stupid head?
How is your great mood now?
Please stop talking to me.
So why you such a good
mood anyways?
Not that it’s your business but
good things are happening to me.
That's great,
I hope it continues.
Thanks
Well, have a nice life
and try not to steal any more cabs.
Yeah, you do the same.
Hey, there's a penny right there.
Why don't you pick it up, its good luck.
Only if it's heads.
Now somebody else can have good luck.
- Bye.
Thank you for coming to Hudson Mutts.
- Hi Nutzy
- Oh my God.
You're glowing.
- Oh my God, she's glowing, right?
- Uh, huh.
- Tell us everything.
- There's not much to tell.
No, no, no... you just got shot up with a wad of
red headed, freckle sperm. There's something to tell.
Wait, he had red hair and freckles,
why'd you do that?
- I tried to talk her out of it.
- Red pubes... ew!
I never saw his pubes, it was a vial of semen.
So come on, what happened?
I laid down, put my feet up over my head
and five minutes later
it was over.
I barely felt a thing.
Basically it was like having
sex with Clyde.
You wish.
If you need me I'll be back
with legs over my head.
- Red hair and freckles!
- You had your chance!
What?
I do not know, it’s just weird, you know
who was this guys she was with anyways?
- She wasn't actually with him.
- Yeah, but I still want to kick his ass.
- Is that wrong?
- You're stupid.
Ok, alright.
Welcome to Single Mothers
and Proud.
As the name suggests
we are all single... mothers
and, uh, proud.
Some of us have adopted
some of us have conceived
with a donor,
every stories is different,
but with the same common denominator
wanted a child
and we made it happen on our own.
We sure did, we sure did.
Are you already a single mother
or you trying to become one?
I was just inseminated a few days ago.
Inseminated,
makes me feel like
a cow or something.
Well, we do what we have to do
when we don't have a penis partner.
So, let’s hear about you.
Oh, ok. Let's see ...
I own a pet store.
Yeah, I use to work in the corporate world.
Which was great for a while
but just didn't feel like the life
I wanted to live.
So, now I am happy on the work front
but, you know, I don't know
even though I have more balance,
personal... I still haven't found the one.
Well, the elusive one.
Good luck.
If I had a dollar for every
time I hear that.
I thought I'd be married
with kids by now
but that’s just not happening
so, I guess it’s time for my
backup plan.
Well, Zoe listen,
if you really want a baby
we here at Single Mothers
and Proud... ah ha...
We can be your partners.
From inception to graduation,
everything in between
We can be here for you.
Great.
Dakota was born here,
in this very room.
Right where you are sitting actually.
Really?
Right here?
Imagine that.
So how old is your baby, now?
I'm three.
So cute.
Why do you need a support group?
- You're not very supportive.
- What?
You just told me that if I breast feed, my girls
are going to end up looking like empty tube socks.
Hey, I'm just being honest.
Don't even get me started on what
child birth does to your bladder.
What does it do to your bladder?
Oh, I just peed a little bit.
I don't think I'm pregnant anyways.
The doctor said it would take a few tries.
Something about frozen sperm being lazy.
Oh, come with me for a minute
I have to make some muffins for some
bullshit teacher's appreciation day.
You're going to make muffins?
Oh hell no.
There is a place here that sells them,
I pick out the worse ones
and I pretend that I made them.
Come on.
Okay. Which is the ugliest?
It seems too much trouble
over something so trivial.
Welcome to motherhood.
There's that guy?
What guy?
The one selling cheese
I know him.
He's hot.
He sells cheese?
You sell hamsters.
Can I help you ladies?
No, we're good, thank you.
Like what you see?
What?
Just talking about the muffins.
- Hey you.
- Hey.
Hi
What.. what a nice surprise!
How did you know I worked here?
I didn't.
Oh, ok.
Did you follow me here?
Follow you?
To the farmers market, are you kidding me?
We... we came to buy muffins.
You where here, tell him.
Well, you better buy something,
because you ate all my samples.
It's really nice to see you,
I never got your name.
- I'm Stan.
- Oh, Zoe.
I'm Mona. So how do you
two not know each other?
- He stole my cab.
- She stole my cab.
Oh, ok.
We should go.
We should?
Yeah, we have that important thing.
Well, can your important thing
wait for a few minutes?
I'll give you a taste of my cheese.
I can rephrase that.
Ok, this is our basic chevre.
Probably our best seller,
or the cheese that started it all
as they say.
These are our surface ripen
cheeses, these are fantastic.
And these are the aged
raw milk cheeses.  Now...
This is really boring, isn't it?
- Uh, Yes.
- Um, No.
This is Louie,
he works for me.
- Hi
- Hi, Zoe
Can I get you a sample box?
Um, I'm ok.
You're not lactose intolerant
are you? I hate that.
Hey, you're still coming over
tonight right?
I... um, yeah, yeah.
We should go.
- Ready?
- I want a sample box.
Ok, well I got to go.
Bye.
Uh, bye.
- You said free sample box, right?
- Yes.
Ok, spill it.
Who is he , what does he do,
how do we know him?
Who?
Stan, from the farmers market.
He's called twice already.
I'm going to kill Mona.
Is he a farmer?
He makes cheese.
He's a pilgrim?
Oh, Mona called too, she says his feta was
incredible. That makes so much more sense now.
Who is this guy?
He's nobody,
he's just some guy.
Are you blushing?
She's blushing right?
- You're totally blushing.
- She's blushing.
Can we just calm down and get
ready for the book signing?
No, this is exciting. I'm
not calming down.
Look, he's nobody,
and even if he was somebody,
it doesn't matter
cut, I don't want to be with anybody.
Okay?
So let’s just get back to work.
- Finding a relationship is work...
- I do not want a relationship.
Well, it is.
So dogs have a ingrain pack mentality.
If we don't assert leadership
over our dogs
our dogs are going to show unstable
behaviour or dominate behaviour.
In other words,
in the dog world, who you are
is stable or unstable energy.
A leader or a follower.
So, when a dog introduces
himself to another dog,
What do they do?
Exactly.
When a human wants
meet a dog ...
Oh my God! He's so ...
So, I mean, it’s like poor dog ..
And so they're interacting based on
energy and also the nose ...
Ok, now this is getting weird.
I know we keep running into
each other, it's crazy.
Oh, so your being here,
is just another coincidence?
Oh no, I love this guy.
- Don't you have some place to be tonight?
- Not 'til later.
- Do you even have a dog?
- No.
But I might get one now that
I can be the pack leader.
I'm really busy here.
Ok so, you have a boyfriend or something.
Just tell me, I can take it.
Or you're just no, you're
not interested in me?
You're making a big mistake,
I am very interesting.
I'm just not interested
in men right now.
Oh, you... you're gay?
I'm not gay!
Hey you two, would you please
take it outside?
- Sorry.
- Ok, sorry, sorry about that.
This is not a good
time for me, ok.
I'm going through some changes.
Menopause?
Seriously?
How old do think I am?
Ok, you know, let’s start over,
because the more I think about it,
we'd never make it as a
couple anyway.
You're way too sceptical,
We should be friends.
I have enough friends.
You can never have
too many friends.
What are you doing tonight?
Getting take out and
going home to bed.
Clearly you don't have
that many friends.
Ok, here's my proposition
and don't freak out because
it require very little commitment.
I'm getting take out too,
let's walk together towards
the same place,
order and pay for our
own respective meals
and we'll say goodbye.
Where do you want to go?
Thank you.
No fair, you chose this place
because it takes two seconds.
No, I chose it because it's the best.
Alright, well I want to see you take a
bite of that. I don't believe you'll eat it.
Fine.
There, happy now?
You have no idea how good this is.
I cannot believe you lived
New York your whole life
and you've never gone
to Gray's Papaya.
What's wrong with you?
Actually I haven't lived
here all my life.
We moved out of the city when
my parents bought the farm.
No, not die, they actually...
they bought a farm
and we moved upstate.
They retired to Phoenix
five years ago,
and I run the place now.
What about your family?
Actually my parents died
when I was young.
It's just me and my
grandmother now.
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
It's ok, it was long time ago.
I really have to go.
Alright, but I cannot let
you walk home alone because...
this is very dangerous neighbourhood.
What school did you go to?
Well, I kind of dropped out. I met this
Swedish girl during my semester abroad...
Let me guess,
you fell in love and got married.
- And started an inn in Vermont.
- Of course.
It lasted like three seconds,
I didn't know how to run an inn
and she didn't know how not to sleep
the everyone that worked there, so...
- Ouch
- we got divorced, yeah...
She took everything.
I had to move back
in with my parents.
Work myself out of debt,
and tried to figure out how not to blame every
women on the planet for honest Harish ways.
How's that going?
Not so good.
Ok, I want to know everything.
First kiss?
Some jerk with a dirt
bike and chapped lips.
You?
7th grade, she wore braces
and head gear
- It was terrifying.
- Ouch
Hey, look.
- Here's one for you.
- That's weird.
Ok, best kiss?
Um, that's a tough one.
Because, if we weren't just friends.
I'd kiss you right now,
and I'd be your best kiss.
How do you know?
I know.
Someone looking for you?
Yeah, I have to go.
- Okay.
- Bye.
I'll call you.
You think it was
the muffin girl?
I guess... I don't know.
Why do I even care?
You like him! Ow!
What if I'm pregnant?
Then it'll work out perfectly.
- What do you mean?
- Because,
if you really like him, as soon as
that happens you'll break up with him
because you're pregnant
and you wouldn't have to put yourself
out there, possibly get hurt.
Hey, that's your dream.
Ah, besides ...
I'm not pregnant.
And I'm ok on my own.
You're going to see him again?
Yeah, I think so.
It's not going to happen Nutzy.
Hello.
Oh, Stan.
Go away.
Stop it.
You're making me nervous.
You're early.
I'll be a minute, okay?
Uh, 3 to 5 minutes actually.
You want a beer?
Uh, yeah, yeah, sure.
You want one?
- I'll let you know.
- Okay.
Oh my God. Is he ok?
He's fine. Happens all the time.
I'm sorry.
Can you give me a minute?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Ok, good.
Damn it Nuts.
Give me that.
Give it to me.
Let go. Now!
Zoe, everything okay?
Yeah!
You know, just showing
him who's the pack leader.
You idiot!
You better not swallow that thing.
Give it to me.
Nutzy, open.
Open.
- You look really pretty tonight.
- Thank you.
You always look really pretty
but tonight you look, uh,
especially pretty.
And that dress is, uh, ...
is really something.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Did you buy a new dress
for our date tonight?
- Don't flatter yourself.
- I'll take that as a yes.
I guess you'll never know.
I guess not.
- Except you left the price tag on.
- What?
Allow me.
I got it.
You know, I had this dress
for a long time,
it's just I haven't worn it yet.
It's why the tag still on.
You're not that special.
Really?
Look at this place.
I don't know what to say.
Finally.
What's that suppose to mean?!
It just means good.
Don't say anything.
You don't have to say anything.
You know, just come
over here, sit down.
You think I talk too much?
- I did not say that.
- So what'd you say?
It's just you're very quick, you always
have an response for things. Which I like,
but tonight, just you know,
just be surprised.
Surprise.
You're good.
- So you work for an internet company?
- Uh huh.
- I don't see that at all.
- Oh, I was a very important person. You
would have been very impressed.
- Really?
- Uh huh.
How did you get the pet store?
Actually it was due to my dog, Nuts. I bought
him at this fancy dog store near my house.
Cutest puppy you've ever seen.
6 months later he almost dies.
Turns out he was from one of those puppy mills,
where the dogs are so in bred, he was falling apart.
What did you do?
Did you sue them?
I thought about it, but then
I thought what good would that do,
they'll still sell in bred dogs,
So I quit my job,
and I took the
stock option money
over to the pet store,
and I bought it.
I know how to milk a goat
Does that do anything for you?
No, not really.
Can I ask you a serious question Zoe?
What?
Did you buy that dress
to wear for me tonight?
I will never tell.
Really?
Because, uh ...
I have ways of
making you talk.
Let me get that, let me get that.
Oh!
Hose... hose over there
behind the fence.
You see it?
Got the hose?
Ok, this is war.
You weren't even pointing at the fire,
you were pointing at my face.
I wasn't even trying to soak you,
I swear.
Whatever, I looked into your eyes and saw
you had this crazy look, like a crazy person
Not true.
It is true and... you know what else,
I think I owe you another dress.
And I definitely own you another date.
Well, I'd like that.
Why don't you come to the farm
with me next weekend?
I'll call you.
I'll wait by the phone.
What?
Holly shit!
I know.
Are you sure?
If I'm not then my dog is.
You're not making any sense.
So you're definitely pregnant?
Congratulations
How we feeling?
- We're freaking out!
- What she said.
Why? We preformed an
intrauterine insemination
using sperm that you purchased.
This isn't exactly what
we call an accident.
It's just happening so fast.
Keep breathing.
Pump those arms.
What did you all eat last night?
- Hey Arthur.
- Well, hello my dear.
Oh no, no, don't get up. It's ok.
I can't get up.
- Came to see my lovely fiancée?
- Yes.
Oh, she's looking fine today,
let me tell you, just fine.
- Hi sweetheart.
- Hey.
- I need to talk to you.
- Sure.
Alone.
Surely! Don't worry about them,
they can't hear anything anyways.
I am pregnant.
- What?
- I'm pregnant.
- How what?
I cannot hear you darling.
Oh Jesus, Judy, she's pregnant!
Turn up your hearing aid.
I'm confused...
you said that this was what you wanted.
But this guy, he's special.
Now the whole thing is going to fall apart.
What makes him so special?
I do not know, he's very... real,
and funny.
And different.
I like him Nana.
What should I do?
Zoe, you always get ahead of yourself.
You barely know him.
Spend some time with him,
see what he's really like.
He could be a total douche bag
and then the whole thing is moot.
- Maybe he is a douche bag.
- Oh come on.
You really think he would ask you away
for the weekend if he had a girlfriend?
There's no way he's dating
that muffin bitch, Zoe.
Trust me.
Who can say?
Maybe he's looking to get laid?
Well, don't have sex
with him, ok? You can't
- because that would really complicate things.
- I know.
Oh, it’s going to be hard though
with three times the blood
coursing through your body.
Excuse me?
Oh, yeah.
That's why pregnant women
are so Horney all the time.
Is that what it is?
I thought it was me.
No, when I was pregnant
my body was so sensitive
I could have an orgasm
sitting on a bus.
I think I'm going to get sick.
- Me too.
- What?
It's a happy story.
Alright, I'm just
going to go up there
and tell him that I'm pregnant
- just lower my cards on the table.
- Ok, good.
Just don't lay on the table.
Ok, because you cannot have sex.
Don't look at me like that.
I know, this is a big mess we're in.
I'm going to fix it.
Shit, here it is.
Watch out for that tree.
Yeah, thanks.
- Hi.
The tree should not have been there,
that's all I'm going to say.
Whatever Mrs. Magoo.
- Oh, ok.
- Come on now, I am glad you're here.
Me too.
Stan, there's something
I need to tell you.
I am pregnant.
Yes, pregnant.
I'm going to have a baby.
I'm with child.
Shit.
Stan... Stan... Stan...
I've been inseminated.
Yes, inseminated.
I'm going to have a baby!
Uh, would you like a plate?
Um, a napkin? trough?
These are for you.
- That's sweet, thank you.
- You're welcome. You're good.
It's just that stew is so delicious.
I knew you liked it.
So, what's the next step
for a cheese farmer?
Very funny.
I want to start a sustainable
Gourmet Shop, okay.
Cheese, wine, bread,
prepared foods.
But everything local,
nothing from farther than 30 miles.
All based on the farmers markets.
- That's a good idea.
- Thank you very much.
I'm good at ideas, I'm just
not good with follow through.
I wasn't good at marriage,
I wasn't good at running
a bed and breakfast,
thank God we didn't have kids.
You don't want kids?
I don't think so.
Well, I don't know.
For years I've never thought about the future,
just kind of lived in the moment.
But maybe I'm different now.
I really want to take the next step,
I want to move on with my life.
- About the future ...
- Uh huh.
- Let's talk about that.
- Ok.
Because the future is now.
- Right?
- Right.
There's something
I need to tell you.
Hold that thought.
Come here.
- I want to show you something.
- What is it?
- It's cheese.
- I can see that.
No, no, no, it's new.
I had this idea to use these two
different types of goat's milk
to come up with something
really unique.
It's sweet and sassy
and complex.
I was inspired.
So what are you saying?
I'm your cheese muse?
Yeah.
You're kind of hard
to read right now.
Well, I really want to kiss you,
but it smells like
cheese in here.
We have to ...
take it slow, Okay?
- We can't have sex.
- Fine.
Ok... Ok... Ok... Ok...
Did you just ...
Holly shit!
Is my nose bleeding?
You punched me.
- Sorry.
- It's ok.
It was amazing.
It was like over the top amazing.
What was that, like a 3 or 4 for you?
Stan... Stan...
There's something I have to tell you.
Ok, what is it?
Why are you crying?
I'm pregnant.
I'm pretty sure it doesn't
happen that fast.
I know it... it's hard to explain.
What are you talking about?
I'm pregnant.
Who's the father?
I don't know
I mean, I know who it is,
I just don't know his name exactly.
It's a donor of a
sperm bank.
Seriously, what the hell
are you talking about?
When did all this happened?
Actually, it was the day we met.
Yeah, I didn't think to
tell you because
I didn't think there was any way
that I could be
pregnant so fast.
But why?
Because I wanted a baby.
And I never met the right guy
and I thought that if I waited any
longer, I might miss my chance.
Alright, we just make love
and you're telling me that your
pregnant with some stranger's child.
Don't say it like that.
You make it sound dirty.
I wanted a baby
and I thought I had
to do it alone.
It was before I met you.
I don't know what to say.
What am I supposed to say?
Congratulations,
this is terrific news?
I made this big decision,
this... this thing
and then I met you.
I'm sorry.
About what? Getting pregnant
or lying to me about it?
- I didn't lie.
- You didn't tell the truth.
Where are you going?
I thought this would be easier.
To just disappear at the crack of dawn?
Don't I get a say?
You said everything there
was to say last night.
No, I didn't.
Oh, you left out the part that you had
a girlfriend, that was pretty convenient.
I don't have a girlfriend.
That girl from the farmers market?
She's not my girlfriend.
She was, but was a few years ago.
Olivia is in my class,
we study together.
Study what?
I'm a student. I'm still in school,
I go at night.
Why didn't you want to tell me?
Because it's embarrassing.
You're this incredibly accomplished person,
and I didn't even finish college?
I mean, I have this great life but...
barely passing economics, you know.
Where are you going?
Look, let’s not drag this out, ok?
I lied to you,
you lied to me.
We both have other plans,
and being together is just
messing everything up.
We should just go
our separate ways.
Goodbye.
So how did you two meet?
- We can, uh, talk later in your office.
- Ok.
Well, everything seems
right on track.
A little blood, quite normal.
Stan, you have to stay here
if you don't want.
I'm fine, I'm good.
Now, I'm going to do an ultrasound.
This is how we view the future
Oh, I see, you rub it on her stomach. For a minute
I thought you're going to put that huge thing...
In her vagina?
It is too early to go
through the abdomen, you see.
We have to go through the vagina.
Vagina. Vagina. Vagina.
Vagina. Vagina.
Maybe if I say enough you'll
feel a little more comfortable.
- Vagina.
- It's not working.
Ok now Zoe,
with a little bit of luck,
we'll see a heartbeat.
That's it? That little thing?
Is everything okay?
Oh, everything is ...
- What, what?
- I see another heartbeat.
It has two hearts?
No, but you have two babies.
Are you going to leaving now?
Because this is more than
you bargained for.
It's more than I
bargained for.
But, just tell me, ok, so...
I can be prepared.
I just... need to sit here.
You know?
- Okay.
But then are you going to leave?
Ok, one kid is a lot,
two kids is a posse.
I'm just getting use
to us as a couple.
And now all of a sudden
you're having a posse?
Are you ready for a posse?
I don't even know if I like kids.
Hey! Beat it pal!
I don't want to cause a scene, but
get your hands out of your pockets
and get the hell out of here. No,
I'm talking to you
because you're the only pervert
with his hands in his pockets
at a playground.
- I'm not a pervert!
- Hey, if you don't have kids, get lost!
I have kids, Ok?
A week ago I didn't even
know she was pregnant
and now she's having twins!
I just saw the ultrasound.
The one that goes inside.
I know what you need.
How did this happen?
- Take that off
- This it?
- Yup
- Oh man, I'm dizzy.
I'm sweating and dizzy.
- That's normal, bro.
- Is it?
- Which one's yours?
- I've got three.
- Three?
- Yeah.
There is Charlie right there,
and that's Roxy.
You see the little fella over there? That's Matt
- He's eating sand
- Yeah
By the time you get to the third one,
you don't worry so much about that stuff.
What's it like, the whole kid thing?
It's great!
Except for the lack of sleep,
free time ... sex with my wife,
butt naked Friday's
in the family room ...
That's not the answer
I was looking for.
its fine.
The best way
I can describe it is ...
... It's awful, awful,
awful, awful
and then something incredible happens
And then awful, awful,
awful, awful, awful
And something incredible happens again
It's like this all day, every day
I feel like I'm drowning
like I'm gasping to
get my old life back
and then a small moment happens ...
... that’s so magical
So life affirming that it
makes it all worthwhile.
This will be best thing you ever do.
Dada.
Hey, son
I guess this would be that moment right?
Yup, this would be it.
- Hey, what do you have there, son?
- Poo poo
Well, almost.
- Son, is that cat shit?
- No
- That's your shit?
This isn’t even his shit.
Charlie, Roxy, meet me at the bathroom!
What I tell you about playing
with other people shit?
So, why are you upset?
It's so lucky. To get pregnant on
the first try with frozen sperm
is rare but to get
pregnant with twins ...?
Come on, that's unheard of.
Ok, when you want to
speak you can.
Does anyone else have anything in
the mean time that they like to share?
- Tabitha?
- Yeah, I'm having a hard time
Luka keeps asking me why
his friends have two parents
and he only has one. I guess
I knew this would happen someday
- But I just wasn't prepared ...
- Ok, there's this guy, his name is Stan
- and he's fantastic
- Wasn't I just speaking?
You know, whenever you meet somebody,
the kind of guy who makes you
rethink everything like...
maybe I can be a stay
at home mom
Maybe I can. I love
being barefoot and pregnant
Maybe he can teach me how to make cheese
and we can live off the land
Zoe, this group is called
Single Mothers and Proud
I know. I know. I know
I'm sorry.
I wasn't planning to meet anybody.
It just... it just happened
And now I've thrown all
my plans out the window
and really... fallen for this guy.
I'm just afraid he might not stay.
What should I do?
I don't know
This is wildly outside my
field of expertise
Yeah, because we are a...
single mothers group.
So don't tend to give advice on
how to get your boyfriend to commit
Not usually.
Maybe you should join
a different group.
Ok, we are going to have to
take a vote on this Zoe, because ...
I think we all collectively
feel you are in a very
wildly different place
than where we are
- So we are going to take a vote.
- Ok
Hi
How did you find me?
I called the store. I said
it was an emergency
What is it?
You're crazy
- I don't expect you to stay
- I don't expect you to expect me to stay
What if I want to stay?
Well then I would be surprised
and happy.
- I can't promise anything.
- Neither can I.
Ok fine, give me the hot dog
Perry and Hudson. Feel
free to run every red light.
You got it.
- Here we go.
This sucks! Nothing fits me!
Please let me wear sweats.
Honey, you can't wear sweats. This is important.
- I'll get that.
- Wait, let me suck it in.
Do you have a jacket or something?
- Gotcha, I gotcha. You alright?
- Yes.
I can't.
Watch it!
- I'm going to throw up.
- What?
Hey, how are you?
Stan, you are a prince. Thanks for coming.
Sea urchins?
- Hi
I ripped my dress and I didn't
want to go... how about that?
- What is that thing?
- Oh, Mona gave it to me
It is supposed to help me sleep
- Hold on.
- Ok.
It has been two weeks now
and all she ever wants to do
is to sleep with that pillow
The pillow is a bitch. It's
totally replacing you, right?
Totally, completely. She
drags it everywhere
My wife, she drew eyes on hers.
So when I went to make a move
in the middle of the night
the pillow is staring at me
like... uh uh bro!
I don't think so.
We used to have sex all
time, every day!
Now I can't touch her.
I can pearly go near her.
Dude! she's pregnant. You can't win,
the one who wins is the pillow.
- Screw that pillow, man!
- You might have to.
I did once.
We're going to be fine.
We're going to get through this. Everything is going to be fine.
In a year’s time this is just
going to be a funny memory, right?
That’s right. Before you know it
the kids will be in school
and you long for the days when
a pillow was your biggest problem
It must be hard when they
first go off to school
Little school shoes, little backpacks
No, saying goodbye to the kid is easy
Saying goodbye to 20 grand,
now that's hard
What are you talking about?
20 grand? What's 20 grand?
And you will have twins.
Double whammy. That's a
whole lot of parmesan.
Oh my God!
Alright, this one says,
most natural nipple
That looks nothing
like my nipples, nana
This one says,
BPA free.
- What is BPA?
- Don't know
So how do you know you don't want it?
It's Biphenyl A and you don't want it.
If you're going to use a bottle, which we
do not advocate because the breast is best
- Better
- Use a glass bottle
- How are you, honey?
- Good.
We miss you at the meetings
Yes
I never heard back after the vote
so I assumed that I was out
No, it was unanimous. Didn't
anyone called you? No?
This is my nana and this
is Arthur, her fiancé
- Hello
- Nice to meet you.
- How do you do?
So ... when are you get married?
She's kept me waiting for 22 years
so I'm not holding my breath
So, Zoe, can I put you
on the phone tree?
Kind of want the whole group
there when it happens.
- Thanks, that means a lot
- Ok, Well, happy shopping
and check out strollers on aisle
six because they're awesome.
- Do not you call her?
- I don't know
- Stan? Cookie!
- Zoe?
- What is that?
- It's a twin X deluxe
The Rolls-Royce of strollers
- Isn't it awesome?
- It's big.
It's supposed to fit through
most doorways
I don't think so. OK, let me help.
Turn it sideways...
Keep trying... there
Just hang on, It's got to
have a thing here
Hang on, hang on.
- Aw, Shit!
- Are you okay?
It bit me
What the hell is going on here?
You're suppose to get an outfit to bring
the babies home in from the hospital
Yeah, but how many babies
are you having?
Well, I just got two of everything
Look... baby village people
How much money did you spend today? Where
are we going to put all this shit anyway?
Do not worry it, everything will be ok
Yeah, I don't see how that’s possible.
You haven't even had the babies
and everything has changed
You know what? There's the door,
Stan. If you want to go, you can go
Stop! I hate it when you do that
I know, I'm sorry.
Let me see.
Sorry.
Have you gotten through page 279 yet?
No, I stopped reading when you tore
one of my pages and used it as a napkin
Well, it says here that
women in the third trimester
experience hormonal mood swings
and their partner just have to be
extra understanding about it
You coming on to me right
now? It's kind of hard to tell.
- What?
- You have chicken in your hair
- Just right there?
- I do?
Did I get it?
You know what, honey?
Just... I'm sorry, but not tonight, ok?
- Sorry
- It's okay
Hey babe, you want some breakfast?
No, thank you. It's still night time
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
Do you know how much
preschool is? 20 grand.
For circle time.
What about college? Actually, I think
colleges run about 50 grand right now,
but that’s right now. So figure in
18 years it'll be doubled that at least
and... well we have twins
so double it  again.
So what's that? like 200 grand a year?
We haven't even bought books,
or clothes or shit you know?
Probably going to need
cars when they' re at school
You know I'm going to be a push over
and buying whatever they want
So what's that?
Half a million a year?
I don't have half a million a
year. I'm in night school
It's just something I was thinking
about. It's no big deal
Why don't you come back to bed, honey?
- Did I wake you up?
- No
We're going to be ok. I have money saved
It's not just about the money
You know, I'll figure out a
way to make enough money
What is it then?
It's just ... I need to know
Are you still in there?
I'm still here
Excuse me, can I... help you?
What do you think?
It's a bit overwhelming huh?
There're so many and are so... big
Well, they have to be
big. Two babies right?
Yeah, but... babies are small
These are for
giant mutant babies.
Well you should see some
of babies that come in here,
total fat asses.
By the way, my boyfriend
and I do customer work
We can solve this
- What are you doing?
- Nothing
- How was your exam?
- Shitty
Come on, come on,
what were you doing?
Nothing
I gained three more pounds this week
And I think it went all to my ass
You look great.
You always look great.
I missed you today.
I miss my old ass.
You know what’s weird?
I never knew your ass.
It was kind of like this ass
but way hotter.
Baby, this is my old ass.
What?
Why do you have a picture of your ass?
My college boyfriend took it.
I mean, so, in all fairness
it doesn't look exactly like that
but it's pretty close,
it's held up
Yeah, it's a nice ass.
This is me in 7th grade
This is me and nana at
my confirmation
This is the last
picture I have of my mom
I mean, she lived a few years
more after this but...
We didn't take any pictures because
she didn't want us to remember her that way
I was 8 years old when she died
I can't imagine
She had this great laugh
and really soft hands.
She use to rub my
back before I went to sleep
Such a small thing but
I think about it all the time
Why don't you ever talk about your dad?
She was in a coma for two
years after this
- He didn't stick around
- Oh, God, Zoe
- I'm so sorry
- It's no big deal
It was an important lesson for me.
That's when I realized
that nothing lasts forever.
So now you know everything.
Some things can last forever
Maybe
So about my exam...
I didn't exactly...
That's weird.
I'm confused
- Why'd you say you'd come in the first place?
- Seemed like a good idea at the time
Is that Zoe?
It's so nice of you to come!
Hi!
Yeah, we just wanted to come and
stop by, say a quick hi and good luck
Oh, no, you're staying. You have to
stay. Lori wants us all here for this
I, I, I really want to stay...
She's having a contraction
- So... what were you saying?
- This is Stan
- Hi
- Of course
- Hi, um... Congratulations
- Ooh, Thank you
Hey, you two should get in here...
- Oh no... no, no, no, this is your special moment...
- Oh, no, oh God, I'm not shy
Come on, I've been through this
before. I'm not shy, Zoe
It is really quite beautiful
How long do we have
to stay here?
Let's just wait till it starts
and then we'll sneak out
Come on everyone, it's happening
Come on, she's about to
get into the water
The what ...?
I'm going to be out here, Ok?
Just relax... good.
I know, isn't it amazing how the
human body can just open up like that?
I think I'm going to go get
a little air. I'm feeling a little ...
Don't you move, Zoe.
You're my focal point
- What?
- Oh God
Push, push!
Shit!
You can't leave, you're her focal point
Can't you use somebody else?
She's in labour, you can't
argue with her now
Someone grab her legs
- Ok, lift them up...
- Push, that's it push...
- Jesus! What is that?!
- Perfectly natural
Sometimes the bowels just release
Ridley...you could...?
No Zoe, don't you move!
You are my focal point
But what does that even mean?
I need to turn over,
I need to turn over, please,
I need to turn over...
I need to turn over.
Here comes the head!
Give me a mirror! I want to see it!
- No! You don't, you don't!
- No! God damn it, Zoe! Don't move!
- I thought you wanted a mirror?
- Stan, the mirror!
- What?
- The mirror!
- What mirror?
- Get the mirror!
For the love of God,
Stan, get the mirror...
- Get the mirror!
- Bring it! Hurry up!
Hi, I'm Stan. Hi, I'm sorry.
Give me the mirror, nobody cares!
... No... No...
Look at all the hair!
It's not the baby's hair!
- One last... push!
- Push, push baby, push!
- Push!
- Aaaah!
- Beautiful!
- Look at that!
Everyone says that it's so beautiful
I thought it was terrifying
I don't ever want to see that again
But you want to see ours right?
I don't know, baby... It was just...
I shouldn't have seen that.
Hey, I was just coming by
to see if you were okay
I was worried about
you after the exam
- What happened with your exam?
- Trying to tell you last night but...
- What happened?
- I walked out on the exam
- Why?
- I'm quitting school
I can't believe you're pregnant
- Why are you quitting school?
- Because if I stay in school,
I can only work part-time
and if I can work part-time,
I can't afford all expenses
- I need to work, baby
- I had no idea it was this serious
You're having a baby? I didn't know
you've been together that long.
Well, yeah, they're not mine but...
yes, we're having a baby
we're having twins actually
What do you mean they're not mine?
Oh, I didn't mean it like that
- Why would you say that?
- I'm sorry, honey
I'm not exactly thinking straight
I've been up all night
watching Orca give birth
- I'm such an idiot
- No, Zoe
I'm so stupid. This is...
this is not about the money
Or that you can't afford kids
You do not want this. That's the problem
He always told me he didn't want kids
Why are you still here?
- That's it isn't it?
- Really?
After everything we've been through
you think I don't want kids?
- You really think that?
- That's what you just said
It's not what I just said,
it's what you just heard.
There is a big difference!
I don't think you're ready for this
Now that it's all happening, now that
you seen a woman push a baby out
Now... it's all too real for you
- And you're scared
- Damn right, I'm scared
- Yeah. Aren't you scared?
- You know what I'm scared of?
I'm scared that I'm going to have these
babies and then you're going to walk away
You're going to say, "They're not mine",
and just going to walk away.
Every day you’re looking for some
kind of hint that I'm leaving
no matter how many times
I tell you that I'm not.
I don't know what else to do. What
else am I supposed to do?
Nothing
So what are you saying?
- Just go now
- Don't want to go!
- Go
- This is crazy, Zoe
It's crazy!
If you don't go, I'll go.
You know what? Just so you know
when you do the autopsy here
You better realize you have
no one to blame but yourself
You had to come along didn't you?
I was fine with my plan
Totally fine with it
You've lost your mind!
- Just give me a boost
- If you think you're getting into this dumpster...
I need that pillow
Ok? I can't sleep
I will never sleep again
without that pillow
Well, go to his house. Tell him you're
sorry, then you'll be able to sleep
This has nothing to do
with that stupid pillow!
I'm not going to his house, Ok?
- He walked away from me
- No, you made him walk away
What do you know? You weren't even there
I've known you for 30 years
I know that you would
never see this through
I know that you don't trust people
You and your grandmother, crazy pants.
She's been engaged to Arthur for how long?
She's never going to marry him. Just
like you would never stay with Stan
- Ok, Mona!
- No wonder you got a sperm donor
He's the perfect boyfriend.
He'll never let you down
You know, I used a sperm donor
because I wanted a baby
Because I wanted a family
Because Nana is not going to live forever
And then I'll just be me
Go home, ok? I don't need you here
I need my pillow
I'm sorry... that was too far.
Yeah, that was too far.
But you know I'm right.
Stop talking. My pillow doesn't talk
it just lies there and shuts up.
Don't beg, Nuts
My God, you're stubborn
Knock, knock. Who's ready to celebrate?
Oh, Mona, I'm so glad you're here
cut now I can tell both of you together.
- I'm getting married
- What?!
Next weekend.
We finally decided to do it
My God!
It finally hit me. This
man loves me and I love him
What the hell am I waiting for?
I have you to thank it, Zoe.
Just seeing you and Stan
together, how happy you are
You know, the way you just thrown caution
into the wind and decided to go for it
I want some of that too
- What?
- Stan and I broke up
- He said that babies weren't his
- He didn't mean to say it
- Tell her the whole story
- He said it
And if he said it, he thinks it, and if
he thinks it, he feels it,
And if he feels it what choice do I have?
Zoe, you know that's not true. Your
just looking for another way to back out
- Thank you
- I'm not going to do this
This man has chosen to be with you
and raise your kids as his own
You're just going to throw it all
away for some stupid word choice?
- Look at you
- I'm worried about you
- No, don't... don't worry
I'm great. I'm great.
I'm just emotional
Come on, let me just
finish your makeup
Honey, you don't always
have to be so strong
You know, I know you learned
it me but it's no good
- What does it get you?
- It means that I take care of myself
- Just like you always did
- No, Arthur takes care of me
He's been taking care
of me for 22 years
I just don't want to admit it
Zoe, stop pushing people away
- I don't want to talk this, ok?
- Listen to me, Zoe
You'll never have a healthy relationship
Stan or any other man
if you don't. You have
to learn to trust people
- What is that?
- It's your custom stroller
The Twin X Torpedo
- I didn't order this
- Your husband did... or your boyfriend.
- I don't know exactly what is your relationship is?
- Stan?
- When did he do that?
- About a month ago
You don't like? Shit!
We worked really hard on this one
He wasn't going to leave, was he?
I'm not really sure what
is happening here
We got to go get him
What? I'm getting married in 20 minutes
Weddings never start on time
We can't be late, he's 93 years old
Stop it.
Pick up!
I'm going to hurl that thing into
the fucking holy water
Ah, is this new? The Zoe?
Yeah, yes, it's the first
week it’s been out
Can I have a sample? What's it like?
It's stubborn, overly
suspicious and distrustful of men
- This song is taking forever
- This song is never going to be over
What time is it people?
That's right, its conga time
Everybody, get out there and
check those titanium hips
Conga time!
...we need to talk like two seconds.
I've been thinking...
- We really need to go, come on
- We have to go
Don't seem real...
- Please, get me out of here
- Can't find any exit signs
- behind the tub of flowers
- I mean, who knew the Congo was this much fun
~ She drives me crazy and I can't help myself ~
I have rhythm all of a sudden
- Oh shit!
- Why is the floor wet?
Damn it, not again
- No, not me
- Not me
I think my water just broke!
What? ... Oh!
Baby time!
Just stop it, stop it
What can we do for you, darling?
- This dress is tight
- I can do it
If you just want to let me... grab the strap ...
- Fingernails!
- Can we make a pit stop?
- You can't park in here!
- Ok, move it, out of the way. Lady with a baby
- Are you going to leave it there?
- Zoe, what's going on?
- Your muffin suck ass!
- I must be going out of my mind
What are you doing here?
I'm trying to call you and doing the
conga, my dress is falling
and when they say labour is
painful, they're not kidding.
- It really hurts
- You're in labour?
But the stroller came in,
it's so beautiful
God, that hurts!
- Why didn't you pick up your phone?
- Wait what?
I called you a hundred times.
I wanted you at the wedding
- What wedding?
- It was so beautiful
and then it wasn't... it was
people slipping everywhere
Oh God, I hope nobody
got hurt
Ok, you're not making any sense
But that's just it,
everything make sense
All of a sudden everything is
just so... crystal clear.
And the thing that's the clearest
is that I am so madly, deeply
and completely in love with you. I can't
imagine spending another minute apart.
Zoe, after all this time
you come in here and expect ...
I got to go to the hospital.
Move it, move it. Get the lead out.
- Zoe, wait up!
- Lets go, let’s go, let’s go
Listen to me, how do I know when things
gets tough you won't just run away again?
You know? I can’t handle it,
you broke my heart...
you completely destroyed me.
You destroyed me too. It's not
like this has been easy for me
Son of a ...!
Just, uh, breathe through it.
It's going to be ok.
Don't you tell me it's going to be ok!
You don't know it's going to be ok.
I'm so scared!
- It is going to be ok!
- Let's try to refrain from yelling at the patients?
I'm not yelling! I'm just
try to get her to see my point!
Sounds like yelling to me.
What's it going to take for you to
believe that I'm here forever?
You had to see a stupid stroller?
What about the fact I've been to every
doctors appointment with you?
I picked out names with you
I saved this from the
very first day we met
It's the one that was tails up and you
flipped it to heads
I've kept it this whole time
And it's brought me the
most incredible luck
I can't believe you kept that
What about the fact that like it or not
I'll be here holding your hand through this?
What about the fact that I'm going to be
here when these babies are born?
Because I love their mommy
And what I want more than
anything else in this world
is to be their daddy
But you have to promise me
that from now on you'll
believe me when I say I'm in
And I'm not going anywhere
Can you do that?
Can you?
Yes
- Okay
- Alright, now push. Time to push.
Breathe, breathe
Remember my three rules:
No touch, no talk,
and no eye contact
while the dog's nose is busy
analyzing our energy
and all the different scents on our body
This sniffing can last from
3 seconds to 1 minute
It's important not to interrupt the dog while
she's intent on accomplishing this ritual
You know, one day... I'm going to tell
you girls a story of your mommy and me.
She should write a book about that one.
Talk about a best-seller
Come here
That's nice
It was a battle but
they finally fell asleep
Penny had a poop...
Don't talk about Penny's poop
when I'm about to kiss you.
It's perfect. You know
what the best part is?
We can stop in for lunch every single day.
- Alright, they’re here!
- Speech... speech!
- Hey!
- Okay, thank you, um, wow!
Thank you all for coming
This had been a dream me
for a long time
I need to thank one person for
giving me the courage to do it
- To Zoe
- To Zoe!
From the moment you stole my cab
From the day you dissede
me at the farmers market
I have been totally and
completely under your spell
I love you
And you've made me the
happiest man alive
It was my cab
So, come over here for a minute
- Givme that
- What?
Since we do everything
backwards and in hyper speed
I was wondered if we could
do what naturally follows
having twins girls together
Holly shit!
Will you marry me?
- Yes
- Yeah!
- I can't believe it
- I know
- Did we really just get engaged?
- Yes we did
Soon you will be my wife
Stan?