Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Made By Chebo
Watch full movies online for free at www.awooh.com
The Next Three Days
Take me to the hospital, please!
I can not breathe.
Three years
You know something? If you have the spirit
you never talk nonsense.
Give me the costs.
You know a woman should not
you have never worked for another woman.
- How can you say something like that?
- Because they are constantly threatened.
Especially if she is beautiful
and the other is ugly.
Wonderful! And your leader
He never threatened not?
Ever, and you know why?
Because her man.
Erythema, please shortest you and me.
I just want to go home
and kiss my baby. My dear ...
See, you really need to keep the names mentioned
you have a child, and we have not.
- What I meant.
- Yes, but none of these words ...
Do not apologize, it's genetic.
Women are in a tournament continues.
That's why you have problems with your boss.
- Because it's a woman.
- Exactly.
Women should work with men,
men and women. Is the solution.
- And men with men?
- And back and a. They are common Nuith it.
- You do not want to go?
- You do not want something to drink?
May we be a force.
- Double, right?
- Men can do amazing things.
And I'm like, I know. But even if I
and does the job for me.
There really agree with you.
Good Night, Mick.
- You are a bad mood.
- He's right, my brothers!
I prefer to work and
with you than with her.
Very nice!
And I prefer to work with him.
- Do you prefer to "work" with John?
- No, it's not convenient Thi?
No! Why I would not mind
your sexual innuendo bit?
- What happened to you this evening?
- You mean something?
If you do advances
My husband against me?
Lara, if wants him and your husband
him and have a look and a.
- How? Maybe if you show her breasts and more.
- You know that's your problem?
My problem is that you have breasts
above in mind!
They are huge! It
- Maybe if you had another brain!
- Honey, calm down!
- Good night, Brother Bear!
- Good night!
- He is a liar.
- Do not try to calm me down!
I did not even
his dentist.
Shut up!
Maybe you do not know
how to write "anesthetist."
- This woman is a crook.
- I went to his party, stupid!
I think he wanted to give me
like last time.
Ithier vain illusions. Not even
Thi has not made sexual advances.
- I do not wear it!
- I understand. I'm serious! I know how it is
People like him
would be allowed to transact orally.
You're a moron!
You put on your seat, trying to stay calm
and "stuff" you hit on the forehead ...
Rendezvous next weekend.
- Okay.
- Bye!
- Good night!
Damn!
- You say you started.
- Give it up!
- Super!
- A small resort apropiaþi.
You can not do this every morning.
It is downright ordinary.
Come zâmbiþi!
Only until they reach age 18 and older.
- A gift.
- Splendid!
- What is it?
- Thi-s do not brush their teeth.
Periuþa teeth that wash Ithier
in 30 seconds.
Like brushing my teeth.
Do not listen to what mama said, mind.
- When multiple classes of arrival?
- Three hours.
But we need to correct certain documents.
We can help you Luke?
After yesterday, you probably have remained
unemployed. He and so ...
You think I exaggerate
when I told him that a cow?
I think I'm happy to head
This frank exchange of opinions.
- Have you called your father?
- When?
Yesterday, on his birthday.
Yes, I sent a bouquet of roses
and a map made by my mânuþa.
And I finished the sewing
and coverage.
You're impossible.
You've seen what we've received this year
my birthday? I get a grunt.
My mother said: "In many years, baby!"
and my father ...
It was the happiest moment of my life.
They gave me tears, nothing else.
Have you ever thought that someone should
to be more mature in such situations?
I want to tell you that memory
the custody hearing.
How it all the time nannies and mother you dad.
Yes? "You'll remember that?
You how you feel when Luke
will grow and will not call you on your birthday?
- Now try to divide us.
- I give up!
And now, you give up.
Are you ready?
They line up.
Now they are aligned.
You tell me when you start.
Give it up!
Open it!
- Police! Your wife is stopped.
- Why stop?
- Is accused of murder.
- Hey, hey! Little station!
- Laura Brennan?
- If you touch me one time, you under arrest!
Stay there!
- Keep the place!
- This is my house!
- Lara Brennan?
- Yes!
Can I ask you something?
You are arrested for murder
Gesas Elizabeth.
- Calm down!
- I want to take my baby!
- Sir, what are you doing? Put him and handcuff them!
- But what is happening here?
- Mom!
- John!
Honey, I am committed to a lawyer.
- It's okay, baby! It does not matter!
- Do not touch me!
Mom!
Luke! It does not matter!
It does not matter!
Dad! Dad!
- Papa!
- What? What happened?
You can sleep here
as long as you stay on your side of the bed.
We understood?
And mecherule!
I do not know why I always fooled.
Or maybe, I pretend I do not know.
Hey!
Lie. Sleep.
- Sam is your friend, you do?
- When it comes to food, not really.
- Ithier steal food?
- No.
- He spoke ill of Mom?
- Yes.
- Have you beaten?
Well.
- Where did you beat?
- On the playground.
- Wow! I think it hurts.
- Yes.
Wait a bit, and children.
It's a toy.
Thank you!
Mânuþa Give me that,
her.
Do not worry about me and inuþã,
retrieve it later.
Hello!
Hey, baby!
N-Mom a kiss?
- Come on, kiss her mother.
- Angry, my mother a kiss.
- Thi-Daddy read my letters?
- Every night at bedtime.
Yes?
How nice! He and Miro
Today, what you build?
Build your own castle?
What's this?
A castle gate?
I was afraid to go to school?
No. I went to class, and not embraced
and even turned his head to greet me.
Look at his friends!
Bãncuþa and years.
- When you how was your first day?
- Super!
Half of the class
did not sleep, you know.
- I talked to your mother.
- When it comes to see me?
He is busy with her business.
He and so ...
I have been a few years
are safe and I'll come here.
- Have you heard anything?
- About the call?
Yes, but do not say anything.
Bring Thi remember what Meyer says.
- Do not ...
- It could take several months
until a court decides.
I saw this woman. He was there.
He had to disappear and how, suddenly.
- Meyer will find another investigator.
- And the clothes in my bag agatha.
I heard that I skipped a button
to be blind not to find it.
We re-evaluate all the evidence.
It's great!
Because we are not yet faliþi.
- We can cope.
- Minds all the time.
But you are very beautiful.
Sorry!
- You do me a favor?
- I do not know, are very busy.
I want to run
for the post of governor.
I think I can help.
Maybe you're successful and change the rules
conjugal visits,
because I do not know if more
about 20 years.
Hey!
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Everything will be fine. I promise!
You think he wants
you ever kiss me?
Stand up, please.
Leap and Ah!
You're next.
Luke! Let's go.
We'll be late.
- Did you have fun?
- Yes.
It's a little crazy about that girl you?
Have to go, Carrie!
No!
Read what you write there.
We must make a decision ...
What happens if they find
Women who left the parking lot?
Appeal was dismissed.
- We can not present other evidence.
- It was a holdup!
And if I use a credit card
we can say that.
Sorry.
It's crazy!
All Rights Reserved.
So we have no choice.
All you can do is call
Supreme Court, and you?
John, over the past 30 years, the Supreme Court
has not even solved a murder case.
No decent lawyer
not one to call.
Thus, A and all I have to do
ask a lawyer "indecent."
It would be very difficult to find.
I'll handle this.
- But I want to do something for me and you.
- What?
I want to analyze samples,
but remember that your wife Lara.
We have seen evidence, Meyer.
Thi not to judge the criminals
or innocent, but to analyze the samples.
An officer saw her
when he left the scene,
victim had blood on his clothes
and fingerprints on murder weapon ...
I took it out for dinner in town!
How could you do
after killing someone?
- Must be a psychopath!
- And the fight ...
- Lara is not psycho!
- Fight in the office?
- Everyone is and fight with their heads!
- But that ended with a crime.
There and then, you say you do not think
I never that innocent?
- How can you say something like that?
- What do you mean?
I want to say that no matter what we believe
Lara was a child to escape from the cavity!
You do not know how I hate to say it.
You will find someone else
for appeal.
John. John!
Be serious! John!
John!
For the love of God!
Come.
See for Scouting.
Let's hug eZi Peng
Micuþul Peng,
Kiki and Opossumy.
With lots and lots of love, Mom.
You do not want to write about us?
- I have 25 cents?
- To give you 25 cents?
Yes, but you allowed them to spend it all.
Where is the remote that me and mom
We pick you up when you were a baby and you.
- Can I take them all?
- Sure.
My wife, Lara Brennan
was sent here.
B-R-E-N-N-A-N. You have to see!
- Sorry!
- Lara! Lara!
You can not go there!
- No you do here!
- Turn it up! Come back!
- What do you do, sir?
- Lara!
- Come here!
- Sir!
- But what is happening here?
My wife tried to commit suicide!
He was brought here. You have to see, please!
- It is allowed to receive visitors.
- Why the Emergency Room?
- He was transferred to the prison.
- Only two minutes, please!
Two minutes.
Well.
Thank you.
Two minutes.
"Life and Adventures of Don Quixote."
What's this?
About the fact that faith in the virtue
But it is more important than virtue?
Yes, it says in the book.
But what is it?
It could be about
Ithier soul-destroying rational thought.
Or the triumph iraþionalitãþii
and the power that lies within her.
We lose a lot of time
try to organize the world.
Manufacturing by clocks, calendars,
weather forecasting.
What part of our lives
is really under our control?
What happens if we choose to run
facing the reality that surrounds us?
Prisons GUIDE
It would be a total madness.
What would be probably better
a life full of hopelessness.
BEYOND THE WALLS
Damon Pennington
This is a course they need people
than to be free, regardless of cost.
For another teacher
i was put on the spot "Butterfly".
Listen, you've missed
seven times in prison.
And what do you want to know?
How have you managed to escape when
does anyone else managed this?
I took courage and a little luck.
All prisons in the world
"Weaknesses".
Everyone has a key.
You only have one finds you.
How did you do?
I looked closely. Especially when things
who were not part of daily routine.
The guards are common Nuith
and doing these things every day.
And they make mistakes, what happens.
When you see this, you must be prepared.
You need to have everything well prepared plan
even before you decide to escape.
Escape is a breeze,
the hardest part is to remain free.
You need to know where to go
and how.
Need to know when they plan
to take, how and where.
- How on earth can you find these things?
- You pay someone who knows.
And if the prison is very important
is in the province or city.
He is in town.
- How are you?
- From Pittsburgh.
Pittsburgh is a city difficult,
with many bridges and tunnels
which can be easily blocked.
Once they received a call
Police may close the downtown
and to isolate it completely in 15 minutes.
How can I be so for exacþi?
In the wake of 9 / 11
Homeland Security has decided that each city
to have a safety plan:
downtown Pittsburgh, Philadelphia, Boston,
Minneapolis to close in 15 minutes.
They can become "dead zones"
within 10 minutes.
And 35 minutes each border point
between states will be guarded by police
and all secondary roads will be closed.
If you do not take a picture with you,
Your description will be detailed.
- And if I do not fit in 30 minutes?
- Then, you teach.
Because the site will draw on
you and those who are with you.
Stay away from stations
and bus stations.
Look for local airports.
Escape to another state.
The second thing: identity.
It is easy to obtain false documents,
but it is difficult to obtain documents
you can pass control of the airport.
Need a passport book
management and social insurance.
If you rent a car
Find a place where you can pay in cash.
Will check the books of credit and thus,
for acts uses a real name.
The third thing: the destination.
You must go to a place
not attract American tourists.
Remember to Yemen
and I know what I mean.
Second, money.
You need a truck of money.
All hotels are expensive,
travel information.
For how much money do I need?
Both come to tell you how
at least five or six years.
If you're short of money, short of friends.
But before you do something, you must
ask if you are able to do so.
You can get to say goodbye to parents
because I never see more.
Can you kill a guard, you can thi
abandon your child in a gas station
or if you are slammed on the ground a little old lady
Nice that stands in your way Thi?
Because if you want to do
things, he and the future.
And if you're not in this state
does not start, because someone will be killed.
What is your sin?
I willingly surrendered.
I never thought I supported him to find
and waits on the threshold of the door of the bedroom.
So how much money you have in your pocket?
Good luck!
3 months
All prisons in the world have "weaknesses".
Everyone has a key.
You only have one finds you.
How did you do?
I looked closely. Especially when things
who were not part of daily routine.
In the left Allegheny County Jail's.
The world's biggest prison.
There were three attempts to escape
but they paid for it with life.
E. Right ..
"The first landing by turning
this pillar to provide housing,
a sort of niche, on a stage wide and about
further, so as to adapt ... "
LIFT
25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30.
Okay?
Second, money.
You need a truck of money.
All hotels are expensive,
travel information.
Continue to select image
and the magic lasso tool "that you can do
dramatic changes.
Hey!
Identity.
It is easy to obtain false documents,
but it is difficult to obtain documents
you can pass control of the airport.
- Oxycodone.
- $ 10 each.
Or 5-40.
- Hey, I need someone passports.
- Get out of here, man!
Gone!
Very well, my boy?
For passports
should you pay for vans.
- I think I can do.
- You know where I Hotel Lafayette?
Ave E Street. Go
enters the bar and asks the Harv.
- You like the name?
- Tell him I sent you Moussa.
Harv? I'm looking Harv.
- You're Harv?
- Yes.
- Moussa told me to look for you.
- He sent you? And what do you want?
Three passports, driver's license
and a true social insurance.
Where does the Musa you know?
Takes care of my little boy.
Well. Follow me.
- Do you have pictures of you?
- Yes.
- How?
- $ 1500.
If you see you again,
I'll put an eye.
- God! What happened?
- It was stupid. I fell off my bike.
The thing that is in the garage for bikes
Our more than three years?
- But ...
- The head Thi Let's back.
Someone made a joke
Lara sore.
So do it now, on all his bath
those who believe that Lara is guilty?
- What does this mean?
- It is important that you think.
- Not what people think.
- Really? Do you really think, mother?
- Why do you argue?
- Come on, baby, go.
- Where do you want to check?
- Why do this?
No reason. In my shit
I really thought that people who love
I really think she is innocent.
It was my mistake.
Stop!
Go fuck her grandmother.
Come.
Evil face?
A little.
You hit and you?
No, I did not hit.
It's a good thing.
That's okay, baby?
Looking for someone to make me someone acts:
passports, social insurance.
- Yes?
- I was there at the bar, I know what you do.
I am deaf, dumb!
But I can lip-read what you say.
- What do you need?
- For passports.
For a driver's license
and social insurance of a real person.
- 3700 dollars.
- Too much.
There are a lot if you do not.
I need pictures
and $ 1,000 in advance.
- Thi make Wednesday.
- Hey, do not bring them here.
I do not want you here.
Rendezvous in the parking lot to Don.
Eckert Street. Under the bridge at 14:00.
If you are not there on time, get out.
Place your thumb there.
- Thanks. That's all I needed.
- Thanks.
We can give you a moment?
- Safety glasses?
- Yes.
Still asleep when I read.
- When?
- When we read Luke.
Anyway ready!
Sãrãcuþul you!
How could you have injuries like that?
Without my wife I feel useless.
Not a bike, they can no longer walk.
I am sorry that we sell the house.
I'll know where
imagine that you are.
Close your eyes and see Luke
in her room
and on the sofa near the window ...
I'll know where
imagine that you are.
Show me how to download it.
Hello! I'm John.
Luke is not feeling too well.
I'll try and take him home, right?
I would go to Carl for me
rate at 14:30.
Thank you!
Are not you going to answer
This phone crazy?
You gotta go!
I need them.
Have you noticed this kind of policeman?
Give me money!
Ithier as you want.
You ruin everything.
Hello, Mr. Brennan.
I show you how to make a key
to open all doors.
Is called the cocoa leaf keys. "
You have to find a key that corresponds to
where you want and lock open.
I have a door key
the entry into force and my
but I just changed all the locks
I can keep them open.
The first thing you need to do,
Attach it to key in a vise,
you take a cell
and all his teeth piliþi equality
so that the key to enter
easy to block.
The key will push our
bolþurile hub of this lock, unlock.
And we will turn key
and open the door to a.
- Here.
- Get your hands off her!
You want me to do my job?
So, where were you?
Somewhere in the middle.
Towards the middle.
Can you show me where were you?
That's me. It's there.
So, is that you are not.
One who stands near the elevators.
No, no.
I was somewhere around here.
Tell me you want one thousand
what happens?
Thiele I tell you?
Yes.
You know what a cocoa leaf keys?
No, sorry.
If that was the key to your
think you should get it
what will happen to your children
if both parents are in prison.
KEY?
Dad!
I'm coming.
Yes.
Well.
So I arrested his wife,
and now accuses him threw up?
Q and the house and sell and the buyer a.
The market from here?
It's a lucky man.
Now we can return
The police in the section?
Now understand why you left
single so long.
Dad, give me cookies?
- Thi-hungry? Want a sandwich?
- No.
Here.
Carrie!
Sorry.
any planning in advance.
Nicole.
- I remember ...
- Really?
I remember your daughter.
It is hard to forget.
- Luke had to bring this home.
- That his father is forgetful.
It is an invitation to a party
Carrie birthday.
Please come.
I would like your wife.
It can not come.
It's complicated.
I understand.
And that's just me.
Carrie, go, go.
We're going to eat something.
Come with us and you?
- No. I do not know. We are a little ...
- Occupation?
Come on, I stayed connected
cake.
It is true. Especially
which were made myself.
And I learned how to pack.
Come on, Luke.
Ithier then divide free time with Luke?
No. Me and Luke are
always together.
Wow!
And I sincerely hope that she and
to be here with him.
Lara e. ..
Even without this.
I guess it's priorities, is not it?
No, not about that.
E jail.
- I said that too many people.
- I understand.
He is innocent.
I killed a woman on it.
Well.
I'm sure she did not kill her.
I think it would be better to go home.
Well.
Thank you for the invitation.
We'll try to come.
- It would be great.
- Bye.
- Luke
- Bye!
Come.
Carrie, go!
Diabetes Complications
Hyperkalemia - an abnormal increase
level of potassium in the blood
How to break an MA and INA
HOW TO OPEN A MA and INA
With a tennis ball
GLUCOSE
- Hello!
What happened?
What?
No!
I can not move without you announce.
Three days are not sufficient.
I was there when I filed the appeal.
I knew that I go to jail.
LAST 3 DAYS
Can not wait two weeks.
We must resolve by tomorrow.
The title is not very clear.
We can not ...
- How can I give?
- Nothing!
- What research here?
- I hours.
Be good, yes?
Thank you.
Shit!
- You happened to you?
- What are you doing? He was killing us!
- I'm sorry!
- You're crazy! Do not forget where you going?
Get away!
Leave us alone!
Hello!
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- There was something wrong with Luke?
- No.
What?
I asked Meyer to do something
do you get out of here.
I said I would be very difficult
for us to travel so much,
and Luke and which must have enough problems
at school, what he really
because I spent
enough time with him.
- I spent enough time with him?
- No.
You never dealt fairly by him?
Jesus! John.
This time around, even exaggerating.
Luke welcomes you because the weights
his mother is in prison for murder,
not because his father
I spent enough time with him.
Your father was right. You are life
in a different world from ours.
It is good that you say you
and you in business.
- I live in the world, Lara?
- I do not know John, but not true.
I'll spend the rest of my life here
and you want to believe
I do not know this fantasy in which he did not ...
It is everything okay?
Yes. Sorry!
And now, with a face that time on,
I want you for your leaves.
What do you want to do
You want to make you feel better?
I understand!
- Sorry.
- Ithier apologize?
- You are a true gem!
- What do you want me, Lara?
What I want from you?
Nothing. Already you're too perfect!
You never asked me
so I did.
- If we really killed.
- Because I know I killed you.
Then, you and Eli.
I'm done.
Mr. President, did you leave the station there.
Sir!
- What?
- Shut up!
I do not care what you say and how you say it.
I do not think you did something like that.
I do not believe it.
I know who you are.
I promise you that ...
one to tell you not to spend life and a.
Shut up!
- What happened to my merchandise?
- I know you?
How dare I not Trimithi?
Move as you! Back!
Back!
- This time both of them!
- Shoot the dog!
- Take your dog here!
- If your dog shoot, kill!
- Police want to come here, asshole!
- Good idea!
- Take the dog out of here!
- That he was shot!
Paint it!
- Enter and you there!
- I'm not going there!
Go ahead!
Go! Go there!
Close!
Close with the!
- Move!
- You're a dead man!
- I have done nothing!
- Did you bring me here!
I never did!
Put your knees!
Down!
Where are the prices?
Here. I hope to be helpful.
- Where are the others?
- Here, take them to everyone.
- Where the money Ithier different?
- Wait until I give you money, yes.
- I shot C!
- You can not pull that not even a dog.
- We kill them both!
- No, I'll kill you both!
- Give them money!
- Shut up, zdreanþã!
Give them money!
Jesus! you stop!
See?
You are not able to kill me.
That's all you can do?
Go home. I'll come get you
and I'll kill you.
Waste and your kindness of spirit.
Yes, good things.
Contains a large amount of alcohol.
- What do you do, give me fire?
- Yes.
- That I will do.
- Jesus Christ!
This is a drug lab, you idiot!
No, it was.
- Phooey!
- Where is the money?
My baby is upstairs!
Arise! Arise!
Please!
Let me go! Please!
Anyone there?
Do not leave me here!
I do not want to die here!
Please!
Take me to the hospital, please!
I can not breathe!
Please!
Give yourself a hand.
- What have we here?
- A strange miracle.
The basement is a drug lab,
and the house is still standing.
- Must be a crater there.
- We know who is the victim?
Alex Gaidar. He was known to history
violence and drug trafficking.
Can a child?
His neighbor said his wife left him
last year. Once there, surprise!
Blood that here ...
to know who owns it?
No, but it seems that someone who was bleeding
it out through the back door,
and in District 3, on a bench next to the passage
we found a victim who was shot and how much.
- I came to pick up Luke.
- Your son is asleep.
Yes, we got Luke to take him home.
John!
- You okay?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Hey, chicken and the city.
Wake up, you go home.
- How do you say?
- Thanks, Mom!
Go fuck her grandmother.
- I'm too tired to give them more kisses.
- Baby!
There is no problem.
O give me many kisses
next week.
We want to take the Harvest Festival
Kutztown, see Clydesdale cãluþii.
- Goodbye!
- Bye!
Bye!
Hey!
- Bye, Dad.
- Bye!
Goodbye!
- Bye, Mom!
- Bye!
- At bãtrâneþe become sentimental.
- Yes, the so-i.
Me and someone serves me a coffee?
Hey, idioþilor!
Can I take it and him?
No, baby.
Everything that goes in the backpack.
- But in your pockets?
- Or in the pocket.
Hello!
Hello?
Hey, chicken and the city!
I'll be back soon, yes?
Well.
Baby.
A and a.
- You okay?
- Yes.
See where spending occurs.
Yield 922, street.
What would you say?
Do you agree?
Here we go.
Stop all models
The Prius did in 2004-2009.
What's killer and that
driving a Prius?
A very responsible
socially?
The city has recorded more than a thousand
Prius and sites throughout the state, about seven miles.
How many have been recorded
on behalf of criminals?
The statewide, six. Four crook
evazioni're or a rapist and murderer.
- Start with the murderer.
- Is in jail for the rest of life.
The rapist is free.
it finds.
- Hi!
- Hello!
- Glad to see you.
- And us.
- Hi, Luke.
- It's a pony.
Gifts are packed.
You know the party starts
11:00, you?
Really? Read more carefully
what is written on invitation.
There is no problem. Why do not you
give her gift to Carrie?
- I think you could help me.
- Actually, I must go. I have something to do.
Sorry.
Then you will see later.
Thank you very much.
Hey ...
Is the phone number
the jacket of my parents,
the top pocket of his jacket.
Where the end.
No problem.
The rapist is in a wheelchair.
I do not know if it was karma or bad luck.
Criminal ...
Where is incarcerated?
In state prison,
here in town.
She has a husband or an adult child
I could drive a car?
- Yes. What?
- Lara Brennan blood tests.
Get me to the lab.
You angry against someone, it is clear.
- Busy, try again.
- No.
Call the ambulance, one to go
University Hospital. Appointment there.
All Rights Reserved. Thank you.
- Her husband is a teacher.
- You know the address where she lives?
There is no car in the garage.
Want to ask a warrant?
Yes.
Do you in the office!
Lara Brennan is transferred
University Hospital.
- Right now?
- Yes.
Call them and tell them ambulance escort.
Tell them that we meet in hospital
in 10 minutes.
Yes! Yes, we agree.
Location: it's not serious.
There is no problem, sir.
The so-us.
- Hands Up!
- John!
Give me the phone.
- What are you doing here, John?
- Hold your hands up!
- John! What are you doing here?
- Let the handcuffs.
Sit!
John stops you!
Sit down with the front wall.
Washing police at the entrance waiting for you ...
- He just said that ...
- Do not stop at traffic lights.
Tie his hands and feet
close as you can.
If you leave out of here with him
I'll kill you both.
- Stop the silence Thi!
- John, he's right.
Listen to him. You will die here.
Why do this?
Because we have no other choice!
- Dress up!
- No, not really!
- Dress up.
- No!
- Now!
Well.
Tell your son.
Tell him you do not want to live.
- It's Where?
- You wait.
- You tell him you do not want to live?
- Why do this to me?
Click "send".
Tell him that I return without you.
- John ...
- You think you can come back to me, Lara?
Call him. Tell anyone who has not
and mom and dad do not come back!
Jesus! John ...
You're an idiot.
I'm Dr. Lifson.
I have a patient who was transferred
a prison, Lara Brennan.
Yes, I used initially
20 units of insulin.
Security!
Out! Exit the elevator!
Back!
- Hey, do not be silly.
- Back!
We have people at each exit, John.
You'll both be shot and move the
If you try to go.
- Press the button!
- Sit there!
- John, no!
- Where are the stairs?
- Il.
Look in the parking lot of a man
and a woman in white coats!
- Please, please ...
- Everything will be fine.
Look at me. Look at me!
Everything will be fine. Do what you say
and they tell you and everything will be fine.
Lara! Show below Thi dress.
It does not matter.
You stay here.
- Guard and your door!
- Okay.
Stop!
Shit!
Someone at the entrance?
Hey, listen!
Do not look.
Run!
Here!
Move as you!
Get away!
Over here!
- Look around you!
- Detach Thi hair.
Phooey!
Harris there.
Faster!
Harris, are the underground!
- Harris, in the subway!
- I understand.
I'm on the platform!
lockout stations from all directions.
Anunþaþi authorities.
Turn off all trains!
Stay here.
Attention, be-close the doors!
Move! Police!
I want to stop the train
with 47 number.
Switch it up!
Hold on to me.
Hey, kid! Hold on tight.
- Is the red traffic lights!
- Hold on!
Red E u!
Lock City. All stations
and bus stations.
You send them the description of the State Police.
I understand!
- How old is your child?
- Six.
To find out where it is
- Why do not you say?
- You stopped.
Thi and I had personal things.
You have a makeup kit,
creams, tooth periuþã ...
Everything you've got there were old.
Hope and one that should be taken.
Bring Thi remember where you saw it.
Would you guess that escaped're
prison?
Wait a bit.
- Hello.
- Good. I came for my son.
Not yet returned.
- How to return?
- The zoo.
Part of the zoo.
About an hour would have to return.
Can you expect if you want.
No. Thank you.
What happened?
When Luke?
- Where is he? When Luke?
- It is a party.
What party?
You said it is a party.
I could be wrong.
The went to the zoo.
Destination.
Who?
Destination: Zoo.
Estimated time until the destination:
17 minutes.
Carrie mother. Nicole.
Ask neighbors if they noticed
something strange in recent days.
It does not matter. I have no words to say thank you
because you took care of him.
We really enjoyed it.
Hello!
And I'll stay here, OK?
Sure.
Traffic is blocked until the customs declaration.
The city center and for worse.
Police blocked all stations
and checks on all his travels and
însoþitorii them, as well as luggage ...
John!
... I checked all the cars ...
What do we do?
We go to the station.
- Station in the car.
- Okay.
Sir, I am sorry that the post late,
but I told them to stop all the washing machines.
Only those in which the
a couple with one child.
Mr. Speaker, I know why ...
Yes, sir.
Are you sure that's enough
$ 20?
A ticket to Buffalo
it costs three times more.
Yes. It's a way to save money.
Go and send their images in all countries,
bus stations and airports,
a radius of 500 km.
So in Ohio, Maryland, West Virginia
New York, New Jersey,
Virginia, Michigan, Kentucky and Indiana?
You know the direction
will, isteaþo?
- Goodbye!
- Thank you again!
- And you want to see the map?
- Only if you tell me where I am.
You lucky.
Sorry.
This coffee you appointed?
How many airports are in Ontario and Quebec?
Let a little sun slowly
And start counting?
On how long the road
few have all kinds of baggage.
What?
Travel too far.
And now, you just check?
You know how many times we lost baggage?
You have tickets here
and boarding passes.
Thank you.
I found the parents.
Station there.
So you've decided plimbaþi all day?
George wanted to see the leaves on the trees.
N-you have no idea
where they went, you?
Thi-I said,
I never talked about it.
Hey!
I'll handle this.
Come on, Luke.
Hello!
I think you can use a vacation.
Thank you.
Too bad you did not find him any more.
Yes. I would love to
to know what it is.
I searched all the sights,
but I found nothing.
- It's the presidential palace.
- What?
They aired on CNN and when it was the collapse
the earthquake.
- I know where they went.
- Me and my show.
Open the door!
And I'll take a look!
Let's go!
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen.
Yet nobody gets up on the plan.
Sorry!
Excuse me, please!
Sorry, nobody on the flight
who fit this description.
Not at all. I'm here.
You have pictures?
We have their pictures
but not in this plan.
There are flights to Haiti and other
tonight?
There are no other flights, sir.
There are no other flights.
May want something?
No.
No, thank you.
It started to rain.
I'll tell the FBI.
Have you wondered why I find
this bag and others not?
Captain of the lights
seatbelts.
Flight to Caracas, Venezuela, in the evening
it takes 5 hours and 15 minutes.
If you're sitting on a chair, Captain
asks you to put seat belts.
- This guy is a teacher.
- In a college.
- It heard how he jumped on a button.
- Huh?
It heard how he jumped on a button.
- It was raining when we investigated the crime scene?
- Three years ago? Why are you here?
Behave like a real cop.
Take the other side.
You're crazy.
- Ready?
- Yes.
- You can call?
You really believed that we find it for you?
Made By Chebo
Watch full movies online for free at www.awooh.com
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org