Life is
a spinning wheel, it has been said.
With each spoke,
a tale to be told.
So keep silence
along the banks,
and I will tell you
one ofthese tales.
A story as enchanting
as the jungle itself.
It is about pride
and powerand treasure...
and about fangs
and claws and talons.
But mostly, it is about love.
My new command was
at the edge of the world,
surrounded by
a million miles ofjungle.
With me was my daughter, Katherine,
whom everyone called Kitty.
Leading us was an Indian guide...
whose son was called Mowgli.
From the moment they were born,
Mowgli and Kitty had a common bond,
for both oftheir mothers had left
this world while bringing them into it.
Also with us was my good friend,
Dr.Julius Plumford,
who was to be oursurgeon.
Oh, look atthat.
- Damned elephant!
Pullyourselftogether!
Shere Khan.
-All right.That's enough.
That's enough!
I say, could somebody
possibly grab this elephant?
Sorry to botheryou.
-And as surely as
a tiger named Shere Khan...
was to be the jungle's
royal keeper,
Mowgli was destined
to become its lord.
-Well done, Mowgli.
Buldeo, what on earth's going on?
-Shere Khan!
He's returning!
-Shere? Atiger?
-Shere Khan, king oftigers!
He's angry because these men with
their guns have gone into his jungle...
and killed more
than they can eat.
What is a tiger caring,
a few animals here orthere?
Would you allow someone to break
into your house and stealyourfood?
-These three broke the jungle law.
Shere Khan knows it.
We best beware.
All right.
What is this?
Baloo.
-And in English?
- Bear.
Good.
I'll betyou can't tell me
what this is.
Bagheera.
Panther?
Very good.
And who do you think this is?
-That's me!
-You? Shere Khan?
The holy man say I'm halfa tiger.
You are half a tiger?
He saywhen I see Shere Khan
and show no fear,
then I be whole tiger.
Where did you see
this holy man, Mowgli?
In my dreams.
No.
Help!
Tiger.! Tigerattack.!
Geoffrey,what in God's name
is going on?
Atiger!
I think it got Claibourne!
Claibourne? Right.
I'll see to him.
Stay here, Mowgli!
- Bapu?
Damn!
Get him outofthe way!
Bapu.! Bapu.!
-Shere Khan!
Ha!
Shoot him, Buldeo! Ha!
God! Mowgli!
Mowgli!
- Mowgli!
-Gotyou!
- Damn it! Damn it!
Getoutof myway!
Outof myway!
Oh, my God!The boy!
Where's Mowgli, Father?
He's gone, Kitty.
The boy is gone.
Bapu?
Bapu? Bapu?
Bagheera.
Shere Khan.
- Baloo?
Keep up, ladies, keep up!
Now,who can tell me what kind
of monkey that is overthere?
Nevermind, nevermind.
Um--
Whataboutthose overthere?
Who can name those? You see them?
[ Dr. Plumford]
Anybody?
Kitty!
Yes, Doctor?
Perhaps you can name the primates
thatwe are aboutto paint.
Thatone there is a macaque,
those two are rhesus,
and the bunch up there are langurs.
Well, at least I've taught
somebody something.
Oh, my goodness!
There's a spidermonkeywith a mustache!
-Oh,where?
-Where?
He's gota white haton
and a linen suit.
Now,this bridge...
separates mankind
from the animal kingdom.
To cross overthere is
to take your life in your hands.
You see this sign?
Itsays, ""Danger:
""to cross this bridge
is to enterthe black jungle,
the jungle of death.''
-Actually, Doctor,
- Hmm?
all the sign says is,
""Beware,this bridge is old.''
It's a very literal
translation, Kitty.
Come on, ladies.
We'll do our painting down there.
- I dare you to cross it.
- I would never.
- Neitherwould I.
-Well, I certainlywouldn't.
I would.
Why am I notsurprised?
- Hello.
Hello?
He'll killyou.
Whoa!
Katherine!
- Hello,William.
-Whatare you doing here?
You're notsupposed to cross the bridge.
You know it's dangerous.
- I know, I know.
-You're a very naughty girl.
- Not in public,Willie.
- Public?
What public?
[Snickers]
I seem to remember our last kiss
being quite public.
Heatofthe moment, my good man.
Heatofthe moment.
-Nowwe best get back across the bridge.
-I should warn you.
I'm feeling quite the huntertoday.
And am I to be your prey?
Whatthe--
Why,you little savage!
And what have we here?
An animal.An animal that needs to be
taughta lesson in manners, I think.
Come on.!
Put them up.! Put them up.!
- Be careful,William.
- Don'tworry, Katherine.
I'll protectyou.
Actually,William, I think
that's what he's trying to do.
Come on.
Putthem up.
Thrash him!Thrash him good,
Billy boy! Come on!
You're a dead one,you are.
-You all right, Billy?
-Get him!
Nowyou'll getyours, sunshine.
-Well, get him!
-Yes! Raah!
-Stay exactlywhere you are!
- Put the gun away.!
- William, tell him.
- Keep outofthis, Katherine.
- I'm warning you.
-Shoot him!
Shoot him.!
-Just--Juststay back.
- I said shoot him,Wilkins!
That's an order!
- Leave him,Wilkins. He's harmless.
-Come on, man.! Shoot him.!
- I'm warning you!
Left, right, left, right, left.!
Left, right, left, right,
left, right.
-You heard from them lately?
- Nota one.
Atten-tion!
Officer present.!
-Stand at ease.!
Bloody elephants.
Intruder! Intruder!
Don't juststand there!
After him! Sound the alarm!
Intruderat the main gate.!
Whatare you doing here?
Please leave.
If I scream,they'll hearme.
Please,you must go.
All right, I'll take it,
butonly if you promise to leave.
There. Go now.
What is itwith you
and flowers and kissing?
- Billy! Billy!
It's the savage we fought
in the jungle. He's here.
What?
Who are you?
- Do you speak English?
No. Hindi?
Do you speak anything?
Don'ttouch that.
Oh. I told you.
Here.
- It's all right.
It's all right.
Where did you getthis?
This used to be mine.
Mowgli.
I'm Kitty.
Kitty Brydon.
-Oh, God!You've gotto leave quickly.
- Go.! They'll kill you. Go.!
-Get him!
- No!William.
-Are you all right?
-Yes. I'm fine.
-Are you sure?
- Did he touch you?
- No, no, no. He's harmless.
-Wilkins!
-Gone!Just listen to me.
All right, stay here
and lock the door.
No, please.You don't understand.
William!
There he is!
On the wall!
Patrol, on the double!
Outofthe way!
Outofthe way.
Getoutof here,you swine!
There he is!
Outofthe way!
We've got him!
Come down here! Get down here!
Down, down, down!
Come down here!
-Go ahead.You've got him!
-Are you all right?
Hunaman.
Thank you, Buldeo.
That's Queen's evidence now.
Yes, Captain, sahib.
Stolen from some
rich maharaja, no doubt.
No doubt.
Captain, sahib.!
That dagger... is having
very importantfamily.
-Come on.
Ah, my favorite officers.
Evenin', gents.
- Harley.
- Evening, Harley.
And what have we
got here,then?
Caught this one attempting
to kill the Colonel's daughter.
Well,we can't be having
any ofthat now, can we?
And...we found this on him.
May have a brotherand sister.
Well,we can't be separatin'
no family now, can we?
- No,we mostcertainly cannot.
- Right.
Come on, my little
brown brother.
Time to wake up.Tell Uncle Harley
where you gotthe dagger.
Come on!
You little--
Hold him! Hold him!
Push him in! Push him in!
Sergeant Harley.!
Come to order, ifyou please.!
What is going on here?
This is the, uh, intruderwe caught.
I'm aware ofthat, but does
detaining a prisonermean you
have to beat him halfto death?
He kicked me in the sweets, sir.
- Yoursweets, eh, Harley?
-Sir!
-What's his name?
-  Don't know, sir.
What is your name?
If I may say so, sir, congratulations
on your perfect Hindi, sir.
-Shut up,Wilkins.
-Sorry, sir. Stupid--
He, um, hasn'tsaid a word.
Notyet, anyway.
But I can assure you, sir,
I intend to investigate
this business personally.
All right, Boone.You're a good man.
I will entrust him to your care.
Kindly showthe boy some charity.
-Carry on.
-Very good, sir.
You heard the man, Sergeant.
Showthe boy some... charity.
Stupid jungly!
- Father?
- Katherine, how are you?
Fine.What is that boy
doing in the dungeon?
Well, it's self-evident. He stole into
the palace and broke into your bedroom.
He's gentle and harmless.
Well,tell thatto
Sgt. Harley's sweets.
- I'm sorry?
- Nevermind. Nevermind.
-Anyway,
he's Captain Boone's concern now.
- Father, please, listen.
Speaking of Captain Boone,
no news foryour old father?
- Father, please.
- Hello, Geoffrey.!
Isn't itall very,very exciting?
Exciting? What?
The boy, Father.
He's Mowgli.
Mowgli?
Mowgli,the boy--
Your little friend?
No, itcouldn't possibly be.
He's was five years old.
No child could survive in the jungle.
Notforten minutes,
much less--
It's yourmother's bracelet.
I gave this to you
when you were--
Yes, and I gave itto
a small boy named Mowgli. Remember?
Could it be him?
Well, it's our duty
to help him.
Be a fascinating
case study, Geoffrey.
You know, chart his development, his
ability to learn language,to reason.
Find outthe effects of growing up
away from civilization. It's--
-A unique scientific--
-Opportunity!
- Exactly.
-Thoughtthis out, haven'tyou?
-Justcame to us.
-Spontaneously.
-Whatam I supposed to do?
Invite him forthe weekend?
Well,we've been preparing a place
for him outside in the garden shed.
So he won'tfeel so confined.
Of course.Justcame to you.
Splendid!
-Where did you getthe dagger?
Harley, my dull friend,
your Hindi is worse than your breath.
- He's really something,
this one, isn't he?
- He's an animal, isn't he?
Hello, William,
John, Sgt. Harley.
- Miss Katherine!
- Katherine.
Whatare you doing down here?
Dr. Plumford and I believe your
new prisoner's the jungle boy
the villagers all talk about.
-The one raised by the animals?
-Yes.
We wantto help him reenter
man's world,teach him to speak.
But he's vicious and uncivilized.
Then we'll make him civilized.
What did you do to him?
He did itto himself.
We tried to stop him.
He has, miss. He's done it to himself.
- He's mad,you see.
Don't putyourfingers
in there, miss. He'll bite them off.
Mowgli.
K-Kitty?
Shh. Billy.
If he can be taughtto speak,
then he can be made to talk.
Come on, Mowgli.
Come on. Good. Nice hot English
bath foryou.You'll enjoy it.
There's nothing
to be scared about.
Splendid.
All right,then.
Thank you.
Hey!
-Ah, look.
-""A.''
-""B.''
-""C.''
- ""C.''
O, P, Q Rrr,
Sss,T, U,V.
- No, no, no! Clockwise.
-Clockwise.
Clockwise.
- Engine.
- En-gine.
- Fire.
- Pass.
- [ Heavy British Accent] Pass.
Road,people, roof,
window and door.
Next.Ah.
Lots ofwater.
Boat. Boat.
- Boat.
- Good, Mowgli. Well done.
Lake. R--
Mowgli!
Next.
- Prince Albert.
-Al-bert.
-Albert.
-Albert!
-These are animals.
Animals are ourfriends.
Animals are ourfrien--
Whatfriend?
I'm yourfriend and, uh,
Dr. Plumford's yourfriend.
Tongue depressor.
Also friend.
Birds are beautiful.
Birds are b-ful.
- Dr. Plumford, please.
- Kitty, I'm trying to examine him.
- Kitty is pest.
- Pest.
-You see? He understands.
-You is pest.
No, no.You are pest.
You are pest.
-Are, are, are.Ahhh.
-Are, are, are.
Ah-ahh-ahhh-ah.
Good.
Birds are beautiful.
So is you.
So are you.
Yes.You are.
Thank you.
Picking up fast, isn't he?
-Where are we going?
-Animals are friends.
- Isn't that the same bearyou fought?
Saving my life?
Baloo?
Yes, Baloo.
Right hand goes here.
One,two,three,
four,five, six.
One,two,three, [Chuckles]
- It's all right.
Man, woman,
woman.
One man,two women.
Lucky man.
Good.
-One,two,three. One,two,three.
Horse, saddle,
temple, riverDoctor.!
This big tree--
No,that's nota boat.
That's Queen Victoria.
House, iron,jump, king.
Lamp, mail,
quick, royal,victory.
- Extra,yellow, zebra.!
-Very good!
So, can you speak
with the animals?
Yes, butthey speak
notas men speak.
With animals, every move, every look,
every sound has a meaning.
-Aha.
-The jungle speaks to me.
Because I've learned
howto listen.
If you could have spoken
to me the firsttime in the jungle,
whatwould you have said?
Oh!
Did you, uh--
Did you feel anything?
Fire.
Fire?
Agreatfire.
Oh.
It's late.
We'd better go.
Please, stay here.
With me.
I can't.
There are conventions,
formalities,
things thatare just not done.
I must do what's civilized.
Whatmust I do?
- Katherine!
- Hello, Father.
Don'tyou ""Hello, Father'' me!
I've had men combing the whole
bloody district looking foryou.
Where were you? You were with
that jungle boy,weren'tyou?
Mowgli, Father.
His name is Mowgli.
Savage! He's bred in the jungle,
raised by animals.
It's not rightfor a girl
of your standing, of your background.
It's-- It's not done. Do you hear?
It's just not done!
What's not done?
I haven't done anything.
- People are beginning to talk.
-Well, people always talk, Father.
Ijustwantwhat's
bestforyou.
Well, I think you want
what's bestforyou.
I'm sorry, Father.
Yes,well, so am I.
It's my fault, dragging you
halfway around the world.
Well, I'm thinking... perhaps
it's in your best interest if I...
send you home.
To England? But India's my home.
I love it here.
In England you'd have dozens
of handsome young suitors.
It's time you turned
yourmind to... settling down.
- I've plenty oftime forthat.
- No, no.There's no good reason
foryou to stay on.
Unless
- Unless, of course,
there's a better offer.
- Hmm?
-Yes, Father.
All right,
what's this all about?
What it is all about,
my good Captain, sahib,
is the lostcity of Hunaman.
Yeah,yes,
I knowthe legend.
- It is nota legend!
-Oh, no, sahib.
Mostcertainly it is not.
Many thousand years ago
in the time of Hunaman,
deep in the heart
of black jungle,
there was a most
magnificentcity.
All people in Asia traveling there
for a chance to save their souls.
- Boughttheirway
into heaven, did they?
-Ah,yes.
And the treasures,
they're piling higher and higher.
'Til one day black jungle
is becoming very angry...
and is swallowing the whole city.
And itwas lostforever?
And all these centuries,
it's been waiting for
the rightman to come and find her.
Men like us.
Lots of men have gone
in search of lostcity,
but no one
is ever returning.
To go into the black jungle is
to invite death. Understand?
Unless, of course,
one knows the way.
-The jungle boy!
- Precisely.
But, uh, getting
his cooperation...
may take some... persuasion.
Whatyou looking at?
- I have seen that hat.
-That's King Louis of France.
King Louis. If you see him,
tell him I know
who took his hat.
I'll do that.
Captain William Boone.
- Mind yourmanners, Mowgli.
Hello,William.
Hello, my dear. I thought
I'd pay you a surprise visit...
seeing as we've been, uh,too busy
to see each other of late.
I broughtyou these.
I knowthey're yourfavorite.
Thank you.
You're very sweet.
So... lessons
going well, I hope?
-Verywell.
-Good, good.
Attentive fellow, isn't he?
-Yes,very.
I've been doing a lot
ofthinking... aboutyou and I.
-You have?
-Yes.
And, uh,well--
Katherine Ann Brydon,
willyou marry me?
-William, I'm flattered.
-Good.Then it's settled.
- Butmy father's planning on
sending me back to England--
-Shh.
I've already spoken to yourfather,
and he feels this is the better offer.
Oh, I don't knowwhatto say.
Then don'tsay anything.
Oh, Katherine,we shall be
the most perfectcouple in all India.
-We'll have success,wealth, power.
- Love?
Yes,yes,thattoo,
of course.
You know, I feel awful.
I've been quite remiss in my duties
to you of late, haven't I?
I'll tellyou what.Why don't
I take yourfriend--What's his name?
- Mowgli.
- Mowgli. Mowgli.Yes.
Why don't I take him for a tour ofthe
palace.You'd like that,wouldn'tyou?
You know,William,you can be quite
sweetwhen you putyourmind to it.
This one is a personal
favorite ofmine.
You, um--You thrust it into your
opponent's belly, like that,you see?
And then you
twist ita little...
and you rip out his stomach.
Then do you... eat him?
- No, of course not.
- Does he wantto eatyou?
Why, no.
Then why kill him?
Because he's your enemy.
What is enemy?
Someone you hate.
What is hate?
Fifteenth century. Smart little buggers
back then,weren'tthey?
And this one.
-This one belongs to you, doesn't it?
- Mm.
Where did you get it?
- From Monkey City.
- Monkey City?
Was there more treasure there?
More like this?
In Monkey City,
there's mountains oftreasure.
Mountains,you say?
I wantyou to take me
to this, um,
Monkey City of yours.
- No!
- No?
For heaven's sake,why not?
Only those who keep
the jungle lawmay go.
My dear boy, I'm a British officer.
My job is to keep the law.
-You keep notthe jungle law.
- Look here.
I don't know aboutany jungle law,
but I do keep man's law.
And man's law rules around here.
Man has many laws.
Mostabout killing.
You kill for sport...
and anger and treasure.
The jungle law say
we may only kill to eat...
orto keep from being eaten.
You know,you almost
sound like a man,
instead of an animal that's been
trained to sound like one.
The more I learn what is a man,
the more I wantto be an animal.
I huntanimals,you know?
Maybe someday...
you huntme.
Thank you for inviting me, Dr. Plumford.
Oh,think nothing of it,
my boy. Now, look atthat.
The color and majesty of India.
The exquisite manners
and food of England.
All the bare necessities of life.
Oh, incidentally,
I was joking aboutthe food.
Adrian.
My, my, my, but don'twe
look dandy tonight?
-What does he think he looks like?
- I'm notentirely sure, Billy.
But perhaps he could teach us
howthe apes dance, hmm?
-Thatwould be fascinating.
And then we were supposed
to name these monkeys
and I couldn't rememberthe names
Come on.
May I?
Fascinating.
Come, Katherine.
-Yourfather has a little
announcement he'd like to make.
-Thank you.
All right, ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen, if I could
have yourattention please.
I have an announcementto make.
This evening,
to my greatsurprise and delight,
one ofthe finestyoung men that
I've ever had the privilege to know,
has sought my consent
to marry my daughter, Katherine,
-she having accepted his proposal.
Nowadays, of course, parents are
the lastto knowthese things.
Still, never having been one to stand
in the way of progress ortrue love,
I am glad
to give that consent.
And so it is with the greatest pleasure,
that I announce the engagement...
of Katherine Ann Brydon
to Captain William Boone.
A toast...
to Katherine and William.
Katherine and William!
What does this mean, Doctor?
Itmeans, Mowgli,
thatthey are to wed.
Itmeans...
she belongs to him.
Excuse me, Doctor.
Dreadfully sorry, old bean.
Pardon me, old chap.
The poorthing.
Let him go.
Katherine!
Mowgli! Mowgli,
where are you going?
-To my home.
-You can't go back.
-You're notan animal.You're a man.
- I am nota man!
And I am notan animal.
Please don't leave.
Why should I stay?
I run with the wolf pack.
You...
must run with the man pack.
It is the properthing.
I will shame your house no more.
You know, I think you
owe me an apology.
-There's been a mistake,William.
- Mistake?
I can'tmarry you.
I won'tmarry you.
No, Katherine!
I think it is you who is mistaken.
I realize this adolescent
infatuation you have with this
savage has addled your brain,
but I can'tallowyou to make
a fool of me and I will not lose
you to some puerile jungle boy!
-You sure you won't reconsider?
After all, Captain Boone is--
- No, Father.
Ah,well.
Sure you'll be very happy in England.
Yes, I'm sure I will be.
I shall miss you dreadfully.
We're ready.
Well, then, where do you suppose
my little brown brother has got to?
Oh, nothin' personal.
Keep youreyes open, laddies.
A bob forthe man thatspots him.
Ahhh!
Me sweets!
Baloo?
Dr. Plumford.!
-Where's the doctor?
They just leftto bring Miss Katherine
to the ship to England.
-Where?
-They're on the road toJaipur.
Go on.
Hyah!
You'll absolutely love their house.
Rightacross from Holland Park.
- Bloody hell!
- Bandits. Get down.
-What's happening?
Make room!
Return fire!
- Father! Doctor, help him!
-Geoffrey?
Farewell, sahib!
-You!
Mowgli!
Why did they do this?
Theywantme to come for her.
They know I'll come for her.
You saved my life, Mowgli.
Yes, Doctor.
Now I need you...
to save the life of another.
You bloody swine!
Leave her alone!
-Ow! Getoff me!
- Rememberme, Colonel, sahib?
-[ Katherine] Let me go.!
Yes, I rememberyou.
Buldeo,you bloody coward!
Letme go!
- Hello, darlin'.
-Sergeant Harley.
Aye.
Look who's here, lad.
Hello, Katherine.
- Looks like the last dance
belongs to me.
-Willyou sh--
Captain Boone,thank God!
What is he doing here?
Thatwasn't partofthe plan,
nowwas it, Buldeo?
- Itwas a mistake.
-Captain Boone.
Am I to understand
you're with this scum?
Much to my surprise, sir.
I have many friends
in low places.
Sgt. Harley?
I've had 25 years ofthe likes ofyou
without making a penny from it,
so don'tyou Sgt. Harley me,
you sillywee man!
My God! I've never heard such
insubordination! LieutenantWilks?
It's Wilkins, sir. Look,
I knowthis looks bad, sir.
Oh, shut up,Wilkins.
Look here.
You're all soldiers
in the British Army.
You're undermy command, and I order
you to return to the fort immediately!
To be hung, drawn or quartered?
No, no, I'm afraid thatwon't do atall.
-This is treason!
-No.!
Oh, God, nowwe're in it.
-Ah!You woman,you!
- How could you do this?
Butyou don't knowwhat's
atthe end ofthe rainbow, my sweet.
-Why have you brought us here?
- I will answerthat!
Ah... righton time.
Come down here.
Or else unpleasantries may occur.
Tabaqui! Schula!
-This is good!
-Take us to the treasure
and she'll live.
I will take you there,
and we will see who lives.
Why do you suppose
he stares at us like that?
Because to him...
you are food.
Oh, good.
My God!
Listen to that.
Aw, are the noises
botherin'you, sonny?
Can'tyou get'em to shut up?
Aman talking to animals?
Is this done?
Ifwe don't getmy father
to a doctor, he'll die.
He's a British officer.
He can make do.
-So, my jungle friend,
where do we go
from here?
Followthe mountains.
-And then?
-And then, if you are still alive,
I will tell you more.
Shut up.
-Shut up.
-Shut up!
-Aye. Shut up.
Calm yourself,Wilkins.
-What's that?
Howthe hell should I know? Never
heard anything like that in my life.
It is Shere Khan. He's returning.
Good.
I'd like to bag me a tiger.
Do not be wishing for this tiger, sahib.
He's the devil.
Shere Khan hunts us.
I must protectyou from him.
I mustescape.
-We're going with you.
- No.
It's saferwith these men
and their guns.
Be careful.
I will come back foryou.
I know.
Oh, stop.
Ah!
He's escaped!
Wake up!
No, no.
No, no!
Boone, help me!
Boone!Wilkins!
-Somebody help me.!
- Harley,whatare you doing in there?
It's quicksand,Wilkins!
It's sucking me down.
- It's gotmy legs!
It's sucking me under!
-Gimme your hand!
-Get--Gimme your hand!
-Stretch to me. Come on.
-Gimme your hand,Wilkins!
-Come on, reach!
- I can't.
-Come on.
-That's a boy.
-Come here.
Harley,you're pulling me. Harley!
- Don't!
- Don't let go.!
-You're pulling me in!
Damn you,Wilkins!
- Harley.
-Well,
let's not be discouraged
by every little thing.
- Let's go.
-Go on.
- Butmy father.
You can't leave my father!
He'll die!
Such is life.
God!
-Come.We must go, quickly.
Hey.
- My friend will take you
back to the village.
- Friend?
An elephant.
It had to be an elephant.
Bring her back forme.
Please.
Mowgli.
I think a man lucky
who can countyou as a friend.
Tut,tut,tut,tut.
Tut,tut,tut,tut?
-Whoa! Bloody elephants!
Bane of my existence.
This'd be a damn fine country ifit
wasn't forall the bloody elephants.!
- Nowthis is just great.
Great.!
Just--Just be careful
with thatthing,willyou?
- Bloody oaf!. ""Join the army,''they say.
""See the world,''they say. This is
singly the most ridiculous thing...
I've everdone in my life.!
Once I get back to soci
Ow.! [ Grunts]
Bloody mosquitoes.!
Bloody jungle.!
My father lives.
Whata shame.
Well, shall we continue?
Kill him.
Mowgli.!
- No!
Come on.
My God!
-What is that?
-  Sounds like monkeys.
- Monkey City.
Shere Khan!
- My God, what are they doing?
-They run from Shere Khan!
Boone?
Boone.!
- Boone.!
Boone!
Wilkins.!
You bloody shot me.!
-Oops.
- Wilkins.! I am going to be killing you.!
Stupid.
Oh, my God, I've been shot.!
Wilkins!
You could die too,you know?
He won't letme die.
-You're hurting me.
- Behave yourself and I won't.
Follow him!
Follow King Louis to yourtreasure.
Damn.
See, Katherine?
It's notall that disgusting.
It's notthe place,William:
it's the company.
It's beautiful.
Brilliant.
- Mowgli!
-Come on!
I'm knowing you are down here,
my little man cub.!
Huh?
My leg!
No!
Help me!
Buldeo?
- No!
So,you've returned
to sealyourfate, have you?
Friend of yours?
Aha.
Oh, dear.
What do you think you have
that I don't, huh?
Strength of a bear.
-Speed of a panther.
- No!
- No.!
- Heart of a wolf!.
And very sharp teeth.
Oh.
Kitty, come!
We must go quickly!
-We have to take some with us.
-This treasure only brings death!
-Justone thing.
- Please.
- Katherine.!
Look whatwe can have together.
- Katherine, come back.!
All right, go then!
Go!
Go with your jungle boy.!
I gotwhat I came for.!
I don't need you.
What's happening?
Shere Khan sees me notas a man,
butas a creature ofthe jungle.
Hello.
Look who's here.
Baloo.
He was a very good patient.
Hmm? Yes,you are.
Look!
So that is how it came to pass,
that Mowgli, keeperofthe jungle law,
protectorofcreatures great and small,
became lord ofthe jungle.
So listen well
and hearthe call...
and long life
to those that keep the jungle law.