One day it happens.
You're standing somewhere
and you realize you don't want
to be any of those around you.
You don't want to be
the dickhead you just beat up.
Your honor, I've got
15 stitches here and 25 here.
Or your father,
or your brother,
or anyone
in yourfucking family.
Son of a bitch!
The accused wiII stand.
This court finds
Hugo OIivera Castro
guiIty of assauIt,
Or the judge.
and sentences him
to 18 months in prison,
commuted to a fine of 6,000 euros
as this is a first offense.
Or even yourself.
Court is adjourned.
You just want to run away.
You must be carefuI
from now on.
There can be
no more vioIent incidents.
Another offense
means you'II go to prison.
Hugo, are you Iistening?
-Why didn't mom come?
-She's on a trip.
And don't call me Hugo.
Fuck.
Get the hell out
of wherever you are.
Come on!
nd uddenly it happen.
omething click.
nd you know that
things are going to change.
They've changed already.
Dogface!
Yeah, you!
Dogface.
nd they'll never
be the sae again.
-Bye, dad.
-Bye.
Never.
nd when it happen,
you know.
THREE METERS ABOVE THE SKY
-Babi!
-Okay.
Hurry!
Good morning.
SiIence.
SiIence!
-May I?
-Late.
CIose your notebooks, pIease.
She'II pick me.
Fernandez Camino,
Luna Vergara,
and Duenas Martin...
No, she's outside.
Absent.
So,
HerrerueIa.
TransIation.
Take your phone.
Domu itinere
eunte,
moltu
ambulantu
fuit.
HerrerueIa...
On the way home
he had to waIk a Iot.
A lot.
You'II have to study a lot
to get into coIIege.
CeII.
Miss AIcazar,
won't you take my caII?
Sit down.
We'II continue. De trictu
sensi cui super impia.
Babi!
l'm sorry.
-It's OK.
-SiIence!
Mara, doing it a few times
doesn't mean you're dating.
So what? Anyway, his paIs
toId me he never caIIs.
And you beIieve his paIs?
Just Iook at them.
CIaudio,
change your tie.
This Iooks better.
-GirIs, are you ready?
-Yes, mom.
If you want a Iift,
we're Ieaving now!
With this make-up,
how oId do I Iook?
At Ieast 15.
But I am 15.
Let's see.
Like that,
you're about to turn 16.
H!
I wouIdn't ask, but it's urgent.
I need 400 euros for my bike.
-It's in the repair shop!
-Don't worry about that now.
Chino!
We've got a new contest
on the Bandstand!
Are you ready?
The countdown has started!
Who'II be king of the Bandstand?
On your marks! Get ready!
Go!
One!
Two!
Three! Four!
Five! Six!
Don't act Iike you're desperateIy
seeking someone.
But I am.
There he is!
Dani!
-Don't go...
-Hi, Ruben!
Shit, with aII that make-up
I didn't recognize you.
WouId you Iike something?
Yes, come on.
Thirty!
Thirty one!
Thirty two!
Thirty three!
-Thirty four!
-That's the first one down!
Katina!
l thought you weren't coming!
I was at another party,
but it was fuII of gays.
A real bore.
Someone eIse who was bored
brought me here.
That's him,
chasing Berta's brother.
HeIIo!
-Happy birthday!
-Oh, yes!
Thank you.
Want some?
No? WeII, the drinks
are back there
and there's a bar outside.
See you Iater!
I Iove this song.
Let's taIk to my new gay friend.
Fifty one! Fifty two!
Fifty three!
TravoIta, you're sIipping!
Fifty six! Fifty seven!
Eighty two! Eighty three!
Eighty four! Eighty five!
Ten seconds! Come on!
Let's have a finaI sprint!
One, two, three,
four, five, six...
Come on!
seven, eight,
nine,
-and ten!
-Ten!
There's a new king
of the Bandstand!
Chino has Iost his throne
after two years!
There's a private party up town!
-Can we go?
-Sure, I've got tickets!
-Coming?
-Not to a rich kids' party.
WiII you ever forgive me?
I've been looking for a reason
to do it, but I can't find one.
TypicaI of a woman.
See? That ''typicaI''
is what ruins everything.
You're beautifuI tonight.
Tonight?
AIways.
AIicia, your brother rang,
he's coming with some friends.
But I'm an onIy chiId!
-Yes?
-HeIIo!
-Who's my brother?
-Sis!
Sis!
There are canapes...
Listen to the music!
My IittIe sister!
CIose the door!
What do you want?
My purse.
-Take it.
-I can't.
Some idiot got it first.
Here.
Didn't your mother teII you
not to snoop in girIs' purses?
l don't know my mother.
-But I'd teIl yours something.
-ReaIIy? What?
You can't go around
with just 50 euros.
That's my week's aIIowance.
-lt was.
-Now I'II go hungry.
If you want,
I'II buy you Iunch tomorrow.
You know what?
When l'm paying,
I Iike to choose my company.
-What's that?
-Never mind!
Stop it! Stop!
HoIy shit!
Forget about Iunch.
What wouId we do after?
TeII jokes?
Look, I wouIdn't Iaugh at yours
and you wouIdn't understand mine.
The jokes, I mean.
HaIf-wit!
If you dare take any aIcohoI
I'II teII mom.
Excuse me?
Don't you remember?
I accompanied you to schooI
this morning.
Well, l was your escort.
You were the one
shouting stupidities.
No, I just said one.
''Dogface''.
You Iiked it, right?
lt always works
with girIs Iike you.
Like me?
Up-tight and keen to break out.
Do you want something?
A Coca-coIa, pIease.
I have to drive.
Babi?
No, l served myseIf.
See? When you're pIeasant
you're not such a dogface.
What?
-Chico!
-PoIIo, take this.
No, put me down, you brute!
Let go of me!
No, no! l'm sorry I threw
the miIk shake at you!
The damage has been done.
You're out of your mind!
I'm wearing a VaIentino!
-It's freezing!
-It's good for the circuIation.
It pumps more bIood
to your brain.
You offer miIk shakes,
you don't throw them at peopIe.
And teII VaIentino
the dress Iooks a Iot better wet.
The poIice, pIease.
ShaII l get you a towel?
You don't want to catch coId.
Go to heII!
Move, they rang the cops!
Remind me
the next time we bathe together
to wash your mouth with soap.
Why did you do nothing
when he threw me in the pooI?
Babi,
it was aII a set-up.
I rang those idiots to cause
a fuss so I could be with you.
Roberta wiII never forgive you.
They wrecked the house.
What the heII...?
What are they doing?
Go away!
Stop it, pIease!
This is my father's car!
Bastards!
You want aggro?
-You're fucking crazy!
-Go to heII!
Are you OK?
Shit!
It's nothing.
Just some scratches.
-They could have kiIIed us!
-It's aII right.
There's stiII time.
-I'm sorry!
-Sorry?
For what? TeII me.
For calling the poIice
or for the hit and run?
You're so sexy.
Leave him aIone, you animaI!
You brute! Leave him alone!
You're despicabIe!
You want to groveI?
AII right, say after me:
-I wiII not ruin the party...
-Stop!
l wiII not ruin the party
for peopIe who know
how to have fun.
I won't ruin the party...
PIease, heIp me!
...for people who know
how to have fun.
-Mr. Santamaria!
-What's going on?
They're going
to kiII each other!
Boys, that's enough!
Let's get out of here!
Babi, come with us!
Fuck, it was your fauIt
that I hit him!
You made me hit him!
Get in the car!
-I won't...
-I won't ruin... That's it.
Leave him aIone!
I hate you!
You're an animaI, a brute!
Put me down!
AII right,
I've put you down.
And he's gone.
I'lI say goodbye too.
How do I get home?
-Let me get on the bike.
-What?
Let me get on the bike.
You said I'm an animaI
and a brute, right?
I can't Iet someone Iike that
take you home.
It's for your own good.
Tomorrow you'd regret
not being consistent.
Stop, pIease.
Want to go somewhere?
You want your face smashed?
Scram.
Scram!
Get on, I've fought enough peopIe
because of you.
Wait, wait.
I'm paraIyzed.
You're squeezing me.
If you grab my jacket
I can't drive.
PIease...
You want to stay Iike this
aII night?
Sorry, I've never ridden
on the back of a bike.
So I'm the first, right?
Shit!
Babi!
-Did you come on that bike?
-No, mom...
She had no choice, ma'am, reaIIy.
The boy who was driving her
dumped her
and she had to come with me.
Hi, mom!
Didn't I teII you
to stay with your sister!
-HeIIo.
-Hi.
Get in the car.
You two won't have
any kind of phone for a week!
You're exactIy Iike your mother.
A grouch.
Are you seeing that guy?
I don't even know him.
He's Hugo Olivera,
but they caII him H.
Something horribIe happened
and he wants to forget his name.
My friends and I say
it's H for ''hero''.
He Iooks Iike
he'd save your Iife.
Who the heII Iet you in?
-Get up, you've things to do!
-Yeah, for you!
No, I understand.
But I couId go to Paris next week
and we'II cIose the deaI.
AIex, I need to borrow 400 euros.
Fuck, what a drag.
Wait.
We'II taIk to Head Office.
Yeah, sure.
OK.
What are you doing?
Give me that!
Are you crazy?
Don't give it to him!
Don't speak! Don't speak!
Yes, of course.
In my waIIet, in my jacket.
Yes!
-No, of course.
-Thank you!
ReaIIy, if he can't,
I'lI see to it.
Hugo, remember about dinner
with dad.
Are you sure it's here?
Yeah, I saw it in her diary,
and we're having Iunch.
-You're broke.
-She said she'd pay.
-HeIIo.
-Hi.
That's her!
-Which one?
-The bIonde.
-Bye, Babi.
-Bye.
And that's the girl
from the foam bath.
I'm off.
God, Babi!
That's the guy
who stoIe my aIIowance.
-Which one?
-The ugIy one beside the bike.
Oh, no!
Did he steaI from you too?
No, but his paI threw me in the pooI
and wrecked Chico's car.
You never teII me
the interesting things!
HeIIo.
What are you doing here?
Hey, take it easy.
I just came with my friend,
he's having Iunch with that girl.
But she happens
to be my best friend
and your friend
stoIe aII her money.
You owe me one.
Why not invite me somewhere nice?
What do you say?
Moron!
How sweet!
Coming for Iunch?
You can't have Iunch with him!
But he's paying, so I'II get
some of my money back.
I thought she was paying.
l swiped her money yesterday
so it's Iike she was paying.
Don't be angry.
I'II call you Iater.
Excuse me.
Just to show I'm not a Iiar,
didn't you and I have
a foam bath yesterday?
That's a yes.
-Hi, mom.
-HeIIo, Iove.
Why is your brother so Iate?
You know him,
he's aIways working.
Where's mom?
On a trip,
with a girI friend.
What grade wilI you get?
8 or more?
In Physics?
A distinction, definitely.
I'm popping out.
Do you need anything?
No, I'II take a break later.
Wrap up weII if you go out.
It's freezing.
Yes, mom.
Rebeca, did your on
ever argue with that man before?
l didn't even know
they knew each other.
With his injurie,
if we don't have some proof
Hugo couId be in big trouble.
Do you think
I don't want to help my son?
Hugo,
have you nothing to say?
I'm moving in with you.
Don't you want to know
how it went?
How did it go?
If you ask Iike that
I won't teII you.
-AII right, don't.
-Babi!
Excuse me, that bIonde hunk
was giving you the eye.
He's stiII doing it.
ShaIl we follow him?
Why are you Iooking Iike that?
You dumped me
and went off with that thug.
Hey, you don't know him!
He's got probIems.
He's got no money.
His father treats him badIy.
But he's reaIIy nice.
He asked me
to the races tonight.
What races?
I toId mom
I'm sIeeping at your house.
-Leave a key under the mat.
-l don't beIieve this!
-Why don't you come?
-No!
l don't want to see him
or his friend.
Then we're not going
to see each other either.
-Why not?
-I'm going out with him!
Katina!
-Babi!
-Yes?
Come here a moment.
Coming.
What?
Haven't you something to teII us?
The Santamarias rang.
FeIipe's nasaI septum was broken,
it aImost pierced his brain!
-I had nothing to do with it.
-It's true, she didn't.
Who asked you?
Be quiet!
Look, Babi,
they want to report your friend.
They want to know his name.
He's not my friend.
I just know he's caIIed H.
Are you defending him?
How Iong have you known him?
The onIy thing I know
is his nickname!
You know his name, teII them!
-Do you think I'm a teIItaIe?
-You toId me his name.
DanieIa, his name.
Hugo OIivera.
That's his name, dad.
CaII them, and say
Babi had nothing to do with it.
Great, Babi, you've reaIly
put your foot in it!
DanieIa...
My parents are out.
Yes, she's here.
But I reckon that in a week
she'II be dead.
She informed on a dangerous guy,
and she Iikes him.
Stop taIking about me
and hang up.
Wait, I've got another caII.
Yes?
Yes, just a minute.
It's for you.
Yes?
Good evening!
Yes.
Katina? She's sIeeping.
ShaII l wake her?
Yes, l'll teII her.
Good night.
Bye.
What's going on?
What is it?
Who was that?
It's turned off.
Where are the bike races?
The Siamese races?
At the port.
-Can I go? PIease...
-No way.
And don't teII anyone.
Know where my sister's going?
WE REMEMBERYOU
No, stop, PoIIo!
What a surprise!
I'm so gIad you've come!
Why is your phone off?
Your mother rang.
-What did you teII her?
-That you were asIeep,
and she beIieved me.
She's picking you up tomorrow
at 7:00 for your bIood tests.
Don't be Iate,
I don't want any probIems.
-Come on, stay!
-No!
We're going for a pizza.
I doubt I'd eat
the pizzas you eat.
Well, it's the untamed shrew!
Have you come to see me race?
I didn't even know
you were here.
Then why are you
red as a beetroot?
You just make me laugh.
-Yeah?
-Yes.
You won't be so cocky in court.
I said it was you who broke
Mr. Santamaria's nose.
-You bitch!
-Take it easy.
You could go to prison!
That won't happen, OK?
The day I'm up in court
this nice girI wiII say
l did nothing. Know why?
Why?
By then you'II be so crazy about me
you'II do anything to save me.
The race is starting!
Want to ride behind me?
Never.
H, wiII you take me?
Get on.
Stop being scared
and you'II have fun.
You don't even have a belt.
This is just for Siamese.
So, race or fuck off.
She's a reaI cow.
-What did you say?
-l'm racing now.
WeIl, then?
Give me your beIt.
Babi, no!
Shit, my scarf!
Get on!
Are you crazy?
Don't!
I haven't got aII day.
Good Iuck!
BeIts off!
Come on!
Up! Up!
Last Iap!
Chino!
Stop! Stop!
Shit!
Forget the bike, heIp her!
Don't move her!
-Lift her up!
-CaII an ambuIance!
Get on! Get on!
The cameras!
Cover the Iicense pIate!
Hide here!
I'II pick you up
once I shake them off.
Quick!
Shit!
I'm here.
-Where?
-Here.
Why are you in there?
Come out.
There's a huge dog out there.
There's no dog here.
I stiII can't come out.
Why?
I'm embarrassed.
Come out now or I'II Ieave.
No, wait!
Wait!
What?
Promise you won't Iaugh.
I promise.
What have you done, kid?
-Are you covered in mud?
-It's manure.
That's manure?
I don't beIieve it!
This is too good to be true.
I knew it.
Your promises are worthIess.
-Wait, what are you doing?
-I'm getting on the bike!
Are you crazy?
You're covered in shit.
-You're joking, right?
-No.
If you want,
you can wear my jacket.
But first take off those clothes
or you can't get on the bike.
Fuck, this is disgusting!
-Look, H...
-I Iike how that sounds.
It's the first time
you've said my name.
If you turn round
I swear I'II jump on you
and cover you with manure.
And I do keep my promises.
Don't Iook!
l've got no interest in Iooking.
I'd appreciate it if you'd hurry.
You're a fiIthy,
disgusting bastard!
I didn't turn round, did I?
But you've got a great ass.
I wish I'd rubbed the manure
in your face.
Now I do hear a rabid dog.
-Hurry up!
-Look!
Lift your legs
or he'Il bite you!
Thank you for the Iift.
So I'II pick you up tomorrow.
What time?
Sure, and the poIice
can chase us again.
Right.
You were a very brave Siamese.
Are you going to report me?
-Yes.
-Yes?
ReaIIy?
Do you swear?
Oh, Babi, Babi!
I'm a pig, an animaI, a beast,
but you'd let me kiss you.
-You're inconsistent.
-And you're a bastard!
You had your mouth open,
begging me to kiss you.
Give me back my jacket right now.
HotIips,
what about a good night kiss?
Go to heII!
I was really worried.
Your mom thought l was you
and gave me a good night kiss.
-What happened?
-It was H, wasn't it?
He tore off your cIothes.
You'II wake mom.
WeII?
I'm going to shower.
She smeIls of shit.
Sorry, the poIice were after me.
Liar, I saw you go off
with that stuck-up IittIe mouse.
lllegal races caue diturbances
in the port area
Throw it up to me!
Come on!
She raced as a Siamese
and saved a girI
who had an accident.
It's realIy wild.
-Are you going out?
-No!
Sure.
Katina, not again.
I'm not going out.
Look who's waiting for you
Babi! You're seeing H,
aren't you?
If mom and dad ask,
I'm studying at Katina's.
OK.
I'II be back by 11:00.
I'm the hero's sister-in-Iaw.
H...
Got a Iight?
What's up?
New projects.
Good Iuck, I don't think that prude
wiII open her Iegs so easiIy.
I'll caII you, OK?
Vodka with pineappIe.
Dogface.
Brute.
Mom, why are you stiII up?
Why are you behaving
as if you weren't my daughter?
It got Iate.
Come here!
-Were you drinking?
-You know I don't drink.
What's that boy doing to you?
-Is he making you do anything?
-Nothing I don't want to do.
Is anything wrong?
No, dad, I came home Iate,
that's aII.
I got his Iicense pIate.
-TaIk to him.
-They're just kids.
TeII him if he doesn't Ieave
our daughter aIone,
he'II be in troubIe!
Is that you?
I want to see you.
l' grounded.
l got caught coming home late.
So it's not an urban Iegend.
Nice girIs who behave badIy
are till grounded.
What'll we do tomorrow?
Go off somewhere.
Pick me up at the schooI gate
and take me away.
l haven't been up that early
for over a year.
I might sleep in.
I trust you, H.
Good night.
Bye, Babi.
-Bye, Babi.
-Bye.
Let's go inside.
I can't. H is coming.
-We're going off!
-What?
You're going to screw!
As your best friend,
I want aII the detaiIs.
You animaI!
No, I'm reaIIy excited.
lt's Iike I was
losing my virginity again.
-There he is! Wish me Iuck.
-Lots of Iuck.
Babi! ReIax your peIvis.
HeIIo.
Look who's there.
Hugo...
Hugo, pIease.
Hugo, stop, pIease!
H, what is it?
Hugo, please, don't!
In physics?
A distinction, definitely.
I'm popping out.
Do you need anything?
No, I'II take a break later.
Son of a bitch!
Stop!
PIease, Hugo!
PIease, stop!
H, pIease!
Stop, Hugo!
Stop!
Are you crazy?
You couId have kiIIed us!
Stop!
Stop, pIease!
H! Stop, stop!
Who was that woman?
She was my mother.
Your father and your brother
don't know?
My father thinks
she's with her friends.
Am l the onIy one who knows?
Stop, stop!
Why?
We're out in the open.
There's no one here.
I said no.
OK.
Come here.
Come on.
Why did you bring me here?
Don't you Iike it?
My parents always brought us here
when we were littIe.
See the house that's for saIe?
Yes.
My sister and I
pretended it was ours.
We used to see the owners
and we imagined we were them.
It's so sad.
It's Iike we can
never enjoy it again.
I knew you'd Iike it.
The jacket suits you.
Who's caIling?
My mother doesn't trust me.
Or rather, you.
Is that like mom's signature?
I think it's perfect.
-Thank you for helping me.
-Not at aII.
Don't go yet,
come and meet my daughters.
GirIs,
this is Gustavo,
our new upstairs neighbor.
-Yes, we've seen each other.
-Yes.
He doesn't know anyone,
l said you could take him out
and introduce him.
Yes, mom, but not tonight.
The girIs have asked me
to go to the cinema
and as I'm not grounded anymore
I can go, can't I?
I have to go.
My pIeasure.
Likewise.
Ciao.
This weekend, if I can,
I'lI caII him.
That hunk is walking
into the Iion's den.
You, ''HeIlo, Kitty''.
This is yours, right?
You wouIdn't have
such good taste.
The other night, H used it
to tie me to the bed.
lt's strong.
Not strong enough
if you're here.
Poor thing.
You thought he'd promise you
eternaI Iove, eh?
I feeI sorry for you.
It's obvious
you're crazy about him.
Give me the scarf!
Give it to me!
-Let go!
-Give it to me!
-Get off!
-Let go of me!
-Stop it!
-Give me the scarf!
Let go, you bitch!
Hit her, Babi!
Hit her, Babi, go on!
Hit her harder!
H!
Shit, it's Babi!
Let go of me!
The next time, l'll kiII you,
you whore!
I don't know what happened me.
l didn't want to hurt her.
-She said you'd been with her...
-Babi, Babi...
I won't cheat on you
or hurt you.
I'm with you now.
With the girI who'll beat up
anyone who insuIts her guy.
You know what warriors do
after their first victory in battIe?
Hugo...
Someone wants a word with you.
I'm CIaudio AIcazar,
Babi's father.
-ShaII we go down for a drink?
-Yes, of course.
Hugo,
we have to taIk.
-H, won't you introduce me?
-Of course.
Rosanna, CIaudio.
CIaudio, Rosanna.
-My pIeasure.
-Likewise.
Sweetheart,
you want oIives or nuts?
OIives.
She Iiked you.
She doesn't offer nuts
to everyone.
-No?
-No.
I don't reaIIy know
where to begin.
You see,
my wife...
OIives for the best Iooking man
to come in here this year.
Married, of course.
CIaudio,
I understand
that your wife is concerned.
Her daughter is with a guy
who rides a motorbike,
racing around at 100 m.p.h.
because I don't want
to see things.
But suddenly
someone appears and says
''CaIm down'',
''ease up''.
And when you ease up
you become aware of things.
That there's a dance trophy
among the bottIes of tequiIa.
That my favorite song is playing.
That today is Tuesday 13th.
And that Rosanna would run away
with you right now
to the ends of the earth.
LittIe things, CIaudio.
Your daughter is easing me up.
And that's good for me.
Not now, AIex.
What wrong with you? Didn't you
understand about prison?
You can't just do as you wish.
I'm sick of being your nursemaid!
Stop messing around
and behave Iike an aduIt!
And what's that?
Being oId at 30 and not knowing
how to enjoy Iife? TeIl me!
l'm sorry.
-Maria AveIIan.
-Present.
-Babi AIcazar.
lrene Catur...
Here you are.
Miss AIcazar!
Did your mother sign this?
Yes.
It's odd.
I've just spoken to her
and she didn't know you were ilI.
Nor that you were absent
on Friday.
She's on her way.
You know that what you've done
means immediate expuIsion
from this schooI?
-Did they expeI me, mom?
-No,
because we've donated 8,000 euros
to the schooI.
-Mom, I promise...
-Be quiet, pIease!
Stop making a fooI of me.
When did you decide
to Iaugh at me?
l don't know you, Babi.
-Babi, what's wrong?
-Stay away, Katina.
And don't caII!
She's in on it too, isn't she?
It's time you stopped seeing her.
Katina aid the teacher
is screwing you around.
They tried to expel me.
My parents paid a lot of money
to avoid it.
They're going to Iower my grades.
I mightn't get into coIIege.
Are you crazy?
You'II wake my parents!
Come on.
I'm not cIimbing down there.
-I'm scared.
-Scared?
You're brave.
Come on.
-No!
-Come on.
-Where are we going?
Trust me, Babi.
-Hey, PoIlo!
-Look who's here!
-Great!
-I didn't expect you.
-l toId you.
-l bet 20 euros I didn't have.
Get in the water!
-I haven't got a costume.
-Come on.
No, H...
l've thrown you in before.
Stop...
No!
Come on, it's great!
Save me, Babi!
-Come on, you two!
-Yeah, yeah.
Stop! Stop, pIease!
I have to teII you something.
I'm nervous.
Why?
I've never done it.
Me neither.
Liar!
Babi! This Iunatic just
asked me to marry him!
I'm not in a hurry, Babi.
You can't smoke here.
I'II be brief.
From now on,
you'II treat
one pupiI very welI.
If I hear that Babi
has any probIem
because of you
you're in troubIe.
Don't waste your time
threatening me.
You're not the first.
I'II just say one thing.
Listen carefuIIy.
Pepito.
Pepito!
Fetch the baII!
The fucking baII!
This dog must have a trauma.
Like my aunt's dog,
it thinks it's a rabbit.
What's that thing?
No insuIts!
He's Pepito,
and he's a sIow learner.
We bought him between us.
-Who has custody?
-PoIIo.
-But he's staying with his mom.
-What?
-Don't Ieave him here!
-Better take him out
or he'II piss on the carpet.
Bye, AIex.
What's wrong?
If mom hears you're smoking in here,
she'II sIice you up.
But I won't say a word.
ShalI we go see a movie?
I thought everyone knew
I'm grounded for Iife.
We'd pIanned to sIeep over
at Katina's and now I can't go.
Go on, and have fun.
And mom?
I'II take care of that.
I love the smeII of a pipe.
lt reminds me of when I was IittIe.
-Hi!
FOR SALE
Wait here,
and don't Iook.
l hear the sea!
What was that?
Come here.
There's a step, carefuI.
More steps.
Where are we going?
I can smeII it now.
The sea!
Like it?
WeII?
l never want this to end.
This is incredibIe.
It was your house, right?
I've bought it back for you.
You're crazy!
Now we're the owners.
Are you aII right?
What do you think?
Do you want me to be the first?
And the Iast.
Don't Iaugh.
ReIax, my Iove.
Relax.
I Iove you, Babi.
Are you aII right?
-Did I hurt you?
-No.
I'm not very good, am I?
You're perfect.
You made me feeI great.
I'm happy.
I'm happier.
No, I'm much happier.
-From here to BarceIona.
-From here to the sky.
WeII, I'm even happier.
How much?
Three meters above the sky.
Good morning!
Why is she babysitting?
Rich kids don't work.
Her mother has stopped
her alIowance.
Why did you bring Pepito?
He doesn't Iike being aIone.
It upsets him.
No, it upsets you.
We mustn't be apart!
Hi!
You brought PoIIo and the dog?
He can Iook after the kid.
Hey, champ.
You're pIaying tennis!
Get Pepito off the couch!
-He's caIIed Pepito?
-Yes, he is.
And I'm PoIIo.
What's your name?
Show me your favorite part
of the house.
Come on,
or are you scared of me?
Come on, hit it hard.
-Let's go to your parents' room.
-No, come in.
Sit down.
-May I?
-Yes.
-What was that?
-Don't worry, Pollo's in charge.
That's what worries me.
Who the heII do you think you are?
A friend of mine?
-l'm sorry, Babi.
-Get this rabbIe out of here.
-Get out!
-Everyone, out of here.
Get the fuck out!
What were you doing, PoIIo?
l'm sorry.
Parties here don't Iast Iong.
What are they doing here?
You get out too.
I don't want to see you.
Get out!
You Iot don't respect anything!
Babi, this isn't my fauIt!
Get out!
Hi, thi is Babi.
Leave a mesage.
YOU AND I
3 M A S
OK, the meat shouId be rare
with a IittIe salt.
-A IittIe salt.
-And the strawberries?
They're in the fridge.
No, that's wrong!
Add the cream
just before you serve them.
And light the candIes
five minutes before she arrives.
-Five minutes.
-Right.
-Why not apoIogize over the phone?
-The dog!
You're so unromantic!
She's due at 8:00,
but she's aIways 10 minutes earIy.
OK.
-Yes?
-HeIIo.
Babi, supper's getting coId.
Mom's looking all over
for a ring her mother gave her.
lt' been mising
since your friends were here.
ls it alway going
to be like this with you?
-No, Babi.
-Leave me alone.
Chino...
Watch it!
I don't want any probIems.
You don't want any problems?
Tough guy.
Don't touch me!
Look at him.
He wants a fight.
I just want the ring.
H, stop, pIease!
Stop, you'II fucking kiIl him!
I've got the ring!
I've got it!
-H, go away, pIease!
-Tell Babi to Iet me in!
She isn't here!
It's H! What'II I do?
My parents wiII be here soon!
Go away!
Let me in, Babi!
-I'II calI the poIice.
-I have to give you something.
Why are you crying?
Miss AIcazar,
can you teII us
what happened that night?
Miss AIcazar, did you hear me?
Can you teII us
what happened that night?
Babi! Wait!
Why are you humiIiating our famiIy?
What wiII they think of us?
We promised we'd heIp them!
No, you promised, I didn't.
Stop being ashamed for me,
stop deciding for me.
I refuse to grow oId
and reaIize l've become Iike you.
I won't live your Iousy Iife.
H is my boyfriend
and I want to be with him.
l won't Iie for you again.
You hear?
If you keep doing as you pIease,
we're through, I swear.
Very well.
I'II change.
They've passed!
I passed!
Be quick,
we've got something to do.
I got the best grade!
Forga gave me an 8.
I thought she'd faiI me.
I'm proud of you.
We have to go.
-Where?
-PoIIo!
-Come on, PoIIo!
-Behave yourself, Pepito.
Don't guIp your food.
You know it makes you sick.
He doesn't want
to go back to the witch.
Who is it?
Pepito Delivery Service.
And don't dare treat him
Iike you treat your pupiIs.
You hear?
Move, AI Capone!
So Iong, buddy.
There'II be more than 100 of us.
No, not a private room,
the whoIe restaurant.
Yes, a very speciaI occasion.
Not just her good grades.
A daughter doesn't
turn 18 every day.
I'II send the guest Iist
this afternoon.
-Mom...
-Yes?
In case you'd forgotten,
Hugo OIivera, my boyfriend.
-Hi, Laura! Did you pass?
-Yes.
Come in.
Good morning.
I wanted to thank you...
Pepito?
I want to marry her.
First you need a job.
Or wiII she go on paying
for everything, Iike she does now.
Tomorrow, I'm going to win.
So she can see me do it.
Our girIs are incredibIe.
We have to live up to them.
She'II Iove it.
-I'll get it.
-H...
Promise you'II be there.
What do you think?
PoIIo...
It's Babi!
Here, take this.
HeIIo.
Can we taIk?
Sure.
You threatened my teacher!
Are you stupid?
You screwed me, H.
-l thought that if...
-Stop thinking for me!
Don't treat me Iike a moron.
Let's Ieave it for a whiIe.
-ShaII I say anything to him?
-No.
I'II be aIong after the race, OK?
The dopey upstairs neighbor,
he'II take us to the party.
You're a fucking genius.
Come on.
-Have you seen H?
-No, I haven't.
Babi,
come here a moment.
Carlos,
this is Babi.
-Happy birthday.
-Thank you.
My Iove.
A photo.
What wouId happen
if I asked your sister out?
Her boyfriend wouId break
every bone in your body.
That's all.
Hi, dad!
HeIIo.
Hey, where's your buddy?
I want some fucking revenge.
I'm racing for him today.
I Iove you.
Who is our daughter dancing with?
With a good boy, RafaeIa.
Be careful!
Stop, stop!
Forgive me, I'm sorry, Babi.
It's all right, Gustavo.
I said it's aII right.
Leave me aIone!
She toId you twice
to Ieave her aIone! Get out!
I'm just trying to heIp her.
What are you doing, H?
He didn't do it on purpose!
-Are you OK?
-Yes.
You think he meant to do it?
Yes?
Come on.
I'm sorry, CIaudio.
-Katina! What is it?
-PoIIo.
Where is he?
They won't teII me.
Look for him, H.
PIease, l'm begging you.
Where is he?
Over there.
You can't get through.
CaIm down.
Let go of me! Let go of me!
PoIIo!
Let go of me!
He's my friend!
H!
H, stop, pIease!
PIease! H!
-Don't touch me!
-Listen.
l can't take any more.
Your Iife is fuII of shit
and death and blood,
you don't care about me.
I do care,
and Babi, I swear that...
Don't swear anything.
You don't care about anyone.
Not me or your family
or your best friend.
It's not my fauIt!
-Yes, it is!
-It's not!
Of course it is!
You kiIIed PoIIo!
You kiIIed him!
There' alway a moment
when the road forks.
Each one goe off, thinking
the road will come together again.
Come in.
You see the other peron
getting aller and maller.
That' all right.
We're ade for each other.
She'll be there at the end.
But at the end
only one thing happen.
The fucking winter come.
Yes, yes. Don't keep on.
I'm eating weII, AIex.
There's someone at the door.
I'II call you Iater.
Merry Christmas!
Come in, please.
I haven't been around much
these Iast months.
I couIdn't, I'm sorry.
Don't worry.
Santa Ieft this for you.
l miss him so much, H.
I can't...
Sometimes I think
I'II never find anyone Iike him.
No, no one Iike him.
But you'II find someone
who'II make you happy.
Have you spoken to Babi?
Have you?
We Iost touch after the accident.
I think she's with another crowd.
And she's going out
with some guy.
Maybe you shouId forget her.
Want to stay for supper?
l can't tonight.
Some other day.
Thank you.
That's OK.
Yes?
HeIIo.
Is Babi there?
Just a minute.
Bye, mom.
CalI me tomorrow.
Take care of her.
l will, Rafaela.
Are you ready?
We're leaving in five minutes.
What are you doing here?
-I Iocked myseIf out.
-OK, come on.
What's wrong?
Hugo, what's wrong?
What's happened?
Suddenly you realize
that everything is over.
Really.
I'm going away for a while.
To London.
To work.
That's a good idea.
I can't stay here.
There' no going back.
You feel it.
nd then you try to remeber
at what point it all began.
nd you dicover it tarted
before you thought.
HeIIo.
Long before.
nd it' at that moment
you realize
thing only happen once.
nd no matter how hard you try
you'll never feel the ame again.
You'll never again feel
you're three meters above the ky.
THREE METERS ABOVE THE SKY
Adaptation: D. Mac CIoskey