[Wind Howling]
[Laughing]
Ayear younger than I was for my first.
- When can I have a stag?
- [Scoffs] A stag?
- Come on!
- Tell me again what you said last week.
[Wind Howling]
Let that be a reminder to you.
[Chuckles]
I got it. I got it.
[Laughing]
Why would they join
against the Irish?
- Because someone has to stand up to them.
- You?
Me, Marke, all the tribes.
We can't resist alone.
- I could.
- [Chuckles] My little warrior.
We have to be careful.
[Indistinct]
Come home without something
for your lady, you'll have hell to pay.
- Can I?
- [Man] Of course you can, boy.
- The Angles have arrived, my lord-
- [Duck Quacking]
As well as the Celts, my fellow Jutes
and the Saxons.
Good. With Marke...
- we'll all be here.
- Yeah. It's a great day.
- Let us hope so.
- Yeah.
Thanks.
[Goat Bleating]
We heard the news.
Pray for a son.
- Mother.
- [Father] Welcome to Tantallon.
I made this for you.
[Rapping]
Friends.
Look at us, the tribes of Britain.
Divided.
Weak.Just as the Irish like us.
[Murmuring]
But if we were one land- united-
we would outnumber them 2- to- 1.
We could defeat them once and for all.
That's why we're here today.
- To sign this treaty of unification.
- Who would be king?
The strongest among us...
- Lord Marke.
- [Murmuring]
Look, if you're happy sending
all your gold to Ireland...
living as slaves,
by all means, do nothing.
If we were happy doing that,
we would never have risked coming here.
[Chattering]
Friends, my wife is with child.
My heart tells me it's a boy.
I want him to grow old
in a land where all of us-
all the tribes- Pict...
Celt, Angle, Jute, Saxon-
are at peace.
[Shouts]
This island has not known unity
since the Romans left.
That is why I sign this treaty.
- And why should we follow you?
- Perhaps, Wictred...
because your last attempt
to form an alliance...
without the knowledge of half
the barons in this room has failed.
- [Laughing]
- [Man] Alarm!
- [Man #2] What for?
- The Irish are here!
- [Screaming]
- [Shouting]
- Take all your men, guard the women.
- But you won't have enough-
Go!
[Clattering]
Quickly! Tristan!
Back this way. Hurry!
- [Horse Whinnies]
- [Man] Move down the ranks!
[Shouting]
- [Pounding]
- How did they know?
- [Pounding Continues]
- [Shouting]
[Shouting]
- Tristan!
- No!
Let me fight!
[Grunts]
[Shouts]
- [Feet Trampling]
- [Panting]
Please, don't hurt him!
Father.
[Thuds]
- [Screaming]
- No!
[Screams]
[Groans]
[Grunting]
Tristan. Tristan.
[Woman]
No!
[Man Speaking
Foreign Language]
## [Drumbeat]
She's with the gods now, Isolde.
You'll see her again someday.
Will I?
Morholt returns.
What news of the treaty?
Good, Morholt.
Good.
[Woman]
Your mother loved you so much, Isolde.
Why did she die, Bragnae? Why?
It was an ill vapor that took her...
a fever.
No. It was her heart.
[Horses Approaching]
[Man]
The Irish have been here.
[Baby Crying]
[Coughing]
[Sobbing]
Your husband?
Oh. Oh, Sister, I'm so sorry.
[Sister]
The executions lasted a day.
They made sport of us.
A whole generation of men.
Who's this?
[Marke]
Tristan, son of Aragon.
We're his family now.
I have a son about your age.
Melot. Melot?
Melot, this is Tristan.
What shall we do, my lord?
Rebuild.
[Man]
Three, four.
- One, two-
- Don't hold back.
Come on!
Three, four.
Tristan won't fight me.
Look, he's scared!
[Man]
Three, four.
One, two, three-
- Still won't fight?
- He's got the heart of a lion.
Just needs some time.
Why'd you take off your helmet?
You going to cry?
My father died too,
but you don't see me crying.
- Melot.
- That's right, run.
Find another trapdoor
to hide under, coward.
[Grunts]
Tristan!
Tristan! Tristan.
We found something.
Come on, this way.
Quick, come on.
- You are gonna love it.
- You'll love it.
Yeah, l- I found this trapdoor.
- Who found a trapdoor?
- [Laughs]
All right, Simon.
Well, you tell us how you found it.
Look at that.
Where does this lead?
You'll see.
Well, I like that vase.
Think I'll have that.
We always knew the castle
was built on Roman foundations...
but we didn't think
anything was left.
Must be a burial crypt
or something.
Here we are.
Bottom of the keep.
Who else knows about this?
- Nobody.
- Good.
[Man] These savages have rebuilt
the castle in Cornwall...
only now it's made of stone.
For Cornwall's next tribute,
I want slaves-young ones-
their future.
If Marke resists,
have Morholt crush him.
- My king.
- Morholt.
I have led your armies
to victories far and near.
I've made you rich and powerful.
Yes, you have.
You have been most loyal.
When I return from Cornwall,
I was hoping-
What would please you?
A wife.
It's dark in an hour.
What do you think
is really out there?
Britannia.
The old Roman lands.
A world full of evil and grief.
I want to see it.
Do you know what the future
looks like, Bragnae?
[Bragnae]
I see the life you were meant for.
Your father will speak with you.
Am I just a chattel
to be traded at your pleasure?
Do I have no say in my own life?
You have a duty to your king.
You are my father.
Then obey me, Daughter.
[Sighs]
Your father has given you the news?
- And do you welcome it?
- I accept it.
You know, we're more alike
than you might guess.
How so?
I, too, dabble in elixirs.
[Sword Unsheathes]
Poison. It's from
the livers of puffer fish.
Just a taste...
paralyzes all the senses.
So if the blade doesn't kill-
Rendered safe by thistle and bark.
And do you know
the antidote for this?
Yohimbine.
Makes a hard man even harder.
The only cure: Wild abandon.
Till our wedding day.
I'm to Cornwall to deal with rebels.
Release them.
Hey. Around. Around.
[Shouts]
Off me!
- Go find Tristan.
- Leave her!
Take him there. Get a rope.
Anyone foolish enough
to interfere in any way...
- shall suffer the same fate.
- No.
Please don't. Don't.
Take me. No! No!
- [Gags]
- [Screaming] Widseth!
Widseth!
If there are any more attacks,
we shall put our guests...
- to death and raze this entire land.
- [Sobbing]
Take the horses.
- [Marke] When would you strike?
- At once.
- Throw everything we have at them.
- They're hoping you'll do that.
On horse they outnumber us 2-to-1 .
You'll lead the men straight to their deaths.
- So we do nothing?
- Donnchadh would like that even more...
me to lose face in front
of the other tribes.
No. We must act.
It must be decisive.
But we cannot act alone.
So have the good men of York
come to fight with us?
Hmm? Or the Saxons of Wessex?
My men don't want
to follow a Pict into battle...
let alone one leading
a pack of Angles and Celts.
Then why are you here?
I thought Tristan
should let me command his men.
- I make it my habit to follow no one.
- Except Marke?
Marke delivered me from that palace
when I was a boy. You ran.
So you can understand
when I think ofkings, I think ofhim.
- And when I think of cowards-
- [Marke] They're one day from
their boats on the Roman road.
Now, who will ride out
with Tristan to fight them?
What is your plan, Tristan?
I need our two fastest runners.
- [Man] There they go! After them!
- [Whinnies]
Hold off.
Halt!
Go around!
[Whinnies]
Morholt! They're back.
- [Laughing]
- They've got a head.
- [Shouting]
- It's a trap!
Kill the slaves!
[Screaming]
[Cracks]
[Horse Shrieks]
- Simon.
- [Grunts]
We're gonna get you home.
Simon.
I don't want to die.
[Exhales]
Tristan.
I can't feel my legs or my hands.
Poison.
A second boat.
Tristan.
[Melot]
He shall have a king's service.
Farewell, Tristan of Aragon.
Death to the Irish.
[Wind Howling]
When the Irish came to Cornwall...
and my father surrendered...
you spared a dozen out of a hundred.
I am even less kind.
The leader and three
will take this message home.
As for the rest-
- [Thunderclap]
- [Chattering]
Victory.
And Tristan?
Simon too.
Did I love him like a son...
- or did I misuse him for my own purposes?
- He knew.
[Sniffles]
He knew.
[Wind Howling]
- [Flapping]
- [Gasps]
- Where are we going?
- Away.
Are you afflicted, child?
Speak to me.
Your father will find us
and have my head.
You are my charge. Please.
I am no one's charge.
You are.
And you will be Morholt's lady.
And live a loveless life like my mom?
What's that?
Where?
Isolde, wait. Don't.
[Speaking Foreign Language]
Isolde, don't.
- Isolde!
- It's a man.
Dead?
Alive! Bragnae, help me!
- [Foreign Language]
- Help me!
- Isolde.
- Quickly!
[Grunting]
Start a fire.
- Oh.
- Quickly.
His heart falters.
- What are you doing?
- He needs heat. Now.
Get your clothes off, quickly.
Hurry.
Quickly! Smell that?
Smell the poison?
When he warms,
we'll need thistle and bark.
I've not been naked
with a man for 15 years.
[Isolde]
Hello.
You've been sleeping a long time.
You're in Ireland.
Did you know that?
Shh.
It's all right.
You're safe here. No one knows.
Don't be scared.Just sleep.
Sleep.
[Hoofbeats Approaching]
Oh.
[Screams]
- No!
- It's all right. You don't need that.
I forgot to tell him about you.
I'll wait outside
with the other beasts.
- You said no one else knew.
- Sorry.
She's my maid, sworn to silence.
Um, lie down, please.
Please?
It's good you're remembering things.
This might sting.
Do you remember anything else?
The boat I found you in?
How you got this?
Too many questions.
There. Keep that dry.
Here are clothes, bread.
You have water and fire.
The ocean's outside
if you wish a bath.
You won't know where you're going,
so please don't try to leave.
Just trust me.
Why are you doing this?
I'll be back.
This is a dangerous game
you're playing.
- He's English, Isolde.
- And we've got him prisoner.
Under no circumstances
tell him your name, you hear me?
I thought you wished
to escape this place.
Did you hear me?
- [Whispering] You'll do no such thing.
- He'll need more food tomorrow.
He's not of your concern.
- You've been away.
- Oh, you noticed.
- Yes, I have a bit.
- Where?
Bragnae and I were spying
the convent at Brittas.
- Seeking sanctuary?
- Some women need it.
You'll find no refuge
in the new religion.
Your place is here, with Morholt.
Any word of my betrothed?
Overdue.
But comforted, no doubt,
that you yearn for him.
[Wind Howling]
What's your name?
Oh, I think it's better
we don't bother with names.
How can I thank you
if I don't have your name?
You just did.
If you insist, my name is Bragnae.
I'm a lady-in-waiting at the court.
My parents are dead.
My mother, she's the source
of the kindness you find so puzzling.
My father would have
left you where you fell.
I'm Tristan of Aragon.
Well, Tristan of Aragon...
I'd guess about you too,
but I think I've already seen everything.
Sir, I hope you appreciate the risks...
we are taking and will honor us
by leaving as soon as you are able.
She likes me.
She's right though. You do risk.
Here. And what of your parents?
[Clears Throat]
They also died when I was a child.
Of what?
A different type of Irish kindness.
I'm sorry.
Tomorrow then?
Tomorrow.
[Isolde] "There she who bore you
brought you forth.
"Set me as a seal upon your heart...
"as a seal upon your arm...
for love is as strong as death."
Ridiculous.
I happen to believe what that says.
Don't you think there's more to life?
- [Tristan] Than what?
- Something more than duty and death.
Why be capable of feelings
if we're not to have them?
Why long for things
if they're not meant to be ours?
Oh, don't listen to me.
You're so sure of things.
Your certainty, it's-it's like armor.
I wish I had that.
- Why would you need it?
- The joy of being a lady.
Wanting something I can't have-
a life of my own.
Time you must leave now.
I'll follow you later.
You need a rest...
in case your betrothed
would want to see you.
[Door Opens, Closes]
You're promised?
Yes.
What's he like?
Dark, tall, nearly twice your size.
An absolute gentleman.
I thought...
earlier when you spoke
of wanting something you can't have-
I didn't know what
I was talking about.
Outside, just past that bluff,
there is a boat.
That's how you should go
when you leave.
You should go soon.
[Sighs]
How do you feel?
I don't know.
[Kisses]
[Chattering]
[Man]
It's Lord Bodkin!
[Groans]
Tristan! They found your boat.
At this very moment,
the king himself is scouring the coasts.
He'll find you. He finds everyone.
The tide is coming. You must go.
Come with me.
- Come with me.
- I can't.
Why not? Please.
Tristan, we both know this can't be.
We've known it from the start.
That doesn't mean
it isn't true. It is.
It just cannot be.
I want to know that you're alive somewhere
and thinking of me from time to time.
I want to know that there's more to this life,
and I can't know that if they kill you.
Please.
Go.
A Cornish warrior may be ashore.
Beware. We seek him as I speak.
Hopefully, it's just
his rotted corpse we'll find...
for he has slain your betrothed.
Morholt is dead, fallen in battle.
Isolde?
Bragnae, catch and comfort her.
- She is stunned.
- As am I by her grief.
We should, uh-We should assault
the British straightaway.
Crush them with maximum force.
Maximum force?
The one butchered by Marke's tribes?
Would that be the force you speak of?
We'll not confront them again
until our numbers are refreshed.
And until then...
we'll have cunning divide them.
Of what nature?
A prize, perhaps.
What's this about a tournament?
Donnchadh.
He's offered his daughter
and the lands of Lionath...
as dowry to whichever
English tribe wins.
It's a clever way of setting us
against each other.
Well, the other barons
will see through that.
As baron of Wessex...
it's my duty to fight in this tournament
for my people.
- For yourself, you mean.
- And what of the support you promised Tristan?
Tristan's dead.
My people have suffered enough.
They see the wealth of Lionath on offer.
That seems more real than any alliance.
- My mind is set.
- And ours as well.
So be it.
You're weary. Let me rally our friends.
I'll lead them against Donn-
Melot, Melot, Melot,
Melot, Melot.
You're my blood...
and you're a noble presence, but-
[Man Shouting]
- [Man #2] He's back!
- [Woman] He's alive!
- Tristan!
- We thought you weren't alive.
He's back! Lord Marke, it's Tristan!
It can't be.
I saw you dead.
I am delivered.
How?
[Crying]
[Chattering, Laughing]
##[Folk]
[Man]
Please, Tristan, tell us more.
Tristan, there must be a story.
A toast to Tristan...
- back from the dead.
- [Man] Yeah, back from the dead.
Tristan, the Irish king offers his daughter
in tournament and divides all our tribes.
Whether for the power
or the wealth, half the barons...
- are sending champions to fight at Dunluce.
- Tristan.
God knows what happened to him.
[Isolde's Voice]
"My face in thine eyes...
"thine in mine appears.
"And true plain hearts
do in the faces rest.
"Whatever dies was not mixed equally.
"If our two loves be one...
"or thou and I love so alike...
that none can slacken,
none can die. "
- [Marke] What?
- It's the only way to keep the alliance alive.
I fail to see how fighting
with our partners keeps us allies.
Well, they're all going
to the tournament anyway.
By announcing you'll share the dowry
with every baron who remains loyal...
while in turn offering support
to whomever prevails...
- the others will be compelled
to follow you when you win it.
- If we win.
If we lose, we could end up
following Wictred.
I'd need an infallible champion.
- Me.
- [Laughs]
You're not yet healed.
Well, this trip will be my tonic.
I'll be ready.
You know I will.
What's the source of this fervor?
Let me go and win you a wife.
She can make peace
without spilling one drop of blood.
And maybe heal the wound
from which you still ache.
[Chattering]
Truce.
You have safe passage.
[Swords Clanging]
You'll all go over there.
- How do I look?
- How do you look?
Where's this princess?
What's her name, Isolde?
I want to see what she looks like.
[Door Opens]
There. Almost done.
No, not quite.
If I'm a present, I should be fully wrapped.
- Name?
- Lebourne of Bracht.
[Man Laughing]
I don't believe you.
- [Man #2] It's true.
- [Rattles]
Name?
Ah, see how the bees
come to the honey.
- Name?
- Tristan of Aragon.
- So he lives.
- For the moment.
Name?
- [Purse Rattles]
- Name?
Wictred of Glastonbury.
I fight with no champion in my stead.
Note that.
Why Wictred?
[Donnchadh] Because the barons
will never unite behind him.
- [Horn Blows]
- [Cheering, Applause]
You think she's got the pox?
[Cheering]
Since the dawn of time...
the knight has gathered
at tournaments.
Here he sharpens his skills,
settles his differences...
and proves his worthiness before God...
for only a true heart
can prevail in battle.
Warriors, begin!
[Cheering, Applause]
He's got him now.
- Make it look real.
- What?
I yield!
[Grunts]
Real enough, I hope.
- [Swords Clanging]
- [Booing]
[Whistling]
Water? You did great.
[Laughs]
- Yeah! [Laughs]
- Look.
- No!
- Hey! You can't do that!
- [Booing]
- Allow it.
- [Groans]
- [Laughing]
[Announcer]
Hunwalt yields to Tristan of Aragon.
##[Folk]
Antwon of Wessex
will fight Kingsid.
- Hey!
- It's too easy for you, eh?
- Good, Tristan! Good!
- So much for a fair draw.
- Lord Wictred of Glastonbury-
- Be sure. Choose the right time.
- Wear him down first, huh?
- [Announcer] Tristan of Aragon
will fight Singbard.
Hallach yields to the Lord Wictred.
Yeah!
[Cheering]
Singbard yields to Tristan of Aragon.
[Swords Clanging]
Kingsid yields to Antwon of Wessex.
Lord Wictred of Glastonbury
will fight Fohall.
- [Booing]
- Fohall yields...
- [Cheering]
- to Lord Wictred.
Anwalt yields to Tristan of Aragon.
Lord Wictred of Glastonbury
will fight Morlock.
- Mace.
- Tristan of Aragon...
from the house of Cornwall,
will fight Hunwalt.
- [Screams]
- [Booing]
Morlock yields to Lord Wictred.
- [Cheering]
- Hunwalt yields to Tristan of Aragon.