1 ! 2! 3!
Hello.
Okay.
Shaina from Mumbai.
Let her hold.
Kill her.
Yes! Give me.
Don Gani..
Yes, Shaina, tell me.
Don Gani, l was trying to
contact you. - Yes, go ahead.
Golden has been murdered and there
is a blood bath happening here.
You guys don't do anything.
l'm coming to Mumbai
the day after tomorrow.
Tony here. Gani is coming to
Mumbai the day after tomorrow.
Confirmed?
Hundred per cent.
'To rein in the crime in Mumbai..'
'..the government has roped
in the lG of Punjab police..'
'..Mr. Ashraf Taufiq
Khan and appointed him..'
'..the new police
commissioner of Mumbai.'
'He will hold a meeting with
top police officials today.'
Who is this Golden?
He's a big name in
Mumbai underworld.
Two third of Mumbai is
controlled by Golden and his gang.
Kidnapping, contract killing,
extortion, land grabbing.
This is what the gang does.
This gang is run by a
person called Gani, not Golden.
He operates this
gang from outside lndia.
Don Gani.
Yes, tell me.
Yourjob will be done.
We got information from
the intelligence report..
..that in the terrorist
attack on Mumbai last week..
..Gani used his local gang
to help the terrorists..
..come via the sea route.
He never stays in the
country for too long.
That's why he has not
been caught till now.
And who is Datta Pawale?
Datta Pawale used
to be work for Gani.
Tie him to a rock and throw him in.
He built his own gang.
He does the same kind of
work as Golden's gang.
But on a smaller scale.
His right hand's name is Shiva.
He operates in the
area around Versova.
Every other day there's
a gang war between them.
Some from the police department
are hand-in-glove with them.
And both gangs have
political support.
We arrest them in the morning.
But they get released by evening.
Come on. Get in.
Unless we finish the Mumbai
underworld and these local gangs..
..this city can't be safe
from foreign terrorists.
'The moment Ashraf
Khan took charge..'
'..he started
operations against the mafia.'
'ln the past 48 hours more than
200 goons have been arrested..'
'..and eight dangerous
goons have been shot dead.'
'Because of Commissioner
Ashraf's tough stand..'
'..against the Mumbai underworld,
the gangsters are really frightened.'
'Ashraf Khan says it's his
dream to make Mumbai crime free.'
'And to do this, he
will not worry about..'
'..political or
bureaucratic pressure.'
We have to take care of a man.
Who?
Genghis.
The one from Ghatkopar? - Yes.
We have to beat him
up in his locality.
Money.
Which one of you will beat him up?
Radhe.
He's wanted.
ls he any good?
He's more ruthless than Rambo.
More destructive than Terminator.
Smarter than Rocky and
Quicker than Bruce Lee.
He's the last action hero.
Stop!
Nab him!
You scoundrel! Stop there!
Stop!
He's wanted.
The stuff is here brother.
They are just too many.
Go get some more money.
Okay. Excuse me.
Move aside.
Hey! Who are you?
You won't get beaten up
without knowing my name?
So you've taken the
contract to beat me up?
Once l take a contract,
l don't listen to myself even.
You fool. Can't you see
how many men are with me?
Pigs always hunt in groups.
And a tiger hunts alone.
Shankar, pull down the shutters.
Brother.. Keep it slightly open.
He might find it
useful while escaping.
Stop!
Move aside!
You'll die today.
You've made a big mistake
by throwing away the key.
Hey, what will you do? What?
l swear on your mother.
Today, you won't be able to crawl
out of here, let alone walk out.
You're swearing on my mother?
Now that l've sworn on her..
You swore on my mother..
l'll keep it.
You..
Brother.
l'll break the lock
as well as yourjaw.
No! No!
My charisma.
l want the magic.
Here and there.
One. Two. Three. Four.
Break it down.
Here and there.
lt will be all
around the world. What!
My charisma..
Here and there.
lt will be all
around the world. What?
My charisma..
All rise.
With the rhythm and the beats.''
So high.
This is my charisma.
Do the rock and roll some night.
All rise.
To the rhythm and the beats.
so high.
This is my charisma.
Do the rock and roll some night.
Charisma..
Just magic.
l don't know to
go back on my word.
Friends, it's a promise
l'll die fulfilling my promise.
l have a unique way of living.
l have a different style.
My charisma..
One. Two. Three. Four.
Break it down.
My charisma..
Yes. Yes. Yes, Charisma..
Will you work for me?
Come on, sit inside.
Charisma..
That's right.
Let me show you how to
make the world bow to you.
lf you're courageous like me,
the world will be afraid of you.
Be it a storm or a hurricane.
nothing can stand in front of me.
My charisma..
One. Two. Three. Four.
Here and there.
lt will be all
around the world. What!
Your charisma..
All rise.
To the rhythm and the beats.
So high.
This is your charisma.
Charisma..
Do the rock and roll some night.''
All rise.
To the rhythm and
the beats. ''So high.''
This is my charisma.
Charisma..
Do the rock and roll some night.''
Do the rock and roll.
Come on, do your magic.
Hello, tell me..
Hey, stupid. Why did you disturb me?
Prabhudheva and Govinda had
joined me in celebrations.
Blasted them.
Sir, please check your iPod.
l'll be right back.
Where are you going?
l'm going to meet my cousin.
She lives in the neighbourhood.
She's throwing me glances.
What kind of a girl
will be interested in you.
She's a cat.
Really?
Someone like me won't get a
Miss World or Miss Universe.
l have only one principle.
Try to woo the least
beautiful girl in the group.
She gets enticed quickly.
And she won't betray you in love.
You fool. lf you
run after the girl..
..the girl will take
your money and run.
lf you chase money,
the girl will chase you.
Excuse me!
l don't agree with you.
Don't look at my face.
Look in my eyes.
There's so much truth in them.
Your eyes express what
your heart wants to say.
Right.
l love you very much.
ls it?
Really?
You love me, too, don't you?
Then, why don't you express it?
l'm scared.
You're in love. Don't get scared.
When you're in
love why get scared?
You've loved, it's no..
That was superb!
'Thank you. lf you
record a video like this ..
.. and give it to your boyfriend..'
'..he'll be crazy about you.'
What l was saying is..
lt will be done.
Brother!
Yes.
Who was the girl on TV?
She's a customer.
Oh, Really?
Yes, sir. Her
handycam was not working.
The cassette got stuck. So
we were just checking it out.
Okay. Go on. - Hello. Yes.
You'll get it by 4 o'clock.
When you're in love,
why get scared?
How much?
5000,Your Highness.
When you're in love,
why get scared?
We are in love and not thieves.
Thank you.
Why to sigh in solitude?
When you're in love, why
get scared? -Radhe! Radhe!
Radhe! Radhe!
What happened to you?
You we-re going to
meet your cousin, right?
Then go on.
lf she has two more cousins,
then take them along.
Dad, money..
What?
l don't want it.
Where were you all these days?
No phone call. No message.
Do you think this is a guesthouse?
You come and leave
whenever you feel like. Get up!
Don't look at girls. Okay?
Absolutely.
When you're in
love why get scared?
We're in love and are not thieves.
Why to sigh in solitude?
When you're in
love why get scared?
l'm working till date.
And you're ruining your
life with your loafer friends.
Excuse me, sir.
Yes.
Some boys are peeping
in through the window.
lt's uncomfortable.
l'm coming.
Thank you, sir.
Hey! What's going on?
We're learning aerobics.
Straighten up!
Now.
Shut up!
All perverts!
What are you looking at?
Take away these goons.
And don't bring them
here again. ldiots!
You'll get me in trouble.
Let's go. Come on.
He is too much. You
don't know or what?
Girls like these, do
things like this for us.
Check if he has gone.
He's gone.
What are you doing? Look
who is doing better? Me or her?
Let me do it. Let me do it.
Are you crazy? Please.
Let me do it. Put me down.
Good morning, sir.
Lakshman Dongre.
lt's my first day on duty, sir.
Why do you want to be a policeman?
For money? - No, sir. l
want to serve my country.
l want to work as a policeman
and get a medal from the president.
Can you shoot? - l'm the
gold medallist of my batch.
Pick up that rifle.
Yes, sir.
Load it.
lt's loaded, sir.
Now take aim and shoot me. - Sir?
Come on, shoot.
You'll die, sir.
All right. then l'll shoot you.
Fine. Shoot this.
One. Two.
Shoot!
What happened gold medalist.
How did you miss?
l don't know, sir.
The rifle we are given
during training is brand new.
The barrel is straight and
so is the body, isn't it?
And the service weapon that we get..
..is like some old used junk.
The barrel is not straight
and the body is quite loose.
The bullet is released,
but we miss the target.
Do you understand?
lf you know how to shoot
at point blank range..
..only then join the department.
Got it? - Yes.
Go on. The school is over.
Sir, someone's here to meet you.
To hell with him!
Send him in.
Tell me.
Sir, my name is Ashok Gulati.
l'm a builder. And l've
bought a plot in Worli.
A local goon has been troubling me.
He tells me to either give him
protection money or stop the work.
What's his name?
Dilip Topi.
Who is he? You may go Mr. Gulati.
l'll handle him.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Yes, Mr. Talpade.
Did You threaten Gulati builder?
l told him to give me Rs.1
million or else l'll finish him.
You're behaving like a beggar.
Tell him to pay up Rs.2.5
million or else you'll finish him.
All right, boss.
ldiot.
Sister! Sister, your boyfriend
is coming here all dressed up.
Go away. Go on!
Hi!
Had he not been our landlord,
l wouldn't have taken him in.
Aunt!
What are you doing?
Aunt, l'm fed up of
the girls of this colony.
Look, another girl has sent
me a love letter. Read it.
How can l read a letter sent to you?
Please.
Give it to me. l'll read it.
What are you doing? You shouldn't..
Let him read it.
'To the young, charming and
handsome hero of our colony.'
'Sonu Gates.'
'Hi, dude. You don't
know how much l love you.'
'The way you walk.
The way you dress up.'
'And your cute muscles
have driven me crazy.'
Read it quickly.
'All the girls in the colony are
crazy about you, let alone me.'
'For God's sake, don't lose
your heart to anyone else but me.'
'l can't sleep at night..'
Enough!
Just imagine, if you're
ashamed to hear all this..
..what would a young and
handsome guy go through?
Do you know how old the girl is?
Only 16.
lf she were of Jahnvi's age,
l would have considered it.
Janu. Janu!
You may not know this, but l know..
..how possessive you're about me.
Okay. l apologise to you on
behalf of those girls. Cool?
Oh, gosh. She's so upset.
Why am l so handsome?
Brother!
Yes, oldie.
Get married quickly. One year
later it wouldn't be of any use.
You smiled and now you're trapped.
Who is Radhe here?
Are you Radhe? Are you Radhe?
Are you him? Speak up!
Hey!
What's going on?
do You know Radhe?
Do you know him?
Lay off!
Now tell me, who is Radhe?
Hey!
Where is Radhe? Move it!
Speak up. Speak up.
Where is Radhe? Who is he?
Speak up! Where is he?
Where is Radhe?
Can't you hear me? Are you Radhe?
Where is Radhe? Where is Radhe?
Excuse me.
Move it! What is it?
You want to meet Radhe?
Yes.
l'm Radhe.
Let go off my collar.
What did you say?
Oh God.
Come on.
Come with us.
Come on, brother.
Come on.
Sit down.
Why Did he ask him To sit?
People are scared
even to look at my men.
But you beat them up.
Hang on.
Yes, Brother.
They don't steal
footwear from a mosque.
The one who needs
them takes them away.
lt's your footwear that's been
stolen, not the Kohinoor diamond.
Go buy another pair from the market.
Do you know why you're still alive?
What? You couldn't get pilaf?
Do one thing. Get
chicken from the market.
Bring some rice. Add water in
a pan and prepare the pilaf.
Cool.
Will you work for me?
No. l only work for Gandhi.
Gandhi? Who is this don?
Shut up. He's talking about money.
Stop doing odd jobs from today.
You got to follow two rules
if you want to work with me.
First. Don't mess with the police.
And second. Never
be afraid of death.
The one who talks about the
police is actually afraid of them.
This is your right hand man?
Hey!
Stop!
l punched your goon in your own den.
This was in reply to
your second requirement.
Don't grab me by my collar again.
l'll do any job that you want.
But l should get half the share.
Hey, hero. You have a great style.
Sister, are you here to
make them your brothers?
Don't worry. l won't
make you my brother.
My name is Shayana.
You play well with the weapon.
l'm a good at shooting also.
He's a resourceful man,
but he's too smart.
it's just your mouth
that's bleeding right now.
Just imagine what will happen later.
Hey stop, stop.
Stop! Stop you, idiot.
Wait here.
You loafers, your father
is getting married? Move on.
Don't you have a college to go to?
Oops! Sorry.
Where are you going?
Who are you?
Police.
We're checking everyone. Clean up.
What's your name?
Jahnvi.
What do you do?
l work at a call centre.
Which call centre?
GCS.
Be careful. Careful.
Where are you going now?
Fitness centre.
You are pretty fit.
There is no need to go there.
Want to go to the police station?
No.
Will you come?
Excuse me!
Write down your address.
Why?
Will you write here or
at the police station?
Write down your
phone number as well.
She's like cocaine.
Hey, take me to the guest house,
not the police station.
Who is this guy
you're going to kill?
One of Datta Pawale's men.
l see.
Yes, tell me. - Pakiya, is
he there? - No, not yet.
Tell me as soon as you see him.
All right. Don't worry.
Do you have a light?
l don't. Now go away.
l said l don't have it..
Whom were you talking to?
What were you talking about?
Speak!
The police are here.
Yes.
Police? The police are here.
What happened, sir? Who is this man?
This is yourjurisdiction. And
you're asking me what happened.
Something's going to
happen here. Find out.
Hey, come on.
He's here.
Get ready.
Darn it.
You take care of him.
l'll handle them.
Hey, stop! Stop!
What's this?
lt's a gun.
What?
l found it there.
Where?
There.
At first l thought it was a toy.
But by its weight l realized
it's real. - is it real? Hey!
Where do you live?
Nearby.
Where are you coming from?
Movie.
Movie?
Hey!
Come here.
Me?
Yes, you. Come here.
Search him.
Let's go.
We're rounding up people.
We'll have to search you.
Sir, may l leave?
Wait a minute.
How long do l have to wait?
l said wait a minute.
But sir, l'll be late.
You're getting late?
You want to go home?
Sir, don't hit me.
are You threatening me?
Are you threatening a policeman?
What wrong did l say?
l'm getting late. My
family is waiting for me.
That's all l said. That's all.
lf you don't shut up then they
will have to wait life long.
Hey, where is the girl?
Sir, she went away.
Went away?
What's happening here? Who is he?
Sir, l was just returning
from a movie. He stopped me.
Someone has been murdered here!
A dead body is lying here!
Gani's men killed Rafiq last night.
They have the support of
that scoundrel MLA Yadav.
He is Gani's stooge.
Gani.
l'll kill him one day.
There will be only one
don in Mumbai. Datta Pawle.
Shoot that MLA. Shoot him!
Hail Sushil Yadav!
Don't get scared. Sit here.
Yes.
Switch it on.
Sir, you..
l shot MLA Sushil Yadav.
Why?
He was a hurdle.
That's why l killed him.
l'll kill anyone who
blocks our path.. like this.
And if police tries to stop us?
Yes.
Police? l'll blow them away.
Write like this.
Yes.
Take my photograph.
Wait.
Ready?
Yes.
lt's a bad, bad, bad world.
Nobody is good in
the world except me.
Oh, priest, please bless me.
Sweetheart..
She's not looking at me.
Your Anarkali.
Hi.
Thank you very much.
What for?
Had you not been there that night,
that inspector would have..
You were very helpful.
Coffee?
No thanks.
l have to go for my class. Aerobics.
l'm fit, ain't l?
Anyway, hi, l'm Jahnvi.
What's your name?
Radhe.
Nice name.
Help! Help!
Hey stop! Don't let him go.
Taxi!
He is bleeding badly, sir.
What can l do?
Fill in the form first.
Pay the fees.
And then we will
start the treatment.
The queue is pretty long sir.
lt will take too much time.
You please start the treatment.
What if there's a long queue?
Don't you understand?
This is the hospital rule.
lt's mandatory.
The rules come first,
then the treatment.
Doctor! Doctor..
Don't touch me.
Yes.
Help! Somebody, help!
Hey, Stop! Stop there.
Don't behave like an illiterate.
Don't get emotional.
We will first stand the queue,
fill the form, pay the fees.
And then get treated.
l'm bleeding pretty badly.
What can l do?
You've laid down these rules.
First come the rules
and then the treatment.
First the treatment
and then comes the rules.
Hold this.
Come on, Son.
Where are You taking him?
We will treat him first sir.
Forms can be filled in later.
Thank you, Doctor. Thank you.
Thanks.
Why did you have to get
violent to get me treated?
The results are in front of you.
Why did that man try to kill you?
l must have beaten him up.
He was only taking revenge.
What do you do anyway?
She's asking such a direct question.
What do you think?
l think you're a hoo..
a hooligan?
Correct.
Why don't you work
somewhere to earn money?
Mother Teresa, who
says l don't earn money?
l can do anything for money.
What do you mean?
l beat up the doctor, didn't l?
Yes.
l take money for such things.
But why?
That's my talent.
People get scared of me.
Self-employment.
Self..
You're wondering whether l'm
a good person or a bad one.
No. no.
No?
Gabbar Singh.
Shall we go, Sambha?
Yes!
Where do you want to go, sir?
Let's go.
How did you call the taxi?
l whistled. Why?
How?
Don't you know how to whistle?
No.
Bring out your tongue a little.
Bring it out. Come on.
A little more.
Now bend it like Beckham.
Great whistle!
Oh, my darling, l can do
anything for your love.
l can fight the world for you.
How do l believe you'll
do everything for me?
Who knows? You'll dump me anytime.
l love you, darling. l can
give my life for you as well.
Take away my heart. Baby,
become mine.
ln return, give me your heart.
Listen to me, baby.
You're young.
Come on, baby. Come on,
baby. Listen to me.
Let's go party.
l've taken lessons in love.
l'll run on the path of love.
Go away. Don't boast so much.
Don't teach me about love.
All day..
Go away.
l'll chase you..
l'll drag you to court.
ln your love, l can
sing the melody backwards.
l'll perform fire
rituals to win you over.
How do l believe you'll
do everything for me?
Who knows? You'll dump me anytime.
l love you, darling. l can
give my life for you as well.
Darling, don't make
me suffer so much.
You have my head,
you may behead me.
Don't talk so much about love.
Go away. Stop chasing me.
Finish the matter.
Why do you break my heart?
Go away.
Why are you upset?
Why do you want to
fall in love with me?
lf l make a mistake,
l'll accept any punishment.
l'll do the sit-ups.
l'll accept the punishment
and then steal your heart.
How do l believe you'll
do everything for me?
Who knows? You'll dump me anytime.
l love you, darling. l can
give my life for you as well.
Come on.
Hey, get up!
Search the house.
Yes, sir.
What's going on?
Raid.
We've got information that
this is a house of ill repute.
Do you understand?
What are you doing?
This is my house.
You've been mistaken. This..
l've been mistaken?
l?
Hey, come here.
Who is she?
my sister.
Who all live here?
Me, my mother and my sister.
And your father?
My father is no more.
Who comes here everyday?
No one.
Then who is that peeping tom?
He is the landlord.
Whenever he comes here, he
troubles us. Just like you.
Come to the other room.
l want to talk to you.
l'm saddened by your condition.
lt must have been
difficult to raise the kids, right?
How do you run the house?
My daughter goes to work.
Where is she?
She hasn't returned yet.
She works the nights?
No. No.
Hey, don't cry. Please.
l can understand your feelings.
You have a young daughter.
You must be worried thinking
how you'd get her married.
Don't worry.
l'll keep her.
She's amazing.
Hey, please.
l'll take care of you too.
You're fine even at your age.
The ruin says it was beautiful once.
Think about it, Laxmi.
lf there's a
policeman in the house..
..will anyone dare
misbehave with you?
Or else the same drug
case or a prostitution case.
Can your family
endure so much bad name?
l know you'll take
the right decision.
Great escape.
Thank you.
Are you the uncle who lives here?
l'm not your uncle. l'm
Sonu Gates. Software Engineer.
You're Jahnvi's watchman from today.
Call me and inform me about..
..who comes here,
who meets her, etc.
Do you understand?
l understand, sir.
l got it.
Hey, come here!
Why are you gossiping over there?
Take the order quickly, or
else l'll cut your wages.
Go on!
Who is Ganesh?
That's me. Why?
And who is she?
Who is she?
As soon as you got married,
you abandoned your mother?
Mother! Mother!
lf you do this again,
l'll break yourjaw.
Radhe, my father. My father.
What's going on?
And what are you doing here?
l had come to meet my friend.
They are your friends?
They are my friends.
So, Ganesh, take
care of your mother.
We'll move.
Did you understand?
Why were they beating you up?
They are my childhood friends.
They beat me up
every time they meet me.
Yes, l saw that.
l saw who was beating whom.
Serve a cold drink
to this gentleman.
Sweetheart! Sweetheart! Sweetheart!
Yes!
Talk to your dad. He
appears out of thin air.
With age everything..
Rots.
But your dad is troubling us.
Hi.
Shopping?
You?
Warning.
Warning?
Sweetheart!
Mister! What?
l wanted to return your Rs.10000.
Rs.10000? When did l give it to you?
You're not Mr. Naren.
You're not? Sorry.
Sweetheart!
Do anything you can. The
lift should stop. - Okay.
The job's done?
lt's done.
Sweetheart! Open the door.
What happened?
Hold on.
Why did the lift stop?
lt will take 10 to 15 minutes.
Have fun, man.
What? An hour?
One hour?
lt will take an hour?
l got it.
lt will take an hour now.
What happened?
Listen.
l hope you've had food.
Yes.
Have you been to the washroom?
Why?
Because you'll get none of it here.
lt will take an hour.
An hour?
We can die of
suffocation in an hour.
lt's a good thing
that you'll die young.
Or else afterwards..
..old age, overweight, grey hair.
Artificial dentures, wrinkles.
And this heavy make-up
to hide those wrinkles.
Hello. Apart from lipstick,
l don't use anything else.
What's this?
Mechanic, the lift is
not working. Come, quickly.
Give him to me.
Come quickly. But the lift
shouldn't start soon. - Yes.
Can l ask you a question?
Shoot. - What's the
name of your girlfriend?
l don't have a girlfriend.
Do you have a boyfriend?
Haven't found someone who
l could call my boyfriend.
What do you want in a boyfriend?
The guy should be well-educated.
He should have a greatjob.
He should be a good human being.
Handsome.. l won't mind if he's not.
That's the only quality l have.
And there is no requirement for it.
Did you say something?
Best of luck.
Check what the problem is.
What kind of a girl do you like?
l could do with any kind of girl.
Wow!
But they have their own long lists.
And l don't fit any of them.
l hate girls.
Sometimes l feel l
should have a boyfriend.
ldiot, as soon as you repair it..
..the lift should
go two floors below.
What is that?
My cell phone is on vibration mode.
l am not sure whether
it will work or not.
Now you may land.
Okay?
Yes. Now. do it Now.
Do it quickly.
Okay?
Okay.
l'm feeling very hot.
Me too.
Vicco Vajradanti?
Yes.
Me too.
Should l show you?
For me.
Okay.
Now this lift will
stop on the ground floor.
When you're in
love why get scared?
We are in love and we are not
thieves. Why to sigh in solitude.
When you're in
love why get scared?
Oh, thank God.
Excuse me.
Sweetheart! , where is he?
Where is that hooligan? Where..
He escaped. Come, Sweetheart!.
l've already paid Don Gani's man.
Who is this Don Gani?
l don't know any Gani.
What did he say? He
doesn't know Don Gani?
l want Rs.2.5 million.
Right now or else..
Hello.
Golden.
Why did you call?
l want a meeting with you.
Why?
Call Radhe for the meeting.
Your men crossed into my area.
Let me take a look at him carefully.
Why are you staring at me?
Do you want to marry
off your sister with me?
l paid you to beat up Genghis.
And now you've
joined hands with them?
l work only for money.
You pay me handsomely.
l'll kill him.
Scoundrel, you're very cunning.
l have two
conditions for the compromise.
First, your men will
not operate in my area.
And second, l want Shiva.
Golden, will you kill me?
You want to kill me?
His photograph got
published in the papers.
Does that make him a hero?
He extorts money in my area and
says he doesn't know Don Gani.
l'm a hero. And l'll
say it in front of you.
Who is this Don Gani?
You..
Golden!
Why are you getting angry?
Sit down. Relax. Just sit down.
Why are you getting angry at him?
He says what l tell him.
Even l don't know your Don Gani.
You've come to meet him
and he has set you up.
Let's finish them all and go.
What did you say?
Look at me and say it.
Hey, tell him what kind
of a man is Datta Pawale.
Stupid! ldiot! Have
you lost it? He's crazy.
You'll kill us? ln our area?
Let go of his collar.
l won't. What will you do?
What will you do?
Don't worry about this
loud mouth. Just say yes.
Who is he to say anything?
What will you do if he says yes?
What will you do?
l have decided.
Who are You To decide anything?
Hey, you're just a new kid.
l've been in this
business for 20 years.
l've killed more than 50.
Why are you looking at him?
tell me quickly. Say Yes.
What can he say? l
say yes. Look here..
Kill him!
No! No!
He says he doesn't know Don Gani.
He doesn't know Don Gani!
Let him go. He has got know.
You fool! Because of you,
all of us would have been dead.
Do you need him?
Will you kill him?
Hey, come on. Get going.
Darn you.
When will the Mumbai police wake up?
Sir, so many people
are being killed..
..and you're giving
such routine answers?
You can't stay silent like this.
lf the media can reach the
gangsters, why can't the police?
The police don't know
anything but to take bribe.
She has come.
Hi.
You're going home?
Yes.
What's in the box?
Pasta.
Let me have it.
lt's empty.
Are you annoyed with me?
l tried to call you several times.
Sometimes it's
switched off and other times..
Which number did you dial?
9821066660
That's not my number. 9894536993.
Three.
l tried your number
several times as well.
lf you want my number.
Just ask for it. l'll give
you a missed call. Feed it in.
They are my friends.
Hello. - Hi.
Oh, sorry.
These Mumbai trains are so shaky.
Yes.
Excuse me.
He is sitting here already.
Who?
My husband.
He has gone to the toilet.
There's no toilet in a local train.
Please get up.
Why?
Get up!
What?
ldiot, don't bug me. Get out
of here or else l'll punch you.
She's such a bully!
Don't panic. Please be seated.
The train on platform number 7 is..
Sister is at home.
Son, don't push like that.
We are men. lt might
hurt our delicate parts.
There must have been pasta
in this lunch-box. - Correct
You are of no use to me, Brother.
Brother? l see. You
mean brother-in-law.
My sister is great, isn't she?
But tell her to call me.
All right.
But only on one condition. - What?
How did you build such a physique?
Are you trying to make fun of me?
No. l'm serious. Give me some tips.
Eat less and go the
toilet many times.
Yes, that's what my sister does.
What?
Yes.
Oh no!
Which song were you playing?
Pasta, pasta, l've fallen in love.
Hi, Laxmi. How are you?
ls your health all right?
Did you talk to Jahnvi about me?
What is it? Why are you silent?
Why are you troubling us like this?
Should l come tonight?
Poor guy.
What..
Sir! Sir, Dilip Topi was
troubling Mr. Gulati, the builder..
..for Rs.2.5 million.
He has been killed in an
encounter near Haji Ali.
But sir, one of our constables
Lakshman Dongre also got killed.
Sir, can you send some
people here? Thank you, sir.
You can keep the Rs.2.5 million.
Do you think l'm a
corrupt policeman?
Sorry. Sorry, sir.
l've never taken a bribe till now.
Got it?
Do a thing.
You're building a
2000 sq ft shop.-Yes.
Gift it to my wife.
Sir, it is worth Rs.25 million.
Will you take 25
million to your grave?
What name should l register it to?
Mrs. Nandini Talpade.
Your sister has a
long life. Look. Look.
Hello, Nandini. Yes.
Live for a thousand years.
Every year should have 50000 days.
ls there a strike? Auto..
Listen!
Halt!
The police is chasing me. - l see.
Don't tell them anything.
But What should l not tell them?
But..
Don't tell them anything.
Follow me.
sir.
Where did he go?
he went that way.
Follow him.
Okay, follow..
Where are you going?
Alright, then..
He's a thief.
Yes, he looked like one.
The police are chasing him.
Yes, he told me.
l saw him whisper
something into your ear from there.
What did he tell you?
He told me not to tell you anything.
Look, l'm an inspector. You
shouldn't lie to the police.-No.
Tell me what he told you.
He just told me not
to tell you anything.
l've been telling you to tell
the truth. What did he tell you?
Sir, l swear he told me
not to tell you anything.
Darn you! The same thing again.
Okay
The same thing again.
Okay. l'll tell the truth.
l'll tell the truth.
That's good. Tell me.
l'll only tell the truth
and nothing but the truth
Sir, he told me not
to tell you anything.
Hey, l'm taking a rest.
Okay.
Yes, ready.
Wait here. l'll be right back.
Did you tell him anything?
Beep! Beep!
He said something to you again.
He did.
What?
No, sir.
You..
No, l'll tell you. l'll tell you.
Give me your ear.
Beep! Beep!
What did you say?
From there!
Hello.
This is your watchman speaking.
Hurry up!
Sir! Sir!
l had told you about
the guy who meets Jahnvi.
He is right here.
Which one? Throw! Throw!
The one who looks
like a hero. That's him.
Pass. Pass. Yes. Yes. Radhe,
over here. Come on. Pass..
Everybody move back.
l have to search this guy.
Didn't you hear me? Move back!
You're the guy who found a
gun in the lane, aren't you?
You gave it back.
Now that you found
the girl, you kept her?
What's this? What is this?
You sell drugs?
You're a drug dealer?
come to the police station with me.
For what?
For this.
Where did it go?
Stop. Stop.
'You're wanted.''
You're a drug dealer?
You sell drugs?
lt's gone.
The headmaster of the school
where you learnt all these tricks..
..comes to learn from me even today.
She's mine. Only mine.
Do you understand?
Yours? She's yours?
She's yours?
The gun l found that night was mine.
Look, l still have the bullets.
Are you threatening me?
You have to
account for every bullet.
l may shoot as many as l want.
l don't have to give any account.
l'll kill you in a
police encounter one day.
Do you think l'm the
constable from your police station?
Should l tell you
how you killed him?
A 2000 sq. ft. shop has been
registered in your wife's name.
l don't want to argue with you.
The construction is on fast track.
Go away.
Air conditioned.
Centrally air conditioned.
Don't follow me. l warn you.
You're using ltalian marble,
aren't you?
Nandini will be very
happy with you. - Go away.
l'll take care of you.
l won't spare you.
You're messing up
with the wrong guy.
Let's go.
l'll take care of you.
Scoundrel!
Let's go. Come on.
Oh, God!
Jahnvi is mine. Only mine.
And l can do anything for her.
Three. Four. Five.
Six. Seven. Eight. One..
Oh God!
What's going on?
Hey, shut up! Shut up!
Who is that boyfriend of yours?
you want a real man?
Am l not good enough?
Did your mom talk to you about me?
You are mine.
He says, ''Jahnvi is mine and
l can do anything for her.''
lf you meet him again,
l'll kill you.
Jahnvi is mine and l
can do anything for her.
Sister, what you're
saying is fine, but..
He's a goon, isn't he?
But he's good at heart.
l'm sure l can change him.
Do you love him so much?
Yes.
All right. But he will have to
bring chocolates for me everyday.
Hello?
Hello..
Hi, would-be mother. How are you.
This is Jahnvi's friend,
Madhuri, speaking.
And this is Radhe's friend,
and your husband, Nene, speaking.
Sorry, this is Jahnvi speaking.
l know.
l want to meet you.
Why?
Actually, l wanted
to meet you because..
Don't beat around the bush.
l wanted to say
something personal to you.
So, can we.. can we..
Love me, love me, love me.
Your mama says you love me.
Papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
Love me, love me, love me.
Mama says you love me.
Your papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
l'd like to spend my
whole life with you.
Love me, love me, love me.
You say love me,
love me, love me. Stop.
l promise l'll be
with you till the end.
Love me, love me, love me.
You say love me,
love me, love me. Stop.
l'd like to spend my
whole life with you.
l promise l'll be
with you till the end.
You are my desire.
You are what l wish for.
l'm in front of you.
You can ask for my life.
Love me, love me, love me.
Your mama says you love me.
Papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
Love me, love me, love me.
Mama says you love me.
Your papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
You're my future.
You're my destiny.
l don't like anyone else but you.
My sweetheart. My darling.
l can't love anyone else but you.
lt's your name on my
lips all the while.
None of my dreams are
without you in them.
You are my desire.
You are what l wish for.
l'm in front of you.
You can ask for my life.
Love me, love me, love me.
Your mama says you love me.
Papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
Love me, love me, love me.
Mama says you love me.
Your papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
My darling. My beloved.
You kindled love in my heart.
My darling, this is true..
..but love has thrilled our lives.
My heart has gone
out of my control.
You don't think
before you fall in love.
You're my desire.
You're what l wish for.
l'm in front of you.
You can ask for my life.
Love me, love me, love me.
Your mama says you love me.
Papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
Love me, love me, love me.
Mama says you love me.
Your papa says you love me.
Then love me, baby. Love me.
You wanted to meet me. Here l am.
l've been sitting here like
a stone since half an hour.
What do you want to say?
l just wanted to say to you..
..that you don't have
any qualities that l like.
Still, l don't know why l
think of you all the time.
Whenever l asked my
heart who's my Mr. Right..
..it took your name.
By now, you must have
guessed what l want to say.
So, why don't you say it first?
l'd like it.
Yes, l love you.
But l haven't said
it to you until now..
..because l'm not worthy of you.
Why?
l don't know myself
how big a scoundrel l am.
But l like you very much.
Think again.
Once l commit something, l
don't listen to myself even.
Close your eyes.
Just close your eyes.
l love..
No.
No..
No!
They must have
finished Radhe by now.
Take the call, rascal!
Rascal!
You thought l was a petty thief.
l'm a murderer.
Would you still
say that you love me?
Listen, l love you.
You think about it again.
Jahnvi, don't you
want to go to office?
'Our sources have informed us..'
'..that in a shoot-out
between two gangs..'
'..12 dead bodies have been found.'
'Police are trying to find out
which gang they belonged to.'
'Mumbai Commission
Ashraf Khan has given..'
'..shoot-at-sight orders
to his special forces.'
He's assured that very soon he'll..
..investigate about
the gangs in Mumbai.
Hello.
Did you kill Datta Pawale's men?
Yes.
He's crazy! He's totally mad!
Why?
They started it. l finished it.
Do you know what has
been the reaction to this?
Datta Pawale has killed Golden.
Hey, what happened?
What happened?
You're his next target.
Stop! Stop!
Will you never change?
Today, again you
You know l love you very much.
Yes, so what?
l thought after knowing That,
you'd try to change.
Why?
Murder there! - There has
been a murder in the back lane.
What do l do now?
Should l love you or forget you?
Forget me.
How can l forget you?
Then don't forget me.
You know only know to kill.
How many more will you kill?
lf you don't shut up
right now, l'll kill you.
For me, it's not wrong to kill.
You've done the wrong thing
by falling in love with me.
l've just liked a nice girl.
That's it.
Don't play this
emotional drama in front of me.
l'm allergic to tears.
Fine. l won't cry.
Good.
What is your relationship with me?
Hey!
l'll never cry again.
l said that's good.
You took my heart
and gave me heartache.
You said l'm your life
and then took my life away.
You robbed me of my identity.
You said l'm your life
and then took my life away.
l had never thought
you'd come so close to me.
Unknowingly you'll be mine.
You've kindled love in my heart.
Let's walk together..
Let's walk together, my darling.
You took my dreams away.
You robbed me of my identity.
You said l'm your life
and then took my life away.
ln your love l've
begun to cross all limits.
l stopped myself, and yet
l fell in love with you.
Let me hide you in my heart.
Let me lock you
away in my heartbeats.
Let me lock you away in
my heartbeats, my darling.
You took all my desires away.
You said l'm your life
and then took my life away.
Hello.
Don Gani.
Yes, Shaina, tell me. - Boss,
l've been trying to contact you.
Yes, go ahead. Speak.
Golden has been killed and
there is blood bath happening here.
You don't do anything.
l'm coming to Mumbai
the day after tomorrow.
Tony here.
Don Gani is coming to Mumbai the
day after tomorrow. - Confirmed?
Hundred per cent.
Tomorrow, Gani will
come to Lakshwadeep.
He'll reach 'Bhau
Cha Dhakka' by sea.
His men will be
waiting there with a car.
We'll attack him right then.
Tomorrow, that scoundrel
will be in front of me here.
Today, not tomorrow.
l had sent you the
information of my arrival.
Datta Pawale. You used to
handle my work at the docks.
You broke away and now
you're destroying me.
You've become a big man.
Sir.
Yes.
Datta Pawale has been killed.
We've got information
that Don Gani has done this.
Come.
Hello.
Yes, papa is at home. Hold on.
The car can't go from this place.
Make a way from here.
We will have to take
the other route. - Sir.
Papa, phone.
Hello.
Dear, please go inside.
Shrikant, l want to
meet you right now.
Aunt!
Aunt?
Ballu, make Uncle
Sonu sit when he comes..
That fatso is coming now?
lf l see his face,
my day gets ruined.
l'll go away before
that old man comes.
Good morning, Sweetheart!
Sorry, l didn't see you. That's
why l referred you as a fatso.
lt's okay.
l called you a bad omen.
l called you an old man..
Okay.
You said it because you
didn't see me. No problem.
l understand.
You really didn't see me?
l swear.
Cool.
l'll go change.
Darling, you change. l'll take it.
Okay.
Hello.
Who are you?
This is lnspector Talpade.
Sir, this is your watchman speaking.
Watchman, what are
you doing in her house?
l had come to collect the rent.
l'm having tea now.
Pour the tea on your head.
Done, sir.
Now put Laxmi on the line.
Aunt, your call.
Hello.
Laxmi.
lt's an auspicious day today.
l'm coming to spend the
night with your daughter.
Please, don't ruin
my daughter's life.
Stop chasing her.
We are a respectable family.
Darn, l totally forgot.
They are a respectable family.
You get inside.
Who are you?
What are you doing?
Let go!
Let go off my sister!
Mother!
Open the door!
Where are you going?
What are you doing with my daughter?
Jhanavi.
Open the door!
Uncle please save my sister.
Please.
please Let her go.
Let her go.
Open the door!
Let go off me! Let go!
Let go off me! Let go off me!
Save my daughter.
Now people will think
that you've been raped.
Save my daughter!
My dear!
My dear.
What happened? Come on, leave.
Find out what happened here.
And how did it happen?
Yes, sir.
Who was raped? Her?
Sister..
How many were they?
You'll have to tell us
where they touched you..
..to file the first
information report.
Patel.
sir.
Note down. - Sir! - No. We
don't want to file a case.
Go away from here.
You have been disgraced.
Who will marry her now?
Don't worry.
l'm here.
l'll take care of her.
Can you identity them?
Yes.
Hey handsome!
Come if you want, or l am leaving.
Hey, come here.
Sir, pay up.
Add it to my account.
Hey, stop. Stop!
Salute, sir.
Pay me protection money.
Sir, this week the
business was down, so..
Get going. Go!
A thorn pricked me.
Hey! Who is it?
Who is it? Who was it?
Stop.
Scoundrel!
Who is it? Who was it?
Who is it?
Hello.
Scoundrel!
l just suspected it, so l
shed some of your blood.
The day it is confirmed..
..there'll be no
blood left in your body.
Who are you?
Radhe.
Everyone is praising you.
Except him.
l hear you carry out dangerous
jobs with the snap of your fingers.
You look like a romantic hero.
And you look like a
villain in a B-grade Hindi movie.
You have no idea how
villainous l can be.
What will you drink?
Nothing.
Don't be scared. Have it.
Liquor and blood. l
take it when l want it.
No holds barred.
He is exactly as you had told me.
Are you hurt? Then smile.
Don't shout.
lf you'd like to be a goon.
So, you're a rough guy.
And crazy as well.
You'll take
Golden's place from today.
You have to eliminate central
minister. This is your firstjob.
On 14th November, Children's day..
..the minister is
coming as a chief guest.
Blow him away with a bomb.
And the kids?
What kids?
Those who will be
around the minister.
Kill them. This is my style.
l don't kill women and kids.
Why?
That's my style.
lf you don't do it,
Genghis will do it.
Even if he were Genghis Khan,
l wouldn't allow him to do it.
Hey!
Arrogance.
Such ego.
l like it.
Bring it down.
You'll be very successful.
Or else you'll go up there.
Think about it.
Once l commit to something, l
don't listen to myself even.
Pour ke lo se (Spanish).
Everybody come on let's do baila.
Pres do se uno (Spanish).
Pour ke lo se (Spanish).
Everybody come on let's do baila.
Pres do se uno (Spanish).
Aami tambe tambie faenite siem
pere kare verme sua (Spanish).
No way no way karaye (Spanish).
Emsu thrampa
thrampa vez (Spanish).
Aami tambe tambie faenite siem
pere kare verme sua (Spanish).
No way no way karaye (Spanish).
Emsu thrampa
thrampa vez (Spanish).
Enjoy to the fullest.
Make the most of the night.
Make the most of today.
lt is a moonlit night.
There's a secret in the
intoxication of the night.
There's opportunity.
There's excitement. Have fun.
Time is with us tonight.
Enjoy to the fullest.
Make the most of the night.
Make the most of today.
Enjoy to the fullest.
Do re me pha sota te to.
Let's get engrossed in each other.
We should be
oblivious of the world.
No matter how l spend my life.
l live my life on my own terms.
Enjoy to the fullest.
Make the most of the night.
Make the most of today.
Enjoy to the fullest.
lt is a moonlit night.
There's a secret in the
intoxication of the night.
There's opportunity.
There's excitement. Have fun.
Time is with us tonight.
Enjoy to the fullest.
Make the most of the night.
Make the most of today
Enjoy to the fullest.
Shit!
Come.
Ashraf Khan, you've made the
biggest mistake of your life..
..by arresting me.
lt's not a mistake.
lt's my life's
ambition to punish you.
You don't want to punish me.
You want something else.
You want to cut a deal with me?
l'm giving you an opportunity.
You offer namaz five
times a day, don't you?
l kill five people
at that same time.
Look at my hand.
lt is very charitable.
With this hand,
l've made millionaires..
..out of honest policemen.
Shake hands with me.
l'll make you filthy rich.
You've not faced a
strict police officer yet.
The moment you come across
an honest police officer..
..you'll wet your pants.
lt's not wet.
ls it wet?. Then?
Listen, you fool.
You're only a police
commissioner of Mumbai.
l'm an international don.
Higher ranking
officers than you salute me.
l salute only the lndian Tricolour,
not a scoundrel like you.
You'll salute this
scoundrel one day.
l will. l'll surely salute you.
Listen, he's a big don.
See to it that he
is served properly.
Fulfil every wish of his,
but don't let him sleep.
Break his bones if
he tries to sleep.
l won't sleep.
My eyes will be open even if l die.
Sir.
Have You arrested Don Gani?
No, sir. How can l arrest Gani?
Not even lnterpol can do it.
Quiet!
l won't rest till l arrest him.
As soon as l arrest him,
l'll inform you.
Sir.
He said he didn't.
What?
He..
The minister had called.
Nobody should know that he's here.
Okay?
sir.
Hello.
Hello. Yes, This is Gani speaking.
Over here.
lncoming free. No outgoing.
Latest stuff.
Keep an eye on him. Understand?
Okay, sir.
What's this nonsense?
Commissioner didn't
put Gani behind bars.
These high level tricks
are hard to understand.
Brother, do you want the
friend or the girl? - girl.
Yes, tell me.
Where are you?
Outside Andheri post office.
No. You're nearby.
l feel you're looking at me.
l'm at the post office.
lf l truly love you,
then you're here.
Brother, what are you eating? Pilaf?
No, tobacco. Want some?
Find one more friend. He'll be
helpful while carrying your coffin.
You can have it then.
So this is Andheri post office?
Go straight and take a right.
lt's near the railway station.
You said you're not here.
How would someone who
only knows to kill..
..understand someone's feelings?
lf you really love me,
you'd understand this.
Do you love someone?
l did till now. But now l don't.
You are getting angry on a joke.
Would l dream that you are around?
This is why l hate you.
l hate you.
Why are you harassing me?
Go on. lt's time for
your aerobics class.
Vent your anger over there.
Aslam.
Yes.
ls your girl like her?
How?
Emotional.
Having a girlfriend is a bad thing.
Waste of time.
You'd better have a
pet than a girlfriend.
l'll do just what you said.
l'll never meet you again.
Tell her to go.
She keeps appearing
like advertisements on TV.
Tell her.
she already left.
She didn't leave. She is fuming.
Scoundrel! Why did you
come back to Mumbai?
What's your plan?
Speak! Answer me!
The plan is in my head.
Let go of my hair.
You may be a big don for the world..
..but you're nothing for me.
l can kill you like this.
Then do it.
Kill me. Why don't you?
l'll tell you what you can do.
At the most you can
present me in court. That's it.
Nothing else.
You know what l'll say in court?
l'll tell the court that Amitabh
Bachchan is a good friend of mine.
And Shah Rukh Khan is
my business partner.
We had met at a wedding in London.
l have video evidence.
lt's different that l
have no relations with them.
But it will take ten
years to prove this in court.
Yes.
What are you thinking?
lt's not too late.
Cut a deal.
Scoundrel!
You talk of striking
a deal all the time.
Did you strike a deal with
your mother to bring you out?
l was too small. l don't remember.
l think he's very angry with me.
lt is Churchgate local..
Hey let's go!
Where are you going?
lt will stop on all the stations.
Oh you missed the catch.
Hot tea! Hot tea!
Sir, would you like some hot tea?
Chhotu, give me a cup of tea.
Yes.
Go away!
Don't sell tea here.
Hot tea. Hot tea.
l've been sitting
here since a while.
The train has been delayed.
ls it my fault?
Why are you doing this to me?
Why don't you give it all up?
Why don't you leave
your loafer friends?
They are my friends.
They are not like cigarettes that
you throw after you're done smoking.
l'm not a balloon that you let
go after filling it with air.
Balloon?
l mean l'm not a chewing gum..
..that you open it,
chew it and spit it out.
When did l open it?
When did l chew it?
You talk about spitting it?
What have you done for me till now?
Pasta. Pasta. The whole
family lives on pasta.
Have you ever asked me?
Listen, have some pasta.
No.
You want to spend your life with me?
Do you know how l live?
l live on snacks.
Then eat. Eat me. Eat me!
l don't like meat
which has too much fat.
Eat it. Have some pasta!
Gani, my friend. Don't sleep.
They will kill you.
They will..
Why are you staring at me?
Strike a deal for me
with the commissioner.
Go on. Talk to him.
l'll give you whatever you want.
Just get me out of here.
Scoundrel.. you don't listen to me.
The world is sleeping.
So is the sky.
l've found out about Don Gani.
This is his passport to freedom.
Commissioner's daughter.
l had seen itjust two days back.
What are you doing?
Who are you?
Help me! Please help me!
Let me go!
Let go!
l say let me go!
Sir, the courier delivered this.
Check what is it.
l've couriered a CD to you.
View it. l'll hold
the line till then.
Play it.
No!
Hey, you scoundrel!
l'll finish you all!
Shut up!
lf you don't release Gani..
..the whole world will see this
CD on TV, internet and cell phone.
Do you get me?
Scoundrel! Don't spare him.
The commissioner will not sleep
peacefully from now on. - Yes, boss.
Scoundrel! The CD
should be all over.
Let me see.
lt's superb.
Look at this. New stuff.
lt's great.
Tell you husband to keep
his mouth shut. Understand?
lf he takes any action
or orders an enquiry..
..we'll kill you daughter.
Being a woman, you don't
respect another woman.
What kind of a woman are you?
Hey!
What?
You..
Let him go.
Radhe, Let him go.
Radhe, let him go!
Radhe.
Let him go!Let go.
Radhe, let him go.
Rascal, l'll..
Let him go! Radhe, let him go!
Let go.
Radhe, let him go!
Let me go!
We had great fun today.
Yes.
Sit quietly.
Hey, move it!
Yes, tell me. - Where are
the babe and the boy going?
Shorty, where are you going?
Don't touch me.
Hey, don't trouble my sister.
l know all three of you.
You had come to our
house and troubled my sister.
So?
And you're troubling us
again in this moving train?
What? What did you say?
Smarty, you talk too much.
We'll be at Andheri
station in a moment.
Watch what l do then.
Just shut up!
What will You do?
Fatso, what will you do?
Why are you hitting me?
You will stop us?
Look, we're at Andheri station.
Now speak.
Now watch what happens.
ls that him?
You'll beat us up?
Do you have the guts?
Look, the don of Andheri. Scoundrel!
More than the goons
l'm afraid of you.
l don't know whether
you're good or bad.
All l know is that l love you.
Sweetheart, Radhe is the
right guy for you, not me.
Forget me if you can.
He's the right guy.
No! Let me go please!
Let me go!
Let go. Papa!
What is it? Who is shouting?
Commissioner's daughter.
Your father dishonoured me in jail.
Now my men will rape you.
l want to hear her scream.
Okay, sir.
My papa won't spare you.
None of you will live.
One of his officers
is your gang member.
He'll finish you.
What did you say?
Tell me, who is he?
Who is he? Answer me!
Speak! Tell me, who he is.
Who is he?
Shrikant..
Shrikant? Shrikant..
Tell me more.
Shekhawat..
Shekhawat. What does he do?
What does he do?
Retired police officer.
tell me more.
Speak further.
Darn it!
Call up Talpade.
Shrikant Shekhawat.
Hello. Yes, Don.
Yes, Who is he?
He's a retired inspector.
l know.
His son is undercover.
More! More! Give me the details!
There are no more
details in the file.
Nobody in the
department knows about him.
l've only found his photograph.
Fax it to me! Right now!
Shaina, take the girl
away and wait for my call.
Hello, Mr. Shrikant Shekhawat.
My name is Shamshuddin Asgar Gani.
Pet name Don Gani.
The whole world craves to meet me.
And l've
personally come to meet you.
Ask me why.
l want to play a game with you.
Shall we start?
What's your son's name?
First clue. He's an undercover cop.
Fine. Second clue.
The undercover cop.
You still don't remember?
Bad contestant.
Third clue.
l see. You remember now.
So you're Rajveer Shekhawat.
Yes, you scoundrel!
l am. What will you do?
Don Gani!
Gani, kill me if you
have to. Not him. Not him.
You were dreaming of arresting me.
l won't arrest you. l'll
kill you, you scoundrel!
Quiet! Quiet.
l beg you.
l'll fall at your feet.
No, Dad!
Don't beg to him.
Fall at my feet.
l'll spare his life.
Please don't do it.
Fall at my feet.
Dad, don't. Please, Dad!
Darn you!
No! No!
Get up, son. Nothing
will happen to you.
Look at me.
Look at me. Nothing
will happen to you.
Ajay! Ajay?
Ajay!
No, Ajay.
Ajay..
No, Ajay, you can't leave me alone.
You can't leave me like this.
lf he is Ajay, then
who is your son Rajveer?
l..
Yes.
Rajveer. Rajveer.
Death will force you
to speak the truth.
He's not your son, is he?
No.
But he was like my own son.
He was so small when
l brought him home.
He loved me more than his father.
You killed him.
Who is your real son?
Speak.
Who is he?
Who is your son?
Answer me! Who is your son?
Rajveer Shekhawat!
lPS! lndian Police Service!
Batch No. 57!
Cadet No.32567!
Trained at Dehradun!
Topper of the batch!
Got it? Rajveer Shekhawat! lPS.
Son of Shrikant Shekhwat!
l vow on God..
..that l'll be honest
towards the law of the country.
He is my son.
My son.
l'm proud of him!
What more would a
father want from his son?
Only a police officer
can feel this happiness.
Not a scoundrel like you.
Ain't l right?
Absolutely right.
Where is he at the moment?
He is undercover.
24 hours. 365 days.
Don't..
Where is he now? What is he doing?
He is on a mission.
To free this nation
of viruses like you.
Criminals like you are violating..
..the courts, law, order
and justice of this nation.
He is finishing them off.
What has he done?
He couldn't touch me.
Here l am in lndia.
You didn't come on
your own free will.
You were forced to come here.
My son killed your right hand.
So that you're
forced to come to lndia.
Master plan.
Yes?
So either of us will live?
One patriot is in front of me.
Where's the other one?
You'll kill me if l tell you.
And you'll kill me even if l don't.
But don't worry.
You'll die in front of his eyes.
He will kill you.
He will stand in front of you.
He will look you in the eye.
So, you're scared of death,
aren't you?
Remember one thing,
the moment you kill me..
.. the countdown to
your death will begin.
None of you will live.
He'll kill all of you.
lt's 12th November today.
The day l die.
Tomorrow, it will be 13th November.
The day you die.
Nice meeting you,
Mr. Shrikant Shekhawat.
Nice meeting you.
All right, tell me something.
Will your son come to
cry over your dead body?
Or he will hide away out of fear?
He's a real man. He'll surely come.
Tell me.
there are policemen everywhere.
How do we kill him?
Don't even attempt
to do such a thing.
Did you find out who he is?
No.
Oh, my God!
Him?
Move! Move!
O Lord.
'A person lives on his own terms.'
'Fight courageously
while performing your duty.'
'This is the right path.'
'l'll be proud to call
you a good police officer..
..rather than a good son.'
'To annihilate crime
should be your life's ambition.'
'Alone, you're equal to an army.'
'You're a one man army.'
'Serve the people.
Die for your country.'
'Live like a legend.'
'Hail lndia.'
He is still here. As soon as
he leaves here, l'll call you.
Okay.
Gani deserves to die.
He should suffer so
much while dying..
..that even death gets afraid.
Scoundrel! l didn't
know he's an lPS officer.
And l told him everything.
Sir, he'll change his plan.
Because he told me about it.
Yes, he'll think along these lines.
But l'll not change the plan.
November 14th. He'll get
this job done by someone else.
November 14th is my day.
Everything will go as per my plan.
He knows the plan. So only the
location will change, not the plan.
Move! Move! Move, everyone!
He still has my daughter.
l'll go there, sir.
Nothing will
happen to your daughter.
l'll kill or get killed.
Think of me being a
criminal for one more day.
Me?
Yes, you.
Yes, sir?
Sir.. sir everyone is watching.
Will you perform your duty
or should l free you of it?
l didn't get you.
Where is he?
Who?
Gani. Your boss.
l..
Ask him where he is.
Boss..
Hello, Talpade.
Hello, Don Gani.
Yes, tell me. Did he leave?
No. No. l'll inform
you when he leaves.
Are you safe? Don't enter the city.
Don't teach me. l'm safe.
ln which safe place are you?
Binny Mills. - Okay. l'll
call you later. - Move! Move!
Yes. Yes.
Hello, Don Gani.
Yes, tell me.
He.. he has come.
Where?
Binny Mills.
Who told him l'm here?
l did.
ldiot! Fool!
Why did you tell him?
When you called, he was with
me and his gun at my temple.
What could l have done?
Where is he now?
He has entered the mill.
He is here. Come on! Move!
Come on! Move!
Boss, he is right in front of me.
Kill! Kill him!
How much will you pay to kill him?
have you eve counted 10 million?
l'll pay you Rs.50 million.
Kill him.
Boss! Over there!
Come on, kill! Kill him!
No!
Darn it! Scoundrel!
You..
Kill him! Kill him!
Go!
'The moment you come across
a honest police officer..'
'..you'll wet your pants.'
Darn you! You killed everyone?
You killed everyone.
Can't you differentiate
between animals and humans?
They're criminals. Such
men are so rare to find.
l've nurtured them for years.
l searched and picked
each one from the streets.
Anyone can become a policeman.
l can make hundreds of
policemen like you ..
..stand in front of
me tomorrow morning.
Where will l get them?
Darn you!
Stop it, man. Stop it.
You're overdoing it. Stop it.
You're too much.
Why are you killing a murderer?
Who are you?
What do you want?
l'll give you whatever you want.
Justjoin hands with me.
How much will you
get in a police job?
lf you die on duty..
..the government will give
Rs.50000 to your family.
That's it.
And they'll wear black
bands around their arms..
..to mourn your death.
Just for a day.
Join hands with me.
Heaven..
l'll show you heaven.
l'll show you heaven..
Did the deal fall through?
Sir?
Everyone will die.
Sir, your daughter is safe.
Gani has been killed.
Sir, the bad news is that
lnspector Talpade also got killed.
Sir?
What are you saying, sir?
You scou..
Once l commit to something,
l don't listen to..
.. myself even.