- Do not be afraid.
- I'm not, fuck you ...
- Do not be slack.
- I'm not ...
- Okay
- Right
- Okay?
- Yes.
- Not doing anything.
- You can not.
Jesus Christ, I am better than you.
- I'm closer to you, you from me.
- How so?
- I am moving and you do nothing.
- You're an idiot.
- Shut up.
- Do not be foux.
- Here goes.
- Okay ...
- Yes ..
FRIENDS
- Sorry.
DOUBLE
- This has been good.
- Yes.
I like that. We leave for
dinner and a drink ...
- Was ...
- Civilized.
- Yes!
- It was great to see you.
- You too. Goodbye.
"You - ..
- Thanks.
Okay.
- Good evening.
Now he's safe.
- Bye.
- Hello
THE EX
Want to go?
No.
Not because of you. You're beautiful.
It's late.
I think the ladies at work
have warned you about me.
Probably told
not seem interested.
I have history with women and
I think it would be better for both ...
If you know me better before.
My true self.
- How old are you? 24, 25?
- I'm 23.
I have 31 years.
You know what that means?
Means I can not leave
eating all these girls.
Half the time never talk to them.
It's rude, it is what it is. It is immature.
It's embarrassing.
It's very embarrassing.
There comes a time when we want
this is more than sex.
Understand what I'm saying?
So I'm leaving. And wonder if I'll
Can I call you this weekend.
I say what I do for you.
I'll follow up on your doorstep.
FIRST MEETING
- You're so good.
- I love you so much.
How did I hook,
a girl like you? My God!
This has been here for four days.
Looks like milk.
Do not want to be boring, but has
to stop living like a pig.
How many times do I have to ask you ...
What's with the shoes?
Look at this ... Choose ...
Look at those shoes!
Are they all yours?
There can be all yours.
Whose are these shoes, Dave?
Whose are these shoes?
No, I said 4000 times.
Do not want to be boring.
Oh, my God ...
You're so good.
Not good?
- Let's have fun.
- First go to the kitchen for cookies.
- Let's have fun with cookies?
- I will.
- What will you do?
- I will eat them.
What are you doing home?
Why are not you a hot date?
What are you doing home? Not working
tomorrow. Go to a nightclub or so.
You can not stay home
like an idiot.
You're young, for God's sake!
You hear what I'm saying?
At least go out and eat
whores. It's Friday!
Hello, who is this?
It's the party, where is it?
the roomies
It's Tuesday.
Dave.
Dave!
So think Inez okay today?
Hottie?
Legal and Foxy?
So I was thinking ...
Want to come to my room?
With us?
Okay.
Prelude I-|-Preliminary II | III-Sex
IV-Interlude | V-Orgasm | VI-Final
I - Prelude
- How was it?
- It's still going.
- Hey, Ken?
- Yes?
Do me a favor? Do not look for
medicine cabinet, okay?
I am not of those who never eat.
Normally my freezer is full.
Herb had last night and I went through,
so ...
... I could not go shopping.
I have a bad thing to tell you. I hope
do not think I'm crazy or something ...
But ... just got it.
- Whitening of teeth?
- Sorry?
Tooth whitener, it's about that?
- In the medicine cabinet.
- Do you think my teeth so white?
Ali has a bra.
I should think that a great flood.
My teeth are white because when
slept with a few small bulbs.
Wait, what?
I was afraid of the dark, so my
parents bought these special lamps,
whitening my teeth.
- Really?
"Berrycuda" ... It's good!
Crispy.
- So when you say lamps ...
- Okay, I lied.
Do not know why I said that.
He had no lights.
I'm just not accustomed to guys
here in the first meeting.
Listen. Snoop many cabinets
drugs while pissed.
I'm sure that what you have on your
will not make me want to not be here.
I think a relaxed, no?
Okay you can say ...
No, I ...
Yes, I think you relax.
But no matter, really.
That's not why I'm here.
I'm here because I like you.
I like
I do not care if this is
confusion,
or if the Muppet Babies were here.
- Oh, my God! Sorry ...
Relax, I'll stop snooping
and you do not care for what I think.
Let's laugh, let's talk, let's drink.
What do you think?
- Yes.
- Great.
- Here is the problem.
- What?
- I do not want to drink it.
- Me neither. Is the pence.
Come here.
- Sorry.
- No problem.
- I think I'm drunk and you?
- I think people expect too much.
Let's take another ...
It worries me that ...
Do you think we should do this?
Okay. I understand what you feel, but
listen to me because I will not say twice.
I have no desire to return
to hold meetings,
because all the guys I met,
fooled me.
- Except me, because ...
- Shut up.
We know that if no action, I will lose
for any one working there.
In addition to the only man at hand,
is you.
which incidentally was with a bitch.
- Do not call it a bitch ...
What made you seven months ago, and I
treated like shit for six years.
- Six years and four months.
- Oh, you need a shag! ...
- Okay, yes ...
- Desperately ...
and instead of talking, focus on
empty balls. Now. That's it.
It's just that it should think,
because that's all it is.
- Do not want to spoil anything.
- Listen. Sometimes it's something.
Sometimes it has meaning. Sometimes
are caresses and fingers interlaced ...
... And secrets in his ear.
But sometimes,
a fuck is just a fuck.
It is clear the balls,
and sleep soon.
That is, we will do, because it is
That's what friends are for.
Stop thinking, drink your "Shot"
for his friend Chris, will you suck.
Go ...?
- Are you ready for this?
- Yes.
Scared?
See what I said?
- Yes.
- Okay, give five more!
Legal.
Yes I got so many bottles
of wine when I was promoted.
No, I was talking
the place.
Yes I think it also came
with the promotion.
But wine is also great.
I'm amazed,
because you hated wine.
Now taste.
Jasmine will kill me.
- Why?
- She is so protective.
- I do not tell anyone.
- No?
No. I think they'll tell me,
that is a bad idea ...
Or ... will be hoping to
that we will be together.
Or anything.
Are you still ...?
- Sorry.
- No. Continue.
It was just silly, nothing ...
This is stupid.
You see?
It should not be strange.
We can have a relaxed relationship,
and get excited ...
... And, remain separate.
- I think so.
No, do not you think.
Look at the top, he is wearing.
Look at that outfit.
- Enhances the chest.
- I try.
That's what I'm saying. This top is made,
to bring guys like me here.
- Guys like you? How so?
- Gentlemen who like breasts.
No. You're wrong.
This top was made for guys like that
you want to come home with me.
- Ah, I see!
- Do you understand now?
- You want to fill me with regret.
- Repentance is good.
I had no intention of
come?
- No.
- I feel stupid.
Well, it was great to see you.
Give my love to Jasmine.
- Kisses for his mother.
- Will be delivered.
No, not going away.
- Andrew?
- What?
What is this?
Are you his birthday.
I do not want all the attention.
I love you baby.
- You're the best.
- I am very good ...
Happy birthday.
Good night dear.
- Abby ...
- Andrew.
I do not know if I will today.
Is that a question?
No, it's a statement.
I'm tired.
Honey, I have worked very
lately.
And I do not see well with my glasses.
I was pricked in her eyes.
You know.
And eat as much pasta for dinner;
I do not feel very well ...
When going to want?
Do not have a specific day.
- Can be tomorrow?
- Three weeks ago they did not have sex.
- It's been three weeks.
- When was the last time?
- Andrew!
- Did not know he had to say.
No need. The response was
always be, "last night."
Nobody does every night.
- Malcolm and Beatrice do.
- You can not believe what they say.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
- I need orgasms, Andrew.
- I know.
Okay. Go for it.
Now.
I want to do. I'm ready.
I'm anxious.
- Honey?
- What?
Thought I'd start.
It's always me that first.
It's always me that got the initiative.
Why do not you get
this time?
As is already excited, could
help me catch up.
- No. I know your tricks.
- My what?
- You do not suck.
- Do not say, never!
I expected to do before.
Then, pretending to be very
excited and full of passion,
as needed
I hold fast,
and conveniently skips my turn.
- I think this is not true.
- Yes yes!
Not to pretend to believe a lie.
- What is happening to us?
- I'm saying do it now!
You want passion and excitement?
You can count on it.
How am I doing so far?
- Well
- Is that okay?
That's good.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
- There are new?
- St.
Appear expensive.
I thought we talk about big purchases.
- Andrew ...
- Sorry, that's fine.
So ...?
Oh, yes Dave. I'm not going
meter, so to speak.
I told you, but I
just watch and be on my own.
- Great.
- Dave, I always thought it was really cool.
- So.
- Okay.
Sometimes we do not get along,
and sometimes even hate.
But soon, we get
a place e. ..
... Where we want to do this.
and now here you are.
- I always found you ...
- She always says you're cool.
Right.
We love each other very much.
I love you baby.
- Oh my God, you're so hot.
- My God, how I love you!
It's the sexiest thing in the world.
Today we'll make new friends.
- There may be a problem.
- Am I?
She's hot, is not it David?
Yes, she's great ...
You're great.
There's something in me that can lead
you do not want to do this.
You know.
Gord ...?
That? That's the problem?
I already knew.
It will be great.
I'm very excited!
- I know ...?
- Not excited?
Am.
- How did you know ...?
- We discovered, was not it?
- Should I ...?
- Yes, very well, very well.
Oh my God!
You're so sexy!
You're very tasty!
Oh, yes ... Only
Get over there!
This is cool.
II - Preliminary
It's amazing!
Oh, my God!
Is this true?
- I asked if it is true?
- Sure.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Is it true?
Jamie ... Do not know what you
're talking darling, sorry.
When I said I liked
even me it was serious?
Yes, of course.
- I bet it says it all.
- I say yes.
What?
Shall I lie to you?
I tell others that I love them, but with
you're different. With you is the truth.
How do I know what's different?
I respect you enough to
put it aside.
- What?
- I respect you.
Respect is the opposite
to like someone.
Not always.
This is not coming out,
as I had thought.
Look ...
I'm just trying to say
I like you. That's it.
If trans is night, great.
Otherwise ... If you still do not trust
me enough, is understandable.
And if it means having to suspend
physical contact ...
... And back to the conversation,
then talk to you all night.
I want to know everything about you.
For example, what is this?
This is my digital massager.
I should not have seen it.
Digital massager ...
How does this work?
- Ken.
- Yes.
We have to talk.
I believe in you.
Really?
This means that not
like my conversation?
No, I love your conversation.
Can we talk later?
Okay.
Think of others
when we make love?
What?
Sometimes I feel that is not here.
Looks like you are somewhere else.
You see what I'm trying to do?
Where could I be?
Sorry. You're right.
Continue.
Oh! Thanks.
- It's that I'm not as accomplished?
- Sorry?
The reason for not wanting to suck me,
is not to be so fulfilling?
Who says I do not want?
I'm doing the best I can.
Just because I stopped shaving
you stopped sucking me.
Want to talk about oral sex, or
want to let me perform oral sex?
Okay. Sorry.
Now it seems that you missing. Never
look at me when I'm down here.
- What all four times?
- I'm serious.
- Think about other people?
- No.
Honey, that's fine, you can say.
I think.
- Think! Why not me?
- Only sometimes. You also think, confess.
Yes, I think. Sometimes.
Who?
- Who?
- Yes Who?
Who do you think?
- Had to make a list.
- There is always the same person?
No, it's like a carousel
people with whom I have sex.
You always think in
same person?
Think. It's Malcolm?
Why do you think he's a doctor?
- Not the Malcolm.
- Then who is?
Ian Ziering. He does, Steve Sanders
on "Beverly Hills" ...
I know who it is.
Are you angry?
- Let's just continue, okay.
- Okay.
It'll be good, I'm ready, come on.
- We do.
- Yes!
- Wherever resume?
- Want to start with a kiss?
I do not know. You want it?
Okay. Stop, stop,
Stop, stop!
- You can not do that.
- What?
You can not look at me
while doing so.
- Why not?
- Why me crazy.
I thought you said you liked ...
No, yes. It's different all right.
With other girls I think:
"A hot making me a blowjob!"
As you think, "It's Kris Anne, with
my cock in the mouth and it drives me mad. "
Okay.
Forget the blowjob.
Let's stay calm.
Let's put a song.
We need rhythm, sensuality,
noise and distraction.
- I was thinking ...
- What we need is music.
- All right.
- Okay.
We have better than this.
- You're so gay.
- You who are gay.
This is better, right.
We could ...
I hate this.
- Why hate?
- It was my song with Dimitris.
Jessica and I had no song.
At first I thought it cool, but after
that stupid touched everywhere
and I, every time they heard it,
went crazy.
Oh my God!
Have you seen how it is disturbed?
We should leave this
and you pretended I was him ...
- Fuck you.
- You are right. Sorry. It was stupid.
- Want to talk about it?
- This is the same.
- It's OK I'm here?
- No.
Just want to know.
It's okay, right?
Do not want to feel
an idiot tomorrow.
It does not hurt to be here.
Seriously.
So you do not love me anymore?
- What? Do not do it.
- You do not love me, right?
- Of course not, Mia.
- Eric, this is just for fun, is not it?
According Yes.
- So we're well?
- Certainly. Say no more.
That's better.
Hello ladies.
- Stop talking to my chest.
- I'm just being polite.
I said, not said ...?
If there were any problems ...
Maybe I should stop talking ...
Never thought this would happen.
Please.
What style. Do not use it ...
... Because it is comfortable.
- Shut up.
Grab it, have, throw yourself into it.
- Go and have it all.
- What?
I'm just saying
grab it and owns it.
We're already doing it ...
Not now.
But before ...
It made sense when I said:
"Grab it and owns it."
- That's it.
- Okay.
She likes that you fool
in your hair.
I said, she likes
that stir in your hair.
I'm just saying. Do not be afraid.
Grab it, have, go up to her.
We're fine.
I am helping you. So when
I say you should do what I say.
Because I'm here.
This is also for me.
It's not like sex,
in front of the dog.
Do not want to be boring.
I'm just saying.
Sorry. I wish this were
smooth and nice and soft and sensual.
So ... I'll be here.
- Likes to mess with hair like that?
- Yes ..
Yeah, great. Relax and
naturally do everything ...
- So?
- Yes.
This. Who is this?
Who is your new friend?
What?
What happened?
I put hair spray here.
The perfume bottle was empty.
Sorry.
Okay, okay. Just shit.
If caress. Nobody wants that.
- I like ...
- No one wants that vote.
We do not cherish.
Therefore, do not want you to caress.
Go to it and finish it.
Have fun and treat her like a piece
meat. Only a sex game.
Just holding. Only pleasure.
An erotic ride.
Okay.
Gimme.
Why are you looking at me?
Give it to her.
- Gord, I love you.
- You're so hot.
Oh my God!
Continue ... So! ...
Okay, here we go.
That's cool.
III - SEX
Can I say something?
- I love your sheets.
- They're good, are not they?
- You know I'm not wearing anything.
- I know.
As you know everything?
- Something.
- I think so.
- I am healthy.
- I believe you.
I take tests regularly.
I believe. Otherwise the
girls had said.
- I'll take, to be sure.
- Just tell me when it comes.
Okay, I promise.
I promise not to spoil
These wonderful sheets.
- Can I say one more thing?
- At ease.
You're beautiful.
Seriously! Seriously! Seriously!
Your eyes are like
pots of hazelnut.
Sorry, I do not ...
Normally I do not ...
Damn! You're beautiful.
Thank you.
Wait, I know that look!
It's the look that I do
the girls ...
Who say never
had come so far.
Fucked it, right?
Kriss ...
Oh, Kristine ...
- Kristine Armstrong!
- I need some dirty, now.
Must be kidding?
- Excite me.
- Okay.
Do not invent.
Just follow your intuition.
I'll stick in your ass so hard
that even your breath will smell the cock.
After you thread it into the mouth to
the taste of her ass.
- So here goes ...
- Jesus Christ!
What?
I thought that was what he wanted.
- Why would you want that?
- Because it is a disgusting whore.
- Sorry.
- Okay, okay, it's my fault.
- Carry on, friend.
- Okay.
Like it?
We should be having sex,
and not talking about it.
Perhaps the fault is not ours.
Maybe we're older and
with reduced sexual appetite.
We have 26 years!
There are 19.
But when we do not
love you masturbate, do you?
Not every day.
Listen, make love, it is very
different from masturbating.
It's like eating a barrinha,
and this is one meal.
And you have eaten bars. I
I've seen, so do not say no.
- Yes.
- So there it is.
This is bullshit. If we masturbate,
why not do together?
Why do not we have sex
more times?
I think we both know ...
I'm not very interesting
in bed.
I see they can not excite you,
and I lack motivation.
- What?
- I know I've never been to, "Mr. Sex".
I have no way. I know.
No need to say.
Not true. If it was not good,
Why would you marry me?
Why, afraid to be alone.
What?
You think the only reason,
to be with you ...
Oh, my God!
You think the only reason for being
with you is afraid of being alone?
- There is a little truth?
- Are you asking me?
Oh my God! If you think
only reason for being together ...
I think I do not attract you.
I am no longer beautiful.
No dear, no!
- Up to guess, it's prettier.
- You think?
- I think.
- Really?
I mean, you put on e. ..
No, dear.
Was a positive way.
Gave a stuffed.
No longer looks like a girl.
Did you mean ... I do not know what to say.
Whatever I say?
- I wish it would work.
- Me too.
Maybe we're just
Tired of the same thing.
- I think not.
- Admit it, please.
- Okay. Perhaps, yes.
- We have to try something different.
Sure. For example ...?
Something exciting.
Okay.
How to type in the bathtub
or something?
I have the perfect idea.
You can do anything with me.
Anything you want.
- You talking to me?
- Yes.
It means putting in the ass
face.
- They had forgotten me? Do not stop.
- Did not mean: "Meta in the ass."
I did not want to stop. Thought
were close. I know I am.
Continue, continue.
Come on.
Not mean: "Target in the ass."
His hand ...
- Yes.
- Your hand is on my ass.
I know. It is to feel the rhythm of the thing.
Still not finished, man.
- Come on.
- No.
- Do you mind sitting over there?
- Oh yes, of course.
- Did not mean: "Meta in the ass."
- He has done almost everything ...
What is meant by:
"You can do everything with me?"
I do not know, but would not say, "Ass."
I do not do that.
- We both do.
- Yes, but this is different. It is ...
Ah yes! I think she is saying,
you're too big.
That's what you meant?
Okay, calm down a bit.
If you want to control the speed,
back up.
- How long does this, Mary?
- Slower. Seriously.
- Too much for you, Nancy?
- To call me with these names?
- Suzie. Debbie.
- Stop, stop, stop.
Would you stop?
- I was almost coming.
- No. ..
- Still has not come.
- It's too careful. Relax.
Sorry.
I had to stop.
I knew what he was doing.
Just wanted to take, "my first man"
the path.
Relax, okay?
I'll get a drink.
Also want one?
A drink would be great.
Thanks.
- What about you?
- You talking to me?
No.
- Here, sweetie.
- Thanks.
- "My first man '! It's like the name?
- It's better after the first.
Stop worrying on hold.
Stay present, give me more pleasure.
Think you know me well,
huh?
I was talking to her
penis just was not she?
Yes it was.
IV - Interlude
- We can take a break?
- Sure. Yeah, sure, sure.
I have to pee, so ...
Okay.
So ...
Why me?
We're almost changing, and Inez
you know. This is important.
It had to be someone who
were able to do ...
And as you know was very
equipped ... It was perfect
- How is what ...
- Would you stop? I do not like you anymore.
Do not hate you
but we were friends and we are not.
Of course, when we leave
to be roommates,
I'll stop hating you.
Until we can be friends again.
But it is easier to see you do it
than someone who I ... Do not like it.
And also because Gord,
you find attractive.
Right!
We never had problems with that.
We're good at it.
- Secondly, all the rest ...
- Yes.
- What do you mean?
- I mean ...
- Yes, of course ... But ...
- But what?
We had no physical contact,
because we had problems.
I did not mean that he disliked,
do not think so.
Okay, but ...
Blame me for that?
- You think it's my fault?
- It's not you, Eric.
- Do not tell me what I think.
- So you think it's my fault?
Stop.
I know what you think,
because it is very obvious.
Stop it. Seriously.
- Still got that ...?
- No, I do not ...
I do not do well with this
of a man and a woman ....
Right now gives me no pleasure.
But would not be here ...
- You're with someone?
- No.
- What happened to the guy's job?
- Which one?
- There were two.
The one that told me,
Tristan was.
A true male.
One of the tight T-shirts?
- No. Stop.
- What was the name the other?
- It's not important.
- Why? He was a friend of mine?
- No.
- No? What was his name?
- Sorry? Really?
Should tell me your name.
Give it up, ma'am.
Contact. Come on.
F-Dog Mac
- Do not say anything.
- F-Dog Mac?
Is the name of a rap or
a street or something.
Or name of prison!
What the fuck?
What you're jealous.
No, not jealous. Am
trying to understand what the F.
- Why are you so jealous?
- I'm not jealous.
I'm not jealous.
I just wanted to know ...
Just wanted to know if you're treated well ...
I want to be happy.
I'm happy.
Great. Very good.
- And you?
- Me? I am very happy.
- Very happy.
- Great.
- Sorry to have stopped.
- Okay. No problem.
If you slept with all there
work as ...?
Let me stop you there.
I did not sleep with all ...
For example, Mariah.
Never sleep with Mariah ...
Was there before you. And Christina ...
It was beautiful. I never touched her.
Shakira ...
Damn, I'm lying. Sorry.
I'm reading the covers of CD's.
Yes, I slept with them all.
Continue.
I thought it would be different.
With all this intimacy.
Not that you do not like ...
I like it, but ...
Sorry. It was my fault. I was rushed
and said things that did not say in bed.
Not sure why. I. ..
What do you say?
You know, "It has the best ass I've ever seen"
the kind of thing that builds self-esteem.
- What do you think of my ass?
- I think is the best ass I've ever seen!
- I'm serious.
- Me too.
And you have to believe me.
I'ma professional. It is a masterpiece!
Very good. I'm going back
with you on one condition.
It has to stop the conversation
because I'm a player,
and this triggers the schema.
Agreed?
- Deal.
- Great.
I know what you're thinking.
I lied. I do not know what you're thinking.
What are you thinking?
To get started ...
Where did you get that?
It was a prize, the festival of Michelle.
I won it.
- So you ...?
- I use it.
- And you ...?
- I'll fuck you.
You like a little finger
there occasionally.
You put my hand there,
when you're drunk.
This is a little bigger than a pinky.
- We use a lubricant.
- Really?
Neither wants to try?
You know, it ...
G may have a point there,
not yet discovered.
Not, not the least bit curious?
I have what? I do not know that.
How do you know? Where is it?
I have a what?
Sorry I brought it up.
Okay?
I'll take it.
You can relax.
After we ...
I do not know what we do.
And what this has to
good for you?
Here is a small vibrator
for me.
Then have an orgasm?
Oh, yes!
- Okay.
- Really?
Yeah, okay, okay.
Okay, okay.
I'll just ... Lie.
And if we kissed
a little before?
I think it will not make me
become wetter, so ...
I'll just ...
It's okay dear.
Only bad initially.
It's what everyone says.
- Try to relax.
- Yes ..
Honey?
I'm here love.
I'm not going anywhere.
- It's okay.
- Okay. Okay.
Happy birthday, dear.
- So a new plan?
- Yes, give me just a second.
- Can I do anything?
- No, it's not with you.
What are you thinking?
I dunno ... Tit.
I find it funny that Jessica's bitch
athlete is considered by jumping on horseback.
- What's this?
- Riding.
Riding. The horse is the athlete.
Does all the work.
It seems like the Olympics, ran
100 m with the dwarves in the back ...
... And then give the medals
the dwarves.
Yes, it would be nice.
- I'm not thinking about it.
- Okay.
- Seriously.
- Shall I ...?
- No. I'll handle it.
Maybe we should stop here.
I take the blame.
I thought it was a good idea but is not.
How about shake hands
and blame the other?
Not going anywhere. I would not want
remember this as something that did not work.
I hate to give bad news, but ...
The fault was not mine.
I was a little nervous.
Everything you nervous.
Everything? I was not eating you
twenty minutes?
Just did it because he felt
I had to do.
I know you. Only did so because he felt
bad because of the fiasco blowjob.
Listen. Nobody eats
a woman's obligation.
I know what you think.
I'm not a whore, that in six years
unable to meet you.
- I've known you for almost twenty years.
- Do not call her a whore.
I know that plays the male, when
over, because if you call a coward.
I know it touches my neck,
Dimitri said that because he played.
I know all about you
you know everything about me ...
That's why we can not harden it.
Where are my pants?
You know I've been in love
for you?
He knew, but I was
Morris or whoever it was.
I've also been in love with you
but you did not know.
Yes knew.
When I was with Jessica.
Wait. Did you know?
Now I leave it.
This should never have happened.
I did not know you knew that.
Where are my pants?
I thought we could do this, but ...
Drop the fucking pants!
A fuck, it's just a fuck.
Said this or not?
- I said this or not?
- Do you want me to answer?
We are excited, let's go!
Then we can be friends again ...
... But now, for me,
you're just a piece of meat.
- Only a "good proportion" with feet.
- Sensual ...
And for you, I am lonely,
"Face with a huge cock."
Together we can do this.
Go back to bed and start again.
It should not be so hard.
- But it is.
- No, if we meet like meat ...
I mean, is ... Hard.
You know what's going on here?
You know?
- You are pointing at you.
- Oh is it?
Wants you to return
to bed.
If he could do so would.
So go back to bed and let's have sex.
Nothing more.
- I will not get involved with an idiot?
- I need to empty the balls.
Just me and my "thing"
against you and your "thing"?
Here is a nice fuck
with eyes ...
Are you ready?
V - ORGASM
- How are you darling?
- Well, well what about you?
Great.
This vibrator is fantastic.
- Can I go deeper?
- Know ...
- Come on, deeper to the point G.
- So what?
- And then, dear?
- Not bad.
Oh dear.
Okay.
Wait. Stop.
Honey, honey.
- It's coming.
- Honey, honey, honey.
Why are you so slow?
I do not know.
Want it faster?
- Yes, maybe.
- Good job.
- You too, partner.
- Yes, yes.
- Do you like this, my bitch?
- I'm almost there.
- Oh my God! Me too.
You are so beautiful.
- This is better than I thought.
- So good ...
Oh my God, you're so good!
- You are so beautiful.
- I love you.
I love you too.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
- Damn! You were awesome.
- Me?
Only once you've done and enjoy
you made me cum three times.
- My goodness ...
- So, any note?
Well had a thing,
that was a bit much.
- Really?
- You know what I mean.
- Was ...
- Shut up.
Well you can reduce it a bit.
- Nobody believes. Exhibitionist too.
- I'll try to remember next time.
- You know what I can do for me?
- What?
Oh no, dear ...
I'm still recovering.
Can not approach.
I'm so sensitive.
- You know what I would love?
- What?
A bowl of ice cream
with a biscuit.
You can put the bowl in the microwave
and warm up a bit ..
Want an ice cream cone is nice!
- May have to wash a bowl.
- I serve the ice cream and wash the cup.
- And to me?
- Trago.
With a biscuit?
Glad you made it.
What did you say?
Of course I am happy by sex, all
men are equal but I'm happy ...
I'll stop talking, because clearly
have the same opinion about this ...
I hope it does not take to recover,
because I am ready to repeat.
Forgot my biscuit.
- Lift the leg.
- So?
- Yes.
- Oh, yes. Oh my God!
I think I'll enjoy.
I will enjoy!
Here we go.
We did it.
Look.
Oh man, it was fantastic!
You are so sexy. Yes!
Oh boy, I know we had some
disagreements, but ...
... It was so good!
I am leaving for a while.
If you need me ...
A little juice.
Just this, that you leave me?
So I have to go buy another
packaging? You think I'm stupid?
- Think you're smarter than me?
- Please dress!
VI - FINAL
I did not hear the "ding" of the microwave.
I'm confused.
She was massaging?
- He said he enjoyed four times.
- I know I said.
- I was lying?
- I was not lying. I just ...
What?
I can not reach orgasm.
I try, I try. Do you have any
something wrong with me.
Should be a fun thing
and casual ...
It is not.
For me it's so overwhelming and staff.
I can not. I keep
think of my picture ...
As he thinks of me,
which my smell ...
And I can not.
I can not enjoy.
I think I am not a person
very sensual.
Sorry.
Really sorry.
It'll be fine.
So ... When you say
is not very sexy ...
It's a lie.
It is a crazy lie.
Not too sexy?
You're lying.
Fuck. Do not get so angry
because he could not give me an orgasm.
That's not why I'm angry. Has
many girls that I enjoy many.
- I believed you, Jamie.
- This is not my name. It's Dora.
But Dora would ruin my sensuality
so I decided to say it was Jamie.
Changed his name to Jamie Fox?
What? It is a sexy name. How would
guess who would win those Oscars?
You're crazy!
Sure, it's folly to lie, to take
someone to bed. Never the right.
I know all about you. I know you like
certain things so fake, what then?
Wanted to be fucked.
Not figured it was a lazy
I would try to love me. What was that?
How could he come up with that?
You're not the man I have heard.
You're a fucking hypocrite.
Goes around lecturing,
and putting his dick in everything around you?
And then come here to spread crap
all over my apartment ...
... And still call me a liar?
You did not say a word not
had to do with their sexual prowess.
- Hello
- Was it good?
- No, no.
- So it was bad?
No, it was boring.
This shit is just lies.
Never again.
Swear to God. Never again.
Not worth it?
Hey
- Do not you hear me?
- It was great.
I said, wait.
I said, stop.
I said, no.
Look at you!
Sorry. I was close and
it seemed that he enjoyed it.
- It does not matter.
- No?
It's the principle. A woman
orders to stop, and we stopped.
This was to be closer.
To do something exciting together.
But you went inside again. Not me
heard ... He pretended that I was not even there.
- Bet you thought about Ian Ziering.
- Andrew. Did you?
- I think it does not matter.
- But he enjoyed like crazy.
How do you know? I was too busy ...
Thinking I had a stick ... Wavy!
I know because I felt.
Really?
Felt when I came.
Therefore, and because it has
sperm everywhere.
Not bad! But the best,
was so excited to see you.
Can not remember the last
time I saw you so.
And you were doing
new noises.
- Honey ...
- Yes ..?
I'm not tired.
- Is that a question?
- No. I'm saying.
I'm also not tired.
- I forgot. Can we ...?
- Yes I'm sorry.
So ...
I thought that was what
you wanted.
Wanted. I want to.
You were awesome, baby.
- I love you so much.
- I know.
I know.
You know?
She did all this for you.
No, no, no. We talked about it.
She was so excited as I am.
- She wanted as much as I do.
- Just wanted to make you happy.
- I just wanted to make you happy.
- You make me happy.
Please. Do not do it.
Let's look at me.
I do not deserve a girl
like you.
When we left, it's as if to say:
"What is she doing with that guy?"
Do not tell me not to notice.
I quite see.
Just wanted to say what he deserves. See you
happy. So excited me so much.
Dear. When I see people
in the street looking like this ...
You notice. I knew it.
Yes, repair and adore.
It makes me feel,
I have this wonderful secret.
As if he knew that nobody else knows.
You is the right guy for me.
Look at this guy.
It has a firm ass, a nice nose ...
- And look at this shit!
- Could you please ...
Yes It was nice and it's legal,
but I was always thinking of you.
- Really?
- Yes.
I am ... A pervert.
- Me too.
I love to steal shoes
people that the smell ...
- I love you.
- My God! You're so sexy!
I love you so much!
- Honey, you're so hot!
- I've said it.
I love you too, baby!
- I do whatever I want.
- Everything?
- I'll have you in every way.
- Yes?
I'll grab, pull hair, you have!
I'll hold you, caress and make love!
- As crazy as love!
- Yes
It's very personal.
I think I'll go.
Dave, wait.
Sorry for ...
I do not want to be boring.
I know.
And I wanted to thank you,
by fuck my girlfriend. It was ...
- Okay.
- No, no!
Our cocks are
touching.
So long, abnormal.
Good night, pervert.
So ... We are well?
- Yes, you love me?
- Yes.
- Will you give me?
- Oh, yes!
- It's all for me?
- Everything, everything you want honey.
You know?
I saw them holding each other there.
And it was good. Good and sexy.
I opened another bottle.
I did not know which to choose.
- Toma.
- Thanks.
- Health
So is leaving?
I do not want to impose too much.
I also have to work in the morning.
- Okay. Follow you to the door.
- Yes.
Yeah, okay.
- Give my love to Jasmine.
- I send you.
- Say hello to, Fuck Dog.
- Shut up!
Okay.
I can not call you for a while.
My work has been crazy.
Yes, mine too.
It was fun.
Yes
- Well ...
- Yes.
- It was fun.
Give me five!
Man, I'm so drunk.
Me too.
Okay. Good night.
Matt listens. Listen.
I said ...
What is this?
This? I do not know what it is.
Has a mess of CD's in the reader.
Come on, tell.
I'm the biggest coward.
I love this song.
"You - ..?
- Yes.
- I'm not drunk.
- Me neither.
Sorry I called
your ex a slut.
- She's a bitch.
- Just say it, because I said.
It's nothing.
He always says things and then I
say why you think it should say.
I say nothing.
Wait. You are talking about what
I said then you say ...?
Because I felt what I said.
Do not say I felt because I felt.
- Shut your mouth now.
- I have to say that I felt what I said.
- Shut up.
- Shut up you.
Matt. Stop talking.
Ah ... Do you want ...?
We can do something else.
I can not think anymore.
"Hey, wait. The movie is not over yet !..."
"In five minutes is over"
Dave?
Dave. Are you awake?
Is not she?
Cool, cool!