(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
NARRATOR: Thebes, City of the Living,
crown jewel of Pharaoh Seti the First.
Home of Imhotep, Pharaoh's high priest,
keeper of the dead.
Birthplace of Anck-Su-Namun,
Pharaoh's mistress.
No other man was allowed to touch her...
But for their love,
they were willing to risk life itself.
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
What are you doing here?
Who has touched you?!
Imhotep?!
My Priest!
(SCREAMING)
(PHARAOH SCREAMING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Pharaoh's bodyguards.
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
- You must go! Save yourself!
- No!
Only you can resurrect me!
I won't leave you! Get away from me!
You shall live again!
I will resurrect you!
My body is no longer his temple!
NARRATOR: To resurrect Anck-Su-Namun,
Imhotep and his priests broke into her crypt
and stole her body.
They raced deep into the desert,
taking Anck-Su-Namun's corpse
to Hamunaptra, City of the Dead,
HAMUNAPTRA - 1290 B.C.
ancient burial site for the sons of pharaohs
and resting place for the wealth of Egypt.
For his love, Imhotep dared the gods' anger
by going deep into the city,
where he took the black Book of the Dead
from its holy resting place.
(CHANTING IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Anck-Su-Namun's soul had been sent
to the dark underworld,
her vital organs removed and placed in
five sacred Canopic jars.
(GASPING)
Anck-Su-Namun's soul had come back
from the dead,
(SHOUTING)
but Pharaoh's bodyguards
had followed lmhotep and stopped him
before the ritual could be completed.
(HOWLING)
(SHOUTING)
Imhotep's priests were condemned
to be mummified alive.
(PRIESTS GROANING)
(PRIESTS SCREAMING)
As for. Imhotep,
he was condemned to endure the Hom-Dai,
the worst of all ancient curses.
One so horrible,
it had never before been bestowed.
(IMHOTEP SCREAMING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(MOANING)
(GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
(CREATURES SKITTERING)
He was to remain sealed
inside his sarcophagus,
be undead for all of eternity.
The Magi would never allow him
to be released,
for he would arise a walking disease,
a plague upon mankind,
an unholy flesh-eater
with the strength of ages,
power over the sands,
and the glory of invincibility.
(LEGIONNAIRES SHOUTING)
HAMUNAPTRA - 1923
For 3,000 years,
men and armies fought over this land,
never knowing what evil lay beneath it.
(SHOUTING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
And for 3,000 years, we, the Magi,
the descendants of
Pharaoh's sacred bodyguards, kept watch.
You just got promoted.
(YELLING IN FRENCH)
(ULULATING)
Steady!
- You're with me on this one, right?
- Your strength gives me strength.
RICK: Steady!
Wait! Wait for me!
Steady!
Fire!
(MEN GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
Run, Beni! Run!
RICK: Get inside! Get inside!
Hey! Don't you close that door!
Don't you close that door!
(GUNS FIRING)
(GUNS CLICKING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(MAN WHISPERING)
MAN: (WHISPERING)
You will die. You will die.
(HOWLING)
(SHOUTING)
(RICK COUGHING)
(GRUNTING)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
The Creature remains undiscovered.
And what of this one?
(PANTING)
- Should we kill him?
- No.
The desert will kill him.
CAIRO, EGYPT - 3 YEARS LATER
EVELYN: Sacred stones,
sculpture and aesthetics,
Socrates, Seth, volume one, volume two,
and volume three.
And...
Tuthmosis. What are you doing here?
T. T, t, t...
T.
I'm going to put you where you belong!
(SCREAMS)
(GASPING)
(EXCLAIMING)
Help.
(SCREAMING)
Oops.
CURATOR: What... How...
Oh, look at this!
Sons of the pharaohs!
Give me frogs! Flies! Locusts!
Anything but you!
Compared to you,
the other plagues were a joy!
I am so very sorry. It was an accident.
My girl, when Rameses destroyed Syria,
that was an accident.
You are a catastrophe!
Look at my library!
Why do I put up with you?
Well, you put up with me because I can...
I can read and write Ancient Egyptian,
and I can...
I can decipher hieroglyphics and hieratic,
and, well, I am the only person
within 1,000 miles
who knows how to properly code
and catalog this library, that's why.
I put up with you because your father
and mother were our finest patrons.
That's why!
Allah rest their souls.
Now, I don't care how you do it,
I don't care how long it takes,
straighten up this meshiver!
(CLATTERING)
Hello?
Abdul?
Mohammed?
Bob?
(THUDDING)
(SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING)
Have you no respect for the dead?
Of course I do.
But sometimes I'd rather like to join them.
Well, I wish you would do it before you ruin
my career the way you've ruined yours.
- Now, get out.
- My dear, sweet baby sister.
I'll have you know
that, at this precise moment,
my career is on a high note.
High note, ha! Jonathan, please,
I'm really not in the mood for you.
I've just made a bit of a mess in the library,
and the Bembridge scholars have
rejected my application form again.
They say I don't have enough experience
in the field.
You'll always have me, old mum.
Besides, I have just the thing
to cheer you up.
Oh, no, Jonathan,
not another worthless trinket.
If I have to take one more piece of junk
to the curator to try and
sell for you.
Where did you get this?
On a dig down in Thebes.
My whole life,
I've never found anything, Evy.
Please tell me I've found something.
(EVELYN GASPS)
- Jonathan.
- Yes?
I think you've found something.
You see the cartouche there?
It's the official royal seal of Seti the First,
I'm sure of it.
- Perhaps.
- JONATHAN: Two questions.
Who the hell was Seti the First,
and was he rich?
He was the second pharaoh
of the 19th dynasty,
said to be the wealthiest pharaoh
of them all.
Good. I Iike this fellow.
- I like him very much.
- I've already dated the map.
It's almost 3,000 years old.
And if you Iook at the hieratic just here,
well, it's Hamunaptra.
CURATOR: Dear God, don't be ridiculous.
We're scholars, not treasure hunters.
Hamunaptra's a myth
told by ancient Arab storytellers
to amuse Greek and Roman tourists.
I know all the blather about the city
being protected by the curse of a mummy,
but my research has led me to believe
that the city itself may have actually existed.
- Are we talking about the Hamunaptra?
- Yes. The City of the Dead.
Where the earliest pharaohs were said
to have hidden the wealth of Egypt?
Yes, yes, in a big, underground
treasure chamber.
- Heh!
- Oh, come on. Everybody knows the story.
The entire necropolis was rigged to sink
into the sand on Pharaoh's command?
A flick of a switch, and the whole place
would disappear beneath the sand dunes,
taking the treasure with it?
As the Americans would say,
it's all fairy tales and hokum.
Oh, my goodness! Look at that!
You'be burnt it!
You've burned off the part with the lost city?
It's for the best, I'm sure.
Many men have wasted their Iives
in the foolish pursuit of Hamunaptra.
No one's ever found it.
Most have never returned.
Come, come! Step over the threshold.
Welcome to Cairo Prison, my humble home.
EVELYN: You told me that you got it
on a dig down in Thebes.
- JONATHAN: Yeah, well, I was mistaken.
- You lied to me.
I lie to everybody.
What makes you so special?
- I am your sister.
- That just makes you more gullible.
You stole it from a drunk
at the local casbah?
Picked his pocket, actually,
so I don't think it's a very good...
Stop being so ridiculous.
What exactly is this man in prison for?
This I did not know.
But when I heard that you were coming,
I asked him that myself.
And what did he say?
He said he was just looking for a good time.
(YELLING)
- This is the man that you stole it from?
- Yes, exactly?
So why don't we just go sniff
out a spot of tiffin...
RICK: Who are you?
- And who's the broad?
- "Broad"?
I'm just a local sort of missionary chap,
spreading the good word,
- but this is my sister, Evy.
- How do you do?
- Oh, well. Guess she's not a total loss.
- I beg your pardon?
I'll be back in a moment?
- Ask him about the box.
- We have found...
Hello. Excuse me?
We both found your puzzle box,
and we've come to ask you about it?
- No.
- No?
No. You came to ask me about Hamunaptra.
How do you know
the box pertains to Hamunaptra?
Because that's where I was when I found it.
I was there.
But how do we know
that's not a load of pig's wallow?
- Do I know you?
- No, no.
I've just got one of those faces.
You were actually at Hamunaptra?
- Yeah, I was there.
- You swear?
- Every damn day.
- I didn't mean that...
I know. I was there. Seti's place.
City of the Dead.
Could you tell me how to get there?
(MAN YELLING IN ARABIC)
I mean, the exact location?
- You want to know?
- Well, yes?
- Do you really want to know?
- Yes?
Then get me the hell out of here!
(SOLDIERS YELLING)
Do it, lady!
- Where are they taking him?
- To be hanged?
Apparently, he had a very good time?
(CROWD CHEERING)
I will give you £100 to save this man's life.
Madame, I would pay £100
just to see him hang.
- £200.
- Proceed!
£300.
Any last requests, pig?
Yeah? Loosen the knot and let me go.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Of course we don't let him go!
£500!
And what else? I'm a very lonely man.
(CROWD LAUGHING)
No!
(CHOKING)
(LAUGHING)
His neck did not break.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Now, we must watch him strangle to death.
(CROWD CHANTING)
(GRUNTING)
He knows the location to Hamunaptra.
- You lie.
- I would never!
Are you telling me
this filthy, godless son of a pig
- knows where to find the City of the Dead?
- EVELYN: Yes!
- Truly?
- Yes!
And if you cut him down, we will give you...
(GRUNTING)
- 10 %
- 50 %
- Twenty.
- Forty.
- Thirty!
- Twenty five.
Deal.
Cut him down!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(SHIP HORN BLOWING)
GIZA PORT - CAIRO
EVELYN: Do you really think
he's going to show up?
JONATHAN: Yes, undoubtedly,
knowing my luck.
He may be a cowboy, but I know the breed.
His word is his word.
Well, personally I think he's filthy, rude,
a complete scoundrel.
- I don't like him one bit.
- Anyone I know?
Oh.
Hello.
Smashing day for the start of an adventure,
eh, O'Connell?
Yeah. Yeah, smashing.
Oh, no, no, I'd never steal
from a partner, partner.
That reminds me?
No hard feelings about the...
- Oh, no, no. Happens all the time.
- Mr. O'Connell?
Can you look me in the eye
and guarantee me
this isn't some sort of a flimflam?
- Because if it is, I am warning you...
- You're warning me?
Lady, let me put it this way,
my whole damn garrison
believed in this so much
that without orders, they marched
halfway across Libya and into Egypt
to find that city
When we got there,
all we found was sand and blood
Let me get your bags.
Yes, yes, you're right.
Filthy, rude, a complete scoundrel.
Nothing to like there at all.
Bright good morning to all.
Oh, no. What are you doing here?
I'm here to protect my investment,
thank you very much.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Quit playing with your glasses
and cut the deck, Burns.
Without my glasses
I can't see the deck to cut it, Dave.
JONATHAN: O'Connell, sit down.
We could use another player.
- I only gamble with my life, never my money.
- Never?
What if I was to bet you $500
we get to Hamunaptra before you?
- You're looking for Hamunaptra?
- Damn straight we are.
- And who saya we are?
- ALL: He does.
DAVE: Well... Well, how about it?
Is it a bet?
- All right, you're on.
- What makes you so confident, sir?
- What makes you?
- We got us a man who's actually been there.
Oh, what a coincidence,
because O'Connell...
Whose play is it? Is it my play? I thought...
Gentlemen, we got us a wager.
Good evening, Jonathan.
Night.
Sorry. Didn't mean to scare you.
The only thing that scares me,
Mr. O'Connell, are your manners.
- Still angry about that kiss, huh?
- Well, if you call that a kiss.
Did I miss something?
Are we... Are we going into battle?
Lady, there's something out there.
Something underneath that sand.
Yes, well,
I'm hoping to find a certain artifact.
A book, actually.
My brother thinks there's treasure.
- What do you think's out there?
- In a word? Evil.
The Bedouin and the Tuaregs believe
that Hamunaptra is cursed.
Oh, look, I don't believe
in fairy tales and hokum, Mr. O'Connell,
but I do believe one of the most
famous books in history is buried there.
The Book of Amun-Ra.
It contains within it all
the secret incantations of the old kingdom.
It's what first interested me in Egypt
when I was a child.
It's why I came here. Sort of a life's pursuit.
And the fact that they say it's made out
of pure gold makes no never mind to you?
- Right.
- You know your history.
I know my treasure.
By the way,
why did you kiss me?
I was about to be hanged.
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
What? What'd I say?
(MAN EXCLAIMING)
(MAN SHOUTING)
Surprise! My good friend, you're alive!
- I was so very, very worried.
- Well, if it ain't my little buddy, Beni.
- I think I'll kill you.
- Think of my children.
You don't have any children.
- Someday I might.
- Shut up!
So, you're the one
who's leading the Americans?
I might have known.
So, what's the scam, Beni?
You task them into the middle of the desert,
and then you leave them to rot?
Unfortunately, no.
These Americans are smart.
They pay me only half now,
half when I get them back to Cairo.
- So this time I must go all the way.
- Them's the breaks, huh?
You never believed
in Hamunaptra, O'Connell.
Why are you going back?
(CAMEL GROANING)
You see that girl? She saved my neck.
You always did have more balls than brains.
Yeah. Goodbye, Beni.
(SCREAMING)
(BENI COUGHING)
BENI: O'Connell!
George Bembridge...
In 1860...
1865, was...
Was...
Oh, for heaven's sake, girl,
it wasn't that good of a kiss, anyway.
(THUDDING)
(GASPS)
Where is the map?
It's... It's... There.
And the key? Where is the key?
The key? The key? What key?
RICK: Evelyn!
(SCREAMING)
The map! The map! I forgot the map!
Relax. I'm the map? It's all up here?
Oh, that's comforting.
(GROANING)
- The key!
- JONATHAN: Evy.
(SCREAMING)
Hold on to this.
(GUN FIRING)
Can you swim?
Of course I can swim,
if the occasion calls for it.
Trust me. It calls for it.
(YELLING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
O'Connell! O'Connell!
What are we going to do?
- Wait here! I'll go get help!
- Right!
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
(EXCLAIMING)
Americans.
I say, bloody good show, chaps!
And did I panic?
I think not.
HENDERSON: Get them out of the water!
Get them out of the water!
Come on, doggies!
Give them a smack, would you?
This is a messed-up country.
We've lost everything!
All of our tools, all the equipment!
All my clothes!
O'Connell!
Hey!
It Iooks to me Iike I've got all the horses!
Hey, Beni!
Looks to me
like you're on the wrong side of the river!
Yeah?
(SWEARING IN HUNGARIAN)
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
JONATHAN: I only want four! Four!
I only want four, not a whole bloody herd!
O'Connell! Can you believe the cheek?
Just pay the man.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
Can't believe the price of these fleabags?
Yes, happy? Very good.
You probably could've got them for free.
- All we had to do was give him your sister.
- Yes.
Awfully tempting, wasn't it?
Awfully.
JONATHAN: Never did like camels.
Filthy buggers.
They smell, they bite, they spit.
- Disgusting.
- I think they're adorable.
Oh, baby
(SINGING IN ARABIC)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(MOANING)
(CAMEL LOWING)
(SHUSHING)
(SNORING)
(MUMBLING)
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
This one is strong.
BENI: Good morning, my friend.
What the hell we doing?
Patience, my good barat'm. Patience.
Remember our bet, O'Connell?
First one to the city, 500 cash bucks.
A hundred of them bucks is yours
if you help us win that bet.
Oh, my pleasure.
Hey, O'Connell. Nice camel.
(GRUNTING)
RICK: Get ready for it.
- For what?
- We're about to be shown the way.
- Will you look at that?
- Can you believe it?
Hamunaptra.
Here we go again.
(MARSHALLING)
So long, Beni!
That serves you right.
(MARSHALLING)
(WHOOPING)
Go, Evy! Go!
(EVELYN EXCLAIMING)
(MAN SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(MEN CHATTERING)
Do they know something we don't?
They are led by a woman.
What does a woman know?
EVELYN: That's a statue of Anubis.
Its legs go deep underground.
According to Bembridge scholars,
that's where we'll find a secret compartment
containing the golden Book of Amun-Ra.
Jonathan, you're meant to catch the sun
with that.
- So, what are these old mirrors for?
- Ancient mirrors.
It's an ancient Egyptian trick. You'll see.
Here, this for you.
Go ahead. It's something
I borrowed off our American brethren.
I thought you might like it,
you might need it for when you're...
Yeah? What are you looking at?
WARDEN: Hey, look for bugs. I hate bugs.
EVELYN: Do you realize
we're standing inside a room
no one has entered in over 3,000 years?
What is that god-awful stench?
(SNIFFING)
And then there was light?
RICK: Hey, that is a neat trick.
- Oh, my God. It's a sah-netjer.
- What?
- A preparation room.
- Preparation for what?
For entering the afterlife.
Mummies, my good son.
This is where they made the mummies.
(SKITTERING)
What the...
JONATHAN: What was that?
Sounds like bugs.
- EVELYN: He said bugs?
- What do you mean, bugs? I hate bugs!
EVELYN: The legs of Anubis.
The secret compartment should be hidden
somewhere inside here.
(CREATURE MOANS)
(VOICE MUTTERING)
(YELLING)
You scared the bejesus
out of us, O'Connell.
Likewise.
- Hey, that's my tool kit.
- RlCK: No, I don't think so.
Okay? Perhaps I was mistaken.
Have a nice day, gentlemen.
We have a lot of work
to be getting along with.
- Push off! This is our dig site?
- We got here first.
This here's our statue, friend.
I don't see your name written on it, pal.
BENI: Yes, well, there's only four of you
and 15 of me.
Your odds are not so great, O'Connell.
- I've had worse.
- Yeah, me, too.
Oh, look, for goodness' sake,
let's be nice, children.
If we're going to play together,
we must learn to share.
There are other places to dig.
According to these hieroglyphics,
we're underneath the statue.
We should come up right between his legs.
When those damn Yanks go to sleep...
- No offense.
- None taken.
We'll dig our way up and steal that book
right out from under them?
Are you sure
we can find this secret compartment?
Oh, yes, if those beastly Americans
haven't beaten us to it.
- No offense.
- None taken.
Where'd our smelly Iittle friend get to?
Hey.
What have we here?
Blue gold.
This will fetch a mighty fine price.
(CHUCKLING)
(ULULATES)
- HENDERSON: Let's get us some treasure!
- Careful!
Seti was no fool.
I think perhaps
we should let the diggers open it.
BURNS: Oh, I think we should listen
to the good doctor, Henderson.
Yeah, sure. Let them open it.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
RICK: Let me get this straight.
They ripped out your guts
and stuffed them in jars?
They'd take out your heart as well.
You know how they took out your brains?
I don't think we need to know this.
They'd take a sharp, red-hot poker,
stick it up your nose,
scramble things asbout a bit,
and then rip it all out through your nostrils.
- That's gotta hurt.
- It's called mummification.
- You'll be dead when they do this.
- For the record,
if I don't make it out of here,
don't put me down for mummification.
Likewise.
Oh, my God. It's a...
It's a sarcophagus.
Buried at the base of Anubis.
He must have been
someone of great importance.
Or he did something very naughty.
Oh, Allah.
One more.
(SKITTERING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
Help me! Help me!
Help me!
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
Well, who is it?
"He That Shall Not Be Named."
(PUFFING)
This looks like some sort of a lock.
Well, whoever's in here
sure wasn't getting out.
RICK: Yeah, no kidding.
It'd take us a month
to crack into this thing without a key.
A key?
A key! A key!
That's what he was talking about!
- Who?
- The man on the barge,
the one with the hook.
He was looking for a key.
Hey, that's mine.
(WARDEN SCREAMING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
- EVELYN: What do you suppose killed him?
- Did you ever see him eat?
Seems that our American friends
had a little misfortune of their own today.
Three of their diggers were melted.
- What?
- How?
Salt acid.
Pressurized salt acid.
Some kind of ancient booby trap.
Maybe this place really is cursed.
(WIND HOWLING)
Oh, for goodness' sake, you two!
- You don't believe in curses?
- No, I don't.
I believe if I can see it and I can touch it,
it's real. That's what I believe.
I believe in being prepared.
Let's see what our friend
the warden believed in.
(GRUNTING)
- What?
- My God, what is it?
A broken bottle.
Glenlivet, 12 years old!
He may have been as stinky fellow,
but he had good taste.
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Take this. Stay here.
- No, wait, wait! Wait for me. Wait!
- Evy!
Excuse me,
but didn't the man just say stay here?
Evy!
Mr. Henderson! Wake up!
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
JONATHAN: O'Connell!
ARDETH: Enough!
(ARDETH SPEAKING ARABIC)
We will shed no more blood,
but you must leave?
Leave this place or die.
You have one day.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Evelyn.
Hey.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
- You sure?
- Thank you.
BURNS: That proves it. Old Seti's fortune's
got to be under this sand.
For them to protect it like this,
you know there's treasure down there.
No, these men are desert people.
They value water, not gold.
You know, maybe just at night,
we could combine forces.
RICK: Hey, tough stuff, try a right hook.
Ball up your fist and put it...
Put it up like that.
And then mean it. Hit it right here.
- Mean it!
- Okay.
Okay, it's time for another drink.
Unlike my brother, sir,
I know when to say no.
And unlike your brother, miss,
you, I just don't get.
I know. You're wondering
what is a place like me doing
in a girl like this.
- Yeah, something like that.
- Egypt is in my blood.
You see,
my father was a very, very famous explorer.
And he loved Egypt so much,
he married my mother, who was an Egyptian
and quite an adventurer herself?
I get your father
and I get your mother, and...
I get him, but...
What are you doing here?
Look, I may not be an explorer
or an adventurer or a treasure seeker
or a gunfighter, Mr. O'Connell,
but I am proud of what I am.
And what is that?
I...
am a librarian.
And I am going to kiss you,
- Mr. O'Connell.
- Call me Rick.
Rick.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
- There is a curse upon this chest.
- Curse, my ass.
- Who cares?
- Have a care, Mr. Henderson.
In these hallowed grounds,
that which was set forth in ancient times
- is as strong today as it was then.
- We understand.
What's it say?
(READING IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
"Death will come on swift wings"
"to whomsoever opens this chest."
(WIND BLOWING)
(ALL CHATTERING)
(ALL CHOUTING)
BENI: We should not be here.
This is not good.
It says,
"There is one, the undead,"
"who, if brought back to life,
is bound by sacred law"
"to consummate this curse."
Let's make sure we don't bring anyone
back from the dead then.
"He will kill all who open this chest"
"and assimilate their organs and fluids,"
"and in so doing, he will regenerate"
"and no longer be the undead,"
"but a plague upon this Earth."
HENDERSON: Well, we didn't come
all this way for nothing.
- DAVE: That's right.
- It's the curse.
It's the curse.
It's the curse! Beware of the curse!
Beware!
Stupid superstitious bastard.
Oh, I've dreamt about this
since I was a little girl.
You dream about dead guys?
Look, the sacred spells
have been chiseled off.
This man must have been condemned
not only in this life, but in the next.
- Tough break.
- Yeah, I'm all tears.
Now, let's see who's inside, shall we?
(HISSING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Oh, my God,
I hate it when these things do that.
Is he supposed to look like that?
No, I've never seen
a mummy look like this before.
He's still... Still...
- Juicy.
Yes.
He must be more than 3,000 years old,
and, well, it looks as if he's still
decomposing.
Hey, look at that.
- What do you make of this?
- My God, these marks were made with...
Fingernails.
This man was buried alive.
And he left a message.
"Death is only the beginning?"
Oh, my God.
It does exist.
- The Book of the Dead.
- A book?
Who cares about a book?
Where the hell's the treasure?
This, gentlemen.
This is treasure.
Hell, I wouldn't trade you for a brass...
Look at that.
EGYPTOLOGIST:
There's your treasure, gentlemen.
BURNS: Now, we're on to something.
(MAN GRUNTING)
I believe you need a key to open that book.
HENDERSON: Say, O'Connell,
what do you think
these babies'll fetch back home?
We hear you boys found yourselves
a nice, gooey mummy. Congratulations.
If you dry that fellow out,
you might be able to sell him for firewood.
EVELYN: Look what I found.
You're in her seat.
- Now!
- Yup.
Scarab skeletons, flesh-eaters.
I found them inside our friend's coffin.
They can stay alive for years
feasting on the flesh of a corpse.
Unfortunately for our friend, he was
still alive when they started eating him.
RICK: So somebody
threw these in with our guy,
and then they slowly ate him alive?
Very slowly.
He certainly wasn't as popular fellow
when they planted him, was he?
Well, he probably got a little too frisky
with the pharaoh's daughter.
Well, according to my readings,
our friend suffered the Hom-Dai,
the worst of all Ancient Egyptian curses,
one reserved only
for the most evil of blasphemers.
In my research, I've never heard of
this curse having actually been performed.
- RICK: That bad, huh?
- Yes, well, they...
They never used it because they feared it so.
It's written that if a victim of the Hom-Dai
should ever arise,
he would bring with him
the 10 plagues of Egypt.
That's called stealing, you know?
According to you and my brother,
it's called borrowing.
RICK: I thought the Book of Amun-Ra
was made out of gold?
It is made out of gold.
This isn't the Book of Amun-Ra.
This is something else.
I think this may be the Book of the Dead.
The Book of the Dead?
Are you sure you're meant to be
playing around with this thing?
It's just a book.
No harm ever came from reading a book.
(WIND HOWLING)
That happens a lot around here.
So, what's it say?
"Amun Ra. Amun Dei."
It speaks of the night and of the day.
(READING IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
(GROWLING)
No! You must not read from the book!
(CAMEL GRUNTING)
(BUZZING)
Run!
Go, go!
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
What have we done?
- BURNS: Where the hell did they come from?
- I ain't waiting around to find out.
BURNS: My glasses. My glasses!
Leave me! Leave me!
Hey! Hey!
Could you help me find my gl...
Wait for me!
(THUDDING)
Who's there?
(CREATURE GROWLING)
BURNS: (WHISPERING) Daniels?
(GROWLING)
(CREATURE GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(RUMBLING)
Oh, Jon!
(SKITTERING)
Scarabs!
JONATHAN: Run, Evy! Go, go, go! Run!
(SCREAMING)
- Evelyn?
- JONATHAN: Evy?
- Evy!
(WALL CLOSING)
(MAN MOANING)
Oh, Mr. Burns. Thank goodness.
I was just starting to get scared.
I've lost everyone.
(GROANING)
My eyes. My eyes...
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(MUMMY GROWLING)
Please help me.
My tongue. He took my tongue.
Please don't leave me.
(GROWLING)
Anck-Su-Namun.
Damn it! It's a trap door.
There's gotta be a switch
or something around here someplace.
(MAN SHOUTING)
- Run, you sons of bitches! Run!
- Go.
(SCREAMING)
Go! Go!
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Come with me my Princess Anck-su-namum.
There you are!
Will you quit playing hide-and-seek?
Come on. Let's get out of here.
(SHUDDERING)
JONATHAN: Evy!
(ROARING)
(GROWLING)
- Move!
- JONATHAN: Yeah, right.
BENI: Did you see that?
It was walking. It was walking!
I told you to leave or die.
You refused.
Now, you may have killed us all,
for you have unleashed a creasture
we have feared for more than 3,000 years.
- Relax. I got him.
- No mortal weapon can kill this creature.
He's not of this world.
- You bastard.
- What did you do to him?
We saved him. Saved him
before the creature could finish his work.
Leave, all of you, quickly,
before he finishes you all.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
I must now go on the hunt,
and try and find a way to kill him.
I already told you, I got him.
Know this,
this creature is the bringer of death.
He will never eat, he will never sleep,
and he will never stop.
(CREATURES SQUEALING)
(CREATURE GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
(GROWLING)
May the good Lord protect
and watch over me
as a shepherd watches over his flock.
(CHANTING IN ARABIC)
No. Okay.
(SPEAKING GIBBERISH)
(SPEAKING HEBREW)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
The language of the slaves...
I may have use for you.
And the rewards...
...will be great.
My prince.
Where are the other sacred jars...
(MARSHALLING)
(GROWLING)
FORT BRYDON - CAIRO
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I thought you said you didn't believe
in that fairy tales and hokum stuff.
Having an encounter with a 3,000-year-old
walking, talking corpse
does tend to convert one.
Forget it. We're out the door,
down the hall, and we're gone.
- Oh, no, we are not.
- Oh, yes, we are.
Oh, no, we are not. We woke him up,
and we are going to stop him.
We? What we? We didn't read that book.
I told you not to play around with that thing.
Didn't I tell you?
Yes, right then, me, me, me, me.
I, I, I woke him up and I intend to stop him.
Yeah? How?
You heard the man.
No mortal weapons can kill this guy.
Then we are just going to have to find
some immortal ones.
There goes that we again.
Look, will you listen to me?
We have to do something.
Once this creature has been reborn,
his curse is going to spread
until the whole of the Earth is destroyed.
- Yeah? Is that my problem?
- Lt is everybody's problem.
Evelyn, I appreciate
you saving my Iife and all,
but when I signed on, I agreed to take you
out there and to bring you back.
I have done that? End of job. End of story.
Contract terminated.
That's all I am to you? A contract?
You can either tag along with me or you can
stay here and try and save the world.
- What's it gonna be?
- I'm staying.
- Fine.
Fine.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm the last of the Royal Air Corps
still stationed out here, you know...
Some bloody idiot spilt his drink.
All the other laddies died in the sky
and were buried in the sand.
Good chaps, every one of them, too.
- Hi, Winston.
- Yeah...
You know, O'Connell,
ever since the end of the great war,
there hasn't been a single challenge
worthy of a man like me.
Yeah? We all got
our little problems today, Winston.
I just wish I could have chucked it in
with the others
and gone down in flame and glory,
instead of sitting around here, rotting
- of boredom and booze.
- Of boredom and booze.
Cheers.
Oh, well, back to the airfield.
- Tell me, has your sister always been...
- Oh, yes, always.
We're all packed up, but the damn boat
doesn't leave till tomorrow morning.
Tail set firmly between your legs, I see.
You can talk. You don't have
some sacred walking corpse after you.
So, how's your friend?
He had his eyes and his tongue ripped out.
How would you be?
I'm so pleased to meet you.
Prince Imhotep does not Iike to be touched.
A silly Eastern superstition, I'm afraid.
Please forgive me.
BENI: Mr. Burns, Prince Imhotep
thanks you for your hospitality.
No.
And for your eyes,
- and for your tongue.
- Wha...
- But I am afraid more is needed.
The prince must finish the job
and consummate the curse,
- which you and your friends...
- No!
- ...have brought down upon yourselves.
- No! Wait! No!
(BURNS SCREAMING)
Good luck, boys.
Sweet Jesus!
Tasted just like...
Blood.
"And the rivers and waters of Egypt
ran red and were as blood."
He's here.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
MAN: Oh, looks Iike it's gonna storm.
- Oh, Evelyn!
- Oh, so you're still here.
We've got problems.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Hey!
Beni, you little stinkweed. Where you been?
(IMHOTEP ROARING)
(GROWLING)
(ROARING)
We are in serious trouble.
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
You saved me from the undead.
I thank you.
(GROWLING)
(CAT MEOWS)
We are in very serious trouble.
JONATHAN: He does seem to like you Evy.
RiCK: Yeah, what's that about?
HENDERSON: What's this guy want?
There's only one person
that can give us any answers.
EVELYN: You!
CURATOR: Miss Carnahan.
- Gentlemen.
- What is he doing here?
Do you really want to know,
or would you prefer to just shoot us?
After what I just saw,
I'm willing to go on a little faith here.
CURATOR: We are part
of an ancient secret society.
For over 3,000 yeasrs,
we have guarded the City of the Dead.
We are sworn at manhood to do any and all
in our part to stop the High Priest Imhotep
from being reborn into this world.
Because of you, we have failed.
You think this justifies the killing
of innocent people.
To stop this creature? Let me think.
- Yes!
Question. Why doesn't he like cats?
Cats are the guardians of the underworld.
He will fear them
until he is fully regenerated?
Then he will fear nothing.
You know how he gets
his self fully regenerated?
- By killing everyone who opened that chest.
- And sucking them dry!
EVELYN: Jonathan, will you stop
playing with that.
When I saw him alive at Hamunaptra,
he called me Anck-Su-Namun.
And then juat now in Mr. Burns' quarters,
he tried to kiss me.
It's because of his love for Anck-Su-Namun
that he was cursed.
- Apparently, even after 3,000 years...
- He is still in love with her.
Yes, that is very romantic,
but what has it got to do with me?
Perhaps he will once again
try to raise her from the dead.
Yes.
And it appears he has already chosen
his human sacrifice.
Bad luck, old mum.
CURATOR: On the contrary,
it may just give us the time we need
to kill the creature.
We will need all the help we can get.
His powers are growing.
JONATHAN: "And he stretched forth his hand
towards the heavens"
"and there was darkness
throughout the land of Egypt."
EVELYN: We must stop him
from regenerating.
Who opened that chest?
HENDERSON: There was me
and Daniels here.
- And Burns, of course.
- DAVE: And that Egyptologist fellow.
What about my buddy, Beni?
No, he scrammed out of there
before we opened the thing.
- Yeah, he was the smart one.
- RlCK: Yeah, that sounds like Beni.
We must find the Egyptologist
and bring him back to the safety of the fort
- before the creature can get to him.
- Right.
She stays here. You three, come with me.
HENDERSON: Not me...
DAVE: No, no!
Just a minute! You can't leave me behind
like some old carpetbag.
Who put you in charge, O'Connell?
What do you think you are doing?
Jonathan! O'Connell!
- Sorry, but he's a bit tall.
- Jonathan, coward that you are...
O'Connell, you are not leaving me in here!
EVELYN: Jonathan, if you don't
open this door in one minute flat...
- EVELYN: O'Connell...
- This door doesn't open.
- Let me out of here.
- She doesn't come out,
- and no one goes in, right?
- Right.
- Right?
O'Connell! Jonathan!
Let's go, Jonathan?
Oh, I thought I could just astay at the fort
and reconnoiter.
- RICK: Now!
- Yeah, right.
We're just gonna rescue the Egyptologist.
(WINGS FLAPPING)
(WATER SPLASHING)
(BANGING)
(CLATTERING)
(BENI GRUNTING)
Well, well, well. Let me guess.
Spring cleaning?
JONATHAN: Nice shot.
Oh, Beni, did you fall down?
Let me help you up.
You came back from the desert
with a new friend, didn't you, Beni?
What friend? You are my only friend.
What the hell are you doing with this creep?
What's in it for you?
It is better to be the right hand of the devil
than in his path.
As long as I serve him, I am immune.
(GRUNTING)
Immune from what?
(SWEARING IN HUNGARIAN)
What did you say?
I don't wanna tell you.
You'll just hurt me some more.
What are you looking for?
And try not to lie to me.
The book!
The black book they found at Hamunaptra.
He wants it back.
He said to me it would be
worth its weight in gold.
- What does he want the book for?
- I don't know.
Something about bringing
his dead girlfriend back to life.
But that's all.
He just wants the book, I swear.
Just the book, I swear. And your sister.
But other than that...
(MAN SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
(SHOUTING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(BUZZING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- That's two down, two to go.
- Then he'll be coming after Evy.
SOLDIER: (YELLING) Guards in place!
Reporting all clear, sir!
To hell with this?
I'm going downstairs, get me a drink.
You want something?
- Yeah. Yeah, get me a glass of bourbon.
- All right.
- And a shot of bourbon.
- Yeah, okay, okay.
- And as bourbon chasser.
- I'll get your damn bourbon!
Don't worry about the door.
(HOWLING)
(VOICE MUTTERING)
(SCREAMING)
(SIGHING)
Anck-Su-Namun.
(GASPING)
Hey, get your ugly face off of her!
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Look what I got.
(SNARLING)
(GROWLING)
(PANTING)
- You all right?
- Well, I'm not sure.
Well, according to legend, the black book
the Americans found at Hamunaptra
is supposed to bring people
back from the dead.
Until now, it was a notion
I was unwilling to believe.
Believe it, sister.
That's what brought our buddy back to life?
Yes. I'm thinking that if the black book
can bring dead people to life...
- Then maybe the gold book can kill him.
- That's the myth.
Now, we just have to find out
where the gold book is hidden.
CROWD: (CHANTING) Imhotep.
Imhotep.
ALL: lmhotep.
Last but not least,
my favorite plague, boils and sores.
ARDETH: They have become his slaves.
So it has begun, the beginning of the end.
Not quite yet, it hasn't. Come on.
Imhotep.
CROWD: (CHANTING) Imhotep.
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Imhotep.
According to Bembridge scholars,
the golden Book of Amun-Ra
is located inside the statue of Anubis.
- That's where we found the black book.
- Exactly.
Looks Iike the old boys
at Bembridge were mistaken.
They mixed the books up.
Mixed up where they were buried.
So, if the black book
is inside the statue of Anubis,
then the golden book must be inside...
(CLAMORING)
- Come on, Evy, faster.
- Patience is a virtue.
Not right now, it isn't.
- I think I'll go and get the car started.
- I've got it.
The golden Book of Amun-Ra
is at Hamunaptra inside the statue of Horus.
Take that, Bembridge scholars.
(CLAMORING)
Imhotep.
ALL: lmhotep.
Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Get this thing in gear, boy.
Let's get out of here.
- JONATHAN: Evy. Come on, Evy. Hurry up.
- Imhotep!
Imhotep!
(GROWLING)
You're gonna get yours, Beni! You hear me?
- You're gonna get yours!
- Oh, like I've never heard that before!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(JONATHAN SCREAMING)
Hang on!
(GRUNTING)
Hey! O'Connell! O'Connell!
(SNARLING)
(GASPING)
(ROARING)
(CRUNCHING)
Jump down!
Move, move, move!
ALL: (CHANTING) Imhotep.
Imhotep.
It's the creature.
He's fully regenerated.
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Come with me, my princess.
It is time to make you mine forever.
For all eternity, idiot.
BENI: Take my hand,
and I will spare your friends.
Oh, dear.
- Have you got any bright ideas?
- I'm thinking, I'm thinking.
You better think of something fast,
because if he turns me into a mummy,
you're the first one I'm coming after.
No.
- Don't.
- No!
He has to take me to Hamunaptra
to perform the ritual.
She is right.
Live today, fight tomorrow.
I'll be seeing you again.
Evelyn!
- Hey, that's mine.
- Thank you.
Kill them all!
No! Let go of me!
ALL: lmhotep.
EVELYN: Let go of me!
- Goodbye, my friend.
- Come here, you little...
Imhotep.
Come on!
- What about my sister?
- We're gonna get her back!
Go!
RICK: You're next!
Come on! Give me your hand!
- You go!
- Come on!
Go!
(GRUNTING)
(CURATOR SCREAMING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
RICK: Morning, Winston. A word?
What's your little problem got to do
with His Majesty's Royal Air Corps?
Not a damn thing.
- Is it dasngerous?
- You probably won't live through it.
By Jove, do you really think so?
Everybody else we've bumped into has died.
Why not you?
What's the... What's the challenge, then?
Rescue the damsel in distress,
kill the bad guy, and save the world.
Winston Havlock at your service, sir.
Are you all right?
Do I bloody look all right?
How you doing?
See that? I've never seen one so big.
- Never?
- No!
Get off me! Get off!
I need a new job.
EVELYN: Oh, my God.
We're back.
(AIRCRAFT HOVERING)
O'Connell.
(ROARING)
Oh, my God.
Hey, Winston! Pedal faster!
Hang on, men!
Stop it! You'll kill them!
That's the idea.
(ALL SCREAMING)
Here I come, laddies!
(LAUGHING)
(ENGINE SPLUTTERING)
I love the whole sand-wall trick.
It was beautiful.
Bastard.
(GRUNTING)
JONATHAN: Excuse me.
A little help would be useful,
if it's not too much trouble!
Yeah, yeah. All right.
Winston! Hey, Winston!
Quicksand! Get back! It's quicksand?
Keep moving!
Nasty little fellows such as yourself
always get their comeuppance.
- Really? They do?
- Oh, yes.
Always?
(SKITTERING)
JONATHAN: I'd take
those bigger stones first.
Take them from the top, otherwise
the whole thing will cave in on us.
Come on. Put your backs into it.
Yes, well, you've got the idea. Chop, chop.
(CREATURES SQUEALING)
I say!
Gents, you should come
and have a look at this.
(SKITTERING)
(SCREAMING)
What?
It's my arm! My arm!
- Do something!
- Hold it!
Do something! Do something!
Not that! Not that!
(JONATHAN SCREAMING)
O'Connell.
(CHANTING IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
(CREATURE GROANING)
(BOTH GROANING)
Bembridge scholars never wrote about this.
Get off me. Get off!
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Kill them...
...and wake the others.
Wha... Wha...
- Can you see...
- Yeah.
- Can you believe...
- Can we just...
- No.
(CREATURE GRUNTS)
- Who the hell are these guys?
- Priests.
Imhotep's priests.
All right, then.
(CREATURES SHRIEKING)
(CREATURE SQUEALING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
There he is!
Hello, Horus, old boy.
(PRIESTS SHRIEKING)
Time to close the door.
(MUTTERING IN HUNGARIAN)
(PRIESTS GRUNTING)
IMHOTEP: Anck-Su-Namun.
EVELYN: O'Connell!
Jonathan!
(CREATURE CROAKING)
Damn. These guys just don't quit, do they?
Keep digging.
(JINGLING)
JONATHAN: The Book of Amun-Ra.
Save the girl. Kill the creature.
(YELLING)
RICK: What are you waiting for?
Get out! Get out!
You all right. Let's go.
(PRIESTS CHANTING)
(IMHOTEP CHANTING
IN ANCIENT EGYPTlAN)
(SHRIEKING)
(SCREAMING)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
With your death, Anck-su-namun shall live.
And I shall be invincible!
JONATHAN: The Book of Amun-Ra!
I found it, Evy! I found it!
The Book of Amun-Ra.
EVELYN: Shut up
and get me off here, Jonathan!
Open the book, Jonathan.
It's the only way to kill him.
You have to open the book
and find the inscription.
JONATHAN: Well, I can't open it!
It's locked or something.
- We need the key, Evy!
- EVELYN: It's inside his robes.
EVELYN: O'Connell!
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
(ALL GRUNTING)
Mummies.
(MUMMY GRUNTING)
Look out! There's one there... O'Connell!
Here's an inscription.
(READING IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Oh, boy.
Oh, yeah.
This just keeps getting better and better.
- Do something, Jonathan.
- Me?
- You can command them.
- You have got to be joking.
Finish the inscription on the cover, idiot,
then you can control them.
Oh. Right.
(SHRIEKING)
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
(YELLING)
(GROWLING)
(PANTING)
Hurry up, Jonathan!
(MUMMY ROARING)
(GRUNTS)
- I can't figure out this last symbol.
- What does it look like?
(SCREAMING)
It's a bird. A stork!
(GASPING)
Ahmenophus.
Oh, yes, I see.
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
(IMHOTEP SPEAKING
ANCIENT EGYPTlAN)
Destroy him!
I command you to destroy him!
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Anck-Su-Namun!
Give me that book!
(SCREAMING)
Now you die.
Evy, I've got it.
Keep him busy.
No problem.
- Hurry, Evy! Hurry!
- You're not helping.
Now it's your turn.
EVELYN: Oh! I've got it?
(READING IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
(SCREAMING)
(SHOUTING IN ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
RICK: I thought you said
it was gonna kill him!
(GROWLING)
He's mortal.
(SPEAKING ANCIENT EGYPTIAN)
Death is only the beginning.
(COINS JINGLING)
(CREAKING)
(RUMBLING)
Time to go.
You've lost the book!
Jonathan, I can't believe...
- Hurry!
- Come on!
- Couldn't we just...
- No, Jonathan!
BENI: O'Connell!
- O'Connell! Wait!
- Come on, come on!
- Wait! Please!
- Come on, come on! Beni!
Goodbye, Beni.
(SQUEAKING)
Go away.
(SKITTERING)
(SHOOING)
(BENI SCREAMING)
JONATHAN: Look out, look out!
(SCREAMING)
Thank you. Thank you very much?
You have earned the respect and gratitude
of me and my people?
Yes, well, it was nothing?
May Allah smile upon you always.
And yourself.
- Yes, anytime.
- RlCK: Stay out of trouble.
He's just leaving us here?
Well, I guess we go home
empty-handed again.
I wouldn't say that.
Oh, please!
How about you, darling?
Would you Iike a little kissy-wissy?
(GRUNTING)
(JINGLING)