Previously on Alcatraz...
Meet the 63s...
The worst criminals
this country has ever known
are coming back.
My grandfather wasn't a guard.
He was an inmate.
Aah!
That's him.
He killed my partner.
Police!
So we have to find
these 63s.
We need to find
who took them.
I need you to watch them.
They're not so bad.
This is the place.
Manager I.D.'d Cobb,
room 123.
Lucy, get down!
Scream...
And I'll kill your brother.
Hey, child killer.
Teach him a lesson.
That's right,
I'm talking to you!
Nowhere to run now, son.
Hey, child killer.
How long's it been?
Not long.
Third dance they took him on
since the weather turned?
Could be the fourth.
Could be his last.
We'd all be better off.
Just get him inside
before they kill him.
You have
the best life ever.
Smoking hot partner,
secret task force,
comic book guru.
And you don't have
to go to school ever again.
So what you're saying is
I'm a 16-year-old's wet dream?
- Hey, here's one for you.
-  Chrysanthemum.
I'm not even sure
if I'm saying it right.
- Chrysanthemum?
-  You planting a garden, Vic?
I'm filling out a report.
11-year-old boy
went missing last night.
His mom says all she found
in his bed this morning
was a flower.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Whoa.
You okay, Doc?
Any change?
Sinoatrial node.
You ever heard of it?
It's a group of cells
in the wall
of the right atrium.
It's supposed to generate
electrical impulses.
Well, there's...
Still every chance that she
could come out of it, right?
Hey, um...
Guys.
I know it's Saturday
and all,
but there's a boy missing
in Walnut Creek,
and they found a flower
on his bed.
A chrysanthemum.
Which might just sound creepy
and not, like,
you know, a clue,
except the same thing happened
in 1958 three different times
with an Alcatraz inmate.
And since some of those guys
are, you know, back,
I think...
I mean, I know it's him,
Kit Nelson, AZ246,
who stole the kid
from his bed.
Where did you hear
about this?
I heard it
on my police scanner.
You have
a police scanner?
Not the point.
We need to go.
I mean, I know
what this guy does.
I know
what happens next.
What exactly is that, Soto?
He kills him.
He steals them on a Friday,
brings their bodies back home
Sunday night.
If we don't find this kid
in 48 hours,
he's gonna be dead.
On March 21, 1963,
Alcatraz officially closed.
All the prisoners
were transferred off the island.
Only that's not what happened.
Not at all.
ALCATRAZ
Ep. 3 - Kit Nelson
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com
So tell me about Kit Nelson.
Does he have any family
that might still be alive?
No.
His mother died
while he was in Alcatraz,
his dad in the early '80s.
He had a kid brother who died
of Scarlet fever
when he was 11.
11?
Same age
as our victim.
This is it.
I found it
on Dylan's bed this morning.
I don't know
where it came from.
But Dylan wouldn't run away.
He's a good kid.
Did Dylan's brother
see anything?
No.
Liam was asleep
the whole time.
Do you recognize
this man?
Yeah, that's Warren
from Keller's hardware.
He knocked on our door
looking for work.
I didn't think...
Wait, why do you have
his picture?
Does he have something
to do with Dylan?
Did he take my son?
He's a suspect
in another case.
A case
of kidnapping?
What about you, Liam?
Do you remember this man
working at your house?
Did you talk to him?
He gave me rock candy.
Oh, okay.
When's the last time
you saw him?
Was he in your bedroom
last night?
I pretended to be asleep
because I was scared.
You know what, Liam,
you helped us out a lot.
I really appreciate it.
Thank you.
Do you have the address
for the hardware store?
Remember the rules.
One hour or two?
Ay...
Give me two hours
and a pail of worms.
This ought to do you.
I'd set your nose,
but, given your popularity
around here,
I don't think it'll hold.
You got anything stronger?
How about a cigarette?
No, not my brand.
Suit yourself.
You know, I got an eight
and ten-year-old.
So if you're looking
for something stronger,
you're crap out of luck.
Hey, what's so damn funny?
You don't want to mess
with Dr. Beauregard
or you'll end up on this side
of the screen,
giving enough blood to put
the red cross out of business.
You know, your situation
might improve if you made pals
with some of your fellow lags.
But you don't like grown-ups,
do you?
No friends your own age,
as far as I can tell.
Shut the hell up
and get off my back, would ya?
What does make a grown man
pick on kids?
You really hate 'em
that much?
That's it for today,
Madsen.
Wow. They really did
a number on you, didn't they?
Damn prison pecking order.
Now is it rapists,
robbers, thieves,
or thieves, rapists, robbers?
Robbers, murderers, rapists.
Then child killers.
They didn't beat you
because of what you did.
They beat you
because of what you are.
I've never seen him before
in my life.
Said his name was Warren
and that he worked here.
Hey, Warren.
That's Warren.
Where's his uniform?
We had a break-in last week.
They took it.
Take anything else?
A couple of kids'
fishing poles.
I mean it stood to reason
that it was kids
did the stealing,
so I didn't report it.
Where do people fish
around here?
Well, there's
really only one place.
Lafayette recreation area.
Okay, I need you
to get into the water now.
What do you mean?
Into the water.
Now.
Okay, now I want you
to hold me under
for as long as you can.
I can't.
You're bigger than me.
Just do it.
And don't let me up.
Do it.
Do it!
Your turn.
So, he took the kid fishing.
Rental guy said they
were wet when they left.
I guess they went swimming too.
So he wants
a buddy now?
Someone to play with?
You know,
a teenager in '58
said he saw Nelson
playing miniature golf
with one of his victims
the day before he killed him.
No one believed the kid.
They thought it was too creepy
to be true.
Didn't make it
in any of the crime reports.
I dug it up doing research
for my book.
But if he did take
that kid to miniature golf
and he took this kid fishing...
Maybe he lets the kids pick
things they like to do?
Like some kind
of sick last hoorah.
Lures 'em in,
makes 'em have fun
before he...
You know.
You okay?
What?
Yeah.
No, totally fine.
Okay, let's go find out
what else Dylan likes to do.
Eat your popcorn.
I don't want it.
Eat it,
all of it.
Let's you and me take a ride.
I'd rather stay in my bed
if it's the same to you, warden.
Get in the chair.
I take no offense
off your hostile tone
since it's me responsible
for the inmates
who wrought on you
this beating.
But know this.
Dusk till dawn,
I've racked my brains
and still can't fathom
what in heck to do
with the likes of you.
So I've decided to separate you
from the pack.
Meals in your cell,
ten minutes private time
in the yard.
Once you're back
on your feet, of course.
That's not what brings me here
to speak to you today.
I received a letter
from your father.
He'd like to visit.
Well, he's not on my list.
He's your father.
And served two tours
in the war, as did I.
Well, he's still not
on my list.
Well, that puts me
in a bona fide conundrum.
Lord only knows
what kind of family business
he needs to speak to you about
so urgently.
But if he's willing
to travel all this way,
he's earned the right
to see your ugly mug.
You leave it to me
to amend your list myself.
Now get up.
Hey.
How am I supposed to get back?
Walk.
The Amber alert
for Dylan Callahan...
You need
to cancel it immediately.
I already canceled
on a national level.
Walnut Creek's
all that's left.
No, no, you're not listening
to me.
I don't have time
to get down there.
She's still in the hospital.
That's why I'm calling.
We need to know
some of Dylan's hobbies.
Are there places
he likes to go?
Anything he likes to do?
Um, he goes to the comic book
store every Wednesday.
And he likes to watch cartoons,
the Simpsons, South Park.
King of the Hill sometimes.
Okay, does he like to do
anything outside?
Boating? Fishing?
- Swimming maybe?
- No.
He's not athletic.
He likes to be indoors.
Wait.
Wait, I got it wrong.
- Doc, that's okay.
- No, it's not okay.
- We got to figure it out.
- Doc.
Wait.
Wait, wait.
The other case
this man is wanted in,
I want you to tell me
this time.
Did they get their kid back?
- Cherry pie.
- Cherry pie?
Doc, why don't you go wait
out front for me?
Yeah, good idea.
I'll wait out front.
Thank you.
Uh, where are you guys
going?
Amber alert's
been canceled.
Wait.
What?
Probably has something to do
with the mom
divorcing the kids' dad
last year.
Dad? You think
the dad has any idea
what a chrysanthemum
even looks like?
You're not going anywhere.
The Amber alert,
it's uncanceled.
I'll take care of this.
You did this?
You canceled the Amber alert?
Yup, I did.
For the greater good.
The greater good?
What's more important
than finding this kid?
What's important
is that the house
doesn't look
like a crime scene.
Well, how else are we gonna
find out where he's going?
We know exactly
where he's going.
Right back here.
Oh, so that's how you're going
to catch him?
Great idea.
The only problem
with your strategy there,
Dr. Strangelove,
is the kid'll already be dead.
Lower your voice, Soto.
You don't get it.
We can save this kid.
We need the Amber alert to get
Nelson's photo out there.
That's exactly
what we can't do,
put out photos
of a '63.
Oh, 'cause God forbid
someone figures out
- your little secret.
- Whoa, whoa.
Did you just cancel
the Amber alert
while the kid's
still missing?
- It's complicated.
- No.
It's not complicated.
It's simple.
I know this,
- because I'm a human being.
- Doc.
- I'm not like you.
Calm down.
Just let him walk it off.
The kid, Lucy,
he's emotional.
What if the mother had heard?
These situations
need to be handled...
Well, maybe you should have
told us about the Amber alert.
He's just not cut out
for this job.
He's a comic book writer.
In the past three days,
he's seen
about ten dead bodies,
and he watched Lucy
get shot 5 feet
away from him.
Look, we're a man down.
- We need him.
- You need him.
You know what,
you're right.
Just get rid of him.
While you're at it,
I'm out of here.
You're free to go
anytime you want.
But you can forget
about finding your grandfather.
Oh, my God, this isn't
about my grandfather.
There's 302 men, right?
And they're all coming back.
And they're all as evil
as that sick freak
that took Dylan.
Yes, I need Doc,
but I need you too.
I know how upset
you are about Lucy,
but unless you have
a better idea,
you're gonna have to
trust me... us.
If you don't, you're gonna end
up alone in this.
Hey, you got
any cherry pie?
Best in the County.
You think this guy's
been in to order any?
Might have been
with an 11-year-old kid.
No, if he had tried
my cherry pie,
he wouldn't look
so damn unhappy.
You've
reached Doc, Dr. Soto,
Doc's comics,
your Doc in shining armor.
Take your pick.
Come on, Doc.
Where are you?
I was thinking
about what you said.
The cherry pie thing.
Okay, I don't know.
If Nelson isn't doing
what the boys like to do,
is he doing
what he likes to do?
Is that what you meant
by cherry pie?
Is that something
Nelson likes?
Just call me.
Please.
He's not picking up.
You think he's out searching
for cherry pie?
Hey, he has a theory,
which is more than anyone
in this room can say.
Kit Nelson's box.
Nail clippers,
cigarettes, soap.
To you and me,
it means nothing.
To Doc,
it's a life story.
And that's why we need him.
Get him back.
Another round?
Make it a double.
Hey, miss. Give us two
slices of cherry pie, would you?
A couple of waters
with that.
Thanks.
Oh, hey...
Honey.
How are you?
Doc, what's going on?
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I mean, no.
I'm at the Hillcrest Diner
on Pacific drive,
just, you know,
hanging out.
Is Kit Nelson there
with you?
Yes.
Is Dylan with him?
Huh?
Doc, stay put.
I'm on my way.
There you go.
Thank you, ma'am.
All right.
Dig in.
No, hold your fork
in your left hand.
Do it.
I'm glad to see
they're treating you
like you deserve.
Say what you came for...
and leave.
Your mama died.
She left you something.
A dried chrysanthemum.
Your mama told me
how she went
to her daddy's funeral
for the weekend
and left you boys alone.
How, when she came back,
Elliott was dead,
his body burning
from Scarlet fever.
But that wasn't the truth,
was it?
You hated your brother because
he was different than you.
He loved life...
Swimming in lakes,
miniature golf,
cherry pie.
But not you.
Your mama knew
what you did.
But she wasn't prepared to lose
two babies in one day.
So she protected you.
And she told everyone a lie
and buried the body
before they could look.
But your little plan
backfired.
You got rid of him,
and your mama ignored you
even worse.
She was scared of you,
of what's inside you.
So tell me,
son...
Did you kill your brother?
It was Scarlet fever,
just like mama said.
Yeah.
I thank God
for Alcatraz.
When I die,
it'll be in peace,
knowing you will be
a rotting corpse
before they let you
out of here.
Let's go.
Come on.
No.
This way.
Honey,
let me get that for you.
Excuse me!
Do you have change for a dollar?
No.
Hey.
What are you guys up to?
Beat it, fatso.
Kit Nelson.
Let him go.
Dylan,
don't give up.
Police.
Let the boy go.
- No!
- Take it easy.
Drop your gun on the ground.
Over there.
Now!
Now your phone and your keys.
Get over there.
Now what you're gonna do is,
you're gonna handcuff yourself
to that dumpster over there.
- We just want Dylan.
- Do it!
Okay.
Get in the car.
Now, if I see
any headlights,
anyone's,
this kid dies.
Oh!
I just got that kid killed,
didn't I?
Doc, wait up.
Doc.
- Comb.
- Take it easy.
Padlock.
Nail clippers.
Soap.
Guy that evil
who uses soap.
Same as us.
It's not your fault.
We're gonna catch this guy.
12 hours.
That's all we got.
Ottomans.
Look, there's got to be...
Eight, ten packs in here.
Okay,
didn't they all smoke?
Yeah, prison-issue cigarettes.
Not name brands.
These went for 5 bucks
a pack.
Only Al Capone or Machine Gun
Kelly could afford these.
So how did a guy like Nelson
get the money
to buy 'em?
Okay. So I went through
every check that came in
while Nelson was there,
and I found this...
A check from C&C cement company
for $148.28.
Ten days later,
a deposit
in the same amount made to Kit
Nelson's commissary account.
So Nelson worked
for C&C.
It must have been back pay.
There's only one check
made out to cash.
No paper trail.
C&C went belly up
in the early '60s,
but when they were
in business,
they built bomb shelters.
150 in the Western U.S.,
including the towns
where Nelson's three victims
from 1958 lived.
Bomb shelters, yeah.
That's a perfect place
to hide in.
If he worked there,
he'd know
where they all were.
Including one
in Walnut Creek.
50 years ago,
there was a house there.
Now it's just woods.
No. No.
No!
That was the wrong move.
I want to go home.
When can I go home?
Soon.
Where are you taking me,
huh?
I didn't do nothing.
Where are you taking me,
huh?
Where are you taking me?
The best
Alcatraz has to offer.
Two impermeable layers
of steel encasement.
Guaranteed not to bother you
is light or sound.
- Get him inside.
- No, no!
It's thinner rations.
You'd be wise
to conserve your strength.
No! No!
This conversation's
four matches long, son.
Phillumeny.
Word describes the collecting
of match-related items
such as matchbox labels
and matchboxes.
This matchbox
is a Swedish safety match
from the Jonkoping
match factory.
It was manufactured
in 1858.
Just in time
for the American Civil War.
I like it very much.
I guess that makes me
something of a...
Phillumenist.
That's number two.
Now tell me what you did
to your brother.
My brother died
of Scarlet fever.
That's a lie, son.
Your father would like
to know the truth.
It'll give me great pleasure
to be able
to tell it to him.
I think
you killed your brother.
I think your daddy
was off to war
and your mama left you alone,
and you killed him.
Maybe you didn't mean to
at first,
but once you got a taste,
indulged your dirty appetite
three times further
before they finally caught you.
How's your math skills?
I believe
that's number three.
You're doing this
out of loyalty
- for another vet?
- No, son.
I'm doing this...
Because I'm a father too.
Is it your intention
to remain in this dark casket
for the remainder
of your time,
or are you gonna say
what you did?
Last match, son.
Okay.
Yeah, it's like you said.
Yes?
I liked it.
We were in a bomb shelter
out back,
and I squeezed his neck
as hard as I could,
and I got to tell you,
it was not...
Difficult.
He was kicking and screaming.
He was trying to get
my hands off him, but...
And then he just
looked up at me.
His eyes were red
with little specks
of blood in them
where the blood vessels broke,
the pressure from all
that screaming
and nothing coming out.
Not even air.
And then his body
just went soft.
And heavy.
And that's when I knew.
That he was dead?
That I had to do it again.
Bonus match.
And the flower?
Oh, I put that
on my mama's bed.
A consolation prize?
Yeah.
It was her favorite.
Him too.
Good boy.
I'm gonna do something
for you now.
Mm-hmm.
I'm gonna let you keep
your clothes.
What?
No.
No, I told you
the truth,
just like you said.
You're gonna leave me here now?
- That's not fair.
- Fair?
Interesting choice of words
for someone
who outweighs his victims
by 100 pounds.
Make 'em last.
I'm hungry.
Is there any food?
You'll get food.
It's cold down here.
Could I at least get
a blanket?
Hey!
Doc, there it is.
- Stop!
- Help!
Please, help me!
Please!
Help!
Don't move!
You know,
you didn't shoot before.
You're not gonna shoot now.
You don't have a weapon.
Let the kid go.
I think I'm gonna take
my chances.
Dylan.
You know,
even if we were allowed
to tell people what we did,
I doubt they'd believe us.
You're probably right.
I need a word.
With me?
Yeah.
I'd like to stay.
That's up to Soto.
Arrested development
is what happens
when we're traumatized
as children.
We get stuck
at the age we were
when the trauma occurred
for our entire lives.
And you were what, 11?
Do you know why I allow you
to be here, Soto?
10,000 hours.
That's the time it takes
for a person to become
an expert at something.
And I'm guessing you've spent
twice that
studying Alcatraz.
But I need
the adult Soto,
not the 11-year-old.
Yes, Mr. Hauser.
Sir.
Uh...
The thing
he was talking about...
When I was 11, uh...
It's okay, Doc.
Whatever it is,
I bet you've got a pretty good
origin story yourself.
Oh.
The cherry pie thing...
I read that
in your book.
Nice call.
Wait for me.
It'll only be a minute.
Saw you were missing
12, 27, and 35.
No way.
This is awesome.
So...
You okay?
I'm fine.
Well, let me know
if you need any others.
I'm still scared.
When I was a kid,
about your age,
something happened...
Where someone took me.
Just like that guy
who took you, right?
And it wasn't easy,
but...
I got away too.
And once that happens,
once you know
that you can do that...
It sort of gives you
a superpower.
Like theirs,
but real.
I didn't give up,
like you said.
I know you didn't.
Dr. Beauregard,
I got one for you.
Roger that.
I may need your help
with something...
Depending on how things turn.
It's for a friend
of mine.
Armed and ready, sir.
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com