Previously on Alphas...
Gary and I just found
something that is huge.
- Stanton Parish.
- This is from the Civil War.
He was about
40 years old, right?
Same guy,
100 years later.
War
it's inevitable,
in two years, maybe three.
Nothing that you or I
can do to stop that.
[Sighs]
Bill, you all right?
It's too early.
Come back to bed
and warm me up.
[Chuckles]
In fact, you know what?
Why don't we both call in sick--
No, no. I-
I-I've got to go to work.
Bill, you need a break.
You've been so stressed,
and those pills
are not working anymore.
Jeannie, I--
[Sighs]
Jeannie, I got this.
Okay?
I gotta go.
Gary?
Breakfast.
In a minute.
[Screaming loudly]
[Footsteps approaching]
It sounds to me like it's
a cathartic release, Sandra.
It's releasing some tension
and some stress, you know?
It's--it's basically
a coping mechanism.
No, I-it's happening
every day, Lee.
That's not coping.
They locked him up.
They put a metal chip
in his head, for God's sake.
He's gone back to work
way too soon.
Well, Sandra,
Gary needs to work.
It's good for him,
you know that.
He really needs
to talk to somebody
about what happened to him.
Listen, I-I'm on my way
to pick him up now.
I'll find some time today
to speak with him.
I mean, you know
that I love my parents to death,
but they're all over me again.
I mean, all of the sudden,
it's like, "where are you going?
"How late are you
gonna be at work?
Are you being safe?"
They need to understand
that I'm an adult
and that I'm gonna do
what I want to do.
[Muttering] I'm gonna do
Yeah, exactly, Gary.
Well, perhaps
you should look into getting
your own apartment again.
[Cell phone rings]
Yeah, I thought about it,
but after everything
that happened last year--
- Nathan.
Yes, what is it?
- [Sniffing]
- Hi, yeah, what's up?
- What is that smell?
- What happened?
[Sniffs] I smell nice.
I smell like a washing machine.
No, it's not you, Gary.
Someone reeks of cologne.
[Sniffs]
Hicks!
What are you doing?
[Groans]
Harken.
Hello, Rachel.
Listen up, old spice,
I will hose you down.
What are you talking about?
You know, that's not me.
You've got perfect timing.
Meet John Bennett.
This is Rosen's new choice
for our lead tactical.
Rachel Pirzad.
Rachel,
I've heard a lot about you.
- What did you tell him?
- I didn't tell him anything.
But if I did,
I would've told him
all of the good stuff.
So you're gonna
be working here now?
Only on an as-needed basis,
but, yeah.
Well, on an as-needed basis,
you need to know that
your body spray or whatever
is--
it's way too distracting.
It's not that you smell,
exactly, ju--
Rachel, Bill.
Hello, John.
Welcome.
Thank you, sir.
Cley just called.
An Alpha's been killed.
We need you to go.
Jack Duffy--
Building Seven escapee.
He can generate electricity
in his bare hands.
[Electricity crackling]
Those look
like chemical burns.
There's an extremely
high concentration
of hydrochloric acid.
Did someone pour it on him?
No, more like
spit it at him.
The acid is mixed
with the attacker's saliva.
So you can smell
this guy's spit?
Hey, saliva has
a very distinctive smell.
That's cool.
It's poison spit.
- Yeah.
- It's like a cobra.
I like that.
He didn't like it, though,
'cause it melted his--
I-I'm being inappropriate.
Check out these hands.
There's some skin
under the nails.
He definitely put up a fight.
[Screams]
So we're saying
another Alpha killed him?
[Screaming]
Unh!
Rachel, there's something
written on his hand.
Can you take a look at that?
Oh, yeah,
that's a phone number.
718...
555...
[Phone dialing]
0012.
It's a voice mail.
"Delivery.
"8:00 p.m. tonight.
"286 Crawford.
Bolivia."
Bolivia?
- What kind of delivery?
- Didn't say.
No, Bill, there's
no "Crawford" in Bolivia.
It's not even Spanish.
There's--there's
a "Cristo" in Caracas.
Bill, would you take point
on this, please?
Maybe you can find someone
who knows what happened
to Mr. Duffy.
- That's what I do.
- Good.
I need to keep looking
for Parish.
Gary, come with me, please.
This is 286 Crawford, but...
this definitely
isn't Bolivia.
[Hearts beating]
There's a lot
of heartbeats inside.
People are yelling
and cheering.
Maybe squatters.
Happy squatters?
Rachel, do you smell
that acid?
It's hard to tell.
Um, I need to get a closer look.
No, no, no.
Area's not secure.
I'm gonna go check it out.
I'll cover the street.
You stay with me, okay?
What?
- Yeah, let's go.
- Bill!
No, he's lead tactical
now, Rachel.
Stay with him.
[Indistinct shouting,
loud impacts]
Who are you?
286 Crawford?
What about it?
Bolivia.
So you're a fighter?
You got skills?
Wouldn't be here
if I didn't.
Well, we'll see.
Smooth talker.
Well, it got us in here,
didn't it?
Into what?
Well,
from the looks of things,
this is probably where Duffy
got that blood on his knuckles,
so...we need to find out.
Split up.
Yeah.
[Coughing]
You okay?
Yeah, I just--
I thought I caught a whiff
of his scent, and--
Well, what's wrong?
What's wrong is, John,
is that you stink, okay?
My eyes are watering.
My nose is burning.
It's like a spice rack
exploded in my face.
No, Rachel, Rachel,
you can't go out there.
I actually
have to do my job,
so can you please
just stay in the car?
Rachel.
Thank you.
[Exhales deeply]
[Sniffs]
Hicks, I can smell it--
hydrochloric acid.
Want to narrow that down
a little bit?
Not yet. It's faint,
but the killer's here.
[Door opens]
[Chains rattle]
I'm sorry.
I thought, um--
You thought what?
Oh, wow.
That's an acid burn.
Looks like
it must have hurt.
Some piece of crap
spit at me,
soon as he knew
I could beat him.
That piece of crap,
what--what was his name?
Bazevich.
You know,
you're pretty cute.
What's your name?
Hey!
Everything okay here?
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah, it's good.
Hey, um,
the Bazevich guy, huh?
We came to see him fight.
I've been waiting for him
all night,
and when he shows,
I will kick his ass.
You come and watch that.
Huh, little girl?
Sweet guy.
Tell me about it.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Hey, thanks...
For not staying in the van.
All right, who's next?
Step up! Step up!
Who is next?
You! Hotshot!
Okay, no time-outs,
last man standing
gets the win.
Your knee touches the ground,
you lose.
No, I thought I'd just
check it out first time.
Yeah, well,
you figured wrong.
First-timers gotta fight.
[Laughs]
[Upbeat rock music]
♪ Alphas 2x03 ♪
Alpha Dogs
Original Air Date on August 6, 2012
♪ don't say no ♪
♪ for an answer ♪
♪ and there's no telling ♪
♪ where we've been ♪
♪ ♪
♪ 'cause people
don't understand ♪
♪ understand,
understand ♪
♪ people don't understand ♪
♪ people like me ♪
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Your friend thinks
he's a tough guy.
Trust me,
short stack, he is.
- He's gonna get his ass kicked.
- Yeah, right.
Aah!
What's the problem,
old man?
The son of a bitch
is all over the place.
I can't hit him.
You see that dude?
He messes with your eyes.
Like a camera flash
going off in your face--
makes you see
all double and triple.
How the hell's he do that?
He's got a special talent.
All the fighters do.
They're Alphas.
Jacob Dunham,
Stanton Parish.
There's no connection.
Jacob Dunham,
Stanton Parish.
Gary, how you doing?
You tired?
You've been at this all day.
Yeah, I've been at it
all day, and I've--
I've found bubkes.
That means "nothing."
It's like "zilch."
I've found zilch.
That's not entirely true.
You found that this picture
is of a Major Jacob Dunham,
and he was treated
by a Doctor Harrison,
who worked
at New York hospital.
- Y-yeah.
- You know, I'm thinking
that if he had continued
to treat Major Dunham,
his notes might still be there
in the hospital records.
So, Gary, I-I hear
you've added a new element
to your morning routine.
You're screaming.
Okay, yeah.
I scream for ten seconds,
but then--
then I go
and have my breakfast.
Or are you angry
about something?
It might help
if you discuss it.
I...no.
I don't want to discuss it.
I scream, so we don't have
to discuss it.
Right, I see.
You know, you have every reason
to be angry.
The government
took you away from your home,
put a chip in your neck--
they killed her.
They killed her--
Anna.
They shot her in the head.
She was my friend.
Gary, it's a--
it's a healthy thing
to express yourself.
I'm glad that you are.
Um, maybe you can find
a way to do it
without terrifying
your mother.
[Wincing]
Bill!
Are you okay?
No, I'm not.
Don't worry about it.
What you got for me?
Rachel got the name
of our acid spitter--
Ivan Bazevich...
did a stretch upstate,
no known address.
So how do we find him?
Well, we know he's a fighter.
Hey.
I heard things
got pretty rough last night.
Things get rough every night.
You take your chances.
So when's the next fight?
For you?
[Laughs] Never.
You ain't cut out for this.
Hey, wait.
I-I'll work with him.
- This guy, Kat?
- Guy's got moves.
He just doesn't know
how to use 'em.
Give him another shot.
For you, fine.
But I don't see it.
So I know all their tricks,
so if you want to win
next time,
give me a call.
I'm Kat.
So why do you
want to help me out?
So I can bet on you,
cash in.
[Laughing]
Okay, later.
[cereal pouring]
What's all this?
Dr. Rosen said that
I should find a way to scream
without terrifying you,
so I did--I'm moving out.
What?
Yeah, I'm gonna go live
at my office.
What are you talking about?
Sandra,
I know you're upset,
but I did not recommend
that Gary leave home.
No, but that was your solution
for Rachel.
Why's it different for me?
W-why's that not my solution?
Gary, you are not
going anywhere.
I want to do
what I want to do.
You know what? You're not
going to work today either.
Yeah, Mom, come on,
of course I'm going to work.
I go into work every day.
They need me there.
I need you here.
No! You don't need me.
Go in the house.
I'm going to work.
Gary!
Gary, it's, uh--
it's quite all right if you
don't come to work today.
There's nothing urgent,
and if we need you,
w-we'll call.
And I think it would be
a good idea
if we all sat down very soon
and discussed your future.
My future?
Yeah, my future.
Yeah.
[Sighs]
[Door closes]
We're still focused on
Bazevich as our killer.
We finally got his records
from D.O.D.
Well, are we any closer
to finding this guy?
Cops have been by all his
usual hangouts--no sign of him.
Harken's checking a lead,
but look, if you ask me,
these Alpha fights
are still our best bet.
Just as long
as it's a stakeout
and no more fighting.
I wasn't the one fighting.
[Chuckles]
To be honest with you,
I don't know
if we can keep him away.
I mean, the guy's
in training right now
for his next fight.
The human nervous system
of the body
sending and receives
while also processing
neurological impulses
throughout our brain.
It controls all physical
and fine motor skills
while also impacting
our thoughts,
emotions,
and cognitive function.
The spinal cord serves as
a telegraphic cable,
sending various messages
throughout the body.
The spine itself measures
approximately
a quarter of an inch
in diameter,
and varies in length
from person to person.
The synaptic impulses...
[Knock at door]
Are responsible for all sense--
[Turns off TV]
So watch out for that guy,
'cause he'll mess
with your eyes.
And then there's this
other guy, super flexible.
You punch him,
pops right back,
so you gotta drive him
into a corner.
That way, he springs back
and forth against your fists.
What about, um,
that guy that spits acid?
Bazevich?
He's badass, scary as hell.
Okay, pay attention.
So you kickbox too?
No, never have.
Yeah, but you just can't
pick that up right away.
I'm a quick study.
Ahh.
You're an Alpha.
So are we done chatting?
We got a lot of work to do.
Hi.
Um...
so I raided the soap aisle.
I figured
while we're on stakeout,
you should get to at least
choose how I smell...
which really sounded
a whole lot better in my head.
So you actually went
and bought all of these things?
Yeah, I mean,
I thought about unscented,
but I figure nothing's
really unscented to you.
You're right!
There is no such thing
as unscented to me.
Tom's of Maine
is probably the mildest.
Okay.
And thank you.
You're welcome.
Is that it?
I'm not gonna amp up
just for practice.
It's not healthy for me.
Well, my bet...
is using your ability
is not your problem.
It's holding back.
You got all this pressure
all the time that's building up.
That's why you get cranky.
You have no idea
what you're talking about.
Stop fighting who you are.
Just let it go, man.
What do you want me to do,
huh--sit on the floor,
burn some incense,
say "om"?
As much as I would like
to see that, no.
Harken, you need to relax.
Just try to listen.
Just trust me.
[Distant heartbeat]
Okay?
There's no reason
to struggle.
There's nothing to control.
[Heartbeat grows louder]
You don't have
to reach for it,
'cause it's part of you.
When you want it,
it'll be there.
Told you.
I never thought we'd have
something so ancient.
Dr. Harrison's files were
right there in the archives.
This must be my lucky day.
"It was two years ago,
the 22 of October, 1862,
"it was only my fourth week
"serving with General Wood's
Army of the Cumberland,
but I had already seen hundreds
of men killed in battle."
Shot in the head.
There's nothing we can do
for this poor soul.
"Hundreds more
maimed irreparably.
Can you hear me, son?
His artery is shredded--
- "none of that prepared me
for meeting Jacob Dunham."
[Gasps]
[Knock at door]
- Hey, Cameron.
- Hey, Doc.
Um, are you busy?
'Cause I can come back.
- No, I'm--I'm--
- You know what?
Don't worry. I'll come back.
No, no, of course not.
Come on in.
Wow.
Did you, uh, rob a library?
Looks that way,
doesn't it?
They're Civil War documents.
Right now I'm reading
a physician's war diary.
It's pretty fascinating.
Have a look.
"The journal
of Dr. Zachary Harrison."
Any headaches?
None this week.
You haven't mentioned my name
in any of those records,
have you?
My descriptions
remain anonymous, as we agreed.
You weren't
quite this distrustful
before you survived
that bullet two years ago.
[Chuckles]
Shall we?
[Wincing]
[Gasps]
It's even faster now.
You're getting stronger.
And with no scarring--
simply amazing.
How'd he pull off
that little trick?
By using his Alpha ability.
I think Dunham
is Stanton Parish.
Parish?
You really believe
this guy's been kicking around
for two centuries?
Well, it is hard to fathom.
I-I think this incident
is the first time
he realized
what he's capable of.
How exactly does this
help us catch him now?
Well, learning
about his formative years
might help us understand
what drives the man.
Hmm.
As the old saying goes,
"zhi bi zhi ji
bai zhan bu Dai."
Yeah, that old Chestnut.
That's Sun Tzu.
"Know your enemy
like yourself,
and you may win 100 battles."
So is there something you want
to talk about, Cameron?
You know how much
I respect you, Doc,
and I just--
I wanted to let you know
that, um,
I'm in a relationship--
Dani.
I know.
Well, Nina took it upon herself
to make sure I knew.
- Well, isn't that just perfect?
- Well, I sort of knew already.
I mean, it's--it's obvious,
seeing you two together.
So, as long as you make
my daughter happy,
you can keep your job here.
[Laughs]
[Chuckles]
[Exhales deeply]
♪ I haven't been myself ♪
♪ of late ♪
♪ I haven't slept
for several days ♪
♪ you know you drive me
up the wall... ♪
[Knock at door]
Yeah?
Jeannie?
Jeannie, what are you
doing here? I--
I'm--I mean,
is everything okay?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
I've never felt better,
actually,
and without the pills.
What you got there?
It smells good.
I brought you
some herb-crusted chicken
and scalloped potatoes.
You hungry?
Am I hungry?
You want to know...
If I'm hungry.
- Mm-hmm.
What
[Laughs]
Shh.
- Isn't it--
- What? What? What?
- Bill! What are you doing?
- What?
What are you--oh!
[Giggles]
Gary, you can't live
in your office.
You've gotta be practical.
I am being practical.
You won't have to hear me
scream every day.
But you need to be safe.
Yeah, it is safe.
It's safer.
I won't have to drive
to work anymore,
'cause people die
in car crashes all the time.
And Dr. Rosen--
he forgets to signal a lot.
And anyway, the building
has security, so there--
it's more secure
than this place.
Don't you tell me
you support him in this.
I think we both
need to support Gary
in whatever steps
he needs to take
towards his independence.
But this is too big a step.
For him or for you?
Yeah, let me get a turkey dog
with everything.
Coming up.
And for you?
What do you want?
Uh, what do
they taste like?
They taste like hot dogs.
What, you've never had
a hot dog before?
Must have, right?
Um, yeah, I'll just have
the same thing.
All right,
give me two, please.
Thanks.
- So you coming tonight?
- Hell, yeah.
There's gonna be
a boatload of people there
with deep pockets,
so you got to crush everyone
so we can rake it.
Yeah, you need
some of this here.
Some peppers and...
so what about, uh, Bazevich?
Think he'll be there?
You have, like, a man-crush
on him or something?
How should I know
if he's coming?
What do you mean
how should you know?
I thought you knew everything
about these fights.
How did you get involved
with them anyway?
Just kind of
found myself there.
These are amazing.
This is good.
- You like that?
- Yeah.
That's good stuff.
What do you mean
you just found yourself there?
I. I have this thing
where I can't remember
anything that happened, like,
more than a month ago.
Like, a month from now,
I won't remember this
or you or the hot dog.
- You serious?
- Mm-hmm.
My brain's wired to,
like, make room
for all the new crap
I learn, you know?
Yeah, but what about
your family, your home?
Home's the fights for now.
You got to be careful.
That's a rough crowd.
Don't get all "Papa bear"
on me, okay?
I've been taking care
of myself for...
Well, I can't remember,
but it--it's been a long time.
It's got to be lonely,
though.
It's stupid, though.
I don't know
why libraries do this.
Dr. Rosen, it's just
a big waste of space.
They could fit everything
in here just on one microchip.
Inside voice, please, Gary.
What?
Inside voice, please.
My inside voice
is too quiet.
Well, split the difference,
then, huh?
Oh, we are fortunate
this university
preserved its newspapers.
[Door closes]
[Sighs]
Jacob.
This is a surprise.
You're making
a presentation tonight.
Your abilities
are extraordinary.
Cancel your presentation,
Zac.
Promise to never speak
of what I can do.
I can't, Jacob.
It's too important
to keep to ourselves.
[Gasps]
[Gasping and choking]
This crowd is hot tonight.
Well, Rocky, try and remember
why we're here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
You see Kat anywhere?
Don't worry about that kid.
She can take care of herself.
No, look, she can't take care
of herself.
She forgets things.
She could be lost or confused.
I think she's gonna be okay.
Just stay focused.
All right, all right,
all right.
Let's go, let's go,
let's go.
Who is gonna start the show?
I will.
No, no, no, no, no, man.
We need a real fighter.
Bring it on.
All right, all right,
we got some fresh meat.
Now, who is gonna
be the challenger?
Rubberman!
[Crowd shouting]
[Laughs]
I'm gonna remember
to send you some flowers.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
you know what time it is.
Time to place your bets!
There's nothing to control.
You don't have
to reach for it,
'cause it's part of you.
When you want it,
it'll be there.
[Crowd shouting]
[Cheering]
Unit one still clear.
So your dad and both sisters
are in the military.
Your brother's a cop.
You must have felt
a lot of pressure
to make certain choices
about your life, huh?
- Sounds like you can relate.
- [Chuckles]
I smell something.
Seriously?
I mean, I--
No.
That S.U.V.
He's not in there now,
but Bazevich--
he was definitely in there.
All right, all right,
all right.
Who's next?
[Laughs]
I am.
[Crowd oohing]
Nah, nah, nah, nah,
nah, nah, nah.
Surprise.
You trying to play me, Kat?
I never said
I wasn't a fighter.
There is gonna be
some action tonight!
Place your bets!
Right now!
Kat, this isn't
a good idea.
Harken,
this isn't personal.
All right, all right.
What you waiting for?
In battle, a warrior
who remains calm
and remembers their training
will always vanquish a foe
who does not.
Shift your opponent's weight
to one leg
and attack
the weighted knee.
If you lack size,
compensate with speed
and precision.
The brain
is the most sensitive organ
in the human body.
[Crowd shouting, cheering]
Aah!
[Cheering]
Hey.
Hey, you all right?
Is he okay?
He's awesome.
Yeah, thanks.
Hey, Harken.
Harken.
Come on.
Not bad.
Some people want to talk
to you about a job.
- What kind of a job?
- Well, I don't know.
They didn't say,
but I know they pay big.
Hear 'em out.
Let 'em buy you a drink.
Okay.
You all right?
Oh, that's that girl Kat
from the other night.
Bill! Hicks!
Come on!
What happened?
You okay?
- [Sighs]
- Ask him who did it.
[Groans]
Hicks, I will kill you.
Hey, listen,
we got a lead on Bazevich.
He was in that car.
[Engine turns over]
Oh, and your friend Kat
just got in there.
All right, let's go.
Come on.
[Tires squeal]
That's their S.U.V.
What the hell is this place?
Okay, Bazevich is inside.
You can smell him?
Believe me,
he's unforgettable.
Rachel,
what's going on in there?
There's, uh...
[Heartbeats in distance]
There's multiple heartbeats.
An EKG, respirators,
hospital machines?
The place is wired
with sensor alarms.
I hear weaponry...
[Guns clack]
And heavy boots.
Unit One to tactical,
send backup to our position.
Wait.
It's that girl Kat.
No! Let me go!
Her voice is weak.
She's fading.
A male voice now.
"Make sure she stays under."
They want to prep her
right away.
Prep her for what?
- I can't wait.
- Harken, wait!
Damn it!
Kat!
[Alarm blaring]
[Gunshots]
[Blaring continues]
Harken!
[Machine creaking]
Kat!
[Monitor beeping]
Hey!
- Bazevich?
- What are you doing?
Kat!
Wait-unh!
[Monitor beeping]
Kat.
Kat!
Harken...
You're gonna be okay.
Harken!
Unh!
Good job.
Is she okay?
- Kat...
- [Groans]
You okay?
I beat you.
Yeah, you beat me.
We'll need three ambulances
and transport for prisoners
to Binghamton.
104, gotcha.
- So that's Bazevich.
- Hmm.
The guy we've been chasing
the last two days
is a dead man.
Hey, turns out Bazevich
was a prisoner here too.
Poetic justice
for killing Duffy, I guess.
Can you believe it?
Experimenting on Alphas.
More like treating us
like animals.
I could have gotten
out of there myself, you know.
You know what?
You can just say,
"Thank you so much,
Bill Harken,
for rescuing me."
I kicked your ass
once tonight.
Do you want to go again?
Easy does it, young lady.
You're going to have to take it
easy for a while.
You've been through quite
an ordeal.
Just give me a couple weeks.
I won't remember.
Hmm.
I want to have a look
at you, too, later.
No, no.
I'm--I'm fine. I'm fine.
Look, I got to use my ability
and feel no downside, so...
- No downside?
- No downside at all.
Hey, Dr. Rosen,
who are you guys anyway?
So Harken was undercover, right?
I wasn't undercover.
You were
definitely undercover.
And then he--he barged in
with those guys.
We're consultants.
We work with the government
now and then
in situations
not unlike this one.
You're Alpha Secret Agents,
right?
- You're gonna be fine.
- You're Alpha secret agents.
Just take it easy.
- I to--I'm totally right.
- No, no.
I'm right, right?
You want me on your team.
I'm awesome.
It's the perfect soap.
It'll blend really well
with your natural scent,
which, by the way, is--
is really good
on its own anyway, so...
there.
Thanks.
Um, I'll try it.
I was--I was,
uh, in the village,
and I found it at this shop
next to my favorite restaurant,
which is Italian.
Oh.
Do you like Italian?
Um...
Rachel, if--if we're going
to be working together--
Right.
Forget I mentioned it.
What can I get you?
Earl Grey tea, please.
Okay.
Hello, Lee.
May I join you?
You made it
very easy for me, Stanton.
Or do you prefer Major Dunham?
I prefer Stanton.
Well, thank you for providing
Dr. Harrison's research.
So you'd know how I began.
Yes.
By murdering a friend.
Dr. Harrison
wanted to use me.
So you scarified
an innocent man.
Have you ever sacrificed
an innocent man?
Not intentionally.
Every man must control
his own destiny.
I reenlisted
after the doctor's death.
I helped saved the Union.
Hmm.
So you're what--
looking for the thanks
of a grateful nation?
No.
Just some understanding
of my unique perspective.
I was shot again
at Cold Harbor
and again at San Juan Hill,
fought at Verdun,
in the streets of Berlin.
Oh, a very impressive resume.
Thank you.
Every change brings bloodshed.
We can stop that.
And yet you say
a war is coming.
Hmm.
Because...
[Liquid pouring]
ordinary men react
with fear and violence
to anything
that's new and different.
You know,
one of my favorite subjects
in medical school
was cellular research...
Mmhmm.
Examining the constituent
parts of things,
trying to figure out
how it all...
works together.
It was very tedious,
but, um...
It was exciting,
because eventually...
I could see the whole picture.
Try the tuna melt next time.
It's excellent.
No, Mom.
Don't do that.
That's how I like it.
Yeah, but that's the way
you keep it at home.
No, this is home.
It's how I like it here.
Right.
Good night, Gary.
Yeah, good night.
Uh, Mom.
Where'd you go?
I'm right here.
I'll call you at 8:00
after I scream,
but before
I've had my breakfast.
I'll answer.
Yeah, okay.
[Indistinct shouting,
loud impacts]
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Well, look who's back.
Here to watch?
Hell, no.
I'm here to fight.