NARRATOR: Previously on
Battlestar Galactica.
BALTAR: Now you tell me you're a machine.
The robot.
You knew l wanted access
to defence mainframe.
Do you have any idea
what they'd do to me if they find out?
NO. 6: Get down.
[Glass shattering]
ADAMA: Moments ago,
this ship received word...
that the Cylon attack
against our home worlds is underway.
As of this moment, we are at war.
All right, we can take three more people.
Giving up my seat.
[Tense instrumental music]
l've decided you're an expression
of my subconscious mind...
playing itself out during my waking states.
So l'm in your head?
[Tense instrumental music]
No.
There're maybe Cylon agents
living among us.
Some may not even know
they're Cylons at all.
They could be sleeper agents...
programmed to perfectly impersonate
human beings until activation.
[Clock ticking]
[lntense instrumental music]
[Tense instrumental music]
[Electronic beeping]
And one minute to mark.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
[Electronic beeping]
God has a plan for you, Gaius.
He has a plan for everything and everyone.
Gaius? Are you even listening to me?
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
PlLOT: Passengers, 30 seconds to mark.
ROSLlN: Planet. Men. Women. Age.
You know what? Do this after the jump.
lt's all right.
[Sighs]
[Tense instrumental music continues]
[Clock ticking]
You have to believe in something.
BALTAR: l believe in a world
that l can and do understand.
A rational universe.
Explained through rational means.
l love you. That's not rational.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
l know.
No, but you're not rational.
You're also not really here.
Neither am l.
[Doorbell rings]
PlLOT: Madam President,
ladies and gentlemen...
our 33 minutes are almost up once again.
Please prepare for our faster-than-light jump.
Thank you.
[Clock ticking]
Cutting it a little close this time,
aren't we, Billy?
Pilot says he's had to reboot
the FTL computer again.
[Tense instrumental music]
CALLY: Why do the Cylons come
every 33 minutes?
Why isn't it 34, 35--
TYROL: Cally.
CALLY: What?
Shut up.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
Fifteen seconds.
Sir, Jump 237 underway.
Fifty-three ships have jumped.
Ten still reporting trouble
with their FTL drives...
including Colonial One.
We're getting slower.
[Electronic beeping]
Maybe this time.
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
[Beeping]
[Rapid electronic beeping]
[Alarm ringing]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
GAETA: Dradis contact.
It's the Cylons.
-Damn it.
-Not this time, maybe the next.
Got another idea for the next cycle.
PlLOT: Ladies and gentlemen,
I'm afraid the Cylons have appeared again.
However, our FTL drive is now working
and we will jump momentarily.
BALTAR: Five days now.
[Tense instrumental music]
There are limits...
to the human body, the human mind.
Tolerances that you can't push beyond.
Well, those are facts...
provable facts.
Everyone has a limit.
All right, you know the drill, people.
Scatter formation.
APOLLO: Keep them off the civies
and don't stray beyond the recovery line.
[Guns firing]
Watch the ammo hoists for the main guns.
You've got a red light right there.
[Electronic crackling]
[Rapid beeping]
DUALLA: We have a hit on the starboard
bow. Away the damage control parties.
Basestar is launching raiders.
[Tense instrumental music]
Colonial One is ready to jump.
All civilian ships away,
including Colonial One.
Recover fighters. Stand by to jump.
Combat landings.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
-All fighters aboard, sir.
-Execute jump.
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
Jump 237 complete.
All civilian ships
present and accounted for, sir.
TlGH: Start the clock.
And let's start prepping for the next jump.
Clock is running. Thirty-three minutes.
Mark.
TYROL: You have 32 minutes, people.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Sighing]
NO. 6: You know you're not safe.
No, of course not.
The Cylons will follow us again...
as they have the last 237 times.
NO. 6: You're right, you know.
There are limits.
-Eventually, you'll make a mistake.
-And then you'll kill us all.
Yes.
Yes, l know.
But not for another 33 minutes.
[Clock ticking]
[Theme music]
[Tense instrumental music]
[Clock ticking]
ADAMA: l want to try
something new this time.
Divide the fleet into six groups.
And they jump--
[Adama sighs]
ADAMA: And they jump two more times
and on the fourth jump, we rendezvous at...
a common set of coordinates.
TlGH: Twenty-four jumps to plot,
we're breaking our humps...
calculating one jump every 33 minutes.
Get off my jacket.
-You eating this?
-Not anymore.
APOLLO: Combat landings expected again
to be the order of the day...
so double-check
your undercarriage before....
Look, you all have done this 237 times.
You know what to do.
No mistakes.
And let's make it to 238.
Good luck and be careful out there.
[Solemn instrumental music]
Can you do me a favour?
Tell Capt. Apollo he owes me one wing.
DAVE: You got it, dude.
No, Cally, there's three. l know there's three.
-Can you check it again for me, please?
-Yeah.
Let's get some of them starting to work.
TYROL: We'll sleep when we're dead.
Come on.
Boomer.
Heard the latest?
They say Cylons look like us now.
-Primary fuel?
-Primary fuel 2893 KRG.
Marine told one of the pilots that
we marooned some guy back on Ragnar...
because they actually thought
that he was a Cylon.
You know what? l don't give a frak.
Red light on the number four thruster.
Go make a visual lD. See if it's blocked.
-Right.
-''Right.''
A little rough on your new ECO,
don't you think?
He's not my ECO.
He's some refugee from Triton
that l'm saddled with and l didn't ask you.
-Helo's gone, Sharon.
-l didn't ask you that, either.
Sorry.
-Colony?
-Saggitaron. How many have you got?
5,251 survivors from Saggitaron, last count.
SOClNUS: We can't transmit photos yet.
lf you want, you can leave them with us...
or you can put them on the board outside.
Sorry.
DUALLA: Thanks.
SOClNUS: Next.
SOClNUS: Colony?
[Sombre instrumental music]
[Sombre instrumental music intensifies]
[Sighing] Update on the headcount,
Madam President.
How did we lose 300?
There were some overcounts...
a few deaths from wounds
and a few missing during the last attack.
[Grave instrumental music]
Do you want children, Gaius?
[lntense instrumental music]
Let me think about it for a minute.
No.
Procreation is one of God's commandments.
Really?
l'm sure some day
if you're a good Cylon he'll reward you...
with a lovely little walking toaster
of your very own.
l want us to have a child, Gaius.
BALTAR: You can't be serious.
-lt's Dr. Amarak.
-What was that?
l'm so sorry for interrupting you
while you were speaking.
You were just saying?
l was just saying that a Dr. Amarak...
-has requested to speak with the President.
-Dr. Amarak. l see.
You know him?
Have you always been able to multitask
like this?
Yes.
l used to work with him
at the Ministry of Defence.
lt says here that
he's uncovered important information...
regarding how the Cylons
were able to defeat colonial defences.
l was always a little worried he was on to us.
Were you going to speak to him?
BALTAR: Perhaps l should speak to him
if you're busy.
BlLLY: l think he wanted to speak directly
with the President.
lt sounded urgent.
lt must be very important.
Maybe something about a certain traitor
in the President's inner circle?
There's not enough time before we jump.
l want him on board first thing
during the next cycle.
Thank you, Doctor.
-l'd say you have a serious problem.
-lf l can help.
He's a strange one, isn't he?
[Eerie instrumental music]
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Helo panting]
[Continues panting]
[Explosions]
[Robots grunting]
[Robots screeching]
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
[Screaming]
[Helo panting]
[Ticking]
MAN: [Over PA] Landing base Team Alpha,
check three.
DUALLA: Can you see it?
Twelve more cases of nervous exhaustion.
That makes 61 .
Have the docs start pumping them up
with stimulants...
and get them back on the line.
ADAMA: Pilots, too.
DUALLA: Fuel report.
One out of every three, every other cycle.
TlGH: That's gonna come back
and bite us on the ass.
ADAMA: We have too much work
and not enough people to do it.
DUALLA: Fuel report.
-l've already signed one of these.
-Yes, sir. l'm sorry, sir.
Comm traffic two from the President.
-ls this my 10 minutes or this yours?
-Yours. l took 10 last time.
See you guys in combat.
l believe it was your 10 minutes.
lf the old man's so tired he can't remember,
then it's his turn.
-You see the note from the XO?
-Yeah, l saw it. No way.
APOLLO: Kara, everyone else--
STARBUCK: l don't fly with stims.
They blunt your reflexes, your reaction time.
-Come on, Kara, give me a break. Just--
-Why are we arguing about this?
APOLLO: l have no idea.
Neither do l. You're the CAG, act like one.
What the hell does that mean?
lt means that you're still acting
like you're everyone's best friend.
We're not friends, you're the CAG.
''Be careful out there''?
Our job isn't to be careful,
it's to shoot Cylons out of the frakking sky.
STARBUCK: ''Good hunting'' is what you say.
And now, one of your idiot pilots
is acting like a child...
and refusing to take her pills.
So she either says, ''Yes, sir''...
and obeys a direct order
or you smack her in the mouth...
and you drag her sorry ass down to sickbay
and you make her take those pills.
[Kara laughs]
Well, l'm glad l'm not working for you.
You're damn right you're glad.
So, do l have to smack you in the mouth,
Lieutenant?
No, sir. l'll take my pills.
Perfect.
-Carry on.
-Yes, sir.
DlSPATCHER: Pilots to ready room
for pre-flight briefing. Pilots to ready room.
What?
[Rain pattering]
[Gasping]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Tense instrumental music]
[Panting]
[Gun cocking]
[Gasping]
Jump 238 complete.
ADAMA: Start the clock.
GAETA: [Over PA] Thirty-three minutes.
Mark.
All civilian ships present and--
[Electronic beeping]
Strike my last.
One civilian ship
missing and unaccounted for, sir.
TlGH: Which one?
DUALLA: The Olympic Carrier.
DUALLA: Commercial passenger vessel.
ADAMA: Were they left behind?
DUALLA: l think l accounted
for all civilian ships before we left.
You think? Did you or didn't you?
[Electronic beeping]
They're not logged in, sir.
l think they may have been left behind.
How many people aboard ship?
1,345 souls, sir.
You're telling me we left over 1,300 people
to die at the hands of the Cylons?
lt may not have been her fault, sir.
lt may have been a navigational error
and they jumped to the wrong coordinates...
or the Cylons destroyed the ship
before the jump--
Or 50 other things may have happened.
The point is we don't know
what the hell did happen.
Yes, we're tired. Yes, there's no relief.
Yes, the Cylons keep coming after us
time after time...
and yes, we are still expected to do our jobs.
We make mistakes, people die.
There aren't many of us left.
Carry on.
[Melancholic instrumental music]
Okay. Next crisis?
[Billy sighs dejectedly]
-List of calls?
-Yes.
But first, where's the doctor
who's supposed to be on board?
What's his name?
-Dr. Amarak.
-Yes.
Dr. Amarak.
Oh.
He was on the Olympic Carrier.
[Seagulls cawing]
NO. 6: God is watching out for you, Gaius.
The universe is a vast and complex system.
Coincidental, serendipitous events...
are bound to occur.
lndeed they are to be expected.
-lt's part of the pattern, part of the plan.
-Dr. Amarak posed a threat to you.
Now he's gone.
Logic says there's a connection.
BALTAR: A connection, maybe. But not God.
There is no God or gods, singular or plural.
There are no large invisible men,
or women for that matter...
in the sky taking a personal interest
in the fortunes of Gaius Baltar.
Be careful.
That which God gives, he can also take away.
[Sombre instrumental music]
[Tense instrumental music]
Fifteen seconds.
[Electronic beeping]
Maybe this time.
Dradis?
No enemy contacts.
Keep the clock running.
What do you think?
l think we wait.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
[Beeping]
[Sighs]
Get me the President.
Why this time?
Was it something that you did?
We had a new plan,
but we didn't have time to implement it yet.
We lost a ship during the last cycle,
the Olympic Carrier.
Does that have something to do with it?
ADAMA: Possibly.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
Are you there?
Yeah, l'm here.
What do we do now, Commander?
l've got people on the verge over here.
We're gonna go to Condition Two.
We have to take advantage of this time...
-and let our people get some rest.
-All right.
And how long do we stay at Condition Two?
Until l'm satisfied they're not going to return.
ADAMA: It's a military decision.
lt is. l know that.
You're right and l defer to your decision.
And, Commander...
let your men and women...
know how grateful I am
for the job that they are doing, please.
Thank them for me.
ADAMA: Thank you, Madam President.
ADAMA: Thank you.
ADAMA: Contact Apollo.
ADAMA: Tell him to set up a combat patrol
around the fleet...
and order his other pilots
to land immediately.
All right, people, you heard the order.
Boomer, Starbuck, form up with me.
We'll fly the first CAP.
APOLLO: I want everyone else
back on Galactica and in their racks.
APOLLO: Three-hour rotation.
STARBUCK: Hey, Apollo...
not that I'm not honoured by being chosen
to sit in my cockpit...
for the next three hours but--
APOLLO: But why you?
-Take a guess.
-Because I'm on drugs?
[Chuckling] You got it.
This patrol is 100%% stimulated.
CRASHDOWN: Anyone else feels like...
they've got frakking ants crawling
behind their eyeballs?
APOLLO: How about you, Boomer?
Doc tells me you're holding up
better than anybody in the squadron.
BOOMER: l'm tired like everybody else.
APOLLO: You never seem it.
STARBUCK: Because she's a Cylon.
You're gonna make me come over there
and kick your ass.
Okay. Let's set up a patrol here...
before somebody gets hurt.
APOLLO: Follow me.
STARBUCK: Copy that, Apollo.
A couple hours rack time
does sound awfully sweet...
TlGH: right about now.
ADAMA: You deserve it.
Thank you. The truth is...
all this has me feeling
more alive than l have in years.
You look that way, too.
lt's good to you
without the cup in your hand.
Don't start.
l know there's a whole lot of people
aboard this ship...
that wish you weren't feeling
as good as you were.
lf the crew doesn't hate the XO,
then he's not doing his job.
Besides, got to make the old man look good.
l always look good.
-Did you look in a mirror?
-Seriously...
GAETA: Sir.
...it's one thing to push a crew,
it's another to break them.
[Loud beeping]
Dradis contact.
Bearing 348, carom 1 20, one ship.
Getting recognition signal.
MAN: Initiating response flash mode.
Alpha, alpha.
lt's the Olympic Carrier, sir.
ADAMA: ls that confirmed?
DUALLA: lt's confirmed, sir.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Thank the gods.
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
Action stations.
[Suspenseful instrumental music intensifies]
Put the fleet into Condition One.
I want all Vipers manned and ready,
but keep them in the tubes.
TlGH: Mr. Gaeta.
GAETA: Sir?
Restart the clock. Thirty-three minutes.
[Electronic beeping]
-Hope you're wrong.
-So do l.
GAETA: Clock is running.
ADAMA: So do l.
[Beeping]
No. lt's all wrong.
lf they were left behind,
why didn't the Cylons destroy them?
And why are they showing up now?
lt's God's punishment for your lack of faith.
That's just great, that is.
A more logical and useful explanation,
please.
All right.
The Olympic Carrier has been infiltrated
by Cylon agents.
[Ominous instrumental music]
They've been tracking the ship all along.
No.
Then that means....
Logically, in order for you to survive...
the Olympic Carrier should be destroyed.
BOOMER: Olympic Carrier...
this is Raptor 478, call sign Boomer.
I have you in visual contact.
Please respond to this channel. Over.
MAN: Raptor 478, this is the Olympic Carrier.
We have you in visual contact.
Thank the Lords of Kobol. You don't know
how relieved we are to see you.
BOOMER: Roger that, Olympic Carrier.
Can I ask about your whereabouts?
MAN: We had trouble with our FTL drive.
Took us almost three hours to fix.
ADAMA: Have Boomer ask them
how they escaped the Cylons.
BOOMER: Olympic Carrier, Boomer.
I've been directed to ask how you escaped
from the Cylons.
MAN: They were closing in on us
when the rest of you were jumping.
I thought we were goners,
then they just broke off.
Someone must've been watching out for us.
BOOMER: Roger that.
MAN: One other thing, Boomer.
I've got a Dr. Amarak on board...
who has an urgent matter to discuss
with the President.
-He's been driving me crazy.
-Can you be more specific?
MAN: I can't. He says he knows
something about a traitor in our midst...
and he's unwilling to share more than that.
Madam President, l strongly recommend...
that we cut off all wireless communication
with that ship right away.
Why?
Look, forgive me for being rude,
but wake up, all right?
The Olympic Carrier is still flying
because the Cylons let them survive.
They've been tracking that ship all along.
-There's probably a Cylon agent aboard now!
-Calm down.
Start over.
Please, Madam President, l implore you.
Listen to me.
Cut off radio communication with that ship...
before they send via broadcast signal
another computer virus...
to affect our ship
shortly before they blow us all up.
Commander Adama, are you on the line?
Cut off the speakers.
Put her through on the line.
ADAMA: Yes, Madam President.
And l'm inclined to agree with Dr. Baltar.
Good. So do l.
Thank the gods you're with us.
God's got nothing to do with this.
[Tense instrumental music]
[Beeping]
DUALLA: Boomer, Galactica.
Your orders are to jam all transmissions
from the Olympic Carrier.
No further voice contact is authorised.
Roger that, Galactica.
DUALLA: Boomer, Galactica.
Orders are to send the Olympic Carrier
the following message by signal light.
Message begins: Maintain present position.
DUALLA: Do not, repeat, do not approach
the fleet until further notice.
Message ends.
l'm getting a bad feeling
about where this is headed.
So am l.
lf the ship poses a threat to us,
we have to eliminate that threat.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
I don't think they got the message, Apollo.
Yeah, l see it. Boomer,
break wireless silence on my authority.
Warn them to stop their engines immediately.
l suggest that we evacuate the passengers,
then destroy the ship.
Solves the problem
if they're tracking the ship.
What if they're tracking
one of the passengers?
BOOMER: Olympic Carrier...
you are ordered to stop your engines
immediately. Acknowledge.
BOOMER: Apollo, they're not responding.
APOLLO: Are you using the same channel?
BOOMER: Yeah,
but suddenly nobody's home.
Starbuck, fire a burst across their bow.
Copy that.
[Ship's guns firing]
[Suspenseful instrumental music continues]
Boomer, let Galactica know we have
a problem out here.
Commander, message from Boomer.
The Olympic Carrier is heading
directly for us, sir.
They're refusing all orders to stop.
[Suspenseful instrumental music intensifies]
BOOMER: Galactica,
they're still not responding...
and continue to head towards the fleet.
Request instructions.
Order the fleet to execute Jump 240.
Get us between that ship and the fleet.
GAETA: Commander! Dradis contact.
Strike that, multiple Dradis contacts.
[Rapid electronic beeping]
lt's the Cylons.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
CRASHDOWN: The Cylons
are on an intercept course.
They'll be in weapons range
within two minutes.
[Alarm beeping]
Radiological alarm!
-Radiological alarm!
-From where?
[Alarm beeping]
The Olympic Carrier, sir.
They've got nukes on board.
Madam President, we have to eliminate
the Olympic Carrier immediately.
There are 1,300 people on that ship.
ADAMA: We don't know that.
The Cylons may have captured them already.
She's not going to do it. She has to do it.
-lt's not her decision, Gaius.
-No?
NO. 6: lt's God's choice.
He wants you to repent.
Look, at this point there's no choice.
lt's either them or us.
Repent of your sins...
and accept his true love
and you will be saved.
[Tense instrumental music]
l repent. Then l'll repent.
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
l repent.
Do it.
BOOMER: We have new orders.
We're directed to destroy
the Olympic Carrier...
and return to Galactica.
lt's a civilian ship.
APOLLO: Yeah, a civilian ship with nukes.
[Sombre instrumental music]
APOLLO: I don't see anybody in there,
do you?
The Cylons will be here any second.
lf we're going to do this, then just do it.
Starbuck, form up with me.
APOLLO: We'll make one pass from astern.
STARBUCK: Lee, what if you're wrong?
[Sombre instrumental music continues]
STARBUCK: Lee, come on.
Okay, fire on my mark.
No frakking way, Lee.
Lee? Come on!
[Tense instrumental music]
Mark.
[Ship's guns firing]
[Rain pattering]
[Helo grunting defiantly]
Are you alive?
[Panting]
Agathon, Karl C.
Lieutenant, junior grade, Colonial fleet.
-PK-789-9348.
-l know who you are, Helo.
lt's all right. l'm a friend.
[Gunshot]
[No. 6 gasps]
[Solemn instrumental music]
[Both gasping]
Sharon?
HELO: What are you doing here?
BOOMER: Can you walk?
[Helo grunting]
Yeah, l think so.
-What are you doing here, l thought--
-Let's move, mister.
[Solemn instrumental music continues]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
APOLLO: Sir.
ADAMA: Son.
[Adama sighs]
l gave the order. lt's my responsibility.
l pulled the trigger.
That's mine.
[Sombre instrumental music]
BlLLY: Madam President?
l'm sorry, you were saying something?
Twenty-four hours, no Cylons.
-At least you know it was the right choice.
-The right choice.
l'm sorry, Billy.
l think l'd like some time alone, please.
BlLLY: Of course.
[Sombre instrumental music continues]
What is it?
-Update on the headcount?
-Subtract how many?
Actually, you can add one.
A baby was born this morning
on the Rising Star.
A boy.
-A baby.
-Yeah.
Thank you.
[Serene instrumental music]
[Theme music]
NARRATOR: Previously on
Battlestar Galactica.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
DUALLA: Radiological alarm!
TlGH: From where?
The Olympic Carrier, sir.
They've got nukes on board.
lf the ship poses a threat to us,
we have to eliminate that threat.
The Cylons will be here any second.
lf we're gonna do this, then just do it.
-lt's a civilian ship.
-Do it.
-Giving up my seat.
-Like hell.
[Tense instrumental music]
HELO: Sharon? What are you doing here?
BOOMER: Let's move, mister.
[Eerie instrumental music]
[Gasps]
[Tense instrumental music]
-Excuse me, Lieutenant.
-Specialist. Good evening.
-Sir?
-ls something wrong?
No, sir. lt's just morning, sir.
-What time is it?
-0545.
[Electronic beeping]
[Gasps]
[Tense instrumental music]
BOOMER: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
BOOMER: Where are the rest of them?
[Beeping]
[Beeping intensifies]
[Tense instrumental music continues]
[Theme music]
GAETA: Attention. Colonial One will arrive
in 30 minutes.
GAETA: Honour detail report in quarters.
TlGH: Where the hell is it?
Damned son of a...sash.
l heard you the first time!
TlGH: One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
ROSLlN: Do it.
APOLLO: l can't stop thinking
about the Olympic Carrier.
That was three days ago.
lt's ancient history
under these circumstances.
Leave the second-guessing to the historians.
But don't we have a responsibility?
l mean, as leaders, don't we have
an obligation to question our actions to....
l don't know. To make sure the decisions
we make are the right decisions.
We did what we had to do, Son.
A man takes responsibility for his actions,
right or wrong.
He accepts the consequences
and lives with them...
every day.
[Slow instrumental music]
LSO: Colonial One, Galactica.
Proceed to Omega Docking.
Contact CIC when you have hard seal.
PlLOT: Roger that, Galactica.
BlLLY: Excuse me, Madam President.
We've arrived--
Please don't tell me
that we have to go through this...
every time l step on that ship.
No, ma'am. But they will always
render honours for your arrival. lt's protocol.
The military, they do love their protocol.
l'm sure if they knew you didn't like it,
they'd be willing to--
ROSLlN: No. Let Adama sound the trumpets.
lt makes him feel more comfortable.
Maybe if he feels more comfortable...
-he'll be a little easier to deal with.
-That's smart.
No, it's not smart. lt's politics.
ROSLlN: l think l'm going to get tired
of this outfit.
Seeing as l only have three
for the rest of my life.
-That looks fine.
-Fine?
lt looks great.
You don't know anything
about women, do you?
-Shall we?
-Let's go be ''presidential.''
l am confident that l speak for the entire fleet
when l say thank you.
Without your extraordinary dedication,
your tireless effort, your sacrifice...
no one of us would be here today.
l'm proud to serve as your President.
Thank you.
[All clapping]
Carry on.
Sir, the Virgon Express
is manoeuvring alongside.
-They're standing by for unrep.
-Thank you very much, D.
Officer of the Watch,
you'll proceed with the unrep, please.
Aye, sir.
ADAMA: lf you'll step this way.
ROSLlN: Thank you.
-Excuse me, Chief. A word with you, please.
-Just one second.
You know what? Just let's do it. What's up?
Got a problem.
TYROL: Yes, sir, Lieutenant, sir.
TYROL: l believe the navcon modules
are ready for inspection.
DUALLA: Virgon Express, Galactica.
We have you in visual contact.
Maintain current course and speed.
PlLOT: Roger that, Galactica.
Powering up stabilisation gyros
24A through 48C.
Galactica's water recycling system
is close to 100%% effective.
For all intents and purposes, there's not
a drop of water that's wasted aboard.
ADAMA: We have enough water
for several years before replenishing.
-l see.
-Many of the ships like the Virgon Express...
were not made for long-term voyages...
-and will have to tank off of us periodically.
-Right.
Whatever it is, we're gonna take care of it,
okay? You all right?
Now, tell me what happened.
What's going on?
There are at this moment
six G-4 detonators...
missing from the small-arms locker
on Deck 15.
Commander, ready to extend the water boom.
Excuse me.
TlGH: How's it going?
ADAMA: Oh, boy, l feel like a....
-Tour guide?
-lt shows?
Well, she was a teacher.
Probably sees all this
as one big educational experience.
-He thinks l'm a total idiot, doesn't he?
-What? No, sir. No.
lt's all right.
What are you telling me for?
lf munitions go missing,
you got to tell the master-at-arms now!
BOOMER: l know that!
You can't screw around with stuff like this!
l'm not screwing around, okay?
The only reason l didn't tell anybody...
is 'cause they're gonna think
l'm the one who took them.
How are things?
DUALLA: Things are good.
BlLLY: Good.
You look good.
l really like your hair.
My hair?
[Chuckling]
l don't know anything about women.
Madam President, if l may?
l think you should know that my father....
-Well, this entire ceremony was his idea.
-l know.
l think he's enjoying it.
Actually, he hates protocol, pomp,
and all that.
-Really?
-He's making a gesture.
Trying to make you feel like the President.
Open Valves 3 and 5.
[Rumbling]
BOOMER: l took the one detonator
from the duffel, replaced it...
and then l went back to my quarters.
Well....
[Tyrol clears throat]
You know what? lt's not your fault.
Someone's obviously setting you up
to take the fall for something.
That's what it is.
You wake up somewhere,
you don't know how you got there.
You're drugged, or manipulated,
or who knows what. Something.
[Tense instrumental music]
What do we do?
Because if l report what's happened,
they'll think l'm a Cylon agent.
No, they're not. No.
Why would they think that? That's crazy.
People are getting crazy, okay?
You've heard the rumours.
Cylons who look like humans,
sleeper agents hiding in the fleet.
[Rumbling]
[Alarm blaring]
Decompression alarm!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
ADAMA: Damage report, Mr. Gaeta.
Ruptures in Tanks 3, 5, 7, 9.
TlGH: Strain on the unrep lines.
They're gonna blow.
Release the lines. Veer away, starboard!
Every tank on the port side has ruptured.
We're venting all our water
directly into space.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
ClC, it's DC One. We're entering the tank.
DUALLA: Roger that, DC One.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Raptor 478, DC One. l have you in my sights.
Copy that, DC One, l have you in sight.
TYROL: Understood.
How's it look in there?
Can you tell what happened?
Lieutenant, don't worry...
about my team. l've got things under control.
Copy that, DC One.
l feel better knowing you're on it.
Watch the light, you're off target.
How much water did we lose?
Ten million JPs, sir.
Almost 60%% of total potable water reserves.
Emergency rations.
Shut down laundry, showers,
anything nonessential immediately.
Yes, sir.
-How long will our water supplies last?
-Aboard Galactica, about six days.
But one-third of the other ships in the fleet
were depending on us for replenishment.
lf we don't find new supplies
they'll run out of water in two days.
One-third? That's 16,000 people.
Get the names of those ships.
Tell their captains to go
on emergency rations immediately.
There's gonna be riots in those ships.
Civilians don't like hearing they can't
take a bath, wash their clothes...
-or drink more than a thimble a day.
-Thank you for the warning, Colonel.
-That'll be all, Mr. Gaeta.
-One more thing. Lieutenant?
Do you have any theories
about what may have caused the accident?
There are many theories at this point,
Madam President.
Do you have a guess?
l tell my officers not to guess.
l prefer to wait until we have fact.
Um-hm. lndulge me.
Take a guess, Mr. Gaeta.
l'd have to say
the most likely explanation is...
that the tank was structurally weakened
during the Cylon nuclear detonation...
during the first attack,
and that caused it to buckle and rupture.
GAETA: But it's too early to say. Sir.
ROSLlN: lnteresting.
-Thank you, Lieutenant.
-Back to the matter at hand.
l've ordered an astronomical survey
of nearby stars systems...
-for potential water sources. Colonel?
-Yes, sir.
[Eerie instrumental music]
Chief, take a look at this.
TYROL: What do you got?
CALLY: Not sure.
CALLY: lt looks like burn marks
from an explosive.
CALLY: What do you think?
Umm....
[Stammering] lt's tough to tell.
lt's pretty rusted out.
Optical and x-ray telescopes say
there are five systems...
within our practical jump radius.
All five have planetary bodies
with the potential for finding water...
in either a liquid or a frozen state.
Put together a plan for Raptors
to scout each star system.
-l want the first launch at 1 7:30.
-Yes, sir.
Colonel, how likely are we
to find water on any of these planets?
Now you want me to guess, l take it.
-Colonel.
-Sir.
My apologies, Madam President.
Difficult day for everyone.
l understand.
Most planets are just hunks of rock
or balls of gas.
The galaxy's a pretty barren, desolate place
when you get right down to it.
ADAMA: Thank you, Colonel.
ROSLlN: The water rationing'll
make our supply problem worse.
ROSLlN: Dr. Baltar, please share the results
of your study.
l've calculated the rate of consumption
regarding basic foodstuffs...
for the civilian population.
BALTAR: This is based on information
available to me at the time.
The current civilian population of 45,265...
will require, at minimum...
82 tons of grain, 85 tons of meat...
1 19 tons of fruit, 304 tons of vegetables...
-and 2.5 million JPs of water.
-ls that per month?
Per week.
[Thunder rumbling]
HELO: They found your Raptor.
A few or a lot?
HELO: That's what you get
for coming back for me.
BOOMER: Frack.
HELO: Yeah.
l was sure they didn't track me coming in.
-l know.
-l set the jiggers to pulse.
HELO: l'm sure you did.
l didn't set off any detection grids,
any dradis sweeps, or pingers.
-Never send a pilot to do an ECO's job.
-l can do your job.
l guess that's why the toasters are crawling
all over our ride out of here.
HELO: l don't suppose there's a Plan B.
Plans B, C, D and E are the same as Plan A.
Get off the planet and get back to the ship.
Come on.
Where are we going?
BOOMER: Don't ask questions.
Just follow your pilot.
Yes, sir.
Umm....
So far we've found five discrete
detonation points in the tank...
and we believe that there may be a sixth.
l've suspected due to the size
of the residual scoring...
and the burn points...
that we are dealing with a G-4 type explosive.
So l've requested a spot check
of all inventory...
from the master-at-arms
and she indicated to me...
that there are six detonators missing
from a small-arms locker...
in the port flight pod.
So one detonator may still be
unaccounted for.
Have the master-at-arms post guards
at all small-arms lockers immediately.
lt's already done, sir.
She also has opened an investigation...
into who may have had access to that locker.
However, due to spotty record-keeping...
and lax internal security procedures
since the attack...
she believes that we may never know
who took the detonators.
[Tense instrumental music]
[Both whispering]
ADAMA: Chief, thank you very much.
Everyone except for Col. Tigh,
Capt. Adama, and Dr. Baltar...
are now released.
ADAMA: Please remember:
this briefing is strictly confidential.
[Door closes]
There is at least one Cylon
aboard the Galactica.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
How many people know
the Cylons look human?
The rumour mill's been working overtime.
Half the ship's talking about it.
There'll always be rumours.
For most people, that's all they'll ever be.
l'm asking how many people actually know?
TlGH: The five people in this room,
plus three Marines.
ROSLlN: Let's keep it that way.
Once this gets out officially...
people will be accusing each other
of being Cylons for no reason at all.
l agree. Dr. Baltar,
how're we doing on the screenings?
The screenings?
You were supposed to be screening
Galactica crew for potential Cylon agents.
NO. 6: Do you remember
the first time you lied to a woman?
Other than your mother, that is.
BALTAR: Other than my mother.
Sherry Bennett. Fourth grade.
On the playground, behind the band room.
''lf you show me yours, l'll show you mine.''
She did. l did not.
You know, l think l slept with her actually,
many years later, of course.
NO. 6: Of course.
[Tense instrumental music]
NO. 6: Did she turn out to be
a beautiful woman?
As a matter of fact, she did.
Very beautiful.
But every woman has her beauty...
her feminine charms that are hers
and hers alone.
ADAMA: Doctor?
Doctor?
BALTAR: The screenings.
To tell you the truth,
there are significant problems...
with implementing
my Cylon detection method...
that l used aboard Galactica previously...
and basically because
l've run out of natural resources.
l need chemical compounds.
For example, the precursor test.
l need large samples of tetrahydrocycline...
which l don't have to tell you....
Maybe l do have to.
BALTAR: lt's a highly volatile chemical--
ADAMA: Let me stop you there.
Your intellect obviously outstrips
everyone in this room.
But it's also obvious
by the way that you're talking...
that in order to make
large-scale screenings...
you're going to need help, staff, resources.
Yes, that's exactly what l'm saying. Exactly.
Although, more staff?
Someone snooping around,
watching your every move?
Maybe it'll be a woman,
you could find her secret beauty.
ADAMA: l'm going to assign Lt. Gaeta
to aid you...
in anything that you might need.
So much for that.
But the need for secrecy?
Clearly, this falls
into the ''absolutely necessary'' category.
Your screening techniques
may be critical to our very survival.
Humanity's very survival rests in your hands.
Now, if only you had
an actual Cylon detector.
APOLLO: This is a critical mission.
APOLLO: Fights have already broken out
on some ships over the rations.
There's panic in the air. You don't find water
out there and find it soon--
-l understand, Captain. We'll find it.
-Good hunting.
APOLLO: Hey, Chief.
TYROL: Captain.
-Lieutenant.
-Chief.
l feel like my head's about to explode.
TYROL: Just relax, calm down.
Focus on the mission.
We'll take care of everything
when you get back.
BOOMER: What about the investigation?
Master-at-arms is running it.
Don't worry, there's no connection to you.
ln fact, there's no reason to believe
you had anything to do with it at all.
BOOMER: l didn't.
TYROL: l know.
-l would never do something like that. Never.
-Sharon, l know.
lt's really important you believe me on this.
-You do believe me, right?
-Absolutely.
TYROL: Yes, sir.
BOOMER: Thank you, Chief. Carry on.
Please excuse me for keeping you waiting.
l was called into the engine room.
lt'll just take a moment.
ROSLlN: That's all right.
Sometime l'd like to borrow a book or two.
l only brought one with me
on the flight to Galactica.
ADAMA: What book?
ROSLlN: A Murder on Picon.
ROSLlN: l have a weakness for mystery.
ADAMA: Ever read Dark Day?
Edward Prima. l am embarrassed to say...
it's one of those classics
l've never gotten around to reading.
l think you'll enjoy it.
Thank you.
[Soft instrumental music]
lt may be a while
before l get this back to you.
lt's a gift. Never lend books.
Well, then thank you for the gift.
l'm really looking forward
to working with you, Doctor.
-You have a friend.
-As am l, Lieutenant.
l actually studied genetics in college.
l was planning on going
for my graduate degree...
through the military extension program.
Wonderful. ls that a card game?
And the girl wins again. Another round?
Come on, guys. Grace under pressure.
Nothing like losing a little money
to take your mind off those 14-hour patrols.
-Mind if l sit in, Lieutenant?
-lf you got the cubits, we've got the chair.
Of course if you've got anything to drink,
we'll take that in lieu of cash.
You know l don't have any money, but...
this jacket must be worth at least 15 cubits.
lt's made of the finest Caprican cloth,
warm in winter, cooling in summer.
lt'd look great on you.
Anybody else got any civilian clothes
they'd be interested in putting on the table?
[Rapping on table]
Don't let me keep you.
Col. Tigh was right.
Rioting broke out on a cruise ship
when they reduced water rations.
We need to demonstrate an ability
to maintain order. We need to do it now.
We don't have extra manpower
for fleet security.
You have the only armed,
disciplined force available.
Yeah, but l'm not going to be
your policeman.
There's a reason why you separate
military and the police.
One fights the enemy of the state.
The other serves and protects the people.
When the military becomes both...
then the enemies of the state
tend to become the people.
l appreciate the complexity of the issue
and l won't let that happen.
-l'll send troops to the cruise ship.
-Commander, l won't let that happen.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
-Beginning dradis one sweep.
-Beginning dradis two sweep.
So l'm thinking we should give
this lovely little rock of nothing a name.
-l'm thinking ''Kimiko.''
-''Kimiko''?
After a lovely little lady, in a lovely little city,
in a lovely little colony...
-that l used to know.
-Whatever.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Electronic beeping]
[Music intensifies]
Sorry. So sorry.
You had such a good run, though.
Looks like the bet's to me.
BALTAR: l'll try and muddle through
for another round.
I'm going to raise you five.
No guts, no glory, Doctor. l'll see your five...
and raise you 20.
Now it's just you and me.
l'm not used to playing
in this kind of high-stakes game.
STARBUCK: lt's not too late to bow out.
Now there's an excellent suggestion.
And before proceeding any further...
l should really examine my motivations
for doing so.
Staying in the game,
l run the risk of losing my entire stake...
and being humiliated
in front of these lovely people.
''Humiliated'' is a such a strong word.
''Embarrassed'' would be my choice.
You do play rough, don't you?
STARBUCK: A little too rough for you.
My hand's not that strong. lt wouldn't
take much to knock me out of the game.
Well, thank you, Doctor.
[Starbuck giggling]
However, without a little risk...
life would be so dull, wouldn't it? Calling.
[Clears throat]
Three on a run.
BALTAR: Full colours.
[Pilots cheering]
Thank you all for a most pleasant evening.
A parting gift.
BALTAR: Hand-rolled from some
of the finest fumarello leaf in Caprica.
And it's also one of the last left
in the universe.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
[Baltar coughing]
Excuse me.
The Raptors have reported back
after three star systems.
-So far, all report negative for water, sir.
-l just checked with Astrometrics.
They're coming up with big goose eggs.
There's no star systems
within the range of our telescopes...
with planetary bodies
likely to have water on them.
Sir. Another Raptor just checked in.
Negative on water as well.
ADAMA: Who's left?
DUALLA: Boomer and Crashdown, sir.
lf they come up negative as well...
what's our back-up plan?
We'll jump to another sector
and start the search all over again.
-Needle in a haystack.
-More like grain of salt on a beach.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
Still nothing and...
more nothing.
l got nothing here, either.
CRASHDOWN: Then that's it.
Five moons, five zeroes.
l'm getting thirsty just thinking about it.
Hope somebody else
has more luck out there.
Yeah.
CRASHDOWN: What's on your mind,
Boomer?
l don't know. l have this feeling.
-Let's run that last sweep again.
-You're the boss.
-Beginning sweep 21 .
-Beginning sweep 22.
CRASHDOWN: Boomer,
l'm getting nothing again. How about you?
[Tense instrumental music]
BOOMER: l'm having trouble saying it.
CRASHDOWN: What do you mean?
[Tense instrumental music continues]
l think l see....
Oh!
l have positive contact! Yeah!
[Tense music reaches crescendo]
Oh, yes! Yeah!
Good call, Boomer.
Sir. Dradis just picked up Boomer's Raptor.
ADAMA: Let's hear it.
CRASHDOWN: Galactica, Crashdown.
Dradis sweeps indicate it's time
to break out the swimsuits...
because we've found water!
Repeat.: Positive water contact!
[Crew cheering]
Patch me in to the entire fleet.
You're connected, sir.
Attention. This is the commander.
We have found water!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Let's go have a drink.
l think they're pleased. l can hear them
screaming in the background.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
[Thunder rumbling]
HELO: Sharon, be careful with that needle.
We're running low
on anti-radiation medicine.
-Not really Mom's home cooking.
-Yeah? lt beats eating grass and leaves.
We'll be cooking up a fine meal
of twigs and moss by the end of the week.
You spoil me.
Can l ask you something, Sharon?
Why'd you come back for me?
l hate to fly alone.
Come on. You disobeyed orders,
flew back into this hellhole...
and not that l don't appreciate it, but why?
l just couldn't leave you behind.
Let's leave it at that.
[Signal beeping]
lt's a Colonial Fleet signal.
l can't decode it,
but it means there's someone.
Someone in the military
is still alive and kicking here in Caprica.
Yes!
[Soft instrumental music]
Now all we have to do is find them.
[All cheering]
-Way to go, Boomer!
-Nice work, sir!
-Nice job. Let's get you debriefed.
-Yes, sir.
Chief. You think you could take a look
at my ejection pyros?
BOOMER: l think there's a short.
TYROL: Yeah. Cally.
No, Chief.
You could take a look at it yourself.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
ROSLlN: Thank you for coming, Capt. Apollo.
l am aware that you were in charge...
of the mission
that destroyed the Olympic Carrier.
ROSLlN: l know what a hard thing that is
to live with, for all of us.
ROSLlN: l'm struggling
with it myself, frankly.
APOLLO: l can't stop thinking about it.
[Sombre instrumental music]
But a man has to accept responsibility
for his actions.
He doesn't second-guess
the choices he makes.
He lives with them. Every day.
You know, l remember when President Adar
sent the Marines into Aerilon.
ROSLlN: Fifteen people died.
ROSLlN: ln public, of course,
he had to say all the usual things.
He was sure of what he'd done,
he made the right choice...
he stayed the course.
But he knew it was a mistake.
ROSLlN: And he kept the names of the dead
in his desk drawer.
He said that it was imperative for a leader...
to remember and learn from the mistakes...
even if they can't admit to them publicly.
-You think we made a mistake?
-l don't know.
ROSLlN: l don't have a desk drawer yet,
but l have a pocket.
ROSLlN: l don't want to add
to your burdens, however.
l have a request. l would like you
to be my personal military advisor.
l'm sorry.
My father is the senior military officer.
He should advise you.
No, l don't mean to go
behind your father's back. Nothing like that.
l'm not looking for military advice.
l'm looking for advice about the military.
ROSLlN: That little insight about your father
making a gesture, that really helped me.
lt made me reassess the man.
l would appreciate more of those insights.
And you can keep your day job at the C-A-G.
lt's pronounced ''CAG.''
Do you see why l need you?
So who's going to tell my father?
Well....
l was thinking that...
that would be your first assignment.
Somehow l knew you were going to say that.
Thank you, Captain.
Hey.
BOOMER: That is just what l needed.
TYROL: Oh, yeah?
-Did you find that detonator?
-Yes, l did.
-l gave it to master-at-arms.
-What?
TYROL: No, no.
l told her l found it during maintenance.
Listen, calm down.
This is the best way to go about this. Okay?
That puts them on the same trail we're on...
and it doesn't raise any suspicion of you.
Listen. Trust me on this, Sharon.
l'm not going to let anything happen to you.
Okay?
-Okay.
-All right, okay.
TYROL: Don't worry, sweetie.
-l better go.
-All right.
[Man's voice on PA system]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Theme music]
NARRATOR: Previously on
Battlestar Galactica.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
BlLLY: The captain of the Astral Queen
wants you to know...
he's got 1,500 prisoners under heavy guard.
Tell him l want daily reports
on the well-being of his prisoners.
The President has given me a direct order.
ADAMA: We're in the middle of a war...
and you're taking orders
from a schoolteacher?
HELO: Don't suppose there's a Plan B?
BOOMER: Plans B, C, D, E are the same as A.
Get off the planet and get back to the ship.
ROSLlN: How much water did we lose?
Almost 60%% of total potable water reserves.
lf we don't find new supplies
they'll run out of water in two days.
[Microphone screeching]
GAETA: [Over PA] Reveille,
morning stations aboard Battlestar Galactica.
All hands report to your stations.
[Tigh grunting and groaning]
[Sighing]
TlGH: So, what do we have?
TYROL: Good news, Colonel.
We scouted the ice moon.
Found an entire subsurface ocean.
We've got reports and video for you.
TlGH: Not exactly Caprica Beach
down there, Chief?
No, sir. We've registered temperatures
180 and below...
venting of methane and C02.
lt's gonna be a bitch to work down there, sir.
Cheer up. You know how lucky we are
we found this ugly rock?
Water riots breaking out
all over the fleet. Civilians.
TlGH: Whiney civie cry-babies can't stand
less than a hot shower every day.
TYROL: Yes, sir.
Even Galactica's down
to 10,000 JPs of water.
TlGH: Ever see a man die of dehydration?
TYROL: No, sir.
Let's hope you never do. lt isn't pretty.
So, where were we?
We drilled 23 core samples.
13%% sodium chloride. What the hell?
We can't drink salt water!
No, sir. That's why l had Cally test the ice.
Well, there you go. Pure water.
Couple of lemons, we could make lemonade.
TYROL: Yes, sir.
We'll have to melt the ice
before we transport it up to the ship.
What's that gonna take?
High-capacity heater expansion tanks,
D-25 plasma torches...
-Myrex hoses, centrifugal pumps.
-Sounds like a lot of manpower.
ldeally 1,000 men, sir.
One thousand men?
And where're they gonna come from?
Slave labour.
They are criminals. They've been sentenced
to hard labour. And this is very hard labour.
Not to mention physically dangerous.
This is not for civilians, but....
APOLLO: Their ship wasn't designed
for long-term incarceration.
APOLLO: These men have been stuck
in cramped cells for weeks now.
They might even prefer to get out.
Do something, even if it is dangerous.
lf they volunteer. But these aren't slaves
and l will not have them treated as such.
No. We could offer incentives.
APOLLO: Points towards earning freedom.
ADAMA: Excuse me.
You wanna start releasing
hardened criminals into the fleet?
Sir, these men were on their way to Caprica
for parole hearings...
which at least implies
they may be ready for release.
-Make it happen, Captain.
-Yes, sir.
To address Commander Adama's
concerns, l'd like you to go along...
and set up a screening procedure
to weed out the hardened criminals.
l would like to have a representative
from Galactica...
who will report directly to me
about security issues.
How about D?
BlLLY: Second Class Petty Officer Dualla.
ADAMA: l know who she is.
l'm not sure she's conversant
with the technical details.
She'll be fine, but we should send someone
from ground crew...
who'll make sure the chosen men
know to use the equipment.
-Agreed.
-l have to get to the ClC. Excuse me.
BlLLY: Madam President? The doctor.
ROSLlN: Excuse me?
BlLLY: The doctor?
Commander, do you have a ship's doctor
aboard Galactica?
-Maj. Cottle. ls there something wrong?
-No, nothing urgent. Allergies.
He's out on the fleet
checking medical conditions.
ADAMA: l'll tell him that you want to see him.
ROSLlN: Thanks.
Petty Officer Dualla.
Conversant in technical details.
Thinking entirely of the mission.
Something on your mind, Captain?
l just thought maybe you had something
you wanted to say.
l have nothing to say to
the personal representative of the President.
l'm still Galactica's lead pilot.
l have nothing to say to him, either.
Every man has to decide for themselves
which side they're on.
l didn't know we were picking sides.
[Sombre instrumental music]
That's why you haven't picked one yet.
[lntense instrumental music]
WlLKENS: I'm a bus driver, not a warden.
APOLLO: How many total?
WlLKENS: 1,500.
WlLKENS: They don't give me their files
or their names.
WlLKENS: Hell, they're just numbers.
APOLLO: Thanks, Wilkens.
All right. They're all yours.
[PA system beeping]
[Tense instrumental music]
[Apollo clears throat]
I'm Capt. Lee Adama,
personal representative of the President.
We're in a crisis.
Thousands of us are on the verge
of dying from dehydration.
The good news is we have found water.
The bad news is, it's located on a moon
with harsh environmental conditions.
We need 1,000 able-bodied men
to help us get that water.
President Roslin feels
that you represent our best chance.
She also recognises that you are not slaves.
Any man who volunteers to help us during
this emergency will earn ''freedom points''...
which can be applied
toward earning his release.
We're offering you a chance
for a new beginning.
Whoever is interested,
please just step out of your cell.
[Electronic buzzing]
[Tense instrumental music continues]
[Slow footsteps]
ZAREK: Thank you for your offer.
We respectfully decline.
PRlSONER: Zarek!
Oh, my God, that's Tom Zarek.
The terrorist?
PRlSONERS: [Chanting] Zarek!
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
[Theme music]
WlLKENS: So who the hell is Tom Zarek?
BlLLY: He's a freedom fighter.
-He's a prisoner of conscience.
-He's a butcher.
His colony was exploited
by the other 1 1 for centuries.
His people were marginalised, brutalised--
l'm from Saggitaron,
and that man doesn't speak for all of us.
He blew up a government building,
there's no excuse for that.
Captain, l've been watching the clock and
if we won't get any help, we should move on.
Zarek's got the prisoners united.
Let's go through Zarek.
[lntense instrumental music]
HELO: Hello? Anybody out there?
Anybody wanna help two stranded pilots?
HELO: That's what l hate about big cities.
No one will help you.
BOOMER: No more shouting.
You're making me nervous.
Feel like l'm in a movie.
-At least it stopped raining.
-For now.
[Tense instrumental music]
Where is everyone?
Some are dead. ln their beds, at their desks.
Ones who weren't killed outright
probably ran into the hills.
Won't do any good.
-Guess l'm getting a little--
-Depressing? Morbid?
Sorry. Been here longer than you.
Wish l could say it gets easier.
[Loud banging]
[Squeaking]
BOOMER: There's more.
HELO: Boomer, you might not wanna--
Frakking rats. Let's go.
Come on.
Let's find a hospital,
score some anti-radiation meds, okay?
We've only got two days' worth left.
Sharon, we've made it this far.
We're gonna make it all the way.
-Right.
-Damn straight, all the way.
We're doing good, real good.
l guess someone must be
watching out for us.
DORAL: She's good.
-So far.
-Jealous?
[lntense instrumental music]
NO. 6: This all makes me makes so sad.
DORAL: They would've destroyed themselves
anyway. They deserve what they got.
We're the children of humanity.
That makes them our parents, in a sense.
True. But parents have to die.
lt's the only way children
come into their own.
[Cell door opening]
[Zarek sighs]
No, that's not necessary.
l'd like to talk to you.
Guard. Prisoner 893893...
requests permission
to speak with his visitor.
SEABORNE: Granted.
We're not allowed to speak
unless asked a direct question.
And you didn't ask me a direct question.
ZAREK: You've never been
in a prison before, have you, Captain?
APOLLO: No.
ZAREK: You're fortunate.
-May l sit down?
-Yes, of course.
[Cell door shuts]
[Tense instrumental music]
APOLLO: We need these men of yours
to help us.
They're not my men. They belong to you.
l belong to you. You own us.
You're the master, we're the slaves.
[Tense instrumental music continues]
APOLLO: You're clearly a man of principle.
APOLLO: l respect that.
ZAREK: Really?
The things you've stood for over the years,
the book you wrote.
The book that had to be smuggled
out of labour camp...
because stumps aren't allowed
freedom of expression?
l read it. ln college.
Thought it was radical, challenging.
Made me question some things
l'd accepted before without thinking.
Nice to hear l'm a big hit on campus.
You weren't, the book was banned.
l read it anyway.
Point is, l understand
where you're coming from.
But I don't think you understand
how critical the situation is out there.
People are gonna start dying.
Hey, Starke. lt's time for your break.
BlLLY: How can you say that?
DUALLA: lt's the truth.
Zarek and the SFM,
they don't care about justice.
BlLLY: His people, your people
have been exploited.
-You can't tell me about my people.
-l'm not telling you about your people.
All l want, the President wants...
is to offer you a chance
to earn your freedom.
Now you've said the truth: freedom is earned.
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
Stay where you are, Captain.
lt'll all be over soon.
[Electronic beeping]
SEABORNE: Nobody try anything! Back up!
[Prisoners yelling]
[Prisoner grunting]
SEABORNE: We've got the guards
and the crew in separate cells in Block 7.
Mason is looking after the hostages.
ZAREK: Nice job.
SEABORNE: Everything's under control.
The men are organising exactly as planned.
l knew l could count on you.
[Cell lock clacking]
Stay frosty there, Billy.
Everything's gonna be all right.
l don't know about that.
They don't wanna hurt us.
That won't get them what they want.
Which is what?
-Lt. Thrace. Good to see you.
-Good to see you, too.
BALTAR: Really?
STARBUCK: No.
[Starbuck giggles]
[Sympathetically] Oh.
-l wonder if she's a real blonde.
-l doubt it.
Now, one of you has been
coming in a little hot lately.
A little too hot. A little.... l don't know.
He's burning up the deck
with his skids because...
he can't pull back on the throttle.
Who is the speed demon, my prince?
Flat-Top, sir.
[Pilots chuckling]
STARBUCK: Flat-Top.
You got a need for speed, do you?
Can't wait to get back to the Big G
and the loving embrace of your fellow pilots?
Or maybe you have a hot date
with your right hand.
lt never gets a headache.
Tell you what, Flat-Top,
you come in too hot today...
you may have to start using your left.
[Pilots exclaiming]
All right. You've been fun,
you've been a great audience. Dismissed.
[Pilots chattering]
TlGH: There's no smoking in the ready room.
STARBUCK: My room, my rules, sir.
-Where's your mummy?
-Dead. Where's yours?
-l'm looking for Boomer.
-1 400. Boomer's in the tool room.
A pilot blows his landings
and you make a joke out of it?
Screaming at people
doesn't always get the best results, sir.
l learned that at officer candidate school.
You are right on the edge, Thrace.
Careful you don't fall off.
Speaking of falling off...
[Starbuck sniffs]
glad to see you've found a way
to quench your thirst.
[Tense instrumental music]
They won't negotiate
while you're holding hostages.
-l don't wanna negotiate.
-Then what do you want?
To be treated like men, not animals.
-Finally have something to bargain with.
-So what happens now?
-We're gonna talk.
-What about?
Your father.
-ls this a Monclair original?
-Yes.
BALTAR: Fantastic.
ADAMA: Would you like some water?
Yes, thank you.
l'm not a collector myself, but l....
l am familiar with his work, and may l say...
you really do have an excellent eye for art.
Thank you.
[Tense instrumental music]
-Where's my Cylon detector, Doctor?
-Oh, that.
Yes, it's taking longer
than expected, unfortunately.
What's the hang-up?
lt's not working this time, Gaius.
He can see right through you.
There are a number of obstacles...
none of them insurmountable,
but they do tend to slow us down.
For a start, the lack of proper facilities.
The water shortage, of course.
The water shortage, not to mention--
ADAMA: Cut the BS.
You said you had a way of detecting
human from Cylon.
Do you or don't you?
[Tense instrumental music continues]
-l don't.
-What?
l don't think that l'm the man for this job.
BALTAR: l'm not cut out
for this kind of work.
-You have to do this.
-Why do l keep putting it off?
lt's my subconscious telling me...
that l'm not the man for this job, please.
Listen to me.
lf you don't tell him what he wants to hear...
he's going to find you out.
And when he does,
they're going to tear your head off...
and throw your body out of an air lock!
Pardon me.
l haven't had much sleep recently, so....
[Adama sighs]
Unfortunately, Doctor, for both of us...
you're the last man we have.
So what's the game plan, Doc?
[Tense instrumental music]
This is what you say:
''Commander, the truth is, there is one way.''
-Say it!
-Commander, the truth is...
there is one way.
[Repeating after No. 6]
l didn't wanna have to ask you for this...
but what l really need
to complete the project...
is a nuclear...
warhead.
That how you got to be the
''personal representative of the President?''
ZAREK: Because of your father?
APOLLO: Hardly.
[Zarek scoffs]
So, they don't get along, Adama and Roslin?
They have their differences.
But not when it comes
to dealing with terrorists.
l thought you said you respected me.
Read my book.
That was before you resorted
to violence and hostage-taking.
Always better when the oppressed
don't fight back, isn't it?
A warhead?
NO. 6: Technically,
l need the plutonium inside.
Technically, l need the plutonium inside.
Figure out the rest for yourself.
[Baltar sniffling]
As you may know, the Cylons are...
susceptible to certain kinds of radiation...
and by taking the plutonium...
and embedding it
in a carbon nanotube matrix...
and it really is that simple...
l can construct a filter that will
preferentially ionise synthetic molecules...
and thus deliver to you your Cylons.
We have five warheads left aboard this ship.
ADAMA: We may need them.
BALTAR: Yes, of course.
lf you really think that this project
has a low priority...
then you're totally within your bounds to....
[Tense instrumental music continues]
You'll get your warhead.
Good boy.
Thank you, Commander.
TYROL: Look, the master-at-arms
has been over every inch of that locker.
She's come up with nothing.
BOOMER: So they've got no idea
who took those six G-4 charges...
-or who put that detonator in--
-Don't worry about it.
l'll take care of it, okay?
[Tigh grunts]
l need to speak with the Lieutenant, alone.
[Door shuts]
You don't honestly think
you've been fooling everyone, do you?
l know. The old man knows.
TlGH: Hell, the whole ship
knows about you and the Chief.
lt stops. Now.
Sir, the Chief and l are just friends.
When the ship was being decommissioned,
we let it go.
Hell, we let people get away with murder.
That was then and this is now.
We're at war, this is a combat unit
and you're his superior officer.
Put a stop to it. That's an order.
Yes, sir.
GAETA: [Over PA] Attention.
Pass the word for Col. Tigh.
Col. Tigh, please report to the CIC.
[Door shuts]
ZAREK: [On radio] The crew are
my prisoners. They will not be harmed.
ADAMA: Are you recording this?
GAETA: Yes, sir.
TlGH: What's this?
ADAMA: Trouble.
ZAREK: [On radio] But I have
two conditions before I release my captives.
First, the government
which controls our fate...
is illegal and illegitimate...
and it must submit to the will of the people.
I demand the immediate resignation...
of Laura Roslin and her ministers.
Second, l demand free and open
elections to choose a new leadership.
And a new government
that represents all of the people.
These demands are made not for me
or the former slaves held on this ship...
but for you,
the people, the survivors of the holocaust...
and the children of humanity's future.
l am Tom Zarek...
and this is the first day of the new era.
-We've jammed his transmissions.
-A little bit late for that.
-Every ship in the fleet heard that broadcast.
-lt doesn't matter.
lt does matter.
He's trying to bring down the government.
ADAMA: No one'll take it seriously.
You have something to learn when
it comes to public opinion, Commander.
Tom Zarek is a name with weight. He's
a very sympathetic figure. A legend, almost.
Twenty years in prison
over a matter of principle.
He's a criminal and a terrorist.
People won't give him credence.
ROSLlN: Don't be so sure, Commander.
Rebellions are contagious. People are
already rioting over the water crisis.
We can't afford
to destabilise this government right now.
ADAMA: l agree.
ROSLlN: When are you going in?
l assumed you were gonna talk to him first.
-We don't negotiate with terrorists.
-l said talk.
There's nothing to talk about.
What he wants, l can't give him.
We're not ready yet. Talking to Zarek
gives us a little bit more time.
That's what he wants, legitimacy.
He wants to be recognised.
He wants his crimes validated.
l watched President Adar offer him
a full pardon if he'd apologise...
and give up violence
as a means of political change. He refused.
[Sombre instrumental music]
-No commitments. No deals.
-l'll let you know what happens.
Three assault teams:
Alpha, Bravo, Constellation.
We jam their dradis, the Raptors cut
through the hull here, here and here...
without being seen.
Once we're inside, Alpha takes--
What's this ''we'' crap?
-l'm going, sir.
-Like hell.
We have a few marines left on Galactica.
-Let them handle it, Starbuck.
-They don't have a sniper.
With all due respect, l'm the best shot
in or out of the cockpit.
She's right. For once.
Wonders never cease.
All right, you're going in.
You get a clear shot at Zarek, you take it.
l wanna control that ship immediately.
-And l want all the hostages alive.
-Yes, sir.
l don't even know how l drew this detail.
-President thought you'd be valuable.
-President doesn't know who l am.
l told her. Sorry.
On the other hand,
it's nice to get out of the ClC.
Break up the day, meet new people.
Yeah.
[Tense instrumental music]
MASON: You're not asleep.
CALLY: Not anymore.
MASON: ls that your way of telling us
you're not scared?
No, it's my way of telling you l'm tired.
-You don't know what tired is.
-Right.
Don't! Don't mock me, little girl.
l'm not mocking you.
MASON: Tom and l,
we go way back. Long time.
lf you know what's good for you,
you'll be nice to me.
[Pilots chattering]
Frequent wireless contact.
TlGH: Keep us informed all the way.
STARBUCK: Yes, sir.
Good hunting.
[Engines whining]
Who voted for Laura Roslin? You?
Did you vote for her?
-She was sworn in under the law.
-The answer is, no one voted for her.
And yet she's making decisions
for all of us, deciding who lives...
and who dies. ls that democracy?
ls that a free society?
What is it you want from me?
You want me to say she shouldn't
be president? We need a government.
-We need rules, we need a leader.
-We need to be free men and women.
lf we're not free,
then we're no different than Cylons.
[Solemn instrumental music]
ZAREK: They call you Apollo.
APOLLO: lt's my call sign.
Apollo's one of the gods. A lord of Kobol.
You must be a very special man
to be called a god.
lt's just a stupid nickname.
Son of Zeus, good with the bow,
god of the hunt...
and also a god of healing.
Now, a god...
can reconcile those two opposing forces,
but a mortal...
has to pick one side or the other.
Have you picked a side, Apollo?
Astral Queen, this is the Battlestar Galactica.
Commander Adama
wishes to speak to Mr. Zarek.
-Please respond.
-[Scoffs] Zeus is calling.
ZAREK: [On phone] Commander Adama?
Tom Zarek. How can I help you?
First, l want to make sure
that my people are unharmed.
This is Apollo. l'm fine, so are the others.
APOLLO: They're located on the lower--
ZAREK: That's enough, thank you.
l'm glad to hear that no one's been hurt.
That would have tragic consequences.
-How long until you storm the ship?
-l'm hoping that won't be necessary.
I think that you and I can come up
with some kind of understanding.
This is not the only crisis
that l'm dealing with.
[Tense instrumental music]
The water shortage affects the entire fleet.
Your men are on their way even as we speak.
There's still time to work this out.
Have the President step down
and call for elections.
That's not gonna happen.
Then l look forward to meeting your men.
[Phone clicks]
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
-l knew you were faking.
-l'm a light sleeper.
-l don't think l have your respect.
-l respect you.
Get up.
BlLLY: Hey, what's going on?
Hey!
[Gun clicks]
-What are you doing?
-Move.
DUALLA: Where are you taking her?
It's okay, Cally. You're gonna be okay.
-They know where we are, Cally.
-Capt. Adama!
Hey! Capt. Adama!
-They're willing to talk.
-Sounded that way.
[Tense instrumental music]
You want them to storm the ship.
Soft seal. Pressurised.
Eyes.
That's it, isn't it?
You don't want elections, you don't want
your freedom. You want a bloodbath.
You don't understand.
Tom Zarek's been out of the headlines,
out of the news...
forgotten for 20 years as he rots in a cell.
Now he's got a chance to go out
in a blaze of glory...
and he's gonna take it.
Alpha One, we're in.
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
Once Roslin uses Adama's soldiers...
to massacre the people on this ship...
prisoners and hostages alike...
people in the fleet will never forgive them.
The entire government will collapse.
-She can take care of herself.
-You sure?
She's been trained.
We've all been trained in capture, it's--
[Cally screams]
You've been saying
everything you're doing is for freedom.
APOLLO: But the truth is...
it's all about Tom Zarek
and his personal death wish.
[Door opens]
SEABORNE: Tom. Something's up.
MASON: Frakking bitch!
ZAREK: That's Mason. What the hell.
[Gunshot]
They're killing the hostages. Let's go.
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Prisoner grunting]
[Tense instrumental music]
Constellation Team, set.
[Mason screaming]
ZAREK: Mason!
[Mason groaning]
ZAREK: Mason, what're you doing?
-Bit my ear off.
-Frak you!
APOLLO: Open the door, she's been shot!
You said they weren't animals.
What do you call this?
MASON: Twenty years l've been waiting!
APOLLO: He's gonna kill her. Do something.
You did this! You put him in a cage!
You made him a monster!
[Prisoner grunts]
[Tense instrumental music continues]
Bravo, set.
You filthy bitch!
You all deserve to die!
[Cally sobbing]
You first.
[Sobbing]
STARBUCK: All teams, sniper in position.
-He's gonna do it.
-You reap what you sow.
You look at me. You see me! Look at me!
[Seaborne grunting]
[Gun firing]
[Cally gasping]
[Tense instrumental music intensifies]
Come on, Lee. Take out the son of a bitch.
[Apollo panting]
How about it, Tom?
You still have a death wish?
You ready to leave this world,
right here, right now?
-Yes.
-Too bad.
'Cause this is what you're gonna do.
APOLLO: You're gonna tell your men
to help us get that water off the moon.
APOLLO: They're gonna work
for their points.
APOLLO: And they're gonna earn
their freedom. And then...
you're gonna get your elections.
-What?
-'Cause you're right, Tom.
You are right about democracy
and consent of the people.
[Tense instrumental music]
l believe in those things,
and we're gonna have them.
And you can have them, too.
Or you can have this bullet. Your call.
What are you doing, Lee? Come on.
How do l know your father...
and the President will honour your word?
You don't.
You let the rest of the hostages go,
we'll leave this ship in your hands.
They try and come after you,
you can still have your last stand.
lt's your choice. You reap what you sow.
All right.
ZAREK: Lower your weapons.
PRlSONER: Do what he says.
Put them down.
APOLLO: Back off.
[Cally gasping]
APOLLO: Cally, you're gonna be okay.
You just hang in there, you hear?
STARBUCK: Got you.
[Tense instrumental music]
[Apollo grunts]
[Gunshot]
[Guns clicking]
APOLLO: Cease fire!
[Prisoners shouting]
PRlSONER: Don't shoot!
STARBUCK: All teams, hold positions.
[Starbuck panting]
Frak.
[Gasping]
-Thanks.
-l need a medic here.
God.
l don't believe this.
-lt's unacceptable.
-lt's done.
Prisoners have full control
of the Astral Queen.
We evac'ed all the guards
and support personnel. lt's their ship.
-They're a threat to the entire fleet.
-They've been disarmed.
-The ship itself has no weapons.
-The ship itself is a weapon!
They're totally dependent on us
for food, fuel...
and they've agreed to organise the
workforce for the water detail on the moon.
You've committed me
to holding elections within a year.
Madam President, with respect...
you're serving out the remainder
of President Adar's term.
When that term is up in seven months,
the law says there's an election.
l only committed you to obeying the law.
-You were not authorised to make any deal.
-You sound like a lawyer.
l swore an oath to defend the articles.
The articles say there's an election
in seven months. lf you're saying...
the law's out, then l'm not a captain,
you're not a commander...
and you are not the president.
And l don't owe either of you
a damned explanation for anything.
He's your son.
He's your advisor.
An election.
l guess you finally picked your side.
ADAMA: Madam President.
[Entrance opens and shuts]
[Door shuts]
[Starbuck clears throat]
What the hell is this? Water?
Bet your ass.
There's plenty more where that came from.
l have my flaws, too.
The difference is, my flaws are personal,
yours are professional.
[Starbuck chokes]
Thank you, Lieutenant. That'll be all.
[Sombre instrumental music]
[Door shuts]
[Sighs]
Specialist Lazy, how are you feeling?
Must be nice...
lying around, doing nothing, as usual.
Sorry, Chief.
l didn't think you'd find me here.
TYROL: l am so on to you.
SOClNUS: Cally, is it true?
SOClNUS: You really bite that guy's ear off?
CALLY: He's lucky that's all l bit off.
[Tyrol laughs]
That's my girl.
[Knocking on door]
-l'm sorry, l can come back.
-No, it's all right. Come on in.
l just wanted to say goodbye
before l head back to Galactica.
And to tell you...
l hope you understand,
l wasn't being disloyal, Madam President.
l understand.
You're upholding the law. l admire it.
l believe in you. ln what you're doing.
And for what it's worth,
seven months from now, you'll have my vote.
Could you sit?
There's something l need to tell you.
The truth is,
l might not be here in seven months.
-Are you planning a vacation?
-l wish.
l told your father that l...
[Clears throat]
had allergies, but l have cancer.
ROSLlN: l found out
the morning of the attack.
[Apollo sighs]
l'm so sorry, Madam President.
l don't know what to say.
ROSLlN: l understand.
l'm going to fight this,
but there is a great need for secrecy.
Of course.
[Sombre instrumental music]
Whether or not l survive this illness...
it is of great importance to me...
that there's a future for the people.
And l fear that knowledge
of my illness will erode hope.
So this has to stay between you and me.
-You can count on me.
-l know l can.
You're Capt. Apollo.
[Theme music]
NARRATOR: Previously on
Battlestar Galactica.
[Dramatic instrumental music]
Zak failed basic flight.
But he didn't because l passed him.
l can't decode it,
but it means there's someone.
Someone in the military
is still alive and kicking here in Caprica.
[Cheering]
l have cancer.
And l fear that knowledge
of my illness will erode hope.
So this has to stay between you and me.
-Zak was my brother.
-What was he to me, nothing?
Same old Lee. You haven't changed either.
[Warning system beeping]
[Coughs]
[Spacecraft engine droning]
Helmet!
-You are so unprepared.
-Shut up!
[Laughs] You're the worst CAG in the history
of CAGs actually.
DUALLA: Raptor pilot
Lt. Dwight Flat-top Sanders...
entering hangar Deck 12 B.
Deck hands, please report.
DUALLA: Repeat, deck hands,
please report to 12 B.
PlLOT 1 : There he is!
PlLOT 2: Way to go, Lieutenant!
[Pilots cheering]
PlLOT 1 : Raptor Pilots flying high!
PlLOTS: Raptor Pilots flying high!
-Red paint, incoming!
-Brush?
You're the worst. The absolute worst!
Here.
PlLOT 1 : Raptor Pilots flying by!
PlLOTS: Raptor Pilots flying by!
What the hell is this?
Flat-top's 1,000th landing and
nobody tells me. Now we look like idiots.
TYROL: Find a wagon!
DECK HAND: Yes, sir!
Somebody get me a wagon!
One, zero, zero.
ADAMA: You're not ready yet?
[Laughing]
Someone's going to have to pick that up.
[Giggling]
-Stop it!
-Let's go, come on.
This one is perfect. Take this.
Here, give me a hand.
Unload this. Put it wherever.
You two, come here.
Take this wagon to the palace.
[Pilots singing and cheering]
STARBUCK: Did the Commander tell you
what happened on his 1,000th landing?
-l don't remember telling you what l did.
-Whatever.
STARBUCK: He's landing on the Atlantia...
and he's been having this ongoing fight
with the LSO...
and so he decides he'll stick it to him good.
This has all been over-exaggerated.
PlLOTS: Come on, people, watch them bake
PlLOT 1 : Three Little Cylons in the air
PlLOTS: Three Little Cylons in the air.
PlLOT 1 : Watch their metal burn and flare!
So, he skids to a stop on the flight deck...
and the LSO hears over the wire
there's this big, loud, long, obnoxious....
[Farting noise]
[Laughing]
ADAMA: l was young.
STARBUCK: lt was great. lt was really funny.
PlLOT 1 : Two Little Cylons jump in their cave
PlLOT 1 : Come on A-CARS make their grave!
The LSO is freaking out...
your dad doesn't care because
he hates the guy.
He figures he can get away with it
'cause it's his 1,000th landing.
''l can get away with anything today!''
PlLOTS: Watch that tin can hit the spot!
[Dramatic instrumental music]
PlLOT 1 : Five Little Cylons in the grass
PlLOTS: Watch the Raptor light their ass!
[Explosion]
DUALLA: Attention!
Fire on the port hangar deck.
DUALLA: Away the fire and rescue team....
ADAMA: Let's go!
[Theme music]
[Struggles and pants]
[Warning system beeping]
Metal fatigue, old equipment.
Worn strap fails, drops a million cubic drone
to the deck.
Kills 13 pilots and lands seven more
in sick bay.
HADRlAN: lt's hard to hear this,
but we got lucky.
lf that had been a missile
instead of a cone drone...
it could've taken out the side of the ship.
Never had a death in my hangar deck.
Accidents. Never a death.
Services for the dead.
APOLLO: Services will commence
at 1 100 hours on the forward hangar deck.
Mid-ship's hangar deck remains closed...
for investigation and clean up
until further notice.
Uniforms for the services will be
dress greys.
l wish l knew what to say,
words to make this better.
Can anything make this better?
l don't know.
ADAMA: Attention on deck!
ADAMA: As you were.
ADAMA: May l?
APOLLO: Yes, sir.
[Eerie instrumental music]
Are you Lt. Thrace?
Give me your eyes.
l know this has been a hard day.
ADAMA: There's been plenty of them lately.
l can guarantee you
there'll be more to come.
ADAMA: Remember your self-esteem.
Your self-respect.
And your self-worth.
Hold strong to them,
because people are watching.
You're the guardians of the fleet.
They need to know that they can
count on you.
ADAMA: Even at a time like this.
ADAMA: Are you Lt. Thrace?
l'm Cdr. Adama. Zak's father.
l know, sir. l'm sorry, sir.
l was planning on coming to see you
tomorrow before the funeral.
You don't need to explain anything.
GUARD: Present arms!
GUARD: Order arms!
Once again, we are charged
with the solemn duty...
to return the bodies of our own
to the universe...
from which the Lords of Kobol brought
them to us.
CLERlC: The burdens of this life are with us
but a short time.
For Lt. Zak Adama,
son of William and Caroline Adama...
brother of Lee, the time was too short.
CLERlC: But we take comfort in knowing
his life was willingly given...
in service to all of us.
CLERlC: We honour them for that.
CLERlC: And, thus, it falls upon us
to repent our sins...
and with the help of the Lords of Kobol...
make our own lives worthy of that gift.
CLERlC: And now, we commit his body
to the ground from which we were all made.
ELOSHA: Secure in the knowledge...
that we will be reunited with them...
in a better world to come.
[Melancholic instrumental music]
So say we all.
[Snare drums sounding military drumbeat]
GUARD: Present arms!
[Gunshot]
ADAMA: Pilots we've known.
ADAMA: l have to start training new pilots.
[Starbuck chuckles]
There it is.
[Clears throat]
l kind of thought this was about that.
l don't know if l'm the right person for this.
-Do you know someone better?
-No.
But there's almost 50,000 people out there.
Trying to tell me there's not one
flight instructor?
There's two. Civilians. Both.
ADAMA: But l need someone
to teach combat tactics.
You know, l don't know
if l'd be of any use to you.
-l wasn't the most patient.
-Let's get down to it.
This is about Zak.
lt was not your fault.
You had nothing to do with what happened.
lt was an accident.
Lee? Zak failed basic flight.
-What?
-Or at least he should have, but he didn't...
because l passed him.
His technique was sloppy
and he had no feel for flying...
but l passed him.
Because he and l....
Because l felt something and l let it
get in the way of doing my job.
STARBUCK: And I couldn't fail him.
Zak passed basic flight.
ADAMA: He was trained
and ready to sit in that cockpit.
What happened to him could've happened
to any qualified pilot.
-You know that's true.
-Right.
You did your job to the best of your ability.
That's all l can ask.
l need new pilots.
And l want you to train them.
l can do that.
[Sighs]
Just give them the attention and
the professionalism that you gave my son.
And they'll be one hell of a squadron.
Ten cubits says she takes him this time.
You're on.
Thanks for the vote of confidence.
Ten to stay.
So, Gaeta, how are you and the Doc here
doing on your Cylon detector?
What Cylon detector?
CRASHDOWN: Rumour has it
that Cylons look like people...
and you guys are working on a way
to weed them out, right?
ZAK: l want you to tell me the truth
about something.
STARBUCK: You passed.
By the skin of your teeth, but you passed.
ZAK: l don't want any special treatment.
Not from my father...
and certainly not from you.
GAETA: lf there were such a programme,
it would be classified...
and l wouldn't be able to talk about it.
BALTAR: Something smells horrible in here.
ls that you, Crashdown?
CRASHDOWN: Yeah, that's me.
BALTAR: Your card.
Zak, l'm a flight instructor.
l'm not going to send you to Vipers
if l don't think you got the chops. Okay?
Hello? Are you all right?
BALTAR: Look....
[Pants]
Maybe you'd like to take a break?
[Clears throat] l'm out of here.
Starbuck?
CRASHDOWN: Okay, she can't do that.
BOOMER: She can and she did.
[Mysterious instrumental music]
BOOMER: This is it.
HELO: Restaurant.
BOOMER: l'm almost on top of the signal.
l don't get it.
How does a military coded signal
end up coming from in here?
Let's find out.
Nothing. ls that thing working?
BOOMER: l checked it three times.
BOOMER: This thing says
we're right on top of it.
HELO: Of what?
What?
BOOMER: Helo.
HELO: You're frackking kidding me.
[Helo laughs]
HELO: Food. Medical supplies.
[Helo yelps]
HELO: Wait a minute, the signal.
[Beeping]
BOOMER: Disaster beacon.
lt's been set to go off if there was an attack.
Some poor slob goes to all the trouble
of building a fallout shelter, stocks it...
has a beacon, the whole planet....
Then what? What happens to him?
Let's just call ourselves lucky
and leave it at that.
[Eerie instrumental music]
-Madame President.
-Would you close that curtain, please?
ROSLlN: Thank you.
You are obviously an intelligent,
well-educated young woman.
Would you mind explaining to me why
you waited five years...
in between breast exams?
Yes, l would mind.
lt's none of your business.
l was busy.
-And now, here you are.
-Yes. Here we are.
-Would you mind?
-l do, actually.
Your doctor back on Caprica was right.
lt's too damn late to operate,
the cancer is too far advanced.
DOC COTTLE: We can try to shrink
the tumour with gamma treatments...
and follow that up with lV cis-Doloxan.
Did he explain to you the side-effects
of Doloxan?
Hair loss, nausea, muscle degeneration.
l watched my mother endure two years
of Doloxan before she died.
l would like to explore alternate treatment.
DOC COTTLE: Prayer?
ROSLlN: Witty.
Have you ever heard of Chamalla extract?
DOC COTTLE: Gods. You're one of those.
ROSLlN: What if it works?
All the evidence on Chamalla is anecdotal.
DOC COTTLE: lt's nothing but a bunch
of loose talk and false hope.
ROSLlN: l'll take that as a yes.
All right.
l'll put out a med request
to the civilian fleet.
Maybe there's some other wide-eyed dreamer
out there...
with a secret horde of Chamalla extract
in their luggage.
DOC COTTLE: Put your clothes back on now.
ROSLlN: Thank you.
DOC COTTLE: And for what it's worth...
l would seriously consider prayer.
Boonie jumpers. Shuttle jockies.
And a Fleet Academy wash-out. This is
the best that you could come up with?
-Diamonds in the rough.
-Yeah, right.
APOLLO: They're the most qualified pilots
in the fleet.
STARBUCK: Great!
STARBUCK: Attention on deck.
That means get on your feet, nuggets!
You are joining the Colonial Fleet,
boys and girls, not some after-school club.
Seats.
STARBUCK: Pilots call me Starbuck,
but you may refer to me as God.
You've all flown before, but you're about
to enter a whole new world...
so pay attention.
We don't have any flight simulators
on board...
so we're putting you into the cockpit, today.
This is the Viper Mark II.
lt's as manoeuvrable as a jack-rabbit,
and can flip end for end...
in 0.35 seconds.
You've never flown anything remotely like it,
so don't think that you have.
STARBUCK: Today we'll do basic launch,
approach, and landing manoeuvres...
and anyone not paying attention
is liable to end up...
as a puddle or something to be hosed
out of the cockpit by the chief of the deck.
She's laying it on a little thick.
STARBUCK: Costanza, right?
COSTANZA: Yes, God, sir.
Not anymore.
From now on, your name is ''Hot Dog.''
And when God speaks, Hot Dog, you listen.
Maybe if you had learned that at
the Academy, you wouldn't have washed out.
Sit up!
LSO: Viper 791 Galactica,
you are cleared for approach.
LSO: Speed 175 port bay,
hands on approach...
checkers green. Call the ball.
l have the ball.
STARBUCK: Easy on the throttle, Kat.
STARBUCK: Are you listening to me?
Don't chase the lights, okay?
KAT: Roger, Starbuck.
STARBUCK: Kat, don't chase the lights!
Set it by the numbers
and correct with thrusters.
LSO: Wave-off!
Punch it, Kat!
Worse than awful.
Wretched beyond belief, actually.
STARBUCK: You call yourselves pilots.
It'll take the knuckle draggers a week to
pound your divots out of the flight deck.
-With due respect, sir, that's unfair.
-Yes, sir. This was only our first day.
No. lt's your last.
lt would be criminal to let any of you
near a Viper again.
So pack your gear and
get the hell off my ship. You're done.
What are you doing here, Kara?
-You can't wash them out on their first day.
-l just did.
Look, l got 40 Vipers, and 21 pilots.
That's it.
We are sitting ducks
until we finish water-op's.
We can't even maintain a CAP.
And Gods forbid the Cylons show up.
Gods forbid.
Let's bring in the next group of candidates.
The next group has never even been
in a cockpit.
-They're starting basic flight.
-Then they start basic flight.
Because that group is done.
lt says so right there.
Maybe you should read it again.
APOLLO: Lt. Thrace, this is not a request.
STARBUCK: Well, Capt. Adama!
l am the flight instructor, sir.
My word is scripture, sir.
STARBUCK: l will not, repeat, not pass
another student who isn't ready.
So, that's what this is about.
lt's not them. lt's Zak.
Careful.
Step back.
[Pants and grunts]
[Grunts]
ADAMA: Starbuck says they can't cut it,
they can't cut it.
She's not giving them a chance. lt's Day 1 .
She's one of the finest pilots
l've ever seen in my life.
One day in the cockpit is all she needs
to know if they can hack it or not.
ADAMA: She got that.
APOLLO: l'm not arguing that, sir.
l'm just saying that l think she's letting her
personal feelings cloud her judgment.
Please sit down, Captain.
ADAMA: What are those feelings?
About Zak.
-We've talked about, Zak.
-You did?
ADAMA: We've talked about a lot of things.
We've been aboard this ship for over
two years. We know each other very well.
When l asked her to be the instructor...
l knew it was going to release
a lot of loose baggage.
She acknowledged it.
She's a professional. She'll do her job.
Okay.
l'm just saying that you should talk to her.
APOLLO: She's walking around
with a lot of emotion.
She almost decked me in the rec room.
Right. You wouldn't smile if you were there.
-l'll talk to her.
-Thank you.
Personally...
l think she's trying to work out her guilt
over what she did for Zak.
l think she's making up for it
by beating up on these guys.
Guilt? Over what?
What did she do for Zak?
-l thought you just said--
-What did she do?
lt's not my place to say and l've already said
more than l should have.
-You'll have to ask her. l'm sorry.
-Captain, just--
Dad, you'll have to ask her.
ZAK: I don't want any special treatment.
Not from my father,
and certainly not from you.
You passed.
By the skin of your teeth, but you passed.
DUALLA: Attention.
Pass the word to Lt. Thrace.
Lt. Thrace, please report
to the CO's quarters.
Yes. Come in.
ADAMA: Lee was just here before.
STARBUCK: l knew it.
He thinks you washed out...
the nuggets without giving them a chance.
They didn't cut it. That's it.
He thought you were letting
personal feelings cloud your judgment.
STARBUCK: Really?
ADAMA: Your feelings about Zak.
That's not the case.
Okay.
ADAMA: He said something else.
He said something that
l would like to ask you directly.
ADAMA: He said that you might be feeling
guilty about something that you did for Zak.
What did you do for him?
STARBUCK: l don't know. Ask Lee.
ADAMA: l'm asking you.
l don't know....
l don't really know
what he was talking about, so--
Don't fence with me, Kara.
l love you like a daughter.
l don't deserve that.
Zak failed basic flight.
He wasn't a bad pilot.
He just had no feel for flying.
And when it came to his final check-ride,
he busted...
three of the test manoeuvres.
And l should have flunked him, but l didn't.
The bottom line is that your son...
didn't have the chops to fly a Viper.
And it killed him.
ADAMA: He told me that you were
an amazing instructor.
And that he was involved with you,
and that it was serious.
He asked me to come to his graduation
from flight school...
-to watch him get his wings.
-l know. l read the letter.
l see.
Then, maybe you can tell me
what he was hinting at.
Surprise, about you.
We were going to....
You know what, it's not important.
-l don't want that to--
-You were engaged, right?
You did it because you were engaged.
[Sombre instrumental music]
Because l made a mistake.
And because l was just....
l was so in love with him.
And l let that get in the way of doing my job.
He just wanted it so much and l didn't want
to be the one who crushed him.
Reinstate the trainees to flight status.
l will.
-l just want you to understand that l....
-Do your job.
Yes, sir.
And walk out of this cabin
while you still can.
[Starbuck clears her throat]
Unpack your gear.
You are all returned to flight status.
We're going to try this again.
Those of you who can be trained to safely fly
the Viper Mark II will pass.
Those of you who cannot, will be cut.
STARBUCK: lt's my job to figure out which
is which, without personal feeling either way.
And l'm going to do my job.
Kat, Chuckles, Hot Dog, you're up first.
Pre-flight briefing in 20 minutes.
CHUCKLES: Where the hell
are you going, Hot Dog? Stay on me.
HOT DOG: Target acquired and destroyed.
Not bad, Hot Dog,
but you left your leader behind.
KAT: Looks like you're having a bad day,
Hot Dog.
-And the moral of this story is?
-Never leave your leader.
Thank you. That is correct.
You never want to be out here alone.
STARBUCK: Okay, Chuckles, take Kat's wing.
Hot Dog, you're on me.
We'll try a little manoeuvre called
''Thorch Weave. ''
l'll be damned. What's got into Starbuck?
TlGH: She actually sounds like
a real instructor for a change.
TlGH: She may actually make Viper pilots
out of some of those nuggets after all.
STARBUCK: Holy crap, we've got incoming.
TlGH: Where the hell did they come from?
Dradis. Multiple contacts.
GAETA: lt's the Cylons.
TlGH: Why didn't we see them coming?
Launch the alert fighters.
Attention! Set Condition 1
throughout the fleet.
Galactica, send the Calvary.
Nuggets, punch it for home.
[Suspenseful instrumental music]
ADAMA: Where's the base ship?
GAETA: No base ships detected, sir.
GAETA: Eight raiders, bearing 047
carom 1 18. Range 22,000.
They found us. lt was only a matter of time.
Galactica, Starbuck.
Where the hell are the alert fighters?
ALERT ONE.: Starbuck, Alert One.
Be there in two minutes.
The Cylons are gaining!
All right, listen up, nuggets.
Stay together and keep your throttles
firewalled until you hit the deck.
STARBUCK: Now, go.
ADAMA: What's she doing?
TlGH: Starbuck's gonna take on all eight.
And get herself killed.
KAT: Hot Dog, where are you going?
STARBUCK: Hot Dog, what are you doing?
HOT DOG: Got one!
STARBUCK: Hot Dog! Get out of here!
STARBUCK: Hot Dog, I told you
to get your ass home!
HOT DOG: You said never
to leave your leader.
STARBUCK: I also said
never to disobey an order.
-I'm hit!
-I got you, Hot Dog!
We're going to make it through this.
Break right. Now!
[Thrilling instrumental music]
She'll make it.
I just lost all three mains.
It's all right, Hot Dog. You did good.
We're gonna be okay, I promise you.
At least one of us will.
STARBUCK: That about does it.
I think there's only one left.
Frack!
STARBUCK: He's right on my tail,
but I got it covered.
Starbuck's wireless and transponder
just cut out.
ALERT ONE.: Alert One, we spotted Hot Dog.
No ID or visual on Starbuck.
[Chuckles]
Frack me!
[Struggles and pants]
[Theme music]