(Michael) My name is Michael Westen.
I used to be a spy until...
[ Cellphone rings ]
Man: We got a burn notice
on you. You're blacklisted.
[ Whistles ]
When you're burned,
you've got nothing --
no cash, no credit,
no job history.
You're stuck in whatever city
they decide to dump you in.
- Where am I?
- Miami.
You do whatever work
comes your way.
You rely on anyone
who's still talking to you.
[ Laughs ]
A trigger-happy girlfriend...
Should we shoot them?
...an old friend who used to
inform on you to the FBI...
You know spies --
a bunch of bitchy little girls.
...family, too...
Hey, is that your mom again?
...if you're desperate....
Someone needs your help, Michael.
...and a down-and-out spy
you met along the way.
That's how we do it,
people.
Bottom line --
as long as you're burned,
you're not going anywhere.
[ Gunshot ]
Nate.
Nate!
Would you please say hello
to the man who murdered
your brother Nate --
Tyler Gray.
Thank you, Tom.
Go get 'em, champ.
Tom,
I've apprehended Gray.
You will wait
for backup.
Don't move.
Buddy,
you got no clue.
This is supposed to be
a suicide mission.
Card wants us all dead.
Please tell me it's done.
Michael:
When we get back to Miami,
I'm going after Card,
and I'll need help.
You'll have to
wear a wire.
We need Card's confession
on tape.
He'd never suspect that
I'm working with the man
who killed my brother.
If I could
take that shot back --
you can't. Just help me get
the man who gave you that order.
[ Static crackles ]
Okay, what the hell?
We just lost him.
Frequency jammer.
That's not good.
[ Explosion ]
Listen to me, Michael.
Gray killed Anson.
Gray shot your brother.
He murdered Nate.
You ordered him to!
Guys like you and me --
we make calls.
We know the ends
justify the means.
We can do things, Michael --
great things, necessary things.
Can we move
into the future?
I'm so proud of you, son.
[ Body thuds ]
Spies are trained to deal
with catastrophic events.
They're taught to separate
how they feel
from what they need to do,
but some circumstances
are so extreme
that the separation
is impossible.
Then, even a seasoned operative
will have the same response
as everyone else --
horror, disbelief, shock.
Jesus.
What happened?
Mike, what'd you do?
I did what I had to,
Sam.
"Had to"?
How do you
figure that?
Card's gun is
in the damn holster.
He killed my brother,
Sam.
He was
going to get away with it.
I had no choice.
I was right outside
that door, Mike.
Why didn't you come and get me
before you made that call, huh?!
Because you know damn well
I would've had
something to say about it!
[ Elevator bell dings ]
Card's team is coming, Sam.
We got to go.
[ Indistinct talking,
footsteps approach ]
This isn't finished.
We need to go out
through the balcony.
This just keeps
getting better.
We're gonna need help
getting out of here, Mike.
I'll call Fi. First,
let's get up to the next floor.
Michael:
Fi, you outside?
Yeah, we're here. You want
to tell me what's going on?
Hotel security's
buzzing around like bees.
And there is a CIA caravan
rolling in --
two S.U.V.s
and a command van.
Michael, what happened?
Card's dead.
They're coming for me.
What. Michael, why?
I can't explain right now.
We need a way out of here.
We made it up to the 9th floor,
but we don't have much time.
Got it.
I'll call you back.
I don't like that look.
What's up?
Those suits
are after Michael.
We need to find him
a way out of here.
All right,
you check the front.
I'll circle around
the east side.
I want you to make contact
with hotel security.
You get me the manager.
Fi, how we looking?
Not good.
There's a full
tactical support team on-site,
and some heavy-hitter
seems to be running the show.
Fi, I need a door.
Give me one exit
they haven't covered.
There isn't one.
They got the whole place
locked down.
Michael,
you're trapped.
Burn Notice 6x13
Over the Line
Original Air Date on November 15, 2012
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
If you need to escape a building
that's being locked down,
speed is key.
There's a small amount of time
when the authorities
coordinate their efforts.
Intelligence operatives
are trained
to take advantage
of that window.
Of course,
when the person in charge
of locking down the building
is also a trained
intelligence operative,
that window may get closed
before you can use it.
Who authorized you
to override fire protocols?!
'Cause I sure didn't!
I did, Captain.
The elevators, P.A. system,
and security cameras
belong to me now.
I want fire
to fall back.
Get your officers
on channel 3.
You're taking orders
from me now.
What kind of control do they
have on the east side, Fi?
I'd say
complete control.
Anyone who tries to leave
isn't getting past the lobby.
There's no way out.
They're not guarding
the 2nd-floor access
to the garage.
If I can make my way down there,
I should be able to get inside
and find a way
to the street.
It won't work,
Michael.
They're stopping
every car that comes out.
Okay, I need you to meet me
in the north side alley.
There's no access
from the garage to the north.
Just get there.
Ms. Riley, we have visual
on all floors.
We found two bodies
upstairs.
Gray?
Who else?
Tom Card.
I want a team outfitted
and ready to sweep in five.
The son of a bitch
who killed Tom
is probably
still in this building.
And he's not getting out.
Well, I thought we were screwed
seven ways from Sunday,
but you can go ahead
and make it eight and nine.
They've got a guard
on every floor,
and they're recruiting
hotel employees
to help lock it down.
It's not just the guard.
They've got cameras outside
the elevators on every floor.
If I can
take out the guard --
Okay, whoa.
I'm not gonna kill him, Sam.
You sure about that, Mike?
'Cause last time I let
you out of my sight --
I can
get us out of here.
You can kick my ass
or you can hear my plan,
but you can't do both.
All right,
let's hear it.
[ French accent ]
Attention, valued guests.
We are experiencing
an emergency.
Please go back to your rooms
immediately
and await
further instructions.
Once a location
is completely locked down,
the only thing hiding does
is delay your capture.
To get out,
you need to generate action
to keep security off-balance
and on the move.
And the only way to do that is
to come right out in the open.
Man: Norm,
what's taking so long?
I need you down
on the mezzanine level.
I got six floors to cover.
I'm moving as fast as I can.
Where's the ice machine?
Sir, you need to go
back to your room.
Over here.
I have something.
Oh, my God.
I think that's --
that's Michael Westen.
He's one of ours.
I need that team
on the 9th floor. Move!
[ Elevator bell dings ]
[ Gun cocks ]
Freeze! Hands up!
Jesus! Don't shoot!
I work here!
What happened here?
Some psycho
just zonked Norm.
I came around the corner.
He was gone already.
Any idea where he went?
Yeah, I heard him
run down the stairwell.
Go!
What --
d-don't try and talk.
Now, Norm, I don't know
who did this to you,
but don't you worry --
we're gonna get him, okay?
Hey, come on!
The guy's been injured.
Can we help him to the lobby?
Once you get
a security team moving,
your best chance to escape
is to move with them.
If they don't know your face,
you can hide in plain sight.
If they do know your face,
you have to get
a little more creative.
You sure
he said the north wall?
Yeah, I'm sure.
I don't know.
They got all the king's horses
and all the king's men
surrounding that hotel.
If you need to escape
a parking garage,
the limited exit points
can be a problem.
[ Tires screech ]
Of course, with the right
large-body, older-model car,
you can create
your own exit point.
You know, I hate to say it,
but if they're not out by now,
then --
...they're
on their way?
Mike, you all right?
Where's Sam?
We had to split up
so he could make it out clean.
We'll meet him
at the emergency spot.
Officer needs assistance.
[ Tires squeal ]
I want make and model
of the car,
where it's headed,
and who's driving.
Shut down every causeway
out of Miami Beach.
We don't know
how Westen got to the garage,
but he didn't
take the stairs.
Come with me.
Make sure he gets some oxygen.
He's a little delirious.
I don't know this m--
You're gonna be fine,
bud.
Just hang in there.
Stay strong.
Excuse me, sir.
May I speak with you a moment?
My name is Agent Riley.
I'm in charge
of the investigation here.
Oh, boy.
You must have your hands full.
Yeah, we sure do.
First of all, I'd like to thank
you for your bravery in there.
Well, look, I'm just glad
Norm's gonna be okay.
Yeah, we are, too.
Unfortunately, the man
who attacked him escaped.
No way.
He got out of there?
His name
is Michael Westen.
Look familiar?
Uh, no, but look,
it's like I told you guys --
I mean, by the time I came
around the corner, he was gone.
Right.
And you said
he took the stairs.
Yeah, but I didn't know
if he was going up or down.
Well, thank you, uh,
Mr...?
Finley. Chuck Finley.
That better be the last time
you lie to me today.
See, I know
your real name...
Mr. Axe.
Jesse: Mike, what the hell
happened in that hotel?
I killed Card.
Okay.
We need to just take a second
and think this through.
There's no time.
It won't be long
before they set up a perimeter
and block
the causeways.
Right,
and once we run it,
we're gonna have to
keep running -- forever.
Mike, you had a bug
in that hotel room with Gray, right?
We can -- we can use it.
Card had a frequency jammer.
There's nothing on tape.
Okay, forensics. There's gonna
be forensics from the scene.
I'm afraid not.
It'll look like Card killed
Tyler Gray in self-defense.
And what? And --
and wh--
When I shot Card,
it wasn't in self-defense.
Any more questions?
Yeah, just one.
Can you make it
to the 96th Street bridge
in under five?
[ Engine revs ]
[ Tires screech ]
[ Police radio chatter ]
Fi, they're setting a roadblock.
Turn around.
They haven't set it yet.
Are you out of your damn mind?
Shh!
If we're gonna do something,
do it fast.
I got this.
For the record,
4 minutes and 36 seconds.
[ Sirens wailing ]
Fi.
I see it, Michael.
[ Tires screeching ]
Making an escape
in an urban environment
is as much about precision
as it is about power.
Another cop, Fi.
You need a car
that can make sharp turns
and accelerate quickly.
[ Sirens wailing ]
Car just turned in
behind us.
I repeat, 5-0 on our tail.
Let's go.
Would you keep it down
back there?
But even
when you're in a fast car,
if the numbers
aren't in your favor,
the focus has to change --
from outrunning...
[ Tires screeching ]
...to outsmarting.
They're gone, Fi.
Let's get out of here.
[ Tires squeal ]
Riley:
Anderson, talk to me.
Still no word, but I'll check
with local traffic again.
Maybe they know something.
Forget it.
If they haven't
been spotted yet,
they've broken
the perimeter.
You.
You want to tell me
where Westen's headed?
Lady, I told you
everything I know, okay?
He asked me to drop him off
at a meeting. That's what I did.
I don't even know the guy
that well.
Oh, really?
From what I know
of the Michael Westen dossier,
if he got married tomorrow,
you'd be his best man.
[ Laughs ]
Michael Westen
getting married --
boy, that's a good one.
You know, you really should
finish reading.
Look, you're both
trained operatives.
You have fallback plans,
rally points.
Nope --
something goes bad,
we all just go our separate ways,
no looking back.
So as of this minute,
Mike is long gone,
and I'm just somebody
he used to know.
And someone who lied to help him
escape a murder scene.
I will catch Westen
with your help or without it.
[ Cellphone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
I wonder if that's somebody
you used to know.
[ Ringing continues ]
Here.
You ever seen this?
It's a program that answers
the phone so we can run a trace,
but the caller
still thinks it's ringing.
Nifty.
Yes. It is.
The trace
is under way.
[ Ringing ]
[ Cellphone beeps ]
No answer?
Still ringing
when I hung up.
Probably hasn't made it
to a safe place to call.
I'm sure he's fine.
We need to grab whatever we can
at the storage unit,
switch cars and find out
where the hell Sam is.
You should
call your mom first.
It might be
your only chance.
[ Telephone rings ]
[ Telephone beeps ]
Hello.
Ma, I can't talk long.
I need you to meet me
at 9:00 tomorrow morning
at dad's
old fishing spot --
the one we went to
when I was 12.
Michael, slow down.
What?
Ma, there's no time.
I'll explain it in the morning.
[ Telephone beeps ]
What -- you think
they're tracing that phone?
Just being careful.
Phone's dead.
Riley: You got a lock?
Not enough time.
He was heading
towards Homestead.
Well, then I guess
we're headed to Homestead.
Let's go.
Get me an overhead.
And get a flag
on that line.
If it goes live again,
I want Westen in surround sound.
[ Laughs ]
You really think
that was Mike?
Trust me -- he ditched his phone
a long time ago.
You probably got pocket-dialed
by some hobo in University Park.
It was moving east to west
before we lost the signal.
Any idea
where he's pit-stopping?
All right, look,
let's start at the motel on 9th,
then go
to Kehl's Self Storage,
and then let's hit
the surplus store on Palm.
No, check it.
Let's start
at the storage units.
That means
we'd have to backtrack.
Why not
go to the motel first?
'Cause I've been watching
Mr. Axe,
and the only time
he flinched
was when I mentioned
the storage units.
Don't forget
that six-pack.
Sam's gonna want beer,
even if it is warm.
Sam would drink it if it was laced with
cyanide. Let's be honest.
I shouldn't have left him.
If he goes down for what I did --
Stop thinking the worst,
Michael.
Maybe he just didn't want
to risk taking your call.
Maybe he's in CIA custody,
wishing he never met me.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Uh, I think
we're about to find out.
The guy I paid off
at the gas station
just saw a van and two S.U.V.s
heading this way.
We got about two minutes until
they're right on top of us.
Guess they got a bead
off your phone after all.
Michael, what are you doing?
If we're gonna get Sam back,
this might be our only chance
to get ears on them.
Look, if we don't
get out of here right now,
we're not gonna need a bug
to hear what they're saying, Mike.
You said
I had two minutes.
An R.F. transmitter
can broadcast audio
up to 3 miles away.
But a bug with that range
needs a steady power source,
like the wiring from the lamp
above a license plate.
Michael, come on!
It takes a little longer,
but when you're trying to save
a friend, it's time well spent.
Michael!
Mike, I will leave you here.
I'm not playing right now.
I'm almost done.
[ Tires squeal ]
[ Police radio chatter ]
This is Glenanne's car.
Looks like
we can officially add her
to the list
of accomplices.
Well, whoever Mike's with,
they're long gone by now.
No, I don't think so. I can
still smell the burnt rubber.
They didn't even have time
to lock up.
We must've
just missed them.
I'm going to catch your friends,
Mr. Axe.
So you need to decide
exactly how you want this
to end for you --
either with a slap on the wrist
or with life in prison.
Should I assume Westen's
armed to the teeth now?
No, that's where
Mike kept his, uh...
vintage-sneaker
collection.
He probably stopped by just to
pick up his lucky Chuck Taylors.
You know, the more I talk to
you, the more confused I get.
You're a patriot,
a decorated war veteran.
Why would you protect
a murderer?
Listen, Riley,
I guarantee you --
Mike is not
the bad guy here.
Oh, really?
Were you there
when he shot Tom Card?
No, but I was there
when we buried Mike's brother --
thanks to Card.
And I was there
when that son of a bitch
tried to bomb us
to kingdom come in Panama.
Oh, so you're saying you
would've done the same thing?
I'm saying
Mike had his reasons.
That's not the question,
Mr. Axe.
Would you have shot Tom Card
in cold blood?
Yes or no?
No. Of course not.
That's what I thought.
He said "Riley."
That must be the woman I saw
at the hotel.
Olivia Riley.
You want to fill me in?
She's a bit
of a counterintel legend.
Half the case studies
they use in training these days
are written by her.
No one's better
at hitting where it hurts.
Look, I know
this thing can't be easy --
seeing a side of someone
you didn't know.
It's not your fault.
Sometimes people just aren't
who we think they are.
Mike is not a murderer.
Then he should
just explain himself.
He's only digging his hole
deeper right now.
And believe me, Mr. Axe,
if you don't help me find him,
I will throw you in that hole
right along with him.
So if you really want
to help Westen,
you'll help me.
Okay. So,
how does this work, then?
Fiona: Did he just say
what I think he said?
It's simple, Mr. Axe.
I'm saying no jail time
if you give me Westen.
I want your word
that Mike gets a fair shake.
You got it.
[ Sighs ]
We were supposed to rendezvous
at the Copperfield Marina.
It's on Key Biscayne.
Mike's got a boat there
gassed up
and ready
to get the hell out of Dodge.
There. You happy?
You made the right decision,
Mr. Axe.
Guy's got
his neck on the line,
and he's still
taking one for the team.
Okay, sending Riley
on a wild-goose chase
to Copperfield Marina
just bought us some time.
Well, he couldn't have picked
a better place.
There are enough boats
and buildings there
to keep them searching
for hours.
No.
I'm gonna end this.
I'm turning myself in.
What, are you crazy?!
Mike, what good
is that gonna do?
She's not just gonna let Sam go,
and you know it.
I created
the situation --
While sacrificing yourself
might help you sleep at night,
it's not gonna fix this,
Mike.
Then you tell me
what will!
Because I'm not gonna let Sam
take the fall
for something I did.
[ Sighs ]
Michael,
I have an idea.
There's only one road
into Copperfield Marina.
There's good cover.
If we hit them
at the entrance,
we might be able to split
Riley's team and grab Sam.
You want to go
to the one place
we know
they'll be looking for us?
She's right, Jesse.
It's our best shot. You know it.
All right, fine.
I'm in.
I'll drive.
There's a reason
spies try not to involve family
in operations.
The strain of waiting,
worrying, and wondering
can drive a trained agent
to the brink,
much less a civilian.
And, of course, no matter
how bad a situation is...
[ Doorbell rings ]
...it can always get worse.
Yes?
Mrs. Westen.
I'm Agent Harper
with the CIA.
Officer Castro here
is Miami P.D.
What can I do for you?
Have you heard
from your son today?
My son?
Is there -- is there
something I should know?
No need to worry,
ma'am.
We just need to know
if you've heard from him.
Yes.
Uh, h-he called, uh,
just a while ago.
Really?
What did he say?
I-I wasn't able
to hear him very well
because there was
a lot of static and noise.
Damn cells, you know?
It sounds like he's underwater.
Frankly, my hearing
is not what it used to be.
Sorry.
[ Police radio chatter ]
You're sure
I shouldn't be worried?
No, we just need
to speak with him.
You would tell me
if there was anything wrong?
Wouldn't you?
Of course we would.
Oh, do you have a card?
'Cause if he calls again,
I can give him your number.
No need.
We'll be
right out front.
Man: All units, we have
fugitive alert response
from state police...
Uh, if you're waiting...
would you like to wait inside?
I made lemonade.
Unless you'd rather
sit in a hot car.
You're sure
it's no trouble?
No bother at all.
It's the least I can do.
Please, come in.
Thank you.
Hello.
Please, sit down.
Oh, sorry.
I'll get rid of this.
[ Chuckles ]
Lemonade or iced tea?
I have both.
Lemonade is fine.
I'm sorry -- which one?
Lemonade is good.
Oh. Perfect.
[ Chuckles ]
Man:
Possible fugitive sighting --
state route 874, toll road 5.
Agent Riley
awaiting confirmation
of positive I.D.
Stand by for further.
Man #2: 20-02.
Thank you very much.
During an operation,
you never want to make a move
until everyone's
on the same page.
But sometimes,
you have no choice.
Hey, hey!
What's going on?
This was taken six minutes ago
east on the Shula Expressway,
2 miles outside of
Copperfield Marina.
Right. Okay.
So, uh, what about me?
You're headed
to federal detention.
We'll discuss
your situation later.
Get him out of here.
Whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa. Wait, wait.
You're putting me
on the bench now?
When someone on your team
gets a surprise,
you have to hope they realize
there's a plan in motion
and they can find a way
to be part of it.
I thought
you wanted Mike alive.
I have cuffs,
I have guns.
I'll let him pick
which we use.
What about your men?
What about their families?
There's no need
for bloodshed here.
And come on -- if anyone
can talk Michael Westen down,
it's his best friend,
right?
You're worried
about my team?
Look, listen, lady,
I just don't want to see
anybody else get hurt.
I've seen enough killing
for one day.
Get him in the van.
The best place to rescue
a prisoner in transit
is at a choke point...
...a place where you can
force the action
into a narrow zone
that you control.
Well-timed, synchronized blasts
on both sides
of the choke point
can separate the vehicles,
isolate the person
you're trying to retrieve,
and create
an effective barrier.
And when you add covering fire,
your opposition will worry more
about staying alive
than stopping your escape.
Oh. Nice work.
Are -- are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Just keep thinking what
I could've done differently.
Michael, you made the call
you thought you had to make.
And if I was wrong?
If there was another way?
Look what I've done to Sam --
to everyone.
Look. [ Sighs ]
There's a price to pay
no matter what you do.
If it's a choice between
betraying everything
you believe in
and pulling a trigger...
...I'm glad
you pulled the trigger.
[ Cellphone rings ]
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Hate to interrupt whatever
moment you guys are having,
but I suggest
you get moving.
Riley's coming
around the mountain.
On our way.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Tell the Coast Guard
to get us two defenders
and a response boat
headed our way now.
[ Cellphone beeps ]
You get
the first crack at Westen,
but you better
make it good.
I'd rather end this thing
peacefully,
but I'm prepared
for any outcome.
Lady, I'm only here
for one reason --
to make sure
nobody else gets hurt.
All right,
this is about to happen, people.
Remember -- first go is Fi,
second one's Mike.
1,000 meters.
Come on, baby.
Come to papa.
Oh, and one more thing, Mr. Axe,
before we go in.
This is the most recent
satellite image
we have of Copperfield.
Where is Westen's boat?
Oh,
it's right over here.
Which one?
Mm, that one right there --
the Mer-Mistress.
We can't afford
any mistakes on this.
Are you
absolutely positive?
Yeah, 100%.
He took me fishing on it.
I had a two-hour slug fest
with a barracuda.
Look -- you can see the mark
where it hit the boat.
When was this?
I don't know.
Couple weeks ago.
Stop the van! Now!
[ Tires screech ]
They're stopping.
Something's wrong.
They're not coming in.
What the hell
are you doing?
Trying to figure out
how that mark got there
on your fishing trip...
When this photo was taken
six months ago.
I gave you a chance.
I hope you remember that
when they lock you up.
It looks to me like something
was about to go down here.
I want to know what they were planning,
and I want to know now.
Get moving.
Oh, damn it.
Let's go.
Man: We got a device
on the left.
Man: We've got another device
on the right.
As well as one
at the base of the tower.
Mike, we got a problem --
they came in on foot,
and they found
all the charges.
We're gonna need
a new plan.
Looks like
directional charges
with remote detonators.
Go get a look
at those detonators.
Um, ma'am,
these charges are live.
Shouldn't we wait
for a bomb squad?
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Fuller.
I thought you were
a field operative.
Will someone who remembers
their job description
go get a look
at those detonators?
I need a range.
One. Follow me.
It's tough
to get good help.
Receiver's got
a 5-amp relay.
Range can't be
more than 350 meters.
That means
your friends are here.
This ends now.
How the hell did she know
what we were up to?
Riley must've
seen something,
or maybe
Sam didn't want to risk --
Guys, that couldn't
matter less right now.
Riley's got us pinned down.
We can't save Sam.
Only real question is,
what the hell do we do now?
Fuller:
Secure the perimeter.
The charges
have been defused.
S.R.T.'s
about 20 minutes out.
Okay, we've got them boxed in.
Set your team up to contain.
When the extra bodies
get here,
we move in
and we take Westen out.
Uh, excuse me.
Don't you mean take Westen in?
What happened to all this talk
about not hurting anybody?
Oh, this isn't a chase
anymore, Mr. Axe.
This is a standoff.
And any hope
for a peaceful resolution
flew out the window
once your friends set us up
for an ambush.
Get him in the van.
Well, they're in position,
but they're not moving in.
They got to be
waiting for backup.
Then it's all over.
Maybe not.
I think this storm drain
has sewer access.
We move now, we got a chance
of getting out of here.
And Sam?
Our best bet
is to get out of here
and try to find a way
to save him later.
Uh, maybe not.
If you're right
about the storm drain,
we might be able to save Sam --
right here, right now.
Mike,
you use that phone,
Riley's gonna hear
everything you say.
That's
what I'm counting on.
If I can convince her
she has no choice
but to move in right now,
she'll send her team after me,
and you and Fi
can make it back to the van.
We surprise Riley,
take back Sam. I like it.
Well, except for the part where
Michael uses himself as bait.
How are you gonna fight
her entire team?
You take down Riley,
I won't have to.
And if we can't get back to Riley in time?
If you're wrong?
Sometimes there's a price
to be paid, Fi,
no matter what you do.
Whatever we're gonna do,
we got to do it now.
Let's go.
I don't even want to think
about what's in this water.
This was your idea.
Let's just hope Mike's call
makes this worth it.
[ Cellphone rings ]
[ Cellphone beeps ]
Go for Sugar.
Sugar?
It's Michael Westen.
M-dub! I'm getting
suited and booted.
What's crackin',
super spy?
Our conversation is about to be
recorded by the authorities.
Uhhh...
so should we be talking?
It's gonna be fine. Just say
"yes" to every question I ask.
You got it?
What?
Not a good start, Sugar.
You have to say "yes."
Do you understand?
Uh, yes.
Once authorities
have flagged a cellphone,
they can access every relevant
piece of information
stored on the device.
Anderson:
Westen's phone is live.
Get me on that call.
Pinpoint his location now.
...less than 10 minutes
before they sweep.
Can you be here
in five?
Yes.
We're gonna need
to slow them down.
Do you have C4
and phosphoflares on board?
Yes.
And is the copter ready?
It'll be ready.
Tell the chopper pilot
we're not waiting for Sam.
We leave immediately.
All right.
[ Click ]
Yo.
You done
drinking that?
Who is Sugar?
This time,
I want the truth.
All right. Fine.
The truth is, he's a two-bit,
drug-dealing loser
who used to be
Mike's neighbor.
You've got quite the sense of humor,
don't you, Mr. Axe?
I do hope a life in prison
doesn't beat it out of you.
Got that bastard.
Exact location?
He's hiding in the second
structure from the back.
Ground level,
the entrance by the alleyway.
Reading should be accurate
within 2 meters.
Tell Fuller
to get his team ready.
We need to take Westen
before his backup gets here.
Good luck.
Let's go!
All right,
target is located
in the second structure
from the back.
He's at the ground-level
alley entrance.
We know he's armed.
Prepare for full breach.
And I want running updates
on the fly.
Okay, looks like
Mike pulled it off.
But she's still got one guy
for backup.
This won't be
as easy as we thought.
Fuller:
Target's location surrounded.
Preparing to breach.
Thwarting a breach attempt
typically involves
meeting force with force,
but if you want to buy yourself
time without hurting anyone,
you don't need firepower --
you need a diversion.
Without a blasting cap, C4 is
really just flammable clay.
Luckily, C4 doesn't
have to explode to be useful.
When your goal is to scare
people without killing them,
a flaming block of C4
stuffed with bullets
will do just fine.
Go!
Go, go, go, go!
[ Gunshots ]
Take cover! Take cover!
Shots fired.
Shots fired!
Riley:
Where's Westen?
Clearing the structure now.
Stand by.
Do not
let him get away.
Target has retreated
to second level.
Bradley,
do you have a shot?
Bradley: Negative.
Target is in the room.
Awaiting clean shot.
Damn it, Fuller!
What's taking so long?
Get your team in there.
Take him down now.
Whatever it takes,
I want it finished.
Do not hesitate
to take a shot.
Jesse: Fuller,
do not take the shot.
I repeat,
Agent Riley, confirm
your order to stand down.
Please confirm stand-down.
Jesse: Here you go.
You can have the honor
of calling the rest of your dogs off.
Confirmed.
All units, stand down.
Nicely done -- commanding,
but not trying too hard.
I hope you realize this is the
biggest mistake you've ever made.
Because it just became
my mission in life
to put you behind bars --
all of you.
Lady, you sure know
how to make a guy feel special.
A spy gets used to
having enemies.
It's just part of the job.
But you never expect
to be hated at home.
When your own country
thinks you're a traitor,
everything changes.
Allies become enemies,
and the people
who used to fight at your side
become the ones
who want to hurt you the most.
We'll take you down, Westen --
sooner or later.
So, this is what becomes
of the great Michael Westen.
Murderer, kidnapper,
traitor.
There's more to this, Riley,
than you know.
Card killed my brother,
he tried to kill --
To kill you, too?
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah, Mr. Axe told me
your sad story.
Unfortunately,
the evidence in the hotel room
tells a completely different
story.
And then there's the fact
that you ran.
I didn't know who was
coming through that door --
somebody who wanted
to know the truth
or somebody
working with Card.
What is the truth,
Mr. Westen?
[ Sighs ]
Card was running unauthorized
Ops around the globe,
and he wasn't
going to stop.
He used Anson.
He used Gray.
He was trying to use me.
Now, I didn't betray my country.
I was trying to protect it.
Whoa.
Now that I know
your side of the story,
I want you to know...
...I don't care.
You killed Tom Card --
one of our own.
And your friends
helped you escape.
You are now enemies
of the United States of America,
and it's my job
to make sure you face justice.
Should take about an hour
to make it back to the road.
[ Snap ]
Good luck
finding a phone.
I'll never stop,
Westen.
I'll hunt you down to the ends
of the earth if I have to.
Then I'll see you there.
Mom.
Gee--
Michael!
You scared the hell
out of me.
Sorry.
Card's dead.
I killed him.
Good.
He deserved it.
It isn't over, is it?
The CIA's after me.
Sam, Jesse, and Fi
helped me escape.
They're hunting us all.
They'll be
coming for you.
I already talked to them.
They came by yesterday.
It's all right.
I...pretended I was
some helpless old woman.
I served them lemonade
and pretended I was...
hard of hearing.
Anyway, eventually
they started talking
like I wasn't even there.
I wrote down
as much as I could remember.
Thanks, mom,
but they'll be coming back.
You still need
to leave.
Yeah,
I thought of that.
And then I came up
with a better idea.
I'm staying
right at home.
Ma.
Michael.
If all you guys
are going into hiding,
you're gonna need a lifeline
to the outside world.
You wanted to leave. I think
that's the best thing to do.
And now
you want to stay.
I was angry.
I still am.
There's a part of me
that will never get over
what happened to Nate.
If I don't forgive you,
I'll lose you, too.
I'm staying.
This is a fight
I can't win.
Well,
you have two choices.
You can give up now...
or you can
go down swinging.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==