Previously, on Continuum...
Change of plan.
Kiera, you're with Elena
in the chamber.
Kiera!
We both know
you're not what you seem.
And I got a pretty good feeling
that those answers are going
to reveal themselves
as long as someone is watching.
I am done
getting my hands dirty.
He who will not yield to reason,
will yield to persuasion.
What will you do
when that kind of persuasion
comes looking for you?
Because it will.
Go!
CPS freeze!
Primary target.
Thermite detonators.
Go.
Put your weapons down,
stay where you are.
(Gunfire)
Tango down.
Searching for target.
Target obtained.
Elena?
Tango down.
Mom?
Wanna trade?
Mommy?
Hand me the detonator.
(Gunshot)
Training simulation terminated.
Why the hesitation, Cameron?
We acquired the target, sir.
Not good enough.
That's your problem right there.
They have nothing
to do with this.
We had this,
and then you saw Sam.
I wasn't counting on my son
being used in a SIM like that.
CPS uses your psych eval
against you.
They know your weaknesses.
They think they do.
You didn't give me a chance
to take down Verta.
I saved you.
You were reckless.
You froze.
Thanks for the support.
That's what this is, partner,
whether you realize it or not.
Hey, hi sweetie!
You heard of Liber8?
Yeah.
Get out of the truck.
Get out!
Keep your hands up.
This isn't about you.
It's about big oil.
Tell the company you work for
to stop ripping off the people.
Get outta here.
Get outta here!
Let's go!
(Explosion)
(Laughing)
Go, go, go, go!
Another one, Ladner Trunk Road.
That's seven in four hours.
You've got to be kidding me.
Well, it looks like your pals
have found a new trajectory.
Catch me up.
Well, all the tankers
are owned by Ultra Gas,
they're targeted strikes
and all the drivers
were handed propaganda material.
That's smart.
Liber8 is trying to gain favour
with the public
by going after companies
they already hate.
They dress themselves up
like Robin Hood,
the public is buying into it.
Social media
is actually rooting for Liber8.
Kiera, are you there?
This is Cameron.
Yeah, I know that.
Uh-huh.
What is with the connection?
That's actually why I'm calling.
I've been experiencing
this interference issue.
Kiera, listen.
Do you remember the night
that you landed?
Unlikely I'd forget it.
Well, when you crashed through
I knew something was up
even before you called
for back-up.
How?
Random dada suddenly spiked up
on my com-channel.
First, I thought it was static
or interference,
but now I know it came from you.
Random data, what are
you talking about, Alec?
Let's call your arrival
Hiroshima.
You get that?
We do have history
in the future, you know.
Good.
Then you know what Nagasaki is.
The second bomb to hit Japan.
You had another data spike.
Boom.
Are you sure?
Sure as I can be.
Someone else's future tech
just tried to access my network.
Similar to mine?
Another time traveller is online.
You've got company.
2077.
My time.
My city.
My family.
When terrorists killed
thousands of innocents,
they were condemned to die.
They had other plans.
A time travel device
sent us all back 65 years.
I want to get home,
but I can't be sure
what I will return to
if history is changed.
Their plan?
To corrupt and control
the present
In order to win the future.
What they didn't plan on,
was me.
Are you positive it originated
from this location?
49.175 North, 122.586 West.
It's as close as I can get.
I've got it,
looks like a garage sale.
You look a little lost.
Ah, well, 49 degrees North
and 122 West,
so no, not lost.
Okay, now I'm lost.
Oh, uh, Kiera Cameron.
Vancouver PD.
Have you seen anyone around here
this morning unusual,
a little odd, maybe?
Uh, besides me?
The person that I'm looking for
might have been wearing
a very distinctive suit.
Copper... reflective...
Most of this stuff is my mom's,
but I do remember
something like that.
Or not.
Or I did, but I sold it.
I wish I could be more helpful.
It's imperative
that I find that suit.
Could I speak with your mother?
I mean, you said this stuff
was hers.
I don't know about that.
It may be significant
to the investigation.
If you give me your number,
I'll see.
And that is not just an excuse
to get your number.
People need excuses?
With good-looking lady cops?
Usually.
You might be right.
Might be?
The data spike:
It may have come
from another suit like mine.
I knew it.
Thanks!
Your welcome.
Sorry...
Everything okay?
Yep.
You have to track that spike.
Your timing sucks.
Alec, I need you on this.
I'm barely operational
at my palatial digs,
my mobile unit is a joke...
Okay, so go home.
I hacked into the Aldergrove
weather radar
and paired it with a lighter
network that I'm not supposed
to know about.
It's a weird combo,
but it might work out
if it happens again.
You built a time travel app.
If you have to call it that.
Wait, the traveller's already here
so...
I have to go.
What?
If it happens again,
I'll let you know, okay?
Alec?
I'm Emily.
Meet to please you.
Sorry.
Alec.
Hi.
Nice to meet you.
I've seen you here before.
I come here a lot.
Travis, oh Travis.
Now you are going after
gas stations.
You know once people have
to start lining up for fuel,
they are going to be pissed
at you.
Yeah, he's using the attacks
to spread Kagame's message.
That's too smart for Travis.
You always underestimated him.
Clearly you did as well.
How bad was it?
Well, they hit ten
fuel transports in the mainland
all with the same message:
Big oil is enslaving the people,
price gouging,
raping the earth, etcetera.
Tapping into the public's growing
sense of conspiracy.
Yep.
For terrorists,
they sure have a flair for PR.
Think Sonya's behind this?
The violence is more
Travis's domain.
Maybe they got back together?
I think it's safe to say
they're still on the outs.
Well, whoever's behind this,
they've sure got
the public's attention.
Ah, section six calling?
Actually, no.
You know, it's ok, I'm dating other
police departments, too.
Kiera Cameron.
Hi.
Great.
I'll meet you there.
Let me guess: Going somewhere?
Gotta see a guy about a suit.
Um, it feels weird.
Well, get out here and show me.
I could just use my med uniform,
And maybe throw a tux jacket over
it?
Come on!
That's fantastic!
It's a dead ringer for
Captain Armstrong's suit!
It's a bit tight.
We call that form-fitting.
Yeah. Okay.
It is Patrick's big day,
what if he goes as Armstrong?
Patrick told me he's going
to be General Carter.
He can't resist those medals.
Best five bucks I ever spent! Hoo!
I don't know.
I think maybe Junior Medical
Officer Keaton,
that's more my speed.
Be the hero, baby.
You're mine.
And if you can't trust
your second Lieutenant Rosara,
then who can you trust?
I need to know you have my back,
Rosara.
You know I do, Captain, and
when you're ready for more...
Save it for the debrief...
How long has your mother suffered
from Alzheimer's?
Six years.
The doctor says she's done pretty
well, considering.
She's still there, you know.
But sometimes I'm her son,
other times...
But this is palliative care.
She's in liver failure now.
That's why we're here.
I really appreciate you
letting me come visit.
Hopefully it's a good night.
She really perked up
when I mentioned
you were looking for this suit.
Hi Mom, I brought that
police officer we talked about.
Hi, Mrs. Stanton.
How are you feeling today?
Partner!
Yeah.
You look just the same, Kiera.
Elena?
What took you so long?
In the first months I looked for
anyone else from the execution chamber
that might have come through
with me but...
no one.
No one.
When did you get here?
1975.
You look like everybody else,
you sound like everybody else,
but you're a freak.
A time traveller?
No one understands,
who can you tell?
But you must have, I mean,
you got married...
I never told.
I wanted to be normal.
And my husband, he gave me that
and so much more.
What about your husband, Kiera,
and Sam?
Didn't they come with you?
Elena, when you came through,
you were wearing your CPS uniform,
right?
Yes.
Yes, so...
I took it out kayaking, you know?
I've loved that since I was a kid.
I went out this morning.
You alright, mom?
Hmm.
He swore
he was going to be Mederic.
(Cheering and Applause)
Captain?
Oh, at ease General.
I think I out-rank you.
You may be in charge
of this wedding, General,
but I booked the restaurant.
Glad you're here.
Dude, it's your big day!
Two cutest assassins in the room.
Yeah. You guys um...
Oh, well, you know...
every time she comes over,
I'm still surprised.
Rex, the girl loves you.
Right, yeah, a college drop out.
The guy who runs
a dry-cleaning store.
I don't think so.
She sees the man.
I'm glad she does.
Rex!
Ah!
I'm on fire!
Rex!
Get some water!
Aaah!
Come on!
You alright?
Yeah!
I am!
I'm fine.
Oh, you're so stupid!
(Laughs)
What's the problem?
I'm not sure
and that's what worries me.
She was always mysterious
about her background.
Said her life really started
when she met my dad.
That's sweet.
How do you know her?
Our mothers were friends.
Elena helped out my mother
more times than I can count.
But she recognized you.
They probably kept in touch.
So, she got married,
had a family...
Four kids.
Once we were all in school,
so was she.
She studied urban planning,
then went to work for the city.
He's boasting about me.
Because you deserve it.
I deserve chocolate.
I'm old, and I'm cranky,
and I want chocolate.
I'm on it, mom.
My eldest.
The younger ones are all married
with kids. Not Dan.
Do you have it on?
Almost always.
Does it make you feel safe?
Elena, Alec Sadler is here.
He's a teenage boy.
You're shitting me.
We connected
the night I came through.
Suddenly, he was just...
in my head.
All the time you were here,
you never heard anything?
I turned my CMR off years ago,
felt like it was always looking
for voices that weren't there.
It drained me.
I could have never made it through
four kids
with that thing turned on.
What about your suit?
I put it away in a box somewhere.
I'm sorry.
You couldn't have known.
We hit all five targets.
Good.
Make sure they're in and out
in 10 minutes
before the cops can react.
Hey, we were professionals
before you bought the franchise.
I...
I still think we should have it
looked at.
It's fine, I'm fine.
No, it's weird.
What kind of material doesn't burn?
There are all kinds of flame
retardant material out there.
I guess you'd know.
Dry-cleaning god that I am?
That's not what I meant.
(grunts)
Hey!
I'm calling the cops.
Get rid of this guy.
Go!
I hate heroes.
You better get going, hero.
Rex!
Oh my god!
Oh, Rexy!
Oh you're such a bad dog!
(Gunshots)
(Screams)
Whoa! Go closer!
Get an ambulance!
I want that.
And get me those plates.
Say please.
What's it mean?
Remember, I found a way
to track the Protector
but she shut us down...
That code disruption.
At first I thought it was Cameron
but these data packets
come from a different source.
Someone else?
Kagame came through weeks after us.
This could be someone else
from the execution chamber.
Find them.
Travis is choosing
his targets well.
It's like you two never broke up.
I don't condone the violence.
But the message doesn't suck.
It's like he's trying to send you
little love notes.
I doubt that.
You're really good to her.
She deserves it.
She's always been there for me.
You know?
The suit is active again.
I've got coordinates.
Have a good night.
Goodnight.
Those guys were off their meds.
It was chaos in here!
Then, the guy walks in,
takes two shots to the chest,
and walks away.
The place would have blown up
if he wasn't here.
He saved my life!
Was he wearing something
that resembled a uniform?
Form-fitting, shiny?
I don't know about that,
but he sparked
like an electrical storm
when that asshole shot him.
Hey, hey, hey,
is he that superhero
that's taking down Liber8?
Was it, Miss Cameron?
Someone wearing a super suit?
Did you ever hear
of anything like that?
Look at this ass clown.
You can clearly see
his Syndicate tattoo
right there on his arm.
I think I liked Travis more
when anarchy was his end goal.
He could really score some points
with this endeavour.
Looks like Sonya
might be rubbing off on him.
He's still got his wild side:
Beatings, weapons...
There's our hero.
Excuse me.
I thought you said
there was only one event.
I Missed one.
You gotta get your head
in the game, Alec.
You mean your game?
Alec, track down the suit.
Alec, find the bad guys.
You know how powerful
these suits are.
I don't need you to tell me
about something I invented.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
Is there any way
we could track the suit
If the owner wasn't wearing it?
Well, the suit has certain
latent functions on its own.
Something called
a positional contact relay.
It's basically
like a homing beacon.
It'll pin the user's CMR
and then you can triangulate
the suit's location.
What if it's out of power?
That's doubtful, I mean these suits
can draw a charge
from any power source
they come in contact with.
Even kinetic energy
can be absorbed.
Can we turn it on
with some sort of remote?
Let me guess:
Someone's standing
right beside you?
Oh crap.
Exactly.
So?
Well, if you can find
the actual traveller,
and get them to turn on their CMR,
then we could link it to the suit
and send a steady signal.
Any idea how to find them?
I'll call you back.
Gotta go visit a sick friend.
(cell phone buzzing)
(chuckles)
Your garage sale guy did not know
what he was selling.
Maybe he did.
You gonna give me
one of your Rosara speeches?
Captain, save the jokes
for the epilogue?
This is not a TV show.
This is your life.
You were shot!
And now you think
you're invulnerable
because of that stupid costume!
You saw what happened.
The wedding?
I should have been burned!
When I put the thing on,
something happens,
something bigger than me,
I saved that guy's life!
What about yours?
Okay, look.
It was a fluke.
I'll get rid of it.
Okay.
It just feels like
the world's gone crazy.
Make sure you don't.
What do you want?
Well, one shouldn't
have to drive alone
to see a sick friend.
Look.
We have mutual interests:
Stopping Liber8, restoring order...
Why don't we just help each other?
I don't think our methods
are compatible.
I'm sure you could talk
to your Mr. Escher
and tell him know
that I'm one of the good guys, no?
Ah, so it's Escher you really want.
Well, he's the one pulling
your strings, isn't he?
You seem to think so.
Tell you what, let's drive over
to Piron Corps right now,
we can all sit around
and talk about Section 6?
Maybe after I visit my sick friend.
You're connected
to these terrorists.
Maybe just in the way
that a good agent
becomes close
to whoever he or she is tracking.
But, until you get truthful
with me,
we're gonna be spending
a lot of time together.
Hmm.
Our first date.
It's not starting well.
Well, next time I'll bring flowers.
Come on.
Beth!
Oh Beth, you brought your husband.
Yes I did!
He really wanted to say hi.
Didn't you, honey?
It's so good to see you,
you look well.
Are you still a marine biologist,
Ben?
I remember the dolphins.
So pink.
Mmm hmm, in China
well they're so memorable.
I'll be outside.
Excuse me.
You are sharp as a tack.
Who's the asshole?
Federal agent.
He thinks I'm special.
He's right.
Listen, partner.
I think Liber8
knows about your suit.
I can't let them
get their hands on it,
and I need you to help me find it.
I don't know what I can do
from this bed.
Can you turn on your CMR?
If you can connect with the suit,
Alec can trace it,
it's like a homing beacon.
Turn it on...
it didn't feel good.
I know it makes you nervous,
but when we were together
during the wars,
I always felt safer
with you as my partner.
It's been too long.
You were always the strong one.
Not anymore.
It scares me.
I know.
But I'm right here with you.
Alright.
Do it.
Go ahead, Alec.
You sure?
Yeah.
What about your new boyfriend?
I can handle him.
Okay, here goes.
I'm cycling all other CMRs.
Elena?
I forgot how it feels.
It's so powerful.
When I find the suit,
I'll switch it off.
There it is, I've got it.
I'll get an address.
Sonya, it's live again.
You do have a partner.
Carlos is my partner.
He's a good cop.
I'll be the judge of that,
I want to meet him.
I'll see what I can do.
You should go.
You ready to lay down some cover?
Deal me in.
Yes, everyone.
Where is she?
Escher?
You're looking for Escher,
the mystery man?
You don't know anything.
I'm here, she's not.
You wanna roll the dice?
Come out, hero.
Strip down now,
I'll go easier on you.
(fighting grunts)
Pretty head, shame to detach it.
(Gunshots)
Are you hurt?
Well, you shot me!
Yes, but you're not hurt.
Perfect.
That suit won't protect you
forever.
Drop the gun.
This again.
You're not gonna shoot me.
You'd have already
pulled that trigger.
You've been busy.
Take off the suit, you might live!
You don't need that uniform.
Need.
Want.
Semantics.
(fighting grunts)
(Gunshots)
(grunts)
Aaah!
Put it down,
and you get to walk away.
Is that what you told Travis
before you shot him?
You're a lot smarter
than I gave you credit for, Garza.
It's not too late to reconsider.
You made my bed,
I like lying in it.
I don't want to hurt you.
(Gunshots)
Shit!
(fighting grunts)
Let's move!
(Gunshots)
We gotta go!
Dammit!
Civilian down, I need an ambulance.
Suspect is heading East
from 95 Parker.
You've got one, too?
Shh, it's okay.
It's gonna be okay.
Rest.
We're getting you help.
I thought it would make me a hero.
You don't need a suit for that.
Okay, okay, okay,
alright, okay, okay, okay...
Okay, I'm just going to open the...
okay.
(crying)
Rex, oh... you okay?
Ma'am.
Agent Gardner.
Where's the suit?
Was he wearing a suit?
Go away!
Was he wearing the suit?!
Stop!
Don't shout at her.
Save it for the debrief.
Here you go.
You're bringing this here?
Is this some sort of elaborate
attempt to get rid of me?
I deactivated it,
there's no signal.
I knew you'd wanna play with it.
Plus, I don't think this place
is on Liber8's radar,
so you should be safe.
This place is only temporary.
How temporary?
I don't know, we'll see.
Look, I kinda have some stuff
to do.
Like what?
Alright...
You have a life.
Trying to.
Alec!
Hey!
Hey, sorry I'm late.
No, I just got here myself.
What?
You lost a bet, right?
You forgot to save a country
from a burgeoning debt crisis
and this was your punishment?
To date below your level?
Right, because smart and funny
is such a step down.
Do I really seem like I'd date
a jock kind of girl to you?
I don't know, I'm just thinking
about the fact
you called me smart and funny.
Oh, but there's plenty of time
for you
to disabuse me of that notion.
Well, I'll give it my best shot.
I guess you drink coffee?
Um, yes...
What kind of coffee?
Are you sure this is okay?
Yeah, just a heads up,
she's a little scattered,
she might say some things
that don't make sense
but she insisted on meeting you.
I guess she wants to check you out.
Sounds like a good friend.
She's more than a friend.
Thanks for the support.
That's what partners do.
Hi.
It's okay.
Dan, this is Detective Fonnegra.
Nice to meet you.
Likewise.
We managed to get
most of the family here,
she knew us all.
Remembered everything.
Never checked out,
not even for a second.
She came back
for most of the night.
But she wasn't even that sick?
The doctors said
that kind of resurgence
isn't unusual just before death.
I'm so sorry.
Don't be.
We had a beautiful goodbye.
You were a tonic for her.
I don't know if that's true.
She said you should have this.
She must have read it
a dozen times.
Only Connect.
It's a little sermon, really,
about ending isolation.
She wanted you to know
that she loved her life,
and you can too.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Sure you don't want to go
out there with them?
Who would have imagined,
he has such a beautiful family.
Am I ever
going to meet your family?
You have no idea
how much I would love that.
Have you seen your son lately?
Oh yeah, I see him all the time.