Previously on Dominion...
Don't remove it.
I'll bleed to death.
Then what am I supposed to do?
You're leaving.
You and Bixby almost died because
that thing came after me.
If anything ever happened to you,
I couldn't live with myself.
So, what, this is goodbye?
That's it.
For now.
Get a line.
Hang in there, Michael.
Hang in there.
He's losing too much blood.
He's gonna be okay.
Get him out of here.
Come on.
I'm right here, Michael.
Let's go.
I'm right here!
Wait out here.
Lannon!
Yeah.
You're under arrest.
What? What for?
Desertion of duty. No, I gotta be here.
I gotta be here.
No, no... Michael...
Michael!
Front. GUARD: Walk in
through the gates.
Strip.
Forward.
Strip! GUARD: Those in the
line, keep your eyes forward.
No!
Scan him.
Put it down.
Strip. I said strip!
Strip or you go
into the hole.
Get him out of here.
Next.
Strip.
What you looking at?
Lannon. AWOL.
Theft of government
property.
You got something
against Vega?
You'll speak when spoken to.
Speak!
And I'm speaking to you.
Throw this piece of shit
in solitary.
Get him out of here.
You're alive.
It appears so.
We couldn't stop the bleeding,
so I brought you here.
The blade
is Empyrean steel.
It should have
killed me.
Where is it?
I don't know.
I never saw it.
We must find that blade.
I need to see Alex.
You need to rest.
IthoughtPdlostyou.
Would that be
such a bad thing?
Michael.
You deserve better,
Becca.
You shouldn't have to live
a life cloaked in secrecy.
There are good men in Vega.
Men you could have
a normal life with.
I don't want a good man.
I want a great one.
A man who I love.
What makes you think
I'm capable of love?
I know you are.
You must really like her.
Haven't you learned
your lesson yet?
Relax.
I was only trying
to scare her.
No doubt you would have
been spotted on radar.
Soldiers will be en route.
Ooh.
You do like her.
Uriel, enough!
Why are you here?
You've been keeping something
from the rest of us.
What might that be?
Don't play dumb!
You've found the Chosen One.
We need to talk,
little brother.
Meet me up north.
Bixby?
Hi.
They told me you were
finally out of surgery,
so I brought you a friend
to keep you company.
Cute, huh?
Yeah.
He was here.
Who was here?
The Chosen One.
When?
Last night
he brought in Michael.
He was here
in the infirmary?
Was he all right?
Soldiers took him
in handcuffs.
They have no idea
he's the Chosen One.
Hi. Excuse me.
Okay.
Um, so, I have to go now
but I am gonna come back
and I'm gonna check on you.
You're gonna feel so much
better realsoon,okay?
He's gonna look after you. Okay.
You're all set,
Senator Frost.
Thank you.
May the Savior bless you.
We have a long agenda.
Let's begin
with Senator Blake's proposal
for increased
defense spending.
Actually, General,
all this time,
money, and energy
might be put
to better use
if the Chosen One would simply reveal himself.
Might make our
defense budget obsolete.
Well, yes, and if the tooth fairy
should visit our pillows tonight,
that would solve our budget issues, too.
Moving on.
I'd rather not.
We're in a crisis, Frost.
Please.
Rumor has it that the child
is here in Vega.
Our time of waiting
may well be over.
Rumors and lies.
Back to business.
Yes.
Senator Frost is right.
The Chosen One is here.
It's me.
Your hope is inspirational,
as always, Senator.
Let's keep our
prayers in our hearts
and move on with the
business of running Vega.
Hear, hear.
Agreed.
I cede the floor.
You ordered Furiad to kill me.
Oh, I've wanted to.
Even dreamed
about it.
But good old Furiad
acted on his own.
So hard to control
that temper of his.
It's getting increasingly
hard to control mine.
Boys, calm down.
Take a deep breath.
It's time for a talk,
not a fight.
You should know better than
to stick us in the same room.
First off, you kill
all the humans you want,
but when it comes to Michael,
you don't touch him.
I told you,
I had nothing to do
with the attack.
Furiad's your soldier, and he
almost killed our brother.
Although
I don't blame him.
How could you keep the
child a secret from us?
An odd question
coming from the sister
who won't tell us where she's
been for the last 25 years.
Father's markings were
meant for all of us.
Not just you. I had to
protect him from Gabriel.
Didn't Father teach us
to share our toys?
Quiet, Gabriel. You idiots
have fought a thousand times,
but never like this.
You've got to end it.
You could end it.
Is that why you're gracing us
with your presence, Uriel?
You've finally chosen a side.
Uriel, you love mankind as much as I do.
So protect them.
I'm here to remind you
we're all we've got left.
That's why I never
choose sides.
I love you both.
Even Michael?
Who's spent the last two
decades soaking his steel
in the blood
of angels?
Don't pretend you care
about the eight-balls.
You use them
as cannon fodder.
What's that
supposed to mean?
Our brother's
learned a new trick.
He can possess
the eight-balls.
That's disgusting.
It's no different than what
Michael does with the child.
I've never forced him
to do anything.
But you will.
Does the child know
about your colorful past?
Is that a threat?
I'm taking the high road.
Waiting for the child to find his true
nature, and come to me on his own.
Like he's destined to do.
Stay away from him,
Gabriel.
Enjoy some quality time
with the boy while you can.
Lannon!
You got a visitor.
What?
You can leave us now.
Lady Riesen,
you have no idea what
this man is capable of.
I'm okay. Close it up.
Claire...
What did they do to you,
Alex?
Nothing I didn't deserve.
I had to keep
the tattoos hidden.
I wouldn't have even known you
were here if it wasn't for Bixby.
How is she?
She's okay.
And Michael?
Yeah, he's fine.
Listen, Alex, I'm
gonna speak to my dad
and I'm gonna get you
out of here, okay?
No. No.
It's safer if I'm in here.
People around me
get hurt.
You, Bix, Michael...
I don't wanna find out
who's next.
So when Bixby asks
to see you, what...
What do you want me
to say to her?
You tell her to always listen
to her Aunt Claire.
And you tell her I miss her.
Why don't you just
write her a letter, Alex?
You know,
like your dad did for you.
That was different.
H ow?
Release him.
Yes, ma'am.
Has my company really
been that unpleasant?
No, not at all.
Then stop watching
for your shift change
and come join me
for a drink.
He keeps the good stuff
at the back.
You're not like other
soldiers, are you, Sergeant?
No. I'm not. I have
a functioning brain, ma'am.
Yes, but...
There's something else.
Something deep inside.
I'm intuitive.
Makes me
a shrewd negotiator.
I know when someone's
hiding something, and
you, my dear,
are guilty as charged.
All right.
You really wanna know?
I'm scared of heights.
Hmm.
I understand
if you don't want to share.
I'm from Helena,
after all.
Happy drinking.
Fingers crossed Whele doesn't
feed you to his lions.
You know, when I
eventually return home,
I'll need someone
at my side
to protect my interests.
Why would I ever
leave Vega?
Why would you ever stay?
Here you go, sweetie.
EHJOV- Thank You-
Alex!
Bix. Hey.
Easy,easy,
you'll pop your stitches.
What flavor
did they stick you with?
Red. You know there
used to be more colors.
What did they
taste like?
Red.
It's not your fault.
Yeah, it is.
It is my fault.
Here. I saved an extra.
You take it.
All right.
They don't make it
how they used to.
Hey-
You know, Frost has been begging to show
off this irrigation system for weeks.
Where's the rest
of the Senate?
It's time the three of
us had a private conversation.
Oh, this isn't about more
silly rumors, is it?
You know I'd never been
a religious man.
Never believed
in anything
I couldn't see
with my own eyes.
Then, one day, a being came down from
the sky, with wings on his back,
came to our defense,
protected our city.
Told us
he'd saved a baby,
and that baby would
one day save us all.
Thathope is what got
us through the war.
What gets me
through every day.
What gives so many people in
this city something to live for.
I'm sorry
to disappoint you, Thomas,
but we're
the only ones here.
Don't lie to me, Edward.
I know that the Chosen One's
here and that you're hiding him.
Because you know that once the
people have their savior,
your power means nothing.
Oh, Frost, come on.
Haven't we been through this?
Don't patronize me, David.
A little girl in the
infirmary told his daughter
that the Chosen One
had been arrested.
And Claire Riesen seemed to
know exactly who he was.
What's that in your hand?
This is a wireless
control unit.
It has a biometric lock that
responds only to my thumbprint.
Covers the entire tower.
Icanlock all the doors.
Open the irrigation tanks...
...all of them.
600,000 gallons
of water,
rushing into the tower
all at once.
We'll drown.
All of the crops
will be destroyed.
And the people
of Vega will starve.
What is it you want?
I want to meet the Chosen One.
Wait, she asked you
to go back to Helena?
No, not in so many words.
Word of advice. Run.
Ethan.
The woman had
a body in a box
delivered to
her doorstep.
Don't worry about me.
Yeah, I'm sure that's what
the woman in the box said.
You know what I think?
I think a strong, regal
woman like Madam Arika,
I think she
threatens you, huh?
I think you're right.
Besides, what good am I
really doing here anyways?
Noma, you've saved
my ass at least once.
Lannon, where
you been, bro?
Been looking
all over for you.
I took a drive.
Needed to clear my head.
I get it.
Uh, I don't.
What's going
on,guys?
It's nothing.
You go outside
the walls,
disappear for an entire
day to clear your head
and you're all "I get it"? Guys,
come on, that's not nothing.
Ethan, I've been seeing
Claire Riesen.
As in the same Claire Riesen
whose father orders executions?
All right, let's saddle up,
hostage situation at the
agri-tower in progress.
Prep for a raid.
We're up in five.
What's going on, Lieutenant? Our
entire food supply is at risk
of being destroyed as well as the lives
of the General and Consul Whele.
Look alive, troops!
Listen, we can't simply walk
in there and start shooting.
We need an executive
order from Riesen.
Well, he's not here.
The message Frost
sent us made it clear
that all security systems in the
agri-tower have been placed on lockdown.
So call in the engineer
and unlock them.
Frost is
that engineer.
Our grains are in that tower.
The food supply is at risk.
We have no choice but to use force.
Don't you see that?
Becca, I got your message.
Is my father okay?
He's fine, Claire.
By the power vested in
me as second consul,
I appoint you Lady of
the City pro tern.
Oh!
Please take
a seat.
She does not havethe
authority at all.
So what are we doing?
What's our response?
The Corps are in a holding
pattern, awaiting our
decision to enter
and liberate the hostages.
What are Senator
Frost's demands?
He's going to
flood the tower
unless he's given an audience
with the Chosen One.
What?
Let's vote on
sending the Corps in.
Wait, uh, before we vote, I'd like a
moment to confer with my consuls.
Frost, if you know me at all,
you know the food supply for
this city is not negotiable.
Oh, I do know you.
I know both of you
I can't allow
a few politicians
to control the destiny
of the entire human race
just because they feel their
grip on power is threatened.
Why would we be
threatened by a myth?
Why would Gabriel attack
Vega after 10 years of peace?
Look I... I know what it's like
to believe something so strongly
that you're blinded, Thomas.
It blinds you to the simple fact that
your faith is nothing but a crutch.
It's a Band-Aid
for your own fears.
Belief in something
doesn't make it real.
Nor will it save you.
My faith is made of stronger stuff
than dime-store televangelism, David.
I know that he will
save the human race.
And that he will lead us
against these monsters.
These monsters
you're talking about.
They haunt my dreams
to this day.
I... I try to make sense of it,
but for the life of me I can't.
But after all my long nights,
after all my heartache,
you know what
I came to realize?
The Chosen One? It's us.
It's the people of Vega.
That's what's gonna save us.
I wish that were true.
You have 30 minutes
to bring him to me.
You know how much
I respect you, but stalling
any longer is gonna get
both our fathers killed.
William, raiding the tower will scare
Frost into releasing the water.
The only alternative is to
give him what he wants.
Yes. Would that be
such a bad thing?
I think the people of Vega deserve
to know he's finally arrived.
Claire, I share your faith, I do, but
Alex's safety's far more important.
What if things go sideways
and Frost pulls the trigger?
He'll kill both our fathers and the
Chosen One in the process. What then?
Right now, we need to
vote on sending in the Corps.
It's our only option. They
can be there in 15 minutes.
Fine. Fine.
I give you permission to cast
my vote with yours.
Excuse me.
Claire! Where
are you going?
We have to vote.
It's always been like this
with the two of you,
fighting over a world that was
never even created for us.
How could Father just
desert us like this?
Uriel, be patient.
He will return.
How do you know? I know.
I miss him.
Sister.
Train your chosen one.
Unlock the markings and help
him fulfill his destiny
and I promise,
you won't face Gabriel alone.
You'll have my sword.
Thank you.
Don't thank me.
They were once Father's
greatest creation.
Odds are the Senate is authorizing
an armed assault as we speak.
What? Risk both of us
and the tomatoes?
Come on, Edward. You know Thorn
needs the kids to pass that vote,
and we both know they
are not up to the task.
It's all because of that V-1 runt
your daughter took under her wing.
I should've dealt with her
when I dealt with those techs.
Look,
Thomas,
despite all the unkind things
I've said about you
behind closed doors,
in front of them as well.
Up until this afternoon,
I've always known you
to be a reasonable man.
Look what you're doing here.
Come on. Let's be reasonable.
Open the doors.
I am tired
of being reasonable, David.
Go!Go!Go!
We have confirmation. Consul Whele is down.
Prepare to move.
I don't get it. Last time
I was on Frost's detail,
the guy spent all his
free time baking.
I gotta say, his butterscotch brownies?
Pretty damn good.
This is a hostage situation.
Frost must want something.
What aren't
they telling us?
Yeah, apparently the Senator
demanded to see the Chosen One.
What?
Yeah, crazy, huh?
The guy's totally lost it.
Hey, cheer up, man.
You know we don't get to
do shit like this anymore.
Looks like it
missed the artery.
You're gonna live.
Sorry to disappoint you.
I'm the one who
just got shot.
How come you look like
you're gonna drop dead?
It's your heart, huh?
My heart is fine.
What are you taking for it? Pills.
For what they're damn worth.
What kind of pills?
If I could pronounce the name, don't you
think I would've damn well said it?
You know,
between the two of us
we've probably beaten
death a hundred times.
Resisted
the possessions.
Fought off how many
black-eyed beasts?
And now
it will probably come to
an end at the hands of
Thomas Frost.
Crazy son of a bitch.
I wish I could say
he was crazy.
Mack, Lannon, Banks,
take forward position.
Gomez, Rogers, O'Neill, take flank.
Yes, sir.
You're authorized
to terminate the target.
Sir, what about
collateral damage, sir?
The crops are our priority.
Wait.
Lieutenant. You
heard your order.
Lieutenant? Lieutenant,
let me go in.
Get the hell back in line
before I kick your ass.
He has
my approval.
Sergeant Lannon
can negotiate.
Miss Riesen, with all respect, I
have the orders from the Senate.
I'm acting Lady of the City.
This is an executive order.
You and your negotiator
have five minutes.
All points, hold position.
They're getting Lannon to do the talking?
I'm the talker.
Senator Frost, we are
complying with your request.
Please back away
from the door.
Only one person
comes in. Only one man.
I'm the one you want to see.
I'm the Chosen One.
Is this some
kind of joke?
I'm afraid
not, sir.
Please, let the General
and the Consul go
and we'll talk.
You're a V-2.
I've seen you
guarding House Riesen.
What did they do,
paint those things on you?
What the hell do you
take me for, Edward?
Just take
it easy, Frost.
Come on, Frost,
this is what you wanted.
Sir, please. Please.
I swear. I'm the one.
I'm the baby Michael saved.
Prove it.
She died for you.
What did you say?
Yes, she did.
My daughter, Abby.
She died for me.
It was the first night
of the war.
And because of Abby,
I was able to survive.
Please, Senator,
turn off the water.
You can change things.
Now, we are gonna go outside
and let the people know that
things are gonna be different now.
We will. We'll tell everyone.
We'll tell them together.
Please, just... turn it off.
Thank you, Savior.
Thank you.
What did you do that for?
Put your shirt on.
These should help with the pain. But
you've got to stay off your feet.
Thank you.
You shouldn't
be drinking.
And you shouldn't have sent
the Corps into the agri-tower
a remarkably poor
decision, even for you.
I did what's
best for the city.
No, Claire did that by sending in the only
man capable of defusing the situation.
You, you let
your faith interfere.
You put the life of your
precious Chosen One
before the city,
before your own father.
Alex Lannon? He's the one
destined to save mankind,
not two old men
past their prime.
Have fun.
Praise the Mother of All.
David, you could
have been killed.
Well, forgive me if I'm
not really in the mood.
You're burning up.
There's a Helenic remedy
that'll take the fever down.
I'll have a guard
fetch the ingredients.
I'll stick to bourbon.
Wow, this is the last place
I thought I'd find you.
Twenty years,
Frost served Vega.
One of the city's founding fathers, and
now he'll be remembered as a madman.
Mmm-mmm,
my father has become an
expert at rewriting history.
Frost is gonna get
a state funeral.
He's gonna be
remembered as a hero.
A hero who saved the agri-towers
from an accidental flood
at the cost of his
own life.
He didn't die for nothing.
You came forward, Alex. Ihadto.
People's lives
were at stake.
But when I
was in there,
these words came to me
through my markings.
Those words made
Frost believe in me.
Maybe Frost was right.
Maybe the people do
deserve to know about you.
I don't know
what I'm doing, Claire.
I got lucky this time,
but I...
I don't know what
any of this means.
So maybe it's time you
start figuring it out.
lﬂleave
youtoit
Where have
you been?
Family
emergency.
Yeah, I had an emergency of my own.
I could have used your help.
Alex, I can help you.
I can teach you,
but only if
you're willing.
I want to learn
about everything.
What do
you want?
I don't want
to fight.
That was never what I
wanted with any of this.
I thought I could fix things
between you and Michael.
But I'm afraid Michael's
lost his way.
I've been telling you
that for centuries.
Well, now that
the Chosen One's here,
I can't just sit back
and do nothing.
You say you can sway him,
that he's fated to you,
and not our brother.
As Father wanted it.
Then prove it to me.
Help him help the humans
to their own destruction.
And I promise, you won't
face Michael alone.
You will have my sword.
Thank you, sister.
You won't
feel a thing.