I'll kill you!
Ko!
She left herself wide open.
I'm not nice enough to overlook that.
Her attack didn't hit him...
No, she sent a little aura with that swing.
Feitan's idea to use Ko backfired.
After focusing his aura into one point,
he didn't expect to deal no damage.
The miscalculation left him a second
late guarding with his Nen.
In other words, he was basically defenseless.
A puny Emitter attack could
have dealt serious damage.
She knows how to use her aura.
She has good reason to call herself Queen.
This body has no weaknesses!
Shouldn't we help him?
Huh? Why?
This is a race...
If he loses, the next person gets to try.
Who's up next?
We use order of arrival.
That's me, then.
Wait...
We both arrived at the same time.
Fool, I was waiting until you finished your fight.
Now, now... We'll flip a coin to decide.
S-Something's...
wrong with them!
Heads.
Then if Feitan's defeated, I go next.