Previously on Jericho...
Jake Green!
How you doing, man?
Wait a minute.
--Where the hell you been?
--Around.
Jake, no one's been around for five years.
Seriously, where have you been?
Hey, brother.
What you put this family through...
--Johnston, for God's sake.
--Now, he could have been...
We could spend a week talking
about what I could have been, all right?
--I've apologized, but I need my
money to make a clean start.
--It's not your money.
It's your grandfather's money.
--Stay one more day.
--I've got to get back to San Diego by tomorrow.
All right, it looks like the explosion came
from the west, maybe Denver.
Did something happen?
Are we under attack?
Hi, Dale. Sorry I didn't call
sooner, angel, but we...
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
Sheriff? Robert Hawkins.
I am so sorry.
--I didn't know your mother was in Denver.
--She wasn't in Denver.
She was in Atlanta.
Oh, my God!
Look, I know you're telling people
it was an accident
but if it was an attack, Sheriff
and there's chaos out there,
you might not want the wrong people knowing
that Jericho is still here.
It's the wrong bus!
Riley!
Get April.
We'll meet you at the medical center.
There's an empty prison bus out there.
--What's your name?
--Heather.
Nice to meet you, Jake.
--It's a great thing you did t there tonight.
--Thanks.
Something happened in Denver, Atlanta,
and it could be that we wake up
and we find out that's where it stopped.
But, until we know,
are we going to use our imaginations
to solve problems
or to cause them?
--Is there any sign of the sheriff, Mr. Hawkins?
--No, sir.
I need to speak to your mayor.
We got trouble coming.
Oh, my God.
Mom, where's April?
--Jake, where have you been?
--Where is she?
She's down the hall.
--What's going on?
--Get Dad on the radio.
You'll be fairly mobile on it.
How do you feel?
I feel like a badass.
--April, does the clinic have a fallout shelter?
--Yes. What's going on?
It's bad. Come on.
Jericho has two underground shelters,
one right here under the Town Hall
the other under the medical clinic
What about basements and storm cellars?
They're better than nothing
but you've got to seal off
the rest of the house
with, uh... duct tape, plastic sheeting,
anything you can get your hands on.
How do you know about radiation, Mr. Hawkins?
Because I was a cop in Saint Louis
and, after 9-11, we got up to speed.
So our biggest problem could be the rain.
Won't the rain clear the radiation out of the air?
Yes, and bring it straight down on Jericho--
a direct, concentrated hit.
Anyone exposed too long...
Mr. Mayor? Sir?
All right, look.
We're gonna divide the town in two.
Everyone over here can go
to the Town Hall shelter
all those on the north side will
go to the clinic
We'll get the word out, Dad.
--How long before the radiation gets here?
--Oh, I'm new here.
This is your town.
How long does it normally take
a storm to get here from Denver?
--Less than two hours.
--Sounds right.
Two hours?
--We can't do that in two hours.
--Not enough time.
We've got work to do, guys.
Jake  and I used to play down
here when we were kids.
I don't think anyone's
been down here in ten years.
--How many people can we fit in here?
--300.
You do know that there's almost
5,000 people in this town.
--Eric?
--Yeah?
Make sure all the people
that have basements use them.
--We are not running out of room
here today. You understand?
--Got it, Dad.
Jimmy!
When was the last time someone was in here?
You're kidding me.
I can't put people in here.
There's no air.
There's no air in here.
I hope the fan works.
We got a lot of work to do.
Wait, wait! Hey, hey!
Oh, thank God. I haven't seen anybody for hours.
I ran out of gas.
--There's dead birds all over the road.
--Yeah, we saw them, too.
They must have flown through the radiation.
What radiation?
There was a mushroom cloud.
Somebody nuked us.
Oh, my God.
Look, Miss, we're running low on gas.
Do you know if there's
a gas station nearby?
Well, what do you think it is?
--Do you think it's an accident or...?
--Ma'am, we don't know yet.
Okay.
Did it come from Wichita,
--because my fiance, he's flying in from...
--No, no. Wrong direction.
It looked more like Denver.
Look, we need gas.
--Do you know if there is a gas station nearby?
--Uh... yeah. No.
No, the pumps are...
They don't work.
They've all been abandoned.
No, we could... We could try
the Richmond Ranch.
--I think they might have gas there.
--Then get in.
We'll take you there.
Miss?
It's  okay. Get in.
Dale?
Wake up.
Wake up, angel.
Mom?
Don't you remember what happened last night?
Your mom's gone.
Gracie? Come on, Gracie!
Open up!
Gracie, we need to stock the shelters with food!
Attention! Attention!
There is radioactive fallout
coming from the nuclear blast.
You have less than 90 minutes to get indoors
I repeat, you have less than 90 minutes to get indoors.
Use your basements.
Use duct tape or other tape to seal your home.
You have less than 90 minutes.
You can go to the shelter at Town Hall
or the shelter at the medical center.
There is radioactive fallout coming.
You have 90 minutes to get yourselves indoors.
We are indoors!
You're not from around here, are you?
I came from D.C. to supervise
a little audit on a farm.
Is God punishing me?
Look, you really should get
to the basement at Town Hall.
You think?
--Jake, I'm not going anywhere.
--Mom...
Mom, I'm not going to argue with you.
--Go to the other shelter.
--I'm staying.
Mom,  I don't even know if we can fix it
and I can't concentrate knowing you're here.
Please, I'll be fine.
I'll be fine.
Promise me you'll come to the shelter
after it's fixed.
Promise me.
I promise, Mom.
I want my boys with me.
Okay, go.
Please.
Frank! Quit messing with the TV.
I don't want to waste my generator on static.
--Mary, what are these people still doing here?
--They won't go.
I can't leave these clowns in my bar.
All right, listen up.
Radiation's on its way from Denver.
If you don't have a basement,
you need to get to Town Hall.
There's a shelter there.
I'm not going to Town Hall.
Well, you don't have a choice, people.
You're being evacuated.
And who are you?
I'm the deputy mayor.
What, did your daddy make you a deputy?
Just forget it, Eric,
you've told everybody.
--Do you realize a nuclear bomb went off yesterday?
--So?
If I'm going to die in a nuclear blast, so be it.
I'm going to be right here
playing pool with my buddies.
But you're not going to die in a blast.
You're going to get radiation poisoning.
Within the first couple of hours
you're going to be vomiting
and have crippling diarrhea.
Your hair is going to fall out in chunks.
Your skin,
it's going to blister.
Your internal organs are going to start to shut down.
Because, well, frankly...
...they're being cooked from the inside.
You're going to get sicker and sicker
until you can't move.
And then you will die.
Over there on the floor by the pool table...
with your buddies.
Ooh.
Don't mind me.
Sit tight.
We'll be right back.
Sheriff, come in.
Come in, Sheriff, over.
Randall, no one's heard from the sheriff
since last night
There was a prison bus out there.
I think we better assume the worst.
You're on your own.
What about Jimmy or Bill?
Deputies are missing, too.
You're  just going to have
to handle this yourself.
Don't think we forgot you, did you?
--Anything wrong, Miss?
--No, nothing.
Doesn't look like anybody's here.
Yeah, well, the pump's locked, so...
You know, there is this other place
that I can take you to.
Look, we're running on fumes as it is.
Make a sound, you die.
I'm sorry, sir,
I don't think anybody's home.
Ms. Sullivan...
--What a surprise.
--Hey, Bonnie.
Oxygen tanks, IVs,
all non-electrical medical supplies.
--When was that written?
--1957.
The population of Jericho was 1,000 people.
I'll start moving everyone.
I'll get the ventilation system fixed.
God, they chewed through everything.
Mind if I pitch in?
You know how to strip wires?
Ever since junior high.
Yeah, I was that popular.
All right, great.
Check the fan belt,
I think it's frayed.
Well, then you might want to get another one.
Any mid-century American car would
be a good match.
And check the brushers.
--We don't want the motor to seize up.
--Okay.
All right.
You take over.
I'll  look for a fan belt.
Excuse me, sir.
You're doing that wrong.
April.
She thinks we shouldn't move the baby.
Ma'am, your baby's protected
in this little bubble.
She's got fresh air and food.
Right now, she's the safest
person in Jericho
but you're not.
We need to make sure she has
a mother to take care of her
when this thing is over, okay?
Please.
--Please, let us take you both
down to the shelter, okay?
--Mm-hmm.
Okay.
--Bobby.
--Jake Green?
Just a second, ma'am.
--obby, there's two in the nursery.
--I'm Emily Sullivan's aunt.
...taken to the shelter in our basement.
Mrs. Dawson, hi.
--Have you seen Emily?
--No, not since yesterday.
Maybe she's at the other shelter.
No one over there has seen her
and she's not at her house.
I heard you were back in town
--and I figured the one person who would know...
--I'm sorry.
I have to go.
If I see her, I'll tell her
you're looking for her
but I'm sure she's fine.
So we'll just, uh,
use your pump and be on our way.
Stanley has the key.
What did she just say?
Oh... her brother, Stanley,
he's got the key to the pump.
Wait a minute,
--she's deaf?
--Yes.
I read lips.
--When do you think Stanley gets back?
--Another hour.
--Whoa, whoa, whoa.
--What did she just say?
It's going to be about an hour.
Oh, we can wait an hour, can't we?
Ms. Sullivan, you all right?
Yeah, fine.
I'm just hungry.
Yeah, uh...
Why don't we make some food for the officers?
Oh, I want eggs.
It's a farmhouse,
you've got eggs, right?
Yeah, why don't we, uh...
Why don't we all go make something to eat?
Sure.
People south of Main
go to you at Town Hall?
Yeah, that's right,
all those to the north of Main Street
go to the medical center.
--Johnston.
--Right, yeah, I know, you want me
to take it easy.
--I'm just going to go help Eric
get the supplies from Gracie.
--I've already sent people to do that.
Gail, who is in charge here, you or me?
You do not want to play that game.
Here's every book we have in the library
about nuclear radiation.
--Our Friend The Atom.
--Some friend.
Anything in here for grownups?
I'd like to know what we're supposed to do
if this town gets hit.
None of the books are specific.
Atom bombs have only gone off in
populated cities twice in history.
And Denver was probably hit
by a hydrogen bomb, anyway.
What's the difference?
Hydrogen bombs, they literally
explode the air.
So, what you're saying
is that nobody knows
what's really coming?
Then we pick worst case scenario.
--What needs to be done?
--One second, sir, I have that.
Let me just...
Anything left outside
will have to be scrubbed down.
And if it rains, the top
18 inches or so of soil
will have to be removed before planting again.
And tell everybody to cover
all the water wells.
That's about what it says, right?
Yes. Yes, that's right.
Well, you heard the man.
Jeff, let's make sure all the ranchers
get the livestock inside.
I'm going to work on the radio.
This may be our last chance
to make contact for a while.
There's a bunch of people in the church.
They held a vigil there all night.
I'm going to make sure they get into shelter.
--Hurry back.
--Yes, ma'am.
--I'm telling you they need to be replaced.
--Listen, girlie...
Please, don't argue with me.
don't tell me...
The brushers are shot,
it's revving too high. It's...
Turn them off!
Jake, everyone's ready.
--What do we do now?
--Don't let them in here!
The rain's going to be here soon.
People are getting scared.
Do we have air or not?
You seal them up in here
they're going to die.
Hello,Dad
Dad, can you hear me?
Dad's checking on the church, Jake
What do you need?
Our shelter's no good.
I'm bringing these people to Town Hall.
Whoa, whoa, hold on.
Jake, I don't know how many more
people we can hold.
--What about the basement?
--They don't have basements, Eric.
That's why they came here.
Eric, we've got 200 people here.
Some of them need medical attention.
Handle it.
Look, I will be at Town Hall soon.
I'll check to see how much room we have.
--And I will call you back.
--I don't have time. We're coming.
--Sorry, my husband needs a kick sometimes.
--You don't have to apologize to me.
I've got to go to the shelter.
Bring everything you can.
H-How much more do you need?
--Enough to feed half the town, Gracie.
--Half the town?
Wait--
--Skylar, you have to come to the shelter.
--I'm not going to some stupid shelter.
I'm going home to wait for my parents.
--Don't be crazy.
--I'm not crazy!
--I'm going home.
--Fine.
Excuse me, ladie
Are you going to pay for those?
What are you talking about?
Everybody is just taking stuff.
This is still my store.
Is that for an emergency?
All right, you know what?
Fine, keep it.
Her parents are in New York, okay?
Who knows if they're even going to come back.
--It was just a couple cans of soda.
--They're my soda.
I say we head east.
She was headed east, wasn't she?
Hey, how far from here
would you say those crows were?
About five miles west
from where you picked me up.
Hell,  then we'll go north.
Hey.
You want to help me out with the coffee?
Yeah, I'll show you where it is.
You better get down to that shelter.
--The wind is moving faster than we thought
--I'm watching it.
Just get everybody underground.
You know, if you get that thing to work,
just do me a favor, and find
out who did this to us.
--Eric, come in.
--This is Eric, go ahead.
A couple of busloads coming to Town Hall.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
People, please!
Don't get off the bus.
--We can't take any more.
--Eric, what the hell are you doing?
They can't come in here, Jake.
--What do you mean they can't come in here?
--We're packed!
What? I got a whole bus full of
people here that need shelter.
You're really gonna turn away
all these people, Eric?
You're going to turn away your wife?
We let everybody in,
we'll all suffocate.
Eric, there are really sick people here
and the storm is coming!
Okay, we can take ten.
And I saved a spot for you.
All right, the ten most critical, fast.
Gray, the salt mine,
how many people will it hold?
As many as you want,
--but I don't think...
--It has a ventilation system, right?
--Yeah, and water.
--All right, it's the best option
we have right now, all right?
Mom?
Have you seen your father?
He told me he was going to the church.
Well, Gail, people from that church got
back 20 minutes ago.
Eric?
Mom, we'll find Dad.
--Jake, take your people to the mine.
Leave us 10.
--I'll go with you, Jake.
After 27 years, nobody knows
that mine the way I do.
I guess you can fit 11 people now.
Yeah, make it 12.
It's my place--
I should be there.
Yeah, let's go.
Hey.
We're going to be okay.
Hang on.
--That smells good.
--Oh, no, no, I'll get it.
Oh!
--I am so sorry.
--Damn it.
Oh, that looks bad.
Look, go in the kitchen right now
and run cold water over it.
It'll stop it before the blisters.
I'll clean up this mess.
--What happened?
--She...
I burnt my hand.
You left her alone?
She's fine.
Is he okay?
He'll live.
I can only get 12 down
on the elevator at a time!
That's the best I can do!
Shep, we have to seal the entrance.
There's no door, Jake.
Well, we can't just let the rain
pour down the shaft.
These people won't be safe.
--We won't be safe.
--Well, how do we seal it?
I don't know, but it's a mine.
--You got dynamite, right?
--Whoa, whoa...
--We put charges here, here, here...
--Are you crazy?
How do we know we won't bring
the whole thing down on top of us?
We don't.
I am going to the little girls' room.
--Hey, where is that?
--Right up the stairs.
--Right there, see?
--Good to know.
Straight back!
--Eric, any sign of Dad?
--No, not yet.
Checked the church, Main Street.
We're going through every inch
of Town Hall right now.
Listen, Eric,
I'm going to need you
to bring a crew over here
and dig us out when this thing's over.
What? What? Why?
--We're ready, Jake!
--Are you crazy?
Just dig us out-- and find Dad, okay?
Let's go.
Mr. Hawkins, did my father come through here?
No, I haven't seen him.
--Mom, check the offices again.
--Maybe we missed something.
I'll go check out the parking lot.
--Look, we'll find him, okay?
--Okay. Be careful. Be careful.
Could you use some help, ma'am?
No, we need you on the radio.
You know, I can't get this old thing to work.
--Okay, come.
--Fine.
Please.
You are not in my house.
Get off my property, right now.
And my property goes all the way down the hill.
You need to get back to town.
The radiation's coming from Denver.
I'm not leaving here.
My parents are on their way back.
--You talked to them?
--No, freak, the phones are dead.
But I'm not leaving here without them.
All right, stay inside,
tape up the windows,
and don't use the water.
--Don't tell me what to do.
--I'm serious, Skylar.
Stay inside.
Dale?
Dale, stop!
Please.
Stay here.
It's not safe out there.
Please stay here.
Jody, where you at?
All right, everybody...
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Take some of that out, all right?
Seal the entrance, not cause a cave-in.
Hey.
Where'd you learn how to do that?
I knew a guy once.
Did you blow him up?
Hello? Is anyone here?
--How does that look?
--It's good, that'll do.
--How we coming, Gray?
--This is the last of 'em.
--I'm almost done here.
--Same here.
This is Emily Sullivan.
We're at the Richmond Ranch with Bonnie.
Please, help us.
Can you hear me?
Is there anybody there?
What was that?
Did you hear that?
--Somebody's on the radio.
--This is Emily Sullivan.
--I'm at the Richmond Ranch.
--Everybody be quiet!
There are men here with guns.
I think they might have
killed the sheriff. Hello?
Can you hear me?
Emily! Emily!
Emily, can you hear me?
Emily.
Come in, come in.
Come in, can you hear me?
Is there anyone out there?
Is there anyone on this channel?
Can anyone here me?
Shep, give me your keys.
--Jake, it's gonna start raining any minute now.
--Give me your keys, I can make it.
--All right.
--Jake, you're out of your mind.
Gray, get everybody down there, all right?
--Hey, Jake?
--What?
When everybody's down,
say "all clear."
"All clear," okay?
Almost ready, Jake, stand by.
Come on, come on.
Jake?
We're all clear.
Johnston? Johnston?
Gail...
Oh, my God.
Mr. Hawkins!
Where's the brother?
Where the hell's the girl?
I think they might have killed...
I think they might have killed the sheriffs.
Please, help us.
Hello. This is Emily Sullivan.
I'm looking for the Jericho Police Department.
Can you hear me?
Is there anyone out there?
Is there anybody on this channel?
There are men here with guns.
I think they might have killed the sheriff.
Please, somebody help us.
Run, Emily,
run.
Hey! Hey!
Stop!
Think this through! Let her go!
No.
We just want gas.
Supplies, that's all this is about.
It's just about fuel.
Let her go.
Look.
Please, please, let her go.
No.
Is this what you want to see?
Are you ready to talk now, Miss?
Please, let her go.
April...
April, come here.
Hey, Dad, can you tell me what happened?
Sit down.
Here, sit him down.
I just found him on the floor in his office.
Did you hit your head?
All right.
Bonnie, take him to the storm cellar now!
Go, guys, go!
Emily, we've got to get inside.
Emily? Emily, hey.
It's going to be okay
All right? I promise.
Everything is going to be okay, all right?
We've got to gin now, babe.
Babe?
We've got to get inside
before the rain, okay?
Come with me.
Come on.
Run. Run.
Get inside!
--Hey, Dad.
--Hey. How you doing?
You comfortable?
Just like camping.
You hate camping.
Yep.
Where's Allison?
--She's up in her room.
--Samuel, go get Ali.
Yes, sir.
--Tell her I'm home.
--Yes, sir.
Robert. Robert.
--What's happening out there?
--I don't know.
You know.
--You always know something.
--Hey, hey...
You are alive, Darcy,
okay?
And the kids are safe.
You know, don't ask me questions.
I think my mom died yesterday.
I think my mom died yesterday, too.
I thought you were gone.
--Emily...
--Why are you here?
Trying to keep you safe.
It's never safe around you.