[Woman]
*Every night and day *
- [Bell Ringing]
- *And I never lost one minute of sleepin'*
* Worryin' 'bout the way
things might have been *
*Big wheel keep on turnin'*
[Chattering]
*Proud Mary keep on burnin'*
* Rollin', rollin' *
* Rollin' on a river *
* Cleaned a lot of plates in Memphis *
*Pumped a lot of'tane
in New Orleans *
[Dice Rattling]
Coming out, folks.
Place your bets.
[Yells]
I can't lose tonight!
Don't say that.
It brings bad luck.
I do not believe in luck.
*Rollin; rollin'*
*Rollin'on a river *
Okay, Lonnie,
he's winning big.
It's now or never.
I think it's goin' down.
Wilson just sent Lonnie
to the elevator.
Loud and clear, Lieutenant.
If she's comin', I have a front-row seat.
I've got her.
She just went into Acton's suite.
*Rollin; rollin'**
Muntzy, be careful.
[Over Earpiece]
Hey, hey. I got 10 years on you, buddy.
I'm the original man of steel.
You're the one I'm worried about.
You're in that bed of snakes.
[Lonnie On Earpiece]
Wilson, I'm finished.
Well, be sure nobody sees you.
There's no one in the hallway
but an electrician.
Electrician? You didn't say anything
about an electrician.
He works for the hotel.
I've seen him around.
- Stay in the room.
- Croupier, for you.
Wilson.
**[Woman Singing, Indistinct]
We are calling it a night.
Come on, sweetheart. Let's go.
Make sure security is behind us
until we get these in the room safe.
- All right?
- All right.
Delay him.
I want you to stay close to Mr. Acton.
He's carrying a great deal of cash.
Right.
Lonnie, get out of the room fast.
Acton's on his way up.
What about the guy on the ladder?
If he follows you, I'll handle him.
You get in your car
and head east out of town.
We'll pick up the film from you there.
She's leaving in a hurry, Lieutenant.
I know. Wilson just put me in charge.
We've got a broken play.
Can you follow Lonnie?
Back me up if I blow it.
We've got six months
in this one, Muntzy.
I'll be right behind you.
Charles, security can only do so much
in a crowd with you carrying
all these chips.
I'd feel a lot better
if we took it to the cashier.
No, I don't wanna...
- That's good advice, Mr. Acton.
I'd recommend it.
- You're probably right.
They're clumsy as hell anyway.
*But it's time you got the news *
*I'm gonna harden my heart *
*I'm gonna swallow my tears *
You can relax, Lieutenant.
Be careful, Muntzy.
I don't know where Wilson is.
Gray, they've burned her.
She's got a guy on her tail.
He's in a maintenance suit.
Now stop him.
I got her.
And I got him.
Excuse me.
Wait here, Mr. Acton.
And don't leave.
What are you talking about?
Where are you going?
Michael.
I think he made you. Muntzy.
Muntzy.
[Acton]
Wait a minute.
Michael, what are you doing?
[Engine Starts]
Muntzy!
Watch him. I'll get help.
No, look, Lieutenant.
Forget it.
Uh... Uh- uh.
Muntzy.
- Go after her.
- Muntzy, you gotta hang on.
Muntzy.!
Stay here with him.
No, I'll go with you.
[Chattering]
[Man]
Get an ambulance.
[Woman]
Call for a doctor someone!
Michael, why are you doing this?
You were hired to protect Charles.
You can't leave him.
These people are no longer
interested in your boss.
They just got
what they were after.
What are you talking about?
I don't have time
to explain it all to you now, Tanya,
but your boss's chief of security
is up to his Bahamian bank accounts
in industrial espionage.
And now murder.
I don't believe it.
Did you believe
that dead cop back there?
He was my partner.
I was supposed to be
covering him.
Will you step out
of the car please, Lonnie?
You did a really nicejob.
I'll take that microfilm.
[Vehicle Approaching,
Tires Screech]
All right. Hold it right there.
You move, I fire.
Drop the gun, Symes,
and kick it over here.
Looks like we made a small mistake.
I'd call treason
more than a small mistake.
It draws the death penalty.
Tanya, pick up his gun.
[Tanya]
That won't be necessary.
I have my own.
Drop it.
[Gun Clatters On Ground]
- You're workin' for them?
- Oh, I've disappointed you.
Tanya, give me the gun.
I can still make a deal for you
if you cooperate.
- Give it to me.
- I intend to.
[Man]
My God, we're too late.
[Beeping]
Well,
what's the word?
I'm gonna give you the same answer
that I've been giving you
for the past four days.
He's probably the only human being
on this planet...
who's in worse condition than you are.
Is he going to die?
He should have.
That bullet was fired point-blank
right into his skull.
Well, how did he survive?
The man has a metal plate
in his forehead.
You see?
Probably military surgery,
I would guess.
It deflected the bullet,
which was heading
right toward his brain,
and it came back out...
through his face.
We'll never know what he looked like.
[Murmurs]
Muntzy.!
[Yelling]
That's all right, son.
Keep hurting.
It'll keep you living... just like me.
I've got good news for you.
The Knight 2000 will be ready...
Shh, shh, shh.
- That bad?
- On the contrary.
It's an excellent job.
Here. Why don't you take a look?
It isn't me.
It gives you
a second chance to live.
Unless, of course,
you'd prefer to walk around with a face
that might get you killed all over again?
You take my word.
You'll be much safer with this face.
And it's, um,
rather handsome,
if I do say so myself.
Does it strike you
that there's an uncanny resemblance...
between this young fellow
and you as a young man?
[Clears Throat]
My imagination, I suppose.
Stick to your task.
- When will I see it?
- I've been trying to tell you.
- It could be ready within the month.
- Excellent.
I pray that it leaves me enough time.
- What have you told him?
- I've told him he no longer
has anyone to fear.
In the eyes of the law,
Michael Long is legally dead,
and we haven't done
anything wrong.
Wilton, stealing a body
from the medical school...
so that the police can find it...
is hardly what I would call
playing by the rules.
I make my own rules.
So does the government.
They fake deaths
and identities all the time.
Not to mention our adversary.
All right.
But why are you doing it?
I think you know why, Devon.
I want to leave something behind me...
something worthwhile.
Not just a lot of numbers
in a bank account.
Now, when will the Knight 2000 be ready?
Soon. I have the crews working
double shifts.
Make it around the clock.
I want it done.
I want it done within the next 48 hours.
Forty-eight hours?
Wilton, has the doctor said...
Don't you worry about
what the good doctor has told me.
I'll worry about the doctors...
and Michael Long.
Aren't you pushing it
a bit, Michael?
[Grunts, Panting]
I gotta get back in shape real fast.
[Panting]
I got one last debt to pay.
Is revenge the only thing you can think of?
You're better than that.
You were a good cop.
Was I?
As I recall, I blew it.
What if I were to offer you another shot?
I want Tanya and her friends too,
but that's only the tip of the iceberg.
- Now, if we were to work together...
- Mr. Knight, my last partner is dead.
Nothing personal,
but from now on I work alone.
I can't take responsibility
for anybody's life but my own.
I think you can understand that.
[Footsteps Descending Staircase]
[Whirring]
[Engine Starts]
[Tires Squealing]
Enough, Devon.
You've had your fun with our guest.
It isn't polite
to sneak around uninvited.
[Chuckles]
Be gracious, Devon.
I think an explanation
is well overdue.
Damn right it is.
What is all this?
What are you guys up to...
people sneaking in and out of here
at all hours of the day and night?
Look at who's talking.
Oh, be quiet, both of you.
And let's get down to business.
I'm running out of time,
and Michael here is...
now healthy enough to carry on.
Carry on what?
I don't know what
you people do out here,
but I just want to get on with my life.
That's not very grateful.
Aren't you the least bit angry
at the people who left you to die?
Angry?
Angry doesn't even come close.
But I'm gonna adjust.
You know why?
Tell me.
Because they're too big.
The kind of criminals
that operate above the law.
Nobody can touch 'em.
I don't agree with you.
Well, you're entitled to your opinion.
As for me, I'm pulling out
ofhere tonight, and I, uh...
I'm taking my car with me.
Prepare the car for him, Devon.
A great deal he'll have to know about it
before it's safe for him to drive.
I must go to bed.
I'm not, uh...
[Chuckles]
Feeling very well.
You've just struck a dying man.
Hey, listen.
I like that old man.
I really do.
But, Devon, I gotta get on
with my own life.
You wouldn't have a life
if we hadn't brought you here.
Remember,
there are still people who will kill you
if they find out you're alive.
But I'm legally dead, remember?
Devon, I don't even know me
with this face.
Now what's all this about my car?
Any resemblance between that car
and your own is purely superficial.
What are you talking about?
Devon, that's my car.
I left it out in the desert.
No, it may look like your car,
but in actuality,
this vehicle is probably
the most expensive car in the world.
Come on. This is my car.
What's this? A new paint job?
It feels like baby skin.
Boy, those guys did a nice job.
There's not a ripple on it.
Like a mirror.
It's not paint.
It's a finish bonded
into the molecular structure
of a new substance.
You mean the metal?
It's not metal, and it's not fiberglass.
Excuse me.
Here. Strike the surface
as hard as you can.
Come on, Devon. I'm not gonna
hit my car. It's beautiful.
Hmm.
There's not a mark on it.
How did you do that?
Don't just stand there
with your mouth open.
Get in the car.
I'll show you.
Welcome aboard the Knight 2000.
Thank you.
What's all this?
Looks like Darth Vader's bathroom.
It is a one-of-a-kind car, Mr. Long.
It is the fastest, safest,
strongest car in the world.
It is also completely fuel-efficient...
and is operated entirely
by microprocessors...
which make it virtually impossible
for it to be involved in any kind of
mishap or collision.
Unless, of course,
specifically so ordered by its pilot.
Pilot?
Don't tell me this thing flies.
No. But it thinks.
It thinks?
My car thinks?
We like to think of it as our car.
Now, in order to
motivate it forward...
I recognize
the more rudimentary controls,
such as the accelerator, Devon.
I do know how to drive.
I would have preferred you
to have let me open the door first.
However, as you see,
no harm has come to the car.
You also told me this machine
couldn't have a collision.
Not if the system is operable.
And to do that, you have to, uh,
switch it on first.
[Beeping]
- Like that.
- Now you're telling me...
I can't hit anything?
Trust me.
I'll never trust anybody again.
I'm warning you, Devon.
I'm gonna put this thing
to the test.
Be my guest.
[Engine Revving]
[Michael]
I don't believe this.
I'm playing chicken
with a 10-ton semi.
[Beeps]
Devon, the car just
drove around the truck.
It steered itself!
Yes. It's marvelous, isn't it?
I hate it!
I like to make my own decisions.
Well, the microprocessor deduced
that you were acting contrary
to your best interests.
It had two choices.
Either to slow down...
or to maneuver around the obstacle.
Why didn't this thing slow down
instead of driving around?
It would have been a lot safer.
- Well, um...
- Well, why? Did I find a flaw
in your perfect machine here?
No, no. No flaw. I assure you.
It's just that, um...
It's just what?
Well, it was showing off for you.
- What?
- [Chuckles]
[Tires Screeching]
Come on. You're telling me
that this car can just take off...
and go for gas or a car wash
just like that, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Well, that would be terrific
if I happened to be working under it.
It wouldn't harm you.
I assure you.
Its primary function is
the preservation of human life...
your life.
By me you mean...
anybody driving this thing.
No, no, no. I mean you specifically.
You, Michael Arthur Long.
You'd better hurry.
[Door Closes]
We're too late.
Almost.
What kept you?
Car not fast enough?
[Chuckles]
Look, you gotta
put that thing on the market.
It could save
thousands of lives.
Have it taken away from me
and kept off the market
like they did my air... airplane?
Don't try to talk.
I'll explain everything.
Mr. Knight is the last of his breed.
He built his own empire
just as the Fords and the Rockefellers did.
Devon, we've been all through this.
All right.
Michael, come closer.
You were spared to lead a great fight.
Don't turn away in fear.
One man can...
make a difference.
And you are going to be that man.
Mr. Knight, uh,
I'd like to be able to promise you...
that I feel like I could
take on the world someday,
but I can't.
I still wake up in the middle
of the night shaking.
[Gunshot Echoing]
That... That gun in my face
and the whole world blowing up.
Remember that moment.
Think of it as your... baptism by fire.
My... adventure has ended.
Yours has just...
just begun.
For God's sake,
don't go quite so fast.
I'm puffed.
Sorry, Devon,
but I got places to go.
What the hell does that mean?
Heard you on the phone this morning.
You found the girl in California.
What? You mean to say
that you deliberately listened in
on a private conversation?
Listen, I don't do things like that,
but you got so excited,
you were talking
a mile a minute.
The gardener could have
heard you over the lawn mower.
Now, what's she up to?
She's working
in a place called Silicon Valley.
All right. LfTanya's in Silicon Valley,
that's where I'm going right now.
- I forbid it.
- Devon, you can't forbid it.
I can certainly take away the car.
I'll get another one.
Besides, it's in my name.
That's where you're wrong.
"Michael Knight"?
Michael Long is dead.
Remember that.
How do I suddenly become
Michael Knight?
Yes, well...
Driver's license,
credit cards.
It's all on Mr. Knight's orders.
These are good now.
You could have dated these ahead
if you wanted me to stay here.
You knew I'd leave
when I wanted to.
You're a primitive, Mr. Lon...
Mr. Knight.
You're quite predictable.
- You think the old man
was pretty smart, don't you?
- A certifiable genius.
He must've known
what he was doing when he picked me
to get a little revenge for him.
I'm on my way.
Oh, just a minute.
There are several things
about this car that I ought to explain.
That's all right. I'm a fast study.
I'll pick things up as I go along.
[Engine Starts]
Look. Th-That's very foolhardy.
Good-bye. Thank you.
Oh, and I want you to know something.
- I kind of got to like you.
- What?
Never mind.
What's that mean coming from
a primitive anyway?
[Tires Squealing]
Well, Wilton,
he's doing everything
you said he would.
What have you gotten me into?
[Michael]
Millston, in Silicon Valley.
110 miles.
All right.
Might as well put on some music.
With all these weird gadgets,
you'd think they'd give you a radio.
- [Computerized Male Voice]
What would you like to hear?
- What the hell was that?
Do you wish further information
on Silicon Valley?
Hell, no. I want to know who you are
and how you're listening in.
There's no reason for increased volume.
I am scanning your interrogatives
quite satisfactorily.
I'm the voice of
Knight Industry Two Thousand's
microprocessor.
K.I.T.T. For easy reference.
KITT, if you prefer.
No, I don't prefer, and what's more,
I don't intend to drive around
in a car that talks back to me.
So, either Devon pulls your plug,
or you get yourself another driver.
I am not qualified
to overrule your wishes.
Well, that's real good to hear, KITT,
because I don't want to hear
another peep out of you
until I can get a call off to Devon.
So clam up.
I'm gonna listen to some good music.
And don't offer any suggestions.
I'll choose my own.
As you wish, Mr. Knight.
But since you are still recovering
from your ordeal,
and I detect are in
a slightly irritable mood
caused by fatigue,
may I suggest you put the car
in the auto cruise mode
for safety's sake?
No, you may not.
And that's final.
- Good night.
I can't believe this.
A car that talks back to me.
**[Soft Rock]
* Take it easy *
*Don't let the sound of your own wheels
drive you crazy *
* Ooh, ooh *
*Lighten up while you still can *
*Don't even try to understand *
*Just find a place to make your **
*In my mind I'm going to Carolina *
* Can't you see the sunshine *
*And can't you just feel the moonshine *
*Ain't itjust like **
*Desert tonight *
* With a billion stars all around *
* 'Cause I got a peaceful easy feelin'*
[Tires Squealing]
*And I know you won't let me down *
Yoo-hoo, Michael.
* 'Cause I'm already **
Michael.
Hello, Michael.
[Beeps]
[Tires Squealing]
* Open your eyes
and look at the day *
Did you see that?
What?
That guy was plumb asleep
at the wheel.
Nah!
*Don't stop *
Hurry up.
[Tires Screeching]
*It'll soon be here *
[Siren Whirs]
* Yesterday's gone *
That man can't be asleep.
He's got to be dead.
Well, if he ain't, he's gonna be.
That's Dead Man's Curve up ahead.
[Siren Whirring]
[Tires Squealing]
* Why not think about *
[Siren Whirring]
How can he be asleep
and drive like that?
- ** [Continues]
- [KITT Whispers]
Michael.
- Michael.
- **[Stops]
[Horn Honking]
Hey! Hey!
- [Honking Continues]
- Michael.
Hey!
Pull back.
What the...
What's going on?
What'd I do?
Deny everything.
If I may suggest,
deafness is always a good approach
to law enforcement officers.
You shut up.
You were probably
weaving all over the road.
Okay, out!
I might also suggest
you display a slight kink in your neck...
since you were driving
with your head against the window.
- I said out!
- Why didn't you warn me?
You told me to keep quiet.
Who's he talkin' to?
Nobody.
This boy's a hard-core alkie.
Did you hear me?
I said get out
if you don't wanna
spend the night in jail.
That's better.
Now come on out.
Get the balloon out, Deke.
[Loudly]
I'm sorry, Officer.
Could you speak in sign language...
or a little slower.
I haven't gotten
lipreading down yet.
You mean you can't hear?
Could you talk a little louder?
Into this ear... here.
You mean you're deaf?
Oh, that explains everything.
I told you he couldn't drive
that smooth if he was drunk.
What?
He said...
Never mind!
Just be on your way.
We're sorry we bothered ya.
Uh, but keep your eye
on the rearview mirror.
We've been flashing ya for miles.
Yes, sir. I'll do that.
Why do I get the feeling
this isn't gonna be the last time
I'm gonna run into trouble in this town?
[Michael]
"Comtron. '' That looks like
a good place to start.
Social gathering places
where alcoholic beverages...
are consumed in quantity...
can create an environment in which
indiscretion becomes commonplace.
Just remember,
this is business, not pleasure.
You're about as much fun as a divorce.
Which is not a bad idea.
I want custody of me.
I should have gotten rid of you
before I turned you on.
Now I can't shut you up.
Hi, ladies.
Some guys sure start early.
He's not our problem.
Those guys are.
Stick to business.
* Sittin' in a tiny table *
*In a ritzy restaurant *
*She was starin'at her *
Do you see what I see?
Mm-hmm.
[Man Speaking Spanish]
Yeah. And it's mine.
- Say what?
- It's mine.
I have died
and gone to automobile heaven.
Cover me.
Cover you, man? Here?
Are you out of your mind?
- For this machine I am.
- Look here, Jackson. There's a right way
and a wrong way to do things.
And doing this here now is wrong.
You may be right.
Hey, I know I'm right.
This happens to be the most popular,
not to mention
the most populated place in town.
- There will come another time.
- That's a fact.
And we will be ready.
* Talk was small
when they talked at all *
* They both knew what they wanted *
* There was no need to talk about it *
Your tab is starting to get up there.
I'll need a credit card.
Yeah. Sure.
Listen, do you happen to know
those people in the corner booth
over there?
*She said
You don't look like my type *
Let me do you a favor.
Unless you like waking up
sucking dirt, don't get interested
in anyone at that table.
Well, it wasn't anyone at that table
I'm curious about.
It's somebody else.
You know, I noticed
they all came across the street
from Comtron.
Yeah?
Well, I'm trying to find
an old friend of mine that works there.
I thought she might be able to help me.
Well, I used to work there.
Who's your friend?
Name's Tanya.
Tanya Walker.
- Hey! What's the matter with you?
- [Glass Shatters]
That's what I think of friends
ofTanya Walker.
Hey, what happened?
- [Michael]
Nothin: It was just an accident.
- [Woman] Oh, it was no accident.
Maggie, this is the last time
that I put up with your discourtesy.
Hey, that's not necessary.
[Maggie]
Why don't you go hang out
with those Comtron bums?
I can fight my own battles!
Look, I'd better get out of here
before something else comes down.
Yeah, right.
* They left the bar
They got in his car *
*And they drove away *
* They went to the family inn **
I heard you mention Tanya Walker.
You a friend?
You're not gonna
throw anything at me, are ya?
Why should I?
She's a friend of mine too.
Yeah? You know how I can
get a hold of her?
Oh, I'm afraid
she's already seeing someone.
Well, I'm not interested in her body.
I'm interested in her money.
Come again?
I've got something to sell.
Something rather valuable.
Like what?
That's between her and me.
Uh, who shall I tell her inquired?
- [Engine Starts]
- Tell her an old friend.
Security. Gray speaking.
This is Tanya.
Someone's come into town
and has been asking about me.
I'll give you the car and the license.
It's a new black Trans-Am
with a California license,
lettering "KNIGHT."
If it's another cop,
we'll handle it like we did the other ones.
Exactly what I had in mind.
Mmm.
Oh.
Who you calling, love?
Oh, just our people in Security.
As president of this company,
you're an irreplaceable asset,
and I don't want anything
to happen to you tomorrow.
[Chuckles]
You know how I worry about you
when you go out in public.
Nothing's going to happen to me.
Now, honey, in this day and age,
there are a lot of people out there...
that would love to get their hands
on a rich man like you.
Mmm.
You just be grateful
you have somebody like me to
take care of you.
[Michael]
Maggie.
Get lost.
I'm warning you.
This bag is full of mace.
I stayed in my car
so I wouldn't scare you.
Well, ain't you the David Niven.
Look, I'm sorry about
what happened in there,
but you misunderstood.
I'm not a friend of Tanya's.
I just need to find her.
Well, who cares?
Not me.
She and that group of parasites of hers
have taken away everything that
ever meant anything to me.
My husband, myjob, my house.
I can't even afford
decent clothes for my kid.
Now, please leave me alone,
or I'll put a dent in the middle
of that machine. I mean it.
I'll pay to get that fixed for ya.
[Sighs]
I don't believe it.
How can I go through life
with luck this bad?
I plow into your car
and my bumper falls off.
Maggie, let me help you
change your luck.
Why don't you just leave me alone?
I just lost the last job
I'm ever gonna get in this town.
What ifTanya and her crew
could be run out of Millston?
[Sighs]
Don't tell me. You're just about to
offer me a silver bullet.
Just a chance to get even.
For what?
How much do you know
about what's going on here?
- I was hoping you could tell me
what I need to know.
- Why?
- You really think
you can make a difference?
- Yes!
Now, will you help me?
It's a regular boomtown.
There's more money flowing
through here now than there was
during the California gold rush.
All because of tiny microchips.
Yeah. Every calculator,
every electronic kids' game...
they were all born right here.
How do you fit into Silicon Valley?
My husband came here
to take a job as head of security
for Comtron.
- Didn't work out?
- Oh, yes.
It worked out just fine...
till the president decided to hire
a brand-new executive assistant.
- Tanya Walker.
- Yep.
Before she rode
that flashy tail ofhers to the top,
Comtron was a relatively happy family.
Then she came along,
and she started making
wholesale changes.
You mean your husband was fired?
Not exactly.
He couldn't accept what was going on,
and he started... poking into things.
And one night he didn't come home.
Disappeared?
They found him dead in a gully.
Said he'd been drinking.
He didn't drink.
Not even beer.
Maggie, how could they make that stick?
Witnesses.
Half a dozen truck drivers
who hang out in that place where I work.
All animals who work for Comtron.
You wouldn't have taken that job
to find some answers, would you?
I took that job
to feed my little boy.
This is where I live.
[Maggie]
I suppose you'd better come on up.
Ay, señorita,
I was so worried.
Luce, I'm sorry.
I... ran into something.
I hope it was nothing serious.
Oh. Oh, my goodness.
I hope it is something serious.
Luce, please.
You're embarrassing me.
Uh, this is Mr. Knight.
- Tanto gusto.
- Luce takes care of my son.
He's sleeping.
Well, I'll be leaving you two.
Have a good time.
Especially you.
She's a wonderful girl.
A saint. Remember that.
[Chuckles]
Good luck.
He's a winner.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what to say.
She doesn't usually behave like that.
No apologies. I'm flattered.
Well, it's important to me
that you believe me.
I haven't had a man
in my apartment
since my husband was killed.
Mom.
Buddy.
What are you doing out of bed?
This is Buddy.
I figured. Hi, Buddy.
Hi. Are you gonna marry my mom?
Oh.! I don't believe
hejust said that.
Now will you go back to bed.
Right now. Just a minute.
If I wanted to talk to Tanya alone,
where would I go?
Just a second.
[Buddy]
Who's Tanya? Competition?
[Maggie]
Shh.! Now you go to sleep.
Look, I'd... I'd forget
trying to get to her off duty.
I think she's staying
at Benjamin's estate.
- William Benjamin.
- Mm-hmm.
He owns Comtron,
and she rarely leaves his side these days.
Now you go to sleep.
Wait a minute.
Uh, tomorrow's one day
that she and Benjamin do have to go out.
Uh, Comtron's sponsoring
a charity show out at the track.
The track?
Yeah. It's a, uh,
demolition derby for charity.
Buddy wanted to go.
You see, in Silicon Valley,
they have so much money,
they don't use junkers.
Every plant is putting up
a brand-new car.
People are just eating it up.
- Can anybody enter?
- Oh, come on.
Who can afford to get
his brand-new car totaled out?
- Tell your son I'll be by to pick
the both of you up at 10:00 tomorrow morning.
- Why? You mean we get to watch it?
Yeah, you two get to watch.
I'll be in it.
Yeah!
[Sighs]
[Coin Jingles]
What, uh...
What do you think?
Piece of cake.
- Michael, where on earth are you?
- You act as if you didn't know.
- I'm not clairvoyant.
- You got a spy though.
KITT? Don't be ridiculous.
He answers only to you,
unless, of course, you're
incapacitated and release him.
It.
- Huh?
- It is an it.
Not a he.
Don't ever forget that.
I don't see
what difference that makes.
That's because I'm the one out here
all by his lonesome.
I'm a he.
I could get my face shot off, not it.
- What's happened, Michael?
- Nothing so far,
but I made contact.
- Marvelous.
- Let's hope so.
We'll know in a couple hours.
- What happens in two hours?
- Demolition derby.
Ah, that's splendid. Demolition...
What's a demolition derby?
Well, it's where people
enter their cars
in sort of a competition.
It bent my pick!
Come on. Quick pick.
Sensational! We can't lose.
We have the best car on earth.
- And what happens next?
- All the cars get demolished.
That's not very funny.
Now, what really happens?
That's what really happens.
Ow!
Here. You idiot.
Don't be using a foot, man.
Use something that ain't gonna get hurt.
Hey. Hey.
Hey, Jackson. Jackson.
Talk to me, man.
Devon, if the car
is everything we think it is,
we can't get hurt.
But much of what we've designed
has yet to be proven in the field.
I think it's safe to say,
by the end of the day,
everything will be tested.
For better or for worse.
Michael.
[Dial Tone]
Demolition derby indeed.
I'm gettin' mad, man.
You understand? Mad!
Yeah. Yeah, well,
l... I can understand that.
That car will be mine.
Mine, you hear!
[Man Announcing]
Haven't we been graced
with a beautiful day...
here at the Millston Speedway
for the first running
of what we hope will be an annual event...
the Comtron International
Demolition Derby.
We've got a full field
ofbeautiful brand-new vehicles,
right off the showroom floor.
You're probably going to get to see them
all turned into a body shop bonanza
before the end of this day.
[Man Continues, Indistinct]
[Buddy]
Wow, this is better than an auto show.!
Well, you better
take 'em all in now, Buddy.
There's not gonna be a lot left of them
after the race.
[Michael]
Maggie, why all these trucks
from Comtron?
Well, because they're sponsoring the race
and providing the drivers.
Oh, you're not really thinking
of entering your beautiful car?
It's for charity, isn't it?
Yeah, but it's also for people
who can afford it.
I can't figure out
why you're doing this.
I have my reasons.
You're a strange man, Michael.
You're nice, but you're strange.
Thanks, I think.
Now let's get you two some seats
in owners' row, huh?
Me in the owners' row?
Oh, that'll frost 'em.
[Laughs]
[Announcer]
Only about 20 minutes left, folks,
before we drop the green flag.
We'd appreciate it now if you'd leave
the infield and the pit areas...
and start making your way
to your seats for today's thriller.
I understand this is where
I check in, Tanya.
- I beg your pardon?
- I'm Michael Knight.
Oh, you're the one that called.
Then you were serious
about entering your car.
- Dead serious.
- Well, your car will serve as the entry fee,
but I wouldn't expect
much of it back if I were you.
But the winning car
does receive a nice trophy,
and the driver walks away
with 5,000 in cash.
Oh, that's real nice.
I'll give the prize money to the charity.
By the way,
did anyone mention to you
that I was in town looking for you?
As a matter of fact,
yes, they did.
But I didn't understand the message,
and I don't deal with salesmen.
You don't know what I'm selling.
It wouldn't matter.
You wanna bet?
After the race,
you'll be looking for me.
I guarantee it.
Come on, Tanya.
Let's go, let's go.
The crowd's a-waitin'.
Mr. Benjamin,
I sure do admire your charity work,
and I'm very happy to do my little part.
Doing your part?
Yes, sir. You see,
I'm the only independent driver
in this race, but it's still an honor.
Uh, we don't allow jalopies
in this race, Mr...
Knight. And my car's no jalopy,
as you can see.
Well, you're a very generous man.
Make sure the crowd
appreciates his gesture, Tanya.
Thank you, Mr. Benjamin.
Oh, I'll need two tickets
in the owners' row.
Lonnie, would you give him
some owners' passes, please?
I'd be glad to.
Good-bye, Mr. Knight.
Why are you so hostile?
Come on. You're acting like
there's a kidnapper behind every tree.
Come on.
Here you go.
Take your place
with the valley's finest.
Oh, you're a doll.
But I can't find Buddy.
I don't know where that kid's gone.
Don't worry about him.
He'll turn up.
A lot of cars to see.
Michael,
good luck, okay?
Piece of cake.
Our sleek field of cars are revving up.
Getting ready to go.
The starter's in position.
By the way,
we've got a new entry...
Michael Knight,
an independent driver
in a black Trans-Am.
And the race is on.!
Remember, ladies and gentlemen,
this is a figure-eight track,
and as the cars begin spreading out,
it becomes increasingly more difficult...
to get through the intersection
without colliding with another car.
So far, the cars have not attained
full speed.
They're feeling each other out
like boxers in the first round
of a title match.
It's gonna be
a great afternoon of racing.
We know you're going to enjoy it.
Gosh! I've never seen anything like it.
What are you doing here?
You're supposed to be with your mother.
This is much more fun.
[Announcer]
Ooh, that was powerful.
Aw, why'd you chicken out?
Because you're standing there
ready to be flipped out of the car.
Now get in that seat right now
and strap yourself down!
Hurry up!
Now, once again, ladies and gentlemen,
the young independent
is challenging on the outside against
a car weighing again half as much.
Let's see if he backs down again.
A tremendous race.!
Now it appears that teammates
are working on the young independent.
- They've blocked him.
- Okay, KITT.
I need to knock out about four feet.
I'm gonna put you on auto pursuit.
You figure out the rest.
[Announcer]
Look at this.! Michael Knight
in the black Trans-Am...
He's gonna get through there.
I'll be doggone!
[Announcer]
Oh, no.! A tremendous collision.!
Yeah! You not only wiped him out,
you wiped out the truck too!
These guys aren't supposed to
hit my trucks.
Where'd you get these new drivers, Tanya?
Thanks. I needed that.
You're welcome.
It's so good to be
communicating again.
Golly! This car even talks.
Oh, that was, uh...
that was just the radio, Buddy.
No, it wasn't.
I may just be a little kid,
but I'm not stupid.
The car talked to you.
It might be better if we don't
mention this to a whole lot of people.
Like any, if you know what I mean.
I think I know what you mean.
[Announcer]
And Carney Miller up front.
And Knight has got the lead.
- Hey, Carney!
- Yeah?
I figure this kids's
trying to horn in on some money
that rightly belongs to us.
- If you get my drift.
- Loud and clear.
Let's give him a little room
to slide through.
It's school days, pretty boy.
Come on!
[Announcer]
Demolition derby
and all about it.
- [Beeps]
- [Announcer]
Oh, look at that.!
- Hey, how'd he do that?
- I don't know,
but nobody makes a fool out of me.
[Announcer]
Apiece of sheet metal
in a viselike maneuver,
but Knight rocketed
right between 'em...
and averted certain destruction.
He hit us.!
He can't do that.
It's against NASCAR regulations.
I don't think this is
a regulation race, Buddy.
- I wonder what this button does.
- Don't start pushing things.
I don't even know
what those things do.
[Announcer] I'll tell you.
When you're in a race like this, you better
have a good, firm grip on that wheel,
because anybody...
Whoa.! Here's a slide-out right now.!
Wow! All right!
[Announcer]
And a spinout by Dolan.
And it appears
that Dolan is stalled over there.
He'd better get that vehicle going fast.
He's a sitting duck.
All right, Buddy.
Just sit tight and don't touch anything.
[Announcer]
A move on our lead car,
driven by Michael Knight,
the daring independent
in that black Trans-Am.
- This wily veteran has the equipment
to catch the Trans-Am.
- [Beeps]
- Uh-oh. Smoke coming out...
- Hey! I can't see!
And he may be disqualified.
Oh.! Crashes the barrier.!
Buddy, take your finger
off that button.
Will Michael Knight
get the black flag?
Nearing the end of the race,
only six cars left...
and now only five...
as the Caddy gets caught
in the intersection there.
Knight's got trouble
getting around the Caddy,
but he barely made it.
Two more cars
flying over that Cadillac,
our field is further reduced.
And now it looks like...
Oh.! Here comes the Lincoln
into the pileup.
[Laughing]
Come to papa. Come to papa.
And now only two are left.
Now you're up against number one.
All right, Buddy. You ready?
Ready.
[Michael]
Here we go.
That car's incredible, Tanya.
[Announcer]
A bump in the road
caused the Trans-Am to go airborne.
And that means the only one
who got to the finish line...
We won! We won! We won!
It's Michael Knight.!
As he takes the checkered flag.
The amazing thing,
from our point of vantage,
ladies and gentlemen...
I want to know
all about that young man.
That makes two of us.
A demolition derby
with a car coming out
without a scratch is unheard of.
An absolute miracle.
And Michael Knight,
the young independent from nowhere...
and I mean literally
from nowhere...
Tanya. You saw what I'm selling.
If you want to know more,
meet me at the House of the Rising Sun.
8:00.
What did you find out about him?
He doesn't exist.
We've checked his credit card
numbers from the club,
car license... everything.
Up until three months ago,
there was no Michael Knight.
Well, phony credentials
don't surprise me.
He said he's here
to sell me something.
- Since when did we go public?
- Since I saw that car perform.
Tanya, it's one thing
to sneak out of a development lab
with secrets to sell,
but quite another
to steal an entire prototype.
I don't like it.
It smells like a setup.
Did you run his fingerprints?
I don't have any.
Anyway, that's a fallacy.
Fingerprints are only on file
if somebody's got a criminal record.
Or has worked for the government
in some law enforcement capacity.
I can think of one way to get 'em,
but it might be a little messy.
Well, I leave that entirely in your hands.
Buddy, come on back here,
and you say thank you.
Come on. Right now,
young man. Come on.
Thank you!
I gotta go tell everybody!
Okay.
You don't look very happy.
I thought it was a real nice day.
Who are you really?
I'm a friend.
I'd like to be...
Michael.
I still hurt from the last man
who made me feel...
I can't go through it again.
Maggie, it's okay.
I understand.
Tell me I'm dreamin'.
[Man]
I see it, but I don't believe it.
She's gonna meet me
at the Rising Sun at 8:00.
Michael, I don't think
it's likely that she'll meet you alone.
I know.
But I doubt she'll get tough
until she satisfies herself
that I'm here alone.
You may have a point there.
Only a fool would be out there
all by himself.
The old man and I
would disagree with you
on that one.
There's two ways to fight a war, Devon.
With an army or all by yourself.
But you can have an army.
That's always been my point.
But not the biggest army.
That's my point.
If you can't outnumber 'em,
you're better off alone.
[Engine Starts]
Hey!
Hey.!
You're gonna get
yourselves killed!
Michael. Michael!
Whoo-ooh!
Hey! Wow!
Man, this thing
must make coffee too.
I do nothing of the kind.
Now, pull over immediately.
- Say what?
- I didn't say nothin'.
Yeah, you did, man.
You said pull over.
I didn't say pull over.
Hey, don'tjive me, Browne.
Because if you didn't say pull over,
somebody else did.
That's right. I did.
Who are you, dude?
[KITT]
That's irrelevant.
You are not the proper owners
of this vehicle,
so either you get out,
or I will take the appropriate measures.
Hey. Hey, hey.
All right!
Now, I've heard of
some far-out burglar alarms,
but this is heavy!
All right, mama.
Do your baddest.
Good heavens.
And I thought Michael was difficult.
[Tires Squealing]
Gentlemen, I have attempted
to dissuade you
from this wayward behavior.
Rave on, machine.
Rave on!
Wh-What do you think he is?
Some kind of tape recorder?
Who cares, man?
It's mine, and I will do with it
as I please.
Watch this.
Whoo-ooh!
Yeah! Whoo-ooh! All right!
[Speaking Spanish]
Very juvenile.
Now watch this.
Hey, man.
What's happening?
Hey, look out!
Whoa!
Where you goin; man?
What are you doing?
Hey, man.
I ain't doin' nothin'.
Hey, well, don't go this way, man.
You're... You're taking us uptown.
And I said I ain't doin' nothin'.
Hey, man. Don't do that.
Man, I ain't doin' nothin'.
I can't stop it!
Come on, man.
Stop this thing, Jackson.
Step on the brake or something.
- I'm steppin' on it!
- Well, then push somethin'.
I don't know what to push.
You push something.
[Browne]
Hey, man. Where is this car
taking us?
- Hey, look out!
- [Tires Screech]
Hey, man.
What's this car doing?
[Both Yelling]
[Groans]
[KITT]
Of all the irresponsible behavior.
To leave me with my keys in the ignition
and my doors open?
I'm sorry.
It won't happen again.
KITT.
I said I was sorry.
- What do you want from me?
- A little consideration
would be a beginning.
I have a lot on my mind,
and we got a lot of work to do.
If it weren't for me,
you'd be walking.
If it weren't for you,
I'd be missing our
most important rendezvous.
The whole point of my mission.
I am very, very grateful to you.
Our mission.
Our mission. Forgiven?
I suppose so.
- After all, we're only human, right?
- Don't press your luck.
It was just a thought.
* I'm gonna harden my heart *
*I'm gonna swallow my tears *
*I'm gonna turn and leave you *
Hi, fellas.
*Here **
Nice race, huh?
Well, uh, let's, uh,
go outside and talk about it.
Well, I'm sorry,
but I'm here to meet a young lady.
Uh, Miss Walker got the message.
She sent us to pick you up.
Tanya did that?
You guys work for her too?
Well, she suggested that we, uh,
show you outsiders...
what we do to people
that come in here and take away
our little prize money.
Oh, didn't Tanya tell you?
I'm donating my share
of the prize money to the charity.
Well, each of us got a little
donation for you too.
[Dolan Chuckling]
Hold this.
No, no. I'm first.
Well, listen, guys,
I hate to mention this, but, uh,
I'm heavily trained in martial arts.
Martial arts!
[Banging, Thumping]
*Hit me with your best shot *
*Fire away *
* You come on with a come-on
You don't fight fair *
*But that's okay
See if I care *
*Knock me down
It's all in vain **
[Groaning]
I want that car examined
from top to bottom,
inside and out.
Yes, sir.
What's that gonna tell us?
Who Michael Knight is working for.
The car is gonna tell us that?
Well, even cars that are
specially designed
require stock parts,
and they have serial numbers.
Benjamin's engineers should be able to
give us a pretty good idea
where the work was done and by whom.
- You're where?
- [Michael]
I'm in jail.
But it's a trumped-up charge.
It always is.
Look, I'm dead serious.
The people we're after here
are practically running the town.
Michael, where is the Knight 2000?
I, uh... I'm not sure.
What do you mean you're not sure?
How can you call me long distance
and tell me you've misplaced it?
I didn't misplace it.
They impounded it.
The trouble is, I think Comtron
talked the sheriff into letting them
check out the car.
Congratulations. You're living up to
my every expectation.
There's no time for insults.
What are we gonna do?
"We." That's wonderful.
A couple of days ago, you practically
drove over my foot to be on your own.
All right.
I'm sorry.
I was a little hasty.
Time's up, boy.
Let's get back to your cell.
Devon, I'm telling you.
I'm counting on you.
You come through now,
we got these people
right where we want 'em.
It'll take me a while to get there.
- We may have to resort to
other means... temporarily.
- What do you mean by that?
Devon. Devon.
Hey, did you guys cut me off?
I demand another phone call.
[Whirring]
[Man]
We've gone through three
diamond-bit drills.
Perhaps I can explain.
- What's this mean? I don't understand.
- The sheriff fingerprinted Knight
when he was arrested.
- These are the results.
- What's this mean? "No identification possible."
Keep reading.
- "Altered."
- "Expertly done."
But still not the man's own prints.
Hey, cowboy.
Hey, I'm talking to you.
Hey, I want to know
what that machine of yours is made of.
Sit and spin.
It's unraveling.
Somebody from a very high level
is breathing down our necks.
Now, it's time to get out.
But we're just a few days from penetrating
all of Comtron's top secrets.
We go for the main one.
I have the access code
to the bubble memory chip
from Benjamin.
It's worth more
than all the others combined.
Now, we get it out of the computer,
and we'll fly out tonight.
Tanya, you're panicking over nothing.
Lfhe had any proof of anything,
he wouldn't be wasting his time
at demolition derbies...
or letting himself get locked up.
- He'd tell the sheriff why he was here.
- Trust me.
I had a feeling
when I looked in his eyes.
He's no ordinary cop.
He's far more dangerous.
Now he has to be eliminated.
Now you go get
Michael Knight out of jail,
and I'll get the microchip design
out of the computer.
You're making things worse.
First time in the can?
No. I used to nose around for
Army Intelligence back in 'Nam.
I got caught once by the 'Cong.
Yeah? What happened?
I had to punish 'em.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah, well, look,
I hope you don't take
what we did to you tonight personally.
No, man. You look like
you already paid your price.
Yeah. You got any friends
on the outside at all?
I mean, you made one phone call,
but I don't think anybody showed up.
- Yeah, I got one friend.
- Hey, that's good.
But we're not on
the best of terms right now.
Oh. That's bad.
[Whirring]
[Power Surging]
[Engine Starts]
[Beeps]
[Tires Squealing]
[Whirring]
Those other drivers...
the ones that tried to beat me up...
they local boys?
Nah.
We all got hired by Wilson,
the new security chief.
I heard about it in stir
when I was gettin' my parole.
Pay is good,
don't have to break too many laws.
You ever wonder why
a nice, polite electronics company
needs strong-arm boys?
[Chuckles]
I don't ask those kind of questions.
[Tires Squealing]
Deputy, I have a court order
for Mr. Knight's release.
Okay. I guess he's yours.
[Tires Squealing]
[Crash]
What's going on back there?
- I don't believe this.
- Must be a drunk.
See if he hurt himself.
I won't even ask you
how you did this, KITT, but thanks.
You're welcome.
Who you talking to?
There's nobody in there.
What in the...
[Deputy]
Those bullets arejust
bouncing off that windshield.!
Knight's escaped.
Let's go.
[Siren Wailing]
Well, it's no use
trying to catch that machine.
Then how are we gonna stop him?
He must be heading out of town.
There's nothing else out this way.
Oh, yes, there is.
[Michael]
Now how do I get up there?
It's times like this I wish I listened
more closely to Devon.
Is it all right to respond?
Yes, yes. It's all right.
Look, KITT,
I gotta get up to a roof about
a hundred feet.
Very well. If you'll set the pressure
adjustment for precisely 600 pounds,
you should land quite gently.
That's it?
I just set the pressure
and hit the button?
It would help
if you also opened the auto roof.
Smart-aleck car.
[Beeps]
- Okay.
- [Beeps]
You guys aren't gonna
believe this, but it's back.
What...
What do you mean it's back?
Back where?
Right out here
on the south parking lot.
Okay. Let's see.
Third floor.
[Tanya]
Where's Knight?
I don't know.
He busted out of jail.
You think he's here?
- There's no way he can get in
without being seen.
- How much do you wanna stake on that?
I'm gonna go back up
to secure the microchip design.
Now, you tell the guards
to shoot to kill.
[Door Closes]
[Phone Ringing]
Yes.
No, everything's okay.
I've got the microfilm,
the new memory chip.
I'll be leaving for the airfield soon.
Alert the pilot.
Tell him I'm flying out
on Benjamin's orders.
Pick up Knight
and meet me at the field.
Very kind of you to organize
the evidence for me, Tanya.
Look. Don't do this.
Whoever you work for
can't be worth what I can do for you.
Would you prefer this?
It's not a starry night in Nevada,
but it'll hurt just as much.
Michael Long.
Look, please don't do this.
If I hadn't done it,
Wilson would have.
He would have shot you.
He gives the orders.
We... We could share millions.
How can we share the millions, Tanya,
if you're not the boss?
Come on, Tanya.
You're the boss.
No one else.
All right. I'm the boss.
But we need somebody like you.
I promise you a very rewarding...
partnership.
Not this time.
[Door Opens]
All right. Hold it right there.
[Tanya]
Shoot him.
I want every guard to check in.
[Man]
I'll take Personnel.
You take Accounting.
[Groans]
[Man On Walkie-talkie]
Nothing in Personnel.
What about you, Baker?
Baker? Baker.
Nothing here.
Well, that wasn't Baker.
Halt.
[Panting]
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
- It's Baker.
- What's goin' on?
Wilson. He wants you up in...
in the administration building.
[Wilson On Walkie-talkie]
All guards be aware that Baker's
uniform has been stolen. Repeat.
The suspect is now wearing
a guard's uniform.
W... W...
Hold it right there, Knight.
I've got him.
Dead in my sight.
Right out here next to his car.
Don't let him move so much
as an inch, and you've got yourself
10,000 in cash, boy.
Yes, sir.
Let's go.
Almost made it.
But I was just a little
too smart for you, fella.
Sorry.
Don't look behind you.
[Whirring]
Oh, no. No.
There's no one behind me
for 200 yards.
- What about the car?
- There's no one in there either.
I looked.
[Gasps]
No, no, don't kill me.
Don't kill me.
I got a dog at home.
I got a sick mother.
All right.
Toss your weapon down
and get against the wall.
[Groaning]
[Siren Wailing]
That Trans-Am's loose
and heading right for us.
Look out!
KITT. KITT, you there?
Where would I go?
Look, I know we've had
some misunderstandings,
but I'm not so sure
I'm gonna be around
at the end of this trip.
If it's of any assurance,
your vital signs are still quite good,
but you do need
immediate medical attention.
[Beeping]
We can't stop, pal.
They're gonna be
coming at us from all directions now.
What can I do?
Any way you can get in touch
with Devon?
You could reach him
on the microwave mobile line.
He's en route to Millston.
Good. Do it. Do it fast.
What in the name of heaven
is going on?
Devon. Devon, they were gonna kill me.
They would have if it weren't for KITT.
Michael, what's wrong?
KITT, what's the matter with Michael?
I'm afraid Mr. Knight's been injured.
His vital signs are deteriorating rapidly.
He's losing blood.
I really feel I should take over.
You're not taking over anything.
You hear me?
Michael, forget everything.
Save yourself.
We can regroup to fight another day.
Don't worry, Devon.
- I'm gonna take us out winners.
- What have you learned?
Tanya and her buddies
are about to rip off Comtron.
Can you prove that?
Right now they're trying to
get away with millions of dollars...
worth of Comtron secrets.
- I'll contact the local police immediately.
- Forget that. They've been bought.
Contact the F.B.I. Or the state police,
have them standing by.
Standing by where?
They're making a run for it
to the airport.
I'm going after 'em.
[Devon]
KITT, can he make it?
You want the truth?
In front of him?
If I'm goin' out,
I'm taking them with me.
This is Chief of Security Wilson.
Patch me in
to Comtron truck dispatch.
I want everything we've got on the road
to stand by for special instructions.
[Chuckles]
- [Michael]
Great.
- What is?
I just figured out how
they intend to stop me.
Okay, KITT.
With all due respect,
you aren't possibly considering...
Oh, my word. You are.
That's right, baby.
Come to papa.
Hey.
Hey. That guy's nuts!
If you're going through with this,
may I suggest you permit me
to activate the turbo boost?
- The what?
- Never mind. Allow me to demonstrate.
[Coughs]
I'm gonna kill him.
I gotta admit,
this car is something else.
KITT. KITT, are you there?
- Come on, buddy.
We both can't pass out.
- We aren't speaking.
At least I know you're all right.
Then you really do care.
- Yeah, I care,
but don't tell anybody, okay?
- Okay.
Dolan. Come in, Dolan.
Did you get him?
I blocked the road and cut him off.
Good work.
Yeah, but he went right through
the side of my trailer.
- Have you been drinking?
- Not yet, but I plan on it.
I'm telling ya. There ain't no way
you're gonna stop that thing.
[Wilson On Radio]
Attention all drivers. Attention all drivers.
Anybody wanting a $15,000 bonus...
is to smash that Trans-Am head-on.
Do you read me?
I said head-on.
He's currently heading north
on Highway 17.
This is Truck 41 on 17.
You're nuts.
What good's $15,000
if you're dead?
Well, jump clear, you idiot.
But make sure you level that Trans-Am.
Forget it.
Make it $25,000 to the first man
that smashes and levels that Trans-Am.
Do you read me? $25,000.
- All right. I'll give it a shot.
- Devon, did you hear that?
[Devon]
I'm afraid so.
You know what KITTcan do. Can he do it?
I can't recall ever having put him
to that precise test.
Oh, great.
I suggest we'd better reach the airport
before we reach the truck.
You know something, KITT.
I think you're right.
[Wilson]
Where are you, 41?
Just coming up to the airport turnoff.
Oh, yeah. I see you.
You've got him.
Just over the next rise.
Here. Just in case he gets by.
We should be seeing them
any minute now.
No one survives a head-on collision
with a semi. No one.
Mr. Knight, this is foolhardy.
- I really must assume control.
- Negative. I'm driving this machine.
Devon, Michael is in no condition
to be making decisions.
KITT, I'm afraid as long as
he's conscious and in the driver's seat,
we have no choice.
An absurd set of circumstances.
Too bad, KITT.
The guy who designed you
believed in the strength of the individual.
We may have to put that to the test.
[Wilson]
He isn't stopping.
The man's nuts.
Well, I hope so.
- Any last thoughts, KITT?
- I wish you hadn't put it that way.
- He's heading right for him.
- We'll need a magnifying glass
and tweezers just to find him.
Or a blotter.
I got him in sight.
Remember, 25 big ones
if you nail him.
- That car just jumped over the truck.
- Don't be ridiculous.
- That's about as close
as you can get.
- Tell me about it.
Take her down. It's up to us.
- He hit us.
- No, you hit us.
Shut up and make another pass.
You want to make another pass,
you can jump out.
We'll be lucky to make the airport.
You get him?
Does it look like it?
Let's get that aircraft rolling.
Not till I finish Knight.
Forget it. Let's go.
You'd better let me take over.
Your reflexes can't handle it.
It's two out in the bottom
of the ninth, KITT.
I'll finish the game.
[Engine Powering Down]
Run for the hangar.
We've gotta find another way out.
I'll get you a way out of here
that nothing can stop.
Tanya, come back here.
You lose, Michael.
No, Tanya. Don't!
The windows are...
[Sirens Wailing]
It's over, KITT.
It's all yours.
I'm getting you to a hospital
as soon as possible.
[Maggie]
Michael, are you sure you're all right?
Yeah.
I'm a little stiff, a little sore,
but the doc says I'm mobile.
That's good.
I don't know
what I'm gonna do with Buddy
now that you're leaving.
Oh, I'd keep him.
He's a real good kid.
You know what I mean.
He needs a man.
I can see that now. L...
I guess I thought
I could just go on not caring.
And not looking.
Stupid, huh?
Here I had a prime candidate
right under my nose, and l...
I chased him away.
Ah, don't consider it
a permanent condition.
You mean that?
I mean, you might
come back and visit us sometime?
Tell Buddy it's a promise.
Oh.
You know, he, uh...
he was hoping you'd take him
for one last ride in your car.
Yeah, well, that might be
one small problem.
Only you could have
dented this car.
Hey. I'm sorry.
Nothing's perfect.
When do I get it back?
Who said anything
about getting it back?
Devon, it's my car.
I have the registration.
Don't remind me.
You know, I'd like to be
getting on with my work soon.
Very well.
Step aboard. We'll discuss it.
Now then, about my car.
Well, simply stated,
Wilton Knight was my friend
as well as my employer.
And my legacy is to see
that his final dream is faithfully pursued,
like it or not.
Your options are still open.
- You don't have to...
- Devon, the old man wanted me.
It was his dying request.
Yes, to rid the world
ofTanya and her friends.
But the rest of his dream
would bore you to tears.
The majority of our activity here
involves legal research,
class-action suits...
strictly bureaucratic stuff.
- What else?
- Yeah, the part he wanted me for.
- Well, Mr. Knight also believed that
under certain circumstances,
direct action might be
the only feasible solution.
That's what the Knight 2000
was designed for.
The pilot program consists
of one man and one car.
Absurd really.
I mean, who would want to
take on such a thing?
I was supposed to be
that man, wasn't I?
Well, he seemed to feel that you were
singularly well-qualified...
to "go it alone, ''as he put it.
But who could expect it of you?
I mean, you barely came through
this misadventure with your life.
Not to mention the damage
to the Knight 2000.
I spent years of my life fighting
criminals of one type or another who always
had the upper hand, and now this.
It's a loner's dream.
It's been handed to me
on a silver platter.
The world's most fantastic car.
All the money and all the resources
of the Knight Foundation.
And most of all,
the best chance I'll ever get
to prove that one man...
really can make a difference.
I was afraid
that would be your attitude.
Well,
shall we drink to what may be
the start of, um...
Of what?
One man's dream.
And to our future.
No matter who it may
take us up against... or where.
[Wilton]
One man can make a difference, Michael.
[Man]
Michael Knight,
a lone crusader in a dangerous world,
the world of the Knight Rider.