[magical incantation]
[howling noise]
That spell, it's awakening the
dark spirits that guard this place.
It's a wolf.
The wizard who sold me this scroll swore
it was a spell of opening, not awakening.
Then the evil spirits were already awake.
Stop thinking about spirits.
Let's think about the treasure that's inside.
Old idols with emeralds and ruby eyes.
Scabbed and encrusted with moon diamonds.
[thunder]
Open it then.
Hurry.
[magical incantation]
Follow me.
Don't be a fool.
It's not real.
Let's get those statues.
[wind howling]
Hold the door!
Ignaz, hold!
Ignaz!
Open that door!
Who are you?
[screaming]
Legend of the Seeker S01E13
"Revenant"
subtitle by rogard
[horse neighing]
RICHARD: The Seeker's last battle had been won.
But the Seeker was mortally wounded.
The Confessor knew that she too was dying,
but she had no thought for herself,
only for him.
Kieran.
My quest is finished.
And now, Vivian,
I am dying.
We die together,
as it should be.
RICHARD: Their deaths were witnessed
only by the Great Wizard Anfortas.
He picked up the sword,
knowing he must keep it hidden
until the rise of a new Seeker,
who might also be asked
to die for a glorious cause.
It's too bad they couldn't have lived
to see the world they've saved.
But they died, knowing
they'd fulfilled their destiny.
And...
at least they died together.
ZEDD: Soon we'll arrive at the crypt of Tavarang,
and you'll see wher the ancient Seeker lies buried.
And there, we'll hide the Box of Orden,
where Darken Rahl will never find it.
Are you sure the Box of Orden
will be safe there?
The outer door is sealed by magic.
And I have the only key to
the crypt where Kieran lies.
It's fitting that he will for one last time
help protect the world against evil.
Richard?
What is it?
I was thinking.
My quest will end
with the death of Darken Rahl.
Are you worried you won't succeed?
No, it's not that.
Then what?
The prophecy says I will defeat Rahl.
It doesn't say what will happen to us.
[magical incantaion]
This way.
Here, look.
There's the story from the book.
There's the Sword of Truth.
It's hard to believe this is the same sword.
It's more than just a story.
This is it.
The inner crypt where Kieran lies.
[magical incantation]
RICHARD: I would've liked to have known him.
ZEDD: Ancient Seeker,
you once defeated those who
would enslave the Midlands.
We ask you to keep this box safe
and aid us once again.
Take the box, Richard.
Place it inside with Kieran.
Where is the remains?
RICHARD: There's nothing here.
No bones, no burial cloth.
ZEDD: I don't understand.
This key has been held only by wizards
since the day Kieran was buried.
Something's not right.
Zedd? The door.
It sealed itself.
[magical incantation]
We must've sprung some sort of
magical trap when we opened the sarcophagus.
We need to find another way out.
Wandering around blindly
we'll get into even worse trouble.
Worse than being trapped alive
in an ancient tomb?
[distant knocking]
What was that?
Maybe this wasn't
some magical trap.
Maybe we're not alone in here.
[sobbing noise from a woman]
Someone's crying.
ZEDD: Richard, be careful.
Who's there?
[crunching and cracking noise from below]
Apparently it's not as hard to
get in as it is to get out.
[distant sobbing continues]
Stop!
Richard!
[echoing] KAHLAN: Richard?
Where are you?
Kahlan, wait!
KAHLAN: Stay where you are.
Wait for me.
[sobbing, gasping]
Kahlan?
Richard.
I'm right here.
Then who was I following?
[sobbing continues]
Who are you?
What do you want?
Don't follow her.
RICHARD: She's crying.
She needs help.
How did she--?
She is not of our realm, Richard.
She's a spirit.
I thought that spirits were supposed
to spend eternity in the underworld.
Most spirits are
content in the underworld,
reunited with the people
that they loved in life.
But sometimes they have
unfinished business.
She was wearing a confessor's dress.
Maybe she was Vivian's spirit.
Vivian helped Kieran complete his quest.
She died with him.
What unfinished business
would she have?
Maybe she's trying to tell us.
There's a door here.
Maybe she was trying
to show us a way out?
Can you open it?
[magical incantation]
MAN: Stop!
Don't open it!
Stay back!
You don't know what you're doing!
The door must not be opened!
No!
Who are you?
Why did you attack us?
I came to steal treasure.
I didn't believe the tales of evil spirits.
But then I found myself possessed by one.
That light that left you?
It was the spirit who has owned me
for five long years.
It forced me to attack you
to keep you from opening that door.
Why?
This place is
full of great evil.
Get out.
Get out while you still can.
We are dealing with
more than one spirit.
One of them led us to this door and the other
tried to kill us to keep us from opening it.
It could be a way out.
Restless spirits
are unpredictable.
I've heard stories of
the spirits of mothers
mourning for their children,
leading them to their deaths.
But Vivian was a confessor.
Even as a spirit she'd
never harm the Seeker.
We should open the door.
I don't know.
What choice do we have?
There is no other way out.
[magical incantation]
It's an ancient language.
The same as the
Book of Counted Shadows.
It says:
"Here lies Kieran, the True Seeker."
Why would his body be
hidden away in a plain casket
when a secret crypt
was built just for him?
We don't know for certain
that his body is even in there.
Let's find out.
Richard, don't.
You don't know what's in there.
RICHARD: Someone's cut off his head.
Why?
This is a wizard's spell.
These magical bindings
keep the spirit
from moving to it's final
resting place in the underworld.
So he's never been reunited with
his family, his loved ones?
That must be why Vivian walks here.
That's why she was crying.
Because the Seeker is trapped here.
She can't be with him.
And she's been waiting for a thousand years
to be reunited with him.
We might wait for her for the next
thousand years if we don't find a way out.
I think this is our way out.
Maybe Vivian trapped us here because
she wanted us to help Kieran.
And maybe, once Kieran's free,
she'll free us too.
Undoing another wizard's
magic is a violation.
So is beheading a Seeker.
Kieran gave up everything for his quest.
His spirit should be with
his father, his mother,
his confessor.
People he loved.
Not trapped here alone in the dark.
I agree, it's terrible, but wizards
don't do things like this lightly.
Who knows what will happen
if we unbind him?
We can't leave him like this,
alone.
Think of everything he sacrificed.
I sincerely hope I don't
end up regretting this.
ZEDD: As I destroy these bindings,
so shall this spirit be free.
As this cloth is consumed by flame,
so shall the bindings release.
[crumbling sound]
Richard!
Can you hear me, boy?
I'm fine.
Are you sure you're not hurt?
ZEDD: Now let's see if that door is open.
Not yet.
Kieran's spirit is free,
but his body is still hidden,
like something shameful.
We need to return him to the crypt.
[Zedd groans]
KAHLAN: When the road you walk is dark,
may you always see the light ahead.
May you always remember
that you do not walk alone.
ZEDD: Now that Kieran is laid to rest,
let us hope our task here is done.
Lead the way.
[threatening music...]
Richard, what are you doing?
Richard!
It's not Richard anymore.
It's Kieran.
Fight this, Richard.
Fight this spirit that possesses you.
He can't hear you anymore.
Richard freed your spirit,
and this is how you repay him?
I'm taking back what that wizard Anfortas
stole from me a thousand years ago.
What are you talking about?
He didn't understand the bond
between Confessor and Seeker.
And he betrayed me.
ANFORTAS: Kieran, Vivian must leave us.
Why?
There is too much between you.
I see it in oyur eyes.
- You love her.
- We've done nothing wrong.
Yet.
I have watched the
two of you growing closer.
Vivian has become a distraction,
and that's putting your quest in jeopardy.
I swear I will
remain true to my quest,
but you must swear
you won't send her away.
Swear it.
I swear.
But Enfortas lied to me.
Just as you lied to him.
I'm a confessor.
I can see that you loved Vivian.
What if I did?
My feelings for Vivian
weren't keeping me from my quest.
But Anfortas wouldn't trust me.
Vivian. Vivian!
Wait!
Where are you going?
Anfortas thinks that it's too dangerous
for me to stay at your side.
How could the?
He swore he wouldn't send you away.
He said that you think more of me
than you do of your quest.
Oh Vivian.
We belong to each other.
We never can,
and you know why.
Because your love would enslave me?
Yes.
Vivian, there's no harm
you could do to me.
Kieran.
Vivian.
I will already do
anything that you ask,
because I'm already yours to command.
She gave in to her passion.
And you were confessed.
She violated her
most sacred duty,
to protect the Seeker.
No.
Our love only
strengthened our bond.
But Anfortas thought as you did.
He was determined to destroy us.
What you did was wrong.
What you're doing now is wrong.
You have to release the Seeker.
Release him?
Why would I do that?
What good does it do you to possess
his body when Vivian is only a spirit,
waiting for you to join
her in the underworld?
Stay back!
You won't do anything to hurt me.
You hurt me,
you hurt your Seeker.
I have no intention
to join Vivian in the Underworld.
I have a body now.
And once I finish with this grace,
Vivian will have a body too.
Yours.
Richard!
Kahlan!
Stay back, creature,
or I'll blast you back to whatever
dark hole you came from.
If you do that, you, your Seeker
and your Confessor will be trapped
in this tomb for all eternity.
Who are you?
I am the spirit of Anfortas.
Wizard to Kieran.
Now when your Seeker killed this body,
I've used an ancient spell of
awakening to occupy it once more.
But I only have a thousand
heatbeats before it dies again,
so listen to me.
- Can you open this door?
- Not until you listen to me.
I'm the one that tried to stop
you from unbinding Kieran's body.
Why?
Because the story you know
of Kieran is a lie.
KAHLAN: How did you come to learn this magic?
Maybe you don't know as much
about Seekers as you thought.
ANFORTAS: One thousand years ago,
Kieran and Vivian did the worst thing
a Seeker and a Confessor could do.
- They consummated their love.
- Yes.
And it ruined Kieran.
He let Count Elrond, his greatest foe,
slip through his fingers
because he thought only of protecting Vivian.
I need to protect my Seeker,
my Confessor.
Now open this door!
You must listen to me!
I went to Vivian
and made it clear she had
a terrible decision to make.
He is unsure in battle.
He thinks of nothing but you.
You must release him.
Do you know what you're asking?
There is only one way to
release a confessed man.
The Seeker can not fulfill his destiny
as long as you are alive.
ZEDD: Has she defied you,
the Seeker remained confessed
and failed his quest because of it.
No, wizard.
Vivian knew her duty.
Vivian!
Vivian, where are you?
Vivian.
Vivian, what have you done?
What I had to, Kieran.
I will wait for you in the underworld.
No.
Vivian.
No, Vivian,
you can't leave me.
Kieran.
You have betrayed me, Anfortas.
I will never stop loving Vivian
or hating you!
I've never seen a look
full of such loathing.
But we had a quest to complete.
I thought once Kieran was no
longer under Vivian's control,
his grief would fade,
and he would come back to himself.
But he didn't.
A normal man,
freed from his Confessor,
would return to his former life
as if nothing had happened.
But a Seeker and a Confessor
have a special bond.
It's stronger than even I could fathom.
And even Vivian's dath could break it.
It was as if Kieran's soul
had been torn from him,
leaving nothing but anger and hate.
When he took up the sword again--
The Sword of Truth feeds on rage.
It made his anger grow.
It overtook him.
It drove him mad.
[screaming with rage]
ANFORTAS: These people weren't soldiers.
You have betrayed innocence.
This world has no innocence.
You have betrayed your quest.
You have tarnished the name of Seeker.
And you took everything from me!
Vivian and I won't be kept apart.
Even if you kill me,
you won't stop me.
I must!
I will!
I feared Kieran's vow,
that he wouldn't rest,
even in death.
I realize in my prey
of the spirits of the underworld,
destroying the peace they'd found in life.
So I had to bind his spirit.
If you had allowed his spirit
to reunite with Vivian,
then Kieran would've found peace
and none of this would be happening!
If you hadn't unbound Kieran,
Kieran wouldn't be trying
to reunite with Vivian now...
in the flesh.
[magical incantation]
Vivian?
Kieran.
My love.
He's using Kahlan's
body as a vessel.
Richard will be confessed.
Yes.
He'll become a monster,
just like Kieran.
Finally what the wizard
stole from us is ours,
forever.
I have enough power left to cast a spell
that will keep him here in the crypt.
Forever.
You can't do that!
Without the Seeker, Darken Rahl will
conquer the world. Thousands will die.
And how many will die if Kieran's
wrath is unleashed upon the world again?
Then let me into the tomb and I will drive
Kieran's spirit from Richard's body.
And if you cannot?
Are you willing to kill your Seeker?
No.
This is wrong.
We can't do this.
We sacrificed our love.
Once we deserve to be happy together.
You said you would wait for me,
and you did.
We're finally together.
We can't throw this chance away.
Richard is more than just the Seeker to me.
That was Kieran to me.
I loved him,
protected him, taught him.
So I hesitated because I loved him.
That hesitation led not only
to the loss of many innocent lives,
it led to the loss of Kieran's soul too.
You led a wizard to my hiding place
where Anfortas had bound me.
Why would you do that if you
didn't want us to be together?
I only did that
so that he would free your spirit.
So we could be together
in the underworld.
Our love is beyond flesh.
That is a lie that the wizard told us,
so we would be content to live without
something everyone else takes for granted.
But this Confessor,
this Seeker,
they have a destiny too.
A destiny that is destroying them,
just as it did us.
They love each other.
I know you can feel it.
This will be a way for them
to be together too.
Oh, Vivian.
I've wanted to touch you for so long.
And I missed you so much.
This is all that matters.
We're all that matters.
If you tell me you don't love me,
I will release you.
Tell me you don't love me,
that you don't want me.
I can't tell you that.
ANFORTAS: The door to the outside world is open.
If you're unwilling to do your duty,
wizard, then leave.
I will do my duty as First Wizard.
Now let me in!
[magical incantation]
You said you could open it.
ANFORTAS: This body is weakening.
I'm not strong enough.
Maybe if you join me.
[magical incantation]
[groans in pain]
Look!
Remember what happened to Kieran.
Death is not the worst fate
that can befall a Seeker.
No!
Stay away, Wizard.
Your Seeker and Confessor are gone.
Kieran, stop!
What are you doing?
This time the story
is gonna end the way it's supposed to.
I won't let you kill him.
Vivian, don't make the Seeker lose everything
for a love that is not even his.
And what about my love for Kieran?
Go back to the underworld
and let Kieran follow you there.
I trusted Anfortas and I waited in
the underworld for a thousand years!
- Alone!
- That won't happen this time.
No.
You'll bind him again
and we'll never be together.
I left him once.
I'll never leave him again.
No!
Anfortas was right about one thing.
A Confessor can be replaced.
A Seeker cannot.
Stop it!
What are you doing?
I will do anything to
protect the Seeker.
Including killing his Confessor!
I will drive Vivian from this body
and I will bind her spirit
so that you'll never be together,
in this world or the next.
Please!
then leave Richard's body and I will allow
Vivian to follow you in the underworld.
Kieran.
Why should I believe you?
Because I do not Anfortas.
I believe a Seeker and a Confessor
belong together, Kieran.
In the Underworld, you and Vivian
can exist in peace.
But you can't be together here.
Your only choice is to trust me, Seeker.
Then this time, Vivian, it is I
who'll be waiting for you in the underworld.
You're free, Vivian.
Go find him.
Thank you, wizard.
Obviously we can't leave the box
in this cursed place.
The Story of Vivian and Kieran,
the one that's in the book...
it's been handed down for a thousand years.
Passed down as truth.
Maybe it was a necessary lie.
People need a heroe.
So the legend can be preserved
no matter what the truth is?
I won't judge Anfortas
for changing the story.
It's a great responsibility
to name a Seeker.
One mistake and send
them spiralling into darkness.
When Kieran possessed me,
I sensed that darkness.
And there was something else.
Something I've never felt before.
A power.
Magical power.
Kieran had magic.
He was strong enough to draw a grace.
How could he do that?
It's Rahl.
- I don't understand.
- It's a tracer cloud.
Powerful magic.
He's tracking us.
I don't think it's us he's focused on.
It's the Box of Orden.
I'll cast a Spell of Obscuring.
[magical incantation]
Following the box won't be
such an easy task for him now.
Where do we take it?
Not we. I.
You can't go off on your own.
I won't allow the box to be the beacon
that leads Rahl to Richard.
I'll rejoin you once I'll hide it.
Where?
It's safer if only I
know the answer to that.
I'll find you once
the box is hidden.
I don't need to tell you both...
Be careful.
I don't like it when
Zedd goes off by himself.
He's willing to take the risk
for the sake of your quest.
In the crypt he was ready to sacrifice you.
He was jsut doing what he had to.
To keep us from becomeing
like Vivian and Kieran.
That won't happen.
They probably thought the same thing.
But in that moment of weakness,
they lost everything.
You know, we're stronger than they were.
I hope you're right.
Love isn't something to fear, Kahlan.
For me it is.
subtitle made by rogard