Yo, what you wanna do?
Let's go down to 40 Street.
I don't feel like goin' there, man.
Let's do somethin' better.
Think of somethin' better.
Come on.
Let's go down to 40...
? Lord, I miss you ?
Hey.
? I've been hangin' on the phone ?
? I've been sleepin' all alone ?
? I want to kiss you ?
Yo, brother.
Hey!
Got a couple twenties
I can hold, my man?
Toss in some plastic while you at it.
For the wash and wax.
Beat it, punks.
Dude think he be MichaelJackson
or somethin', man.
I'm gonna cut you good, sucker.
Can it wait?
I'm a little busy right now.
Absolutely, man.
Hey, nice talkin'to you, boss.
Come on!
?Just because I shake and party
and roll my sexy body ?
? Don't mean
that I'm tryin'to tease ?
? It's called body talk
It's not like the walk ?
? 'Cause this time
you're wearin'bluejeans ?
? You rub your left leg slow
and let your body go ?
? And do a little sexy scream ?
? Ah ?
?Jam this party out
Make your body sweat and shout ?
? A visual sex machine ?
? You're talkin'body talk ?
? Talk body to me
Body talk ?
It's okay.
?Jigglettes gonna slam
Your pimp dolls jam ?
? Let your body talk to me ?
? You're lookin'real fine
You're workin'overtime ?
? You're footloose and fancy free ?
? Body talk
Talk body to me ?
? Body talk ?
? Say, baby, what's that you're doin'?
? Well, it looks like
your body is talkin'to me ?
? I'm hearin'somethin'?
? What's that ?
? Go on
Get it, girl ?
? Ooh ?
? Sexy body ?
? Sure looks good to me ?
? Body talk with me ?
? Sexy body ?
? Oh, babe ?
? Sure looks good to me ?
? Come on and shake your body ?
? I want to hear your body ?
? Your body ?
? So come on and shake your body ?
? I want to hear your body ?
? Your body ?
5,000 street corners
in Greater Miami,
and Gumby here
has gotta pick ours.
So, you think he's gonna show?
He better.
I was up till 5:00 this mornin' trading
shots of tequila with the little bozo
just to close the deal.
It'd be well worth it
if he leads us to this Colombian.
So, anyway,
you lost your temper, right?
You did the hot-blooded
Latin machismo number,
- and you stomped
out of the house, right?
- Yeah, yeah. Something like that.
She's due in five months, Sonny.
I don't want her working
in some greasy spoon.
Maria knows how tough it is
to raise a family on the kind of bread
cops make.
Hell, Eddie, a baby carriage alone
will put you back
a week's take-home.
No wife of mine ought to
have to work for a living.
That's dumb, right?
Hey, shortstop.
You wanna crank down
the decibels a notch?
You got a dime?
I wanna give her a call.
Now you're talkin'.
I just wanna let her know
how much I appreciate the effort.
Maybe take her out on the town tonight
for a little, uh, romance.
What it is? My man!
Showtime, Eddie.
Corky's here.
You can call her later.
Where did I fly in from this time?
Malibu.!
Too much, my man.!
I mean, the whole geocultural
concept of it all, man.
I mean, farmers, man...
Farmers in Bogota.
Bogota to Miami to L.A.
I mean, all that money, man.
Sometimes I feel guilty, man.
You should send
some money there, man.
You should send some money
to sponsor a child
or a farmer, man.
I did.
Hey, Corky. You forget
where the ocean is?
My boat's in the Atlantic.
We're not gonna need
your boat, dude.
Different stash,
and it's already in, so...
Uh-uh. That ain't the plan.
Remember?
Eddie here flashes the cash,
and we take my boat
and pick up the Colombian's stash.
Hey, what Colombian?
Forget him, man.
I got a whole new supplier.
Free enterprise, dude, is the basis
of Western democracy.
Okay, boy scout,
you wanna change the game plan?
I'll change the rules.
It's now 32 grand a key, not 40.
Half the bread now,
the rest contingent upon
a purity test back at my place.
And you pick up Eddie here's expenses...
hotel and airfare. Got it?
Hey, I got profit margins
to consider here, guys,
and that's a rip-off.
Free enterprise, dude.
Take it or leave it.
Ninety-two percent, lab-tested,
pure Peruvian flake, Eddie.
None of that baby-laxed rat poo
they push on the coast.
Root canal quality.
Burnett, I left the scale.
Do you mind?
Check it out, Eddie.
Twelve grand cash.
I was gonna spring 18
for the presidential,
but it just screams dealer.
You know what I mean?
It's nice.
We are gonna make it happen,
my man.
We're gonna do it.
In Miami.
Right here.
And don't worry. I'm gonna get you
some new clothes.
Eddie. No!
Lieutenant?
Yeah, Lieutenant,
it's, uh, C-4 plastics.
Bomb Squad says it's C-4 plastics
rigged up to the trunk lock.
Six keys of cocaine
went up with the Chev, boss.
Those mutts will be up
for the next three weeks.
Watchin'late-night TVand, uh,
jackin'up their phone bill, right?
You guys have got
a sick sense of humor.
- Where's Crockett?
- He's in the patrol car.
He's pretty shaken up
about Eddie, Lieutenant.
Four days ago, we got a line
on that Corky Fowler kid
that bought it back there.
He works for the Colombian.
I was the middleman.
I told him I had a big buyer
in from L.A.
Eddie.
They'd already gotten the word
that I was a legit runner
with a fast boat down at the marina.
After Eddie flashed the cash,
me and Corky were supposed
to make the pickup...
off a Panamanian shrimper
eight miles off Bal Harbour.
Long way from Bal Harbour.
Corky had found a new pipeline
and was gonna cut the Colombian out.
He was goin' into business
for himself, he said.
So this ghost you've been
chasing for two months...
this Colombian drug king...
what makes you so sure
he was behind this?
For God's sake, Lou,
Corky was on his payroll.
Then he decided to go it alone.
Who else could it be?
Haven't changed much
from your old football days,
have you, Sonny?
Listen, Lou...
No! You listen!
I haven't heard word one from you
for a whole stinkin' week.
No case reviews, no updates,
no progress reports.
I was under. I was setting up...
And no backups!
The last time I requested a backup,
I nearly got shot to death...
by Bluto and Lee Harvey Oswald
over there!
And as for progress reports,
I'd just as soon buy radio time.
Hey, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Are you implying that I've got
a bad cop in my department?
All I know is,
every time I've gotten
within 20 blocks of this Colombian,
I've had the pavement pulled
right out from under me.
By the book.
By the book, Sonny, from here on,
or I swear I'm pulling you
off the street.
Sonny.!
Police officers.
I'm sorry.
Hi.
Heard about Eddie.
I'm really sorry, Sonny.
You free for a drink later?
I wish I could, Sonny, but I can't.
I'm workin'.
I'll see ya around.
There's somethin' I gotta do.
Here, Rudolfo.
This is for you.
Ah. What is this, Maria,
the diet plate? Come on.
Rudolfo is what you call
a light eater.
As soon as it gets light,
he starts eating.
Maria.
Hi, Sonny.
¿Qué pasa?
Oh, God!
Just tell me he's okay. Please.
Oh. Oh.!
Tell me he's okay, please.
Tell me he's okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Maria.
It happened about an hour ago.
Eddie got killed.
No!
Ground transportation
to Miami, Miami Beach,
Coral Gables, Coconut Grove
departs from the main concourse level.
Oh, wait. Kids,
no ice cream on the piano.
It's about that time, huh?
Caroline, we're gonna help you
and then go.
It's all right, honey.
Thanks.
Just a little.
Something must have came up
last minute, you know?
Sure.
You know how it is.
- Comes with the territory, Caroline.
- Oh, I know the territory.
Nice of you to make it, Sonny.
Hi, Dad!
Hi, Son.
How's my boy?
And why were you so-so late?
I'm sorry, Son.
I didn't mean to be.
But look what I found for you
on the front lawn.
Can I open it?
Right now.
Hey, man, what's with you?
You're half in the bag,
for God's sakes.
Eddie Rivera got killed today.
Wow! A police car!
Gee, thanks, Dad.
- Awesome.
- You're the best, Dad.
How's Billy takin'all this?
He's six years old, Sonny.
How do you expect him to take it?
Caroline? You suppose if I had been
in some other line of work,
things would have been different?
Doing what?
Dealing real estate?
Selling Porsches
for my brother downtown?
I've been takin'
an informal survey...
of my unit this week,
marriagewise.
Seems out of 16 Vice cops,
we're barely battin'.250.
It's not the job.
Oh, sure, it's got a lot to do with it.
Seeing you shot that time.
And your drinking.
I've been doing
a lot of thinking about it.
I've been doing a lot better...
In a lot of ways, you and your
Vice cop buddies...
than when I started in plainclothes.
Are just the flip side
of the same coin...
I mean...
from these dealers you're always
masquerading around with.
You're all players, Sonny.
You get high on the action.
I'm just gonna check in
on my boy,
and then I'd better be goin'.
You're welcome to spend the night.
I'll make up the couch.
Sonny?
Yeah, you too, babe.
Catch ya later.
Hey, man, look out.
Feed your face later, Leon.
We're gonna do a lap
around the block together.
Maybe some other time, Burnett.
I'm a little hungry right now.
If l...
Why put off
what you can do today?
Drive.
You must be crazy, man.
You get in my car
and you slap barbecue
all over my upholstery.
Man, I've killed people for less.
Spare me the tough talk, Leon.
You and the Colombian already
made your quota for the month.
Car bomb... late yesterday,
59th Street underpass.
People get blown away
all the time in this town...
tryin' to go into business
for themselves, so lighten up.
You also blew away my end
of a $200,000 deal, man.
Now, you tell the Colombian
I want to meet with him
about my commission.
Hey, damn it.
I've seen the man put together
$20 million deals, Burnett.
I'm not just talkin' once either.
There's no way
the man is gonna meet with you.
Unless, of course,
you up your status a bit.
I'll tell you what
I'm gonna do, Burnett.
I got a new shipment
comin' in tonight.
Our original deal is still open
if you're interested.
That's 10 grand
for you and your speedboat.
One hour max...
pickup and delivery.
Look, man, I'm real sorry
about your client and all that,
but that bomb wasn't meant
for nobody else but Corky.
Then again,
there's always buyers.
? I'm just an average man
with an average life ?
? I work from nine to five
Hey, hell, I pay the price ?
? All I want is to be left alone
in my average home ?
? But why do I always feel
like I'm in the twilight zone ?
? And I always feel like
somebody's watchin'me ?
? And I have no privacy ?
? Whoa-oh, I always feel like
somebody's watchin'me ?
? Tell me, is itjust a dream ?
Hey, Lou.
Hey, Lieutenant.
Scotch.
You got it, my man.
What do you got for me?
Jamaican... the one dancin' around
on the floor over there.
Been here three nights in a row
tryin' to score.
? When I'm in the shower
I'm afraid to wash my hair?
? 'Cause I might open my eyes
and find someone standing there ?
? People say I'm crazy
just a little touched ?
? But maybe showers remind me
of Psycho too much ?
Hey, twinkle toes.
Yeah, mon.
We gotta talk.
Cool.
? I always feel like
somebody's watchin'me ?
? Who's playin'tricks on me ?
Keep up the good work, princess.
I love it!
What?
This guy you've been lookin' for.
What do you want with him?
His name is Calderone.
You know him?
Do you?
He's a friend of a friend.
He used to supply a certain...
merchandise...
to a friend who supplied me.
Take your bar jive
back to Brooklyn, Rastas.
You're outta your league.
Hey, listen, man.
I can handle four times the weight
that my friend could.
I got 200 grand
in my "shavin's" kit alone...
and unlimited resources
in New York City.
Excuse me...
while I catch my breath.
Hey, tell him... Teddy Prentiss,
Tooney's friend.
I'll be at this number
until tomorrow night at the latest.
I'll see what I can do
to accommodate you, Prentiss.
More great rock and roll
comin'your way. Let's check temperatures
around the country first.
That cold spell still grips
the Northeast.
Hello.
Speakin'.
Two hours.
I'll be there.
You wanna
slow it down a little bit.
Slow it down a little bit.
It's just around here.
You got the money?
120,000.
You got the party favors?
Got three keys
in the boat.
Hey, look,
I don't know y'all!
Who sent you an invitation?
Since when do you need an invite
to your own party?
I hope you took the keys
out of that monster.
Come on, Scott.
Who do you think
you're dealin' with here?
A guy who's about to lose
a hundred grand worth of speedboat.
Like hell!
A little early,
aren't you, airheads?
You beast, you!
Freeze! Miami Vice!
Congratulations, pal.
New York.
Two weeks.!
Two weeks of legwork
I put in on this bust,
and three-fourths of the dealers
turn out to be cops!
Me, Scottie Wheeler
and Dr. Voodoo here...
putting in a surprise guest appearance
direct from Fun City.
Crockett...
Not to mention Heckle and Jeckle
jumpin' the gun by a good five minutes.
Is that what you mean by team playin'?
What I'm trying to tell you
is there was a foul-up...
You know, my badge says "Miami,"
but lately it's been lookin' a lot
like Disney World.
Shut up, Crockett!
And I'll explain.
Now, Tubbs is here
on priority clearance...
per direct request
of the N.Y.P.D.
Interagency memo, Crockett.
Confidential.
I'd sort oflike to keep it that way,
if you catch my drift.
Hey, no offense, but when it comes
to security leaks,
this town of yours
ain't exactly Pentagon South.
Interesting perspective.
So, uh, tell me now, "Dubbs. '"
Tubbs.
My friends call me Rafael.
Are you down here for some
specific value to the taxpayers,
or are you just workin' on your tan?
Well, hush my mouth!
He's so funny.
You ever hear of a local dealer
named Calderone?
Well, about four weeks ago,
one of our detectives...
set himself up in a meet with Calderone
and a New York pusher named Tooney.
The bust went sour.
Our man was shot to death.
But he took Tooney with him,
and Calderone got away.
New York figures
he's back down here.
Yeah, alongside
5,000 other bush-league pushers...
with five aliases each
and passports to match.
He's a major-league, Crockett.
He killed a cop.
That dude I showed up with tonight
is one of his front men,
and I was settin' him up for a rollover
before you and that cavalry
of yours showed up.
The guy's in town for three days...
already he's an expert.
That "dude" you showed up with tonight
works undercover for the D.E.A., pal.
His name's Scott Wheeler.
And as for Leon,
he's on the payroll of a Colombian
I've been two steps behind
for months now.
Surveillance photo...
taken before the shootout.
Our man, Tooney.
Dude on the right is Calderone.
The Colombian.
Who?
Suspect in a half-dozen
drug murders down here.
Moves a lot of weight.
Yeah?
Well, looks like you two
are after the same man.
Look, instead of beatin' up
on each other,
why don't you guys
consider workin' together?
Forget it.
Night, Lou.
I want a copy of that
first thing tomorrow.
Hey.
Yeah.
Ensign Tubbs
reportin' for duty, sir!
Oh!
Damn it.
Hey, Crockett.
It's a great day to be alive, man.
Yeah, or beat someone to death,
dependin' on your disposition.
What are you doin' here?
Here.
Photocopies of your good friend
Calderone. Remember?
Have some coffee and doughnuts.
Rodriguez told me
I'd find you here...
under the name of Burnett.
- Is that your cover or somethin'?
- That's the general idea, Tubbs.
As far as the locals are concerned,
I'm just another hard-partyin'
ocean guy with questionable means.
With a hundred thousand dollar
cigarette boat and a sideline
of recreational stimulants.
This cop that bought it up in New York...
friend of yours?
Yeah. We knew each other.
Hey, listen, Crockett.
I've been thinkin' about what
Rodriguez said last night...
about us workin' together
on this thing, and I think...
Save your breath, Tubbs.
I got enough problems
with this investigation already...
without playin' tour guide
to some wide-eyed understudy...
down here on a weekend pass.
Wait a second!
No, you wait a second.
You might have commendations
up the ying-yang
in the Bronx or New York...
or wherever the hell it is
you're from,
but this is Miami, pal,
where you can't even
tell the players without a program.
Down here,
you're just another amateur.
And what are you,
God's gift to law enforcement?
From what I hear...
a suspension and misconducts...
and car bombs aside...
you're not the safest...
I guess I asked
for that one, huh?
No. No, you didn't, man.
That was totally outta line.
- You mean that?
- Absolutely.
I couldn't let you handle
all that bad karma by yourself.
You wouldn't happen to have any ice
on this bucket, would you?
Yeah. Down below.
Help yourself.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, hey.! Hey.!
Uh, Crockett.! Hey.!
Officer Tubbs, say hi to Elvis.
Former mascot
of the University of Florida
football Gators.
Currently, he's a watchdog
and resident dope-sniffer
of the St. Vitus Dance.
He got benched his senior year
for takin'a little chomp out of
a Georgia free safety.
Hey, hey! Uh...
Hey, hey! Call him off, man.
I don't even like alligator shoes.
Hey, hey, hey.
Don't talk like that, man.
You're gonna
hurt this feelings.
Don't mind him, Elvis.
He's from New York.
Yeah.
He's ticking.
Alarm clock. Some frat punks
pulled a Captain Hook on him.
And he ate a flight bag full of L.S.D.
On a Key West lab bust last Thursday.
Been a little freaked out
ever since.
But all in all, I feel he's
in a much better environment.
Takes a licking
and keeps on ticking, huh? Whoa.
Gotta move.
Got a bail hearing downtown
on last night's bust.
Leon's long-awaited debut
as a lead vocalist.
Hey, dream on, Crockett.
Leon ain't gonna roll over
on Calderone.
Wanna bet?
Do me a favor, will ya?
Feed ol' Elvis his breakfast for me.
Bon appétit.
Hey! Crockett!
Hey. Nice alligator.
Crockett!
I'll give you seven points
if you take the Dolphins.
For an even hundred.
Leon Mohammed Jefferson,
please approach the bench.
In accordance with prior recommendation
of the state attorney's office...
I'm gonna have to open
a trust fund in your name.
One move,
and you're history, buster.
A little overload problem
on account of the heat,
Your Honor.
Maintenance
is workin' on it.
Not exactly a high watermark
for our physical plant,
but nevertheless
a glowin'testament...
to our constitutional right
to bear arms.
Martha.
Martha?
Put the gun away now.
Now, Mr. Jefferson,
as per recommendation
of the state attorney's office...
and in consideration of your
investigative cooperation
with that office...
What is he talkin' about...
cooperation?
I don't know what he's talking about.
...and release you on your own recognizance.
- I didn't cooperate with no state attorney.!
- Let me take care of this.
- This man's gonna get me killed
talkin' this stuff!
Whose side are you on anyway?
Just get outta my face.!
I advise you to accept
your blessings, Mr. Jefferson.
Your Honor, I didn't cooperate
with no state attorney!
I didn't roll over on nobody!
- I say put a lid on it!
- Are you listenin'?
You're not listenin'to me.!
I said put a lid on it, sir...
Get your stinkin', filthy hands
off of me!
Or I will personally hold you
in contempt of this court.!
I need help!
You're not listenin' to me!
You're not listenin'!
Next case.
I didn't roll over on nobody!
You hear me?
You know anything
about this?
Sonny T. Burnett.
Give me a light.
And quit lookin' so sure of yourself.
There's no guarantees here.
Are you kiddin'?
They practically needed a tow truck
to get Leon out of that courtroom.
Eight-to-five,
he'll be on the horn
within the hour...
screamin' for protective custody
and beggin' to roll.
Hey, Avery just filled me in
on the ride over here.
Very slick, guys.
Very slick.
So, how do you like workin'
with the feds, Scottie?
No complaints so far.
Uh-huh. Yeah, sure.
But I have to admit
I do miss the old days.
We made one hell
of a team.
Get outta here.
I carried you the whole way.
Oh, oh. Smart aleck.
Uh, Line 21, Lieutenant.
He wouldn't give his name though.
Rodriguez.
Yeah, right. Well, uh, I know
all about that, Leon.
Mm-hmm. Well, I, uh, suppose
that depends on you.
All right.
Tell you what. You hold tight there,
and I'll call you back in 10 minutes
and let you know.
Pick him up, Crockett.
He's ready to roll.
? Oh, girls just wanna have fun ?
? The phone rings
in the middle of the night ?
? My father yells
What you gonna do with your life ?
? Oh, Daddy dear
you know you're still number one ?
? But girls, they wanna have fun ?
? Oh, girls just wanna have fun ?
? That's all they really want ?
? Some fun ?
? When the workin'day is done ?
? Oh, girls, they wanna have fun ?
? Oh, girls just wanna have fun ?
Look out.
? Some boys take a beautiful girl ?
? And hide her away
from the rest of the world ?
? I want to be the one
to walk in the sun ?
? And girls, they wanna have fun ?
You're startin' to get
on my nerves, New York.
So, I tailed him down here
from the courthouse.
How'd you know he was here?
It's called protective custody, son.
I'll explain it to you sometime.
? When the workin'day is done ?
? Oh, girls, they wanna have fun ?
? Oh, girls just wanna have fun ?
Surprise, Leon.
I mean, you...
Hey.
Back off, people.
Police.
He's dead.
Is he dead?
You.
I want the film from that camera
and every camera within 50 yards ofhere.
Do it now.
What happened?
Hey, Crockett.
Hey, man.
You know, you and me
been bumping knees and elbows
ever since we first met.
I think it's time
you reconsider my offer, pal.
Hey, man, why don't you
get off of yourself?
You know this investigation
is dead in the water
without me, man.
What are you talking about?
That bust last night.
As far as Calderone's people
are concerned, I made off with both
the party favors and the cash.
I'm gonna be hearing from 'em.
You need me, Crockett.
Well, I don't know
how this is gonna work, Tubbs.
I mean, uh, you're not
exactly up my alley...
style and personawise.
Heaven knows
I'm no box of candy.
But all things considered,
I think we might have to consider
some sort of temporary...
working relationship.
Shouldn't I be asking you
for a search warrant or something?
Got it right here. "Hereby granting
a warranted inspection...
"of one Leon Mohammed
Jefferson's premises...
Charmaine!
This 20th day of, uh..."
Charmaine,
answer the phone, will ya?
Here. Drop it in the mail slot
when you're through.
Hey, man, this is a two-year warranty
on a set of steel-belted radials.
No.
Oh, man. Damn.!
Let's give it
a quick once-over anyway.
Maybe they forgot something.
You enjoy beating
a dead horse, Tubbs?
In football, we call this
a fourth down passing situation.
Yeah.
Crockett.
James "Sonny" Crockett.
Very good, Tubbs.
Next week we'll work on your name.
University of Florida.
All-American wide receiver
number 88. Am I right or what?
Oh, that was a long time ago.
You were sensational.
I remember one time
I watched you run
a screen pass 90 yards...
with 10 seconds left on the clock, man,
for the winning T.D. Against Alabama.
Funky honky.
Ahh! It was 92 yards, Tubbs.
Six seconds remaining.
Yeah, well,
excuse the hell outta me.
You know, not that Vice isn't
the most glamorous gig in the world,
Crockett, but what happened, huh?
I mean, you must have
had half the scouts
in the NFL on your tail.
Traded it all in on two years
in the Southeast Asian Conference.
'Nam?
No, Coney Island.
Hey, what have we here?
It's a phone book.
No names, only numbers.
I'll have Ma Bell
do a back-trace.
You know, Leon was real panicked
outside that courthouse, Crockett.
He must have changed cabs
three or four different times.
I know for a fact
the only tail on him was mine.
So how'd the hitter
know where to find him, huh?
What are you
trying to say, Tubbs?
I'm saying that the only people
who knew Leon was there
were cops.
You know, buddy, you got
a leak in your department
the size of the East River.
Listen, pal, I'll worry
about my department.
Now, unless you got a secretary
back at your motel, I suggest
you scoot on back there...
and wait for the phone to ring.
Lou, I'll see you in a minute.
Uh, Gina.
Hi, sweetheart, look.
I need to ask a favor of you.
Oh, yeah?
Last time you said that,
I ended up babysitting
a sick crocodile
for an afternoon.
Alligator, darling.
Alligator.
Look, I got a couple of rolls of film
I need dropped off at the downtown lab.
Are you gonna be
anywhere near there?
Sonny, I gotta be in costume
and on the pavement
in less than an hour.
How 'bout dinner tonight?
Token of my appreciation.
I'll think about it.
Oh, also, Gina,
uh, could you, uh,
gimme a little file computer readout
on a New York narc named Rafael Tubbs?
Since you're gonna
be there anyway.
Give him an inch,
he thinks he's a ruler.
Sonny.
Line two.
Crockett.
We're back
in business, my man.
Calderone's right hand
just called about the cash.
Name's, uh, Trini DeSoto.
A voice a little on the festive side?
A cross between Tito Puente
and Carol Channing?
You got it, man.
Pick you up in 15 minutes.
Hey. ¿Qué tal, huh?
You see, most of the Marielito riffraff
stuck in detention with me...
killed the time
watching Family Feud,
uh, Hollywood Squares,
In Search of the Ryan's Hope.
All that garbage. Huh?
Not me, man.
I figure, dig it, Trini.
You could be stuck
in this place six months, man,
waiting for your papers.
Use the time, man.
Improve your mind.
You read
a lot of books, huh?
You're missing my point, man.
I skip all that network jive.
I Love Lucy, Father Knows Best,
Leave It To You, Beaver,
Gilligan's Island.
It's where I learn to
speak English so good, man...
The golden age ofTV.
And forget about Desi Arnaz, man.
The fact that dude never got
an Academy Award...
says something very deep
about the American psyche.
New York critics, Trini,
don't let it throw you.
Whatever. Anyway,
I bored you enough
with my background, man.
Do you got the money?
Not until I see Calderone.
Teddy,
I'm his personal representative.
Look, I didn't have to
show here today.
This is strictly gratis.
After that little fiasco last night,
I'm through dealing with a middleman.
You tell Calderone
he wants his cash,
he deals with me,
Teddy Prentiss, personally.
No more intermediaries.
And you, Mr. Burnett,
what's your stake in all this?
Burnett's gonna be handling
all the transportation.
Wise choice, Teddy.
Your reputation
as a boating enthusiast
precedes you, my friend.
If you mean that slack-jawed Leon,
the word I got is
he's done preceded all of us.
Preceded all of us, eh?
That's muy bien, huh?
9:00. Key Biscayne Club, eh? Hmm?
You bring the money.
The dude gives new meaning
to the word "alien."
Come on, let's blow
this pop stand.
You know, Crockett,
I've been doing some thinking
about that possible leak,
and, uh, well, how well do you know
this Lieutenant Rodriguez?
What are you getting at?
Well, he's the point man
in this whole operation.
Whoa! You're down here
on a courtesy pass, New York,
so take a major conversational
detour right now.
Hey, lighten up, man.
Lighten up.
Capisce?
I was just asking.
You were just asking
about a man...
I consider to be one of
the most righteous cops
in the entire country...
and who I've worked with
for six years,
which is six years longer
than I've known you, my friend.
Well, since you know him so well,
maybe you wanna explain
an $18,000 deposit...
he made at First National
10 days ago.
You've been doing makes
on my friends?
I've been doing
a little local research.
It's called staying alive.
I'll explain it to you sometime.
? Walking along
the beach last night ?
? Who do you think I spy ?
? A girl with ebony fire eyes ?
? Soft and low do she cry ?
? Now what could be
such a source of pain ?
? I so boldly inquire ?
That's not true.
That's not what he told me now.
No?
Now, Crockett,
you told me that.
That he volunteered?
Oh, God. You're kidding me.
Aside from an occasional
massage parlor bust,
Sonny Crockett
has never volunteered
for anything his entire life.
Sorry to keep you waiting
so long, Theodore,
Senor Burnett.
I trust dinner
was to your satisfaction.
Righteous, man. Righteous.
Gina and Trudy, my love,
the man, Trini DeSoto.
Los ojos son preciosos.
Well, if you boys will excuse us,
Trudy and I are due for a little
paint and body work.
Muy hermosas, huh?
It's in the coat check...
120 even.
Good faith money, man.
A working relationship,
remember?
I love this place, man.
Pretty people,
first-class restrooms,
selective door policy.
? Only in Miami ?
? Is Cuba so far away ??
Trini, come back, baby.
Come back.
Don't mind me, man.
I've been up four days running.
What kind of weight
are we talking about, Teddy?
I can have 10 million U.S.
At my disposal by noon tomorrow.
Forty grand a key.
You figure it out.
I no making any promises,
but you have arrived
at a very opportunistic time.
Tell me about this killer boat
of yours, Burnett.
Thirty-nine feet, all engine.
It can handle a good 80 keys
and still outrun anything
that the Coast Guard's got.
In that case, you might
wanna have a second one
of the same on call.
Toda está bien.
If you hear from us at all,
it'll be sometime tomorrow.
We'll be at the boat number,
day or night.
Not so fast, Trini, man.
You said Calderone would be here.
He has been.
Compliments from the gentleman
across the room, sir.
Come on, y'all.
Tubbs.
? Ba-da ?
? Whoa-oa-oa ?
? Well, my friends
the time has come ?
? To raise the roof
and have some fun ?
? Throw away the work to be done ?
? Let the music play on
play on, play on ?
? Everybody sing
everybody dance ?
? Lose yourself in wild romance ?
? We're going to party
Come on and fiesta, forever ?
? Come on and sing along ?
? We're going to party
Come on and fiesta, wherever?
? Come on and sing along ?
? All night long ?
? All night ?
? All night, all night long ?
Hospitable gesture,
Mr. Calderone.
Thank you.
I look forward to doing
business with you.
Welcome to Miami,
Senor Prentiss.
? See the rhythm all in their feet ?
? Life is good wild and sweet ?
? Let the music play on
play on, play on ?
? Feel it in your heart
and feel it in your soul ?
? And let the music take control ?
? We're going to party ?
? Come on and fiesta, forever?
? Come on and sing my song ?
? All night long ?
What are you
gonna do, huh?
A regular Hoover convention
in the loo tonight.
Six legs to a stall.
I guess that's why they call it
the powder room, dear.
Hey, partner, you okay?
Yeah, mon, everything irie.
Champagne, anybody?
Look, I don't know about
you party types, but I gotta
be at work tomorrow.
So, can I just drop anyone?
Yeah, me.
Okay. I'll talk to you tomorrow.
Good night.
Good night, Trudy.
Good night, Tubbs.
I thought he said
his name was Prentiss.
No, it's Rafael Tubbs.
Did the, uh, computer
come back with anything?
Yeah, it sure did.
I don't know who
that joker is, Crockett,
but according to the readout,
Detective Rafael Tubbs
has been dead and buried
over three weeks now.
Come on,
pick up the phone, man.
Pick it up.
I mean, who knows
who this guy is working for.
D.E.A.? I.R.S.?
State? County?
Never trust anyone
in this business.
Damn it.
For all I know,
he could be working
for Calderone.
Well, unless you wanna wait
outside his hotel room all night,
there's not a hell of a lot
you can do about it now anyway.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm getting too old
for this line of work.
Scraping by on four hours
of sleep a day.
Living undercover
for weeks at a time.
Dealer this week,
outlaw biker the next.
It's Tuesday?
I must be working drugs.
Hell on the old nervous system,
I'll tell you.
- Disastrous on a marriage.
- I know.
- Huh?
- The kind of work we do.
It's tough on a relationship.
You ever forget who you are?
Forget who I am?
Darling, sometimes
I remember who I am.
But what the heck.
I'm not complaining.
I got a terrific
six-year-old boy.
Six years old.
Two boats,
one freaked-out alligator.
And a just-announced
free agency in the Southeast
string bikini league.
It's like the song says,
"She left me at Sears
and I cried all the way to Walgreens."
You can play that
beach bum, cowboy routine
with the football lingo...
and the beer commercial mentality
from now till doomsday,
but I don't believe it.
You know something, Gina.
You can be a real pain
in the butt sometimes.
But I like you.
I like you a lot.
I like you too, Sonny.
Oh, really.
Well, why have you tossed
four dinner invitations
in three weeks back at me?
And you wouldn't have come along
tonight if you hadn't had Trudy
along to block tackle.
My father
always told me, Crockett,
never to get involved
with a man on the rebound.
And as far as I'm concerned,
you're bouncing so hard,
you're practically
out of the ballpark.
What the hell
is that supposed to mean?
You're still in love with Caroline.
Try again, lady.
What are you looking at?
Mm-mm-mm.
I'm in Miami.
Mm-mm-mm!
Gina?
Hey, Crockett.
Rise and shine, buddy boy.
Crockett.!
Whoa, Elvis.
Hey, Crockett,
now you tell this lapdog of yours
he makes any false moves,
I'm gonna make a suitcase
out of him.
Crockett?
Crockett.
This here's
a flare gun, sucker.
So, unless you want
your entire intestinal tract
lit up like Cape Canaveral,
you got exactly 10 seconds
to tell me who you are.
You crazy, man?
What are you...
Eight seconds!
What are you talking about, man?
You know who I am!
Rafael Tubbs died three weeks ago
in that New York shootout
with Calderone.
Four seconds.
Who are you, man?
His brother.
I'm his brother, Crockett!
I know we all look alike
to you Southern crackers,
but not this much.
Look at the picture, man.
Look at it!
Rafael was the best.
He was the reason
why I became a cop.
I.D.'s in my right pocket, man.
Ricardo Tubbs, the Bronx.
Armed Robbery Division?
Why?
Homicide up north
wasn't getting anywhere.
The interdepartmental memo?
Priority security clearance?
All forged.
How else could I have
gotten down here?
A Bronx street cop
on a Brooklyn narcotics
investigation?
Tell 'em there was
a death in the family?
Or as a veteran detective
first-class on assignment?
That bastard killed my brother.
Counterfeit setup bread,
fake memos,
forged security clearance.
Gee... God!
The biggest score of my entire
godforsaken career,
and I'm teamed up with
some outlaw New York street cop...
out on a hit mission.
It's called justice, Crockett.
It's called vengeance, my friend.
Plain and simple.
Now, I may seem somewhat
unorthodox to the untrained eye,
but when it comes to being a cop,
I am strictly business, pal.
And I'll be damned
if I'm gonna put my life on the line
with some outlaw cop...
on a personal vendetta.
'Cause when it gets personal,
it gets messy.
And when it gets messy,
the wrong people get killed.
¿Comprende?
I'm blowing the whistle
to Rodriguez.
You're out of this operation,
Tubbs, as of now.
There is no operation
without me, Crockett.
Calderone will back out
of this place so fast,
it'll make your badge spin.
It's probably them now.
Four people dead,
two months'work
and all for nothing?
Crockett, please!
Answer it.
Yeah, mon.
Three hundred pounds?
8:00 tonight
off Virginia Key.
Geez.
Panamanian registered shrimp boat.
Terrific.
Oh, I took the liberty
of calling a little pregame
strategy meeting about, uh,
10 minutes for all the backups...
Switek, Zito, Hoban, Dibble,
Gorman and Augustine.
I figure we run down
the fine points then?
Terrific. Great.
Uh, what about, uh, Tubbs?
I got him low-profiling it
on my boat till the party starts.
Lieutenant, you've got a call
from a Sister Agnes
at Immaculate Heart.
Uh, ye... Um, look, uh,
I'll have to get back to her.
Immaculate Heart?
Yeah.
I'm sending my boy Hector
there in the fall.
Good school.
Expensive too.
Wish I could afford
to send Billy there.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing, Lou.
Seems like an awfully tough nut
to make on a lieutenant's salary.
What's the matter
with you, Crockett?
If you wanna know
where I got the money,
just ask me.
Okay, Lou,
where'd you get the money?
None of your business.
Get outta here.
You got the name trace yet
on those phone numbers
we found in Leon's apartment?
Should have them
in about an hour for you, Sonny.
For my eyes only, pal.
I need some blowups.
Here and here.
High-priority rush.
Yo, Crock.
Whenever you're ready,
Professor.
Be with you
in a minute, girls.
Sonny, you got
that Mendoza case?
L... Just a minute, Trudy.
Gina, I, uh, got everything
straightened out on Tubbs.
It was a little computer mix-up.
You, uh, sure made
a fast exit this morning.
I got nothing to say to you.
Gina, what are you...
Gina!
Hey, Gina. Gina, wait.
What are you so mad about?
Think about it.
I'll get back to you.
Gina, look.
What are you doing in here?
Get out!
Look, I didn't plan
for that to happen last night.
But I think it's pretty terrific
that it did.
Sensational, Crockett.
Full moon, the boat,
a few drinks too many,
soft music, uh,
a little sudden onboard romance.
What's so bad about that?
Do you mind?
Funny thing is, is you know
I almost believed you
till this morning.
Nothing like having some guy
roll over at sunup and whisper
his ex-wife's name in your ear...
to boost your self-image.
Gina, I'm really sorry.
This is the last situation
I wanted to find myself in, Crockett.
I don't need it.
Do you understand?
You know what...
You know what upsets me the most?
Is that I let it happen
because I wanted it to happen.
Hey, Elvis.
? You ain't nothin'
but an alligator ?
?Just a-cryin' all the time ?
? You ain't never caught a rabbit
and you ain't no friend of mine ??
Hey, Waylon Jennings.
GeorgeJones.
Jimmy Buffet.
Dickey Betts.
Waylon Jennings.
Hey, Elvis, where does
Crockett get his music?
Sears and Roebuck catalog?
Oh, yeah.
Be cool, man.
Let me see how this goes.
St. Vitus Dance.
Hey, Trini, mon.
What happening?
What do you mean...
change in plan?
No, no, no change in plan, man.
In 40 minutes.
I'll be there.
Sonny Crockett.
Switek, Zito and Augustine
in the Cobra out of Key Biscayne.
Hoban, Dibble, and Gorman
in the 39-foot cigarette
out of Fisher Island.
Two Metro choppers
and the C.G. Cutter
won't be given final coordinates...
until 30 minutes
before blastoff.
Any questions?
Yeah, I got a question.
You roll some fruit
for that shirt, or what?
As a matter of fact, Stan,
your old lady gave me this shirt,
and it wasn't my birthday.
Okay, weapons check
and final pep rally
back here at 1800, girls.
That's big hand on the 12,
little hand on the six.
Get outta here.
Oh, grow up.
Look at this.
Yea! Yea!
Say, baby.
Wheeler.
If Wheeler's the leak,
then DeSoto knows Tubbs is a cop.
Didn't wanna
bust up the lecture
with any phone calls, Sonny,
but a guy named Tubbs
called about 20 minutes ago.
He said he's rushing out
for a meeting with
a Trini DeSoto or something.
Waiting's over, dead man.
Tubbs... you okay?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Tell Rodriguez to meet me
at 550 Belinda Street.
Tell him I found the leak.
Hey, Sonny.
What brings you out
to this neck of the woods?
Come in, come in, come in.
Hey, uh, Donna, look who's here.
Hey, Sonny. I hope
you brought an appetite.
Hi, gang.
Uncle Sonny,
Mom's cooking spaghetti.
Are you gonna eat?
No, not this time, son.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
You're gonna be sorry.
I know.
What's up?
If that's not enough,
I've got a list of payoffs
from DeSoto's place.
I think we'd better
handle this outside.
Um, uh, honey,
I've got some business.
Um, I'll be right back.
Don't be long, okay?
No, no, I won't.
Three months behind
on the mortgage.
Thirty-six grand in ScottJr.'s
medical expenses last year alone.
And me clearing
a lousy 30 a year,
getting shot at by guys
who blow that much
in a restaurant in a month.
Six months ago, a guy comes up to me
outside of a club in Little Havana.
Hands me a suitcase.
He says, " Compliments
of Mr. Calderone."
Nothing else.
Just... compliments.
I didn't even open
the damn thing for two weeks.
Sonny...
How much?
How much to buy you, Scottie?
Seventy grand.
The calls from DeSoto
started about a month later.
Information.
That's all they wanted
was information.
Information?
I tried to pull out
at least a dozen times,
but it was too late.
I mean, I never expected
anybody to get killed.
They changed the game plan
on us, Scott.
Is it still going down
tonight?
Yeah.
Where?
You gotta help me, man.
I got a family.
Where? Where?
I got 15 years
as a stand-up cop.
I got two medals of valor.
I took a bullet for you,
for God's sakes.
They're runnin' a sports fishing boat
out of Keys Marina.
The drop-off's up river.
Am I, uh,
am I missing something here,
or what, Scottie?
I don't get it.
I don't understand this.
You were my partner.
I had you and Donna
and the kids over to dinner,
what, 20 or 30 times.
Thanksgiving, birthdays.
I trusted you!
I trusted you, you bastard!
Crockett!
? I can feel it coming
in the air tonight ?
? Oh, Lord ?
How much time we got?
? I've been waiting
for this moment ?
Twenty-five minutes.
? All of my life ?
? Oh, Lord ?
? Can you feel it
coming in the air tonight ?
? Oh, Lord ?
? Well, if you told me
you were drowning ?
? I would not lend a hand ?
Honey, don't do that.
Come on, use your spoon.
You know better than that.
I want to eat it like this.
No. Hello.
? But I don't know
if you know who I am ?
Caroline.
Sonny?
I need to know something, Caroline.
The way we used to be together.
L-I don't mean lately,
but before.
? It's all been a pack oflies ?
It was real, wasn't it?
? Well, I remember?
Yeah, it was.
? I remember don't worry ?
You bet it was.
? How could I ever forget ?
Sonny, what's wrong?
? The first time ?
? The last time we ever met ?
Nothing, Caroline.
? But I know the reason why
you keep your silence up ?
? No, you don't fool me ?
? Well, the hurt doesn't show ?
? But the pain still grows ?
? Some stranger to you and me ?
? I can feel it coming
in the air tonight ?
? Oh, Lord ?
? I've been waiting for this moment
all of my life ?
? Oh, Lord ?
? I can feel it
in the air tonight ?
? Oh, Lord ?
? Oh, Lord
Oh, Lord, oh ?
? But I've been waiting
for this moment ?
? For all my life ?
? Oh, Lord
Oh, Lord ?
Hey, hold on, pal.
Why, I forgot something?
Yeah, us.
Miguel, Tito, adelante.
Freeze!
Miami Vice, drop 'em!
Drop 'em.
Mátalo.
Come on, you $400-a-week cop.
It's getting late.
Gotta arrest me now.
You're not gonna
shoot me, are you?
It's against the law.
Tubbs, not like this, man.
Not like this, Tubbs.
Contact a female subject
at 1549 East Charleston.
1549 East Charleston
will be at the Bell, Book and Candle.
What do you mean
you're gonna transfer him?
What's wrong with this jail?
By hiding Calderone away
in an out-of-town lockup,
we buy the D.A. Enough time
to prepare a no-bail plea
at the preliminary tomorrow.
Yeah, but he's
still due a phone call.
Can't his people just hire
some crooked judge to cruise on up
to the suburbs and spring him?
Nobody will know
he's in the suburbs,
not even Calderone himself.
We're transferring him
in a blacked-out paddy wagon.
Because I don't like those people.
Hey, Dolan,
you're a genius.
Look, honey, if you wanna
eat with those people,
you eat with them.
Come on. Tonight.
Honey, I'll call you back.
I gotta go.
Transfer of a prisoner...
Calderone, Orlando.
Let's see.
Cabanez, Cadwood,
Caldoni, Calderone.
Oh, yeah.
How he got
some judge in here...
this hour of the morning
beats the hell out of me.
- What judge?
- Ajudge?
- Where is he?
- He's gone.
What do you mean gone?
How could you let him go?
- Had to. He had a judge with him.
- How long ago?
I don't know... 10, 15 minutes.
What's the big deal?
Nobody skips
on two million dollars bail.
Gonna need two units
at 244 Baycrest Drive.
No, 4-4.
It's a residence.
Yeah.
Come on. Come on.!
The hell with the channels,
there's not enough time.!
- For cryin' out loud!
- Run it!
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault, man.
He'll be back.
New name, new people.
But he'll be back.
Hell, this is
the Sunshine State, right?
I guess you got a job
to get back to up there
in New York, hey, Tubbs?
Get outta here, Crockett.
You kidding?
After the little show
I put on down here hits the fan,
I'll be lucky
to get back on payroll
as a meter maid.
Hey, Tubbs,
you ever consider a career
in Southern law enforcement?
Maybe.