Check this out.
I'm the only truck in town
that's got soft-serve.
I know what you're thinking,
but I got a great deal on this truck.
I'm thinking I haven't seen
you this excited
since I took you to the Bronx zoo
for your eighth birthday.
I know you were worried
about me, okay?
But you don't need to be,
not anymore.
I knew you'd turn it around.
There you go, sweet pea.
Oh.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Enjoy.
Ice cream sandwich.
Hey.
Sir!
- Hey, I need two vanilla cones.
- Okay.
Sorry.
Just give me a sec.
Hello?
Without further ado,
I give you one of this organization's
biggest champions,
senator Charles Irving.
He's got a gun!
Darren!
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com
"Hey, Birkhoff,
I need to use your computer.
Is that cool?"
"Sure, Nikki.
Thanks for asking."
Birkhoff, I need to borrow
100 grand.
Is that cool?
See how easy that--
wait a minute. What?
We have a lead
that could help us identify
another member of oversight.
We have a lead?
Spain's defense minister
is doing business
with an oversight member.
One of his staffers is willing
to sell us the identity,
but he needs a lot of money
and in 24 hours.
So we're also gonna have to take
your jet to Lisbon.
Hmm.
No.
No?
Get used to that sound, baby.
'Cause I'm not joining you
on some crusade
to take down oversight.
And you are not taking
my jet anywhere.
Right, because this is
about you,
right, Shadow Walker?
Well, it is my life...
And my house.
In fact, I think you and Mikey
should start looking for new digs.
Guys...
There's something
that you need to see.
The suspect was shot twice
by the senator's security detail.
Eyewitnesses describe Lancaster
as being in a trance-like state.
This is P9.
No way.
Nobody got out alive.
Apparently, the kid
just suddenly changed.
People said he looked like
he was in a trance.
P9?
Do you remember Eustice,
the militia group that got
into the siege
with the FBI in 2003?
Yeah, FBI raided the compound,
and they burnt the whole cult down.
Ah, it was no cult.
That was a cover.
The compound housed a program
to breed assassins...
P9.
An assassination program
that's different from division?
Way more x-files...
They used a super-teched-out
version of hypnosis,
neurohypnotic reprogramming.
When they were done,
they put those people
back in the world
with no idea
what had happened to them...
Sleepers.
How do you know all this?
Because those weren't
FBI agents
who burned down the compound.
It was division.
Division was sent
to clean up P9
after a sleeper went awol and
shot two policemen in Eustice.
The question should be,
why has it resurfaced?
I take it oversight
didn't brief you on P9...
One of their less successful
programs.
So the idea was abducting
foreign nationals
and brainwashing them.
The idea was a clean strike.
Say you wanted to assassinate
the president of Pakistan.
Why send in seal team 6...
When you can get
the local ice cream man
to do it for you?
And then commit suicide.
The hits look like
random acts of violence
from mentally disturbed individuals.
Personally, I found it disgusting.
Why? Because you prefer
more old-school
brainwashing techniques?
Because the concept is flawed,
just like its creator was.
Oversight had hired
Dr. Joseph Mars,
a brilliant neuropsychiatrist
who specialized in brain waves.
He was killed
along with everyone else.
Man.
I can still hear the sounds
from that day...Screams.
Clear the perimeter,
then exfil.
Copy that.
Yeah, I...
Supervised the raid from ops.
What happened
to those people is terrible,
but the chances
of this being P9, I mean...
They said Lancaster was happy.
He was doing well.
He just put 10k down
for an ice cream truck.
Does that sound like somebody
who's planning to commit
an assassination?
Birkhoff, transfer the schematics
for the Eustice compound to my phone.
That should give us
an hour or two to get there.
Michael, we leave
for Lisbon tonight, remember?
- Change of plans.
- Whoa.
We can't just drop everything
because you have a hunch, okay?
Our contact is waiting for us.
If we don't show,
he will get spooked.
I understand.
If P9 is back...
If...
Lisbon is real.
We've been waiting months
for a shot like this.
If you think Lisbon
is more important,
then you go.
If I think Lisbon's
more important?
Wait a minute.
So taking down oversight,
putting a dent in them...
All of the sudden,
not a priority for you.
If I'm right, God only knows
how many sleepers are out there
and how many assassinations
are planned.
Oversight can wait.
This can't.
As much as I love hosting
couples therapy,
you guys need to hit Craiglist.
You got to the end of the week.
I'm sure this is
very difficult for you.
I'm getting better.
Some wounds heal
quicker than others.
Something tells me
you didn't come here
just to talk about my health.
I'd like you to talk to Percy
about an old mission...
Operation falling ash.
- Is Nikita involved?
- No.
I'm sure you've heard
about the attempt
on the senator.
Oversight is concerned
an old pet project
may be to blame,
and Percy might be able
to allay their fears.
Think of it as a favor.
Friends do favors
for each other.
I don't think we're there yet.
I think your current condition
is evidence
of how fleeting friendships can be.
Our relationship is different.
I'm your business partner.
As such, I'll provide
necessary incentive.
I don't think a pair
of $500 heels
is gonna do me much good right now.
What if I were to provide you
with a list
of the men close to Sergei Semak...
All his top brass?
Exactly what do you need me
to find out from Percy?
If there were any loose ends
on P9 or Eustice...
Anything else we should know.
I thought this
was a restricted area.
What changed your mind?
I thought about you here alone,
and I didn't like it.
But you still don't believe me.
I believe in you...
And in us.
What are we looking for?
Part of the original
objective here
was to retrieve the research
Dr. Mars kept on file,
something we failed to do in '03.
Probably because
it burnt up in the fire.
Maybe, maybe not.
But according to Percy's
private notes on the box,
Mars had a private safe
hidden in his office.
Have you ever read
any Dostoyevsky?
No.
Tolstoy?
You Russians really know
your pain, don't you?
I need to ask you
about an old mission.
At the moment,
I'm more interested
in your new wounds.
They look like they go deep.
Falling ash...
Tell me what happened.
You first.
I encountered Nikita
in the field.
She tried to kill you
and failed?
She tried to dissuade me
from my mission and failed.
Her tactics seem pretty brutal.
Have they made you
reevaluate your own?
There is a value
in an eye for an eye, you know...
Or a leg for a leg.
But I guess that's your problem.
Let's talk about mine.
If oversight wants me to fill in
their missing piece of the puzzle,
I will require the following...
A pot of hot water,
a bag of Earl Grey on the side,
every morning, 7:00 a.M.--
proper English tea.
You can smoke the tea leaves,
for all I care.
Just start talking.
We radioed the doctor,
told him to line up everyone
for extraction.
They thought the killers
coming through the door
were a rescue team.
No wonder this place
feels haunted.
Nikita.
Owen?
Owen, what are you doing here?
What the hell
are you doing here?
Answer the question.
I know about this place
'cause I was on the strike team
that burned it down.
Now answer my question.
I quarterbacked the op.
So you saw that kid
on the news.
You came to track down the survivor.
There were no survivors.
Owen, what survivor?
The guy that invented
the program...
Joseph Mars.
I saved his life.
It's ironic, isn't it,
but an organization
known as oversight
should have such little foresight?
Meaning what?
They wanted to eliminate
Joseph Mars
along with the rest of P9,
which would have been
a terrible waste.
Nobody knew their way
around the human brain
better than he did.
Percy ordered me
to extract Mars.
But he didn't want anybody to know.
That's why everyone else had to die.
Mars knew that stimulating
certain parts of the brain
would improve focus, the senses.
So Percy had him create something
to give division agents an edge.
The regimen.
- How low is your supply?
- It's getting low.
Want to warn us before you turn
into the Tasmanian devil again?
I find Mars,
I find my way off of it.
Before the attack
on the senator yesterday,
I didn't even know
if the guy was still alive.
Last time I saw him,
he was trying to take
his research with him.
But there was no time.
Looks like he made the time
to come back for it.
For two years,
Mars worked for me
under lock and key.
And then he just disappeared
into thin air.
You're telling me
you have no idea where he went,
- how he got out?
- No idea.
But I can tell you this.
When the next shooter makes
an attempt on the senator,
it'll look like a copycat...
Another lonely lunatic
gone off the rails.
By the way, I saved the data
for falling ash on the black box.
Assuming she's read the file,
I imagine Nikita will come
to the same conclusions.
What makes you think
there'll be another attack?
If at first
you don't succeed...
...Made a statement condemning
the act of violence.
I am uninjured.
And I will not let the act
of a lone, troubled individual
derail my duties.
Dr. Mars,
have you dispatched another?
They're in place,
awaiting activation.
Read & unite is possible
because of you,
so thank you.
And grab a cocktail while you can.
You clean up nice.
First time I've seen you
look like a girl.
Owen, we need to work
on your compliment skills.
Keep an eye out
for people on cell phones.
I'm guessing that's how Mars
activates his sleeper.
I think I got him...
Thick black glasses, on his cell.
Heading towards the senator.
Feed the Siamese
fighting fish first.
Then...
Do you mind?
Ugh.
False alarm.
I put you guys
next to the senator's table
so you can rub elbows
with the bigwigs.
This is Alicia.
Purple dress...
She's headed toward the senator.
Hurry.
I got her.
Got her.
Down on the ground.
Down. Let's go.
So where'd you get a black box?
Come on, Nikita.
I'm not stupid.
The things you know
about P9 and the op,
all those details...
I was on the ground.
I don't know half that stuff.
Michael took Percy's
master drive
when he left division.
So you peeked inside it?
I thought you were
"miss destroy all boxes."
He convinced me that this one
we would use for good.
Oh.
So you and Michael can handle
all the dangerous secrets,
but I can't.
Am I wrong?
The last time I saw you--
- I was suffering
from regimen withdrawal
when I tried to upload
the box in London.
I wasn't in a sound state of mind.
I'm better now, Nikita.
You still need a cure.
Yeah, and once I get it,
I'm gonna hunt down the rest
of Percy's guardians,
and I'm gonna destroy
their black boxes.
And then I'm gonna finish Percy.
You think I can handle that, right?
- I won't stop you.
- You mean you won't try.
What...
Who are you?
What am I doing here?
We had to get you
away from the cops,
but you're safe here.
Oh, my God.
Is that me?
Oh.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Look, I know this is scary.
Nothing makes sense.
But you have to trust me.
The search continues.
Everyone in the tri-state area
with a badge and a gun
is looking for this girl.
They track her back here,
and I'm toast.
We are the only ones
who know she's innocent.
We have to help her.
There is no we, okay?
There is me, and there is you.
Now, get rid of her, or you
and your super-friends crew
gots to go.
Don't give me the goatee
of intimidation, okay?
I know you won't hurt me.
No, but I might.
Those are mine, man.
You're kind of small.
You'd dissolve quick.
Whatever.
Just remember,
you're on your own with this one.
Okay.
I was gonna kill him.
I mean, I-I don't even kill spiders
when I find them at home.
I believe you, Alicia.
Someone did this to you.
They trained you to kill
without giving you a choice.
But that's...
How?
I don't remember anything.
What about him?
That's Dr. Francis
from the Vory clinic.
I, uh...
Went to rehab there...
Pain pills.
Well, you got clean.
That's all that matters.
I tell myself the same thing
every day.
I tried n.A.,
therapy.
Nothing worked.
Then one day I got this letter
from Vory.
They said they could change
the feedback loops in your brain
so you wouldn't crave a fix.
I figured I had nothing to lose.
What do you mean,
change the feedback loops?
I'd...I'd wear these headphones
and sensors
to monitor my brain waves.
Then I'd get kind of sleepy, and...
Next thing I knew, I was awake,
and that need...
You know that feeling?
- Yeah.
- It was gone.
Oh, my God.
You mean this whole time
it was Dr. Francis?
We got to raid the clinic
and grab him.
There are rehab patients
in there.
We need to find out how many
and what kind of security
Mars is using.
Mars would recognize Owen.
He wouldn't recognize me.
Michael, my love.
Jag officer, yes.
Junkie, no.
Hey, I've passed as worse.
Infiltration is our best chance
at getting recon.
I know.
That's why I'm going.
Excuse me.
I think I need help.
I'm in.
I have ten minutes
to fill out a questionnaire.
Do you see Mars?
No.
No, they must do the treatments
in another wing or something.
I'll let you know what I find.
Okay.
Nikita, be careful.
You get how lucky you are?
You got out of division
with the woman you love.
That's what I used to want
for me and Emily.
Yeah, I know what happened
to Emily.
I'm sorry.
You know,
when things like that happen,
you...
Feel like the sun should turn dark.
The earth should stop spinning.
But the world keeps going on
around you.
Yeah, and you wonder
if it's a place
worth living in.
You and Nikita...
Why are you still living this life?
If I had a chance
to do it over again,
I'd just take off
with Emily, you know.
I wouldn't wait
for the right moment...
'Cause that's when it happens...
The threat you don't see coming.
Oh.
Sorry.
Still a little woozy.
Have your partners left already?
They're not my partners.
Pizza?
Actually, yeah.
I'm starving.
Thanks.
I'm Alicia, by the way.
I guess you could say I was
out of it when I came in.
It's cool.
They filled me in on your sitch.
You care if I hang down here?
That bedroom's kind of depressing.
Not that...
- I'm sorry.
- No.
- That came out wrong.
- You're right.
It is, um...
It is depressing.
Sit, please, uh, wherever.
Mi casa es su casa.
You've got nice hardware.
Uh, thanks.
I, uh... yeah, made some upgrades,
tweaked the video card a little bit.
Did you get the m.C.R.
Above 6,000?
7,000, actually.
What, were you, like, a gamer
in a past life or something?
I used to work I.T.
For a big company,
though I do know my way
around Azeroth.
You like the gig?
Yeah, the offices
were super high-tech.
Gear was top of the line.
Then one day I showed up
to a meeting so high,
I passed out.
A couple weeks later,
I started treatment at Vory.
I thought I was finally taking
control of my life.
But now my life is basically over.
Listen...
Nikita and them...
They're gonna set things straight.
Okay?
That's, like, what they do.
Things are gonna work out.
I promise.
They sent you
with the "get out of jail free" card?
Lose a bet to Amanda or something?
I want to know
what the hell you were thinking
going to that event
without telling anyone.
I knew Nikita would be there.
I didn't want to lose
another shot at her.
You mean that
in a literal sense?
Because I saw
the security-cam footage.
You had Nikita in your sites,
and you lost her...
Her and the shooter...
Oversight's only link to Mars.
Your approach was stubborn, stupid,
and tactically inept.
And you came all the way
over here to tell me that.
You must have a lot
of free time on your hands.
Like I said,
I saw the security-cam footage.
You saved the senator's life.
I came to bring you home.
Michael, I think I got him.
Excuse me.
Um...
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I'm totally turned around.
Um, the receptionist told me
that the...
The interview rooms were back here?
You came in for treatment?
Yeah, my, um, friend...
She told me that you got her
clean in, like, a month,
so I thought that was awesome.
Yes, that's one word for it.
Yeah, okay, well, I guess
I'll just see you outside, then.
Actually, you can answer
some questions right here.
You see, the interview rooms
are all up in the front,
and Lucy wouldn't have sent you
in back.
So the first thing
that I want to know is,
why are you really here?
Who are you working with?
I told you.
I'm here alone.
Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait.
We have no idea where she is
or how many guys
we'd be dealing with.
We'd be going in blind.
Okay, maybe we don't have to.
- Oh, wait for it.
- Yeah.
Yeah!
- Oh, it's funny every time.
- It's so funny.
It's them.
Maybe they got something for you.
Yo.
Birkhoff...
I need you to hack into Vory...
Phones, security cameras, the works.
I'm sorry. Did you just say
you need me to...
Mars grabbed Nikita.
Give me two minutes.
What's going on?
Everything's cool.
I just got to save their asses...
Again.
Oh, wow.
I bet you could give Shadow Walker
a run for his money.
Did you just say
"Shadow Walker"?
Yeah, he's done, like,
the most ingenious hacks
of the last decade.
What, you've never heard of him?
No, I...
I know him.
Dude's a legend.
You know, most of his targets
are, uh, shady wall street guys.
- I didn't know that.
- Yep.
He's kind of Robin hood.
Where the hell
did you lift that from?
You always assume
the worst in me.
Look, all I know
is that gear cost 10k.
The last time I checked,
you were unemployed.
Yeah, well, a lot of people
are willing to pay
- for my skill set.
- Yeah? Like who?
Okay, looks like
your best point of entry
is gonna be the southeast corner.
Think we can kick it in?
- On my count.
- Yeah.
One, two, three.
Go check it out.
So, if you're here
because of P9,
that means there's only one
person who could've sent you...
Percy.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Please. I worked for the man
for six years.
I know division personnel.
You all have that same look.
There are people
that will wonder where I am,
and they will come looking for me.
Oh, I'm sure they will.
That's why these Venezuelan
gentlemen are here.
There were quite a few Venezuelans
in the original P9 program...
Before the government incinerated it.
They're ready for retribution.
And so am I.
That's the hallway
to Dr. Francis office.
Okay, you guys are gonna want
to stay to the right.
On second thought, maybe not.
Talk to me, Birkhoff.
Three of them...
Armed, dead ahead.
Go see what's happening.
I think they're out.
Judging by the sound of it.
Hands up!
You think you're so righteous,
don't you, huh?
I know what it's like
to want revenge,
but I would never hurt
innocent people to do it.
You.
I want everything
on the regimen...
Every formula,
every piece of research,
all of it.
Here you go.
Turn it off.
Hey!
Turn it off!
Man, are you seeing this?
Alicia?
- What's happening to them?
- They've been triggered.
But I don't think they've got orders.
Get down, get down, get down!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Yeah?
- Birkhoff.
- It's Alicia.
She heard the tones at the clinic
and got all zombified.
She grabbed a gun and took off.
I'm tailing her now, but I'm not
sure where's she's headed.
She's back
on her original mission.
God, I'm so stupid!
I should've remembered the tones.
She doesn't deserve to go out
like this, Mike.
You didn't get what you needed.
I still got hope.
Those files got to be somewhere.
Alicia's been re-triggered.
Two guesses where she's headed.
St. Joseph's hospital, where
the senator is recuperating.
Michael, he'll be crawling
with security.
She'll get herself killed.
Or Birkhoff...
He's right behind her.
You guys go.
I'll stay here.
I know a little something
about cleaning up crime scenes.
I'll tee everything up for the cops...
That Mars is the bad guy.
I'll get everybody
the help they need.
Might want to erase
the Venezuelans as well.
No need to create
an international incident.
Well, that goes without saying.
I can't figure out
why the Venezuelans
would target a junior senator
from Connecticut.
Even if their motive
was straight revenge...
Hang on.
Where are you?
I was about to ask you
the same question.
Somewhere in back-ass
country Greenwich.
Probably gonna lose my signal.
Michael, isn't St. Joe's
in Stamford?
- Yeah.
- Birkhoff, tell me exactly
where you are.
Birkhoff.
Alicia's not headed for the hospital.
What if the Venezuelans
were targeting someone else?
- At the dinner?
- And the picnic.
It was the same charity.
They have to have the same guests.
Judge Kathy Bridges sits on the board
of read & unite.
Rumor is she's about to rule
against an oil company
for price fixing.
A Venezuelan oil company?
Venezuelan, baby...
Petroleos orinoco.
And I bet the judge has
a nice place in Greenwich.
Alicia!
Wait, stop!
You don't know what you're doing.
Listen, I know.
I know what it's like to get orders
that feel so strong,
you think you're gonna die
if you don't follow them.
But deep down...
There is a part of you that knows...
This isn't you.
And that part of you
can choose to stop.
Oh, no.
You guys took your sweet time.
Birkhoff,
if you want to be conscious
for the car ride home, shut up.
Hey, computer guy.
It's Birkhoff...
Seymour Birkhoff.
Right, Seymour Birkhoff.
Nikita says you know where
the other black boxes are.
That true?
I know where they were
before Percy scattered
the last three guardians
to the wind...
Johannesburg, Tokyo, and Rio.
Is that where
you're going next?
Land of the lambada, crystal waters,
white sands...
Sounds nice.
First things first.
This is everything on the regimen.
I pulled it off Mars' computer.
It includes a way
to chemically detox.
It's, uh...It's the answers
I've been looking for.
You know it could take a while
for all that to get out
of your system.
Maybe you could stay here.
Absolutely not.
Yeah, it's, uh,
probably better I get clean
on the road.
The longer I wait,
the colder those guardian trails
get, you know.
Good luck.
Yeah.
Owen...
If you ever need anything...
I'll be around.
Okay?
Okay.
I know why you lost Nikita
at the dinner.
You didn't blow your shot.
You were never gonna take it.
Tell me I'm wrong.
What difference
does it make to you?
As long as I am committed
to the mission...
I just want to give you
some advice.
Look, I don't need a lecture
on when to...
Will you shut up for a second?
When I was a Navy seal,
if you knew that your comrade
faced certain death,
you were supposed to take
his life first.
So one day I'm in combat,
and my partner gets grabbed.
And I had a gun,
but I couldn't pull the trigger.
I froze.
And I later found out
that he was tortured for months
and then slaughtered.
And I could've prevented it.
He was your partner.
No matter what the situation was,
you didn't want to play a part
in his death.
He suffered because I was weak.
Do yourself a favor.
Next time you have Nikita
in your sites, take the shot,
because once she falls
into oversight's custody,
she will not be afforded any mercy...
By anyone.
The doctors
are deprogramming me.
The only side effect is
my memory's gone a little weird.
I can barely remember
the last couple months...
Every place I've been,
everyone I met.
I can't remember anything.
What is this?
That is Shadowbot.
Runs a 24-hour news feed
against every piece of data
in the black box.
Any story correlates
with an old division mission,
that bad boy pieces it
together for us.
Us?
That means
you're not kicking us out now?
You were right
about P9 being back.
You saved all those people.
We did...All of us.
And I know what it took.
I trust the equipment
we provided you with
proved satisfactory?
Guns worked fine.
You were able to get
the information you required?
I have what I need
to come off the regimen...
No side effects.
I'm glad to hear that.
Health is everything.
Tell me, is Nikita in good health?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Please, Mr. Elliott.
We're all friends now.
This is a business arrangement.
Well, our arrangement concerns
the black boxes.
We heard a rumor that Nikita has one.
Can you verify that?
She doesn't.
And if you do anything against her,
I'll kill you myself.
I like you, Mr. Elliott.
You're very direct.
Allow me to be direct in return.
Gogol will fund your search
for the remaining guardians.
You will destroy their boxes,
and then...
Percy will die.
And you're gonna help make it happen.
But anything outside
those parameters
is out of my control.
As you said,
this is a business arrangement.
Sync and correction by Mlmlte
www.addic7ed.com