Now, can I count on your
support for school trustee?
I've been thinking of
running against you.
We can't afford a campaign.
We would like
to buy your business.
She's the midwife.
You're doing very well,
and you're very strong.
You're not locking
Gracie up any more.
Run!
She says they have
the same tattoo,
Picture of
a two-headed horse.
It was the only way I could
see to get you out of dyad.
Betray my sister?
For Kira.
That's not your bloody decision!
What the hell's going on?
This is Seth.
They wrote down all my information
in this little notebook.
And then Seth yanked out
a piece of my hair
And put it in a bag.
Mommy.
Duncan had tissue samples
of the castor original.
My people will get you
out of the country.
Now we find Helena
and we finish this shit.
We should close his eyes.
Yeah.
- Do you want a drink?
- Yeah.
Okay...
S.
S is gonna know
how to get rid of it.
Either that
or someone she knows well...
I'm not asking her
for anything else.
Then fine, I'll ask.
So, I'm gonna need a bath
After we've cleaned
all of this up.
Jesus christ! What a mess.
- Sarah, we need to talk.
- -shit!
- Art, it's not a good time.
- Talk to him!
- Why won't you talk?
- Because he knows me!
- Sarah, I've got something.
Yeah, just a second.
I'm really sick.
I've been throwing up for hours.
- Open the door!
- Art, one second.
One sec.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hey yourself.
What's going on?
It all depends.
What's with you?
Nothing.
Hello, arthur.
- Felix.
- How you doing?
What's up? What do you need?
Oh, that. Yeah.
That's a new project.
That's very fresh.
What?
- Art. Hey!
- Art.
- Art, do not go in there.
- What is that?
- Art!
- What...
okay.
First off, it wasn't us.
Do you understand
the position this puts me in?
We do, art. But can't you
just, like, look away?
It's a dead body,
not a bag of weed.
Well, look away and it too
will go up in smoke.
Very professional,
nothing on you.
Hey, art.
I've got someone
who wants to meet ya.
Hi, art, I'm Cosima.
- Welcome to clone club.
- Oh, shit!
I know. Sorry.
I knew beth.
I knew what
she was going through.
We really miss her.
Yeah.
Yeah. Me, too.
Um, cos, what's your take
on these glitchy bastards?
'Cause this one's not talking.
You said they were looking
for samples of their original,
That's very interesting. Um...
- Oh. Yeah, here's Scott.
- Hey.
- Hello, lieutenant Scotty.
- Don't call me that.
No, he's like barely a trekie.
He only went
to comic-con, like, once.
And it's "lieutenant commander".
Yeah. Anyway?
Basically, dead guy's
symptomology
Sounds like they have
a design flaw.
- Yeah, like me.
- Only neurological.
Which explains why they need
the original genome,
To find a cure.
But that's just
hypothetical unless...
- Unless what, scooter?
- Don't call me that either.
Unless we examine his brain.
His brain?
Okay. Well, chop-chop
then, get over here.
I don't want any part of this.
Sarah, come here.
- Do you wanna see the body again?
Yeah.
I really
shouldn't be doing this.
You don't have to.
You just got back on the job.
Which is how I got a lead
on the prolethean, Mark.
You did?
Gracie?
Come inside.
I went to get us breakfast.
Please, don't leave without me.
It was just across the street.
The baker had a turban.
He said he makes the best cinnamon
buns in the whole county.
Your family will be
looking for us, Gracie.
Damn them, if they
want to ruin our honeymoon.
There's a whole world out there.
Why are we here?
I told you,
we're just laying low.
You sat up again last night.
Why won't you come to bed
with me?
It's not a sin.
We're husband and wife.
I know. It's just...
You can share your secrets now.
Hey, say no to bullies
on the board or in the class.
I will speak to your children
so you don't have to.
Hello, Vera.
Could I talk to you
about Marci Coates?
She plans to
re-zone the district.
And have you seen
her lunch proposals?
Nothing but starches.
Sorry, I can't.
You don't have five minutes to
talk about your kids' education?
Alison, honestly,
Someone with your issues
handling my children?
Of course. No, I understand.
Uh, we have something for you...
...From Ramon.
We took over his business.
Bath beads, body lotions,
Anything you need to relax.
...oh! Here you go.
- Thank you.
- Here you go.
- Uh-oh.
- Oh!
It's 60 now for the soap.
Though we do offer discounts
for referrals.
So, can I count on your support?
Well, tell me about
this re-zoning thing.
At the military academy
The other boys did
the sex things.
They'd chase girls.
But not me.
I was waiting.
I know this town.
Willard Finch lives here.
We're not just
laying low, are we?
Gracie...
I'm not who you think I am.
I told your father
that I went awol,
But the truth is that...
I never left the army.
What do you mean?
It's all about your father.
He stole
valuable scientific material,
I was assigned to recover it.
We brought you in.
- Trusted you.
- Gracie...
- All those years...
- I'm sorry.
- It was all a lie?
- No!
Gracie...
We are free of your people,
but we are not clear of mine.
I have to find
something for them
And then I can get out.
That's why we're here?
You're looking for something
my father stole?
You think Willard Finch has it?
I think that he hid
certain things for henrik.
Gracie, you had to know
that your father had secrets.
No, I don't know!
I don't know anything!
Gracie...
Don't ask me
what for, it's personal.
He has to be back
by the end of the day.
Beth couldn't keep still either.
Well, it just doesn't seem like these
people get downtown much, does it?
Yeah, well, they all scattered
After Helena torched the ranch.
So, the samples that these
castor guys are after?
Yeah, from the original.
Blood slides and skin samples,
that's what Cosima said.
So, what?
You think that
if you find them first,
You can trade Helena for 'em?
Right.
Hey, that's the midwife.
Here we go!
Alexis McGann.
Recognise me?
I'm looking for my sister.
I don't know where Helena is.
I was cast out because of her.
Well, I don't give a shit.
What about him?
Mark fled with Gracie.
He betrayed the family.
Wait, he's with the daughter?
Are they the ones
that took Johanssen's truck?
Mmm-hmm.
Hey, look.
Johanssen did something
to my sister, what did he do?
She has a special purpose.
Well, I don't know what that means.
What does that mean?
He harvested her eggs,
And she's pregnant
with his child.
Helena's pregnant by him?
It's a miracle.
I didn't know he would
do it to Gracie, too.
55, that vehicle
was ticketed for speeding
In Halton yesterday
at 18:44.
- 55, roger.
All I regret is breaking bread
with abominations.
Oh, trust me,
if Helena's an abomination,
- I'm much worse.
- Hey.
Next time
she'll bite your head off.
Gracie,
I've gotta go and do this.
This child inside me...
...You know what it is.
Yes.
I can't do it alone.
I'll be there for both of you.
I swear.
Then let me help you.
Willard Finch
is a dangerous man.
If he was hiding something
from my father,
He's not just gonna
hand it over.
I can take care of myself.
The last thing we need
is another violent mess.
Have you got a better idea?
What?
Hello, Mr. Finch.
Remember me?
Little Gracie Johanssen.
You really have blossomed.
Yes, sir.
Thank you, Mr. Finch.
- Just gotta say it was a...
- Just a damn shame
what happened to your daddy.
He was a good man, your father.
He always spoke well
of you, too.
Kept you under lock and key,
though, these last few years,
Didn't he?
- We have our ways.
- Uh-huh.
Well, I remember a time when
he used to bring you up here.
I used to play in your fields
while he did business.
That's right.
- Which is why I'm here.
- Oh?
To...
...Collect what you held
in trust for him.
There is a storage fee that's
applicable here, it's $1,000.
- I don't have it.
- Ooh!
That's gonna be a problem.
The problem, Mr. Finch,
is your lack of faith in us.
We proletheans make fast friends
But fearsome enemies.
Shall I disrupt my mother's
grief to tell her
That you're holding out
for your 30 pieces of silver?
You be sure to give
your family my condolences.
Of course.
So, why did Mark take the girl?
He wanted a chew toy.
Oh, come on, think like police.
Why take baggage on the run?
Love, or a hostage? I...
Art, shouldn't you be
getting back to your real job?
Johanssen was a large animal
vet in Halton in the '80s.
You've got to read
the entire file. He's a ka.
Known associate?
Seriously,
why are you doing this?
I don't know.
'Cause I'm riding
with my partner.
- Art. -Look, I'm not
confused, Sarah.
But you are beth's sister
through and through.
You didn't even know her.
This isn't your fight.
You know, she tried to tell me.
What she was.
She called me the night
that she...
The night she came along and...
I thought it was the pills,
more bullshit.
I turned my back on her
when she needed me the most.
You couldn't have known.
Yeah. But I should have.
She was lucky to have you.
Just look up
that asshole ka for me.
Let's get your sister back.
Ma'am, I can explain.
- You killed your brother!
- Virginia, calm down.
He was stage five
in the field. I had to.
If you had followed major
dearden's extraction orders,
He would have been at home.
I'm sorry, mother. I'm sorry.
Hey, he screwed up,
But he had to put Seth down.
It's protocol.
My office. Wait for me.
Oh, shit!
Come here, doc.
Bless you, paul.
Oh, yeah.
I'm blessed all right.
What's your 20?
Yeah, that's us. Systems
and weapons check, right?
It's getting worse, isn't it,
the defect?
You saw it?
Seth went from asymptomatic
to stage five in a day.
What about Helena? Any help?
We did the stress tests,
the neurocog,
She doesn't have the defect.
Her biology may hold answers.
But the fastest way to a cure
Is still the original
genetic material.
Well, I run field operations.
I want rudy
confined to the base.
But I run the programme.
We've lost contact with Mark,
I need rudy back in the field.
I'll go after Mark.
You can't.
It gets worse.
The director wants you
in arlington.
Our weapon system
has a glitch, paul.
We are one budget review
from oblivion.
They can't shut us down.
I serve with these men.
We owe them.
If you can protect them,
I can cure them.
Just buy us more time
with the director.
You okay, Scotty?
I could barely get through
the scalp, man.
Oh, god.
Go easy on him, Cosima.
Scott's not a hardened
criminal like you and i.
Once I got to the calvarium
I just...
- Scalpel?
- Yeah.
Hey, you have
done this before, yeah?
...YouTube is an
amazing resource.
Scott?
No sign of aneurysm.
No, no lesions.
God, is this all we are?
Huh?
I mean, some neurons, and axons,
And a few pounds of grey matter.
How about we just get it
back to the lab?
Yeah. But, like, when he died
you think what he saw,
It was just
a temporal lobe trip?
...oh!
Or did his soul actually say,
"I'm out of here.
I'm out of this dimension"?
Please, Cosima,
this is weird enough.
Scott, a good lab partner should
be metaphysically empathetic.
Tongs or spoons?
- Ah.
- Oh, my god!
Well, I looked.
I shouldn't have looked.
Okay.
Ugh!
Oh, bollocks.
Receptacle.
Hey.
You all right there, Igor?
Still with me?
Tell me what you see.
Bi... Bird.
Um...
Star.
- Knife.
- Close.
Key.
Your aphasia's
improving already,
And so are your motor skills
With the help of art
and physiotherapy.
Outside.
Sadly, the Rachel Duncan
Topside knew has passed.
Plane crash.
Delphine?
Um, i...
...Finished?
Let's focus on your recovery.
You're more valuable
than you know.
Horses.
Clear the room.
At ease.
Man, I thought
you were really mad at me.
I am.
Your logs.
Sit.
Her name was patty.
Mark's gone dark.
Man, that guy is such a pussy!
Don't underestimate him.
If he's off task,
just bring him home.
And the major?
I'll handle the major.
Mom?
I saw that star in Seth's eyes.
- Oh.
- They took him so fast.
Come.
If there was any chance that
Sarah still had the samples...
I had to try.
My boy.
- Alison, hi.
- Hi!
We heard about
your new business.
Yeah.
Could we maybe get some...
Soap?
Yes. We actually have
a special for new customers.
Free sample?
Sure.
How about you? Yeah?
Have you two made your
decision for school trustee?
We're still thinking about it.
Don't think too hard.
Soap is the perfect cover.
- Ali, we're gonna break even in months.
- Mmm-hmm.
We should have been
drug dealers years ago.
Mmm-mmm.
Pharmaceutical entrepreneurs,
donnie.
As long as every new customer
Is a vote against
Marci flippin' Coates.
...hello!
Hi, Marci.
Oh, the kids said that
you were in the garage.
You shouldn't be back here.
There is fumes and lard.
Well, this is, uh,
quite the operation.
I had no idea
soap-making was so involved.
Would you like a lesson?
Enterprising,
and a head for politics.
That's quite the dark horse.
What's her secret?
Oh, you know, just good
old-fashioned stumping, Marci.
We can't all be the incumbents so
some of us have to work for it.
So, Alison, I have
a little proposal for you.
Hmm.
I can get you an amazing
deal on this house.
The sellers are very motivated.
This is in a different
school district.
Honey,
they have a salt-water pool.
- Oh, look at that.
- Donnie!
Look, Alison,
You can buy a few votes
with your soaps
And you can quite possibly
carve out some of my support,
But you can't actually win.
Go sell a house, Marci.
Do you seriously think
that people are gonna
Trust their children
to an infamous alcoholic?
Why not?
They trusted a conniving
second-rate realtor.
May the best woman win, Alison.
Goodbye, Marci.
I need to cut something.
Drop your accent,
this isn't scotland yard.
Willard Finch.
This is private property.
Well, you're a long way
from home, son.
That's funny. I don't look
a thing like your son.
That you wouldn't.
We're hunting this guy.
- Can I?
- Yeah.
Nope. I don't know.
He's travelling with the
daughter of henrik Johanssen.
Who's that now?
Henrik.
He was part of your little
militia back in the day.
"My little militia"?
You remember?
Back when the feds dug up all
those guns in your cornfield.
What's your point?
One tip to the feds,
And they backhoe
the whole thing again,
Looking for your little arsenal.
Okay.
I don't know
your friend here, okay?
This idiot, I don't know.
But that daughter,
Young Gracie, she did swing by.
What for?
Just to pass on the sad news.
Women running things
over there now too, huh?
What is this world coming to?
Is there anything else?
Bye.
We'll be in touch.
You're banished.
We have no use for a midwife.
Wait!
I know where
mark may have taken Gracie.
It's just junk!
There's no
test tubes, no slides?
This is what he gave me.
Biological samples
need to be kept cold.
Did you see, like, a tank
or a cooler?
- No.
- Think, Gracie.
I don't know.
Okay, it's okay. I'll just...
I'm just gonna have to
go back myself.
No, Mark.
...don't worry.
It's too risky!
You know what?
Just, um, go down
And treat yourself
to something special.
I'll be back for you in an hour.
Come home safe. Okay?
Don't you dare leave me alone.
I won't.
Never.
We've got, like, six hotels.
They won't give you anything
over the phone.
You've got to go in,
show them his picture.
Shit!
Hey, you've got
real fires to tend there.
I'll finish the canvas
and you just go back.
I'll take the bus back tonight.
I showed you a dead clone
in a tub this morning.
No, you did not.
Just tell me you're not
risking your job being here.
Hmm?
You know,
I may not be your partner,
But I know
when you're holding back.
Beth called you that night,
Not Cosima, nor Alison.
What is it
you're not telling me?
Just say it.
I've never said it.
You were in love with her.
She was my partner...
...And we were
never gonna be together,
But it happened.
You're just as fierce
As she was, Sarah.
And you need my help, too.
You're no good to us suspended.
We need you as a cop.
Beth would want that.
Be careful. Okay?
We're fierce, remember?
Call me if you need me.
Don't leave it too late.
I thought
you'd smell like Sarah.
Another one.
You are the ugliest Mark yet.
Tell me something,
Sarah manning,
the gather of sisters,
But when she sold you out,
when she gave you to us,
That must've been quite a blow.
You come inside,
I tell you about it.
Well, sweetheart,
There is nothing more
That I would love.
That's enough!
Just getting to know
the enemy, major.
You have an assignment.
I will brief you
so this time you don't stray.
- Sir...
Dirty paul.
He lies with my sisters,
even Rachel.
Come inside.
Have another.
You won't believe me,
But I am sorry
it has come to this.
Mmm.
One day, I kill you all.
Forgive me my trespasses
against the family, lord.
Please keep Mark safe,
And help guide us
through this uncertainty.
Amen.
Do you know who I am?
Are you Sarah?
Helena told me about you,
I didn't really believe her.
Yeah, she tells
some nutty stories.
I'm lookin' for her.
You'll have to try at the ranch.
- I don't know where she is.
- And Mark?
He and his brothers know
where she is.
My husband
doesn't have any brothers.
Husband?
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
You're the first person
I've told.
Did Helena tell you
I have a kid?
Yes.
My kid and yours
are going to be cousins.
I know you're carrying
Helena's baby.
That does not make us family.
Why, 'cause we're abominations?
I don't really know
what to think any more.
Yeah, there's a lot
mark's not telling you.
He was sent by the army.
He had to collect scientific
material from my father.
I know. He told me.
Didn't tell you about
his brothers, though, did he?
There's probably more of them.
He's...
He's a...
- Hey, hey, hey!
Look.
Helena's the mother of your
kid and she's in trouble,
I need to know where Mark is.
- Gracie took everything.
- All right?
We got nothing
to talk about here, kid.
- Just... You go and tell bonnie that,
would ya? Bonnie didn't send me.
In the field there are only
two types of prisoners,
Assets and liabilities.
Ahh. Ow. Ow. Ow.
Okay, okay. Okay.
Be an asset, Willard.
Where are the rest
of henrik's things?
Okay.
I don't know any more
than what I told ya.
Where?
- Willard?
Hello, Gracie.
Mother.
Your family
cares for you, Gracie,
Even as you refuse
to care for yourself.
You've been crying.
I made a mistake.
Mark, he...
He took advantage of you.
Yes.
And your stupidity.
We let a wolf into our flock,
and you ran.
I had doubts, mother.
When your father told me
That you would be the one
to carry the child, i...
I struggled.
Lord, I struggled.
But, you didn't stop him.
We're not like other people.
We have a purpose.
We still have a purpose.
It's like swiss cheese in here.
Amyloid plaques,
rampant cell death.
Like spongiform encephalopathy?
Yes. Like
creutzfeldt-jakob disease.
He wouldn't have lasted a week.
No wonder they're so motivated.
- Assays done?
- A few, yeah.
Just cross-referencing
against Leda DNA.
Let's see if it brings up
a new synthetic sequence.
- Scott?
- Hmm.
Hello?
- Hello.
- Hey.
You're not gonna believe this,
um, 'cause I don't either.
But I just thought with a few
100 matching base pairs,
But it's almost half a gigabase.
Uh, not a good time, Cosima.
Tell her about the loci.
Yeah. A dozen short tandem
repeat loci in common.
That can only mean
one thing, Sarah.
In english, I hope.
The boy clones are our brothers.
What?
Shit. Shit.
I've gotta go.
Sarah?
Hello?
Heart attack.
I thought he could take it, but he
must have had a heart condition.
How did you find this place?
I had a chat
with your blushing bride.
Gracie?
What did you tell her?
She knows you're like us.
She knows you're just like us,
a clone.
What have you done?
What I had to
to get Helena back.
Look, I don't care about Helena.
You have to.
She's your sister.
You're lying.
- I'm your sister, Mark.
- You're lying.
We did the science, you're...
You're my family.
You would say anything
to get your sister back.
Think about it, castor and Leda,
Two donors,
two originals, siblings!
You are not my family.
Now, I need to go find Gracie.
Mark. Mark!
Mrs Johanssen, please.
We shared
everything with you, Mark.
- Our home, our hearts.
Our daughter.
Now you'll answer to us.
Please.
I love her.
Not like her mother.
You're the one
with the blessed child.
...guards!
You're a shit mother!
- There was a car following me.
- Was it Marci Coates?
My boss wants a meeting.
- Whoa, mister, that my wife!
- Shut up.
I'm not gonna let an app
decide who I love.
Nobody meets anyone
in person any more, darling.
- I'm not. No.
- Why not?
...there you are, mommy.