You are being watched.
The government has a secret system.
A machine that spies on you
every hour of every day.
I designed the machine to detect
acts of terror, but it sees everything.
Violent crimes involving
ordinary people.
The government
considers these people irrelevant.
We don't.
Hunted by the authorities,
we work in secret.
You will never find us.
But victim or perpetrator,
if your number's up, we'll find you.
The mayor's office
is up for grabs and Councilman Ed Griffin...
... threw his hat in the ring today.
A new candidate
in the race, Assistant DA Landon Walker.
This is a bloodbath.
Griffin and Walker are neck and neck.
Yeah, I hear that's
about to change. That reporter, Maxine Angelis...
... she says one of Griffin's money men
has been cooking the books.
Who are you?
I'm the person not telling your wife...
... that you're in a hotel room
waiting for a hooker.
Your office wasn't returning my calls,
so I thought I'd reach out to you personally.
Maxine Angelis, New York Journal.
This little game cuts both ways.
What will your readers think when they
find out you get stories using blackmail?
They'll think I'm good at my job.
In the next five days,
New York elects a new mayor...
...and I'm very curious
about the illegal fundraising you've done...
...for Ed Griffin's campaign.
Give me straight answers...
...and I'll be kind enough to omit
the circumstances of our interview.
What is it you wanna know?
You've raised over $100,000 for Griffin.
I can see why Maxine
keeps making headlines.
Investigative journalists like Ms. Angelis
are an endangered species.
In order to keep up with bloggers
and social media...
...dedicated reporters have to be
increasingly creative to get the truth.
Finch? Is that feedback?
No, I simply made the grievous error
of buying Bear a squeaky toy.
In the six years
she's worked at the Journal...
...she's penned exposés on New York's
most dangerous criminals.
The Cartel, Elias, HR.
She's made some very powerful enemies.
Odds are one of Maxine's stories
is about to get her killed.
Okay, I got what I need.
Thank you for your time, Mr. Hicks.
Oh, and tell your wife I said hi.
Max, remember how you thought
HR had a lot more dirty cops out there?
You were right. The feds are indicting
dozens of NYPD officers.
On my way.
FBI, you're under arrest.
You two, out of the car.
You have the right to remain silent.
They're making the bust,
but I know this was you.
- Nice work, detective.
- Keep your voice down, huh, Carter?
You think John put me under with HR
because of my spotless record?
- I'm glad the feds haven't come after me yet.
- The day's still young, Fusco.
Agent Donnelly. Big day for you.
Thanks, Carter. And don't think
I've forgotten about your man in a suit.
We will catch him,
as soon as we're done with this.
Looks pretty done to me.
Over 75 dirty cops in bracelets.
So why aren't you smiling?
Oh.
You don't have the big boss, do you?
Head of HR.
- So got a particular cop in mind?
- I'm not so sure it is a cop.
If a lead I'm working pans out,
soon I'll know exactly who is running things.
Hey, Carter.
My two cents? Let this one go, okay?
Every crook HR screwed over,
every cartel they were in bed with...
...they're all gonna want the big boss dead.
Whoever catches that guy
better be bulletproof.
Is it weird that that just makes me
wanna catch him more?
For you? No.
Hey, kiddo, it's Dad.
Remember, I'm picking you up today.
So don't take the bus. And think about
what movie you wanna watch tonight.
All right, I'll call you later.
- Hello, Lionel.
- Look, Simmons...
Spare me whatever steaming pile
you're about to serve up.
I saw you.
The day the FBI got into HR,
I saw you helping that guy in the suit.
You know, it even crossed my mind...
...you might be the rat who tried
to take us down.
But you wouldn't be that stupid,
now, would you, Lionel?
- No.
- Good.
Because HR might be down,
but we are not out.
My boss is pulling strings right now
to save the upper management.
What do you need me for?
Because the FBI keeps digging.
We got word that they're on to something
that could still bring us all down.
Me, my boss, probably even you.
What do they got?
Why don't you tell me?
Your partner's all buddy-buddy with Donnelly.
You're gonna find out
what they're looking for...
...and you're gonna make it disappear.
And if I don't?
Well, I guess I'll see you in prison.
I mean, what's your kid gonna think
when he finds out what you did?
You think your ex-wife's
gonna let you see him again?
I mean, you need this to go away
as bad as we do.
Push comes to shove,
who's got your back here?
That goody-two-shoes partner of yours
or me?
Just do this one thing for us, Lionel.
Then if you want out, you're out.
So, Quinn, what brings you out
of campaign HQ?
My boss' screaming, mostly.
You've made this a very tough day for me.
Well, when you sign on as campaign
manager for a crook like Ed Griffin...
...you gotta expect a few tough days.
- Sorry.
- I'll survive.
Politicians come and go,
but you and I are here forever, right Max?
Off the record, it's not Griffin's year.
Walker's ahead, and I can't find any dirt.
The cleaner they are on the outside,
the more rotten they are.
I actually came by just to warn you.
Griffin wants your head on a pike.
Well, tell him to get in line.
- You hear that, Finch?
- Edward Griffin.
Our newest suspect, but likely not our last.
Oh, Bear, please.
Look, here's your ball.
I should have access to Maxine's
cloud storage site shortly.
Once I get inside, I'll scan through
everything she's working on...
...see who else might want her dead.
- That's not the real story, Glen.
- The hell it's not.
Seventy-five cops in cuffs. That's news.
The story's not who they busted,
it's who they didn't.
The head of HR.
The FBI knows they don't have the big boss.
They're scooping up everybody
hoping they'll catch him...
...if they cast a wide enough net.
- You wanna write about the big boss? Fine.
Get me a name and something to back it up.
Until then, there's nothing to print.
So she's looking for the head of HR.
Should we be looking at Simmons?
Actually, my analysis of the evidence
from Detective Fusco...
...suggests that Simmons is just
a high-ranking lieutenant.
Then who's really in charge?
Someone's dialing Maxine's cell.
Number blocked, no ID.
Maxine Angelis.
I can't tell you my name.
- But I have information you want.
- Okay. What is that exactly?
HR's big boss. I know who it is.
- All right, I'm listening.
- The head of HR is Christopher Zambrano.
- They're arresting him tonight.
- Who is this?
A friend.
Christopher Zambrano.
Son of the late Mafia don.
Whom I'm sure you will remember.
But unlike his father, Christopher seems
to have kept his nose clean.
Which would make him a good liaison
between the mob and the police.
He owns an import-export business.
Perfect cover for the smuggling operations
that have lined HR's pockets.
She's calling one of her contacts in the FBI.
Agent Clark.
Willis. Maxine Angelis.
Remember when you led that meth-lab raid
and busted into the wrong house...
...and I left your name out of the paper and
you said you didn't know how to thank me?
Well, I just thought of a way.
What do you want, Maxine?
What do you know about
the HR investigation? I just got a tip...
...that Christopher Zambrano
is the boss of the whole operation.
Okay. This is deep, deep background.
But, uh...
Yes, I know they're looking at him
in connection with HR.
When Donnelly was working
on the indictments...
...I heard him talking about Zambrano
a lot.
Okay. Well, thanks, Willis.
I'll keep your name out of this story too.
Sounds like she's on to something.
We definitely need to check out Zambrano.
I think Maxine might beat me to it.
Mr. Zambrano.
- Maxine Angelis, New York Journal.
- Nice to meet you. Get off my property.
Why? Do you have
something to hide from a reporter?
- Got eyes and ears on Zambrano, Finch.
Search all you want.
All you're gonna find is imported furniture,
a kiddie carousel, which I bought.
For charity.
Does that make it into the papers? No.
Because my last name is Zambrano,
you guys all think I'm a wiseguy.
No, I think you're the head of HR.
What are you talking about?
Who told you that?
I think you know
exactly what I'm talking about.
Did you get a visit recently
from Agent Donnelly?
- Never seen him before.
- Funny.
Because the guard at the gate
has seen him here. Arguing with you.
The son of a Mafia don,
owner of an import-export business...
...getting grilled by the FBI agent
hunting HR.
If you're not involved,
how would you explain...?
Shut your mouth.
I don't know anything about that, okay?
If you keep asking questions,
somebody's gonna get hurt.
- I don't like this. I'm going in.
Reese, you can't.
Maxine has another pet story.
She's been scouring through records...
...talking to witnesses,
hunting for a man in a suit. Meaning you.
We're fugitives getting illegal information
from a secret government machine.
The last thing we need is publicity.
You must protect Miss Angelis,
but you have to do it...
... without giving her any more proof
that the man in the suit exists.
You expect me to believe
you're gonna hurt me at your business...
- Mr. Zambrano...
- You don't write that!
Suspected HR boss assaults reporter.
Do you think that headline
makes you look less guilty?
Hey, Teddy,
escort this bitch off my property.
Okay, Finch,
how am I supposed to save a woman...
...who wants to put me on the front page?
Despite this complication,
we must focus on keeping Maxine safe.
I can't find anything
in Zambrano's digital file...
...to suggest he's the head of HR.
But brilliant criminals have fooled us before.
I do wish you wouldn't do that here.
When I do it in the park,
people look at me funny.
Okay, let's assume Zambrano
is the head of HR.
He might want to have Maxine killed
before she can reveal his true identity.
It'll be damn hard to stop him
if I can't let Maxine see me work.
And when you step out of the shadows
to help her out...
...she'll know you're the man in the suit.
Until we can figure out a way
to hide you in plain sight...
...perhaps you should enlist some backup.
Maxine Angelis, yeah, I've heard of her.
That woman leaves no stone unturned.
How you expect to work with her around?
Aren't you and your friend
staying out of the papers?
I'll keep my distance.
The other photo I sent you
is Chris Zambrano.
Maxine thinks he's HR's big boss.
So he's crooked like his dad, huh?
- Everything okay, Fusco?
- Yeah, just something I ate, probably.
Yeah, well, you don't become
head of HR by being sloppy.
If Zambrano wants your reporter dead
he'll do it in a way that's invisible.
With no strings leading back to him.
Fusco, when's the last time
you saw your pal Simmons?
Haven't talked since I shot at him
covering your ass.
Find him. Tail him.
And if he gives you any trouble,
I've got your back.
I'll talk to Donnelly, see who else is
on HR's payroll that hasn't been arrested yet.
And if your reporter friend gets into trouble
before we find the shooter?
Guess I'll have to call the police.
Though I'm unaware of any wrongdoing...
... the funds will be donated to charity.
Ed Griffin issuing a statement
about allegations in the New York Journal.
Landon Walker is in our studio,
your response?
Bob, hiding the evidence
doesn't erase the crime.
- This is what my opponent doesn't get.
- Look what you started.
If I'm elected, I'll bring honesty
and integrity back to the city.
I got him, Glen, the head of HR.
Christopher Zambrano.
The Mafia don's kid? Based on what?
Four sources:
Anonymous tip, guard at the docks...
...an FBI agent familiar with the case,
and Zambrano himself.
- He admitted it to you?
- He wasn't yelling because he's innocent.
I hear Donnelly's already filed the indictment.
We'll run it on the website
and back-edit it once the feds pick him up.
Well, the cat's out of the bag.
But Ms. Angelis is not out of danger yet.
Zambrano may order her execution
for simple revenge.
She's not safe until he's behind bars.
Finch, I can't protect her like this.
- I've got to get close to her.
- Oh, you're about to.
It seems Maxine's job doesn't afford her
opportunities to meet nice men...
...so she somewhat reluctantly signed up
with a popular online dating site.
I took the liberty of back-engineering
the matching algorithm...
...to create the profile of her ideal man.
She really likes that you love dogs.
Wait, you're trying to get me
a date with her?
Already have. Tonight at 8.
You've been flirting all day.
Finch, what did I just say to her?
New cuff links I could understand,
but buying a $100,000 sports car...
...was that really necessary?
- Relax, Finch, the car's stolen.
Nice car.
Let's hope you're not
compensating for something.
Remember, your name is John Anderson.
VP at Jensen Actuarial.
You like walking your dog,
kayaking and Hitchcock movies.
And Maxine's fondness for intellectuals...
...presents us with a graceful way
to cover up your identity.
Are you wearing those glasses I got you?
Sure.
I, uh...
I called ahead and ordered us a bottle.
I hope you like champagne.
I don't. Don't you remember
joking about this online?
- Sorry, can I get a Boulevardier?
- Did you not review the notes I sent you?
So, John...
...I've always wondered,
what does an actuarial actually do?
Most days, just try to stay awake.
Mr. Reese, wrong answer.
Maxine is passionate about her career
and wants a partner who feels the same.
Okay, time for reinforcements.
John?
How are you?
Zoe. Heh.
You trying to make me jealous?
Finch have you on standby?
Social psychology.
Women are more attracted to men...
...who receive the approval
of other attractive women.
Maxine, this is Zoe.
- She's a friend.
- So how do you two know each other?
Oh, we spent...
...two very long nights together last year.
It was great seeing you again, John.
You dated Zoe Morgan?
There's not a reporter in town
who wouldn't kill to interview that woman.
Science. The tenets of social psychology
are firmly rooted in an understanding...
So tell me about your job.
What's the most exciting story
you're working on now?
You'll just think I'm weird.
Okay, well, there's a rumor about this guy...
...the police just call him
"the man in the suit."
No one's seen his face...
...no one knows his name,
I'm not even sure he exists.
But he's like something out of a comic book.
When people are in trouble
he comes out of nowhere.
He always seems to be there just in time...
...and, whoever he is, he saves a lot of lives.
And he shoots a lot of kneecaps.
Sounds like a great guy.
- And an urban legend.
- Maybe, but if he's real...
...I'm going to put that man on the cover...
...of every magazine
and newspaper in this country.
Uh...
What about Christopher Zambrano?
I read your website.
Ever worry that writing about a man
like that might put you in harm's way?
Occupational hazard.
Still couldn't hurt
to skip town for the weekend.
- Let this blow over.
- Thanks for your concern, John.
And for that very slick offer
to whisk me away.
But this is what I do.
I find out what people need to know...
...what those in power
don't want them to know...
...and I make sure everyone hears about it.
To me that's worth a little risk.
In times of universal deceit,
telling the truth is a revolutionary act.
George Orwell.
Oh, I'm sorry, I have to take this. Sorry.
Glen. Okay... Glen, Glen, Glen, slow down.
- Kind of busy, Carter.
We have a problem.
I just got off the phone with Donnelly...
...and Maxine's story about Zambrano
being the big boss of HR, it's not true.
Oh, my God... Okay. Oh, my God.
- Zambrano's not the boss?
- He isn't even a suspect.
Then she wrote that thing
and put a bull's-eye on his chest.
Every crook, HR screw, every cartel
they work with, everyone wants him dead.
Maxine's not in danger, Zambrano is.
We need to find him before it's too late.
You were wrong, Max.
The FBI's on their way, they wanna talk to you.
Okay, forget about me.
Where is Zambrano, and is he okay?
He's not answering.
No one knows where he is.
Work emergency, I'll call you.
I don't know what your emergency is,
but I bet mine's worse.
I just put Zambrano's life in danger,
so I need you to give me a ride.
Okay. Wait in the car.
You're close, Mr. Reese.
Zambrano is 300 meters west-north-west of you.
Guess the FBI doesn't have him bluejacked.
Mr. Zambrano!
Mr. Zambrano?
Chris!
Where's Zambrano?
Help!
Finch.
We didn't get here in time.
Okay, Miss Angelis and Mr. Anderson,
was it?
Uh, you can call me John.
I just need to get a statement.
You found Mr. Zambrano, right?
He was shot. He wasn't breathing.
It was all my fault.
I'm sorry. Can l...? I just need a minute.
Yeah, sure.
You're dating her?
That's how you're keeping your distance?
It's, um, complicated.
Your killers are knocked out of the scene.
My guess is they're Toreros Cartel.
One of the many organizations
that wanted HR's boss dead.
Just got the wrong guy.
Look, this isn't the best place for me to be
but I'm not leaving her.
Can I get her out of here?
Yeah.
Come on. She said we could go.
Some first date, huh?
Maxine Angelis.
Special Agent Donnelly, FBI.
You're gonna answer some questions.
The gate guard told me
that you'd been arguing with Zambrano.
- And an agent I spoke to said...
- Agent Clark didn't know anything.
But I am really not interested in hearing
you try to justify what you did.
All I want is the person who first told you
that Chris Zambrano was the head of HR.
I got a call. It was an anonymous tip.
It was a man. A blocked number.
Eleven forty-one, that's it.
But if he wasn't the boss,
then why were you even?
Do you have any idea how colossally
you just screwed up?
Zambrano wasn't HR's boss.
He was the witness
that could bring the boss down.
Zambrano's father
was the mob's point man with HR.
And he kept records. A ledger.
With names and dollar amounts
for everyone on HR's payroll...
...including the boss.
And when the don died,
Chris Zambrano found that ledger.
But unlike his dad, Chris was a good man,
totally clean.
When he realized what he was holding,
he called the FBI.
- Why didn't you protect him?
- What do you think we were arguing about?
I tried to convince him.
But because of people
calling him a criminal...
...Zambrano was afraid
we would think he was dirty.
He'd only hand over the ledger
once he'd signed an immunity deal.
And the paperwork came through tonight.
And if you print one word of this,
I will lock your ass up for obstruction.
Well, your tip came from a disposable cell.
The first choice of criminals
and virtually impossible to trace.
So congratulations, Miss Angelis,
you just got played.
Probably by the real head of HR.
So Maxine wasn't the victim,
she was the perpetrator.
Unwitting, involuntary,
but a perpetrator all the same.
The boss wipes out the only witness
who could bring him down...
...and destroys the career
of a troublesome reporter to boot.
And we're gonna find out
who that bastard is and bring him down.
And I'll search Zambrano's digital footprint...
...see if I can find out where he hid
the ledger with the boss' name in it.
And I'll see what our undercover can dig up.
Fusco, you and Simmons need to have
a little talk.
See if he knows who the real head of HR is.
If Simmons knew that,
I would have brought down the boss.
Well, ask anyway and let me know
if you find anything out.
Will do, boss.
All right, Zambrano,
where'd you hide that ledger?
Maxine Angelis.
Max? Quinn. How are you?
- Guess I was due for a tough day.
- Yeah.
We have to use this to discredit you.
Everything you wrote about Griffin.
We're throwing you under the bus, Max.
I'm sorry.
You're a true friend, Quinn.
Glen. What can I do?
I think we've got it handled.
We're moving the election off A1...
...to make room for our retraction
on Zambrano.
I can write the retraction.
I'm afraid you won't be writing anything
until we sit down with Legal.
Ms. Angelis'future
as a journalist may be in doubt...
...but she's not done investigating.
She's calling that disposable cell.
You have reached a voicemail
box that has not been set up yet.
I don't know who you are...
...but I know what you did,
I know where to find your name.
And when I do, I will put a picture of you,
in handcuffs...
...on the front page of this paper.
She's looking for that HR ledger.
And I need to get her to stop
before she gets herself in trouble.
- Hello?
- Maxine. It's John.
I thought maybe you could use a drink.
I was surprised to hear from you.
There's generally no second date
when the first one ends in homicide, heh.
Well, I was, um, thinking about you.
Wanted to see if I could help.
Well, now that you mention it...
...I could use your accounting skills
to scope these records.
Here's everything I've got on Zambrano.
We're looking for where Zambrano might...
I think maybe we should just leave that
for the proper authorities.
I put getting a scoop before getting the truth.
And my arrogance cost a good man his life.
Now, I can't do anything to fix that...
...but I sure as hell can catch the bastard
behind all of this.
Thanks for the beer.
Maxine. Maxine.
I know how it feels
to do things you can never take back.
And I can't stop you from hurting
or wanting to fix this.
But I just don't want you to think
you're alone.
Get down.
Finch, I think the boss got
Maxine's message.
Give me your keys.
Finch, we're heading to my place.
Oh, shoot. I've got your dog.
Bear's even cuter than his picture.
And he really likes that closet, huh?
His, uh, treats are in there.
So that was interesting.
Maybe we should call the cops.
Which ones? If HR's boss is still out there,
I don't know who to trust.
Any idea who was shooting at us?
No, but if they're trying to kill me,
I must be doing something right.
Wow. Guess your boring job pays all right.
I'm calling in sick tomorrow.
I won't leave your side until this is over.
You're a good man, John Anderson.
I'll sleep on the couch.
Like I said, a good man.
And if I want to take my contacts out?
Oh, um...
That way.
When were you ever going to need
all those?
You shouldn't have brought her back here.
Even the best cover just goes so deep.
The longer she stays,
the more questions she'll have.
Imagine how many questions she'll have
if she comes out and sees you here.
Get a look at the men shooting at you?
- I tried but they were shooting at me.
I'll get in the pub's security system,
see what I can find.
I've got a lead, Mr. Reese.
I got images of the shooters
from the pub security.
I found a photo-sharing site
that had a facial-recognition app...
...shut down by a lawsuit.
I hacked in, turned the app back on,
and identified our gunmen.
- They're FBI.
- Ex-FBI. Agents Bogle and Pitt.
They took early retirement last year.
But if they've still got contacts
at the bureau...
...I'd guess that they told HR's boss
about Zambrano's ledger.
Finch, I know you want me to keep my cover.
Maxine needs to know
what she's dealing with.
And I need to be able to protect her.
Calm down. I sent your girlfriend
a text with the same information.
Anonymously, of course.
I need to talk to a friend of yours.
Leonard Pitt and Craig Bogle.
Forced out for harassment
and malicious prosecution.
Word is that
they were in someone's pocket.
They were using those badges
to do favors for their real boss.
The man who got Zambrano killed
with one call from a disposable cell...
...the head of HR, who is he?
There are some secrets
that even I don't know.
But you know who buys disposables
by the case?
Criminals, sure.
But also political campaigns.
They're cheap, untraceable, anonymous.
And if they get caught pulling dirty tricks...
...it can save their ass.
His attendance record is deplorable.
Is this the kind of experience
we want running our city?
Landon Walker is the responsible,
reliable choice for mayor.
Zambrano gets killed for knowing the name
of HR's boss five days before an election.
Are you telling me
the boss is running for mayor?
I'm rendering an opinion.
Personally, I avoid politicians.
They so rarely have any real power.
You know, it was a pleasure meeting you
but it's a shame we never met.
Be good, John.
Yes. Okay, perfect. Thank you so much.
One of Griffin's old opponents
just confirmed...
...being harassed by Bogle and Pitt
during their campaign.
If Griffin's hired them before,
they're probably still working for him.
Do you have enough to unmask him
on the front page?
I will never make that mistake again.
I'm not going to press
until I have that ledger in my hands.
We just need to find where Zambrano hid it.
Pretty smooth conning me into a third date,
by the way.
I like to think of it as a third attempt
at a first date.
Wait.
Wait. Zambrano said everybody thought
he was a wiseguy...
...and nobody ever looked
at the good things he did.
If he were looking for a place
to hide that ledger...
...maybe he would put it where
he thought no one would go looking.
Does that fancy car of yours
have a crowbar?
Here. It's unlocked.
Start with the horses.
They were still being delivered yesterday.
Found something.
Zambrano's ledger.
Wanna find out who's running HR?
Thanks, Maxine.
Our boss has been looking all over for that.
I've called Detective Carter
and help is on the way, Mr. Reese.
You can't take action without Maxine
learning who you really are.
If at all possible, wait for rescue.
I'll try to keep that in mind.
I gotta tell you, you've been a huge help.
First Zambrano, then the ledger.
Now you're kind enough
to bring your boyfriend.
We're gonna dump you at your place.
We'll make it look like a lovers' spat
turned murder-suicide.
When I wind up dead...
...think the police won't find your names
in my notes, Agent Bogle?
Or is it Mr. Bogle now?
And now you're doing a double homicide
to shut me up.
But when you get caught,
will your boss even think twice...
...before killing you to cover his tracks?
Who is your boss, by the way?
Should we open that ledger and find out?
Guess that's a "no comment."
N.Y.P.D. Drop your weapon.
FBI. We're here on official business.
Miss Angelis is a witness
in a homicide investigation.
Drop your guns.
You hear sirens, Pitt?
Two N.Y.P.D. Detectives just took a hot door
without calling for backup.
So you're not here
on official business either.
Where's Griffin? Where's Griffin?
Where's Griffin?
Walker.
Dispatch, I need a bus.
Got a suspect in custody
with a GSW to the shoulder.
- What did I miss?
- Nothing you can't read in tomorrow's paper.
Excuse me, ma'am.
We're gonna need that as evidence.
Thank you.
We've got the fundraiser in midtown.
We have to get there by 3.
Do you think we can do that? Yeah?
Let's go.
Landon Walker.
You're under arrest for receiving bribes,
enterprise corruption and conspiracy.
- You have the right to remain silent.
- Whoa, whoa!
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
So you're off the hook.
Your boss is locked up.
Are we done here?
Once you're in, you're never out.
You want anything else from me...
...never mention my kid again.
I'm not a threat to your son, Lionel.
You are.
No bodies, no bullets.
So this is what a normal date
with you is like.
Nice, isn't it?
And I'm afraid it has to be our last.
I like you, John.
Quite a bit, actually.
But I'm married to my work.
And, honestly, I still think
you're a little hung up on Zoe Morgan.
See you.
So you're off to chase
your "man in a suit"?
No, you were right. Urban legend.
And with the week I just had,
if there really was a man like that...
...I think I'd have met him by now.
Mr. Reese, this may not be over.
You're paranoid, Finch.
Be that as it may...
...I don't think we got the right guy.
Walker was on HR's payroll.
He'd have motive to want Zambrano dead.
Yes, yes, and he definitely hired
Pitt and Bogle to hunt down Maxine.
But that's what troubles me.
The head of HR is brilliant.
Not the type to hire washed-up feds
to gun down a reporter.
And Walker? I'm not convinced
he has the cunning or the connections...
...to mastermind something
this complicated.
All right. If Walker isn't the real head of HR,
who is?
The people of New York have spoken,
and I'm proud to be your next mayor.
So you had Walker on the payroll too, huh?
Hedging your bets.
Smart.
Remind me never to cross you, boss.
That's why I never put my name
on the payroll.
Who needs money
when you have real power?
The politicians come and go,
but we'll be here forever.