It's not my eyes that can see them.
To tell you the truth, I had hoped
that this day would never come.
I wished that this journey would go on forever.
But that was too much to ask for.
Who are you?
" Elegy of Entrapment, Verse 2
(Lamenting the Evils of the Times, Verse 2)"
Maybe we should wait here for a bit.
Jin might come back.
He's not gonna come back unless
he tries to make a move on her
and she kicks him in the nuts.
I wish you'd get serious for once.
Look who's talking.
Geez, do you wanna find that sunflower
samurai guy or don't you? Let's get moving!
This is terrible! Something
terrible's happened, everybody!
The bridge! The rope bridge
outside the village has fallen!
It's what?!
Was anyone on it?
Just come on!
Weren't those two headed in that direction?
You don't think that they--
Sara was carrying those!
Somebody was on the bridge?
Nobody could've survived
a fall from that height.
It can't be...
I found somebody!
She's still alive!
Sara...
Jin... Where's Jin?!
Did you see anyone else? A man?
No. When I got here, there was just that woman.
Hey, don't go down there!
--Mugen!
--Shut up!
What are we gonna do? There's no sign of Jin...
That moron can't see a
damn thing without these.
Those are for show.
Now, now, there's no cause to worry.
Oh, thanks for your help.
Luckily, her injuries don't look too serious.
Go ahead and rest up in this shack for a while.
Thank you so much.
Mugen! Hey, wait!
Sara...
I'm sorry. If only I hadn't
asked him to come with me...
I could say the same thing.
If only I hadn't told him to go with you.
Do you still...
Do you still intend to go to
Nagasaki, no matter what?
I'm going. No matter what.
Oh.
Mugen! Sara's regained consciousness.
Take over for me, okay?
I'm gonna go look for Jin!
I found these in the river.
They're the tools of your trade, ain't they?
I'll be waiting at the riverbank.
I have nothing against you personally.
This is the only life that is open to me.
My son's life is at stake.
Show me what you've got.
I wanna see if you really killed him.
Looks like I don't need to hold anything back.
You bitch!
Shit!
Don't need to hold back? Who am I kidding?
I've crossed swords with all
kinds of people over the years,
but you're in a league of your own, lady.
I never fought anybody like you before.
And that's fine by me!
What was that?
Mugen!
What's going on?! What are you doing?!
Who the hell are you?!
Even though I can't see you,
I can still sense it.
Say what?
Powerful hatred and rage swirl within you.
They are so powerful that I can't tell
whether or not it's actually sadness.
It's as if you've never been loved by anyone.
It's as if... you're like me.
Are you telling me that you know
how I'm gonna come at you?
What a load of crap!
Please, stop!
Just stop it!
--Mugen!
--Stay back!
Stay away!
No!
Don't! Don't kill him!
Come back here! Hey!
Come back here, bitch!
Careful, now. You shouldn't try to get up yet.
Who are you?
Isn't it obvious? I'm the
man who saved your life.
What?
At any rate, you're the first
person I've met in a long time.
Take it easy.
There's something that I must--
Don't be in such a rush. Humans need
to eat to build up their strength.
Want some?
I am in your debt.
You can't have any.
I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
I'll leave it over here, so you get it yourself.
You fell for it! You fell for it!
Why are you tormenting me like this?
You've healed up enough to
make it that far, didn't you?
I'm joking, I'm only joking.
I'll get you something to eat.
I guess I'll go catch you
some fish or something.
Come on, hold still.
Forget it! This scratch will heal by itself!
Geez...
You're well enough to be up and about, huh?
Do you know where a fish's eyes are?
The eyes of a fish?
In the water.
A fish knows what's happening around it by
the flow of the water that surrounds its body.
If you go against the flow of the water, the
fish senses it at the last minute and gets away.
But if you don't fight the current and let
your body move with the flow of the water...
Oops.
Well, sometimes they get away.
Hey, let's just give up.
I mean, if I lost you, too,
I don't know what I'd--
That woman...
Her guard is completely up,
but there's no malice in her, either.
Next time, I might really buy it.
Thank you for all your help.
You're leaving?
That's too bad, I was hoping
to have more fun with you.
I can't.
Here's a souvenir for you.
I will take your wise teachings to heart.
Teachings?
Give a man a fish, and you feed him for a day.
Teach him how to fish,
and you feed him for a lifetime.
It is an old Chinese proverb.
You say the craziest things.
I didn't teach you anything.
You never told me your name.
Musashi Miyamoto.
I'm lying, I'm lying!
I couldn't possibly be him!
You can call me Johnny.
Johnny...?
Stop by again sometime.
What's made you lose your composure?
Did you become attached to them?
Surely you haven't forgotten.
Your life is not your own.
Do you remember that your
son's life is in your hands?
Yes.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Make sure that the job is finished by tomorrow.
A g-g-ghost!
Are you hungry?
I've been worried sick about you, and the best
you can come up with is, "Are you hungry?"
Even a ghost would have
something more thoughtful to say.
That's what you get for trying
to hog all the fun for yourself!
Hey, what are you talking about?
You went off by yourself with her
because you knew damn well
that she was trying to kill us.
What's become of her?
That lady is one serious badass.
I see...
Jin...
It's likely that we've been
thoroughly investigated.
She was ordered by someone to befriend us.
She said something about
her kid's life being on the line.
Hang on. If that's true, doesn't it
mean that Sara's being used, too?
Do you have any idea who it could be?
We've skipped out on our restaurant bills,
snuck through a checkpoint, and killed people.
Take your pick.
I find it hard to believe that anyone would
hire an assassin of her caliber over that.
True enough.
I guess not...
Well, whoever it was who sent her,
if she's trying to kill us,
she'll show up again soon enough.
That woman can see our moves
a split second before we make them.
Sure looks that way.
A fish...
A fish knows what is happening around it by
the flow of the water that surrounds its body.
Don't fight the current.
Let your body flow with it.
If you do that, you might
be able to grab the fish.
Where'd you hear that?
It's something I picked up
from the man who saved my life.
Well, if this is the only life open to you...
...then I'll do what has to be done.
Do you still intend to go to
Nagasaki, no matter what?
I see.
Mugen!
Shit!
Don't fight the current.
Let your body flow with it.
If you do that, you might be able to catch her.
Why'd you do it? Why'd you hold back?!
You could've killed me!
I figured it out today.
My son died a long time ago.
I was just being used.
Then why--
I can't fight them. They're the government.
I want you to live, Mugen.
Dawn comes, and we part ways once again
My dreams becoming distant apparitions
I turn to the warm wind for help,
the wind I felt every time you held me
As I was bathed in the light
that followed on your heels
Spring is announced when the
wild plants break out in a dance
Summer comes to Uji, and in the fields
are patterns of grass set out to dry
The autumn moon rises,
let's celebrate its fullness
Winter passes by, and I count off
the days and months again
I can still see the too-distant blue sky
when I close my eyes (It was so warm)
As I reminisce, I take your hand
as I pluck flowers and sing
Within the memories that
are now coming back to me
I'm setting out to find my way back to you
Spring is announced when the
mountain leaves break out in dance
Summer comes to Uji, and textiles with
plains grass patterns are set out to dry
The autumn moon rises,
let's celebrate its fullness
Winter passes by, and I count off
the days and months again
Dawn comes, and we part ways once again
My dreams becoming distant apparitions
I turn to the warm wind for help,
the wind I felt every time you held me
As I was bathed in the light
that followed on your heels