PICARD:
Captain's log, stardate 41697.9.
We're en route to Sarona VIII
for a much-needed shore leave.
The entire crew is looking forward
to the diversion.
On a personal note, I have allowed
myself the luxury of a head start.
[DEVICE BEEPING]
I took advantage.
No, no, lieutenant,
the advantage was yours.
Come again.
En garde.
[PICARD YELLS & DEVICE BEEPS]
Interesting move, sir.
But what technique was that?
The technique of a desperate man.
Interesting move, sir.
But what technique was that?
The technique of a desperate man.
Captain, what was that?
- Picard to Bridge.
RIKER [OVER INTERCOM]: Captain.
Number One, did something unusual
just occur on the Bridge?
RIKER:
Yes, sir.
We experienced some kind of loop
where everything repeats itself.
Here too.
Hm o n m Y way
Report, Mr. Data.
Sensors show nothing, sir.
But it appears a moment in time
repeated itself exactly. For everyone.
It was like a feeling of déjà vu.
Reports coming in from all decks, sir.
Computers were also affected, sir,
which would indicate the phenomenon
was not an illusion,
but occurred in real time.
PICARD: Number One,
find out if anything similar happened
in this sector.
Sir, I am receiving
an emergency transmission
from the Pages Minor system.
Put it on.
[STATIC CRACKLES]
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
--542.2.
I repeat, this is Dr. Paul Manheim.
We are in need of help. Urgent.
All ships, please respond.
I repeat,
coordinates are 66728.9 by 7075...
It is an automated signal, sir.
I am unable to establish contact.
MAN: This is Dr. Paul Manheim...
- Shut it off.
Mr. La Forge, lay in a course
on those coordinates.
Aye, sir.
Captain,
you act as if there's a connection
between the time distortion
and the distress signal.
There is.
Paul Manheim.
Fifteen years ago, he went off
to work on experiments
relating to nonlinear time.
It appears he may have achieved
some measure of success.
- Speed warp 8.
- Aye, sir, warp 8.
Engage.
PICARD:
Space, the final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its continuing mission:
to explore strange new worlds,
to seek out new life
and new civilizations,
to boldly go where no one
has gone before.
Estimated arrival Pegos Minor,
four hours 35 minutes 17 seconds.
I've never heard of Paul Manheim.
Mr. Data?
A highly respected scientist,
considered a visionary.
He advanced
several time-related theories.
One regarding the relationships between
time and gravity was quite intriguing.
But neither that theory nor any other
received wide acceptance.
Fifteen years ago,
he assembled a team of scientists
to expand that research.
They disappeared.
Haven't been heard from since.
RIKER:
Did you know him, captain?
I knew of him.
He was teaching at the university
when I was in Paris, but I, uh,
didn't have the pleasure.
I must change.
Number One, inform me half an hour
before we reach those coordinates,
and keep trying to determine
if the time distortion was specifically
located on the Enterprise.
RIKER: Yes, sir.
- Captain.
- Excuse me.
PICARD: Yes, what is it, counselor?
I think you would prefer
to discuss this in private.
No, that's not necessary. Go on.
When Professor Manheim's name
was mentioned,
you reacted with intense emotion.
Yes. Please, get to the point.
I don't want to interfere
with your personal life,
but unresolved, strong emotion
can affect judgment.
[DOOR OPENS]
Well, thank you for your concern.
As ship's counselor,
I offer my assistance.
What do you suggest?
Confronting deep personal issues
is not easy for you.
You tend to suppress them.
There are a few hours
until we arrive.
Perhaps you should use this time
to analyze your feelings
and put them into perspective.
Thank you, counselor.
If I should need you further,
I'll let you know.
Bridge.
Belay that.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
Computer,
estimated arrival at Pegos Minor.
COMPUTER:
Two hours, nine minutes.
[SIGHS]
Holodeck 3.
Computer, this is Captain Picard.
COMPUTER:
Holodeck 3 is clear.
Location, Paris.
Café des Artistes
as it appeared 22 years ago.
April the 9th, 1,500 hours, 3:00.
Warm spring day.
COMPUTER:
Program complete.
[BAL-MUSETTE MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
Monsieur,
welcome to the Café des Artistes.
- Is this your first time in Paris?
- No.
This way.
That table.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
We are here to please you.
I've been away far too long.
Some wine? Some cheese?
I'm not very hungry.
I really came for the view.
Perhaps what you hunger for
is not on the menu.
Perhaps not.
It was many years ago.
I had a rendezvous.
I was to meet someone.
Someone here, at that very table.
Your young lady, she did not come?
Actually, I don't know.
I always imagined that she did.
Oh, you, however, did not.
Ah.
Well, trust Edourd.
I will bring something very special
just for you.
Let's go, ah?
We've waited long enough.
Fine, you go. I'll stay a little longer.
FRANCINE:
He's not coming, Gabrielle.
No. After last night, I know he will.
I just know it.
FRANCINE:
Then he would be here.
You are making a fool out of yourself,
and I will not watch.
- Do we know each other?
- No.
Well, the way you look at me.
Do I remind you of someone?
No.
Yes. You do, somewhat.
He's not coming.
Why? What did I do
to drive him away?
Maybe you did nothing.
Maybe he had no choice.
Maybe he was afraid.
Of what? Of me?
Oh, of being connected, rooted.
Perhaps if he's as young as you are,
he doesn't know yet exactly
what it is he wants to do.
Maybe...
Enough of this self-indulgence.
Exit.
Captain, we received communication
from the freighter Lalo
as well as from a farming colony
on Coltar IV.
Both described
the same time distortion.
The captain of the Lalo described it
as a hiccup.
- Hiccup?
DATA: Actually, sir,
that may be an incorrect analogy.
PICARD:
How so, Data?
A hiccup is a spasmodic inhalation
with closure of the glottis,
accompanied by a peculiar sound.
If we were to continue this analogy
to a body function,
- what occurred would be best--
- Enough, Data.
Have you been able to learn any more
specifics about the Manheim project?
All I have found, sir,
is what you already know.
Manheim was concentrating on
time/gravity experiments when he left.
Captain, we've reached
the coordinates specified.
There's nothing here.
I'm receiving new coordinates.
It's a relay signal.
Same source as the first one.
LA FORGE:
What are they, Worf'?
664.8 by 1323.7 by 4949.9.
Very remote area, sir.
It's in the middle of the Render system
a binary star system.
The main star is a B-class giant,
the companion star is a pulsar.
Set course for the new coordinates,
Mr. La Forge.
LA FORGE:
Aye, sir.
Why is he making it this difficult
to find him?
Hopefully, he'll tell us, Number One.
We have reached the coordinates,
captain.
Sensors indicate it is Vandor IV,
a planetoid in elliptical orbit
around the binary system.
- Standard orbit, Mr. La Forge.
LA FORGE: Aye, sir.
Give me a visual.
Viewscreen on.
There's a small force field
on the planet.
Latitude 20 degrees,
nine minutes north,
longitude 40 degrees, two minutes
east of the present terminator.
- Penetrable?
- No, sir.
Open hailing frequencies.
Hailing frequencies open, sir.
This is Captain-- This is the captain
of the USS Enterprise
responding to your call for help.
WOMAN [OVER RADIO]:
Enterprise, thank you for hearing us.
Where are you?
We're in orbit around Vandor now.
WOMAN:
Then you can help me.
I don't know what to do.
It's only the two of us left.
He's having convulsions.
Please.
Can you lock on to her coordinates?
No, sir, the force field is preventing
any kind of contact other than audio.
- There is a force field at your location.
WOMAN: Yes. I know.
Good. But it is preventing us
from helping you.
Now, you must try to find some way
to shut it down.
WOMAN:
I'll try.
[COMPUTER BEEPING]
Force field is off.
Good. Lock on to their coordinates,
beam them up directly to Sickbay.
Dr. Crusher,
prepare for a medical emergency.
Two to beam directly up to Sickbay.
CRUSHER [OVER INTERCOM]:
We'll be ready, captain.
That's where I'll be.
Number One, Mr. Data.
[PAUL GRUNTING]
I'll help.
Easy. Easy.
I've got his legs.
- How long has he been like this?
JENICE: Several hours. Al least.
He was in his lab, so I can't be sure.
I need to do some tests.
I, um...
Jean-Luc.
I thought the voice sounded familiar.
Hello.
[CHUCKLES]
I should have known.
Who else would have charged
to my rescue?
This is my first officer,
Commander William Riker.
Lieutenant Commander Data.
This is Jenice Manheim.
- A pleasure, Mrs. Manheim.
JENICE: Thank you.
I have a number of questions for you.
I hope I can be of some help.
Why don't we sit down here?
You said there were only two of you left.
What happened to the rest of the crew?
They were working at the second lab.
Something happened there
a few weeks ago.
They were all killed.
[JENICE SIGHS]
It was a terrible accident.
I don't know exactly what happened.
So many brilliant, wonderful minds
just gone.
Do you know the nature
of Dr. Manheim's work?
Paul's always been interested in time.
He's never believed
that it was immutable
any more than space is immutable.
Over the last decade,
he came to believe
that we reside
in one of infinite dimensions,
and what holds us here
is the constancy of time.
Change that, and it would be
what he called “opening the window"
to those other dimensions.
Which begins
to explain what happened.
Have you been experiencing
something up here'?
Yes. What is emanating here is
having repercussions light years away.
Maybe even further.
That would explain his anxiety.
I had no idea it had gone so far
beyond Vandor.
Why this place? Why Vandor?
All I can tell you about that
is that Paul and the rest of the team
searched for two years to find it.
Vandors exactly what they needed.
A planetoid around a binary star.
Because of the dense gravity
of the pulsar?
Did your husband ever attempt
to define these dimensions
to give you an idea
of what he expected?
No. But he did say that he was
very close to proving his theories.
And then the accident.
Did he anticipate that these
experiments might be dangerous?
I didn't think so.
But now, in retrospect,
he probably did.
That would explain the unusual
precautions he began taking.
Even before the accident.
The force field,
the elaborate security system.
And every time
he started a new experiment,
he insisted that I stay
in what he called "a protected room."
Aha. And that's why
you weren't affected.
Jean-Luc, he would never knowingly
do anything to hurt anyone.
Yes, I believe that.
But as he saw his goal getting closer,
seeming possible,
he became
more and more obsessive.
Maybe that clouded his judgment.
This is not howl imagined
seeing you again.
PICARD:
Nor I you.
JENICE:
You've done well.
A great starship
on the far reaches of the galaxy.
It's everything you'd hoped.
[CHUCKLES]
Not exactly.
Nothing works just as you hope.
If you can't tell us any more,
I need to send a team down to the lab.
You can't. it's protected.
One of the young scientists
made sure no one could get in.
CRUSHER:
Uh, excuse me.
- Is he worse?
CRUSHER: He's resting.
But I'd like you
to undergo some tests yourself.
My nurse will start them.
Thank you for your kindness, doctor.
- She's an old friend.
- I gathered that.
It's her husband I'm more concerned
with at the moment.
- What's the prognosis?
- I believe he's dying.
His neurochemistry's been affected,
but I don't know how or why.
I've never encountered
anything like it before.
- How long does he have?
- Maybe a couple of days.
It's hard to predict.
All I can do is maintain him,
or attempt to maintain him,
until I find out
what's causing the damage.
- Can we talk to him?
- Not now. Not yet.
DATA:
Incidentally, captain,
the effects of the time distortions are
now being felt in the llecom system.
PICARD:
Bridge.
In the past decade, Manheim
has turned some vague theories
into a practical application.
Yes. But without his help,
I'm not sure we'll be able
to pose any intelligent questions,
let alone come up with any solutions.
DATA:
Incidentally, captain,
the effects of the time distortions are
now being felt in the llecom system.
It's us
before we stepped into the turbolift.
It's happening again.
I feel no disorientation.
Nor do I.
What was that?
I believe what could be termed
as the Manheim Effect
is becoming more pronounced.
RIKER:
This is where we started.
If we are us.
Oh, we are us, sir.
But they are also us.
So, indeed, we are both us.
At different points
along the same time continuum.
[DOOR OPENS]
Bridge.
PICARD:
What have you learned?
We have completed a scan
of the planet's surface, sir.
We've discovered the second lab
is on the far side of the planet,
completely destroyed.
Unable to determine what caused it.
Otherwise,
very little to clarify this situation.
Our sensors
show an immense volume of energy
emanating deep within the planet
and concentrated
near Manheim's remaining laboratory.
- How is the energy being used?
- No idea.
PICARD: What's its source?
- I cannot be sure, sir.
But I believe Manheim
has developed a method
for harnessing energy
from the pulsar.
RIKER:
It comes down to this.
We've learned everything we can
from here,
and we are no closer to understanding
it than we were 12 hours ago.
Manheim is unable to help us,
but hopefully, having been
a good scientist, he kept notes.
I would need
to study Manheim's records.
To do that, we're going to have
to go down there.
What about the defense system
Mrs. Manheim spoke of?
It may have been connected
to the main system.
When she lowered the shield,
she may have turned that off as well.
If not,
we'll deal with it as best we can.
Prepare your team
Aye, sir.
RIKER: Coordinates set?
HERBERT: Yes, sir.
Energize.
There's a lack of integrity
at the landing point.
[OVER INTERCOM]
I'm losing them.
Bring them back. Now.
Chief Herbert, what's going on?
There seems to be some kind
of strange bouncing effect.
I can'! get them to materialize.
My readings aren't complete.
Keep trying-
What are we doing back here?
You're lucky
you made it back at all, sir.
Where am I?
Paul.
Thank God.
You're on the USS Enterprise.
They answered your distress signal.
I sent one?
Oh, Paul, you're gonna be just fine.
No. I'm not fine, Jenice.
I'm not even close to fine.
Bridge, this is Dr. Crusher.
Professor Manheim is conscious.
PAUL: Remember, it was worth it,
what happened.
What will happen, all of it,
it was all worth it.
Again. it's changing again.
What is? What do you see?
PAUL:
I'm having difficulty...
With what? Are you in pain?
I have been on the other side.
I have touched another dimension.
Part of me is still there.
Help him.
Try to stay calm, Dr. Manheim.
I don't think it's going to help,
your struggling against it.
My mind is ﬂoating
between two places.
It is difficult to know which is which.
There is no way to explain it.
Dr. Manheim, I'm Captain Picard.
The same one?
She has told me about you.
Not all, but enough.
We need your help.
This situation is not good.
It will get worse.
What do we do? How do we stop it?
I'm having difficulty
holding the moment.
Doctor,
this is Lieutenant Commander Data.
Will you explain the situation to him?
I am fully versed, sir, on all your
theories regarding time and gravity.
How is that possible?
I am not even fully versed
on all of my theories.
I am an android.
Android?
On a Starﬂeet vessel?
I am the only one, sir.
PAUL:
Your knowledge is useless
because the work we have done has
made most of those theories obsolete.
Then you have harnessed
a dynamic energy source.
PAUL:
Then you do understand, yes.
We were able to locate an energy
source in the center of this planetoid.
We learned to enhance it, to focus it.
Everything worked too well.
The energy from the pulsar,
the energy from the planetoid...
We opened a crack.
A window into another dimension.
The time distortion we felt.
Felt?
Then it is not confined
to the planetoid?
The range is at least
several thousand light years.
Captain, it must be stopped.
You must help me
to execute a controlled shutdown
of this experiment.
Get my notes. They are in the lab.
How do we bypass
the security system?
I'll give you the correct coordinates
to beam safely down to Vandor
and the codes you'll need to bypass
security systems to get into my lab.
[GASPS THEN WHIMPERS]
[PAUL WHIMPERING]
If what the professor has given me
is accurate,
it is possible to repair the damage.
But it must be perfectly timed to coincide
with another time-distortion episode.
- Can we predict the timing?
- I believe so, sir.
We have to.
If we don't seal that hole,
this other dimension he's opened
will rip into the fabric of the galaxy.
Reality as we perceive it
will not be the same.
- Lieutenant Worf.
WORF: Yes, sir?
I want those codes
that Manheim gave Mr. Data
rechecked and then checked again.
No one is beaming down to Vandor
unless we can be reasonably sure
they can get through.
WORF:
Aye, sir.
[DOOR OPENS]
I'm sorry for intruding.
I was told I'd find you here.
You're not intruding.
We've just finished.
Come in. Thank--
[DOOR CLOSES]
Uh, I knew you wouldn't come to me.
No. Not under these circumstances.
We have unfinished business.
PICARD:
Yes, we do.
Why didn't you come to meet me
that last day in Paris?
- I was afraid.
- Oh. I didn't want this.
- What?
- The truth.
- Oh, you want me to lie?
- Of course.
[CHUCKLES]
A nice, soft, painless lie.
Oh, I got the days confused. I thought it
was Tuesday when it was Wednesday.
I went to the Café Moulin
instead of the Cafe des Artistes.
Ah. That's better.
It was raining
and you couldn't find a cab.
Mm-hm.
I waited all day.
And it was raining.
It rained the rest of the week.
I went to Starﬂeet headquarters
looking for you,
but you had already shipped out.
So...
Come on, Jean-Luc.
Let's hear the truth.
It was fear.
Fear of seeing you
and losing my resolve.
Fear of staying.
Losing myself.
Fear that neither of these choices
was right and that...
And that either would have...
[SIGHS]
For a long time, not a day went by
that I didn't look up into the sky
and wonder.
Each time that I returned to Earth,
my thoughts were filled with you.
I've thought a lot about this
over the years,
and perhaps you're leaving out
your greatest fear.
The real reason you left.
Which was?
That life with me would have somehow
made you ordinary.
[SIGHS]
[CHUCKLING]
You're wonderful.
And am I that transparent?
Only to me.
I wish I could talk to you,
Professor Manheim.
I bet you were really something.
[GRUNTING]
Deanna.
I wanted to see how he was doing.
The same.
Nothing I do seems
to make any difference.
That's not why you're here.
I thought I was the empath.
Are you all right?
Why wouldn't I be?
I've got one of the medical wonders
of the galaxy dying in my Sickbay.
That's not what I meant.
I don't think I want to talk
about what I think you mean.
- Captain Picard--
- I can't compete
with a ghost from his past.
No one could.
She's not a ghost.
She's here right now.
She may be in the here and now,
but it's the ghost he sees.
Excuse me,
I have to get back to my patient.
How soon, Mr. Data?
If Dr. Manheim's information
is correct,
by my calculations, the next time,
distortion should occur
between 28 to 47 minutes.
CRUSHER [OVER INTERCOM]:
Bridge, this is Sickbay.
Dr. Manheim is awake
and asking to speak to you, captain.
Alone.
On my way, doctor.
You asked for me.
I am not sure that I remembered all
of the codes for the security system.
You should warn anyone
going down there.
Thank you.
I'll tell them to be cautious.
What I really wanted to talk
to you about is Jenice.
Dr. Manheim, I did not come here
to discuss your wife.
It is only this.
If anything should go wrong, please,
take care of her for me.
Of course.
She never would admit this,
but she has had a terrible time
these last years.
Had we not been so isolated,
she might have left me
and I never would have known.
At least, not right away.
Perhaps I am not a man
who should have a woman like her.
She deserves better.
You underestimate her.
I know because I once did.
In both cases,
the time distortions occurred
along the same continuum
as a preview, or a reprise,
of a specific point in time.
Where we are, where we were,
and where we will be.
Data, I want this
to be an away team of one. You.
I don't think there's any reason
to risk anyone else.
It is reasonable, sir. After all,
I am a machine and dispensable.
"Indispensable"
is the appropriate word.
I think it should be only you
because you seem more able to
control the effects of a time distortion.
Oh, I see, sir. That is quite true, sir.
I see time as a constant, whereas
humans perceive time as flexible.
Hence the expression
"Time flies when you're having fun."
Which until now
has always confused me.
Well, I want you to put a stitch in time
and, uh, save much more than nine.
Sir?
If other members of the away team
became disoriented,
it could create additional problems
and perhaps increase the danger.
I will go immediately, sir.
Good luck, Data.
All right. We have the coordinates
exactly as the professor specified.
- Enterprise.
PICARD [OVER RADIO]: Picard.
I am proceeding to the lab, sir.
PICARD: Maintain an open frequency,
Mr. Data.
Aye, sir.
[LASER POWERS UP]
[LASERS FIRING OVER RADIO]
Mr. Data, what's going on?
Dr. Manheim forgot to mention
one of his security precautions, sir.
I am proceeding into the laboratory.
PICARD: Mr. Data,
this channel will remain open.
Please continue to report.
This appears to be the instrument
Dr. Manheim described.
It should confirm
when the next time effect will occur.
RIKER [OVER RADIO]:
Data,
did Manheim give you
enough information
to decipher the security code?
I will know in a moment, sir.
According to calculations,
the next time effect will occur
in one minute 30 seconds.
What's the next step, Mr. Data?
I will need to add a specific amount
of antimatter
to rebalance and align the system.
PICARD: Will that plug the hole?
- Theoretically, yes.
In reality, I do not know.
When the effect hits,
the force fields will align,
opening a clean, straight path
to the other dimension.
Whatever the time distortion,
I must add the antimatter
at the appropriate moment.
Geordi, if the professor was right,
I will need a 27-second countdown.
LA FORGE [OVER RADIO]:
You've got it, Data.
Captain, I now have the antimatter
and am moving towards the opening
at the end of the lab.
The next time distortion
should occur within seconds.
Geordi.
Begin countdown on my mark.
Now!
LA FORGE:
Twenty-seven, 26, 25,
- 24, 23, 22,21...
LA FORGE: Twenty-four, 23, 22, 21...
Captain,
there appear to be three of us.
Should I drop the antimatter
or wait for one of you?
Only one of us
is in the correct time continuum.
Which one?
Me. it's me.
LA FORGE: --six, five, five, five,
four, four, four, three, three, three,
two, two, two, one, one, one.
PICARD:
Data?
- Report. Are you all right?
- Yes, sir.
PICARD:
Is it closed?
It is well patched, sir.
Closed indicates a permanent
condition which I cannot guarantee.
Patched is good enough. Well done.
Beam back immediately.
With pleasure, sir.
This is amazing.
All your readings
are completely normal.
PAUL:
Where is my wife? Is she all right?
She's right here.
- Jenice.
- Paul.
The effect has been reversed.
I can feel it.
We're safe.
- How is he?
- He needs rest.
There might be some residual effects.
But other than that, he'll be all right.
I feel like I'm coming out
of a long tunnel.
It's there.
Not at all like I thought it would be.
Different.
Describe it.
I can't. Not yet.
The only words that fit are too pale
because the images are so vibrant.
It's not like anything
anyone has ever experienced before.
There was--
No, no, there is this kind of life.
Not like us. Not like this.
What's the condition of my lab?
Intact, for the most part.
Don't tell me we-'re going back.
Oh, Jenice, we are so close.
We have learned so much
to walk away.
Besides, we owe it to the others,
our friends.
There have been so many sacrifices
by so many good people.
We'll be going back.
Mm-hm. Yes, I can see that.
I'm sure the Federation will want
to help in any way that it can.
Thank you.
This time it will be different.
I promise.
[JENICE LAUGHS]
JENICE:
It always is, my love.
You said my life would never be dull,
and it never has been.
Thank you.
Computer, this is Counselor Troi.
Request access.
COMPUTER: Do you wish
to terminate the current program?
No, continue the program.
COMPUTER:
Enter when ready.
The captain is waiting for you inside.
How is this possible?
It's Paris.
Unbelievable.
Madame, this way.
The captain is waiting for you.
This is so real.
[SPEAKING IN FRENCH]
[EDOUARD CHUCKLES]
Jean-Luc, don't tell me how you did it.
I don't care.
It's perfect.
It's as if we were really there.
I wanted to say goodbye properly
this time.
I shall always picture you here.
I expect you to always come charging
to my rescue.
I'll do my best.
Goodbye, Jean-Luc.
Be well.
And you.
Thank you for Paris.
Well, so much
for my dramatically romantic exit.
- Is anything wrong?
- No, sir.
PICARD:
Then set course for Sarona VIII.
As I remember, we were on our way
for some much-needed shore leave.
Course plotted and laid in, sir.
Warp 5.
Engage.
I've only been there once,
but they've got this great club.
I don't remember the name of it.
They serve those blue concoctions.
It's across the square
from the Zanza Men's Dance Palace.
It's called the Blue Parrot Café,
and you're buying.