Teen Titans [01x01] - Divide And Conquer EN v1.0
Subtitles by Mr.Henky
Code red! Cell block Nine! Move out!
Main yard secure.
There he is!
He’ll free the criminals!
Fire!
You know, Cinderblock, normally the bad guys break out of jail.
And I can think of five good reasons why you don’t want to break in.
One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
Five!
No matter how you do the math, it all adds up to you going down. So, are you going to go quietly…
…or is this gonna get loud?
Titans! Go!
I am sorry to disappoint you, but I am stronger than I look.
Azarath Metrion—
Heh…watch out for falling dinosaurs?
I’m gonna leave you alone now.
Thrashing only makes me hold tighter!
Now there’s an idea.
Want to give this guy the Sonic Boom?
I got the Sonic if you got the Boom.
Yo, Rockhead!
Hey, hey, look at this. It’s freedom!…Let’s do it!…Let’s get outta here!…Yeah!
Let’s go, let’s go!
I think we’re gonna make it!
Yeah!
Huh?
Think again.
Jailbreak? I don’t see any jailbreak.
None of us would have seen one if Cyborg hadn’t messed up!
Me? I messed up nothing!
You got in my way!
You were too far forward, and Cinderblock got away because of it!
You saying this is my fault?
Want me to say it again?
Stop! No more mean talking!
Yeah. If you two are gonna fight, we need time to sell tickets.
Cinderblock escaped. No amount of yelling will change that. So stop acting like idiots, and let’s go home.
Hmph!
Loser.
Jerk.
What did you say?!?
Do you have a problem, Tin Man?
Yeah! It’s four feet tall and smells like cheap hair gel!
Well, you’re an oversized klutz and your feet smell like motor oil!
You’re bossy, you’re rude, you got no taste in music!
I don’t even know why you’re on this team!
That makes two of us! I QUIT!!
Cinderblock. I see your mission was a success. Good. We will proceed with Phase Two. Wake him.
I’m…awake? I should never be awake! I’m only human when I’m sleeping!
But for what I have in mind, your human form is useless.
I need Plasmus.
This is Cyborg. I’m either in the gym, playing GameStation-
-or kicking bad-guy butt. Leave a message.
Hello? Cy? Pick up!
Come on, Cy, pick up!
I know you’re there. The phone’s built in your arm!
Taste.
What is that? Cream of toenails?
Pudding of Sadness.
It is what the people of my planet eat when bad things happen.
Try. The displeasing taste will ease your troubled mind.
My mind is never troubled. People come, people go. It’s pointless to be upset about Cyborg.
What?
Here, Robin. You must need this most of all since…well…
I’m fine.
Who knows? Maybe we’re better off without him.
Yo! Whose turn to do dishes?
Cyborg.
Come on, come on…I’m not scared to take…no! Yeah! Got it! Just one more and…yes!
New high score!
I’m sorry.
Cinderblock strikes again?
You wish.
That stuff can’t be good for you.
Nice one!
Star! Let him have it!
Did I let him have too much?
I’m thinking not enough.
Maybe he just needs to chill.
Azarath Metrion Zinthos!
Come on! Let me go, you giant zit!
Robin!
I’m okay…sort of.
And I thought Star’s pudding tasted bad!
Disappointing.
With one Titan missing, this is almost too easy.
I was expecting more of a challenge. Cinderblock.
Begin Phase Three.
I feel like the underside of a Zornian muck beetle.
Tell me about it.
Dude, I am not on the menu!
Maybe the best way to take you down…
…is to tie you up!
We did it!
Nice work, team.
Yeah. Didn’t think we’d pull it off without-
We finished just in time. Cinderblock’s been spotted downtown. Come on!
Huh?
Uh…heads up.
Four against five. Not good odds.
Forget the odds. We need a plan.
Titans! Separate!
I still got the Sonic if you still got the Boom.
Teen Titans! Go!
Look, uh…sorry about…
Yeah.
So…are we cool?
Frosty.
You made up! Glorious! I wish to initiate a group hug.
Pass.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, warm fuzzies all around. But we still gotta stop Cinderblock.
No, we don’t.
Thought I’d bring a present, ’case you were still mad.
Thanks. But there is one thing that’s still bothering me.
Breaking into jail? Using Plasmus to distract us? The whole plan seems to be a little too smart for Cinderblock.
I’ve been thinking the same thing.
Someone must have been pulling the strings. But who?
Well, whoever they are-
-they’re no match for the Teen Titans.
I heard that!
Next time my plans will succeed. And the Titans will pay.