Enter the action zone.
Scanning for Teenage
Mutant Ninja Turtles.
Locked ! Access now !
Teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtles
Turtle power
They're the world's most
fearsome fighting team
They're heroes
in the half shell
and they're green
When the evil shredder
attacks
turtles fight back
Teenage Mutant
Ninja Turtles
Turtle power
3, 2, 1.
vortex crystal
demutation ray activated.
if this works,
our wild mutations
may soon be history.
aah aah uhh.
he survived
the energy ray.
now if his genes
check out as normal,
we're home free,
fellas.
uh--uh, dudes,
i--i feel kind of funny.
he's mutating !
leonardo: whoa, look out !
get out of the way !
snap out of it,
michelangelo.
i don't want
to have to hurt you.
sorry,
michelangelo,
but you asked
for it.
come on, michelangelo,
snap out of it.
just our luck,
a swiss army mutant.
whoa.
ah, well,
that didn't work.
it's a good thing
we ran a virtual
reality simulation
on that demutation ray
before we tried it
on ourselves.
look on
the bright side, guys.
we can make a bundle
selling that
as a video game.
can i play it again ?
this is no joke,
raphael.
we've got
to find a way
to stabilize
our mutations.
stormy seas
grow calm
when the wind
stops blowing.
calm you mind and you
will find the answer.
ahh, all right.
let's start over
with the calculations.
lord dregg,
sensors indicate
that vortex crystals
have been activated
within this quadrant
of the galaxy.
the readings are
coming from earth !
of course.
those mutant turtles
must've figured out that
the crystal has the power
to stabilize
their mutations.
but the readings
are so low, lord dregg.
they must only have
a few fragments.
with even the tiniest piece,
i can genetically recreate
another crystal.
then i can complete
the vortex transporter.
where's mung ?
here, your lordship.
when will
the dreggnaught be ready ?
oh, it is ready now,
your lordship.
but, dregg, even if
we return to earth,
it will take months
to reconstruct
the vortex transporter.
may it please you,
sire...
with this you can build
whatever you dream
in just hours.
that's impossible.
you are looking at
over a million
computerized microbots.
mung, how would you
like to leave
this slimy planet and
be my second in command ?
but i am your
second in command !
no one but dregg
is superior
to the high-tech.
i'm sending you on
a mission, high-tech.
you'll orbit the galaxy
like a space probe
and return with untold data
in say, 2,000 light years.
high-tech: lord dregg !
no !
i will not
disappoint you,
my lord.
i've adjusted the crystal
oscillation frequency
to automatically match
your genetic codes.
it should work
this time.
all right, let's run
another v. r. test.
whoa, dudes, i feel like
totally perfectimundo,
even though i am
a virtual turtle.
we did it.
now all
i've got to do
is run a simulation
on my genetic code.
carter: commencing
simulation.
no, it didn't work.
the vortex crystal
has no effect on
my genetic code.
the same notes
played another way
make
beautiful music.
you must find your
own song, carter.
scanners have located
the vortex crystal
emissions, lord dregg.
i trust your microbots
will be able
to accomplish the task.
it will take only one
to track down
the vortex crystal.
a microrocket.
brilliant.
vital signs
are holding steady.
crystal fragments
are charged and ready.
stabilizing raphael's
genetic code.
excuse me.
stabilizing donatello.
aah.
hmm.
stabilizing michelangelo.
stabilizing leonardo.
ah, that was easy.
yeah, but how
can we be sure
we're really
back to normal ?
leonardo's
got a point.
we need to test
your genetic stability.
yeah, we usually
mutate under stress.
too bad we don't have
that alien sleazeball dregg
to deal with.
i wouldn't be
so hasty
in your assumption,
raphael.
but in the meantime,
i suggest you try
some sparring.
hyah !
oh, i think we're...
totally back to normal.
i think
i'm totally... wasted.
it appears you are back
to your stable form.
hey, carter,
where are you going ?
well, i came here
to learn from splinter,
and i'm grateful for
all you've taught me,
but i think i should
go back to college.
maybe if i continue
my studies
in biochemistry,
i can discover a way
to change myself
back to normal.
don't be silly.
we'll find a way
to stabilize
your mutations.
yeah, and besides, we've
gotten used to having
a non-turtle
in the family.
thanks, guys,
but i've made up my mind.
and you're sure
we can't change
your mind, carter ?
well, then we're
sure gonna miss you.
huh ?
whoa !
come on, leonardo.
first, you rag on me
for goofing off
at the v. r. simulator,
now you're doing it.
hey !
whoa !
ohh !
that's no simulation.
leonardo's mutated !
no kidding.
we've got to stop him
before he trashes
the whole lair.
take it easy, dude.
we're your buds.
yeow !
uhh.
talk about
a terrible time
not to have our
super mutation powers.
donatello:
he's getting away !
we'll catch him
in the van.
raphael:
carter, let's roll.
carter:
leonardo's mutation
was caused by
a power drop.
i should've seen it.
hey, let's worry about
whose fault it is
after we get him
under control.
no. i've got to find out
what went wrong.
you go on without me.
the microbot has returned,
lord dregg.
mung: and it's got
the crystal fragment.
excellent.
once the genetic cloning
of the crystal is complete,
it will power
my vortex transporter.
capable of
transporting anything
from one end of
the universe to the other.
oh, just what you need
to conquer the earth.
exactly. and eliminate those
meddlesome turtles as well.
prepare
the remaining microbots.
yes, lord dregg.
cab driver: yeah, sure
there's plenty of kooks
and crazies, lady.
but on the whole,
i think the city's
getting better.
uh, like
i was saying,
the city is no kind
of place to live !
look, there he is !
i sure hope our insurance
covers mutant damage.
easy, leonardo.
now, we're not gonna
hurt you.
he's definitely having
a bad hair day.
michelangelo: oh, great,
just what we needed,
more bad press.
we've got to get leonardo
out of here and fast.
get ready, guys.
hey, leonardo, catch !
get the van, dudes !
yeow !
whoa ow !
raphael, call april
and see if she can keep
us off the 11:00 news.
oh, sure, give me
the impossible job.
april,
it's raphael.
what's up ?
leonardo's mutated
out of control.
he's doing
a king kong routine
for the local news.
can you pull the plug
on the story ?
hmm, let's see.
oh, sorry, guys.
it's a live feed.
raphael: in that case,
how about calling
the department of
animal regulation ?
he's headed
toward downtown.
we might be able to
catch him in the van.
lord dregg,
look at this.
newscaster: and then
the mutated creature,
believed to be one of
the infamous ninja turtles,
destroyed a gas station
before being helped
to escape
by his turtle accomplices.
so, one of the turtles
has mutated
into an even more
degenerate creature.
this will make my plans
to conquer the earth
and destroy those
turtles even easier.
mung, prepare
the shuttle.
yes, lord dregg.
eh, first it's roaches,
now it's ants.
well, i'll fix 'em.
huh ?
whoa !
he's got to be
around here somewhere.
hold it.
what ?
shh.
what's wrong ?
ohh.
oh, no.
it's dregg !
and he's got some
seriously ugly new buds !
oh, you say that as if
you're not glad to see me.
turtles: look out !
atta boy, leonardo !
protect your
fellow turtles !
mung, get us
out of here.
way to go, dude !
give me three !
oh !
whoa.
he should definitely
cut down on his sugar.
huh. there must be
an answer here somewhere.
can i get you
anything else, hon ?
wait a minute.
it looks like someone
or something
stole a piece
of the crystal.
maybe it wasn't
my fault after all.
aah !
whoa !
aah ! oh !
aah !
look out !
quick ! tie him up !
sorry
i ducked out on you,
but i finally figured out
what went wrong.
you can tell us about it
on the way back to the lair.
oh, great.
well, can you tell me
when the power's going
to come back on ?
what do you mean,
no one knows what's wrong ?
ok. thanks.
the power went out
at the hydroelectric dam,
but they haven't been able
to contact anyone there.
sounds like that's
where the problem is.
what the heck
is going on here ?
whatever's going on,
i bet i'll find the answer
at the end of these cables.
incredible. dregg !
power connections
are complete.
soon, when the vortex
transporter is complete,
i shall transport something
very special to earth.
something which will assure
my conquest of the planet,
as well as the destruction
of those meddling reptiles.
i've got to warn
the guys.
guys, it's april.
it's an emergency.
what's wrong ?
it's dregg. he's back.
and he's building
some kind of a transporter
in the old atlantic
steel mill.
he's got some other
cronies with him
and thousands of little...
aaa--mmph.
she's in trouble,
dudes !
yeah, and so is
the rest of the world
if dregg's up to
his usual stuff.
looks like leonardo
will have to wait.
it's done.
and you, my fine
young specimen,
shall be
its first occupant.
no ! let me go !
i hope you enjoy
your trip...
to the other end
of the universe.
oh, the turtles !
that's teenage mutant
ninja turtles to you, pal !
destroy them !
carter ! whoa !
michelangelo,
give me a fastball.
low and outside, dude.
got them.
yeah, but who's
gonna get him ?!
whoa !
look out !
oh !
whoa !
cover me !
i'm gonna cut this dummy
down to size.
i got you covered,
dude. go for it !
timber !
have a nice trip !
see you
next fall.
whoa !
oh !
place these fools
on the transporter
with the girl.
hey, where are you
sending us ?
the center of the sun.
oh, and me without my number
50 million sun block.
oh !
way to go, bud !
cut us loose !
thanks.
get back.
dregg's
getting away !
what are you doing ?
computer:
vortex crystal overload.
meltdown in 10 seconds.
i'm making sure
he never comes back.
let's get out of here !
forgive me,
lord dregg.
i have failed you.
on the contrary.
everything went just
as i intended.
ha ha ha ha !
this piece of mutated
turtle shell
will help me gain
unimaginable power.
but--but what about
the vortex transporter ?
how can you
build another ?
easily. i kept
a spare piece of crystal
and one microbot.
oh, of course !
one can build two...
two can build four...
and soon
i'll have billions !
then i'll build another
vortex transporter,
and the earth
will be mine !
hey, i thought
you were leaving, carter.
well, i've decided
to stick around
until we find the antidote
to leonardo's mutation.
hey, that's great news,
'cause we're sure
gonna need major help
taming this beast.