There are those who believe that a child
in her womb shares his mother's dreams.
Her love for him.
Her hopes for his future.
Is it told to him in pictures
while he sleeps inside her?
Is that why he reaches for her
in that first moment
and cries for her touch?
But what if you'd known since he was
inside you what his life held for him?
That he would be hunted.
That his fate was tied
to the fate of millions.
That every moment of your life
will be spent keeping him alive.
Would he understand
why you were so hard?
Why you held on so tight?
Will he still reach for you
if the only dream
you've ever shared
with him was a nightmare?
Would he know my love
runs through him like blood?
John, now.
Now!
The cops make you at the diner?
I don't know. Maybe.
Yes.
Definitely.
Sarah Connor! John Connor!
Drop what you're carrying.
Put your hands on your head
and kneel on the ground.
Now!
Do me a favor, will you?
Fix it.
Drop your weapon!
Go!
You run!
Run!
Do it!
Do it! Kill me!
Nothing matters anymore.
Kill me!
You're right.
Nothing matters anymore.
Only the boy.
The future is ours.
And it begins
now.
You yelled, or something?
No.
Let me see it.
Did you forget?
No, I didn't forget.
I just am not used to it yet.
You sure we don't need
to have it sized?
No. It's perfect.
Just make sure it fits.
The Projet-SG Team
v. 1.1
Special thanks to Herb.
Mom, how many times have I told you?
It's freaky when you do that.
I'm sorry.
What time is it?
It's almost nine.
You're gonna be late for work.
What's going on?
We can't stay here, John.
What?
It's not safe.
Not safe from who?
Who mom? No one knows us.
No one asks questions.
It's been almost two years.
School starts in like three weeks.
- We need to go.
- No, we don't need to go.
You need to go.
You're scared.
He gave you a ring, you're freakin out.
- I know you like him.
- So do you, mom!
So do you. You love him.
I know you do.
Listen to me,
the cops will never find us.
We're safe!
Don't you think that, John!
Don't you ever think that!
Look at me!
No one is ever safe.
Half an hour.
One bag.
Plus the guns.
I'll make pancakes.
Every family has rules.
And we had ours.
Keep your head down.
Keep your eyes up.
Resist the urge
to be seen as important or special.
Know your exits.
I mean, she's not actually missing,
right?
- The way you explain it, she...
- Right.
The way I expain it,
she's not missing, she left.
- It happens more often than you think.
- You don't know her.
I can say the same about you,
Mr. Daniels.
F.B.I.?
You've been together long?
Six months, maybe.
A bit of a whirlwind.
You have no idea of the whirlwind.
Tell me.
Does the Skynet Defense System
mean anything to you?
How about this guy?
Miles Dyson.
I've never seen him before.
That's because he's dead.
Your fiancée,
firstly escaped from
the Pescadero Mental Hospital.
Blew him apart, two years ago.
Leveled a 4 storied research lab
along with him.
But since there's no lethal injection
for the destruction of property,
we'd stick with the murder of one of our
country's brightest computer scientists.
and...
a dedicated family man.
That's...
That's just not...
- Why would she do that?
- Well, Mr. Daniels,
it's the robots!
The ones from the future.
The ones Skynet sent to kill her son.
- Robots...
- Which makes total sense.
Because in the future,
John is not just her son...
He's the... I'm sorry, excuse me.
The leader of the resistance,
fighting artificially intelligent
machines,
determined to annihilate
the human race.
Skynet...
Did he strike you that way?
John!
A leader of a scrappy band of rebels?
- Luke Skywalker type.
- Don't be ridiculous.
I came here for help.
You can't really be asking me this.
No, I'm not.
This is just my pattern, Mr. Daniels.
This is just me,
impressing upon you
that I'm not here
because you lost your fiancée,
the love of your life,
and all around good time girl.
I'm here because my boss,
the United States of America,
thinks Sarah Connor
is a deluded, dangerous
Grade A wacko-mo
who killed a man because she believed
that in the future,
he will invent a computer system
that declares war on the world.
So...
let's start with her name, shall we?
I understand
it's not Connor.
You'll be responsible
for three chapters a week,
you have a quiz each Friday,
you'll be allowed one makeup test
with a parent's note.
What's your name?
- John.
- Cameron.
And no talking while I'm talking.
John?
- Hey.
- Haven't seen you around here before.
- Did you just move here?
- Yeah.
Sucks for you.
My dad sells tractors.
- What about yours?
- Insurance.
Really? What kind?
Boring kind.
It's the kind of tractors my dad sells.
What about your mom?
My mom stays home.
You know, I've really
got to get to the next class, so...
So...
Maybe I'll see you later?
Sure. Yeah.
Bye.
This is a hick town, mom.
We've been in worse places.
A lot worse.
All my clothes are wrong.
I need like...
some different shirts.
You know here,
everyone wears boots.
Like cow-boy boots.
Hate cow-boy boots!
I'll see what I can do.
Their computers are like
in the 40, 50's, or something.
Their computers?
- I thought we agreed?
- No, no, it wasn't my fault.
They switched my class.
Last thing I need
is you getting caught hacking.
I'm not hacking, mom.
God, I know the rules.
They're like, written on the inside
of my eyeballs, right?
Hey!
You meet any pretty girls?
No.
I'm telling you, it's a hick town.
Come on.
Agent Ellison.
Welcome to New Mexico.
The sheriff's detached me to hustle
you around in your business here,
whatever that is, he wouldn't say.
He doesn't know.
I lied to you yesterday.
My dad doesn't sell insurance.
He's dead.
He was a soldier,
he was killed on a mission.
I'm sorry.
It's... it's all right. My mom
was pregnant with me when it happened,
I never even knew him.
So, it's all right.
My mom...
she, she... she's kinda uptight.
Actually, no. She's...
She's really uptight. She likes me
to come home straight after school
and hang out wit her,
that kinda thing, you know?
I'm all she's got.
Thank you for explaining.
That'll be our secret.
Mr. Ferguson is ill today.
My name is Cromartie.
Is that your only name, like Madonna?
Madonna?
Why? No.
Let's take attendance, then.
- Mary Buoy?
- Here.
- Donald Chase?
- Yeah.
- Franklin Lane?
- Cynthia Nolan?
- Here.
- Wayne Parker?
Cameron Philips?
Cameron?
Here.
Reese?
Do we have a John...
Excellent.
Class dismissed.
This breaking news just in.
Violence striking close to home
here in New Mexico.
Witnesses are reporting gun fire
just minutes ago, at Crest View
High School in Red Valley. Police...
Come with me if you wanna live.
Now, the science teacher.
Very dead.
What about her?
She blew at the diner.
Into the wind.
Do you know why anyone
would wanna kill that boy?
No.
Someone wanted to kill that boy.
Damn!
Sarah Connor.
Where is he?
What have you done with him?
You don't know.
Killing yourself is the best strategy.
If you're alive,
I can use you against him.
- John?
- Hello, Mom? Mom?
- I tried to call you.
- I have been trying to call you!
Mom, it's back, you gotta...
All these kids...
John, slow down.
- Where are you?
- I'm going to the house.
- I'll be right there.
- Mom.
I love you.
Stay right there.
John?
- Are you OK?
- Mom?
- John?
John!
No!
Neat trick.
You like?
Next time you do
what you're trained to do!
You run! Go!
- Did you stop him?
- 120 seconds and the system reboots.
- I was sent here to protect John.
- Not now!
Not yet!
You might want to put those back
in the holster.
We should be good here
two more hours.
Hit the border at lunch time.
What year are you from?
2027.
How long have you been looking for us?
73 days.
And the war?
The Skynet Missile Defense System
goes online April 19th, 2011,
declares war on mankind and triggers
a nuclear apocalypse two days later.
Miles Dyson died.
Someone else built Skynet.
Who?
We don't know.
You don't know who builds
the computer that blows up the world?
I wasn't sent here for that.
No.
You were sent here to keep
my son from being assassinated.
Your fiancé went to the police.
You should have changed your alias.
Go to hell!
They'd have found you anyway.
They always do.
It's kevlar in that chair.
APB's statewide but it's been...
19 hours.
What the hell happened here?
Like, why don't we have any bodies?
Where is the blood?
22 witnesses, deputy Ridge.
22 of your good town folk.
That's a whole football team.
Guess what 19 of them saw?
A shooter with some kind of robot leg.
A shooter
with some kind of robot leg...
Why is this happening again?
I don't know.
You stopped it.
I guess I didn't.
But you can.
Look, you changed the future.
You just didn't change it enough.
So you can do it again.
I don't know, John.
Because I can't keep running.
I can't keep doing this.
I'm not who they think I am, OK ?
Some messiah.
You don't know that.
I know.
I can't lead an army.
Maybe that's you but it'll never be me.
So you've got to stop it.
All right?
Please.
Mom.
All right.
All right what?
I'll stop it.
We're not going across the border.
Where are we going?
To find Skynet.
Two years ago, I had to tell Miles Dyson
his research at Cyberdyne
would lead to the birth of Skynet.
I had to tell him he was the unknowing
father of a nuclear apocalypse.
He refused to accept his fate
and died trying to change it.
And if I'm to have any chance
of tracking down Skynet again,
I have to tell his widow that
even though Miles changed his own fate,
he didn't change ours.
Sorry, Miles.
Mom! Pizza's here!
Mom! The pizza!
Mom?
- You!
- We need to talk about Miles, Theresa.
Danny, go to your room.
Right now.
- How dare you come here?
- I know what they told you
- but it didn't happen that way.
- Get the hell out of here.
- Now!
- It didn't happen that way.
I can't let you do that.
- Let go!
- Listen to me!
I didn't kill Miles.
I didn't do it.
I would never.
Miles was a hero.
But why are you here?
We're back.
You told me there'd be no more machines.
It's happening again.
Everything we fought to stop.
Miles' work at Cyberdyne
is the only link we have.
Is there anyone...
anywhere, who's shown
an interest in his work?
Anyone he could have told,
someone
he forgot.
There is nobody. It's all gone.
You destroyed it all.
You and Miles destroyed...
You destroyed everything.
We have to go.
Now!
Help me.
Help my son.
Mom!
Oh, God!
What time is it?
7:52
How are you feeling?
Better.
Good.
We need to go.
Where?
I'll show you.
Tell me what's going on.
We're making a withdrawal.
Do you have an account here ?
Safety deposit box.
When did you open that?
1963.
Everybody on the floor!
Please.
Keys of the safety deposit boxes.
- Get inside.
- Keys.
Lock us in, and then
get away from the door.
I'll know if you don't.
You said you had a safety deposit box.
I do.
Open these boxes.
Put everything you find on the table.
Carefully.
Hey, James!
You gotta see this.
The alarm tripped seven minutes ago.
The camera dumped a digital copy
to the LAPD servers.
Don't you know 'em?
Less and less all the time.
Is that from the future?
Can't bring anything through
when you come.
No weapons, no clothing, nothing.
You sent someone back to build it.
What is it?
Hope.
Is that the police?
- No. Get away from the door.
- Why?
That's why.
That'd better be what I think it is.
One of our best engineers.
To be made once he scavenged the parts.
When the isotope solution turns red,
- you can fire.
- Isotope...
- Is this nuclear?
- No, not really.
I don't get why you locked us in,
we didn't have to get trapped like rats.
We're not trapped.
What is that?
Engineer got a job building the vault.
So we'd always have a way back home.
What have you done?
You want to find Skynet?
You want to stop Skynet?
- This is the way.
- You don't know who built it.
No. But we know where
and we know when.
We can go kill it before it's born.
We can stop running.
Stay in one place.
Fight.
Mom!
We gotta go. Now!
Do it!
Where are we?
Same where.
Different when.
Check this out!
- Yeah!
- Oh, yeah!
Hey, baby.
I got something for you.
So this is where it all starts?
This is where Skynet begins?
Somewhere in there.
And nobody knows we're here?
You're safe.
- No one is ever safe.
Come on.
It is said that the death
of any one person
is the death of an entire world.
Certainly for parents,
the death of a child
is no less than a holocaust.
In the case of my son,
these words are literally true.
And finally tonight, an amateur video
of what we can only assume
is a college prank gone wrong.
Hi! Did you hear me?
We're late.
- Come on, babe.
- I heard you, were late.
And even though
we've traveled through time,
bent the rules of nature...
In the end,
no one lives forever.
They will keep coming for him,
keep trying to kill him.
But until that day,
it's gonna be a goddamn dogfight.
http://projet-sg.net