Earth
Fire
Air
Water
Only the Avatar can master
the four elements
and bring balance to the world.
The Legend of Korra
After a close encounter with Amon
Korra took a little absence from Tarrlok task-forces.
But the Avatar still had it work
bringing the Fire Ferrets to
the pro-bending championship finals.
Only one team stand in their way :
The Wolf-Bats
Lead by team captain, Tahno,the brutal
Wolf-Bats look to repetitive champs.
Have the Fire Ferrets finally
met their match?
Book I: Air
Chapter six : And the Winner is...
The music hour brought to you by
Cabbage corp.
Republic City's trusted name in
technology for fifty years.
Man, I got a good feeling
about tonight.
I don't care if we are the underdogs,
we can take those Wolf-Bats.
It's gonna be our toughest match ever,
but I think you're right.
Introducing your new champs:
the fantastic Fire Ferrets!
Good morning citizen of Republic City.
This is Amon.
I hope you all enjoyed last night
pro-bending match
because it'll be the last.
It's time for this city to stop worshiping bending athletes
as if they were heroes.
I'm calling on the Council to
shut down the bending arena
and cancels the finals. Or else...
there'll be severe consequence.
- That guy's got some nerve.
- You think the Council will give him.
I'm not waiting to find out.
We need to get to the city hall.
Korra, you shouldn't be here,
this a closed meeting.
As the Avatar and a Pro-Bending player
I have a right to be heard.
You can't cancel the finals.
I know winning the championship
means a lot to you.
But as far as I am concerned
we need to shut the arena down.
What about the rest of you? Tarlokk
there's no way you're backing down for Amon, right?
Actually, Tenzin and I agree for once.
The Council is unanimous.
We're closing the arena.
No, you can't.
I don't understand, I thought, you,
out of all people would take a stand against Amon.
While I'm still committed to bring
that lunatic to justice,
I'll not put innocent lives at stakes,
just so you and your friend can
play a game.
Pro-bending might only be a game to you,
but think of what it means to the city.
right now the Arena is the one place
where Benders and non-Benders
gather together and in peace
- to watch Bender...
- Beat each other up!
In peace!
It's an inspiration to everyone!
I appreciate your naive idealism
but you're ignoring the reality
of the situation.
The reality is, if you close the Arena,
you let Amon win.
Yes, exactly what she said! Yes.
I'm sorry, but our decision has been made.
This meet is adjourned.
I can't believe I'm saying this,
but I agree with the Avatar.
- You do?
- Yeah, you do?
I expected this cut and run response
from Tenzin.
But the rest of you?
Come on, show a little more backbone.
It's time that the bender of this city
to display some strength
and unity against these Equalist.
But we must prevent the conflict
between Benders and non-Benders
from escalating into all-out war!
The Council isn't changing
his position.
Now, just a moment Tenzin.
Let us hear what our esteemed chief
of police has in mind.
If you keep the Arena open
my metal benders and I
will provide extra security
during the championship match.
There's no better forces to deal
with the Chi-blockers.
Our armors is impervious
to their attacks.
Are you saying that you will
personally take responsibility
for the safety of the spectator
in the Arena.
I guarantee it.
It is hard to argue with Chief Bei Fong
track record.
If she's confident her elite officer
can protect the Arena,
then she has my support.
I'm changing my vote.
Who else's with me?
The Arena stays open.
Good luck in the finals.
And good luck to you
Chief Bei Fong.
A word please, Lin.
Tarrlok's playing you and I don't want
to see you get hurt.
I know what I'm doing and the risk
that come with it.
In that case, I'm going to be
by your side during the match.
You don't need to baby-sit me.
It's for Korra.
I want to make sure she's safe.
Do what you want.
It's not like I've ever been able
to stop you before.
Excuse me Chief Bei Fong,
I want to thanks you for your help.
It... really... means... a lot.
What is her deal? Even when
she's on my side she's against me.
I've known Lin she's we're children.
She's always been...challenging.
What did your father do to
make her hate the Avatar so much?
My father and Lin got along famously.
I'm afraid her issue is me.
Wait a second.
It all makes sense now!
You and Bei Fong, Bei Fong and you,
you two were a couple!
What? Where did you get that idea?
Your wife.
I'll have a word with her.
So Pema stole you from Bei Fong.
I'm surprise our esteemed chief of
police didn't throw her in jail.
Well she tried.
Anyway, Peme didn't steal me, Lin and I
have been growing apart for some time.
We both had different goals...
Why am I even telling you this?
It all happened a long time ago
and we've moved past it.
Apparently Bei Fong hasn't.
What are you...
Of course she has!
Anyways this is not of your business.
See you at home, Mr.Heart-breaker.
I just got word.
The Council defied your threat.
They're keeping the Arena open.
Perfect.
Everything is going according
to the plan.
All clear, Chief.
How's the security sweep going?
Fine.
They checked underneath the stands?
Yes.
Had you enough officers to cover
all points of entry?
I have the sky, the bay and every
looking cranny of this place covered.
Now leave me alone and
let me do my job.
Lin, with so much on the line
it would be nice if we could
help each other out.
At least for one night.
- Like old times?
- Like old times.
Ok, I'll try to be less abrasive
than usual.
I'll appreciate that.
Anticipation is palpable as we are just
moments away from the championship match.
Will the Wolf-Bats ferocity
our repetitive champs?
Or will the underdog Fire Ferrets serve
up a surprising bowl of smack-down soup?
Now I know there's a big crowd,
but don't be nervous.
You're gonna do great,
I believe in you.
Introducing the challengers,
the Future Industries, Fire Ferrets!
We're along, Pabu!
Yes! Nailed it!
He's so talented!
And their opponents,
the three times defending champions,
the Whites Falls, Wolf-Bats!
They got nothing on us buddy,
anybody can howl.
Whatever.
I'm gonna knock Tahno's stupid
hair off his stupid head.
The champs and challengers face off
at the center line.
And here we go!
Tahno try to clean the Avatar
with some dirty water mud.
Ming escape Mako's attack
and return the favor.
Shaozu get fancy, but Bolin
ricochet his disk off the cords
and says "No thanks you, sir!"
Nice shot!
The water benders slug out
with an evenly match.
Tahno get a little too worked up
and unleash a deluge on Bolin
that will certainly gives him a fault.
Apparently not.
What's the big idea, ref?
That was an hosing fault!
And the Wolf-Bats advance despite
Tahno exceeding the water bending
time limit.
A questionable call by the official.
Ming trips out Mako with
another dirty trick.
Oh come on ref! There was some funny
business in that last hit!
Who would have guessed you knew
the rules of pro-bending?
I've been brushing up.
That Wolf-Bat blatantly bended
outside of his zone.
The Ferrets brother are backed up in
zone 3 and the Wolf-Bat smells blood.
Looks like Tahno snugged an
illegal icing move.
But once again there's no call.
I don't what match the ref are watching
but it's obviously not this one.
Oh! A splashing par send the
Avatar in zone 3 as well.
It's a K.O. The Wolf-Bat win the
championship for the fourth year
Oh! Hold on a second folks.
Scotch that! The Ferrets are still alive,
but just barely.
What an unbelievable move!
These Ferrets aren't just bending
elements, they're bending my minds!
The underdogs survive to see round two.
What's wrong with these refs?
They've been paid off.
It's the only explanation.
Somebody wants us to lose.
If the Wolf-Bats  are gonna fight dirty
then should we.
No we can't.
The refs have it out for us, if we're
gonna win this thing it
has to be fair and square.
It's not fun, but right.
Round two!
Dealing with Tahno's a brutal call as
both side give it their all.
But once again Tahno sneaks in little
ice to get the upper hand.
Wow those look likes illegal
head shot to me.
Round two will be decided with
a tie-breaker!
The Fire Ferrets win the coin toss!
Which element do you choose?
I'm taking this one!
Let's go!
You and me, pretty boy!
Thought you'd never ask.
Come on little girl, give me your
best shot.
Chump.
Round two goes to the Fire Ferrets!
Nice one!
That's the stuff you're my heroooo!
We might actually win this thing.
Let's dig them a watery grave!
I can't believe your sweet heart father
was reincarnated into that girl.
She as though as nails.Remind me
of someone else I knew at that age
You two might get along if you would
give her a chance.
One round a piece.
Who wants it more?
The Wolf-Bats fire up the game swinging
bad intention.
The challenger are showing a lot of
heart, but the champs are really starting
to find their rhythm now.
Can the Ferrets hang in there
with the best,
especially when the best are frankly
getting a little from the ref?
It's all to this final round.
Mako is giving all in the ring.
but it look like Tahno and Ming are up
to more shenanigans.
This has gone too far.
That water had rock in it.
K.O.!
Come on those were illegal head shot!
Open your eyes ref!
Well folks it's a controversy calls,
but the Wolf-Bats notch a nasty K.O.
to win the match.
For the fourth year in a row,
they'll be crowned tournament champion.
I barely broke a sweat.
Anybody else want to scrap
with the champs?
Look out!
What?
Folks there's some sort of electrical
disturbances in the stands.
Metals benders cops are dropping
like bumble flies.
There appear to be masked members
of the audience wielding strange
device on their hands.
One of them is in the booth with me
right now folks.
He's leveling one of those globe device
at me now.
I believe he's about to electrocute me.
I'm currently wetting my pants.
What's going on here, ref?
I don't know!
Alright, you want a piece of
the Wolf-Bats?
Here it comes.
Wait, please, I'll give you the
championship pot,
I'll give you everything just please,
don't take my bending.
I believe I've your attention,
benders of the Republic City.
So once again, the Wolf-Bats are your
pro-bending champions.
It seems fitting that you celebrate three
bullies who cheated their way to victory,
because everyday,
you threaten and abuse your fellow
non-bending citizen.
Just like the Wolf-Bats did to their
opponents tonight.
Those mens were supposedly the best in
the bending world.
And yet, it only took a few moments to
cleanse them of their impurity.
Let this be a warning of you all benders
out there.
If any of you stand in my way,
you'll meet the same fate.
To my followers :
for years, the Equalist have been forced
to hide in the shadow.
But now, we have the numbers
and the strength
to create a new Republic City.
I'm happy to tell that the time for
change has finally come.
How are we gonna get out of here?
There is soon, the current tyrannical
bending regime...
Pabu! Listen up buddy.
will be replaced by fair minded Equalist
government.
Stop fooling around!
I'm trying to save us!
See?
Pabu's not just one trick poodle pony.
For centuries, benders have possessed
an unnatural advantage
over ordinary people.
But thankfully modern technology,
has provided us a way to even out
the play field.
Now, anybody can hold the power of a
chi-blocker in their hand.
My followers and I will not rest,
until the entire city has achieved
equality.
And once that goal is achieved,
we'll equalize the rest of the world.
The revolution has begun!
Tenzin.
It's okay Pabu, it's just a little
explosion.
Keep chewing, you're almost trough it.
Yes! Great job buddy.
I'm going after Amon!
Be careful!
You alright?
Yeah, I,m fine thanks to you.
It's nothing.
Looks like we lost this one.
I'm so glad you're okay.
Me too!
I can't believe Amon did this.
I played right into his hand.
He played us all.
Republic City is in war.
Sous-titres : nathbot
~ bufgelfly ~
English sub by Patrick of addic7ed.com