PHIL: Previously on
The Amazing Race...
..11 teams raced
to Cartagena, Colombia.
Darius and Cameron got
off to a rocky start...
Oh, we got the last flight.
..but once in Cartagena,
it was Marty and Hagan...
I can't find the right one!
..who sunk into last.
I never thought we'd be
at the bottom of the race.
Does not feel good.
At a festive detour, Tyler
and Korey were all business.
Tyler, we're killing this!
We're going good.
Passing leaders
Brodie and Kurt...
Oh, my God, is
this even possible?
..to win the leg.
You are team number one.
Yeah!
Scott and Blair overcame a fishy
Speed Bump to stay in the race.
Agh! It bit me!
Marty and Hagan
cooked up a comeback...
Ah!
..but one final mistake...
What?! Hagan and
Marty are running.
Yeah, I guess they left
their taxi over here.
..cost them dearly.
You have been
eliminated from the race.
10 teams remain.
Who will be eliminated next?
Hey, dogs, do you want
some fish scales for lunch?
Do what you want to
do. Just do it quickly.
Like, it's a race.
You want to ask if this
guy has phone, ask him.
Not him.
Matt, you're going to
over-think us to death.
MATT: The last leg
was really difficult
and we got a little
bit worked up.
There's no-one over
here. -This guy...
What are you
doing to us, babe?
This guy. -My God,
you're so stupid.
Being chaotic
isn't helping us.
Sometimes you have to calm down
and hopefully we can learn that.
Indecision is the thing
that kills the race.
OK, calm down.
"Make your way on
foot to Plaza San Diego
"and search for
your next clue."
OK, Plaza San Diego,
make your way...
KOREY: We've been
friends for eight years
and it's only
ever been friends.
Although...
(LAUGHS)
..Tyler did have a
crush on me in college.
And then I met him and then
I realised nothing here.
So you thought I was good-looking
but my personality sucks?
Your words.
It's hot out.
You want me to splash you? -No.
Plaza San Diego?
Our biggest flaw
is going too fast.
Plaza San Diego?
He doesn't know,
he doesn't know.
Also, I'm constantly talking
and just spitting out ideas.
Hey, he doesn't know.
Kurt, he doesn't know!
If he doesn't know...
Kurt! -We're good.
Sometimes, it might be a little
annoying to Kurt but he's used
to me talking all the time
so it's nothing new for him.
Just straight and then left.
No, this way, Brodie. Listen
to me on the directions.
Just go, go, go, go!
Beautiful.
It's there in the hat,
in the hat, in the hat.
"Make your way to
Castillo San Felipe."
PHIL: Teams must
find this fortress -
Castillo San
Felipe de Barajas -
and search the claustrophobic
catacombs for their next clue.
"#Catacombs for
your next clue."
Taxi?
Wah! You got it?
"Search for the catacombs
for your next clue."
Taxi, taxi, taxi, taxi!
Kurt, you're scaring him.
Plaza San Diego.
ASHLEY: As a gamer we
are used to trying again
if we don't get
quite the score.
We're looking for
the first time around.
You can't do that in the race.
You don't get a second go.
In games, checkpoints
are like save points.
Here, checkpoints are how you
get eliminated from the game.
Let's go, this way.
-Burnie, please, your pace.
Just keep it in check
from the beginning.
Plaza San Diego?
-Yeah. Try left.
Are you sure?
Wait a second, don't just run.
It's just too hot for us to
make any mistakes and run extra.
Look at this.
"Search the catacombs
for your next clue."
OK, let's go.
Is this it right here?
Wow!
I hear the trumpeter.
Ready? Holy shoot!
Korey, I don't want to
go down there, it's scary.
Breathe. -Now we
take deep breaths?
Oh, my God.
You look to the right,
I'll look to the left.
Look in every nook and cranny.
I'm looking.
Please, please, please.
Oh, my God! -Do you think
this way or that way?
Watch your foot,
it's super slippery.
Here we go.
"Detour. Tickets or Tejo."
PHIL: Colombia's reliable
and efficient bus system
allows passengers to hop
on and off as they please.
And here in Cartagena,
it's the easiest and quickest
way to get around town.
Right? OTHERS: Yeah!
After boarding a local bus, teams
must play the role of conductor
using their persuasive
skills to collect 20,000 pesos
and earn their next clue.
Congratulations.
Take a 3lb metal disc,
some gunpowder
and a clay target
and you've got this
country's national sport.
Tejo.
Throwing the disc,
teams must hit three explosive
targets to receive their next clue.
Let's do Tejo. -Tejo.
Muchas gracias, senor.
I hear the trumpeter.
Is that him?
Go, go, go!
Don't get lost once we get in.
-This is my nightmare.
Let's go this way.
-What are we looking for?
Clue box. -Where is it?
I don't know.
Make sure we look
down each one, Brodie.
Here it is, here it is.
Tejo. -Yeah, Tejo.
Taxi! Taxi!
Whoo!
-They're right behind us.
Plaza San Diego.
Plaza San Diego. Let's go.
Let's just follow them.
Hopefully, they're right.
We're just following the
maroon team right now.
Zach's definitely more in the
spotlight way more then I am.
And I'm always kind of
thrown in the background.
Will you open this for me?
Thanks.
So I think the race is
more of a time for us
to be in the spotlight
together as a team.
We're trying to catch
up with the clever girls.
Just speed walk.
It'll look better
on camera anyways.
Keep a steady jog, it's
going to be a good little run.
Just do a steady
jog and I'll be good.
Hold on, Daddy.
You want me to carry your pack
for you? That might help you.
Can you? -Yeah.
"You must toss it underhand."
It's going to be like
cornhole. We've got this.
Dude, their whole shtick
is hitting targets!
I didn't even think of that.
If we don't do well at this,
I'm going to be probably be
getting a lot of Twitter hate.
Alright here. Follow
them, follow them.
Follow, follow,
follow! -OK, OK, OK.
I don't think they know
where they're going.
Tap him on the
shoulder and ask.
Senor?
Senor, do you know?
Here it is. -Yay!
Yes!
Oh, what is this?
Oh, we're watching.
One line, OK?
Oh, dang, that's hard.
So, we each have two.
Let's go this middle one.
Alright, here we go.
Way too much.
Soft.
There you go.
It's all about speed
once you get it.
There is.
Get in.
Whoo!
Let's go, baby! -That's one.
That was ridiculous.
-Let's go, let's go.
The catacombs.
-For your next clue.
"Search the catacombs for your
next clue." -Castillo San Felipe.
We're going to the catacombs.
Go left.
Hey, I've got a great idea.
You're not claustrophobic?
Hey, look what I found.
Oh, did you find it? -Yeah.
Let's go.
Up there. -I hear a trumpet.
Let's go. I'll follow you.
Keep those eyes peeled.
OK, you check the left
caverns, I'll check the right.
I think I grabbed,
like, a rat.
Go, go, go.
Stop it, Matt.
Don't "go-go-go" me.
We're searching for
something, stop yelling.
Oh, I found it. -Good job.
Nice.
I say we throw it.
Let's try to get down before
any other teams start coming up.
Yeah, Brodie.
Hit it, nail it.
Ooh, just short.
Come on, Kurt.
We essentially have to throw these
rocks into this little bullseye
and it explodes if you get it
in, so it's made a really loud...
Ah! Oh! No way!
Let's go, baby!
Let's go. Vamos!
We've gotten two. We need
one more and we're good.
OK, OK, OK.
Get it this time, baby.
(BOTH CHEER)
I told you! I told
you! -That was sick!
Gracias, senor.
Muchas gracias.
"Make your way to
Calle San Juan De Dios
"and search for the
marked mochila vendor
"along the wall of
Museo Naval del Caribe."
Taxi!
Hola. -So you're just trying
to get right in the middle.
(LOUD BANG)
Oh, my God!
I don't like that. -I love it.
Just a couple of
dudes being bros.
Just good couple
of bros being jocks.
TYLER: We went
to Michigan State
and we spent some
Sunday mornings
playing cornhole.
Except this was
with rocks and bombs.
So similar, a
little different.
Oh, sugar fudge.
We're the last team to lead today
but we're still feeling pretty good.
Hopefully we can
make a big comeback.
Plaza San Diego?
Being able to spend all
this time together is nice.
We want to go as far
as the race can take us.
Darius, slow down.
We need just three,
we're going to get three.
Blow it up, Kore.
Oh, my Go...
(LAUGHS)
Bam! That freaked me out!
I jump at any type
of... Like, anything.
We got this.
Ah! (LAUGHS)
He doesn't just jump.
He jumps and screams
for no reason.
I can't handle
that. It was a bomb!
We were safe.
Got two down, one to go.
Come on, Kore.
Yeah! Gracias.
Museo Naval?
We've got to get three, babe.
-There you go. Get three bullseyes.
Oh, so close.
(CLANG!) Oops!
Don't sweat it.
-You got this, babe.
It's just like cornhole.
Got it.
Nailed it, OK. (LAUGHS)
I think I got it again. Oh!
Come on!
Look at you! You show-off.
I rimmed out!
"Search for the #catacombs
for your next clue."
Oh good, let's make
all that time up.
Search the catacombs.
Another cave. Are you
kidding me with this?!
I am so claustrophobic.
I really hate tight spaces.
You've got this.
I hear the trumpeter.
Do you hear him?
There he is. He's
up there. Nice hat.
Scary.
We're going to
go down. -Careful.
Oh, scary!
Come on, baby, you
know you hate caves.
You're doing awesome. Why
don't you get the clue?
Let's do Ticket. OK,
we're doing Ticket.
Oh, this way.
This way. Come on.
We have to get in here?
Oh, I'm so claustrophobic.
I feel light-headed. -It's OK.
No more underground!
(HEART BEATING)
Oh, my God, Jess,
I'm so afraid.
I don't how we get
to where we're going.
OK, OK.
Oh, my gosh. Anxiety attack.
Were going down. Be
careful, it's kind of steep.
Oh, more caves.
Oh, my gosh.
(SOBS)
I'm getting really claustrophobic.
Just keep breathing.
Right here. I've got
the clue box here.
Hurry, hurry.
Good job. (SOBS)
Breathe slow. Slow
down. -OK, I'm OK.
Slow, slow.
Anything to get us out of
here. I'll do whatever you want.
I'll cut off my left arm if
that's what you want me to do.
Gracias, gracias.
Thank the Lord
Jesus for sunshine.
What are we looking
for? -I don't know.
Right here.
We are choosing Tejo.
Reading that clue down
there was just hell.
That was even worse than the
cave, and that's saying something.
This is going to
be fun, though.
We're going to
get to interact.
It's going to be so fun and
we'll get to smile and laugh.
The name of the
game was catch-up.
We don't know where anybody
else is, so all engines ahead.
Catching up is what we do.
Trumpeter, trumpeter.
Are you sure the
trumpeter's up here?
Right there. You see
him? -Oh, they're coming.
Come on, baby, you got it.
It's right here, guys.
You got this, Sheri.
I can't believe I had to go in a
cave twice. -We're doing Tickets.
We're doing really good.
I say Tejo. Let's do it.
We're hoping that we
picked the right one.
I'll put on a show.
I'll twerk, I don't care.
That's not going to
make it. You're up, babe.
Yeah! -Yes!
Great job, baby!
Let's see that pop.
You did it!
That was so incredible!
I love you so much.
That was actually
a lot of fun.
Nobody else is here.
Is that good or bad?
It's probably bad.
We can do this, baby.
Let's make this baby pop.
Throw it like this, with
the flat, I think. -Shh!
Put your toe right on the line.
-Babe, don't tell me what to do.
Play your game.
OK, there's some
bus stuff over here.
Babe, it's over here. -OK.
Hola. -Hello.
I am the bus supervisor.
OK, today, you will
be the bus attendant.
RACHEL: For the Tickets Detour
we had to get people on the bus
and then collect their
fair until we got 20,000.
20,000 pesos.
After the person sits down,
they will pay 1,800 pesos.
Per person? -Yeah.
When we get the full
amount, we come back.
Remember the bus destination.
Zaragocilla Hospital,
Calamares and Campestre.
This is your bus. -OK.
OK, here we go riding
the bus. -Good luck.
Oh, wow, we are going
down some back roads here.
This is crazy. How
does the bus even fit?
Hola, hola! Hi.
It was really fun because we
got to really immerse ourselves
in some of the culture.
Race me.
Zaragocilla. -Zaragocilla?
Whoa!
Oh. Zaragocilla? Zaragocilla.
Calamares.
Campestre.
-Add a 'por favor'.
Add a por favor! -No.
Oh! (LAUGHS)
I want to get out and just go.
Cuantos kilometros,
senor? -500 metros.
500 metres.
Let's go. Gracias.
Get in, get out.
Let's take our time.
Slow and methodical. Make
sure you don't miss it.
Right here, right here!
Alright, here it is.
"Roadblock. Who's
left holding the bag?"
The indigenous people of
Latin America have been making
beautiful mochila bags like these
for as long as people can remember.
One team member
must choose a mochila
and then search the old city to find
two more bags by the same designer.
Once they've found their matches,
they'll receive their next clue.
My gut feels, it
tells me you. -OK.
Alright, you're doing it.
Choose one of the
vendor's custom mochilas.
I'm taking this
one. -You got it.
Alright, "Two mochilas
by the same designer..."
Slow and steady.
It's going to be running so
fast in between, slow and steady.
We've got to find something that
matches this designer right here.
Disenos de Emelina.
Oh, my gosh.
Nothing here matches.
OK, got to find
other marked vendors
between Plaza Santa Teresa and
Plaza Santo Domingo. (SIGHS)
KURT: Basically what I needed to
do was run around the walled city
and find a vendor that had that same
handbag that matched the designer.
So I had to stop and ask couple of
people directions just to make sure
that I was in the
right vicinity...
Donde esta la
Puerta del Reloj?
Aqui?
..so the ability
to speak Spanish
was a definite,
definite positive for me.
Sabe donde esta la
Puerta del Reloj?
You got it, baby.
Whoo!
Yah!
Come on, come
on. You can do it.
Too hard.
Yes!
Yes? -Whoo!
Alright, let's go.
Trumpet.
Oh, man. You hit your head?
We're choosing Tejo.
Tight taxi.
I hit my head again.
Were hoping that other
teams took that bus detour.
Hasta luego! Gracias.
Hola!
The bus supervisor gave us a bag
of change and some directions.
Here is your bag. -OK.
Hola! -Whoo!
Whoo-hoo!
Joslyn, this is real life!
What is going on?
Hola!
Oh, my God, tree.
BOTH: Argh!
Whoo!
We have no idea where
the other teams are
but we're having a great time.
We're doing great.
Good luck.
Hola!
Hey, guys. Hola.
Whoo!
Go over here.
Pfft!
This is hilarious, I know.
OK, Don't worry about it,
it's going to take us a couple.
Broke a nail on that one.
Es el mismo aqui, no?
Esta?
Si, si. Gracias, senora.
Muchas gracias.
So it's the same designer.
Gracias. Muchas gracias.
OK, I need to find
one more mochila.
Roadblock.
I'll do it.
"Choose of the vendor's
custom mochilas."
OK, green.
Santo Domingo?
No! (SPEAKS SPANISH)
Muralla y El Reloj. -OK.
Y que es esto? La catedral?
Come on. Uh!
Where do I go?
We just hit rush-hour
traffic, babe.
Rache, we just hit
rush-hour traffic.
This is really bad.
Ugh! -It's crazy.
What's up? How are you?
Oh, boy.
Zaragocilla Hospital!
Calamares, Campestre.
I don't think people trust us.
Come ride, come
ride a little bit.
Zaragocilla
Hospital. Campestre.
Si, come on. Come,
come. Help us.
They think it looks weird that we're
hanging out the door, so I hope...
Si.
Para, para.
Si, si. Come. Come help us.
1,800. We need
1,800. Gracias, senor.
I saw your videos on YouTube.
Gracias.
We have fans in
Colombia, that's crazy.
On the streets of Colombia.
Zaragocilla Hospital.
Get on the bus, ride the bus.
Come on, come on!
Si! Oh, Daddy, we got one.
I was able to coax
some people on.
I said, "Beso for peso,"
and they all came on.
We got another one! Oh,
my God, we got another one!
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Oh, my God, yes.
Yes! Si, si.
Yeah! You want
to come? Come on.
Yeah!
Vamanos.
No-one asked me for a beso.
They gave dad the peso
and then I think they
might have thought,
"If I give you the
peso, do I get the beso?"
Beso, beso!
Yeah.
But I blew some kisses
to a lot of people.
That's as far as
that needed to go.
This is kind of fun.
Get ready for this.
Yes!
Yes, that's my girl!
OK, one more, one more.
Oh, someone's coming, Jess.
It's Cole and Sheri. -Hey.
The pressure's on now
we know someone's coming.
This one's on it.
Whoo!
Yes. Good one.
Thank you.
Bye, guys. Hasta luego.
Just got to pop
three combined.
Whoo! First one.
Oh. Lame.
So bad at this.
I'm very sorry.
Roadblock. OK.
"Who's left holding
the bag?" I can do it.
You can do it. -"Who's
left holding the bag?"
Hola.
Same designer?
Same designer.
Disenos de Eugenia.
Oh, no.
OK, gracias.
It's not the same one.
I'm looking for Eugenia.
OK I'm looking for...
..matching, this is a
little different though.
By the same designer.
This...
Ah, OK, OK.
I think this is a match.
Hold it.
"Who's left holding the bag?"
OK, I'll do it.
Come on, you got it.
Doubtful that's it.
No.
This is hard.
I don't see any
that match my bag.
Am I doing something wrong?
Shoot! There's a
tag inside here.
Designed by Ana.
That might be
what's going on here.
Hola.
Can I take this?
OK. -Good. Bueno, one more bag.
Ese ahi.
Como este, por favor.
Esta? -Si, senor.
Muchas gracias,
muchas gracias.
Este es el mismo...
Emelina. Awesome.
Muchas gracias, senor.
Muchas gracias. Vaya con Dios.
OK, let's go back,
let's get the clue.
Eugenia...
Can I take it? Gracias?
Gracias.
Got my third one.
OK, OK.
Yah! -That's two.
I want to give you
a hug. -No, just go.
I'm sweaty, I don't
want to hug you.
Take your time, you got it.
You'll get this final one.
Ooh, I thought I did
that there. -I know.
You popped it, you
popped it midair.
(BOTH CHEER)
Yeah! We got it, let's go.
Three by the same designer.
(SIGHS)
Muchas gracias!
Thank you so much.
"Make your way on foot
to the next Pit Stop.
"Baluarte de Santiago,
the old city wall.
"Warning, last team to be
checked in may be eliminated."
Let's go. This
way to the wall.
Hey, good luck. Good
luck. Good luck, guys.
OK, I saw Tyler come
from this direction.
Hey, Kurt, up
and to the right.
Eugenia, Eugenia y...Eugenia.
Perfecto? -Yes. -Ah!
It's the old city wall.
-I think it's this way.
I'm ready to run when you are.
Come on, Kurt!
Wow. That's my boy.
How's that, Phil?
Welcome to Baluarte
in Cartagena.
Gracias. -Thank you so much.
Gracias. -Muchas gracias.
Brodie and Kurt...
Yes, sir.
..you have won this
leg of the race.
You are team number one!
(BOTH CHEER)
You have won a trip
for two from Travelocity
and you are going
to Mykonos in Greece.
Yes! Score!
Man, that's sick! -Greece!
During your five nights at the
Myconian Avaton in Platis Gialos,
you'll take a tour
of Delos island,
enjoy two spa treatments
and a VIP dinner for two.
That is mental! I'll take it.
Perfect.
This is a once-in-a-lifetime
opportunity
and every leg is an
amazing experience.
We want to keep
experiencing all that stuff.
Tyler and Korey, you
are to number two.
Congratulations.
Did you expect
to do this well?
We had dreamed we
would do this well.
I knew Korey
could do this well.
I just wanted to
keep up with him.
Although every time you've done
the Roadblock, we've got in second.
Every time I've
done it, we've won.
It's true! -Rude.
I think I've won something.
You won America's heart.
Hmm, that's what I won.
How many do we need to hit?
Blow the bullseye three
times. -Three times.
I play this on the weekends.
Oh!
Be loose.
Let's go. Whoo!
Come ride, come
ride a little bit.
Zaragocilla Hospital.
Zaragocilla. Want
to come on the bus?
I need 1,800 pesos.
Come ride a little
bit. Gracias, gracias.
How much do we have, Rache?
Two, four, six...
Gracias, senor.
11,000.
Para, para, para, para.
Zaragocilla Hospital,
Calamares, Campestre.
Yeah!
Hola, bonita!
Let me help you here.
Which aisle would
you like to sit in?
All of these seats have
been hand-washed by myself.
Hola!
I was so in the zone. -Mm-hm.
I was selling
this bus to people.
Erin, I feel like
this is our calling.
I think I might just quit
my job and just run buses.
Only if I can it
do with you, Joslyn.
Only with you, baby.
Only with you. -Only with you.
Hola! Hola!
Daddy, another.
Zaragocilla.
She was bringing
the money in so fast,
I couldn't count the
money fast enough.
Whoo! -Muchas gracias,
muchas gracias.
You're so pretty.
Magnifique. Daddy,
another one, another one.
OK. Great. -Vamanos.
Come on, they're so cute,
Daddy. Blow them a kiss.
No, they don't want me to
blow them a kiss, Blair.
All this money is
your kiss blowing.
Oh.
You might be better
at this than me.
Can't hate the game.
We can't hate the game, we
can hate the player though.
With this game, I
don't know what to hate.
We blew up one tejo.
We got two more to go.
It took us a while
to get a stroke down.
Let's go.
Let's go, yes!
Thank you, thank you.
Alright, let's go.
We are blazing
through this. Nice!
BOTH: Hospital,
Calamares, Campestre.
(BOTH WHOOP)
This is one of the best
experiences of my whole life.
OK, Joslyn, are we
done? I think we're good.
Let me count it.
OK, we're way over.
O, let's go back. Gracias.
Calamares.
Campestre.
Hola! Daddy, another.
Thank you, thank
you. Muchas gracias.
We're done.
We're done, we're done!
Para.
Oh, my God. Para, para!
Oh, my God. Gracias, gracias.
Oh, er...
..hug? Hug.
Alright, let me do the math.
I think we're doing,
I think we're done.
Are you sure? Double-check,
count the money.
I have two 10s and we needed
20 so I think we're way over.
We got it, OK.
Gracias, senorita.
Let's get a taxi on the
other side of the street.
OK. It's crazy.
I think this is
very dangerous!
Taxi! Taxi!
Gracias, gracias!
Count the money. I
have two 10s right here.
Oh, OK, those aren't
10s, babe. Those are ones.
Oh, my goodness. You've
bean counting wrong.
Two, four, six...
11.
12, 13, 14...
Babe, we didn't do
enough. I'm so sorry, babe.
What do we do?
-We have to go back...
We have to...
Oh, my gosh, I'm so sorry.
The money is different
here. (BREATHES HEAVILY)
Those aren't thousands. -Oh!
I knew that was too
fast, it was too easy.
I'm so sorry.
We have to... -Get on
our bus and go back.
Get on a bus, a new bus.
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, baby.
This is not good.
And you're the
CFO of our company.
It was so fun!
Hola!
We have all our
money right here.
Veinticuatro, veintiseis,
veintiocho... OK.
It's more.
Yeah! -Thank you!
We can run it, there's
the purple team.
Where is it? Back there?
Keep going, keep going.
How was it? -It was
wonderful, we had a ball.
Wonderful. -You count.
OK, the money is complete.
Ah-ha-ha!
Thank you, thank
you. Thank you.
Darn.
It was all my fault.
This is totally me.
We need to go on
another bus. -Ah, OK.
We're about 5,000 pesos short.
I mean, we are
dead last right now.
Here we go again.
Oh, I think I got
it, I think I got it.
Let's be smart.
Let's not go crazy.
OK. I got 'em.
Alright, three bags.
Hola. It's OK?
Sorry.
Lo siento.
Come on, designed by Ana.
I know you're here.
It looks like these.
I really thought
it would be here.
I think I have to go
a little bit further.
I don't think it's here.
Ah-ha-ha!
Yes!
"Warning, last team to
check in may be eliminated."
Great.
Come on, Dana.
You're good, babe.
I've run, like, three miles.
I just can't find
the second one.
Ashley just finished.
You're doing good.
Babe, don't talk
to me! -OK, OK.
Go back into your own world.
Let me live my
life. -Right, right.
Burnie and Ashley, you
are team number three.
Yeah!
I don't think I've been here
yet. It's got to be here.
Ana, come on, Ana.
Yes! This is my second one.
I found it.
OK, we need to
tell Cole and Sheri.
It's right here,
it's this one.
You're doing it,
right? -I am, yeah.
I'm left holding the bag.
-Cole's left holding...
We'll just look down
each street as we pass it.
I see one right there.
Whoo!
I got it. -Good job, good job.
Gracias, senora.
"Last team to check
in...may be eliminated"
Or die.
Campestre, Zaragocilla!
Pesos. Oh, gracias, gracias.
We are trying really hard to get
our last amount of money here.
I'm starting to lose my
voice. This is really hard.
Gracias, senoras.
Gracias, senoritas.
Gracias.
Hey. Yeah, we're doing good.
Let's go back. -Taxi!
Here we go.
Come on, babe.
Give us a little dance. Give
us a little dance, come on.
MATT: The race
is a partnership
and weed to make sure that
we're on the same page.
DANA: Not only for the race but
for our relationship moving forward.
We have to try and stay a
little calmer, communicate better
and just make sure that we
remember to work together.
Here's some bags - these
are marked? Yes, these are marked.
I see one right
there. That's ours.
This is ours.
There's another one,
there's another one.
There's got to be. Is
that it right there, Cole?
You found yours...
No, Cole. I'm going
to run with you, Cole.
We're still ahead
of other people.
Let's go to another one.
JESSICA: Cole and I teamed
up because I trust him.
I had all of my bags, Cole
just needed his last one
so I was going to run around
with him all the way to the end...
Oh, my God, nothing. Next.
If you're not the last team...
If you want to be nice, be nice.
Is this where we started?
Let's check it again.
Is Cole with her?
Yeah, they're together,
they're together.
Good. Oh, that's so good.
No. It's not it.
Cole, this isn't it. Come on.
How you doing? Are
y'all doing good?
I have them, I'm just
trying to help Cole.
Oh, you're so sweet.
You guys go ahead.
You've done really good.
Alright. Love you, Cole.
It's OK, Cole. You can do it.
Man, there can't
be many more left.
Gracias, senorita.
"The old city wall. Warning,
the last team may be eliminated."
I ran for a while with him.
OK, let's go.
OK, sir, we did
it right this time.
Diecisiete, dieciocho,
diecinueve...
Twenty. -Whoo! -Finished.
Gracias! -Arriba!
Come on, Cole.
You can do it, baby.
Could that be it?
Yeah. I got it.
Modelo?
Whoo!
Gracias. -Gracias.
Last team may be
eliminated! -Good job.
Maroon team.
They're right there.
Come on, let's do this.
Along the wall.
Could it be inside?
Is that marked right there?
Marked for the next clue.
You want to do this or do you
want me to do it? -It's up to you.
You do it, you do it.
Let's go over here.
You've got it.
Erin, be confident.
There's another one.
Designer...
This designer...
..is Carmen.
OK. (READS CLUE QUIETLY)
I'll do it, man.
-Alright, you got it.
Oh, come on.
Sheri and Cole, you
are team number six.
Yeah!
Congratulations.
Anyone speak English?
English?
No. OK.
I'll just have to figure
out where I'm going.
Did you see Scott
and Blair here? -No.
Maybe they're coming.
Have you seen them?
I haven't seen them.
You haven't seen
anybody today? -No.
We've been by ourselves all
day. We could be first, last...
We have no idea.
I was hoping that there's some
teams still here at the Roadblock.
This is where Joslyn's Spanish
would come in very handy.
Adriana. Looking for Adriana.
Custom pattern.
There you go, let's go!
OK, one more.
Mochila?
That way! Oh, Daddy, come!
You're left holding
the bags. -OK.
This is taking so much time.
Where is it?
Is this marked?
There's no marker here.
Oh, my gosh.
OK, that's not marked.
Need two like this.
No?
Nothing?
Same designer, yeah?
Designer. Person.
No tengo.
We're sitting in a lot of traffic
here and the sun is also going down.
It looks like it's going
to be night-time really soon
so we'll probably be doing the next
section of the race in the dark,
which makes it harder.
And we have to search
for a mochila vendor
and if it's getting dark on us
here, we're going to be in trouble.
How you doing?
I'm trying to find these streets.
The vendors between these streets.
Yeah, I've got a map and
it doesn't help, so...
So where are we
now? -I don't know.
That's a great question.
Let me help you
here a little bit.
Let's work together on it, OK?
It's getting dark out, which might
make this challenge a little harder.
If it is about
colours and matching.
It's kind of a long day.
SCOTT: We stopped,
we got a map.
We circled the three places
where we've got to go.
Let's keep going. -And now
we know where we're going.
This place is not
that big, it's just...
Marked mochila right here.
No, I've already looked here.
I need two like this.
You have to check the tags.
There are tags in here?
Catalina. Catalina?
Catalina.
Does that match your bag?
This IS my bag.
Oh, my gosh, I've got to go.
I'm going to look
somewhere else.
Are you helping me?
Here it is.
Did she leave me?
Come on, babe. Go,
go. -Let's go, baby.
Can I have the map?
Can I have the map? -No,
you ran off without me.
No, I didn't!
OK. -Come on with me
if you want the map.
Scott, I'd already looked in
those bags earlier for my bag.
I understand.
That's why I ran, because
I can wait for you.
That must be it.
-There's Rachel and Zach.
I'm left holding the bag.
Check over here.
I've been over here.
Oh, my goodness.
Senor, sabe usted donde
esta la Plaza Santo Domingo?
Scott, Scott!
There's mine, there's mine.
Is that your bag? -It's mine.
OK.
Do you see mine?
Let me see yours.
Is that it? That's
not it right there?
No, my bag is not here.
Let's go.
I didn't mean to
leave you back there.
You got excited. It's OK.
The horse is beating me.
Come on, horsey.
I'll race you.
Oh, my goodness. Adriana!
OK, I've gotten all three.
Now I need to find
the right vendor
and she might be where
my brother's waiting.
Here.
Oh, my God. Thank you, Jesus!
Oh, my... Alright,
where do I go?
Wait, I've got to find
mine. Where is yours?
This one doesn't have
one in it. -I'm sorry.
It's alright. You need
to go, you need to go.
Mochila, mochila.
Ooh, good mochila.
Si?
Si. Mochila.
I found one. I need one more.
OK...
Was I here before?
Might have been
here before. Oh, man.
Oh, my goodness.
I thought I'd never find it.
OK, let's go.
This could be it. OK,
got the bag, got the bag.
I got it, I've finished.
Here he is. I got you.
You got it? Good
job. Got it, baby.
OK, now it says
find the vendor.
The name inside the
bag says Adriana.
So I've got to find Adriana.
Darius actually had already
finished but he didn't know
where the vendor was,
which was right next to us.
It was so close.
I do not see my vendor.
OK...
Don't worry, don't
worry. We got this.
Permiso. Se llama Adriana?
Adriana. Adriana, no es...?
Alright, cool.
Se llama Adriana, su nombre?
(SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY)
I'm looking for the
vendor. Her name is Adriana.
Adriana? Adriana.
Uh!
OK, I think I'm in
the totally wrong spot.
I hear drums.
It's going to be the Pit Stop.
Yeah, good?
You got it, Daddy! Stay quiet.
Thank you. Just go.
Dad, hurry. -This
is so frustrating.
Phil! Phil!
Welcome to Baluarte
in Cartagena.
BOTH: Thank you.
I am Miss Cartagena.
Of course you are.
You're beautiful.
Are you crying again? Oh.
Keep moving.
Uh.
It might be here.
It's this one.
Si.
Si?
Si! OK, that's three.
I'm going back.
Hi, Phil!
You're still here.
You've completed three legs.
I have to say
my dad carried me
literally through
this leg of the race.
OK.
It's getting late.
I'm getting tired.
I think I'm doing the right thing
by looking for somebody named Adriana
but I'm going to make sure.
I'm going to head
back to where I started
because I really can't
think of anything else.
You've got it? -Yeah, baby.
Good job, baby. Good job,
good job. Read your clue.
And I know where
the Pit Stop is.
Here you go. Three mochilas.
Thank you so much.
I think it's where I just saw.
There's a bunch of
drumming and noise.
Let's go.
Darius has all three.
It's a foot race.
He has all three.
I am not getting
out on this leg.
Darius can't figure out where the
vendor is so I guess we're last.
Hopefully, he
can figure it out.
Babe, babe, slow down.
Here, take your right.
Hear that? -Yeah.
Adriana? Adriana, su nombre?
No? Your name isn't Adriana?
Oh, my goodness. You've
got to be kidding me?
Is that it?
-I think it's here.
Do you see Phil? -No.
What the heck?
The clue to go here.
This is El Museo Naval.
Along the wall, Museo Naval.
And that's where I was.
I don't see Phil!
OK, then I was wrong.
This is not it. -Ask someone.
Baluarte de Santiago!
Baluarte de Santiago
Plaza?
Baluarte de Santiago?
Esta esquina, la
otra, la tercera.
Just three...
Si. Izquierda...
Let's go. We are going
to be on a foot race.
Oh, dear Jesus! -Go.
Are you our vendor?
Gracias.
Cameron, that was messed up.
We just don't
know where it is.
Please be it.
Shall we ask one more person?
Darius could have
caught up, no.
Let's go. I don't blame...
-I'm running faster.
We did well, huh?
I love you. -I love you.
Let's go! This way.
There it is.
Ah... alright.
Zach and Rachel, you
probably know where you're at.
Give us the bad news, Phil.
The last team to
check in is behind you.
What? -Oh.
Darius and Cameron...
..unfortunately, you are
the last team to arrive...
..and I am very
sorry to tell you
..that you have been
eliminated from the race.
OK. Alright.
Ooh!
I know you guys gave
it everything you had.
I can see it in your eyes.
I feel like we gave
it our all, this leg.
The last couple of legs,
we made some mistakes.
A mixture of bad
luck, bad decisions.
It didn't work out, you know?
I mean, you lose
bit by bit but...
I mean, I couldn't really
run it with anybody else.
Yeah. If anybody,
this guy, you know,
'cause we're the closest,
I know him the best
and know he's capable
of doing amazing things.
Captions by:
Ericsson Access Services
Synced and edited by:
Dzony95
PHIL: Next week on
The Amazing Race...
(YELLS INDISTINCTLY)
..love is in the air.
Blair plus Brodie
equals Blodie.
Blodie.
Teams do some bench work...
Stop, move over. -Sit on
his lap, sit on his lap.
..and the competition
switches gears.
There they are, I saw them.
Now hide!
Can we have everyone
down, please?