NARRATOR: Previously on X-MEN...
Now he'll be able to control his powers.
(BANSHEE AND MOIRA SCREAMING)
What's happening?
MOIRA: Charles! This is Moira!
- What is it?
- Come quickly! I need your help!
He's young and scared.
And he has no idea how powerful he is.
- Joe?
- Moira?
- Kevin's out!
- Well, put him back!
What haven't you told me
about this mutant?
I don't know how to...
Kevin, please,
you've got to come back with me!
Never!
- Who are you looking for?
- My father!
- Don't touch him! He is my son!
- Your son?
Charles, I'm sinking!
Hey! Stop it!
He's down there somewhere.
They can't stop me.
(WOLVERINE MOANING)
ROGUE: Wolverine!
What did he do to you?
I'm fine. I don't need your help!
(WOLVERINE VOMITING)
- You wanna talk about it?
- No. Not now, not ever.
It's just a matter of time
before someone gets hurt.
Moira, don't worry.
We will stop Kevin
before that happens.
Might I suggest we find Proteus' father,
Joseph MacTaggert,
and prepare to confront him there.
Yes. And if needed, we can try to afford
Mr. MacTaggert some protection.
- Joe won't accept your help.
- He's the least of our worries.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Father! Who are those children?
I'm a lad on the way up, Maeve.
I think we should save Wales,
even the whole of Britain,
if that's what it takes.
Oh, it's a keen mind you have, Thomas.
You'll go far in politics.
With me, however,
you'll not get far at all.
Good night to you.
No!
XAVIER: MacTaggert's campaign office
should be in the next block.
He's here. Over there!
Proteus!
(THOMAS SCREAMING)
- What is that? What's that?
- Oh, no!
Kevin! It's time to come home!
Can't you understand, Mother?
I'm going to see him!
Your father can't help you.
He won't help you.
That's not true!
You never gave him a chance.
It'll be okay, Kevin.
Just listen to your mama.
No! No one can keep me from him!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
- Just leave me alone!
- I wish I could!
(ROGUE GRUNTING)
This kid has some temper.
He won't listen.
And if Kevin does reach Joe,
he's going to find out
that Joe left me because of him!
Joe didn't want a mutant for a child!
It's gonna make him crazy.
There'll be no way to stop him,
short of...
Destroying him?
We will find another way.
KEVIN: He'll know
where my father is.
Moira wanted custody.
Kevin is not my problem anymore.
What do you want me to do?
Put him on telly?
No, Mr. MacTaggert.
Just talk to the boy.
He doesn't know why you left him.
Tell him the truth.
Are you nuts? The vote's tomorrow.
There are cameras everywhere I go.
I don't want people to remember
I'm divorced,
much less find out
I'm the father of some sort of...
Son, Joe! He's a boy.
And he needs his father.
Well, tell him that Xavier's his father.
You always wanted it that way.
You fool, MacTaggert!
He's coming for you,
whether you like it or not!
Don't you think I want to help the lad?
Remember, Moira, he's mine too.
I appreciate your offer of protection,
but I have my own.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Where is my father?
Father?
(GASPS)
JOE: If the boy shows up,
keep him out of sight
until after the vote.
If you don't,
all our work will be for nothing.
MAN 1: How bad is he?
How should I know? I haven't seen him
since he was crawling.
(ROGUE SCOFFS)
Ought to just let Proteus
get a good look at dear old dad.
- How much trouble can one boy be?
- And don't get careless.
Professor, we got to change shifts.
I need a shower
after babysitting this slime.
(SUPPORTERS CHEERING)
Joe MacTaggert.
Appreciate your support.
Hope you'll be with me on election day.
MacTaggert, how you doing?
Good man.
It's in the bag, Bill.
I don't go along with abandoning kids.
BEAST: "Political campaigns
are designedly made to paralyze
"what slight powers of cerebration man
can normally muster."
James Harvey Robinson.
Just remember to report
the least sign of a disturbance.
- Is that understood?
- BEAS T: Certainly, Professor.
Logan, are you there?
Are you all right?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm here.
No angry boy clouds in the basement.
Hold it!
- All clear.
- Are you holding up okay, Logan?
Worry about that kid if I find him first!
(SUPPORTERS SCREAMING)
Thank you! I take that as support
not just for me, but for my platform
for every family in Scotland,
for our children!
Guess he likes children if they ain't his.
I've seen that happen before.
- My own flesh and blood, a mutant!
- Daddy, please!
You're a disgrace!
I'm ashamed to be seen with you!
You ain't my daughter! Not anymore!
Daddy! Daddy, please!
I wonder, Professor,
if Proteus might not wish
- to avoid so public a location...
- He's here! Proteus is in the hall!
I know that without my children,
I would simply cease to exist.
They're my life.
Our children are more than our future.
They are...
Father, it's Kevin!
Careful, sugar.
Mr. MacTaggert may not recognize you.
I told you, stay away!
Moira, stay back! I'll help them.
Where are you, Logan?
XA VIER: Wolverine!
I can't!
(ROGUE GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Where are you, Logan?
Blast it!
I paid you to keep this from happening!
That's no boy!
Talk to me, Kevin.
Stop fighting us and I'll listen.
Where is my father?
You frightened him, Kevin!
He ran away because...
Shut up! You kept him from me!
Stop!
(ROGUE SCREAMING)
Get them off of me!
(XAVIER SCREAMING)
Hold on, Chuck!
BEAST: A set of claws would be
extraordinarily useful right now.
ROGUE: You ain't going
anywhere, Beast.
Better talk to your boy, Professor.
'Cause he ain't listening to any of us.
XA VIER: Kevin. Kevin Mac Taggert.
ROGUE: (SIGHS) That's more like it.
- Kevin, please listen.
- Why?
I sense that beneath your anger
there's a yearning, a reaching out.
I am a doctor.
Let me help you understand
what it is you seek.
What I want is my father.
If you want to help me, bring him to me!
My father wants me! Get out of the way!
(X-MEN SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Fascinating. His power seems limited
only by his imagination.
- And that temper.
- Stopping him is beyond our power.
We must continue to try
to reason with him.
No, Charles. You've tried.
It is I that must do something now.
- Moira! Wait!
- Do you wish me to bring her back?
If only I had more time with him.
Even with more time, Professor,
what could we possibly accomplish?
Proteus attacks
with the speed of thought.
Though a young man, he has
the immature emotions of a child.
- I say we nail him.
- What are you talking about?
And by the way,
when he was tossing us around,
where were you hiding?
- Back off, cornpone.
- Your anger serves no purpose, Rogue.
Wolverine could not
prevent his hesitation.
What's that supposed to mean?
Only that there's no emotion
harder to control than a paralyzing fear.
We have all experienced it.
But it must be even worse for you,
who has never felt it before.
- You saying I'm a coward, Blue Boy?
- Stop it, both of you!
We cannot afford petty fights
among ourselves!
Moira feels responsible
for Proteus' actions.
And she's gone to do something.
She may try to destroy her own son.
Do you know what that means to her?
To me?
Help me make sure
that it doesn't happen.
...where, earlier this evening,
MacTaggert was victim
of a vicious physical attack.
An attack he says was instigated
by his opponent, Bill Wallace.
While the opposition
denies any involvement,
sources close
to the MacTaggert campaign tell me...
(AUDIENCE MURMURING)
MAN 2: What is this? What's going on?
WOMAN 1: What's happening here?
MAN 3: What's going on?
MAN 4: What's happening here?
Good evening. Thank you all
for having me here tonight.
Of course, after this afternoon,
I'm thankful to be anywhere tonight.
(EVERYONE LAUGHING)
Now where was I? Oh, yes.
Telling you what you already know
and pretending I just thought it up.
That boy's slick as hog fat.
The only real hope for a solution
to all this is there, behind that podium.
But MacTaggert decided long ago
that his career was more important
than his son.
A real prince.
And I have a personal stake
in that future,
my love for my children!
(AUDIENCE CHEERING)
(PROTEUS SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE EX CLAIMING)
KEVIN: Father! Everybody says
you don't want to see me.
But that's not true! It can't be true!
Here now. A joke's a joke.
(WOLVERINE STRUGGLING)
You're not real!
You're a trick to ruin me!
(AUDIENCE SCREAMING)
MAN 5: Look out!
MAN 6: Let me out of here!
(PROTEUS SCREAMING)
- Get away!
- Rogue! Beast! Stand aside!
- Say what?
- Let them talk.
Don't you know me, Father?
Somebody do something!
- Does this help?
- What on earth...
- It's me, Father. It's Kevin.
- It can't be!
- Father, I need you!
- No, no, get away!
But, Father...
Guards! Darnley! Security!
Somebody get him!
- No! Don't!
- Kevin! Kevin, listen!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Come on, kid, your old man's no saint,
but that's no reason to trash this dump.
If you don't like Xavier,
maybe you can talk to me.
(WOLVERINE SCREAMING)
Charles. Banshee's brought
the one thing that
seems to affect Kevin.
Used at low power,
it helped control him.
At full power, it might...
If you can't stop him, I'll have to!
- Moira, there's no choice!
- Moira, wait! I have to try one last time.
Charles, no! It's too late!
Kevin! Kevin, listen to me.
My name is Charles Xavier.
You know me now.
I've come to help you face your rage,
and face it you must!
Possess me
as you have others, Kevin.
Look inside my mind
and see that I know your pain.
Otherwise it will consume you.
I can get you through this,
if that's what you want.
It is what I want.
Give me your hand, son,
and come here.
I have helped many like you, Kevin.
With time, you will learn
to master your powers, and this rage.
But only if you learn to trust those
who love you, mother and father.
- Kevin? Darling.
- Kevin?
- Son, is that really you?
- It is, Father.
Aye, child,
though I've no right to the name.
- Can you forgive me?
- Go ahead, Kevin.
(PIECES BEEPING)
(BEEPING)
His progress is remarkable.
BANSHEE: Aye.
Though it's hard-fought, indeed.
I feel much better with him
fighting his teacher
than taking on the whole world.
I am sure Mr. MacTaggert
is equally thankful, and relieved.
Whatever Chuck did in there, it worked.
I don't know how he faced that thing.
He never loses his cool.
Forget it, hon.
In our business, we all get shook up
every now and again.
I don't.