Previously on Z Nation.
El Murfi.
The savior.
I have been looking for
you for a very long time.
I'm Javier Vasquez.
You killed my family.
I should've killed you too.
That's it?
That's it.
Doesn't look very high tech.
Maybe it's just another
front for an underground lab.
One last cosmic joke at my expense.
Either way we're gonna check it out.
Would you like some tea
and finger sandwiches?
How 'bout you put the weapon
you got under the counter
on top of the bar?
- [wind blowing]
- [fire crackling]
Delta-Xray-Addy,
do you copy?
[radio static]
Anybody copy?
[radio static continues]
Citizen Z, down to my last battery.
If you can hear this broadcast,
tell the package to abort mission.
Repeat.
Abort mission.
Location compromised.
I
[static ceases]
All good things must come to an end.
What is taking so long?
I hope it's not another
top secret underground lab.
That last elevator made
me nauseous for a week.
Whatever it is, I just
want to get it over with.
Got that right.
[thump, thump]
How's your tea, dear?
Excellent. Thank you.
What brings you to California?
Just passing through.
What's the matter, young
man? You don't like tea.
I like tea just fine. It's
surprises I don't like.
Nothing out of the ordinary.
Except her.
Here she comes.
Here we go.
I gotta say,
I kinda like the new you.
You don't want to meet the new me.
So is this a real working restaurant?
Well except for Black Summer,
we've been in continuous
operation since 1967.
We've had a limited menu at times. But
where you folks from?
New York.
New York?
I didn't know anybody could
still be from New York.
Upstate. The city's gone 100% Z.
Long drive.
What was it like out there?
Nothing but Z's
and those soon to become Z's.
Wasn't there anybody safe? Anywhere?
There are.
Few and far between.
So what does bring you to California?
[car tires on gravel]
Bounty hunters.
Busy day.
Can I get you boys some tea?
You got any brown liquor?
Oh, I think I can squeeze
some out of the still.
Are you Auntie?
I am.
We heard you're the one to
talk to about the Murphy.
Show her.
[snarling]
We're here to claim our bounty.
Let me get you those drinks.
[snarling]
[electric guitar theme music plays]
♪ Have mercy.
[gunshots]
♪ Oh, have mercy. ♪
- Sync and corrected by TheDelta -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Another round of drinks for my men.
This time make it the clear stuff.
Hey.
We're celebrating over here.
How 'bout I buy you a drink?
No thanks.
I already got one.
Well if you won't come drink with me,
you won't mind if I just mosey on over
and have a drink with you?
Relax, fellas.
I'm gonna buy you a drink too.
Hell, drinks for everyone.
Don't worry about the
Murphy. We got him sedated.
[snarling]
How 'bout a toast?
To the Murphy.
(all) To the Murphy.
[clink]
[snarling]
Hey, Auntie. We could use some music.
♪
Yeah, that's better.
So what brings you folks here to Auntie's?
Passing through.
♪
Well you sure are a shy one.
How 'bout a dance there, shy girl?
[snarling]
Come on, baby.
It's a slow song.
♪
No, no, no, no.
I don't dance.
♪
Hey, shy girl.
Shy girl.
♪
Think fast.
[snarling]
♪
Now that's interesting.
When shy girl here moves,
my Murphy moves the same way.
Like they're connected or
something. It's interesting.
Why don't you take off that hat?
♪
No.
Take off the hat.
♪
God.
Wow. That's life like.
That's good work.
Hell, if I didn't know any better,
I'd think you were the real deal.
You wouldn't be hiding any bites
under that dress, would you?
♪
Take off the dress.
[snarling]
♪
[growling]
[gunshot]
[splorch]
♪
That'll be enough of that.
Put down your weapons.
Please.
Your name Murphy?
Yeah.
Well it's about time.
[moaning]
10K?
I've been shot.
Don't move, kid. I'll
try to stop the bleeding.
[moaning]
Auntie, do you have a first aid kit?
Where are you going?
[whispering] Okay.
[gunshot]
Who are you signaling?
Doctor Merch.
And what's left of the
Mount Wilson CDC lab.
- He's losing a lot of blood.
- [whispering] Can you do anything?
Way out of my league. Sorry, kid.
Maybe the submarine has a surgeon.
They're bound to have a sick bay.
What's the deal with this submarine anyway?
Is that where Doctor Merch has
been hiding this whole time?
Sorry hon. That's classified.
Classified? From who? The zombies?
Say goodbye, pup.
Cuz we ain't coming back.
All right. Doc, you stay with 10K.
Vasquez and Addy, you guys cover us.
Dearie, put your guns away.
They have a nuclear submarine.
She has a point.
Hey.
You ready?
No.
But when did that ever matter?
Cap'n.
Auntie. Looks like you had a busy morning.
We had a bit of a lunch rush.
That's not him, is it?
No, sir.
Lieutenant Roberta Warren.
Missouri National Guard.
We have the package here.
Safe.
So, you're The Murphy?
Actually it's just Murphy.
I don't know where this
whole the came from.
We have a wounded man.
I'm the ship's doctor.
Let me take a look at him.
Lot of people been looking
for you, Mr. Murphy.
Well you found me.
Now what?
First we have to make sure
you are who you say you are.
Oh.
I am.
How do we know you are who you say you are?
I understand your
reluctance, Lieutenant Warren.
We've been tracking
Delta-Xray-Delta for two years.
If I'd been through
what you'd been through,
I'd make damn sure I was giving
that package to the right person
too.
Doctor, would you mind joining us?
Is that him?
I don't know.
I'm sorry.
I only saw him for a minute
before we were evacuated.
Everything was so chaotic, there was
Perhaps this'll jog your memory.
Pike me.
Pike me!
Or I will hunt you down
and eat your brains!
That's him.
Satisfied?
Very.
Now let's get you back to the sub.
We got a lot of work to do.
What happened to your Delta Force Escort,
Lieutenant Hammond?
He didn't make it.
A lot of people didn't make it.
Easy, easy.
Hey.
It's okay.
I need your word
that he will be treated
humanely. He may be The Murphy.
But he still is a human being.
You have my word, Lieutenant Warren.
We'll treat him like the
celebrity he's about to become.
[laughing] Celebrity? You hear that?
I'm about to become the first
post-apocalyptic reality star.
Yay me.
Well don't forget the little people.
It's gonna be okay, kid.
They got a real surgeon.
They're gonna fix you up.
I'm his physician. I'm
gonna need to go with you.
Sorry, sir. We barely
have room for these two.
But I, I have to be
Don't worry.
We'll take good care of him.
Hey.
Sorry about your family.
Whoa, whoa. Hey.
That's it? No goodbye? Nothing?
A handshake? After all the
shit we've been through?
Hey. I have something for you.
I knew it. Damn it, Murphy.
Just trying to survive, man.
I got something for you too, brother.
In case you get seasick.
Thank you, brother.
[whispering] Take care.
We're ready, Mr. Murphy.
Psst.
Thank you.
For everything.
You better get going.
Who knows?
Maybe I'll actually enjoy doing some good.
Count on you.
Amen.
No shit.
So that's it then, huh?
I hope the kid's gonna be okay.
He will.
Let's get these bodies out of here.
At least there's no harm
done to the gene pool.
Give you mercy.
Hey.
What about this poor blue son of a
[gunshot]
[screaming]
[automatic gunfire]
[automatic gunfire continues]
Bounty hunters?
[gunfire continues]
No. Zeros.
[automatic gunfire]
[automatic gunfire continues]
Warrennnnnn.
[whispering] Warren.
[whispering] Come and get some mercy.
[gunshot]
[automatic gunfire]
So remember,
there is no such thing as death.
There is only eternal life
for La Reina de la Muerta.
[automatic gunfire continues]
So bring me El Murfi.
[muffled sounds]
[automatic gunfire continues]
Now!
Everybody inside!
[automatic gunfire continues]
Come on. Come on.
How the hell did they find us?!
[automatic gunfire continues]
Well my hat's off to you, Doctor Kurian.
Once again you've proven your value.
I must admit,
I can't believe I'm
getting such good directions
from a head in a box.
My queen
Wait.
Where are you, little kitty?
Oooh.
There you are, pretty pretty.
Violence at such a range is so impersonal.
Where's the dignity?
Ammo? Who's got what?
I'm good.
Doc?
Well I'm okay, but I left my
bag out there. I don't know
how far Im gonna be able
to chuck the damn crowbar.
I'm out.
And without range, this
cover won't do us much good.
Well if you just ask nicely
Well aren't you full of surprises.
Well I'm a little low on ammo.
But I think we can give
them hell in the meantime.
All right. Let's rock and roll.
The fact that they haven't
started beating down these doors
yet worries me more than
if they just kept attacking.
Mindless mayhem we can handle.
Whatever the hell they're planning,
I'm not so sure.
Young male. Single large caliber
gunshot wound to the abdomen.
Pulse weak, irregular.
He's lost a lot of blood.
Is he gonna be okay?
They'll do everything they
can. Now we need to leave.
We'll make sure to get him back
to his friends in one piece.
Your man's in good hands.
He's not my man. He's just
a byproduct of the apocalypse
I couldn't seem to shake.
Follow me.
We've been waiting for you
a long time, Mr. Murphy.
Yeah, well I got a little sidetracked.
Have there been any side
effects from the vaccine?
Side effects? Lady, I am a
giant walking side effect.
Any cravings?
You mean for brains?
No.
Who are you working for?
I thought the U.S. Government
collapsed years ago.
It did.
The whole idea of a nation
state is a thing of the past.
A new world is rising
from the ashes of the old.
A better world.
Zona.
Zona?
I've heard of that.
This crazy pilot in Roswell.
He was gonna fly some
experimental aircraft back to Zona.
We thought he was nuts.
Zona's real?
Zona is more than just
real. It's the future.
Early in the apocalypse, a
group of visionary world leaders
and businessmen embarked
on a plan to save humanity.
Together they created a zombie free island
where the seeds of the next
human race have been planted.
What about the old human race?
Time may be running out.
The pilot you met was part of a larger plan
to recover advanced technology
and cultural heritage
before it's lost forever.
Unfortunately, both
tend to be very fragile.
We're in a race against time to
hold onto what makes us human.
[clank]
Sorry.
My bad.
So if we are going to save the human race,
maybe we better get started.
Anybody tries to come in that front door
is stepping right into our kill box.
Cubrirse! Cubrirse!
Now what are they up to?
Hey, Roberta!
Hey!
It's not you I came
after. Just Murphy. Hmmm?
I only want Murphy!
You give him to me, and
we can still be friends.
Too late, Chica! He's gone!
Dónde está Murfi?
[gunshot]
Shit. Missed.
Ready.
(all) Apunten!
Machetes!
Go!
[stabbing]
[yelling]
[automatic gunfire]
That's it!
Nobody comes into my house
and shoots up my stuff! Nobody!
[automatic gunfire]
Nice shooting!
[automatic gunfire continues]
[growling]
[gunfire]
- [yelling]
- [growling]
[crash]
[growling]
[slice]
[breathing heavily]
Mercy.
[crash]
Are you comfortable?
Perfect. Just like when I was a kid.
I'm gonna need a few samples
of your blood to run some tests.
I'm all yours.
This should be interesting.
What's the deal with the crew?
Their eyes?
It's a side effect from
one of the early vaccines
given to everyone on Zona.
But not you?
I've never been.
I've only seen the inside of this sub
since we evacuated Mt. Wilson.
How do you even know Zona's real then?
I worked for some of the
people who first founded Zona
before the outbreak.
They're the only ones left
with enough power and
resources to stop this plague.
We almost had it.
But the vaccine only slows down the virus.
It doesn't kill it or make you immune.
Some of the earliest people vaccinated
are losing their immunity
and starting to turn.
Including the founder of Zona.
That's why we need you.
I thought the vaccine
was for all of humanity?
It will be.
Have you had any major childhood diseases?
Measles, mumps, chickenpox.
Yes, yes, and I think yes.
I was sick all the time when
I was a kid. I had everything.
Mono, whooping cough,
poison ivy, you name it.
Any sexually transmitted diseases?
The usual.
You don't have to go into detail
The tests will tell me more.
Any children?
These are awfully personal questions.
You mind?
A little privacy?
Would you mind?
We'll only be a minute.
[whispering] Jesus.
I thought you might be
different than Doctor Kurian.
But I was wrong.
You met Doctor Kurian?
Oh we're old buddies, he and I.
I know all about you two.
He's still alive?
Sort of.
[gasping]
I did not spend three years fighting my way
across ten thousand miles
of zombie crazed America
just so I could be a human blood bag
for a few billionaires in Hawaii.
What are you gonna do?
What I should have done a long time ago.
[mumbling]
[automatic gunfire]
[crash]
[click]
[whispering] Shit.
[automatic gunfire]
[clang]
[grunting]
[crash]
[clang]
[crack]
[thwap]
[moaning]
[gunshot]
[gasping]
Roberta!
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Can we talk? Like sisters.
We can.
As you can see, I am unarmed.
You're not going to shoot me, are you?
You know I've missed you.
We would have made a wonderful team.
But it is not too late.
Hmmm?
You come join me.
Be my consigliore.
Escorpion is dead.
I need you.
Hmmm?
Help me find the Murphy.
Too late.
He's gone.
Gone where?
We gave him to the CDC.
That was a big mistake.
Not my first one.
[screaming]
[thwap]
[smack]
[thump]
[crash]
[moaning]
[smack]
[crash]
[moaning]
[smack]
[grunting]
[crash]
[yelling]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[smack]
[moaning]
[screaming]
[smack]
[moaning]
[thwap]
[smack]
[crash]
[breathing heavily]
We could've been
such good friends.
[yelling]
[slice]
[gasping]
Escorpion?
No, mi reina.
Soy Hector.
Te doy misericordia.
Thank you.
De nada.
Wait! [smack]
Never leave a zombie to do a man's job.
He saved my life.
I don't care.
Well ding dong. The bitch is dead.
You killed your queen?
Why?
She wasn't my queen.
Not since she got that cooked
batch of Kurian's vaccine.
I followed them here through
all their death and destruction.
She wasn't human anymore.
None of them were.
I won't rob you of your revenge.
You've earned it.
Escorpion deserves to
die for what he did to
What I did to your family.
If you want to kill me, you go right ahead.
I've been a one man apocalypse all my life.
I'm not afraid to die.
Death, shit, that's all I know.
I know it don't mean shit,
but I apologize.
I'm not that man who
killed your family, man.
That man is dead.
Killed by the Zs when you
threw me down that hole.
In that one second,
I saw every horrible and
malicious thing I ever did.
And I wanted to die right there and then.
But I knew if my life
were to have any meaning,
I had to get out of there.
I had to survive and make up
for all the things that I did.
Maybe this is how I do it.
Do me a favor, man.
You pull that trigger.
Do what you have to.
But who are you gonna be
after you pull that trigger?
[gunshot]
What happened?
I couldn't do it.
I know.
I'm glad.
Not for him.
For you.
Never did show you this did I?
No.
She's beautiful.
They both are.
Come on. We better get going.
My mission is over.
Yeah. So is mine.
You better go.
Well I ain't gonna say goodbye.
Me neither.
Well.
Watch out for those
puppies and kittens, huh?
I will.
What happened?
Is he alive?
He's alive.
He's not coming.
Well, what do we do now, Chief?
I don't know.
I'm not in charge anymore.
[alarm sounding]
- [alarm sounding]
- [rapid footsteps]
You need a ride?
I got enough food, ammo,
and z weed for a month.
I'm in.
Well look.
If we need to, we kill
him and we take the truck.
We're only going as far as the beach.
I like the beach.
[crash]
[growling]
[gunshot]
Think 10K's all right?
Big sub like that, they got
to have a real medical team.
Well I hope they don't bleed him dry.
I hate to admit it,
but I kinda miss Murphy.
Really?
I didn't get to know him too well,
but he seemed like kind of a dick.
That doesn't look good.
Is it submerging?
No.
It's sinking.
Murphy.
10K.
Is that a boat?
It's Murphy. He has Doctor
Merch and the Sub Captain.
What about 10K?
[muffled explosion]
Tell me he's on that boat.
Doc, tell me 10K is on that boat!
I don't see him.
Hey, check it out.
[jet engines roaring]
Those don't look American.
They're not.
What do you suppose they want?
What do you think?
[wind blowing]
- [snarling]
Drink your tea.
[laughing] Bad zombie.