[WIND WHISTLING]
NARRATOR: Only time can teach us
what is truth and what is legend.
Some truths do not survive the ages.
But the legend of the child
with the blue eyes will live forever...
... and be whispered in all four winds
of the Great White Mountains.
We, the Yagahl, were hunters
of the mightiest of all beasts...
... the Mannak.
But our world began to change.
The Mannaks came later and later
to our valley...
... and there were times
when they did not come at all.
Our hunters grew restless.
And our people grew hungry.
Only one amongst us...
... the one we call "Old Mother,"
the last of her kind...
... only she could speak
to the spirits of the earth...
... and ask the wisdom of the Fathers
to save our people.
[CHANTING]
Many times she asks...
... until one night they answered her call
and sent us a sign.
[GIRL WHIMPERING]
A sign of the beginning of the end.
HUNTER: We found her in the mountains.
She was holding on to a dead woman.
[CHANTING]
The Fathers have sent her.
[PANTING]
She came to tell us
of four-legged demons...
...that will put an end to our world.
They will come to our valley
at the time when...
...we go on our last hunt.
But do not fear.
From this hunt a warrior will arise...
...and this one will be his woman.
They will lead us into a new life...
...where the Yagahl
will know hunger no more.
That night...
... Old Mother did not see the face
of the warrior of which she spoke...
... but she knew that the child
with the blue eyes...
... was a blessing she must protect.
To our people, she was Evolet...
... the promise of life.
To a boy named D'Leh,
she was much more than that.
Only one of the Yagahl did not believe in
Old Mother's prophecy:
The young boy's father...
... the one who carried the White Spear
and blew the whistle for the hunt.
I will watch over your son
as if he were my own.
I know you will. But promise me
you will tell no one why I left.
We cannot wait for the last hunt.
[GRUNTS]
- Good throw! Throw again!
- Good throw!
Ka'ren?
Ka'ren? Hmm?
No. Not you.
Your father abandoned our people.
Go away.
Fight well!
You must win, Ka'ren!
TIC'TIC:
Leave him!
Ka'ren! I said leave him!
D'Leh.
He is the son of a coward.
You never say that again.
Any of you.
BOY:
Good throw.
You are alone...
...like me.
What happened to your people?
They were killed...
...by four-legged demons.
You will never be alone, Evolet.
Do you see that light?
That one?
It does not move across the sky
like all the others do.
That light is like you in my heart.
It will never go away.
It will never go away?
No, never.
OLD MOTHER:
Evolet, come here.
Don't stray from the hut
without telling me.
And for many moons...
... Evolet and D'Leh
looked at each other...
... and the love in their hearts
grew stronger.
Until finally, after many years...
... the day of the last hunt arrived.
BAKU: D'Leh, how long do we
have to keep watch?
Until the Mannaks come.
And when will they come?
Do not know.
D'Leh, when will I become a hunter?
When you stop asking
so many questions.
The Great Hunter Tic'Tic
came to Old Mother's hut today.
She thinks the time of prophecy
has come.
She told him not to kill
the Mannak this hunt.
She thinks Ka'ren will win the White Spear
and claim Evolet.
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
- Baku, look what I found for you.
- Ah.
Mm.
You know what a good hunter Ka'ren is.
We must run away. Together,
we can cross the Great Mountains.
And abandon our people? Like my father?
I cannot do that.
I worked on this for many moons.
The only way we can be together
is I must kill the Mannak.
[MANNAKS TRUMPETING]
They are here! They are here! Look!
Look how many there are.
[CHATTERING]
Today...
...I will not pierce the heart of the Mannak.
It will be one of you.
One of you will claim the White Spear.
May the Fathers of the Yagahl...
...and the spirit of the mighty Mannak
choose the best of you.
[YELLING]
MOHA:
Ka'ren, you have the first throw.
LU'KIBU: Ka'ren, the Mannak is yours.
You will be our leader.
D'Leh? What about you?
I hunt to win Evolet.
We hunt together as one!
HUNTER:
Tic'Tic found the lead bull.
[YELLING]
[GROWLING]
[ROARING]
[MANNAKS TRUMPETING]
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[YELLING]
TIC'TIC:
Slow down!
D'Leh!
They're breaking away! Bring them back!
[SHOUTING]
[GRUNTS]
Baku! They're coming!
They're coming, Baku!
They're coming! They're coming!
The last one is coming! It is a big bull!
HUNTER:
Now!
[TRUMPETING]
MOHA: D'Leh is coming!
Ka'ren, make your throw!
Keep him down! Hold the net!
[SHOUTING]
[GRUNTING]
He is too strong! Let go, Ka'ren!
D'Leh, we have to let go!
I can't! My hand is caught!
[ROARS]
LU'KIBU:
Look! Look!
It's D'Leh!
[GASPING]
BAKU:
You killed him! All alone!
No one has ever done that.
That was brave.
[CHEERING]
D'Leh killed the Mannak!
He did not let go of the net!
He was the only one!
What are you waiting for?
Wise Spirit, I killed the Mannak.
I claim the White Spear...
...and with it my woman...
...Evolet.
[CHEERING]
From that day on, D'Leh was no longer
the son of a coward.
Now the Yagahl would honor his name...
... for bringing to them the blessings
of the Mannak for one last time.
And though Old Mother was pleased
in her heart to see Evolet so happy...
... she feared in her soul...
... that the one who had slayed
the mighty beast...
... did not have the courage
for what was to come.
[CHANTING]
Why does Tic'Tic not celebrate with us?
- D'Leh?
- There is something I must do.
What do you want?
I was not brave.
And I did not hunt as one.
The Fathers of the Yagahl
played with us today.
What should I do?
If I give up the White Spear,
I give up Evolet. I cannot do that.
Is she yours to give up?
Hmm?
It is not the way of the Yagahl
to claim the White Spear with a lie.
I gave the White Spear back to Tic'Tic.
Why would you do such a thing?
Because I did not kill the Mannak, Evolet.
- Of course you did, you held on to the net.
- No, I lied.
I tried to let go like all the others.
My hand was caught in it.
After that, the Mannak ran into my spear.
I did nothing.
Evolet, remember what I told you
about our light?
I still feel the same.
You will always be in my heart.
That will never go away.
But still...
...you gave me up.
That night the great white rain
came to the valley of the Yagahl.
And like an icy veil,
sadness fell over D'Leh's heart.
And with the white rain
came the four-legged demons.
[SNORING]
[GASPS]
OLD MOTHER:
You stay here.
Baku.
[SHOUTING]
Moha! Look out!
[GRUNTING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
- Baku, hide.
- Yes, Mother.
TIC'TIC:
D'Leh!
We cannot help them!
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Please.
Let me!
Let me go!
- What are you doing?
- I am going after them.
Over the Great Mountains?
That is not possible.
D'LEH:
They came over the Great Mountains.
They are demons. Maybe they can fly.
I did not see wings on them.
You think you can bring them down
all alone? Only you?
TIC'TIC:
He is not alone.
I go with him.
Without the other hunters,
we all will die.
I will go too.
No, Baku, you will stay here.
But you, Ka'ren, you must go with them.
[CHATTERING]
Don't touch me!
[MEN LAUGHING]
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
And as they bid farewell to the elders
and the children of our people...
... the Wise Spirit of the Yagahl blessed them
and the spears by their side.
Old Mother knew they would
never be hunters again...
... but warriors instead.
It will be night soon. We stay here.
No, we go on. We are getting closer.
I cannot see in the dark. Can you?
We stay here. We eat and sleep.
Why do you not carry the White Spear?
Are you afraid?
Answer.
Ka'ren, go to sleep.
Baku? Baku!
What are you doing here? Go home.
I can help you. I can carry a water bag.
Go home!
They killed my mother!
He's alone.
He will only slow us down.
D'Leh, I'm thirsty.
Fire still lives in these stones.
D'Leh!
She's alive. We must hurry.
[WIND HOWLING]
[PANTING]
Why is Old Mother freezing?
The white rain is not a friend
to the hunter.
It swallowed all the marks
of the stolen brothers and sisters.
It was now up to the Fathers of the Yagahl
to guide their way.
And they walked for many days and nights
to a faraway land...
... where the Great Mountains ended...
... and where the story of
the child with the blue eyes began.
The place where the four-legged demons
killed Evolet's people.
We've walked for days now,
and still no marks.
Maybe they do have wings.
TIC'TIC:
Maybe they do.
But our brothers and sisters do not.
Don't forget to chew.
[MEN SHOUTING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GRUNTING]
Maybe she only lost it.
[BIRDS SHRIEKING]
It is hot here.
Baku. Stay close.
[ANIMAL GROWLING]
[WHIP CRACKS]
[YELLS]
[ROARING]
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[MAN SCREAMING]
[ROARING]
[HORSE WHINNYING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
What was that?
[SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
We must free them tonight.
Not tonight. This is not a good place.
They know there is danger,
and they keep a good watch.
We'll do the same.
I will go first, then Ka'ren, then you.
D'Leh.
Come.
I understand your pain.
But you must be patient.
[ANIMAL GROWLS]
[HORSE WHINNYING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
D'Leh.
I will never give you up again.
[ANIMAL GROWLS]
This way.
Come.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GRUNTING]
D'Leh!
Run! Run!
MAN:
D'Leh!
D'LEH:
This way!
[GRUNTS]
Over here! This way!
Go! Go!
D'LEH:
Ka'ren!
[ANIMAL GROWLS]
[GROWLING]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[SCREECHING]
[MAN SCREAMING]
TIC'TIC:
Run!
D'LEH: Tic'Tic!
- Go!
Tic'Tic!
[YELLING]
[GRUNTING]
[ROARING]
D'Leh! Evolet! Up here!
- D'Leh!
- I will lead them away.
- No, do not go!
- I will come back for you.
I promise.
[GRUNTS]
[SHOUTING]
[ROARS]
Oh, Baku.
You should not be here.
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
I think he speaks of D'Leh.
D'Leh will come back.
He promised it to me.
[WHEEZING]
Ka'ren. Do you think he's still alive?
It does not matter now.
He tried to save us.
[GRUNTING]
[PANTING]
[HORSE WHINNIES]
[MEN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY]
[GRUNTING]
Forgive me, Tic'Tic.
I should have listened to you.
Do not die.
I will bring you food.
[YELLING]
[FLIES BUZZING]
[ROARS]
[GASPING]
Old Mother was watching over their journey
with all her strength...
... and her spirit stayed always
by their side.
[THUNDER CRASHING]
But that night, she could not rule over
the forces of the earth...
... and could not stop the waters
of the heavens.
D'Leh would have to face alone...
... the mighty beast
who rules these lands.
[COUGHING]
[GROWLING]
Ha! Ha!
[GRUNTS]
Do not eat me when I set you free!
[GROWLING]
[SNIFFING]
[ROCKS CLATTERING]
I feared you were dead.
Do not fear for me.
Look, over there.
There was an attack.
I heard them scream.
This is where they went.
[YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[ROARING]
Tic'Tic, move away. Go.
D'Leh, come back.
Move away.
You must remember me.
I gave you life.
[GROWLING]
You speak to the Spear Tooth?
How do you come to speak our words?
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[PANTING]
You not like Naku food?
[HICCUPS]
It's different, but good.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CHEERING]
We come from over the mountains.
- We know where you come from.
D'LEH: How do you know?
And how do you come
to speak our words?
A man come from the mountain before.
He was looking for new land.
Our wise man told me to learn his words.
You. You have his face.
What happened to him?
He was taken a long time ago.
Taken where?
Come.
NAKUDU: When your father came to us,
he became my friend.
Then the evil spirits stole your father,
like many of our people.
They bring them to the nest
of the great birds...
...and fly away over the sand.
TIC'TIC:
Where do they take them?
To the mountain of the gods.
No one has ever returned.
[MAN SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
NAKUDU:
Our wise man says you will lead us there.
Me?
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
We have a telling that...
...one day the one will come...
...who will free our people.
The one who speaks to the Spear Tooth.
NARRATOR: At last, the brave people
of the Naku buried their dead.
They sent word to all the tribes
of the land...
... that the one who speaks
to the Spear Tooth had come.
[CHANTING]
Their call...
... was a call for war.
Why do they think
I can free their people?
There's something you must know
about your father.
When your mother died
bringing you life...
...your father took upon himself
not only the weight of you...
...but all our people.
We were starving.
He could not wait for Old Mother's
prophecy to come true.
Your father did not run away.
He left to save our people.
How could you let me believe all this time
that my father betrayed us?
Because he wanted it to be that way.
Your father carried the White Spear.
He feared that when he left, others would
follow him and abandon our people.
And why do you tell me this now?
A good man...
...draws a circle around himself
and cares for those within.
His woman, his children.
Other men draw a larger circle...
...and bring within
their brothers and sisters.
But some men...
...have a great destiny.
They must draw around themselves...
...a circle that includes
many, many more.
Your father was one of those men.
You must decide for yourself...
...whether you are, as well.
[CHANTING]
This is Kawu, our fastest runner.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
He bring words from the people
who live that way.
They stole many more men.
And now they are moving
to the great birds, fast.
We must find them
before they reach these birds.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
You have no woman?
The day before you came...
...they took her breath...
...and they stole our son.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[YELLING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SOBBING]
I am Baku.
Tudu.
No. I am Baku.
Baku, Tudu. Baku, Tudu.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[YELLING]
He's killing him! You must help!
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
The word of the Naku traveled fast
and from all winds came many warriors.
The Tutt Tutt who move like big running
birds and hide their eyes behind trees.
The tribe of the Kula.
They are short like our young ones.
And from the valley without sun
came the ones with blood on their heads.
But the strongest of them all
were the Hoda.
Their leader spoke for all the warriors
of the land.
Tell him if his people walk with us,
we will bring them down.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
He says you are only a boy.
Tell him I am older than I look.
Quina is Hoda. Hoda do not laugh.
Hmm.
- Yahalah!
ALL: Yahalah!
They walked faster and faster
and did not slow down to eat or to rest.
And more spears joined them
with each passing day.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
This word "Yahalah," what does it mean?
They are your words.
"We must bring them down."
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
The great birds have arrived.
Evolet!
Baku, D'Leh is here.
[YELLING]
BAKU:
D'Leh!
Tudu! Tudu!
Tudu!
Tudu, that man with the spear,
he will not give up.
Him with her.
- Ew.
- Maybe the boy is right.
D'Leh cannot fly over water
like they can.
Who would've thought
he could find so many spears?
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
NAKUDU:
This river moves like a snake in the sand.
He says the eye of the snake
rests under the sun...
...and under the moon it does not move.
Is there a shorter way
to the head of the snake?
We must look beyond the great sand.
But no one can walk that far.
The mountains and the sand...
...they all look the same,
and we will lose our way.
We will all die.
We will find the head of the snake.
And we will free our people.
We must rest.
The man from the river
had spoken the truth.
They had walked in circles for many days
and lost their way.
And the eye of the snake
was nowhere to be found.
[GASPING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Tic'Tic, Tic'Tic.
I have found the eye of the snake.
You see that light?
That one? Remember
what the river people said?
It rests under the sun,
but under the moon it does not move.
Nakudu, tell them what I said.
It will guide us to the head of the snake.
And as the last moon had come
to the valley of the Yagahl...
... it seemed that all spirits
had left Old Mother.
She did not eat or speak
for many moons...
... because she knew
there was one last destiny to fulfill.
Wise Spirit...
...it's me, Katan.
[HORN BLOWING]
NAKUDU:
The mountains of the gods.
And the head of the snake.
[GRUNTING]
Evolet. You are well.
Shh. Do not speak.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[BELLOWING]
KA'REN:
Baku, over here.
How can men do such a thing
to Father Mannak?
They are not men like us, Baku.
Then what are they?
Some say they came from the stars.
Others believe that they flew across
the great water...
...when their land sank into the sea.
[HORN BLOWING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
No! Moha!
[YELLING]
Moha!
There are too many of them
for every one of us.
No one can bring them down.
No, D'Leh.
The ones they force to do their work...
...they are even more.
Do you think they will fight with us?
That is for you to find out.
Hmm?
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Ah, D'Leh.
D'Leh.
NAKUDU: Tudu.
D'LEH: Do not be afraid, Baku.
I'll bring you home.
Where is Evolet?
The women sleep in different huts,
but I saw her today.
Tic'Tic is waiting with many spears,
behind the sand.
They killed Moha today.
He was sacrificed.
It was my mistake that put you
in this terrible place.
I need your forgiveness.
The Fathers chose you to lead us...
...and we will stand by your side.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Tell him how many spears we have.
Ask him to fight with us.
He says the number of spear
does not matter.
- Men cannot bring down gods.
- Shh.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
He says the blind man
knows much about the gods.
He was once their servant but ran away.
They have hidden him here ever since.
Wise man...
...tell us more of these gods.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
NAKUDU: First, there were three,
but now there's only one left.
There must be a way to defeat him.
He said, once...
...only once, he heard the god
speak of one he fears.
They have a telling of one
who wears a mark...
...that you can see in the sky at night.
They call it Uru-Anna,
the Mark of the Hunter.
The brightest star of all heaven.
He asks if you wear
the Mark of the Hunter.
[SHOUTING]
Without the mark,
you cannot bring down the god.
[DOOR OPENS]
D'LEH:
Wait, wait. The band on your arm...
...where did you get it?
NAKUDU:
From the man who saved his life.
Where is he?
His bones are buried in the sand
with all the others.
He wants to know why
you ask of this man.
He was my father.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
D'LEH:
Ask him where Tic'Tic is.
[SHOUTS]
D'LEH:
They found us!
[GRUNTING]
I am full with days.
Please, great hunter, do not say that.
We need you.
They will not fight with us.
They have their own prophecy.
D'Leh...
...a prophecy has many faces,
many ways to come true.
Your father...
Your father, he gave this to me.
- No, great hunter, this is yours.
- Take it.
Be as your father.
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CLICKING TONGUE]
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[GROWLING]
NAKUDU:
D'Leh...
...I know how it feels
to lose a good friend.
Your father was mine.
I barely remember him.
He remembered you.
His heart hurt when he spoke of
a young boy behind the Great Mountains.
He was preparing to leave
to go back to you.
That is when he was taken.
D'Leh...
...the men are waiting.
We, the people of the Yagahl...
[NAKUDU SPEAKING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
...hunt the mightiest of beasts,
the Mannak.
He is great and we are small,
and still we bring him down.
Because we hunt together, as one.
When the sun rises...
...we will join our brothers and sisters
on the mountain of the god...
...and convince them to fight with us,
together, as one!
[YELLING]
What is happening?
Listen, Baku,
today you must become a hunter.
Me?
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
D'LEH:
Yahalah.
[HIGH PRIEST WHIMPERING]
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Look, Ka'ren, look.
- That one.
- Him?
Baku, we found the lead bull. Go!
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Now!
Quina, not yet!
[YELLING]
[GRUNTING]
Ha! Ha!
- They will not charge.
- The Mannak have been beaten too long.
Ka'ren, look.
[HORN BLOWING]
You must move everybody up the ramp!
- Move! Move!
- Go! Go!
Ka'ren! No!
[KA'REN YELLING]
[YELLING]
[SCREAMING]
[WHISTLE BLOWS]
[YELLING]
[YELLS]
Yahalah!
- Yahalah!
ALL: Yahalah!
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CHEERING]
Yahalah!
Stop!
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
He says the one who follow this woman
should turn back or she will die.
Like this traitor.
Turn back to your mountains
and you can take your woman.
Tell him I will take his offer.
[CROWD MUTTERING]
Tell him I accept.
Tell him!
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
But I will take all my people with me.
Each and every Yagahl.
Tell him!
They are yours!
Ask him what will happen to the others.
They belong to the god, he says.
They will do his work, forever.
No.
They will not.
He is not a god!
[YELLING]
EVOLET:
D'Leh!
Evolet!
Baku!
Tudu!
No!
[GASPING]
KATAN:
Help! Help! She's bleeding!
[SPEAKS IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[CHEERING]
You came for me.
No, no, please.
Please.
[SOBBING]
To have journeyed so far...
... to have walked to the end
of the world...
... to bring down the one
they called the Almighty...
... only to return without Evolet.
This was not what Old Mother
had foretold.
But just as she was lost to him forever...
... the legend of the child
with the blue eyes began.
[TRUMPETING]
[GASPING]
NAKUDU:
Evolet and D'Leh!
[CHEERING]
Evolet had brought the promise of life
to our people.
And now, with her last breath...
... Old Mother had given it back.
NAKUDU: Your father wanted to
bring these back to you.
They will feed your people.
Tell them the people of the Yagahl
thank the Naku people.
[SPEAKING IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
Thank you, brother Nakudu.
My heart walks with you, brother D'Leh.
That was the last time
they saw their friends the Naku.
And then the long journey home began.
BOY:
They're back! They're back!
[CHATTERING]
And as the ones who walked
with the Fathers...
... looked down on them
and guided their way...
... so the Yagahl looked to Evolet and D'Leh
to guide their people.
And when the first moon was born again
to their valley...
... it brought with it
the first fruits of their land.
Look how fast it is growing.
And so it came to pass
that the promise of life...
... was fulfilled.
Subtitles by LeapinLar