By:
|| killer_sub ||
---
Libyan visa.
Official.
Pull over for inspection.
Sorry, sir, I can't do that.
Pull over for inspection!
How willing are you
to die for your country?
I'm ready to go right here,
right now.
Everybody, this is Jack Silva.
Jack.
He trained SEALs at Coronado,
so he knows the drill.
Welcome to Club Med.
We need immediate assistance!
We are overrun.
- State's under attack!
- Let's go, man! State's under attack!
Let's go, we got to move!
If you do not get here soon,
we are all going to fucking die.
- We have a US Ambassador at risk.
- The Ambassador is in his safe haven.
You're not the first responders.
You're the last resort.
You will wait.
None of you have to go.
But we are the only hope they have.
---
I called for air support.
Never came.
---
You're not giving orders anymore.
You're in my world now.
---
We have 36 American lives to save.
Title