Thy name shall be Abraham, for I will
make thee a father of many nations.
The Book of Genesis, Chapter 17, verse 5.
History prefers legends to men.
It prefers nobility, to brutality.
Soaring speeches to quiet deeds.
History remembers the
battle, and forgets the blood.
Whatever history remembers of me,
if it remembers anything at all...
It shall only be a fraction of the truth.
For whatever else I am, a
husband, a lawyer, a president...
I shall always think of myself as a
man who struggled against darkness.
I leave in your trusted
hands, my dear friend Henry,
this record that begins
when I was just a boy.
Come on there, hurry up!
Get them down there, let's go!
Please sir, no! It's some kind
of a mistake, I ain't no slave.
No! Let them go!
- Go back inside!
Will! - Be quiet!
- He's my friend!
Look away Abraham, it's
not our place. Look away.
Oh my God! Abraham!
Are you alright?
Did you strike my friend here?
- He was beating my son!
Did you strike him, Lincoln?
- They're not slaves, and you know it.
I suggest you get back to your work before
you find yourself led away in chains.
Until every man is free, we are all slaves.
Very well then. Since y'all
are so concerned with freedom,
you may consider yourself free
from the burden of my employ.
Come on, let's go.
- And the debt you've been working off,
I'd like it paid in full,
with interests. Now please.
If you get one more
penny from me, Mr. Barts,
it will come with a fist wrapped around it.
Alright Mr. Lincoln.
There are other ways to collect a debt.
What's happening to her
father?! Please, help her!
You got to do something, father!
Easy child.
- Look away Abraham.
I've never seen anything
like this. Strange.
Promise me...
Let's step outside.
Abraham, come and lay next to me.
I've been writing, mama.
Days are swift as an indian arrow.
Flying like a shooting star.
The present day is here.
Then slides away in haste.
That we can never say is ours.
But only say is past.
Mother?
Mama once told me that I
hadn't cried when I was born.
That I simply opened my eyes,
looked at her smiling face,
and smiled back. My light was gone.
I don't know how he did it...
- Abraham, you promised me.
You promised me you won't
go and do nothing foolish.
Nine years later, my
father joined her in death.
No longer bound by my
promise, I tried to fortify
the nerve to pursue my vengeance.
Haven't you had enough?
A boy only gets this drunk
when he wants to kiss a girl,
or kill a man.
Adam, let me explain.
- Last one Barts.
I'm not coming up here to
clean up your messes any more.
So, where's Henry?
Ah yes, we've been looking all
over sir, searching high and low.
Low is more likely. Just find him Barts.
Oh and, send a fresh crop south,
we have a lot of mouths to feed.
Yes sir.
For my mother.
Well that was unlucky. Might
have put me out of my misery.
Where the hell are you running to?!
Nobody likes chasing chickens.
Little boy all grown up,
come to avenge his dear mama.
There are 2 kinds of men Mr. Lincoln,
those that have the guts to pull
the trigger, and those who do not.
Powder, patch, ball, don't mess it up.
You weren't asleep that night, were you?
You dropped the ball Mr. Lincoln.
Your mama's blood was sickly sweet.
Hope yours taste better!
Might I suggest that we
begin by, closing the door?
Yes, I'm sorry.
I didn't see anything.
Can we dive right in?
Or are you finding
Gabrielle too distracting?
I'm sorry sir but, who are you?
Who I am is Henry Sturges,
where you are is my home.
What has happened...
I saved your life, during your more than
pathetic attempt of taking another's.
What were you doing there and how
did you know I tried to kill Barts?
How? I watched boy carry out
his first long awaited mission,
drunk might I add, and I think you've
waisted your time on this one Henry.
He's not a promising recruit, he is just a
selfish boy with his
heart set on vengeance.
You did not realize that
his boy is a goddamn idiot!
I doubt he even knew
his target was a vampire.
A vampire?
- Yes, immortal, bloodsucking demons.
Fortunately for you Mr. Lincoln,
hunting them is something of a hobby.
Vampires are just myths.
- Myths don't beat you senseless
after you put a bullet
in their brain. Thank you.
No Mr. Lincoln, vampires are
real, they exist in every city,
in every state, in the Union.
If what you say is true,
you could help me kill him,
I could pay you to kill him.
- My services are not for sale.
And word you are looking
for is "destroyed",
it is quite a feat to kill
that which is already dead.
But you don't understand,
my mother was murdered.
And if I teach you how
to murder her murderer,
so what? How will that honor her memory?
How will that benefit the
next boy whose mother is taken?
If vengeance is all you
seek, seek it elsewhere.
Teach me to fight as you do,
please, I'll do anything you say.
You promise to cast aside
all notions of vengeance?
And commit to the life of a hunter?
You will have no friends, no family.
I told him what he wanted to
hear, but all I cared about
was killing the monster
that took my mother.
I'm in.
Clearly you don't hate him that much.
Tell me what you hate.
I hate that my mother was taken away.
Inadequate.
- I hate that we were afraid.
And? - That my mother, father,
everyone that we knew lived in fear.
Pathetic.
- I hate that I was too small.
Too weak.
- Yes.
And that you failed, to protect her.
- Yes!
And that you let her die.
Power Lincoln, real power
comes not from hate, but from truth.
Before you can protect others from darkness,
you must first be able to protect yourself.
Your enemies have the power
to render themselves invisible.
You must have the ability to
fight blind, to see without seeing.
Again.
In the weeks that
followed, Henry endeavored
to impart a lifetime of
vampire hunting secrets.
Their ability to adapt to sunlight, the
power to render themselves invisible.
But most of all, he taught
me how to destroy them.
When Judas betrayed Jesus, his
reward was 30 pieces of silver.
At that moment those pieces became
the symbol of betraying God, of evil.
And silver became a curse, upon the cursed.
You'll never see a vampire
with silver on his person.
You'll not see them reflected in mirrors.
The one thing God placed
beyond the reach of a vampire.
The one thing he can never poses, and
the only thing that renders him powerless.
Henry it's Jack Barts...
I give you the targets, that was our deal.
This is not only about Jack Barts.
Vadoma, ruthless enforcer.
And her brother.
- Wait, I've seen him before,
I saw him with Jack Barts.
- They call him Adam.
He from whom all others are made.
Vampires have been in the
new world for centuries.
Slaughtering native
tribes, and early settlers.
But when the Europeans
arrived with their slaves,
the dead saw a sinister opportunity.
They built an empire in the south.
In recent years they pressed
north, leaving death in their wake.
It falls to us Abraham, the hunters,
to keep the balance, to ensure
that this remains a nation of men.
And not monsters.
What we do, we do not for one man,
but for the good of all mankind.
Henry sent me off into
the world with a reminder.
No attachments, no distractions,
no friends or family.
Besides, who could I
trust? Anyone in this well
mannered city might
very well be one of them.
You son of a bitch!
If I ever see you here again I will
have your balls as a coin purse!
I will get you! I'll get you some day!
Good afternoon sir, Joshua
Speed at your service.
Abraham, Lincoln.
I need a bit of help.
- Alright.
A friend in need, is a friend
of Speed, what can I get for you?
I don't suppose you know of
any rooms for rent, Mr. Speed?
What sort of a room are you
looking for, Mr. Lincoln?
Cheap one, as I've spent all of my money on
law books have none to spare at the moment.
As you say you have none, am I to take
your meaning as cheap or free of charge?
On credit. - All the same, I don't think
you'll find such a room in Springfield,
people here are strangely
accustomed of being compensated.
Good day.
There is one room, Mr. Lincoln.
I was recently forced to part ways
with a thieving prick of an associate,
and am therefor in need of a replacement.
There's a room upstairs, it isn't much
but, I suppose it could be had on credit.
If you intend or are willing
to work here in return.
Dear Henry, life in Springfield
is less than desirous.
Fear not, my pittance of a salary doesn't
allow me to deviate from your rules.
No friends, no family.
And certainly no woman would
find me and my existence enticing.
Excuse me?
Excuse me, I'll be needing these.
- Just one second ma'am.
Well, you needn't call me ma'am
as if I'm some haggard spinster.
I'm sorry ma'am...
I mean, miss.
I'm Abraham, Lincoln.
Mary Todd.
Darling, there you are.
You mustn't clip from
store to store so quickly.
Perhaps if you didn't stop for jaw
with every gentleman in Springfield...
I could say the same for you.
Steven Douglas, how do you do.
- Abraham Lincoln.
Are you a voting man Mr. Lincoln?
How do you feel about keeping slavery out
of Illinois I'm running for the legislature.
I'm sure he'd love to
hear your campaign speech,
but Mr. Lincoln was just
about to attend to my list.
We were talking dear, slavery,
it's a complicated issue.
I couldn't disagree with
you more Mr. Douglas.
Mr. Douglas, miss Todd, you met my new
associate Abraham, a letter came for you.
Dear Abe, your prescription
awaits you at the local pharmacy.
Ask for Aaron Stibble, jr.
Mr. Lincoln?
I'm so sorry.
Good day work, Abraham.
- Thank you.
But don't forget.
Always have a contingency plan.
Aaron Stibble junior?
- Yes?
Don't worry, it'll only
hurt for a second or two.
Did you eat today?
I had killed a monster,
and I would kill again.
But no amount of death
could make me forget.
Merciful Christ Lincoln,
what happened to your face?
I'm alright, I'll still be able to work.
- Work? To hell with work.
We got invited to a ball.
Could be your chance to save
Mary Todd from a life of boredom.
This suit makes me look ridiculous.
- Nonsense,
but that hat makes you
look ridiculous, come on.
There she is. Mr. Douglas,
Joshua Speed, nice to see you.
Marry you look lovely as usual.
He is still missing.
- Who is that?
Aaron Stibble.
- Junior or senior?
Junior.
Who is that man?
- I don't know.
Mr. Douglas, you know
senator Nolan of course?
Ah yes, Steven good to see you.
- Have you heard the news?
We're looking into it. Rest
assured, this kind of lawlessness
won't stand in the noble state of Illinois.
It's called a dance.
If we were meant to sit alone they
would have called it something else.
Yes, I suppose they would have.
Come Mr. Lincoln, you'll ruin
upholstery if you sit there any longer.
I'm sure you're a very nice
man Mr. Lincoln, but you're a...
A shop keeper in a borrowed suit.
No, it's not a matter of means, really, no.
Actually I'm looking for someone different,
someone whose life is a bit
more, adventurous, and well...
My apologies, I'm never this...
- Honest? - Rude.
Miss Todd, may I speak candid?
I too came here to better myself,
That's why I've taken an interest in
the law and why, if I may be so bold,
I've taken an interest in you.
And as for the adventure that you seek,
I suspect that few men could
ever hope to provide that for you.
Least of all your fiancee, Steven Douglas.
Mr. Lincoln, you are full of surprises.
Miss Todd, you have no idea.
Dear Abraham, I've made a
deposit at the local bank.
Be careful, it can quickly disappear.
Henry, there are more than
I ever thought possible.
Pharmacists, inn keepers, pastors...
That's more than a man can bear.
Well, I see I'm such interesting company.
- I'm sorry.
I've been working nights.
Really? Is that true?
Do you really want to know the truth, Mary?
Each and every night, I go out.
Hunting vampires.
Well, how do you hunt these vampires?
With an axe, special silver axe, of course.
Of course.
And how many would you
reckon you've killed?
Five, no, six.
I've killed six vampires.
My goodness.
Abe.
You, here I thought you
were a honest man, really.
I had a wonderful day, Abe.
- As did I, Mary.
Miss Todd, you are a woman
of ravishing resourcefulness.
Mr. Lincoln, you have no idea.
You have no friends, no family.
I should be going, it's late.
How could I bring her into this world?
A world of demons, of danger?
Good night then, Lincoln.
- Good night, Mary.
Happy hunting.
If I truly cared for her,
the kindest thing I could do,
was walk away.
This, hunter, is another
of Henry's disciples?
They say he's a madman.
I can't wait to meet him.
Stock boy reading a law book.
What, studying to be a lawyer?
As a matter of fact, I am.
Alright, what about a little test? What's
the law for free slaves in the north?
According to the Fugitive
Slave Act of 1793,
enforcing article 4, section 2
of the United States Constitution,
all runaway slaves must be
returned to their owners.
However, Personal Liberty law
states that anyone who was born free
can not be taken under this act.
- I heard a good woman once say,
"Until all men are free, we're all slaves".
Will? Will Johnson?!
How did you...
- I was back home.
Heard you moved here,
studying to be a lawyer.
That's good, I'm in need of a good lawyer.
- Are you in some kind of trouble?
I was freeing slaves down
south on the rail road,
hoping to find my brother down there.
Some bounty hunters got after
me, said I was a runaway.
I need a writ Abe, saying I was born free.
You know Will, come on.
Speed, this is Will Johnson,
my oldest friend in the world.
Store isn't gonna run itself Abe.
I'll have him back as soon as
possible, Mr. Speed, I promise.
You're getting tall Abe, look
you still don't eat much either.
Still afraid of the dark too?
- Not so much anymore.
That's him Abe, that's the
guy that's been chasing me.
Gentlemen, gentlemen I'm
sure we can work this out.
I suggest you walk away son.
- No sir, I suggest you do.
I've sent word to senator
Nolan, I'll have you out soon.
You're far too kind Miss Todd.
And he's far too ugly
to have a woman like you.
I think that common looking
people are the best in the world.
That's why the Lord makes so many of them.
I just thank God he was there.
I won't always be there, Mary.
What if something was going
on, something terrible...
And you knew that there was no way
on Earth that one man could stop it?
What would you do?
I wouldn't back away from what's
right, just because it's hard.
My father used to say: "Plant
your feet, and stand firm."
The only question is
where to put your feet.
We may fail in this fight, we may only
shatter trankful veil of oppression,
but we must not be detoured!
For ours is a just and noble
cause, the cause of freedom,
the very cause upon which our founding
fathers built this great nation.
Voice like that, it's too
strong to be stuck keeping shop.
I'm actually studying to be a lawyer.
Mr. Lincoln, maybe it's time
you thought about politics.
I can connect you with the right people.
- Thank you senator Nolan.
A pleasure, young man. - Same.
- You're on your way, Mr. Lincoln.
I sent you to Springfield to
hunt vampires, not to chase votes.
Lesson 1: Always have a contingency plan.
If vampire hunting doesn't pan out,
I'll need a career to fall back on.
I'm being serious.
- So am I, Henry.
I have done everything you've asked of me.
Every letter, every name, but
never the letter I wait for,
and never the name I want most.
When do I get to kill Jack Barts?
Barts knows about Mary, it's time.
Abraham.
Be careful.
Abraham fucking Lincoln...
Miss again!
Hope you're better with an
axe than you were with a gun!
Come on Lincoln!
Catch me before I get to Mary!
Catch me if you can boy!
There's thousands of us here...
He won't stop until this
whole country is ours.
They're coming for you
now, ask your friend, Henry.
Shut your mouth you stupid whore, give me
what I'm here for or
I'll knock your teeth out!
You lying son of a bitch.
Goddammit!
No Abe! Stop!
You weren't ready to know.
- What, that you are a vampire?!
You are not the only one who
has lost everything to vampires.
Just because the carriage stops,
doesn't mean we have to.
Get in the carriage.
Take this. Run, just run.
Her soul is pure.
But yours, Henry...
It's one of God's little tricks.
Vampires cannot kill their own kind.
Only the living can kill the dead.
Welcome to the family.
You can't save the world and the ones you
love, Lincoln. You need to make a choice.
I'm sorry. But goodbye.
Abe?!
- Mary?!
What on earth are you doing?
- Come on in.
What are you hiding?
- Nothing. - Abe?
It's nothing.
- Abe I know when you're lying.
What are you hiding from me?
- Alright.
I didn't want to tell you this way,
this is not the way that I planned it.
But if you really must know...
Mary Todd...
Will you make me the happiest of men?
And do you, Abraham, promise to love
her, comfort her, be honorable and honest
with her in all things, in sickness
and health, 'till death do you part?
I do.
Then by the power vested in me by almighty
God, and the great state of Illinois,
I now pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Your mother would be so proud.
- Thank you, Will.
I'm happy you could be here,
you're the only family I have.
Except for this one.
- Congratulations.
May I introduce, Mr.
Henry Sturges, my wife
Mary, and my dear friend Will Johnson.
Heavens Mr. Sturges, you're
as chilly as the winter wind.
Henry please. I'm afraid that's the
hazard of carrying one's own bottle.
You know what they say, cold hands
warm heart. - I highly doubt that.
Mr. Sturges is a business associate. - And
I thought we could talk a little business.
Of course, excuse me.
What the hell are you doing here?
- Be cautious Abraham,
one forgets how easily we can
lose the most precious things.
They don't even know, who I am.
Go up river, and invite this,
Mr. Lincoln, to join
us at the plantation.
We're gonna throw a ball in his honor.
What makes you think he'll accept?
I think we can find a way to tempt him.
Abe, we got a problem.
They took Will.
What are you gonna do?
- I'm gonna accept his invitation.
Speed deserved to know to truth
what we were about to face.
I told him everything, not
knowing if he would believe me
or think me mad, not knowing
if he would have the courage
to face the monsters that
I had come to know.
You and me Abraham, together
we can accomplish anything.
NEW ORLEANS
There are no slaves, where are they?
I was just wondering that.
Something isn't right about this, Abe.
- Yeah.
I don't know how to dance.
- Don't worry, I'll teach you.
Wait here.
Ladies and gentlemen, dinner is served.
Bravo, Mr. Lincoln. Bravo.
Even better than I'd heard.
Shame to sacrifice so many of my best men,
I needed to know if you were up to the task.
What do you want with me?
- To see you liberated.
To see you rise up and
destroy your oppressor.
That's interesting advice,
coming from a slave owner.
Man have enslaved each other since they
invented gods to forgive them for doing it.
I have seen Jews build Egypt's glory.
Seen Christians thrown
to lions with my own eyes.
And I have seen Africans sell
their own kind to Europeans.
May I share, one of the
revelations of my 5.000 years?
We are all slaves to something.
I to eternity, you to your convictions,
others to the colour of their skin.
All I ever wanted was to see my
kind granted their rightful place.
But there are those of us,
those like your friend Henry,
who enjoy living in the dark.
As you're doubtless aware, I cannot
personally destroy him, nor he I.
You, Mr. Lincoln,
you could eliminate those
last pockets of resistance
beginning with Henry Sturges himself.
All I ask...
Is for you to break your chains.
Kill your master, be free.
And if I refuse?
Then you can go on your merry way.
After I make you one of us.
And spoon feed you your friend.
Simple yes or no will suffice.
Kill Henry, save your friend.
Feel free to take your time to decide, 5...
4, 3,
2, 1.
Come on!
This way!
Miss Tubman, we've been waiting for you.
Come quickly.
People getting killed every
day, slaves disappearing,
some people talk abut monsters and demons.
Good morning, how can I assist
you on this beautiful day?
We're looking for three men.
You know, I did see
someone ride down that way.
You're welcome to come in if you'd
like, my service is about to begin.
I take it y'all came from up north?
- Yes ma'am.
I suggest you get back
there as fast as you can.
There's a war coming, a war
for the soul of the country.
Gonna be all colors of blood spilled.
Their labor, their blood! More blood
than you could possibly imagine!
I have seen this horror
of the south, first hand.
I say the need for peace
outweighs the needs of the blacks,
I say that if the people of
this great nation want slavery,
then let them have it. - The demon of
slavery is tearing our country apart.
We must stand up, we must
stand strong and fight,
fight for the very soul of our nation
Until every man is free, we are all slaves!
You cannot take on slavery, Abraham!
You cannot take on the whole south!
- Why? Because of Adam?
No.
- Are you afraid of him?
Because it is the only thing that has
kept them satiated for all these years.
And you take that away,
then no one is safe.
So you get to choose
who lives and who dies.
A great man once said,
what we do, we do not for
ourselves, not for one man,
but for the good of all mankind!
Not all mankind, Abraham!
- Abe?
May I have my husband back?
He is all yours, Mrs. Lincoln.
Henry only saw the struggle his way.
But I began at last to see it another.
To see and to feel the
even grater issues at stake.
So he and I would go our separate ways.
As the Bible says, the time had come
for me to put aside childish things.
I would fight not with an
axe, but with words and ideals.
For a time, they proved a stronger weapon.
In compliance with a custom as
old as the Government itself...
I appear before you to to take in
your presence the oath prescribed...
by the Constitution of the United States,
to be taken by the President "before he
enters on the execution of this office."
The question of slavery is better
settled with a pen than with a sword!
Through twists of fate, I
found myself at 50 years of age,
a father of a nation, that
was tearing itself apart.
While trying to be the father to a boy, not
much older than I was when I lost my mother.
Three thousand more, dead.
When was the last time you had something
to eat? - Not hungry, thank you.
You got to eat Abe, you're only human.
Come along, Willie.
Willie?
Brother?
If you do this, there
is no turning back, Abe.
I know.
I'm trying to protect
the freedom of a nation.
If this war is truly a stand against evil,
then let it stand for something.
If it is a war for the freedom of men,
why not give all men a reason to fight it?!
All persons held as slaves, within any
State or designated part of a State,
the people whereof shall be in rebellion
against the United States shall be then...
Thenceforward shall be, free.
Morning.
Precious little one.
What's your name?
- Willie.
And your father, what's his?
- Abraham.
How is our little soldier faring?
I've never seen anything
like it. I'm sorry.
I don't know what else to do.
Abe...
Mary's calling for you.
I'm so sorry Abraham.
Why didn't they take me?
- Because they know.
It is a fate much worse than death.
Mary...
Is inconsolable.
She says she doesn't
want to go on without him.
There is a way Abraham, you
know that I can restore the dead.
Do it.
- Mary?
That journal, the one you always
kept in your coat pocket...
I know I shouldn't have Abe, but I
needed to know what you were hiding.
If what you say is true, I beg you...
Give us our little boy back.
Mary, he wouldn't be our little boy.
He would be something
else, something terrible.
Trust me, you don't want that.
- You're asking me to trust you,
after you lied to me for all these years?!
I did it to protect you,
to protect our family.
And how did that work out?!
You did this Abe!
You did this! You brought this on
him! You brought this on our boy!
Let me go to them, make a truce with Adam.
We must stop this war, Willie's
death is just the beginning.
Don't you dare say his name.
- I warned you.
You didn't heed me. How many more boys
will have to die before you listen to me?
These boys are dying in vein.
We should pull the troops back.
Abraham, this war has cost us countless
lives, not to mention millions of dollars.
I thought we were gonna make this
country great, not tear it apart.
This is the only way we can
save the country now, Speed.
Send in troops.
Union troops are flooding onto the field.
We are now outnumbered, and
ill-equipped compared to the North.
We'll support you, but you
will need to support us.
No, thank you.
Rest assured, Mr. Davis.
You'll have as many of my kind as you need.
Fire!
Ready!
Aim!
Here they come!
Fire!
Why did they drop their rifles?!
The first day of Gettysburg.
It's been a disaster. I don't
think the army can survive another.
If the rebels break through
they'll be here, in days.
Generals think we should
evacuate Washington,
run north for New York
or Boston if need be.
You have to win this war.
If you don't then all of it...
Then our son's death will have been for
nothing. - How can I win a war,
when I can't even protect my own family?
Our men have no way of defending
themselves against this enemy.
When our bullets are useless, our
bayonets are as powerless as this fork!
This...
Will! Speed!
This, this is what me need.
A fork.
- Silver.
OK, how much do we need?
All of it.
And why are telling me this, Mr.
Speed? Why betray your friend?
He is my friend, but I
love this country even more.
And he, more than anyone, is responsible
for tearing this nation apart.
You've done the right thing.
I know.
32, 33, 34, 35...
That is a lot of silver Abe.
But how are we gonna get all this there?
I'm sorry, Mary.
I'm sorry I've kept you in
the dark all these years.
I need you Mary.
I've waited a long time to
hear you say those words.
I want you to leave Washington, Mary.
Evelyn, please have some tea.
I very much appreciate you
coming to speak with me today.
Things have not been easy with my...
The death of my son and the war...
I need to get out of Washington,
and I need a lot of help.
This war, ends tonight.
And with it, our millennium of darkness.
We have to do this on our own, no
one can know what's on that train.
If we don't get those weapons
to those boys as Gettysburg,
war is over.
It's time we had a nation of our own.
Come.
We have a train to catch.
It's 80 miles from here to Gettysburg.
80 miles will decide whether this
nation belongs to the living,
or the dead.
Is everything alright Speed?
I just can't believe you're
still writing in that book.
It's all in here Speed, good with the bad.
What's this?
- They're fleeing the nest,
leaving Washington free for us.
Look at me.
I said, look at me.
- Leave her, don't want to miss this train.
Henry, what the hell are you doing here?
I just wanted to see how far
your foolishness would take you.
I don't have time to argue.
- I didn't come here to argue with you.
I came here to tell you that
your dear friend Speed back there,
is a traitor.
He betrayed you Abe, Speed is leading..
You have no idea what you're talking about.
Well, that's all according to plan.
They're here Abe. A whole heap of them.
We can't let them stop this train.
- You go through there and you're dead!
Get out now, it's your last chance.
You loaded that thing?
We gotta come away from the locomotive.
Why don't you let him go, Lincoln?
Emancipate yourselves.
I'll never follow you.
- You don't have to follow me Abe.
I have the train, I have your silver.
Soon I'll have the whole country.
I'm gonna destroy a
myth of Abraham Lincoln,
so that history will forever know
you not as a man, but as a monster!
Lincoln set us up.
We've been tricked, Adam.
There is no silver on this train.
Abe!
Hello, Speed. Where's the silver?
Silver? It should be here.
Why did you lie to me?!
Get you all on one place, to finish you.
- Speed?!
No!
Mr. President!
You have nowhere left to run, Lincoln!
Where is it?! Where's the silver?!
Right here!
Thank you Henry.
I suppose some vampires can be trusted.
As can some men, Abraham.
If the train was a decoy,
where is the silver?
This isn't the only rail road.
A wise man once taught me,
always have a contingency plan.
Bayonets, bayonets for Springfield muskets.
Springfield muskets!
Fire!
Four score and seven years ago,
our fathers brought forth on
this continent a new nation,
conceived in liberty, and
dedicated to the proposition
that all men are created equal.
Now we are engaged in a great civil war,
testing whether that nation, or any nation,
so conceived and so
dedicated, can long endure.
It is for us the living, rather, to be
dedicated here to the unfinished work
which they who fought here
have thus far so nobly advanced.
It is rather for us to be here dedicated
to the great task remaining before us
that from these honored dead we
take increased devotion to that cause
for which they gave the last
full measure of devotion,
that we here highly resolve that
these dead shall not have died in vain,
that this nation, under God,
shall have a new birth of freedom,
and that government of the people,
by the people, for the people,
shall not perish from the earth.
Our enemies have made their exodus.
Some back to Europe, some to
South America and the Orient.
They've seen that America shall
forever be a nation of living men,
a nation of free men.
We make rather a good team, you and I.
One can't help but think of all the
good we could do if we had more time.
Limitless time.
- Yes well, time waits for no man.
We're gonna be late for the theatre.
Hold on to this for me, Henry.
Mary, darling, have you seen my hat?
On your desk, in the office.
Have you seen my hat?
- Abraham, let me make you immortal.
Let us fight through
the ages, side by side.
Vampires are not the only
things that live forever.
History prefers legends to men.
It prefers nobility, to brutality.
Soaring speeches to quiet deeds.
History remembers the
battle, and forgets the blood.
However history remembers of
me, if it does at all...
It shall only remember,
a fraction of the truth.
One more.
A guy only gets that drunk when he
wants to kiss a girl or kill a man.
So which is it?
Subtitle by: Sentinel