Don't give up.
Oh, I never do.
May I?
You work with your hands?
- Redhead.
- Luther.
Your life would be a whole lot simpler
if you could learn to operate a VCR.
True. Truer words were never spoken.
What's that?
Here we go.
That is nice.
It's okay. He's not here.
Anyway, I told him that I was sick.
So you can relax.
I'll be right back.
You like that? Do you?
Oh, yeah.
So you wanna play, huh?
You okay?
How would you like that?
- You slap...
- Don't slap me!
You little bitch!
Alan, what are you doing?
Alan!
Alan, you're hurting me!
I'll hurt you, goddamn it.
You're hurting me!
Goddamn you!
You wanna be hurt?
I'll hurt you.
You like this?
- Let go!
- Do you?
You like that?
Goddamn you!
- Son of a bitch!
- Get away!
Get back here.
Get back here!
Stop it!
Stop it! Alan!
What are you doing?
Bitch...
...you wanna play?
I'll show you how.
You fucking bastard!
You bastard!
You like that?
- Come back.
- Don't!
Let go of me!
Bitch, you cut me, goddamn it!
Fucking asshole!
I'm gonna kill you!
Help! Help!
Help!
Did you kill her?
No choice in the matter, sir.
What am I gonna do?
- Jesus, Tim. What do we do?
- No choice in the matter.
What the hell was that?
Oh, shit.
Oh, my God.
Do you realize
what a shitstorm we're in?
Go on, tell me.
Nothing to tell.
He screamed for help.
You heard no sounds
of violence till then?
Nothing we haven't heard before.
- Maybe I should call the police.
- Oh, Jesus. What?
Bill...
...why don't you think about that.
Just take a second...
...and think about that.
Think real...
...fucking...
...hard.
Probably not a good idea.
Here's what happened.
Poor Christy...
...came home alone
and interrupted a burglary.
Sound logical?
Yeah, sure.
We have to sanitize this place.
Alan.
Did you have sex with her?
I don't know.
Bill, you're gonna have
to examine her.
- I'm no gynecologist.
- I just made you one.
Christ!
I'll take that.
- It has both fingerprints.
- Thanks for sharing.
Gloria.
- Did I kill her?
- Everything's gonna be fine, Alan.
Don't worry about it.
- Oh, God.
- Now be careful.
Just don't get blood on you.
I'll take care of everything, okay?
Just like I always do.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
Madame's purse.
- Miss Russell, let me get him.
- Thank you.
- I got him.
- All right.
Nice and easy, sir.
Oh, my God!
No knife!
- What?
- Where's the knife?
In the bedroom.
- Come on.
- Get up there!
Shit!
Go!
Excuse me.
I got the number.
Gee, guys, maybe it was the bogeyman.
Check under the bed.
You may have buried us!
I got his license number.
You think he'll sit around
waiting for us?
Look, take it easy.
Everybody, shut up, all right?
What have you got?
Oh, boy.
Two-way mirror.
We better get cracking
on that license number.
That's all we've got.
He's got the letter opener.
Blood...
...fingerprints.
Jesus!
Think what he can do.
The man's a thief.
A thief who witnessed a murder.
It looks like he stole
a whole bunch of money.
I'll tell you what he's gonna do.
He's gonna run like hell.
They beat us by seven.
By seven?
Who'd have thought that?
Kate.
I guess it'd be a little late for me.
The jogging, I mean.
Kind of dumb way to start.
But I did want to talk to you.
About?
The weather, actually.
It's getting cool in the evenings.
That happens this time of year.
I was thinking...
...of moving to a kinder,
more gentle climate.
I thought I'd talk with you,
since you're the only family I have.
Luther, you don't have me.
You know what it's like
to be the only kid...
...who got to talk about visiting day?
This move, it would be
a permanent one, you understand.
We never see each other anyway.
We haven't since Mom died.
That's a year.
Look, you chose your life.
You had that right.
You were never around for me. Fine.
I have no plans to be around for you.
Wait a minute. Wait.
You're lying, aren't you?
Are you active again?
Is that why you're here now?
I don't believe you.
Oh, Christ!
Father, what have you done?
Christy Sullivan?
Wife of Walter.
Most likely came home,
stumbled onto a burglary.
Some burglary.
I wish my carpets were this clean.
I couldn't find
a single fingerprint.
- Are you serious, Laura?
- It's like Mary Poppins was here.
Where's Mr. Sullivan?
Sorry, Seth.
The entire Sullivan household went
to Barbados two days ago.
Thanks for your support.
Oh, no, wait. It gets worse.
The shots came from here.
If she stumbled on a burglary,
she should've been here.
But she was killed
exactly where she is.
See, the blood patterns indicate that.
What is she doing here?
Looks like someone sat here,
but I couldn't find any prints.
So you think old man Sullivan
holed up in this chair...
...and watched his wife perform?
God, I hope not.
For his sake.
You know, he's such a great man.
Be careful digging that out.
Looks like he tried to strangle her.
Then he went to the door
to shoot her from behind?
He also inspected her vagina.
He did what?
Why?
Maybe he didn't remember
that he did her.
A strong burglar with a weak mind.
Obviously, it's another
open-and-shut case.
We can expect
tomorrow's temperatures...
... to climb into the 70s
with lows around 50.
Turner will start things off
for the Cougars.
- One man to beat.
- He's going all the way!
Nothing but clear sailing now.
Six points!
Mr. Sullivan.
Sorry to bother you.
I'm Seth Frank, senior homicide
detective, Middletown County.
My client is in no mood
for conversations.
It's all right, Sandy.
You're in charge of the case?
Yes, sir.
I've gotta ask you a few questions.
What do you want?
Positive identification?
Yes...
...that was my wife.
Anything else?
You'd been in Barbados for two days.
I took the staff,
always do this time of year.
Your wife didn't come with you.
Well, she was.
Had it all planned.
But you know women.
She changed her mind.
I'd been married
to my Rebecca for 47 years.
When she died...
...I decided I never wanted
that pain again.
One thing I knew about Christy...
...she was going to outlive me.
I think that's enough for today.
Sir, I have to ask you
about the vault.
You mean, the contents
of the vault, of course.
Sandy, you go on.
- Walter.
- No, really.
I'm all right.
You go on to the reception.
Obviously, I can't make it.
I'm sure everyone will understand.
You don't mean the contents.
You mean the chair.
You must ask about the chair.
Yes, sir. I do.
Why? Are they connected?
Someone sat in it and may have
been involved in the murder.
I have the deepest respect for you.
I'm sorry to have to do this.
I promise you, none of this
will make my highlight reel.
Well, I hoped I could satisfy her.
But, you know...
...she had needs.
She didn't want to go
behind my back.
She suggested the chair.
She hoped I might get
to like sitting there.
I didn't.
For 80 years, I've tried to live...
...a decent life.
I've given a billion dollars
to charity.
If this comes to trial...
...none of that will be remembered.
I'll just go out...
...the joke of the world.
I understand, sir.
I'll do what I can.
Would you listen to me whine?
I apologize, Mr. Frank.
Just do your job
and I'll try to do mine.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen, the President.
Sandy.
Mr. President.
- Take a walk with me.
- Certainly, sir.
Tell me about Walter. How is he?
Well, he's 80 and alone, Mr. President.
He understands that
officially my hands are tied.
Yes, but he's very moved
by your concern, sir.
Any news of the killer?
Why isn't there?
Who's in charge of this?
The top man.
He spent eight years,
homicide work in New York.
I understand how you feel.
It's hard to be patient.
No one understands how I feel.
I'm supposed to have all this power...
...and I can't even help
my oldest friend.
You and I know, more than any man alive,
Walter Sullivan put me here.
Now when he needs me most...
Well, he must feel abandoned.
I'll have a press conference.
I'll have Walter come and
I'll embrace him in front of the world.
He'll treasure that.
What a generous gesture.
Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Tennis elbow.
This is getting worse, Gloria.
I need to see a doctor.
The country would have
to be informed, Mr. President.
What happened to my rights to privacy?
I think she nicked a tendon.
Burton says it's a flesh wound.
Since when did you
become an expert, Bill?
You ever been wounded?
Yes, sir. A few times.
You're serious about
this press conference?
Of course I am.
Walter's like a father to me.
Shall I bring Mrs. Richmond home?
I don't think
Mrs. Richmond's mission...
...to help the poor in Asia
needs to be interrupted.
What do we know so far?
We've checked his license plates.
He stole the car from
a police impoundment lot.
We're not dealing
with a fool, are we?
Has he initiated contact?
Burton doesn't think he will.
I agree.
I apologize for my behavior.
Consider it a blip on the screen.
As far as I'm concerned,
that's all he is.
He could be a little more
than that, Alan.
He saw.
He saw nothing. He saw a drunk woman
who liked rough sex too much.
He's a burglar.
Who's gonna believe him?
After all, it's not as if
he has any evidence.
He's a burglar.
Who 's gonna believe him?
After all, it's not as if
he has any evidence.
Boy, you always did
disappear good, Luther.
You're trying to say
I have a weak face?
No, I'm saying you're lucky.
Some customers, no matter
what I do, still stand out.
How many passports you want?
Four ought to do the trick.
You want different looks, matching
international driver's licenses.
I'll throw in dummy credit cards.
How are the rugs I made you
holding up?
Good. The mustaches
and the beards also.
We try to give quality
for our money.
You leaving the country for permanent?
That could be.
Does it matter where you've been?
I hate doing Asian passport stamps.
No. Make it European.
Caribbean in the wintertime.
How long is all this gonna take?
It usually takes time.
For you, I'll rush it.
You're always dependable, Valerie.
Listen, Luther...
...I don't wanna know
what you're into.
I do, but I'm not gonna ask you.
But leaving the country forever...
What is it?
I never figured you for a runner.
Thirty percent of my runners
kill themselves within five years.
Right now, five years
doesn't sound too bad.
Take care.
See you.
Okay, see if this makes any sense.
I am Christy Sullivan.
I come in and I surprise a burglar.
Okay, now you're the surprised burglar
coming from the vault.
Gold star. I draw my gun. Boom.
Then why strangle her
when you could just shoot her?
Why do I bother to strip her
and put her clothes back on?
There, I can help you out.
You used to be a dry cleaner
and you love beautiful clothes.
Thanks a lot.
And you dress her because...
She was a good customer and you didn't
want her embarrassed when police came.
She had a 0.21 blood-alcohol level.
Not that it matters.
She didn't drive.
The chauffeurs, they keep
exact mileage on these cars.
They haven't been driven
since they went to Barbados.
I checked every cab
and limo service in the area.
Somebody drove her home. Who?
Why haven't they come forward?
Maybe because whoever drove her
home killed her.
Maybe.
I love this case.
Lieutenant?
Sorry to bother you,
but the phone problems?
- I took care of them.
- Thanks.
Just part of the job.
I hate people who say that.
It is your fucking job.
Remember the bullet hole
in the wall?
Guess what?
No slug.
Why take a slug out of the wall
when there's one stuck in her head?
Different from the one in her body?
Two different guns means two burglars.
Two guys broke in?
They both went out the window?
Bullshit.
By the way...
...why did he or they
go out the window anyway...
...when he or they got in by breaking
a zillion dollar security system?
Bill Burton from Secret Service
in the parking lot.
Thanks, Bob.
What's he doing in the parking lot?
Bill Burton. Hi.
Hi. Seth Frank.
To what do I owe the honor?
You must be going crazy...
...but the boss is interested
about your progress.
Maybe we could help each other.
What do you have in mind?
Well, you know how close
he and Sullivan are, right?
The minute anything breaks...
...I'll tell the President.
He'd be the first
to alert Mr. Sullivan.
It'd mean a lot to him.
Any red tape you want cut, done.
Here's my numbers.
Any leads?
We're still figuring out
what happened.
- I love playing Sherlock Holmes.
- You guys do that?
I was a state trooper
before the government got me.
Wait. You're that Bill Burton?
- I was younger and dumber then.
- I was younger. I'm dumber now.
Keep in touch.
My chef makes them especially for me.
I promise you, they're sinful.
You're a salesman, Mr. Sullivan.
This is a new arena for me.
But from what I'm told,
you have a flawless reputation.
Which is why I need to employ you,
Mr. McCarty.
Understood.
I don't know who it is I'm after yet.
Until I do...
...you wait in Washington
for instructions.
That's out of the question.
Mine is not creative work.
I do it because I enjoy
living beyond my means.
I can't afford to sit around.
My father died
when I was 10 years old.
He was a miner.
He died of lung disease.
I became rich at 25.
The first thing I did was buy
that mine, close it down...
...and give every miner
$50,000 to retire on.
You will wait in Washington,
Mr. McCarty.
And I will put
one million dollars' expenses...
...in a Swiss bank of your choosing.
And when the time comes...
...2 million dollars a bullet.
You are a salesman, sir.
Selling sin is easy.
- Who is he?
- It's Luther Whitney...
...one of the great thieves
of the world.
I've been going nuts.
I was up all night.
I remembered your notion
how it was two burglars.
Around dawn, I thought,
"What if it's not two burglars...
...but just one guy trying
to make it look like two?"
I called my buddy at the Bureau.
They keep track.
There's only half a dozen guys
who could've done the Sullivan job.
I've been tracing all six.
Whitney's the only guy
that lives here.
- Why haven't I ever heard of him?
- He hasn't been arrested in 30 years.
What's this? His graduation
picture from Harvard?
That's history.
He was just a punk, part of a gang.
Three-time loser.
Since he got out last...
...no one's touched him.
When something big comes up,
they question him, but nothing sticks.
Oh, Seth.
We can make this stick.
I bet you he's our guy.
He's a local.
You can't ask for anything more.
Well, we got a problem.
What?
He hasn't killed anyone in 45 years.
Korea.
So what? He's a veteran.
Not just a veteran,
he's a wounded veteran.
I got his war record here.
Battles, commendations,
decorations up the kazoo.
He lives alone on disability.
That's what he says anyway.
But I don't see him as a killer.
He's just a great thief.
And besides, I don't do war heroes.
Boy, you must be smart.
Pardon me?
It usually takes you guys
a week to get to me.
Oh, Seth Frank.
I recognize your picture
from the newspaper.
Luther Whitney.
Nice to meet you.
Would you like a signed confession now
or do you want coffee first?
Before I send you away for life,
I should probably check out your alibi.
I was watching a football game
with an old friend, Red Bransford.
He owns a saloon here in town.
You can ask me about the game.
I could be lying.
You been following the case?
Yeah, I have.
I love true crime.
FBI says there's only a few guys
who could have handled this job.
I got a list here.
You're on it.
How I wish it were true.
This person,
they go in the front door...
...and out a window, down a rope
in the middle of the night?
Now, if I could do
something like that...
...I'd be the star
of my AARP meetings.
- What's that? The American...
- Association of Retired Persons.
Luther, why was this so difficult?
You want me to help you
solve your case?
Just looking for insight.
How would you...?
Scratch that.
How would one go about it?
What kind of person
should I look for?
Except for the rope trick,
an older person, like me.
Because?
Well, you need patience.
The secret is research, research
and research. I've read that.
What kind of research?
Well, from what I saw on the tube,
this is a rather large home.
Must be an architectural office.
You'd go to the library,
go through public records...
...find out where that architectural
office is and break in.
And then you xerox the plans
and get them back by morning.
Why not just steal them?
Anyone can break into
an office, but doing it...
...without having people know
you were there is the trick.
Then there's the general contractor.
And then there's the security company.
Do you realize the skill of breaking
the security of a security company?
I don't know how those guys do it.
Why go to all that trouble, Luther?
There's a vault in the house.
There must be a secret way into it.
There was.
That's what I don't get.
How do you mean?
This guy obviously did
the research you're talking about.
So why does he take a crowbar...
...to open the vault when
there's a clicker right there?
A clicker?
Well, a gizmo, like a VCR remote.
Sounds amazing to me.
Must've been a lot
of valuables in that vault.
Close to 5 million total value.
Is that funny?
I feel like you're trying
to surprise me.
I was trying to.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
There you go again.
Would the burglar use a disguise?
Yeah, he might.
Get with the program
if you're gonna catch this guy.
It is a guy we think, anyway.
Some sort of a Ioner? Weirdo?
Maybe like you.
Well, I'd be the perfect
prototype, actually.
Except you see a face around
long enough and put things together.
That's why these top guys
have disguises.
Some of them, I even understand,
become makeup experts...
...hire wigmakers
and things like that.
Go on about the wigmakers.
I would...
I've gotta go have
my pacemaker checked.
It's been so exciting talking to you.
A: You don't have a pacemaker.
And B: I'll be back tomorrow.
Tomorrow is promised to no one.
Goodbye.
Pacemaker, my ass.
Oh, Katie.
You gotta start eating
better than this, darling.
I'm having this
press conference here...
...because it is here,
at this courthouse...
...that Christine Sullivan's killer
will be tried.
As you know, I came from
an impoverished family...
... in an impoverished town.
We lived with our doors...
... unlocked.
We all lock our doors now.
- That's not what concerns me.
- A ginger ale.
We are also locking our hearts.
Could you turn that off?
- That is the sadness.
- In a second.
That...
...is the loss.
We are locking our hearts
to the weary.
We are locking our hearts...
... to the poor and their pain.
Sisters and brothers...
... we are locking our hearts
to ourselves.
Turn it back on.
- But you said...
- I know...
...but turn it on.
We feel that savagery and violence
must be allowed a place at table.
That is wrong.
That is not America.
I shall fight that battle.
Dear friend...
...old friend...
...we shall fight that battle.
Who can explain chance?
If we had not met...
...I would not be President today.
If Christine had not taken ill...
... she would be with you
in Barbados even now.
Walter, you've been
like a father to me.
I would give the world
to lessen your pain.
Thank you.
You heartless whore.
I'm not about to run from you.
Thomas Jefferson used
the Green Room as a dining room.
The walls are covered
with green silk...
...just as they were
when James Monroe was President.
Many valuable objects
and paintings in this room.
We'll move on to the Blue Room.
James Hoban built
the Blue Room as an oval...
...to please President Washington.
During the holiday season...
...the White House Christmas tree
stands in the middle.
The view from the window
includes the Jefferson Memorial.
We'll be moving on to the Red Room.
The walls of the Red Room
are covered with red silk.
He was in the building.
He took a guided tour.
I've never dealt
with blackmail before.
- He doesn't want money.
- You're a mind reader too now.
No, I just looked on the back.
See?
"I don't want money."
He has the guts of a burglar.
Wish we had him.
Finished your recruiting speech?
Because I'd like to know
how I handle this.
Like you handled the letter opener?
Gee, Bill...
...that could be construed
as criticism.
You want me for an enemy?
I should've called the police
that night but I was weak.
You convinced me to stay silent.
I regret that.
Know this:
Every time I see your face,
I wanna rip your throat out.
Fine.
You win the pissing contest.
What do I do?
Nothing.
He's making a mistake.
He thinks he has time. He doesn't.
Seth Frank's too good.
He'll bring him in.
Then what?
Then I kill him.
Miss Whitney?
Thanks.
I'm Seth Frank. Excuse me.
For a tough prosecutor, you sure
don't resemble your reputation.
Is that good or bad?
I don't know.
Look, lieutenant,
I told you on the phone.
I'm not involved with my father.
So this is a waste of time.
Do you expect me to walk out of here?
All right.
Your father disappeared.
- I need your help.
- Look.
Lieutenant, I don't know the man.
He was in jail. When he got out,
my mom and I lived by ourselves.
He doesn't care about me.
I've seen him once this past year.
Yeah, when?
A few days ago.
He said he might leave town.
I helped you. Can I work now?
- Any idea where he went?
- Quit wasting my time.
He doesn't want you to find him,
you won't.
You're saying
he skipped the country?
I'm saying you won't recognize him.
He could be right around the corner.
- He always had a safe house.
- Where?
He never said.
How do you know he had one?
My mother loved him, all right?
Even after she left him, when she was
dying, he was all she talked about.
"If only he hadn't done this.
- Lf only he hadn't done that."
- What else?
- How long has he lived here?
- Years.
Never been.
This is a strange place
for a thief to leave a key.
He always did that.
He left in a hurry. I wonder what
scares a professional thief like that.
He wasn't at these places.
My college graduation...
...my law school graduation,
the night my mother and I...
...we went out to celebrate
because I'd gotten my first job.
Me alone on the steps.
I'd won my first case.
I used to think sometimes...
Sometimes I'd come home and could sense
that he'd been in the apartment.
That he'd checked the fridge, shook
his head because I never ate right.
I mean, I know it sounds crazy,
but I've always...
I've always felt
that he was around.
You can do a good thing.
Help me bring him in.
Leave a message
you're worried about him.
No.
It's true. You're worried.
This is no normal case.
His life is in danger.
You call, you could save him.
He won't come.
Of course he'll come.
You're all he has.
He's on the run and he's scared
because he'll get caught.
- You don't know the heat.
- He's not a murderer.
Maybe he is innocent.
If that's true, I'll have him
home in a few hours.
What if a hotshot trying to
make a reputation tracks him down?
I can guarantee his safety.
You make the call,
I'll make a promise.
You'll have him back.
- Seth Frank.
- Hi.
I left a message on his machine.
He called me back within the hour
and I'm meeting him tomorrow.
Where?
Open-air place near my office,
Cafe Alonzo.
What time?
Four o 'clock.
It'll be deserted then.
Sounds good. Thanks a lot.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
Dad, hi.
It's Kate calling.
I was wondering
if you could call me, please.
There's some things I'd like
to talk with you about...
... and maybe even get together,
if that's possible.
Okay?
Thanks and talk to you soon. Bye.
Dad, hi.
It's Kate calling.
I was wondering
if you could call me, please.
There's some things I'd like
to talk with you about...
... and maybe even get together.
So you all know where and when
you're supposed to be there.
He's slippery. He's an eel.
He gets a whiff of a cop,
he disappears.
Nobody moves until I order you.
Then we move in on him.
Expect Whitney to show up at 4.
His daughter will be waiting for him.
It's important to stay
in your positions...
...until you hear the order
to move in on him.
Here you go.
Could I have some cream?
Gather around, gentlemen.
Nobody moves till
the suspect's in place.
Any questions?
See you at the Alonzo.
Boss is grateful.
He'd appreciate
an eyewitness at the capture.
This is our guy.
If he isn't, he sure disappeared fast.
See you there.
Tums?
I got my own.
Come on, Kate.
- She gonna show?
- Yeah, she'll be here.
Miss?
What you want, please?
Nothing. Thank you.
Got to.
Pardon?
You sit, you eat, please.
Jeez, this guy wasn't part
of my master plan.
Unbelievable.
I'm waiting for someone.
Oh, he must eat too, please.
He will. We will.
We're gonna...
We'll order half the menu.
Just not now.
Maybe that's him disguised
as a Chinaman.
Check out this guy in the hat.
I believe that's our man.
All units, suspect's approaching.
Stay in place.
Wait for my signal.
I did not kill her.
I want you to believe that.
Just hold on.
Let him get settled.
You've gotta believe that.
I think we're ready.
Damn it!
Almost.
You okay?
What was that?
Anyone see where those came from?
- Did you do that?
- No, we didn't do it!
Anyone see where
those shots came from?
Where's Whitney?
Quit standing around here!
Go find him!
Take it easy.
Take it easy, now.
Stay calm. Stay calm.
There's no reason to panic.
If everyone will just
kindly take it easy.
Messy.
I like that in a woman.
Here.
I got a few numbers here.
The top one's...
...Iocal police. That's
my office, my home, beeper.
I live alone too.
You can call anytime.
Want me to get
someone to stay here?
No, I wanna get some sleep.
Surveillance is outside
until it's over.
I've got a feeling he'll contact you.
You're on a hot streak, I guess.
Listen, I'm sorry.
Anything unusual at all...
...call right away.
It's not a bother.
I live alone.
You said.
Feeble.
You want something for the road?
I got water and water.
Deal.
A Pellegrino would be great.
What's so funny?
I say it wrong?
I'm tired.
I'm just tired.
Listen...
...there's one thing...
...I forgot to tell you.
I live alone.
Lock up behind me.
- How's that?
- Real good.
Now get some sleep.
Thank you.
I betrayed you twice, Luther.
You should know that.
You're not the first.
Why'd you come?
I can't have my daughter
thinking I was a murderer.
No, I mean this afternoon.
Why'd you come?
You suspected something
or you wouldn't have prepared.
My daughter wanted to see me.
The robbery was going fine
until they came in.
They were drunk.
I was hidden in the vault.
And the sex had started
getting rough...
...and he started beating her...
...started strangling her.
I thought he'd kill her.
Then she somehow got the upper hand.
She was gonna stab him with
a letter opener and two guys shot her.
The same two guys
who tried for you today.
Possibly.
Unless Walter Sullivan
was taking a shot.
It's a pretty powerful enemy.
That's very good going.
Not as powerful as
the President of the United States.
That's right.
Alan Richmond, he was the drunk.
The two guys were Secret Service.
Chief of Staff Russell
handled the cover-up.
Well, then you go to the police.
That's what innocent people do.
They go to the police.
Sure.
That young man who was here...
...he'd believe me
over the President, right?
Why should I believe you?
Because I swear to you, Kate.
I swear to you on Mattie's grave.
That's right.
Your mother's grave. I'd kill myself
before I'd lie about that.
Oh, Jesus, Luther.
- Yeah. I know.
- They'll kill you.
- I know.
- Can you run?
I was all set to.
I was at the airport ready to go.
Then there was that press conference.
And there was Richmond
using old man Sullivan.
You know, I might not
have been able to...
...save Christy Sullivan...
...but I didn't even try.
What are you gonna do?
I'll think of something.
I watched you argue a case last year.
You won it.
Thank God you got
your mother's brains.
Dangerous outside.
It always is.
Excuse me.
Could you give this
to Gloria Russell?
- Anything for me to sign?
- No, you have an honest face.
Oh, my God.
You're a vision tonight.
Thank you, Mr. President.
And thank you, Mr. President.
For...?
Come again.
You know.
You sent it to me this afternoon.
Of course.
Would you excuse me, all?
I'm overcome with a desire
to dance with my chief of staff.
Look after this for me, would you?
What is this nonsense?
I'm hoping there's an explanation.
Your gift, Alan. I was...
...overwhelmed.
And, you know, your note
was so gratifying.
I sent a note?
Yes, yes.
You think I don't know your writing?
I assumed you wanted me
to wear it tonight.
- Gloria, it's lovely.
- Yes.
And you know what else?
What, Alan?
Christy wore it the night
she was killed.
Know what this means?
No.
Whitney's been heard from.
It's not precisely the first time.
You been keeping things from me?
Well, it's just that you have
so much on your plate.
We wanted to spare you.
He sent me a Polaroid...
...of the letter opener yesterday.
I have to give this some thought.
Come to my office in the morning.
This'll make an interesting
chapter in my memoirs.
Do we know who the forger is?
I talked to Seth Frank. Apparently,
Whitney learned how in prison.
A gifted man.
How close are we to him?
We're working around the clock.
Well, that's good to know.
He'll make a mistake.
Well, that's good to know too.
There is...
...one other thing...
...that we need to take care of.
He has a daughter, doesn't he?
You sure you wanna do that?
Sir?
She's a young prosecutor.
Prosecutors ask questions.
Maybe she knows what he knows.
Let's get cracking, boys.
Show that you love your country.
How's Kate doing?
Where are you?
I won't hang around for you
to trace the call.
Just answer the question.
She couldn't be in better hands.
Secret Service is
taking over surveillance.
Hello?
It's entered in the chart.
We upped her from
250 to 500 milligrams.
Nurse, I need you right away, please.
He's having a seizure.
Dr. Kevorkian, I presume.
My guess is that this is right
in your carotid artery about now.
You're gonna get a little woozy.
But if I give you the rest...
...it'll fry your brain down
to the size of a peanut.
Drop that.
Luther...
...he was my President.
Right or wrong.
Well, he made a mistake.
You made a mistake.
When you went after my girl,
that was entirely unacceptable.
Mercy.
I'm fresh out.
Daddy?
Go to sleep, darling.
Oh, Jesus!
Just one question.
Did Walter Sullivan say
why Christy didn't go to Barbados?
Just that she changed her mind.
You know who did it, don't you?
So will you.
Check your phones.
Good night, Mr. Sullivan.
You're taking a shortcut, Tommy?
I'm your substitute driver tonight.
Don't worry about Tommy.
He's fine.
Very unusual.
What do I call you?
Luther, sir.
And are you familiar with
how to get to my townhouse, Luther?
Oh, yes, sir.
I know where all your houses are.
I'm the man who robbed you.
You're the man who tried to kill me.
I'm sorry I missed.
I believe in the Old Testament, sir.
There's nothing wrong with
an eye for an eye...
...when a terrible deed is done.
A deed such as yours.
You'd like to believe that.
That'd be simple for you
to believe that.
What do I have to gain by being here?
I have no idea.
You going to rob me again?
I don't need your money, Mr. Sullivan.
Did you check your vault lately?
I put everything back.
I'm afraid we're a little late
for an attempt at leniency.
A lot of crap's coming
down tonight, sir.
You wanna be a player or not?
You wanna know what happened
or don't you?
Because I was there.
I want to know.
You think you can stand
hearing about it?
How he beat her,
tried to strangle her?
You really wanna know?
I could walk through fire.
I was in the vault when they came in.
They were drunk.
He knocked her around.
She fought back.
He got really rough.
She tried to defend herself.
Well, he started screaming...
...sniveling simp he is.
Who else was in my house?
Secret Service.
They're the ones who shot her.
Nonsense.
Gloria Russell handled the cover-up.
Stop this!
You wanna know who it was?
It was you.
Come on, Mr. Sullivan.
We're too old to bullshit each other.
Who was it, then?
You know.
Don't shake your head.
When you're alone and rage takes over
and you want revenge...
...what face do you put
with your enemy?
Stop the car!
We're going straight ahead.
This is too terrible.
Yes, it is.
I know about Alan's reputation
as a philanderer...
...but he'd never dream
of betraying me.
I gave him the Presidency.
Remember that press conference?
Where he put his arm
around you and said...
...if Christy hadn't been sick,
she'd have been in Barbados with you?
How the hell did he know
she was sick?
You didn't tell anyone.
It's because she told him that night.
I was right there watching.
That's not real proof.
Well, maybe this is, then.
You could've stolen this.
I did steal it.
But that's not my blood on there
and that's not my prints.
Mr. Sullivan.
I did love her, you know.
Jeez, Burton.
Is he working late? I don't have
an appointment but I want to see him.
You don't need an appointment.
Let's go, Miss Russell.
Walter.
Come in.
We interrupt with a breaking story...
... that's shocking
the nation and the world.
Information just came from the White
House about a tragedy within the hour.
We go now to our correspondent.
Diane, what can you tell us?
Sources tell us Walter Sullivan
had seen President Richmond tonight.
That was for an unscheduled
private meeting.
You're still here.
I'm still here.
- I would not be President.
If Christine had not taken ill...
... she would be with you
in Barbados even now.
Walter, you've been
like a father to me.
This is the President's
most recent news conference...
... where he clearly outlined...
... his loyalty to philanthropist
and friend, Sullivan.
The President vowed to find
Sullivan 's wife's killer.
Sullivan had a meeting with the
President. Unknown what they discussed.
Now to the White House
for a live interview.
Have you no idea why the President
would take his own life?
I know he's been feeling the pressure
of office, more than ever, lately.
He talked about it a great deal.
But why would he stab himself?
That's a question that will
haunt me forever.
Of course I tried to stop him.
Alan...
... was like a son to me.
Was that Seth?
I think he'd like to come over
for supper when you get well.
You don't have to fuss.
I know.
Am I gonna be all right?
Yeah.
We're gonna be just fine.
Subtitles by Filou ;-)