My mommy
always said there were no monsters.
No real ones.
But there are.
We've seen no additional defects.
- She's perfect.
- Mm-hmm.
- Careful.
- Two centimeters.
Okay.
Yeah.
Ready with that amnio.
- Oh.
- And...
there it is.
Oh!
No.
Be careful.
Jesus.
Clamp it.
What about her?
Can we keep her alive?
How's the host?
Doing well.
Sew her back up.
Excellent work, everybody.
And how is
our Number Eight today?
Appears to be
in good health.
- Hmm? How good?
- Excellent...
as in completely off
our projected charts.
Look at the scar tissue.
- See the recession?
- This is from three days ago?
- Exactly.
- Oh, this is good.
This is very good.
You're gonna make us all
very proud.
Don't! I'm all right.
Now try this.
- Hand.
- Close.
Glove.
Number Eight?
Fruit.
- Good. Cherries.
- It's unprecedented.
Totally.
She's operating...
at a completely
adult capacity.
- What about her memories?
- There are gaps.
And some degree
of synaptic dissonance.
She's freaked.
"It" has connective
difficulties...
caused by a biochemical imbalance,
causing emotional autism.
- Certain reactions...
- All right, wait a second!
"It"has memories.
Why does "it"have memories?
Well, I'm guessing, but...
inherited memories passed down
generationally at a genetic level...
by the aliens,
like "its" strength.
Plus a, uh,
highly evolved form of instinct.
An unexpected benefit
from the genetic crossing.
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho.
I see.
Stupid me.
Of course.
An unexpected benefit
of the genetic process.
Oh! And I didn't
even think of that!
Let's try this one.
Ripley?
Ripley, what is it?
You're not thinking
termination?
Oh, boy,
am I thinking termination.
General, we do not perceive this
to be a problem.
Ellen Ripley died trying
to wipe this species out.
For all intents and purposes,
she succeeded.
I'm not anxious to see her
taking up her old hobbies.
- That won't happen.
- We won't tell her.
Oh, I see.
And that's supposed to comfort me?
Identification, please.
Please try again.
Thank you, General Perez.
Bottom line is,
she looks at me funny one time...
I'm putting her down.
Okay, as far as I'm concerned,
Number Eight...
is a meat... by-product.
Her Majesty here
is the real payoff.
When does she start producing?
Days. Less, maybe.
- We need the cargo.
- I told you, it's on its way.
Fork.
- Fuck.
- It's-It's "fork."
How did you...
How did... we get you?
Yes.
Hard work.
We used blood samples...
from Fiori Sixteen on ice...
where you died.
We've remade you.
We cloned you.
Fiori Sixteen.
Does that ring a bell?
Are you
remembering something?
- Does it grow?
- Yeah.
Very rapidly.
It's a queen.
How did you know that?
She'll breed.
You'll die.
Everyone in the company will die.
In the... In the...
In the company?
Weyland Yutani.
Ripley Eight's former employers.
Terran growth conglomerate.
They had...
defense contracts under
the military.
They went under decades ago,
Gediman. Way before your time.
Bought out by Wal-Mart.
Fortunes of war.
I think you will find
that, uh...
things have changed a great deal
since your time.
I doubt that.
We're not flying
blind here, you know.
It's United Systems Military,
not some greedy corporation.
Oh. Well, it won't
make any difference.
You're still gonna die.
How do you feel about that?
I wish you could understand
what we're trying to do here.
The potential for this species
goes way beyond urban pacification.
New alloys, new vaccines.
Nothing like this we've ever
seen on any world before.
You should be very proud.
Oh. I am.
And the animal itself...
wondrous.
The potential, unbelievable,
once we've tamed him.
Roll over. Play dead.
- Heel.
- Mm-hmm.
You can't teach it tricks.
Why not?
We're teaching you.
Hey, son, I'll give you
my authorization code.
It's E-A-T-M-E.
I'm sorry, sir. Could you repeat that?
Little prick.
You know...
no matter how many times
you see it...
the sight of a woman all strapped up
in a chair like that just...
- What? - Just bring us in
on a 3-0 descent, would you?
- And ride the parallel.
- Darlin', it is done.
Good girl.
You, uh, want
anything there, Trigger?
Mmm. Yeah.
How 'bout a cup of coffee?
Anything else,
while your mouth's warm, I mean?
Little milk.
Hey, don't cut thrust
till about 600 meters...
and we'll give 'em
a little scare.
Vriess. Call.
Lock down.
We're gonna dock.
- Hey, Call?
- Yep?
What has two thumbs,
one eye...
a pink tongue...
and screws like a god?
What?
Two thumbs, one eye,
a pink tongue...
and screws like a god?
What?
Hey.
Time to enjoy some of
the general's hospitality, Christie.
Great.
Army food.
Yeah. It'll do till we get
the family wagon up to spec, I reckon.
- Yeah.
- That is if the natives are friendly.
- How's that?
- Good.
We expecting any,
uh, trouble?
Nah. From Perez, I doubt it. But you
never know. We've been there before.
What is wrong with you?
Just a little target practice.
Vriess isn't complaining.
Goddamn it!
Johner, you son of a bitch!
Come on, man.
You didn't feel a thing.
You are an inbred motherfucker,
you know that?
I'll take the knife back now.
Whoa.
Call, forget it.
He's been sucking down
too much home brew.
The knife.
Son of a bitch!
Don't push me, little Call.
If you hang with us for a while...
you'll find out I am not the man
with whom to fuck!
It's about time we start associating
with a better class of people.
I am Father.
Welcome to the U.S.M. Auriga.
Step forward for
contraband and weapons search.
Please report
any infectious diseases...
to the medical officers.
- Levels seven through twelve
are off-limits to civilians.
Thank you for your cooperation.
Go.
- Put your hands up, please, sir.
- What?
Could you get
your hands up, please?
There are no weapons
allowed on board, sir.
My own recipe.
Way more dangerous.
Nice welcome, Perez.
What the hell is this?
What, are you afraid the six of us are
gonna hijack your damn ship or what?
Just a minor concern that one
of your asshole crew members...
is gonna get drunk and put
a bullet through the hull.
We happen to be
in space, Elgyn.
No shit.
How you been?
Wanna check the chair?
- Elgyn, these were very,
very hard to come by.
So was our cargo.
You're, uh, not about to plead
poverty on me, are you, General?
Just saying very few people
deal in cash nowadays.
Just the ones don't like
to keep business records.
- Yourself, for example.
- Drink, Elgyn?
Constantly.
Now, I'm gonna take
a wild guess here, General...
but I'm thinking whatever
you got going on here...
it ain't exactly approved
by Congress.
Who's the... new filly
you got on board, Elgyn?
Call. Little girl
playing pirates.
She makes an impression.
She is severely fuckable,
ain't she?
Mighty handy with a monkey wrench too,
I might add.
I think Vriess's got a bit
of a light in his eye for her.
Fine little ass like that'd make
a man walk. You know what I mean?
Mind you, uh, I think
she's just a tad curious...
about, uh,
this transaction of ours.
I mean, I can't say
as I blame her.
It's awfully
cloak-and-dagger stuff.
It's a military operation.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
Correct me if I'm wrong,
but, uh...
I was under the impression
that, uh...
most army medical labs don't have
to operate outside of regulated space.
- What do you want, Elgyn? What can I do for you?
- Me?
- Yeah.
- Oh, two days bed and board.
You know, Vriess might wanna
snag a part here or there, whatever.
I mean, uh,
if it's not imposing.
I don't see any problem.
- Couple of conditions, though.
- Ah.
Conditions?
Not you...
nor any of your...
formidable crew members...
will go anywhere near
restricted areas.
Rule number two:
No trouble.
- Good behavior.
- No fights.
Mi casa es su casa.
Please direct cargo
to med lab center, area "G."
Follow the lit path.
Do not deviate.
Cargo status... stable.
Life-forms intact.
Stasis uninterrupted.
Med lab center
is off-limits to civilians.
Thank you.
- Oh.
- Hey. Chill.
- Oh, please.
- You know I can't lay off the tall ones.
How you doin'?
How about a little one-on-one?
What do you say?
You got some moves
on you, girl.
Oh, man.
Mm-hmm.
Well, if you don't wanna play basketball,
I know some other indoor sports.
Come on, now.
Give me the ball.
Oh, God!
Okay, I got a new game.
Tag!
Ripley? Ripley.
You've had enough fun.
What the hell are you?
Something of a predator,
isn't she?
Yes, she continues
to make us all very proud.
We're coming up on just
one minute and 30 seconds left...
to order this one-of-a-kind
collector's item.
Jesus Christ, Johner, what do you
put in this shit, battery acid?
Just for color.
So, we're a fast learner.
This is a really good show, man.
It's from the
Gut Cutter's Celebration Collection...
makers of premier
knives and edgeware.
The knife features
a stainless steel blade...
perfect for any use
in hunting or in the home.
The pro handle is made
from authentic antique plywood...
and stained in brilliant colors
for an uncanny charm.
Hey, man, that shit
is not easy to come by!
Why don't you take
a walk outside?
Great!
- I'm so sorry.
- Now I smell like this shit!
Lfbitches can't handle this shit...
bitches should stay away
from this shit!
Identification, please.
Please try again.
Thank you, General Perez.
Well?
You gonna kill me,
or what?
There's no point,
is there?
They've taken
it out of you.
Where is it?
Is it on the ship?
You mean my baby?
I don't get it.
If they took it out...
why are they
keeping you alive?
Well, they're curious.
I'm the latest thing.
Look...
I can make it all stop.
The pain, this nightmare.
That's all I can offer you.
What makes you think...
I would let you do that?
Who are you?
Ripley, Ellen,
Lieutenant First Class...
number 3-6-7-0-6.
Ellen Ripley died
200 years ago.
You're not her.
I'm not her.
Who am I?
You're a thing,
a construct.
They grew you
in a fucking lab.
And now they brought it
out of you.
Not all the way out.
I can feel it...
behind my eyes.
I can hear it moving.
You gotta help me stop this thing
before it gets loose.
It's too late.
You can't stop it.
It's inevitable.
Not as long
as I'm around.
You'll never
get out of here alive.
I don't care.
Really?
I can make it stop.
Go on.
Get out of here.
They're looking for you.
I think you're gonna find that
this was very ill-advised.
- Where are her friends?
- They're in the mess hall, sir.
Well, you find them, now.
Quietly.
What the hell
is going on here?
Smells like a double-cross, boss.
Where's the other one?
With the chair?
Don't ever touch me!
Ever!
You wanna tell us
what this is?
- You wanna tell me who you're workin' for?
- What?
- Wren, they got nothing to do with this.
- To do with what?
Do you know what the penalties
for terrorist activity are?
No goddamn terrorists on my crew.
Call, there something you wanna tell me?
I don't care whether you knew or not. You
brought a terrorist on board a military vessel.
And as far as I am concerned,
you all die with her!
Do you understand?
Yeah. I understand.
Christie.
Freeze!
Stop!
Drop your weapons!
And you! Drop that piece of shit,
or I blow his head off!
- Can't do that, man.
- Drop it, now!
- Can't do that. They're attached to me.
- I'm not fucking with you!
You're all under arrest for a code eight,
which is concealed weapons...
and a code twelve,
which is murder!
- Release Dr. Wren!
- Kiss my ass.
Put down your weapons
and assume the fucking...
Everybody okay?
Real easy, soldier boy.
- Security!
- Get up!
There is a serious problem
in the mess hall.
You lie to me now,
little girl...
I will cut your throat and leave you
here to die, you understand me?
- This is Security, section two. We do not read you.
- Hello? Goddamn it!
- We do not copy you. Please repeat.
- Hello?
Gediman!
He's conducting illegal experiments.
He is breeding some sort of...
- Ice the goddamn mole!
- Listen to me! He is breeding an alien species.
More than dangerous.
If those things get loose...
it's gonna make the Lacerta Plague
look like a fucking square dance!
Shut up!
Listen.
Your attention, please.
Security breach, med lab,
level fifteen.
Go. Let's get back to the Betty. Doctor
and soldier boy here can see us to the door.
- What about Vriess?
- Fuck Vriess.
Your attention, please.
Unauthorized opening
of cage three.
of cages five...
seven, eight, ten...
- Move it!
- Evacuation.
- Go! Go now!
This is not a drill.
- Evacuation.
- Go! Get on board!
Your attention, please.
Nonhuman presence detected...
levels 21, 23...
27, 14...
level 38, level 39.
Evacuation.
Proceed to lifeboats.
This is not a drill.
Thank you for your cooperation.
I'll give you holes, you slimy bastard!
Move it! Let's go!
Final lifeboat ready for launch.
- Get aboard!
Go!
Complete evacuation now.
Grenade.
Alert. Alert.
Evacuation incomplete.
Civilian presence detected
in area "H." Warning.
Main vessel
declared uninhabitable.
Elgyn, come on. Let's move, man.
Yeah.
Elgyn? Elgyn, where are you?
Elgyn, where are you?
Elgyn?
Elgyn!
- God. Elgyn?
- Elgyn?
Elgyn!
Easy, Hillard!
Christie, give me a hand here!
- Get him up!
- Give me a hand here!
- Come on! Let's get him up!
- Move out of the way!
- No!
- Ah, shit.
- What the fuck did this?
- What's in this place?
- Call, get down! - What the
fuck is that? - Don't shoot!
It's in front of the hull!
What is that?
- Come on, man. Time to go. Time to go!
- Get back!
Damn!
Call, time to go!
Come on, Call!
Get the goddamn door open!
We can't open it!
We can't open the door!
- We gotta go back!
- I'm not going back! You go back!
What the fuck?
Was it everything
you hoped for?
Leave him alone!
What do we do now, man?
- Same thing we're doin'. We get the hell outta here!
- What if there's more?
I say we stay here, man.
Let the army guys deal.
Where the fuck
are the army guys?
They're dead!
Well, then we don't need
this asshole anymore.
- Step back!
- No, you step back!
- Stop it!
- You got no authority here!
Doctor, that thing
that killed my partner...
- that's your pet science project?
- Yes.
- Let me do him right now, man!
- I should let him do you right now!
How many more are there?
- How many more are there?
- Twelve.
- Twelve?
Twelve.
There'll be more.
So...
who do I have to fuck
to get off this boat?
I can get you off.
Maybe not the boat, but...
- Let's get out of here.
- No, wait a second here.
She was the host
for these monsters.
Wren cloned her because
she had one inside her.
She's not human.
She was part ofhis experiment,
and she will turn on us in a second.
I don't give a shit what she is.
She's too much of a risk.
We have to leave her.
- She comes.
- We can't trust her!
I don't trust anyone.
If we're gonna survive this mess,
we all stick together.
Agreed?
Hillard, we gotta go. It's not over.
We gotta get to the Betty.
Make a nice souvenir.
I can't believe
you did that.
- Did what?
- Killed one of'em.
- It's like killing your own kind.
- It was in my way.
Oh, man!
Oh, no.
Who were you expecting,
Santa Claus?
- Thought you were toast
for certain, man.
Where's Elgyn?
Oh, shit.
Hey, man, what if we get to
the Betty and they're all over it?
All the activity's been in the aft sector
by the barracks. Why would they move?
They won't.
If they send anyone out...
it'll be, uh, here...
where the meat is.
Yeah. Well, I say if we wanna make any
decent time, I say we ditch the cripple.
- No offense, man.
- None taken.
Nobody is left behind.
Not even you, Johner.
- What's the quickest way out of here?
- After the cooling tower...
there's a freight elevator.
It runs from the top of the ship
down to engineering level one deck.
- Take us straight to the dock.
- Sounds reasonable. Let's do it.
We're moving.
- What?
- The ship is moving.
- I can feel it. - The ship has
stealth-run. There's no way you can tell.
She's right.
The ship's been go
since the attack.
- That's a standard emergency procedure.
- That's right.
Any serious problem and the ship
autopilots back to home base.
And you were planning
on letting us know this?
Nobody asked.
What's home base?
Earth.
Oh, great.
- You bastard.
- Earth?
I'd rather stay here
with the things, man.
How long until
we get to Earth?
- Three hours almost.
- We gotta blow the ship.
Call, you're not
blowing this ship.
Not while we're on it,
okay?
We get out of this shit,
you do as you please, all right?
Earth, man.
What a shithole.
It's clear.
Hey, Ripley...
I heard you, like,
ran into these things before.
- That's right.
- Wow, man.
So, like,
what did you do?
I died.
Not that way!
Ripley?
Ripley, come on.
Ripley, we got no time
for sightseeing here.
Ripley, don't.
Kill... me.
Kill me.