You've sold us a bill of goods,
Gordon.
Promised new drugs to fight everything
from the common cold to cancer.
-We'll deliver everything we promised.
-I'm sorry, but the adventure is over.
We're exercising our option
to liquidate...
...Byron & Mitchell Research Limited.
Jack, show these people how filthy
rich we're gonna make them, please.
I don't think you understand
what I just said.
Oh, I think I understand.
Jack.
Perrinia immortalis.
The Blood Orchid.
First described in 1 892
by Houghton...
...the last person to see it until our
team brought a sample from Borneo.
It lies dormant for seven years,
then blooms for just six months.
Which means we just got
lucky as hell, gentlemen.
Anyone here familiar
with the Hayflick limit?
He proposed a cell
could only replicate 56 times...
...before it died from
a buildup of toxins.
According to him,
it's the reason we die.
But what if we could
transcend that limit?
That would be impossible.
Not according to our data.
Our research indicates the presence
of a chemical in Perrinia immortalis...
...that can significantly
prolong cellular life.
I can't support this.
Does that mean
what I think it means?
Are we talking about
a pharmaceutical equivalent...
...to the fountain of youth?
Exactly.
That'd be bigger than Viagra.
-Have you put this into human trials?
-We can't yet.
Our sample was degraded
in the initial study.
We need more of the orchid.
See, and that's our only problem,
gentlemen.
That orchid is only in bloom
for another two weeks.
Well, what the hell
are you waiting for?
Get your asses down to Borneo.
Yes.
-Welcome to Borneo.
-Thanks.
-What's wrong with this picture?
-I don't know. Let me see, you're in it?
We don't have a boat, okay?
Your company had one responsibility:
get a boat.
-And you've already screwed it up.
-Wait. Your girl chartered the boat.
Sam confirmed with the company.
They're waiting for your payment.
Hey. Hey, I've got something.
Payment cleared.
Really?
-Where's the boat?
-It's not coming.
All of the charter companies
have shut down.
No one'll risk going upriver
till after the rainy season.
-And when's that?
-Two, three weeks.
The orchid's only in bloom
for one more week, tops.
There's a local captain
named Jin-Soon.
I'm told he'll take anyone upriver,
for the right price.
Are you sure this is the place?
They said the one
with the red door.
I bet you somebody's playing
Russian roulette in there.
Maybe we'll get lucky
and you'll get a turn.
Hey, why don't you two just get a room.
Come on, Sam.
Wait here.
Yeah, if you insist.
Hey! Hey!
Jin-Soon.
Jin-Soon?
Your lndonesian sucks.
-Stick to English.
-We heard you could take us upriver.
In rainy season?
Won't be cheap.
We can pay you 25,000.
-I'll have a talk with the captain.
-You're not the captain?
Jin-Soon!
These tourists need a boat.
I told them not in the rainy season.
-You're Jin-Soon?
-Local nickname.
Name's Johnson. Bill Johnson.
It's a pronunciation thing.
And you can rent my boat
for 25 grand.
Now, you want me to drive it,
well...
...that'll cost you 50.
Fifty grand? Are you high?
You know what?
Don't answer that.
I'm not trusting him
with the expedition.
Listen. Lady.
Let's cut the bullshit, please.
If one of the other charter
companies could take you...
...you'd be on the river by now.
You only came to me
because you're desperate.
Fifty grand's my price.
Take it...
...or leave it.
I've seen subway cars
in better shape than this.
Yeah, she may be ugly...
...but she puts out.
-Shit!
-What took you so long?
Hey, you try getting a GPS locator,
a Sat-Nav EchoStar...
...and a UV spectrometer
past lndonesian customs.
-Complaining already.
-Yeah.
-You rather be back in the office?
-Hell, yeah.
I had courtside seats
at the Garden on Saturday.
I was gonna sit right between
Spike and Woody.
Oh, man, is that our ride?!
Look at the bright side, Cole.
At least the weather's nice.
Ben Douglas, team doctor.
You must be Sam.
Yeah. We spoke on the phone.
Glad to have you aboard.
I'm gonna get you for this.
Oh, yeah. This could be fun.
You can forget about that, dog.
That's one car you ain't
never gonna catch.
There's always a way.
-Your team's a little green, huh?
-My former grad students.
Best in their field.
Here's a tip for Wexell-Hall:
You want the best young talent...
...recruit early.
Yes, I'm sure Sam's very talented.
I think I resent that.
You and the other gal can stay in here.
You live here.
The way you say that,
I can tell you're impressed.
All right.
If you need anything....
Well...
...if you need anything,
you're shit out of luck.
Okay.
Now, this is where the exploratory
team found the orchid.
In the Selatan Basin.
-lt took them three days to get upriver.
-Yeah.
That was before
the rainy season.
These waterways
could be dangerous now.
-You said you'd get us there safely.
-And I will.
But safe isn't always quick.
We'll work our way up
one bend at a time.
If I don't like what I see,
we change course.
Can't chart the fastest route
before you begin.
Already have.
Check it. All right.
Now, we're uplinked in real time
to NASA and AsiaSatCom.
Now, under ideal conditions...
...this is the fastest route.
But once we superimpose weather
patterns for the past 1 0 years...
...and then extrapolate....
Bingo! It's Padrang
to the Selatan Basin.
I'm a bad man.
We got less than a week
to get to that orchid.
If you can't get the job done,
give our money back...
-...and we'll get somebody who can.
-I'll get you there.
God help me.
Something attacked me!
-Oh, my God!
-She said something attacked her.
No, no, no!
It's okay. It's okay.
What the helI'd you do?
You scared him.
I scared him?!
This is Kong.
Kong lives here.
You're guests.
Be nice.
Disgusting animal.
You okay now?
I'm fine. Just keep
your hands off of me.
Oh, yeah. Well, it's gonna be tough,
but I'll try.
No, no, the S-1 has to be on file
before the week is out.
-That's the whole point.
-Hello?
-The S-1 needs to be on file before....
-Yes, we were able to get on the river.
That's the purpose. We need
the comments from the SEC.
-Excuse me.
-It's the only place I can get reception.
-No, just get it done. Be ready to go....
-No, that's impossible....
-Hello? Hello? Damn!
-Hello? Bob? Damn it!
Try my phone.
Works just as good,
but it's free.
Okay. Maybe you can use my special
antenna to boost your reception.
We're dealing with a lithophytic vine,
so we want to search any rock face.
Now, this ridge here
seems a good bet.
Sam.
Come on, Sam. What do you say?
We're young. We're single.
We're in Borneo.
What do you got to lose?
Not satisfied, walk away.
No commitments.
"No commitments."
That's your pitch?
Did I say "No commitments"?
I meant marry me.
Am I gonna be dealing with this
for the next two weeks?
Yep.
So you were one of Jack's students?
Yeah. He was teaching a seminar
on botanical pharmacology.
Soon as I finished my dissertation,
he hired me.
Well, that's one way to get a leg-up.
What's that supposed to mean?
I had a professor
who wanted to hire me.
Of course, he wanted me
to be his secretary.
Look, if I've done something
to offend you--
No. No, dear, not at all.
Actually, I admire you.
Took me 1 0 years to get where I am.
Clearly, your generation
has it figured out.
Man, this is good.
Where'd you learn to cook like this?
-Little recipe I picked up in Sri Lanka.
-What were you doing there?
Doctors Without Borders.
It's my day job.
You guys expect to need a doctor?
Can't get the expedition
bonded without one.
Well, you just think of me
as a charming insurance policy.
Hey!
You've had your dinner.
Get out of here.
What'd I say?
There's not that much....
I'm not sleeping up there.
I ain't sleeping on the floor.
I ain't sleeping on no damn....
-Oh, shit. What was that?
-What the hell was that?
-Something's getting eaten.
-By what?
Everything gets eaten out here.
It's the jungle.
Kong.
Hey. You guys seen Kong?
No. Not since last night.
Where are you?
Kong?
We need those results by next month
if we want the FDA off our backs.
Hello? Shit!
I can't hear you!
Can you hear me now?
How about now?
-Can you hear me now?
-We can!
Can you hear me now?
-Gail! Oh, my God.
-Shit.
Stop the boat!
-I'll go.
-All right.
Hey, Gail! Can you hear me now?!
Oh, I'm gonna kill you!
Stroke, Gail, stroke. Come on.
-Watch your back.
-Hey, Gail! How's the water?
Drop the phone.
It's probably holding you back.
-All right.
-Stay calm.
-Use your phone for flotation.
All right, come on, Gail.
-You're almost there.
-It's just like a phone.
I got it.
-Holy shit!
Come on! Come on!
-Get out!
-Hurry up!
Hurry up! Hurry up!
-Come on! Come on!
-Gail, grab it.
-Look out!
-Watch out!
Oh, my God.
Get him, Bill! Get him, Bill!
Get him in the eye, man!
Bill?
Where'd he go?
-Where'd he go?!
-Bill!
I don't see him.
-Where's he gone?
-Oh, my God.
Oh, shit, you won.
-You're okay?
-I lost my phone.
Sorry to hear it.
That was either the bravest
or the stupidest thing I've ever seen.
It's a fine line.
-Good as new.
-Thanks.
To Gail...
...who knows it's better to eat
than be eaten.
-To Gail.
-Yeah, yeah, baby.
Almost eaten just to find a flower.
-Hardly seems worth it.
-Oh, it's worth it.
I mean, think about it.
A pill that you take every day
for the rest of your life.
Now, even if we charge,
say, a dollar a pop...
-...we're billionaires.
-Yeah.
-That's what I'm talking about, baby.
-At $1 00 a bottle...
...I'll dive in that river
and fight that croc myself.
So how many flowers does it take
to save the world?
Figure 50 orchids will yield
about an ounce of chemical.
You could have a football field
full of those orchids...
...still doesn't mean you can get it
through human trials.
She doesn't even believe in you.
Comes with the territory.
In research,
you've got to go out on a limb.
And there's always someone
waiting to chop it off.
Where the hell have you been?
-Damn that thing!
-Where you been, boy?
Calm down. Calm down.
-Poor guy.
-It's okay. It's all right.
Looks like he's seen a ghost.
It's all right. It's all right.
It's all right.
What if Gail's right?
I mean, cells in a petri dish
are one thing.
-Human trials are another.
-She's wrong.
And when it goes to product...
...and you and I can cash in
our stock options...
-...we'll rub her face in it.
-Stock options.
I spoke to Mitchell.
We're each giving you half a point.
I don't know what to say.
Don't say anything.
You deserve it.
All this...
...wouldn't be possible
without your work.
Jack.
Thought we decided against that.
Yeah. Yeah.
You're right.
It would be fun, though.
I mean, here we are,
traveling upriver...
...to the greatest discovery
of our careers.
Now, if this orchid thing
works out, then...
...who knows?
Is that why I'm here?
So you can give us one more try?
You're here because
you're the best researcher I've got.
Am I interrupting something?
No. No, I was....
-I was just going to bed.
-Yeah.
Well, before you do that,
we need to talk.
We got a problem.
See the water level?
In high water,
the Mendranang gets rough.
We could turn around,
try to find another course.
-But that would take at least two days.
-We don't have the time.
If the river becomes impassable,
it'll take a lot longer.
And if we turn back,
then we're definitely screwed.
We're gonna have to risk it.
What if I don't wanna risk it?
Do you have any idea
what this flower means?
We're talking about the biggest
medical discovery in history.
That does sound great, Jack.
But I was never any good at history.
You want me to risk
the Mendranang...
...it'll cost you
an extra 50 thousand.
Done.
Done?
You gotta ask the boss lady
or something?
I'll pay it myself.
All right.
You got yourself a deal.
But if we hit trouble...
...your people do what I say,
you got that?
You're the captain.
Research proposals?
Yeah. Research proposals.
You're not the only company
we're in bed with.
We're the prettiest
and most popular.
Like sleeping with
the head cheerleader.
Not quite.
Come on, you know you love us.
I love your cash.
Then let me
get a look at that file.
After this orchid thing goes bust,
you'll be finished at Wexell-Hall.
Unless you got
something else lined up.
You really wanna see us fail,
don't you?
No.
I just think that you will.
I am a scientist, you know.
Scientist.
What're you doing at Wexell-Hall?
I like science.
I just like money better.
I'll drink to that.
River's flooded.
We can't see the banks.
Miss our turnoff?
It's just ahead.
What the hell was that?
-Rudder's jammed.
-What?
Watch out.
Shit!
Get up! Everybody up!
Hey.
What's going on?
Goddamn it.
Shit! We've blown the head gasket.
Are we all right?
Hey, what's going on?
-What is it?
-We got problems.
-What's wrong, man?
-Bill, wait.
What are you talking about?
What problems?
Son of a bitch.
The current's too strong.
-We missed our turnoff.
-I know. Come on, baby.
Come on, man.
-What is it?
What do you see?
Come on.
You got this. Come on, girl.
-Everybody! Hang on!
-Hang on to what?!
Come on!
Oh, shit!
Holy shit.
It's sinking, it's sinking!
-Where's Cole?
-Swim to the rocks, this way.
Keep going.
-Come on, get to the rocks.
-Get to the rocks.
-Where's Cole? Cole!
-Over there.
Over there! Over there!
Come on, man. Give me your hand!
Come on.
You got it, Sam. Come on.
Give me your hand.
I've got you, I've got you.
Give me your hand,
give me your hand.
Okay, I got her.
You almost got us killed!
You think I wanted this?
I just lost my damn boat!
You'll lose your pay
if you don't get us out.
You said you'd get us there safely.
You should've turned around.
That's enough!
There's nothing
we can do about that now.
It's a waste of energy.
What have we got?
Some specimen jars,
a map, a little water, no food.
Hard drive's ruined.
Well, pretty much
all the equipment's shot.
Except one of the SAT phones
still works. It's on-line.
Thank God, we can call the police.
Police. The nearest river patrol
is back in Padrang.
The only way to get to us
is over that.
Are you saying we're stuck here?
Maybe not.
We're here.
The valley's completely flooded.
But I got a friend who operates
a boat on the Tokut River.
I can give him a call, and he can
meet us here at Naga Rock.
How far is that?
I don't know.
A two-day hike down the river.
But if we bushwhack,
we cut at least a day off the trek.
Oh, my God.
You wanna go through that?
It's the shortest way.
We could be safely in the Tokut
by nightfall.
So we can continue
with the expedition.
-Yeah. I'll get you to the flower.
-I don't care about that flower...
-...just get us to safety.
-It's the same thing.
We can either be on my buddy's boat
in 1 0 hours, or we can sit here...
...and wait for the river patrol
for days.
Your friend. Is he reliable?
Absolutely.
You better not screw me on this.
Sounds like you're already
screwed, mate.
Pay you two grand.
I need you on this one, John.
Yes, yes, so it seems.
Look, Billy, I'd love to help you out,
but I'm flat out, mate, you know.
Probably squeeze you in for,
say, 5 grand?
You're killing me.
That's mates rates.
Or you could always...
...hike back to Padrang
if you wanna save bucks.
-Up to you, pal.
-Fine. Five.
-Yes!
-But you better be there.
Otherwise, I'll tell your wife
about that little trip to Bangkok.
Wife's long gone, Billy.
Long gone, mate.
All right, people, we're on.
Saddle up.
Stay together. This jungle is all green
all the time, and you will get lost.
It's like doing a StairMaster
in a sauna.
Yeah. I might die of a heat stroke,
but I'll have a nice tight ass.
That's the spirit, Cole.
-You want me to grab that?
-ls that a trick question?
Here, man.
Right between Spike and Woody.
You okay, Sam?
I'm fine.
See, a crisis separates
the real men from the pretenders.
Yeah. Can see that.
What, that?
That's nothing.
I tricked him into taking my bag.
Hey. Mind if I give it a try?
Knock yourself out.
Hey.
I'm sorry about your boat.
Yeah, well...
...it was a piece of shit anyway.
Can we go around?
Yeah, we could.
But we'd lose another day.
Let's go.
Shit.
Hey. Knock it off.
-Shit! What was that?
-What was what?
-Something just moved.
-Please don't say that.
I'm serious. Something moved.
"Something just moved"
as in something's alive?
Shit! There it is again.
There's something in here!
There's probably
a million things in here.
He's right. Just keep moving.
Stop it.
I swear to God, if you don't stop it....
Very funny.
Ben?
-Where'd he go?
-Shit!
Help me!
Run!
-What the hell was that thing?!
-Anaconda.
-Oh, great!
-There's snakes out here that big?
-Yes, but--
-But what? It swallowed him whole!
Calm down and listen for a second.
I can explain--
No, you calm down and listen!
Ben was eaten by a freaking snake.
-Okay? A freaking snake!
-Cole.
-Oh, God. Oh, my God. I mean....
Oh, my God, did you see that thing?
We don't got a chance against that!
I mean, Mitchell. Mitchell.
Listen to me, man.
I watch the Discovery Channel.
I'm telling you, we got no chance!
We're like mice in an aquarium.
You understand?
I mean, we're gonna die, girl.
We're gonna die!
Cole, calm down. Okay?
-Okay?
-All right, Jack, I'm okay.
Okay. I'll just....
I'm gonna--
I'm gonna sit right here.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Listen. Anacondas are territorial.
A snake that size
will hunt a huge area.
There won't be another one
for miles.
We gotta get to the boat.
It's not that far.
So if we keep moving
and stick together...
-...we should be fine.
-We should be?!
How big do they get?
That was the biggest one I've ever
seen by far. A freak of nature.
The odds of running into another
that size are astronomical.
Yeah, but how do we know
the one that got Ben...
...is not gonna come after us?
It takes them weeks to digest.
Meal like that,
he'll be sleeping it off for a while.
Let's just get to that boat
and get home.
What about the orchid?
You've gotta be kidding me.
It won't bloom
for another seven years.
-This expedition is over, Jack.
-Now, hold on a second, Gail.
-There's a lot of money at stake here.
-I don't care. Ben is dead!
We have lost someone.
As Wexell-Hall's representative,
I am calling this expedition off.
-You don't have the authority.
-Check your contract.
We're in the middle of the jungle.
At this point, your authority
is what we say it is.
Jack, I'm with her.
I gotta get the hell out of here, man.
Look. Ben was my friend, okay?
I got him into this, and no one
feels worse about it than I do.
I don't wanna do
anything stupid.
I just wanna accomplish
what we came here for.
If we turn back now,
Ben's death would be for nothing.
Let's just get back to the boat.
We can regroup
and make our decision then.
Fine.
Jack.
-Maybe Gail's right.
-She's just scared.
Once we get back to the boat,
she'll be okay.
When we get back to the boat,
this expedition is over.
I'm taking these people to safety.
Hey, hey, hey. We had a deal.
Keep your money, doc.
Someone is dead.
We're officially in over our heads.
You said we wouldn't
run into another one of them.
And we probably won't,
but I can't guarantee it.
So I'll get you to the boat...
...and after that we're done.
Well, that answers it.
That answers nothing. I'll just throw
more money at him at the boat.
If he doesn't take it,
I'll offer his friend the same deal.
-Jack. Maybe we should listen--
-lf we don't get to that orchid now...
...all of our work
will have been for nothing.
I need your support, okay? You have
as much riding on this as I do.
Don't let me down.
I saw this special on Animal Planet.
Anacondas are vicious.
They hunt for sport.
Don't even need to see you.
Just use their tongues
to sense body heat--
Shut the hell up.
I knew this guy who knew this guy
who shot documentaries.
He went to the Amazon with this crew,
and they were all eaten by snakes.
Come on, you knew a guy who
knew a guy, that's an urban myth.
I'm sorry about Ben.
I never should've stayed
on the Mendranang.
What do you mean?
Well, I figured he didn't tell the others,
but I thought you knew.
Knew what?
Byron offered me an extra 50 grand
to stay on the river.
I told him it might get rough,
but he wanted to risk it.
Hey. Don't blame him.
It was my call.
I took the money.
I thought I could get us through.
You wanna blame anyone?
You blame me.
These boots are killing me.
-Cole.
-What?
You got some....
Oh, God, what is that?!
Get it off! Get it off!
-Oh, my God! Take it off!
-Relax.
-Help me! Help me!
-Hold on.
-Get it off me!
-Hey! Calm down!
-Get this off me!
-Calm down!
Cole! Cole! Calm down.
What is it? What is it?
-Get it off me. Get it off.
-All right. Look.
-Just a lighter. Just a lighter.
-Oh, hell no! You ain't burning me!
Okay. Okay. Okay.
You burn me, I'll kill you.
-Okay, okay, okay.
-All right.
-You all right? You okay?
-Yeah. I'm fine.
-What?
-Hold on. Put your arms up.
What are you doing?
Why are you going under my shirt?
-What are you doing?
-Jesus.
What, what? What is it?
What is it? What is it?
Anybody got a blowtorch?
Stop!
Careful.
-What's it--?
-lf that thing bit you...
...you would be lumpuh.
Paralyzed, like stone, for two days.
-What do you call this fella?
-Laba laba batu. Stone spider.
I may have discovered a valuable
new anesthetic agent for Wexell-Hall.
Oh, no, no, no. Forget Wexell,
we can get this to the highest bidder.
All right. Show and tell's over.
We gotta get to that boat.
Put your boots on and let's go.
Bugger it.
What the hell was that?
Holy bloody hell.
Whoa! What was that?
Oh, my God.
What the hell was that?
Come on.
No, no, no! Oh, come on, man!
What the hell happened?!
Livingston!
Here we go.
He got drunk and fell off
the bloody boat!
Your friend! Your friend!
Now what we gonna do now?!
Shit!
Search the wreckage.
Find anything we can use.
And hope to God there's a phone.
Come on, come on.
Yes.
Hello?
-Come on, come on!
-Anything?
-Nothing.
-Keep trying.
What do you think I'm doing, Jack?!
Hello? Shit.
Hello?
Come on, man. Hello?
All right, keep looking!
No phone?
-Nothing.
-Couldn't get a signal on the radio.
Now what?
What's going on?
Where'd these come from?
-Lopaks.
-Who?
Local tribe.
-Descended from headhunters.
-What?
Been in this region
for thousands of years.
-Headhunters?
-There's still some villages here.
-Must be one of their fishing spots.
-Hold on, excuse me.
Did you say headhunters?
There haven't been practicing
headhunters in Borneo for a century.
Just because they ain't practicing
don't mean they don't remember how.
They must be along this branch
of the river.
If we can find their village,
maybe they can lend us a boat.
So wait a minute. We just gonna walk
towards the headhunters, not away?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, that makes sense.
Oh, God. I'm so hungry, I'd sell
my grandmother for a Tic Tac.
You mention food one more time...
...I'm voting you off this island.
Oh, God.
-ls that--?
-Livingston.
Oh, my God, man.
What the hell happened to him?
Anaconda.
If he was eaten by the snake...
-...why is his body--?
-Listen, listen!
All right. These things are
at their weakest when they digest.
But if threatened, they will spit up
their food and attack again.
What? There's a snake out there
with an empty stomach?
-Yeah.
-The same one that got Ben?
No. No. There's no way that snake
could've gotten to Livingston.
-lt had to be another one.
-You said there wouldn't be...
-...another one for miles.
-There wouldn't.
-Unless....
-Unless what?
-Unless it's mating season.
-Oh, my God.
-Mating season?
-Yeah.
You see, the males are territorial,
but when they smell a female in heat...
...they come running
from everywhere.
Females find a nice, wet, muddy pit,
and they all go after her at once...
...in one big mating ball.
So there's some snake orgy
out in the jungle?!
Yeah. Something like that.
Look, we're losing the light.
All we gotta do is get to that village.
So please, pay attention.
Do not stray from the group.
Let's go.
Stay quiet. Sacred burial ground.
Jesus.
I thought you said that anaconda
was the biggest you'd ever seen.
It was.
-Well, this one's....
-Bigger.
The males must've come through here
looking for the female.
Some bullshit.
-They took their boats.
-Good for them.
Bad for us.
Which one's the Mendranang?
On the right.
The Tokut keeps going to the left.
-Fastest way to Kotabaru.
-How long?
You'll be soaking in a tub
at the Four Seasons in two days.
How, man?
We don't even have a boat.
We're gonna build one.
Man, do that in my neighborhood,
and that's your ass.
Shit.
Sam.
What does this look like to you?
My God.
Perrinia immortalis.
Now we know why these snakes
are so big.
What?
Anacondas keep growing
till they die, right?
And these are the biggest
Bill's ever seen.
-Because they're living longer.
-Exactly.
Because Perrinia immortalis
is part of the food chain.
These snakes have transcended
the Hayflick limit.
The chemical in the orchid
does exactly what we predicted.
And not in theory, in the real world.
This is proof, Sam,
of your research, carved in stone.
This is proof?
It's anecdotal evidence at best.
-Let's get to the orchid and find out.
-You are out of your mind.
Do you have any idea
how close we are?
The orchid was found here...
...on the Mendranang,
just around the next bend.
-We'll be going right past it.
-No, we won't.
We are going down the Tokut.
If we go down the Mendranang,
it's gonna be a week...
...before we reach another village.
I'm not waiting that long for my bath.
Yeah, well, it's not up to you.
Jack.
Maybe you can just come back.
Come back?
In seven years?
What if it's not here?
What if some local farmer decides
to slash and burn the entire basin?
Instead of the fountain of youth,
we'll have a giant rice paddy.
This is our only chance.
You know it is.
Do you wanna give in
when we're this close?
Look. You know
I got your back, right?
We've been in the trenches
a hundred times together.
-But I'm not going in that jungle.
-Damn straight, man.
Thank you.
This is my expedition,
and we're going to the orchid.
No.
We're not.
Don't be an idiot, Sam.
This is bigger than penicillin,
for God's sake.
Lives will be saved by this drug.
People will live longer.
They'll stay young longer.
If we don't put this to human trials,
it'll be a crime against humanity.
Two people have died already.
Scientists have always risked
their lives to change the world.
If they didn't, we wouldn't have cures
for yellow fever, polio and smallpox.
-We all knew the risks.
-We thought we did.
Until you decided to start making
decisions behind our backs.
-What are you talking about?
-He offered Bill an extra 50 grand...
...to keep going, even though
he knew it wasn't safe.
Oh, my God.
Is that true, Jack?
-I was thinking of the expedition.
-You were thinking of your career.
Look. You're my assistant.
I don't need to consult you!
I'm the one with the authority here.
We're in the middle
of the jungle, Jack.
At this point, your authority
is what we say it is.
Guess you got a mutiny
on your hands.
Thank you.
Okay. Keep it high.
Careful.
Center it right here.
All right.
What are you doing?
Never seen a man shave before?
Probably a lot sharper
before you attacked that alligator.
Crocodile.
What's that mean?
That means "a new beginning."
It's Korean.
I got it when I was in the military.
What brought you here?
-Long story.
-Where am I gonna go?
All right.
Here's the deal.
I was in the Special Forces...
...and I saw and did things...
...that I wanted to forget.
Sometimes we do the wrong things
for the right reasons, you know?
It's not very long, as stories go.
Yeah.
Well, I got out of the military...
...came here and bought
the Bloody Mary.
Just wanted to start a new life.
Thank you, Jack.
On three.
Ready? One, two, three.
It works.
All right.
Let me explain.
Why in the hell didn't you tell me
about this?
The minute someone makes a call...
...this expedition's over.
Exactly.
All I'm asking for
is a few more hours.
We continue on the Mendranang...
...take our orchid samples,
then we call for help.
Forget about it, Jack.
I'm getting us out of here.
Think about this, Gordon.
You're about to become a billionaire.
Do you really want to give all that up?
I don't care about the money,
all right?
I wanna live.
It bit me.
Jack, what are you...?
What are you...?
Help.
Help me.
Where's Mitchell?
Resting his feet.
-Should I go get him?
-No, no.
-Let him rest till we get loaded.
-Okay.
Those blisters are pretty nasty.
Mitchell...
...you okay?
Mitchell?
What is it?
Tell me.
What did you do to him, Jack?
-What is it?
-Something's wrong with Mitchell.
-What are you talking about?
-You were alone with him.
What did you do?
He was resting his feet.
I didn't do anything.
-Shit.
-Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Gail, no! Let's go!
Get out! Get out! Go!
Come on! Come on!
Move! Move! Move! Go!
The raft!
No! You son of a bitch!
We can build another one.
With what?!
With what, Sam?!
We gotta get to the raft.
-It's our only way out of here.
-FYl, Bill, the raft is gone!
-We can get it back.
-How?!
How? We gonna swim
after it now?
Look...
...the village is here.
Jack is following
the Mendranang.
We cut across the jungle.
-We can catch him on the other side.
-Right.
-Catch him where?
-He's going to that orchid.
We find that flower...
...we find that raft.
Oh, thank God. It's Jack Byron.
Listen, something terrible
has happened.
We took the wrong way
on the Mendranang.
We went over a waterfall.
I haven't seen anyone since.
I am....
I think I'm the only one left.
Wait, wait. Listen.
Oh, shit. Come on!
It's in front of us.
Son of a bitch.
It's trying to separate us.
Oh, shit.
-Oh, Christ, it's everywhere.
-Turn that goddamn thing off.
-They can see it.
-Doesn't matter.
-They can sense our body heat.
-He's right.
Let's just get the hell out of here.
-Which way?
-Hold on.
Any way.
-Let's go, Cole!
-Okay, okay!
-Wait for me!
-Come on!
Hold on, wait for me!
Oh, my God.
If there's a way in, there's a way out.
Oh, shit!
-Guys?!
-Cole!
Which way?!
Over here!
-All right, say it again! Say it again!
-Cole! Over here!
Over here, Cole!
-Hello!
-This way, Cole!
-Guys!
-Cole!
Oh, my God. Oh, God.
God, come on!
Cole!
Oh, no, no!
Stay together.
Okay. I promise.
Now can we please go?
-Let's go.
-No problem. Okay, okay.
Which way?
-I don't know.
-What?
What do you mean,
you don't know?
I found you, didn't l?
Tran?
Tran!
Say something!
Oh, shit! Guys! Guys!
I can see light.
-ls there a way out?
-I don't know.
Cole!
Tran!
Can you hear me?
Cole!
Where are you?
I think I found a way out.
Take this. Go. Now.
-Where are they?
-Go.
Oh, my God.
Go.
-Help!
-Cole?
-Hey, right here!
Almost there.
Holy shit!
Move! It's coming up my ass!
Help me! What did I do?!
Where's Cole?
-Cole, come on!
-Cole! Come on!
-Give me your hand.
-Oh, God! I'm stuck!
-Give me your--
-I'm stuck! Pull me!
-Give me your arm!
-Hurry up! Come on!
Oh, my God! It's coming!
Let's go! Pull!
Pull!
That's what I'm talking about, Sam!
Oh, my God! You're the bomb, Sam!
You Lorena Bobbitt-ed that ass!
How you like her now, bitch?!
She sliced you, diced you,
cut you up!
Sam with the samurai action!
Hell, no.
Cole!
Get up, Cole. Get up, man.
Wake up, man.
Come on, man. Wake up.
No, no, no.
Cole. He's not breathing!
-He's got a pulse.
-Give him air!
Okay.
Again, again!
Come on, wake up!
Don't you die!
Don't die. Come on, no.
What the fuck?! Get it off me!
-No, no. It's okay! It's okay!
-Hey, it's okay.
It's me. Stay down.
-You're okay.
-I'm okay?
-Yeah.
-You're okay.
Perrinia immortalis.
-Son of a bitch finally got his orchid.
-Yeah. He can have them.
All I care about is that raft.
Let's go.
Oh, my God. Thank God.
I think I know what happened
to Mitchell.
I can't let you take that.
You guys look like hell.
-You don't know what hell is.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-But you gave me no choice.
-Did you give Mitchell one...
-...before you killed him?
-I didn't kill Mitchell.
No...
...you just let him die.
I saw the spider bite
on his arm.
What was I supposed to do, Sam?
-The right thing?
-It's always a good place to start.
Let's not be stupid about this.
Let's get to the flower,
we can all go home.
The mating ball.
Give me the flare.
Tie him up.
Now!
-Fill it up.
-You've gotta be kidding me.
Do I look like I'm kidding?!
Fill it up!
Get up!
-Now get the flowers.
-Okay.
Throw me the pack.
Drop the gun!
Get up, Bill! Get up!
Come on, man!
Get up!
-Sam, come on!
-Sam! Come on!
-Come on, girl! Hurry up!
-Come on!
-Sam! Come on!
-Come on! Hurry up, Sam!
-Come on, baby!
-You got it, honey, come on!
Shit!
-Come on, baby.
-You got it!
-You got it, honey!
-Almost there! Come on!
-Spider....
-Reach for me!
Come on, Sam, please!
Just reach! Reach!
Give me your hand.
-Come on!
-Right here, Sam! Right here!
No! No! No!
No!
Oh, God!
Come on, Sam! Come on!
-Keep coming!
-Come on!
Climb up that wall, Sam!
Keep coming.
Come on, girl!
-Come on!
-Come on. I got you!
Come on, Sam, get back!
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Hey!
Over here, bitch!
Holy shit.
Nice shot.
What can I say?
I'm a bad man.
You two look like you made up.
He's not so bad.
How's that?
Much better.
I think I'll live.
Good.
It's kind of nice having you around.
-So how much further to my bath?
-Kotabaru?
I'd say...
-...another day downriver.
-Another day?
-I'm not rowing another day, homeboy.
-All right.
Let's see, we got this shortcut
right up--
No!
Subtitles by
SDl Media Group