[Church bells ring in distance]
[Child singing in Spanish]
[Dramatic instrumental music]
[Rifle clicks and echoes]
[Child singing in Spanish, background]
[Pigeons squeal]
[Thunder rumbling]
[Birds chirping]
KETCHAM: Son of a bitch!
When I first saw you, I wasn앖 scared.
Just wondered why you wore those boots.
Now I know.
KETCHAM: Shit!
[Cackling]
KETCHAM:
We았e both played this game, Rath.
What kind of shoes will you be wearing...
...when your day comes?
I앏l double the contract.
Say you couldn앖 find me.
Listen to me.
I앐 talking like a mark!
[Gun clicks]
KETCHAM: Oh, God. Don앖 pull yet.
Not yet.
KETCHAM: I았e killed a few innocents
in my time.
Youre so high and mighty!
You and your principles!
KETCHAM: Someone had to do
the jobs you wouldn앖 do.
I can앖 die like this!
I앐 not a mark.
Not like a mark.
[Sobbing]
It압 chambered.
Thanks, Rath.
Good-bye, old friend.
[Gunshot]
[Duck whines]
[Thunder rumbles]
[Siren wails, background]
[Digital beeping]
[Rapid digital dialing]
[Phone ringing]
[Beeping]
I don앖 care what you believe. I았e had it.
I want out. I quit.
Go away, you son of a bitch.
You should be.
[Continuous beeping]
REPORTER 1 :
The attention is not for the man...
...being buried,
but for one of the mourners.
REPORTER 1 : Just arriving is reclusive
billionaire Alan Branch...
...attending the funeral of his brother,
who died in an auto accident.
REPORTER 2: Branch was last seen
testifying before the Senate 10 years ago...
...for his alleged financing of...
REPORTER 2: ...right wing death squads
throughout South and Central America.
Branch was born in Queens, New York,
and, as you can see...
...from the wheelchair,
the victim of a hit man압 bullet.
10 years ago Alan Branch was brought
before the Senate and questioned...
REPORTER 1 : ...about his alleged
involvement in money-laundering...
...drug trafficking
and death-squad financing.
[Male operatic voice singing,
"Ave Maria" in Latin]
[Wagon squeaking]
PRIEST: Let us pray.
Lord Jesus Christ...
...by the 3 days you lay in the tomb...
...you made holy the graves
of all who believe in you.
Though their bodies lie in the earth,
they trust that they will rise again.
Bless this grave, Lord,
and give Samuel peaceful rest....
[Birds chirping]
[Multiple silenced gunshots]
My God!
[Woman screams]
BODYGUARD: He압 been shot!
[Woman shrieking]
[Scattered yelling]
[Man grunts]
[Silenced gunshots]
[Shots ricocheting softly]
[Loud gunshot]
[Multiple silenced shots popping]
Come on, you little bastard, be brave.
Run for it.
[Mockingly] Ooh, oh-oh.
[Mumbling gibberish]
[Sirens blaring]
COP 1 : Put it down!
Fuck.
COP 1 : Throw the gun away!
COP 1 : On the ground!
COP 1 : Face down!
All right!
COP 1 : Throw it away!
COP 2: Don앖 move!
COP 2: Hands behind your back!
[Whispering] What압 he doing?
[Handcuffs clicking]
COP 2: Check him for more weapons.
COP 1 : Where is it?
COP 1 : Don앖 worry.
BAIN: I앐 not worried.
COP 2: There.
COP 1 : The area압 secure.
[Breathing heavily]
Nice to meet you.
[Chuckles]
COP 3: Come on, let압 go.
Right through here!
[Sirens wailing]
[Tires screech]
COP 3: Come on! Let압 go, let압 go!
Wait. Ambulance, let압 go!
[Rath honks horn]
Hold it!
COP 3: #1, move it out!
COP 3: #2, come on!
COP 3: Get out of here!
[Sirens wailing]
DISPATCHER ON RADIO:
What is the disposition ofyour suspect?
COP 1 : 1 Bravo 5.
COP 1 : Were proceeding to the precinct...
COP 1 : ...suspect in custody.
DISPATCHER: Roger. I show you en route
to the precinct with one suspect.
COP 4: Look.
COP 1 : Watch it.
[Bain muttering in Spanish]
[Truck roars]
[Knuckles cracking]
[Glass shattering]
COP 4: Look out!
[Neck snaps]
[Tires screech]
[Crash]
[Bain screams]
[Siren stops]
[Tires screech]
[Bain grunts]
COP 5: Oh, my god!
BAIN: Don앖 fucking try it!
[Gun clicks]
[Siren blares]
COP 5 ON RADIO: Officers down.
COP 5: Victoria Ave. 2700 block.
[Tires screeching]
COP 5: Repeat...
...officers down.
[Gunshots popping]
[Siren blaring, Cop 4 screaming]
[Thunderous crash]
DISPATCHER ON RADIO:
1 Bravo 3, what압 your status?
[Tires screeching]
DISPATCHER: 1 Bravo 3, please respond.
[Tires squeal]
DISPATCHER: All units, officers down.
DISPATCHER: Repeat, officers down.
[Fierce growling and barking]
DISPATCHER: All units, suspect in the four-
officer-down call is still at large.
Male Hispanic, thirty years,
armed and dangerous.
Monitor all bus stations and the airport.
[Sirens echoing]
[Thud]
CABBIE: Goddamn it!
You okay?
I just got this car!
RATH: I앐 sorry. Are you okay?
What압 it going to take?
I don앖 have insurance.
Take it.
RATH: I앐 sorry.
TAXI DISPATCHER:
Who압 near Denny Way and 5th?
We have a couple going to Crown Hill.
Who압 near Christina압?
We have a man going to the airport.
RATH: 501, I앐 there.
TAXI DISPATCHER: Pick up three sailors,
pier 91, take 안m downtown.
Come on. Be the right one.
[Gun clicks]
MAN: Taxi!
RATH: I앐 booked.
MAN: We saw it first!
Airport.
You got it.
You got a cut on your head. You see that?
I had an accident at work.
What kind of work do you do?
I am, how do you say...
...dead tired.
So, save the chitchat for someone else.
RATH: [Chuckles] Okay.
Chitchat.
I haven앖 heard that word for a long time.
TAXI DISPATCHER:
Cab 117, pick up at Lincoln Park.
BAIN: Whatre you doing?
RATH: What?
There was a turnoff.
I앐 sorry.
You blew your tip.
Think I앐 trying to run you up?
Just do your job.
RATH: [Yelling]
I never ran up a fare in my life!
BAIN: Do your job!
Get out.
BAIN: What?
You think I앐 running you up?
Just get out.
You can앖 just....
The hell I can앖.
Out.
RATH: Find another cab.
[Bain chuckles]
BAIN: I don앖 believe this.
[Mumbles in Spanish]
Robert...
...Rath.
You can앖 shoot me through the glass.
Bulletproof.
So, I get out...pow...
...you got me.
No.
So...
...now what?
Who are you, kid?
Robert Rath...
...wants to know me.
I don앖 believe this.
Bain.
Miguel Bain.
Let me see. You rolled some cabbie...
...then waited for the right call.
That압 genius, man.
Then you got the balls to bullshit with me.
No way I could have done that.
You stole my contract.
How앇 you know of it?
A silenced...
...Ruger .22.
Classic.
You know, I switched...
...when I heard you used one.
Excuse this.
It was a long shot.
But a good one.
Wasn앖 it?
Who압 your contractor, Miguelito?
Why don앖 you drive?
We can get acquainted.
Chitchat.
Let압 sit.
Okay?
[Automatic window hums]
[Muttering gibberish]
[Rifle clicks]
[Referee압 whistle blows]
[Whispering] Drive.
Number 13 looks tired.
BAIN: Maybe she needs a rest.
[Whispering] Drive.
Drive.
BAIN: Drive, drive, drive, drive....
[Bain giggling]
Protect the innocent.
BAIN: That압 weak.
You could았e had me at the cemetery
but you couldn앖 shoot the cops.
You are anticuado.
[Glass pops]
[Bain cackling]
I had to try! Who knows?
Maybe it wasn앖 made in America!
[Thud]
BAIN: Oh! Whoa, whoa.
[Sirens screaming]
Ooh.
They look pissed, huh?
RATH: They get that way
when you kill 4 of them.
How do you like the cemetery?
Rome, 14 B.C.
They killed a general, Flavius,
at his brother압 funeral.
I couldn앖 wait for Branch압 brother to die,
so I killed him too.
Proud of me, Bobby?
[Rath laughing]
Well....
It was nice meeting you.
Someday, I앏l tell my little ni籍s
about this wonderful encounter.
[Violent shattering]
[Tires screeching]
[Truck horn moans]
[Silenced gunshots]
[Car horns honking]
Shit!
[Bain screaming]
[Loud gunshot, glass shattering]
[Crashing]
[Tires squealing]
[Silenced shot pops]
[Bain grunts]
BAIN: Ah, fuck!
RATH: Who압 your contractor, kid?
[Bain grunts and yells]
[Engine revving and accelerating]
BAIN: [Yelling] You blew it!
I am still alive!
[High-pitched cackling]
[Car horn honking]
Not for long.
[Sirens screaming]
[Giggling]
[Tires screeching]
What are you doing?
BAIN: What the hell are you doing?
Watch it!
BAIN: You앏l get us killed!
Let압 get them.
COP 6:
2 Robert 2, in pursuit of Yellow Cab, 501 .
DISPATCHER: ln pursuit. Request backup.
COP 8: 2 Robert 3 responding.
DISPATCHER:
All units, Yellow Cab number 501...
...stolen near vicinity of officers down.
PILOT: 10-4, Regional Air responding.
DISPATCHER:
Regional Air hasjoined the pursuit.
DISPATCHER: Suspects considered
armed and dangerous.
Robert 2, received.
[Sirens blaring]
Turn here!
BAIN: I know this area!
BAIN: Hit it!
[Bain cackling]
Don앖 give any more advice.
PILOT: This is Regional Air. Were heading
over to the Michigan Viaduct.
All units, maintain your positions.
We앏l box him in.
COP 6: Don앖 lose him.
PILOT: This is Regional Air. We copy.
BAIN: I studied everything you ever did.
Goddamn it, you were good!
You and the Russian, Nicolai Talinkov.
Tachlinkov.
Yes.
BAIN: You know, they say
he압 living on some Greek island.
But I say, you were the best!
I say, Nicolai압 dead as a doornail!
Am I right, Bob?
I heard you guys played chess coded
in the New York Times obituaries.
Ten fucking miles of microfilm!
But I found it! I found it!
BAIN:
The last game ends before anyone wins!
BAIN: He thought you were his friend.
And now I know, that압 how you took him.
You killed him to be number one.
[Cackling]
Psst!
[Whispering] Bishop...
...takes rook pawn.
[Truck horn blares]
[Tires screech]
[Bain grunts]
[Sirens scream]
DISPATCHER: All units, Regional Air has
a visual. Repeat. Regional Air has a visual.
Suspect headed east on Sycamore St.
[Propellers pelting]
[Crashing]
[Car horns honking]
DISPATCHER:
Regional Air, do you have a visual?
PILOT: We got him!
[Tires squeal]
We don앖 got him.
[Sirens wailing]
[Chopper humming]
RATH: [Whispering] What is he talking
about, "Bishop takes rook pawn"?
COMPUTER: [Digital voice]
Replay game. Game started May 5, 1980.
15 years, and I still remember this game.
It압 like yesterday.
COMPUTER: White pawn to King 4,
Red pawn to King 4....
COMPUTER: White Knight to King
Bishop 3, Red Knight to Queen Bishop 3....
I hate to admit it,
but youre the world압 best.
Yeah, I remember that one.
COMPUTER: White Knight takes Knight.
Enter next move.
Let압 see what the kid knows.
COMPUTER: Enter next move.
Bishop takes...
...rook pawn.
COMPUTER: D6, H2.
COMPUTER: Check, game in check.
[Rifle clicks]
A mark.
I앐 a goddamn mark.
[Background sound of gunshot]
Miguel Bain.
Don앖 play with me now.
Are you setting me up?
Is this how it went, Nicolai?
That압 it. I앐 gone.
[Whispering] Wherere you going?
Wherere you going?
RATH: $2 million and I앐 out of here.
I앐 gone.
Seattle.
Surveillance expert.
Buyers.
[Computer buzzing]
RATH: The mark. Who압 the mark?
[Sixties rock song playing]
[Giggling] Here you go, Pearl.
Here you go.
No, thanks. I won앖 have any.
I앐 just going to have some coffee.
[Hair dryer humming]
Oh! You know what? I forgot to tell you.
We got our pictures.
Let압 see what we have here.
This is good. I like this one.
It압 your good side. Look.
That압 not so bad.
And you say you don앖 photograph well.
BOB: I don앖 have time
to talk about this right now.
JENNIFER: You never have time
to talk about it!
BOB: That is not true!
BOB: [Yelling]
But now is not a good time!
JENNIFER: I wanted to talk
about this last night and you didn앖!
BOB: I had to get my sleep!
[Woman singing opera, background]
ELECTRA:
Hi, Mrs. Slattery. What you making?
JENNIFER ON TV:
Every time we start talking about this we--
BOB ON TV: Why앇 you bring it up?
Guys...
...what are you doing?
BOB ON TV: Don앖 walk away,
because were going to have it out.
[Pager beeping]
Youre not helping matters here.
Youre not.
JENNIFER ON TV: Stop it!
BOB ON TV: Youre so concerned
about what your mother thinks.
[Whispers] Jesus.
[Jennifer screaming and sobbing]
BOB ON TV: You want to slam doors?
[Phone beeps as dialed]
ELECTRA: [Whispers] Ah, Jennifer....
WOMAN: Room 115.
I have the disk.
WOMAN: The buyers arrive at noon.
Flight 1055.
I앏l attempt contact at 12:30
and every 15 minutes after that.
WOMAN: Do you have hard copy images?
Yes. What do I call the principal?
WOMAN: Call him Remy.
How앏l they know?
ELECTRA: They앏l know.
Try and trace that one, baby.
[Jennifer sobbing]
Poor baby.
ATTENDANT: Hi. Welcome.
How are you today?
ELECTRA: Here압 twenty dollars.
Keep the car handy.
Great. Is there anything else
I can do for you?
ELECTRA: No thanks, pal.
ATTENDANT: Let me get your ticket here.
ATTENDANT: Need help with your bags?
ELECTRA: No, I got it.
ATTENDANT: You need your ticket.
Here압 your ticket. Thanks.
[Elevator rings]
I hated that restaurant.
What a terrible place.
I didn앖 like anything about it.
All those foreigners.
What an awful, awful restaurant.
WOMAN:
Don앖 make another reservation there.
You can certainly find a better spot.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Fourth floor.
[Elevator rings]
Youre welcome, baby. My pleasure.
INTERCOM: Arriving passenger Remy,
please go to a white courtesy phone.
INTERCOM: Passenger Remy,
[Jet hissing in distance]
This is Remy.
Are you ready to go shopping on
the Home Network? Price is $40,000.
Where are you?
Are you ready? Yes or no.
Yes.
The Marriott Hotel. There are pay
phones across from the elevators.
You았e got 20 minutes,
give or take 10 seconds.
[Ambient airport noise]
Cut your hair.
RATH: Taxi!
[Dramatic instrumental beat]
[Elevator rings]
[Phone rings]
Hello.
ELECTRA: Good, youre early.
Get the Yellow Pages.
Right.
Lonely?
ELECTRA: ln town on business?
Check the escorts.
Got it.
Room 718. I smell a rat...
...the disk and I are gone.
We simpatico?
Simpatico, yes.
[Elevator rings]
RATH: Hold the elevator, please.
Damn.
RATH: Sorry.
MAN: Excuse me.
RATH: lt압 okay.
Maintenance.
Operator.
I앇 like to report a problem
on the 12th floor. Electricity압 out.
[Elevator rings]
AUTOMATED VOICE: Fourth floor.
MAN: Pardon me.
The 12th floor? What room?
I앏l check the circuit breakers.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Seventh floor.
BAIN: Excuse me. Sorry.
I앇 like to make a reservation.
Buyers, seller,
let압 see if they booked multiple rooms.
Come out, wherever you are.
[Lock clicks]
718.
[Computer beeps]
ELECTRA: Hey, fellas, slow down.
ELECTRA: Relax.
First, I앏l need a $10,000 deposit.
That wasn앖 the deal.
Then we have nothing to discuss.
REMY: Wait. Hang on.
REMY: Okay.
ELECTRA: Here압 today압 menu.
One second...
...I must put in a disk.
REMY: All right, it압 in.
[Computer beeping]
Where do you want the 10 thousand?
[Muffled buzzing and clicking]
ELECTRA: There압 a screwdriver on
the table. Then you앏l find a conveyance.
RATH: Chicago Bulls. Good team.
Twenty rooms.
No. No.
Katz. Two rooms: 718, 542.
Paid in cash.
Let압 check out the room service.
[Bain humming]
[Toy truck rattling]
BAIN: Hi.
MAN: Hi.
[Silenced shots pop]
[Bain humming]
BAIN: Twin 9 millimeters.
RATH: Room 718, nothing. Room 542....
Coffee, coffee, coffee, coffee...
...tuna fish.
RATH: Tuna fish?
Meow.
Here it comes.
[Truck buzzes]
Look out, Pearl!
Yes!
Pennies from heaven.
Baby, you keep this warm for me.
[Pearl meows]
ELECTRA: I앐 going to format your disk,
orient it to receive the data.
You getting this, Hans Brinker?
[Fly buzzing]
[Computer beeping]
Interpol.
[Sighing and muttering]
[Phone beeping as dialed]
[Pearl meows]
[Rapid typing on computer]
Next.
[Pager beeping]
REMY: Telephone?
BUYER 2:
[Dutch accent] It come from here.
BUYER 2: This is not my beeper.
[Door crashes open]
[Multiple silenced shots popping]
[Bain yelling in Spanish]
Interpol.
Hey! What압 going on?
ELECTRA: Hello? Can you hear me?
Hans Brinker, Mr. Dutchman, talk to me.
I앐 not kidding.
ELECTRA: Hello?
Please complete the transmission.
[Whispering] Who is this?
Who is this?
Please complete the transmission.
Shit!
[Keys clicking, computer beeping]
No, wait.
Fuck.
Honey...
...I앏l tear your heart out.
Holy Mary.
Let압 get you your case.
Don앖 do this to me.
We must go. Come on.
Shit!
Pearl, come on. Come on, please.
Don앖 do this.
[Breathing heavily]
Pearl, come on.
[Pearl meows]
[Electra gasps]
[Electra yelps]
Don앖!
Don앖?
Don앖 what?
Rath...
...is that you?
[Bain chuckling]
The disk.
BAIN: lt압 you.
Disk.
BAIN: You tried the move.
Bishop takes rook pawn.
It압 a powerful move.
Would have been Nicolai압 move.
Don앖 you think?
You got a move for me, Rath?
Huh?
You know, it압 like chess.
Is she alive?
BAIN: Did you kill her?
BAIN: Did you kill my mark?
[Chuckling]
Are you there, sweetie?
542.
Is she dead yet, Bobby?
BAIN: I took care of business on my end.
Did you?
[Electra shrieks]
[Bain cackles]
BAIN: A woman.
It압 not the same as killing a man.
You have to pull the trigger
a different way.
Is she beautiful, Bobby?
Pull the trigger. Kill her.
[Whispering] Come on. Do it. Do it.
Pull the trigger.
[Electra sobbing]
Pull the trigger. Kill her. Be professional.
BAIN: Kill her.
[Silenced shots pop, Electra yells]
[Giggling] Ooh, ooh....
It압 my beeper.
[People chattering, background]
MAN: Hey!
RATH: Go on.
RATH: Where압 your car?
I don앖 remember where it압 parked.
ATTENDANT: I got your car right here.
[Tires screeching]
ATTENDANT: That압 all right. I got it.
[Tires screech]
[Laughs]
[Engine roars]
[Digital dialing beeps]
ELECTRA: Who the hell are you?
A government employee.
Bullshit.
Just drive and don앖 speed.
Where?
You앏l know when we get there.
[Computer keys clicking]
RATH: Slow down.
I can앖, I앐 too nervous.
This other guy,
does he work for the government too?
It압 between you and him, right?
Just leave me out of it.
We can앖.
Youre the mark.
[Engine revving, tires squealing]
[Crash]
[Car horns honk]
MAN: Take it easy!
[Man groans]
Hey! My cat!
[Car horns honking]
My cat!
[Bus rumbles]
[Traffic noise, sirens wail in distance]
Damn!
Oh, yes!
[Door bells jingle]
CLERK: Hello!
RATH: Hi.
Pearl, come out, don앖 be afraid.
Why are you here? How are you?
Where압 her mama?
I was going to ask you that.
BAIN: Thank you, pussycat.
Cold.
BAIN: Cold.
Hot.
So that압 where you live.
BOB ON TV: I really love you.
BAIN ON TV: I love you, too.
[Electra screams]
Baby!
[Pearl meows]
Where is he?
BAIN: You sick bitch.
Downstairs.
Do you want to live?
Give me your house keys.
Meet me at the pet shop.
[Bang of door being kicked]
[Thud]
[Dishes crash]
BAIN: Blank. Shit.
BAIN: Blank.
[Jennifer honks horn]
JENNIFER: Hi!
ELECTRA: Jennifer!
ELECTRA: Jennifer, wait!
[Horns honking]
Come on! Move it!
I앐 sorry!
Jasmine.
[Multiple silenced gunshots]
[Mirror smashes]
BAIN: Your gun is slow!
[Bain speaks in Spanish]
I앐 not the one shooting at mirrors.
Who do you think--
BAIN: Surprise.
[Jennifer gasps]
The disk.
The disk!
[Jennifer sobs in fear]
[Yelling] Wait, wait!
[Silenced gunshot,
Jennifer breathes heavily]
[Whispering] I said to wait. Shut up!
Disk.
[Whispers] Get out.
I got the buyers.
BAIN: Now, I beat you to the mark.
I앐 sorry...
...but I think I picked
the wrong guy to be my hero.
[Multiple silenced gunshots]
BAIN: Macho. Macho.
[Breathing heavily] You know...
...it압 my birthday.
BAIN: Today...
...I become number one.
And I got a present....
[Angry] Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
[Multiple shots, glass smashes]
Happy birthday.
[Hissing of gas pipe as it ignites]
Shit!
[Flames roar, glass smashes]
[Sirens blare, horns honk]
RATH: Goddamn it.
ELECTRA: The girl from downstairs,
I saw her come back here.
She압 not in her apartment. She could
be here somewhere. I must find her.
She압 dead.
[Sirens wail]
ELECTRA: Come here, Pearl.
Get back here.
Hello, Pearl.
Come here, girl.
She likes me.
She likes dead fish too.
What압 your name?
Robert Rath.
Right.
I앐 Electra.
Are you one of them?
Was.
Retired.
I don앖 believe you.
RATH: I told you...
...if I wanted to kill you...
...I would have already.
Look what she did.
It압 not loaded?
It압 loaded. It압 silenced.
Just shoot.
I could.
I앇 be 500 miles away
before they found you.
How압 that?
[Yelling] Stop! She doesn앖 like it!
I say she압 afraid she might hit you.
[Gunshots, smashing]
Sorry I have the gun?
ELECTRA: You think it was a mistake?
You think I앐 scared?
You don앖 know me!
-Youre wrong. I know--
-Shut up!
ELECTRA: Today was supposed to be
a good day.
Payday.
40 grand.
I was going to buy Pearl a boyfriend.
Now two people are dead.
ELECTRA: I앐 in way over my head.
I just want out.
You got the gun. The key압 on the dresser.
Go.
I don앖 have a social security number,
or a driver압 license.
I barely remember my real name.
I앐 a ghost. I앐 nobody.
I앏l disappear.
I found you. So did he. You can앖 hide.
I just want my life back.
That압 all.
I앐 sorry.
[Silenced gunshots, glass smashing]
RATH: I앏l take that.
I need to be alone.
I haven앖 spent this much
time with someone in years.
Neither have I.
Well, the disk....
You앏l get it.
[Rath chuckles]
[Mumbling]
Fuck you.
I don앖 care what you are.
Fuck you!
Then who the hell압 Miguel Bain?
Who the hell is Miguel Bain?
Christ.
[Pearl meows, toilet handle clinks]
[Voice of television reporter]
[Pearl meows]
RATH: Hello, Pearl.
ELECTRA: What앇 they say
about the shooting?
RATH: Nothing.
I don앖 need details, just in general.
-Nothing.
-Impossible.
Not really. Not if....
If what?
The CIA or lnterpol....
What압 on this?
It압 encrypted.
Breaking the code on my lap top
could take 200 or 300 years.
Aren앖 you a genius?
I am.
ELECTRA: I was the best.
If it was stored electronically, it was mine.
Was?
Yeah, I앐 retiring too.
I wish I had an insight...
...but it was anonymous,
an intercepted satellite transmission.
ELECTRA: Probably just industrial secrets.
There압 one bed.
ELECTRA: I guess you noticed that.
-It압 yours.
-You want the couch?
No, thanks.
A trick so you don앖 get comfortable?
Tie a string from your toe to the doorknob.
It opens in.
You wouldn앖 feel it.
Yeah, I got it. I understand.
[Pearl meows]
Pearl!
Thanks.
For what?
I don앖 know.
Saving my life, I guess.
How앇 you like to make $1 million?
ELECTRA: What do I have to do?
Nothing cheap, I hope.
What is it?
Tell you tomorrow.
I can앖 sleep.
Be patient.
What? Tell me.
Thanks for the chocolate.
ELECTRA: Good night.
ELECTRA: Forget something?
You be careful.
[Scattered noise, subway intercom]
[Passenger sings folk music]
[Tires screech]
INTERCOM: Stand back,
away from the doors.
INTERCOM: Please keep back
[Computer beeps and dials]
away from the doors.
[Rock song plays on radio]
[Subway roars]
[Car revs and squeals]
[Car horns honk]
I앐 right here.
[Horns honking]
[Subway screeches to a halt]
What압 going on?
ELECTRA: I앏l move!
[Dogs barking]
RATH: I hate that music.
ELECTRA: Let압 go.
ELECTRA: Got it? ls it all there?
[Static and distortion sounds]
Whatre you doing?
-Drive!
-What?
Drive, fast!
RATH: I mean, fast!
Get off this street!
[Tires screech]
RATH: Stop!
Hit it!
Go!
[Violent explosion]
No money, no disk.
What압 so funny?
I wasn앖 sure you앇 come back
so I switched the disks.
And all they have is file names.
-No, you didn앖.
-Yes, I did.
And they got bubkes. Zero, zilch...
...zot, nix, nada, dry hump, squirt...
...diddley-squat.
I read a slang dictionary once.
Keep reading.
Contractor tried to kill you.
ELECTRA: That압 not good.
ELECTRA: Come here, Pearl.
I have caviar for you.
Come here!
Good girl.
"Caviar" is not a Russian word.
RATH: lkra. I think the word is ikra.
How do you know?
I had a Russian friend, Nicolai.
He told me.
ELECTRA: Had a friend?
RATH: Yeah.
RATH: About 15 years ago he was taken.
He was killed?
[Gun clicks as loaded]
[Computer beeps]
Yes, I앐 still alive, you bastard.
RATH: Not this time.
Let압 see how valuable he thinks this is.
Three million?
Four?
RATH: More.
$20 fucking million?
Where do you suppose
this person is right now?
A mile away?
1,000 miles from here?
Never thought about it till now.
You quit your job,
you have thoughts you never had before.
Sounds like a mid-life crisis.
Youre right.
Twenty million dollars.
Were partners?
That압 $10 million apiece.
8. The bank keeps 20%%.
I thought I was a thief.
Passport?
12. Where to?
To the bank.
[Bain howls]
[Classical guitar plays Spanish tune]
What happened to the hotel?
CABBIE: They had a fire years ago.
Nobody had money to fix it.
-Wait here.
-Okay.
ELECTRA:
Keep the air on and watch my cat.
CABBIE: You got it.
ELECTRA: ls that our bank?
Where our money is?
What압 up there?
He앏l be.
[Crash as floor caves in]
RATH: Hug the wall.
ELECTRA: Careful.
RATH: Go light.
[Gun clicks as loaded]
ELECTRA: You okay?
RATH: Ten o앆lock tomorrow morning,
I앐 going in that bank.
He앏l be in the plaza somewhere,
in the crowd.
When he sees me go in,
he앏l make his move up here.
You앏l be in the cafe over there.
You앏l see him when he goes inside.
Then we wait.
We wait.
Tomorrow will be a long day for him.
He앏l begin to doubt himself.
He앏l think he missed me.
He앏l want to see whether
I앐 still in the bank.
Then it앏l be sunset...
...closing time.
He앏l get desperate...
...real desperate...
...but he must leave his rifle...
...inside.
He압 right-handed.
He won앖 take a pistol because
the doors have metal detectors...
...and he앏l be nervous.
When he압 out of sight...
...you come get the rifle.
He앏l shoot you before you go in.
He앏l wait for the prime shot.
When I come out.
He앏l want to see my eyes.
[Gunshot]
[Flapping of birds wings]
Whyre you so sure?
He loves history.
15 years ago...
...in this room...
...in this same window...
...I was here.
Oh, my God.
Your friend, Nicolai. He was taken.
You killed him.
[Classical guitar begins]
MERCHANT: Gracias.
BAIN: lt압 fine.
[Memorial parade singing religious song]
Who is it?
WAITER: Room service.
I didn앖 order room service.
ELECTRA: I did.
You should tell me these things.
Where should I put the tray?
Over here압 fine.
What압 going on outside?
The Day of the Dead.
Whatre the flowers for?
The families make a path from
their homes to the cemetery...
...with the flower petals...
...so the souls of the dead
can find their way home.
That압 nice.
Call me anytime for the tray.
Okay, gracias.
Gracias se籍r.
Sounds great, huh? Can we go?
No, he압 here now. I know he is.
So were staying in the hotel.
The enemy of fun.
I got you a beer.
ELECTRA: Hey, Pearl. Come here.
[Singing continues]
Electra....
I wish I could explain to you why...
...I killed Nicolai.
At the time it was
the right thing to do, but...
...I앐 sorry I did it.
It압 something I았e had
to live with for 15 years.
I used to wish it would happen to me...
...and that앇 be my way out.
Permanently.
But not any more.
Not since I met you.
Electra?
[Ceremonial music continues]
-Comprende ingl乶?
-No.
Too bad you don앖 understand English.
I would like to tell you how wonderful
this cemetery is. It압 gorgeous.
I love cemeteries. I really do. I really do.
Youre here, the next day youre there.
I put a lot of people down there.
A lot of people down there.
[Women giggle]
[All speak Spanish,
women speak with a tone of surprise]
[Bell rings]
Jasmine.
[Electra gasps]
[Laughing] lt압 all over the place.
[Silenced gunshot]
[Gun clicks as loaded]
I just killed your brother.
"Contract has been paid...
"...transferred to the specified account."
And her disk?
"You앏l be advised. Good-bye, Robert."
Good-bye.
Let압 get ready.
Don앖 lose this.
Two-way?
They saw you coming.
This is a piece of junk.
Tell me when he leaves the hotel,
I앏l tell you when he leaves the bank.
-What압 this for?
-Just in case.
No. I can앖 shoot anybody.
I can앖.
You almost shot me.
I aimed at the lamp.
Aim at him.
Ever play cowboys and lndians?
-Sure. Everybody did.
-And which were you?
An lndian.
-I was always an lndian.
-Always the lndian.
Just pretend he압 a cowboy...
...and pull the trigger.
Then pretend he gets up after.
But you must pull the trigger.
You았e got to.
I never depended on anyone in my life.
I앐 depending on you.
[Ambient street noise]
I don앖 see him.
ELECTRA:
I앐 looking all around the square.
RATH: I앐 in the bank.
RATH: Where do I go for transfers?
Oh, my God!
He압 here.
ELECTRA: He압 going to the hotel.
He압 almost at the door.
He압 going in. He압 going in.
That압 what we wanted.
Relax, try the decaf.
ELECTRA: He must be upstairs now.
Should I stay or go in?
No. Stay? Wait, wait. I앏l just wait.
It압 hot.
ELECTRA: Goddamn, it압 hot.
RATH: I앇 rather be out there than in here.
CLERK: May I help you?
RATH: I앐 expecting a transfer.
CLERK 2:
Se籍r, we have received your transfer.
I앇 like to close the account.
Today?
Close it today?
Right now.
-How would you like the funds?
-American currency.
Would you please step right over there.
I앏l be right back.
No problem.
Mr. Rath?
Youre aware there may be
a withdrawal fee.
Yes, I am.
This will take some time.
I았e got all day.
Take care of him.
BANK OFFICER: Please, follow me.
Right this way.
BANK OFFICER: You may sit right here.
Relax. We앏l get you some coffee.
What are you doing there?
Fuck!
[Bain breathes heavily]
RATH: Talk to me.
ELECTRA: No sign of him.
He압 just sitting up there, same as us.
RATH: I mean, talk to me.
Tell me some of that weird stuff you know.
ELECTRA: Tell you weird stuff.
Like what?
RATH: Tell me ajoke.
May I?
Sure.
Tell me something to distract me.
I앐 not getting paid.
RATH: Be generous.
Once upon a time...
...there was a little sparrow...
...who, while flying south for the winter,
froze solid...
ELECTRA: ...and fell to the ground.
To make matters worse,
a cow crapped on him.
But the manure was warm
and defrosted him.
So there he is, warm and happy
to be alive and he starts to sing.
A cat comes along...
...and he clears off the manure
and eats the little bird.
ELECTRA: The moral of the story is this:
Everyone who craps on you is
not necessarily your enemy...
...and everyone who gets you out of crap...
ELECTRA: ...is not necessarily your friend.
And if youre warm and happy...
...no matter where you are,
keep your big mouth shut.
[Rath giggles]
You like that?
ELECTRA:
I think I앐 running out of stories.
RATH: Keep your eye on that building.
He must be getting impatient.
He앏l make his move soon.
Thanks for the stories.
[Bain mumbles in Spanish]
Sorry I았e been taking up the table.
Thank you. Thank you.
[Bain gasps and mutters]
[Yelling] Fuck! Shit! Motherfucker!
Fuck! Shit!
BANK PRESIDENT: We have deducted
our fee and are making a second count.
The funds will be available in a half hour.
I hope you are comfortable.
[Shallow gasps] No, no...no.
Oh, my God. He압 coming.
ELECTRA: He압 coming.
He waited longer than I did.
ELECTRA: Here he is.
Go.
-I have your property.
-Be right there.
Where are you?
I앐 here in room 303.
[Bird squawks]
The rifle should be on the right.
If so, the gun is going to be right here.
It압 not.
What압 happening?
It압 not here.
Listen to me.
Get out now.
Damn it.
Forget the rifle. Get out.
RATH: Have you left?
Found it!
Damn hot day, isn앖 it?
Scorcher.
I got it.
Tell me...
...how did you know?
Who the hell taught you?
History.
Nicolai.
15 years ago I walked into this bank
just like you.
That makes you good...
...because I was the best.
Now you feel like a mark.
You think you were sold out.
Don앖 know who to trust.
And you, anticuado?
Who do you trust?
BAIN: No one.
BAIN: Youre alone. Same as me.
I don앖 have it!
I don앖 have the gun.
[Crash of floor caving in]
Why the sunglasses, kid?
Afraid I앏l see your eyes?
Just between you and me...
...I앐 nervous.
I have $16 million in there.
This is where we can change history.
Our history.
I앐 willing to give it to you...
...if you앏l let me walk.
But...
...you won앖 do that.
No.
Excuse me, but...
...you are...
...pathetic.
You sound like a mark.
BAIN: What happened to you?
Nothing. I know where youre going.
I tell you...
...that night in the taxi...
...I thought I was lucky just to be alive.
BAIN: Now...
...I think differently.
You were the lucky one.
I앐 a very, very lucky man.
No more chitchat.
Good luck.
Where are you? Talk to me.
ELECTRA: Can you hear me?
Fuck.
Everything is in order.
Please, come with me.
[Electra screams]
BANK PRESIDENT:
This is awkward. It압 not really my affair...
...but I was told you would
give us something in return.
Oh God, I앐 fucked. I앐 fucked.
Now...
...we are closed.
BAIN: Step outside.
Step outside...
...and I앏l set you free.
BANK OFFICIAL: Excuse me, sir,
would you please sign this receipt?
BAIN: I got the sword...
...right here.
There is no shame.
BAIN: You won앖 feel a thing.
Thank you for your business.
Youre welcome.
Here he is.
BAIN: Here he is.
Thank you.
We았e got it.
We did it.
Come on.
BAIN: Step outside.
Were in.
RATH: You there?
RATH: Where are you?
You there?
Can you hear me?
Look up.
BAIN: I want to see your eyes,
motherfucker.
BAIN: Look up.
Jasmine?
Howdy.
[Silenced gunshot, Bain groans]
[Wings flutter]
[Multiple gunshots]
[Thud, Bain screams]
[More silenced gunshots]
[Electra gasping]
RATH: Electra!
ELECTRA: [Yelling] Yes.
RATH: You have something of mine.
I need it now.
Shit!
BAIN: We got something for you here!
[Rapid gunfire, Rath gasps]
ELECTRA: What the fuck do I do with this?
BAIN: Two against one!
Is that your edge, Rath?
You didn앖 take the mark!
You took the bribe!
[Multiple silenced gunshots]
BAIN: [Yelling] Don앖 worry!
Don앖 worry, I앏l take her!
He압 serious, Rath!
Even the odds!
BAIN: Are you scared, honey?
I앐 going to find you!
[Electra screams]
BAIN: I told you I was going
to tear your heart out!
And I will!
I will!
I promise you that!
[Wings flutter]
[Silence]
[Bain yells, Electra gasps]
[Rapid gunfire]
[Bain wails]
[Thunderous smashing and crashing]
[More crashing]
RATH: Wait here.
I said, stay up there!
ELECTRA: I앐 not going to.
The floor could give way!
RATH: Goddamn it,
why don앖 you listen to me?
MALE VOICE: Don앖 move.
Throw it away.
Throw it away!
That was no way to talk to a lady.
Nicolai.
It압 been a long time.
The years have been good to you.
Miguelito?
Never pictured him so young. A shame.
Second best, after all.
He killed you...
ELECTRA: ...15 years ago.
Yes, he did.
ELECTRA: I don앖 understand.
Walking out of that bank was
the worst moment of my life.
He always went for the heart.
Predictable.
RATH: 15 years.
For 15 goddamn years...
...you let me think I앇 killed you.
Son of a bitch.
Youre forgetting you shot me.
You son of a bitch.
RATH: Why?
Why did you set me up?
The Cold War was ending.
I needed to die...
...to leave no past behind.
You delivered me.
Youre the mark?
You must be the contractor.
I앐 disappointed. You were to kill her.
NICOLAl: Youre a thief.
A good one.
I retired.
NICOLAl: You were so good.
I had to use both my best
to track you down.
There압 something on that disk
that would bring you to life?
NICOLAl: Enough information
to expose us all.
NICOLAl: Especially me.
Can앖 you kiss and make up?
NICOLAl: This is sad for me, Robert.
Sentimental, but...
...I did not want to find you alive.
NICOLAl: First things first.
[Multiple silenced gunshots]
Don앖 do this.
She압 right.
RATH: She always is.
Female intuition.
Where are you going?
BAIN: To finish something...
...you didn앖 finish years ago.
What?
[Silenced gunshot]
Just to make sure.
Take it.
Are you going to kill me?
RATH: I never wanted to kill you at all.
BAIN: Help me up.
Will you?
Don앖 even breathe hard.
You want to die?
Help me up.
Thank you.
Now what?
I앐 finished.
What do you mean?
The history stops here.
No more.
I앐 gone.
I quit.
That would make me number one.
Number one.
I can live with that...
...can you?
BAIN: Absolutamente, compa嫡ro.
Then live with it, Miguel.
Live with it.
BAIN: It was very nice meeting you...
...Robert Rath.
It was very dangerous meeting you,
Miguel Bain.
[Bain giggles]
BAIN: You know...
...as long as youre out there...
...I앏l never be number one.
BAIN: Say good-bye...
...Bobby.
ELECTRA: No good-byes.
Good-bye, Miguel.
[Silenced gunshots]
Thank you.
Wait a minute.
ELECTRA:
You앇 better keep the disk, Robert.
RATH: My real name is Joseph.
ELECTRA: I앐 Anna.
Nice to meet you, Joseph.
ELECTRA: So, Joseph,
let압 go get Pearl a boyfriend.
RATH: Sure. And after that, if you
don앖 mind, I앇 like to go to the hospital.
Subtitles conformed by SOFTITLER