In the beginning,
God created beast and man
so that both might live
in friendship
and share dominion
over a world at peace.
But in the fullness of time,
evil men betrayed God's trust,
and in disobedience
to His holy word
waged bloody wars,
not only
against theirown kind,
but against the apes,
whom they reduced to slavery..
Then God, in His wrath,
sent the world a savior,
miraculously born of two apes,
who descended on Earth
from Earth's own future.
And man was afraid,
for both parent apes possessed
the power of speech.
Come on!
Cornelius!
[Gunfire]
so both were brutally murdered.
But the child ape survived
and grew up to
set his fellow creatures free
from the yoke
of human slavery..
Do.
No!
Yet in the aftermath
of this victory.,
the surface of the world
was ravaged
by the vilest war
in human history..
The great cities of the world
split as under
and were flattened.
And out of one such city,
our savior led a remnant
of those who survived
in search of green erpastures,
where ape and human might
forever live in friendship
according to divine will.
His name was Caesar,
and this is hisstory.
in those far-off days.
You'll never
make it,Jake.
Nah, we'll make it.
I'll show you how.
Thanks, Aldo.
You will call me by
my proper rank--General!
Yes, General.
Don't put him
in the corral.
I won't be long.
Ape shall never kill ape.
Shall ape
ever kill man?
You're late, General Aldo.
Come and read this
to the class.
I won't.
You won't
because you can't,
and you can't because
you don't want to learn,
and it is my duty to
report this to Caesar.
[Growls]
If my father
were a gorilla,
we'd be learning
riding instead ofwriting.
[Laughter]
Silence.
Cornelius, you are
Caesar's son and heir.
Being a good rider isn't enough
for being a good ruler,
though in human history,
quite a number
of military dictators
seem to have thought so.
Now, all of you take up
your charcoal sticks
and your parchments
and copy down
what I've written.
The best shall be hung
from these hooks.
I can think of better things
to hang from those hooks.
But, Virgil, can we
tamper with time?
- Accept my premise.
-What premise?
That since man once learned
to travel faster than sound,
he could later have learned
to travel faster than light.
We accept.
Imagine a musician
giving a live broadcast
from what was once London
to what was once New York
on a Wednesday.
He then travels
faster than light
from London to New York,
where he arrives--as
physicists would confirm--
on the previous Tuesday,
Iistens to his own
broadcast on the Wednesday,
dislikes
its quality intensely,
then travels back
faster than light to London
in time for him to decide
not to give his broadcast.
Come. I'll prove it
to you logically.
Good, Cornelius,
butyou've made
a mistake here.
You have put a " B"
in place of
the second " P".
Teacher, have you
forgotten your own name?
Everyone has always called me
teacher that I had forgotten.
"Ape shall never
kill Abe."
Thank you, Cornelius.
That was a very kind thought.
Gorillas.
All right, Aldo,
Iet's start with you.
General Aldo.
With respect,
General Aldo,
this is barely legible
and will have to
be written again.
Your capital "A" Ieans over
like a tent in a high wind.
Ha ha ha!
And your capital " K"...
"Ape shall never
kill Abe."
No, Aldo! No!
Teacher!
Teacher, you've spoken
the unspeakable.
I n all ouryears
of slavery to mankind,
the word " no"
was the one word
we were electrically
conditioned to fear.
Caesar has forbidden you
its utterance in perpetuity.
An ape may say no
to a human,
but a human may never
again say no to an ape.
Tell him you're sorry,
Abe, and go home
while you've still
got a home to go to.
I'll put in a good word
foryou with Caesar.
General Aldo,
I'm sorry.
The writing you destroyed
was by Caesar's son.
I did not want you to
suffer Caesar's anger!
What do I care
for Caesar's anger?
Let me give you
a taste of mine!
Grab him!
Stop, teacher!
Stop!
Grab him.
Grab the teacher!
Stop!
We'll teach the
teacher a lesson.
Throw him in the corral,
where all humans belong.
I said stop, Aldo.
He broke the law.
With his own mouth,
he broke the first law.
I am the law.
What has he done?
Caesar, I was there.
Teacher only reverted
to type under provocation.
He spoke like a slave master
in the old days of our servitude.
When we were conditioned
to mechanical obedience.
He uttered
a negative imperative.
Could you put that
into words
which even Caesar
could understand?
Um, he said,
" No, Aldo. No."
[Grunts]
The schoolroom
was wrecked.
The class is ended.
The schoolroom
is closed!
Now we'll go back
to riding horses!
Aldo!
You and your friends
will return
to the schoolroom
and put it back
in order.
Abe, no gorilla
is to be dismissed
until everything
is back in its place.
Yes, Caesar.
Father, since there won't be
any more school today,
may I go out
and play?
Can't you study
in the house?
I could,
Father, but...
Run along and play.
Where are
my students?
I wasjust
in the midst
of explaining my theory
of time relativity.
If Caesar permits,
I would like my--
Caesar permits.
You look concerned,
MacDonald.
I am, Caesar.
I think
that Aldo's hatred
is not confined
to humans.
Look out!
I think Aldo may be
riding for a fall.
If only my mother
and father,
whom I was too
young to remember,
if only
they'd lived,
perhaps they would
have taught me
if it was right
to kill evil
so that good
should prevail.
But you know,
Caesar, history shows--
oh, no, no, no.
That is human history,
not ape history.
Ape never kills ape.
oh, here's the list
of our winter
supplies so far.
I've got to be
getting along.
I'm starving.
I could eat a horse.
A horse?
oh, you remember Lisa.
They used to eat
lots of things--
dead cattle, dead chickens,
dead pigs.
Now we live
and chew nuts
at our master's
command.
That will be all,
J ulie.
Thank you.
We are not
your masters.
We're not
your equals.
MacDonald, I believe that
when you truly grow to know
and trust a person,
you cannot help
but like him.
When we grow to know
and trust your people,
then we shall
all be equals
and remain so until
the end of the world.
Which may be sooner
than you think.
You are such a pessimist!
or a prophet.
Now that apes
are at the helm,
the Earth will sail
safely through space
until the end of time,
and Virgil says
time has no end,
so you see
I cannot believe you.
Would you believe it
if you heard it
from the lips
of your own parents?
Are my parents alive?
No, but their images
and their voices are.
MacDonald, when you talk
about my parents,
please do not speak
in riddles.
I cannot see them.
I cannot hear them.
They came out
of the future.
They cannot
give me knowledge.
Caesar,
you can see them.
You can hear them,
and they can
give you knowledge.
How?
Under the dead city
where we once lived
in the archives near
the old command post,
there are tapes--
sealed tapes--
of Cornelius and Zira
being examined by officials
of the American government.
When my brother was
Governor Breck's assistant,
he told me about them.
I know where they are,
and I know that they
concern Earth's future,
from which
your parents came.
But the city
was flattened.
The bomb left nothing.
Except, I suspect...
the archive section.
I ndeed, many sections
of the underground city
were designed
to survive the impact
of a 1 0-megaton overblast.
Well, then the tapes and
pictures of my parents--
Are still down there.
ohh...
oh, MacDonald.
I want to see
what they look like.
I suppose
every orphan does.
I want to hear
what they thought
and knew.
The city's radioactive.
oh, yeah, well...
Iet me see.
Who is there
among your people
who knows something
about radioactivity?
No one.
And among mine?
Who knows everything
about everything?
oh...
oh, Virgil.
Go find him.
Lisa, you remember
your parents.
I was too young when
they died to remember mine.
I don't want to have
to remember my husband.
I want to
love him now.
Well, Virgil
will be with us.
Now, we'll take good care.
Say good-bye
to Cornelius.
I don't want him
to know I'm afraid.
Cornelius.
Father.
I'm going
on a journey.
What will you
bring me back?
What would you like?
More nuts
for my squirrel.
He's growing fast.
So are you.
one day, you will be
as tall as a king.
Mandemus.
He's asleep.
Not eternally,
I trust.
Mandemus.
Who's there?
Caesar.
What does
Caesar want?
Weapons.
For what purpose?
For self-protection
in the pursuit
of knowledge.
Self-protection
against whom or what?
We don't know.
Well, then what is the point
of protecting yourself
against a danger ofwhich
you have no knowledge
in pursuit of a knowledge
you do not possess?
oh, God.
Is it a knowledge
for good or evil?
All knowledge
is for good.
only the use to which you
put it can be good or evil.
Well put.
Thank you.
The sun is rising.
I should like to get this
matter settled before it sets.
Caesar has appointed me
not only as the keeper
of this armory,
but as the keeper
of his own conscience.
That is why I have asked
six boring questions
and now propose
to ask a seventh
before issuing or not issuing
the weapons you require.
What is the nature
of the knowledge
you cannot seek
without weapons?
The knowledge of
Earth's ultimate fate
recorded on tapes
in the archives of
the forbidden city...
Which is
contaminated,
but still may be
inhabited by humans.
Hmm. Come in.
Name your
protective pick.
Three submachine guns.
For?
The removal
of obstacles.
Hmm.
1 ...
2...
3.
Now what?
Ammunition.
I really don't hold
with knowing the future,
even my own
which is short.
A geiger counter.
I mean, ifwe knew for a fact
there was an afterlife,
and that the afterlife
was bliss eternal,
we'd all commit suicide in
order to be able to enjoy it.
Pistols.
To remove
smaller obstacles?
It's a 3-dayjourney.
With Caesar's permission,
MacDonald may want to
shoot, cook,
and eat a rabbit.
But who needs
three pistols
to shoot one rabbit?
Enjoyyour meal.
Thank you.
He may be old, but he's
got a mind like a razor.
When I was a boy,
he was my teacher.
Let's collect our stores
and be on our way.
There it is...
or was.
Like a storm at sea,
but solidified.
By a bomb from an armory
1 ,000 times the size of ours.
And nobody to keep
its owner's conscience.
This is the hell
my forefathers
used to speak about.
[Geiger Counter Ticking]
Do you know where
we are, MacDonald?
Yes.
Now, this is--
I mean was--1 1th Avenue.
Ape Management was
2 blocks east from here.
The archives section,
2 blocks west,
corner of Breck
and Agamon.
Get us there quickly.
[Ticking]
The governor's very
irritable lately.
Who wouldn't be,
living in this hell
of radiation
for all these years?
If the bomb hadn't
killed the old governor,
boredom certainly
would have.
Alma, I just want somebody
to talk to, anybody.
We are at best brave
and at worst mad
to be here.
This background
radiation alone
will give us
300 roentgens per hour.
Meaning?
That unless we leave
this place within 2 hours,
we shall become inmates.
This is a ghost city.
I want to put
some flesh on it.
Radioactive flesh?
Well, we're all radiated,
but at least we're active.
[Ticking]
[Ticking Gets Louder]
It's getting stronger.
We must hurry.
[Alarm Beeps]
oh, Governor, look!
F-6! F-6!
[Beeping]
Alert Mendez.
Mendez to control room.
Somebody's breached the
warning system at entry F-6.
one of our scavengers.
No. It's been
locked foryears.
It couldn't have
been one of us.
It must have
been someone else.
Well, that's impossible.
There is no one else.
We must act quickly.
- Alma.
- Yes, sir?
Work the B console.
Quick, Mendez. Quick! Quick!
oh, quicker! Faster!
[Ticking]
Keep going.
No, no. Back.
This is the place.
That's Caesar,
come back to reconquer
his kingdom.
Doesn't he know that
the bomb did that?
[Ticking]
[Ticking Gets Louder]
We're still all right.
This way.
Quicker!
There. Hold it.
Can anything live
down here for long?
oh, yes.
But in the end,
not recognizably.
The black man
is the brother
of my predecessor's
personal assistant.
He supervised
the archives.
I don't think
I know the orangutan.
Look!
It's been there foryears.
The late governor had this whole
place equipped with cameras
to forestall ape conspiracies,
as I remember.
Hmm.
Archives.
We haven't been in
there since, uh...
I wonder what the devil
they want in there.
We'll find the tape
that we're looking for
under the heading of
" Presidential Commission."
" Proceedings of the
Presidential Commission
on Alien Visitors,
1 973."
Is this it?
Let's see.
Yes, that's it.
Now, if this thing works,
the picture should come out
on that screen over there.
All security forces, alert.
Check out all sections
in areas M-5.
Apprehend 3 strangers
you will find there:
one human and two apes.
But caution.
I repeat, caution.
If they resist,
you may shoot,
but shoot to maim.
We want them alive
for interrogation.
Ifwe shoot, we break
1 2 years of peace.
Yes, it has been rather
boring, hasn't it?
My mother.
Who wonyour war?
It wasn't our war.
It was thegorillas' war.
What didthespaceship's
date meterread
af terEarth's
destruction?
3950.
And you talk to your pupils
about eternity.
There are only 3.
There must be more,
but how many?
We'll know
when we get them.
My father.
That's my father.
Howdidapesfirstacquire
thepowerofspeech?
Theylearnedto refuse.
On a historic day,
an apespoke a word
which hadbeenspoken
to him byhumans.
Hesaid, "no. "
No wonder all of mankind
thirsted for my blood
and wanted
my birth aborted.
I n the year 3950,
apes will destroy Earth.
Not apes, gorillas.
Besides, that's
only one future.
How can there be
more than one?
You remember
the old motorways?
I believe that time is like
an endless motorway
with an infinite number of lanes all
running from the past into the future.
A driver could
change his lanes
and change
his future.
If you left
this room right now,
you might
wind up shot dead.
If you left
a minute later,
you might survive.
It's a blind choice,
but you can
change lanes.
I know what it is
I want to change.
[Rattle]
The camera. It moved.
Are you sure?
Virgil's right.
Governor, wejust
lost the TV monitor.
I'm not interested
in equipment failures.
It wasn't a failure.
It was destroyed, sir.
We've got to find
another way out of here.
Is there
another way?
They got past you?
Then shoot on sight.
Never mind about
bringing them here.
J ust get them.
Don't let anyone
escape alive!
Sections 2-5
and R-7 and 8,
form a group here.
Quick! Quick!
All right, move out!
Move! Move! Move!
Hurry!
Run!
I've got your guns.
We need another patrol.
Quickly, men.
Hurry. Hurry.
The rest of you go
to M-5.
What are you
waiting for?
To R-8,
through the transverse!
Aah!
All forces
into exit level 3.
They're getting away!
Kill them!
Kill them! Kill them!
[Gunshot]
You knew every bolt and nut
in those corridors.
You have 1 00 armed men.
How could they escape?
They were fast
and smart, Governor Kolp.
Many of my men
were sick,
and the chimp
surprised us.
Yeah. He surprised
me too, once,
But he's an animal.
He's only an animal.
No, Governor.
He's more
than an animal.
He can speak.
So can they all.
So speech
makes them human?
Speech makes them
intelligent,
and intelligence may make them
not human, but humane.
Perhaps they
came in peace.
Idiot.
They were armed.
From what we saw
on the monitor,
only for their
self-protection.
Let them
return in peace.
To where?
To wherever they live.
So they can return to
exterminate those of us
the bomb hasn't
already exterminated?
Where do they live?
They came with
few provisions.
It can't be far.
Which way
did they head?
They headed north,
Governor.
organize
scout parties,
assemble
workable equipment,
and follow them
to their camp.
Yes, Governor Kolp.
Why, Governor?
So that we
can exterminate them.
Stop!
It's Caesar!
We should have
stayed in the city.
Visiting the city
is forbidden.
I know.
I forbade it.
Then why?
Aldo, if a king forbids his
subjects to wear a crown,
that doesn't mean
he can't wear one himself.
Caesar is Caesar.
He went to the city
for a reason.
What reason?
I went looking
for my past,
but I found our future.
Explain!
You wouldn't understand.
Aldo will make
the future--with this!
Well, then Aldo
may very soon
be in the past.
Hee hee.
Aah!
Cornelius!
Cornelius,
are you all right?
No, Mother.
I'm just dead.
Dead?
We were playing war.
War? Cornelius,
hasn't your father explained
that war is not a game?
Yes, Mother.
Hasn't he also forbidden
you to play with guns?
Yes, Mother.
Then you'll stop it.
Now, come along.
Father wants us.
My friends,
I have convened
this extraordinary meeting
of the council
in order that I may
report upon an action
which I deemed necessary:
a reconnaissance expedition
to the forbidden city
with Virgil and MacDonald
as my aides.
Why MacDonald?
Why not a soldier?
Because we went in peace
to what we thought
would be a dead city.
But in case
there were some survivors,
we took MacDonald with us
so that he could parley
with them
and secure permission
for our search.
Survivors there are...
maimed,
mutated,
hostile,
and human.
Did the humans
followyou here?
We saw no sign of it,
but we must prepare
for the day
when they may
come out of the city,
when they may come
to find us.
No humans in council!
- No!
Yes!
They are here
because I sent for them.
Now that we know the danger,
we need their help
and their counsel.
- No!
Yes!
Come. We shall not sit
in council with humans.
Now, let us
reason together
and make plans.
Governor, somewhere
along the line of history,
this bloody chain reaction
has got to stop.
A destroys B, B destroys C,
C destroys A
and is destroyed
by D, who destroys E.
Before anyone knows
where they are,
there won't be anyone left
to know anything anywhere.
Governor, the captain
has come back.
We found it, Governor.
We found Ape City.
Where?
This is
a gorilla outpost.
Below is a valley
with orchards and vineyards,
enough to feed hundreds.
Here is Ape City.
Was it very large?
It is of a size we
can deal with, sir.
Were you seen?
No, sir.
Caesar was too busy
with a council ofwar.
one day soon, they'll
be coming for us.
No. We're going
after them--now.
Captain, you
have your orders.
Caesar, on the night
of the fires,
you swore an oath
that in the future
apes and humans would live
together in kindness and peace.
Why are you now making
every sort of preparation
to break that oath?
Because unlike
the humans in our city,
those in the
forbidden city are mad--
mad enough not to want
peace and friendship,
but enmity and war.
Did they tell you that?
oh, yes. Yes.
By opening fire on us
without giving us
a chance to explain.
You were trespassing
on their territory.
But, Lisa, we didn't know
the city was inhabited.
But how, if you
didn't speak to them,
do you know its
inhabitants are mad?
Lisa, you
didn't see them.
They're...oh...
They're malformed.
Like the freaks in your
foster father's circus?
Were they mad?
What's malformed?
Cornelius, go to bed.
I'm giving
Riki his water.
Lisa, freaks
are different.
These humans are
the end product
of nuclear radiation.
They are mutant,
and they're mad.
Keep all emergency
channels open.
Yes, Governor. All emergency
channels will remain open.
If anything
should miscarry,
I'll signal you
as arranged.
Yes, sir.
Hurry, man.
We need it!
The school bus will be
operational, Governor.
The rest of the convoy
will join us
atjunction C.
Get moving.
[Chattering]
Riki!
Well...
they have guns.
We have no guns.
We shall take the guns,
and we shall beat them.
[All Growling]
We are the elite.
We are the super-race.
We have
the right to lead.
Without us,
there would be no army.
[All Growling]
We need power, guns!
[Growling]
We need power!
Guns! Guns.
Guns are power!
We shall get them,
and we'll beat them
with guns.
We will smash
the humans.
[Growling]
All humans!
And then we will
smash Caesar!
[Twig Snaps]
Hmm?
Look!
It's Caesar's son.
And he overheard
every word we said.
Cornelius, come down.
Come down, or else.
[Grunt]
Father!
Cornelius?
Mother!
Aah!
Grrr!
[Twig Snaps]
[Grunt]
Cornelius!
I only heard about it
this morning.
His squirrel is missing.
He must have been
looking for it.
How is Cornelius?
Hurt. He's badly hurt.
oh!
Speak the truth.
Even ifwe had
a hospital...
I'm not going to
tell Caesar, notyet.
He still believes
he can change the future.
Humans, going
towards our city.
I'll get him.
Aah!
Get ready to fire.
Fire!
The doctor
is doing her best.
I don't believe
Cornelius can live.
Caesar does.
He refuses
to leave his side.
MacDonald, how can
a benevolent God
allow a branch
of his own tree
to crack and injure
an innocent child?
It didn't crack, Virgil.
It was cut.
order at council!
order! order!
The humans
are attacking.
They've killed one gorilla
and wounded another.
Tell them.
We were scouting
desert approaches to the city
and saw their army.
They fired.
My companion was killed.
I have come
to warn you.
And how long before
they get here?
Soon.
So now,
we must prepare.
Take the humans out.
Lock them all
in the corral.
Aldo! Aldo,
you can't do this!
You're acting against
Caesar's orders.
Caesar is not here.
Hey! What the--
Hey!
Jake.
Strongman, take him
to the corral.
Take all humans
All humans, take them
to the corral.
Where are you going?
Martial law
has been declared.
Everybody is to stay
in their homes.
By whose orders?
Go home!
We want guns!
Guns are power.
Now we go and get guns!
Mandemus.
Who's there?
Aldo.
General Aldo.
What do you want?
Guns! Guns!
What will you do
with them?
We shall do with them
what we will.
" Do what you will"
is the devil's law.
And who are you,
Mandemus, God?
I am the keeper
of Caesar's conscience.
And I am the keeper
of Caesar's army!
Under allegiance to Caesar!
Where is he?
Mandemus,
as I speak,
our city is being
attacked by humans
from without
and within.
Who cares
where Caesar is?
I care!
There is a law
that weapons
may only be issued
from this armory
under direct orders
from Caesar
and not under threats
from one of his
thicker-headed subordinates
for whom war means
only personal glory.
Now, find me Caesar.
I will listen to him.
First,
listen to this.
Take every gun
in the place, everything.
Get the ammo boxes.
Get the handguns,
grenades.
Stop! Stop!
Caesar forbids you!
Ah!
Well, there it is:
Ape City.
When we leave,
I don't want to see
one tree left standing,
2 pieces ofwood
nailed together,
or anything left alive.
I want it to look like
that city we came from.
What the devil is all
that rubbish down there?
It looks like some sort
of barricade, sir.
Nothing that a couple of
flame bombs won't take care of.
Caesar, forgive me,
but I couldn't
get here before now.
Aldo has seized power.
He's broken
into the armory
and imprisoned all
humans in the corral.
MacDonald?
He was dragged from
the council meeting
by Aldo's gorillas.
I can't leave
Cornelius.
He needs me.
Every ape and human
in Ape City needs you now.
I think you should go
to Cornelius.
Father?
They...hurt me.
They want...to hurt you.
Who hurt you?
The humans?
No.
Then who?
Sh...
Shall...
Shall I be...
malformed?
No.
one day
you are going to be
as tall as a king.
[Sob]
All right, Captain,
lay the smoke screen.
When I give the signal,
start the bombardment.
Men and equipment
out of the bus.
Deployyour weapons,
quickly!
All is
in order, sir.
All right. Let's go.
He said
they hurt him.
Who?
Who would hurt him?
I think you'll
have your answer,
and soon.
What do you know?
That's what I know.
You did this.
For security.
Did you also raid the armory
for the same reason?
For security!
Caesar, Caesar!
I orderyou
to stop this!
to stop it now
and release
those people!
See? Aldo was right.
War has come.
Let's go.
Aah! Aah! Aah!
Go to the barricade!
To the barricade!
[Gunfire]
Come on!
Go to the barricade!
They're laying
a smoke screen.
Here they come.
Where's Aldo?
Probably the other side
of the valley by now.
Hurry! Fall back,
fall back!
Fall back.
Go back to the village.
Get away from the fire!
Fall back! Hurry!
Leave the barricade!
Fall back! Fall back!
Get back to the village.
Nothing left alive!
You can't stay here
any longer.
You must
save yourself.
Ah!
Caesar.
Your people
weakened our city
by rebelling against
your human masters.
But we who survive
will create a new race,
and you and yours
will be brought low,
and you shall
learn again
what it is to have a master.
Ha!
You're learning
already...
clever ape.
oh, no.
Ape.
Clever ape.
But then,
you always were clever.
I was told how
you chose your own name.
But every Caesar
must have his Brutus.
Did you know that, ape?
Do you
understand that, ape?
And now Ape City is
about to lose its king.
No, Kolp! No!
Now fight like apes!
Stop! Stop. No killing.
Take them captive.
Get moving!
No, no!
Don't kill them.
Take them prisoner.
No.
No, Virgil.
All right, Virgil.
Let's go.
No prisoners.
No prisoners!
[Gunfire]
Dismount.
Hail Caesar!
Caesar!
We've done it!
Hold!
Let the humans go,
Virgil, all of them.
No!
They stay.
Aldo says what we do now.
They have done nothing.
They shall go free.
You like humans?
You want them
out of the corral?
All right. Kill them!
Aah!
Kill them.
Kill them all.
Stop.
No more killing, Aldo.
Put down your weapons.
Take them back
to the armory.
No! We shall
keep the guns!
Move, Caesar,
or we shall kill you.
[Grunting]
Ape has never
killed ape,
Iet alone
an ape child.
[Grunting]
Aldo has killed
an ape child.
The branch
did not break.
It was cut...
with a sword.
[Grunting]
[All Growling]
Aldo.
You...you killed.
Ah! Ah!
Aldo killed.
[All Growling]
Aldo has broken
our most sacred law.
[All Growling]
our child.
He killed our child.
What's the matter
with them?
I guess you might say they
justjoined the human race.
Ape has killed ape.
You murdered my son.
You murdered my son!
[Hiss]
Aah!
Should one murder
be avenged by another?
only the future
can tell.
So let us
start building it.
Ifwe appear to be lacking
in gratitude, Caesar,
what have we
to be grateful for?
If you mean
to set us free,
then free us
completely.
What do you mean?
We are not
your children, Caesar.
We have a destiny, too--
as equals,
respecting each other,
Iiving together,
with love.
Love?
The human way
is violence and death.
Aldo wasn't human,
was he, Caesar?
Virgil...
you are
a good and wise ape.
And you, Caesar, are
a good and wise king.
We'll rebuild what's ruined
and begin again.
Tell me something,
MacDonald.
Can we make the future
what we wish?
I've heard that
it's possible, Caesar.
There. Every weapon
is back in its proper place.
Caesar, I want
to ask a favor.
This armory's been
my home for 27 years.
You may live in it for
the rest of your days.
But I don't want
to live in it.
No, no. Now that
the danger is over,
I want to see it
destroyed. Blown up.
The greatest danger of all
is that danger never ends.
And so, Mandemus,
we must be patient...
and wait.
We still wait,
my children.
But as I look at
apes and humans
Iiving in friendship,
harmony, and at peace
now some 600 years
after Caesar's death,
at least we wait
with hope for the future.
Lawgiver, who knows
about the future?
Perhaps only the dead.