Jesus!
Asshole.
Man, did you see that?
I mean, he pulled right out in front of me.
I took my eyes off the road for a second,
but, I mean, come on.
Maybe it's time we take a little break.
We'll pull over the next chance we get.
Nice car.
Thanks.
You got your air, CD.
Leather.
Looks to me like you sprung forth whole nine yards.
I guess so.
But that rig of yours is what you really need out here.
Why would you want this piece of shit
when you got this ride?
What a man needs out here is a C.B. Radio.
Is that right?
Yours could be "Shit-for-Brains."
Do you even care that you damn near killed us?
I didn't even see you.
You kind of pulled out in front of me.
Like hell I did.
Let's just forget this.
I'm sorry. I don't want any trouble.
No, I'll bet you don't.
Howdy, Ma'am.
You should be more careful who you ride with.
- What was that about?
- Nothing.
He thinks I tried to hit him.
Let's go.
Should I drive?
Later. Just get in.
What if I promise not to sidewipe anyone?
- Just get in.
I'm kidding.
Getting ready forth Grand Prix?
What'd you get?
A junk food fiesta.
Let's see.
Sno Balls.
Yoo Hoo.
And Moon Pies.
Can you believe they still make this stuff?
Gourmet cuisine around here.
This is crazy. Look at this.
It says if you win this mail-in contest...
you can choose between $90,000 or 90,000 donuts.
What would you do with 90,000 donuts?
I don't know.
Sell then for 30 cents each and pay off this car.
No kidding.
$90,000.
That'd solve some problems.
What the hell?
What did you do?
Nothing.
Hang on. I can't steer.
Perfect.
Outta range?
So much fortaking the scenic route.
The baffle gasket's burned out.
What?
It's connected to the connecting rod.
Shut up.
Can you believe this?
This could be our worst decision ever.
What are you doing?
Just listen.
We're changing jobs.
Our finances are pretty fucked.
And we're in the middle of the nowhere.
I'd say this is our worst decision ever.
Get out of here. You're bugging me.
Okay, sweetie.
Good luck. I'm going to California.
Just leave me the Moon Pies.
- Jeff?
- And the donuts.
No, there's a car.
Christ, not these guys.
Assholes.
Jeff.
What the hell...
- what's he doing?
- I don't know.
This isn't good.
Are you okay?
Fine. Except our car broke down.
I saw that.
Can I give you a hand?
Thanks.
Honey, you steer.
Massachusetts plates. You folks on vacation?
No, we're moving.
Oh yeah? Whereabouts?
San Diego.
Do you think we can use your C.B. To radio a tow truck?
I wish I could, but I blew a fuse on it this morning.
I'll fix it at the truck stop.
How far is that?
About 60 miles.
I was just driving along and she quit on me.
Belts... Battery's working.
You used to just give...
these things a kick and a holler and they'd start.
It is a new car.
Have you been riding it pretty hard?
Yeah, I admit a little...
Tell you what.
I'll give you a ride to Belle's Diner.
You can call a tow truck from there.
That's nice of you to offer, but I think you got it.
We'll just let her cool off.
Thanks. We appreciate it.
Good luck starting it.
- Thanks.
- Thanks a lot.
Honey.
It's probably just overheated.
What if it's not? We don't want to be stuck out here.
No, but if we just let it cool off, we'll be okay.
It's getting pretty toasty.
Are you sure you want to blow this ride?
No, but...
I don't want to leave the car.
What if I go, call the tow truck,
and order a nice cold iced tea?
And I stay with the nice hot car.
Right.
You'll be okay?
I'll be fine.
Excuse me.
Can I take you up on that ride?
Sure. Step up.
Sure your husband doesn't want to come?
No, he'll stay with the car.
What the hell?
Tow truck, my ass.
Belle's Diner
Excuse me. I'm supposed to meet my wife here.
She's dark-haired, about 5'5"...
wearing a whit Benetton sweater.
White what?
Benetton sweater.
Hank!
Your order's up.
I'm busy here. People come and go.
This was within the last half hour.
She might have been with a trucker.
Trucker?
Doesn't ring a bell.
You sure?
This man's looking for his wife.
Dark hair, a white button on sweater.
Traveling with a trucker. Anybody seen 'em?
Looks like she got away from you. Cowboy.
Maybe she left a message with one of your employees.
Impossible. I'm the only one that works here.
Is there another Belle's Diner?
No siree. Definitely not.
Excuse me.
She and I must have gotten our signals crossed.
How far is the next town?
20 miles.
Do me a favor.
If my wife, Amy comes in...
tell her I was here and to stay put till I get back.
Would you do that, please?
- Okay.
- Thanks.
Hey! Pull over!
I don't believe it.
Jesus!
Hey, man.
What are you doing?
I wanted you to pull over. Didn't you see me?
Well?
Never mind. I'm looking for my wife.
What?
Where's my wife?
How should I know?
I'm the guy with the Jeep.
You gave my wife a ride to Belle's Diner.
Not me. Sorry.
Sorry? This was a half hour ago. You don't remember?
I've never seen you before in my life.
What are you doing?
Amy!
I don't know what you want...
I want my wife back.
Officer, I need your help.
What's the problem?
I think he's done something with my wife.
Calm down. What's going on?
I don't know.
Last I saw her, she was in this guy's truck.
- Now he says he never saw her.
- I don't know what he means.
You son-of-a-bitch!
Calm down. Tell me exactly what happened.
Our car broke down.
He stopped and offered to help.
He took my wife to a pay phone. Whenever show up.
What do you have to say?
I don't know.
I'm driving along and he runs me off the road,
starts hollering about his wife.
I swear I've never seen him before.
He's lying.
May I search your truck?
Hell, yes. Go ahead.
My name's Barr - Red Barr.
My permits are current. Take a look.
Stand back behind the line. Both of you.
License and registration, please.
Are those yours?
My personal stuff.
Want to look?
I think we're done.
You can go.
Wait. You're not going to question him anymore?
I've searched the truck.
Maybe you confused my truck with another.
Go to hell! Let me see that.
Hold on. Your want to get arrested?
The man has a point.
This is a plain looking truck.
Looks like a lot of trucks.
Maybe you got them mixed up.
Stay put.
Mr. Taylor?
It was him.
It was this truck.
I can see that.
- Did you get a license plate number?
- No.
How about the information on that door?
I wasn't paying attention.
Mr. Taylor, did you have a beef with your wife today?
What's that got to do with anything?
Is there a possibility she could have left you?
I don't believe this.
My wife did not leave me!
I've seen it before.
Put two people in a car long enough, they'll go at it.
Lovers, married couples, gay guys.
They dump their mates on the side of the road.
Officer.
I'd like to help, but I have a long haul to Fresno.
This is insane. Officer. Please.
I have his information if I need to find him.
Much obliged.
No hard feeling. I really hope you find your wife.
Mr. Taylor, come with me.
I believe you that your wife's missing.
Maybe you got confused and maybe you didn't.
I'm just trying to help.
The town of Brackett is 31 miles that way.
My deputy's name is Len Carver.
He'll help you if you want to report your wife missing.
Mrs. Gilbert's locked out of her trailer again.
Can you help her?
I'm on my way.
Will do.
Mr. Taylor, do yourself a favor.
Go see my deputy.
It's a couple months old.
Is her hair still like this?
We'll certainly do your best, Mr. Taylor.
Over 100,000 people go missing in this country every year.
Runaways, deadbeat dads...
dropouts, folks hiding from the I.R. S...
All vanishing without a trace.
We get these kinds of pictures all the time.
I'm not saying your wife if one.
I sure hope not.
But unless there's a ransom demand
or evidence of forced abduction...
the F.B.I. Won't look at your case
until it's been 24 hours.
Nevertheless, we'll keep our eyes peeled.
Mr. Taylor.
Why don't you go to Belle's?
Get a cup of coffee, wait for your wife.
If anything comes up, I'll contact you.
How's that sound?
Did my wife come in?
Didn't see her.
She didn't come in?
Like I said, maybe she was in, maybe she wasn't.
I'm saying I didn't see her.
It ain't my business, but if I was you...
I'd check the ladies' room.
Amy!
I'll be right with you, cowboy.
Let me see your order slips.
What?
You write down the names.
Are you nuts? I don't have to show you jack-shit!
If my wife was here, her name's in that pile.
You calling me a liar?
Let me see the fucking slips!
I've had just about enough of you.
Get me the Sheriff's office.
My name's Billy.
You the fella looking for his wife?
Have you seen her?
If you know something, tell me.
I saw her, maybe.
Where? When?
Inside a little while ago.
She came in on a truck.
- A big semi.
- Then what?
Then she left on another truck.
With who?
With some men.
They think I'm a dummy, but I ain't.
I'll get my trucker's license one day.
This is important.
Did you see where they took my wife?
Route 7 North up by the river.
By the river? Where?
They don't tell me that kind of thing.
Who doesn't? The bartender?
The men in the truck?
I ain't talking to you no more.
Come with me to the police
and tell them what you saw.
Now you're the dummy.
What does that mean?
Don't you get it? The police are in on it.
Work, god damn it.
Hello, Steve, this is Jeffrey Taylor.
Please don't put me on hold.
I need a favor.
I have to talk to your friend at the F.B.I.
Right. It's about Amy.
Something's happening...
I thing she's been... She's missing.
Steve? No, don't call me back.
Don't, Steve.
Get out of the car now!
What do you want?
He's getting away!
What the hell's going on?
He went down the river.
We're pulling it out now.
Careful. Don't let it come loose.
I got it.
This is what happens
when you get one without the other.
How will we explain this to Boyd?
I ain't.
You all right?
According to your wife...
you have a lot of cash in your bank account. True?
There's some.
"Some' doesn't cut it.
She gave us an exact amount.
There are different accounts.
The balance fluctuates.
Fluctuates my ass.
A hotshot fuck like you always watches his bottom line.
What do you think?
I think we've been lied to.
He ain't a goddamn donut king.
The slut lied to save her ass.
Piece of shit.
I'll do him.
$90,000!
$90,000.
Crawl your ass out of there.
You're a tough man to reach.
What do you want?
It's not what I want, it's what you want.
How bad do you want it? It will cost you.
I can't show it to you now...
It's about 5'5". 115lbs.
Three or four of that is pure tit.
Nice curly brown hair upstairs and down.
Interested?
Why?
What does this... why us?
Bring him up here.
The town of Brackett.
It's a shit-hole in the middle of nowhere.
See that bank?
You're going to tell the manager to express wire...
$90,000 from your bank account in Boston.
How do I know she's still alive?
Shut up!
Come on, Jeff.
Pay attention.
See the building with the flag pole on top?
That's the sheriff's station.
There are two cops. One has desk duty,
the other is patrolling the foothills.
A minute ago, Billy...
called in an accident on the l-40 connector.
See? There he goes.
It will take him 20 minutes to get there,
spend 10 minutes there,
200 minutes back.
That's 50 minutes.
Exactly the time you have to get my money.
Before you get any half-baked ideas
about calling in the cavalry...
remember, we'll be watching you.
We'll be listening on those scanners.
If we see anything unusual...
an unmarked car, a plane,
anyone who even smells like a cop...
you can just keep your fucking money.
I'll send you pieces of her from time to time.
Billy.
Give him the jacket.
Put it on, Jeff.
Can't go into a bank looking like that.
We don't have to do this. I'll get you the money.
I swear.
I promise. Just let my wife go, please.
49 minutes, Jeff.
Time to get the show on the road.
My driver's license and credit card.
My bank account number.
How long will this take?
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
I only have $5,000 in that account.
How much can you advance me?
Excuse me?
Can you advance me the $6,000 limit on my credit card?
No, I'm sorry, I can't.
The limit for non-customers is $500 a day.
Sir, are you sure you're all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Just transfer the money, okay?
I'll tell you something.
What I'm about to tell you...
you can't tell anyone. Understand?
Whatever happens, just keep writing on that pad.
Please, just keep writing.
They're probably watching me right now.
The town's under surveillance.
If I don't walk out of here with...
Excuse me. You the manager?
Yes, I am.
That lady said to see you about a car loan.
Certainly.
If you would take a seat.
Just forget it. I had a car accident... a miner one.
I'm just kind of...
How long will this take?
It will take a few minutes.
Yeah, I um, I'm calling regarding account number
98258103.
Jeffre Taylor.
Well, he'd like to liquidate his account.
Shit.
It's me.
No shit. I can see that. How much do you have?
The whole thing. $90,000.
That's good.
Start walking toward the main road
and get in the first car that stops.
When do I see my wife?
Soon enough. Just start walking.
Throw the money on the seat.
First tell me where she is.
Wrong, asshole. First you give me the money.
Unless you want me to shoot your ass dead right here.
Turn around.
Do it!
Put your hands behind you.
Get in the truck. On your knees.
Get in here.
I gave you the money, now let her go.
What the hell...
It's a done deal.
I'm heading in.
You're the dumbest mother fucker yet.
Think we picked you out of the clear blue?
Shiny new car.
Massachusetts plates.
Probably be a week before anybody misses you.
I gave you the money, now let her go.
"Rich Assholes Looking for Trouble?"
I wish I had been there to see your face
when your car seized up.
Maybe you'll learn not to leave your hood open...
when you go in the store.
These are goddamn singles!
Where is she?
Fuck you.
No, fuck you!
You like that? How about this?
- Where is she?
- I don't know.
The fuck you don't know.
Stop.
What? You want me to stop?
Want me to stop?
I'll bet this baby stops on a fucking dime!
What the hell?
Where is she?
She's with Billy.
Where?
Driving around.
Bullshit!
I'm in pursuit of a black Ford pickup truck.
Contact the State Police.
We're headed north on Highway 31. I need backup.
- Where were you headed?
- The truck stop.
Where exactly?!
On the main highway. The Texaco.
Help me. My wife's been kidnapped.
Drop the gun!
Get down!
I know where she is.
I'm down. Listen to me.
He's in on it.
They kidnapped my wife.
They have her at the Texaco truck stop.
Shut up!
You in the pickup, you okay?
Yes, sir, I'm okay.
Can you get out?
Yes. Please don't shoot.
There's a bag of money in there!
Face down and shut up!
Get out, damn it!
God damn it, listen to me!
Shut up!
Shit-for-Brains.
Shots fired.
Officer down.
Suspect identified.
This is dispatch. What is your 20?
Send an ambulance.
Who's this?
Can you respond?
They're coming.
We'll get you an ambulance.
All units. Officer down. Repeat. Officer down.
He was supposed to be here a half hour ago.
I heard a report about a cop down.
There's too much heat around here,
so stay off the airwaves.
Get his wife and meet me at the barn,
even if you have to drive all night.
Daddy, you're home!
- Miss me?
- Yeah.
Deke, get back to bed.
I expected you back next wee.
I finished early and now I'm home.
Al and Billy are coming over.
It's 6:00A.M. Can't they come another time?
We have stuff to do. It'll take a couple hours.
Would you make breakfast?
Hey, Deke!
- Will you open the barn?
- Okay.
Hey, Dekey. Thanks.
I have something for you.
Here, son.
Look at that.
Cool!
A real Swiss Army knife.
Good boy.
Deke?
Deke, you back there?
I hope I never see another couple from Massachusetts.
We have a lot of work to do.
Any word on Earl?
Not a thing.
Me neither.
We have to get this stuff off the truck.
None of this would have happened...
if you'd gotten them at the same time.
He wouldn't get in the truck.
I suppose you'd chase him down with a gun.
Fucking idiot.
I'm just saying...
we should have gotten rid of them like that Ohio couple.
So we stay out of the area for a few months.
Al!
Come on.
Okay, homey. Time to get up.
- Let's go!
- Come on, move it.
Get up!
Dead?
Must have died from the exhaust. Suicide!
Couldn't be any cleaner than that.
We'll bury her out back.
Jesus! Goddamn!
Scared me to death!
Let me do her. I'll cut her head off.
Warren?
Shit, it's my wife.
Cover her. Put her in the freezer.
She's a feisty one, isn't she?
Don't give me any trouble.
God damn it! Cut your fucking squirming!
Come on, it's not as bad as it sounds.
It will take you 10 minutes to suck all that air out.
Come on, fellas.
Let's go eat!
Hey, Mrs. C.
Are coming to breakfast?
I've been calling you.
We could use some pancakes.
This rooster must have weighed 10 lbs.
It's reaching out forth highway patrol cop.
Give me the key.
Mister.
You son-of-a-bitch!
My wife is locked up in your fucking barn!
Give me the key or I'll blow your fucking head off!
What's going on?
I don't know. Stay calm.
- Your husband's a murderer and a kidnapper.
- Give me the fucking key!
Freeze, Mister.
Just keep that gun on him.
My daddy's rifle is always loaded.
So I can protect Mommy when he was away.
I won't hurt your mom.
He's lying, Deke.
Go on, son.
Squeeze that trigger.
Don't listen to him.
Go on, Deke.
Do what I say. Squeeze that trigger.
Put it down, Deke. Nothing will happen.
Do it!
Don't move.
Nobody move!
Get over by you mom.
Get over there!
Shit!
Stick together and get out out that door.
Move it!
Turn around! Turn around!
Open it.
Open that freezer.
Warren, what is this?
Pull the chain, Arieen.
Open it!
You'd better pray she's alive.
Amy.
Jeff.
You made it, baby.
Get away from me!
Come on, honey.
You son-of-a-bitch, get down there!
All of you!
You remember this.
You fuck!
It's all right. It's okay.
Listen to me, Amy. Honey, listen to me.
There's one still out there.
We need to get out of here.
Shit!
Can you get to that truck?
Come on.
My name is Jeffrey Taylor. This is an emergency.
Someone's trying to kill me and my wife!
We're on a farm.
Start tracing this call.
Got them!
Move!
Come on.
Give me the keys!
Come on!
Go!
Do you see him?
- Do you see him?
- No.
Are you okay?
Want some?
Hang on!
Shit.
I'm out.
- Let's go.
- I can't get out!
Don't move.
I'll get you out.
Come here. Come on.
Pull!
That's it!
Are you okay?