You know, sometimes it seems
like life is all planned out.
There's no choice
in the matter.
We're all gonna end up in the same
place, whether we like it or not.
But sometimes things
aren't so simple.
You can end up hurting the
people you love the most,
betraying the people you
want to come through for.
That's not me.
That's my best friend, Steve.
We've been best friends
since third grade,
when he punched this kid, Billy Utsch,
for slamming a locker door on my head.
That's me. I"m Darren
Shan, and this is my story.
Oh, and, trust me, spending
this much time in a coffin
was never part of my plan.
Guess I'm just lucky.
Up until recently,
my life was pretty good.
I was popular enough.
I got good grades, 'cause
my allowance was tied to it.
A's! I love you.
I love you.
Yeah, that's the boy.
That's the boy.
Hey, you.
What's up, D?
And I had
some cool friends.
Hey, what's up?
Uh,
not including that dude.
I mean, we were friends in fifth
grade, but he'd become kind of a freak.
See, that used to
matter to me.
There was one thing in my life
that was a bit insane, one friend.
Hey.
My best friend.
Let's cut, all right?
What?
No, we're here.
Class is starting, man.
All right, folks.
What you got for me?
Okay, listen, I cannot
deal with that jerk today.
All right, Mr. Perfect, come on,
take a risk. Take a risk. Come on!
So, hey, I'm thinking about
moving to Mexico. You want to go?
Yeah, sure. Why not?
Yeah, you're not going
anywhere, Mr. Perfect.
Oh, shit.
Hey, man, I bet you can't hit that
light from all the way back here.
What? No, we're
gonna get busted.
"Steve, we're gonna
get busted. "
Hey!
Rock. Come on.
And so the Mutually Assured
Destruction policy of the Cold War
was just that. Mad.
What the heck is that?
I'm so sorry.
It's that Steve.
It's that damn Steve.
Uh...
Did Darren tell you he got
an A on his math test?
Yes, he did, honey.
Go to your room.
You are not going to be
friends with that Steve anymore!
Mom, I'm not
five years old.
You can't tell me who I can
and can't be friends with.
You are on
a good path, Darren,
and that Steve is knocking
you right off that path.
What path?
The path to a happy,
productive life.
To a good college, a great
job and a family of your own.
A happy, productive life.
College, job, family!
College, job,
family!
And one day, if you're really lucky,
you'll be standing here yelling
at a teenager of your own!
College, job,
family!
College, job, family!
It's not that hard!
Darren,
are you listening?
So, wait. You...
What, you told your parents you're
not gonna be friends with me anymore?
Yeah, but, I mean,
it doesn't mean anything.
We're still like
best friends.
Okay, like what,
secret best friends?
Yeah, kind of.
I mean, no, it's like...
Look, I don't care
what they say.
Bullshit.
You do care what they say.
You do whatever they say.
That's just who you are.
You never stand up for
yourself or anybody else.
Maybe your parents
are right.
Maybe you shouldn't be friends
with me. I'm nothing. I'm garbage.
You're not garbage.
You're my friend.
You're my best friend.
Whoa!
"Cirque du Freak. One night only.
The world's greatest freak show.
"Five hundred years. "
What the heck?
Dude, that
looks awesome.
I can't go, though.
I'm grounded for two months.
Right. And we're also
not friends anymore.
What's this?
A freak show?
This is illegal.
I hope you weren't thinking
of attending this.
Because the idea of taking
a group of disgusting,
weird, deformed people and exploiting
them for money... Not in our town.
I'm assuming no one in this
class would actually go to this.
Hey. You know that means something
when the moon looks like that.
I read about it...
In one of your
vampire books?
I should explain.
Steve was obsessed
with vampires,
and I, on the other hand,
was obsessed with spiders.
I don't know why. It was just like
it was in our blood or something.
"Back in three seconds"?
One, two, three.
It's been three seconds.
Uh...
Okay.
I guess they want money.
Hey, I need two
tickets, please.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, come on. I gave you the
money, give me the ticket.
Ow! Whoa!
Holy crap!
God, what was that?
Hey, come on!
And it's gone.
You okay?
Yeah.
Hello?
Are you boys 21?
Are you 21?
Say yes.
Yeah.
Good. You don't have
a tendency towards panic,
sudden cardiac arrest or
crippling anxiety, do you?
Say no.
No.
All right, then.
Go ahead in.
Show is about to start.
Welcome.
Welcome to the
Cirque du Freak,
the oldest continuously operating
freak show in the Western hemisphere.
We have toured
for 500 years,
bringing the bizarre to
generation after generation.
May I present the Wolfman!
No sudden noises.
Dude, he totally just
scratched his balls.
No!
Call an ambulance!
It's okay.
That's not necessary.
Good boy.
And stay.
Ladies
and gentlemen,
the enchanting recycling
queen, Corma Limbs.
And now our resident hunger
artist, Alexander Ribs!
Freaky-freak,
freak for freak freak.
Oh, look, a candy corn.
And next, Gertha Teeth!
And Rhamus Twobellies!
I have arrived!
Hey, nice bike!
Come on.
That is so rude.
And next,
Evra the Snake Boy!
Stay, Bippo.
So, I'm Evra Von Britow,
and we are Serpentine.
Who's "we"?
There'll be some CDs for sale in the
lobby immediately following the show.
Bippo! No!
Bippo, drop it,
spit that out!
Yes, I'm glad you're all enjoying
this so much. It's awesome.
Evra, please
be professional.
It's not my fault.
I just want to play music.
We'll discuss it later.
But...
And now,
the voluptuous,
the exotic,
the insightful
Madame Truska!
Do we have someone brave
enough to be my assistant?
Over here.
Oh, yeah.
Come on. Come on.
You.
Who are you?
My name is Fred Smith.
I'm from out of town.
Larten, finish your act quickly,
and let's leave this town early.
What? I have someone
here tonight.
Ready for more?
Larten Crepsley
and Madam Octa!
Don't go on.
I have a foreboding.
You always have
a foreboding, beautiful.
Larten!
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
I am so excited to be here
in anonymous small town
which used to have character
but is now just a bland suburb
filled with chain stores
and surrounded by slums.
It really is a pleasure
to be here.
And I am so honored that
blah, blah, blah and so on and
so forth, et cetera, ad nauseum.
I'm afraid I have some
unfortunate news, however.
I had hoped to present my usual
act, but my spider, Madam Octa,
seems to have escaped from her
cage and is currently missing.
Use caution when retrieving your
belongings from beneath your seats.
She is very poisonous.
But not to worry.
Tonight I will perform for you
some startling illusions.
First, a rabbit from a hat.
This is Madam Octa.
Interesting fact, one bite from
this spider means certain death.
But don't worry.
As long as I stay calm...
She's beautiful.
If I could just get
my flute, that usually...
Darren. His name's
not Larten Crepsley.
It's Vur Horsten.
He's a vampire.
I saw his painting
in one of my vampire books.
It's him. He's got
the same scars,
the same hair,
the same everything.
You seriously think
he's a vampire?
Yeah.
May I have my spider
back, please?
Now, boys,
vampires don't exist,
but if one did and he
thought someone knew,
he might smother them
in their sleep.
That's it! Show's over!
It's Mr. Kersey.
Come on, let's go.
By order of the Health Inspector,
this theater is shut down!
Good Lord, not again.
Welcome to the Cirque.
What seems to be the problem?
We don't want you
filthy people here.
That's not the problem.
The problem is you are exploiting
these poor people for profit.
Thank you. Thank you so
much for looking out for us.
So you gonna let us move
in with you? Give us jobs?
Freak!
So clumsy. I felt like a
manatee. It felt terrible.
No.
Octa.
Anyone here?
Whoa.
Hey, Octa. I'm Darren.
I'm a big fan.
We can speak in private.
It's the only...
We can talk in private.
The police have left now.
So, this is what you've
been doing with your life.
You didn't
like the act.
I'm insane.
I'm insane. I'm insane.
Well, I saw the
spider bit coming.
Everybody's a critic.
It's not easy to hold an
audience's attention these days.
To us and Charna's Guts.
Did you see that
fingernail moon tonight?
The first one
in 50 years.
Yes. I noticed it.
Look, Vincent's dead.
Murdered. Sucked dry
by one of them.
They're after us, man. They're
after us. They're after us!
Those damn Vampaneze!
They're gonna pick us off.
First Vincent,
then you, then me.
Why me before you?
Well, because I'm the toughest,
and they'll save me for last.
Oh. Of course,
I forgot.
Well, what about
the Vampire Council?
They must have something
to say about Vincent.
Yes. They say good riddance.
They're a bunch of wimps now, Larten.
They'll do anything to avoid
a war with the Vampaneze.
There are no real generals left, hombre.
You and I were the last of the Mo-Freakins!
And to top it off,
Tiny's back.
Mr. Tiny?
Back from the other side?
Yes! Just last week he
was at the Council Library,
messing with
the Book of Souls.
He's trying
to destroy us all!
Megalomaniac!
That man's a megalomaniac!
And those murderous,
scumbag Vampaneze,
they're up to something, too,
and it's all connected.
It's all connected.
I can feel it!
Come with me.
We can avenge old Vincent.
Kill us some Vampaneze!
No. I'm sorry.
No? Why?
I'm done fighting.
I left that life for a reason.
I'm just a vaudevillian.
It's a simple life,
and I like it.
Steve.
I know who you are. I know
what you are, Vur Horsten.
Who sent you? The Apocalypse
Monger? The Blood Barons?
No... No one. I... No
one sent me. I just...
I have these vampire books,
and I saw a painting of him
with some girl in,
like, 1819.
It said that she broke up with him
when she found he was a vampire.
Did you hear
that, Gavner?
Missy broke up with me
because I was a vampire.
Funny, I always thought it was
the only thing she liked about me.
Let the kid go.
Let him go.
Now, are you
mentally unfit?
Didn't you hear me
threaten you at the show?
I did.
It was awesome.
You see, I want this. I want
you to make me into a vampire.
I mean, vampires, they
don't take crap from anybody.
They live by their
own set of rules.
It's true they do have their
own rules. We wrote some of them.
Yes, and one of them is
children can't become vampires.
Look, look, blood.
Blood.
You see, Gavner,
blood.
Look, if you
become a vampire,
you have to leave your
friends and your family.
It's deeply depressing.
Trust me.
Now get out of here.
I haven't seen
my dad in years.
My mom is drunk
all the time.
I absolutely hate my life.
I never actually said it
before, but it's the truth.
This is what
I was meant for.
What you're
meant for?
Well, if that's the case,
let's test your blood.
No. No.
Who sent you here?
Your blood tastes of evil.
You can never
be a vampire.
What?
I have what, bad blood?
I'm never gonna
forget this.
One day, I promise you,
I will hunt you down.
And what?
Kill me?
Do you know how easily I could
kill you? I could do it tonight.
I could knock you out and
lay you in front of a bus,
and no one
would ever know!
Calm down. Save that stuff for
the enemy. He's just an idiot kid,
who should be
leaving right now
while he still can.
You're out there, man.
All right.
One for the road.
I'm headed back
to the Mountain
to try to convince those old cowards
to stand up against the Vampaneze.
Gavner, if we kill one
of them, it means war.
Wouldn't that
be a shame?
Poor old Vincent.
You've been awfully
quiet under there.
Get in.
Thanks. Thanks,
I really needed a ride.
Oh, absolutely,
absolutely delighted.
Are you the one
known as Steve?
No, I'm the one
known as Darren.
I actually had a bike.
But I'll just get it
tomorrow in the daylight.
No need.
It's in the trunk.
Now, if I
may ask, Darren,
do you believe in the
immutability of the human soul?
The what?
So, he knows nothing
of souls, does he?
Knows only
of blood, huh?
The pulsing, the
delicious, the ruby red.
Wow, wow, you know what? You
can just let me off right here.
What's the rush?
After all, didn't we save you
from the scary, scary vampire?
Doesn't act like
leadership material.
Acts more like a bag
of blood. Are you? Huh?
Bag of blood?
Shows how much
you know, Murlaugh.
I think he reeks
of potential.
Ow!
Sorry.
Souvenir.
We all have
a destiny, Darren.
And with a few simple tests,
we can find out what yours is.
Wonderful to
meet you, Darren.
It's like looking
in a mirror.
Darren!
We'll be in touch.
Freaky dream.
Freaky. Freaky.
Hey. Hey, I'm gonna try
to get you some food, okay?
Just hold on one sec. I'm gonna go get
some flies from the window sill, okay?
Hey. Why have you
been acting so weird?
I'm not acting weird.
You were just talking
to your backpack.
What?
No, I wasn't.
Darren, yes, you were.
I wasn't. Let me... Just
let me see it a second.
You see? It's just my
backpack. Seriously, stop it.
Hey, give me my backpack,
man. Hey, just let me see it.
Holy shit! That's...
That's the...
Yeah, I went back to the theater after
the show and I kind of borrowed it.
You stole from a vampire? Do
you realize you're a dead man?
Shh!
You're a dead man!
He's never gonna find me.
Okay, just...
Wait a second. When did you
go to Vur Horsten's room,
and what did you see?
All right,
I saw everything.
Steve, are you crazy? Why would
you want to become a vampire?
Listen, you can't understand.
You have everything.
What do I have?
A secret best friend?
Hey, leave it
in there, okay?
It's fine.
I want to see it.
Be careful. Hey, be careful,
okay? Be really careful.
This thing's even
more hideous close up.
Can you just put it
back now, please?
Okay,
I need the pipe.
GIRL: I got a B-minus
in history.
No!
Oh, my gosh,
what is that?
Move!
Steve! Wait!
What's going on?
Move! Get out of
the way, idiots!
Watch out! Move!
Hey! Steve, don't!
Now I got you!
Hold still!
What's the matter with you?
Whose side are you on?
Hey! No! Hey!
GIRL: Guys, look,
it's in his shirt!
Get it off me!
GIRL: Oh, my God!
So what have you come to
steal from me this time? Thief!
Nothing. Nothing.
Look, Octa bit my best friend,
Steve, and he's in the hospital,
in a coma,
because of me.
And I was wondering
if you had an antidote.
I do.
Thank you.
But I only have
a couple doses left.
Why should I waste any
on some little psychopath?
Please, I'm begging
you, okay?
Look, I'm really sorry
I stole Octa.
I don't know what came over
me. I never steal things.
Why not?
Because it's wrong.
So then you've learned
a valuable moral lesson.
Yes, I have.
And you'll never do anything
wrong again, as long as you live.
No, I won't.
You see? Now you're
a thief and a liar.
What did
Mr. Tiny want?
Mr. Tiny?
The fat man
in the limousine!
I don't know, something about
souls and... And destiny.
And he knew
where I lived.
Looks like you're in deep
shit, my larcenous friend.
Mr. Tiny doesn't just take
a random interest in people.
And the people he does take an
interest in wind up dead or worse.
What's worse than dead?
Oh.
Lots of things.
All right. I'll do it.
I'll make you a bargain.
You'll become my assistant. I'll
turn you into a half vampire.
You'll be able to go out in the
daylight, very useful for me.
You'll do chores for me and
guard my coffin on the road.
And in return, I'll try and
keep Mr. Tiny away from you.
Oh, and I'll save
your stupid friend Steve,
despite the fact that
he threatened to kill me.
You'll save Steve?
Why not?
If I became a half vampire,
would I have to kill people?
Interested, huh?
Vampires don't kill the people
they feed on. Vampaneze do.
Big source of controversy, war
for about 80 years, then a truce,
getting ugly again,
apparently. But time's wasting.
Want to become a vampire?
It's a lonely life,
but there's lots of it.
I can't make that
decision right now.
Do you wanna go home and
ask your mommy and daddy?
Do they make all the decisions
for good little boys like you?
No, they don't.
Poor Steve doesn't
have much time left.
Fine, I'll do it. To save my
friend, not for any other reason.
So get the antidote.
Right here.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
First things first.
Let's test your blood.
What are you doing? I'm not gonna bite you
in the jugular. I could kill you that way.
Show me your hands.
Ow!
Mmm.
You have good blood. This will
work. All right, hold up your hands.
We're going
to exchange blood.
That's creepy.
I know. But that's
how it's done.
This may hurt when
it gets to your heart.
I feel cold.
Lick your fingers.
Whoa, is that like vampire
power? Do I have super-spit now?
Yes, you have super-spit.
The rest will take a while.
The rest of what?
What will I be able to do?
Can I, like, turn into a bat and stuff?
No, that's bullshit.
Now hop on my back.
We're going to flit.
We're gonna what?
Just shut up
and hop on my back.
You held your
breath, right?
Did I not tell you
to hold your breath?
Oh...
Sorry.
Hold on.
Why didn't we just
take the elevator?
I get claustrophobic.
Strange, huh, given
where I sleep every night.
But somehow when it's my own
confined space, it's different.
He looks horrible. Can you
give him the antidote, please?
She really
didn't like him.
Be careful.
Hey, what are you doing?
Shh.
That's it, right?
He's gonna be better now?
That's it.
You are insufferable.
Back! Stay back!
Code blue...
You have no idea how
ridiculous you look right now.
Code blue...
All right. If you want to pretend
this isn't happening, fine.
But being a vampire takes
skill. What is a code blue?
Code blue, code blue...
Try not to do something
stupid like kill your family.
Code blue, code blue,
room 519, stat.
You are not supposed
to be in here!
Code blue. All available
staff please report to room...
It must have hurt.
Yeah, it hurt.
It wasn't...
It wasn't fun.
It's great
you're back.
Yeah.
We missed you.
Well, well, well,
Steve is back, huh?
So, Steve, what
you got for me?
Stay away from those
brownies. They're for dessert.
Okay.
No brownies.
Next...
Hey, Darren, do you think that this
outfit looks better on her, or this?
What's going on?
You look weird.
Darren.
Darren!
Sorry.
Sorry, I... I was just
pretending to be a vampire.
Nice room.
Some excellent reading
material you have here.
Thought this was all
on the Internet now.
Mine's blocked.
Hmm.
Don't... No, don't
do that. Don't cry.
Honestly. Stop, stop.
No.
I'm not crying.
Of course not.
That's what...
Look, I don't want to hurt
people, okay? I'm not like you.
I was this close away
from killing my sister.
Perhaps you should have thought
of that before you stole my spider!
Look, I'm sorry,
but you can't stay here.
You're going to
have to leave them.
Like forever?
Like forever.
It's time to admit that
to yourself, Darren.
But you can't
just leave.
You're going to
have to die first.
Hi, Mom. Hi, Dad.
Hmm?
Hi. Hi.
Hey, I just wanted to say that you
guys are really, really good parents.
You're doing a great job, and I'm
sorry for not doing all my chores
and for complaining
so much.
And I love you
guys a lot.
We love you,
too, sweetie.
Bye, Annie.
How old were you when
you became a vampire?
Twenty. It was 1803,
the third of May.
I'd just been left by my
fiancée, Hesther Collins.
I thought she was the most
beautiful girl in Baltimore.
I saw her again 60 years
later. She was an old crone,
but my heart still
beat like a jackrabbit.
Wow, dumped, huh?
So big, bad, old Crepsley became
a vampire 'cause he got dumped?
Have you ever
been dumped?
Yeah.
Then perhaps you should
be more sympathetic.
Here it is.
Drink up.
My lips are numb.
Good.
I've got pins and
needles in my hands.
Excellent. That means it's working.
Nice night,
actually.
Is that the Little Dipper or the
Big one? I can never remember.
Sorry about that.
I had to do that or they would never
believe you were dead. Don't worry.
There's no damage
to your spinal cord,
and I'll sneak into the funeral
home and fix your broken neck.
Oh, and sorry about
this next part.
Darren,
I hate you so much for leaving
me here with these idiots.
Darren.
Hey, Shan!
Asswipe, are you in
there? Darren! Steve.
Okay, time out, time out. Not
about you. We're all feeling grief.
Wake-y, wake-y.
Here.
Fill that hole.
I can't do that. I'm all cramped
up. My legs are still numb.
Can you feel this?
Ow! What the heck?
Do you smell
a rotting corpse?
Ha, ha, very funny.
Get back in the grave.
I'm not getting
back in the grave.
Don't argue
with me. Get in.
No.
Hello, old friend. Old
Crepsley. How's the scar?
Shall I give
you another?
Hello,
bag of blood.
You're coming with me.
Run!
You come with Murlaugh now.
You're one of us.
Not one of those
filthy vampires.
Let me go!
Where are we going?
Hold your breath.
What? No, no,
no, no, no, no.
Let's go!
Not yet!
Don't look behind you.
Oh, my God. Oh, my
God! Are you all right?
Come here!
Breathe.
GIRL 1: Right over
the plate!
GIRL 2: Oh, my God.
Do you know
those guys?
Are we there yet?
Almost.
Where are we?
The Cirque's
winter campgrounds.
You'll be safe here
if they let you stay.
Try to fit in.
Come on.
So all the freaks
live here?
Yes.
Don't stare.
It's really...
You want to go to my tent? You
know, we can rehearse in my tent.
I'm not gonna
rehearse in your tent.
It'll be great, you know. You
always have fun in my tent.
Wait here for me.
Well, I was
thinking about it.
I mean, you're not gonna be
able to do this forever, right?
If you set everything up,
so I can just fill it out.
Neutral. The Cirque has
always remained neutral.
That's how it has
survived all these years.
You'll still
be neutral.
I'm not trying to drag you into anything.
I'm trying to keep myself out of it.
And why exactly do you
think Tiny wants this boy?
I'm not sure yet.
But whenever Mr. Tiny
wants something,
I make it my policy to try
and keep him from it.
That's a
dangerous policy.
Hey, what are you doing?
That's Mr. Tall's tent.
Hi, I'm Darren.
What are you
doing here?
That's what I'm trying
to figure out.
You can listen
if you want.
How much does
the boy know?
Nothing.
He's waiting by my tent if
you want to speak with him.
You know, Larten, the thing you
might not realize about children is,
they don't always do
what they're told!
Rebecca. Don't you have
work you should be doing?
Yes. Sorry, Mr. Tall. It won't happen
again. I mean, I don't eavesdrop on people.
It was his idea.
I didn't make you
do anything.
Well, you couldn't make me
do anything if you tried.
Oh, really, huh?
Enough. Rebecca,
I would like you to take
Darren to Evra's tent.
Evra will be his roommate
while he stays with us.
You'll have to work, Darren.
Everybody here pitches in.
That's fine.
I actually worked for my dad's
office a couple of weeks this summer.
I did photocopies, so...
This is on a temporary basis, Larten. I
can't endanger everybody for your sake.
Of course.
Thank you.
So, what are you doing here
anyway, with all these freaks?
Why? Do you have
a problem with freaks?
No, I mean, they kind
of freak me out, but...
They freak you out.
Clever, really clever.
Well, I really have to get back to
work. Harkat can show you the way.
Harkat, take Darren
to Evra's tent, please.
Well, you better
follow him.
Okay, see you sometime.
No, I saw what you did to my friend
Steve's hand at the theater, buddy.
Dude, I'm not giving
you my hand, okay?
I'm sorry. Here.
Harkat!
You have to stop biting people, or
no one will want to be around you.
You.
Death.
Redemption. Despair.
Triumph. Disaster.
What did I say?
"Death, redemption,
despair, triumph, disaster. "
Well, don't worry about it. Go
ahead, Harkat. Take him to Evra's.
And no more teeth.
You mean, this is it?
Chill in the laundry for a
sec. There you go. Good girl.
Good snake. Love you.
So, I guess we're gonna be
roommates. So how are you f'd up?
F'd up?
Freaked up.
How... What kind
of freak are you?
Oh, I'm not a freak.
I'm normal.
You're normal?
No. I mean,
I'm half vampire,
but I'm completely
normal.
You're a half vampire,
but you're normal.
I like that.
And don't worry about, like, if I'm
gonna drink your blood or anything.
I'm not gonna drink
anyone's blood.
What a relief. Okay,
this isn't awkward at all.
This is your corner
of the tent. All right?
You do not cross over to
any other part of the tent,
except to enter and
exit the tent. All right?
And you are never, ever to touch my
stuff, especially this stuff over here.
This is my
recording studio.
Oh, cool. Yeah, I... I actually
used to have a drum set,
but, you know, my parents
made me give it away, so...
Mmm.
Yeah.
Well, there are
no parents here.
Oh...
Yeah. Shedding,
itches like crazy.
You should actually go wash your
hand off before you get pink eye.
Did you forget to tell me you were going
to go away for a couple of days? Huh?
I can't believe you're treating me
like this. I've been worried sick.
Why can't you just
get a cell phone?
Because vampires
don't need cell phones.
"Vampires don't need this,
vampires don't need that. "
I'll tell you what
vampires need.
They need to listen. Didn't I
tell you that I had a foreboding?
And what do you do? You
show up here with that kid.
It's been a long night. I
just flitted across two states.
I think I'll just hit
the pine early.
No, wait.
You don't love me
anymore. It's my beard.
You know how I feel about you. I
just don't want to outlive anyone.
It's depressing watching people you
care about grow old while you stay young.
Have you looked at yourself
in the mirror lately?
You're no kid.
Oh, no, no. I'm still
angry at you. Mmm-mmm.
Mmm-mmm.
Your mouth says no,
but your beard says yes.
I can't believe
he's gone, man.
I know. He was
like my best friend.
No, he was
my best friend.
I knew him first.
So what?
I thought he
was a dick.
What?
Dude.
Oh, my...
Here, get up before one of the
teachers see you. That kid's psycho.
Mr. Leonard, what you got for
me here? Finish the quiz already?
MR. TINY: Careful.
Whoa!
The first step
is a big one.
Oh, I know. You miss
the one known as Darren.
You feel betrayed, abandoned.
You're a loyal friend,
unlike him.
Darren was
a loyal friend.
Oh, really?
What if I told you he's still
alive? He's taken your place,
stealing your dreams. Oh, I know.
You dream of killing people,
drinking their blood.
You dream of leading a
great, bloodthirsty army.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Mr. Tiny.
Are you a vampire?
No, I'm not a vampire.
I'm not a Vampaneze.
I'm an aficionado.
I want to see
a marvelous war.
What do you want
from me, you freak?
I'm not a freak.
I despise freaks.
Can a freak travel back and
forth between life and death?
I think not.
Can a freak create new life from
rotting flesh and dead souls?
Please.
Can a freak bring about the
apocalypse and rule the world?
No.
Sadly, neither can I, not
without help. I need a champion.
One of two boys,
two dear friends.
And by the way,
I love your DNA.
You care
for a pancake?
No, I can't. I'm...
We know
what you are.
You're bad news.
That's what.
But nothing I couldn't deal
with in just about two bites.
Don't mind him. He
just needs some Ex-Lax.
Welcome to
the Cirque.
Thank you.
Would you like to eat one of
my hands? I can grow them back.
Yeah, they
are delicious.
Hey, Vampelina.
Come on, we gotta go
clean out Wolfie's cage,
and then Crepsley left, like, a
list of stuff for you to do for him.
It looks like you're
Crepsley's bitch now.
Evra.
What?
Okay, so you guys are
gonna do it. And go.
I can't believe the tiny
people eat these rats.
They'll eat you
if you don't watch out.
Don't!
So where do you
come from anyways?
I guess I could probably,
like, open this up,
and you'd probably turn
into dust or something, huh?
You wouldn't like that
now, would you, Dracula?
Who's the boss
now, baby?
Okay. Concentrate now.
How hard can it be to flit?
Ow. Perfect.
What's the point?
I'm just not that
much of a freak.
Gertha, you're
a major freak.
Sorry, you're
not my type.
Do you ever
miss your family?
Not really.
I joined the Cirque when I
was two. Two days old, that is.
Mr. Tall found me in a dumpster.
So I guess this is my family.
Dumpster baby,
oh, dumpster baby
I wanna be your
dumpster baby
No.
Hey, this is Steve.
You know what to do.
What are you doing?
Oh, nothing.
May I see it?
Yeah, I guess.
I've always wanted
one of these.
Hey! What are
you doing?
We must be very careful
who we talk to, Darren.
Go to your tent
and stay there with Evra.
Yes. I have returned.
I have returned!
Unacceptable. Unforgivable.
To blood a child?
By the way, is he drinking
enough blood?
He's not drinking
any blood.
Not drinking blood?
Crepsley, don't you know
he has to? He must.
Or perhaps you're worried
he'll love it too much.
He might be
Vampaneze at heart.
You'd like that.
You've been favoring them
for the last 100 years.
On the contrary, I'm strictly
neutral, like the Cirque.
Correct, Mr. Tall?
Correct.
Then tell us
why you want him.
It's one of your self-fulfilling
prophecies, isn't it?
Well, one does dream
of the cataclysm.
This truce may
not last forever.
There might be new leaders.
New blood, as it were.
Perhaps a boy,
a bloodthirsty boy.
It's all been written.
Then why do you care? You're
up to something, Desmond.
Me? I may
write the script,
but the characters have a
tendency to do as they please.
You, for example, have an
unseemly amount of free will.
Now, Mr. Tall, will you be
reasonable and give me the child?
I've always done what you ask.
I'm not one to cause trouble.
But I need to think about all this.
I won't make a decision hastily.
You know, I always get
what I want, in the end.
MR. TINY: Keep an eye
on him, my pets.
Hey, dude. Sorry,
we're on our own today.
Rebecca's back in
the costume shop.
Hey.
I'm here for
Crepsley's cape.
It's that red one
with, like, the...
I know what Crepsley's
cape looks like.
What do your
friends want?
Hey! Beat it!
Does this trailer have, like,
a back entrance or something?
Yeah, it's right back there.
Wait, your pants are ripped.
Take them off.
Try this pair on.
They fit.
Yeah.
So, you know,
Rebecca, you...
You never really told me what
you're doing here with the Cirque.
Well, Darren,
since you ask,
I'm a monkey girl.
You're a what?
What?
Nothing, I thought you just
said you were a monkey girl.
Well, oh, yeah.
Yeah.
What does that mean?
It means I have a tail. Do
you have a problem with that?
No, because... 'Cause
you're joking, right?
No, I'm not joking. I keep it wrapped
up because people kept stepping on it.
Oh.
Yeah.
Anyway, your pants
look really good.
Yeah, I know. You picked
it out. That's really good.
Shush!
Thanks. They've been
spying on me all day.
So if you were interested in a
girl, okay, and she had like...
Like a tail, let's say,
would that be a problem or...
Well, I'll put it
to you this way.
If you had told me a
couple hundred years ago
that I would someday be dating a
woman with bristles on her chin,
I would have told you you
were insane. But here we are.
By the way, there's a new rule.
You're not to leave camp anymore.
Why not?
Because I said so.
You're not my dad. You can't
just tell me what to do...
When was the last time
you were in a fight?
Uh...
Second grade.
Steve's usually the one
that gets in all the fights.
Well, Steve's not
here to fight for you.
And what if
I wasn't, either?
What if you were alone in the dark
and someone wanted to kill you?
Rip out your heart
and drink its blood?
What then?
Crepsley?
Crepsley,
come on.
Crepsley?
You're hurting me.
What are you going
to do about it? Well?
You're soft. You're a soft little boy.
They're looking for you, Darren.
This is not the schoolyard.
You either have to learn to fight or
to run. So which is it going to be?
Good. But don't use your fist.
You have something better.
Use your fingernails
like a dagger. Watch.
Try it. Extend your fingers
and follow all the way through.
Use all your strength.
Ow!
God, I think
I broke a nail.
You broke a nail?
You need blood. We have
a lot of work to do.
Blood will have blood.
Are you ready, you filthy
little pig, to be stuck?
Do you renounce living
with the living?
Are you prepared
to die with the dead?
Steve, what the hell
are you doing?
Well, hi,
Mr. Kersey.
I just wanted to
stop by real quick
and actually apologize
for the way, you know,
I've been acting
in school lately.
It's 3:00 a. m.
My teachers troubled
me when I was a lad.
They caned me and caned
me till I was bloody.
Then one day, I took up
a broken switch,
and I rammed it in
my teacher's eyeball.
Who are you?
I'm his mentor.
You see, Steve?
Ow!
This is what Crepsley
wants us to live with.
So, Mr. Kersey,
what you got for me?
So you really
don't kill people?
No, Darren.
You just sedate them and feed
a little bit, and then leave.
I actually developed
the method.
Well, two other vampires
and I, Gavner and Vincent.
We were the freaks of the vampire
world. No one understood us.
And then they
started to realize
that if you don't kill your prey
every time like a little piggy,
then you don't get hunted down by irate
townspeople with pitchforks and torches.
And now half the vampires feed this
way, and the other half hate us.
Quiet now.
Whoa! How'd
you do that?
Vampires can exhale a gas
that knocks out humans.
Really?
Drink some blood, you'll be
able to do all kinds of things.
Now, we just make a small incision
in his shoulder. Right here.
And then you
take a sip.
Don't worry. He won't become a vampire
unless you exchange blood with him.
Go ahead. I had some a couple of
days ago. It's very refreshing.
No, I'm not gonna
drink human blood.
Hurry up, before someone sees
us. We haven't got all night.
I'm not going to.
You have to drink blood, Darren, or
you'll die. It's as simple as that.
Damn kid is gonna
get himself killed.
Larten, what made
you blood him?
I needed someone
to run errands for me.
Oh, come on, you didn't
need to blood him for that.
I had a feeling if I didn't,
something terrible would happen to him.
Something terrible? As
opposed to becoming a vampire?
I think you're
getting lonely.
After 200 years of living alone, why
on earth would I suddenly become lonely?
I don't know. Midlife
crisis? What is it?
They're here.
Watch out!
That's not fair.
Back!
Darren,
get out of here!
Duck!
Move.
Get in.
Psst.
Hey! Hey!
Look, I don't even
like the Wolfman,
but that don't mean you can come
in here and beat up on a freak!
You're messing with the
wrong sideshow, baby!
I'll bite your
damn noses off!
I'm gonna ram
my head up your ass.
Stop!
There'll be
no fighting here.
How dare you enter this campground?
The Vampire Council will hear of this.
Tell the little vampire
it's time to come home.
It's almost dawn. I have a spare coffin
here. I suggest you get some rest as well.
Aren't we gonna, like, double
back and attack them or something?
Do you want
to stay alive?
You're not even drinking blood yet.
I doubt you'd be much good in a fight.
Well, what if they
hurt someone?
People can look
out for themselves.
You've been
looking out for me.
Why?
Why? Because I'm
an idiot, that's why.
Only an idiot would spit
in the eye of Mr. Tiny.
Because he doesn't just kill
people, he brings them back, as well.
And when I finally die,
I plan on staying dead.
Life may be meaningless, but
death I still have hope for.
Life isn't
meaningless.
Tell me that after 200 years
of it, kid. Good day.
You know
I never liked him.
I never did,
either.
I told you
when I first saw him.
Should never
have let him in.
We all know
it's his fault.
I just can't believe he has the
nerve to walk around in here.
That poor Rebecca.
They took her?
Where?
I don't know, but they said
to tell you to come home.
Which, of course, you're not gonna
do. Wait, Darren, Darren. No, buddy.
Those guys are huge, man.
Hey, Mr. and Mrs. Shan.
Hey, Annie.
Steve. What are
you doing here?
Well, you know, I've been thinking.
You guys probably really miss your son.
And my mom is drunk half the time, so
she doesn't really notice I'm there.
How about you
guys adopt me?
No interest?
Told you they
wouldn't go for it.
Hmm.
How disappointing.
So few "people" have the
parenting instinct the way I do.
Ready for the prom?
Make new friends,
but keep the old
One is silver
and the other's gold
Make new friends,
but keep the old
One is silver
and the other's gold
Hey, Octa. Say goodbye
to Crepsley for me, okay?
Tell him I'm sorry
but I have to go home.
It's time, isn't it?
Twenty-six.
Twenty-seven, 27.
Twenty-seven.
All right, no, no.
Twenty-eight.
May I borrow
a couple of these?
Don't forget to bring them
back, though. Both of them.
You're in danger,
terrible danger.
Your life and soul
are in jeopardy.
What did I say?
Nothing. Something
about the weather.
Chance of thunderstorms tomorrow.
Don't worry. I'll stay indoors.
Applause! Applause!
Look. Little vampire.
Take a bow.
Where are my family
and my friends?
Please.
Must have patience.
Will spoil the show.
Do you like? Does Murlaugh have talent?
No? What do you
know about talent?
Where is Crepsley?
Too bad for Crapsley.
Because he will
miss the show!
Here is freak all
wrapped up tight.
And here are beloved family
members. Applause. Applause.
Hello, beloved son.
Hello, loving parents.
Hello, cute little sister.
Four bags of blood.
Don't worry.
You're all gonna be okay.
Will be better than okay.
Will be delicious!
But now, may I present
reunion with oldest friend
and blood brother,
with he that shall
one day rule us all,
the one known as Steve.
Thank you!
Steve.
You're alive?
You know, that was really an
asshole thing for you to do.
Make your whole family and your
secret best friend go through all that?
Look, I didn't mean
to hurt anybody, okay?
Who cares what
you meant to do?
What you did was take my
place. That was my dream.
Steve, what are
you doing with him?
Who? Murlaugh?
Come on, man, he's
not as bad as he looks.
You know, for one thing, he didn't
say I had bad blood like Crepsley.
And for another thing,
he didn't lie to me.
And you know what?
They think I'm awesome.
They say I have a destiny,
or whatever. Look at you.
Who wants to be a vampire
anyways? Vampires suck.
Vampaneze rule!
Juicy!
First guy I killed,
Mr. Kersey.
Blood just gets me going,
you know what I mean?
I wouldn't know. I
haven't been drinking any.
I know you. Always trying to look
like Mr. Goody-Two-Shoes all the time.
I bet you'll, like,
resist drinking blood
and resist drinking
and resist drinking it,
at the last second become
this total bloodhound!
All right, man,
here's the deal.
See, the fat guy, he still wants you on
the team, and despite everything else,
you are still my best friend.
So I'll tell you what,
I'll make you a deal that
might just save your ass.
If you kill your family,
I'll let the freak go.
Wait. My bad,
that's backwards.
If you kill the freak,
I'll let your family live.
What? Let the
juicy one go?
Hey, look, man, it's part of
the plan. Talk to Mr. Tiny.
So what do you say?
Just kill her. Oh, yeah, you
got to drink her blood, too.
You can do her in
with this.
MR. TINY: Wait!
Allow him in,
gentlemen.
I want to see
this play out.
Man, that was pathetic. You're
totally weak. You need some blood.
Murlaugh.
Finally.
And we thought you
weren't gonna show.
I hate spiders!
Darren. Come here.
Okay.
Is that your tail?
Well, yeah.
I'm really sorry I got you
involved in this, okay? I...
Please stop staring.
So you really need blood?
Yeah.
All right.
Can you just take
a little? Go ahead.
I'm offering it to you.
Thanks. But I just
can't lose it.
What?
Whatever's still
making me human.
Darren, being human's not about
what you are. It's about who you are.
No.
He's all yours, lad.
Good.
Right in the heart.
So fair and foul a day
I have not seen.
My people aren't
weak like yours.
They will avenge me,
Crepsley.
The truce, 100 years,
is over.
The war begins.
Marvelous. Magnificent.
Really. Bravo. Bravo.
It's just like you said.
We started the war.
It won't start a war if
nobody hears about it.
Young people today are
so difficult to control.
I hate you.
I hate you!
I became a vampire
to save you, Steve.
Thanks.
Go ahead. Just do it!
That's enough, boys.
Steve, come with me.
Not before
I kick his...
You will behave!
It's not time for you to fight. Not yet.
What does that mean?
Oh, it's all written
down in a book.
You do read books,
don't you?
Steve.
Look, don't...
Don't go.
What else am
I supposed to do, man?
Live with you
and a bunch of freaks?
It's too late now.
I have my destiny,
and you have yours.
How poignant. The parting
of two dear friends.
Such sweet sorrow.
Then again, you will
come home to us one day.
My prodigal son.
After all, you are
the bloodthirsty one.
No. Just because I'm a vampire
doesn't mean I'm bloodthirsty.
It's not about what you are.
It's about who you are.
Oh.
I almost forgot.
Cover yourself.
You have to teach me
how to do that someday.
Oh, I'll teach you
everything, son.
All my gibes and gambols. Now,
ready to go meet your people?
Bye, Annie.
Will it work?
Hypnotizing them?
It works on the memories, but
not on the emotions, not really.
They'll always feel that
you're still alive, somehow.
Well, that's good,
right?
Is it?
Hey, can I ask
you something?
Can I kiss you?
Darren, I let you drink my
blood. Sure, you can kiss me.
Come on. We don't have all night.
I have an injured spider here.
All right, how are we going to do
this? I can't carry the both of you.
You carry Rebecca.
I can flit now.
Just like a real vampire.
Oh, Larten, you did it.
You stuck your
neck out for him.
You'd think a vampire would know
better than to stick his neck out.
I am proud of you.
All those who vote
for making Darren
a member of the Cirque
raise your hands.
One hand, Evra.
Damn it.
It's done.
He will stay.
So we get to stay.
Not for long,
I'm afraid.
You know, Crepsley,
it's okay.
It's weird. I spent so much time wishing
that none of this would have happened
and that we never would have been
to the Cirque in the first place.
But now I really can't imagine
my life happening any other way.
Dawn's coming.
I had something made for
you. It's in your tent.
A little gift.
And it's Mr. Crepsley.
Because you told me to
throw you. Well, I'm sorry.
You did it, man. Once a
general, always a general.
I couldn't have
done it better myself.
At nightfall,
we leave with the boy.
I suppose we
should tell him.
No, let's give him one day
to rest. He's earned it.
Sometimes life does
seem all planned out,
like there's no choice
in the matter,
but that's an illusion.
Speakers. Tasty.
My name's Darren Shan,
and I don't just live with a
bunch of freaks. I am one, too.