Subs By Sobhagya
Check this www.help24online.com
"In between the years
when the oceans drank Atlantis;
- and the rise of the Sons of Aryas ".
" There was an age undreamed of,
when shining kingdoms lay spread across the world ".
" Then, came the dark empire of Acheron ".
" Where cruel Necromacer sought
'Secrets Of Resurrection'."
" They crafted a mask from the bones of Kings ".
" And awaken it's wrath,
with the pure blood of their daughters ".
" The mask, summons spirit of unspeakable evil ".
" Giving them power,
that no mortal man should posses ".
" Echeron enslaved the civilised world.
" Only The Barbarian tribes
were left to rise up against them ".
" The mask was shattered,
And Acheron vanished ".
" Each tribe kept a shrape ".
" So that, no man might attempt to join them back together.
And drive the world once again into
chaos..and ruin ".
" The pieces were scattered across the land,
and remained hidden, for ages ".
"But, prophecy spoke of the man,
who would someday, try to reassemble the mask..
and rule the world!".
" So, came the dawn of Hyborean Age ".
" A time, both bleak and brutal ".
" And so came a child...
" Born... of battle."
Do not speak, my love.
Do not speak.
- I must see my child, before I die.
Name your son.
His--name--is--Conan.
When a Cimmerian, feels thirst.
It is the thirst for blood.
When he feels cold..
It is the cold edge of steel.
But the courage of a Cimmerian is tempered,
He neither fears death,
Nor rushes foolishly to meet it.
But to be a Cimmerian Warrior,
You must have both cunning and balance;
as well as speed and strength.
Conan?
I gave you chores boy.
- I've finished, father.
The first to circle the hills
and return the egg unbroken;
Earns the right to fight with the warriors.
Oh...boy,  What are you waiting for?!
We go back!
Conan!
Make way..make way!
Come, It's time to forge you a blade.
The sword we make,
will be yours one day.
But, before you wield it,
You must understand it.
The sword must bend or it will break.
It must be tempered.
What is most important,
when forging a blade?
Fire or Ice?
- Fire.
- Ice?
- Are you certain?
Fire and Ice.
Together...
This is the mystery of steel
No! Slow down.
Find your footing.
Enough!
You're not ready for this sword.
Fire!
Conan!
Father!
Khalar Singh: Barbarian?
There's no shame in kneeling before me.
Each of these brave warriors...
has surrendered half their lands;
Sworned..allegiance to me.
They do so, because they knew...
One day, I will be a GOD.
- One day...
The other clans of Cimmerian will gather for vengeance.
And then, God Or No God...
You will fall.
- You know why I am here.
One piece is missing, from the mask.
You know it's power.
Give it to me now!
--or die.
Then, I'll find it for myself.
- I prefer death.
This is your son?
I like him.
Come here, my daughter.
Father..
I sensed the last scharp is close.
- Will you find it for me, Marique?
Barbarian, your son has courage.
But my daughter,
has talens as well.
Find it, Marique!
This Cimmerians...
they do not pray.
This is their church.
This is what they worship!
It will be here!
The Charred!
She found the bone charred.
Your mother would be proud.
Remo!
Gather the men.
Burn everything!
No, not the boy!
Not yet.
- Look what he did to my face!
Now...
How do I punish you, huh!?
Feeling of pain or death...
Worst then death, eh? Cimmarian,
Watching your son die.
Because he loves you.
It is complete.
Marique?
We are half way there.
When we find the pure blood...
Your mother,
My beloved...
Will return!
The Mask, is complete!
Conan.
You cannot save me.
Let go of the chain, boy.
- I'm not afraid to die!
- It's alright.
- I love you son.
Noo!
" Conan left Cimmeria..
And wandered the edges of the world."
" Slaying...
Thieving...
Surviving."
" Storming the high walls of Vanerium,
and prowling the dark seas among pirates."
" But the nameless man, who slaughtered his village.
and killed his father,
remained in shadow."
He is a common slaver, Conan.
Not the man you seek.
Why is that?
- No man should live in chains.
Stay and fight!
You pig bellied, motherless..Goat lovers!
Go! You are free.
Go..your masters are dead.
You're no longer slaves.
- But, you've taken all our foods.
All our weapons.
- Where would you have us go.
- We sail to Messantia!
C'mon, old man!
I win!
I still win.
- When I first met him...
He was no bigger than,
just a scrawny little rat.
Picking pockets as a moron.
Even so,
It was he...
Who stole the elephant's heart!
And threw the sorcerer, Yarrah!
We need more mead.
Guards!
There...
Check there.
Hey!
Why are they looking for you?
- No, no..no...no!
No, wait! You don't understand.
They will take us both to the prison.
- Maybe, I want to go to prison.
You take the one in the middle.
- Me?
- You!
- I'll take him.
Run little man.
I am your prisoner.
Where is the captain?
- hmmm..ahh!
The hill ape can speak.
The captain is currently occupied.
- Don't worry, everyone can get their chance.
- Where the hell is the captain?
- ...He can only open it for me.
- Who are you?
- I’m the one who made you pretty.
- You can't do this!
You know who I am???
Where is the man, who killed my father?
- You speaking of the king?
No.
- My people were slain by a common bandit.
Not a king.
- He was a bandit then,
He's a legend now.
A shadow lord!
- A shadow lord..huh?
Speak.
- I will not kill you.
- You know the forbidden forest...
- Nothing there but dead, bodies and the animals who feed on em.
- He's heading there as we speak.
???
- More.
- Not good enough.
- Wait!
- The forest is large, I know.
But that's where he turned to his stronghold,
The Gorcalva.
He returns by the way of the Ravina Charboad.
- That a big place for an ambush.
- What's he looking for, out there?
- He's with his Witch daughter.
They're searching for a  young girl...
A pure blood.
- Are you leading me into a trap?
- No, I would not lead you.
His mad!
He's obsessed with Assyrian sorcery,
I hold no loyalty to him.
Well, Northerner...
I've upheld my part of the deal.
What are you doing!!?
- Toasting, to our deal.
Wait for me.
Prisoners of Messantia!
The key to your freedom!
Sits in your captain's gut.
- You gave me your word!
You swore you will spare my life!
- I said, I will not kill you.
Free yourselfs.
My name is Ela-Shan.
Brother, there's no lock I cannot break or fort I cannot enter.
Ask anyone you meet ther for, Ela-Shan!!!
What do you see?
Why don't you speak, Fassir?
- It is unclear.
I see a journey.
A man.
- A knight?
- A warrior.
From a path, he'll emerge.
It will take you home, to your birthplace.
- Is that all that you see, Master?
The pure blood is close..
I can taste her in the air.
There will be rioting in Messantia,
For days...
Thanks to you.
- Khalar Singh.
- What?
- That's the name of the man, who killed my father.
- Do you know who that is?
I am told, he's the angel of death.
- I'll leave tonight..
to Shapur outpost.
- We can sail as far as the bay,
near the Shapur outpost.
- Then, you wait for me there.
- Wait?
- I'm not your servant maid.
I will go with you.
- Not this time, Artus.
This is something, I must do alone.
Go to the temple!
Go, go.
Go, go!
Come with me.
- Get into the Carriage.
- No, we must stay here, and defend our home.
- For the sake of your people,
you must leave this place and go to ..??
Do not hesitate and do not wait.
- I don't want to leave you.
- Do you trust me, Tamara?
- Yes, with my life, everything I have.
- Then, ask no more questions and do as I say.
- Where is Khalar?
- Who is Khalar?
Step aside, Northerner.
The woman is property of Khalar Singh.
- She's my property now.
- Oh, You have no claim to her.
- No, but I have a claim to you.
- And what claim is that?
- Death!
Who are you?
- When you fight a Cimmerian,
Even a boy.
You best kill him.
- I've killed hundreds of Cimmerian.
- Yes, an entire village.
???
Run from me...
And I will tear apart the moment I find you.
And I will follow you to hell.
Woman!
Come here.
I said, come here.
Which one of you...is the pure blood?
Who ever reveals her...
Gets to live.
And you smell...
Are you?
The one I seek.
Could it be you?
None of them, are here!
You know, who I've come for.
Why suffer for it?
- None of the ancient bloodline remain.
- If that is true...
Tell me, why have you and this monks,
chosen to hide here, like vermins for thousand years?
- We live here, in peace.
We have no rituals.
We do not make war.
We value..life.
- You value life.
You forget what happened, in the forest of Ophea?
When all the nations of Hyborea,
hunted a woman, as if she were an animal??
When both I and my daughter, were forced to watch...
My leige and innocent wife,
being lashed to rear and set aflame!
HUH!!!?
No, what you value is dead.
- Monsier, I had no part in her dead.
- Where's the pure blood?
- Not to fear, father.
He will tell me his secret.
They all tell me the secrets!
- Your vain pursuit for the secrets of Achelon,
Is a  lust for power!
Oh, for love of life...
Your...'innnocent wife'?
Sought to enslave all of Hyborea,
With her Sorcery.
She, deserved to burn!
You..will never rule.
And the evil, will never rise again!
My Lord,
Remo was searching for the one that got away.
- She is the pure blood.
Remo will capture her for me.
Get off.
My master said we'd meet you.
He said our path will emerge.
- You're the one Khalar Zym seeks?
- I know nothing, about it.
- Those were his men, chasing you.
- They attacked our monestary.
- So,
Will you escort me to Hyricanea?
- We willl wait for Khalar.
- We?
There is no 'we'.
I will go to Hyricanea, as my master instructed.
- I said...
We will wait.
- I said, I will go to Hyricanea.
- Why must I be tied up?
- Keep quite, and do as you're told.
- What are you going to do with him?
- I will wait for him to awaken,
...I might as well kill him.
- Do you have a name?
- My name is Tamara Amelia Jhorvi Karushan.
- And yours is?
- Conan.
- Conan. That's it?
- How many names do i need?
- Why would you save me,
Only to tie me up?
....???
If I possess you..
He must come to me.
- Possess?
I am not your property.
- Go to sleep.
- I take no instruction from no man.
I'm a monk.
Of the order of Shairpur.
My people have never been ....anyone who..
What?
- Be quite!
Still no word of Remo, and his scouts?
- Remo will bring her here.
He has never disappointed me.
- The prize is near, father.
Soon, you'll have not only the mask...
But the blood to fill it.
I recount, how your mother yearned..
For the sorcery of Achelon.
Imagine, the secrets
she'll bring back from the realm of the dead.
Imagine...
How indominable I will become,
When she's once again by my side.
- Father?
If the girl is lost...
or the rituals fail???
- It will not fail.
- If it does?
- It will not!
Your mother will return to me.
- My powers...
are growing, inside of me.
My mother's blood flows through me.
I can help you, uncover
the secrets of Achelon,
Just as she did.
I can have them all, kneeling before you.
Just as I kneel before you now.
- My Marique...
You are like your mother.
In so many ways.
But you're not her.
Here...drink.
The truth this time...
Why does Khalar wants you?
- I'm a simple monk.
I am of no value to a Warlord.
Remo: She's lying!
Its her blood.
Her blood is special.
She's last of the bloodline of Achelon.
- Wait?
Don't kill him yet.
You are mistaken.
That bloodline ended a thousand years ago.
- You lying whore!
- You can kill him now.
- No, please!
For her, I can get you a king's ransom.
It is true.
Khalar has been searching for a pureblood decendent
for twenty years.
- Then, we will wait for Khalar.
He will not come this way.
He will be in Shaipurabin, waiting for me.
I can show you.
See, I speak the truth.
If you want...
He will give you, your weight in gold.
For this woman.
I will arrange everything!
I will deliver the message.
- Yes you will.
Remo returns.
- What does it say?
- The Shaipura outpost,
Mid day..
come alone.
It's hers.
You're bold, Northerner.
I admire courage,
even when it's foolish.
Your reward...
- I do not want your gold.
- No?
Then, what?
- I want your head.
- Yes, of course. You do.
Kill him..
Then bring me the pure blood.
- Who are you?
- You left me behind, to watch my father die.
Cimmerian.
That was your chance, boy.
You won't get another.
Wouldn't your father be ashamed of you?
C'mon!
Jump!
I had him.
- The Gods are cruel.
- Bless the Gods,
This was not their doing.
- How does his eyes feel?
Are the tales they tell true?
Does he have eyes, red as fire?
And the hide, of golden scales?
- He is just a man.
- Then, it is he..who has failed.
In fact...
You may be the only man in Hyborea.
To fight Khalar Zym.
and live.
I need to go ashore and find her.
After I go,
you must take her some place safe.
She saved my life.
For that she has my loyalty.
- Then, she has mine as well.
- Charming man, your friend.
- Most man are born to Mother's milk.
His first taste, was of his mother's blood.
He was battle born.
- So, all he can do is kill?
Oh no..
- He has the heart of a King.
The loyalty of a bloodhound.
Barbarians maybe warriors..
But they do not sacrifice their children,
or enslave their allies,
like the priest and princess of the civilised world.
As for his manners...?
- You look like a harlot.
- Yes,
and apparently,
i'm the only one you've ever met..who isn't one.
- Cimmerian women dress as warriors.
Give her the leather and the armour.
I think he likes you.
Wake up!
How many Cimmerians died at this edge of blade..
Not bad.
- Farewell, good friend.
- May you find, what you seek, Conan.
It would seem,
our friend has forgotten his map of the shore line.
You should take it to him.
And say, goodbye.
©© Subtitle By D3xt3r ©©
We set sail at dawn.
Don't be late.
You should go back to the ship.
- Have you ever wonder,
if our actions serves some plan...
Some purpose..
One by the Gods?
- Are we all just doomed to chaos and ruin?
- I know not. and I care not.
- I live...I love
and slay.
And I am content.
Goodbye.
Conan!
Ah...the elusive one.
Welcome!
- You have made a mistake.
I am not the person, you are looking for.
It is she.
The pure blood decendent.
The Nacromancers of Achelon.
- I'm looking for a thieve.
- ...is city of thieves.
- I'm looking for a thieve named Ela-Shan.
- Who are you, to ask?
Barbarian.
Stand down fools!
Fast as ...?
He will gut you like a fish.
- I owe this man my life.
- Well, Ela-Shan...
You have your chance to repay it.
Come.
This is madness.
Breaking into Khalar Zym's fortress is like
reaching under a sleeping dragon to steal her eggs.
Why go in?
- There's a woman inside.
- She must be really pretty.
My mother wore this gown on her wedding day.
It flatters you.
- I am not your mother.
- No.
but you will be.
Imagine that your body is a vassel.
And your soul is the water that fills it.
When your blood seeds the mask...
My father will empty you.
- Then, I welcome death.
- Your dead,
shall herald a new age of Achelon.
The spirits I raise will melt flesh from the bones of Kings.
And my wife will make me a God!
And we will cast all rivals into oceans of blood.
Please, I beg you one last time.
Do not do this.
Let us turn back.
Come on.
Did you know, I met your barbarian...
When he was a boy?
That I took his sword from him.
I'm told, Cimmerians steel is sharper and harder than any other.
That when it cuts,
The pain is close to pleasure.
I know that will please you.
I told you, you see?
I told you I can get you in.
A feast for my sword.
No, a feast for the Nuara!
Watch out!
Conan...
Get me out of here!
- Use the key.
- I can't. I dropped it!
Then, pick the lock!
With what?
You scream like a woman.
I think he headed to that Scor Cave,
- I see no more lucks down there.
- Your debt is paid.
Go on, then.
If you ever need me again,
You know where to find me.
As Victorius Barbarian's shattered the mask.
So, shall it vanquished
if barbarian sword's should survive it.
Pure blood!
Behold!
In despair...
Your new Master!
My Queen!
Hear my call.
Conan.
Barbarian, I don't like you anymore.
This was your chance, Khalar.
You won't get another.
I smell you.
Conan!
Barbarian!
You're too late!
She belongs to me!
Die!
I'm going to kill you,
with your own father's blade!
You're not wielding my father's sword.
Come on.
Barbarian!
I am coming for you!
I summon you here.
His witch has possessed me.
I can't fight her.
Drop me Conan, please.
- Once again,
The little Cimmerian is caught, holding a chain.
Let me go!
Boy...
There's no shame in kneeling before me.
She wouldn't live forever.
Let go of the chain.
Let go of the chain, Conan.
- And let another die in your place?
Like your father.
Drop me!
- I warned him...
That one day,
I will become a God!
And my father warned you...
God or not.
Let me go!
- You will fall!
Thank you for bringing me home.
- I know you have to leave.
- Live well, Tamara.
Until, we meet again.
" The sword we make, will be your one day ".
" Before you wield it,
You must understand it."
Subs by Sobhagya
Check this www.help24online.com