Oh, man.
Man, what's takin' you so long?
It's cold as a motherfucker out here.
I had to get the last stop.
Quiet, punk.
- I'll shut your hairy ass up, man.
- Come on, man. I'm freezin'
my fuckin' nuts out here!
Mush, motherfucker, mush!
Ant, Juanita gave you
some of that pussy yet?
- Man, get out of here, man.
- What?
Man, I thought we was homies, man.
I'm just askin'.
Well, why you gotta be
askin' me all that? I mean...
I'm just lookin' out for you.
All I'm sayin', man, fine as she is,
she should be giving you something.
I bet you ain't even
smelled the pussy, eh?
You two realize that soon
we're gonna be out of school, right?
- Oh, sure.
- After four long years
of that shit, man.
I can't fuckin' wait to get out. That's
all I've been thinkin' about, man.
You know? I just be thinkin' about like
what am I gonna do afterwards, right?
You know, I can dig some travelling.
Nigger, you sound like
you rich or somethin'.
Hear this nigger?
He ain't even got a fuckin' job.
- I know.
- Man, you better take your ass off
to college, man, I'm tellin' you...
before Uncle Sam grab your ass like
he gonna do this stupid motherfucker.
Oh, bullshit, Skip, man.
Ain't nobody gonna grab me.
Jose, a recruiter
can see your dumb ass a mile away.
Look at you.
You're a recruiter's dream. You a 1-A.
A one-way ticket to motherfuckin'
Vietnam if I ever saw one.
That's why I'm goin' to Hunter College.
You goddam right.
I ain't fightin'
no white man's war. Shit.
Them Vietcongs, chongs, whatever
the fuck, ain't done shit to me.
I don't even know
them motherfuckers, man.
And I ain't afraid of no war.
Man, what the fuck you been smokin'?
Look, y'all might think
I'm crazy, but...
I just wanna do somethin'
that's different.
Yeah, well, gettin' your
fuckin' head blown off is different.
Hey, man, turn that shit down!
And slow this motherfucker down!
- Ain't nobody in a hurry
to go to school.
- Man, leave that shit up.
You know I fucked Monica, right? Her
mama came in, caught us the other day.
Came in, seen my dick,
jumped in the bed too.
- Later on, you chump suckers.
- Ah, fuck you.
- Your mama!
- Punk ass, jivin' around.
- Hey, this is for you,
Anthony, right here.
- Close this motherfuckin' door.
It's cold as hell out here.
Sit your nasty ass down.
Oh, hey. How you doin'?
You up kinda early.
Um, I heard your truck.
Seems like you hear my truck
every mornin'.
Well, uh, morning
is the best time to study, so...
You should, uh, try workin'
on your first boyfriend.
I'm too busy studyin'
to be worryin' about boys.
Your sister up?
Uh, Sleeping Beauty?
Yeah.
Look, uh, tell her I said hey.
See ya.
- Good morning, Anthony.
- Oh, hey.
- I thought you were sleeping.
- You woke me up.
- Uh, so you goin' to school today?
- Mmm.
I could lay in bed all mornin'.
Oh. See, now...
Now that'd be real nice.
- Don't even think about it.
- Well, look, uh...
I'm gonna get on out of here.
I'll talk to you later.
- Okay.
- See ya.
Keep on pushin'
- I'll be down there later on.
- Got to keep on pushin'
I can't stop now
Hard shoe.
Come here, hard shoe.
Come here, man.
What's up? What's up?
Listen, I want you...
I want you to tell Kirby I want 645.
- Straight, now. Listen. And, uh...
- Straight.
- We've been rollin' here.
- Come on, man. I ain't got time.
- Let me get the money.
- I want you to be back here tonight...
- Man, straighten your hat out.
- With my money, you little motherfucker.
- What's goin' on, baby?
- All right, baby.
- All right, cat daddy. All right.
- Hey, Anthony. How you doin'?
- Hey.
You know, you brought me luck the other
day. So look, ten of that's for you.
- See? Now, that's how it goes.
- Hey, now.
- L-I'm gonna use the same number too.
- Don't forget me, man.
What's goin' on?
Hey, what's goin' on?
Hey there, Jellybean.
What's goin' on?
Hey, what's goin' on?
How you been?
Kirby back there?
All right. Cool.
- Go on, get that shot. Get that shot.
- All right, thanks, youngblood.
Hey there, Peanut! What's goin' on?
What's up there? What...
Blood.
- Come on, come on, come on.
- Kirby's back there in the back, man.
Put that in Brooklyn
and get ahold of that fuckin' Spyder.
- Okay, man.
- Hey, brother.
- Aw, man, take them.
- Yeah, yeah.
Here's the numbers and the cash.
- We got five.
- Hubba hubba!
Ain't you supposed to be
duck huntin' with your daddy?
Oh, yeah.
We gonna go next weekend.
- Aw, shit!
- Oh, man, Kirby.
Made me miss my shot.
You know these motherfuckers down South.
I wonder if half the time
they believe what they be sayin'.
What's a nigger gonna do?
We got blood in this land
from slaves.
Been to war. Spilt our blood.
Shit, I been to war. I spilt blood.
Ha! That's right.
Tell 'em, Kirby.
You over there fightin' in Korea.
That's how I got this plastic-ass leg.
Nicky, fix me a drink.
Ko-motherfuckin'-rea.
Damn! Mmm!
Never gonna give you up
That's why I had to leave that
motherfucker, because if I'd have...
If I'd have still been down there,
I'd have killed me a motherfucker.
Man, shit ain't gonna change.
What make you think shit gonna change?
Nigger, what's your little
narrow ass doin' up in here, man?
Leave that boy alone
and let him shoot.
Aw, Kirby, man, you know he too
goddam young to be up in here, man.
He can outshoot you.
Oh, shit.
Oh, I know you out
your motherfuckin' mind, man.
Put your money
where your mouth is.
I take your money.
Rack 'em, boy.
- Uh, huh, huh, huh
- Watch this.
I got the feelin'
Baby, baby, I got the feelin'
- Yes!
- You don't know
You got my two dollars?
Game ain't over yet, man.
Got the eight ball,
corner pocket.
Oh, man!
Don't run out of here without payin' me
after that boy whup you.
Yeah, at least I will
run out of this, motherfucker.
People that owe me money don't pay me,
I take care of 'em.
Man, will you get the fuck off
my motherfuckin' table, please?
- Baby-baby-baby, baby-baby-baby
- Chicken-haired motherfucker.
Ain't no goddam business
bein' here in the first place.
Ooh, missed it by that much.
- Cleanup time.
- You don't never play with me.
Eight ball, corner pocket.
Oh! Yes! Game.
Hey, that's a good game, Cowboy.
You're a lucky motherfucker,
you know that?
Aw, I wouldn't say luck,
but, you know.
- Just know how to play a little bit.
- Here's the money.
- Give that to Kirby.
- All right.
Uh, wait, wait.
This is two dollars.
See, uh, you bet me, so that means,
uh, you owe me some money too.
Man, fuck you.
Why you gotta cheat?
Man, who the fuck you think
you talkin' to, man?
You know what? I'm gonna tell
everybody around here...
when it comes to playin' pool,
Cowboy likes to cheat.
Nigger, I'll kick
your little monkey ass, man.
Oh, man.
Shut your motherfuckin' mouth, man.
I oughta cut you.
Little motherfucker. Yeah.
It hurt, don't it?
What the fuck?
What the fuck are you doin'?
Get the fuck off of me, man!
Kirby, what the fuck you doin', man?
- What the fuck are you doin'?
- What the fuck are you doin', man?
- Get on out of here!
- You a bad motherfucker!
- And don't you come back in here
unless you come correct.
- Fuck you!
- You all right, kid?
- Oh, yeah.
Just a little cut, you know.
It's all right.
Yep. You do a real good job
for me with them numbers.
Well, you know, I try.
But, uh, you better be cool.
Don't let your mom and pop find out.
Oh, no way.
I won't do that.
It's for you.
Oh, man. Whoa!
- Hey, thanks, Kirby.
- Ain't nothin' to thank me for.
- You earned it.
- Oh. Twenties.
Hey, kid, you wanna take
a little run with me?
Yeah, I'll take
a little run with you.
Say, uh, Kirby, where we goin'?
Like I told you,
just a little run.
A run. Okay. All right.
- Wanna drive, kid?
- Who, me?
No, not "me."
You, motherfucker.
Well, Kirby,
I don't have my licence yet.
Aw, shit. Fuck the dumb shit.
You wanna drive or what?
Yeah. All right, I'll drive.
Yeah.
- Pull over here.
- All right.
Come on. Come on.
What you call her, Nellie?
Come on, Nellie.
I call this bitch
whatever I wanna call her.
Listen here.
Keep that motor runnin'.
- I'll just be a minute here.
- Yeah, all right.
- Stop messin' with my gold!
- Wait a minute!
- How many times I gotta tell you?
I ain't no motherfuckin'
play toy! I'll kick your ass!
- Get the fuck up!
- You get the fuck up off of Spyder!
No.
You got more heart than
your punk-ass old man. Come here.
- Oh, man, Kirby!
- Oh, what the...
Give me my fuckin' leg,
you stupid son-of-a-bitch!
You grabbed the wrong leg,
you stupid cocksucker. Come here!
- Get on back in here now, Spyder.
- You asshole!
- I want my motherfuckin' money, hear?
- Easy, Kirby.
- Now!
- Easy, man!
- Dumb son-of-a...
Give me my fuckin' leg,
you stupid cocksucker.
- I'll fuck you up.
- Get on back down there.
- They gonna call the police.
- I got 15 miles to go now
- Come on. Come on!
- And I can hear my baby callin' my name
Floor this motherfucker.
Floor it.
Now I'll be so glad
to see my baby
And hold her in my arms
one more time
Now when I kiss her lips
- I'll turn a backward flip
- You did good, kid.
You're almost as good
a getaway driver as me.
Uh, thanks. Say, uh...
So you were a getaway driver, huh?
- Son-of-a-bitch!
- What? Wh-What's wrong?
- I oughta go back there
and kill that bastard.
- Why? What happened?
Motherfucker made me lose
a whole pack of cigarettes.
A pack of cigarettes?
I thought maybe you should be
worried about your leg or somethin'.
- Oh, that shit's funny to you, huh?
- No, no, it's not funny.
I tell you what. The next time
the motherfucker grabs me by...
the wrong leg, I'm gonna use it to kick
his ass between his shoulder blades.
- Hey, man, you really did that sucker.
- Yeah, everybody in town...
know I got one leg, and that
motherfucker grab the wrong one.
Me and Kirby, baby. Yeah.
- This is wonderful news, Edward.
- Thank you.
All right, all right.
You see, Anthony?
You be thankful you can go to City
College on the financial aid programme.
Yeah, in four years,
you can be just like me.
Just like you?
You can graduate and maybe even
go to graduate school too.
Well, I'll tell y'all one thing.
My mama sure would've been proud.
Never would've believed
I got two college graduates.
You think about what
you're gonna major in, baby?
The Marine Corps.
Uh, Dad, could you pass the salt?
What'd you say?
Thanks. I said
the, uh, Marine Corps.
- I'm... I'm joinin'.
- Marine Corps?
- Yeah.
- Now that's original.
What you talkin' about, Anthony?
I'm talkin' about
I wanna do somethin' else.
I don't wanna go to college.
I'm sick of school.
I mean, I don't know why everybody
got this strange look on their face.
- It's my life.
- Yeah.
It's your life.
Looks like to me
you're tryin' to ruin it, baby.
You're an idiot.
You know that?
Dad, I don't wanna go to college.
I'm just not ready for no college.
You always said the marines and fightin'
over in Korea made a man out of you.
I figure I be, you know,
livin' my own life.
I'll talk to your mama.
When your baby and you are tight
and everything is right
- And you is mellow
- Give me that.
There you go.
Now, drink some wine.
You keep everything all right
And you know that
you're the only fellow
Ain't that a groove
Told your little ass
you couldn't drink with me.
- Ain't that a groove
- Hey, James. Want some of this?
- Now, lookee here, fella
- Yeah! Whoo!
Girls like to be in the mood
whenever they think their man is yellow
- Whoo! Yeah!
- Hit me, baby
Say, Skeeter, I still can't
believe you graduated, man.
- Man, shut up.
- Glad we out of school, man.
I'm sick of these
stupid-ass brothers.
I'm about to get
my pimp thing on started.
You know, I got so many ho's now, man,
I gotta get an assistant pimp...
just to keep in track of 'em,
you know, make sure they on
the right streets and shit.
Say, Skippy, why... why you always
talkin' about this pimp stuff, man?
What's happenin'?
'Cause it's real, man. I'm a pimp.
Pimpin' run in my family.
My great-great granddaddy was a slave,
and he was a pimp.
He used to have his ho's
pick his cotton in the field.
He didn't have to do shit.
You better be careful, man. You're
gonna catch something, Skip. Watch.
That's all right, motherfucker.
I was born by the pussy,
I'll die by the pussy.
Don't worry about
what the fuck I do.
Hey, Skip, do you
believe in superstition?
Hell, no.
Well, you should, man.
Your stupid ass jinxed me.
- What the fuck you talkin' about?
- Uncle Sam, man.
Dropped a motherfuckin' 1-A on me.
I told you, didn't I?
Didn't I tell you?
- Say, when did that happen?
- Last week, Anthony, man.
Yeah, right, motherfucker.
Pass the joint.
- Anthony, man.
- What?
You know that, um,
that me and Marisol, we tight, man.
Yeah, man, y'all are...
Y'all pretty down.
- You would say I love her?
- I don't know.
I could say that you love her.
- I'm thinkin' about marrying her, man.
- Oh, wait a minute.
- Hey, don't do that shit.
- Hey, man, you might be goin'
a little too fast now.
Hey, I love her, man, and did you see
how she looks today at that party, man?
- She looks good enough to marry.
- I'm glad to hear you want me.
What you over here
talkin' about, Anthony?
- Why you standin' over here?
- Shut up, Skippy.
- Shut up.
Anthony, I know you ain't gonna
stay over here talkin' to Skip
while my song's playin'.
Not if they expect to be
with us tonight.
- Look here, Skippy, we gonna
have to cut on out, bro.
- Uh, yeah.
- Man, where y'all goin'?
- Uh, we gonna go hang on out.
- Look it, have some chicken.
- I thought we was hangin', man.
- Have some chicken, man.
I told you about them broads,
old punk-ass.
And anyway, Skip,
Brenda lookin' for you.
I don't give a fuck.
You tell her I'm at where I at
and I'll be where I be.
Motherfuckin' pimp.
If I gotta go where every ho
want me to be, I be confused.
Motherfucker. Tell her
don't make me hurt my hand again.
If you want a do-right all day
Woman
You gotta be a do-right
All night
Jose, I love you.
I love you too, mama.
If you give my pussy away
to somebody else...
while I'm gone...
I'm gonna come back
and blow that motherfucker up.
I got this itch
I need to be scratched.
S-S-S-So... So you're sayin'
that y-your, your mama...
is workin' a night shift tonight?
Mm-hmm.
And you know what else?
You could scratch it
all night long if you want to.
You know I'm the nigger. I'm the nigger.
You swear Big Bertha
won't get off work early?
She's not gonna get off
from work early.
- You scared?
- No, I ain't scared. I just don't...
You act like you're scared.
Come on. Shut up.
- Where Delilah at?
- She in her room. Come on!
- Say it loud
- I'm black and I'm proud
- Get out.
- Say it loud
- I'm black and I'm proud
- Go to your own room.
- Say it loud
- I'm black and I'm proud
Once upon a time
I almost lost my mind
I was lonely
So lonely
Once upon a time
Oh, Juanita.
Look, it's okay.
It's all right.
It's okay.
- Okay. Okay.
- Let me get your bra.
- Okay.
- Let me get it.
- Ow. Just unhook it. Just unhook the...
- I can't. I can't.
I'll get it.
I'll do it. I'll do it.
- Okay. Okay.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Don't peek. Don't look at...
Don't look at me. Okay.
Okay. Okay.
- Oh!
- What?
That's not it.
Up, up, up, up. Higher. Ow.
- That's too high. Wait. Down, down.
- Okay, wait.
- Right there? Okay.
- Yeah.
- Okay. Okay.
- All right.
- It's okay.
- Uh-oh. Wait.
Okay. Easy. Ow!
Ah!
Oh, shit. Wait, wait, wait.
- Oh, shit.
- Okay.
- Baby.
You know, Marisol and Jose
goin' down to city hall tomorrow.
Oh, yeah? What for?
To get married.
- Is that right?
- What you think about that?
Nothin', I guess.
So I guess you don't want me
to wait for you either.
Look, Juanita,
I didn't say that.
So then you're gonna marry me
when you get back?
I mean, if you
ain't got somebody else.
I don't want nobody else.
Juanita, have you
ever thought maybe...
maybe I might get hurt out there
and never come back?
You know, I don't want
you waitin' for nothin'.
You're not scared of losing me?
I didn't say that either.
I'm scared of losing you.
So, do you think we could probably
do it one more time before I go?
Uh-huh.
Oh, no.
- It's Ma!
- Shh! But it's just 6:30!
- She just pulled up.
- Well, go stall her. And close my door!
- Shoot! Shoot! Shoot!
- Oh, man.
I shouldn't have never messed around
with you in the first place.
- Right.
- You know Bertha gonna kill us.
- Wait a minute.
- Uh-uh. Ain't gonna wait no minute.
Would you move?
- Wait a minute!
Come on. Let me help you
with them packages.
- Delilah!
- I got it.
Girl, you got my good groceries
all on the ground.
Pick those up.
Since I work, the least you girls
could do is keep this place clean.
You know I'm gonna
wait for you, Anthony.
Juanita, I gotta go.
I gotta go, Juanita.
- Nigger, get out of my yard!
- Fuck you!
Shut up!
What's your status? Over.
Shit.
Head for the rally point!
Get back to the rally point!
Get the fuck outta here!
Let's go! Pick it up!
Pick it up! Come on! Come on!
Come on! Move!
Move! Let's go!
Load 'em up! Load 'em up!
Oh, fuck!
I'm out of ammo!
- Devaughn! Cover me!
- Stay down!
I got him! Hurry up!
Don't check out on us, Martin.
You're gonna be all right.
- I got him!
- Cover fire!
Goddam it! They got us pinned down!
We'll never make the rally point!
Dugan!
You think it's time we get these
fucking dinks off our asses? Huh?
- Relax.
- Fuck you!
Fuck you, fuck you, fuck you!
Radio, up!
God don't like dinks.
- How's he doin', Curtis?
- Thanks. Thanks for not leavin' me, man.
- Where the fuck is that radio?
Get that radio up here!
- No, no, no, no, no.
Radio comin'! Radio comin'!
Get that cover fire, Ferguson.
You wanna die, boy?
Sir, sir! Lieutenant!
Arty freak!
Hammerhead, Hammerhead. Recon Cobra.
Emergency fire mission. Over.
Hold on, brother. Come on.
Come on, come on.
You gonna make it, dude.
You only got a little longer.
- You gonna make it.
- Grid five, seven, one-niner.
- Tell my mama...
- No, no, I don't...
Gooks in the bush.
Request firecracker salvo. Will adjust.
How copy? Over.
Roger. Solid copy.
Firecracker shot out.
Incoming!
Down! Down! Down!
Curtis, get down!
Out-fucking-standing job.
Saddle up. Let's get to the rally point,
take that whirlybird home.
- We got some beer to drink.
- We goin' to the rally point now?
The mission's been compromised.
We're goin' to site 37.
It ain't compromised no more.
They're dead.
Now this is Sneaky Pete.
Reconnaissance.
Some of them dead gooks...
they could have important
intelligence papers on their bodies.
All right.
- Move 'em out.
- Move out!
Hammerhead, Hammerhead.
Cobra on site of your mission now.
I count ten... say again, ten...
November-Victor-Alpha-Kilo-lndia-Alpha.
- How copy? Over.
- I copy, one-zero. Good job.
Hammerhead, Cobra. Solid copy.
Good job. Cobra out.
Aw, shit, man! What you doin'?
He already dead.
Motherfucker.
Looks like we nailed us
an officer.
You lucky bastard. You get back to C.P.,
you name your own price, sir.
No way, D'Ambrosio.
I'm keepin' this one.
Been lookin' for one of these
since Cleon and I got here in '66.
Ain't that right, Cleon?
I walked right by that guy.
You gotta keep your eyes open.
Oh, man, what the fuck?
You hungry or somethin', Cleon?
Just like you, sir.
I'm collectin' me a souvenir.
Saddle up. We're movin' out.
That's all he's gonna say? You ain't got
nothin' to tell this fuckin' shit, man?
- Man, that nigger Cleon crazy.
- Yeah.
- Did you see that shit?
- I saw it.
- Nigger, did you see that shit?
- Yes.
I heard that nigger's supposed
to be a preacher's son and shit.
He cuttin' off motherfucker's
heads for souvenirs and shit.
Now, if you hadn't flunked out
of Hunter College, pimp daddy Skippy...
you would've missed all this
good shit down in Vietnam.
Kiss my ass, nigger. You the reason
why I'm at this motherfucker anyway.
You didn't tell me 'bout
this recon shit.
- That's 'cause you didn't ask me
when you were writin' me.
- Nigger, I didn't have to.
- Shit, I figured it was
better than being a grunt.
- It is.
Ant, motherfucker,
we out in the woods all day.
Them motherfuckin' gooks jumpin' out
like Indians every five minutes.
- Man, a nigger
ain't made for this shit.
- You thought this was a skate.
Nigger, ain't nothin'
wrong with no skate.
You could just call me
a skatin' motherfucker.
I skate my ass right out of here,
they give me a chance to.
- Ain't no shitbirds on my squad.
- Man, what you jivin' about?
Hey. Hey.
Ant. To the Bronx.
Yeah, uh...
to the youngblood
who couldn't be with us today.
- Lance Corporal Martin.
- To Lance Corporal Martin.
- Yes.
- Yo, Ant, man.
What they be puttin'
in your head out here, man?
I mean, you done got into this shit
a little bit too deep, don't you think?
You're in recon now, Skip.
You in deep too.
Man, fuck this shit, man.
- Oh, come on, man.
- Man, this ain't our war, man.
Shit, our black ass should be
back in the Bronx where we belong.
Joe-ass got lucky. They sent him
home, gettin' wounded and shit.
Heard he wounded his hand
pretty bad, man.
Shit, that's all right, though.
He got out of this shit.
I rather be home with a fucked-up hand
up in some pussy than to be out here...
healthier than
a motherfucker without it.
- Shit.
- Same old Skip. Boy, you ain't changed.
That's right.
You heard from Juanita?
She used to write me a lot
during my first tour.
We got a package for ya!
Turns out, man, before I left,
fucked around and got her pregnant.
- Man, you bullshittin'.
- No, I ain't.
- No shit?
- Dead serious, man.
Got a little girl back at home.
Oh, man, that's groovy, man. That's
groovy. I can dig it. That's cool.
Hey, dig, man, I know
you got a picture, man.
- Let me see her picture. Shit.
- Can't even look at her, man.
Man, what the fuck
you mean, bro?
That's your little girl, man.
That's your baby.
You know how I survived
26 months in the bush?
Because I don't think about the world,
Skip. That shit don't exist to me.
I don't give a fuck about anything
or anyone in it...
because the minute I do, I'm a dead man
out here, and you remember that shit.
We'll talk about the world
when we get back.
Yeah, whatever, man.
I'm gonna go get high.
I mean real high. And I'm gonna
get my dick sucked too.
Big dick. Big.
Very, very big.
Can you handle it?
"Hey there, Kirby.
What's happenin' back in the world?
If you hadn't heard,
doin' my second tour."
- Fire in the hole!
"We spend most of our time
livin' in the bush.
Kind of numb to
everything out here.
Tryin' to keep
my head clear.
Our lieutenant is this crazy
white boy named Dugan from Ohio.
He's good at gettin' us
out of crazy situations.
We got this one wild-ass
brother out here named Cleon."
Gook fuck.
"His daddy's this big-time preacher, but
you'd never know from his crazy son."
Now you're good.
Now Jesus loves you.
"He's from Mount Vernon.
Oh, yeah. You won't believe it...
but Skip volunteered
for my unit.
I don't think he's
cut out for recon.
He's always gettin' high and shit,
tryin' to keep his mind off things.
Me, I'm just tryin' to take it one day
at a time and do what's right...
whatever that is.
See you when I get
back to the Bronx.
Anthony."
That fuckin' shit stinks.
I don't wanna pull rank, Cleon, but if
you don't get rid of that fuckin' head...
I don't hear nobody else
complainin' but you.
Well, maybe you should
listen to your team.
Medical advice, Cleon:
You dump that shit.
Hey, Doc, shut the fuck up.
You don't know shit.
Fuck you, man. It stinks like
a sack full of assholes.
Ain't a one of us got as much
as a splinter in his finger...
since I cut this head off.
This head is our
good-luck charm.
Nah, this here's
our good-luck charm.
If you don't mind, Sergeant, l...
My vote is to get rid of it.
Man, Cleon, you need to get the fuck on
with that bullshit, man.
- That head smell like shit.
- Bottom line, Staff Sergeant.
You either get rid of that fuckin' head
A.S.A. fuckin' P., or I'm gonna...
have your ass court-martialed
when we get back to the rear.
We clear?
Cobra, Cobra, Delta six. Over.
Delta six, Delta six, Cobra.
Copy. Over.
Cobra, Delta six.
Execute Charlie, Michael...
We're in a world of shit now.
I just buried our luck.
Listen up. Change of mission.
A patrol from 25 has found...
a shitload of weapons in a vill
about a klik and a half to our whisky.
Platoon commander wants us
to interrogate on the spot.
Betancourt, you're the closest one in
the area that speaks that gook shit.
So that's where we're headin'.
All right, saddle up. We're movin' out.
- So now where's D'Ambrosio?
- He went to go take a shit.
- When?
- When Cleon was diggin' the hole.
- Why the hell didn't you go with him?
- You know how he is.
- He don't like nobody around
when he's shittin'.
- Oh, man.
Grab his shit.
Let's find him.
Aww.
Fuck! Doc.
- 360!
- D'Ambrosio, what'd they do?
You'll be all right.
Doc's gonna take care of you, okay?
This morphine is all
I can do for him right now.
Here, Doc. You can use mine
if that's not enough.
Are you crazy? Another one of those
would kill him right now.
What the fuck
you got there, Curtis?
Somethin' about
"Black men, go home.
This isn't your war."
You get rid of that cocksucking
commie bullshit right now.
- Yeah. Right.
- Hey, Curtis.
- Apply some pressure here.
- We gotta hump this man
back to the rally point.
Oh, shit.
Save me, Curtis.
Look, Adam, you don't
worry 'bout nothin'.
We're a team,
okay, brother?
- We gonna take care of you.
- Please.
Yeah. It's not much longer.
We're almost there.
Kill me.
Kill me!
I would do it
for you.
for you, Curtis.
Buttermilk 17.
Cobra, over.
Cobra, Cobra. Buttermilk 17. Inbound
your buzz. Contact on your visual.
- Shh.
- Buttermilk 17. Cobra.
Hey, you gonna be all right.
The medevac will be here
in a minute.
Do it.
You think
I don't mean it?
I can't go home like this.
- Hey, what's he saying?
- He's delirious, man.
- Please.
- Uh, Cobra, Buttermilk.
- Hooking direct to your 12. Stand by.
- Cobra standing by. Over.
Shh-shh-shh.
Uh, Cobra, Buttermilk 17.
Roger your visual. Pop smoke. Over.
Buttermilk 17, Cobra.
Smoke. Over.
Pop the smoke.
Get that man ready for medevac!
- When'd he go?
- A few minutes ago.
It's better to check out
than go home all fucked up.
No shit.
Oh, shit!
Get down!
Fuckin' assholes!
- Stay down! Stay down!
- I'm gonna get these motherfuckers!
Return fire! Fire!
Get these motherfuckers!
- Skip! Return some fire!
- Shoot them motherfuckers!
Mission aborted! We get the fuck
out of Dodge, back to the rally point!
Ferguson! Get some
fuckin' rounds goin'!
Skip! Cover me!
- Dugan!
- Dugan, wait!
Dugan!
Skip! Skip!
Snap out of that shit. Go!
- Fuck this, man.
Let's bug out, Cleon!
- Cobra, move the fuck out!
- Get up! Come on!
- Move it! Move it!
Move! Get up!
Get up! Come on!
- What are you doin'?
- What is this, man?
- Slow down, man.
- Fuckin' grunts!
- Say, get a special shot for Skip.
My man's goin' home today.
- Count of three: 1-2-3.
All right. Good.
Now come on, now. Skip, come on, now.
Let's see a dap, man.
- All right!
- Get one like this. Get one like this.
Come on, now.
Everybody, come on. Get closer.
- Ah, man!
- This is Cobra, baby.
- Recon Cobra!
- It's Cobra. Hey, hey!
Team Cobra, ready?
Come on
Come along, come on
and get up and get down too
- Get down, get up
- Say, h-h-hold on a sec.
- Keep the metre running.
- Get down, get up and move your feet
Come on and rise, rise, rise
Shake your get-up
Straighten up there, marine!
He a friend of yours?
Friend of yours and
I'll give a discount, marine.
No, man.
Oh, shit.
Man, look who's back
in the motherfuckin' world.
Dig this motherfucker
right here, man.
Look at you, man. That's a mackin'
outfit if I've ever seen one.
- Look, with all the stripes and shit.
What, you a captain now?
- No, man.
Look, man, you wear that motherfucker
for about a month, this nigger
get all the pussy, man.
Check this motherfucker out, man.
Well, look, man... Yeah,
you go get me some squares, man.
I gotta take care of a couple things,
baby. I'll get back with you. All right?
You stay up now, all right?
What's happening, blood?
Hey, man, I'm back.
My nigger!
Come on and get down
Hey, Luther!
Tell your sister I'm gonna
be over there later on.
Hey, fuck you!
Man, the neighbourhood is changin'.
Aw, it's still a good place.
White people movin' out, though.
Oh, dig. I saw Juanita
the other day, man.
Man, she finer than a motherfucker.
Is that right?
You need to go check her out, man.
Go see your little daughter.
Remember them big-ass ears
you had when you was young?
She got 'em, just like you.
That's how I know it was yours.
So, what's up with Joe, man?
Is he, uh... Is he workin' or what?
Aw, post office, you know.
Three-quarter gig, part-time.
He gotta do what he gotta do.
He got mouths to feed, you know.
What about you, man?
How you doin'?
- Who, me?
- Yeah.
I'm cool, baby. I'm Skippy, baby.
I'm still pimpin'.
Need any money
or anything, you know?
Man, I got over like a fat rat
when I got out, man.
Dig, I got my school money comin'
from the government once a month.
I got my veteran's cheque
comin' once a month.
I got my fifty percent medical cheque
comin' to me for the rest of my life.
I ain't gotta do a goddam thing else
but go to the mailbox, you dig?
Hey, man, how the hell you pull
a fifty percent medical?
Nigger, you ain't disabled.
Man, some shit got
into me over there, man.
What?
All I know is my blood cells
are all fucked up.
Some nights I wake up
in cold sweats and shit.
Don't look at me like that, man.
It ain't the heroin.
The heroin ain't never did nothin'
to me. A lot of vets
comin' down with this shit.
- And they don't know what it is?
- Square biz.
Damn. Look, man, you wanna
come on in the crib or somethin', man?
Nah, man. I'm cool, baby.
Hey, I'm gonna split.
But you here, baby. You home.
We got plenty of time to do our thing.
You know what I'm sayin'?
- Brother.
- Brother. Go see your mama.
- Right on. I'm gonna check her out.
- With her fine ass.
You know, I been takin' care
of your mama while you been gone.
Boy, I'll kick your head in.
Don't talk like that.
Mmm.
You all right?
Yeah.
Well, can't you look me in my eyes?
I ain't seen you in four years.
Well, what'd you do over there?
What was it like?
Look, uh, I'd rather not
talk about that right now.
Well, Anthony, you gonna have
to tell us something.
Now, you know a lot of them boys
went over there and got hooked
on them drugs and stuff. You know.
Look, I was in a special unit
out there...
and bad habits could've cost us
our lives.
Well, that's what I'm talkin' about,
them bad habits, honey.
Now, if you picked up some of them
things, there's a lot of places
you can go and get help.
No bad habits, Ma.
'Cept a little killin'.
For my country, of course.
Hey. Let me give you some more
of these collards.
- Yeah.
- Baby, this sure is good.
Oh, shit. Look who back.
Look at this motherfuckin' man.
- Hey, what's happenin', youngblood?
- What's goin' on, cool breeze?
- Long time, no see.
- All right now, Pops. What's happenin'?
Hey there. What's goin' on, blood?
Ain't seen you in a long time, man.
- Boy just got back.
- Hey, blood.
- All right.
- Cheers. My man. Drink!
- All right. How you feel? All right.
Hey, what's goin' on?
Hey, I got next game.
- You know that's my table.
- You call that a break?
- I got the thing made
- Hold up there, now. It's my shot.
Say, chump.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
- Ha-ha!
- My man, Joe! What's happenin'?
- Oh, look at you!
- How you doin', man?
- Good, man. What's goin' on, man?
- Jesus Christ, man.
- I can't believe it's you!
You cool, man!
- What's goin' on, man?
Say, man,
I heard you got wounded out there.
Yeah, man. I was in demolitions
and my fuckin' hand gets blown off, man.
- Oh, man. Shit.
- Yeah, man. But hey...
motherfuckers told me everything there
is to know about explosives, man!
- That right?
- Check you out, Pappy.
You got all those kids now.
Man, hey. You gotta check out Kirby,
man. He's over in the back room.
Yeah. Let's go on back.
He's still back here, huh?
- All right. Dig it.
- Hey. Abre la puerta! Hey! Hey!
Doin' all right. You know, Kirby just
all hangin' in there, you know?
- Who the fuck is it?
- It's me.
Blood! What's up, blood?
- Hey, Nicky. What's happenin', man?
- Skin!
Kirby back there, man.
That boy looked at me,
he say, "Kirby...
when she pulled off them drawers,
I thought I'd never stop seein' ass!"
- What's happenin', Captain?
- Who the fuck is that?
- Youngblood?
- Yeah, it's me!
Youngblood! Come on, boy!
- How you doin'? Come on
in the back here, boy. Come on.
- Oh, boy. All right.
Man, I been everywhere
lookin' for a gig.
Aw, motherfuckers forget about you
gettin' your ass almost blown off...
or whatever the fuck.
Yeah. Look, uh, Kirby, uh...
I was thinkin', man.
Maybe, uh, come back and work for you.
What? Work for me?
Yeah. You know. Runnin' numbers.
Like we used to do.
Shh. Fuckin' pigs run me
out of business.
How... How the pigs run you
outta business, man?
You had 'em on the payroll.
Pigs are greedy.
And you gotta remember I'm dealing
with the NYPD...
greediest, most corrupt pigs
on the face of the earth.
So I got the fuck out.
I told that motherfucker I'd rather
eat cat shit with a knittin' needle.
I wasn't gonna bust my ass sendin'
some cop kids to college. Shit.
I dig it.
This place ain't never
made much money.
So I'm just hustlin' here and there.
Tryin' to get over,
just like everybody else.
It's gonna be all right, kid.
Here's to gettin' over.
I hope, man. Hope. Shit.
- You afraid of blood?
- Uh, that's all I been around
for the past three years.
Anthony Curtis.
You related to Tony?
The actor?
N-No. Not...
Oh! The act... No, no, no.
- Different colour, right?
- Yeah! He's a white cat. Yeah.
And his name was Schwartz.
Schwartz, not Curtis.
- Okay.
- Know anything about butchering?
Uh, I'm a fast learner.
Here, put that on.
- Here. Take this.
- Need some help, man!
All right.