Can I get everyone's attention?
Mr. Williams, please rise.
Please raise your right hand, sir.
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony
you about to give is the truth.
the whole truth and nothing but the truth.
So help you God.
- Yes sir. - Thank you, sir. You be seated.
Mr. Williams, can you
please give us your best
recollection of the event
on the Deepwater Horizon?
I was on the phone
around 9:30 with my wife.
That's when I heard the hissing noise.
I heard the engines start to rave.
The hissing turn into a full blown roar.
Higher than I can even describe it.
And within second there's a huge explosion.
Projectiles coming from everywhere.
The heat was overwhelming.
Can you please tell me how the
Deepwater Horizon alarm system is set up.
The general alarm is set
up to inform the entire rig of
Number one fire,
number two combustible gas.
Number three toxic gas.
Each condition has a
distinct tone and a distinct visual light.
On the eve of April 20th
Did you hear anyone of
those alarm on Deepwater Horizon?
No sir.
Do you know why you never heard that alarm?
Mr. William?
DEEP HORIZON
Passing 3000 feet.
Continuing down.
Need to stick to the north side far east.
Scan on it.
About 500 foot rising up.
BOP is in the view.
Blowout Preventer (BOP)
PRESSURE WELL CONTROL AND RISK FAILURE
Drilling depth 5.6 kilometers.
How's that wellhead service working?
Minor corrosion not much more
than I expected of. Well ahead of it's age.
Allright working. Crank it up.
I just had the craziest dream.
Wow.
Wow...wow was I in it.
I was no...I was at a concert.
and then on the side of the
stage there was this two-legged rabbit.
I don't want no part of it. I want tap out.
Listen to me.
I would moved.
and then he would
mimic everthing I was doing.
Don't tell me anymore
because I know where this is going.
- You think the rabbit was my mother.
- Mother. Yes I know.
I think it was my worst nightmare.
Thank you.
- It was hostile. - Ok.
- It was a hostile rabbit. - I got it.
I'm sorry. What are you doing?
That it? That's how you
going to leave me for 21 day's next.
I want you get your sleep.
Well I need other things beside sleep.
You have to promise
not to bring your mother then.
Hmmm
So you want the thirty?
The sixty?
Or the ninety seconds package?
I'm going to take the whole ninety.
Pressure. Pressure. Pressure.
I gonna miss that laugh.
- That mouth.
Give me those eyes.
I love you.
This is not our deal, dude.
Allright. Allright.
You can see you obviously
overestimating your skills as a mechanic.
What was that?
Let's go baby.
- Let me drive. - Uh uh.
- Let me drive. - Nope.
Pretty please.
- You really want to drive? - Yeah.
Then sell that piece of shit
and get a Ducatti.
Wow. Builder not trying to shop.
I only didn't not knock
because I want a brother.
Okay. That's disturbing.
You're not supposed to
know anything about that.
You're supposed to
just think babies are cute.
- Will you sit down please?
- Really I want a brother.
How's it going?
- Honey, show daddy. - I'm not done yet.
- You did such a good job. - It's showtime.
It's really great.
You can't look at me.
- Why? - Because it makes
me feel uncomfortable.
- Am i looking at you
makes you uncomfortable?
Stop. My dad is Mike.
He works in a drilling rig that
pumps oil out from underneath the ocean.
No, no the Deepwater doesn't pump a
drop of oil okay. We're the explorers.
So my dad and his friend finds the oil
and then puts it in all the plumbing
so other lamer cruise can come in
- Don't say lamer - They're lamer.
Okay listen even those lamer dudes, they
don't have to pump anything, remember.
Because the oil comes rushing out at you.
- No no no - Allright, allright allright.
Because that oil is a monster.
Like the mean old dinosaur
all that oil used to be.
So for 300 million years ...
these old dinosaurs have been getting
squeeze tighter and tighter tighter
We get it. Just use two tighter.
Cause they got a miles of earth
and ocean pressing down on them.
They are trapped under it.
So Dad and his friends
make a hole on their roof.
Yeah!
And these mean old dinosaurs
can't believe it.
So they rush to the new hole. Then smack.
They ran into a big machine that
he and his friends pump down
from the ocean floor called
- Big guy preventer? - Blowout preventer.
They run into this stuff called mud.
- Allright get it in there.
But they cramp on the straw.
The mud is so thick and heavy it
blocks the monster from coming out.
And then they sail away to the next.
That's when all the lame-o showed
up all happy like they did something.
Don't say lame-o.
But it was my daddy who
tamed the dinosaurs.
- Yeah! - Yeah.
That was amazing. Stay 10 forever please.
Daddy you need to get me a fossil.
I will.
I want to be able to put it up and
say my daddy tamed the dinosaurs.
Tell daddy what Maggie's dad did.
Her dad works at the zoo and
he brought a real penguin.
You can't do that!
- He brought a penguin.
- How do you compete with a penguin?
- You get a fossil.
- There should be rules.
Oh my God.
What?
- The hole is so much for the can.
- Stop it!
Calm it.
Buy gas go to work ...
Buy gas back to work.
Buy more gas get to work.
Hey, you know the password right with
all the insurance stuff, agent and all.
- Call Schuman first.
- What are you talking about? - I just...
- What are you on about? - I just got spook
on going home on a chopper last August.
Give me some of that.
Babe the only time you start worrying about
a marine is when he stops bitching.
- Don't use my line against me.
- I'm using your line against you.
- Don't use my line. - I just did.
- Allright bread.
-Allright, fish.
- See you in three weeks.
Behave.
Next.
- Good morning, Mr. Jimmy.
- How are we doing Sarah?
- Good, how are you doing? - All yeah.
You can place you bag on the
baggage scale up and step on your feet.
- Where you heading today?
- Same place. Deepwater Horizon.
- Where you flying to? - Deepwater Horizon.
- And who you work for? - Transocean.
- Want to know how much you weigh?
- You know I do.
- 181
- What I tell you?.
- You did good. Keep it that way.
- All ready have a seat
in the lobby and we'll
call you when your flight is ready.
- Thank you.
Mr. Sims. Mr. O'Bryan.
David Sims.
Jimmy Harrell. Officer
Installation Manager on Deepwater.
Thank you very much for
taking us out today.
I know you guys are swamp.
You didn't have to.
I had to.
Listen you mind losing that tie?
I would.
It's not the tie. It is the color.
Purple?
More magenta.
and?
Well magenta alarm on oil
rig is as bad as it gets.
As worthy as superstitions.
- Name? - Mike Williams.
- Where you heading today?
- Deepwater Horizon.
What you do in your downtime?
- Ahh start working on that boat again.
- Yeah?
I'm upping it to 600
horsepower 1,200 horsepower.
And I got me a Sensenich propeller.
- You trying to make it fly?
- No, I just want it to go faster.
- Clear? - Roger I got everyone.
Boscow, I got Deepwater Horizon
coordinate in the FMS.
492, you tail is clear. Wind is calm
Paris control this is Bristow 2 Bravo Go.
We heading to open ocean.
ETA 45 minutes to Deepwater Horizon.
Roger that, Bristow 2 Bravo Go.
What is it that you do at BP, Mr. Sims?
- Complacent.
- Oh, shit, here we go, Jimmy.
Well as you know we a little behind.
43 days. But who's counting right?
- What are you gonna do with your bonus Mike?
- Dig a pool.
- You? - Fix my car.
You do know the first well collapse on us?
Took us five days just to pull a million-dollar drill pipe.
- Whose fault was that? - You driving this how much it worth?
- 69 Mustang. - Flash by?
- Vinyl top. - What's up with it?
Today, was a rough vital I mean the exhaust
smell like gas right out of a pump.
- Smell gas but it's not over ? - No. So it's not a leak in the tank.
Owww!!!
That was bird strike folks.
I'm ain't saying nothing.
Deepwater Horizon is only a mile out.
We should be fine to land.
We'll run a safety check there.
If anything that big ought to be made by God.
That's beautiful. - You know it's not on a stilt it's not jackup.
Yeah that too and still can't believe that thing is a boat.
You know who you can thank to is a very
talented young lady right back here.
What the hell does Bankston doing here?
Who gave him that order?
2 Bravo Gulf, permission to land.
DEEPWATER HORIZON
OFFSHORE DRILLING semisubmersible
65 KM SOUTHEAST COAST OF LOUISIANA
FREE FLOATING 1,585 M ON OCEAN FLOOR
126 WORKERS ON BOARD
Welcome aboard!
You guys already done?
I don't know what to tell you, Mr. Jimmy.
- Hey you guys finished? - I don't know what to tell you.
- Someone got to talk to Vidrine. - What? Are you finished?
- Hey, Skip. - Yes sir.
- Logging team is leaving? - Yes, Schlumberger is out. The're gone.
They supposed to test that cement down there.
- And now they're finished? - Mike, how are you?
Skip, are we're done?
- You got to talk to Vidrine. - Vidrine?
- What did he say? - I can't hear him.
What did Mr. Skip say?
They were supposed to test to see whether the cement was holding.
I guess they left without doing it.
What?
- BP sons of bitches sent Schlumberger guys home. - Seriously?
Yeah.
Kuchta, why is the Bankston here?
- Good morning to you too. - What is the Bankston doing here?
Good morning, Pete.
Happy to see me?
I am always happy to see you, Andrea.
Where is the bathroom, Williams?
Sign that says toilet.
- Skip saying anything to you about running the cement log? - He didn't call me.
We're in a war here and I'm just now finding out about it?
Cause I'm sure don't know how they have the time to do a cement test cause they're flying away.
- Shit Jimmy i just drive the boat man. - How that positive test go?
Positive test clear. We're in rig down mode.
- Rig down mode - How are we looking?
A 166 degrees. Winds 185 degrees at 5 knots.
The sea is calm as good.
Are you still dating that itsy bitsy guy with the motorcycle?
- Any issue with the thruster? - Andrea.
Yes sir?
Get on radio with Captain Landry on Bankston see what he's doing and why.
You got it, Mr. Jimmy.
Damon Bankston, this is Deepwater Horizon, over.
Deepwater Horizon, this is Damon Bankston, go ahead.
Damon I wants to know what you doing here.
Over here we're getting off this beast and moving on to the next.
You can call it a bitch. When are we supposed to be leaving?
Well I'm told to be ready to start taking on drilling mud about 18:00
Wow.
I heard about the positive pressure test this morning.
They guess the negative test is going to run just as smooth.
- They told me to get ready to start moving on. - Who's they?
BP company men. Vidrine, Kaluza.
I wait for the order and come pick up your mud. Any other question?
No, that's it.
So BP company men Vidrine and Kaluza are hoping that we have tamed this bitch
and are ready to displace drilling mud at 1800 hours is that correct, Captain?
That is correct. Morning Mr. Jimmy.
All the sudden. Just like that.
Thank you, Captain.
And the goddamn phone still don't work, Mike.
Hey, I flew with you Mr. Jimmy.
Can you do me a favor run down to the drill shack
And ask Jason if those Schlumberger guys did their job. If they run the cement log.
Roger that.
Thank you.
Gentlemen, you couldn't perhaps enlighten me on the cement log situation, could you?
Cement log?
You know if they're planning it? Running it? Did it?
Yeah?
Not really. Hey, Ronnie.
Might be the ignition problem on your Mustang.
I'm seeing it maybe failed plug.
Could be a wire. Could be distributer.
- Does it sounds like it skipping? - No.
You know what I'm going to do
for you young lady? You keep
thinking all these expensive things
they be wrong for your ride.
- Geez, thanks. - Hey...
Stickshift or automatic?
Do you know me?
Oh you gonna start grinding shit out of that clutch, I know that.
- Oh yeah says Mr. Toyota. - Aha.
Attention all rig.
Moving equipment.
Come to me, baby. Come to me, baby. Come on.
Three four hundred barrels mud.
Roger that. Beginning actuation.
♪Singing♪
Shut up.
Hey. Duck!
What up, Mike?
- How are you doing, Caleb? - Hey Mike how you doing man?
- It's a lot better couple of hours ago. - Why is that?
I was asleep.
Yeah?
Yeah. We all got woken up guys got us working over.
Got a lot of pipes to pull for if we want to get out of here at night.
What's up with the street clothes? You look pretty.
Aw man, Mr. Jimmy is pissed he wants to know if we got some of that cement bond log test.
I'm not sure. I don't think so.
-No? Hey, Shane! - Yeah?
Come here buddy. Schlumberger run a cement bond log test?
I do not know. I don't think they did it. I just woke up, so ...
- Aren't that stupid? - I  don't know if it's stupid ...
but it ain't smart.
Look at what you guys like synchronized swimmers.
I think if you think too much you going to give him a headache.
- Piped down. - Yes.
Up up.
Fellas
What the hell are you wearing?
Mr. Jimmy wants to know if the Schlumbeger run the cement bond log test.
- The what? - Cement job. Test the cement job. Come on man work with me.
- Who that again? - Cut the shit man come on Jimmy's piss man.
- Schlumberger, you democrat. - Did they run the test?
No, Vidrine and Kaluza sent them home without testing anything.
- Why the hell would they do that? - I don't feel the urge to take me through their thinking Mike.
But I assume it got something to do with...
Money, money, money, money
Money!
The phone is broken.
Shit.
Hey, Mr. Jimmy.
Go ahead.
That BP sent the Schlumberger team home without running any test.
There was no cement bond log.
Thank you, Mike.
Mike, the "A" chair just crash.
- Dammit. - Blue screen of death again.
Hey, Duck, is that chair still up?
My computer screen is shaky and my smoke detector's out.
How you doing, Mike?
Shit.
I double back and grab my tools and I'll be back to fix it.
Doing it all with band-aids and bubble gum my man.
Every time I peel off a band-aid this on this rig i will find three or four more.
Spitting glue ain't getting it done.
One more time with the money. Come on.
- You've been rehearsing for weeks. - Money money...
Nah, nah the good part man.
That is the good part.
It could kill for that money. The almighty dollar.
Hello, Hollywood.
- Mike! - What's the word, Dale ?!
- What do you know? We done? - Not much. Could be.
Yeah I am going fishing tonight. Undercover.
I got a feeling we're not getting off this well tonight I think nobody is going to be doing no fishing.
You going to use your crane man? Maybe catch a beluga or shamu?
Good idea.
Shit. Willing to make a bet we'll hit the same spot next hitch.
- Yeah give me odds? - 50 to one.
Ahh shit. I ain't touching that.
30 to one. Same spot.
No way.
Mike Williams, you cheap bastard.
- Patrick. - What's going on Mike?
- What's the word? - I heard we done.
-We're done? - Yeah.
- Who you heard that from? - I can't tell you all that much.
What do you mean you can't tell me that?
- I just can't tell you. - Why can't you tell me that?
I can not tell you. But I can tell you that Gordon is looking for you.
- Did Gordon tell you that? - No he didn't tell me that.
- What going on then? - I dont know. He got something to show you.
- What do you know? - I know we're done.
Are you on my shop?
- No. - Don't touch my shit.
- I wasn't touching your shit - Go fix something.
- Have a good day, Mike. - You too. Shit.
Wait babe hold on.
What were you saying?
Great news. Chopper didn't crash.
Shit, I assumed and then i remarried.
Oh yeah he rich?
What yo momma always said "Just as easy to marry a rich man Felicia honey"
If I had a nickel for every dumb shit my mom said...
I wouldn't need a rich man.You gotta fix this by the way.
I'm going to fix it as soon as I get home. Don't worry.
Hey come closer to the computer.
Come over to the computer.
Show me those eyes.
How's everything?
Same shit. Well from hell.
You ready? - Three.
Two ...
- One ... - Go!
That face.
Sociopath.
That is focus. That is determination. That is intensity. Drive.
- Hah. - I knew you. I hate it.
- I'll see you soon, okay? - Allright. See you.
Who's touching my shit?
Dont'touch my shit. Don't touch my shit.
Can I tell you where to hit on our next location?
Kaskida.
Was this run by anybody BP? Kaluza. Vidrine, anybody?
Vidrine right about me. He's come from Virginia.
Bob, let me impose upon you what I think is most important here.
We need to go to Macondo to Kaskida by 16 May.
Kaskida is non-common prospect.
3 to 4 billion barrels. That worth more than BP itself.
Do I look like fucking Santa Claus?
You do look a little like Santa Claus.
Coach Miles may played in Michigan but that boy got Lousiana soul.
That's cause we win dummy.
Same we like you went to Alabama
Did I ask you?
When I was potty training I was taught to flush way before I see you in Tuscaloosa.
You boys working for the government? Clean the clean room.
We're still clearing mud from our last gig. Over 5000 psi. Grab a mop.
That's just crazy.
Look at the pressure did to this drill string during the kick.
That's one for the trophy case.
True that. - Hey Patrick said you got something for me?
Yes sir. Before you all took off last time shaky four goes down
after poking around we finally found the source of the problem.
Check this out. I've been hiding this for you since your last hitch.
Is that a tooth?
Ho buddy you just made my little girl's year.
And to her old man. Thank you. I owe you man.
Well, let's put together the kelly.
Hey, Gordon.
Hey, Jason I'm telling you man, it's going to be full-on shift tonight.
They sent him home.
Yeah.
Walk with me, Mike.
- Where we headed? - Murder some BP company men.
- Shit I got hammer, screwdriver. - Excellent.
Say Mike, do you brush your teeth this morning?
Yes sir.
Boy, did you floss?
No, no why?
Save you a lot of pain and money in the long run I tell you.
- Oh shit Jimmy oh we about to go murder BP guys. - They never ran the cement log.
They sent them home and we're doing shit now we going after the BP.
Hey, what's the matter? You owe them a lot of money?
Come on, Mike, stay on my hip.
Get them.
Yeah baby.
Don, look at the line 51. You'll see it cost maximum.
I don't see 51.
Don Vidrine and Bob Kaluza.
- Welcome back Mr. Jimmy. - Yeah
So we got all 500 cc cement poured down?
Yep.
That cement only thing between us and the blowout.
- And it's cued? - Yes.
Had enough time huh? Face time doing it right.
I mean that cement job is compromised then everything above it is too.
It's not compromised you used to don't have a problem.
So I assume Schlumberger guy said the same.
Cement bond log they ran say the same huh?
We are confident in the integrity of our cement job are we not?
We're quite comfortable with the integrity of that cement. That's true.
Just like my grandad.
Pardon.
You see my granddaddy he never even went to the dentist.
He didn't want to know what was wrong.
Cause then he will have to deal with it.
You don't want to know that cement job ran as well as shit
cause you're 43 days and 50 million dollars overbudget.
You really shouldn't include yourself now Mr. Jimmy.
BP picked this spot to drill, Bob.
Consequences that's on you guys.
Of course I got to try and deal with those consequences.
So yeah I'm included the point is
You sent the testing team home before they could do their job.
Maybe give you all some news you all didn't want to hear.
What would it cost you right now? The test?
125 grand?
You're $180 billion dollar company you cheap
That's why we're a $186 billion dollar company
We worry about those bills.
I worry about my rig.
My crew lives on it.
You just ran it.
Don. You and I both know we need some downtime for maintenance.
Mike, how many our machines need repair?
390, Mr. Jimmy. - Three hundred and ninety? - Yes, sir.
Almost all the same to those machinery board.
Name a few for me. - A few?
I would love to exactly what piece of mission critical equipment are down.
Shit where do I start?
A driller chair, process station 18, BOP control part,
telephone system, pipe rack system, GPS antenna, direct TV system, wireless internet,
iron roughneck, top dryer barrack bag, system auxilliary
drivers control, saltwater service pump, smoke alarm in the galley
The reason why you're sweating so hard is because the compressor on the AC is down too.
Everything but the toilet huh?
No, no you got problem there too but I don't do shitters. That's engineering.
Who are you?
Mike Williams, Chief Electronic Technician.
I'm going to tell you what I told your executives on the chopper ride in
At the time...
We're gonna properly secure this well for production platform
coming right after us and start pumping oil.
Unfortunately, to do it properly takes time.
43 days?
44 days?
Keep counting, Bob.
45 days?
46 days?
Have a cookie, Bob.
Can't run a cement log.
I'll tell you what we going to do now.
We going to run negative pressure test before we do anything else.
Do you really think we really need to...
I really think we need one Bob. So should you.
Especially since we got no idea whether this well stable or not.
Hey! Dial tone. Day is looking up.
Mr. Anderson, it's Mr. Jimmy.
We're going to run negative pressure test start tripping out 3,000 ft of pipe.
Thank you.
Days behind schedule: 43 days.
Young man. Pardon me. Can you please tell me where I can find Mr. Mike Williams?
Yes, sir. He is in the ET shops on the second deck by the coffee shop.
- Thank you very much. - Have a good one for the day, sir.
And you sir.
Mr. Williams?
Mr. Vidrine, are you lost?
Not at all.
Just looking to come by and visit with you for a minute.
How can I help?
Seems as though you had something more you wanted to say in there.
I thought I give you the time to say it.
Okay. So this rig is broke?
- I didnt' say that. - Sounds like you did.
Is there a reason why you in my shop, Mr. Vidrine?
We a big company Mike. BP.
Very big complex organization.
A lot of moving parts. Millions moving parts.
Thousands upon thousands of people.
And we all work very hard to ensure that all those people.
All those movement parts are fuctioning properly as a mean to an ends.
A very profitable win for all of us.
They the big picture.
They the little picture. Like you and the malfunctioned shitters.
Don't you see point of fact they all kind of interconnected.
They flow but working, Mike.
So if you off, it's off.
Then I'm off. Then we off. Then the whole damn train is off.
You feel me, Mr. Williams?
You on medication Mr. Vidrine?
I'm merely trying to assess just how close this train
is hugging the track.
Okay I hear you.
You want my take? I mean you really want my take.
- I do.
I think you all trying to run out of fuel as the wheels touch down.
Running on gasoline as the plane land is not smart.
It's flawed thinking. It's hope as a tactic.
Duly noted and much appreciated, sir.
Just the opinion of little guy.
That a catfish?
Yeap. 65 pounds.
What it all caught at? Nibbling?
Noodling. We noodle for catfish.
You know that's funny. Cause when we go noodling
Your best way to fish is the lake. We walk down the boat ramp.
We look for the biggest, darkest, blackest hole we can stick our arm in.
We hope those big son of bitches bite down on us as hard as he can.
So we can rip his ass out of that hole
We want to get bit. That's the plan.
Difference is we're ready for that bite.
We are ready. I'm wearing shoes, hat,
gloves, golf cap, sunglasses and we are ready.
I don't stick my hand with that monster and hope for the best.
Uh huh. Hope ain't a tactic Don.
I thank you for your time.
- Have a wonderful day, sir. - And you.
That some shit.
Attention on the rig!
Negative pressure test is about to begin.
All non-essential personnel please stay clear of the rig platform.
Bring it to the current.
Come right two degrees lock in at 176.
Turn right 10 degrees. Change to 176.
Turning.
- Damon B. Bankson ... - Is that your fifth cup?
Just saying.
Why don't you go ahead and make sure they ready to get after it.
This might be the final test.
Roger that.
- Another negative pressure test? - Another negative pressure test.
- Is there a problem? - We got a bad well.
They all bad wells. Tough prospect.
- Get this, Hollywood? - Have we entered?
In position. Locked.
- Locked at 176, Captain. - Came right 10 degrees.
- We locked in you all can run the negative test. - Yeah.
Hey, Jason.
Lose the annular.
Initiate negative pressure test.
Initiate drill pipe pressure test.
You really think this is the last test?
Shit, I hope so, yes. This is the Well from Hell, girl.
Yeah, that ain't going to last long.
That's all you got.
Goal!
100 pounds per squre inch.
Okay, pushing back on us a little. It's trying to keep us on it.
Don, you get that bottle of wine that I sent you a month ago?
I did I did thank you very much. Not only I got it, I drank me.
- Pretty good huh? - Very nice.
It's Super Tuscan, yeah?
Gaya, right? I know you like it.
Gaja.
Sorry?
Gaja. It's called.
I think they're about halfway there.
How much coffee you drinking these days, Hank?
Look I gave it up several months ago.
I drink nothing but green tea now.
Stop taking the coffee doing yoga everyday.
Two weeks now.
450 psi.
This don't look good to me.
Pressure! Warning!
900 psi.
What the hell? Dammit.
Pressure alert.
1395 psi.
It only 1395 psi, Mr. Jimmy.
That's a lot of pressure.
Yeah. Enough to cut your car in half.
Open up the annular unit.
Hollywood, open the drill pipe valve.
We got to free pressure.
Gentlemen, I had to say this that is a bad test.
Not necessarily.
Don, a good test ...
Starts zero. Stays at zero. Ends at zero.
Thank you.
So there is pressure but there was no mud.
Flowing out of that pipe. Now explain that to me.
That's a confusing result I give you that.
Kaluza and I have talked about this drill pipe.
There's something off with it. He says it's a bladder effect.
Bladder effect?
Bladder effect. He said Jason would know what he's talking about.
I say that flow right there.
Right.
Look at here.
Hey! We actually needed that.
Bladder effect.
It is a pocket of pressure
trapped around the annular
which reeks like drill pressure
because it is trapped right there
sitting right there on the sensor.
If this was a legitimate pressure issue
the we would have mud flowing right back
up and out of that drill pipe right there.
Now how we going to test this?
We going to run that negative pressure test again.
But we going to run it on the kill line. Not on the drill pipe.
Obviously our problem is with that drill pipe.
You cannot have
13,095 pounds of pressure per square inch
enough to cut your car in half.
and not have any fluid being forced up
and out of that pipe by that pressure.
Boys, do you have a whole mess of drilling mud on your boots out there?
Hey, Don.
It got hot in the drill shack.
We have a problem with that drill pipe.
or with the sensor giving us a false reading.
Or any other of a thousands moving parts down there.
Now, the way we going to find out
is run that negative pressure test on the kill line.
and if there is zero pressure Mr. Jimmy
Then that is going to tell us all we need to know.
Are we in agreement?
I don't know about agreement. Never hurts to run a test.
Look.
How we doing here, Mr. Jimmy?
We're doing great aren't we Don?
Yes we are.
BP's well.
It is.
- Bp's oil. - Indeed.
We just to help you all hire a driller hole.
You are correct, Mr. Jimmy.
But we 50 days late. And the hole ain't drilling.
Now Mr. Jimmy, we have issue in the galley.
- A whole bunch of people. A safety issue. - It won't take but a minute.
That's are 43 days, not 50. Simple mathematics.
Where your completion date was March 8. It's 20th April today. 43 days.
Yep.
I thought you money greedy sons of bitch at least good at math.
Allright, gentlemen.
Oh hey, Dewey. Negative pressure test on the kill line.
Switching to kill line test.
Initiating kill line pressure test.
Bladder effect.
It ran true to you?
Well that came out of Vildrine's mouth that rang true to me. Yeah.
I mean on it's face, yeah.
There's a logic to it. It's got merit. But
I don't apply to kill pipes and kill lines
- A little above my paygrade. - We should've seen some mud.
Pressure alert.
PRESSURE LINE OF CHOKING
Yes! Good job!
The Deepwater Horizon is receiving BP's highest safety award.
for the seventh straight year.
And it all starts at the top. The man you call Mr. Jimmy
Mr. Jimmy, Mr. Jimmy.
Speech.
He held at zero, boss. Good test. No pressure.
Congratulations, good test.
We still got 14,000 psi on the drill line.
Drill line and the kill line should be exactly the same.
They should all be lined up.
We already agreed to test something wrong with the drill line.
Why do you keep coming back to it?
I don't know. Good old field practice.
No mud. No flow. We got to go.
Now how quick can we lock the dough on this well?
I'm not doing nothing until Mr. Jimmy is made aware.
Is there a man in you? Is there an adult?
The dip. The steel toes.
But it's all bullshit.
We got zero pressure on the kill line.
You nervous as cat.
Afraid to make it work at every turns.
That will be my summary back to my bosses in London.
Bob?
Agreed.
Again, you can call Mr. Jimmy.
And I no longer keep you from your ice cream for another second. Thanks.
- This Mr. Jimmy. - We ended the negative test.
It was good test. We got no pressure.
I'm about to start in this place. I want your blessing.
You sure about this, Jason?
Kill line was good. It was all nothing I'm sure.
This guys are all over me. What you want to do?
Zero flow, correct?
It's correct. No flow.
Are we good?
Well, it's looks like it's going to be a long night.
You stay on top of it, Jason. I see you on top about half an hour. Thanks.
Okay, guys. Good test.
Yahoo.
Get ready to pull out 10,000 barrels of mud.
I think I'm going to take a shower and wash my day off before I start my night.
- It's gonna be long night. - Get some ice cream, Mike.
I'm gonna watch my figure.
I'll go fix up some smoke detectors before I'm about to pop somebody in the mouth.
That's a good idea. Say hi to Felicia for me.
- Mr. Jimmy? - Yes?
We really need you in this.
- Just a picture.
Alright Mr. Jimmy.
Hey appreciate it a lot guys.
Did you take the picture?
Help me check the house.
We got a good test.
We start sending us some mud. Transfer them to Bankston.
Copy that.
Nervous as cat. Cat ain't scare.
I had a cat named Oscar used to try to mount my Labrador.
i'm opening the annular.
Let's hope that monster ain't awake.
Mud pumps are on.
Removing heavy mud from well.
Displacement Holding in Tank 2.
4%
Boys we got a good test.
Let's pump out all these mud.
We're done.
We're going home. - Bring in the mud. Bring in the mud.
Damon Bankston at Deepwater Horizon.
You are clear to approach and receive drilling mud.
Copy Deepwater. Coming along side to receive heavy mud.
All normal.
Master deck, prepare prepare to receive the mud.
10,000 barrels.
Attention on the rig. Pressure test was good.
Congratulations crew. We about to moving on.
Well from Hell is done, boys.
Oh man. The basin soon.
Two or three days maybe. I'll be in my boat.
Drinking me a beer. Catching us a sucker at the lake.
Yes! You big beautiful mud.
35%.
- Hang on, baby. - We are going home!
I thought you had plans. I thought you going out.
Cancelled.
Sweatpants, bottle of beer and DVR.
My favorite plan.
Just simple country girl.
55%
75%
- Do the same in the next. - Hopefully with fewer problems.
Jason! I got a 20 barrels increased in flow.
- Not slowing down. - Alright, stop pumping mud.
- Pressure alert. - Oh no.
- Standy. - They're shutting down.
They must not be liking something up there.
Hey, boys. I'm going to take a leak. You guys good?
- I got you buddy. - All right.
- Pressure alert. - It's not stopping.
Clear the drill shack. Get him and him out of here.
What is happening Jim?
Jim what is the excitement. We stipulated there aint something wrong.
I never should've let you push me. Now get your ass out of here before I push back.
That comment will be noted.
I'm ready to go home.
Drinking beer and eating a steak.
What's going on?
Probably nothing, Mr. Kaluza.
- Watch your step over here. - Shit.
What you got, Caleb?
What is it you do?
Shit.
Dammit.
- What the hell's going on? - We got flow.
Shit! That ain't good.
Jason, you seeing this?
We got flow out here.
- Warning. - It's not stopping.
Jason, are you seeing this?
You got mud on the rig.
Didn't I tell you not to do anything.
Is she just kicking or just
Clear the floor.
Oh shit.
Mike, what is that? Is everything okay?
i'm closing the annular.
Duck, get in here now.
Are you shutting it in?
Alright we're okay. I closed the annular. We got 30 seconds.
Evacuate the floor, now!
- Duck, are you okay? - Yes.
Get the signal on the EDS. Get ready to cut that pipe.
On your way.
Adam!
Shane!
What do we do?
- Caleb! - What do we do?
Release the drill pipe pressure!
Here here.
i'm doing my best to accomodate it. But look...
Okay. Okay. We're alright. We're alright.
- Caleb, how are we doing buddy? - Did we cut the pipe?
We're good. Annular took care of it.
It's just a kick.
It's the biggest damn kick I've ever seen.
She put a whoop ass on Maggie and her penguin.
Get out of here.
She did.
And she did it all without this?
No!
That is a genuine dinosaur tooth.
Gas alarm in the mud pits. Again.
Same one goes off everytime . Off all down.
Hey, Roy!
I got it. You got to get out of here.
Too late.
Pressure. Warning.
Shit. Jason!
Oh shit!
Caleb, get out of that mud.
The BOP ain't working.
Holy shit. Duck, close the second annular.
Annular failure.
Adam! Shane! They Get down to the mud room now.
Adam!
We got to go buddy.
We gotta get to the mud room.
We must get to the mud room! Caleb!
- Caleb! - Get off the floor! Get off the floor!
It's the Pump 2. Bleed it. Bleed it.
Caleb, close the drill pipe behind them.
They blow everything overboard.
Jason, what do we do?
- Failure. - We got debris!
- OMG! - Dammit!
Caleb, clear the floor.
You're alright?
The alarm didn't go off. I'm going to make sure everyone evacuates.
- Get to the lifeboats. Go! - Ok.
Halt. Stop.
Look out. Look out.
What the hell.
Dammit!
Jesus.
Deepwater Horizon, this is David Bankston. Copy?
The BOP is not responding.
- Duck. Get that button right now. - Okay.
Right now!
Caution. Gas.
Duck! Duck!
What happened?
Keith!
Gordie!
Come on! Get up!
Roy! You gotta go.
We gotta go right now.
Alert gas.
Shit. The gas alarm.
The thrusters are over-revving.
I thruster is running away from me.
- I'm not going to be able to hold the rig in place. - Calm down.
OMG.
Is it just me or does it get all bright in there all of the sudden?
Magenta. Magenta alarm.
- The well is blowing out. - What?
Mike.
Mayday! This is Deepwater Horizon. We're...
What the hell are you doing? Did I asked you to call a Mayday!
I call you back! I call you back!
You don't know the difference between a kick and a goddamn blowout!
- Why is ? - You don't know shit! Why is the monitor out?
Gas.
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
This is Deepwater Horizon.
Come on, Duck. I'm going to get you out.
Goddammit! Dewey! Steve!
- No! - Jesus!
Mayday! Mayday!
This is Deepwater Horizon.
- The rig is on fire. - We got a major explosion. We need assistance.
- Don't you see it's on fire? - I repeat we have mass casualty explosion.
We need assistance immediately.
Mayday! Mayday! Mayday!
May Day! May Day! May Day! This is Damon Bankston.
The Deepwater Horizon has exploded and is on fire.
I say again, Deepwater Horizon has exploded and is on fire.
We saw a huge explosion.
Yes, the Deepwater Horizon is on fire.
- Is everyone off the rig? - We have no idea.
United States Coast Guard. This is State Command Center and Von Huene speaking.
Okay an oil rig on fire. About 48 nautical miles south of Venice.
Okay, yes sir. What vessel are you on? What's the name of your vessel?
Coast Guard, This is State Command Center. Lieutenant Degan speaking.
An oil rig on fire? Sir, do you have a position for that?
I'm not exactly sure, I need to get some information from you first if that's alright.
Can i get your name, please?
What is your location?
We got a 100 miles south of Port Fourchon.
48 miles south off the coast of Venice. I have a report from OSV vessel.
That lat and long. That's a confirmed position.
Sir, we got a satellite images of the scene. Right here.
Oh my God.
Listen guys we need to bump this up okay.
Call land area see what kind of flip cutters we have in the area and
divert them over to the area.
air stations. How many aircrafts do we have left?
Okay get them going.
Shit.
Evacuation procedure in effect. This is not a drill.
Evacuation procedure is in effect. This is not a drill.
Dougie?
Dougie. Hey, Dougie, can you hear me?
What?
Can you hear me, Dougie?
My little brother.
What?
It's his birthday. My brother.
Your brother is not here.
What about your legs, huh? Can you move them.
My little brother.
Look at me Dougie you gonna need to use them.
We got to get to lifeboat. I'm gonna get you out.
Alright.
Shit. All right.
Up.
Failure of Propellant 2.
I just lost fourth thruster on the fourth side. I only have four left Captain.
What do we do?
- We need a damage report. - I'm gonna take manual control for the rig.
Kuchta speaks. I need a damage report.
- Please. - Fire team now!
We Bankston to the Coast Guard.
There is an incident on the Deepwater Horizon.
We're on 90 degrees starboard. Tell me that lifeboat is on water.
Let's go you got the first kits
And oxygen tanks?
Empty out the supply house. Let's go.
Proceed to assigned lifeboat.
Son of a bitch!
Hey! Hey! He needs to get on the boat!
He's hurt. He's hurt bad.
I don't give a shit!
Give him the boat.
Listen to me he's hurt real bad. Do you understand me?
Calm down.
Anybody seen Mr. Jimmy?
I saw him in the accomodation.
I'm going back for Mr. Jimmy. Make sure this man gets off this rig.
Okay, buddy. Calm down. Slow it down. Move it out.
- Yeah. - Okay, let's go.
Hello?
Hey! Hey! Hey! You're good?
- I think so. - Where are you going?
I dont know. Master.
- You gotta go to the lifeboat, okay? - Yeah.
Lifeboat. Right now.
Stay to the wall. Hey! Stay to the wall.
Good.
Hey!
Mr. Jimmy?
Anyone there?
Hey!
- Help! - Mr. Jimmy!
Who's there?
Here quick!
Mr. Jimmy? Mr. Jimmy?
Mike!
I can't see shit. I got. What happened?
- We blew out Mr. Jimmy. - Oh no.
There's secondary explosions. It's on fire everywhere.
We disconnect it? We cut the pipe.
I don't know. I don't think so.
We need to disconnect, Mike. Help me get to the bridge.
I'll take you to the bridge.
I got you. Alright. Come on.
Where are we?
I wouldn't recognize where are we unless we can see it.
This pipe is gonna break.
Come on, Mr. Jimmy. Come on.
If you find yourself in the water you got a light and a whistle.
You understand?
If you get into an oil anything swim away from the rig.
Should we wait for the coastguard?
No way. We need to go. Come on. Let's go.
- Let's go now. - The water's on fire.
- Who's coordinating the air assets out there? - ATC. Fixed wing. They have gear.
West Jefferson and East Jefferson and Tulane are prepared to take...
Start.
Engine power.
Coast Guard 1 clear.
There are people jumping into the water. He sees 3 people jumping into the water.
- Jumper. Do you getting this? - They are jumpers?
What's the ETA on the first helicopter.
Sir, it's going to be 35 minutes.
Let's hope it's not 30 minutes too late.
US Coast Guard B17 departing
on a route to emergency distress call Deepwater Horizon.
ETA to location in 25 minutes.
Get in! Get in!
Come on. You good?
- Yeah. -  Come on.
Help!
Can you hear?
Someone there? This is Caleb. I need help in here.
It's Wyman!
We gotta get out of here. There's methane everywhere.
I found him like this. He hurt real bad now. He ain't getting up.
- Don't look down alright? - No no.
Wait! Shit, His bone caught on the metal.
Mike!
Come we gotta work this. We gotta find something to get it open.
Pull! Pull!
Keep pulling!
I lost power.
Stop. Just stop a second. Let me think.
I want to cut the pipe.
Hey, Andrea, get your ass back on station.
We don't have the authority.
I'm going to seal the well.
Do not touch that button!
We need to take the EDS.
We don't have the authority.
You ain't pushing it.
Can somebody help me?
Go! Get out of here.
You're coming with or without that leg.
Hold on. Hold on.
Hey, look at me.
This gonna hurt like a bitch. You stay calm for a second, okay.
Look at me. Don't look down, look at me.
We got you.
Hold on.
Pull. Pull.
Wyman, can you move?
Let's go.
Okay, take me to the bridge, Mike.
Coast Guard. This is Command Center. Lieutenant Degan speaking.
Hi, sir.
Huh, I just huh. I don't mean to bother you. I'm sure everything are just fine.
but my husband. Mike Williams, is on the Deepwater Horizon and uh
Yes, ma'am. Right now we only have a couple of confirmed reports
with a fire on an oil rig. That's all I can say.
They're on the Deepwater Horizon?
Because there's so many rigs out there. You sure?
Yes, there is a fire on the Deepwater Horizon.
That's all I can say to you, Ma'am. Sorry. I really have to go.
What happened?
- Ken, you alright? - The derrick is gonna fall on us!
Damn, the boat slipped.
My crane is gonna take the goddamn derrick out.
- It's coming down! - Get on the boat now!
I must stop it, or it's gonna kill us all.
Go, Dale!
Go! Go! Go!
Help him up the stairs.
Shit!
Go Dale!
Dale get out!
Get out of there! Now!
Oh my God.
- Who's on the bridge? - Fleytas.
Kuchta.
Get your ass on the lifeboat.
Andrea, Kuchta, did disconnected it?
No.
Andrea, get my hands on the EDS.
I'm gonna cut the pipe and seal this well.
We gonna choke this fire.
- Right here. - No, no, up, up!
Still burning?
- It still flow, Mr. Jimmy. - Oh come on. Please! Please!
It still burning Mr. Jimmy. We gotta go.
Hey! Hey! Couple more.
Get in!
We need to restore power.
- We need to press the standby generator online. - The fire fighting pump?
No, we just want to keep this rig on station as long as we can. So that pipe doesn't break.
- That's all we can do. We can't save this rig. -  It can't hurt to go try.
Thank you very much Mike. It's on the other side of that derrick.
I know. I know.
- I'm coming with you. - What?
- I'm with you. - You sure?
- I'm with you. - Go on, Mike.
Come on.
Natalie, this is Felicia Williams.
Our husbands work on the Deepwater Horizon together.
I just called the Coast Guard and they can just confirmed that there is a fire ...
but I just wondering maybe you heard something.
What the Coast Guard said?
Just that there has been a fire.
Shelly heard there's people jumping off the rig.
What are you doing?
Not now, babe.
- What's wrong? - Not now, baby.
Shit.
Come on.
Easy! Easy!
- Lifeboat 4 is full! - Make your way to Lifeboat 2!
- Lower the boat! - Go!
Shit! Shit!
- You got gloves? - Yes!
Come in, come in!
Come here!
- Mike?
Mike, are you there?
Mike? Bring the power.
You know your way around this thing?
How hard can it be?
Come here. Read this shit off to me.
You gotta be shitting me.
- Come on - All right. "Turn the remote switch to 'local' '.
"Switching power switch."
"Turn rudder on position."
"Press the main start button"
- Red one right there.
I'm impress man. I don't know roughnecks can read.
Very funny.
You know I had a full ride to UT architecture school.
- What the hell you doing here?
- I should've listen to my mom.
You should've.
- Mr. Jimmy, you get any power up there? - This should be it
Do you have the power?
- We still outside the walk circle?
- Yes. For outstation.
- Turn it slow. - Okay.
Bring us back slow.
Come on, baby! Come one!
Shit!
Shit.
"Get your start key turn on."
We got you! We got you!
Watch your leg!
"Wait for the pull plug"
Come on.
This should be it.
There you go.
Mr. Jimmy, did you get power up there?
- We have power, Mike. - Please. No no.
Kuchta, can you help me?
Close the door! Now!
- Get to the lifeboat, Mike. It's over. - Shit!
Jimmy, we have to go.
Look out!
It's all coming down.
We gotta get to the boat.
- Come on lower the boat. - Shut the door
Let's go!
Come on.
They left us. They left us!
Shit!
- The emergency liferack! - Somebody got a knife?
I need a knife!
I got it. Watch out!
Open it up!
Open the shaft.
Shit come one! Hold the flag!
Come on we got to spin it out !
Crank it!
The spinning it as fast as I can!
Come on stay with me, man. Come on!
Shit.
Tie it up! Tie it up!
Shit!
Tie it up!
Come on, come one, bring it in!
Injured first! Come on!
Where is Andrea?
Andrea, let's go!
- Come on, Andrea!
No, wait! Wait!
There is too much fire. We can't jump from here.
We need to get up higher.
We need to get up higher. Come on.
Slow down. Slow down.
It's a raft!
Hang on.
Come on.
Bankston Rescue!
Here! Over here!
We got you. Here you go.
Come on. We got to get up. Come on.
On the stairs going up!
Shit! Shit!
Come on! Come on!
Hey.
Come on.
Original V8 or crate motor?
Your Mustang. Original V8 or crate motor?
It's original.
It's cool. We might need to rebuild that.
Who's we?
Do you see anyone else here?
Me and you.
Listen to me. Look at me!
We up higher we can jump up farther.
Okay? We gonna jump over the fire.
No no.
I can't.
Can't what? Rebuild an engine?
Jump.
Trust me we not gonna hit the fire. You hear me?
- I'm don't wanna die. - We are not gonna die. - I don't wanna die.
Our choice right now.
is to burn or jump!
Will you let go off me.
Don't touch me. Don't touch me.
You jump.
Do what you want.
You know what? I'm gonna do whatever you do.
No.
- My wife is Felicia. My daughter, Sydney. - Don't put that on me.
And I will see them again. Do you understand me?
What are the odds of you getting out of this alive if you don't jump with me right now?
We're getting off this rig. Do you hear me?
You want to stay here? You stay here.
Hey, what color is the Mustang?
Andrea! Andrea!
If you hear your name, holler out.
Albers, Shane!
Here.
Holloway, Caleb!
Anderson, Jason!
Jason Anderson, are you here?
Is there anybody here from the drill shack?
Nobody?
Donald Clark, are you here?
Dewey Revette?
Shane Roshto?
Adam West?
Roy Kemp?
There is a doctor above.
Dale Burkeen?
Gordon Jones?
Karl Inger Klepp?
Stephen Curtis?
Keith manuel.
Thank you.
You're good?
All knees.
Our Father who art in Heaven.
Hallowed be thy name. Let thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on Earth as it is in Heaven.
Give us today our daily bread.
Forgive us our trespasses as we forgive those who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation but deliver us from evil.
What is your name, sir?
Mike Williams.
You need to take some rest and after you done you talk to me.
Hey! Hey! You on the rig?
- Yes sir. - My son did he get off the rig with you?
- Rig? - Did he get off the rig?
I don't know if he made it.
Where is my son?
- Did he get off the rig? - I don't know.
My son. Do you know him?
Did he leave with you?
Somebody better tell me something.
Somebody help me.
Did you hear any of the alarms?
Dad.
Mike Williams never returned to the sea. He lives with his family in Texas.
I remember I closed my eyes and saying a prayer. Asking God ...
to tell my wife and my little girl that daddy did everything he could.
And if I survive this, it's for a reason.
Please raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony you about to give is the truth.
The whole truth and nothing but the truth. So help you God.
- Yes sir. - Thank you, sir.
We went to the next light that we saw in the water and retrieve that person.
It was Andrea, dynamic position operator.
Andrea Fleytas lives in California. She no longer works in the oil industry
I went to the PA made the last announcement and said that we were abandoning the rig.
Who in your view was in charge of the rig?
- The OIM. - That would be Mr. Harrell. Is that correct?
Right.
Jimmy Harrell still working for Transocean
There was a major explosion ...
followed by second explosion.
After the explosion, I called the rig floor. There was no answer.
BP supervisors. Robert Kaluza and Donald Vidrine
They were convicted of manslaughter
In 2015, these charges were dismissed.
Everything they told us could never happen ...
It happened.
Men lost their lives.
11 men died aboard the Deepwater Horizon of April 20, 2010.
The blowout lasted 87 days and spilled an estimated
210 million gallons of oil into the Gulf of Mexico.
It was the worst oil disaster in US history
DEEP HORIZON
Deepwater Horizon (2016)