(Bond) Where is he?
I shan't ask you politely next time.
- Where is Blofeld?
- Cai... Cai...
Cairo.
Cards.
Hit me.
(Bond) One chance. Where can I find him?
Marie... Ask Marie.
Who are you?
My name is Bond... James Bond.
Is there something I can do for you?
Yes, as a matter of fact, there is.
There is something I'd like you
to get off your chest.
(Marie gasps)
Where is Ernst Stavro Blofeld?
Speak up, darling. I can't hear you.
(man) We now come
to phase four: The nose.
In my opinion, the most difficult part
of a plastic transformation.
I want the operation done tonight.
There's no time left.
But, señor Blofeld, this is
a most delicate procedure.
Tonight.
Keep the temperature
at precisely 80 degrees.
(Blofeld) Making mud pies, 007?
He would have been me in a few days,
if you'd given the poor fellow a chance.
Such a pity. I was dying to see
how the operation turned out.
Get his gun.
Hold it! Get your hands up.
Kill him!
Welcome to hell, Blofeld.
(cat shrieks)
(~ "Diamonds Are Forever"
by Shirley Bassey)
~ Diamonds are forever
~ They are all I need to please me
~ They can stimulate and tease me
~ They won't leave in the night
~ I've no fear that they might desert me
~ Diamonds are forever
~ Hold one up and then caress it
~ Touch it, stroke it and undress it
~ I can see every part
~ Nothing hides in the heart to hurt me
~ I don't need love
~ For what good will love do me?
~ Diamonds never lie to me
~ For when love's gone
~ They'll lustre on
~ Diamonds are forever
~ Sparkling round my little finger
~ Unlike men, the diamonds linger
~ Men are mere mortals
who are not worth going to your grave for
~ I don't need love
~ For what good would love do me?
~ Diamonds never lie to me
~ For when love's gone
~ They'll lustre on
~ Diamonds are forever, forever, forever
~ Forever
~ And ever
Star of South Africa:
83.5 carats rough, 47.5 carats cut.
The Akbar Shah: 116 carats rough.
- Are you paying attention, 007?
- The Akbar Shah: 116 carats rough.
But there's no need to bring in our section
on a relatively simple smuggling matter.
Sir Donald has convinced
the PM otherwise.
May I remind you, 007,
that Blofeld's dead? Finished.
The least we can expect from you now
is a little plain, solid work.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Sir Donald will see you now.
Thank you.
Morning, Sir Donald.
This is Commander Bond.
How do you do, Commander Bond?
Please sit down.
- Sherry?
- Not for me. Doctor's orders.
- Commander Bond?
- Yes, thank you.
You've been on holiday, I understand.
Relaxing, I hope.
Hardly relaxing, but most satisfying.
- Cheers.
Pity about your liver.
It's an unusually fine Solera.
- '51, I believe.
- There is no year for sherry, 007.
I was referring to the original vintage
on which the sherry is based, sir.
1851.
- Unmistakable.
- Precisely.
Tell me, Commander,
how far does your expertise
extend into the field of diamonds?
Hardest substance found in nature.
They cut glass. Suggest marriage.
They've replaced a dog
as a girl's best friend. That's it.
Refreshing to hear there's one subject
you're not an expert on.
Yes, well, perhaps I'd better give you
a brief background into our problem.
80 per cent of the world's diamonds
come from mines in South Africa.
Most are dug out of shafts
of diamond-bearing clay
at depths of up to 3000 feet.
The whole process operates
under an airtight security system.
It's an essential precaution,
even though the industry prides itself on
the loyalty and devotion of its workers.
Naturally the security measures
tend to ensure that loyalty,
as do the extensive amenities
and social services we provide.
There's a permanent staff
of doctors and nurses, even dentists.
The whole process operates
under an airtight security system.
It's a necessary precaution,
even though the industry prides itself on
the loyalty and devotion of its workers.
Next.
(man) The scorpion.
Mother nature's finest killer, Mr Wint.
One is never too old
to learn from a master, Mr Kidd.
Dr Tynan? Good evening.
- Who are you? And where is Joe?
- Joe couldn't make it tonight.
I'm Mr Wint. This is Mr Kidd.
I see.
(groans)
- What's the matter with him?
- My wisdom teeth. I haven't had 'em out.
- Would you mind having a look, Doctor?
- Of course.
I'm not going to hurt you. Just open.
No, no, no, open wide.
Argh!
Curious how everyone who touches
those diamonds seems to die.
- (man) Stop right there. Who are you?
- Dr Tynan sent us.
- Why didn't he come himself?
- He was taken sick.
Bitten by the bug. He sent this for you.
If God had wanted man to fly...
He would have given him wings, Mr Kidd.
No security system is perfect. We've
always accepted a degree of smuggling.
But over the past two years, despite all
our precautions, it's gone up alarmingly.
- None of the stones reach the market.
- Sir Donald thinks someone's stockpiling.
What concerns us is someone dumping
the stones on the market, or...
Making you agree to perpetual blackmail.
Exactly.
What we need to know
is who the stockpilers are.
The letter U is for "umbrella".
We take it lest it rain.
We hope we shan't want it
till we're home again.
- Two men to see you, missy.
- (teacher) "Gentlemen", Joshua.
I shan't be long, children.
Joshua is going to read you a story.
How nice to see you again.
Where to this time?
- Amsterdam.
- Amsterdam, how lovely.
I'll have to bring back
some pictures for the children.
Ask, and ye shall receive, Mrs Whistler.
Thus endeth the lesson for today,
gentlemen.
Several recent murders in South Africa
have complicated matters.
If they shut down operations
before we discover them...
It would be catastrophic for us
and for the government.
- I've always fancied a trip to South Africa.
- You're going to Holland.
For some time now, we've had our eyes
on a professional smuggler, Peter Franks.
- He's due to leave for Amsterdam.
- Do we know his contacts?
We do function in your absence,
Commander.
Passport, sir?
Mr Franks, there's a message
for you at Passport Control.
That door over there.
You can park your car outside.
Thank you.
Mr Franks, your passport is quite in order.
Anyone seeing you in that outfit would
be discouraged from leaving the country.
What can I bring you back from Holland?
A diamond? In a ring?
Would you settle for a tulip?
Yes.
(woman on PA) Ahead is one of the oldest
bridges in Amsterdam: The Skinny Bridge.
It was built 300 years ago by two sisters
who wanted to visit each other every day.
Unfortunately they ran out of money. So
that is why it is called the Skinny Bridge.
On your right, those beautiful old houses
can be seen in Rembrandt's paintings.
And now, if you will look to your left
as we go down the Amstel, you can see...
Oh.
Mrs Whistler did want some pictures
of the canals for the children.
How kind of you, Mr Kidd.
The children will be so thrilled.
- (woman) Yes?
- Franks. Peter Franks.
Come up. Third floor.
Make yourself at home.
I'll be out in a minute.
Help yourself to a drink.
Is Mr Case not at home?
There is no Mr Case. The T is for Tiffany.
Tiffany Case? Definitely distinctive.
I was born there, on the first floor, while
my mother looked for a wedding ring.
I'm glad for your sake
it wasn't Van Cleef and Arpels.
Weren't you a blonde when I came in?
Could be.
I tend to notice little things like that.
Whether a girl is a blonde or a brunette.
And which do you prefer?
Providing the collars and cuffs match...
We'll talk about that later.
Let me have your glass.
I'll get you some ice.
That's quite a nice little nothing
you're almost wearing. I approve.
I don't dress for the hired help.
Let's see your passport, Franks.
Occupation: Transport consultant?
That's a little cute, isn't it?
- I'll finish dressing.
- Don't. Not on my account.
I don't care much for redheads.
Terrible tempers.
- But somehow it seems to suit you.
- It's my own.
But it needs some soft lighting.
I know this restaurant...
- I never mix business with pleasure.
- Neither do I.
Good. We can start
by saving the cute remarks
until after you get
the diamonds into Los Angeles.
- Where are they now?
- Your problem is getting them in.
- How much is there?
- 50,000 carats.
At 142 carats an ounce, that's an awful lot
of ice. That won't be easy.
That's why you're being paid 50 grand.
What did you think it was going to be?
A pair of earrings?
And, Franks, for God's sakes,
come up with something original.
I've got to hand it to you, Q.
Quite ingenious.
An obvious little notion.
Thought it might come in handy.
By the way, M's been trying
to get in touch with you.
That Peter Franks has escaped.
He killed one of the guards
on the way up to London.
Hello?
Hello? Are you there?
Oh!
- (Tiffany) Yes?
- Peter Franks.
Third floor.
- Guten abend.
- Good evening.
Bitte.
- (German accent) You are English?
- Yes, I'm English.
I speak English.
- Who is your floor?
- Three, please.
- Is he dead?
- I sincerely hope so.
- Who is he?
- No idea.
This chap's been following me
all day today.
My God!
You've just killed James Bond.
Is that who it was?
It just proves no one's indestructible.
You don't kill James Bond and
sit waiting for the cops to arrive.
We've got to get
the diamonds out of here fast.
Where are they?
A little old lady dropped them by
yesterday morning.
Priceless.
I think we ought to let Mr Bond
carry the load from here on out.
It's funny. All the things one wanted to
say to one's brother when it's all too late.
Let me assure you
of our deepest condolences.
Would you please board the aircraft?
- We were inseparable, you know.
- Please, Mr Franks.
(air stewardess) Lufthansa announce the
departure of flight, LH450 to Los Angeles.
Will you please fasten your seatbelts?
No smoking until airborne. Thank you.
They're both aboard. I must say,
Miss Case seems quite attractive.
For a lady.
(laughs)
(PA) Lufthansa announce the arrival
of their flight, LH450 from Amsterdam.
- Mr Franks?
- Yes?
Follow me to Customs, please.
Peter Franks, Jerry.
Get some lunch, Jerry. I'll take over.
Death certificate, please, Mr Franks.
Well, well, well. Felix Leiter, you old fraud.
On behalf of the CIA, welcome to America.
Someone sent their brain trust
down to meet you.
I give up. I know the diamonds
are in the body, but where?
Alimentary, Dr Leiter.
So long, James. Keep in touch.
The rest of your luggage has been
cleared, Mr Franks. OK, fellas.
You wanna sit in the front, Mr Franks?
It's a lot smoother ride
in the front, Mr Franks.
Yes, I believe I'll sit in front.
The stiff... (clears throat) deceased
back there. Your brother, Mr Franks?
Yes, it was.
I got a brudder.
Small world.
(soothing organ music)
Mr Franks, I'm Morton Slumber.
Please accept my heartfelt
condolences at this most difficult hour.
Well, he is heading
for a better world, Mr Slumber.
There is some consolation in that.
Now then, if we're ready
to begin the final journey...
- May his soul rest in peace.
- Oh, yes. Amen.
If you would care to follow me into
my office, we will bring you the urn.
I'm happy you chose our half-couch,
hinged-panel, slumber-on casket.
I'm sure your brother
would have appreciated it.
I'm sure he did.
Please, be seated.
Ashes to ashes...
- Dust to dust.
- Exactly.
At a moment like this, I'm sure you'd
rather be left alone for reflection.
Most thoughtful.
We've selected a private niche
in our Garden of Remembrance.
It's the one with the restful chartreuse
curtains and the Angel's Breath gold trim.
- I hope you'll find everything in order.
- It has all been impeccable, Mr Slumber.
So far.
Very moving.
- Heart-warming, Mr Wint.
- A glowing tribute, Mr Kidd.
You dirty, double-crossin' limey fink.
Those goddamn diamonds are phonies.
Now, don't tell me. You're St Peter?
Paste, glass. Where's the real stuff?
Where's the real money? You wouldn't
burn up 50,000 real dollars, would you?
One last break, Franks.
Where are the real diamonds?
Get me the real money,
I'll bring you the real diamonds.
Where are you goin'?
I hear that the Hotel Tropicana
is quite comfortable.
My condolences, gentlemen.
Hello, Felix. Very comfortable.
There's one problem.
I want the real merchandise - quickly.
Q has just arrived with it.
We'll be up with them in the morning.
So I'd sit tight, if I were you.
No sense in looking for trouble.
Just enjoy yourself, James.
I'm sure you know how.
Quite. I'll probably
take in a show, or something.
(distant laughter)
(man) How do you like me so far?
People say I have
the body of Rock Hudson.
If he ever finds out what I'm doin' to it,
he'll be madder than hell.
I call these girls my Acorns.
They're a gift from Willard Whyte,
who is upstairs right now,
playing Monopoly with real buildings.
Tryin' to find Willard Whyte is like
tryin' to find a virgin in a maternity ward.
And on behalf of the Whyte House,
I wanna let you folks know,
you've been a lousy audience.
So get lost. See ya later.
(Mr Wint) Shady Tree.
Shady, we just adored your act.
- What taste, style.
- We have a few suggestions.
Critics and material I don't need.
I haven't changed my act in 40 years.
Hold it. Don't go in there.
We didn't get the real diamonds,
so we need Tree alive.
That's most annoying.
(man shouts)
The loser...
That's it, pussycat. I shot the whole wad.
What do you say? Back to my place?
You're a nice person, Maxie.
Really, you are.
Why don't you go take a nap,
and I'll see you next year?
(Bond) May I have 5000 dollars?
No, make it 10,000. 2000 dollar limit.
- Is there some problem?
- Mr Saxby?
This gentleman wants 10,000 dollar credit
with a 2000 dollar limit.
My name is Franks. Peter Franks.
Mr Franks' credit's good.
Good luck to you, Mr Franks.
Thank you. I'll have two stacks now.
Give the gentleman 4000.
(Bond) Thank you.
- Hi. I'm Plenty.
- But of course you are.
- Plenty O'Toole.
- Named after your father, perhaps?
Would you like some help?
On the craps, I mean.
That's very kind of you.
(croupier) Coming up. Coming up.
Next shooter is a lady. Ladies are lucky.
Nine. Mark nine.
Seven, loser. The lucky lady craps out.
Your shot, Mr F.
- (Southern accent) Willard Whyte.
- Tree is dead. Turn on number two.
(Saxby) It's Peter Franks.
Twice ten. Hard ten. Ten's the number.
I'll take the full odds on the ten.
200 on the hard way.
The limit on all the numbers,
250 on the eleven. Thank you very much.
Say, you've played this game before.
Just once.
- Now what do we do?
- Don't bother me with details.
Just get me the diamonds.
You handle those cubes
like a monkey handles coconuts.
Thank you, gentlemen,
for such a sterling service.
Well, that's 50,000 dollars.
Minus 5000 for you. Leaves me 45,000,
and thank you very much.
Well, it was nothing, really.
You know something, Peter Franks?
You're a terrific guy.
A little weird, but a terrific guy.
Say, why don't we go someplace
and have a drink?
A drink?
If you'd like to come in, Plenty.
How pretty. What a super place you have.
(Plenty) Just give me one second, lover.
Good evening.
You've caught me
with more than my hands up.
What the hell is this?
A perverts' convention, or something?
Listen, you can't do this to me.
Stop that. I've got friends in this town.
Exceptionally fine shot.
I didn't know there was a pool down there.
All right. Let's get down to business.
I presume you've come for the real...
The real diamonds.
Good evening, Miss Case.
Sorry about your fulsome friend.
I'll bet you really missed something.
The evening may not be
a total loss after all.
Why don't we talk a bit first?
First?
Well, what would you like to talk about?
You pick a subject.
- Diamonds?
- Good boy.
And you want to know where they are,
and whether I'm working alone or not.
So far, so good. Keep going.
And if not, then with whom.
So you can inform your superiors
and acquire the diamonds.
Peter, I'm very impressed.
There's a lot more to you
than I had expected.
Presumably I'm the condemned man,
and obviously you're the hearty breakfast.
Right?
You're not going to tell me
where the diamonds are, are you?
- What diamonds?
- Sooner or later you'll have to talk.
They'll make you.
At the very least,
you'll never get out of town alive.
I can solve that little problem.
It's lucky for me that I ran into you.
A fifty-fifty split.
You get the diamonds, I get us out.
Us?
Well, I can't very well help you
and then stick around.
We could be on a plane and
out of the country by tomorrow night.
Rio, Hong Kong...
- I know a good tailor in Hong Kong.
- Hong Kong.
All right. I'll get the diamonds,
you get the plane tickets.
No. The airport's too obvious. A rented car
should do us fine for openers.
Good thinking.
And since you're the one who's
being watched, I'll get the diamonds,
you get the car.
- That's very good thinking.
- Oh, Peter.
I have a feeling this is the beginning
of a wonderful relationship.
- Darling...
- Hm?
Where do I pick up the diamonds?
Well, when was the last time
you visited a circus?
Circus Circus proudly presents
the Flying Palacios.
- She's in the building.
- Right. Stand by.
James, next time pick a contact
point when you're standing up.
- If she gives your men the slip...
- Relax.
I've got upwards of 30 agents down there.
A mouse with sneakers on couldn't get by.
Give Maxwell his cue.
This is Quarterback.
Operation Passover, commence.
Quarterback to Tight End.
Roger.
She's on her way. So far, so good.
- Good luck. I'll see you later.
- Where are you going?
The car rental agency.
Our little rendezvous?
You don't think she'll show up, do you?
That's a thousand-to-one shot.
More like even money: Her devotion to
larceny versus my incomparable charm.
(man) All right now, kiddy.
You ready? Aim, fire! Go ahead.
What did I tell you? Didn't I promise you
a winner every time? There you are.
All right, boys and girls, here we go again.
All you have to do is just take your gun...
All right, now here we have a little lady.
Here we have a little man.
And here we have a big lady. You're
a little out of your league, aren't you?
Come on, point the gun.
You know what to do.
All ready? Get set. Now hold it till I say go.
Go!
Come on. That's it.
Everybody point right at the clown.
Winner every time. Get 'em up there.
There we are. All right.
That's the way to do it.
Look at that. And we have another winner.
Annie Oakley on the end, huh?
Here we are. What an eye, what an eye.
Wait a second. Hold it.
I saw the whole thing.
The machine's fixed.
Who's she? Your mother?
Blow up your pants.
(boy) One win! She only had one win.
You're supposed to have 24
to win that dog.
Will you give it a rest, kid, huh? Boys and
girls, here we go. Everybody come on.
(trumpets)
(PA) Here for the first time, see Zambora,
strangest girl ever born to live.
She was captured
near Nairobi, South Africa,
and is believed to be part
of a cruel, inhuman experiment.
This beautiful girl will be locked into
a steel cage right in front of your eyes,
and will change very slowly
into a ferocious 450-pound gorilla.
Please be very still, ladies and gentlemen.
We must have absolute silence,
so we wouldn't disturb Zambora
from her transcendental state.
We must warn you that in every scientific
experiment there's always a danger.
So keep in mind those curtains is an exit.
God forbid something should go wrong
over here, get outta here.
Now we start the transformation.
Very dangerous. Very quiet, please.
(strange bleeping)
(man) Wake, my beauty, wake.
(growling)
(bars rattle)
(screaming)
(man) Here, lady, you can't go
through there. The other way.
Come on.
(car horn)
No show?
- Felix, don't tell me you lost her.
- We lost her.
Nice place you have here.
Take something off, enjoy the sun.
You've got a lot of guts showing up here,
after letting me freeze my behind off
at a blackjack table for two hours
waiting for nonexistent diamonds.
And what the hell is my black wig
doing in the pool?
- She's...
- Dead.
Supposed to be you.
The next link in the pipeline.
What are you talking about?
Poor Plenty must have
stumbled in here looking for you.
I don't believe you.
A dentist is dead in South Africa.
That little old lady in Amsterdam.
Shady got his last night.
They've missed me once, and you're next.
- Who's your connection?
- You sound like a cop...
- All I know is voices on a phone.
They got me this place
and told me to wait for instructions.
You'd find it hard to hear underwater.
Where's the stuff?
Who are you? You're not a cop
and you're not Peter Franks.
You're not the type
to turn the other cheek. Where is it?
(PA) Eastern Airlines announce the arrival
of their flight, 112 from Los Angeles,
gate seven.
Thank you.
- Fill it up, please.
- OK.
- It's Bert Saxby.
- He's Willard Whyte's right-hand man.
Do you see the top? The penthouse?
They say Willard Whyte hasn't
set foot out of there in three years,
and no one has seen him. No one.
- How much is that?
- Did you pay for this?
Cut him off.
Hey, Curly. What about my stamps?
Where are you going?
Are you mad? Let me by.
Stamps? You ain't got no gas yet. OK?
- OK. So shove a coupla gallons in.
- Well, back it up.
(sounds horn)
Keep leaning on that tooter,
and you're gonna get a shot in the mouth.
- Come on, lady, move it.
- OK, lady, you win. You win.
(car horns)
- Will someone move that car?
- Do what he says.
Hey! I wanted high-test.
Forget it, Curly.
You had your chance and you blew it.
OK, Professor.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- I haven't seen you here before.
- Klaus Hergersheimer.
- New here?
- I've been here three years. G Section.
How are things in G Section?
Still the same old grind. Checking
radiation shields for replacement.
By the way, where's yours?
I've been waiting a couple of days
for you guys to deliver them.
Gee, I'm sorry.
You should have given us a phone call.
I've got one here.
Lucky for you, I carry spares.
You keep that on.
You can't be too careful about radiation.
- Absolutely. I feel much safer with this on.
- See you around.
Who are you? What do you want?
Klaus Hergersheimer. G Section.
Just checking on radiation shields.
- Now, let me see. You are...?
- Professor Dr Metz.
Our shields are fine. Now get out.
I'm sorry.
It won't take a moment, but I must verify.
Metz. How do you spell it?
Will you please leave, you irritating man?
Doctor, there's no reason
to run down the little people.
G Section may not be as important
as you are, but we do have our orders.
- Dr Metz, Willard Whyte for you.
- Right.
Out, out.
Hello, WW.
Yes, it's finally here.
Quite enough for completion.
We'll be through shortly.
No. No problems at all.
- Now will you get out of here?
- Certainly, Doctor.
I've seen everything I need to see.
Thank you very much.
Hi. Sorry to bother you.
I'm Klaus Hergersheimer.
G Section.
Checking radiation shields?
(alarm)
There he is, behind the rock. Come on!
(PA) What the hell is this?
Amateur night? Stop him, Harry.
Get him off that machine. That isn't a toy.
Get out of that moon buggy!
It's gone berserk.
- Stop.
- What do you think you're doing? Hey!
That way.
- What happened?
- Get in.
If you see a mad professor
in a minibus, just smile.
Fred, get the sheriff's office.
You can drop me off at the next corner.
This whole thing is getting out of hand.
No regrets, but when you steal moon
machines from Willard Whyte, goodbye.
Just relax. I have a friend named Felix
who can fix anything.
Is he married?
There goes that son-of-a-bitchin' saboteur.
(siren)
Relax. You've got a friend
named Felix who can fix anything.
Unfortunately, so can Willard Whyte.
Why, you dirty...
(siren)
Come in, Larry. Larry?
Larry?
Go get him, Larry.
- I think Larry got him.
- Sheriff...
Attaboy, Larry. Come in. Larry?
Sheriff...
(siren)
I got you now.
Lean over.
(Tiffany) Why are we suddenly staying
in the bridal suite of the Whyte House?
In order to form
a more perfect union, sweetheart.
James...
May I finally call you James?
What's going to happen to me?
You did talk to your friend Felix
about me?
- Uh-huh.
- Well, what did he say?
Something about 20 years to life.
Nothing important.
- 20 years to life?
- Relax, I'm on top of the situation.
Mr and Mrs Jones?
Yes. That's the name on the register,
Mr Leiter. What's the score with WW?
- Washington says no go. We sit still.
- Sit still?
And Miss Tiffany Case "Jones" has
a lifetime reservation at another hotel.
The kind the government... runs.
I'm cooperating, Mr Leiter. Really I am.
I can vouch for that.
This is not the real White House
and he's not the president.
- Why don't we just see him?
- The president I can get you in to see.
But until Washington believes
Whyte's a thief, that's the way it is.
In the mean time, I'm sure
you and Mrs Jones can amuse yourselves.
And just to make sure you're not
disturbed, I have a man upstairs.
And Hamilton is right out here.
So long, James.
- Well, that's a switch.
- What's that?
The wolf being guarded
by the three little pigs.
I won't be long, darling.
Where are you going?
I'm just popping upstairs for a moment.
- Sixteenth floor?
- (man) No, lady. Starlight Lounge only.
OK, folks, stand clear of the doors.
Here we go.
(man) Starlight Lounge to the left.
Express to street level only, folks.
OK. Stand clear of the doors. Here we go.
(Whyte) Howdy. Welcome.
We've been expectin' you.
You got any personal business
to take care of in there, go right ahead.
I suspect you're wearin' a hogleg. Would
you mind standin' up and takin' it off?
Oh, isn't that nice?
You are a pleasant fella.
Why don't you just come on in, son?
Relax, make yourself comfortable.
That's good. Right on over there.
- Good evening, Mr Bond.
- Blofeld.
Good evening, 007.
Double jeopardy, Mr Bond. You killed
my only other double, I'm afraid.
After his death, volunteers were
understandably rather scarce.
Such a pity. All that time and expense,
simply to provide you
with one mock-heroic moment.
(phone rings)
(Southern accent) Willard Whyte speakin'.
Yes, Governor, I got your message.
No, I'm afraid a personal appearance
is quite out of the question.
I'll send a deposition to the committee.
Thank you, Governor.
- That's a neat trick.
- A voice box, Mr Bond.
Science was never my strong suit,
but the principle is easy enough.
Someone's voice patterns and resonance
stored in a small oral-signature tape.
And a miniature, transistorised version
is installed in his neck.
Or is it his neck? I never can remember.
Anyway, no matter. We both sound alike.
My congratulations to you both.
Nice little company.
Explosives, oil, electronics,
houses, aviation.
I've done well with it.
Tried to cut some of the fat off.
Actually, Mr Whyte's
a splendid administrator. (laughs)
- Damn thing runs itself.
- I suppose you killed him.
Nothing so melodramatic. I'm simply
holding him in cold storage, so to speak.
An insurance policy against
any outside interference with my plans.
Hm. The ideal kidnap victim.
No one's seen the man for five years.
- So who'd miss someone who's missing?
- How clever you are, Mr Bond.
Nice to see you haven't lost
that fine mental edge, 007.
Please don't get any foolish notions.
That missile is not a practical weapon.
It's hardly worth the effort.
After all, I wouldn't know
which one of you to kill.
We appreciate
your predicament, Mr Bond.
We deeply sympathise.
(gun is cocked)
Right idea, Mr Bond.
But wrong pussy.
I do so enjoy our little visits, Mr Bond.
However potentially painful they may be.
I'm afraid this one has come to an end.
What do you intend to do
with those diamonds?
An excellent question.
And one which will be hanging
on the lips of the world quite soon.
If I were to break the news to anyone,
it would be to you first, Mr Bond.
But it's late, I'm tired,
and there's so much left to do.
Good night, Mr Bond.
Well, go on, go on. It's merely a lift.
Or perhaps I should say "elevator".
You'll find it much more convenient than
mountaineering outside the Whyte House.
You press L, Mr Bond.
The word "lobby" begins with L.
(hissing)
(Bond collapses)
If at first you don't succeed, Mr Kidd...
Try, try again, Mr Wint.
(bottle breaks)
(they chuckle)
(squeaking)
One of us smells like a tart's handkerchief.
I'm afraid it's me.
Sorry about that, old boy.
(rat hisses)
(man) I don't mind the machine
breaking down twice a day,
but why the hell does it always have to be
500 yards away from the nearest hatch?
All right, Charlie,
it's your turn to play hunchback.
Thank you very much.
I was walking my rat
and I seem to have lost my way.
(phone rings)
- (Southern accent) Willard Whyte.
- This is Bert.
(like Bert) We got a problem.
(as Blofeld) What's the matter with your
voice, Bert? Have you got a cold?
(more like Bert) Never mind about that.
I just saw James Bond in the casino.
- That's impossible.
- Yeah? Have a look for yourself.
Hey, listen, if he's half the genius
they say he is, we're in for real trouble.
- Now calm down, Bert.
- It's a cinch he's not working alone.
This place must be crawling with agents.
I think we should move Willard Whyte.
Nonsense. Mr Whyte is perfectly safe
at his own summerhouse.
It's on the ridge,
about ten miles out of town.
I'm a little surprised, Bert.
It's not like you to panic.
I don't enjoy messing around
with a guy as tough as James Bond.
Never mind James Bond.
You get down to that house.
I'm afraid Mr Whyte has suddenly
outgrown his usefulness. Do it cleanly.
(as Bert) Don't worry.
Just leave everything to me.
(as Bond) That ridiculous contraption
actually seems to work, Q.
- You've surpassed yourself.
- Not a bit of it.
Made one of these
for the kids last Christmas.
James and I are heading for the house. Hit
the penthouse as soon as we find Whyte.
(Blofeld) Let me speak to Metz.
There's a change. Push all plans forward
by 24 hours. I'm joining you immediately.
Give me five minutes to get up there
and five minutes to find Whyte.
Are you sure you know
what you're doing?
Ask me again in ten minutes' time.
Tell Maxwell to stand by
to hit the penthouse.
Well, hi there.
I'm Bambi.
Good morning, Bambi.
And I'm Thumper.
Is there something we can do for you?
I can think of several things offhand,
but at the moment
I'm looking for Willard Whyte.
Oh, Willie. Why, he's right out there.
And that's all there is to it?
Not quite.
First we're gonna have a ball.
All yours, Bambi.
You're on again, Bambi.
Thumper.
(both) Yah!
Hello, Felix.
Wouldn't you know it?
Willard Whyte is about to be executed,
and guess who's giving
breaststroke lessons.
- Where the hell is Whyte?
- I haven't found out yet.
(both gasp)
Still haven't found out.
Right.
FBI? CIA?
No. British Intelligence, Mr Whyte.
James Bond.
I see you've met my friends
Bambi and Thumper.
Yes, we did have a bit of a chat.
What the hell's happened to me
and what can I do about it?
Let's get out of here first
and I'll explain it to you en route.
- Tell Maxwell to hit the penthouse...
- (gunshot)
(machine-gun fire)
Argh!
Saxby.
- Bert Saxby?
- Yeah.
Tell him he's fired.
Hi there, Mr Q. Are you having any luck?
- I'm being somewhat successful, thanks.
- Listen, Mr Q, I was wondering.
Have you heard any talk
about me from Felix or James?
No, I'm afraid not.
I guess I'm working for the good guys
now, but I'm still two steps away from jail.
I thought you might be able
to put in a good word.
That's unbelievable.
An electromagnetic RPM controller.
Been aching to give it a try.
You see, pressure on the case here
when the desired symbols appear,
this causes the rotation of the cylinders to
stutter at the precise moment needed to...
Cab, lady?
Well, well, well.
Look what the cat dragged in.
I'm delighted to meet you, Miss Case.
I'd so dreaded the prospect of
making this tedious journey alone.
It was right here.
About six feet high, with a solar panel.
- It had these aerofoils that seemed to...
- Draw it for me.
Was Dr Metz on your payroll, Mr Whyte?
No, but I heard of him.
Everybody in our business has.
The world's leading expert
on laser refraction.
A committed idealist to peace.
And how in the hell Blofeld got
his hooks in him, I will never know.
How did he get security clearance
to work here?
From you, sir.
I talked to you personally about it.
I even recognised your voice just now.
I'm sure I told you not to keep the usual
duplicate microfilm records of the project.
Exactly.
Tom, what did I tell you to do with this?
Send it to Vandenberg.
Well, get 'em on the phone, now.
(phone rings)
Yeah?
You won't believe this.
Willard Whyte for you.
Wow.
This is a real honour, sir.
Shove it. Where's that satellite
I sent down there?
Blasted off 24 minutes ago, sir.
Perfect trajectory. All systems go.
We expect to enter orbit right on the nose.
- Wait. Something's happened.
- Just a moment, Mr Whyte.
The scanners have gone crazy.
- Premature separation.
- It doesn't make sense.
Stand by to abort.
- We can't control it, sir.
- Abort it.
- It's negative.
- We can't.
Something's taken over
the guidance systems.
- It's as if it had a will of its own.
- And there's not a damn thing we can do.
We're working on it. I'll call you back.
Well, whatever it is,
your friend Blofeld's controllin' it now.
A vast supply of diamonds manipulated
by an expert in light refraction.
The first beam was generated
through a diamond,
and if Metz deserves his reputation, the
power of that thing could be incredible.
And Blofeld's got it.
- Where is it now?
- (man) Approaching North Dakota.
- Alert Strategic Air Command.
- Give me an open line to SAC.
(PA) Attention all personnel.
Attention all personnel.
We have a red alert.
Stand by for emergency procedure.
(phone rings)
Willard Whyte.
Yes, General.
One of our missiles just accidentally
blew up in North Dakota.
Whatever's happenin',
Mr Bond, has started.
- Is this your herd?
- Mr Whyte, phone call from Washington.
- I'll catch it in the john.
- What about Blofeld?
- Not a trace, but we found a tunnel.
- Where's Tiffany?
Do you mind if we find Blofeld first?
Come on, let's hit that tunnel.
Argh!
Well, Washington just got word
from your friend with the cat.
Would you believe that this whole
country is bein' held for ransom
and we've got
till noon tomorrow to pay up?
So that's it, then.
Well, I'm sure you won't be alone.
An international auction, with nuclear
supremacy goin' to the highest bidder.
Tell me, what does he need
to control that satellite?
A simple set of tapes fed into a computer
bank. All he really needs is a building.
And these tapes? Large or small?
Conceivably any size,
from six inches to a cassette.
Assuming he's still using
your empire as a cover,
Blofeld could be anywhere on this map.
From Alaska to Florida,
from Maine to Oregon.
From Texas to Baja California.
Baja?
I haven't got anything at Baja.
(radio) There is still no official explanation
of the simultaneous nuclear accidents
in North Dakota and Russia.
Presidential news secretary John Fenner
has refused comment on a report
that a meeting of the Joint Chiefs
of Staff is in session.
It is believed the United States and
the Soviet Union have assured each other
that no offensive action
has been taken by either nation.
Reports of another nuclear accident
in Red China are as yet unconfirmed...
Two more submarines
have taken up position.
Will those military aircraft
stand off forever?
What if they won't accept our ultimatum?
What if they decide to attack?
Calm yourself, Metz. This farcical show
of force was only to be expected.
The Great Powers flexing their muscles
like so many impotent beach boys.
I regret my threat to destroy a major city
unless they give in, but there it is,
the nuclear powers, like all bullies,
can only be intimidated by force.
- But how can...
- There's still an hour left to reply.
One hour for both of us
to achieve our common dream:
Total disarmament
and peace for the world.
- Sir, there's a single plane approaching.
- Range?
Two miles, and closing.
Stage One alert, please.
Command Centre. All crew to Stage One.
(klaxon)
(guard) Weapons up, second platform.
There he is.
- (guard) Aim.
- (Blofeld) Hold your fire.
(PA) All recovery crew personnel,
proceed to docking level and stand by.
Good morning.
The Acme Pollution Inspection.
We're cleaning up the world and
thought this was a suitable starting point.
How disappointing. I was expecting
one head of state, at the very least.
Surely you haven't come to negotiate?
Your pitiful little island
hasn't even been threatened.
Search him from his toenails to the last
follicle on his head, then bring him to me.
(~ "The British Grenadiers"
played by military band)
I do so hate martial music.
But as usual, Mr Bond,
you were absolutely right.
You guessed correctly, that box contained
the master satellite control tape,
and you came aboard presumably
hoping to substitute this for the real thing.
So sorry to have ruined
the line of your suit for nothing.
Which line did you use on Miss Case?
Miss Case has taken
a reasonable attitude about all this.
Like any sensible animal, she's only
threatening when she's threatened.
It appears that you're holding all the aces,
down to the dragon lady here.
Jealousy? From you, Mr Bond?
I'm flattered.
As La Rochefoucauld observed,
"Humility is the worst form of conceit."
I do hold the winning hand.
Why don't you let me take you
on a little tour of our facilities?
Your chance to see
the real tape once again.
Can I tag along, Ernst?
I'd put something on
over that bikini first, my dear.
I've come too far to have the aim of my
crew affected by the sight of your body.
No word yet from anyone.
Only 12 minutes left.
Oh, well, I suppose
a little gentle prodding is called for.
As you see, Mr Bond,
the satellite is at present over...
Kansas.
But if we destroy Kansas,
the world may not hear about it for years.
Perhaps New York.
All that smut and traffic.
It would give them a chance
for a fresh start.
Washington, DC. Perfect.
Since we have not heard from them,
they will hear from us.
- See to it, Metz.
- Washington. Right.
And this, presumably,
is the control bank with the coded tape.
Right again, Mr Bond. All satellites
are controlled by a coded tape.
The trick is, of course, to have the code.
Obviously.
It all seems so perfectly simple.
I suppose one just presses that
and out it pops.
Put it back, Mr Bond. Immediately.
Hi, Ernst.
- Is Superman giving you any trouble?
- Put it back very carefully.
You've suddenly
become tiresome, Mr Bond.
Target fixed. Commence countdown.
Ten minutes and counting.
Take him away and throw him in the brig.
And search him again, just to make sure.
Bitch.
Your problems are all behind you now.
Stop him!
(PA) Nine minutes and counting.
I did it. I switched the tape in the machine.
- You twit. You put the real one back in.
- Come on, let's go.
(spotter) A weather balloon.
- What do you think?
- That must be the signal.
There isn't a low-pressure area
within 200 miles of here. Let's go.
This is Charlie One to Squadron.
Charlie One to Squadron.
Ready all guns and proceed to target.
I repeat: Proceed to target.
(pilot) Roger, Charlie One. Out.
Come on, Bond.
Get the hell off that rig.
(PA) Eight minutes and counting.
Unidentified aircraft approaching rapidly.
Range five miles.
But I don't understand.
You said they wouldn't attack. You said...
The balloon was a signal. The fools must
think Mr Bond accomplished his mission.
- Activate defences.
(klaxon)
Seven minutes and counting.
This is Charlie One. Commence attack.
Commence attack.
Six minutes and counting.
Get them on the radio, Blofeld.
Tell them we give up.
Give up?
I've waited too long for this moment.
They'll pay dearly
for making a fool out of me.
I see it all now.
You don't give a damn about peace.
- All you care about...
- Shut up, Metz.
Tiffany, my dear.
We're showing a bit more cheek
than usual, aren't we?
Take her below and
lock her up with Mr Bond.
What a pity. Such nice cheeks, too.
If only they were brains.
Destroy this, Metz.
Five minutes and counting.
Four minutes and counting.
Tell them we surrender.
This is utter madness.
One more word, Metz, and I'll have you
shot. Get back to your post.
Prepare my bathosub immediately.
Three minutes and counting.
All systems interlock.
Bathosub to crane: Commence lift.
Two minutes and counting.
Power and breathing systems on.
Release catch is open.
Lower away.
Bathosub to crane: Lower away.
Wake up, man. Lower away.
You stupid idiot! You could've killed me.
Disengage.
Disengage!
Lower. Not up.
One minute and counting.
Blofeld to Command Centre: Come in.
Damn you! Damn you.
Command Centre, come in.
40 seconds and counting.
Get the gun.
- Here.
- Shoot 'em.
Argh!
Jump!
Ten, nine...
So long, James.
I'll wire M you're on your way home.
Don't tell him which direction we've taken.
If you're havin' a good time,
let the captain know and I'll have him
steam around in circles.
James, there's something very important
I've been meaning to ask you. About us.
Oh?
I know in a relationship like ours, the girl's
not supposed to ask, but I can't help it.
And please think before answering.
- That I promise.
- James...
(knock at door)
There must be some mistake.
I didn't order anything.
No mistake, sir.
On the specific instructions and with
the compliments of Mr Willard Whyte.
Oysters Andaluz.
Shashlik.
Tidbits. Prime rib en jus.
Salade Utopia.
And for dessert, the pièce de résistance,
la bombe surprise.
Hm!
That looks fantastic. What's in it?
But then there would be no surprise,
would there, madame?
- If madam would care to be seated.
- Thank you.
This will just take a moment,
and then we will leave you in peace.
Wine, sir? Mouton Rothschild '55.
- May we begin?
- (Bond) Please do.
(cork pops)
- A happy selection, if I may say.
- I'll be the judge of that.
That's rather potent.
Not the cork - your aftershave.
Strong enough to bury anything.
But the wine is quite excellent.
Although, for such a grand meal,
I had rather expected a claret.
Of course. Unfortunately, our cellar
is rather poorly stocked with clarets.
Mouton Rothschild is a claret.
And I've smelt that aftershave before.
And both times I've smelt a rat.
Yee!
(screams)
Whooh.
Whooooh!
Whoa!
He certainly left
with his tails between his legs.
Oh, James.
Yes, what were you about to ask me?
James...
how the hell do we get
those diamonds down again?
~ Diamonds are forever
~ Sparkling round my little finger
~ Unlike men, the diamonds linger
~ Men are mere mortals
who are not worth going to your grave for
~ I don't need love
~ For what good would love do me?
~ Diamonds never lie to me
~ For when love's gone
~ They'll lustre on
~ Diamonds are forever, forever, forever
~ Forever
~ And ever
Visiontext Subtitles: Adrian Isaac