Metal Cannon!
Fist of One Hundred Beasts
So, you want to live?
I...
Even if I were to take your X-Antibody...
...I still wouldn't live any longer.
You have good eyes...
Live for me in this new world.
Carry on, for our future.
I'm sorry to have chased you.
Get lost!
You aren't the chosen!
Because a Digimon like you appeared, with a strange stone on his forehead,
Andromon said the world is going to hell!
Get outta here!
Get lost!
That's enough.
Why... am I here...?
Why am I unwanted?
Why am I not needed...?
Still...
Why...!?
You think it's possible we Royal Knights can execute Project Ark?
It is not a matter of whether we can or cannot...
That is for Yggdrasil to determine.
We only have to fulfill our mission.
And will that work out...?
What do you mean?
Will we not just repeat our mistakes?
Are you saying that Yggdrasil is wrong?
The start of the Digital Hazard...
The X-Program my Lord Yggdrasil will execute.
I, Dukemon, would never--
X-Antibody Digimon and the like!
They are alien!
Such aliens will only bring ruin.
They and us...
We are all Digimon, are we not?
Please, hear me out!
We don't have time to bicker!
At this rate, all Digimon will be exterminated!
Please don't say such things now...
Isn't it your fault that this crisis falls on us!?
That is wrong!
When the X-Program was complete, many of our friends died.
In fact 98% of all Digimon died.
In order to live... we had to flee to this new world.
And so you will contaminate this world as well...
If you had never come here...
Are you saying it's OK if we're the only ones to die?
You don't care what happens to any other Digimon!?
Then what about you guys?
Because you've come here, this child is in danger!
Well...
Sorry...
But we really have no time to squabble.
You came here knowing that, didn't you?
Everything is because Yggdrasil's X-Program was executed.
Soon this new world will be contaminated.
Yggdrasil will begin hunting X-Antibody Digimon!
Lies!
They plan to wipe out all the X-Antibody Digimon.
And behind all that, the X-Program will take this world.
Which in turn means that Yggdrasil itself is our common enemy, right?
You hold an interesting point...
But that's as far as it goes.
Before coming here, we reported it to Yggdrasil...
This is where you'll end.
How could you!?
Our meeting is over!
Everyone, get away from here!
Run!
Great Spirit!
Fool...
This would have never happened if you hadn't reported.
Don't tell me...
Even us?
I see...
You also have the X-Antibody...
It must have been hard for you.
As a friend, I have a favour to ask you.
Friend...?
That's right.
I'm sure you've realized...
I also have the X-Antibody.
We don't have much time.
I will be back.
Before I return, could you look after this child?
Please, protect this child.
Don't worry, I'm sure you can do it.
Okay.
Thank you.
Wasn't that a Royal Knight?
Why is one of the Network leaders...?
That hurts!
Poseidon Force!
Clever...
Return to Yggdrasil immediately.
It's an emergency.
Omegamon, present!
Well, let us begin...
Golden Magnamon.
Urd Terminal, Skuld Terminal...
The resistance groups have formed.
I have seen them.
Similar groups have formed in the Versandi Terminal as well.
Even in Versandi?
Correct.
Certainly...
Those X-Antibody Digimon intend to fight us Royal Knights squarely.
It's a matter of who moves first.
That is right...
What do you mean, Omegamon?
That we must take emergency countermeasures against this resistance.
However--!
Our mission is to guide Project Ark's course.
Yggdrasil's decision is final.
Do not waver!
Then it's futile...
Those Royal Knights...
They sure are strong.
Are they really our enemies?
Fool.
What have you been looking at recently?
The Royal Knights only move in accordance to Yggdrasil.
I don't think they'd move on their own.
It wouldn't solve anything.
And if it's as you say...
Yet it is not.
If the Host Computer wants to kill off all Digimon with this stone...
Then those Royal Knights will comply!
What has happened to the Royal Knights the Digimon were proud of!?
Well...
Still, I...
I want to believe in the Royal Knights!
Whatever Yggdrasil is planning...
We will find that out soon enough.
Are you okay?
Yes~! Mon!
That's good.
I'm just doing what I can.
Metal Cannon!
I'm no match for him...
They know this is futile...
Why do they still come!?
Why...
Garuru Tomahawk!
Are you all right?
I kept... my promise...
Is this the justice of the Royal Knights!?
It is the justice of Yggdrasil's New Digital World!
Garuru Burst!
Gaia Force!
Cocytus Breath!
Not bad.
However, this is the end.
This child--!
This child is dead!!!
Grey Sword!
The X-Program was completed...?
Don't worry.
I will soon die.
I will give this child my X-Antibody.
Do you want to live?
Please live on for me.
Live for me in this new world.
Life is just that beautiful...
I give this to you.
Power Metal!
Why?
Why do you go to such lengths to fight!?
Because I want to live!
I just want to live.
Even if it's just to extend my life a bit more...
I just want to live!
Yggdrasil...
...doesn't want that.
This lance--?
Give up, Omegamon...
I have not come to fight.
I have something to ask you.
Why was the X-Program launched...?
Do you want to know the reason?
Dukemon! What are you saying!?
Yggdrasil set off the sudden extermination of Digimon...
It made its decision on the Old World.
There is nothing to hide...
That's right.
Only a number of Digimon were chosen to come to this world...
...and only a certain number of Digimon will be able to advance.
Project Ark.
The X-Program was set off just for that?
So, you know that name...
However, some of us lived.
And those were the ones that came here.
Both the chosen Digimon, and the surviving Digimon... are they not all Digimon!?
That is wrong!
You are outsiders.
That is what Yggdrasil decided.
Omegamon!
You need not answer.
Yggdrasil's decision will soon reach this level.
What do you mean?
Yggdrasil has passed Project Ark to the secondary stage.
It will delete all Digimon.
How dare you!
That is classified information!
It matters not...
Both the chosen Digimon and you X-Antibody Digimon...
Everything will be erased.
To go that far--!
It is by my Lord Yggdrasil's command...
To see it carried out is the duty of us Royal Knights.
However, I, Dukemon, refuse!
You would betray Him?
Rather than betray my own emotions...
I would defy Yggdrasil.
I cannot help it.
Next time we meet, will we be enemies?
Too bad...
My dear friend, Omegamon!
Is there not something you want to ask to heed my defiance?
I will see.
I wish to give them a chance.
I will never forget this pain...
I waited for you, Dukemon...
I guess we cannot come to an understanding.
I bid thee adieu...
I cannot allow anyone to hinder Yggdrasil.
I will not let my heart interfere either.
Very well!
Y...You--!
This is the only way...
I have something I want to check...
Don't let it get to you...
What is it?
Dukemon...
You look depressed...
Magnamon...
Do you hold any regrets in the battle you pursue?
No.
That confidence comes from...?
My will to fulfill my duty in protecting this world...
...as well as my pride as a Royal Knight.
I asked an unnecessary thing.
Forget it.
Tokomon!?
Stay away!
Tokomon...!
Are you Dorugamon?
Don't--!
Disappear!
Power Metal!
That attitude which drove you to fire...
Whatever.
You brought Dorugamon to Yggdrasil?
Why?
Yggdrasil commanded it.
What?
I merely returned it.
Dorugamon...
No, Dorumon...
...is not a digital being born in our world.
He is Yggdrasil's experimental being.
That is Yggdrasil's very words.
For what...?
Who knows.
I do not understand Yggdrasil's reasoning.
We Royal Knights...
...have perhaps gone too far...
Dukemon...
Where has your Core gone...?
What was it that you wanted to check?
And this reasoning of Yggdrasil's...
There is still much that I do not know...
Where's Dorugamon!?
He's not with you?
R...Royal Knights!
The Royal Knights did something?
No one will hurt you here, don't worry.
You don't need to cry...
Hey!
What?
You must be blind...
Just leave him.
He's probably going for disassembly anyway.
I can't leave something I've found.
Even if he's not alive... I won't leave him.
Don't come crying to me for help...
You know what he is, right?
I just heard from WarGreymon.
He was looking for info on a pal the Royal Knights were after.
In any case, this guy's unique.
He's wanted?
That's what WarGreymon said.
So?
You think we should tell him he's here?
If WarGreymon is looking for him, then we'll let him know.
But I'm afraid the Royal Knights will find out where we are...
WarGreymon knows the risk...
I'll believe in his decision.
Even if it puts all our friends here in danger!?
Have you forgotten what kind of era we live in!?
All our friends in the Digital World are in danger anyway.
I can't think that any one of us is safe.
Fine.
Well, I'll let WarGreymon know!
Don't worry!
I'm sure he's fine!
He won't die so easily.
Yeah! Not so easily!
We're gonna speed up, so hang on tight!
Top Gun!
Get away from the entrance!
Escape further inside!
Leave that guy!
If I was gonna leave him, I wouldn't have picked him up in the first place.
Go on without me.
Lead everyone to the secret platform.
I'll follow behind the rear.
Why do you go to such lengths for this guy!?
I won't let a friend die...
That's all.
What are you waiting for!?
Move it!
Metal!
Metal! Go!
I'll take care of this.
Evacuate everyone!
But--!
Too many are injured!
If this keeps up, this fight will be meaningless!
I'll follow later!
Don't worry!
Fall back to the platform!
Help carry the injured if you can!
Cocytus Breath!
We'll be waiting for you!
Now it's time for me to go wild!
We'll be safe once we pass here.
Don't rush.
Stay calm and go.
This way!
Yeah...
There's a platform up ahead that leads to the hidden road.
There is?
Here...!
This is bad...
Stay here until I tell you to.
Agreed?
Okay!
Good kid...
Keep it orderly!
This way! Over here!
You...
The least I can do is shoot one!
Don't push yourself.
You too.
It's me!
Those who can fight, move out!
We'll back up WarGreymon!
MetalGarurumon?
He stayed behind to fight off the enemies...
He gave us the time to escape.
Please... wait for him!
What's this?
Did something happen to the exit?
At this rate...!
No!
I promised him!
I said I'd wait for him.
But--!
He'll come!
I'm sure of it!
Wait!
Nice timing.
Here too!?
Take care of him...
Thunder Cloud!
Mon! There!
Tokomon!
You survived!
Sorry for making you worry.
Poseidon Force!
Wake up!
Mon! Please, wake up!
Tokomon?
Why...?
Why?
Hang in there!
STOP!!!
What the hell are you!?
You...!
We saved you!?
What?
I-I'm...
I'm...
Why...?
Is this the result of the experimental being?
Why... this form...
I must...
It's still him...
Mon!
Everyone stay calm!
He just assumed their form...
There has to be a reason behind it!
His heart is still with us!
So, that's it...
Yggdrasil has seen the future.
This is what we Royal Knights speculated with Project Ark's deployment.
This is the outcome.
And this is in accordance with the deployment?
What Dukemon meant about the "mistakes"...
And you agree?
I will make certain of Yggdrasil's decision!
Wait! Omegamon!
Final Elysion!
I, Dukemon, have returned from the Data Space.
WarGreymon, MetalGarurumon...
Lead them all away!
Dorugremon and I shall take care of the rest here!
Let's go!
Understood!
Those that can fly, cover those that can't!
Once we clear the wall, we'll head for the forest!
Right!
I'll be all right...
Head somewhere safe.
Mon!
I'll come as soon as I can...
I promise.
I'll leave the rest to you!
Royal Saber!
You were all right!
So, you worried...
I...
Is it truly okay for me to still be alive?
If I were dead... then things wouldn't be like this!
You wish that I, Dukemon, should answer that?
What the hell am I?
Why the hell am I here!?
Everything has the will to live.
From the very first time life existed, that much has not changed...
Dorugremon!
Go to Yggdrasil!
Do you not want to know who you really are?
You will find all your answers there.
What has happened to Yggdrasil even I, Dukemon, do not know...
However, the only way in is there!
But--!
I, Dukemon, am enough to hold them here.
You must go to my Lord Yggdrasil.
Should I, Dukemon, fall... then that is my own sought answer.
I'll go!
It's futile, Omegamon!
No one can touch Yggdrasil!
Intangible things are troublesome.
I have vowed my loyalty to Yggdrasil...
However, that is why I have said I cannot tolerate my master's motives.
Selfishness does not become you.
Then what is this chaos!?
That is...
Why are you here?
This is not a place for one like you...
Leave this place this instant!
Dukemon opened the path for me...
Dukemon?
I came to find the answer...
I want to see Yggdrasil!
There is nothing to ask.
Interesting...
Impossible!
You want to meet Yggdrasil, whom even the Royal Knights cannot touch?
On top of that, the one who opened the path for you was my dear friend Dukemon...?
Then, before you reach that answer...
...you must defeat me!
I will fulfill your wish if you do so...
Defeat you!? No--!
Why must you always get so emotional?
He may be Yggdrasil's experiment...
But didn't I say he was not a digital being?
No...
I think he and I are on the same wavelength...
Then, whichever one of us reaches Yggdrasil's Core and grasps that answer... that will be fine.
That fact that Dukemon opened the path for you has further meaning.
Show me your true form!
Wait...
There's no time!
If I don't hurry up, the Digital World will--!
Are you saying that when you meet Yggdrasil and find your answer...
...the Digital World will be saved!?
How conceited!
You think you can do what I could not...
What is waiting for us at Yggdrasil!?
No...!
I  don't want to fight...!
I have no reason to fight you!
If you do not, then I do...
For what did you come here for?
For the existence of everything!
Then, fight...
Being prepared is more than just words.
Prove that you came here ready to die for the existence of everything!
You aren't the one I want to fight!
So you still say that?
Then who is it?
That's what I want to find out by meeting Yggdrasil!
What are you saying!?
Any intruder would have been destroyed.
Tell us what we want to know!
The Royal Knights protect the order of the Digital World...
For one like you to approach Yggdrasil would oppose that order!
This is the end.
Live for me in this new world.
Please, live on for me.
Carry on, for our future.
Life is just that beautiful...
You must go to my Lord Yggdrasil.
Should I, Dukemon, fall... then that is my own sought answer.
Light!
You are?
It can't be...!
I am Alphamon.
That's impossible!
While I'm looking at Alphamon... such was said to never exist!
An apparition...
A legend among the Royal Knights!
Even so, here I stand.
And thanks to you, I now know what I must do...
I cannot excuse Yggdrasil's intervention in this...
Dukemon led you here for that reason...
I have confirmed...
...and I will acknowledge you.
Come, and together we will bear witness.
Stop!
The Royal Knights are to protect the order of the Digital World.
For the future, that is what you always said!
Is this order?
Seems you have only just realized...
When the order of the Digital World begins to collapse,
Yggdrasil's order is something to be concerned about.
The Royal Knights never move unless told...
You will still go without waiting for such a gracious command!?
I will go.
Just as my dear friend Dukemon would have done.
This is troublesome...
Our friends are in trouble.
All Digimon face a state of crisis...
Yet you still hold high your holy words.
No...
It is because we are in a state of crisis.
Order is necessary.
Who are you!?
This is...
Digitalize of Soul!
Let us go.
This is... Yggdrasil?
I wish to see Yggdrasil.
Where is your Core?
What are you really trying to accomplish?
I wish to know as well.
Why must Project Ark be executed with such overpowering force?
Yggdrasil...
If you intend on remaining silent, you better prepare yourself.
No matter what we do, there is no way we'll get out in one piece.
Magnamon has already warned Yggdrasil of our coming.
We are traitors.
If Yggdrasil insists on remaining silent, then there is only one option.
This might be the end of everything...
Then, what will we learn from this?
There is only one thing I'm sure of.
No matter what we do, at this rate, the Digital World will be destroyed.
Then...
We cannot stand idly by.
Ultimate War Blade King Dragon Sword
So that's how it is...
What is the meaning of this?
I entrust this to you...
I can't, but what about...
He is my shadow...
If I hadn't met my friends... I wouldn't have become this.
I might have been just like him.
However, I am proud to have met you all in this Digital World.
I give my life over to you...
Yggdrasil!
Is this what you wish for!?
I still do not understand...
But I will settle this!
All Delete!
I remember up until then...
Yggdrasil was also desperate...
I'm finally beginning to understand the reason behind Project Ark.
I'm listening...
My Lord, Yggdrasil, generally intervened with this world...
However, the world is a complex place...
This is where it thought about "fixing" it.
And that is Project Ark...?
Most likely...
However, my Lord didn't have the power to carry it out on its own.
And that's why it thought up that experimental being.
In the end, we were also merely pawns of Yggdrasil's?
As I said before...
Yggdrasil was desperate.
Most likely, like you, it only wanted to live...
Just like all life has this desperation to live...?
From now on, they can be happy...
I was looking for you!
Mon!