Are you sure you want to
be on that side of the wall?
They begin to tear down the
walls on Monday.
The police, the post office
and the schools all open next month.
C'mon, will you smile?
You look so down.
I hope things don't get messed up
on the way, and that they keep their promises.
Listen, it's the law and the law is always
Looking for an asshole like me ...
... to make sure
these things are fulfilled.
Three years later,
the government has changed.
... the rest ...
Sector 13 Ultimatum
Stop!
Keep up! Keep up!
There he is! There he is!
What?
Over here.
Hey, man.
Now you bring cops?
Sorry.
I am not enough.
Do you think im a musketeer?
- Yes, I am Dartagnan.
- Are you teasing?
Dudu, leave.
Dudu, I never understand.
Why dont you know anything?
- Say, you look like a child.
- I am a child.
You Take care of others.
come.
Sit back,
What did you do now?
- This city is not a hotel.
- Sorry.
- I got tired.
- Not in the same situation.
You're free, this
whole city just for you.
They treat us like animals.
And so since we were born.
Three years ago
we were promised change.
A government that fails to meet
their promises? That's weird.
If we dont do something,
we will be ignored.
Yet we do nothing
Not your culture, dude.
To us this wall protects us ...
... as a fortress.
And those who come to disturb us
of our society, mean nothing.
We have our own.
And that is fine
the way it is.
And frankly, I prefer to be
the king of this small kingdom ...
... than a pawn out there.
Therefore, will you be polite and stop bombing the wall
... if not, we Will be beat or shoot you
Do you understand?
This is good.
Take this.
A gift.
Yeah, boss?
Yes, boss.
Come on.
Leave!
Come on!
Your merchandise arrived.
Do I send the first client?
So Rude, let me enjoy
a while.
Get him out, at least that.
Everybody out!
Not you.
Go see the boss.
Come on, dance a little.
Mr. Ou will see you now.
My ass hurts sitting out here waiting!
Tell yourself, sir.
Come on, get on you knees.
If you want more money
you should be more inclined.
get on your knees, my man.
And hands on his head.
- Thief?
- Worse.
Police.
Your under arrest,
be silent ...
... until your presented to
the judge ...
If you think that I a. ..
In French it means
shut up, okay?
No, it's a Ming vase
the twelfth century.
Do not worry, it is false,
the real one is in a museum.
And the rest?
Are all fake?
Almost. Except for the Van Gogh.
Central, I have the soap.
Again, I have soap.
Understood,
precise location.
- I am the soap?
- I feel more of a shampoo.
- Since I am going fishing
- What do you mean you're
Going fishing?
Do not worry.
You do not have to understand.
Mr Calma.
Health monitor.
We would like to see the boss.
Lord, there are officers
at the door.
Two police officers for sure,
there are more hidden.
Here is one. Dale.
Dale.
- You bastard!
- You see, already beginning to fall.
You'll never leave here, this building
is monitored by all parties.
If it were that easy,
They wouldnt have sent me.
What is that?
It's simple, if you talk
your cheeks explode.
Want to try?
Okay.
I'll report
you are cooperative.
Central, I'm going fishing.
Mr Ou awaits.
Only you
Stay here
okay.
Mr Ou,
It gives me pleasure to see you.
Do not move.Lift your hands
Forward
Walk.
Gentlemen, after you.
I go last or what?
Them first.
- Hugo.
- How did you know?
Yes, I have photos of yourself
all over my room.
Shit!
Come on.
Raise the head.
- What is that?
- You should know, it was you who invented it.
Gentlemen, follow me.
He is thumbing his nose at me.
And let it gives the same.
A week ago!
that fat ...!
Come on, calm down.
Drink a margarita, and relax.
the fuck with your margarita!
I'm sick of these guys!
Outside, start
to enter.
Mr. Sam, just went looking for you.
Now I go?
You Do this to your best customer?
Since when am
I left last?
Always leave the shit
for last.
Open arms.
What are you doing?
Fucking ugly?
And this shit?
Did it not do anything?
I used that shit
all the time as a kid.
We'll fix it.
It's nothing,
he fell.
Central fishing is done.
Send in the others.
I already did.
- Nobody move!
- ¡Todos al piso!
Hands on your head!
- Come on, come on!
- Leaving!
Come on!
We'll never come out of here alive, you dirty
Police, there is no way out
You don't have a
Chance!
Are you sure?
Let me go! Let me go!
- I guess I need the code.
- Fuck you.
No matter, I have the key.
Move!
- I'm heading south.
- South?
Send the rest.
Watch your feet!
Push!
Turn it off!
Get out! Shit, get out!
They found it!
I told them I was cheating
everywhere.
What happened?
I will kill you.
Open up!
Crap.
- You okay?
- Yes, but they're here.
Don't move.
This picture is worth
200 million euros.
It's a Van Gogh.
A stray bullet, a scratch
and no longer worth anything.
Die motherfucker!
There he is! There he is!
Okay, I see the keyboard.
hello?
Nice to meet you.
Central, there is a bomb.
- A bomb?
- Any idea?
- Where is it?
- In the kitchen in the basement.
It's good,
we will send you whats necessary.
On guard!
we sent it.
Fantastic!
Nice to see you.
Welcome.
- Do you have scratches?
- No, I do not think so.
- I wasn't referring to you, Damian.
- It's fine, Commander, thank you.
Anyway,
not just these.
Go rest,
make the report tomorrow.
I prefer to continue working
in what I have in my head.
Tomorrow I'll go early,
If you do not mind.
No, I will see you in my office
at noon. Is an order.
Thank you.
- Good work.
- Thanks.
Everything is fine.
All clear.
Bring them.
Gentlemen.
- How goes the work?
- Superb.
How long does it take build
a tower like this?
That depends on the location
But more or less
eight years.
Good.
Yes
Get him out.
As in the neighborhood
Chantier of ...
... twice now, if we give the
guarantee that the constructed.
The operation will begin
tonight.
Perfect.
- Well, thank you, until tomorrow.
- Goodbye, Damien.
Crap.
Damian?
Have you forgotten me?
No.
They gave me time
to rest.
For eight hours I'm
resting, and I'm fantastic!
Wait.
Soft, soft.
My whole body hurts.
your whole body?
Almost.
Is that makeup?
Yes, it's for work.
It is the work.
You told me you spend
the day looking for pictures.
I say it's my job.
Well, you better show me
that the wait was worth it.
Speaking.
The suspect is
in the next seven.
What good music.
Excuse me.
Again, auto blue ...
54, we are close.
Well, received 54.
So, Salim
Is not it?
- Yes, yes!
- Listen!
Yes, hi.
Are you at home?
No, I'm in a palace
overlooking the Eiffel Tower.
- And where is your palace?
- On the Champs Elysees.
Beautiful view.
Well, your listening,
What do you want?
Yes, it is Sofia.
Well, "Push the Air"
is for her.
Well, you know,
Coordinator ...
- No!
- Shit!
What?
Everything will be fine.
- Sami.
- What?
The police.
- Downloaded music?.
- It's our music.
- It's nothing bad.
- I decide that.
Come on, ID,
both of you.
- Come on, here.
- Grab.
- Who owns the car?
- my father.
Driving license?
I have not, take it away.
What about your license?
I'm 17 years,
I have no license!
We're not doing anything,
Only music!
Since when is prohibited to
listen to music?
We're not bothering
anyone.
- Come out of that car.
- No.
Hurry.
Shit! Again.
Go see what happened.
Okay.
- And what is this?
- I don't know, I don't know.
Shoot, Shoot.
- What is it, officer?
- A routine check.
Some girls who listen
music isnt so dangerous.
Why not search? Are
the girls carrying ...
... drugs in this neighborhood.
We'll give you a vote of
confidence tonight.
- Can you drive?
- Yes
- Get out.
- But I have no license.
Get out!
Shit, they left.
But she has no license.
What do we do?
Do we continue?
- Come on.
- No, stay.
- You keep shooting.
- I am.
What service
are you exactly?
Secret Service.
Get in your car.
Shit!
Do not move,
still filming!
- And what is this?
- You keep shooting.
And what is this?
The license, zoom in.
I got it.
Shit, Ive never
seen that before.
Give me here, and I do.
- Samir.
- What?
Policemen killed
police, is a bomb.
Precisely, rather than see it explode
lets hear the official report.
That will do.
What?
- police here?
- What are you talking about?
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Somethinsg wrong, I assure you.
Hey, you,
Have you lost your way?
- This is not a parking lot.
- That you can be sure.
- Do you have framed?
- Yes
Perfect.
They're shooting!
Fire!
Come on, normal
excercise.
- The bomb is well placed?
- Yes
Dale, collects and
we go home.
Diss.
Where are you going?
Go back to sleep, I'm going to see a
film. Don't worry.
Get down, hands behind!
- I'm police!
- Get down!
Damien!
What?
Who is responsible for
your unit? I want answers.
I am.
I think you have the wrong
person.
Damien Tomaso, captain
the armed forces 31 years.
What is the reason
for this arrest?
Captain, we founnd
this in the kitchen.
Well here is why.
Come to collect a few things ...
... we go.
It is unbearable.
Georges, explain.
Six months ago we
gave good results.
Mr. President, we do not have the means to
Observe any of the crossroads, or any position of the vehicle
Ahórreme story
the means, please.
We have set aside five hundred million slum
So something had to
have improved.
Then Explain to me how they managed
To carry out a massacre like this
This does not detract from ongoing efforts
Made so far, believe me
- What is it then?
- Well this is ...
... an isolated case.
No more.
I hope so.
Until then, the appointed person cost
This issue. serious and effective
That Damien, for example.
Isnt his type of mission, huh?
I thought of him but was arrested this
morning for drug trafficking.
Was he? Are you sure?
Unfortunately.
I would climb
next week.
I thought Gazmán, the head of Diss.
They are well informed about the industry.
Yes, very well. Okay.
Sir.
What? Already?
I guess they are
ahead of the situation.
I had the time
to inform you, Chairman.
Well.
If the tape is broadcasted,chaos will prevail in the country
There will be a whole and the possibility of a civil war
We have 48 hours.
It is exactly the time they have
to resolve this matter.
- Under the utmost discretion.
- Yes, sir.
We will, Mr. President.
Take the video you posted on
The Internet to spread chaos
Special Feature:
Last night in District 13 ...
... an altercation between a banda
and law enforcement ...
- Wow!
- Look, it's an inner chamber.
That's bullshit!
That was not by chance!
Yes?
Why are you here?
I was in wrong place,
as the whole world.
Is no reason to
be here.
You did so well,
so get out!
I have rights!
Come on, go get your
colleagues and tell them to take care.
Come on!
- What district?
- 13.
Perfect.
Boss, can I show you something?
They Sent us this.
Its the chamber that
passed yesterday.
But look at this.
Probably some boys who
attempting to get some girls.
When I saw
I did a zoom ...
... and saw this.
Shit, it was filmed.
Yes
Investigate that license number
right away.
- I'm on it.
- Perfect.
Letto.
- I filmed everything and now I need you.
- What are you talking about?
Car on television.
Shit!
There!
Stop!
- This is Samir.
- Stop!
¡Suéltenlo! ¡Suéltenlo!
Let go of my friend!
Estate calm
or we'll take you too.
Let go of my friend!
Open the door 14.
Come on.
- Can I borrow you cell phone?
- What else you want?
Your cell phone.
Thank you.
Pick up.
Letto, It's Damien, I'm fucked up,
partner, I need a hand ...
I am not at home.
... if you need to talk to me ...
... leave a message.
You gotta help me.
I'm Damien.
I'm in the basement of the
Central Police Station.
I'll lay a trap.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can count on you.
Drop the phone!
Hey, guys!
The police are
everywhere, are you crazy?
Yes, I know.
They Are everywhere.
Okay.
Leave for a minute.
Yes?
We have carried out a telephone conversation before he was arrested --
- Who called?
- A one bed.
Located in sector 13.
- Is anyone aware of before this?
- Yes, they were comrades.
Tráiganme in that bed,
we do not risk it.
"You have nine new messages".
Letto, I am calling
but your never home. Okay, bye.
Do not move!
- Do not pass.
- We ask you to think.
Think well.
Let's talk seriously.
Some must die.
You will be some.
Up! Up!
Shit, they left.
But she has no license.
And what do?
Do we continue?
- Come on.
- No, stay.
- You keep shooting.
- I am.
- What are they filming?
- Shoot, shoot.
Shit!
Do not move,
keep filming!
- And what is this?
- keep shooting.
And what is this?
The license, zoom in on it.
Got it.
Crap,
never seen that.
Come on.
You gotta help me.
It's Damian.
I'm in the basement
Central Police Station.
I'll lay a trap.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can on
count on you.
You gotta help me.
I'm Damien.
I'm in the basement
Central Police Station.
I'll lay a trap.
I need to get out of here.
I know I can count on
you.
What are you doing there?
Hurry!
He disappeared.
I'll keep look.
Hurry! Hurry!
Over here!
There he goes!
We have to get to the other side!
Wait! Wait!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, shit! There he is!
Hurry!
Shit!
Were you shopping?
- No, sir.
- Are you unable to catch ...
... a guy with three
drives you?
The individual is very clever, sir
I had never seen anything like this.
Next time, ask
for lessons.
Back to base, I will go
to see Mr. President.
Yes, sir.
And how are
things over there?
I do not think it takes
to react.
Do not kill the boy on purpose
I guarantee it.
Tried to leave alone.
What is going to happen?
Explain to his mother.
Move!
Right in the middle!
Go, go!
Can I help you?
Can I see the head,
please?
Head, a young man who wants
talk to the manager.
- Do come.
- Come on, come on.
- What is it?
- It is a room, please.
Are you teasing?
This is not a hotel.
Outside says
"hotel of the police."
Get out before they
bother me.
Go, go!
Listen, you better be
locked up because I am a criminal ...
in power ... and if I stay outside,
I do some nonsense.
Have you committed any crime?
No.
Well, you know what? Return to us
when you've committed one.
I'll give you a good cell
Okay?
Okay.
Get down! Get down!
Do not move!
Open the door 14.
You're lucky, only
a room.
- But there is no cover or food.
- What?
What did you expect?
Drop him!
I said drop him!
Security.
Security doors
are blocked.
You take your time.
Want me to return later
when you're in a good mood?
No, okay.
- Good to see you.
- you too.
Out there is shit,
Are you sure you want to leave?
Yes, I have accounts
to fix.
Come on, do you have a plan?
Why not have a plan?
I thought we had come in
so easy, you'll have one.
Sign was not so hard.
Exit will be a little more
complicated.
You are well trained.
Yes, more or less.
Come on, I know a shortcut.
Is this your shortcut?
Run! Run!
Tomaso escaped
his cell.
gone?
No, he is still
on the inside.
- Find it.
- Yes
And fast.
... in the 13 ...
Gentlemen.
Already started?
... of law enforcement ...
and incidents ...
multiply.
Among the wounded are
many officers.
Well, commander,
How can we?
Sector 13
is out of control.
And the risk in the next few hours is that
Nearby areas join him.
The entire country may be
alarm in 24 hours.
Overall, how a military intervention is
still advisable as a preventive measure?
Yet. But the army ...
... is not ready to dp
an internal invasion yet.
Unfortunately, time
is a luxury not available.
Mr. Gazmán,
its recommendation.
When the gangrene spreads,
it need to be cut.
Well, I was not elected because
my tolerance for metaphors.
When I request a recommendation
I want a recommendation.
Well, Mr. President,
I will be more direct.
Evacuate area 13
in twelve hours.
Tomorrow morning we fly across
the place and nobody can go back there.
And there are more advantages.
This will create new jobs.
Building a new
neighborhood full of middle class ...
... which will probably vote
for you in the upcoming elections.
Could not be clearer.
Gentlemen.
That inspires them something?
Politically, such a solution
would be extremely serious.
What is your solution?
Well.
I note that none of you
have any specific proposal ...
do to defend ...
our democracy.
Very interesting.
I remember that our function
first is to protect the French ...
... and look after their interests.
And so do the values of
freedom, equality, and fraternity ...
... is still respected
in this country.
Is somewhat, how do I say?
The foundation of our republic.
And the only proposal that I made
is to exploit the site, a nasty.
Thank you.
Mr. President,
the idea is appalling ...
... but we have priorities.
Perhaps in two hours
the situation becomes uncontrollable.
Perhaps not the best idea,
but believe me ...
... is the least worst.
General ...
... Is that we can evacuate one million
civilians in less than twelve hours?
If you give the order now,
it may be possible.
I suppose that some heads of clans
not so easily be evacuated.
Who will mourn?
General.
Proceed to the evacuation.
We will plan
tomorrow morning.
Mr. Gazmán, I demand that all
the inhabitants of that neighborhood ...
... are treated with respect
and dignity, and that means ...
... all.
I will give the order personally,
Sir.
Now go.
Go there!
Keep looking!
Here we are.
- I thought you were a cop?
- They found drugs in my kitchen.
Di not know you knew to save your stuff?
It was not mine.
It was planted.
A classic.
Police want to fuck
other policemen.
It is not common.
Above all,
I wonder why.
Sure to impedirte
you went somewhere.
You are very sociable.
I do not know.
Surely something is up
they do not want you around.
Super police
are not good for everything.
I had been given a holiday
or I would have thought.
You would go on vacation?
No, of course not.
You know what happens
out there?
What's out there?
There is a recording that offers a
banda sector shot 13 ...
... a patrol.
But there is one in which
Moreover banda police ...
... is what you shoot
the patrol.
And what was in the 13?
May have carried.
And then?
After I gave the second
operates a portion of the building.
It was the police.
But I managed to escape before.
They are not policemen.
They must be criminals
posing as policemen.
Why?
For pleasure?
It is a strategy for
end the sector 13.
And then build on it.
Remember tuition?
All have the same
Registration No: DISS.
DISS dont think so.
What is it?
Internal Division Secret
Security.
Well, that is.
Receive direct orders
President of the Republic.
The head of the DISS
Gazmán is fine.
- Did you know?
- No, not really.
No, I wanted to move there
six months ago and I got refused.
Well, there it is. Have mobile
crime and the offender.
Before we need
evidence.
How about this?
The images are not
sufficient.
Something is necessary
the mind.
- What are you doing?
- Reflecting.
I do not like it when your
thinking.
- We must go to the office of Walter.
- I feared that.
- Where is it?
- First floor, room 17.
Do we do the former?
Okay, the old one.
Can you not be discreet
like me?
You do not mind being discreet.
And now what are you doing?
I'm thinking.
There they are!
I said that I do not like thinking.
Do you have any idea?
I will entertain and you
go to the office of Walter.
Remember, first floor
in room 17.
Bring anything
that can serve as evidence.
Are we seeing again?
I do not think I will be
far from here, quick, go!
Now you'll see!
If you stay well, without saying anything,
nothing will happen.
You have my word, okay?
What is the computer
Mr. Garzo?
know the
password?
Good morning, did some of you
have a computer ...
... that moved?
Yes, me.
Service, im installing the new
server
I regret causing inconvenience.
I found it.
Thanks, gentlemen.
Damian
It is more reasonable and let
justice address your problem.
I did nothing,
and you know it.
Yes, I know. Prisons are
full of innocent people.
However, the morgues.
hey, lets go?
What I do for you.
I already pay.
Do not run!
Shit!
We can still walk, no?
Put the belt.
- What are you doing?
- going forward.
Sorry.
listen.
- Damian escaped.
- How did he escape?
Letto came.
He came to look for Damian
and they escaped.
Can you explain
how they escaped?
Go to your office.
What do we do?
Do we pursue?
No, too, the military
are everywhere.
More attentive
anyway.
Understood.
Follow the instructions
that were given.
And where you lead us?
There is always something
about the law.
Yes, that I was promised change?
There will always be a fool
like you to apply.
There are laws which are bad,
and people that deliver them.
Yeah, like religion.
Incidentally, what's yours?
I was baptized when I was a boy,
but my only goal ...
now ...
is the civil code.
What?
My only goal now
is the civil code.
You're worse than a Mormon.
Well, do we or do we
were to give us?
We're going.
- What do you want?
- Talk with Tao.
About what?
About the sector
and its inhabitants.
Are you kidding.
Business.
Let them pass.
What are you doing here?
We have brought a disk from the internal security
All the contents of this disk is classified state secrets
Are we good.
Well?
They will, provided we
get some things that interest us.
And what is this?
A little catechism.
You've always lived here
in sector 13.
Where do you think will live
when they destroy it?
We must avoid that.
ANIEL, get that.
That's it.
Its open.
- They are everywhere.
- Everywhere.
Where did you learn that?
Well, in books.
Come on, do it.
This interests me.
- We are now on Iran.
- I too am interested.
Here it is, sector 13.
These are the goals,
five towers.
There must be something else.
Walter manages to
is angry with you.
The President ordered their destruction
and build everything new.
- As in Iraq.
- Yes
But now
the French.
And how will they destroy the
towers?
In position.
Three helicopters.
They are up there.
Shoot them with lasers.
They sent the missiles.
How?
Probably
from a command post.
Only the President can
have given an order like that.
And what do what
to prevent it?
Go read the manual.
Because your head ...
... starts to sweat
a little.
Bothers you because I do some
Ambivilent, is it?
I apologize.
If you call "lechuguita"
do you prefer?
- What if you call me by my name?
- Okay.
What is your name?
Damien Tomaso, commander
French army.
A police
if preferred.
Now I believe I should
forget prejudices ...
... and let us hand.
Tao delighted.
Alike.
Now, what is your plan,
lechuguita?
- Thanks for coming.
- What is it?
I'll explain.
Hello.
In there.
Alika, guns.
March specialist
in machetes.
Carlos Skin,
specialist cars.
Montana pumps.
Sorry.
Think you can
take place?
Yes, not to lose the opportunity
to show their skills.
Gentlemen.
Thanks to all
who come.
For 19 hours,
Sector 13 was evacuated.
Their intention is to destroy everything.
If you are in need,
I have everything you need.
The idea is to avoid it.
Who is in favor?
Well, you pass the word a. ..
Damien who ...
will explain his plan.
We all have to agree
in the five hours we have left.
Then I need
of about thirty men.
Trained in combat,
and care nothing about weapons.
We will not hunt.
We broke in silence
the neutralized ...
... and let live
center operations.
Questions?
Where is
the command post?
Here, in the Paris.
Over here, Mr. President.
Strengthen security
around the building.
Go to the signal.
Remain in the air,
Over and out.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Sit down.
So, General,
Where are we?
The order is Jaguards
flying over the targets.
Talked about the evacuation,
rather than destruction.
It is a priority, right?
Yes, sir.
Sir.
We evacuated 1087310
people in less than two hours ...
... but there are people who
We have not been approached.
Its all
located here.
We have tried
and there is already injured.
This could be delayed.
How many people
have not been evacuated yet?
Long time no
a census is done in that neighborhood ...
... but I think
a few thousand.
Those few, are many.
Continue the evacuation.
- We are sent here.
- To us too!
Okay.
Turn both keys
at once.
Five missiles, all
at the same time.
To tell you the truth,
Gentlemen ...
... I do not feel very well
with all this.
- Can I give you some advice?
- Please.
I know that guy
men.
They do not respect anything, not to
people and to the laws.
Just kill and steal
for their benefit.
And you are not
responsible.
They were there before
their arrival.
And what can be
do with them?
Are you?
No.
Believe me, to get rid of them,
they must be exterminated.
Warning!
Mr. Gazmán, find your
cynicism, in terror.
No, Mr. President, just
I am being pragmatic.
One of the causes of our
recession is the parallel economy ...
... with these guys that make you lose
million at the box state.
With destruction
like that ...
... we can build a site
we can make money again.
So we are rid of this scourge
and we can build something more.
Destroy to build,
Is that your solution?
In any case,
thats what comes to mind.
Here.
General.
Is the helicopter assault
already in the air?
Yeah.
Landing.
Do not get this key
in the lock ...
... until it is satisfied that
there is no civil strife in that neighborhood.
- Understand?
- Well, sir.
My General, a banda
entered the building.
Well, neutralize them.
They are unarmed,
but many.
To continue, I occupy.
Go see what happens.
Come, dear.
Montana, he said
no injuries.
It is only
my personal safety.
What?
Do not worry, the building
is heavily equipped.
Calm down.
This is mine.
So?
This is How youprefer?
Listen, you ...
The rules are
adhered to.
But not with guys like you.
We love to know
guys like you.
And these orejitas?
You okay?
No answer.
Te llamo.
Mr. President, I inform you that any
the sector is completely evacuated.
I do not understand, one hour ago
risked ...
... you can not evacuate
those thousands.
I do not know, maybe the message
had not come either.
Anyway, everything is
vacuum, we guarantee it.
In that case.
Get in position.
Received signal,
attack in a minute.
They Are in position,
Sir.
Do not move!
Come on!
We say that ...!
This is the hand you get
in the throat if you do not shut up, okay?
Gentlemen, I am the President
of the Republic.
- On the television.
- I've seen on the Internet.
Captain Tomaso,
Can you explain?
The images speak higher
than words, Mr. President.
- Shoot, shoot.
- And what is that?
I do not know,
but still rolling.
Shit!
What is that?
The DISS in action.
The police wanted to
discredit the sector ...
... to destroy everything
and then build.
It sure will
a commission for that.
If the images
do not meet ...
... behold the disk of
special operations of DISS.
Is it not true, Walter?
We have sent
vacation.
Nobody move!
What are you doing?
Remove the key.
Fast.
Come on!
Remove the key.
Get the key,
do what I say!
What?
I think there will be
new elections.
Come on, let the
artifices, the key!
¡Tomaso not move!
If you move, ill kill you.
Come on, turn it
I tell you the key!
Signal received!
Done!
Come on.
Pare, Gazmán,
not going anywhere.
A soldier goes to
the end of their mission.
Even if that
it costs life.
That is called honor.
It is a notion that it is
strange in their neighborhoods, right?
Yes, it is true, we prefer
another concept: the family.
Which unites us
between us.
Which protects us.
Which we believe.
Yes, will be joining.
I am going to mourn.
And die together.
Come on, just fuck!
And you, where are you?
Calm down, I just a. .. go, was
surely there would be a snuff.
Leave it.
Tomaso ¡!
For my collection.
This is a good wallpaper,
Sir.
A gift.
Gentlemen.
Miss, excuse me.
I do not know what to say.
Thank you, thank you very much.
I owe you much.
I think the whole france
owes much.
Well, I guess you do not believe
much to the politicians but ...
I assure you that ...
the next 48 hours ...
... I will do whatever it can to
unlock the previous laws ...
... for your sector
back to ...
... all his dignity and a place
prominent in our society.
Thank you.
- I have a question, Mr. President.
- Tell me.
Instead of spending a fortune
hiding the rotten ...
... Why not
start again?
What do you mean?
A real neighborhood.
A real city.
With green
and places to work.
I agree.
Damian, appoint him responsible for
this project through implementation.
Well, Mr. President.
You have my word, and
as the word of my government.
And the word of man?
And my word of man.
Sir?
- It's OK for me.
- Me too.
Too.
Clear.
Yes
Well.
Well, that's better
que las mías.
Everything is for the better.