I thought this time you'd
be captured...
or that I'd lose you.
To whom?
Roma?
The disc which you gave the police?!
It's a fake.
There was nothing in it.
Don't worry sweetheart...
Now I rule over the Asian underworld
I am the King!
It's been five years since that day.
And I... Don... rule over the
Asian drug trade.
The King.
Now my target is Europe.
The European drug cartel is aware that...
I will takeover their market
by undercutting the prices.
Once I establish my presence in Europe...
they will be out of business.
You speak to me like that again...
I will have my man here slit your throat!
How dare you speak to me...
I speak the way I want.
Gentlemen...
gents...
This is Jimmy Coogan...
this cartel's boss.
He has brought everyone together...
so that they can set
aside their personal issues...
and decide about my fate.
All those in favour of killing Don?
Very well then!
I learnt about this meeting
a little late.
Every heart is beating fast
Guess who is here
Don.
Jaruwan says he is grateful
to see you at his door again.
I'm not here for Jaruwan's door...
but for my consignment.
There goes your consignment.
Damn!
Now I'll have to drive the boat.
You aren't going anywhere, Don.
What brings about this hospitality?
Jimmy Coogan.
If we want to enter the
drug trade in Europe...
your life is our ticket.
And I guess he is the ticket collector.
Hello big boy!
Any last wish?
Which restaurant in Bangkok
serves the best Italian meal?
Meaning?
Well, after killing all of you, I was
hoping to go for a good Italian dinner.
You know, spaghetti bolognese,
a glass of red wine...
No?
What?
Nobody likes Italian?
What a shame!
Shoot him!
Quick! After him!
See you around.
Good evening!
Hi Roma!IHi!
Is this the file I'd asked for?!
YeslT hanks.
It's him!
Any plans for tonight?!
Nothing, why?
Because it's your birthday.
We should celebrate.
My birthday?
It's not my birthday today, Arjun.
I know.
Actually it's my birthday.
Oh my God! I'm so sorry...
I completely forgot!
Happy birthday, Arjun.
Thanks.
Just a second.
Hello...
I'll be right there.
Okay.
Happy birthday!
Thank you.
You wanted to see me, sir?!
Yes.
Have a seat.
Roma, do you know how long
I've served in this department?
37 years.
And in these 37 years
I've worked on 186 cases.
I've worked with
very brave and able officers.
But I know I'll miss you the most.
I'm sorry, sir?
I'm retiring, Romal
What?
Yes.
I wanted to tell you myself.
Come on, I'm not dying!
Come...
walk me to my car.
Sir... you could reconsider your decision...
I don't want tol
What about Don?
He is the only one who got away!
He is your responsibility now.
And I know you will do it.
Good evening, Mr. Malik.
Don?
Put your hands up!
Up where I can see them.
Take it easy guys...
Down on your knees!
Really? I'm wearing white!
Shut up and get down on your knees.
I am very happy to see you too,
my wild cat.
Watch it!
Why is every one so angry?
Absolute immunity.
Drop all charges against me.
In Malaysia and in every country
where there's a warrant out for me.
You're a wanted man in every country!
How can I convince them all?!
Really?
My mother would've been
so proud to hear that.
Proud?
She would've shot you herself!
Mr. Malik, you didn't know my mother.
Immunity or nothing!
Don, that's impossible!
I could probably save you
from the death penalty.
That's all!
The names of my clients,
my suppliers, every one involved...
for all that information and evidence...
your offer is quite small, Mr. Malik.
Do something about it.
You know...
Make me an offer I can't refuse.
Okay.
If you don't cooperate with us...
Believe me, along with the prison term,
you'll also get the death penalty.
We all die, Mr. Malik.
Perhaps going to jail now
will be to my advantage.
I've waited far too long for this day.
How does it feel...
to be in prison?
Yeah, it's okay.
I'm unhappy with the
uniform colour...
But you don't look happy either.
What is it?
Your unexpected change of heart...
why are you putting on this act?
In this trade, when people covet
your death more than your life...
it's understood that
it's time to move on.
I figured I'd do something
good along the way but...
you people didn't give me a chance.
Very sad!
Had we given you that chance,
you would've provided us
with the actual information...
Isn't that right'?!
Yeah, that's right.
I've lied to you once before...
and I didn't like itl
Shut up!
For once, I wanted to
see you behind bars...
and now I have.
So goodbye, Don!
If you let me live,
it would be your biggest mistake.
Welcome to hell, Don.
Shower 14's drain is clogged.
Inform housekeeping.
Still upset?
I'm here to offer my friendship.
Let go of the past!
Let go of what?
I've been trapped in this cage
for five years thanks to you!
You're here because of your
ego, Vardhaan.
You don't know how to change with
time and circumstance.
Come on!
Get up!
If you know,
then what are you doing here?
I've come here for you, Vardhaan.
With an offer.
Well, I have an offer too.
How about I cut you to pieces and
feed you to the dogs in here?
That will benefit neither you nor me,
Vardhaan.
Only the dogs!
And I hate dogs!
I'm on death row, Vardhaan.
Whether you kill me now
or the law does in two weeks...
it's all the same.
Think, Vardhaan!
I could have surrendered
myself in any country...
yet I chose this one.
Though I know you are here,
eager to kill me.
Don!
Get out of here!
All of you... out!
Go on...
I've come to help you escape.
In exchange for'?
You'll know when the time is right.
No, no...
You will tell me right now!
All you need to do right now is to decide
whether you want to escape or not...
If this is another of your tricks...
Trust me, no tricks.
What do I have to do'?
Good.
Two days later, the kitchen supplies
are going to be delivered.
You see him?
I want that janitor's duty.
Pronto.
Okay, but... I
Do it, pleaselOkay.
Now what?
Now we wait till Saturday.
Why'? What happens on Saturday?
My attorney will pay me a visit.
Any more questions?!
Yes, one more. May I ask?
No! Got your answer?
Good night.
Tonight we get out of here...
you ready?
Oh yes!
Hey, you want to eat my food?
You don't want'?
Hate fish!
Help!
He's dying, we need help here.
He's dyillQ
Thank you...
My friend is very sick.
Hi...
Hi.
Hope I'm not disturbing you?
No, not at all.
Are those for me?
Yeah!
Thanks.
Come in!
Who is this?
My brother...
Ramesh.
Your brother...
Where is he?
He's dead.
I am sorry.
That's okay.
Roma, remember
you once told me that...
you didn't want to think about anything
else till Don was arrested?
I do.
Well now the situation is...
that your phone is ringing yet again.
I am sorry... just a second...
Hello?
When?
Mesmerising and alluring
Is his magic
He whose eyes are stars
He who is adorned with diamonds
0 heart, is it true?
O tell me
He is here
Hold on to your heart,
say it out loud
Guess who it is
He is here, once again
Don
I'm the mystery that no one gets
My moves are above everyone else
I'm deeper than the ocean
never standing still
I'm denser than smoke
that never stops rising
Hold on to your heart,
say it out loud
Guess who it is
He is here, once again
Don
You aren't like smoke,
you are the flame
If I come closer to you,
I'll burn and die
If it's me you desire,
what else will you get?
Where do I go next,
even I don't have a clue
Hold on to your heart,
say it out loud
Guess who it is
He is here, once again
Don
Here! Now this is what
I want from you.
There's a safety deposit box in
Zurich's Russian Commercial bank...
that belonged to your ex-boss, Boris.
He gave one of the set of keys to you and
the other to your partner, Singhania.
I have one key, thanks to you.
Come to think of it, if you had
taken the key from Singhania...
either before poisoning him or even after,
it would've been to your advantage.
What's in that box?
You will know when we open it.
Where is the key, Vardhaan'?
Zurich Airport.
Baggage locker number 1-3-5.
Combination lock number 5-4-8-1-7.
Got it.
Sweetheart,
take the next flight out to Zurich.
We'll see you there in two days.
You trust this girl completely?
Ayesha.
Sorry?
Ayesha, my name.
You were saying...
I was wondering if a girl like you should
do something as dangerous as this!
I'm not just a pretty face,
Mr. Vardhaan.
I have a lot of other skills too.
See you in Zurich.
See ya.
Welcome to Zurich.
Know him'?
Fabian Kohl.
President of the German
Deutsch Zentral Bank.
Inﬂuential, powerful and
respected by all.
Not many know that the position
he has occupied for the past 8 years...
was meant for someone elsel
Who?
When the committee was setup to
choose the bank's president...
their first choice wasn't Kohl
but someone else.
James Werden.
So why didn't the
committee elect Werden?
Werden was killed in a car accident.
Kohl was behind that accident.
Guess who helped him'?
Singhania'?
That's right, Vardhaan!
But Kohl's messenger wasn't aware that...
Singhania had recorded
their meeting in this tape.
Are we going to blackmail Kohl?
Yes and no.
I will blackmail Kohl...
through the bank's vice-president,
J. K. Diwan.
The vice-president of DZB is an Indian?
Well sweetheart,
we are everywhere.
Why don't we deal with Kohl directly?
A minister is more concerned about
power than the king himself.
Kohl's messenger to Singhania
was none other than Diwan.
What's on your mind?
DZB has its currency centre here in Berlin.
And that is where they print the
50 and 100 Euro bills.
How much are we demanding?
I don't want the money!I
Then what?
I want the printing plates!
Why on earth would Diwan
give us those plates?
Blackmail or no blackmail,
he will be finished, right?
Right!
Therefore it's important to keep
Fabian Kohl and Diwan out of the picture.
But how?
With Diwan's help I'll break
into the currency centre.
Even if you do steal the plates,
it's no big deal to make new ones.
Of course it's no big deal, sweetheart.
But new bills don't make
old ones worthless.
By the time the bank
replaces every old bill...
it will be years.
By then... how should I say this...
we will be...
billionaires!
Yes sir?IRoma, I just had a word
with German Interpol.
Vardhaan and Don
were spotted in Zurich.
Don and Vardhaan'?
What were they doing together?
That's what we need to find out.
The car they were travelling in
was found at a lonely spot in Berlin...
Leave for Berlin immediately!
Right away, sir.
I have spoken with the Director
of Intelligence, Klaus Wetland.
He is attending a charity
fundraiser tomorrow. -Right.
He'll meet you there. All the best!
Okay, sir. Thank you!
Excuse me, gentlemen...
Mr. Wetland?
Roma Bhagat.
Detective Malik may have
spoken to you about melYes, he did.
This is Detective Jens Berkel.
He will be working the case with you.
Nice to meet youl
Pleased to meet you.
Detective Malik wanted me to
personally thank you for all your help.
Tell Malik, he owes me one.
Big time!
I will, sir.
Good evening ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you all for
being here with us today...
and putting your heart
ahead of your wallet.
Would you please join me
to welcome here today...
our esteemed guest of honour...
the Vice President of the DZB...
Mr. J.K. Diwan.
We raise our glasses to your health.
Cheers!
Thank you ladies and gentlemen.
Enjoy the rest of the evening.
Thank you.
What happened?
That man...
I don't know why but
I feel like I know him.
Only if he didn't look like he did...
lam sure...
Find him, Arjun.
It is extremely important because
if it wasn't for your support...
we would never be able
to raise any funds.
Your phone is ringing.
My phone'? - Yeah.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Congratulations on the new phone,
Diwan.
The inbox has a video clip
which I'm sure you'll find interesting.
I suggest you see it alone...
or it could prove embarrassing.
I kept my word.
Now it's your turn.
Once Mr Werden
is elected as president...
it will be difficult to make our move.
Don't worry, it will be done.
I told you it was interesting
Apart from this clip,
I also have a bank document.
It states that a million
dollars were transferred...
to Singhania's Swiss bank account.
Singhania? I don't know any... I
Signed by you!
It is your good fortune that
I am a nice guy.
What I want is no big deal for you.
There's a black car outside,
registration number BIU 103.
You have...
two minutes.
Who are you?
Don?
No autographs please!
Damn it! Get the car!
You are crazy!
Do you have any idea
what you're asking for?
Of course.
I want the information that will help me
get inside the underground
vault of the DZB.
Listen... if you want money...
please just name your amount,
you will get it.
What you're asking for is impossible.
Would you and Fabian Kohl rather spend
the rest of your lives in prison?
The details of what I want
are on the phone.
And Diwan...
You have 24 hours.
Roma! There!
I see you... my wild cat.
Don!
If I'm caught with you... IRelax Diwan.
It is not just difficult to catch Don...
It's impossible!
Are you alright?
Everybody okay?
Step aside sir.
Police business.
Step away from the car!
It's my car...
Get out! Please!
Got any money?
There he is.
Times up, sorry Roma.
See you soon.
Hello.
A moment please sir.
Sorry, I have to go.
This will destroy us.
Do what ever you have to do Diwan.
I don't want to hear about that man,
Don, ever again.
Is that understood?
So Mr. Diwan...
how can Abdul Jabbar
be of assistance?
I've heard you are a useful man.
You've heard right.
What's the job?
You know of Don, of course?
Hmm...
He is in Berlin right now.
I want you to trace him down and...
you know...
Why'?
Why do you want him killed,
Mr. Diwan?
You need reason or money?
Now you're talking!
Five million Euro.
Half now and...
the rest when I hand you his head.
That's not necessary.
I want it done.
As soon as possible!
Vardhaan!
Now do you see why
we never get along?
It would be better if instead
of watching cartoons...
you were thinking about
the security at the DZB.
Really?
Even if Diwan does help...
stealing those plates from the DZB
won't be a cakewalk.
I know, Vardhaan.
We need a computer hacker to control
the building's security system.
My remote, please.
Thank you!
But who?
All our useful men are
either in prison or...
on the FBI and Interpol watch list.
Relax Vardhaan.
I know just the guy for this task.
Hey! Watch out!I
Are you crazy?
Sorry!
Thank you for coming, Sameer.
Not at all, sir, please... I mean...
I had to see for myself that
it really was you who called.
I'm just a big fan, sirl
Sir?
That sounds too 'honest'.
Call me Don.
I have a job for you.
The security system at the
DZB's currency centre...
is controlled by a master computer.
I want you to hack into this computer...
so that it's under my control.
I'm really sorry sir... Don.
I don't think I can do itl
Really?
Is it the Sameer Ali who at 17 hacked
into the Tokyo Stock Exchange and...
stole 1.4 million dollars?
And then donated it anonymously
to 'Save the Oceans' foundation.
There's nothing to prove that I did it.
And if there's no evidence,
you aren't guilty.
Isn't that right?
Touché!
You've been quite low key
the past three years.
I'm sure love has something to do with it.
Actually tell me... I like love stories.
She is a...
she's very special.
I am sure she is.
But so is your talent.
It would be a shame
not to put it to use at right time.
I can't.
I promised Yana that
I won't do anything illegal.
If there's no evidence,
you aren't guilty, right'?
Hey...
where were you?
I had the interview, remember?
Oh yeah, how did it go?
I got the job, Yana.
That's great, Sam.
How are you feeling?
I feel good.
A little bit tired... but good.
He's not troubling you too much, is he?
No. He's very well behaved.
At 1:18pm
there are two people in the car.
Exactly 6 minutes later...
Here, look carefully.
Only one!
That means the passenger got off...
somewhere between Tiergarten Strasse...
and 17th Juli Strasse.
Probably someone saw
him get out of the car.
Possible.
I'll talk to Berkel.
If there's a witness,
we'll find him.
Hello...
Diwan, I'm sure you are
impressed by my punctuality.
So, what have you decided?
I'm willing to give you what you want.
Good.
Tomorrow morning at 8,
outside the Berlin Cathedral.
Now what?
You will do exactly as he wants you to.
What do you mean?
I can't give him that information!
Who said it has to be real'?
By the time Don figures it out...
He will be dead, Mr. Diwan.
Hello?
A sightseeing bus
is approaching from your left.
I see it.
It will stop in front of you.
Come to the upper deck!
Let's go.
Everything you've asked for
is in these discs.
The blueprints of the currency centre,
security protocols and...
all codes to access the building.
What about the safe
containing the plates?
That safe is in the underground vault.
It can only be opened by a passkey...
which is in the custody of the centre's
chief technician, Dr. Schneider.
Anything else?
Apart from the passkey,
the safe also requires...
Dr. Schneider's fingerprints
and voice match.
Look honestly,
you've got to trust me.
I'm telling you the truth.
You have beautiful eyes...
I trust you.
Keep this phone on you.
You have a reservation
at the Hotel de Rome.
Stay there until my next call.
But what about the tape
and documents?
Relax Diwan.
You'll get what you deserve.
Take the stairs.
Karl, you stay herel
Yeah.
You!
Jabbar...
Don may not keep
in touch with his friends...
but he always checks on his enemies.
Someone is following you, sir.
Thanks, Sameer.
You want this, right?
No, Don.
I want to kill you.
We seem to have a problem.
You see...
I prefer to stay alive.
I think you'll have
to change your intention.
I suggest you join with me.
Whatever money
Diwan has promised you...
I'll give you three times more.
Think about it.
I don't want to put you...
under any pressure!
We found someone.
That's great!
Someone at the station
has identified Don's car.
And he also got a good look
at the person who got out.
Super! Where is he'?
He's with the sketch artist.
Okay, let me know
when the sketch is complete.
Alright then.
Arjun!
Good job.
Thanks.
Don...
Including Jabbar in our plan
was a big mistake.
Really?
- Really.
Have you forgotten that
he was hired to kill you?
Don's enemies should always remember
that Don never forgets.
As for my mistake...
this Abdul Jabbar will be our ticket
to escape from DZB.
Meaning'?
- I mean...
My plan to get us out of the building...
will be a success only if...
we sacrifice Abdul Jabbar and his goons.
Hello sweetheart!
Hello.
Is he dead?
No, but you are!
Don?
Diwan, being stupid enough
to give me blank discs is one thing...
but to hire assassins to kill me...
now that will be your downfall.
Please Don!
Don please...
Please forgive me!
I'm sorry I screwed up.
I'll give you what you want.
Anything you ask of me!
Where is the information I want'?
I have it with me, Don.
It's with me.
Open the door.
Knock knock...
Sir, did you order room service?
Say 'yes'.
Yes, I...
I ordered room service.
But you...
Give her the information.
I have got it.
As a penalty you'll have to do
another thing for me, Diwan.
Wait...
Wait for my call.
That's him.
I've seen him before...
Where...
He was at the charity fund raiser...
his name...
the guest of honour...
J. K. Diwan.
That's it!
The Vice-President of the DZB.
Isn't it?
Yeah, you are right.
But... what was he doing
in the car with Don?
That's what we have to find out!
Okay!
This building has state of the art security!
But obviously that's not news to you.
Can you control their computers or not?
Since you have put your trust in me,
I can't let you down.
I can control everything
except the underground vault.
What about the vault?
The vault isn't linked
to the master computer.
It's controls are in the vault's
enclosure.
The electric supply to the vault
is from a remote source.
Okay, we'll deal with that.
We'll figure the vault from the inside.
Sir...
Yeah?
You see...
I don't mean to demoralise anyone but...
we should realise
what we're up against.
As soon as you enter DZB
is the first security check point...
metal detectors, baggage x-ray.
A little ahead is the lobby
with CCTV cameras all over and...
these are monitored round the clock by
security guards in the surveillance room.
There's a door to enter the vault...
which can be opened by a password.
The stairs inside lead
to the underground vault.
At the foot is a metal gate manned
by two security guards.
If you manage to get past them...
you'll reach the first
entrance to the printing chamber.
The security guards will
have the key to that.
The real problem lies ahead.
The main vault.
It is a sold steel chamber.
The emergency procedure is to lock
the door and smash the controls.
I mean, it's impossible to get
through it.
Fine, we'll blow it up.
No way, sir. Please don't even
think of thatlWhy not?
Because there are two things that
will happen if you try to blow it open.
First...
a chemical gas will release
into the chamber.
The gas isn't lethal but it can knock
a person out for 12 hours.
The second thing?
The vault door and the safe are separated
by a 20 foot long passage.
Now the floor of this passage
is installed with a security system...
that is activated by even
the slightest pressure.
What happens if the system is activated?
I don't know, sir.
But if I were you,
I wouldn't even breathe
Karl, Jabbar and his team
of five will wait here.
Two of you go up and wait for us
on the fifth floor by this window.
Jabbar...
explosives, guns,
ammunition are your domain.
There is no night
And no day here
Is it the darkness
This is Dr. Schneider.
I want his finger prints.
The eyes are betrayed
but nobody knows
Wonder what is here and isn't
Good afternoon,
this is Detective Baruah from Interpol.
May I speak with Dr. Schneider please?
Good afternoon.
- Dr. Schneider?
Yes, I am Diedrich Schneider!
Thank you.
There are many fake ones
like this out on the street.
Could I have the test results by say,
Tuesday?
You could get it by tomorrow,
if you wantlNo, Tuesday is just fine.
Thank you, Dr. Schneider.
Here you gol
Thank you so much.
The eyes are betrayed
but nobody knows
I am Diedrich Schneider.
Wonder what is here and isn't
All an illusion
The eyes are betrayed
but nobody knows
Wonder what is here and isn't
All an illusion
Don?
How do we escape from DZB'?
Here... in the basement...
is the service exit.
Ayesha will wait for us in a police van.
We will escape in that van,
smooth and easy.
That's it?
Yeah, that's it...
You've thought of something better?
No'?
I thought so.
Then I guess we'll have
to make do with my plan.
Hello...
Diwan...
tomorrow at 3...
behind the Paul Loebe house.
And please...
be on time, Diwan.
Nothing can stop me now!
I know Don.
He can sacrifice you...
me or anyone else for his own gain.
Me or anyone else for his own gain.
Is that so?
Then what are you doing with him?
I...
wanted to figure his plan.
I won't make the mistake
of trusting him again.
And quite frankly Jabbar...
neither should you.
Why not?
Don's exit plan says...
you won't get out alive.
He won't leave this place alive!
Jabbar, calm down.
Not now, Jabbar.
Once we have the plates.
I must say Don's plan is pretty good.
Imagine, once we have the plates...
it will be raining money!
What about Don'?
By the time the cops
find Don's corpse...
we would've escaped
through the service exit.
We would've escaped
That's it
The sketch does look like
J.K. Diwan...
But it is also a fact that we are
relying only on one man's memory.
I know sir...
but I think he is right.
Alright, fix an appointment with himl
Thank you, sir.
Roma...
- Yes sir?
Do remember that J.K. Diwan
is a very important person.
So, word your questions delicately.
I understand, sir.
Hello?
Sorry you had to wait but I need to
reschedule our meeting.
Go to DZB and wait for my call.
Hello.
How was the drive?
Lots of traffic but it was fine.
I'm sorry.
Hello DZB.
Now what?
Now, we record.
Good Morning Mr Diwan.
Here we go!
Sameer, can you hear me?
Yes, Don! Loud and clear.
Cameras... now!
Copy that.
I'm switching the live video
with the recording.
Hello.
- Good afternoon, sir.
I'm here for my appointment with
Dr. Schneider, please.
He is expecting you.
Good day! Interpol.
Oh shit!
Yes?
Whatever you do,
don't turn around.
Who is it'?
Interpol officers Roma and Berkel...
get out of there!
Thank you.
He will see you now on the fourth floor.
Thank you very much.
Good day!
Yes, Patricia?
Good afternoon, sir.
There are some officers here
from the Interpol to meet you.
Send them up please...
in 15 minutes.
I have the results of the analysis
on the counterfeit bill you gave me.
Altogether...
there are 7 points
which confirm that it is a fake.
There are 7 points
If you see the bluring
in the corner of the ink.
The third point which clearly confirms
that we are holding a fake note
in our hands is the microprint.
You see here the real one...
here's the fake one.
In the real note the microprint...
You'll come across a ladder to your left.
Above that is the elevator shaft
ventilation duct.
Excuse me...
Mr. Diwan will meet you now.
I hope it crashes after I get off!
Bye.
Package 1 in position.
Sam, stop the elevator
when I tell you to.
NOW!
Sir button...
The doorman at your
apartment block told us that...
on the 15th you left your
apartment at 11 in the morning...
and returned at half past two.
Is that right'?
The 15th
let me see...
Victor, where were we on the 15th?
Mrs. Bergman's fundraiser, sir.
And what time did we return home?
1:30 pm, sirlT hank you.
I think the doorman's
memory is off by an hour.
Victor maintains a record of
my every activity.
And if he is saying I came home at 1:30,
then that's the truth.
Of course.
Thank you.
No, not at all.
You are most welcome.
If I can help you in any way...
please don't hesitate
in getting touch with me.
As you can see here
and on this fake one and as you see...
it is the less obvious point...
if it comes to faking a note.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Boom!
We have to get you out right now,sir!
Lock the vault immediately.
No idea where it came from...
Shut up!
Let me make some calls
and find out what's going on.
Why are the gates being shut'?
Let's go.
Okay.
Open the gate.
We are in the vault.
Get the hostages!
Sam, it's too bright in here.
Do something, will you?!
Copy that.
Lights.
Emergency lights activated.
You don't understand!
I am answerable to the
German government and its people.
Please, I must stay!
Hello?
Good evening, Mr. Malik.
Don?
It's Don!
I'd like to speak with Roma, please.
How do you know...
Oh my God!
God won't come here, Mr. Malik.
He is in the building.
Let me talk to Roma.
He wants to talk to you.
Hello?
Roma, Roma...
you aren't giving up, are you?
People might think you still love me.
What do you want?
I'd like to give you a last chance.
I want you to drop
all charges against me.
You've already seen one explosion.
I can set off other
explosions around the building.
And seeing you so close
to me is suffocating me.
So everybody...
move back a little please!
What is he saying?
If we don't move our men back...
he is going to detonate another
explosive.
He's bluffingl.
- No, I am not.
Roma, tell Commissioner Mueller to take
a look at the fire truck in front of him.
In 30 seconds it'll blow up.
Damn it!
Move all your men back,
we have only 30 seconds.
What?
Hello...
is it me you're looking for...
What do you want?!
My wild cat...
Anybody comes within
100 feet of this building and...
I'll set off more explosions.
Understood?!
Yes.
I'm watching all of you,
especially you...
so no tricks please. And get this
damn helicopter to buzz off!
It's spoiling the mood, sweetheart.
Don!
Damn it!
The cops are going to be busy
deciding their next strategy.
Are all our men in position?IYes.
And the bombs'? - They're ready.
Exactly where you wanted them.
Very good.
Let's get to work.
The gas will be effective
in the chamber for 3 minutes.
I leave the rest to you.
Sam, password?
83675U9
Alarm activated.
Come on!
Get out of there.
That was close!
- Yeah!
Where are the plates?!
You think I'd leave without them?
All good. Pass me the bag please.
Thank you.
Sam'?
Yes?
Time to go!IGot it.
I told you I will never forget
what you did to me.
Even so you trusted me.
Plates, please...
Bag.
Not very smart, are you?
You wanted to leave me
behind to die, huh?
Death will come, Don.
Not for me...
But you!
Jabbar, if you kill me
how do you plan on escaping?
What do you mean?ll mean...
There is neither a service exit
in the basement...
...nor is Ayesha waiting
in a police van.
You see... I didn't have an
escape plan for you at all.
Jabbar! That's a lie!
How did he plan on getting away
if he didn't have an escape plan?
Vardhaan...
Perhaps you weren't paying attention.
I didn't have an
escape plan for 'you'.
You think you can getaway from us?
Remember, Sameer said he couldn't
control the electric supply in the vault?
He was lying.
Hey!
What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Karl? Karl? What's going on'?
Shocking behaviour, dude!
Find Don! Go!
Perfect timing, Sam.
- Thanks.
See you outside. Switching off.
Good day.
- Good day.
Could you deliver this urgently.
Hello, Officer...
Listen to me very carefully.
So, ready to go.
Yeah...
Ready.
Thanks.
Drop the gun.
I said drop the gun!
Hands on your head!
You are under arrest, Don!
You got mell did.
Cuffs.
Hands behind you.
Ooh... kinky!
Glad you like it.
Because they aren't coming off!
It's over, Don.
Where are your partners?!
You may search my pockets.
Where are they?
They aren't my partners... any more,
Mr. Malik.
What do you mean?ll mean...
Vardhaan controls them now, not me.
Vardhaan is in the building?
Vardhaan, Abdul Jabbar and his goons.
They are a dangerous bunch...
Be careful.
Come on.
So you let your heart
overcome your mind.
Very sad.
It was a momentary lapse
of judgment but...
I realised I'm not like youl
You definitely are not!
I have a long life ahead of me...
Whereas you and Yana
don't have a future.
Stop it! Take him away!
Slay!
I'd like to speak to the
officer-in-charge.
Vardhaan...
It's coming from inside
the building, sir.
Give it to me.
Detective Malik here.
Hello Malik'?
Vardhaan.
You better surrender, Vardhaan.
Why'?
I have 25 of DZB's staff as hostages...
And you know I won't hesitate
in killing them.
You are already in a mess,
don't try anything stupid.
No, no...
You'll be stupid to ignore my words.
In two hours I need a helicopter
that will take us to the airport.
And I need a plane waiting for us.
When we reach our destination,
I will set the hostages free.
Is that clear, Malik'?
That's not possible.
Really?
Jabbar!
Vardhaan!
You hear that?
If firing into air can have that effect...
Imagine if I had to shoot one of them.
Two hours.
Do you know
how Don exited the building?
No, really sorry. I was in touch with him
till he got out of the vault.
What was he doing in the vault?
So Sameer confessed everything?
Answer me... Where are the plates?
Vardhaan has the plates.
How did you get out of the building?
Answer my question, Don!I
Why should I tell you?
The hostages could die because of you.
I regret this is happening,
Mr. Malik.
But if you want my help,
then I want something in return too.
You are in no position to negotiate.
Well in that case...
I'd like to talk to Mr. Diwan.
Why'?
I think he will empathize with me.
It's quite simple.
If I go to prison,
so do you and Fabian Kohl.
Look you can't...
Please look... Look we had a deal.
I gave you everything you asked for!
Trust me, this is my last request.
Promise.
He will help us.
Mr. Diwan has promised me immunity
here in Germany.
For some reason, I trust him.
In return, I'll help diffuse the bombs
and free the hostages.
What about the plates?
Don't worry.
You'll get the plates back.
Roma...
What?
I want you to believe that
this change of heart isn't an act...
and as a show of good faith,
I'm ready to deliver the discs to you...
...which will put an end to the
drug trade in Europe and Asia.
Really?
Roma, strange isn't it?
Once again life has brought us together.
You and I can never be together.
You never know.
Perhaps someday you'll realise that I'm
no longer the same Don that you despise
Though a dog may straighten its tail,
it is still a dog.
No wonder I can't let go of you,
my wild cat.
What? Are you going to shoot me'?
Don't tempt me.
Let's go.
Roma, please...
do you really need to do this?
Yes, I do!
- Why'?
The S.E.K unit can do the job... I
Will you just relax?
Stay with Mr. Malik, got it'?
If anything happens to her, I will...
You will... What'?
Your team is very concerned
about each other.
Sweet!
Gentlemen... enjoy the swim.
Where's Don?
- Forget him!
If he wants to live,
he won't come back.
Okay, which way now?
Follow me.
So, what's the deal
between you and... Arjun?
It doesn't concern you.
Thought we'd catch up.
Is that wrong?
You? Besides yourself, you are incapable
of thinking about anything.
And you.
You guys take cover
behind the door.
Herman, go.
Roma.
What?
When I said, I was ready
to give the police the disc...
How did you feel?
Your words no longer
have an effect on me.
I know... but still you were surprised.
Roma, the fact is I'm tired of my life.
Now I loathe people like
Vardhaan and Coogan.
I want to be free from them
and the law.
I want to be a free man.
Please...
Forgive me, Roma.
Come on, we are clear.
Wait Roma.
There are security cameras outside.
Jabbar's goons can monitor
everything in the surveillance room.
This was your brilliant plan?
I had planted one bomb
in the there so that...
...we could destroy
all evidence as we escape.
Karl!
Check where the blast happened.
All positions... report in.
Position 1, all clear!
Position 2, all clear.
Position 3 come in...
Position 3'?
Ladies first.
No reply from the
surveillance room, Jabbar.
Don!
Karl...
Bring me his head.
Ulrich! Sven!
Sven and Ulrich are dead.
You're welcome.
You are shot.
Merely grazed me.
Sorry.
- You okay?
We're good.
Stay down.
I'm going to check on the others.
May I ask you something?
Yeah.
What's the deal between you
and Arjun?
He likes you.
It's not difficult to understand
why he likes you.
And you...
Do you like him'?
I don't need to answer anything.
You know what I think?
You don't like him...
...because you still love me.
I don't love you.
Just checking!
Herman's dead.
And the bomb is still armed.
Karl, can you hear me?
Karl, come in...
Ulrich... come in... God Damn it!
Something is wrong.
Jabbar... detonate the bombs.
Let them know how it feels
to mess with us!
Try the other one!
It's not working...
Jabbar...
Let her go, please!
Please don't kill her!
Malik!
If the helicopter isn't here in 5 minutes.
This poor woman will lose her life.
Vardhaan...
2 hours aren't up yet.
20 minutes to go.
You're lying, Malik.
When I throw this woman's body
out of the window...
...you'll know we weren't lying.
Jabbar, don't!
The police didn't betray you, I did.
Let the woman go.
I'm coming there.
Vardhaan, the helicopter
has left the airbase.
It will be here in ten minutes.
Trust me! If you shoot,
I won't be able to help you.
Ten minutes, Malik!
Don...
Come here right now!
Just a second.
Philip needs medical help.
I think you should stay with him.
I'm going with Don, okay?!
Good luck.
Thanks.
Roma, what are you doing?
It's not safe for you.
That woman needs me.
But it's too dangerous.
Vardhaan and Jabbar can't be trusted.
It's my duty to get those hostages out.
So, come on..
Try to understand, Roma!
If something were to happen to you...
I'm coming with you.
That's it. Let's go.
Well, well, well!
What a happy reunion!
Hello, Roma.
Your weapons on the floor.
I mean really!
Do I need to spell it out?
Please remove your bullet proof vest.
Vardhaan, the police is giving you
everything you asked for.
In return, at least let the women go.
No, not a chance.
I've realised that women are...
more useful in these situations.
If we must let someone go...
Let it be Don.
Sorry?
- Don't be!
I want to kill Don and so does Jabbar.
And I'm sure you won't regret
if he is killed. Right?
Right?
Give her the gun.
Good.
Now...
...kill him.
Amazing!
Now I've seen it all.
You seem to have cast
a spell on her, Don. SCRATCH
Anyway...
Let's try again. Jabbar!
If she doesn't shoot Don
by the time I count three...
Shoot her!
One...
Pull the trigger, Roma.
Two...
Shoot me, Roma!
Three!
- Do it!
So, both of you were under a spell.
You're next, Don.
Vardhaan, you seem to forget something.
What's that?
Before Don's enemy
can make his first move...
Don has made his next move!
Is everybody okay?
- Thank you!
No. Not yet.
Stay right there! Please!
Mr. Malik'?
Malik here.
Mr. Malik, Jabbar is dead.
And you won't have any issue...
...in taking Vardhaan back to prison.
The plates and hostages are with me.
So now...
I hope you have the papers
for my immunity.
We have the papers!
Very good, Mr. Malik.
Send them in...
With Sameer!
Sameer? ll want to see that
traitor one last time.
She's alive.
Bring the file here.
Let him go! Now!
You better find a safe hiding place.
Because the day I find you...
you'll be dead!
You know where I live,
drop in any time.
Of course! I know where you live.
Drop the weapon. Right now!
That's him.
What happened to Roma?
Yours I believe...
Do take care of her.
Here! Hurry!
Gentlemen...
is there anything else I can do for you?!
Where is the disc?
In the bag with the plates.
Can I leave now?
Once I check the disc... I
Of course.
And how long will that take?
Take him away!
Good night, everyone.
Thank you.
Check this out!
What about these plates,
Mr. Diwan?
I'll take them.
They need to be checked for damages.
Is it good?IGood?
It's priceless, Mr. Malik.
You want Mr Kohl to become president,
he will be the president.
That's my responsibility, Mr. Diwan.
Oh my God!
Remember I said
Don's enemies should always remember
that Don never forgets.
The people who wanted to get rid of me,
are themselves in the docks now.
Jimmy Coogan, you are under arrest.
Jimmy Coogan and all his ilk.
The police had to accept that it was
because of my help that
Fabian Kohl was exposed.
Vardhaan got back
to where he belonged.
Now to take care of one last thing.
Yes?
- Package for Mr. Ali'?
Yes, that's mel
Please sign here, sir.
Here you go.
Thanks
- Bye.
Hello?
Don.
I sent you a present.
I hope you like it.
I missed you sweetheart.
Where is he?
He's right here.
When I get out of the DZB,
hand me over to the police.
Sorry?
Don't worry. It's part of the plan.
This disc has all the
information and details.
Here's what I want you to do with it.
Check this out.
The perfect crime!
Plates please...
Thanks.
- Bye.
Everybody thinks the real plates
were destroyed in the blast.
But here they are with me.
Now what?
My enemies are either dead
or in prison.
And the police have nothing on me.
So now...
Now... lam a free man!
What about Roma?
Why did you have to save her life?
Roma is like a bad habit.
And it's not easy to give up a habit.
Forget about her sweetheart.
Imagine how rich we're going to be!
Really!
I still can't believe you got out alive.
Remember this...
It's not just difficult to catch Don...