Keep it.
Is the Cocaine in the case?
No TJ.
I'm here to give you
my birthday card.
Where is my money?
Right here.
Here's your fuII and finaI payment.
Now...
Put your hands up.
No...
Put them up.
ReIax sweetheart!
I said 'No' because TJ...
...forgot to say 'PIease'.
PIease.... put your hands up.
You think you're very smart.
But not this time.
This time I keep the case for free.
And because I know that you wiII
want to avenge this day...
...you'II have to die.
TJ!
Do you know that there are 36
points on the human body...
...if struck right
...couId prove fataI.
Is that so?
Its just that I'm in a
diIemma now.
About what?
About who, between
the two of you...
...I shouId I kiII first!
I aIways Iiked you Don.
Me too, TJ.
I've aIso aIways...
...Iiked me.
Don't shoot don't shoot...
If you kiII me...
...my men won't Iet you Iive Iong.
You wiII get caught.
No, TJ.
Not onIy is it difficuIt to
catch Don...
It's ImpossibIe!
I want to thank you...
...for your heIp on behaIf
of our government.
We know the gang
we're Iooking for...
...has made KuaIa Lumpur its base.
Our Chief Investigating Officer Mr. De SiIva
wiII give you aII the detaiIs.
Sir...
Thank you Verma.
GentIemen I'II come to the point.
FirstIy, Iet me teII you aII we know
about this gang.
Verma...
When the Soviet Union spIit up in 1990,
a number of smaII nations were born.
SeIIing arms to terrorists and
fundamentaIist groups...
...became a Iucrative business for
a few peopIe in these countries.
One of the new empires buiIt with this money
was headed by a man named Boris.
Verma...
When these empires crumbIed under
internationaI pressure...
...Boris disappeared.
And when he wasn't found
after years of searching...
...he was presumed dead.
But Boris was not dead.
He had gone to India.
He invested the money he made
seIIing arms into drugs.
He bought drugs in buIk from
Afghanistan,Pakistan and India....
...and started distributing
them in Europe.
His two invaIuabIe Iieutenants
in this business...
...Vardhaan and Singhania.
We don't have a singIe
photograph of Vardhaan.
Nor do we know who or
where he is.
Reason?
This is Singhania.
It is rumored that Boris wanted to
hand over the business to Vardhaan...
... but Singhania murdered Boris.
Did he kiII Vardhaan too?
Perhaps he did...
Because there's been no trace
of Vardhaan since then.
And this is Don.
...who manages Singhania's
business here.
Given the information we have,
it is dear...
The most dangerous and cunning
criminaI among them aII...
...is this man.
Good shot.
Yeah, Narang.
HeIIo Anita.
Mr. Singhania had caIIed.
He wanted to knowhow the
poIice knows so much...
...about our operation.
It's hard to say.
AII our men are very IoyaI.
Is that so?
What madness is this, Don?!
Narang.. this is a good shot.
Did you see Kumar's feet?
TerribIe shoes!
I didn't Iike his shoes!
Ramesh...
This IoyaI man of yours was
actuaIIy a poIice informer.
The next time before you
recruit anyone....
... pIease get him to meet me once.
Or check his shoes, at Ieast.
Kumar.
I don't understand.
How did they find out
he was our informer!
Good question!
You...
VishaI MaIik. I'm with the InterpoI.
I see.
I am...
- DCP De SiIva. I know.
And now I'd Iike to know how a fact that
onIy top Indian officers knew...
...came to Don's knowIedge?
I don't know.
By the way...
Who toId you?
Excuse us.
I'm sorry, Mr. De SiIva.
I wasn't pointing a finger at you.
Then who?
Inspector Verma.
See... he is young.
RecentIy inducted into the force.
NewIy married.
Its quite possibIe...
Mr. MaIik. I wonder if you're
actuaIIy drinking coffee?
Just checking.
I trust Inspector Verma.
Anything eIse?
Yes. I too am invoIved in this
investigation from now.
Hi Kamini.
That's great news.
Where are the two of you?
That was quick.
I am so happy, Kamini.
If my brother wants a better Iife today,
it's aII because of you.
Thank you.
Anyways, our hero is in a
pretty bad mood.
Why?
Hi Roma.
I know a Iot about them.
If Don even suspects that
I am Ieaving him..
...he'II kiII me.
Ramesh...
By the time Don finds out
we'II be Iong gone.
Anyway, I am gonna see you
at the airport tonight, okay?
I know that after Mom
and Dad died...
...whatever you did was, to an extent,
for my happiness.
But I wasn't happy...
...nor did I feeI that what you
were doing was right.
...untiI today.
I am proud of you.
Yes, Narang.
Poor... Ramesh.
Ramesh...
Very sad...
Very sad.
I aIways thought of you as reIiabIe.
But unfortunateIy, you didn't
think the same of me.
AII you had to do was teII me
you wanted out...
...and I'd have arranged it
aII for you.
Don! I...
Don, I...
Yes.. what?
I made a mistake.
Why are you saying that?
Your Iove for that girI...
What's her name?
Kamini.
Kamini!
Your Iove for Kamini
isn't a mistake?
Anyway...
I am here to say goodbye.
Ramesh...
Have a nice Iife.
Yeah.
One dirty fish can make the
entire pond dirty.
But if that pond...
...is to become mine.
It becomes necessary to kiII it.
Ramesh...
PeopIe don't Ieave Don.
They Ieave this worId.
Kamini, I need to ask you a
few questions.
What do you want to know?
Ramesh was aIways with Don.
Is that true?
Yes.
Do you remember any particuIar pIace
that Ramesh used to go often?
Yes.
TeII me.
This information can heIp me
to catch Don.
It's not my desire to
get him caught,Officer.
Kamini, don't do anything that...
...couId put your Iife at risk.
I don't care whether
I Iive or die now.
But the poIice department cares.
I'm trying to quit...
It kiIIs you.
This camera...this pistoI...
Why do you need
aII this security?
Because a ''Do Not Disturb'' sign
doesn't work in this hoteI.
What are you thinking?
I'm thinking that...
...I don't Iike two types of girIs.
One, who take too Iong
to succumb to me.
The second, who succumb
too quickIy.
And I succumbed too quickIy.
What did you say
your name was?
Sonia.
Sonia, the time between us meeting
and you being in this hoteI room...
...is just haIf an hour.
That's because, when I
saw you I feIt...
... it was you I've been
searching for.
RomantictaIk bores me, Sonia!
ShaII I get it?
No..
It's mine.
Why don't you go inside...
...and get into something more...
...comfortabIe.
Sure!
Yes.. Anita.
Kamini...
Thank God you're okay.
Where are you?
There isn't anything eIse to wear.
I know.
Who were you taIking to?
I'm sorry?
Oh that!
To my Aunt.
She worries needIessIy,
if I'm sIightIy Iate.
I can't teII her the truth,
can I...
... about where I am...
...and who I'm with.
Bring your Aunt aIong
next time.
She's not your type, Don.
Oh.. yes.
Why the hurry?
Why eIse wouId I want
to be here?
This heart of mine
is crazy for my love.
His love is like a flame
burning in my heart
l am willing to let this
flame engulf me
You can't escape from
it's intensity either
This heart of mine
is crazy for my love.
My heart always gets
what it craves for
But my love can take my life
if my lover requests it
My heart always gets
what it craves for
But my love can take my life
if my lover requests it
l gift you my life
in return for yours.
This heart of mine
is crazy for my love.
His love is like a flame
burning in my heart
Every moment that passes,
A storm rages in my heart.
As the goal l desire
is coming closer.
Every moment that passes,
A storm rages in my heart.
As the goal l desire
is coming closer.
You will never forget the day
our hearts collided
This heart of mine
is crazy for my love.
His love is like a flame
burning in my heart
l am willing to let this
flame engulf me
You can't escape from
it's intensity either
This heart of mine
is crazy for my love.
Your Aunt is outside, aIong with
a bunch of undes!
May I know the reason
for this famiIy reunion?
Ramesh was my fiance.
He had never mentioned you.
I can understand why.
It's been a pIeasure
meeting you.
The pistoI is empty.
You're right!
Let's go. The poIice are
waiting for you.
The poIice of many countries are
waiting for me. But...
Sonia...
Not onIy is it difficuIt to
catch Don...
It's ImpossibIe!
ReaIIy...
You know what!
You know this pistoI is empty.
I know the pistoI is empty but...
The poIice don't know
the pistoI is empty.
And wait for my caII,
is that understood.
Verma...
HoId it right there.
Surprise... surprise...
Officers, pIease. Put your
guns down. Or eIse..
It wouId be wise to
surrender, Don!
I don't think so.
It'd be wiser for you
to move back.
I'm asking for the Iast time.
Or I'II be forced to...
Stop.
Okay...
Down...
Good.
Come nice and easy
everyone down...
...and move back. AIittIe more.
I just want to get out of here.
If you heIp me, this girI...
...wiII be gratefuI to you
aII her Iife.
Thank you.
Good night... GentIemen.
Listen to me... Don.
First, caII the Iift.
For the Iady.
Go on.
QuickIy.
Don, I'm unarmed.
I can't stop you even if I want to.
Let the girI go.
Of course I wiII. Once
I get out of here.
Trust me.
No...
Damn it...
Verma...
What's going on!
Who are you?
Questions Iater.
I have to get out of here first.
Put the pistoI down.
You have no idea who I am?
Mr. Narang, PoIice...
Move...
Stop that car.
Put your hands up.
And step out of the car.
Out.. of the car!
Wait, Vikram!...
Let's go.
Go.
Who is this girI?
Roma.
She can be usefuI to us.
Or is she usefuI?
If you had seen her shoot
two cops a whiIe ago...
...you wouIdn't be asking that.
ReaIIy...
Yes, Vikram..
I'II be there right away.
Come, Roma.
Go ahead Narang.
I'm in no danger
from this girI.
So, the poIice is after you.
Why?
I'm charged with murder.
But as usuaI, the truth is
somewhat different, right!
Wrong. The charge is true.
What was his name?
Rajiv.
He was my sister's husband.
Your sister must have
feIt terribIe.
My sister is dead.
He kiIIed her.
So you kiIIed him. Good!
What do you want from me?
Nothing.
Narang saheb said...
Oh, Narang...
Come doser.
Come on.
You know, what I think...
I think...
I think Narang wants to start
a new sort of 'trade' which...
Very good.
I Iike wiId cats a Iot.
WiId.. cats...
What happened?
What did you think?
She tried to kiII me.
ReIax.. Narang.
You wiII work with us
from today.
Thank you Don.
Jairaj caIIed from India.
He wants more cocaine.
I know.
Did you speak to Jairaj?
Yes...
I didn't say anything
to him. But...
...you are asking for more money
than Mr. Singhania had said.
This deaI wiII bring us
profits in miIIions.
Don't you Iike such
a huge sum?
It's not that but it's not your job
to make this decision...
...it's Mr. Singhania's!
Singhania makes the decision.
I do the work.
So what do you do?
I don't taIk Iike a chiId.
Such arrogance isn't good.
Don't forget, this business
was set up by him.
Then teII him to come here
and manage it.
What's this?
Your wedding DVD!
This disc has information of aII
our business and contacts.
The next time Mr. Singhania is here,
you can give it to him!
Don, I'm not saying your
intentions are wrong.
AII I'm saying is...
...you're moving very fast.
For what I want to achieve...
...this speed is essentiaI!
But turning your friends into
enemies for this quest...
...wouId be a big mistake.
The biggest mistake, Don's
enemy can make...
...is to make an
enemy of Don!
You have forgotten
what happened yesterday.
If I ever find out that
your memory has returned...
Then remember this too...
The buIIets wiII be reaI
next time.
Yes.. Verma.
I just got information that
Don is going to India.
When?
Day after tomorrow.
For a deaI with someone
named Jairaj.
We'II Ieave tonight.
And find out where
we can find Jairaj.
Deepak, come here.
It's not nice seeing you
empty-handed,Jairaj.
Where's the money?
In the car.
Hand over the case to me.
Nobody says pIease anymore.
As you Iike...
Here you go!
Sir, he's driving very fast
Sir, he's very dose but
he's moving very fast
Sir, we can't see him any more
Get out of the way,
damn it!
Come on...
Enough. You've run
quite a Iot.
You!
StiII angry about the
girI's death, Officer!
Shut up.
If you want to shoot...
...go ahead.
...but don't even think
about arresting me.
AII right.
Have it your way.
Any Iuck... Verma?
No Sir.
This pIace is so huge that Don
couId be hiding anywhere.
Sure, but for how Iong?
AII the highways and stations here
must be under strict surveiIIance.
Have our men posted in
the hospitaIs nearby.
He won't be abIe to get out of here
even if he wants to.
Is that understood?
Right Sir.
No one knows where Don is
after the poIice encounter.
Not even the poIice.
I'm afraid that Don...
Don what?
I think he is dead.
Or, do you hope he is dead?
You know Mac...
I feeI that he wanted something
to happen to Don!
Oh! caIm down Anita.
- No, I wiII not caIm down.
What was your
probIem with him?
Was it that Don had become more
important to Singhania than you?
Mac...
Take her away from here.
I'II go myseIf.
But remember...
If what you're saying
turns out true.
I'II hoId you responsibIe.
Good morning Sir...
- Good morning Feroz.
Feroz!
Yes.. Sir.
Come here.
Perhaps you remember.
It was about a year ago...
Aman had barged into my office
aIong with a smaII boy.
The boy's parents had
disappeared and...
...he found him on the street.
I had asked you to
fiIe the report.
Yes Sir.
Bring me that fiIe.
Vijay...
Every moment, every day...
...l long for you.
O Lord!
You must reveal your glory,
once again.
You must return next year,
You must reveal your glory,
once again.
You must return next year,
l will wait for you
with longing eyes.
Heed me, heed my plea.
Come back again.
Hear your devotee's plea.
Only when l look upon you...
will my heart be at peace.
Lord O mine...
Dear Lord O mine!
Be it happy times
or days of sorrow...
Our hearts chant
just one name
Because of you,
life is comfortable.
You dwell in our
whole being.
Every second...
...l think of you.
l am your fan
l chant your name
in prayer.
Heed me,
heed my plea.
Come back again.
Hear your devotee's plea.
Only when l look upon you...
will my heart be at peace.
Lord O mine...
Dear Lord O mine!
You must reveal your glory,
once again.
You must return next year,
One, two, three, four!
Hail Lord Ganesha's glory!
Five, Six, Seven, Eight!
Lord Ganesha is with us!
Lord O mine, Ganpati!
May the next year
bring you soon!
Is it fresh?
Here you go, Deepu.
Done counting?
Yes, unde.
How much is it? Grand totaI?
3000 Rupees induding the
Iast three days.
Yuck! What are you doing?
Sorry very much.
What is the worId coming to?
My voice has gone hoarse singing
for three days and what do we get?
3000 Rupees!
Don't worry, Vijay Unde.
- How can I not!
We'II make a Iot of money over
the 9 days of NavratrifestivaI.
Wow, Deepu...
We'II have to make money...
I worry constantIy about enroIIing
you into a good schooI.
Just want you to
pass high schooI!
But what can I do?
There's no money Ieft after
rent and stuff, is there?
Hey, don't feeI sad.
Imagine what your Daddy
wouId say if he met me?
''Why thank you! You've got my son
onto the street!'' Isn't that right?
You don't know my Papa.
He'd never ever say that.
ReaIIy! Then what wiII he say?
Vijay...
How does your he know my name!?
Vijay!
Oh! I don't want lce cream
PIease go!
I'm not seIIing lce cream!
DCP Saheb
I consider myseIf pretty smart.
ActuaIIy I am.
But when you are keeping things
even from your own department...
...why are you teIIing me?
I mean... this Don Sir?
What's he got to do with me?
Look at this first.
You'II understand everything.
Okay.
This is ME!
You're joking, aren't you?
No.
No! You're... not joking!
So then?
In that case I'm feeIing...
...that you want me to
take Don's pIace...?
Yes.
Don't mind pIease.
Okay.
You just toId me...
...Don Sir kiIIed one
of your informers.
To say yes to this job
after hearing aII this...
...you get what I'm saying?
DCP Saheb
Look at Don Sir! He uses his
gun without thinking twice...
...and me?
Forget a gun!
I can't even use a bicyde!
Vijay, I agree this job
is dangerous.
You don't say?
But if we pIan
each move carefuIIy...
...it can be easiIy done.
Sure... sure...
Sir, I'm not afraid of jumping
into this weII, but...
...you teII me...
If something happens to me?
Where wiII Deepu go?
I understand Vijay.
You must understand.
The peopIe I want to catch
with your heIp...
...find it easiest to get kids,
Iike Deepu, hooked onto drugs.
God forbid, if tomorrow...
...he gets addicted to this poison...
how wiII you forgive yourseIf?
Look Vijay. If you agree...
I'II take fuII responsibiIity for
this boy's education.
It wiII give Deepu the choice
to be whatever he wants...
...a doctor, an engineer...or
a poIice officer Iike me.
AII this is possibIe
if you want it.
Okay, DCP Saheb
But teII me something...
If Don Sir's gang find me out
and you find me in a coffin....
Deepu's name won't be cut from
the schooI register, wiII it?
Deepu education wiII be
Iooked after.
I promise.
OK... ok...
One more question...
The fact I am Vijay...
...not Don Sir.
... you aIone wiII
know that, right?
May God give you a Iong Iife
but what if you pop it...
I mean...
Don't worry.
Nothing wiII happen to me.
Stop.. Papa.
Where's Mummy?
Making breakfast.
And she sent you as her
aIarm dock, did she?
WeII, where's the button to
switch this aIarm off?
No....
Thank you Sir.
So... what's the probIem?
Just a moment, Sir...
Sir, is this the password
you entered?
That's the one.
F09AK7 4
If you remember, whiIe instaIIing
the program I had toId you...
... the password recorded in this foIder wiII be
shown backwards for safety reasons...
So your actuaI password is...
47KA90F
Oh God! yes.. I'm sorry.
WiII that be aII, Sir?
Stop! right here.
Is anybody there?!
HeIIo Jasjit.
I hope you are comfortabIe.
Who is this?
The man who can rescue you.
But you wiII have to
do me a smaII favor!
This is a strange way of asking
someone for a favor!
I Iike you, Jasjit.
TeII me something...
Isn't it true that Joshi's computer aIone,
can unIock his safe?
I don't know.
Oh reaIIy!
That means you were Iying to Joshi...
...or are you Iying to ME!
Look...
Think what you want.
But, just get me out of here.
Why?
Is it very suffocating?
If you want, we can send your
wife Geeta to be with you.
Take it easy Jasjit. ReIax!
AII you need to do is one job.
There are diamonds worth
10 miIIion doIIars in Joshi's safe.
Get them and I'II reIease her.
I want to taIk to Geeta.
Of course.
Jasjit...
Geeta...
I am so sorry... Geeta.
This is aII my fauIt.
Forgive me.
I Iove you.
I Iove you too.
That's very sweet but
I've got diabetes.
Now Iets taIk business.
The diamond company
Joshi works for...
...is on the 25th fIoor
of BeIcourt Towers.
The security on the entire fIoor is the kind
required to safeguard diamonds worth 10 miIIion.
We can get you to the roof
via the service Iift.
Rest... is up to you.
HoId it.
Right there!
Take the bag off your shouIder
and put it down.
You must be wondering how
the poIice got here.
I'II teII you.
Mrs. Wadia Iives in the
buiIding across the road.
She and her husband
quarreI pretty often...
...and the poor Iady comes out
to her baIcony to caIm down.
Guess what she saw
from her baIcony tonight?
Inspector De SiIva, pIease Iisten
to me very carefuIIy.
I'm being forced to do this.
Some peopIe have
kidnapped my wife.
You think I am a fooI...?
What's your name?
Jasjit.
You're under arrest.
Shinde...
Jasjit.... Stop.
Inspector...
They wiII kiII my wife!
I must go. Do you understand?
I'm teIIing the truth!
May be...
But I am not authorized
to sympathize with you.
Take him away.
Any idea where Deepu is?
De SiIva..
Your days are numbered!
Wow! Isn't this something?!
He's handsome!
You know, sir... seeing a picture is one thing.
To be face to face Iike this...
...Don Sir is aIive, isn't he?
Yes.
The doctors have kept him in
a sedated state.
I personaIIy beIieve that a person
Iike Don has no right to Iive.
But I need him now.
Vijay, I want you to study
him properIy...
...understand him...
Learn his habits,
his mannerisms,everything!
I wiII Iearn everything.
What's the big deaI?!
Let him wake up at Ieast!
As soon as your work is done,
I'II hand him over to the poIice.
I get it.
First...
AII the marks and scars that
were on Don's body...
...need to be made on you.
Sure.
On me...!!
Yes.
The doctors here can
do it painIessIy.
How can it be painIess?!
Hi.. Ashok.
He's aII yours.
Vijay, this is Dr. Ashok KhiIwani.
He wiII operate on you.
Everything ready as pIan?
Yes, just a few
preIiminary tests and...
...we are ready to get started.
I'II check everything.
Thanks Ashok.
What's the matter?
I've never heard that a buIIet mark on a shouIder
or a scar on the head can be made painIessIy.
Don't be afraid.
- How can I not be!!
I was about to teII you...
I got Deepu admitted to
MaIaysia's InternationaI SchooI.
Inter.... Int...
With that name, it must be good.
It's one of the best.
- Best.
Now you stop worrying about Deepu
and concentrate on your work.
Okay... okay...
Look, I'II teII you aII I know
about Don.
Besides that, I've thought of
another pIan.
When Don, that means you...
...go back to your companions,
you'II be iII and wounded.
You wiII have Iost your memory.
The more you Iearn about
Don's Iife...
...the doser I'II get to
regaining my memory.
Thank you.
You think exactIy Iike the
comicbook hero, Chacha Chaudhary!
You Know Chacha?
Brain working faster
than the computer.
I'II teII you a
great story. Listen...
One day, Chacha Chaudhary took
his dog Rocket out for stroII...
You want it?
Don never ate paan (betel leaf).
- Never ate paan!!
That wasn't very
nice of him, was it!
WeII, I guess that
I must quit too.
Fine.
Come on Vijay.
Is this a binocuIar?
Neha...
Yes Doctor...
Start monitoring the bIood
pressure of the patient.
Why?
- Yes Sir.
Anand...
Patch me through the face map.
Doctor...sir...
It won't be too painfuI, wiII it?
No, it...
How Iong, before he comes?
WeII.... Just another 48 hours, Mr. DesiIva
and then he is aII yours.
Good job Ashok.
Doctor, pIease come
immediateIy to room no. 2
Its an emergency.
My God!
What happened Ashok?
Don is admitted in that room.
What happened?
Heart seizure, doctor.
Have you given the patient
anything to stabiIize him?
Yes Doctor.. 2 mI of adrenaIine
Get me a cardiacinjection, Quick.
What's the bIood pressure?
- 210 by 120 doctor.
I said hurry up.
No...
God damn it...
Ashok...
You and your team know
nothing about this inddent.
This operation never happened.
Is that understood?
OK.
The success of my pIan is Iinked to
this secret remaining a secret.
Ashok...
It's onIy a matter of a few days.
HeIIo...
Yes...
Where have you seen him?
Where did you see him?
- Over there
The doctors are saying that
he has Iost his memory.
He doesn't remember anything.
StiII, we must get him back
at any cost.
You're right... but how?
The passport they found in his
car was MaIaysian...
... and they must send Don back.
Don't worry, Mr. Singhania.
It wiII be done.
Go back!
WeIcome back, Don.
That's right.
Your name is Don.
I am Narang.
She is Roma.
AII of us here, work with you...
and you work for Mr. Singhania.
You remember Mr. Singhania
at Ieast?
I don't beIieve it!
In spite of aII the security,
they took Don away!
Don's testimony couId have exposed
the entire crime ring.
But what can he teII us when he
doesn't remember anything?
I don't think he's of any use
to them now either.
Who is them?
Mr. MaIik, whoever did this either
works for Singhania or for his enemy.
Like who?
Like...
...Vardhaan.
Vardhaan...
Where is Vardhaan?!!
Have you seen him?
Do you know where he's hiding?
Do we even have a singIe
picture of him?
No.
PIease....
And by the way Mr. De SiIva.
Memory isn't something that
once Iost, can't be found.
It's just a matter of time.
Is this...
... mine?
Yes...
For me, Don isn't Don...
...without this.
How do I Iook?
You Iook very dangerous.
Mr. MaIik...
It's been 3 weeks since
Don's escape.
Why can't the poIice catch him?
You teII us where he is and
we'II go catch him!
PIease... Mr. MaIik
- Look, untiI we get the right information,
or a witness comes forward...
...We must foIIow poIice procedure.
What's in it?
Our contacts, bank account numbers
and passwords are aII recorded in this.
You had made it yourseIf
and put it in the safe.
Yes.
Yes, Vijay. TeII me.
De SiIva Saheb...
I know enough about Don...
...my memory can return now.
Good.
We must do this with
utmost care.
I agree.
If you can't Iose your
memory without reason...
...then it shouIdn't come back
without reason either.
I've got a soIution for that.
Tomorrow, make some excuse...
...and come to the pIace I've fixed.
Who are you waiting for?
Maybe... you.
Oh that...
You have done a Iot for me...
I won't forget that.
There's a Iot more Ieft to do.
That there is .
Don...!
It was Iike this the
other day too.
I was in my car...
...and the poIice
were chasing me.
They were shooting at me...
And then I...
I remember everything.
Who I am!
Who aII of you are!
I remember each
and everything!
Mac...
Remembering your friend's
names is one thing....
...in our business, it's important to
remember our enemy's name.
Which enemy are you
taIking of,Narang?
Vardhaan or that officer DesiIva?
Maybe T.J is the one you
were thinking about...
..or the man who betrayed
us aII... Ramesh?
I reaIIy enjoyed kiIIing them aII.
This caIIs for a ceIebration.
- Oh yes, it does.
I am... back.
The people in this world...
have clutched their hearts again!
l have returned...
... bringing back with me
a lot of excitement!
Look who's here.
Back to rule your world.
Who's got you mesmerized?
For whom do you wait
with open arms?
Who is this charming man?
Recognize me.
l am Don.
l bid my life...
...and gamble with death.
l have no regret...
...nor do l care....
...who l make my enemy.
No enemy of mine,
will live too long.
l am very dangerous.
l am very dangerous...
...and forever cunning.
Who isback to win
the world over?
Recognize me.
l am Don.
Their eyes inviting...
...many women have
wanted me for themselves.
But these two eyes
that are glancing into mine...
...have mesmerized me.
These eyes...
...tell me...
that they are hiding
an intoxicating secret.
l am getting addicted to them...
and my heart is falling
under it's spell
Who ishere that has
fallen under this spell?
Recognize me.
l am Don.
Yes, Vijay?
AdeaI is on at 7 tomorrow morning,
outside the city.
If you couId come there...
...I'II bring the discwith me.
I'm sure...
...it has aII the information
the poIice wants.
Can you come there aIone?
Rest assured.
There'II be no one with me.
Mr. Narang, don't you think it's
unsafe for Don to go aIone?
I mean, this deaI couId
aIso be a setup.
Don won't go aIone.
You wiII go with him.
Don't be siIIy Narang...
Are you teIIing me that
I can't do this job aIone?
No. I know that you can
do it aIone.
But Mr. Singhania has personaIIy
ordered me to do this.
Mr. Narang...
Can't Vikram or Macdo this job?
Why is it important for Roma
to go with Don?
Because Mr. Narang knows
me very weII...
... and when, where and
who to shoot...
...is something
I know very weII.
Singhania...
Your time is up.
Tomorrow, the discwiII be mine
and you'II be finished!
Tomorrow... !
This one word separates me
from my success.
And don't worry.
The poIice wiII never find out
that I have the disc.
Because neither do they know
that I am Vardhaan.
Nor is my photograph in
any of their records.
Is this a joke?!
No, its not!
What is this madness?
I have feIt this mad since...
you kiIIed my brother Ramesh
and his fiance.
Ramesh! Your brother?
Yes...
And I didn't kiII you
tiII now because...
I wanted you to remember
why you were being kiIIed!
You don't know this but...
I didn't kiII your brother.
Good bye Don.
Stop!That's enough...
Look! Look at me.
Listen carefuIIy.
You didn't kiII me
aII these days...
... and for that, I thank you.
Now Iisten to the truth.
The truth is...
He...
...is not Don.
Who can say that
he is not Don!
Besides Vijay and me now...
...onIy you know the truth.
Where is the disc?
Vijay...
I'm sorry.
I thought that...
No, it doesn't matter.
Anyone in your pIace...
... wouId have been deceived.
Mr. DesiIva...
Your work is done?
No...
My work isn't done yet.
That too wiII happen.
Singhania is coming here.
Singhania?
Yes, sir.
He is coming to KuaIa Lumpur
for a meeting.
I'II inform you of the Iocation
as soon as I know.
Good.
Vijay...
You may have done this
for Deepu's sake but...
... neither me nor the poIice
wiII ever forget this favor.
Who is Deepu?
Vijay unde...!
Don't you recognize me?
How can I not recognize you?
My... Deepu!
But, honestIy...
... for one second
I did wonder,
''who is this smart young gentIeman
running towards me?''
This new uniform!
New shoes.
WeII unde, you aren't the
same either!
What can I say, Deepu?
Your Vijay unde...
...had to change.
But what about your paan?
Paan is gone!
Just a minute...
Roma, this is Deepu.
Hi Deepu.
Nice to meet you.
HeIIo... me too...
And Deepu, this is Roma aunty.
Unde, is she your auntytoo?
- Hey! Is that anyway to speak!
Vijay...
The things you are doing
for this boy....!
Who does this in today's time?
If anything wouId have
happened to you today...
...I wouId never forgive myseIf!
PIease forget aII about it.
Anyway...
I don't know...
... ShouId I be gratefuI to Don for
making it possibIe to meet you..
or I shouId hate him.
Because I wonder...
...how you can even
sit beside a man...
who constantIy reminds you
of your brother's death.
I can't punish you for a crime
committed by someone eIse.
And pIease.
Stop addressing me so formaIIy.
What do I caII you then?
Aunty?
Excuse me...
HeIIo...
There is some Mr. Jasjit Ahuja
here to see you sir.
Jasjit...
How are you, Haatim?
- Very weII.
What a surprise?
My God, it's been ages
since we met!
BangaIore 2002.
Before you came here.
ReaIIy!..
How time fIies!
UnbeIievabIe!...
What brings you here?
DCP DesiIva is in this
city right now.
Yes...
I heard about what
happened to you...
...I'm sorry.
I couIdn't do
anything for you.
But you can now.
I want his address, Haatim.
What do you pIan on doing?
What time is the meeting?
And Singhania wiII be there?
Good... I'II see you then.
Vijay...
WeII done!
WeIcome back!...
Perhaps you don't know
who I am?
I know you very weII.
DCP DesiIva.
Who are you?
Think back!
9th January, BeIcourt Towers?
10 miIIion doIIars worth
of diamonds?
No!
WeII, maybe a buIIet couId heIp
sharpen your memory.
Hang on!...
Jasjit?
Yes...
Jasjit.
What do you want?
I want to kiII you!
I hope you won't
mind too much!
Look, Jasjit...
Maybe what happened
to you was wrong...
I was onIy doing my duty.
I'm a poIice officer...
... and right now it's crudaI
for me to be somewhere.
Or eIse some big criminaIs
wiII get away.
Let me go!
How can I Iet you go?
Look at these faces!
One of them is my wife...
who is dead because of you.
The other is my innocent son!
Who knows where he is now?
Look at them...
This boy...
Deepu...
Is your son?!
You know Deepu?
Yes. I aIso know
where he is...
...but wiII teII you that,
onIy after I come back.
Wrong!
You wiII teII me right now!
Jasjit...
You can kiII me and
take your revenge...
... but then give up the hope that
you'II see your son again!
I don't hate you as much...
as I Iove my son.
Go.
I wiII wait for you here.
Leave that here.
You do have to come back,
don't you?
Night and wine have met
we are intoxicated
Body and heart
are both ready to melt
Celebration surrounds us
but yet l am anxious
Why does my heart beat faster?
Why does my heart say...
... ''you fools do not know this yet?''
Tonight...
Who knows what will happen?
What will we gain?
What will we lose?
Tonight...
Who knows what will happen?
What will we gain?
What will we lose?
What will happen
in just a few moments?
What was always mine
will be mine again.
The night will decide
who resides in who'sheart
The decision has been made...
...that l will be victorious
You fools do not know this yet
Tonight...
Who knows what will happen?
What will we gain?
What will we lose?
Tonight...
Who knows what will happen?
What will we gain?
What will we lose?
Come, let me tell you
something,secretly
Soon, the night is going to
change itshue, secretly
Then l will take you away
with me,secretly
Where will you go?
Look! Here l am.
You fools do not know this yet
Tonight...
Who knows what will happen?
What will we gain?
What will we lose?
Move it...!
Put your gun down.
Open the door.
Let him go.
Shoot, Mr. MaIik!
Mr. MaIik! Shoot him!
- Shut up.
Let him go. Put your gun down.
Shoot, Mr. MaIik!
Get into the van. Move!
MaIik! Shoot him.
Do you want me to shoot him?
ReIax...
MaIik...
CIose the door.
Shut the door.
Stop!
Turn the engine off!
Now..!
I mean it.
Now!
Yes...
OK... Thank you.
What do you think, Verma?
Is this man teIIing the truth
that he is not Don?
Don is very dever, sir.
CIaiming that he is Vijay,
Mr. DesiIva's informer...
...is sureIy a pIan to
escape punishment.
Hmm? Lets do this...
Bring Narang and Machere.
Let them hear
what he's saying.
Perhaps his words...
...can break them.
Mr. MaIik, how many times do
I have to teII you I'm not Don!
I'm Vijay...
DesiIva saheb's informer.
If Singhania's men are behind bars
today, it's aII due to me.
And why don't you go ask
DesiIva saheb who I am?
DCP DesiIva is no
Ionger with us.
He's dead.
Dead?
Just a minute!
Then...
Where's the disc I gave him?
What disc?
I had given him a discthat contained information
of Singhania's contacts and bank accounts.
I'm sorry but he didn't mention
any such disc.
But it must be somewhere!
...in his apartment or
somewhere here...
in his desk... or...
Mr. MaIik!
If I were Don...
...how wouId I know that
he had this disc?
DCP DesiIva's informer has
toId us quite a Iot about you.
Now if there is anything,
you two wouId Iike to say?
What are you saying, Mr. MaIik?
This man is Don.
And he is doing what
he know's best.
What's that?
Making poIice officers Iike you
Iook Iike fooIs.
Shut up.
Take them away.
Verma, take a smaII team to
DCP DesiIva's apartment.
If that discis there...
...it's possibIe this man is
speaking the truth.
He is teIIing the truth.
He is not Don.
MaIik Saheb, I'm teIIing the truth...
I gave De SiIva saheb the
discwith my own hands!
You don't beIieve me,
do you?
Don, I gave you a chance...
But now even you can't deny
the fact that you are Don.
I'm sorry.
Verma.. just send
the guards in!
Wait...!
There is another proof...
Dr. Ashok KhiIwani!
He operated on me to
make me Iook Iike Don.
PIease...! He knows the truth.
PIease.. Sir...
Thank you, Feroze.
MaIik Saheb...
...did you taIk to
the doctor?
He is not aIive.
- Not aIive?!
Last month, he and his assistant
died in a car accident.
MaIik Saheb...
PIease beIieve me.
I'm not Don!
The Court wiII decide
this matter.
PIease Iisten to me!
I'm Vijay, MaIik saheb!
I'm not Don, I'm Vijay!
Try and understand...
HeIIo Vijay!
We heard everything.
Don't be siIIy, Mac.
I am Don.
I onIy said that to
confuse them.
What's happening?
Stop it.
Narang...!
PIease make them understand.
- Shut up.
You are Vijay...
But if they attack
you here...
...the poIice wiII reaIize...
...are not Don.
Get back.
Get back...!
So...
Behaving a bit too smart,
weren't you, boy?!
Now get ready to die.
The punishment for seIIing
drugs in MaIaysia...
...is death...
... and the court wiII sureIy give
Don the death sentence.
If it doesn't...
... we'II kiII Vijay in jaiI.
What happened, sir?
They say that, tiII we
get a date in court...
...it's not safe to keep these
dangerous criminaIs here.
So what is their intention?
They have a high security jaiI on
an isIand, five miIes off the coast.
They'II aII be fIown there
first thing tomorrow.
Excuse me...
I need to use the
toiIet pIease...!
Very badIy...!
Hey...
Okay.
Come through!
Hey... hey...
- Easy!
Okay... okay...
Sorry.
Come through.
Hi...
Give me your gun, PIease!
Just stay there.
Come on...!
Now the handcuffs...
Go on...!
Quick!
The other one...!
Quick...
Now give me his
gun, PIease...
Quick... quick...!
Take him with the others.
Move it!
Fast...!
Go on...!
No..!
CongratuIations! Jasjit.
The information on this disc...
...is Iike a winning Iottery ticket.
I know a man who can get you
a Iot of money for this disc.
Jasjit...
DesiIva said that he knew
where Deepu was.
Perhaps, the buyer we find
may have known DesiIva?
Haatim...
If he can Iead me to Deepu,
I'II Iet him have aII that money.
I see...
And you have this disc.
No probIem.
It'II be done.
MaIik...
What!
What happened, sir?
Who was that?
An incident on board forced the
piIot to make an emergency Ianding.
Don has escaped!
Thanks...
Thanks for coming!
Thank God you're
aII right!
You caII this being aII right?
Vijay...
I know what the truth is.
The truth...?
Why wiII the poIice
beIieve you, Roma?
OnIy the disccan prove
my innocence now.
We''II get the disc.
The man who stoIe the disc...
... cannot be honest enough
to return it to the poIice.
He's sure to try
and seII it.
Just a minute, Roma.
Singhania has an agent here...
...who kept him informed about
the cops and our enemies.
He couId be of use.
Try and contact him somehow.
But if you are found meanwhiIe...
I mean, the poIice wiII be
searching everywhere for you.
I know!
But where can I go?!
There is one pIace.
Where is Ramesh's pIace?
CIose by. To the right.
Stop pIease.
Your's, sir?
AII units respond...
Wait...
We have a fugitive situation.
Suspect's name is Don.
Last seen wearing a dark jacket,
trousers and a grey shirt
He is of Indian origin.
Who are you, saheb?
What do you want?
How does one expIain
who he is?
Just know that we are
in big troubIe...
...and need sheIter for a whiIe,
that's aII.
It's not a poIice affair, eh?
ShouId we teII them?
Unde...
It's a poIice affair and...
...an affair of the heart too!
WeII! I get it now.
You've run away?
No, unde. I haven't run away...
I've been kidnapped!
That's great!
Where do we witness
Iove Iike this nowadays?!
Come this way, saheb.
Come, madam
Sit down, saheb.
Unde...
Saheb! Bhaang! (MiIk brewed
with Marijuana pIant extract)
Bhaang?
Tonight is Mahashivratri
(Indian festivaI in honor of Lord Shiva)
...it is a hoIy offering
to Shiva. Drink!
Oh, the Iord wiII bIess you for
drinking his favourite brew!
You aIso try it.
Cheers...
Happy Mahashivratri everyone.
It's aII right, brother!
HonestIy speaking, unde...
If I had Iistened to my mother
when I was a boy...
I wouIdn't be seeing these days!
Why? What did she say?
When I never Iistened to her,
how can I teII you what she said!
If you're done,
can we pIease Ieave?
Leave! But where do we go?
De SiIva...
DCP saheb!
You set up a good way to get me
up there before you Ieft..!
WeII done!
Saheb... paan!
Hey buddy!
I don't want it!
Eat it. It's from Benaras.
ReaIIy?
But Don didn't eat paan.
Never...
Don, who?
Don.... Who??!
Don means me, meaning Vijay
a.k.a Don, meaning...
Paan!
- Pawn!!
I didn't understand a thing.
How do l tell you, brother?
The plight l am in.
Tell us... tell us...
l set out to eat ''halwa''
(hot lndian dessert)...
...and ended up burning my mouth!
What can l say?
How can l explain?
l'm in a bad situation...
...that'shard to escape.
lt's like a violent storm!
lt's like a raging wind!
l've had to...
...run for my life!
A long and winding...
...chase has been on!
Day and night,
l've been awake...
...running helter skelter.
Sometimes this way!
Sometimes that way!
Ran this way once
and that way next!!
Then you gave me this paan...
...and life has returned
to mytired body!
Eating a paan from Benaras...
...unlocked my benumbed brain.
Now watch the things l'll do...
...to straighten up everyone
Thisboy...
...this boy from the
banks of the Ganges!
Eating a paan from Benaras...
...unlocked my benumbed brain.
l've been cursed!
...to be caught up in
this maze, alas!
My life is in limbo...
...l'm at the hangman's mercy, alas!
So honest and simple,
So innocent... yes l am.
Don't know how l ended up
amid this educated lot!!
With a sweetened knife...
With a sweetened knife
they've slit mythroat!
This boy from the
banks of the Ganges!
Eating a paan from Benaras...
...unlocked my benumbed brain.
A lovely lass,
unique and desirable...
...her enrapturing charm
turns all heads...
...wherever she goes...
and her body sparkles
like precious stones
Her dazzling eyes carry
a world of dreams...
...her lips, youth'snectar
A flirtatious swagger
in her walk...
...sprinkles the air with her
sandalwood-scented body
The vision of her
sets your heart aflame
Her face ismoon-bright.
Her eyes like a gazelle
She is beautiful...
...as sweet as honey
A beautiful maiden...
...hasfallen for me, alas!
A sweetened skewer...
...haspierced my heart, alas!
So bright and fair
she's a spicy lass
A fighting spirit to match
she stole my heart
Now that l have her love...
Now that l have her love
my life has blossomed!
This boy from the
banks of the Ganges!
Eating a paan from Benaras...
...unlocked my benumbed brain.
Now watch the things l'll do...
...to straighten up everyone
Thisboy...
...this boy from the
banks of the Ganges!
Yes...
Yes, it's me.
There's a buyer for the dischere.
Yes, ready to pay in doIIars.
Just a minute.
You shouId speak directIy.
We have Deepu.
If you want to see him aIive,
bring the disc..
Jasjit...
If you want to see your
son aIive...
...bring that discat 5 pm sharp
to this address
Jasjit...
Haatim Qureishi?
- Yes?
May I come inside?
Who are you?
I've nothing personaI
against you.
But if you don't hand over
the discto me...
...I'II be forced to...
...change my mind.
What disc?
The one you wanted
to seII Roma..
Remember?
Sorry...
The discis with my friend, Jasjit.
And where is your friend, Jasjit?
Where's the disc?
Where's Deepu?
Deepu wiII come.
CaII me when he does...
...you aIready have
my phone number!
Jasjit...
Seeing your punctuaIity...
I must say...
...I'm very impressed!
DesiIva...?!
No...
Vardhaan.
Vardhaan...?
But you...
- ...are dead?!!
Right?
For a man who can keep the
poIice in the dark for years...
...creating the drama of a mere
accident is no big deaI!
Do you want me to shoot him?
ReIax...
MaIik...
Shut the door.
Let's go.
Stop!
Turn the engine off.
I mean it.
Come on.
You're very cunning.
Thank you.
Now aII I want is the disc...
...which you wiII give me.
I don't beIieve it.
Now I get it!
Why the poIice didn't find
the diamonds in that basement.
I recognize that ring.
What did you think?
I brought the discwith me!
Do you think I am a fooI?
Remember?
That night, you had asked me
the same question!
You have a very good memory.
It'II heIp in recognizing
your son.
Daddy...
Deepu...
Vardhaan...
If anything happens...
ReIaxJ.J!
I don't enjoy bIoodshed.
AII I want is...
...the disc.
AII right...
You'II get it.
Jasjit here.
Bring the disc.
My man wiII reach here at 7.
You and your son wiII...
...remain my guests tiII then.
Phone... pIease?
Take him away.
KiII them when you
have the disc!
Are you okay, son?
Deepu...
Listen carefuIIy.
As Iong as they do not get
what they want...
...our Iife is not in danger.
But daddy! At 7, when your...
- Nothing wiII happen at 7.
Nobody is going to come.
That phone caII was
to buy us time.
I'm scared, daddy.
Don't be, my son.
I'm with you now.
Nothing wiII happen to you.
Nothing wiII happen.
Yes, Mr. Vardhaan.
Nobody has come so far.
Okay.
Find them.
Now where, daddy?
- Keep it down!
Just a minute.
Let me see.
They must be hiding dose by.
Keep Iooking.
There, he is.
Don't shoot.
OnIy he knows
where the discis.
Daddy...
Vijay unde...!
Daddy, stop!
This is Vijay unde.
He took care of me when
you went away.
Vijay unde, this is my Daddy.
Take it.
Vijay...
But for you, I don't know
where Deepu wouId be today.
PIease Jasjit..!
Whatever I did for him...
Deepu is a IovabIe boy.
Anyway, why do you need
this discso badIy?
Just know that the onIy way
out of the mess I'm in...
...is this disc...
...and your testimony
I don't understand.
Your testimony wiII prove...
...that this discwas
with DCP DesiIva.
DCP DesiIva?!
Yes.
He was the onIy one in the
poIice department who knew...
..that he is not Don,
but Vijay.
But after he died...
He is not dead!
His reaI name is Vardhaan.
And just a IittIe whiIe ago...
I met him!
No!
This can't be.
I mean...
your eyes must have
deceived you!!
No, I have not been deceived.
DCP DesiIva is Vardhaan!!
He made me pose as Don...
...obtained the disc...
...and a chance to kiII Singhania.
Then faked his own death...
...and Ieft me to die as Don.
DCP DesiIva... Vardhaan!
You've pIayed a big move!
But he must never have thought...
...that I'd steaI the disc.
Give the discto Vardhaan!
Vijay! What are you saying?
Yes, Roma.
AfinaI meeting with DCP DesiIva
is very important.
Don't worry, darIing.
Today wiII be the Iast day
of Vijay's Iife.
I've reached the pIace
you toId me to...
...aIone.
Good.
Buy a ticket from the counter.
There's a bridge on IeveI one...
...come there.
And yes...
...don't forget the money...
...or you'II have to
buy the ticket again.
You seem to be
in a great hurry.
Now where do I go?
Throw the bag down.
What!?
I can see you, Jasjit...
...but I don't see the disc.
You'II get what you want.
Throw it.
Looks good.
Where's the disc?
Upper viewing pIatform.
SiIver briefcase.
Damn!
Poor DCP DesiIva!
You!
What are you doing here?
I shouId be asking
you that!
You're dead, remember?
What do you want?
- Answers to some questions.
PIease! This is no time
for interviews!
AII right then. Here's
the second reason.
I'm going to kiII
you today.
You have the guts to shoot?
You've trained me pretty weII.
What wiII you gain
by kiIIing me?
There are some deeds in which
profit and Ioss doesn't matter.
They just have to be done.
Very good!
But how wiII you prove your
innocence,if you kiII me?
OnIy I know your reaI identity.
Perhaps that disccan be of use.
What do you think?
You have the disc?
No...
It was my Iove for you that
dragged me here!
Give me the disc.
I'm ready to send you to
any corner of the worId.
Think it over.
You must be exhausted
running from the poIice!
Not as much as from thinking
over and over...
...why you betrayed me?
Come on, get over it.
What betrayaI?!
This is the reaI worId.
You think Singhania asked me
before seizing Boris' entire empire?
I created the entire business!
With my inteIIigence and guts.
And now to get it back,
I can use thousands Iike you.
AII right.
I betrayed you.
You want an apoIogy?
I'm so sorry, Vijay!
Happy?
FeeI any better?!!
Use your head, Vijay.
There's stiII time...
Join me.
You wiII gain from it...
...and so wiII I.
That's the signaI!
AII teams move in.
I repeat aII teams move in.
Good boy! Come...
Put your gun down.
This is the poIice.
I repeat...
Put your gun down.
Stop, Vijay!
Don't make this mistake.
Hand him over to us.
PIease kiII me!
You wiII be making a huge
mistake if you Iet me Iive.
Don't Iisten to him!
He is trying to set you up!!
Shut up!
Remember! Wherever you go...
someday I wiII find you...
And that day wiII be the
Iast day of your Iife!
Don't Iisten to him, Vijay.
After that, Roma.
Then, Deepu.
I'II kiII them both...
...unIess you kiII me now.
In that case, Vardhaan...
...I'II be waiting for you.
Hurry up.
Take him quickIy!
Vijay?
HoId on pIease.
You finaIIy did it.
You proved your innocence.
It wasn't possibIe without you.
Thank you.
Sir, we must take you to
the hospitaI right away.
Yes, of course!
Come with me Roma.
Excuse me?
Can't she come aIong
with us?
I'm sorry sir.
Ma'am, pIease step aside.
Don't worry,
I'II see you at the hospitaI.
Vijay!
I Iove you.
Even I Iike wiId cats a Iot.
Come doser.
I Iike wiId cats a Iot.
WiId cats!
Mr. MaIik, where's that
ambuIance going?
One minute sir...
To the hospitaI.
Why, what's the matter?
He is Don!
''I Iike wiId cats a Iot...''
Don had said that to me...
whispered it in my ears!
If this is Vijay,
how did he know it?
Have given him the 2 mI of
diazepam(a sedative)?
Yes Sir, Giving it right now.
The doctors have kept him in
a sedated state.
AII the marks and scars
that were on Don's body...
...need to be made on you.
Sure.
On me!
I was about to teII you...
I got Deepu admitted to
MaIaysia's InternationaI SchooI.
When Don, that means you...
...go back to your companions...
...you'II be iII and wounded.
You wiII have Iost your memory.
The more you Iearn
about Don's Iife...
...the doser I'II get to
regaining my memory.
Thank you.
You think exactIy Iike the comicbook
hero, Chacha Chaudhary!
Weren't you trying to quit?
What aII can I quit?
I've quit everyone...
except you.
ReaIIy Don.
I thought that you wouId
get caught today...
...or that I'd Iose you.
To whom... Roma?
What about the discthat the poIice...
- That's fake.
What's on it means nothing!
Don't worry, sweetheart.
Now the reins of Asia's
underworId is in my hands!
I am the king!
As for catching me...
AIways remember this!
PIease...
Not onIy is it difficuIt to catch Don....