Fat Dog, you've finally appeared
If I don't catch you today,
I can't report back to base
After being in the force for this long,
have I ever arrested the wrong person ?
I'll leave that question for the judge
My philosophy is that...
Cops catch felons
Before the 1997 Handover
4 fives
Open
- Drink !
- This time doesn't count
Come, again... this bottle
7 sixes
You lost again
- Do you know how to play ?
Waiter, give her the rule book
Let me introduce you.
My younger brother, 'Tiger'
Brother Shan
- Hello, Brother Shan
- Hello
You're sweating a lot
That's my adopted brother... Zha
I have a lot of stuff to move.
There are many smugglers who can do it
- You want to a contract deal
- If you want to do Vietnam...
If must be us 3 brothers
Who would know the place better than us ?
We are Vietnamese
However you want to split it,
we'll go along with it
That's all there is to it
I lost again
It doesn't count.  Again, again
- 4 ones, I don't care.
- 4 ones ?
Is that right ?
Just because you don't think so
Police checking ID.
Move in
Check ID
You.  Get out here
I threw that bottle
So what ?
My apologies
Flashpoint
1996, January 2nd
Mongkok, Stanley St, whilst checking ID,
you assaulted a person
And broke the criminal's pelvis in 3 places
He spent 2 months in hospital.
How do you plead ?
1997, February 17th
Yaumatei, Miu St, Triad activity.
You assaulted another person
The criminal sustained serious head injury
According to the doctor,
has permanently lost his sense of taste
How do you plead ?
- 1996...
- That’s enough
I'm guilty
In the first half of this year,
on average you have been involved
in 14 cases per month
In each case, you have injured,
on average, 2.8 people
Half a year.  You have already broken
your record from last year
What's the problem with police
apprehending criminals ?
The person making the complaint is me
Are we here to arrest criminals, or police ?
Inspector Ma,
I know that you are an outstanding officer
You have the highest number of solved cases
But I want to remind you...
You need to pay attention to your
attitude and the way you operate
I don't think there is a problem
OK, you can leave
I've timed it
From when I came in,
you've talked for 1 hour
Who knows, perhaps in an hour,
I could have solved a case
Do you think you need
to reconsider you operating standards
Don't waste everyone's time
Good
That's $50k.
You want to bet with me ?
Betting so big with me,
you'll lose everything
Tiger... that's not how you play golf
It's not martial arts,
where you use that stance
Here, I'll teach you
It’s simple.
You hold the club
Most important is that
your thigh and shoulder is level
Look where you're aiming,
then look at the ball
Then swing through hard
That's what you shouldn't do
Again, again
Brother Zha. something's not right
Hold on
These friends don't know anything
You leave first
I asked you to move the stuff to Vietnam.
But if you're not blaming it on tornados,
then it’s because of storms
It’s been 2 months, friend.
You trying to send it to the moon ?
- You screwing with me ?
- Friend...
Big winds and big waves are inevitable
How about you ?
The blame will be on you if the ship sinks
The shipment was worth $80 Mil.
You've only paid back $2k
You should have told me earlier,
I would have sent it by courier
It’s just a few days by plane
If your shipping it by sea,
of course it will take a few months
Go home and wait
What did you say ?
Don't be stupid now
Otherwise, I'll kill you
You trying to scare me ?
Which one are you ?
Your boss won't come out,
and leaves you flunkies here instead
Get Tony out here !
Mother fucker
This is how we work
Don't do that in public
Put on some suntan lotion
Don't be like that. Is this revenge ?
Wait for me.  You two are always bickering
Tan
Don't let him play cool all the time
If you're going to arrest someone,
then just arrest them
You're always bashing people up.
Yeah, we know you can fight
Every time something happens
you come looking for me. Each time you come
looking for me, you want me to save you
And if something bad happens,
you put it on me.
What do you want me to do ?
What are you still complaining about,
muscle man ?
Taking off your clothes all day,
showing your arse
Last time you injured my arm, the doctor
said that there would be complications
You threw a whole bottle of wine in my face
If I didn't do something,
everyone would be suspicious
You fought back, remember
You hit me, of course I would retaliate.
You want me to lose my street cred ?
Street cred ? ! You're a cop ! Street cred.
Why don't you scream it out louder, idiot
We're all on the same side here,
you shouldn't have been so heavy handed
And you.
You know that he is a loose cannon,
and you still go light a fire under him
Who else would do that ?
When you got me into this,
you made it sound good
[ ?]
How long do I need to stay undercover ?
Don't talk about the past.
Let's talk about the facts
Who is your superior here ?
Oh, this again
What ?
There's such thing as a chain of command
Stop arguing.  The two of you will probably
never work together again anyway
Really ?
The Complaints department report is out
You remain team leader, but next month
you report to the music department
No need to be that harsh
You said it yourself.
There's a chain of command
I want to appeal
Keep at it.  It's up to you now
Same to you
Try not to be so picky.
Do whatever you want to do
If I die, then I die
I've lived my fill
What sort of playing is that ?
Wrong four times out of four
When was I wrong ?
12th section,
after the 6th note, the E sharp
We didn't hear anything wrong,
except for your shouting
As officers, we should take things seriously
You think we are mucking around ?
If you want to do that, leave
Not everyone does things your way,
Inspector Ma
- You...
- You must have been wrong
If an officer makes a mistake
They will ruin someone else’s life,
or their own
Take it seriously, and improve your work
What are you doing here, mum ?
I knew that you were here,
and wanted to let you know...
I'm going back to the country
Wait till I have a bit of free time,
and I'll take you back
I've already waited
Waited until Auntie ChangZhou is dead
I'll go back to pay my respects
If I like it there, I won't come back
Don't be like that, mum.
I'm very lonely here by myself
You worry all day, and have no time for me
Take care.  You shouldn't risk
so much going after crooks
What's the most important thing ?
It's preserving your own life
Without your life, how can you be a person
Take care. I'm leaving now
Everyone's just after a living
You took Shan's stuff
He called you out to negotiate,
and you turn it to a fight
And now you ask us to ignore it.  Why ?
Shan will disappear
If in the end, it is found
that you are involved, it won’t be good
If you leave it alone, nothing will happen
If it wasn't for the 3 of you,
nothing would have happened
Its better if you don't mess up our place
If we didn't take you in...
You'd still be floating in the sea
Our family was stuck in a refugee camp
It wasn't much different to living in prison
Why did we riot ?
Because we wanted a place of our own
If there are those that don't want us around
Then we go to war
Boss
How is it ?  All done ?
No good ?
No yet
It's not that the talks have broken down,
but they haven't started yet
Don't do anything for now,
otherwise there'd  be nothing to discuss
Don't be unreasonable now.
That's it.  Just do it
Wait...
You talk to them
Four eyes,
your wife takes your kid to school so early
It'd be unfortunate if they died
Are you threatening me ?
Of course I'm threatening you,
otherwise I wouldn't be shouting
you breakfast [ ? ?]
I also don't want
to hurt everyone’s feelings
If we can work this one out,
there will be a lot more opportunities
for us in the future
The four eyed woman in red...
taking her dopey four eyed kid
When I tell you to run over them,
I want you to floor the gas
OK
Quickly, have you thought it over ?
Your 4 eyed kid is
about to reach the entrance
I can't hear anyone answering me
We will ignore the situation with Shan
That's too quiet,
he won't be able to hear you
We will ignore the situation with Shan
Don't be careless now, y'hear
Zha, this is Da Xia
Let's go out for drinks when you're free,
we're all friends here
You should have said from the start
Have breakfast
I've spent the money to buy it...
are you not giving me any face ?
Run over them
OK
Turn
Are you a dog ? So obedient
Just because I said it, you'd do it ?
You could have killed someone
How can you be so dumb ?
Hey, it's my shout for your birthday tonight
I going to meet some friends
What ? You have friends ?
- Yes
- OK
Here, have fun
Thank you, Boss
Lily ?
It's me.
Are you free ?  Come over
What are you saying ?
Why are you shouting
at me out of the sudden ?
Hi May, I'm looking for your daughter
She's dead ?
I'm so sorry...
Bobby ? Its Wilson
What's up ? It's my birthday today
Don't talk about that stuff
I won the lottery, I want to spend it up
Hello ? Hello ?
Hi, is Julie there
Happy birthday
Thank you
Have you finished work ?
Not yet. I'll come over after work
OK, bye
Bye
It’s been a while
It hasn't been that long.
We met half a year ago
Have you been to Vietnam recently ?
If you're going, you should be careful
You might get caught
Even if I'm just going there
for a bowl of noodles ?
I thought you wanted
to stop selling alcohol,
Why are you still doing it ?
Do you think I like it ?
What else can I do ?
Unless...
You want me to be a prostitute ?
Don't say that.  Do something respectable
You know that 'Blue Girl' (beer)
[ ?] got popular because she sold herself
How about Carlsberg ?
He was unfortunate
He sold himself until he was an old man
before he got the brand
Otherwise it wouldn't have been
called 'Uncle Carls' (phonetic pun)
How about mine ?
[ ?] Now, it’s wrong to say
that threes no future in living large
[ ?] It was only because he lived large,
that he got the Johnnie Walker brand
I'll let myself out later.
Let's have a shower
Tiger, are we going to do this
This is not for you
Where so you want to go later ?
- I want to go for a picnic
- OK
Take our daughter away from here
Cops ! Get in !
You're lucky
You can leave hospital at anytime
If you keep fighting,
I won't let it go so easily
If you want to die, do it far away from me.
Don't keep involving me
I want to turn state witness
Come in
Inspector Wong, we've bought the criminal
That hurts, Inspector Wong
Do you have something to drink ? It’s hot.
Shan's spilled the beans about Tony
That’s great, go arrest him then
[ ?] We have to prepare
Those guys are insane,
if they wanted revenge,
the first to die would be you
I know, I'm more scared than you
Inspector Wong, please don't tell me
you're leading the team on this one
Relax, I won’t be leading.
I'm not the one that has been keeping
tabs on those Vietnamese kids
Get them to call back
that handsome and outstanding officer
This is a time
when the department needs him the most
It's you who needs him the most
Yes
Inspector Wong
Shut the door
What are you doing ?
Do you want me to die,
opening the door so wide
This time just speak
your mind if there is anything
Fine, otherwise,
why would we call you back ?
Help us out, solve this case,
and we can all go swimming OK ?
Yes, Inspector Wong
Here, put this on your head
Put it on
- Let me finish my smoke
- Forget it, put it out
You won't get any girls
Put it on, you fuckwit
Inspector Wong, he's not co-operating
Take him out for a beating, then
We're about to have the '97 Handover,
can you guys take things
a little more seriously ?
It’s their mother's big birthday tonight
The 3 will definitely come out tonight
First we take care of their associates
Four eyes, we want to interview you
back at the station
about the Vietnamese case
OK
Brother Wilson
- Eat, try a bit
- This way Sir
- It smells good, try it
- Auntie
Wishing you fortunes deeper
than the Eastern Sea, happiness higher
than the Southern mountains
That you become prettier year by year,
and that you are forever youthful
- Thank you...
- Thank you
Auntie, is your appetite good today ?
Stop talking to her, she’s stopped eating
- OK
- Leave
Auntie, enjoy your meal
If they don't return the calls,
then keep calling
You don't need me to tell you that.
What time is it already ? Nobody's here
- Have a bite
- Mother fucker, go !
Here, have a bit
Tiger
Come here
You're so loud
that mothers' not eating any more
Kneel
Apologize to mother
Mother, please eat some
Everyone's here
If no one goes to see Zha,
who will be there to celebrate
their mother's birthday ?
Have a mouthful
Eat
If you don't want this,
then what do you want ?
You don't like it ?
We'll order something else, OK ?
Sea cucumber ?
Abalone ? You don't like it ?
Then I'll order Birds Nest Soup for you
Sharks Fin ?
Big Brother, something's wrong
What's more important
than mother not eating ?
Eat
Tiger, feed mother
Time to work...
Stay here tonight
Someone will take care of you
You must catch them, Inspector Ma
Here
Have a mouthful
The food here doesn't suit you
I'll take you somewhere else, OK ?
- Tiger
- Where ?
Don't worry, let's go
Wilson, come here
Coming
- They're all waiting for you there
- Quickly
OK
Manager
Did you drive today ?
Which car ? Where is it parked ?
Hello ?
Tony, go and get the money
I'll leave with mother first.
We'll meet at the pier
Understood
Where to, Tony ?
To the garage
Second brother, what’s happening ?
- Have you seen these people ?
- What time was that at ?
- Inspector Ma
- What's the situation ?
There is someone injured,
an ambulance is coming
Xiao Ying
- Check his vehicle rego
- Yes
- Xiao Ya, tie up the loose ends here
Hello ?
Where are you ? I'm at your front door
I’m busy. I'll call you back later
I can wait here for you to come back
Not tonight
I've already made a spare key for you
I'll give it to you next time
Can you not talk on the phone
Sorry
Da Pao, the target vehicle is
a dark green Mazda MPV
Registration JL2933
Also, a maroon Acrua
Registration DE3654
Help out
Brother Tiger, did you lock the door ?
Oh yeah
I'll do it, you get in the car first
They're leaving with the money,
call you later
We can go now, Brother Tony
- Have you locked it ?
- I have
Sit in the back
OK
That's the car
Wilson, give me your phone
Brother Tony
Mother, sit tight
Don't drive so fast
Pull over
I said, pull over
Mother, sit tight
Jia Hui, ChangAn direction
Are you alright.  Hang in there
- I want to vomit.
- Vomit in here
You'll feel better after you bring it up
It's alright
We in the chemical factory district
Get out
We're going to the pier
Have a look
Hey, Sir
Are you alright ?
- How's Wilson ?
- Inspector Wong
Don't know yet, they're working on him
If he can be saved then it’s alright.
Stay calm
Hey, what are you doing ?
I won't let you off
What are you doing ?
What's it to you
Are you Julie ?
Assaulting a police officer,
I can charge you
So what if you're a cop ?
Wilson is my partner
He is also a cop
What are you in for ? Triad activity ?
I'm not a Triad member
No ? Then follow me
Call me Brother Zha
Do it
Brother Zha
Have you ever seen your
3 son's beating up others ?
I have 3 sons ?
I've never seen it
Sir, can you call the police for me ?
Sir, call the police for me
My son is missing
No one will come to see her on holidays
Perhaps, never at any other time either
Take care of her for me.
She tends to wander
It's my birthday. I'm 80.
You should have come earlier
I'm 80...
Xian Wei Zha,
there is sufficient evidence to show
That during the period from 1992 to Feb 1997
you were involved in smuggling,
aggravated assault, and Triad activities
Those are the charges. How do you plead ?
Not guilty
Hearing is set for May this year
Transfer the case
to the North Kowloon courts
Use this time to gather your reasons
You are denied bail
or permission to leave the country
All your assets are now frozen
Until sentence is passed
You're putting it all on me
You think you can convict me ?
Let's go
Take your wandering hands off me
I'll sue you for sexual assault
Let's go
3 months later
I won't be able to keep up with you soon
Then I'll slow down to wait for you
Take it slowly. You'll get used to it
Of course it will be slow
I've lost the use on a leg,
you think I'll get used to that ?
Everything's sorted out for you
Next week,
you'll be changed to a desk job
Desk job ?
Why don't you get the HK government
to pay me some compensation ?
Not only won't they pay,
but and I have to cough up my own legal fees
Are you kidding me ? Is this what
you call 'everything's sorted' ?
You know everything
I've done for the force
What have I got out of it ?
When I am out,
which path will lead to wealth ?
There are so many colleagues
waiting for your return, why don't you
persevere for a bit longer ?
I'm persevering now
How many people are waiting for my return,
just one ?
I've forgotten something,
don't wait for me
Slowly...
Big brother,
Tiger and I will return before your trial
I won’t give Wilson
or Shan the opportunity to testify
Tiger
Mother
3 sons
I'll take you home
Mother, do you remember this place ?
We used to live here
After I pickup Big brother,
we can leave HK
Give me
What are you smiling about ?
Nothing.  Perhaps injuring
your leg wasn't completely a bad thing
This way you can't run amok every day
And can stay home a keep me company
You've taken care of me for so long
You must like me a lot
Don't you know
that in the DNA of every woman
is encoded a natural ability
to care for others
On behalf of your godly inherited ability,
I hope that it will be like this forever
Thanks
Don't mention it
They're here
I want to get changed
- Careful
- Quickly
- Hello
Delivery
Be careful
Come and have a look.  It's good stuff
Is it that good ?
Its heavier than a throne
How can you live on the roof ?
I'm so tired
We only helped carry it
Jun, he bought it and delivered it
Where do you want it ?
Over there
OK
Move over
Put some muscle into it
Slowly, don't scratch it
That cost over $30k.  He paid for it himself
That's sincerity.  Accept it
- Do you have a power board ?
- Yes
Here, let me do that.
You guys are so useless
Where's the power point ?
I know you're no good with English,
so it's in Chinese
Like driving, it's automatic
Try using this button
You always said that your leg hurt
This can help improve
the circulation to your leg
The blood moves freely to the leg,
but the leg itself can't
Walking should be simple for a person
with your intelligence and constitution,
Train your right leg to be as mobile
as your left leg, and you'll be fine
What did you say ?
A joke
It’s so funny, but no-ones laughing.
Forget it.
I'll get it
Takeaway delivery
Smells good
What is it ?
Something good
Actually as a cop, there's a lot of pressure
Why don't you have a think about
doing something else ?
Have a good think about it.
Whatever you do, include me
I'm scared that you'll just hit everything
Actually,
the most important thing is having a family
I envy you
What's more important than family ?
If you're like me, you'll be happy
Come over and eat
Wait, let's take a picture first
OK, take a picture as we eat
No, picture first
This is my only request
Picture with the chicken ?
Whatever, just go with it
Come
The chicken is a bit cold.
Wait
Let's heat it up
If we don't improve our standards,
how can we become better people ?
It doesn't matter, we can still eat it
It’s so easy to heat it up
Chicken, 200 degrees
- I'll go help Inspector Wong
- (So don't eat it, Da Pao)
Is Julie alright ?
She's staying for observation
Are you alright ?
I'm temporarily
standing in for Inspector Wong
For security reasons,
you are all placed on leave
They're killing police,
and killing witnesses
Even a retard would know
that those Vietnamese are behind it.
And you want us to take a break ?
I'm worried for your safety
We're all risking our lives
You step in charge, and the first thing
you do is put us on leave ?
You're feeling confused
and emotional right now, please leave
When I was undercover, I was living under
the cover of fear every day
I thought that once I mangled my leg
that I would never have another good day
But even then, they blow up my home
Now you want me to leave ?
Madam,
The uniform you're wearing
was not meant to be so casually abused
If there is sufficient evidence,
I will arrest the people involved
Do you have any evidence ?
You guys ask Madam,
what else needs to be done
Where is Tony ?
Enough ! You're going to kill him
Give me your gun
He doesn't know.  Go to court tomorrow
Madam, what do we do now ?
The most important thing now,
is to find out what happened to Tony
The most important thing now
is to protect Wilson in hospital
He is the only witness
Xiao Ying, let's go
Let's go, Xiao Ya
What are you still writing ?
My mother has a place in the country
I really want to return to Song Flower River
Do you know
why it is called Song Flower River ?
There was a story from long ago
The Song tree used to be able to bloom
The people from my area,
all had to leave to earn a living
Before they left, they would pluck
a Song Flower as a memento
They told the tree that they were just
borrowing it, and would definitely
come back to return it.
But as they left, one by one
None of them ever returned
In the end,
the Song Flower could not blossom
In order to remember it
The people there named the river,
the Song Flower River
You're sick of this place ?
Actually, living in HK for this long
I've never felt that this place was home
Mother said that she would like us to return
The 3 of us
It's 2 months now
You don't like it ?
Everyone entering
the hospital must be searched
All the exits, doorways, backdoors,
back stairs, toilets,
Must all have men posted. Understood ?
Yes
Nothing must happen to Wilson
before he goes to court
The baby's hungry
Should we give it something to eat ?
I'll go buy something for you to eat
Don't go anywhere
Inspector Ma, wait
Wilson,
Inspector Ma told you not to go anywhere
Thanks
Police ! Move
Shots fired inside elevator.
The elevator is heading for the roof
Get backup.  Quickly
She's here with me
OK
What do you want ?
You're scared ?
Yes, yes
Whatever you want, just say it.
I'll do anything
Watch out.
You have a death wish ?
Move
Mummy
Throw the gun over here
Put the child down
I said throw the gun over
Can you hear me ?
Put the child down
Do you want her to die ?
Inspector Ma, what's the situation ?
Inspector Ma
It’s time to go to court
Hello ?
Wilson, where are you ?
I'm heading off to court
Did something happen to your Julie ?
Yes
Don't believe them.
They'll never just let her go
I have no choice
How can you not have a choice ?
You've chosen to help those bastards
I don't want anything to happen to her
I don't want anything
to happen to the both of you
Do you want to die with her ?
You need to record a statement
You beat the criminal to death
Then arrest me
Witness.  You can now testify
I don't remember anything
[ ?] My judgment is
The witness is unable
to testify because he claims amnesia
All charges against the accused...
are dropped due to lack of evidence
Tony
I'm out
Speak. Where ?
South ShengWei
Come quickly. I'll be waiting
Stop it.  Don't hit him
Stop hitting him
Wilson
I never thought
that I would be able to leave
I just want you to let her go
Wilson
Shoot, shoot him, Tony
Come on, you scared ?
Drop the gun, drop the gun
Your momma...
- Bastard
- Shoot
Don't talk about my mother !
Boss
I'm going to kill you two bastards
Fuck
I'll drive
Open the door
What are you thinking ? Open the door
What are you doing ?
Leave with me.  Don't go back
Leave with me.  You promised you wouldn't go
Ma Jun, come out and fight
Fuck you
Ammo
Mother
I have three sons, they're missing
Have you seen them ?
I've lost my 3 sons
Can you help find them for me ?
Have you seen them ? I have 3 sons...
I have 3 sons...
Have you seen them ?
You're finished, Tony
All the time I've been in the force,
have I ever arrested the wrong person ?
This question, I'll leave to the judge
My philosophy is...
that cops catch crooks
Everything that I've done...
Has been to maintain the peace.