Son Goku has broken Piccolo's dream of conquering the world.
Five years have passed very quickly.
Life has gone on peacefully.
But a new crisis is just around the corner.
My name is Gohan! The Mini Goku.
Gohan!
This tree finally becomes useful.
Welcome home. Goku, where's Gohan?
I'm starving.
What do you mean? Have you seen or heard from Gohan?
I haven't.
Then where has he gone to?
If we don't have our meal right away, you'll be late and Muten Roshi will be upset.
All right, let me go find him.
I don't think he'll be too far away.
Be back soon!
Thank you!
There's really nothing I can do about that kid.
I'm almost finished.
W-What was that?
Was that a meteorite or a UFO?
I'll go look.
It's not a meteorite. Then what is it?
So some people are still surviving on this planet...
That damned Kakarotto.
W-Who are you?
With a fighting level of 5, you're just trash.
Don't come near me!
I'll kill you!
What a weak and fragile race.
Someone with immense power...
A distance of 4880...
Is it Kakarotto?
Father... Father!
It's a butterfly!
Wait!
It's flown up so high.
Okay.
Pretend to die.
My hat!
My father gave me that!
Hey! GOHAN!
Father! Mother!
It's a bird!
It's so beautiful.
I'm Son Gohan.
Wait...
Mother! Mother!
Hey...That hat.
That hat belongs to my son, Gohan.
Where did you get it?
Where did you get it?!
Father! Mother!
Gohan!
GOHAN!
It's Father!
Hold on, I'm coming to rescue you.
Gohan!
Almost there!
Father!
Gohan!!
Mother! Mother!
Mother!
Gohan!
I'm scared!
I'm scared! I can't get down!
Father! I was so scared!
Gohan, you...
I don't know...
Gohan, let's go home.
Your mom is worried.
And we have to go visit Grandpa Kamesennin.
Damn that Kakarotto.
What is that power?
It can't be Son Goku.
No!
So it's not Kakarotto.
Who are you?  What brought you to see me?
Nothing's brought me to see you.
Then why are you here?
You want to die?
Those are very strong words.
Fighting force of 322.
So there's someone like this here as well.
But you're still no match for me.
You bastard, do you know who you are talking to?!
How can this guy have such an immense power?
What a foolish attempt.
All you can do is stir up dust.
Now it's my turn. Shall I show you how it's done?
Another unbelievably strong energy force...
It's over there. Distance 12909.
It's big. The biggest power on this planet.
It must be Kakarotto.
I-Impossible...
I'm shivering so hard I can't even move...
Can't he see the honor in being aSaiyajin? The strongest beings in the entire universe!
Kakarotto!
The strongest beings in the entire universe, the Saiyajins. Who are they? And who is Kakarotto?
There seems to be some mysterious relationship between this warrior and Goku.
Madoshi X
DBZ #001
AnimeHQ
Can we clear up the history of Goku?