"Bulma's House in Metro West"
- Have some cake too.
- Okay!
Good for you, Ha-chan!
Yes!
You'll come stay with me?
Congratulations!
Thanks.
Son Goku, you are really
going to leave this village?
Yeah, I really have to
find my grandpa's memento.
It's already getting late,
so spend the night here.
Thanks!
Good for you!
Well, tomorrow morning you'll be
saying goodbye to Goku too, Ha-chan.
Stay here tonight with him.
Starting tomorrow you'll
be staying at my place.
Okay.
See you later.
Good night!
Nope, no good.
What will you do now
that the radar is broken?
I'll go to Bulma's house
and have her fix it.
Bulma?
She's the one who gave me this radar.
Where does she live?
I think she said Metro West...
What direction is that from here?
Metro West...
that would be... let's see...
That way, maybe?
It is extremely far away!
How do you plan to go there?
Walk.
W-walk?!
But there's no other choice, is there?
There aren't any cars or
planes in this village.
Terrible...
I'll give you lots of lunches!
Really?!
Good luck, Son Goku!
Well you need to get
lots of sleep! Good night!
- Good night!
This is the first time
I have slept in a futon...
It feels so nice.
Eh?!
Y-you say you're going to walk?!
Yeah, what with
Kinto Un  broken and all...
What?!
A Kinto Un,  you say?!
Little boy, you rode on a Kinto Un?!
A kinton? (mashed sweet potato)
Yep, I did.
You know about Kinto Un,  old man?
I most certainly do!
When I was a lad there
were quite a few of them.
Isn't that right?
Yes, there were!
But since only those with completely
pure hearts could ride them,
...people who could ride them
grew less and less, and we
almost never see them anymore.
But being able to ride on a
Kinto Un  certainly is something!
But it broke and died.
Kinto Uns  don't die!
Did you actually try calling for it?
Nope. I thought it had died, so...
Try calling it!
Kinto Un!
Nothing's coming.
That's odd...
You were right! Here it comes!
Kinto Un!
Good for you, Kinto Un!
I really missed you, Kinto Un!
Good for you!
Oh! He really can ride on it!
Okay, I'm going now!
Take care of yourselves!
Son Goku, thank you for everything.
You are my best friend.
Good luck!
You better not lose to
the Red Ribbon Army!
Bye, Ha-chan!  Bye, everyone!
Alright, next stop, Metro West!
Let's go, Kinto Un!
Goku!
West is that way.
Oh, okay.
Later!
T-that's a kinton?
(mashed sweet potato)
Amazing...
Goodbye!
Be careful!
- Bye!
- Take care!
- Be careful!
Look, it can fly in the sky too!
Ki Kinto Un
We're out of the cold place now!
bit different from a mashed
sweet potato with chestnuts...
e delightful, delightful cloud
ven by the Turtle Hermit
Whoohoo!
ies easily and
lightly through the sky
me, Kinto Un!
, to the ends of the earth
o, that's funny
e ends of the sky
They're heading westward.
And at a tremendous speed!
Do Dragonball
This place is really bustling!
andpa's memento-
the 4-star ball
en all 7 are assembled
e dragon will
grant everyone's wish.
W-what is this place?!
She lives in a place like this?!
I'll look for her on
foot from here on out.
This place sure is noisy...
Hey kid! Watch where
you're goin'! Stupid!
Hey, can I ask you something?
Where is Bulma's house?
How the hell would I know?!
- What's going on? !
- What're you doing? !
Outta the way, runt!
What are they in such a hurry for?
Hey! Where is Bulma's house?
Eh? Bulma?
Yeah.
I have no idea. Go ask somebody else.
You live in the same
place but don't know her?
Oh man... I wonder if
she really lives here...
H-hey, wait!
Step on in.
Come on in.
Oh, you'll give me a lift? Thank you.
I'm saved! You're so
nice to drive me there!
Where you headed?
Bulma's house.
Where's that?
I don't know. I'm looking for it.
Sir, you do  have money, don't you?
Money? I don't got any.
Don't be stupid!
Getting into taxis
without saying a single word...
Idiot!
So here in the city you need
money to get directions to houses?
So what do I do to get money?
Huh? What is it?
Excuse me... Coming through...
Is something going on?
- Go for it!
- This guy's a pushover!
Here I come!
So, is there anybody else?!
If you beat me I'll give you
100,000 Zeni,  so how about it?!
Come on now!
What's the matter? Aren't there
any challengers out there?!
If you fight me and make me say I'm
beaten then you can get a ton of money!
I can get money?!
It's like the Tenkaichi  Tournament!
Hey, you do it.
Don't be stupid, that guy knows
Kenpo, I wouldn't have a chance!
I'll  fight!
Hold on a sec while
I take off my things.
Kid, you're good at jokes!
I'm not joking.
You wanna fight me?
Yeah! I get 100,000
Zeni  if I win, right?
Okay, whatever. Let's fight then.
Normally you'd have to pay
the 10,000 Zeni  match fee
but I'll make it free
just for you, kid!
Thanks! I'll go easy on you then.
Ready.
Then let's get this thing started.
Alright! Here I go!
Be my guest.
C-could you see that?
Not at all...
Are you beaten?
O-of course I'm not beaten!
Oh.
I-it looks like you've studied
a bit of Kenpo somewhere, kid...
Yeah, I trained!
Okay, the match starts again!
Okay, here I go again!
It would be best to hurry
and say you're beaten!
Little punk!
Watch out!
I- I am beaten...
Thanks a lot!
Now I got some money!
Who should I ask who would know?
Hey!
Take a look at that kid's hand!
Whoa, what a load of money!
Hey you, little boy!
Come over here!
Over here, over here!
What is it?
Right this way.
Are you going to give me something?
We're the ones who're
gonna get something!
We'll take that money now.
You'll tell me where Bulma's house is?
Stop yer yackin' and
make with the money!
How come? Bleh!
You're not going to tell
me where Bulma's house is?
You brat! You want me to kill ya?!
Punk kid!
L-let me see...
Bulma-chan's  house? W-wouldn't a
police officer know if you asked one?
A person named
"Police Officer"? Thank you!
N-no, you're welcome.
If you're looking
for a police officer,
that person over there is one.
Thank you!
Here you go!
Hey! "Police Officer"!
A girl by the name of Bulma? You
don't know her citizen number either?
Don't know what to tell you...
Let's see...
She looks like this!
T-that's a little...
You don't know?
Oh well, I'll check
the computer for you.
Normally we aren't allowed to
do this for civilians, though.
B-u-l-m-a...
That's a rare name so it
shouldn't take long to find out!
There are three people,
which one is it?
Is it this person?
No!
Then what about this one?
It's Bulma!
This is amazing!
This is the daughter of the
head of Capsule Corporation!
Hey! So where is Bulma's house?!
It's a little far so
I'll take you there.
Get on.
I don't have any money.
Stupid! You think I charge for money?!
Sorry for repeating myself, but are you
really an acquaintance of Bulma-san?
I told you, I am!
Okay, we're here.
This is it?! What a huge house!
Bulma!
The reunion with Bulma, at last!