Defending champion, Beau Brandenburg,
wins the fiirst race of the season.
The big story at Miami's Grand Prix
is the second-place fiinish...
...ofrookie, Jimmy Bly.
-Where's he from?
-Racing's new heartthrob.
-Second place in England.
-A contender.
Bly is a natural.
We're in Rio for race six.
A surprise win for rookie,
Jimmy Bly.
Brandenburg's fiirst season loss.
A second incredible upset.
Bly wins in Michigan.
Brandenburg loses.
We're down under for the 1 1th race.
Brandenburg's lost three in a row.
Bly and Brandenburg are tied
for the championship.
Bly looks nervous.
-Cracks are showing.
-Part ofbeing a rookie.
It'll be interesting to see how long
this young man can keep this up.
Hey, DeMille, you promised
a sound bite for tonight's sports!
Jimmy, only talk to this woman.
This reporter only.
DeMille, can we call it?
Wait a minute. Come here.
Think. Let me explain something.
These people love you and buy tickets.
The ones with cameras help sell them.
-l need to focus on tomorrow.
-lt is tomorrow.
This is part of the game.
ln five years, when you're
a brand name, you'll thank me.
Beau, you've had problems before
and never acted like this.
Things change.
Why can't you Just respect
what l need?
A bad season, so l'm
out of your life?
This is my life!
This is not your life!
This is what you do for a living.
Look...
...if l'm gonna win,
l need my mind there, not here.
So right now this is my life.
This is your life.
What am l?
A distraction.
l'm sorry.
We're in lap 193
of this 225-lap race.
The defending world champion,
Beau Brandenburg, is in fiirst...
...driving better than we've
seen him drive all season long.
Christian Fittipaldi
sits in second place.
And the young rookie, Jimmy Bly,
sits back in third.
Bly's been shaky
for the last few races.
He's such a promising star,
just got raw talent.
If Carl Henry could
get him to relax...
...there'll be no stopping him.
Laps wind down.
It's a tightpanel at the front.
Bly tries to make his move
on the number 1 1 ofFittipaldi.
Motorola car comes to the inside.
And he does it!
Sweetpass by the rookie, Bly.
Great. You're doing great.
Close on Brandenburg?
Everybody wants to know that.
Bly really seems to be having a
problem with consistency and focus.
Even so, he now fiinds himself
in second place.
With just 10 laps to go,
Brandenburg leads.
You're looking good.
Right there.
Brandenburg's experience shows.
He knows how to take the corners.
Jimmy Bly coming into the corner
has a tendency to slow down.
-A lot ofpressure on young Bly.
-Pass for chrissake!
What is he afraid of?
Follow Brandenburg's line.
Are you following his line?
I can't. Can Ipick another line?
Take Brandenburg's line.
Bly drafts up into the vacuum
behind Brandenburg's car.
But every time he steps out of that
vacuum he runs into a wall ofair.
-Slows him down and affects momentum.
-Lay it out, Jimmy. Lay it out.
You better win this thing.
Win it or you'll look like a fool.
Bly down to the inside,
tries to get alongside him!
Very, very close as they
try to come off the corner.
Can Bly getpast him here?
It's gonna be close.
Son ofa bitch, not again.
He's gone.
Bly makes his move,
nails the throttle.
They touch and Bly's in trouble!
Can he keep it off the wall?
He slides to the inside.
Bly's spinning out ofcontrol.
Damn it!
And it gives the win over
to the defending world champion.
This is Beau Brandenburg's day.
This is Beau Brandenburg's
fiirst victory in three races.
He's gotta be happy.
Brandenburg's back in the lead in
the race for the world championship.
Crusher, it's time
to call Joe Tanto.
Hello?
You'll never be up before me,
old friend.
How you doing, Carl?
l was Just...
...feeling nostalgic.
You still there?
-Can you push it to the ragged edge?
-Yeah, l think so.
-And the fear?
-lt's gone.
-Fear's never gone.
-Yeah, maybe.
-What about Memo?
-I'm making a change.
Memo's out, you're in.
You're driving for me again, Joseph.
Welcome back to the big show.
What is it, Jimmy?
Because this bad thing
is coming at a bad time.
-So talk to me.
-l said, it's nothing.
What am l, a piece of wood?
-l'm talking to you!
-Look, l can't do this.
l can't handle it.
l'm being pulled in 10 directions.
l thought l could handle it,
but l can't.
You can, and you will.
l don't care, we deal with it.
Okay?
Then stop pushing
like you're one of them.
Wait. ''Them''?
Like l'm the enemy? ''Them''?
That's great. That's....
Ever since you started kicking my ass
on everything with wheels...
...it's been us. My brother
has the touch, l don't. Fine.
But what l do have
is allegiance to you.
So don't doubt me. Don't do that.
l saw this 8-year-old,
goofy-looking kid...
...on a piece of Junk go-cart,
come from three laps behind...
...to beat guys twice his age.
You rebounded then, right?
We'll rebound now.
Everybody trips. That's okay.
That's life.
lt's how fast you get up that counts.
So get up, Jimmy.
But get up fast.
We just got word from Carl Henry
that Joe ''The Hummer'' Tanto...
... will replace Memo Moreno...
...as Bly's teammate.
Excuse me.
How about an autograph, cold fish?
-What are you doing here, Joe?
-Glad to see you're still warm.
They figured you needed
some competition.
Now there's a familiar face.
Sophia!
Don't call her, please.
What's wrong?
-Joe--
-Still working here, huh?
-We haven't seen you in a long time.
-No, no, no.
You keeping him under control?
-You driving?
-Yeah, back with Carl Henry's team.
-Wow.
-Yeah.
That's great.
Well....
l'll see you around, Joe.
-She wants to kill you. What happened?
-Nothing.
Nothing?
Why'd they put you in a car again?
All you do is get in the way.
-Somebody thinks l got something left.
-Somebody?
-Yeah.
-What do you think?
l think it's will over skill.
Will over skill?
Like Detroit in '97?
-Accidents happen.
-Accidents?
You almost killed me.
You know, Beau, l'm Just
glad l'm back. l really am.
-l'm different now.
-You...
...will never be different.
Be seeing you in my rear-view, Joe.
-Excuse me.
-Yeah.
Please, picture. Please.
Picture? No problem.
You gotta be kidding, right?
Smile.
How you doing, guys?
-Joseph.
-Carl.
l want you to meet our sponsors.
You've been gone a while, Joe.
Not really. Been up north
testing cars for us.
Shouldn't he wear our hat?
lt's a little damp, isn't it?
-Just kidding.
-l'm sorry.
-This is Lucretia Jones.
-Hi.
-How you doing?
-Call me ''Luc.''
Luc, l think l can remember that.
She's a Journalist and will
be with us all season.
She's doing an expose
on male dominance in sport.
-Will you have time to talk?
-Gotta ask the legend.
-Whatever he wants.
-For a beautiful lady, of course.
-No speeding tickets, Joseph?
-No, no speeding tickets.
-Bye.
-Nice to meet you.
-See you later, Luc.
Give him hell, Joe.
l thought Tanto was dead,
for chrissake.
Whoa!
Now that ex-wife of yours...
...that's a piece of work.
Divorces you and marries
a fellow driver.
l'm realizing how much
l didn't miss you.
-You missed me.
-Next subJect.
l got a rookie driver. His name
is Jimmy Bly. He's won five races.
He's starting to find ways to stumble.
l'm not losing that lead.
lt won't happen.
-Memo drives great. What happened?
-Memo forgot his damn Job.
His Job is to support the team.
To support Jimmy Bly. So he's gone.
l could've hired 100 young turks
to take his place...
...but l wanted somebody
who's been to the top...
-...and stumbled down to the bottom.
-Thanks for reminding me.
l wanted somebody that
gets his attention.
-Maybe gains his trust.
-Why?
Because you're gonna help him...
-...my old friend.
-Carl.
Let's get something straight.
l thought you wanted me to race.
No.
-l'm gone.
-No, you're not.
l'm not finished yet. We go back.
We go way back.
l carried you for six years.
You owe me, Joe.
All you gotta do is help this kid.
Who knows? You might enJoy it.
You got one offer on the table.
Your choice.
-What did you give him?
-Gas money.
There are a hundred guys more
qualified to back Jimmy. Why him?
Because when he's on, he's
one of the best you'll ever see.
Just sit back and watch.
What's he doing?
He's Just wound up.
Doing his coin bit will relax him.
-What's his coin bit?
-He'll hold a slide...
...going full out, then go over
to pick up three coins.
Not with the front tire,
any fool can do that.
He'll snatch them up with
the back one and not lose speed.
-There's no way.
-You don't want to bet me.
There's number one.
There's number two.
What's that sound?
-lt sounds like humming.
-Yep.
Why is he humming?
Some crazy thing he does
when he's pushing close to the edge.
-Anyone else ever do that?
-Not among the living.
-Want to back off, Joe?
-Let him go.
Let's see if he's still got it.
You passed the audition, and l'm not
mopping up the mess, Hummer.
Not bad, Hummer.
-Your humming's getting better.
-Let me drive again?
l said your humming,
not your driving.
Go talk to the kid.
How you doing? l'm Joe.
-Nice run out there.
-lt was okay.
Hey, listen, l liked Memo.
He's a good guy, good driver.
Just so you know.
We didn't have any problems.
Two out of three, huh?
Why don't you and me grab a cup
of coffee and talk some strategy?
The strategy's simple: He drives,
you block. You block, he wins.
We gotta hit it.
We got a publicity blitz.
Can't we push that back?
Come on, it's part of the contract.
Talk to you later.
Just channel through me, okay?
l channel well.
Appreciate that.
Start coming down.
Last week's big news was Jimmy Bly's
close brush with the wall.
Bly was trailing Beau Brandenburg
on turn four of the last lap...
... when he lost control
at over 200 miles an hour.
I don't know what's going on
with Bly's driving.
It went so well earlier in the season,
surprising everyone.
He can't seem to
get it together on the track.
All eyes will be on Bly
at tomorrow's Toronto Grand Prix....
So, Luc, what have you learned
since you've been here?
-l used to think you Just put gas in--
-Fuel.
-Get it right.
-Fuel. l knew that.
Put the fuel in and push the pedal...
...and that was it.
That is embarrassing,
that's what that is.
Joe, with only 10 races
left in the season...
...why'd they get you?
What makes you special?
Oh, special l'm not.
Do you feel awkward being back?
-Something you're not telling me?
-Well, rumor has it you...
...were the circuit's wild man.
You married a woman named Cathy.
You cleaned up, stopped
living the old lifestyle...
...things didn't work out.
-lnteresting, only that's not me.
-lt's Just what l heard.
-l don't want to upset you.
-Game's over.
You actually have something to say.
These young drivers have barely lived.
Your life is so colorful
by comparison.
You know, Luc, l wouldn't remind
you what a fool you've been...
...and then insult you
by calling it colorful.
-l'm sorry.
-So don't Judge me until you know me.
-How do l do that?
-By finishing this game, wiseass.
Wiseass? Right.
Good luck.
Hi.
-So.
l heard about you and Beau.
And l'm sorry.
Thanks.
lt's my problem.
l'm sorry, Sophia.
l didn't mean to...
...get into your business.
l'm trying to talk.
l Just came out of
a three-year relationship.
-That's a long time.
-Yeah, it's a long time.
When you get used to someone,
it's not....
l don't know.
What?
-l shouldn't be here.
-Wait. No.
-l shouldn't be doing this.
-Sophia, please.
Stay.
l'm not looking to get involved.
l'm not over him.
l understand that.
l'm Just looking for a friend.
You sure?
-Yeah. l think so.
-Think?
Do you want to go sit down,
talk for a while?
Yeah. Yeah, l would.
Welcome to Toronto, Canada,
and this year's Toronto Molson Indy...
...and ESPN's live coverage
of this race.
-Hi, l'm Jeff Oaken.
-l'm Dave Wershafter.
...and this is race day
beside the lake.
Because it is time.
All the qualifying
and practicing is done...
...it's time to play the cards
and see how it goes down.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome today's drivers:
Max Papis, Joe Tanto...
...Jimmy Bly, Beau Brandenburg....
This race is being watched
by millions...
...from Finland to Australia.
Over 250,000 people expected
here in Toronto alone...
...from across the world.
1 10-lap race on a street track.
A lot ofdifferent styles,
but the street track...
...is considered as being
the most hazardous.
That's because it takes place
on ordinary city streets.
You guys here in Toronto
should be the loudest folks to cheer.
Well, well, well.
So, what about me?
How do l look?
Or do you still hate answering
loaded questions?
Go ahead, ask me.
-You love him?
-l love a lot of things.
-Why marry him?
-He's a younger, better you.
Ouch.
-You want to know more?
-No.
You left me, with nothing,
l might add.
Just as Memo and l are starting to
get something here, you steal his Job.
And he still likes you.
How pathetic is that?
l don't understand this
''brotherhood of speed'' crap.
Just answer me one question.
Does hurting me make you feel better,
or does that come naturally?
You think you were better than me.
You weren't.
Hey.
-Joe.
-Memo.
Hey, did Cathy say anything bad?
She better not. Look at you.
How you been, good? Huh?
Listen, l'm sorry about all this.
Somebody had to do it,
why not an old friend?
That makes it even worse.
-You never called about our wedding.
-No, l didn't.
Hey, friends don't do that.
lf they have problems, they talk.
We always did that.
Sometimes good things happen
from bad ones.
But, if it'd make you happy...
-...l'll divorce her.
-Memo, what are you doing?
Right now, right here, today.
l'm divorced.
But only if you marry me.
-Get out. Come on.
-Please. You know, l get so lonely.
Yeah, you look like you're lonely.
l Just want to enJoy my life.
My real life...
...not this one.
And Cathy does that for me.
Amigo, l have to go. Show these
maricas what a real driver can do.
-l'll do my best.
-Okay.
Bye.
Sophia!
Where are you going?
Good luck today, Beau.
Everyone excited to see how
Joe Tanto does today.
His fiirst race since
he nearly lost his life.
-Stop bothering people, wiseass.
-Don't mess with me.
The season's rookie leader, Bly.
It'll be interesting to see if this
young man can handle the pressure.
-What's she doing here?
-lt's all right.
No, this is not all right.
Brandenburg's ''whatever''
enters your life by accident?
-''Whatever''? Hi, l'm Sophia.
-That's your problem.
DeMille, come on.
Weren't you being pulled
in too many directions?
-Man.
-That'll make more legroom for us.
We're ready in Toronto. Time for
the big one to get underway.
Working your way down the track?
Brandenburg is on the pole
fiirst again.
As you have heard,
we are ever so close.
-We have fiive minutes to race time.
-Joseph.
Gentlemen, to your cars.
Hey, Jimmy. Good luck, man.
Thanks, man.
All the racers down in pit lane now...
...are in the fiinal stages
ofgetting ready for this race.
Pace cars are standing by.
We are almost underway
here in Toronto.
Ladies and gentlemen,
are you ready for racing?
Gentlemen, start your engines.
Starting today's race from
the pole position, Beau Brandenburg.
Second qualifiier, Dario Franchitti.
Third, Christian Fittipaldi.
They're warming their tires to desired
temperature for better traction.
This is the fiirst
offour warm-up laps.
All eyes on the green flag
ready for it to drop.
Sixteenth, Joe Tanto.
The race is underway!
They roar toward the fiirst turn,
a right-hander, a treacherous gate.
They funnel down into that corner.
The second passing opportunity
liesjust ahead.
Someone's in trouble!
Two cars sideways, the Visteon car!
Right through the barrier!
He's flipping up end over end!
The Visteon car in big trouble!
An incredible accident!
This puts us at
a full course yellow.
It'll give the drivers a chance
for their fiirstpit stops of the day.
One of the strategies to this game
is when to bring your man in.
An extra second in the pits can cost
a driver a place or two in this race.
There goes Brandenburg.
Bly, and Tanto is out.
All three with very fastpit stops,
just over 12 seconds.
As Andrettiand Tracy almost
get together on the exit!
But now Brandenburg's in front,
Jimmy Bly in second.
l want you to go after Brandenburg.
Go right now. Go!
We have some really interesting
driving by Bly behind Brandenburg.
-l can't find a hole.
-Don't look for a hole. Make a hole.
Back to full speed,
Bly in pursuit ofBrandenburg.
He's right there.
He tries him at every corner.
Jimmy, you got 10 laps to go.
Conserve the tires.
You talk into that again,
l'll make you eat it.
Don't conserve anything. Go get him.
Ifhe's gonna overtake Brandenburg,
it'll happen in Turn 3.
And it's right--
Oh, look at that!
What a way to move!
Jimmy Bly grabs the lead away
from Brandenburg. It's magical.
And Jimmy Bly hasjust taken the lead!
-Joe.
-Yeah?
l want you to pit now.
Why? l don't need to pit, Carl.
l want you to pit.
In a very unusual move, Carl Henry
hasjust called Tanto into the pits.
He hit the marks.
l know what you're doing, Carl.
lt's wrong.
They're changing the tires, refueling.
I see no movement on the chassis,
no wing adjustments.
l'm not asking you to like this, Joe.
Just work with me.
In the meantime, the veteran
Brandenburg behind Bly.
That's gotta worry the young rookie.
One mistake, that's all it'll take.
-Hold. Hold, Joseph, hold.
-Come on, come on, damn!
Come on, Carl, let me out of here!
Bly in front, Brandenburg second.
Carl, l can't hold him off.
Now, Joe. Go get that son ofa bitch.
They release Tanto,
and he roars out of the pit!
I don't know what
Carl Henry and his team were thinking.
Tanto's making a very fast exit
from the pit. Look at this!
Tanto slices in between
Bly and Brandenburg!
The offiicials aren't gonna
like that one.
Tanto has to allow Brandenburg
to pass him after a move like that.
One lap to go now.
It's Bly and Brandenburg battling
it out in the last half-mile.
Brandenburg tries to the inside!
They come off the turn neck and neck.
Who's it gonna be?
And here they come!
The checkered flag is out!
It's Jimmy Bly,
the winner of this race!
As they go around the track,
the checkered flag is flown, and....
Very good strategy, Carl. Thank you.
What a battle between
Jimmy Bly, Beau Brandenburg.
This time, the young rookie
took it to the veteran.
You did all right today, Joseph.
Don't ask me to do that again.
Jimmy, after four lackluster
performances, is Jimmy Bly back?
Well, l hope so.
Everyone falls down.
lt's Just how fast you get up, right?
Beau, the win could be
called controversial.
-Well, a win is a win.
-So you won't protest?
No, but l will have some lunch.
Anyone wants to Join me?
Thank you.
EnJoy. This won't happen again.
Jimmy, want to talk later?
lf he wants to talk, he'll be
talking to me, okay? Come on.
lKnow how much you'll be worth if
you win? They'll buy you in sections.
Your eyes to a sunglass company,
your arm to a watch company.
Your foot to a shoe company. Or maybe
you'd like to keep some parts.
-Come on, he Just finished racing.
-Hey, you're not here.
-DeMille.
-What?
What's so wrong with what she said?
Nothing.
What are you doing?
-Swimming.
-Swimming?
That's swimming to you, huh?
l don't think that's swimming.
That's a little beyond.
l've never seen anything like that.
Pretty fantastic.
Where'd you learn how to do that?
-l was raised by frogs.
-Raised by frogs?
-Well, l'm glad you escaped.
-Oh, thank you.
Jimmy, what's on your mind?
-How does Beau do it?
-Do what?
Stay on top. Stay focused.
He drives scared.
No, l don't think so.
That guy is ice.
To you, he's ice. lnside he's scared.
But he likes it.
He says it makes him try harder.
He says the day he's not afraid
is the day he'll stop.
You're Just as good.
And the day you stop caring...
...what other people think and make
yourself happy, you'll be even better.
Come on.
Don't you ever stop running,
cold fish?
Block me again
and l'll put you into the wall.
Well, that's not gonna happen again.
Believe me.
-What are you trying to prove?
-Got nothing to prove.
No, you proved you could do very
little with very much. Forget it.
Why do l waste my time
talking to this guy?
Because no one else
likes your arrogant ass.
-So that's it.
-That's it. Mystery solved.
While you're in this good mood,
do yourself a favor.
-What?
-Take her back if she wants you.
Stay out of my business, Joe.
What are you doing?
l'm Just talking.
You do want her back, right?
Why do you care?
You two have a lot of history.
That doesn't go away so fast.
-l pushed her away, Joe.
-But you weren't thinking right.
l wasn't thinking at all.
You know, it's really hard when--
When l see her with him.
And l did it, you know?
lt was me. l'm responsible for it.
You wanted to win no matter the cost.
-You want me to talk to her?
-No, Joe, don't do that.
You don't want either of us
to talk to her?
That's Just great.
Hey, Beau, if this is about pride,
you better forget it.
-That's how the whole thing started.
-What would you do?
Me? To get someone back
that l really love?
Get that rock out of my stomach?
Crawl.
-You'd crawl?
-Crawl.
-You never crawl.
-l'd crawl till there's nothing left.
Come on, champ. Use your head.
Welcome to ESPN's coverage...
...of the Twin Rings Race
qualifying section.
And we're live
from the Japan Motor Speedway...
...in front of 120,000
spectators today.
Open wheel racing,
a very popular sport in Japan.
One day to the event,
and it's been a great day so far.
You should ask Jimmy how it is
to have the best manager.
With the fiinal runjust completed,
the top fiive best times were:
Brandenburg, Andretti, Gugelmin,
Montoya and Fittipaldi.
An interesting sideline: This year's
rookie point leader, Jimmy Bly...
...only managing a tie
for 10th place.
Relax, dude, don't shove.
Hey, don't shove. We're friends.
Jimmy! Jimmy, why 10th today?
How come this never happens to me?
All right!
-You seem preoccupied.
-l'm thinking about Jimmy.
You know, Carl thinks he can't cut it.
l think he can. lt's Just--
lt's tough to get close
to this kid. lt is.
l think Carl cares more about
helping you than helping Jimmy.
-You're way off.
-l can see in the way he looks at you.
l mean, with Jimmy it's business.
With you, it's personal.
Keep it steady, Jimmy.
Keep your eyes out of the mirror.
With a steady drive, Beau Brandenburg
has managed to catch up to Jimmy Bly.
The veteran working both sides,
doing all he can to make Bly nervous.
Don't let him intimidate you.
l don't know if l can do this.
-You should talk less and drive more.
-Looking great, Jimmy.
Brandenburg knows every inch
of this racetrack.
He moves inside ofBly,
lets him know he's there.
Let's take him down.
Now it looks like he's gonna try
him on the outside.
They're neck and neck!
He gets by!
Brandenburg is in the lead.
That's some incredible driving
by Beau Brandenburg.
Bly's teammate, Tanto, got Bly to
the front of the pack earlier today.
Jimmy, don't let him get to you.
Shake it off.
-l'll get it back. l can get it back.
-Stay on him.
Now we'll see ifBly has learned
through this season.
Can he come back and regain the lead?
-Bly will try it on the high side.
-Don't overdrive the car.
-The suspension's getting loose.
-Bly is looking everywhere:
Inside, outside, high, low,
just nowhere to go.
Don't overdrive the car.
The rear is drifting.
Jimmy, keep it steady.
Don't overdrive the car.
They're in the fiinal lap.
This is it. Final turn.
Bly still all over the place.
He's coming up around, going high.
Bly's in trouble!
Bly's in serious trouble!
He's off to the gray stuff!
Oh, he slams into the wall!
Oh, my God!
Are you okay, Jimmy?
Safety trucks are rolling.
The crowd on its feet, silent.
We all await word on the fate
ofrookie driver, Jimmy Bly.
They pull him out from under the car.
He gives the crowd a wave.
Jimmy Bly, after that
awesome accident, is all right.
And the crowd responds to it.
What a waste.
It's my pleasure to welcome you
to glimpse into the future...
...and the 1000 horsepower
extreme machines...
...that'll race us
into the millennium.
Kindlyjoin me in welcoming
the power and the glory.
Well, Joe. Now what part of formal
didn't you understand?
Wait a minute.
Oh, my mistake, yeah.
l'm gonna go get a drink.
-You look very nice.
-Thank you.
-Hey, rebel.
-Yeah.
What you got there?
lt's something l want
to give Jimmy later.
Be selective who you spend time with.
Extend yourself.
These people make everything happen.
-He's right.
-You'll stay around, right?
l'll be around.
You do know your way around,
don't you?
-l like your brother.
-l liked him first.
-DeMille?
-Nina. Exactly who l wanted to see.
-You look fantastic.
-Thank you.
Earlier today you said that Jimmy
has to find it off the track.
-What'd you mean?
-Here we go with the questions.
Gotta find that quiet spot.
lf your mind's not right,
you will get torn apart.
So you better buckle up.
lt's gonna be a bumpy ride.
l can't believe that line still works.
Now this is either very
unprofessional, or naive...
...or she swallowed your bullshit
and loved the taste.
-Where's Memo?
-Replacing you. Working his way down.
Joe, if you don't get it by midnight,
you're probably not gonna get it.
And even if you do,
l don't think it'll be worth it.
Just an observation.
Excuse me.
You make any new friends?
Like these people want to talk to me.
When the season's over....
-What?
-l was thinking...
...maybe we could go someplace.
l've never even had a vacation.
-Never?
-Never.
No pressure, all right?
Just think about it.
Two minutes, please?
What a coincidence.
ls this a little experiment
for you or something?
Dark chapter you can tell
your friends about?
Maybe you like being man-handled.
That l can understand.
But it's the being dumped part
that's kind of a drag.
So you were Just used and abused?
Was that attitude?
Saucy. Good for you.
And next time l'm around, look at him.
He ain't over it.
Your mascara's running.
That's cute.
Stupid bitch.
-So, are you two enJoying the evening?
-l'll wait over there.
lf you win a championship,
what would you do first?
l don't know, really.
You've had some peaks
and valleys over the season.
What have you learned?
What have you learned
that you never realized before?
-That it's another world.
-Where air is rare.
Your team can take it all
with a strong show in Germany.
How do you prepare
for something like--?
There you have it, James Bly obviously
very pensive about the upcoming race.
-Yeah, well--
-What's happening?
-What's it look like?
-Jimmy.
-You came with me.
-Maybe she'll leave with you...
...but what l have to say
you don't need to hear.
Just let him talk.
lt doesn't mean anything.
-Yes, it does mean something.
-What, Beau? What does it mean?
We should probably Just go.
Sophia, let's go.
-Don't do that.
-Don't do what?
-That's none of your business.
-Come on. What's going on?
-lt's nothing, DeMille.
-Back off.
Come with me for a second.
Can l talk to you?
-You're doing this all wrong.
-l know.
l do everything wrong.
-Excuse us.
-l can't believe this is happening.
l don't want to spend
more time away from you.
l miss you.
l miss you too.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Do not go over there. Trust me.
Jimmy, please. Calm down, calm down.
Don't blow this. Not over her.
This is not eighth-grade prom.
How you act,
these things are important.
-Jesus Christ!
-He's giving her a ring.
-That's not good.
-Please take it back.
Whatever it is, you can deal
with it later. This is not the time.
Just work with me on this.
Jimmy.
l'm so sorry.
Go. Just go.
l don't--
-Let me explain it to you.
-Hey, you need--
Get away from me.
-Play somewhere else.
-Just listen.
-Five minutes.
-Go away!
-Jimmy.
-Don't push me, don't push me.
-Go.
-Fine, fine, okay!
-Play your game somewhere else.
-Get the hell away from me.
Move, move, move! Move!
l need backup!
Pull over!
Come on, Jimmy, pull over!
Get away from me, man. Just--
You want to go through me? Come on.
l want to fight him.
-For what?
You weren't there?
What do you think he did,
take your woman away?
Why did l let him take her away?
She was gone.
She was always gonna leave.
What do you know anyway?
Your brother puts so much
pressure on you...
...you looked for an edge.
You figured she was it.
Why do you act like you care?
l'm Just a thing to you,
part of the Job.
You pick up a check to help me out
since you didn't help yourself.
Why does that make you better?
lt doesn't.
Why did you take the car?
l don't need to be pushed.
-Go on, say it.
-Forget this.
You hoped this would get you thrown
out. You're looking for the exit.
What are you talking about?
You don't know who you are anymore!
You think you've got to be perfect
or you're a failure.
Well, forget that. Just forget it.
l was gonna give this to you
before all this went down.
lmpressive, isn't it?
-What is it?
-lt's the first thing l ever won.
lt was probably the last time
l ever felt pure victory.
No pressure, nobody breathing
down my back.
Just driving because l loved it.
Pure.
That's where you've gotta get back to.
Doing it naturally, for you.
l don't have your gift, but l do
have some things you don't have.
l got will and l got faith.
Don't laugh, l'm serious.
l believe that you can will yourself
into anything and do anything.
Having faith, that's like
believing in--
That's like having a good disease,
it's contagious.
Hang with people that have it,
you're gonna catch it.
That'll change your attitude.
And winning is an attitude.
So if you trust me--
No, if you trust yourself...
...by this season's end,
you'll be on top or you won't.
But l guarantee you're gonna know
what Jimmy Bly is made of.
Outside Chicago,
at the chicane it goes up...
...and comes down right where you
got Brandenburg--
ls that when l dip down?
Forget it.
l'm tired of these spoons.
We play with spoons.
-Say, ''Ah.''
-Ah.
Welcome to Germany.
Home ofbeer...
...the Autobahn and Beau Brandenburg.
-Qualifying begins tomorrow.
-With two races left...
...Beau is leading in the race
for the world championship.
Jimmy Bly is in second.
Commissioner Gilson has slapped
Bly and teammate, Joe Tanto...
... with a $25,000 fiine...
...for their recentjoyride
through downtown Chicago.
Doing great, Jimmy.
Keep pushing that speed.
Hey.
You don't need to talk to me anymore?
-lt's not like that.
-Really? What is it like?
All right, here you go. Jimmy.
Three, two.
One. Beautiful.
Come on, buddy.
Now, is he a hero, or is it hype?
What do you think?
What do you want me to say?
l want to hear what you think!
Jimmy Just needs time
to develop, that's all.
When he can get it together off
the track, he will on it.
That's what l think.
Like you got it together?
You can help the kid off
the track more than on it.
You're not racing on Sunday.
l'm bringing Memo back.
Come here.
Joseph, over here.
Sit.
At my level.
lt's the moment of truth, my friend.
lf he doesn't deliver
next time out, he goes.
Don't hate me, but you go with him.
l'll come around here in Turn 7.
Driving off Brandenburg,
l'll fake outside.
Eight's a tough place to pass.
l'm gonna carry that speed...
...bring it down the straightaway.
l have plenty of speed.
lKind of flawless.
You're not even paying attention.
Watch this.
Show me again.
Yes, sir.
lf you find yourself in a position
to hold up traffic, do it.
l don't want any front-running.
You know the drill.
-Don't hurt yourself.
-l told you and l told you too.
-What?
-l told you l'll return.
Here l am, returned.
Like the real Zorro.
There's no helmet big enough
to hold that head.
There's so much love in here.
You keep smiling,
your face is gonna crack.
Why shouldn't he smile?
He's got a lot to be happy about.
He's back where he belongs.
Right, baby?
Yep.
Good?
Hey, you're so good.
You win this, yeah?
You're gonna win.
-Be safe, all right?
-You too, be safe.
This is the second to last race
of the season.
And what an exciting one
itpromises to be.
The crowds are here.
It looks like there's a thunderstorm
maybe a mile from the track.
The rain threat hasn't dampened...
...the spirits of this crowd
here in Germany.
What do you want?
Wanted to apologize.
Apologize to yourself.
Let's race.
l want you to stay in your world
and don't get into his.
You push him hard.
You get him thinking about you.
And you're not thinking about him.
Got it.
The skies are opening up
as the warm-up lap begins.
How's Jimmy?
He's all there.
We are racing in Germany.
Beau Brandenburg is starting
in the pole position today.
Jimmy Bly is in second.
Brandenburg moves out in front
on a course you can race in the rain.
Brake tires are on
and they are at speed.
Memo Moreno is back, giving
Jimmy Bly help as his teammate.
I'm sure Memo wants to make
his presence felt today.
Boy, he is on the fly.
It's like he has something to prove.
Good move, Memo.
lKeep it steady.
Somebody wants their Job back.
I think Joe Tanto may want
to watch his back.
Somebody's spinning!
Kenny Brack, he's in trouble.
He's gonna go way back
in the fiield on that one.
Back at the front
the battle continues.
Look at Brandenburg.
He cuts offBly!
-He tries to take me out.
-Detach it. Hold your line.
Ride his blind spot.
I will, Joe,
but I can't see a damn thing.
Neither can he.
Justpatience, my man. Patience.
Take him, Jimmy! Take him!
Jimmy Bly in second place.
Putting the pressure
on Beau Brandenburg.
Push it.
Here we go.
Bly is gonna try to make
a move in the corner...
...on Brandenburg on the outside.
He does it!
Bly takes the lead.
Goddamn brilliant.
Car in trouble, spinning
on the wetpavement.
-Looks like Gidley.
-Oh, here comes Max Papis!
Crash!
Head on into that car!
Max Papis is airborne.
lf he takes it to the inside,
don't follow him, he's setting you up.
In the hairpin, that fiight
for the lead continues.
Jimmy Bly has the lead now.
Brandenburg wants it back.
Brandenburg goes to the high side.
He gets by!
Brandenburg back to the lead.
lKeep going, he's putting on a show.
lt's a hell of a show.
Yeah, hell of a show.
Now Memo Moreno whips out
of the pack and passes Andretti.
He's really trying to get up there
with Brandenburg and Bly.
Memo, what are you doing?
l can almost touch him.
Hold your position.
Why? He's gonna win this.
I'm sure Carl Henry is not
too happy with Moreno.
Now Bly wants to make a move.
Hold on, Memo Moreno
trying to make...
...the same move on Jimmy Bly,
his teammate.
Memo, no passing. Do you hear me?
l'm right there, Carl.
Lift off. Steady.
What are you doing?
Moreno appears to have something
to prove here.
He gets alongside Bly again.
Damn it, we went over this!
Lift off!
Lift off! You work for me.
l said, lift off.
Why don't you let him drive?
Come on, baby.
-Come on. Come on. Come on!
-Shut up!
l've got to do this.
With his teammate in the battle
for the championship...
...Moreno decided to stick
his nose into this fiight.
Hey, Memo, back off.
Only inches separate
these two cars.
Memo, you're too close.
What's going on here?
Bly is spinning.
He gets it under control.
He's going backwards on the track.
Jimmy, what are you doing?
Jimmy, what the hell are you doing?
Memo?
Get out! Oh, God!
We're getting chopper pictures.
This is horrible.
The car is upside down.
It's in a body of water.
Moreno is pinned underwater.
lt's okay, Memo. l'm here.
Beau, Memo crashed.
Jimmy went after him. You gotta help.
He went into the river at Turn 5.
l'll get you out, Memo.
lt's gonna be okay.
-l'm on my way.
-Beau, what are you gonna do?
Please be careful.
Oh, God! My foot!
Oh, come on.
Hang on, Memo! Hang on!
-Help me!
-Get out!
-Get out, now!
lt's gonna blow up!
Hurry!
We've got Bly and Brandenburg
to help a man in trouble.
Rescue teams are on the way,
but the remote location...
...of this crash makes
it diffiicult to reach them.
Lift it up, higher. Lift it!
Take a breath, Memo.
Come on. We're here.
We're gonna get you out.
Now!
Come on. One, two....
Get it over. Memo!
We got you, Memo.
-Come on, Memo.
-l can't move my leg!
Come on.
lt's gonna be okay.
Fuel everywhere.
They better get that driver
out of there and themselves too.
That fuel could ignite,
it could be floating on the water.
Come on!
Hurry up!
That is horrifying.
I've never seen anything like that.
It's unbelievable.
Worried about the well-being
ofanother driver, another competitor.
Goes to show the kind ofmen
they are, their true fabric.
But they worked as a team together.
Oh, my God, look at that!
Are they okay?
It looks like they are.
I think I see--
I see movement.
l can't move my legs.
l can't move them.
Jimmy?
Jimmy? You all right?
lt's Just my foot.
You'll be fine.
You'll come through this fine.
-How's Memo?
-Fine, they're looking after him.
Our thoughts, ofcourse, with Memo
Moreno and his family at this point.
Hey, Memo.
Hey, Joe.
How do l look?
Never looked better.
-Jimmy?
-Yeah?
Hey.
Thanks.
-Memo, l'm sorry.
-You came back for me.
Saved my life.
We race.
We take chances.
l took this chance.
So look at me.
Look at me.
Don't see you.
See me.
One who made a mistake.
That's all.
lt wasn't a mistake.
How are you doing?
l'm all right.
All right if l come in?
Yeah.
You tried to get him out.
So did you.
You were there first.
l mean, he almost got you killed
and you still tried.
Anybody would've.
Would they?
You're a good man, Jimmy.
l'm sorry, l didn't want to win
the championship this way.
See you.
The old Joe Tanto had a couple
of attributes you should hold on to.
Wasn't long ago you would've said:
''There but for the grace
of God, it's not me.''
Quietly taking your place in the pack.
Where is that guy?
Where has he gone?
Who cares?
l do.
l miss him.
You're the first to know
l'm terminating the kid's contract.
-Why?
-l don't think he's the real deal.
l don't think he's mentally
tough enough.
l don't think he's adult enough!
Gets out of a car in a race.
-Saved a man's life.
-l'm not here to debate!
l'm gonna go for Brandenburg.
Next year.
-What are you doing?
-Whatever it takes to win.
-His brother know?
-He's brokering the deal.
-Don't do this.
-lt's done!
-Then undo it.
-You suddenly care.
-Don't kill him off!
-Don't kill him off?
l watched you kill yourself!
You had everything,
and you threw it all away!
And l had to sit there and watch!
The slowest man in the fastest sport.
l wake up every morning,
my legs are on fire.
l know l'm gonna have to sit
in this chair for the rest of the day.
But if they gave me one more chance,
l'd do it all over again.
lt ain't gonna happen.
We are all damaged.
l've got an excuse.
You don't.
Do you?
l want you to know that l know
about you going out to Brandenburg.
Where have you been?
Meeting after meeting.
l've got a dinner right now.
Catch you later?
-Yeah, l'll see you tomorrow.
-Okay.
Hello.
Jimmy, it's Sophia.
ls everything okay?
Something l have to tell you.
What restaurant did you pick?
Nina, you're in great hands.
You are going to love this place.
-DeMille.
-Jimmy.
What are you doing here?
l'll Just be a minute.
Please don't walk away from me.
Did you sell me out?
Are you working for Brandenburg now?
We should take this inside.
Why are you doing this to me?
Wait a minute! Who sold out first?
l would never sell out my own brother.
When you stopped listening
to me that's what you did.
l Just tried something different.
For the first time
l thought for myself.
-Was that wrong?
-Shutting me out is different.
And l was with you all the way
until you handed your mind over...
...to that has-been.
Who got you here?
Who got all the glory? You couldn't
book a plane ticket without me.
You left me, and let me
tell you something:
There's no worse feeling
getting someone...
...to the top only
to have them drop you.
You did that, you.
Ten years, Jimmy!
All a waste.
lt was coming together.
Why not wait a bit longer?
Because l'm not your goddamn waiter.
l was your manager.
And l deserve better than that.
l deserve much better!
Now you're over, and l am not going
down in flames with you, brother.
That's one trip you're taking alone.
Welcome to the Grand Prix.
It's a sunny day.
It's going to be a great race.
After an eventful season...
...this comes down
to championship time.
Everything's set.
Let's get this thing signed.
After the race it'll be a madhouse.
What do you say?
Let's hear what she says.
What's her idea?
Her idea? What do you mean her idea?
How does it feel?
What? How does what feel?
To be used.
What, l didn't treat you with manners?
You're gonna blow this over that?
What, do you want to hit me?
Would that make you feel better?
-Hurt?
-A little.
Didn't hurt.
Call that a punch?
Did you know?
-lKnow what?
-lKnow about my brother?
Yeah, l knew.
You could've told me.
l hoped you could work things out.
He was right, you know.
Never booked a plane ticket.
Remember l said by the season's end
you're gonna know what you're made of?
lt's the end of the season.
lt's up to you.
Carl, you have to let me race.
l can win.
Any driver that can't get out of
the car in five seconds can't run.
Trying to prove you're
better than l think?
Yeah.
Time him.
Ready?
Go!
-Four seconds.
-Great.
Not bad.
Now the vertical test.
Carl, don't push it.
The vertical test.
You Jump up and down
on the bad foot 10 times...
...to see if you can handle
the pressure.
Again, my rules.
Don't glare, Joe.
Makes your eyes look small.
lt's all about commitment, right?
-Right.
All right, Jimmy. One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five. Come on.
Six. Come on, Jimmy.
Seven. Come on.
Eight. Nine. Ten.
-Yeah!
-Good.
Too bad you didn't try
that hard sooner.
There are 100 laps...
...200 miles between this race
and a champion.
Bye-bye, Daddy.
Bye, Lucas.
Going into this race,
Brandenburg was thinking...
...he was the winner
of the championship.
He was four points ahead,
and Bly looked out of the running.
We'vejust received word
that Bly will be driving...
... which is amazing news after
his injury he suffered in Germany.
So as it stands,
if Jimmy Bly wins this race...
...he will become
the new world champion.
So why'd you do it?
You helped me.
l thought maybe l could help you.
-Well, l appreciate it.
-lt's okay.
Don't go too fast.
Take care. Appreciate you coming.
Take care of yourself.
Jimmy Bly is a hero today, along with
Joe Tanto and Beau Brandenburg...
... who all got to the scene
ofMemo Moreno's crash...
... which had his car in the water.
He was about to drown.
Theyjumped in,
got him out of the water...
...before a big explosion
consumed the entire area.
You know that if l lose this race,
l'm going to blame it on you.
That's what l'm here for.
l love you.
l love you too.
Gentlemen! Start your engines!
Let's look at the starting grid.
Beau Brandenburg
in the pole position.
Gidley will be following him.
Joe Tanto in the Nextel car
starts 10th.
Bly is starting
in the 26th pole position.
He didn't qualify today.
He's got 100 laps to catch
Beau Brandenburg...
...ifhe wants to become
world champion.
We're off to a good start
here in Detroit.
Brandenburg'sjumped out in front.
Trouble!
Tanto's caught in traffiic.
He doesn't have anyplace to go!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we are under a yellow flag...
...until the cars can be removed.
Joe Tanto is in the pit
with a broken front wing.
What's the story on Tanto?
Tanto is out of it.
Don't worry about him.
Got it. That's too bad.
Come on. Come on!
Ladies and gentlemen,
we havejust one lap until green.
Go, go, go!
A fastpit stop for the Nextel team,
but this unfortunate mishap...
...is going to drop Tanto
to lastplace...
...right behind his teammate,
Jimmy Bly.
So, Jimmy, what do you think?
lt's not looking too good.
We can work through this.
You think so?
l know we can
if we stay tight and close.
Okay. Let's do it.
Green flag comes out again.
l'll take it right, you cut left.
Look at this amazing teamwork
between Bly and Tanto!
Hey, Joe, not bad for an old-timer.
That's it. Every man for himself.
Hey, not so fast.
Who wants to be in front
of the other?
What the hell are you two doing?
Back off, back off.
Don't be afraid of me.
Why would l be afraid of you?
Carl, let Joe race his race.
Thanks, kid. l appreciate that.
Let's split them at the turn.
l'll take the inside.
They split around another car!
As they battle,
it brings both cars forward.
Pass me on the left, Jimmy.
Way to go.
Tanto and Bly are double-teaming
the entire fiield.
What an incredible display ofdriving!
-Come on, don't stop now.
-Stopping? Who's stopping?
We are now halfway
to the checkered flag.
Okay, Joe. Try to keep up.
Still back there, Joe?
-l'm still here.
-l'm impressed.
Bly passes and Tanto
is following suit.
With just 20 laps to go, Jimmy Bly
hasjust moved into seventh place...
...and teammate,
Joe Tanto, is in sixth.
Everybody's off the pace.
But Bly and Tanto
are coming on strong.
Brandenburg still leads.
In second place is Alex Barron.
Barron has an engine go!
Two cars swerving to miss the oil!
Car up over the wall!
Several cars involved!
Here comes Jimmy Bly.
He closes on the accident.
Bly has nowhere to go.
Bly and Tanto fiind
themselves in second and third...
...behind Beau Brandenburg.
The drivers will take advantage
of this full-course caution...
...and enter the pits
for the last time this season.
Brandenburg, Bly and Tanto all are
completing very fastpit stops.
Now, with 10 laps to go,
Beau Brandenburg is in fiirstplace...
...Jimmy Bly is in second,
and Joe Tanto is in third place.
The world championship comes down
to these last 10 laps.
Jimmy, show them
what you're made of, kid.
Okay, Joe.
Green flag!
We're back to racing!
It's a sprint to the fiinish
and championship.
Bly is right on Brandenburg's tail.
He wants that championship.
Take him now. Make your move.
He comes alongside Brandenburg.
Brandenburg cuts him off!
Bly is gonna try it again.
He cuts and ducks inside!
Bly has the lead!
Jimmy Bly hasjust taken the lead.
Bly gets past Brandenburg.
He's in the lead.
Great driving by Bly.
Brandenburg won't let Bly
get away that easily.
l'll pull him back in. There's time.
Brandenburg is putting
pressure on Bly.
Don't overreach, kid.
Just four laps to go and you are
the world champion.
He's losing it.
Come on, Jimmy!
Bly may be in trouble.
He weaves back and forth.
Brandenburg is right there,
ready to getpast him.
And Brandenburg goes to the lead!
Nice while it lasted.
Bly loses the lead
with three laps to go.
He tried.
This is something we've seen
this young rookie do so many times.
Carl Henry has got
to be disappointed.
-What is he doing?
-Jesus.
He's back.
Now, Joe Tanto making a move.
He comes up alongside Jimmy Bly.
He passes him! Tanto to second.
They're shoving and elbowing
each other.
Brandenburg, Tanto, Bly.
One, two, three.
We've got one lap to go.
Let's do it.
Joe Tanto has taken the lead!
Unbelievable.
lt's incredible. l can't believe it.
Butproblems with Tanto's car!
Tanto's in trouble.
Will it hold together?
No, not for long.
-Hang on, Joe.
-Stay in there.
What's he doing? He ought
to park it but he stays in front!
l can't hold it together!
Take it, Jimmy!
They split him!
He's lifting off!
l see that. He had it!
Tanto has removed himself from
the race, leaving Brandenburg and Bly.
Neck and neck down the homestretch,
battling for the world championship.
Jimmy, just drive because you
love it. Drive for pure victory.
He's humming.
Thanks for going, Jimmy.
Pure victory. You're right there.
Suddenly, Jimmy Bly seems
to have a renewed vigor.
You'll buckle! Back it down!
Tanto's suspension has broken.
He's now spinning.
But the battle is up front
for the flag!
Here it comes.
Right down to the fiinish.
-Bly takes it!
-Bly wins the world championship!
Beau Brandenburg fiinishes second,
and Joe Tanto fiinishes third.
Following Brandenburg, spinning
across the fiinish for third place.
I'll say, the Hummer has taught
us something here today in Detroit.
They're gonna kill me.
Joseph.
-You could've won that race, right?
-l did win.
Thanks.
Hey, you were incredible.
l know. l lost because of her.
This year's champion, Jimmy Bly!
Luc! Glad you stuck around.
You were really something out there.
Beau Brandenburg!
Go on, you're missing
your celebration.
Don't you go anywhere.
Come on, go!
And fiinally, our third fiinisher...
...Joe Tanto!
Jimmy! Jimmy, you did it, man.
Thanks for everything.
You owe your brother too. Whatever
button he pushed got you going.
Listen, enJoy this.
lt doesn't last long.