Visit Mike Vernon Motors
at 13631 Valley Boulevard...
in Garden Grove.
Now. For our report
from the freeways.
To Don Edwards...
and KBMJ's eye in the sky.
Come in. Don.
Things seem to be pretty normal
on our southland freeways...
which is to say they're
about filled to capacity
at this hour of the morning.
There's a stalled vehicle
in the number two lane...
of the inbound San Diego Freeway
just south of Mulholland.
We also have a report
of an accident half a mile west...
of the 605 junction
of the Santa Ana Freeway.
Both vehicles are now
up on the center divider.
Traffic is still slow and go
in that area.
Traffic is also heavily congested
on the westbound Ventura Freeway...
from Woodman to Balboa
due to construction.
We understand this condition
will last until 3:00 this afternoon.
Don Edwards in Airwatch 3.
Back to you.
Thanks. Don. The weather
for today. As promised...
is a carbon copy of yesterday's:
Low overcast this morning.
Clearing by 11:00.
The National Weather Bureau
says the high today will be about 74...
low tonight in the high 50s.
At the beaches
temperatures will stay
in the pleasant 70s.
Water temperature
in the 60s.
The APCD predicts light
to moderate eye irritation...
as if you hadn't
already noticed. I have.
You know how much
your dog likes meat?
Well. Make sure that's
what he's gett...
... Grocery card
double discount value
I mention each week...
is not one of a kind.
Uh-uh.
It's only one of hundreds
of double discounts
always available...
at Grocery Cart.
The giant 49...
... At the first sign of any
hemorrhoidal discomfort...
treatment should begin
at once.
Remarkably successful results
have been obtained...
with a doctor-proven medica...
... 5 to 3.
St. Louis. 6.
The Giants. 4.
Milwaukee defeated
the Royals. 4 to 3.
Texas edged
the Yankees. 5 to 4.
Pittsburgh and
the Padres rained out.
The Dodgers and Angels
were both idle.
In golf. Dave Brewer has
a one-stroke lead...
after the first round
of the Toronto Classic.
He shot a 5-under-par 67...
with Lee Trevino
one stroke back at 68.
Three others tied
four strokes off the pace at 71.
Does your car need
a new muffler or new
shock absorbers?
You know
about these census forms...
That the Census Bureau
has sent out to us all
to fill in. Right?
That will be the basis of this.
Census district office.
I' d like some information.
I'm filling out my census form now...
and I have an awful problem.
Can somebody help me?
Go ahead.
Thanks. Oh. You're
gonna answer my question?
Yes.
Oh. Good. First of all.
I just wanted to say. Uh...
I don't mind being counted
as an American.
I'm one of the silent majority.
But I wish you had made
some of those questions
multiple choice.
The question was. Um.
Are you the head of the family?
Well. Quite frankly.
The day I married that woman...
that. Unfortunately. I've been
married to for 25 years...
Ohh.
Well. It's true.
I lost the position
as head of the family.
You see. What I do...
I stay at home. I hate working.
I hate going out
and seeing people...
and getting involved
in the rat race and things.
So she works
and I do the housework...
and. Uh. Take care of the babies
and things like that.
And so. I was wondering...
you wanted honest answers.
Now. What I did.
I pencilled in all of the marks...
You wanted marks in these circles
I see in front of me.
I pencilled it in first. But I said.
"No. That's being dishonest.
"I'm really not
the head of the family...
and yet I'm the man
of the family. "
Although there are people
who would question that.
But nevertheless.
I was wondering...
how should I answer
that question?
Well, if you
don't consider yourself
head of the household...
and you think your wife
occupies that position...
I would suggest you put
your wife's name there.
But that's so embarrassing.
What will you people
think when I send it?
Nobody is even
going to know.
Are you sure?
I'm positive. No one
will know about that.
We won't know you from
Adam's house cat.
But there are people
in my neighborhood...
They will never see that form.
Are you sure?
No one in your neighborhood
will ever find out.
I don't want people
to know about that.
I've lived like this
for 15 years...
and I admit.
I wear a house dress.
It's so much easier to pick up
stuff in a house dress...
And. You know. Slippers.
And. Quite frankly. I've
adopted most of the ways...
Talk about pollution.
Of the average housewife.
And I' d hate for anybody
to know that.
Anyway. It's very embarrassing.
So would you...
All information that
you include on that form
is confidential.
It's unreasonable
to expect...
- 800.000 others.
So it would be all right?
I wanna be honest with you.
I'm really not
the head of the family.
She doesn't know I'm calling.
That woman just drives me
up the wall.
I like doing this
just to get even with her.
You know how women are
before you marry them.
They're so nice.
And suddenly they become
so aggressive.
I mean. She became
so aggressive afterward.
Just took over everything.
I mean...
Oh. No.
I'm afraid of her. You see.
I've been wanting to divorce her.
The first six months of marriage.
I knew I made a mistake.
But no, I got ahold of this first,
before she did...
and I thought,
"Well, I'll answer it."
But I wanted to be honest,
and I'm a man of conscience...
so I wanted to make sure.
If I put down I'm
the head of the family...
nobody would know
the difference. Right?
No.
I'll put it down...
I really like you.
Are you married?
Hey!
No.
Oh. When you get married...
don't be like
that whippo I married.
Would you?
- I'll try my best not to be.
- All right.
Thank you so much.
It's nice talking to you.
You're welcome.
Good-bye.
This is Mr. Whittington.
You were talking to
a Mr... uh... uh...
Oh. Valenti. The man
who blows bicycle pump...
on the Ted Mack Original
Amateur Hour. Yes.
Yes. Well. I've. Uh...
I've been trying to get
in touch with Mr. Mack.
Mm-hmm.
Because. Um...
well. I've tried to...
Huh.
Well. I play music on
something unusual myself.
We're always looking for
original amateur talent.
Mr. Valenti is unusual
for the fact...
that he not only blows
"Oh Johnny"on the bicycle pump...
but also does nail file
on a high. Flat table...
and also plays
the vacuum cleaner nozzle.
"It's a Great Day
for the Irish. "
You say you do
something unusual?
Yes.
Well. Uh. What do you do.
May I ask?
I... I play meat.
You what?
I play meat.
You play meat?
Yes. Uh... meat.
You know. Beef and pork?
That's sick, man.
M-e-a-t. Meat?
Yes.
It may sound a little strange.
Yeah. I don't mean
to hurt your feelings.
But I've never heard of anybody
who plays meat.
Well... uh...
a lot of people
think it's strange.
Yes. I can understand that.
No offense. Are you
serious about this?
Yes. Yes. I've...
worked here as
an assistant butcher...
and I've found in a cold
storage locker there...
Yes, sir. Whatever
you want, I got it.
What do you want?
Fill it with Ethyl.
If Ethel don't mind.
Want me to check
under the hood for you?
Uh, please. Yes.
Looks like you could use
a new radiator hose.
Where have I
heard that before?
I'll get one later.
- You're the boss.
- Not in my house, I'm not.
Attendant?
Yes, sir?
You got change
for the telephone?
Yes, sir.
I'll get you the rest later?
Be with you in a minute.
Operator, I'd like to call
659-0716, collect.
Uh, Dave Mann.
The number here is 238-2098.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Honey? Uh, it's me.
What's the matter?
Did you have an accident?
No, nothing like that.
Well, what happened?
Well, nothing
happened. I just, uh...
uh, well, l...
I just wanted to,
uh, to apologize.
You don't have to
apologize, Dave.
I know. I wanted to.
When I left the house
this morning,
you were asleep...
so I just wanted
to call you up and
tell you that, uh...
I, uh... I'm sorry
about last night.
I don't really
want to talk about it.
Well...
don't you think
maybe we ought to?
No, because if we
talk about it...
we'll fight, and you wouldn't
want that, would you?
Of course not.
What is that
supposed to mean?
- Oh, never mind.
- Uh, just a minute.
I know what it's
supposed to mean.
It means you think
I should go out and call
Steve Henderson up...
and challenge him to
a fistfight or something.
No, of course not.
But you could have at least
said something to the man.
I mean, after all, he...
Practically tried to rape me
in front of the whole party.
- Oh, come on, honey.
- Just forget it.
- You gonna be home by 6:30?
- If Forbes lets me go in time.
- Is it that important
that you see him?
- Huh.
He's leaving for Hawaii
in the morning.
The way he's been griping
to the front office,
if I don't reach him today...
- I could lose the account.
- You said there'd be no problem
getting home on time.
There probably won't be.
It's your mother.
God knows she's not
coming to see me.
Honey, I said there
probably won't be
a problem.
Well, just be on time, okay?
All right.
Okay, I'll be there.
Here's your card, sir.
Be with you
in a second.
- Save them stamps?
- No, thanks.
Good enough.
Come back, now.
Will do.
I gave you the road.
Why don't you take it?
Why don't you go?
Oh, boy, you're beautiful.
I don't believe it.
I'm in no mood to play games.
Let's go.
Well, it's about time, Charlie!
My God.
Jesus.
Come on, you miserable fathead.
Get that fat-ass truck out of my way.
Well, I'm never going to
make that appointment now.
You miserable...
Okay. Okay.
You want to play games?
You all right. Mister?
Uhh!
Yeah. Yeah, except...
Oh, my neck.
You got a whiplash,
probably.
Yeah. It's all right.
He's all right.
What happened?
That truck driver
tried to kill me.
Kill you? Go on!
He chased me
down the mountain at...
at nearly 90 miles an hour,
and I don't...
don't know what else
you'd call it.
Tried to kill you.
It sure looks like you got
whiplash, all right.
Oh, it's... it's, uh...
You got the whiplash,
all right.
Oh, that's okay.
Thank... It's okay.
Anything I can do for you?
No, nothing. Thank you.
That's okay.
Okay.
Just a little whiplash is all.
What happened
out there. Mister?
Can I use your
men's room, please?
Yeah. Through the door...
on the right,
down the hall...
turn left, second door.
Well. You never know.
You just never know.
You just go along figuring
some things don't change. Ever.
Like being able to drive
on a public highway...
without somebody trying
to murder you.
And then one stupid thing
happens.
Twenty. Twenty-five minutes
out of your whole life...
and all the ropes that kept you
hangin' in there get cut loose.
And it's like. There you are.
Right back in thejungle again.
All right. Boy.
It was a nightmare.
But it's over now.
It's all over.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
What happened out there?
Oh, just a slight
complication.
Oh? Looked like a big
complication to me.
- Well, you ready to order now?
Ahem. Yes. Heh heh.
Yes, thank you. Um...
Oh, I think I'll...
Ahh.
Just give me, um... um...
Why don't you just give me
a Swiss cheese sandwich...
- on rye. R-Y-E.
- Swiss cheese on rye.
- All right.
- And could I have another
glass of water, please?
- Oh, sure.
Another glass of water.
- Oh, uh, miss?
- Do you have an aspirin?
- Aw, your head aches.
Sure, I'll get you some aspirin.
All I did was pass this
stupid rig a couple of times...
and he goes flyin'
off the deep end.
He has to be crazy.
Okay. So he's crazy.
What can I do about it?
Find him a psychiatrist?
Oh. Boy.
Now wait a minute.
Now wait just a minute.
All right. Now. Think.
Okay. He's in here.
Well. That doesn't mean
he intends to continue his... attack.
It is lunchtime...
and Chuck's Cafe may be
the only place to eat for miles around.
Yeah. He probably
eats here all the time.
He was just...
just moving too fast before...
and he had to... slow down.
Turn around. That's all.
That's all.
Why didn't I leave right away
when I saw his truck outside?
Then I' d know what
he intends to do.
What if he followed me out.
Started after me again?
I' d be right back
where I started.
Even if I got a lead.
He' d overtake me soon enough.
He's got some... some...
some souped-up diesel.
My-My car's just not
that powerful. I just...
can't drive 80 and 90
miles an hour.
As soon as I stopped concentrating.
I' d go back to 60 or 70
like I always do.
It's a habit.
I can't help it.
I ca... Take it easy.
Just... take it easy.
Maybe l...
Maybe I should try
some kind of contact.
I' d better do something.
Look. Mister. I... I'm sorry
if I irritated you.
Why don't I buy you a beer
and get this straightened out?
No.
Look. Mister. I'm sorry
if I irritated you. But...
let me. Uh...
There you are.
Anything else?
No, thank you.
Uh...
I'd like some ketchup.
What if I called
the local police?
But then I' d have to
stay here. Iose more time.
What if he stayed too?
Actually talked
to the police himself?
Naturally.
He' d deny everything.
I've got to prove it.
None of these people
would back me up.
The cops' d probably...
Okay... so now what?
Look, uh...
heh heh...
- I want you to cut it out.
- What?
Just-Just cut it out, okay?
- Cut what out?
- Now, come on. I mean...
please, l - l...
Let's not play games.
- What the hell are you
talking about?
- I can call the police.
- The police?
- You think that I won't?
You're wrong, mister.
If you think you can
take that truck of yours...
and use it as a murder weapon,
killing people on the highway,
well, you're wrong.
You've got another thing comin'.
Man, you need help.
Don't you tell me
I need help.
Hey! Hey, hey, come on!
Who the hell
do you think you are...
- knockin' my sandwich
outta my hand?
- You wanna fight, get outside.
- I don't wanna fight.
I wanna knock his head off.
- You already hit him twice.
What more do you want?
Huh? Come on now.
He's sick. Can't you see?
He ain't gonna fight no one.
That creep goes around,
knocks my sandwich outta my hand.
I'll buy you
another sandwich.
Come on, forget it.
No, forget it.
- Forget it.
- I don't wanna stay
around here anyway.
Let me buy you
a beer then, huh?
I'll buy you a beer.
Get out of here, huh?
Yeah?
I'm sorry to bother you,
but I could use help.
What kind of help?
I could use a push.
Damn thing overheated.
Now I can't get her
started again.
Why didn't you flag down
that truck?
What truck?
The one that just
went by here.
I didn't notice.
I must have been inside
tryin' to get that
piece of junk shakin'.
Would you get off
the car?
How about it?
Looks like I'd go
right underneath the bumper.
No.
Hey, get off the car.
You're gonna get hurt there.
Naw, you're all right.
Rodney, get down
from there.
You too. Shawn.
Come on. Everybody!
Back on the bus!
Wait a minute!
Wait, l...
Well, we'll see.
Come on. Come on.
Push! Push! Push!
Push! Push! Push! Push!
Push! Push!
Push! Push! Push!
He can't do it!
You can't do it!