***Soprano Vocalizing*
*** Vocalizing Continues*
***Choir Vocalizing*
***Soprano Vocalizing*
*** Vocalizing Continues*
OculusDeum.
* Speaking Italian *
* Whispering *
She must be killed !
* Speaking Italian *
She was chosen
to bear his child.
lfshe lives to bringabout the End
ofDays, there willbe no redemption.
All our souls
will perish.
* Italian *
*ltalian*
Tomaso.
*Speakingltalian*
*Male Doctor*
Okay, nowgive me a bigpush.
That's it.
You're doing great.
- That'sit. Okay, stoppushing.
- ...five, six, seven--
- lhave the baby'shead.
- * Rapid Puffing *
Don't push yet.
One little push oughta finish
this off. One little push.
- * Shrieks *
- *Baby Crying*
You have
a beautiful baby girl.
Oh !
* Laughs *
- She's so beautiful !
- * Crying *
She's so beautiful !
Just gonna take her
and clean her up.
- Not yet.
- * Nurse * Hospital rules.
- Please.
- You'll have her back
before you know it.
* Elevator Bell Dings *
* Baby Crying *
* Crying *
* Rattling *
* Speaking In Latin *
* Latin *
*Speakingln Latin*
- Here she is.
- * Baby Coos *
All fresh and clean.
* Chuckles *
- You thought ofa name for heryet ?
- Christine.
Her name is Christine.
Happy birthday,
Christine.
*Man*
WBAZtime is8.:06.
Three more nights, New York.
Three more nightsleft in the century.
Three more nightsleft
in the millennium.
Three more nights
untileverycomputerfails.
untilthe biggest celebration
in the historyofthis city...
startsin TimesSquare.
Where willyou be ?
*Man*Hey, Bobby, come overhere.
Something weird'sgoin'on.
- What do you got there, Charlie ?
- I don't know.
- Pressure's climbin' offthe gauge.
- *Rumbling*
* Alarm Blaring *
* Shouting *
Go the other way !
***ChristmasMusic*
* Car Horns Honking *
***Music Continues*
Excuse me.
* Grunting *
* Gagging *
- *Growling*
- * Grunting *
*Growling*
* Indistinct Chatter *
* Gasping *
What the hell are you--
Mmm.
*Man* You're on Gotham Talk.
Saysomethinginteresting.
*Woman*l'm trying to figure out
what everyone'spredictinghere.
ls the worldgoing to come to an end
at exactly 12.:01 on New Year's, or--
*Radio ShowHost*l'lltellyou what.
Youshouldplayitsafe,
not quityourjob
justyet.
Tellyousomething else.:
in two more nights,
thisplace isgonna see
the wildestpartyever.
We'regonna be there
with the first hundredcallers,
we'regonna make the most noise,
and we'regonna be the craziest,
andifthe worldcomes to an end,
what the hell,
we're allgonna be together!
Andifit doesn't,
andldon't thinkit will,
then we'llallhave the best time
anybodyhas everhad.
*Radio SoundFades*
*Banging*
- *Pounding On Door*
- *Man*
Let'sgo. We'regonna be late.
Honey, l'm home.
*HeavyBreathing*
* Groans *
I wasjust pulling myselftogether.
* Chuckles *
It's gonna take a lot more pulling.
* Groaning *
You are looking
verysharp thismorning.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
You got about five minutes
to get ready. Here.
There's enough caffeine in this
to kill an elephant.
Oughta get you
started.
- So what's today ?
- Transport.
Anyone special ?
No, just some
Wall Street scumbag.
Why the hell does he need
all this protection ?
Well, I guess he fucked
with some people...
that didn't like
beingfucked with.
Personally, I like scumbags.
They pay better.
They say breakfast is
the most important meal ofthe day.
No, I'm good.
Thanks.
*Radio Dispatcher*
StrikerOne, F.D.R. Drive--
*Man*
Follow Three, F.D.R. southbound.
*Dispatcher*
StrikerOne, stayclose.
- StrikerFour--
- *Man #2* Okay,youzeroes.
These people are
paying us good money.
Get your heads out ofyour asses
and start earning those paychecks.
*Man #1*
Follow Three, give me a visualsweep.
*Pilot*StrikerOne,
rooftops 125 to 136clear.
- Keep them clear.
- StrikerFour, advise andcontact the--
*Man #1*Follow Three
is on approach. E. T.A., two minutes.
StrikerOne, Follow Two and Three to
report tight formation. Doyou copy ?
- *Man #2*
AirOne, make a finalsweep.
- *AirOne* Rogerthat.
*Man #1*
Follow Three. We have nest in sight.
*Dispatcher*
AirOne, westboundoverzone two.
* Muttering *
*Driver*
Ten seconds out.
*Dispatcher*
Roger. Ten seconds.
*Man #1*
Follow Three, we have arrived.
Keep everyone close.
- We're exposed.
- *Pilot* Roger.
Sky Two,
fire escape, southwest corner.
Fire escape's negative.
You're wrong ! Shooter !
Evac ! Evac !
Get in the car !
- * Screaming *
- * Tyres Screeching *
* Tyres Screeching *
Call N.Y.P.D. !
Get me an ambulance !
- What the hell's goin' on ?
- *Man* lsee him !lsee him !
- * People Shouting, Screaming *
- Shit !
Oh, shit ! Tell me
you remembered ! Come on !
Get up,
you pussy.
* Groans *
Where's the shooter ?
- Headed for the roof.
- So are we.
Sky Two, get the fuck
down here, now !
Come on ! Hurry !
Take us up there !
Move in ! Move in !
- Set us down ! Hurry !
- There's too much crap on that roof !
- We'lltearoffthe main rotor.
- Thenget usdown aslowasyou can !
Hurrynow! Go !
Strap me in !
You're good !
- * Hollering *
- He's gonna jump offthe roof ! Shit !
* Hollering *
He's got him !
Gun ! Gun !
- * Shouting *
- * Gunshot *
* Gunshots *
* Screaming *
* Groans *
Oculus Dei !
The thousandyearshas ended!
The Dark Angel is loosed
from his prison !
Get down on the ground and
put your hands behind your head.
You don't know
what you've done !
- Get down, or I'll put you down !
- The thousand years has ended !
You don't know
what you've done !
* Groaning *
*FootstepsApproaching*
Priest that drinks.
Can't be all bad.
I think the police
may want that at some point.
- They call it evidence.
- I like to get a head start.
- No reason to make it easy for them.
- Yeah.
- * Priest Muttering *
- All right.
- Watch the lines.
- Go through here.
*Police Officers Chattering*
She doesn't look happy
with the statements.
- Should'vejust killed that
son ofa bitch. Less paperwork.
- Yeah.
- Hey, Detective.
- Bobby. Hey,Jer, it's been a while.
- Hey. How are you, Marge ?
- Can't complain. You ?
It's a nice day
tojump out ofa helicopter.
Well, just doing myjob.
Now, listen.
Something I gotta askyou.
- *Jer* Yeah, what isit ?
- You still drinking ?
*Bobby* Oh,yeah,
wegot allliquoredup thismorning.
- We start every day that way.
- I'm just reading his statement.
- You said here the guy spoke to you.
- Yeah. So what ?
The guy doesn't have a tongue.
- What ?
- He has no tongue ?
Why don't I just leave
that little detail out for now.
- No big deal, right ?
- Areyousaying
that limaginedallthis ?
- No, I'm just saying.
- I saved a life today.
- What the hell did you do ?
- All right, let it go.
- No, no. I know what I heard.
- All right.
*Marge* Thosepeople who don't
belonghere, get them out ofhere.
Make sure this place
is secure.
* No Audible Dialogue *
A drunk hangs out in a neighbourhood
bar, passes out enough times,
people would know where he lived
from carrying him home.
I mean,
it's one thing I know.
Yeah, well, it's important
to be an expert at something.
Oh, it tookyears of research.
This must be it.
* Bobby * What do you want to bet
it's rent-controlled ?
* Door Scraping *
*WaterDripping*
Well, I don't think
this is paint.
A real art buff.
* Bobby * I don't go for this look.
It'sjust too damn busy.
Listen to this.
"I have seen the Earth
laid to waste.
lhaveseen the horrorto come. lsit
a sin to wishyou were neverborn ?
The thousandyearshave ended.
Twenty... seven."
lt endsin a footballscore.
That'snice.
*Jer*
Hey, lfoundsomething.
Can you see what it is ?
His tongue.
He must have
cut it out himself.
Okay. And why is it someone
would cut out their own tongue ?
- To keep from talking.
- Right.
Well, I could eat.
- * Screeching *
- Ah !
- Shit !
- What ?
All right, I knew
that was gonna happen.
No, it's all right.
There's something
in here.
- Have you ever seen her before ?
- Nah.
*Jer*
Thisguyisno ordinaryhit man.
No, this one's
extraordinary.
Let's get the hell outta here.
This place is making me itch.
- Drop it ! Don't move !
Don't move ! Freeze !
- Don't move ! Freeze !
Oh. It's us.
Jesus! Howthe hell
didyou two findthisplace ?
Lucky guess.
So what did you find out ?
His name's Thomas Aquinas.
He's a priest.
Why don't you tell us
something we don't know ?
- A homicidal priest. That's good.
- Yeah ? Well, it gets better.
He studied at the Vatican.
He was one oftheir alleged visionaries.
Came here in '81
to St.John's Church downtown.
Sixmonthsago,
he disappeared.
Priests there say he was
having a spiritual crisis.
Oh, yeah.
That's what this is about.
- Spiritual crisis.
- Doesn't make any sense.
What'sapriest doingshooting
at a WallStreet banker?
A WallStreet banker, bythe way,
who suddenlydisappeared.
Maybe we should ask the girl.
What girl ?
- Uh, the guy. The guy. Priest guy.
- *JerClears Throat*
*Jer * There's five million women
living in New York City.
How we gonna find her
without a name ?
Here.
Look, I already gave you some money.
Can you just move on, please ?
He's comin' foryou.
He's comin' foryou, Christine.
How do you know
my name ?
He's gonna fuckyou. He's gonna
fuckyou, Christine. Can you see him ?
- * Chuckles * Can you see him ?
- Who are you ?
Howdoyou knowmyname ?
* Screaming *
- * Glass Tinkling *
- * Gasps *
- He's gonna fuckyou, Christine.
- * Screaming *
- * Laughing *
*Panting*
I'm sorry.
* Gargling *
* Groaning *
Ohh.
* Groans *
The thousand years have ended.
Thousand years have ended.
** * Classical Tune Plays *
** * Music Continues *
"When the thousand years
are ended,
Satan shall be loosed
out of his prison."
"Twenty... seven. "
*Woman*
Christine ?
- Christine ?
- I'll be there in a sec !
* Phone Ringing *
Doctor's office.
Hello.
Is Dr Abel in, please ?
- Who's calling, please ?
- It's Christine York.
Christine, listen to me.
We've been overthisbefore.
It's a terrible thing to lose your
parents. I know it was a long time ago.
The holidays always make
something like that feel much worse.
Understand,
these dreams are your creation.
There's nothing real about them.
You control them.
They don't control you.
Take another Xanax
to relieve your anxiety.
You are fine. Trust me.
Another vision ?
Why didn't you tell me ?
- I didn't want you to worry.
- l'myourstepmother.
lt'smyjob to worry.
No big deal, really.
Justsomeone on thesubwaycar
turnedintoporcelain andshattered.
What's wrong with me ? Whydo l
see things ? Whyam lso different ?
Oh, you don't know
how special you are.
You're better than everybody else.
Just remember that.
I don't want to be better or worse.
I want to be normal.
- I want a normal life.
- You have to have patience.
All good things will come to you.
You'll see.
- Oh, excuse me.
- I'm sorry, we're closed.
I would like to talk to you
about Thomas Aquinas.
- Father, please, I need you downstairs.
-Just take these.
- Father, please.
- Go.
I've already told the police. Thomas
was a friend of mine and a colleague.
He had nothing to do
with what happened today.
There was no one else
on that fire escape.
- You don't understand.
- I understand getting shot at,
and I don't like it.
- He shot at you ?
- No, he shot at my client.
- I happened to get in the way.
- Who's your client ?
That's irrelevant right now.
What I want to know is why would
a priest try to kill someone ?
You've been drinking. I've got
1 4 years sober, and I can spot that.
Well, good foryou. Your friend and
colleague, was he working for someone ?
Yes, he was working for God.
So God ordered a hit
on an investment banker ?
There's a lot that you don't know.
You thinkyou've seen everything ?
You haven't. There are
things you never dreamed of.
There's another world out there.
Thomas saw it, and it destroyed him.
I've seen a lot too, but there's nothing
that would make me cut my tongue out.
- Yeah, well, wait a few days.
- What happens in a few days ?
Did Thomas tellyou
about agirl?
- No.
- I see. Do you believe in God ?
Maybe once, but not any more.
What happened ?
We had a difference ofopinion.
I thought that my wife and daughter
should live, and He felt otherwise.
I'm sorry to hear about the loss. Maybe
it's time foryou to renew your faith.
This girl.
Is she in trouble ?
Does she need help ?
- I have a lot ofthings to do here.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
- I have more questions,
ifyou don't mind.
- I've got a question foryou.
Ifyou don't believe in God,
how can you understand his adversary ?
Now I have to believe in God
in order to solve a crime ?
I'm sure that you
can find your way out.
*Woman Chanting*
* Chanting Continues *
* Chanting *
- How many have received the stigmata ?
- She's the third this week.
* Screaming *
- What isshesaying ?
- Foryour own good,
get out and forget what you've seen !
- Was Thomas part ofthis ?
- There are forces at work
you couldn't possibly comprehend !
Now, please,
leave!
*Recording OverP.A. System*
* Godrestye, merrygentlemen*
*Let nothing
you dismay*
*RememberChrist--**
No, it'sjust I hate the fact that
they put finals after the holiday.
It ruins the whole meaning
ofvacation.
I wouldn't worry.
You always do fine.
Besides, a bad grade
isn't the end ofthe world.
*DoorbellRings*
* Pants *
It's you.
- I didn't--
- Where is she ?
- The girl is safe.
- And what ofthe world ?
Everything is
as planned.
Our acts go unnoticed,
unquestioned.
- We're everywhere.
- Daddy, who isit ?
- Is this your daughter ?
- Yes.
- Andthisisyour wife ?
Mm.
***Rock*
* Oh,you insist
yougotta talk thatshit*
* Yougotta keep
that dogassbreath*
*Allup in myface*
*Andlremember when*
* You wouldneverlie
to a friend*
* 'Causeyou wereso high
you wereso shy*
* You were
so fuckedup anyway*
*Life keeps on tickin',
tickin', tickin', tickin'**
*SongFades Out*
* Screaming *
- *HeavyFootsteps*
- * Gasps *
- What's wrong, baby ? What's wrong ?
- It was a dream.
- He came for me again.
- It's only a dream, angel.
It felt closer.
* Panting *
*Female Newscaster* Throughout
the country, the NationalGuard...
hasbeenput on alert
asaprecaution--
*Male Newscaster*MayorGiuliani
urgedallcitizensandpolice...
to staycalm
during thisholidayseason.
*Female Newscaster*
No explanationsforhowblood
on the hands ofthe Christ child,
depictedin Michelangelo's
famoussculpture ofthe Pieta--
*Male Newscaster*
...atmosphere offearandpanic,
random acts ofviolence...
are beingattributedto satanic cults
who seem determined...
to disrupt New Year's celebrations
throughout the world.
Here in New York--
Sorry, pal,
you can't come in here.
Ahh. The young boys that you seduced
have left their scent upon you.
Remember who it is
that you serve. Hmm ?
Openyoureyes, Thomas.
* Gasping *
*Grunting*
Look. Look at the face that has haunted
your dreams for a thousand years.
* Grunting *
They say you can see
the future, Thomas.
Then you must know exactly
what I'm going to do to you.
* Panting *
*Bobby*ldon't know what
we hope toget from thisguy.
- He's got no fuckin' tongue.
- He can write.
Fuck me.
*Female Newscaster*
There isstillno explanation...
forthe devastating explosions
that rockedmidtown two nightsago.
In the wake
ofTuesday night's explosion,
investigators from the New York
City Fire Department are still
at a loss to explain...
whythe restaurantsuddenlyburst into
flames, killingat least35people.
- Hey, asshole,
watch where you're going.
- Hey, I like the shirt.
Screw you, man !
Hey, kid.
* Horn Honking *
- *Woman Screaming*
- Nice shirt.
l'm tellin'you, no one entered
the room. Maybe he didit himself.
Then how did he get
the last scalpel in !
* Doctor *
Oh, my God.
- Itjust keeps getting better.
- * Doctor *
I've never seen anything like this.
*Police Officers,
Nurses Chattering*
lthink this
is written in Latin.
"When the thousand years
has ended,
Satan shall be loosed
out of his prison."
Uh, this next part is not clear.
I-I-I think it's in English.
ltsays, "Christ--
Christ in New York."
- * Thomas Shouts *
- * Screaming *
- Christ !
- *Nurses Whimpering*
Well, it's official. I'm never
sleeping again, ever. You okay ?
A guy cuts words into his chest.
Someone else nails him to the ceiling.
What's not okay ?
* Sighs *
So where we going ?
The girl. I gotta talk to her,
find out what she knows.
W-W-Wait. We don't have a name.
That would help.
Maybe we do.
Maybe it's not "Christ in New York."
Maybe it's, "Chris in New York,"
"Christine in New York."
"Christine York."
Let's run a D.M.V. check and find out
ifany ofthose names come up.
*Bobby*
Hello, Christine York.
Sometimes you border
on competent.
- I know. It's scary, isn't it ?
- *Bobby Chuckles*
* Speaking Italian *
Christine ?
Mabel called. She'd like you to
get dressed and join her for lunch.
Grazie, Carson.
No !
* Screaming *
Shit !
* Christine Grunts *
No ! No !
Ahhh ! Goddamn it,
get off me !
- Go downstairs
and watch the front door !
- Please!
- Help !
- There is no sanctuary but heaven.
- * Grunting, Gasping *
- You must go there now.
- What are you doing ?
- I commend you to Almighty God
and entrust you--
*Bobby*
At whatpoint is this considered...
interfering with
a police investigation ?
Hey, we are private citizens having
a conversation with another citizen.
I mean, I don't think they've found
a way to outlaw that. At least not yet.
*Christine*
Please! No !
May you return
to Him who formed--
Go down there. Do whateveryou can.
I need more time
to finish the last rites.
- * Shrieking *
- May Christ, the true shepherd--
- *Christine*Help !
- Stairs.
Covered.
Help !
May you see
your redeemer--
- ...forever, amen.
- * Yelling *
- * Christine * Son ofa bitch !
- * Groaning *
* Grunting *
You all right ?
Yeah. Check the body
down the stairs.
What body ?
Call the police,
and get an ambulance.
*JerPanting*
Take it easy.
We're the good guys.
Allright ?
What happened?
Carson. Those men--
Th-Those men--
They tried to kill me.
* Panting *
Why ?
Eightjets, variablespeed.
That's what lcalldyingin style.
What kind of girl lives
in a house like this, anyway ?
Oh, she's an orphan.
Both parents deceased.
After the mother died,
the home nurse married the father.
Now the nurse
is the sole guardian.
I think it's adorable
the way you talk like a real cop.
Yeah ? So you think after
they clean up this mess, we could...
- * Marge * Don't tempt me.
- soaka little ?
- They relax me. You want one ?
- Oh, no, thanks. I drink.
- My little girl had onejust like it.
- Really ?
- Mm-hmm.
- Yeah ? You snoop through
her stuffwithout asking too ?
When I was looking
for something.
What are you looking for ?
A connection.
Most days, I don't feel
connected to anyone.
I noticed a lot
of religious books outside.
Mm. They're
my stepmother's.
- Is she a big believer ?
- No, not really.
It's mostlyjust kind of
like a hobby with her.
Do you know a priest
by the name ofThomas Aquinas ?
No. Is that
your connection, religion ?
I've seen a lot
ofattempted murders,
but I've never seen anyone
perform the last rites before.
- *Mabel* Christine ?
- In here !
Are you all right ? Oh, my God,
I just heard what happened !
Did they hurt you ?
I'm okay, but Carson--
I know. Oh.
I'm just so glad
you came along when you did.
Thanks.
* Sighs *
I didn't realize you knew where
the library was, let alone had a card.
Well, there's a lot
about me you don't know.
*Mabel*
They're right outside.
*DrAbelOn Telephone* You must
bringher. He is waitingforher.
No, that's impossible !
They'll follow me and find the temple !
I couldn't convince her
to come here.
Yuck ! Then I shall
have to go to her.
Didlmention
lhada date tonight ?
Notjust the inflatable kind.
A real live girl.
Did you break up
with the inflatable one ?
Yeah. She was
just too needy.
Everything
was about her.
It'sjust that this is starting
to feel a lot like work.
Normally, l wouldn't mind work
because, well,you know,
we'dbegettingpaid.
Watching rich people for free.
Itjust seems odd, doesn't it ?
Okay, I'll wait here.
- Change your mind about the pill ?
- I found something.
Christine, what are you doing ?
Why is that man here ?
I'll be five minutes.
She lovesme to death,
butshe'sa little overprotective.
I took this from one
ofyour attackers.
- Did you show that to the police ?
- No.
If I did, it would end up in a plastic
envelope on one oftheir large shelves.
- That's pretty cynical.
- Well, I've put
a few ofthose envelopes...
up on that
large shelf myself.
I used to be a cop.
Now, this amulet
is from a Masonic order...
in a former sub-herald
ofthe Vatican knights.
*Jer*
The Knights ofthe HolySee.
Theyawait the return
ofthe DarkAngelto Earth.
So, the men that attacked me
are devil worshippers ?
No. This says
they're the good guys.
They're the ones that are supposed
to stop the devil worshippers.
Those were the good guys ?
What does that have to do with me ?
- * Humans Shrieking *
- * Screams *
*Panting*
I'm sorry.
I have a medical condition.
- Sometimes I see things
that aren't there.
- No. I saw it too.
* Zipper Unzipping *
* Urinating Continues *
I've been having visions
ever since I can remember,
but I've never
shared one before.
There must be
an explanation.
I hope so. I've been waiting
all my life to hear it.
* Flicking Open
Cigarette Lighter *
* Whistling Sound *
- * Christine Shrieks *
- *Jer Grunts *
Let's get out of here !
Come on !
- * Gasps *
- You're not going anywhere.
- What are you doing ?
- There's no time to discuss this.
- Afteralltheseyears ofwaiting,
it'sfinallyhappening.
- What's happening ?
You can't run awaynow!
- *Christine* Stop it!
- Let her go !
- No !
- * Grunting *
Don't you love me ?
Didn't I give you
everything ?
- * Grunting *
- Haven't I been a mother to you ?
* Groans *
- * Gasps *
- * Grunting *
- * Groaning *
* Screams *
No-o-o !
- Christine. You know who I am.
- Oh, no.
- I've come foryou.
- Let's go. Come on.
* Moaning *
* Whimpering *
You only had one simplejob,
and you couldn't even do that.
* Gurgling, Grunting *
*TyresScreeching*
*Siren Chirps*
*Police Radio
Chattering*
Hey, Marge ? Marge, over here !
We need your help !
Easy with the hardware.
Jesus, Marge !
What the fuck ?
*Marge*lt's okay,Jer.
Wejust want thegirl.
- Okay, tell me.
What the hell is going on here ?
- I don't know.
I don't believe you.
- All right. I'm coming out.
- Throw out the gun.
Please don't-- don't
leave me here. Please !
*Cop*
Hands onyourhead.
- What ?
- Hands onyourhead. Now!
What do you want with her,
Marge ? Huh ?
- Whyissheso important ?
-Just the girl. You can kill him.
* Gasps *
Come on !
Quickly !
You, ldon't need.
But you--
Call your people.
Find them.
Over here.
* Pills Rattling *
Goddamn it !
Get up !
Come on. Get up !
My best friend is dead. Everyone is
trying to kill us. I just shot two cops.
- Why is everyone afteryou ?
- I don't know.
I swear. I don't know.
Why is this happening ?
lknowit'smyfault.
ljust don't know why.
That man on thestairs,
what doyou knowabout him ?
- Nothing.
- Come on. I saw your face.
- You recognized him.
- I don't talk about it.
* Softly *
Tell me. I need to know.
I've seen him before...
in my dreams.
- In your dreams ?
- They're-- They're nightmares really.
He takes me, and--
and he makes love to me.
I've been making love
to him my whole life.
I thought I was crazy,
but he was never real before tonight.
Oh, he's real.
I've seen him before.
- I'm afraid.
- Don't be afraid.
I won't let him do any harm to you.
I'm afraid of me. I'm afraid that
if I see him, if he tries to take me,
I'm gonna want him to.
- *Woman Chattering On Police Radio*
- Let's go !
- Where we going ?
- To get some answers.
*Knocking On Door*
- * Gun Cocks *
- You don't need that.
You have no enemies here.
I'm not so sure about that. This girl
wasjust attacked by your people.
- Your Vatican knights
almost killed her !
- Vatican knights ?
Oh, my God.
Well, they're not my people.
They think they're doing God's work.
- But they're not.
- I want to know what's going on,
- and I want to know right now !
- Put the gun away.
Did anybody
see you come ?
- No.
- Good. We should be safe here.
According to the Scriptures,
he can't see inside ofthe house of God.
- Who can't ?
- Maybe now you're ready to believe.
- *Woman ChantinglnAncient Language*
- * Computer Beeping *
* Chanting Continues *
- Her hands are healed.
- That's the power offaith.
- Who is she ?
- She's a Polish peasant.
She fellinto a trance
about two weeksago,
and then she began to speak
in a language she couldn't
possibly have known.
- She made aprophecyabout EndofDays.
- "End of Days" ?
Of man's destruction and
the unholy's reign upon the earth.
Why don't you stop all this church talk
and tell us what the hell is going on.
- Who's after her ?
- Well, ifyou'll excuse me,
I'll try to explain.
*Kovak* You knowanything
about the numberofthe beast ?
Revelation ofSt.John ?
From his dream ?
- Six-six-six ?
- The number ofthe beast
is not six-six-six.
Often in dreams, numbers appear
upside down and backwards.
So, six-six-six
becomes nine-nine-nine.
Like in 1 999,
the year of his return.
What does that
have to do with me ?
Regressus diaboli:
The return ofSatan.
Does any ofthis
look familiar to you ?
She's been chosen.
He's in her blood.
The Holy Church hasbeen searching
foryousince the dayyou were born.
- Chosen for what ?
- Everythousandyears,
on the eve ofthe millennium,
the Dark Angel comes
and takes a body,
and then he walks the Earth, looking
for a woman who will bear his child.
lt allhas to happen in that unholyhour
before midnight on New Year'sEve.
lfhe consummatesyourflesh
with thishuman body,
then he unlocks
the gate of hell...
andeverythingas we knowit
ceases to exist.
So, the Prince ofDarkness
wants to conquerthe Earth,
but has to wait untilan hour
before midnight ofNew Year'sEve ?
- Is this Eastern time ?
- It's got nothing to do
with New Year's Eve.
It has to do with
a temporary celestial alignment.
The Gregorian monks
studiedthe heavens.
They were able to calculate
the precise moment ofthis event.
Theycreatedourcalendar
bymapping this event...
andcountingbackwards
from that moment.
- It was a mistake to come here.
- It doesn't matter
whetheryou believe or not.
He's real, and he won't rest
till he finds this girl.
- Why did he pick me ?
- Because the stars were
right when you were born.
A man'sbody wasalso chosen,
just likeyours.
lfthe devildoes exist,
whydoesn'tyourgoddo anything ?
It's not my God. It's our God,
and He doesn't say that He will save us.
He says that
we will save ourselves.
Save myself? What am lsupposedto do ?
Get a restraining order?
- We have to have faith.
- Faith.
Yes, faith.
lt'san interesting concept.
Ifyou read the Bible,
you can't miss it. Faith !
Between your faith
and my Glock nine millimetre,
I take my Glock. Come on. Let's go.
I'm afraid it takes a person
of pure heart to defeat pure evil.
You did yourjob. You brought her here
to people offaith. We'll protect her.
- We'll hide her.
- You know, you live
in a different world.
We have some real serious problems here,
and this is not solving them.
Satan's greatest trick
was convincing man he didn't exist.
I don't, uh--
This all feels true to me.
You'll be safer with me. At least I can
fight this guy with something real.
You know what to do.
You feelit.
* Softly *
I'm sorry.
Let him go.
* Priest Speaking
In Italian *
It gets easier when you
accept what you are.
A fallen soul.
Tsk, tsk, tsk, tsk.
* Chuckling *
Door'slocked,
no windowsbroken.
- * Whispers * How did I get in here ?
- Who the fuck are you ?
Oh, I think
you know who I am.
You just don't
want to believe it.
I took a bullet foryou.
- I protected you.
- Oh, no-no-no. You didn't protect me.
You protected this body.
Am I-- Am I getting a pattern here ?
So much pain.
"Not to be taken with alcohol."
Remember that.
Oh.
To lose a wife andchild.
I can't even imagine
what that must be like.
- What do you want ?
- To make you happy again.
*Nat King ColeSinging*
*JackFrost nippingatyournose*
* Yuletide carols*
*Beingsungbya choir*
*Andfolksdressedup
like Eskimos*
A gift fromyou daughter?
Hmm ?
- ***Continues*
- *WaterSplashing, ChildGiggling*
*Splashing Continues*
- Amy ?
- Don'tstayin there too long.
You'llturn into aprune.
- Emily !
- Come on, darling.
It's time to get out.
Gottagetyou dressed.
Yourdaddy'sgonna be homesoon.
* Amy * I have the best daddy
in the whole world.
Yes,
you certainly do.
- * Laughing *
- But I don't think he'll be home.
*Emily*Now, what makesyousay
a sillythinglike that ?
- He never comes home.
- Well, honey,you know
yourdaddy workshard.
It's not about how much time you're
there. It's about "quality time."
Now, he'll be homejust like
he promised. You'll see.
He keepshispromises.
I can give it all back to you.
Everything that He took away.
Everything.
You can hold
your wife again.
You can watch your daughter walk
through the door in her prom dress.
All you have to do is tell me
where the girl is.
Come on. She's a nobody to you.
You don't even know her.
You're in the middle ofsomething
you don't really understand.
You thinkyou're saving her from me ?
She wants to be with me.
- You knowthat.
- What did you do in school today ?
You thinkl'dharm her?*Scoffs*
l'dtreat herlike a queen.
- Turn around, sweetheart.
- You toldmeyou'ddo anything
togetyourfamilyback.
You want them ?
This is your chance.
- They're not real.
- Does that matter?
- Oh, yes.
- lthinkyou needto be reminded...
of how painful
reality is.
No !
Oh, shit !
* Snarls *
*Jer Yelling *
* Screaming *
Don't hurt my baby !
- Daddy!
- Let my daughter go !
* Screaming *
Daddy !
- Let go of my baby !
- *Screaming, Shotgun Blasts*
No !
* Panting *
Oh, it's true.
It wasn't your fault.
- I wasn't there.
- No, you werejust--
You were out doing yourjob.
- I wasn't fucking there !
- Oh, look at you. Torn apart by guilt.
You didn't do anything wrong. You were
an honest cop. You didn't take money.
You had to testify against them even
after they threatened your family.
Most people would never
testify against those guys.
They're not like you.
You had to do the right thing.
And where was God, hmm ?
He could've stopped it, but he didn't.
He fucked you.
Then He made you feel guilty.
Me, I don't do guilt.
I didn't do what happened here.
He did.
Now you just think about that.
Then you tell me
who's really your friend.
I can make it like
it never happened.
Allfortheprice
ofa stranger'saddress.
No !
You will never see the girl !
Now, you see--
Now you're upsetting me.
You don't want to see me upset,
believe me.
Oh, you want to fuck with me ?
You thinkyou know bad, huh ?
You're a fucking choirboy
compared to me ! A choirboy !
You're in touch with your anger.
I really like that.
I don't know about you,
but I'm going to have a drink.
You and I are so much alike.
We're nothing alike !
Nothing !
Look at yourself. Look at this.
Look at what you are now.
You walked away from the light,
just like me. You want one ?
- You need to get out, now.
- Come on. You know
what's in your heart.
- We're on thesameside.
- I'm not on your side,
and I never will be.
* Laughs * You're on His side ?
He's the one who took away your family.
Let me tell you
something about Him.
He is the biggest underachiever
ofall time.
Hejust had a good publicist,
that's all. Something good happens:
"It's His will."
Something bad happens:
"He moves in mysterious ways."
You take that-- that overblown
press kit they call the Bible.
You lookforthe answerin there,
what do theytellyou ?
"Shit happens."
* Scoffs * Please.
He treated you like garbage.
You walked away.
I'm not the bad guy.
What about the End of Days ?
Think of it
as a new beginning.
A change of management. And you'll be
right there with me on the ground floor.
It will be so cool.
Tell me what you want.
Tell me what you really want,
and I'll give it to you.
I'll tell you what I want.
I want you to go to hell.
* Sighs * You see,
sometimes the problem is...
* Neck Bones Cracking *
- hell...
- * Gasping, Choking *
comes to you !
- Don't fuck up the coat.
- * Groans *
I've wasted
too much time on this.
You see those insignificant little dots
down there ? Huh ? Do you see them ?
That's what you mean to me.
Now, give me the girl !
* Gasps *
Not today.
* Groans *
Look down.
Now, look in your heart
and tell me you don't want to die.
All you got to do
is take my hand.
- * Grunting *
- And I'll give you back
everything that He took away.
* Groans *
- Come on.
- Okay.
*Panting*
Okay. Okay. Okay.
*Grunting*
Fuck... you !
* Car Alarm Blaring *
*Alarm Continues*
*Knocking*
*Knocking Continues*
Hey.
Hey !
- I thought you were dead.
- Couple ofseconds, I would've been.
All I remember is steppin' out
ofthe van, then I woke up
in the fucking gutter.
- What the hell are you doing here ?
- What are you talking about ?
l've been lookin'foryou allnight.
What the hellhappenedtoyou ?
- Hey. Hey. Hey.
- I can't trust you.
I don't know how much
you had to drink, okay,
but let's not point the gun at me ?
- I just need to know.
- You need to know what ?
- That you are you.
- Ofcourse I'm me !
What the hell are you talking about ?
- You took his body.
- All right. You're ill.
Okay ? You need some help.
All right ?
Oh, fuck !
Jesus !
- Fuck.
- You're bleeding.
Ofcourse I'm bleeding !
You fuckin' shot me !
- I just needed to find out !
- You found out, okay ?
- Stop being such a pussy !
It'sjust a scratch.
- Pussy ? Come on !
- Oh, Christ.
- Does it hurt ?
What do you think ?
Jesus.
What the hell's the matter with you ?
What's going on here ?
I can't explain it.
I shouldn't have left
her alone like that.
- I should be with her.
- *Bobby* Tellme what to do.
I gotta get back there.
* Panting *
Got to get her
as far away from him as I can.
Okay, we'll leave town.
You get her. I'll get a Striker car.
Just tell me
where to meet you.
St.John's Church...
in one hour.
Howmuch longer, Father?
Well, he has to sire his child between
1 1 :00 and midnight tomorrow night.
- So, we must keep you hidden
until that hour passes.
- *Banging*
- We've come to help.
- Your Eminence.
In this hour ofdarkness,
we need all the help we can get.
- How's the girl ?
- The girl's fine. Thanks.
No.
No. Father ! Father, they're
the ones who tried to kill me !
*Groaning*
- No !
- YourEminence, what areyou doing ?
- We cannot allow
this union to takeplace.
- No ! No.
- Please !
- You can't! You mustn't!
- *Christine* Letgo !
- She is only one life.
Howmanylivesareyouprepared
to endifwe do nothing ?
- That's not who we are.
- Ofcourse it is.
We are doing God's work.
We are preventing the End of Days.
But you can't prevent evil
by doing evil.
- There is no time !
- No !
- * Chanting *
- It's the only way.
- No-o-o !
- * Screaming *
- May Godforgive us!
- Amen.
- *Gunshot*
- *Blade Clattering*
- * Groaning *
- I can do this all day long.
- Now, let her go.
You must let us finish.
lfshe isslain, hishope ofcreating
a kingdom on Earth dies with her.
- Herdeath is God's will.
- It's not God's will.
- lt'syour will, andit will
leadto ourdestruction.
-Jericho.
She must be removed.
lt's the only wayto defeat him.
For a thousand years,
we prepared ourselves for this.
- We're not afraid to die.
- Good.
Because I'm not afraid
to kill you.
Let her go.
*Rumbling*
Go. Go.
Get out of here.
*Kovak*
Go !
God help us.
We're too late.
- I've come for my wife.
- Let's go.
Thisis the house ofthe Lord,
ourGod, andyou are not welcome here.
I can stand the pain of being in church.
How much pain can you bear ?
Christine !
Come to me.
lam the one
you've been waitingfor.
I am the answer
to your prayers.
In the name of God,
I orderyou to leave here now !
*Kovak*
Maythe wrath ofGoddestroy--
- *Thunderclap*
- *Screaming*
A thousand years you have waited for
my return. And behold, you have failed.
And with your last breath you shall
bear witness to the End of Days.
* Bones Cracking *
- * Grunts *
- * Gasps *
No ! Jericho !
* Tyres Screeching,
Horn Blaring *
- *TyresScreeching*
- * Grunts *
Get in the car !
Run !
- * Groans *
- *HonkingHorn*
Jesus ! Come on !
- Bobby, what the hell are you doing ?
- * Engine Accelerating *
- What are you doing ? Open the door !
- Open up !
- Come on ! Open up !
- Open the door !
Jer-- Please, stop the car !
Please !
* Grunts *
- *TyresScreeching*
- * Groaning *
- * Horn Blaring *
-Jer !
Jer !
*Jericho Grunting,
Groaning*
Youshould
have taken myoffer.
At leastyou wouldhave
been happyonce inyourlife.
* Groans *
Let her go,
or I'll kill you.
Ooh, so much anger,
so much hatred.
You're almost there.
I'm gonna hurt you so bad,
you're gonna beg to die.
But I'm not gonna let you.
It's not gonna be that easy.
You're mine, and I want you
to see what's gonna happen.
*EngineStarts*
*Female Newscaster* Worldreligious
leadershave askedtheirfollowers...
toprepare forthe newmillennium
not with celebratingandpartying...
but rather with acts
ofkindness, compassion--
*Male Newscaster*
Thisisit, New York.
The last dayofthe first2,000years.
*FootstepsApproaching*
* Speaking In Italian *
* Crowd Roaring *
*Whispering*
* Screaming, Groaning *
- How long have I been out ?
- You almost slept the whole day.
- You're lucky to be alive.
- * Grunting *
* Panting *
The time ?
- It's almost 7:00.
- It's not too late.
- He has the girl.
- But it's not too late.
ln nomine Patris,
et Filii, etSpiritusSancti.
* Crowd Roaring *
*Man*Jesus, what didyou do ?
Get hit bya truck ?
No, the truck missed me.
* Door Lock
Beeping, Buzzing *
*DoorBuzzes*
- Where the hell are you goin' ?
- Doing myjob.
- *ComputerKeys Clacking*
- You know, the copsare afteryou.
*Jericho* Theyhave to wait.
l'vegot to do something.
* Beeping *
That son ofa bitch.
- * Engine Off*
- *DoorOpens*
*DoorSlams*
* Cocks Gun *
- * Gasps * Yes.
- You wish entrance ?
* Grunts * You have much hatred
and vengeance in your heart.
You may pass.
*Distant Chanting*
*Chanting GrowsLouder*
*Chanting Continues*
*LoudChanting*
Angelus obscurus.
* Followers *
*Priest*
Princeps finis dierum.
Princepsfinisdierum.
*Chanting Continues*
You know
this is what you want.
* Chanting Continues *
Angelus obscurus.
You can't resist, can you ?
'Cause you don't want to.
I didn't come here to hurt you.
I came here to love you.
Relax.
Give yourselfto me.
- *Gunshot*
- * Followers Shouting *
*Automatic Weapon Firing*
- No one move, or I kill the girl.
- What are you doing ?
- * Whispers * Trust me.
- You're not gonna kill her.
Yousaidityourself.
lhave a darkheart.
- Then stand with me.
- I'll tell you what.
You let usboth out ofhere,
andl'llstand whereveryou want.
- Step back, or I'll pull the trigger.
- I didn't want to kill you.
But nowyou
leave me no choice.
Let her go,Jer.
Oh, don't lookat me
like that.
You'd be amazed what you agree to
when you're on fire.
Don't do it, Bobby.
You're better than this.
- You're better than him.
- You know, considering
how you've lived your life,
when this is all over,
what makes you thinkyou're
going upstairs anyways, huh ?
Come on,Jer. This is the main event.
It's gonna happen.
- Why shouldn't you have
the best seats in the house ?
- You will never get a shot off,
and you know it.
Don't do it.
Bobby.
I thought we had a deal ?
Well, I guess
the deal's off.
* Screaming *
- No !
- * Screaming Continues *
You son ofa bitch !
- * Panicked Shouting *
- * Muffled Cries *
Here !
This way !
Up here.
Shit !
- * Christine Shouts *
- * Train Horn Blares *
* Wheels Screeching *
- Oh, thank God. I thought I hit you.
-Just get us out of here !
- Let's go.
- Give me a minute.
I'd feel better ifyou'd show me
how to use one ofthose things.
- l want to do something. Let me help.
- All right. Here.
You take the gun.
Line up the sight with your target.
- Uh-huh.
- Beware ofthe recoil.
Here's the magazine.
Put it in. Load.
- Only pull the trigger
when you're ready--
- * Groans *
- Like that ?
- Yeah, like that.
He's on the tracks !
Shit !
- Don't stop ! Don't stop !
- What are you doing ?
* Screams *
He's gone.
* Screaming *
Oh, God.
Go on.
- We must separate the cars.
Separate the cars.
- What ?
-Jericho !
- * Yelling *
Jericho !
* Shouting *
* Grunting *
Jericho !
* Christine *
That's it. Come on.
Jericho !
Here. Hold on !
*Man*Howcanyou expect
to defeat me whenyou are but a man...
and I am forever !
* Cheering *
We must lock the doors !
- Deliverus, O Lord.
- *Jericho* Everyone, out!
Get them to a safeplace!
Get them out ofhere!
* Screaming *
*Man*
Lady, come on !
*LoudBanging*
*BangingStops*
What are we gonna do ?
- Hide. Just hide !
- No.
Please, God, help me.
Give me strength.
*Rumbling*
*Rumbling Continues*
* Roaring *
*Growling*
- * Snarls *
- *Jericho Gasps *
* Snarls *
* Roaring *
* Growling *
* Grunting *
- *Jericho Grunting *
- *Satan Growling*
* Cheering,
Horns Honking *
Christine.
Christine ?
Jericho ?
Are you all right ?
* Panting *
- What happened ?
- It's over.
We won.
Let's go.
Huh ?
- What's wrong ?
- Nothing is wrong.
- * Grunts *
- Everything is the way it should be.
No ! Jericho ! No ! No !
No, please !
What are you doing ?
Jericho !
No !
* Grunting *
* Grunting, Gasping *
No ! Stop it !
You died for nothing.
You just bought them time.
Please. You have to fight him,
Jericho. lknowyou.
- You're stronger than he is.
- * Clothes Tearing *
That's why you came back for me.
Don't let him win.
*CrowdCheering*
* Panting *
*Bell Tolls*
* Whimpering *
*Jericho Grunting *
Run.
- Run.
- * Gasps *
* Grunts *
- Yah !
- No !
* Screaming *
*CrowdShouting*
Six, five, four,
three, two, one!
* Screaming *
* Roaring *
* Shrieking *
*Amy Whispering*
Daddy ?
* Grunts *
Thankyou.
* Sirens Wailing *
* Cheering *
***Soprano Vocalizing*
*** Vocalizing Continues*
***Choir Vocalizing*
***Soprano Vocalizing*
*Boy Chanting*
* OculusDeum*
***Soprano Vocalizing*
***TubularBellsRinging*
*Heart Beating*
*DistortedShout*
- *Heart Beating*
- *DistortedShout*
*Eerie Chanting*
***Rock*
*lt'snot howyou're thinking
Asyou've been mine*
* You been livinga dream now
Believeyou're a badjump*
*Believeyou're in favour
Anddrain outyoursoul*
*And what can ldo
when there'sso manyliars*
* That crawlthroughyour veins
Like millions ofspiders*
*Andseek out their victims
And who is the wiser*
* Watch out*
* Gotcha*
* Oh my God
lcan't denythis*
*l've been taught
just to killandfight this*
*Don't buryit deeper
where nobodycan findit*
*Like nobody wantedto know*
*Sogive it awaylike
they're notgonna fuckyou*
*Howlong canyou beg them
to come backandhauntyou*
* To runpastyourdemons
andcarryyou to someplace*
* You'restartin'to bleed
Andtheydon'tgive up*
*Before it's too late
What willyou offer*
*ln ways ofhealing
Oh, l'm so confused*
* Confused*
*Misused*
* Oh my God
lcan't denythis*
*l've been taught
just to killandfight this*
*Don't buryit deeper
where nobodycan findit*
* 'Cause nobody wantedto know*
* Ooh, ifit opensyoureyes*
* Well,just bet on
a strong compromise*
*l was willing
to be lost in theshuffle*
*lfonlyyou hadlet me know*
* Ooh, ifit opensyoureyes*
* Well, thenjust bet
on a little less compromise*
*l was willing
to be lost in theshadows*
*lfonlyyou hadlet me know*
*Andthey won'tgive in 'cause
theyknow what they're after*
*l'llgiveyou them dayslike
it'sallthat wouldmatter*
*And*
*Screaming*
* Oh my God
lcan't denythis*
*l've been tryingjust
to murderandfight this*
*Don't buryit deeper
where nobodycan findit*
* Well, nobody wantedto know*
* Ooh, ifit opensyoureyes*
* Well, thenyou can bet
on a littlegoodcompromise*
*l was willing
to be lost in theshuffle*
*lfonlyyou hadlet me know*
* Ooh, when they're done
with theshow*
*Like the tide
out on the ocean*
* The wave'salready
set in motion*
* The onlyone in thegame
who'slost isyou**