[???]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
GUARD:
Turn around.
[RATTLING]
MAN 1 :
I'II bite your head off.
[YELLS]
I'II see you out there. Yeah.
Yeah, motherfuckers.
MAN 2: We'II fuck your ass up, man.
WARDEN:
In The Prophet, Kahlil Gibran
writes about good and evil.
''Of the good in you, I can speak,
but not of the evil. ''
You are onIy good
when you are at one with yourseIf.
What you went through in here
I wouIdn't wish on any man.
But you survived.
You didn't ask for troubIe.
But you didn't back down
from it either.
It was as if you were born
to the darkness in this pIace.
[CLOCK TICKING]
I hope to God
that this day,
you put that darkness behind you.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
I want you to know
there is heIp on the outside.
So if you get to thinking it's too much
and you can't handIe the pressure,
pIease caII one of these numbers.
Do you have any questions?
Where's the exit?
[SIGHS]
[GUIDO & MAURIZIO DE ANGELIS'
''GOODB YE MY FRIEND'' PLAYS]
[HORNS HONKING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
MAN 1 : Oh, what are you doing?
MAN 2: Hey!
MAN 3:
Hey, what the heII?
RECEPTIONIST:
May I heIp you?
Sir? Sir?
Now, that happens, we'II be--
[???]
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
MAN:
Jesus.
[JEFFRE Y LUCK LUCAS'
''GRIFOS MUERTOS'' PLAYS]
MAN 1 :
How's it going, man?
[MAN 2 SPEAKS IN SPANISH]
You know how it is.
One day good, the next not so good.
Just have to go with the fIow,
you know?
So, uh...
You don't trust me.
AII right.
[COINS CLATTERING]
Man, what did I teII you
about that hairy change?
Okay, if you don't
want my business,
I'II take it eIsewhere.
It's your jones, hoImes.
MAN 1 :
Wait a minute. PIease.
I'm sorry. I was just
messing with you, okay?
It's me. You know me.
PIease.
[???]
Okay, okay.
[DOOR OPENS]
[KENNY ROGERS
& THE FIRST EDITION'S
''JUST DROPPED IN'' PLAYS]
Oh, no.
Hey.
WiII you Iook at that?
Looks Iike somebody got Iost.
What do we got?
Wha--? What do we got?
Yeah, I caught the case.
CICERO: No, you didn't.
Yeah.
You couIdn't have.
Why is that?
Because MaIIory wouId
never put you on my case.
I don't Iike this
any more than you do.
I'm weeks away from retirement,
got paperwork up my ass.
So when the supervising sergeant
teIIs me to jump,
I just go with the fIow, baby.
You can't smoke in here.
Sorry.
CICERO:
Get me a good tight shot
of that exit wound.
MAN [ON TV]:
It is being reported
that a gunman entered
a downtown Bakersfield building
this afternoon and opened fire,
killing an employee.
The suspect remains at large.
[EXERCISE MACHINE
SQUEAKING]
Stop!
He is described as a male in his 30s,
approximately 6'3'' tall
with closely cropped hair.
Police have not yet released
the name of the victim.
[???]
MAN [ON TV]:
The gunman was described as
armed and extremely dangerous.
Let me caII you right back.
WeII, weII.
You've been a bad boy.
It's a nice set of wheeIs
I got you out there.
You got my money?
Hm.
Now, how'd you smuggIe
that much money out of prison?
You don't wanna know.
[GROANS]
I want the other names.
The price just went up.
It took me 1 0 years
to track down these peopIe for you.
And it cost a Iot of money.
And now I wants to re-negotiate.
Okay.
That's what I thought.
You're pIaying baII now.
The price just went down.
Kenny?
Kenny.
This here is
my Samoan friend.
UItimate Fighting champion
over in Guam.
You don't know haIf the sick shit
they do over there just to win a titIe.
[SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]
[???]
I know what that is.
I know who you are.
Who is he?
Brother,
I ain't got no beef with you.
Do what I pay you to do.
What are you doing?
This dude's a ghost.
I can't mess with no ghost.
You better get back.
KENNY: I ain't messing with a ghost.
BaId-headed Precious. Get your--
Here, I owe you a refund.
Here you go.
CICERO:
He Iooks so famiIiar.
I have seen him somewhere,
I know it.
ReaIIy?
[GRUNTS]
AII right, here it comes.
Look at his face.
He knew
his number was up.
Wait a minute.
That's not just fear,
that's recognition.
He can't see where the gun is.
It's bIocked by the partition.
He knew him.
Maybe.
[???]
WOMAN [OVER PHONE]: Hello?
Marina.
Hey, it's me.
Do you know what time it is?
Yes, I know it's Iate, I'm sorry.
Call me right--
Okay, okay.
You're taking him to the game.
Yes, I'II be there tomorrow.
I'II pick him up tomorrow.
Yes, I'II be on time.
Don't let him down. Promise.
Yes, I promise.
But Iisten-- Listen.
[LINE DISCONNECTS]
[IGG Y POP'S
''I WANNA BE YOUR DOG'' PLAYS]
[???]
Morning.
KILLER:
I did a sequence of poses
this morning
that onIy 1 0 peopIe
on the pIanet can do.
Ending with the corpse pose.
But you know what,
I'm done with yoga.
I beat it.
You beat yoga?
Yeah.
[LILY CHUCKLES]
It's time to move on.
To what?
I don't know.
Something more uItimate.
I worry that a reaI corpse pose
is the onIy thing
that's gonna satisfy you.
No, come on, not death.
Life.
Oh, I've never feIt so aIive.
ReaIIy?
Yeah.
[PHONE RINGING]
MAN [OVER PHONE]:
Got a new client for you.
I know you like a challenge.
We're gathering information
on locations.
I'll send you the target spec now.
The client thinks
the target's coming after him.
He needs the job done fast.
Okay.
[LINE DISCONNECTS]
LILY:
Who's he?
[???]
It's not a question I ever ask.
Sure you don't wanna stay a whiIe?
HoId that thought.
[CAR DOOR CLOSES]
KILLER:
It's my work.
It's getting harder and harder
to go on these jobs.
WOMAN [OVER HEADSET]:
You mentioned this before
at our last session.
Can you take some time off?
KILLER: No, no, that's not an option.
My business is important.
You haven't told me
what it is you do now.
I'm a surgeon. I remove cancer.
Well, I'll have to take you
at your word.
You know, I have other patients
in the medical field.
They find it hard to handle
the stress associated with their jobs.
There's a lot of pressure
when you have someone's life
in your hands.
[SIGHS]
Morning, Detective Cicero.
Sergeant MaIIory.
Don't be mad.
You shouId've toId me.
MALLORY:
You're right, you shouId've
heard it from me. I'm sorry.
I shouId've toId you.
Let him heIp you
with the case though.
[???]
COP:
So, what do we got?
You pIay fast and Ioose
with that ''we'' shit, cowboy.
We got our shooter.
We?
I got a caII from the warden
at Murdoch.
He recognized our guy in the news.
ApparentIy, he made a Iot of money
running contraband in prison.
Any gang affiIiations?
Nope, did his whoIe 1 0.
No protection. A waIk-aIone.
They kept coming after him.
He kept knocking them down.
I see he kept score.
AII he had to do was fIash that
and no one wouId screw with him.
He got popped for a bank job.
Ten years ago, BakersfieId First.
ROBBER 1 :
Don't be a hero, you got me?
Stay down.
Shooter was a bank robber--
He was the driver.
ROBBER 1 : Go, go.
DRIVER: Get in.
[???]
Go, go, go!
[SIRENS WAILING]
ROBBER 2:
Look out.
[SIRENS WAILING]
What are you doing?
You're gonna get us kiIIed.
He knows what he's doing.
Do your thing, IittIe brother.
Go, go, go.
ROBBER 3:
Damn it, what's he doing?
ROBBER 2:
Where you going?
They passed. They passed. Do it.
I don't see anyone. Think we're cIear.
ROBBER 3: SIow down.
SIow down!
[SCREAMS]
ROBBER 3:
Turn it around. Turn it around.
You son of a--
ROBBER 2:
Watch it, watch it, watch it!
Cops, man!
ROBBER 3: They're right there!
BROTHER: You're good. Go.
Cops, cops.
BROTHER:
You're good, you're good.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Rip it. Rip it.
[LAUGHS]
Now, he made a cIean getaway.
So who coIIared him?
Good, this is where
it gets reaIIy interesting.
I wanna show you something.
Check this out.
OLD MAN:
Oh, my.
This is such a big heIp.
It takes me a Iong time
to get up those stairs.
You can put the things anywhere.
Okay.
[???]
[GROANS]
You okay?
Yes.
Thank you for your concern.
You're very kind to heIp an oId man.
Sure.
I'm gonna go.
Can I offer you something to drink?
I shouId be going.
No, Iet me get you something.
PIease,
it's the Ieast I can do.
Be nice to have a IittIe
company for a change.
KILLER: You see,
I changed careers because I--
WeII, I had some issues
I needed to resoIve.
You know, I needed to test myseIf.
MentaIIy and physicaIIy.
ReaIIy re-create myseIf.
WOMAN [OVER HEADSET]:
And now it's all become too easy.
Yes. Yes.
I'm bored, but I mean,
that's onIy part of it.
I mean, it's LiIy.
She's a distraction.
Distractions can be a probIem
in my work.
WOMAN:
You were going to talk to her
about marriage and having a family.
Is that still something you want?
You know what? You're right.
I mean, she's the woman I wanna
spend the rest of my Iife with.
Are you gonna ask her
to marry you?
That's what I'II do.
I'II pop the question. Heh, heh.
Are you off your meds?
Yes.
As your therapist,
I have to advise against that.
Gotta go.
MAN 1 :
All right, look, there's two cars.
MAN 2:
Quiet.
MAN 3:
All right, you're good.
MAN 2:
All right, you guys. Here we go.
MAN 3:
Be quiet.
MAN 2:
Back, back, back!
Hands up!
Back up.
Tell me what's going on here?
After the bank job,
they got ambushed
by another crew.
Somebody set him up.
And somebody taped it?
Sick bastard made
his own personaI snuff fiIm.
MAN 2: Where's the money?
MAN 3: Tell them.
CICERO:
I knew I remembered
this guy from somewhere.
Where did you get this?
First week I made detective,
Vice busted this porn operation.
I waIked into the buIIpen,
they were watching this.
I pretended I got a phone caII,
had to waIk out.
Didn't have the stomach for it.
MAN 2:
Bank robbers, huh?
Tough guys.
BROTHER: Don't tell them.
I fIipped it to Homicide,
but never went anywhere.
Why is that?
Never see the kiIIers' faces, not once.
MAN 2: Where's the money?
Don't tell, bro.
MAN 3: Brothers?
MAN 2: Your brother?
MAN 3: I don't see the resemblance.
MAN 4: Yeah.
MAN 2:
You want me to shoot him, huh?
Like the others?
He's not gonna kill me,
he's bluffing.
MAN 2: Bluffing?
Two down and I'm bluffing?
You want me to shoot him?
MAN 3: Think twice.
MAN 2:
You want me to shoot him, huh?
Like the others?
[MAN 4 LAUGHS]
BROTHER: Don't tell him.
DRIVER: Don't shoot him.
BROTHER: He's not gonna shoot.
Let's tell him where it is.
But it's our only leverage.
[BROTHER YELLS]
I'm sorry I got you into this, bro.
MAN 2:
Just tell me where the money is.
OLD MAN:
I bet you're a good student.
Yeah.
Thanks for the drink.
Sure.
I shouId get going.
BROTHER:
Sorry I got you into this, bro.
Sorry I dragged you into this.
MAN 2: Last chance.
BROTHER: Don't tell him, bro.
Please, don't shoot him.
BROTHER: Don't do it.
MAN 2:
It's up to you.
BROTHER:
Don't you tell him, bro. Don't tell him.
Under the floorboards
in the kitchen.
MAN 2:
There you go.
DRIVER: Gary, I'm sorry.
BROTHER: It's okay.
I'm sorry.
It's gonna be okay, bro.
It's gonna be okay.
No!
MAN 1 :
Oh, Jesus, man, no.
DRIVER:
No!
[BROTHER GASPING]
MAN 3: Gotta get that money.
Jesus, man.
DRIVER:
Gary!
ToId you wouIdn't shoot him.
Watch him.
MAN 4: Okay.
TELEMARKETER:
See if he's Iying.
MAN 3:
I got it.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
TELEMARKETER:
Lift this up in the bag.
MAN 4:
Hey. Hey.
SmiIe for the camera.
[???]
[SCREAMING]
I didn't know.
I didn't know
that was gonna happen.
Don't, pIease.
He made us do it.
PIease don't hurt me.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
[DOOR OPENS]
[GASPS]
[???]
[LOCK CLICKS]
[ENGINE STARTS]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
OLD MAN:
Smile for the camera.
I'm gonna kill you all.
CICERO:
They kiIIed him.
What do you mean they kiIIed him?
He was dead.
At least for a little while anyway.
The hospital pronounced him DO A.
[???]
DOCTOR:
Can you hear me?
BuIIet hit, ricocheted around
his skuII, came out his cheek.
He's got a pIate hoIding
the back of his head together.
I mean, this guy refused to die.
And now, he must be going after
everyone in that video.
[???]
You said you wouIdn't be Iate.
Where have you been?
I caught a case.
You're supposed to
take Tommy to his game.
You made me Iate for my cIass.
I'm sorry, it's a big deaI,
this case.
I saw it on TV.
I do not wanna hear about it.
You want me to have fuII custody?
I wiII take custody.
COP:
You know I don't want that.
Then take him to his basebaII game.
Okay. AII right.
What's up, champ?
What position they got you pIaying?
Don't pIay much.
WeII, you got an arm
Iike a cannon.
I don't know why
they wouIdn't Iet you.
I know.
Maybe I shouId have a taIk
with that coach.
Maybe pinch-hit or something.
What do you say?
[PHONE RINGING]
HeIIo?
CICERO: Hey, it's Cicero.
There's been another shooting.
This could be our guy.
Yeah.
Mallory wants you
down at the scene.
Okay, I'II be there in a IittIe bit.
40 45 Danson oad. Got it?
I'll be there in an hour.
[LINE DISCONNECTS]
Hey, you know what,
I'm not gonna make it in today.
I'm taking my son
to a basebaII game.
It's reaIIy important that I be there.
WeII, you know what?
That's just too bad.
AII right, bye.
Good grief.
Can you imagine that?
I aIready toId them I had
a baII game to go to today.
[???]
[CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS]
IncredibIe.
You're a fuII two hours Iate.
John, did you--?
So, what do we got?
What do you got?
Guy did the worId
a favor on this one.
Found out
who shot our snuff fiIms.
Excuse me.
So we got a teIemarketer,
a sex offender.
What's next, a Iawyer?
WhoIe shebang
just got a Iot weirder.
Witnesses pIaced a
second shooter at the scene.
After our suspect
whacked Mr. Rogers,
he had a IittIe shootout
in the haII.
Maybe an armed neighbor.
Uh-uh.
No one recognized
this dude.
They exchanged gunfire
then disappeared.
Both of them.
COP:
The second shooter,
any description?
The word ''beautifuI'' came up.
BeautifuI?
Like a movie star.
KILLER:
He punked me.
He's reaIIy that good?
KILLER [OVER HEADSET]:
Good's not even the right word.
I mean, you know,
the dude's compIeteIy artIess.
I mean, there's no sophistication
to him whatsoever.
But he's pure, you know?
No fear, no hesitation.
There's nothing.
He as fast as you?
No, he's faster.
You'II get him.
How can you be so sure, hey?
Because you aIways do.
KILLER: Baby.
Yeah?
Marry me.
MAN:
Hey, mister.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
Goddamn it. Shit.
[LAUGHING]
Is that what I think it is?
Oh, the tattoo?
Yeah. Tattoo.
Yeah, I was in the L.A. Crash Unit
before I got transferred up here.
Guns bIazing, ass-kicking cops
with porno mustaches?
That Crash?
Yeah, is it so hard
for you to beIieve?
Yeah.
Can I get in there?
That's where I met Marina,
actuaIIy. She was my CI.
You married your snitch?
Dude, that is wrong
on so many IeveIs.
WeII, she was in reaIIy bad shape.
Got in rehab and we feII in Iove
and there you go.
Was she the onIy one in rehab?
That's ancient history.
You sure about that, Hoss?
Listen, I got 1 0 days
to retirement.
FuII benefits for me and my famiIy,
so why wouId I screw that up?
It's aII I got.
COP:
AII right. Let's go.
How Iong you been cIean?
Since my son was born.
Good for you.
[DOOR OPENS]
MAN:
David, come on.
WOMAN:
David, did you forget something?
You forgot my hug.
BO Y: Love you, Mommy.
[???]
[ENGINE STARTS]
Good job.
[DOOR CLOSES]
[FOOTSTEPS]
[BAB Y BABBLING]
Oh, my God.
You can't do this.
Why did you come?
There's nothing for you here.
Why did you make me stop
coming to see you in prison?
I didn't see any sense
of three wasted Iives.
Three?
Was that him?
The boy?
David?
You shouIdn't think...
You did a dime.
David's 8. Do the math.
When you cut me off,
I gave the baby up.
Did you find a good famiIy?
I had an abortion.
I'm sorry.
[SOBBING]
[???]
[BAB Y CRYING]
AII right.
They know what you're doing.
I saw it on TV.
I hope you kiII them aII.
[???]
PRIEST:
ShaII we begin?
[GUNSHOTS]
[LAUGHING]
Fair enough.
Let's start a famiIy.
FamiIy?
Yeah.
What's gotten into you?
We'II seII the house by the Iake,
and we'II get a Craftsman
in Pasadena.
Fresh start.
You're serious about this,
aren't you?
Yes.
And what about your work?
Oh, um...
WeII, what about it?
WouId you quit before this job?
AbsoIuteIy.
I wiII quit absoIuteIy.
Just Iike that?
Just Iike that.
Marina.
Let me in for a second,
I need to taIk.
I'm gonna stand here aII day,
so you may as weII.
Marina.
[LOCK CLICKS]
WOMAN [ON TV]:
--killed, the first victim
was gunned down less than an hour
after the suspected gunman
was released from prison.
While the second victim
was shot--
What are you doing here?
Thought you didn't care
about my case.
REPORTER:
--to a bank robbery at Bakersfield
1 0 years ago.
Look, I do not need you coming here
and dragging us down again.
Marina, if you just--
No.
I am getting
my associate's degree.
I am trying to
make something better
for Tommy and me.
PIease take me back.
It'II be okay.
It's not okay.
Marina, I'm begging you.
I'm begging you, pIease.
God. Get off your knees.
Marina, pIease. Just pIease--
Don't touch me.
Do not touch me.
Give me the dope.
I don't have any dope.
Give it to me.
Okay. Here.
It's aII I got.
Look, I'II go to rehab.
I swear to God I wiII.
Let's go. Let's go right now.
After the case, I gotta finish the case.
WeII, I can't just waIk out on that.
I just wanna be with you
for one night.
I mean, you know,
with Tommy and--
PIease.
Just one night.
[MAN SINGING IN SPANISH
ON RADIO]
MAN 1 [ON RADIO]: adio--
MAN 2: Twenty-five dollar gift cert--
EVANGELIST:
Brother, put down that bottle.
Put down that cocaine,
that methamphetamine.
Put down that .45,
that .38 and that .357 Magnum.
EVANGELIST [ON RADIO]:
So precious to each one of us.
Why?
The night is far gone,
the day is at hand.
Those that live by the sword
will die by the sword,
unless they learn to forgive.
God made life so fragile
and so precious for each one of us.
You will never truly be free
unless you learn to--
BOUNCER 1 :
Yo, I gotta take a Ieak.
I'II be right back.
BOUNCER 2:
HoId up, big man,
I gotta check you. Arms up.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
BOUNCER 2:
Got any weapons on you
besides these guns here?
I'm onIy kidding, man.
Go on, have a good time.
CASHIER:
WeIcome to the gentIemen's cIub.
It's a two-drink minimum
tonight, baby.
[RICH ROSSI'S ''LEAN'N''
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
My man.
Hey, what's up, big dog?
I'm great.
Right.
[SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY]
Wake up, Joe.
Huh?
[???]
BOUNCER:
I've been expecting you.
Joe.
Huh?
Oh, SheIIy.
Go outside and watch the door.
OnIy one of us
is gonna make it out of here.
No matter who it is, Joe,
you didn't see a damn thing.
Go on.
AII right, then.
[GRUNTING]
[GASPING]
I got a son.
TeII him I said I'm sorry.
I'm begging you.
He's speed diaI number three.
I'm sorry.
He made us take you down.
[LINE RINGS]
BO Y [OVER PHONE]:
Hello? Hello?
Your father's sorry.
Who is this? Is he okay?
Did something happen?
Yeah.
Something happened.
[???]
I thought you said
you were done.
I have to finish this one first.
You promised me you were quitting.
And I wiII. I wiII quit.
But after this one.
No, this isn't fair.
I didn't ask you to marry me.
I'm sorry.
You're sorry?
Mm-hm.
What if I toId you you had to choose?
Don't.
You used to be attracted
to what I do.
I'm your wife now.
What if he kiIIs you?
LiIy.
[SOBS]
Daddy?
Yeah?
I know I suck at basebaII.
You don't have to pretend
Iike I'm good.
You'II get better.
You just need to practice.
Maybe you and I can throw
the baII around one day.
How's that?
Okay.
I gotta teII you a secret first, though.
What, Daddy?
I suck at basebaII too.
[BOTH LAUGH]
[CLATTERING]
You go to sIeep, okay?
I'II be back.
Jesus Christ.
[GROANS]
Oh, Jesus.
Are you okay?
Look at me, Iook at me.
Why did you do this?
I'm afraid.
What are you afraid of,
honey?
We're going to heII for what we did.
Do you know what heII is?
It's not fire and deviIs.
AII that stuff they taught you
when you was IittIe.
We make our heaven
and our heII whiIe we're aIive,
[???]
every time we cause pain,
every time we cause suffering.
[PHONE LINE RINGS]
CICERO [OVER PHONE]: Cicero.
Hey, it's me. Did I wake you up?
No.
You said on your message
to give you a caII, so...
Okay, here's the deaI.
Both of our victims
were informants.
CouId be something there, right?
COP: Yeah, couId be.
Nice work.
CICERO:
Okay, I need you to foIIow up on it.
I gotta be in court,
but I reaIIy think we're getting cIose.
It's gotta have something to do
with how they got set up.
Did you hear about that stabbing
in Henderson?
Yeah, yeah, what about it?
I got a hunch it might be our guy.
It's not his m.o.
Our guy's a shooter,
not a stabber.
Like I said, I got a hunch.
Yeah, so did Quasimodo.
Look where it got him.
I'm gonna go ask a few questions.
After you do the foIIow-up, right?
Got it cIeared with the Henderson IC.
I'm headed up there now.
I have to be in court aII day.
I am asking you to do this.
It's my case.
[LINE DISCONNECTS]
[SIGHS]
WOMAN [ON RADIO]:
--bring us nothing
but the same politics as usual.
I have fought
to keep government honest,
save you money
and to lower your taxes.
Above all,
I will be someone who listens to you.
The choice is simple,
vote Margie Pageant.
MAN 1 :
In local news, a Henderson man
is fighting for his life
after being brutally attacked
at a gentlemen's club.
The man is suffering
from stab wounds.
Doctors describe his condition
as critical.
MAN 2 [OVER PHONE]:
Hello?
[???]
[PHONE BEEPS]
DOCTOR : Sponge.
NURSE: Sponge.
MAN [OVER HEADSET]:
We think he'll be heading back.
Your position?
Tehachapi.
Try the hospital in Clark County.
His third victim survived the hit.
He'll be wanting to finish the job.
Where are you?
MAN:
Good night.
NURSE:
Doctor.
[GUNSHOTS AND MAN YELLING]
MAN:
What the heII is that?
[PEOPLE SCREAMING]
COP:
Back in the room, back in the room.
PoIice officer, get back.
PoIice.
NURSE: He went that way.
COP: I'm a cop. Where'd he go?
He went downstairs, officer.
[SIGHS]
[GUN CLATTERS]
[DOOR SLAMS]
[PHONE RINGING]
BO Y [OVER PHONE]:
How do you have my dad's phone?
He asked me to caII you.
Are you the one who killed him?
Yes.
I'm gonna find you
and I'm gonna kill you.
Do what you need to do.
But you better be sure,
because it's a Iong, dark road
you're headed down.
[???]
[HORN HONKING]
[GROANING]
[GUNSHOT]
[GUNSHOTS]
[PHONE RINGING]
I Iost him.
MAN [OVER HEADSET]:
Client wants to pull the job.
No. No way.
You teII him to back off.
I've got this under controI. AII right?
You're running out of time.
Where's the oId man?
Dead.
Don't Iie to me.
I'II show you the damn grave.
How Iong ago?
I don't know.
Three or four years.
WOMAN:
HoId stiII.
[???]
Okay.
MOTHER:
How Iong you been out?
CoupIe of days.
And why are you here?
Came here to kiII the oId man.
Why?
Because he set us up.
What makes you think that?
Gary went to him for advice
on the bank job
and he wanted fuII share.
Gary wouIdn't give it to him.
So do you think
the oId man was capabIe
of murdering his own son?
Yeah.
No.
Mm-mm.
Nope.
He couIdn't have.
What makes you so sure?
I just... I just know.
TeII me.
Say it.
Mom.
Because...
he Ioved your brother too much.
I'm sorry.
And that's the truth
and that's not your fauIt.
It wasn't Iike
I couId pretend you were his.
He was reminded of that
every time he Iooked at you.
You never stood a chance.
Sorry that I couIdn't...
That I didn't protect you.
The beatings and...
[SOBBING]
Gary was the onIy one
who ever cared for me.
Why'd he puII you in on that job?
You were never a part
of what they did.
When his driver feII out,
I voIunteered.
Why?
He owed the wrong peopIe
a Iot of money.
And he needed me.
If it wasn't the oId man,
then who set us up?
[???]
[MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY
ON RADIO]
EVANGELIST [ON RADIO]:
Driven by his passions and desires.
You will never truly be free
unless you freely forgive.
Hate is like a chain
around your neck
that leads you to places
you don't wanna go.
It'll lead you into darkness
and desolation.
You become a slave
to that hatred,
and it'll only lead
to your own destruction.
You must break free.
WOMAN: Hey, cowboy.
You okay, man?
COP: Yeah.
MAN 1 : You Iaid eyes on him at Ieast.
Hey, weII done.
Thanks, man.
I gotta caII you back.
MAN 2: StiII in one piece.
MAN 3: Good job.
Good Iead, cowboy.
You aImost got him.
We got cIose.
Yeah.
It was a good hunch.
WeII, even Quasimodo
has his day.
And don't ever hang up on me again.
Roger that.
I hate to spoiI your moment.
Got something I wanna show you.
I think we may have caught a break.
You said ''we'' again.
I did.
CICERO:
Our Iatest victim was a CI too.
COP:
So aII three are informants.
CICERO:
Mm-hm. AII got records,
armed robbery, rape, assauIt.
But none did any serious time.
They aII snitched their way
out of the joint over and over.
What are the odds of that?
SIim and none.
I'm waiting on
the informant Iogs now.
COP: Who are these?
Former accompIices of the victims.
Let's spIit them up, check them out.
I'II take these.
EVANGELIST [ON RADIO]:
And I know there's not a man,
woman or child in this church today
that has not sinned.
But God did not bring you down
on this Earth to be perfect. No.
God wants you down here
to be saved.
[CROWD CHEERS ON RADIO]
And when you're down with God,
God is eternally down with you.
[???]
EVANGELIST [ON RADIO]:
When Jesus knew his time was near,
when he knew he was gonna die,
when he knew they would not take
that cup from his lips,
his thoughts were not
upon his own.
His thoughts were for those
that he loved.
WOMAN: Amen.
EVANGELIST: That's right.
His thoughts were for those
that he loved, preparing them.
EVANGELIST:
Why is that?
He used the exampIe of his birth.
That's right. Here it is.
Jesus toId them how a woman
goes through pain and sorrow
in the throes of chiIdbirth.
But then as soon
as she has deIivered,
there is no more anguish.
[CHEERING]
After aII the screaming,
after aII the pushing,
after aII the bIood and the tears,
there's onIy joy that a new chiId
has been born.
WOMAN 1 :
HaIIeIujah!
And I'II teII you my--
WOMAN 2: Amen! Amen!
[CROWD CHEERING]
WOMAN 3:
Amen.
WOMAN 4:
Amen. Amen. Amen.
WOMAN 5: HaIIeIujah!
Amen!
MAN: Amen!
Sing me a song!
[CHEERING]
[BAND PLAYING GOSPEL MUSIC]
[SINGING ''TROUBLE IN MY WAY'']
[SINGING INDISTINCTLY]
EVANGELIST:
I was wondering
when you were gonna show up.
You've been the subject
of many of my sermons
these past few days.
I heard.
You heard.
But did you Iisten?
Everything okay,
baby?
Everything's just fine,
honey.
I was just catching up with
an oId acquaintance.
You go on home now.
Let's take a waIk.
[???]
Was that your son?
Adopted.
One of five.
Wayward boys.
Not unIike me or you
at that age.
You turned your Iife around.
Doesn't change
what you did.
I wouIdn't want it to.
I know it sounds coId,
but every good I've done
hinged on the eviI I did.
Who set us up?
I don't know.
I never did find out
how they knew about
your safe house.
When I got the caII,
''Easy money,'' they said.
AII I had to do
was guard the door,
be the Iookout.
I was in a dark pIace
in my Iife.
Numb to the chaos and--
Right here.
But when they cut
that boy's throat...
Oh, Jesus, man. No.
That boy they kiIIed was my brother.
I can't bring him back.
And in my heart I'm sorry.
I stiII took my cut,
spent it on drugs and women.
Ended up in prison.
But it was there
that I found my caIIing.
To save and heIp boys Iike me.
And Iike you.
It was there
that I gave my Iife to God.
God can't save you from me.
But maybe he couId save you
from yourseIf.
I know there's good--
You don't know me.
I know the deviI
got your heart twisted
with vengeance and hate.
The Lord is mercifuI.
He sees in your souI.
FragiIe, ain't it?
That moment, that sets us
on our road to Damascus.
Sermon's over.
Can you at Ieast find it in your heart
to forgive me for what I did?
I can't.
That's aII right.
Because I forgive you
for what you're about to do.
[SINGING
''JOHN THE REVELATOR'']
Lord, see into this man's heart.
He's good inside.
Oh, Lord, save this man's souI.
I know you see his heart.
[EVANGELIST
CONTINUES SINGING]
ReIease him from the bondage
of hatred and vengeance, Lord.
[CONTINUES SINGING]
[EVANGELIST GRUNTS]
Go back to your famiIy.
[???]
That's one heII of a peashooter
you got there.
How's the recoiI?
[???]
[RINGING]
Yeah.
CICERO: Where are you?
Inyo County at the reservoir.
They're here. Both of them.
What? Did you caII for backup?
There's no time for that.
Okay, don't do this.
I'm sorry
I keep stepping on your case.
CICERO: I don't care about that.
Want you to do me a favor.
If I don't make it out of this,
teII my son that
his daddy went out Iike a man.
I am on my way.
PIease, just wait for me.
I'm just going with the fIow.
Damn.
[FAX MACHINE BEEPS]
Aren't you gonna
reach for it?
Come on.
Sporting chance.
I've got nothing against you.
I've been trying to kiII you for days
and you've got nothing against me?
I'm starting to think you don't
take me very seriousIy, friend.
DRIVER:
What do you want from me?
How about a IittIe respect? Hey?
A IittIe professionaI courtesy
from a peer.
Some acknowIedgment
of my skiIIs.
You've got issues.
Screw you.
I win.
[KILLER CHUCKLES]
You think you're done?
You can't put it together, can you?
There must be one more.
The one who hired me.
He's stiII aIive.
I'm gonna kiII you aII.
Drop the gun.
Don't move.
SIowIy.
Put the gun down.
No.
Put the goddamn gun down.
No! This is my job!
I finish my job.
How you gonna finish this
when you're dead?
So you're the guy that hired me.
You shouIdn't
have done that.
I had to finish what I started.
Why'd you hire me then?
I didn't think I was up to it.
After you missed him,
I figured I shouId get invoIved
before he came gunning for me.
He didn't even know about you.
I figured that out when
he didn't finish me off
at the hospitaI.
His brother's girIfriend
was my informant down in L.A.
She toId me about the job.
Hired some more of my informants
down there.
They helped me take down
their score.
So, what now?
Now?
I ride off into the sunset.
Hey.
I forgot to pay you.
You know,
I don't get you.
Why do you put yourseIf
through aII this shit
for one Iousy doIIar?
It's my price.
CaII it a hobby.
You know what, keep it.
I didn't earn it.
Don't contact me again,
I'm done.
Yeah, me too.
[LINE RINGING]
MALLORY [OVER HEADSET]:
Detective Cicero?
CICERO:
Yeah, I can't reach him.
Okay, hopefully he'll turn up.
We've got units en route,
we'II see you shortIy.
CICERO:
Wait a minute.
You didn't fIip him this case,
did you?
I didn't fIip him the case.
Is that what you thought?
He asked for it, right?
He begged for it.
And I felt sorry for him, so I caved.
Is there a reason why
we're taIking about this
right now?
No. No reason.
Okay, I'II see you shortIy.
''Go with the fIow,'' my ass.
Marina? Hey, it's me, honey.
WeII, I got him, I cIosed the case.
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
As a matter of fact, I feeI perfect.
Better than I ever have.
MARINA: Yeah?
Yeah, and I'm gonna
get rid of the other stuff too.
Don't you worry, I promise.
I'II be home in a coupIe hours.
Listen, you're not gonna
beIieve this.
I've been reading up on women,
and I think I got you figured out.
We're gonna be fine.
Yeah, honey, it's over.
I wanna start brand-new, honey.
[GUNSHOT]
[COUGHING]
[COP GRUNTING]
How?
MetaI pIate.
I can't feeI anything.
I created my own heII.
And I'm the demon
who crawIed up out of it.
[LINE RINGING]
LILY [OVER SPEAKERPHONE]:
Hello?
KILLER:
Baby.
LILY: Where are you?
KILLER: I'm coming home.
[CICERO SIGHS]
[THE HEAVY'S
''SHORT CHANGE HERO'' PLAYS]
Today, I wanna taIk to you
about forgiveness.
[???]