SPECIAL FORCES
sub by rekerukuru
Dragan Milevic
War Criminal
Code three!
the priest is in the church!
Lie down! Lie down! Lie down!
Don't move!
Lie down!
Clear!
Bastard!
I'm so sorry!
Kabul
Afghanistan
Is it recording?
Yes
What are you doing?
There's nothing left to hide.
Do you remember
your first visit to Kabul?
of course
I'm sorry.
I told you the story about that little girl
that was sold to settle a debt.
And you said
The only way
to change the world ...
is to change the story,
Yes I remember
So now, I want to tell you mine.
My mother was in love with one man, but her family forced her to
marry another.
As her children, we watched her everyday as she tried to
erase her shame of infidelity.
until one day ...
She went out into the garden, and ..
poured petrol on her face... and she lit a match.
Her older sister Aisaa ...
that same night, her husband put a knive to her face,
to punish her for having such a weak mother
the little girl that was sold was you
Why are you telling me this now?
to protect you from Zaef.
What's the contection to Zaef?
How do you think I know so much about him?
It's to Zaef family that I was sold.
Why are you risking showing you face
to the camera then?
because this is the last time we see each other.
What do you mean?
Elsa, Zaef knows! He found out!
I am sorry, I must go now.
Maina, please wait,
please stay!
I can get you out, please
come with me!
You must go and change my story,
Go back and never return.
Amin, not now
Maina!
The house had been spotted / Maina!
You have to get out of there. You and Maina
have to leave right now!
Who are they?
You hear me.
Shit.
Elsa, leave now!
Yes, I'm coming to the car.
She splits.
We have to go find her.
That's out of the question
She is in danger,
we have to go by her house.
We will be even more in danger if we
go there!
Amen, just do it!
Take a right here.
Get down, hide hide Quick!
FRENCH
Special Base Unit
This is nonsense, I would never say that.
It's not true!
I wouldn't have say yes to you,
it's impossible because I had an appointment with my mother.
Of course, her mom hates me
Do not slam the door, please!
She doesn't hate you, she just find you immature.
But I'm not immature?
You're not immature ?!?
Pay a little attention to the door ..
It's only a old dirty car ..
You did not tell him?
No.
Look, I think I
immature?
Immature?
Stop it.
OK.
What is the problem?
Lisa wanted us to live together and ..
How long does it make?
Only five years that you're together?
Yes, I know the time elapsed
without realizing it ... and then ...
I'll sell the car, and get
Labrador
and then I have to paint the kid's room in blue ... !
Happy birthday to you
Thank you.
KABUL
Hotel Merindi
What would you want to do?
Elsa?
maybe it's time
to take that holiday you have been talking about?
Pick me up in two hours.
This compass has been saving a lot of life during the D Day in Normandy.
It's place is in the museum
That's why we all agreed to offer it to you.
Happy birthday, my brother!
Happy Birthday  / Thanks!
Thanks ...
Saleymani can help us find her.
Maine was gone, there is nothing you can do for her anymore.
I can't just abandon her!
Saleymani!
Here!
Assalaamualaikum.
salam alaykum ...
Please Saleymani
I need your help.
I want to talk to Zaef ...
and I need to find Maina.
I don't know any Zaef.
I am so sorry  Elsa.
I had no choice.
Shut up. run!
Are you okay?
Yes
Stop! go back!
Quick! Quick!
Quick!
This isn't happening?!
Hide your face.
Slowly. Take it easy.
Do not shoot! Do not shoot!
Did you see Jacques? / Yes, He's just there.
Paris
Editorial  Elsa Casanova
Jacques!
The minister of foreign affairs for you!
Yes, thank you
Hello.? Yes, Jacques Beauregard.
Yes, good afternoon
Mr. Minister ... how?
Sorry, what?
What happened? / I have no idea?
Yes!
understand.
Elsa has just been caught by the Taliban.
PARIS
Elysée Palace
Secret meetings
Green Office
What can the best inform man in this country say a little more about it?
Zaef is a fanatic specially unpredictable.
I want to take her back alive.
Is that clear?
Do we know their location?
Possible Ahmed Zaef
located in the village, where he
feels untouchable.
We can send a
special forces team?
How many?
Around 60.
When?
They are already in the plane
Mr. President.
Province of Wardak in Afghanistan
Commander, your helicopter.
Your equipment will be send later!
Afghanistan-Pakistan Border
Gandamak Camp
Welcome to the Camp Gandamak
Did you see the fat man up there?
We are going to bother him.
Come on.
Attention, my rules are very simple!
There are one left limit and one right limit.
If someone goes out this borders
I put him back with my methods!
You will learn quickly
to spit the thunder from the front and to fart the lightning by behind!
Back to this hole!
Now, they give buckets and shovels in the air army?!?
He is with us / What?
Victor! Stop shooting!
The Commander has arrived
and is waiting for us.
Oh fuck the T-shirt!
I've the same for you in kids size!
Superb. It really is great?
Let's go! What awaits us?
My canary / Stop!
My little canary!
Are you alright?
I'm so sorry, Amen.
I should've listened to you.
Don't be sorry.
I'm afraid.
Don't surrender to fear
Did you hear me?
Don't show them your fear.
They can kill us, but they never can
defeat us. understand?
... Commander, Captain.
Commander!
Sit back.
As you can see we have
a new elite sniper.
New and virgin..
How is your accuracy?
I can kill a rabbit at 253 meters (276 yards).
Not bad!
Killer
Like always , there are two news - a good one and a bad one.
We have rabbits for dinner, that's sure.
The bad one:
the hostages are in Pakistan's tribal areas.
What a nice gift for your birthday!
The good one:
It is just reconnaissance mission.
Finally, at the shelter
... and not at the scene.
Questions?
Maybe you want to konw. Elsa Casanovais the journalist who
says we have nothing to do in Afghanistan.
Another question / Yes!
Is she pretty?
Do not shoot! I beg you!Please
Why don't you ask me for
an interview ?
It would have been the civilized way to
go about things.
Civilized?
You call me "The Butcher of Kabul".
Afghan women worst friend
Wasn't that
the title of your last article?
What have you done to Maina?
What I've I done to Maina?
What have your lies done to Maina?
oh I know you.
Your family, so great,
your studies ...
look at you now ...
sitting here, like a dog.
seven brillant years at Cambridge ...
Mounir Zaef son of Khan
one of the most powerful and
influential chiefs.
and yet ... you are sitting there with me ...
only you chose to be here.
Did I invite you into my country
to spread democracy at gunpoint and drive my people crazy?
it's still better than selling
a 12 year old child.
I believe in an interview it is customary for questions derived from
the person holding the camera should be asking the questions.
and I find this question to be
very appropriate right now.
Do you ...believe in God?
Yes, I believe in God.
out loud
I can't read this.
Why aren't you watching?
look at me
Leave her!
Bring the pigs,
Saleymani!
Don't do this
Do not do that! Please!
to sweeten his death.
Don't do this! Don't do this!
Please do not do this!
Don't do it!
Carrier "Charles de Gaulle"
near Pakistan
Admiral  Gezenek
Commander Special Forces
Permission to take the command of the ship, Commander.
Already approved, Admiral.
I need all the
meteorological data update every 30 minutes.
Contact me when the reconnaissance mission take off.
I need to talk to kovax.
30 minutes later
Stop it.
He is crazy!
It's out of question, we see a french journalist decapitate
in every screen around the world.
When your people will be ready to operate?
within 24 hours.
So we already loose this game.
Not necessarily, we've got a last card to play,
Mr. President.
So ... You know everything ...
There was little change.
What are the chances of success?
In this operation there is no guarantee,
Mr. President.
that's why they are called "special".
You can go on the operation.
Victor, we have to double the number of ammo.
I love the job!
How do you say?
I think we can try.
Opening the door!
Day 1
Preparing to jump.
Thirty seconds!
Ten seconds!
Three ... two ... one ...
Green!
Pakistan
Interest areas.
Welcome to Pakistan, buddies!
We have one hour to go to the position.
Well we don't have time to do shopping!
Pakistan
Peshawar
Pakistan Secret Service
At Zukhan ,
spiritual leader of the Taliban
Assalaamualaikum.
Regards Waalaikum Warohmatullohi Wabarokatuh.
Greetings to all members of the Shura.
He has not killed him!
Many of our brethren think
You do not deserve trust.
No, I can prove?
I prefer the glory, but from
The Almighty.
I am a faithful servant of Shura.
It reminded him of a prostitute,
they spent time in London.
Women, is the weakness of the West ...
is not possible.
If a woman is destined to die
will be the will of God.
I am very disappointed.
That's me or they are not 18?
We won't be enough !
Shut up, Tic-Tac
tell us, where they are.
There is only one house with a parabola
and bars on the windows.
if they are in this holiday club, it's in this bungalow.
movement toward 3 o'clock.
What are they doing?
Don't move!
What do I do?
Don't shoot.
Why?
We're not here for that.
understood ...
in English please
I've had enough of this language today.
What are you going to do
with the French journalist?
I don't know ...
I really don't know.
Move!
Elias,
do you hear us?
Yes.
On the count to "three".
One ... two ... three!
Safe!
Go!Go Go Go
It's them!
French troops,
We come to you!
Stay calm!
Hi!
Elsa Casanova?
Taharud Amin?
Turn over.
You will follow my instructions, okay?
Time to go,
they know we are here!
Back!
Heads down, down!
Next.
I'm good, everything is fine,
I'm fine!
Under cover!
They came from all directions!
Behind us!
Move!
Elias, go!
If you hear me, go!
No, I will keep them
until they arrive.
What happened here?
Zaef!
Commando comes to pick them up!
They relieve me of the power to choose to start with
go get me that snipers head
Now!
Now! Go!
Go!
Sit down.
We lost the two bags with portable devices.
And this one is dead.
The helicopter will come anyway.
Show me your arm.
You take care about her.
Ok.
Everything will be okay,
relaxed.
You will follow me and stay near me.
Hold on to my backpack
Do you agree?
Ok / Good.
Take my hand.
Thank you.
Let's go.
Try again to tighten it and I'll knock you out.
Take cover behind the stone.
A lot of sharks there!
GPS?
36 North, 72 East.
We can skirt them if we take behind the mountains.
We won't be in time
at the rendezvous point.
And the emergency sign?
The Taliban can also tap it.
I think they already tap the signal.
You go ahead with Marius.
Ok.
Where are we going?
I'll explain it later, we have to move!
Can I help you?
Sure, if you got a pack of ammo and a radio.
Look who's here!
It seems he got new friends!
Damn, the whole army!
go, my friend!
What is he doing?
Getting they angry.
Let's play!
wait ... wait ...
Now!
I don't know why, but I hesitate more and more
every time I have to press a button.
It has to be a brain problem,
I have to talk about it with my psychiatrist.
Shut up and do it my captain.
Marius.
May I help you?
I will replace the bandages.
You'll have to sew it.
Of course,
22 km to the extraction point !
On the roof of bum fuck nowhere!
watch the language
There is a lady with us.
Sorry, it should be the emotion.
I remind
I am not very good with the needle.
Are you ready?
You all right?
Good ... All right.
it's a distress signal.
twenty km from the extraction point.
Are they moving?
Negative.
We just have half-hour from our trackers.
Helicopters?
Even if they got our signal,
they'll already go to the meeting point.
Okay?
Sorry, already
3 days we did not eat.
She has to take her time.
Lucas read your article.
Critics of the war,
the soldiers do not like.
You're repaired?
The miss did it ?
Efface your smile.
Your analysis was very interesting.
Thank you.
I didn't say that I agree with you.
We can be here for good or bad reasons,
it's our job, we don't do politics.
It seems to be hot there!
What is it?
Our taxi are getting shooted.
They gain ground, we have less than ten minutes.
Damn!
We stop the recuperation.
Get up!
It has been a failure.
Nobody was at the extraction point.
One helicopter made an emergency landing
with a seriously injured person.
Hostages?
There is still no news about them since three hours.
Day 2
We need to stop,
she can't walk more.
Stop. Break.
Do you have a plan "B"?
No, we do not have a plan "B".
What will he decide?
Don't know.
But I'm sure we won't like it.
Hey, Capitain
Victor!
Thank you.
So
what do we do?
To go to Afghanistan there is only
one exit door and it's there!
Are you crazy?
What are they talking about?
The command is to bring you back
and we will do it ...
Is there a better idea?
An hour of anonymous glory
or my anonymous eternity ...
Every minute the possibility
of their survival is reduced.
Do not stop
keep looking.
Everybody stays in alert.
How did you get here?
Parachute.
You understand well what I mean.
Finally!
Been wondering when you would
woke up as a journalist?
What do you want to know?
How I ended up with this decerebrate gang
in uniform?
No,that's not what I wanted to say.
It's okay!
There is not just genius in the army!
But in you work neither.
Are you married?
Now not.
Do you want biscuits with the tea?
What ?
You know that's impossible.
You prefer if we wait them here !
I hope you know what you're doing.
So do I.
You're very brave.
No, that's not courageous ?
The courage was this woman
in the village.
Before they shoot, she was looking at her killers faces ...
Do you know what she did ?
She smiled to them ...
And what did I do?
Nothing.
Sorry, but the talking is not really my thing.
Are you okay?
Yes.
3rd DAY
Tic-Tac.
Ok, I got it.
Is he trustworthy ?
What ?
Reliable? Yes or no?
His whole family were massacred by the Taliban.
Is that enough?
You can use this?
Alright.
Thank you.
The breakfast is coming.
They will not let us go.
That's because they like you.
Elsa? What did you do to get they angry like that?
This becomes a personnal affair.
Sorry, I don't understand.
I don't want to disturb, but they
are getting closer!
He will not give up.
He will do everything to get me back.
It's getting worse and worse.
Ignore. Let's go.
Let's go.
Damn, they are getting us running for three days.
I agree. Aren't you tired?
You. Stay with her.
Yes, sir.
Shoot, shoot!
Go , go ,go !
Again!
Change!
Got It!
How! The attacks!
Attack!
They're like the devil!
You mean all attacks!
Why?
Hindu Kush Mountains
will kill this woman.
Look what you said?
Okli!
Western women
harder than you think!
Exit all!
All-out attack!
Day 4
We're in big trouble.
"How can there be a failure"?
"Defence indefensible"
We would do nothing,
the critics would always be the same!
I am sure there are six mens
in the mountains to get her out.
Friends or Enemies?
The next pass is in five kilometers.
we won't do it if we don't have food and rest.
What the fuck are they doing there?
What she is doing is very
wise ...
Ask for hospitality ...
We never refuse it.
not even to an enemy .
It is tradition.
Next time I'll handcuff you.
Assalamualaikum!
Greetings!
Ask him where are the children?
This summer the Taliban, they take all
and 17 adults.
What for?
Entered into madrassas.
Then it will return to
implementation of Sharia doctrine.
Not surprising,
they don't like them.
What do you think about it?
Good. Take it.
This is not nothing.
Maybe you will need?
Ok. Thank you.
Look!
Bravo!
Come on! Give the hat / Take it!
kovax! !
Here / Throw!
Throw it high!
High!
Take, friends,
does not fit!
Take cover! Hide! / In the shelter! Faster!
Quick! All to the shelter!
Hide!
Marius! No!
He's dead, dead!
Victor, faster!
Leave him!
He is dead!
Go, go!
Behind the wall!
Want to pray for Marius?
It's an honor.
Day 5
Go! Go!
Wait! Wait!
I have to stay.
If I have to die in the mountains,
I prefer to die here.
Searched the house! Quick!
Quick!
This, too!
May God protect all of you.
Thank you for saving my life.
I'll go with him.
Amen! Wait!
Please, my friend!
Amen! We can not leave it there.
Do not be a martyr.
They gave us
hospitality and because of that they are all going to die!
I don't care!
We already lost Marius because a fucking journalist!
We will not take the risk for
this farmer!
Coward!
This fucking journalist will go with them.
Negative!
lucas! Stay with your new friend.
We will save these people.
Assalaamualaikum.
We look forward to
welcome you in our village!
Your Excellency!
Where are they? Where did you hide them?
Where?
Kill them!
I Don't know what happen to me
I'm sorry.
Just in case.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Take it, he liked this weapon.
For Marius!
Go!
Dengarkah not you,
shoot them immediately!
Go!
Damn! Shoot them right away!
Wait no more.
Quick!
Come on,
Hide!
Down!
inside! inside!
Hurry up, come on!
Take cover!
I told you I like it
this job?
Not the first time I heard.
Go! Go! Go!
Go! Quick!
Go!
Victor!
Damn ... Fuck ...
Victor was shot!
Wake up! Come on!
Stay with me.
Hold!
Let's go.
Tic-Tac!
Amin was killed.
Reloading!
I will cover you!
I'm fine, I can
Go on.
Go, go!
Damn it.
Be careful!
Here, here.
Oh, damn ...
Damn! Damn!
Do you know to stop the blood!
It's hurting !
Hold on here.
At the push!
Harder! Come on!
Tic-Tac, you bastard!
Amen?
Ok ... stand it!
Everything will be fine.
You can do it my friend!
Do we wait Elijah?
No.
Why not?
damn ...
Stop!
Sit down.
Leave me!
Leave me! Leave me here!
Only if you're already dead.
You'll survive!
Stay.
Ok.
We can't go on like that.
How much altitude are we?
3800, 3900 meters
Started snowing.
Temperatures will continue to drop.
This is not good.
Everything will be fine!
We have to find a shelter.
Victor, let's go!
Elsa take my blanket ..
It will warm you...
Come on man !
Ok. Come on!
Day 6
He is convulsing !
Hold him!
Hold his feets !
I hold him !
Give him morphine again?
no!
it will kill him!
He is suffocating!
We have to open his mouth!
Come on, come on!
OK, Victor.
Breathe, breathe! Come on!
Breathe, everything is good!
Come on, come on, breath
breath!
All, I'll kill you all!
I even don't hate you!
How are you?
I'm almost gone, right?
It's important that you get back.
Tic-Tac, nine years ago,
lost his wife.
I wish he can be happy!
Take a break.
Day-7
Victor!
Victor! Victor!
Tic-Tac!
No!
What are you doing?
How many of us have to die, only
to understand that we will never be found?
Who's next
You or me?
What do you want?
Stop it!
Enough! Stop it!
You never listen !
I will stay here!
Do you have children?
No.
So we will take you home,
and you will have children ... a lot.
Listen carefully.
Lisa is pregnant!
So you will go home and take care of your wife !
I do not have children either.
Is it an offer capitain?
No, seriously
I hope we can see each other again later.
Is that true, I'll be a father?
Yes, old boy!
Day-8
Help me!
Fuck.
Damn it.
Damn, why did she never say anything
about it?
because of the honor.
She has guts!
You have balls,
you're waiting she faints to say something nice!
Do not look,
turn around!
Everything will be fine.
Do you know what said Victor
before he died?
I love this job ...
Day 9
How can you become reporter
in a dangerous country like this?
I love this country.
Replace it with the Netherlands
would be better.
Why the Netherlands?
That's flat.
Why do you came here?
It was
here or the Netherlands.
It's better the Netherlands.
Yes, it's flat.
Delicatessen!
Delicious!
Next time,
we will go in an Italian restaurant.
Special place.
You will like it.
They cook risotto with mushrooms just fabulous.
Maybe in another life.
We are still not at this point. alright ?
Do not worry, everything will be fine.
Contact! Contact!
Take cover!
No!
Lucas!
Lucas! Lucas!
Your fate is not yours to decide ...
Lucas ! It's okay!
It's okay.
No!
Do not die! Do not die!
Do not die! Lucas!
It happened so fast ...
No!
No! No!
Why, Lucas?
Everything will be fine!
Day 10
Stay with me.
Three miles in two hours.
Do you see this mountain we just pass?
This is the border.
Welcome to Afghanistan.
Beware!
Pull!
Oh my God!
OK.
Elsa,
You should continue without us.
Take it !
No, no.
I will not leave
you here.
Look at us ...
We won't be further.
Please take this.
Take this compass too.
Take it, Elsa.
Go to the west, Elsa
Did you hear? Just to the west.
Always.
I can't leave
you alone here.
Yes, you can and you will do it ..
Sorry, but I can not.
Elsa, if you don't do it for yourself,
do it for the others.
Go home, otherwise it
will all be in vain.
Go back home!
Go!
Did you see how I get the girl !
Like a playboy !
I like her ...
She can do it.
I'll go home!
I'll be back!
Anyway you're all dead!
Day-11
Day-12
Admiral!
Yes?
She's still alive!
Tonight you'll be in Paris.
I don't want to leave Kabul.
Be reasonable,
it's for your health!
I will fly nowhere while they are not found.
This people are there to take care of you
in a military hospital.
Excuse me, please!
Please ... Excuse me ...
Want to ride!
Yes!
Admiral, what are you doing ?
Just a stroll and we will be back!
Admiral!
Yes, I know, Mr. Minister.
Thank you.
For what?
That was my job to find you.
In memory of Benjamin,
Jonathan
and other French soldiers
killed in Afghanistan
And
for brave reporters,
that they sacrificed their lives around the world
to inform us.