(50,000 MILES BENEATH
MY BRAIN PLAYING)
(SIRENS WAILING)
Can you love me
with a thousand eyes?
Can you see
right through my bones?
I need a doctor!
I'll get you a vet,
you son of a bitch!
You should have
shot him first!
COP: (ON RADIO) We've got two
clowns headed south on Wall 51!
Four miles from the border.
(GROANS)
And stop bleeding
on my money!
COP: (ON RADIO)
All units, be advised.
Suspects are
armed and dangerous.
What the fuck!
DRIVER: Well, hello,
boys and girls.
There's nothing worse
than a sad clown.
Unless it's a clown
bleeding internally
and coughing it
all over your money.
Well, I suppose
this summer vacation
with a big haul
south of the border,
was out of the question now.
But like my old mother
always told me,
"Fuck off, loser."
Let your world spin free
Let it go,
I'll do the same
The jewels will
shine on me
(SPEAKING SPANISH OVER CB)
...gringo border patrols
in pursuit
VAZQUEZ: Bill!
Holy shit!
(LAUGHING)
The circus came to town!
Vazquez, I'll tell you what.
We'll take care of this.
You better. You know
the paperwork involved.
We'll say they landed
on your side. Okay?
No problemo.
Comandante!
(IN SPANISH)
Load these guys in our car
The bags too
And put this shit out!
We might have to
book them ourselves.
Bullshit. These are
our prisoners, Vazquez.
Not the way I see it, Bill.
They are on Mexican soil.
You're a piece
of shit, Vazquez.
There's no way you're
taking these clowns.
You're in no position
to bargain.
I'd hate for our
little arrangement,
every second Tuesday
of the month...
Fuck you, Vazquez!
You thinking about blowing the
whistle on me or something, huh?
Yeah, if I need to.
Is that a threat, cabrén?
Look, you're corrupt,
we're corrupt.
There's one difference.
We're honest about it.
You better bury them
in that goddamn
"I don't give a fuck, slap on the
wrist" beaner system of yours.
You win, Bill.
You won't be hearing
from them again.
Hey, what did they do?
Rob a bank?
(GROANS)
You figure it out, genius.
Let's go.
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
Luis, let's get
the fuck out of here!
It's procedure!
Fuck procedure, let's go!
(IN SPANISH)
No IDS
What's your name?
I'm Bozo,
he's Frosty with the...
What's your name?
Howard.
Dennis?
Fuck! Ruben?
(SHUDDERS)
(IN SPANISH)
This guy's dead!
Don't worry. We'll give
him a nice burial,
relieve you of
your money troubles,
and find you a nice place.
You'll be happy there.
DRIVER: Ah, prison.
I lucked out. It could've
been a hole in the desert.
And since I didn't
have any cash,
I guess they were
forced to charge me.
God only knew
where my cash was.
But at least
I know who had it.
(LOUD MARIACHI MUSIC PLAYING)
That's been playing
for six fucking hours.
Torture by Mariachi.
Ah, what's this?
(MAN SPEAKING SPANISH)
Check your guns,
you know the rules
Oh. Inmates. With guns.
Now that's kind of new.
(IN SPANISH)
Take care of this one
I got a lot to
learn about this place.
(CELL DOOR SLAMMING SHUT)
(IN SPANISH)
Give me your shoes, bitch!
DRIVER:
Dancing with the Stars.
I see
Get your mind right. Soften
you up in a holding cell
with loud music,
deprive you of sleep.
Oh, well, I guess I was gonna have
to take my lumps sooner or later.
(MARIACHI MUSIC CONTINUES)
Zapatos!
H U h?
Yeah?
The shoes, puto!
Ah...
(YELLING) You look like
you have really small feet
and these are size 11!
(GRUNTS)
(GROANING)
DRIVER: Ah. Fucking ouch.
(IN SPANISH)
You'll have fun
in here asshole
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(IN SPANISH)
This will be
your home for a while
and we your family
In a few hours
you will be moved
into the main prison
You'll have some freedom
but remember...
this is still a prison
Use what you've learned
in this holding cell
and don't make trouble
for us or yourselves
Or, as the saying goes...
small town...
large hell
Welcome
This is "El Pueblito"
God bless you
(MARIACHI MUSIC RESUMES)
Jack, you work too hard.
The Consulate's closed.
I just came to
pick up the files.
I think you may be forgetting
to report an American citizen.
That's a serious
offense, Armando.
Honest mistake, Jack.
Come see me tomorrow.
We'll sort it out.
(MUTTERS)
DRIVER: Five thousand songs
or so later,
G-24 - G-25 - G-26 - G-27
we were let out
of the holding cell
G-27
and transferred to the
general prison populace.
(COUNTING IN SPANISH)
Now I've been
in the joint before,
but this was
kind of different.
(MARIACHI MUSIC PLAYING)
Is this a prison or the
world's shittiest mall?
If I was going to
survive in this place,
it was time to do
what I was good at.
What's up, old man?
Anyway,
I was out of cigarettes.
Holy Rolex.
Shit.
(SHUDDERING)
Gracias.
DRIVER: Well, it was
bedtime at El Pueblito.
Hmm. Looked like all the good
pieces of dirt were taken.
(MAN SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(BELL RINGING)
Get up you lazy bums!
(YELLING IN SPANISH)
Move it, move it!
You can talk later,
let's move it!
Move it!
You too gringo,
get the fuck over there!
Let's go, let's go
Plastics
You know, you gotta
love murderers
who recycle.
(IN SPANISH)
Heads up gringo,
here they come!
(CHUCKING)
(GROANS)
This is going
to pinch a little.
(MUFFLED) Cunt.
(GRUMBLING)
(IN SPANISH)
Lunch!
DRIVER: Somebody was running this
place, and it wasn't the warden.
Ah. Now he looks like somebody.
People showing him respect.
Yeah, he's somebody.
He's yelling at people.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
So the little guy in the bad-taste
clothes is working for him
'cause he's making
his life miserable.
And... Wait a minute,
12 o'clock.
Guy in a bathrobe
in the penthouse.
Well, he must be El Hefner.
No, no. Those two guys are
both working for him.
He doesn't even
have to get dressed
and he's making both
their lives miserable.
Where'd he get
a bathrobe like that?
I had to improve my social
standing around here.
It was simple, really.
Two bits bought you
a day off work
so you could focus
on doing a real job.
Need some heroin?
Make tracks to
the smack shack,
where business
was always booming.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
(INAUDIBLE)
Got a cigarette?
Yeah.
Can I have one?
How old are you, kid?
Eighteen.
Get lost.
I'm ten. Can I have one now?
No.
You probably want me
to keep my mouth shut.
Well, Manuel's taco
stand caught on fire,
and Rodrigo the Doctor seems
to have some misplaced cash.
If I talk, the shit's really
going to hit the fence.
Cigarette?
Light?
So, you're a watcher.
You learn a lot
from watching.
What are you in here for?
Very funny.
I'm only ten, man.
My father was a dealer.
Was?
Yeah, I live here
with my mom.
You speak pretty good English, kid.
Where'd you learn?
Sesame Street.
(MUTTERING IN SPANISH)
What's with all the school kids
going back and forth all the time?
If you're not an inmate,
you're free to go in and out.
What? They live here?
Yeah.
Hmm.
If you have money,
you can pay for your family
to come live with you
while you're serving time.
That's a new one. How come
you don't go to school?
I'm special.
Yeah?
How are you special?
(IN SPANISH)
I just lit it for him!
Let's go
What did I tell you about
the fucking cigarettes!
JACK: Most gringos
are in worse shape
after a few days
in El Pueblito.
Yeah. Some vacation, huh?
I bet you'd like
one of these.
Oh, would I!
Oh, yeah!
(SIGHS)
Now, your, uh, file doesn't have a name.
Do you have a name?
Yes. Richard Johnson.
Dick Johnson, huh?
It's unfortunate.
Yeah.
Anybody I can contact
for you, Dick?
Wife, sweetheart?
No.
Boyfriend?
I didn't think SO.
Says here you were
caught buying Valium
in a drugstore downtown
without a prescription.
That doesn't quite fit.
What are you doing in here?
You're right. It doesn't fit.
That is bullshit.
They're making this up.
Two cops got a hold of me,
they rolled me in and I ended up in here.
You gotta get me out of here.
Just misunderstood, huh?
Yes, that's right.
You don't have
any fingerprints.
Guy who burns off his
fingerprints is a career man.
Even I know that much.
You gonna get me
out of here or not?
Seems to me somebody's
trying to bury you in here.
No shit, Sherlock.
What do you want?
I mean,
maybe I can help you.
Like I said,
I can't help you
without any information.
You're not giving me
any information.
You spring me out of here,
I'll give you plenty.
(CHUCKLES)
You know,
it's a lot easier to
end up dead in here
than to survive.
Gringo without money in a
south of the border jail.
Ah, it's not so bad,
you know.
At least it's a shithole.
All right. (CHUCKLES)
You're not gonna tell me.
That's all right. That's
all right, that's fine.
I can respect that.
But I will find the truth
out for myself, you know.
Well, even a blind pig has to
find an acorn now and then.
(BURPS)
You called me fat.
Be careful, my friend.
You'll hurt my feelings.
Let me tell you something.
There's a little
skinny guy inside of me
and you know what
that guy's saying?
He's saying
something stinks about you.
And I'm gonna
find out what it is.
Nice meeting you.
You too.
Thanks for dropping by.
Take care of yourself.
Yeah, don't sweat too much.
Oh, I never do!
DRIVER: The ugly American.
I thought it was me
until he turned up.
I didn't like him
sniffing around my business.
(IN SPANISH)
Nothing's free!
Please! We have
nowhere to go!
You could stay with me
You won't let me help you
C'mon kids,
hurry up, let's go
Hey, you speak English?
Yeah.
I'm looking
for a place to live
and you look like
the guy that knows.
Real estate is
a high commodity.
What are you looking for?
Nothing special.
Here we are!
(SHOUTS IN SPANISH)
Get out, cabrén!
Nothing special. There is a common
bathroom for tenants outside.
TV and cable are
additional if you want it.
Fan, blanket, and towel
are complimentary. Welcome.
Perfect.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(ROMANTIC SPANISH
MUSIC PLAYING)
(IN SPANISH)
All good General?
Take care of him
DRIVER: Well, this must be
cell block A.
Gives a whole new meaning
to doing hard time.
A special wing
for special inmates.
I guess you had to
know someone to get in.
What the fuck
are you looking at?
Fuck!
(IN SPANISH)
Why aren't you in bed?
I didn't want you
walking home alone
DRIVER: Okay.
So escaping is frowned upon.
KID: It's harder
than it looks, guero.
Breaking out.
I don't know.
It looks pretty easy to me.
You can buy anything
in El Pueblito.
Except your way out.
Even Javi has to come back
when he goes out.
Who's Javi?
(IN SPANISH)
King Rat
He runs the joint.
Lives up there,
where the rich people live.
Oh, the guy with the cheesy
bathrobe and the cell phone.
Yeah. Cigarette?
No. What do you mean,
"When he goes out"?
A veces sale. Dinner,
soccer matches, whatever.
But even he has to come back.
Wow, he's really got a good
thing going for him in here.
Oh, yeah.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Hmm?
I'm gonna kill him.
Okay. Why?
What did he ever do to you?
It's personal.
Remind me never
to rub you the wrong way.
Cigarette?
No, kid.
You mother has
a vicious right.
She's asleep.
She worked late last night.
Yeah, I know.
What's she do?
Shit for Javi.
Last night was casino night.
Hey, who are
those two guys?
Ren and Stimpy?
Yeah.
The big guy, Caracas,
that's Javi's brother.
What about the little
real estate cat?
Carnal. He's their cousin.
He's a useless prick.
Even they hate him.
Cigarette?
No.
When I came in here,
they took blood from me.
I'm figuring
it's not a health thing.
No shit
Can I have a cigarette,
for fuck's sake?
You know, the other day
you told me you were special.
How are you special?
Fuck you!
You're so special, get your
own fucking cigarettes.
Quit mooching off me. I got
a 40 year habit. Get lost.
(MARIACHI MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoo!
(LAUGHING)
(SINGING ALONG)
(ALL CLAMORING)
DRIVER: Ah, Sunday.
Visiting day at El Pueblito.
Bring the whole family to the
crappiest place on earth.
Enjoy our ever-popular,
world famous cavity search.
At 20 bucks a pop,
they were making a killing.
(IN SPANISH)
30 pesos for fifteen minutes
Go play kids!
(MOANING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
One.
(MUMBLING)
(IN SPANISH)
Calm down,
there's enough for everyone
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
(IN SPANISH)
That's the kid,
give him a hand!
What's wrong with you?
Tough guy, eh?
Shut the fuck up!
Touch him again
and I'll cut your balls off
Now fuck off!
You good?
Hey, kid, that's more than
a toothpick you got there.
What's your plan?
Stab him in the heart.
Oh.
The aorta, the vena cava.
Those are pretty deep blood vessels.
Chances are you'd miss.
How about the stomach?
Real grab bag.
Full of guts, liver, spleen.
Hmm. Quick treatment would
probably save his life.
The neck?
Yeah, good thinking.
The carotid.
Too high for you, kid.
You'd need a ladder.
Typically, you want to kill
someone instantaneously,
you go for the central
nervous system or the brain.
Lights out.
Fuck!
(PANTING)
Have a smoke?
I really need one.
No.
Not until you tell me why
you're so special around here.
Fuck you,
you can't touch me!
What, if I do this
those guys are gonna kill me?
You're holding out on me, kid.
Spit it out!
Fuck you, puto!
Knock it off.
Is that guy Javi
your father?
Is that why they
protect you, huh?
(GRUNTING)
You're a mosquito!
Sit the fuck down!
A man who won't
level with you,
that's a man
you can't trust.
You don't ever talk to me again.
Get lost, kid.
He killed my father!
I was seven when
I came to live here.
My parents were doing 15,
drug trafficking.
Javi needed a new liver.
And my dad
was a perfect match.
Same rare blood type.
He has my father's liver.
I want to cut it out of him,
and bury it with my dad.
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
Okay.
But what's
the deal with you?
He's going to need
another liver.
Fuck. Well, I guess
you are special.
That's why
they took my blood.
Bingo gringo!
They test everyone,
but I'm the only match.
I got put
on the inside at 14
for trying to fuck up
somebody I really hated.
My dad.
I wish someone had killed
him, I'd given him a cigar.
He'd been beating up on my mom.
The third time that week
I snapped finally and went to
work on him with a baseball bat.
The only mistake I made,
I didn't kill him.
That's why I ended up in the
shitter the first time.
So you gotta
be careful, kid.
If you're gonna do
this thing, do it right.
Otherwise they'll
fry your balls off.
And although you're not
using them at the moment,
trust me, someday soon, you're
gonna want those puppies working.
You don't wanna kill Javi.
You need to kill Javi.
Before he kills you.
Here, look at this.
I was a sniper.
Snipers work
in two-man teams.
I need a spotter.
You up for the gig?
Are we going to shoot him?
It's not about that.
It's about watching.
Waiting. We'll see him,
we'll get him.
Yeah. Fucker's lived
too long.
(IN SPANISH)
What do you mean why?
He's stealing from us,
and he's an idiot
Carnal is family
He's a liability
You straighten him out,
I don't want to deal with it
You may not have a choice
He's getting out of hand
People hate him
What do you
want me to do...
kill him?
Just get him off real estate
It's a big job,
too much money
Give him an assistant
(WHISTLES)
Deal with it brother
Hey, come here.
Mom's here, she's cooking
What'd you find out?
(IN SPANISH)
Mom!
A sight for sore eyes
Aunt Flor
And your cousin?
He's coming
How's his health?
Is he drinking?
Don't worry so much
I'm holding you responsible
JACK: Hey, fellas!
Who the fuck are you?
I'm with the US Consulate
in Tijuana.
Really.
You a cop?
No.
Couldn't pass the physical.
So what do you want?
No. What do you want?
The man who drove this car or the
guys who were spending the money?
Both.
One stop shop.
Welcome to Costco.
Yeah. Here's my
membership card.
Oh, come on.
Take it easy, cowboy.
All I want is the joy
of seeing justice done.
It'll be for the right price,
I'm not greedy.
Hell, I'll get you a picture.
I'll take you
to him personally. Huh?
How do you like them apples?
(CHEERING)
(JAVI SPEAKING SPANISH)
Let me remind you...
that all the money raised...
will go to the family fund
here at El Pueblito
So cough it up!
Straight from Juarez...
the King of the Skies...
Magno!
That's Magno.
He's running in fourth.
And there's no way he can beat Blue Demon Jr.
He's a champion.
And the legendary...
Blue Demon Jr.
The referee...
our dear friend
Mr. Ringo Starr
(COUGHING)
Him and Sanso
are like the best.
They're like the shit, man.
Before my dad got locked away
we went to go see his match.
CROWD: (CHANTING)
Blue! Blue! Blue!
Hey, you gotta... You gotta
knock this shit off, kid.
Come on.
Get yourself another habit.
Sugar. Here.
Get yourself an ice cream.
Orale. Thanks.
Bring me back the change.
Behave Mom!
HEY
Why the money?
Ah, you know,
he worries too much.
He needs to be
a kid for a while.
Why, you gonna hit me again?
(CHUCKLES) He does
worry too much.
Today he looks happy.
He talks about you.
Told me about your dad.
And how you talked him out
of something stupid.
That's not easy.
Well, he's smart.
He listens.
He doesn't talk
to many people.
No?
Want a beer?
(ALL CHEERING)
Yeah.
(IN SPANISH)
You got a visitor!
Oh, I have a visitor.
I'm sorry.
Mmm-hmm.
I'll take you up on the beer later.
Thank you.
Right.
Well, howdy, buckeroos!
(GREETING IN SPANISH)
Looking sharp!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Thank you for your financial
contribution to our families.
Don't mention it.
We took care of Frosty,
by the way.
(HUMS CIRCUS MUSIC)
He did want a cremation,
didn't he?
Oh, I didn’t
know him that well.
We have a serious problem.
Is this something
I can help you with?
Well, the thing is, two of
the cops that were with us
when we first met,
turned up dead.
Cops die all the time,
it's part of the trade.
What is disturbing is the
fact they were tortured.
Badly.
So we wanted to ask you
where you got the money.
We are just concerned that
someone might be looking for it.
And if they are,
we need to know who it is.
I see. Two million bucks
is a lot of money.
Two million dollars is a lot
of money, you're right.
Well, it says here they were
found in a brand new Mercedes.
What... What model was it?
Listen, things can get
a lot worse for you in here.
Oh, let me guess, you've
got friends in here, too.
Well, I'm sure Javi's power
stretches outside these walls.
I mean, he knows about the
money you stole from me, yeah?
I mean, you gave him
his cut, right?
Listen, you fucking gringo!
You may think you have
this place figured out,
but you don't know shit!
Just tell us where
you got the money.
I'll tell you what,
whoever tortured those cops
surely knows you're in here.
If you tell us,
we could help.
Otherwise, it's just a matter of
time before they come get you.
No, you're right.
And here's the thing, and I'm
sure you two will agree with me,
they'll be coming
to get you two first.
So here's my advice, stop
spending my fucking money.
Put it someplace safe and then
go and hide yourselves. Okay?
Because when they find you,
they will kill you.
And then I'll never
get my damn money!
Suit yourself. And watch
your back in here!
Yeah, take it easy
out there.
You have no idea who we are!
(LAUGHS) You're Vazquez.
Badge number 903489.
You're Romero. Badge number 1...
Oh, fuck it!
(SIGHS)
You ever been fishing?
Never been out
of this joint.
No? Well, you got a treat in
store, but it's kinda like this.
There he is.
You know what to do.
Divide and conquer.
(IN SPANISH)
That's my watch
Hey kid!
Where are you going?
Come here you prick
What?
Come here you little fucker
Fucking Indian
Damn!
(IN SPANISH)
Hey, cabrén!
Sorry. Sorry.
(CONTINUES IN SPANISH)
Give me!
Where'd you get it?
I found it in the trash
It's mine
I'm going to tell Caracas
What are you looking at?
KID: Bang, bang.
Come here.
Heart shot.
Yeah. Well, you spot,
I'll shoot. Come here.
We did better than
I thought. Here.
There's your cut.
Oh, nice.
Oh. Here. And I got this
for you, too.
What is it?
Nicotine gum.
What does it do?
Yeah. Stops the craving.
Don't flash it around.
Don't spend it in big chunks,
that's how
you get boned, okay.
Hey, how about
that beer now?
Oh. Twist my arm?
Which one?
This one.
Thank you.
I was a user.
That's how we met.
Then I helped him out,
cutting the shit.
Packing it...
We got busted
with three kilos.
Got 15 years.
Thank you.
At least,
I got cleaned up in here.
You have a cigarette?
Yeah. You remind me
of someone.
Yes. If you tell him,
I'll kick your ass.
Again?
Worse.
Where is he? Is he around?
I think he went for a beer.
What?
Oh, shut up.
So, guero, you married?
Easy, mamacita,
you're moving a little fast.
That's a very
sensitive subject for me.
I was. Um...
She ran off with a former
business associate of mine,
one Reginald T. Barnes.
We were doing a job,
I got away...
He got caught.
He ratted me out
for immunity,
and I did seven years
in the slammer.
She ended up
shacking up with him.
Nice, huh?
You know, I still have
recurring dreams about it.
Yeah, there's a knock
on the door.
Reginald opens it,
he's wearing underpants
and eating a bowl
of cornflakes, weird, huh?
Mmm.
Yeah. Not a pretty sight.
There's milk spilling
down his chin and shit.
And my wife's making
coffee over behind him.
And these two goons
at the door,
whip out these
massive cannons...
(MIMICS GUN FIRING) And they start
filling his chest full of holes,
he hits the floor,
dead as a mackerel.
She drops the coffee and
starts screaming her ass off.
And then?
Well, then I wake up.
The resentment
will kill us all.
But them first. Here...
Here's to resentment.
(DOOR OPENS)
I know you know
about the liver.
Well...
How rare can blood be?
Very. It's called
Bombay Blood.
One in half a million.
Javi found a match.
Your husband.
And my son.
I never know when
they'll come for him.
Yeah, well...
We're not gonna
let that happen.
Are we?
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(IN SPANISH)
What's up?
What do you want?
The money
You trade rent
payments for sex
Others pay you with drugs
You're out of control
You're a disgrace
We never should have
given you this job
Tough shit...
it's a family business
Maybe you're the fuck up
If I was in charge,
no one would steal from us
Enlighten me
I was robbed
BY Whom?
I don't know
There are
a few thieves in here
You and your fucking lies
Don't bullshit me
The money, or the fucker
who robbed you
You're my cousin...
but if you don't deliver,
you're finished
Fuck off,
I'm not your bitch!
The money, fucker
When did you get robbed?
Who knows
When I got my watch back?
I don't know!
Maybe
Do you think I'm an idiot!?
(GRUNTING)
Where'd you get the watch!?
I found it!
Did the gringo help?
No, it was just me!
Get him!
Caracas.
Think you can fool me
you little fuck!?
(GROANS)
(GRUNTS)
(SOBBING)
Get off her,
you son of a bitch!
I'm not done with you!
(GRUNTS)
(IN SPANISH)
What did you idiots do!?
This room was built for me!
Now you're bleeding
all over it
He had the mom...
He was going to kill the kid
Son of a bitch!
What the fuck did you do?
Idiot!
Answer me!
Now what?
Javi!
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
It's Aunt Flor
Answer it
Answer it, man!
Hi, Aunt
He can't talk right now...
he's lying down
Okay, We
It's going to
break her heart
What could I say?
If the gringo hadn't
killed him, I would have
What about the gringo?
What about him?
He's not family,
he's not Mexican...
I'd kill him
I saved your
brother's life.
I saved your life, too. I
protected the kid and the liver.
I terminated two
troublesome employees.
(IN SPANISH)
Fucking gringo!
One of those was my cousin!
Don't tell me you weren't thinking
about killing him already.
I saved you
the embarrassment
of having family blood
on your hands.
And if he was willing
to kill your brother,
he was coming
to kill you next.
In about a minute and a
half, to be precise.
So, I saved your
fucking life twice.
(YELLS)
I need a drink
(PANTING) Fuck!
Fuck!
Cut him loose!
Yeah, okay.
Give me a minute.
I need to change my shorts,
for God's sake!
(IN SPANISH)
He knows about my liver
He knew about
our problems with Carnal
He seems to know
what I'm thinking
Who is he?
I don't know
Armando doesn't know either
So he's in here with no name,
charges, or fingerprints?
You're in charge
of security!
How does this fucking gringo
know everything?
So kill him then
You idiot!
Don't be hasty!
First, find out who sent him
Find out who he is
Then we kill him
DRIVER: Which one?
(IN SPANISH)
Number three
Yup.
JACK: Hey, there.
Oh, hey, Butterballs.
(CHUCKLES)
Yeah, Butterballs.
Just checking in. Wanted
to see how you're doing.
Fine.
Yeah.
Well, you know, I see you're
still hanging in there.
So...
I know there's money.
I could still help you out.
All I want is
a piece of the pie.
Talkative as ever, eh?
That's okay.
It was nice knowing you.
Sorry if we got off
on the wrong foot.
Good luck then.
You're gonna need it.
DRIVER: Butterballs was putting the
squeeze on me sooner than I thought.
It was time to play a card
I'd been holding back.
Try and get my cash
a little closer.
Buen dias.
What do you want, guero?
I have some
information for you
that I think you
might find valuable.
Uh, two cops,
Vazquez and Romero,
badge number 90348...
Okay, okay, okay.
We know our cops.
Oh, you know them?
Mmm.
Well, in that case you'll
find this really interesting.
They took a sizeable
amount of money
from me when they
brought me here.
And I figure I'll never
see the money again
and I just wondered
if they gave you your cut.
Why? What's in it for you?
Mmm. Nothing now. Probably
since I told you, but...
Look, I think a finder's fee
would be fair.
How much?
Oh, I don't need much.
Ten percent, maybe.
Okay, eight.
Uh-uh. How much money?
Oh.
You know, I only stole it. I
didn't have time to count it.
Uh, but ballpark, two
million, maybe a little more.
You know what will happen
if you are pushing my leg?
Si. I know.
I wouldn't push your leg.
See you later.
(IN SPANISH)
Get Vazquez and Romero
And bring the money too
(GRUNTING)
(MUFFLED YELLING)
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
Yep, I rechecked it.
One million seven.
(GROANS)
Where the fuck's the rest?
I swear on God.
That's all there was.
That's bullshit.
No bullshit.
It is true.
Hello. Can you see me?
Uh, yeah, boss.I can.
Okay, good. Is it all there?
No, there's only 1.7 and a
couple of new cars out front.
Where's the rest?
It's all there.
Except for what we spent.
The cars, some hookers.
We bought them shoes.
And tacos. That's all.
Amigos, where is
the rest of my money?
That's all there was.
Talk to the gringo
that stole it.
Cut the toe off.
Well, we already did that, boss.
Two of them.
Cut another one off.
No, please! I swear,
that's all there was!
No! (GRUNTS)
(WHISTLES)
Hey, Mr. Vazquez.
Listen very carefully.
You see, I'm missing
four million dollars.
You're missing
three toes so far.
I'll give you a moment
to do the arithmetic,
then it's up to you
if you wanna talk.
(MUMBLING)
What did he say?
He said, "What does
arithmetics mean?"
Oh, fuck it. Just kill 'em.
No! Hey, hey! No!
(ROMERO SOBBING)
Hey! Hey, no! I swear!
No, please!
There was only two.
Last chance, Vazquez!
No! No!
(GRUNTS)
I swear! I swear!
Sure?
(SCREAMING)
Who the fuck are you?
Hey! That's my money!
(IN SPANISH)
That's Javi's share!
Javi?
I was going to
give Javi his cut!
Javi Huerta?
You keep it!
Hey, hey-'
(LAUGHS) Javi. Motherfucker.
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
Oh, Jesus.
I'm gonna kill you, Javi.
With my own fucking hands.
(IN SPANISH)
Leave them there
I told you the gringo
would be trouble
He stole big time
from Frank in San Diego
Frank knows we have his money
You need to slow down
My big brother...
(COUGHS)
always worried about me
You keep drinking
and smoking like this...
and the kid's liver
may not be enough
Go get the gringo
You Buffet?
You got it.
If you're hungry,
try the tacos de pescado.
It's their specialty.
(IN SPANISH)
There's three of them
Will the watchtower
be covered?
Have we ever failed you?
Three guys
are coming for the gringo
Cover them
They'll be easy to spot
There's some bad shit
coming down on me,
I don't want you two
caught in the middle of it.
So if you don't see me
for a little while...
Okay.
(SCREAMS)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(GROANING)
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
There is something
you're not telling us.
JAVI: This gun
belonged to Doroteo Arango.
Do you know who he was?
No, but I'm guessing he's dead,
because you have his gun.
He was better
known as Pancho Villa.
This is the same gun he fired in the
Opera Restaurant in Mexico City.
Have you ever been there?
No.
The hole's
still there in the ceiling.
They auctioned this gun off
a few years ago
in the States.
They thought
that was the original.
(LAUGHING)
(IN SPANISH)
Fucking gringos!
Idiots!
During the revolution, there
was a shortage of bullets.
And Pancho was
well aware of that.
So he always made sure
that every bullet counted.
(GUNSHOT)
Who the fuck are you?
If you really need a name,
it's Barnes, Reginald T.
And I'm sorry about the mess.
I didn't mean...
(IN SPANISH)
Just kill him already
That's not a good idea
There are two reasons
not to kill me
You never mentioned
you speak Spanish
Nobody asked me
I need practice
Frank is now
a big problem for you
And what's
the second reason?
I can get to him
I did it once already
Don't do me any favors
It's in your best
interest as well
This is too much, Javi
A shootout!
Inside the prison
If you get me out of here...
I'll kill Frank
I'm not joking!
This bloodbath
will have consequences
(SIGHS)
Armando...
You chose sides
a long time ago
We can change that
if you want
No problem
But why don't you clean up
the mess out there instead
Get the fuck out!
Okay
Go kill him
But don't come back
The money you stole
is the price for your life
Okay.
I'll need a little cash...
guns“.
And a car
(CHUCKING)
Okay
You've been spending time
with the kid and his mother.
Keep away from them. And this
is the last warning you'll get.
(IN SPANISH)
Hurry UP!
Javi's waiting for you!
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
What name?
Barnes.
Reginald T. Barnes.
CARACAS: Javi.
(IN SPANISH)
We need to talk, Javi
You look worried
The shootout was
the final straw
The government
is closing the prison
They've tried that before
It's a surprise raid,
even I don't know when
2000 soldiers...
police... snipers
I have to get out of here
It won't be easy
If Armando lets you out...
they'll go after him... then
the Mayor, all the way up
I can't go to another prison
Maybe for a while
until things calm down
No, I can't risk
losing the kid
I need that liver transplant
And I'll be too weak to move
So get me an ambulance
and barricade this place
Nothing interrupts
the operation
What do we do with Barnes?
Have our boys up north
kill him once Frank is dead
(DOG BARKING)
Welcome to the United States.
Hey, thank you.
What's your citizenship?
USA.
Where were you born, sir?
Chicago, Illinois.
(SPANISH)
What if he doesn't
kill Frank?
Give him forty-eight hours...
then kill him
(SPANISH RAP SONG PLAYING)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
STEPHANIE: Good morning,
Warren Kauffman's office.
Oh, one second.
I'll see if he's in.
(INTERCOM BEEPS)
Mr. Kauffman. Um, Clint
Eastwood is on the line.
(CLEARS THROAT) Hello?
Hold for
Mr. Eastwood, please.
Thank you.
(IN DEEP VOICE)
Hey, how are you doin'?
Thank for taking
my call, sir.
Well, it's quite
a surprise, Mr. Eastwood.
I'm a fan of your work.
WOMAN: This is bullshit!
You know what, man? This is
not what you guaranteed me.
Excuse me
for a minute, sir.
WOMAN: This is not
what you said.
Okay, now, that's better. That's better.
Okay, move along.
That's good.
You all right, man.
You all right.
Yeah.
Hallelujah to ya! Whoo!
Cut!
All right,
set up for take two.
Sorry, sir.
I'm a workin' stiff.
You gotta make your time
where you can.
(LAUGHS) What can I do
for you, Mr. Eastwood?
Well, you know,
I'm going to be
in San Diego
for a couple of days
playing a golf tournament,
and all the proceeds are going
to the Stroke Association.
I play golf myself,
you know.
Well, my associates
and I are looking
to make a meeting
with you if we could.
Sit down and let
you know how you could
be part of
the Stroke Association.
It's doing good
in the community
and it's a damn
decent tax write-off.
Well, it sounds interesting.
You think you could make it to
my office tomorrow morning?
Yeah, I'll have
my assistant, Mr. Barnes,
be in touch with
your assistant.
Make all the arrangements.
Great.
You'll, uh, make my day.
(CHUCKLES)
Ha ha. That's a good one.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Go!
(IN SPANISH)
Regina, it's time!
Move it!
JAVI: I'll take better care
of this one.
We have to do this
as soon as possible.
Get in
(IN SPANISH)
Don't come out,
no matter what
I need the donor.
DRIVER: Thanks.
Microwave's over there.
Oh, I'm not going
to eat this shit.
MAN 1: What the fuck
is going on here?
MAN 2: All right,
pop the fucking hood.
(DOOR OPENS)
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
(GRUNTING IN PAIN)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(SIGHS)
(IN SPANISH)
I admire your courage
I didn't expect any less
You know we'll kill you
and find the kid
Why waste more time?
I treated you well
Took care of you both
I tried to find
someone else
But time ran out
(ELECTRICITY CRACKLING)
WOMAN ON PHONE:
Hi, I have Warren Kauffman
from REPCOM for Mr. Jackson.
One moment, please.
I have Warren Kauffman
on the line.
The ship guy?
SECRETARY:
That's what they said.
Put him through.
Hello?
Hello, Mr. Jackson, thanks for taking...
Excuse me for a minute.
Thanks for taking my call.
My pleasure, sir.
How can I help you?
I understand you represent
a Mr. Frank Fowler.
Yeah, in some matters.
Are you familiar with my
business, Mr. Jackson?
From what I hear you're the
largest ship builder in America.
Among other things.
Look, can I assume that our
conversation is confidential?
(SIGHS) Yes. Of course.
Good.
I'm interested specifically in
Mr. Fowler's marshmallow export business.
I don't know what you mean.
You don't?
Well, then, I'm sorry,
I must've been given
the wrong information.
Perhaps.
Well, how specifically
can I help you, sir?
Could I arrange
a meeting with Mr. Fowler?
I'd have to check
his availability...
Ooh la la.
...but I'm sure we can
work something out.
Unfortunately, loan only
meet tomorrow morning.
If that's possible.
Uh, if you can
make that work,
at my office, downtown, the
REPCOM Building, say 10:00 a.m.?
(LAUGHING)
We'll be there.
Great.
Ooh.
WOMAN: Hurry up.
(SINGING SOFTLY)
(SNORTS)
Don't move!
Who's the brunette?
What the hell
are you doing here?
Tomorrow. Morning.
Very important meeting.
Pick you up at 9:00 a.m.
Warren Kauffman.
The Warren Kauffman.
Yep.
What the hell
does he want from us?
We don't build ships, do we?
He wants to do
business with us, Frank.
Okay. 9:00.
(IN SPANISH)
You're a good mother
But I'm tired
You want my liver?
Here's your fucking liver
(SCREAMING)
(ALL SHOUTING)
(WAILING)
(FRANTIC TALKING)
(KID GROANING)
Hi.
STEPHANIE: Hi.
I'm here to see Mr. Kauffman.
Mr. Barnes?
And you can only
be Stephanie.
(CHUCKLES) Yes.
So good to meet you, at last.
Likewise.
Mr. Kauffman is ready for you.
Excellent
Go ahead and just follow me.
Uh, we were expecting
Mr. Eastwood, plus four.
Oh, well,
the tall one is en route.
You'll hear him drop in,
cowboys and helicopters,
he'll probably
buzz the building.
(CHUCKLING) Are you
expecting rain, Mr. Barnes?
Well, you never
can tell, Stephanie.
Please, step in.
Thank you.
Mr. Barnes is here, his
associates are on their way.
Mr. Barnes.
Thank you, Stephanie.
Please show the gentlemen
in when they arrive.
Mr. Kauffman.
So nice to meet you.
Likewise. And thank you for
taking us on such short notice.
My pleasure.
Look at this view.
Mmm.
And this is, uh,
Think Outside the Box.
You know it.
L live by it.
Hi, we have an appointment
with Mr. Kauffman.
Yes, they're expecting you.
(MUFFLED SCREAMING)
STEPHANIE: Please, step in.
MR. JACKSON: Thank you.
Gentlemen.
What took you so long?
Mr. Kauffman's
just in the restroom,
he should be out
in a minute.
That chopper turn up yet?
No, not yet.
No? Okay.
Well, make yourself at home.
Ah, Warhol?
No.
That's a nine-dot puzzle.
Now the trick is you got to
join all nine dots together
using only four lines, never
take your pen off the page.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh.
You gentlemen like
something to drink?
A coffee would be great.
Sir?
No, I'm fine. Thank you.
Okay.
Hey, I think I got it.
Oh...
(GROANING)
Oh, my God!
Mr. Kauffman!
Oh, my God! Mr. Kauffman!
There's a bomb or something!
(SOBBING) Mr. Kauffman...
(SCREAMS AND GASPS)
Mr. Kauffman! Oh!
Are you okay?
Uh, my God! Oh, my God!
SURGEON: The kid is stable.
Barely missed his liver.
How fast can we go?
First thing in the morning.
No.
No, you tell me
when you're done.
We go tonight.
JACK: Put it in your mouth!
Put it in your mouth!
Eat the chili, bitch!
Come on!
Suck it! Suck it!
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
Eat it all! Take it all!
(LAUGHING)
Now! Now! Now! Now!
(SCREAMS)
(SOBBING)
(SPANISH SONG PLAYING)
You better feel something.
JACK: All right, do it again.
Open your mouth.
Open your mouth, puta!
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT TALKING)
Hi.
How did you find me?
I followed the bread crumbs.
Even in a town like Tijuana,
you're kinda unique.
I need to spring somebody
out of prison here.
Oh, yeah,
what's his name, 1.7 mil?
Stupid son of a bitch, why
didn't you let me help you?
We could have
been splitting this.
And now what?
Now fat chance
getting it from Javi,
before he's shipped off to
Federal with a new liver.
What was that?
It's over, the government
is shutting the place down.
They're raiding
the joint tonight.
That fucking moron, Javi,
(LAUGHING) he's having an organ
transplant in the middle of a raid.
You're not going to leave
me like this, are you?
I sure as fuck am.
These credentials will
come in mighty handy.
Hey, hey, hey-
You said my car
was in the impound?
Where is that?
There's a federal impound,
next to the race track.
I wouldn't exactly
call it a car anymore.
(IN SPANISH)
Ladies
Here
(SIGHS)
Take your time.
Make him squeal.
(WOMEN JEERING IN SPANISH)
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
(JAVI SPEAKING SPANISH)
...but you got
the money, right?
I paid you, fucker!
They're here
Go fuck your mother!
(GRUNTS)
Make sure Armando
has the ambulance ready
Leave that open
for a quick getaway
Nobody gets in here!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(MACHINE BEEPING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
US Consulate.
(ALL TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
Ah!
(COCKING GUN)
(PANTING)
Put it back.
Where's the boy's mother?
(STAMMERS) In the dungeon.
Bring her here
or I'll kill your brother.
(COCKING GUN)
Okay. Okay, okay.
(IN SPANISH)
Park over there
(COCKING GUN)
Thank you, Malaina.
(IN SPANISH)
Go fuck yourself!
He'll be okay
Thank you
They were assholes
Just like my husband
Stop!
It's an emergency!
Help us to the ambulance!
Be careful
What happened?
Male, ten years old
Under anesthesia
for liver transplant
Vital signs are stable
Mine.
He needs to get
to a hospital
(SOLDIER SHOUTS IN SPANISH)
We're in a hurry
Gracias.
(SHOUTING IN SPANISH)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Reginald T. Barnes?
Honey, want some coffee?
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
No!
(CHUCKING)
(SIGHS)
Hola.
Please.
Salud.
(IN SPANISH)
To us
Can I bite you?
Yes
Only if it's really hard
And don't leave any marks
(LAUGHS)
Mom!
Come
Hurry up
I'll be back
DRIVER: Well, boys and girls,
to the untrained eye, it looks
as if crime pays, doesn't it?
But bear in mind
J
for guys with my particular
set of karmic could-be's,
there was bound to be
a bump or two down the road.
Ah, what the hell.
I'm going to enjoy
what's left of the summer.
(MARIACHI MUSIC PLAYING)
English - US - PSDH