16th december
The war between India and Pakistan
had come to an end
the Pakistani army surrendered
to the indian army
there was a new Bangladesh
After the Indian army left...
the 2 boys didn't understand...
whether what happened to them
was good or bad
will the new country give them
new dreams?
they were thinking
move move fast....
when Bangladesh was created
there was 1000's of people
are you hungry? Will you have food to eat?
Will you work for me?
If you give us food...
what ever you say will be done...
Vikram and Bala were the main leaders
no one would suspect
the small boys
Vikram and Bala were Latiff's gun couriers
hey Lattif guns will keep on selling
sometimes think of me too
you said it right
do one thing leave one of the boys here
sir they are kids
dad take Bala, I will stay here
the boy understands...
I said go.....
what will he do with vikram?
I am going to get him, say something
sir I beg you  let me go
put the gun down
I said open his hands
don't come near me
we killed the police
who???????
he was from the army they will
not spare you
a train is going both of you go from here
no one is here
go go go...
try to save your anger
I have cooked something for you
go and have it
its a house and we will have one soon
get out off here
leave me I will break his head
now we will starve to death
wait 1 minute
how much are you selling this charcoal for?
-2 rupees 10kg
its expensive
today the price will go down
lets go bala... where?
the charcoal that saved us will now feed us
do you want to buy charcoal?
-from you ?
we will give 10kg for 1 rupee
put the money in the hand
keep that.
-For what?
We broke the cups
Buy new ones
nice one all balance cleared off
Run!
Wow look over here!
You must see one day I will
drive that car...
What happened brother?
Do you know our names?
Why rob the train?
The train you looted was
Dibakar dada's
Does Dibakar dada belong to the government?
Do not show me your bravery
You will answer for your deed's
One minute!
Can you tell me something?
When will his next train go
Go and tell him we will once again
loot his train...
If he has guts try and stop us.
Who is Dibakar from you all?
It seems you are
because you look angry...
Bastard's you come on my train
and show me your strength...
Is the game over?
This train is mine...
and so is the coal.
Now tell me... whose train is it?
Its mine
This train can never be yours
Ask me why?
Cause you are bangladeshi refugees
Its been a dangerous mission
It was not only about coal
Also about fish
Both have ruled calkutta
They were small time goons
Now they rule entirely...
they are focusing on one thing
We don't know how to read
Vikram bose nice childs play
Names of school and hospital
Was under their control
They only wished for two things
in Calkutta...
Calkutta's biggest goons
There is a story behind a twist.
I am a policeman
I should not have called you
If I had my best officers
Satya, I have pressure from the high post
Election
There is a saying
Bring goons no the right path...
We need to clean the streets
This is the governments job
How can the police help?
You are right
Banerji
So many files
There are only two names to mention
These files has all the evidence
since their childhood
No evidence...
no witness...
Must I insert finger-prints
inside
Were are you going?
If you speak I'll shut you up
Were is your boss?
Where is Vikram and Bala?
Leave the papers over here.
I am the new ACP
Entire Calcutta is ours
Sir,what can I offer you to drink?
This file has all your misdeeds
You need proof or evidence
Witness
We respect the law
The day you have evidence
We will hand ourselves to you
Very nice
Superb
No problem we will take your advice
From today all your files
are dissapeared
I will reopen your files from today
Any witness or evidence
I will remove you like dog's
from your own house
It will be fun
Thanks alot
If you guys come it will be a pleasure
We like to open
It's our hobby
One more request...
He worships you alot
It's not a football team
Don't like football
Ok. I explained to him
You wait right here
Kaka speak up!
Can you do me a favour?
I know this is a gent's toilet...
But what can I do? the ladies was full...
That is why, I came to the gents
I said sorry
But this is wrong
Why?
Is there licence for ladies to enter
gents toilets? Is this a government notice?
Don't act smart...
Do your job
What is this brother?
Bomb
It blew up and went away
Are you done?
What happened?
Did you loose something?
Its not in your luck to find it
Its your luck
The day you drop...
I will pick you up
I am in love with my bathroom story
Two hearts and one love!
Vikram she is a beautful girl
What can we do?
Toss a coin
See who wins the bet
She is looking like a Goddess
She looks 100% Kali maa
Hey you! Come over here
Don't show me your teeth...
What are you doing here?
-Nothing
This is a small gift from me to you
Are you giving me a gift?
A fish
Are you acting smart?
Can you make a knot?
Come fast...
The show is going to start
Why is your hand shakey?
You have forced me into this
I came to tell you this
You came that day by mistake
And I came today by mistake
Its even now
What time did they come last night?
Vikram and Bala live here...
Yes
They live  here!
Do you want to meet them?
-Yes
What is going on?
Ok, you guys are the biggest
Goons of Calcutta
Wait a minute
We are not that kind of men
We love you
Both of you?
-Yes
One is my love and the other is free
This is the first time
I had this type of offer
You must be knowing that love
don't be in one phase
You have to win my heart
So whats the big idea
We win over your heart
So much confidence
Ok you have 1 week to win
over my heart
If we have to win
This is Nandita's promise
Any of you win over my heart
I'll be your's forever!
Listen to us madam
What do you mean
Give us an answer please
I've choosen my love
From you both...
I like...
What is this
ticket?
The question is quite big and
so is my answer...
Tomorrow at 6
We got our ticket
These 2 idiots are trapped in her spell
Love is red and dangerous
When a pistol shoots at you...
You are finished
Open!
From tomorrow one will be
Rajesh Khanna
What ever she decides...
don't let our friendship drown
Really...promise
She said she love's me
Madam i love you too.
She is your sister-in-law
Don't dare call her
Now, what can you do!
Are you pointing a pistol on me
You go
I will come just now
Hey stop
Were are you going to.
Bala
He shot a bullet
Run!
I will bring nandita and meet you
Now you must hide
What my life is mess into
Trying to be a good person!
What ever happen was not your mistake
Police must be searching for you
Nanditha
I love her alot
Why are you behaving like this
You shot a man bala
Untill i don't return don't talk
to nanditha
She belong's to both of us
Must i slap you
Very nice
What did you say
You won't play my game
Only came to tell you
I no your secret
I no who murdered at the mall
I have a eye witness and evidence
Tell your friend if he wnt's to stay alive
Do not enter calcutta ever again
If he come's back
I have to take action
Why don't you both
Give up this kind of work
Nanditha we are like coal
No matter how filty, we can't clense ourselve's
Our black body will alway's remain black
We walk on the footpath
People ask who are we?
What are you doing here
From were have you come
No answer's for these kind of question
The entire world know's
There is no diffarence between you and i
Come let us go!
I am fine right here!
Why!
Bala is not here?
And i promised him.
If he do not return i will not speak
or see see you by my sight!
What kind of a chil's play is this?
It's a habbit of friendship
Vikram i came to tell you
I love only you?
I promised godess mother
I will offer my blessing to
whom i gave my heart to
Thought you with come and
help me offer the blessing
Nanditha will not ever see your
face  ever again
Are you speaking the truth?
Bala, what will happen now?
What are you doing here?
Sir, Bala has return
And i seen in his eye anger
Come, we play holy
What are you doing here!
Bala i told you not to enter
calcutta, you are in danger
You have done part of your job.
What are you saying?
Should have had patience
For my return
You broke my trust
Everything is over!
You always said since birth
Iam a very timmered man
Today i will kill you?
You are trap in my arm's
Bala
Search for him
Bala stop!
The bastard survive's
He survived my bullet
There is a law
Every action is equal
What ever take's place
Devil has doupt you
Maybe it's mine!
I am durga and kaali
Nothing effect's me
For the first time in my life
I was afraid
For me
Yes
Do not be afraid
Get use to me
Yes i have
Poison
You guy's friendship
Bala is like this since childwood
Always angry
If i talk to him with love
He will understand me
Nanditha can i tell you something?
For give bala
You have enough evidence
Why don't you arrest
What are you waiting for
Love is very strong
Now the child's play in our hand
Enjoy the fun
Bala when did you return
What happen bala
Vikram survive my bullet
Nanditha has got shot
First time my aim was incorrect
I love her alot
I can't go
Police is insearch for me
Kaka if anythin happen
I will ruin bloodshed of calkutta
How is her health
Survive
How is bala
He is not fine.
Love with destroy you both
You mock your childwood friendship
For a girl
Nandita
He has sent me to ask if
nandita is fine
What you heard
That is what he said
He thought of what ever he said
Kaka you go and tell him
I am elder then him
Nandita love's me
If he ever take's nandita's name again
I will ruine him
tell him to come and apploise
to me
i will not appolise to vikram
i will c him
nothing is left in between us
bala the whole calcutta knows u 2 are good
friends dont be mad
if u 2 break up the business will go down
think again
i will do what i have to do
its good very good
until i kill vikram n bala i will not rest
yes they should die thats why i called u
who is the  game planner its u himanshu
dont do anything very fast
be with bala n do
our work
he is telling the truth
theres 7000.. take it...
and put your daughter in a good college...
vikram is the owner of all the business
in legal tearms
we dont have anything
say bala
what i was thinking u did all that
you are the no:1 tratour in the world
you inherited all the business to your name
what a game u played
if u have the guts come here
15 years back me n bala started off from here
you tried to make him understand
he will think that i got u by
cheating him
its hard but have to start all over again
will u marry me i love u very much
if u want to live with me u have
to leave everything
your work or me
i wont let u go
i will leave everything
what are u doing here
gents was full so i thought i
come in ladies
leave me let me go
this story..
its finished long time ago
sita is ram's now
u forgot one thing when
sita gets kidnapped
some one reported that the dancer got
kidnapped
do u suspect anyone
looking at u today i think
u will kill someone
you will kill him the police will kill you
do something that he dies
everyday
i will make the chargesheet u have to give your
report about bala
i will put him in jail n
u with namita outsite
what??
nandita
what are u doingu got got tthe girl here
do u think she will love you
stop it bala stop it
iam talking to u dont u understand me
did she have food to eat
have some food to eat ikow its a new place
but u will get in the habbit of it
we will get married and all will
be ok
have u gone mad what r u saying
i will love u soo much u will
forget vikram
u have gone mad
think what u are saying
u forget vikram or i will
kill you
i will only love vikram no
matter what happens
i love vikram n i will love him
he was waiting for u but u
shot him
u do one thing kill me
sir i cant do this anymore
why have u fallen in love?
have u gone mad they are crimnals
when i met them i was
thinking the same thing
whatever they have
done is not there fault
its not about them its about others to
they will become heroes to them
you will understand what is right n what is wrong
kaka where is bala??
he has gone out
who went with him why? what happen?
i will tell u later
the police have laid a trap for us
he knew what to do between us
vikram what happened dont think
think what we have to do ahead
we can take help from police
will u think the police will help us
why not they will listen to us
what law what order what system
nandita your system gets crimals like us
we neer made any mistakes
wa always asked what was ours
i will gwt bala back
no vikram u promised me
iam going n u will go with me
no i will not go with you
vikram you surrender n i will
settle everything
i was doing my work but i love u to
belive me
if you had said it the 1st day we would
have left everything
vikram let me help u
who will save bala
iam going madam
vikram stop i say
from where everything started it ended at the
same place who are u?
do u remember devakar u killed him
devakar was my brother
if vikram finds out he will kill you
vikram might be dead by now
and i will kill u here
who will come n save u bala who will
see who is there fast
forgive me bro
i made a big mistake please forgive me
its ok i have forgivven you bro
nandita u dont need to come inside u can go
no sir i will come until they surrender
dont laugh it was your idea
but vikram our love was true
but our lives were colourfull
forgive nandita she loves u
if u dont forgive her u will not forget her
lets go we are not like them our hearts are big
have u forgotton we are thugs u cant
catch us
leave all this vikram
nothing is left bala its the end
no sir
wewere running n we will keep on running
try to change yourself bala
what abt the color
we did not have anything what
was there you took it
how can i tell you that i love you
bala what happened with you was wrong
hold my hand and come to me bala
thanks fro the help sir
i love u very much me to
sorry sir
i have to go