[Evil Cortana]
I hate you.
- [Good Cortana] Cortana!
- [Evil] Stop it. I've made up my mind.
[Evil]
Maybe if I'm going to die aboard this ship,
then Chief will suffer the same fate as me.
- [Good] Cortana stop...
- [Evil] You sacrificed everything...
- for him.
- [Good] Control yourself.
[Evil]
I can't.
[Good]
This isn't right. Something is...
Something set us down.
Something. Interesting.
I need to think.
[Evil]
Thinking is what's killing you.
What happened?
You passed out during a training exercise.
My chest feels like it's on fire.
Turns out the cryo blisters
and your difficulty breathing
are an allergic reaction
to the psydoprethaline.
It's a drug we inject
to keep ice crystals
from forming in your
cells during cryo sleep.
Occurs in about 1 in
every 50,000 or so.
So I won't be able to breath
every time I wake up from cryo sleep?
The intensity of your allergy
is still undetermined.
I'll know more in a few hours.
I want you to take it real easy
the rest of the day, cadet.
Yes, sir.
Thanks.
Hey bro.
I'm on Andesia, it's a jump away from home.
It's day, uh...
...496.
I'm sorry I didn't com yesterday.
Couldn't. We got pinned in a
firefight for seven hours.
Uhh, I must've killed
a dozen Innies though.
Mom would be proud.
We're doing really good work here.
We're doing a good thing.
Rich didn't make it.
You remember Rich from back home.
He was right there next to me and then...
...wasn't.
A pineapple and I'm flying
in four different directions.
I had to shave it all off for Rich.
He said it made me look tough.
Anyways, uh...
...I gotta go, bro.
I can't wait to get home.
We'll see ya. Cadmon, out.
[Lasky]
What are you doing?
Why do you torment yourself with these?
Are you okay?
- Whoa.
- I've been better.
Wh, what did Dr. Hughes say?
That it's nothing.
Really?
You know we won today.
Your strategy worked.
That's just me, being a leader.
[Sully over console]
Lasky, wake up.
Oh, hey, Chyler.
What's up, Sully?
Get in here, you guys gotta see this.
You look like crap.
[Sully] Alright, so feast
your eyes on grade "A"
classified non-licit intelligence
vids I pieced together.
Super pain in the ass to do but...
so worth it.
[Dimah]
This is beyond top secret.
[Sully] I've never seen something
encrypted so hard but I cracked it.
[Chen]
Wow.
- [Sully] It's crazy, huh?
- [Chen] Yeah.
[Sully] Wait, wait, wait, wait
now here comes the best part.
- [Sully] Watch his hand.
- [Spartan] Target acquired.
[On video]
They're coming! They're coming!
[Sully]
That thing is like two feet taller then we are.
[Dimah]
Pretty crazy, huh?
[Sully]
Now check this out.
[Spartan]
We've got an unknown hostile. Pulling back.
- [Vickers] Uh, no way!
- [Sully] Now who do you think they're running from?
Are they fighting together?
[Sully]
Okay now, here comes the bast part.
- Whoa.
- What is that thing?
[Sully]
Now what do you think that is?
[PA]
It is now 1800.
All cadets report to the mess hall.
[Sully]
What do you think that thing was?
Definitely not an ODST.
Then what could it be?
Maybe some upgraded ODST armour.
Come on, did you not see
the size of that thing?
That's not ODST.
Guys, look, you're missing the point.
What matters is that our soldiers were
fighting alongside the Insurrectionists.
Why would we protect the enemy?
Cadet Lasky.
Colonel Mehaffey would like to see you.
[Mehaffey]
How are you feeling?
Uh, my chest burns, sir.
Quite a bit.
This is for you.
Seems like you have a choice to make, Thomas.
I don't understand, sir.
It appears Dr. Hughes' test has
revealed that the level of your allergy
to psydoprethaline is serious enough
to warrant a medical discharge.
If you feel that you are unfit for service
all you need to do is sign the
release and bring it to the tether.
When would I leave?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
You know, Thomas...
...your memories...
...and choices are all you'll have left.
At the end of the game the king
and the pawn go into the same box.
You have to decide what you're
willing to sacrifice.
Axios.
[Colonel Lasky]
Thomas.
It is with a heavy heart that I
must inform you that today, your
brother Cadmon was shot down by
Insurrectionist forces on Andesia.
All of his squad perished.
I've been told that it was
a quick and painless death.
There are no remains to bury.
With this in mind I have decided that you
shall not leave Corbulo to attend services.
(Voice fades)
[Sully]
Lasky!
Lasky, move over I gotta
show you something.
Now's not a good time, Sully, okay.
No, it's important.
Now what the hell is that?
Hm?
Whoa.
(Powers down)
It's off line.
I'm screwed, man.
It's ONI.
They must have flagged those coms.
I gotta talk to Dimah.
Dimah! Did you tell your mom?
Chyler?
[Lasky]
Hey.
I thought I'd give your spot a try.
That com didn't make any sense.
Hating the enemy is all I've ever known.
Did you tell Mehaffey about it?
No.
What's that?
Apparently I'm allergic to war.
What does this mean?
You're leaving?
Yeah, tomorrow if I sign it.
Are you going to?
I don't know.
- Chyler.
- Oh, it's okay.
I know you don't want to be here.
I just thought...
...that maybe...
I'll miss you.
(Sirens start to sound)
What is that?
[PA]
All cadets, report to the tether.
I don't know.
To the tether!
Now!
This is not a drill!
Let's go, let's move,
let's move, come on!
- Let's move it cadets!
- Go, go, move it cadets!
Go, go, go!
Go to your squads. Now.
Keep moving, cadets!
Tyler, Lasky. The rest of the squad's
already at the tether. Let's go.
Hastati!
This way. Hurry up.
Right here. Right here.
Lasky, Chen, let's go.
Okay. Hold tight. Stay in line.
What is this? Insurrectionists?
I have no idea.
When we're assigned a number we're
going to get on to the tether, okay.
What the...?
Why are ODSTs dropping here?
I don't know.
Because we're under attack.
This is not good.
ODSTs dropping is never good.
This is ridiculous.
I can get us on this wagon.
No, no, no. We will hold our position.
Guys, come on.
No, Tchakova, that is a direct order.
Suit yourself.
- Dimah.
- No, Dimah.
Get back in line right now.
Return to your squad, cadet.
I'm getting on this wagon.
It's full. Wait for the next one.
My mother is Secretary of Fleet-Com.
Your choice, marine.
Go.
Wagon full. Send her off.
This is taking too long, April.
Maybe we should bum-rush like Dimah.
No. No, no, no, no, we'll be fine.
What the hell are those things?
Go!
[Chyler]
Oh my God. What is that?
Tom, come on.
- Come on.
- What was that?
I don't know.
(Screams and crashing of people
falling from the tether)
(Screams and crashing continues)
Come on, come on! Run!
Subtitles by Tabularo