ENGLISH SUBTITLE BY :
FRIDODIDO
No1 Subs iNFO | www.psagmeno.com
Hey.
You...
Little...
Pussy..
HARDCORE HENRY
Hello, Henry.
You can not talk,
But it is normal.
No, it's not normal,
but temporary, okay?
Do you remember how you got here?
Okay.
It is also normal.
Henry, wait.
Wait.
Be patient.
Scanner.
Processor sensory  activated.
Relax. whether?
Scanning.
- Video Link confirmed.
- Above.
The following can hurt.
This time too.
But it will not last long, I promise.
Almost we have done.
Soldadora.
I can do it.
Wonderful  Henry.
Tightens.
Stronger.
Great, right?
Integument.
Please do not shake your hand.
You probably do not remember.
You were never fan of my work.
Perhaps this will make you change your mind.
Right?
Memory is a funny thing.
I am an expert and I do not know if some day recover
yours.
You do not remember me at all,
is not it Henry?
My name is Estelle.
You and I were...
We are still...
Husband and wife.
I love you Henry.
I can not wait to hear you say it.
Henry.
Still he is trying to regain his memories.
Oh God.
I'm Robbie.
The wizard of sound.
This you'll love.
Because, sir...
You get to choose your own voice.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Hello Henry.
- Robbie.
- Come on, are options.
What white man would not hear
as Louis Armstrong?
Just one more, wait.
Henry, I am your father.
Robert  enough.
- Sorry mom.
- What if we use Henry's voice?
Yes, whatever you say, you're the boss
.
Boring.
- Security compromised.
- Fuck.
- Level Four.
- Is it a sham?
- What?
- Committed Safety Level Four.
- Close the door.
- It's probably a mistake.
- Estelle, call the base.
- Committed Safety Level Four.
Clear.
Oh, no.
Yes.
Thank you.
Get up.
Henry, right?
Please.
- Shut up.
- No...
What do you think the new you?
I interrupted the procedure?
Still can not speak Henry?
You can not, no.
Not see me and Henry.
You may have rebuilt your girlfriend,
But I gave the matter
premium to do so.
And I mean I gave all
the raw material.
- What is your name?
- Timothy.
Nice to meet Timothy.
Did you see when Estelle
Henry brought his remains here?
Yes.
Are you so kind to describe
Henry
Better understand how well you see now?
Sure. His arm was ripped a shot
below the elbow...
And they ripped a shot
leg below the knee.
- And there was a dent as a ball...
- Do you happen to see your head?
Yes.
Tell us.
The skull was dented and there was a...
She had no eyes and...
The bottom of his jaw was shattered
.
It is correct.
I'm bleeding too.
That was exhausting.
Stay close.
Henry! Hurry up! Hurry up!
Close it.
Henry, come on!
Henry, faster!
Come on.
Kick it.
If Akan takes over my job,
Men like these will be revived
to form his army.
Go!
EMERGENCY EXIT
Henry, no!
Henry!
Take my hand!
Capsule exhaust  activated.
There are two capsules.
- A.
- Marty?
Sorry, man
obviously went crazy.
Marty, no!
Henry.
- It's yours, come in.
- Estelle!
Come in, come in!
Capsule exhaust  activated.
Altitude. Altitude.
The parachute! The parachute!
Open the parachute!
It's going too fast!
Sotente, Henry!
Oh God.
Mercenaries Akan.
Me down.
Henry.
You underestimate, okay?
Let them come and attack them.
Akan, is also weak
a piece of shit.
Attacks!
No, Henry!
Defend yourself!
Come on!
The groom is not a killing machine...
- Henry!
-... What did you expect?
But you you built a good sack of boxing.
Stop!
- Stop!
- What?
- Estelle...
Are not you curious what this motherfucker,
You going to do this motherfucker?
Henry!
You're like a fucking scared rabbit. true?
Okay, I'm not going to hurt.
Voice module you have installed?
Shit.
Well, at least we know you're not deaf.
Right, you can now put your hands down.
I have waited for this moment three years
and I get the damn Charlie Chaplin.
Shit! Come on!
Well, let's take a look.
Open the glove please.
Get that device.
You must untangle the cables.
Is a wedding ring?
Are you...? You are married?
How you doing with that?
Yes, what a surprise.
Good. Now I need you...
Take off your shirt, please.
Open there.
Yes, those.
Connect the cables there.
Yes, there.
So your name is Henry and...
Well, the good news is that you
to live for a while.
Bad news is that in this case,
A while means 20, 30
minutes max. Henry.
Unless you have very, very lucky
.
And you have it.
Uncle Jimmy will take you to his lab.
Resists.
Shit.
We are following.
Disconnect. Hides that.
There are no clothes. Ponte sweatshirt.
No time, fuck.
Only cover your blood with the bag.
Be quiet and let me
handle this, okay?
Perhaps we can proceed directly to the fine
?
So...
Shit.
Cursed  Akan, bribing...
Do you know what is wrong with Mother Russia?
Too hot.
Whatever.
I used to be in charge of all this.
And now...
I'll have to hurt Henry,
but it's for your own good, pal.
Just give me your arm... Hey!
Shit!
I! I'm Jimmy.
We have little time before that we rediscover friend.
Just... good. Just give me your arm.
Well, just relax.
Here it is.
Bingo!
With this bloody  you have been tracking.
Goodbye.
In a few moments your mechanical parts
begin to fade.
Your friend has a contact Akan
important in Russia Dimitry called Slick.
Slick is responsible for the police, guns,
Properties and many other things Akan
,
This point on the map
It is the house of Slick.
All you have to do is go in there
,
Kill him, open his ribcage.
Take your beating heart...
And I eat it.
I'm kidding!
I'm kidding, you have to eat your heart
.
Under
his heart is his power pumper. whether?
Bring it to me.
Use this and will contact you this.
That must be the most
gay jacket I've ever seen.
What good jacket!
Can you get me one?
I'll be in touch!
You!
Come here!
Have lighter?
Why do you think I have arms?
You can go.
You want a smoke?
Yes.
Henry.
Akan already begun.
If we do not stop, will have its army
days or sooner.
You half-machine, half a fag.
Wait, wait.
I tell you something very important
about the man who sent you here.
Hello Henry.
I am in a very classy establishment.
Follow
point and then touches the touch doors.
Do you understand? The knock on doors!
She .
She, bitch.
Take it to Jimmy.
He is Jimmy?
Hello.
I'm a car, baby.
A Lexus convertible!
I will not go back there!
That thing is a destroyer class!
It feels good.
Yes, yes.
God this is amazing. If!
Damn, you're late!
You're late!
The last 15 minutes
They have been a roller coaster of emotions
.
I did not know if I would see.
So I lit some of this.
I turned on my nerves damn you, you know?
There you have it.
Okay. Only you lost energy.
Come on.
Hey, Bring me a bit
of this strong Russian thing, girls.
Well, where is the pumper is?
Where you are...? You got it?
Did you get the goddamn...?
Yes! Very good!
Is this, is this, yes?
Well, wait.
Well, hold this woman.
Shit.
Well, I must get this damn
there.
Who do I cheat?
I am not able to do this.
I'm sorry, I'm not able to do
friend.
I'm not able.
Sorry,
I'm not able to do so.
What happens to your hand?
What is it? A robot?
's Handsome.
I know how to make him feel better.
No, I know a better way.
Lavántalo.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, what have they done?
What have you done this time, Jimmy?
Are you still conscious?
Yes. Hi.
You'll be fine.
We just have to charge you a little.
Girls, give us space, please?
Thank you.
You are very important, you know?
You're not the only one hurt by Akan.
You and I want the same thing.
This may hurt a little.
Here we go.
It's wonderful.
Now I can take back to my lab.
I'm Jimmy, by the way.
I understand that all this is very confusing for you
.
But... but...
It's better if I show
in the laboratory. whether?
Hello?
Oh, thank you.
're Here.
They must have  having followed.
I can not... I can not let them see me like
.
I can not... I'm sorry.
No... I can not stay here Henry.
Sorry.
Demons.
Yes!
Yes, well, his men are here.
I'll face them, okay?
There are more weapons in the drawer for you, yes?
This is war, baby. If!
Oh yeah!
Hello girls!
No, below.
Goodbye.
Already had it!
I'm not with them!
Come on, come on!
Run, run, run!
The floor is lava!
I'll burn this...
Hey, Katya!
Jimmy, you're a jerk!
Please, please!
Please do not hurt me.
I have family.
Is she your wife?
Do not worry about it Henry.
She mourns her dead husband.
I was not sure you'd see.
Your perseverance is incomparable.
And very exciting.
Services Slick Dimitry
were excellent.
I'm glad not to have paid in advance.
I'll tell Estelle you did it right.
Akan!
Akan, open the damn door
Do you hear me?
Is arranged very nice in the
back of my truck down.
I'll rip your lungs!
Go far Henry, unlike
of this motherfucker.
Hi Henry, put the gun down.
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
In peace, in peace.
Relax, calm down.
As I shared something with you.
I need to share something with me.
Where will Akan?
Do you want to Akan?
Here's your Akan.
- Fuck, Shit.
- And here's your Akan.
That's my ego talking to you.
What do you want?
To be better? Ego?
Be superior? Ego?
- Be...
- Being superior!
Higher, yes. It's okay.
The escort
Akan is taking the girl to his base.
Shit. I got this,
I got it.
What have you done?
- All of our dead girls!
- Well girls.
- Well?
- It's okay.
- Okay, just...
- It's not right!
- Who were those guys?
- What do you mean, right?
- He is telling us to relax?
- Henry? Who is Henry?
- You saw what happened up there?
- Sorry you are upset, okay?
- What are you watching?
Henry and I are going to take care of Akan.
- Henry? Who is Henry?
- You saw what happened up there?
- Did you see what you did?
- You're an Idiot!
- We'll go with you to destroy them!
- That fag white hair is dead.
Okay, come on. You want a bike?
Can go on a motorcycle.
Just... just...
Yes. You want to go?
- Well, go on your bike, go on your bike.
- We have our own bikes.
Bloody hell.
Sometimes it is easier to say yes.
Henry, catch it!
God. I thought I'd lost forever
Henry.
I was very scared.
I was very scared when you fell.
I thought I would never see.
I love you Henry.
I love you.
ENGLISH SUBTITLE BY :
FRIDODIDO
How sweet.
If I took this picture and put it
in a cup of tea.
Would not need sugar.
Yuri, please.
Now we can move forward.
Every year thousand
baseball bats are sold in Russia
And at most, 50 baseballs.
Do you get an idea of the great Russian pastime?
This is a rare bat that survived.
Estelle.
Could you be so kind
to stop you please?
No.
Or you want to take your place?
Estelle, your man is all
a knight in armor.
He is sacrificing himself to stay alive.
Just to make my penis kill you later.
Are you sure, Henry?
Are you sure?
I did not hear a "no".
Excellent!
Come here  Henry.
C'mon, c'mon, c'mon Henry.
You...
Small...
Coward.
Knights please go take a look.
Stop!
Give a chance to peace brothers.
My ego wants to kill my
but not supreme being.
My God, baby.
She was talking to the man.
Demons.
Look at this.
The guy has a lock on the memory.
Well, that's all I
I can do for you, friend.
Restart time.
See you in 15 minutes, I hope.
Hey.
's Awake.
You might see a blur.
It's just your depth perception
trying calibrated, okay?
Follow me as I walk, okay?
Stand.
According .
Good.
Now, you can focus being here?
- Yes?
- Yes
Bury you...
It is like burying a treasure.
Not really understand what
Akan think because...
Henry, stop playing.
You're almost there, buddy.
This is where you must go.
Hasten.
's Me, Jimmy.
Walking.
Shit.
These pigs are here again.
Do not put at risk my lab.
Let go.
Baby, Bowing reflect
is psychological. It is only in your head.
Henry, no.
I'm telling you... shit.
Go.
Good job Charlie Bronson.
Bravo 2-0.
Lights.
Plays the video.
Dawn twilight...
an era of cyborgs.
Thank you, sir.
I made lobotomy to all the essentials
Nonessentials for a soldier.
Personal Recollections, speech, taste
, I removed everything.
You may still be a problem with emotional
motivation, which...
Motivation?
What do you think your damned salary, James?
My salary...
Yes, okay.
What the hell, James?
I'm sorry, sir. I am so sorry.
Hell, open the door.
Please open the door.
We have a fault.
Let me out, please.
I'll fix it.
I doubt it.
Damn idiot.
You know Jimmy?
there is something about breaking a bad back...
That never gets old.
- It sounds like...
- The end, the beginning.
Or the same?
Sit  Henry.
When a man is disabled,
all have the same question in mind,
Especially in his.
Does the penis works?
Mine did not, so I planned my escape
of this chair.
I came to Russia when
in the West,
Banned resuscitation of dead tissue.
Akan is a megatómano,
but my research had funds.
He looks at the Nobel Prize.
Who has time for ethics
revolting when you're rich and your penis work?
I paid a high price.
I stopped doing
soldiers and then I succeeded.
Cultivé cyber-skin men.
Mainly, are only
sophisticated prostheses
But do not you dare tell...
My avatars!
Now, cyborgs on the other side have
pieces and a brain.
Think for themselves, at least in theory
.
Do you take a look?
That hippie, always smoking weed.
- NEW DEPOSIT LINKED
- You're not drugged, right?
I hope not.
Good.
You are an amazing man, Henry.
Is very little.
There is very little real man,
of course.
Skeletal system, muscles improved
,
Cardiovascular driven by an atomic battery curio 224.
A good night's sleep and could
to power an aircraft carrier.
Outstanding technology, do not you think?
- Starting...
- You do not.
My boys.
I made the first revenge.
But then I began to explore
new aspects of myself.
Can I have a drink?
I have lived these last years, Henry.
My boys, receive
fines for excess speed, walk barefoot in the grass.
And what they have lots of sex.
You never guess what we do
here alone.
Press "play" there.
Forward.
BROADCAST PROGRESS
What did you do?
Close your eyes.
Something is wrong with you.
Do not worry, not gonorrhea or anything.
I just have to sit in this chair
and have a look, shall we?
The scanner says you're in great danger.
If stabbed for being a traitor, liar
Informant!
I'll shut friend.
Release the prototype baby.
Now!
Try to log off for good,
Even when we knew transmitiste your video
Akan.
Right?
What is this?
What is that?
Be what you are transmitting to Akan!
Enough!
Enough.
Even if you believe, you still have to...
Henry, no!
No!
You brought my lab!
I trusted you!
Henry, kill me please.
Akan will not.
I will live in this straitjacket
rotten and disgusting skin.
What the hell were you thinking?
What toy robot
Akan was my friend?
Thank you, Henry.
Fuck you too,
but mainly thanks.
My lab is in danger,
But I can build a new one using
Akan equipment...
When we come together for your wife. agree?
Put that on the wall.
If I can not have my lab
no one will.
Now, do not miss this.
Fuck you Akan.
Do not change the channel.
We are on the way.
Well, I counted six vehicles.
That's at least 35 men.
We have to reduce by half
before entering the hotel...
To give us the opportunity to fight and get out alive.
There are also certain stigma,
Associated
subjects who likes music.
I just want to leave now clear
I'm a macho man.
Understand?
Here they come.
Wait.
Now.
Well, cover me.
Yes!
Shit, are in the hotel.
We no longer need sniper rifle
either.
Enters, looking the colonel.
Over here, amigo.
Arm yourself to the teeth.
Do not touch that. Emma Gee is mine.
As my father used to say
"A Granada
day keeps the enemy in his lair."
Come on.
Faster.
The great Sally.
Well, home is where the battle is.
Well, soldier, it is our duty to ensure
that nothing happens to invalid, understand?
Continue.
Yes you can hear them but you can not shoot
,
You can probably throwing one Granada.
Strip an egg down there, friend.
Avancemos.
Come on.
My God, how embarrassing.
Dodged a bullet.
You cover.
Surround them.
Do not let
is invalid under you!
Okay.
Wait. Help me with the disabled.
Back five steps when you order.
Disabled  A place for a crippled man.
Thank you, Yuri.
My headquarters is up.
Would you like to see?
We'll see.
I think so.
Do not waste horsepower.
Take the next exit.
Over there, that's right.
Friend's turn off the engines.
Cambiémosles plans these guys.
A load.
Big Ben.
Akan is a jerk!
ENGLISH SUBTITLE BY :
FRIDODIDO
My God.
Akan seems already begun.
Tomorrow these poor guys will
robotic super soldiers like you.
Beware!
What it is red and bad for your teeth?
Lavántate friend.
To your left.
I'll buy you some time.
Seal the door.
I can not tell you how many times I dreamed
be going up this elevator.
It is a pity that can not...
It's just a landing gear, friend.
Now, listen to me.
When you kill Akan
I want you to see him straight in the eye
until the rest of it...
Is so dead like them,
you understand?
Now, I'm afraid I will not go with you.
But you have allowed me to bring you this far,
Been given an old
his greatest gift...
In all his years.
No.
Is fixed at its jugular.
If not be able to retire...
The... the thing in your pocket fast.
I'm afraid I must confess something.
You see, I've been watching for years Akan.
So when you fell that road
and you revealed so splendidly,
All I saw was my chance for revenge
.
You gave me reason with Dimitry,
but then in the forest...
I noticed an implant.
A blockage in your memory, see?
And I could not afford,
You to remember a better life elsewhere, so...
I left there.
It's not something that I take pride, I'm afraid.
Then in my labortorio,
When he tried to analyze what you could do for me.
I realized...
Who you are to me, Henry.
It's very nice to have a friend. Henry.
'll Think that all the deaths
I would have prepared for this.
If you have not yet passed,
You will begin to remember moments of your past, Henry.
And those memories are real.
Are you who you are.
Trust them.
Memories, memories, memories.
My first batch of cyber-soldiers.
All you have experienced today
Has been loaded into
what remains of their brains.
All I remember is waking up in the laboratory...
And his wife screw- legs.
I love you Charlie.
I love you, Edward.
I love you, Thomas.
Do you recognize?
Right?
How strange.
Are your wife.
I can smell what you like about it.
They are almost ready for you.
But I warn you, your
accelerators will seem to you have now...
A damn toy battery.
Go ahead, jódelo.
Get up.
Get up!
ADRENALINE
Can you handle this?
Henry.
Why do you hit yourself Henry?
Love?
Love, are you okay?
I love how much you protect me.
You owe me an apology.
Why?
Dudar me.
Had certain apprehensions.
Why did you let me do it?
Only I gave my wife liked
and losing all my men.
Are they all dead?
- Yes
- Yes.
Do you know when to realize that this was working
?
When?
When Henry got me
to the escape pod,
Trying to get me
lab and out.
Who would have thought that the
vagina is a great motivator?
hundred of you tomorrow, next week
thousand.
The first memory of each one will be his wife
,
Sliding a cheap ring finger bronze.
Every one of my soldiers,
Wake
willing to do any thing my brilliant wife ask them,
Either
march in Paris or in the garden of the White House.
I would pretend to understand the role played
.
You did not make history, Henry.
You helped end it.
You...
Small...
Coward.
ENGLISH SUBTITLE BY :
FRIDODIDO
It's like my mother told me.
It's like if my name.
And I checked
killing all the wrong people.
I love you, Henry.
And never
call by another name than yours, but you must decide.
Are you going to stand there lying
swallowing blood in your mouth?
How you going to get up, spit it out,
and shed them?
Akan!
Damn...
No!
Stop!
I order you to stop!
Henry!
Stop!
Where it is?
No.
Fuck you, motherfucker!
Jódete
How could you
do this Henry?
How could you do this?
Answer me!
EASY
Son of a bitch!
Henry  What happened?
You were supposed to love me.
Henry!
Listen to your heart!
ENGLISH SUBTITLE BY :
FRIDODIDO
No1 Subs iNFO | www.psagmeno.com