[Narrator] Long ago,
in the far away land of ancient Greece,
there was a golden age
of powerful gods...
and extraordinary heroes.
And the greatest and strongest
of all these heroes...
was the mighty Hercules.
But what is the measure
ofa true hero ?
- Ah, that is what our story is--
- [ Woman ] Will you listen to him ?
He's makin' the story
sound like some Greek tragedy.
- Lighten up, dude.
- We'll take it from here, darling.
[Narrator]
You go, girl.
We are the Muses,
goddesses of the arts
and proclaimers of heroes.
Heroes like Hercules.
Honey, you mean "Hunk-ules."
Ooh, I'd like to make
some sweet music with him--
- # [Muses Humming]
- Our story actually begins...
long before Hercules,
many aeons ago.
# Ah #
# Back when the world was new #
- # The planet Earth
was down on its luck #
- Whoa !
# And everywhere gigantic brutes
called Titans ran amok #
# It was a nasty place #
# There was a mess
wherever you stepped #
# Where chaos reigned
and the earthquakes
and volcanoes never slept #
- Whoo ! Say it, girlfriend !
- # And then along came Zeus #
- # He hurled his thunderbolt #
- [Chorus] # He zapped #
- # Locked those suckers in a vault #
- # They're trapped #
# And on his own
stopped chaos in its tracks #
# And that's the gospel truth #
# The guy was too "Type A"
to just relax #
- # And that's the world's first dish #
- Yeah, baby.
# Zeus tamed the globe
while still in his youth #
# Though, honey
it may seem impossible #
# That's the gospel truth #
# On Mount Olympus life was neat #
# And smooth as sweet vermouth #
# Although, honey
it may seem impossible #
# That's the gospel truth #
- [Chorus] # Ah, ah #
- # Ah #
- # Ah, ah #
- # Oh, yeah, yeah #
- # Hey, hey, hey #
- # Ah, ah #
- # Hey, yeah #
# [Chorus Harmonizing]
[ Chattering ]
[ Gasping ]
Hercules !
[ Chuckles ]
Behave yourself.
[ Gurgling ]
Oh, look at this.
Look how cute he is.
- [ Babbling ]
- [ Cooing ]
Hah ! Oh, he's strong...
like his dad, hmm ?
Whoa ! Excuse me !
Hot stuff coming through !
Excuse me.
One side, Ares.
Why, Hermes, they're lovely.
Yeah, you know,
I had Orpheus do the arrangement.
Isn't that too nutty ?
Fabulous party. You know, I haven't
seen this much love in a room...
- since Narcissus discovered himself.
- [ Kissing Sounds ]
Dear, keep those away from the baby.
Oh, he won't hurt himself.
Let the kid have a little fun.
[ Gods Gasping ]
Oh. On behalf of my son,
I want to thank you all...
for your wonderful gifts !
- What about our gift, dear ?
- Well, let's see here.
We'll take-- Hmm, yes.
A little cirrus...
and, hmm,
a touch of nimbostratus...
anda dash of cumulus.
- [ Squeaks ]
- [ Honks ]
His name is Pegasus,
and he's all yours, son.
[ High-Pitched Whinny ]
[ Gods Sighing ]
- Mind his head.
- He's so tiny.
- [ Yawns ]
- My boy.
My little Hercules.
[Man]
How sentimental.
You know,
I haven't been this choked up...
since I got a hunk of moussaka
caught in my throat !
Huh ?
So is this an audience or a mosaic ?
Hey, how you doin' ?
Lookin' good. Nice dress.
So, Hades, you finally made it.
How are things in the underworld ?
Well, they're just fine. You know,
a little dark, a little gloomy.
And, as always, hey, full of
dead people. What are you gonna do ?
Ah ! There's the little sunspot.
Little snootchie.
And here is a sucker for the little
sucker, eh ? Here you go. Ya just--
[ Grunting ]
- Sheesh !
- [ Laughing ]
Uh, powerful little tyke.
Come on, Hades. Don't be such a stiff.
Join the celebration !
Hey. [ Chuckles ]
Love to, babe,
but unlike you gods
lounging about up here,
I regrettably have a full-time gig...
that you, by the way,
so charitably bestowed on me, Zeus.
So... can't.
Love to, but can't.
You ought to slow down.
You'll work yourself to death.
Hah ! Work yourself to death !
[ Laughing ]
- [ Crowd Laughing ]
- Oh, I kill myself !
[ Fake Laugh ]
If only. If only.
If there's one god you don't
want to get steamed up, it's Hades.
'Cause he hadan evilplan.
# He ran the underworld #
# But thought the dead
were dull and uncouth #
# He was as mean
as he wasruthless #
- # And that's the gospel truth #
- [ Growling ]
# He had a plan to shake things up #
# And that's the gospel truth #
- Pain !
- Coming, your most lugubriousness.
Ow !
[ Grunting ]
- [ Yells ]
- Panic !
[ Panting ]
Oh, I'm sorry. I can handle it !
[ Groaning, Sighing ]
[ Yells ]
- Pain ! Ohh !
- And Panic !
[ Both ]
Reporting for duty !
Fine, fine, fine. Just let me know
the instant the Fates arrive.
Oh. They're here.
What ? The Fates are here,
and you didn't tell me ?
[Both Whimpering, Groaning]
[ Both ] We are worms !
Worthless worms !
Memo to me, memo to me.
Maim you after my meeting.
Darling, hold that mortal's
thread of life...
good and tight.
[Woman Screaming]
- Incoming !
- [ Fates Laughing ]
Ladies ! Hah !
I am so sorry that I'm--
- [ Together ] Late !
- We knew you would be.
We know everything.
- Past.
- Present.
- And Future.
Indoor plumbing--
it's gonna be big.
Great, great. Anyway, see, ladies, I was
at this party, and I lost track of--
- [ Together ] We know !
- Yeah. I know... you know.
So here's the deal: Zeus,
Mr High And Mighty, Mr "Hey, You,
Get Off Of My Cloud," now he has--
- [ Together ] A bouncing baby brat.
- We know !
I know... you know.
I know. I got it.
I got the concept.
So let me just ask:
Is this kid gonna mess up
my hostile takeover bid, or what ?
What do you think ?
- Um--
- Oh, no, you don't.
We're not supposed to reveal the future.
[ Sniffs ]
Oh, wait. I'm sorry.
Time out. Can I--
Can I askyou a question, by the way ?
Are you--
- Did you cut your hair or something ?
You look fabulous.
- [ Giggles ]
- I mean, you look like
a Fate worse than death.
- [Giggles Continue]
- [ Groans ] Oh, gross !
- Yech ! It's blinkin' !
Ladies, please. My fate...
is in your lovely hands.
- Oh... yeah !
- Oh, all right.
In 18 years precisely,
the planets will align...
ever so nicely.
- Ay, verse. Oy.
- The time to act will be at hand.
Unleash the Titans,
your monstrous band.
Mm-hmm. Good, good.
Then the once-proud Zeus
will finally fall,
and you, Hades,
will rule all!
Yes ! Hades rules !
- A word of caution to this tale.
- Excuse me ?
Should Hercules fight, you will fail.
[ Fates Cackling ]
What ?
Okay, fine, fine.
I'm cool. I'm fine.
- [BelIDings]
- Pain ? Panic ?
Got a little riddle for ya.
How do you kill a god?
- I do not... know !
- You can't. They're immortal ?
Bingo ! They're immortal.
So, first you got to turn
the little sunspot...
mortal.
[ Whistling Snores ]
- [Glass Breaking]
- [Pain, Panic Tittering]
- What ? What is it ?
- Huh ?
[ Together ]
The baby !
- [ Gasping ]
- [ Sputtering ]
Hercules ! Oh !
[ Sobbing ]
[Sobbing Continues]
No !
Now we did it ! Zeus is gonna
use us for target practice !
Just hang onto the kid, Panic.
- [ Grunting ]
- [ Crying ]
Hurry ! Let's just kill the kid
and get it over with, okay ?
Here you go, kid.
A little Grecian formula.
Look at that !
He's... changing.
- Can we do it now ?
- No, he has to drink the whole potion.
- Every last drop.
- [Man] Who's there ?
[ Both Screaming ]
- Alcmene, over here.
- [ Crying ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh, you poor thing.
- Oh, don't cry.
- Is anybody there ?
- Now ?
- Now.
- [Alcmene Muttering]
- Oh. Well, he must have been abandoned.
Amphitryon, for so many years...
we've prayed to the gods
to bless us with a child.
- Perhaps they've answered our prayers.
- Perhaps they have.
- "Hercules" ?
- [Thunderclap]
- [ Growling ]
- [ Giggling ]
[ Snakes Sputtering ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Giggling ]
Help, help, help !
Hades is gonna kill us
when he finds out what happened.
You mean, if he finds out.
Of course he's gonna f--
If. If is good.
[Muse] It was tragic. Zeus led
all the gods on a frantic search.
But my the time they found the baby,
it was too late.
- # Young Herc was mortal now #
- [ Chorus ] # Mmm #
- # But since he did not drink
the last drop #
- # Oh #
# He still retained
his godlike strength #
- # So thank his lucky stars #
- Tell it, girl.
- # But Zeus andHera wept #
- # Ooh, ooh, ooh #
- # Because their son
could never come home #
- # Ooh #
# They'd have to watch
their precious baby #
#  Grow up from afar #
# Though Hades' horrid plan #
- # Was hatched before
Herc cut his first tooth #
- # Ahh #
# The boy grew stronger everyday #
# And that's the gospel truth #
# The gospel truth #
- [ Shepherd Bell Clanking]
- [ Sheep Bleating ]
- [ Braying ]
- Hercules, slow down !
- Look out !
- [ Men Gasping ]
- Oops ! S-S-Sorry, guys.
- Hey, watch where you're goin'.
- Sunday driver!
- [ Crowd Yelling ]
Thanks, son.
When old Penelope twisted her ankle
back there, I thought we were done for.
- No problem, Pop.
- Uh, don't-don't-don't unload just yet.
First, I have to finagle with Phideas.
- Okay. [ Slight Grunt ]
- [ Braying ]
Oops. Sorry, Penelope.
Now, Hercules,
this time, please just--
I know. I know.
Stay by the cart.
[ Sighs ]
That's my boy.
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Man Groaning ]
Oh, my goodness. Whoa !
- Careful !
- [ Shudders ]
- Why, thank you.
- No problem.
Why, Hercules !
[ Sputtering ]
- It's you !
- Let me, let me help you with that.
No, no, no, no, no.
I got it !
[ Straining ]
I'm fine. You just run along.
- Are you sure ?
- Oh, yes.
Absolutely.
Yo ! Give it here !
[Gasps]
Hey, you need an extra guy ?
Uh... sorry, Herc.
Uh, we already got... five,
and we want to keep it
an even number.
- Hey, wait a second.
Five isn't an even--
- See ya, Herc.
- What a geek !
- Destructo Boy.
- Maybe we should call him "Jerkules. "
- [Laughter]
- [Boy] Heads up !
- I-I got it !
No ! Stop !
- [Rumbling]
- Uh-oh.
- [CrowdMurmuring]
- [Hercules] Oh, no.
It's okay.
[Crowd Yelling]
Hey ! Whoa !
[ Screaming ]
- Son !
- Hang on, Pop ! Be right back!
Oh, my ! Oh, no ! Don't !
Oh, no, no, no, no !
No, no, no, no, no, no !
[Yelling]
[ Sighs, Chuckles ]
- Watch out !
- [ Yells ]
[ Crashing ]
[Crowd Murmuring]
Nice catch, Jerkules.
- Son--
- [Man Sputtering]
This is the last...
straw, Amphitryon !
- That boy is a menace !
- He's too dangerous
to be around normal people !
- [ Crowd Grumbling, Muttering ]
- He didn't mean any harm.
He'sjust a kid.
He-He just... can't
control his strength.
I'm warning you.
You keep that-that-that...
freak away from here !
- [Boy] Freak! Yeah, go away!
- [Crowd Agreeing]
[ Sighs ]
Son, you shouldn't let...
those things they said
back there get to you.
But, Pop, they're right.
I-I am a freak.
I try to fit in.
I really do.
[ Sighs ]
I just can't.
Sometimes... I feel like,
like I really don't belong here,
Iike I'm supposed to be...
someplace else.
Hercules, son--
I know it doesn't make any sense.
# I have often dreamed #
# Of a far off place #
# Where a great, warm welcome
will be waiting for me #
# Where the crowds will cheer #
# When they see my face #
# And a voice keeps sayin' this
is where I'm meant to be #
# I will find my way #
# I can go the distance #
# I'll be there someday #
# if I can be strong #
# I know every mile #
# Will be worth my while #
# I would go most anywhere
to feel like I #
# Belong #
Hercules, there's something
your mother and I...
have been meaning to, to tell ya.
But if you found me,
then where did I come from ?
Why was I left here ?
This... was around your neck
when we found you.
It's the symbol of the gods.
This is it ! Don't you see ?
Maybe they have the answers !
I'll go to the temple of Zeus and--
Ma, Pop,
you're the greatest parents
anyone could have, but...
I-I gotta know.
[Cock Crowing]
# I am on my way #
# I can go the distance #
# I don't care how far #
# Somehow, I'll be strong #
# I know every mile #
# Will be worth my while #
# I would go most anywhere #
# To find where I belong #
Oh, mighty Zeus,
please, hear me
and answer my prayer.
I need to know: Who am I ?
Wh-Where do I belong ?
[ Wind Whistling ]
Huh ?
[ Rock Creaking ]
My boy.
My little Hercules.
- [Creaking]
- Ahhhh !
- [ Grunting ]
- Hey, hey, hey. Hold on, kiddo !
What's your hurry ?
After all these years,
is this the kind of hello
you give your father ?
F-Father ?
Didn't know you had
a famous father, did you ?
- Surprise !
- [ Coughing ]
Look how you've grown.
Why, you've got
your mother's beautiful eyes...
and my strong chin.
- Hah !
- I-l don't understand.
If you're my father,
that would make me a--
- A god.
- A god. A god !
Hey, you wanted answers,
and by thunder,
you're old enough now
to know the truth.
But why did you leave me on Earth ?
Didn't you want me ?
Of course we did. Your mother and I
loved you with all our hearts.
Someone stole you from us
and turned you mortal,
and only gods can live
on Mount Olympus.
And you can't do a thing ?
I can't, Hercules, but you can.
R-Really ? W-What ?
I'll do anything.
Hercules, if you can prove yourself
a true hero on earth,
your godhood will be restored !
A true hero. Great !
Uh, exactly how do you
become a true hero ?
First, you must seek out Philoctetes,
the trainer of heroes.
Seek out Philoctetes.
Right. I'll--
- Whoa !
- Whoa ! Hold your horses !
Which reminds me.
[ Whistles ]
- [ Trilling Whistling ]
- [Zeus] Ha-ha !
You probably don't remember Pegasus,
but you two go way back, son.
[ Whinnying, Sniffing ]
[ Groans ]
[ Laughs ]
Oh, Pegasus !
He's a magnificent horse...
with the brain of a bird.
[ Whistling ]
Huh ?
I'll find Philoctetes
and become a true hero.
That's the spirit !
I won't let you down, Father !
Yee-hah !
Good luck, son.
# I will beat the odds
I can go the distance #
# I will face the world #
# Fearless, proud and strong #
# I will please the gods #
# I can go the distance #
# Till I find my hero's welcome #
# Right where I #
# Belong #
- [Birds Screeching]
- [ Whinnying ]
[ Goat Bleating ]
- [ Bleating ]
- Whoa !
- You sure this is the right place ?
- [Women Laughing]
[Laughter Echoes]
[ Laughter Continues ]
[Bleating]
What's the matter, little guy ?
You stuck ?
- Whoa ! Hey, butt out, buddy !
- Ugh !
- [ All Gasping ]
- Girls ! Stop ! Stop !
Come back, come back, come back.
Whoa, whoa-- Oh. Geez !
Wait ! Whoa, whoa, whoa !
Oh, nymphs!
- They can't keep their hands off me.
- Hey !
[ Grumbling ]
What's the matter ?
You never seen a satyr before ?
Uh... no.
Can you help us ?
We're looking for someone
called Philoctetes.
Call me Phil.
- Phil !
- Ow !
Boy, am I glad to meet you !
I'm Hercules.
- [ Grunts ]
- This is Pegasus.
Animals ! Disgusting !
- [ Snorts ]
- I need your help.
I want to become a hero,
a true hero.
- Sorry, kid. Can't help ya.
- Wait !
- Whoo !
- Uh, sorry.
- Why not ?
- Two words: I am retired.
Look, I gotta do this.
Haven't you ever had a dream,
something you wanted so bad
you'd do anything ?
[ Sighs ]
Kid, come inside.
I want to show you something.
[ Neighing, Grunting ]
Watch it ! That was part
of the mast ofthe Argo.
- The Argo ?
- Yeah.
Who do you think taught Jason
how to sail ? Cleopatra ?
I trained all those would-be heroes.
Odysseus, Perseus, Theseus.
A lot of "yeuseus."
And every single one of those bums
let me down...
flatter than a discus.
None of'em could go the distance.
And then there was Achilles.
Now, there was a guy
who had it all--
the build, the footspeed.
He could jab, he could take a hit,
he could keep on comin'.
But that furshlugginer
heel of his !
He barely gets nicked there once
and-- kaboom !
He's history.
[ Sighs ]
Yeah, I had a dream once.
I dreamed I was gonna train
the greatest hero there ever was.
So great, the gods would hang
a picture of him in the stars...
all across the sky, and people
would say, "That's Phil's boy. "
That's right.
Eh, but dreams are for rookies.
A guy can only take
so much disappointment.
But I'm different than
those other guys, Phil !
- I can go the distance.
Come on. I'll show you.
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Whinnying ]
- Geez ! You don't give up, do ya ?
Watch this.
[ Grunting ]
Holy Hera.
[ Muttering ] You know, maybe if l--
No ! Snap out of it !
I'm too old to get mixed up
in this stuff again.
But if I don't become a true hero,
- I'll never be able
to rejoin my father, Zeus.
- Hold it !
- Zeus is your father, right ?
- Uh-huh.
[ Laughing ]
Zeus. The big guy.
He's your daddy.
[ Laughing ]
Mr Lightning Bolts !
Readme a book, wouldya, Da-da ?
[ Laughing ]
Zeus !
- [ Mimics Zeus ] "Once upon a time--"
- It's the truth !
Please !
# So you wanna be a hero, kid #
# Well, whoop-de-do #
# I have been around
the block before #
# With blockheads just like you #
# Each and every one
a disappointment #
# Pain for which
there ain't no ointment #
- [ Snickering ] Huh ?
- # So much for excuses
Though a kid ofZeus is #
# Askin' me to jump
into the fray #
# My answer is two words #
Okay.
- You mean you'll do it ?
- You win.
- You won't be sorry, Phil.
- Oh, gods.
- So when do we start? Can we start now?
- Oy, vay.
# I'd given up hope
that someone would come #
# Along #
# A fella who'd ring the bell
for once #
- # Not the gong #
- [ Gong ]
# The kind who wins trophies #
# Won't settle for low fees #
# At least semipro fees #
# But, no, I get the greenhorn #
# I've been out to pasture, pal
My ambition gone #
# Content to spend lazy days
and to graze my lawn #
# But you need an advisor #
# A satyr, but wiser #
# A good merchandiser and-- whoa #
# There goes my ulcer #
# I'm down to one last hope
and I hope it's you #
# Though, kid, you're not exactly
a dream come true #
# I trained enough turkeys #
- # Who never came through #
- Whoa !
# You're my one last hope
So you'll have to do #
[ Grunts ]
Rule no 6:
When rescuing a damsel,
[Shrill Whistle]
always handle with care.
- [ Grunts ]
- No !
- [ Sighs ]
- Rule no 95, kid.: Concentrate!
Rule no 96.:
Aim !
# Demigods have facedthe odds #
# And ended up a mockery #
# Don't believe the stories #
# That you read on all the crockery #
# To be a true hero, kid
is a dying art #
# Like paintin' a masterpiece #
- # It's a work of heart #
- [ Chuckles ]
# It takes more than sinew #
# Comes down to what's in you #
# You have to continue to grow #
Now, that's more like it !
# I'm down to one last shot #
# And my last high note #
# Before that blasted underworld
gets my goat #
# My dreams are on you, kid #
# Go make 'em come true #
# Climb that uphill slope #
# Keep pushin' that envelope #
# You're my one last hope #
# And, kid, it's up to you #
Yeah !
[Hercules Laughing]
- Did you see that ?
- [ Whinnying ]
- Next stop, Olympus.
- [ Bugles ]
All right, just take it easy, champ.
I am ready.
I want to get off this island.
I want to see battles and monsters.
- [ Falsetto ] Rescue some damsels.
- [ Whinnying Sigh ]
You know, heroic stuff.
- Well--
- Aw, come on ! Phil !
Well, okay. Okay, you want a road test?
Saddle up, kid.
- We're going to Thebes !
- Yahoo !
- [ Hercules ] So what's in Thebes ?
- A lot of problems.
It's a big, tough town.
Good place to start buildin' a rep.
- [Woman Screaming]
- [ Whinnying ]
- Sounds like your basic D.I.D.--
damsel in distress.
- Hyah !
- [ Gasping ]
- [ Evil Laughter ]
Not so fast, sweetheart.
I swear, Nessus.
Put me down or I'll--
Whoo ! I like 'em fiery !
- [ Gasps ]
- Now, remember, kid.
First, analyse the situation. Don't just
barrel in there without thinking. Eh ?
- [ Nessus Growling ]
- He's losin' points for this !
- You don't know what you're--
- Halt !
Step aside, two legs.
Pardon me, my good, uh, uh... sir.
- [ Grunts ]
- I'll have to askyou
to release that young...
- Keep movin', junior.
- lady.
But you-- Are-Aren't you...
a damsel in distress ?
I'm a damsel, [ Grunts ]
I'm in distress.
I can handle this.
Have a nice day.
Uh--
[ Clears Throat ]
Ma'am, I'm afraid you may be too close
to the situation to realize--
Ohhh ! What are you doin' ?
Get your sword !
Sword. Right, right. Rule no 15:
A hero is only as good as his weapon !
- [ Laughing ]
- [ Fish Shrieking ]
[ Groans ]
Whoa ! Hold it ! Hold on !
He's gotta do it on his own.
- Come on, kid! Concentrate!
Use your head!
- [ Whinnying ]
Oh.
[ Growling ]
Allright! Not bad, kid!
- [ Whistling ]
- Not exactly what I had in mind,
but not bad.
[ Groans, Coughs ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh, gee, miss, I'm, I'm really sorry.
- [ Sighs ] Oh.
- That was dumb.
- Yeah.
- [Splashing]
Excuse me.
Nice work !
Excelente!
Is Wonderboy here for real ?
What are you talkin' about ?
Of course he's real.
Whoa !
And by the way, sweet cheeks,
I'm real too.
- [ Kissing Sounds ]
- Ugh !
Yee-hah ! Yahoo !
Whoa !
[ Groans ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Puffs ]
[ Whistling ]
- How was that, Phil ?
- Rein it in, rookie.
You can get away with mistakes
like those in the minor decathlons,
but this is the big leagues !
[ Sighs ]
At least I beat him, didn't I ?
Next time, don't let your guard down
because ofa pair of big goo-goo eyes !
D-oh !
It's like I keep tellin 'ya.
You gotta stay focused,
and-- You--
[ Whinnying ]
[ Growling ]
- [ Snorting ]
- [ Bleating ]
Are you, uh, all right, Miss, uh--
Megara.
My friends call me Meg.
At least, they would
if I had any friends.
- So did they give you a name...
- [ Grunts ]
along with all those
rippling pectorals ?
[ Shy Chuckle ]
Uh, I'm, um, uh--
- [ Stammering ]
- Are you always this articulate ?
Hercules. My-- [ Clears Throat ]
My name is Hercules.
Hercules, huh.
I think I prefer Wonderboy.
So... uh, how-how-how'd you
get mixed up with the, uh--
Pinhead with hooves ?
Well, you know how men are.
They think that "no" means "yes," and
"get lost" means "Take me, I'm yours."
- [ Chuckles ]
- [ Confused Whinny ]
- Don't worry. Shorty here
can explain it to ya later.
- [ Growling ]
Well, thanks for everything, Herc.
It's been a real slice.
Wait !
Um... can we give you a ride ?
[ Snorting, Whinnying ]
Uh, I don't thinkyour pinto
likes me very much.
Pegasus ? Oh, no.
Don't be silly.
He'd be more than happy
to-- Ow !
- [ Whistling ]
- I'll be all right.
I'm a big, tough girl.
I tie my own sandals and everything.
Bye-bye, Wonderboy.
[ Quietly ]
Bye.
- She's... something. Isn't she, Phil ?
- [ Growls ]
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
She's really something.
A real pain in the patella !
Earth to Herc !
Come in, Herc ! Come in, Herc !
We got a job to do, remember ?
[ Whistles ]
- [ Whinnying ]
- Thebes is still waitin'.
[ Hercules ]
Yeah. Yeah. I know.
[Animals Tittering]
[ Gasps ]
Aw... how cute.
A couple of rodents
looking for a theme park.
Who you callin' a rodent, sister ?
- I'm a bunny !
- A-And I'm his gopher.
- [ Together ] Ta-dah !
- [ Sighing ] I thought I smelled a rat.
[Hades]
Meg ?
- Speak of the devil.
- Meg, my little flower, my little bird,
my little nut, Meg.
What exactly happened here ?
I thought you were gonna
persuade the river guardian
to join my team for the uprising,
and here I am,
kind of river guardian-less.
I gave it my best shot,
but he made me an offer I had to refuse.
Fine. So, instead of subtracting
two years from your sentence,
hey, I'm gonna add two on, okay ?
- Give that your best shot.
- It wasn't my fault.
It was this wonderboy, Hercules.
Hercules ?
Why does that name ring a bell ?
I don't know.
Um, maybe we owe him money ?
- What was that name again ?
- Hercules.
- [ Grunts ]
- He comes on with this big,
innocent farm boy routine,
but I could see through that
in a Peloponnesian minute.
Wait a minute. Wasn't Hercules the name
ofthat kid we were supposed to--
[ Together ]
Oh, my gods !
- Run for it !
- [ Screaming ]
So you took care of him, huh ?
Dead as a door nail.
Weren't those your exact words ?
This might be a different Hercules.
Yeah ! I mean, Hercules
is a very popular name nowadays !
Remember, like, a few years ago,
every other boy was named Jason,
and the girls
were all named Brittany ?
I'm about to rearrange the cosmos,
and the one schlemiel
who can louse it up...
is waltzing around in the woods !
- [ Panting ]
- Wait. Wait, big guy.
- We can still cut in on his waltzing.
- That's right !
And-and-and at least we made him mortal.
That's a good thing.
Didn't we ?
Hmm. Fortunately
for the three ofyou...
we still have time to correct
this rather egregious oversight.
- [ Both Groaning ]
- And this time, no foul-ups.
- [ Whinnying ]
- Wow !
- Is that all one town ?
- One town, a million troubles.
The one and only Thebes.
The Big Olive itself.
If you can make it there,
you can make it anywhere.
[ Crowd Bustling ]
[Bell Dings]
- [Whistle Blowing]
- Stick with me, kid.
This city is a dangerous place.
- Look where you're goin', numbskull !
- Hey, I'm walkin' here !
You see what I mean ?
I'm tellin' you-- wackos.
[Man] Pitta bread. Pitta bread.
Get your pitta bread here.
- Hey, Mack.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa !
You wanna buy a sundial ?
He's not interested, all right ?
Come on, kid.
The end is coming !
Can't you feel it ?
Yes, yes.
Thank you for the info. Yes.
We'll ponder that for a while.
Just stare at the sidewalk.
Come on.
Don't make eye contact.
People here are nuts. That's because
they live in a city of turmoil.
Trust me, kid. You're gonna be
just what the doctor ordered.
It was tragic !
We lost everything in the fire.
-Everything... except old Snowball here.
-[ Weak Meow ]
Now, were the fires
before or after the earthquake ?
- They were after the earthquake.
I remember.
- But before the flood.
Don't even get me started
on the crime rate.
[Heavy Woman] Thebes has certainly
gone downhill in a hurry.
[OldMan]
Tellme about it.
It seemslike everytime
lturn around,
there's some new monster
wreaking havoc and l--
All we need now is a plague of locusts.
- [ Chirping ]
- [ Crowd Screaming ]
- That's it ! I'm movin' to Sparta !
- [Hercules] Excuse me.
It, uh,
[ Clears Throat ]
seems to me that what
you folks need is a hero.
Yeah, and who are you ?
I'm Hercules, and, uh,
[ Loudly ]
I happen to be... a hero.
- [Crowd Laughing]
- Is that so ?
- [Woman Laughing] A hero !
- Have you ever saved a town before ?
Uh, no.
Uh, not exactly, but l--
Have you ever reversed
a natural disaster ?
- Well, uh... no.
- Oh, listen to this.
He's just another chariot chaser.
This we need.
- [ Woman ] That's a laugh.
- Don't you pea brains get it ?
- [ Woman ] Hmm ?
- This kid is the genuine article.
Hey, isn't that the goat-man
who trained Achilles ?
Watch it, pal.
Yeah, you're right.
Hey, nice job on those heels !
- Ya missed a spot! [Laughing]
- I got your heel right here !
I'll wipe that stupid grin
off your face ! You--
Hey, Phil! Phil! Phil!
Take it easy.
- Phil.
- What are you, crazy ? Sheesh.
Young man,
we need a professional hero,
not an amateur.
Well, wait. Stop !
[ Sighs ] How am I
supposed to prove myself a hero...
if nobody will give me a chance ?
You'll get your chance.
You just need some kind...
of catastrophe or disaster.
[Woman Panting]
Please.
Help ! Please !
There's been a terrible accident !
- Meg ?
- Speakin' of disasters.
Wonderboy ! Hercules !
- Thank goodness !
- Wha-What's wrong ?
[ Sighs ]
Outside of town, two little boys.
They were playing in the gorge.
There was this terrible rock slide.
- They're trapped!
- Kids ? Trapped ?
- Phil, this is great !
- You're really choked up
about this, aren't ya ?
- Come on !
- No, I-- You don't under--
I have this terrible fear of heights !
- [ Groans ]
- [ Snickers ]
- [ Panting ]
- [ Crowd Chattering ]
I'm right behind ya, kid !
Whoo !
[ Panting ]
I'm way behind ya, kid.
[ Sputtering ]
I got a fur wedgie.
- [ Whinnying ]
- [ Meg Gasping ]
- [ Trilling Whistle ]
- [ Groaning ]
- Are you okay ?
- I'll be fine.
- Just get me down before
I ruin the upholstery.
- [Boy no 1] Help !
- I can't breathe!
- [Boy no 2 Coughing] Hurry!
- Get us out!
- We're suffocating !
Somebody call IX-I-I!
[Coughing]
Easy, fellas.
You'll be all right.
- We can't last much longer !
- Get us out before we get crushed!
[ Grunting ]
[ Light Applause ]
- How you boys doin' ?
- We're okay now.
Jeepers, mister.
You're really strong.
Well, try to be a little more
careful next time, okay, kids ?
We sure will.
[Hades]
A stirring performance, boys.
I was really moved.
[ Slurping ]
"Jeepers, mister" ?
I was going for innocence.
And, hey, two thumbs way,
way up for our leading lady.
What a dish.
What a doll.
Get outta there, you big lug,
while you still can.
[ Panting ]
Phil, I did great.
They even applauded... sort of.
- [Growling]
- Huh ! I hate...
to burst your bubble, kid,
but that ain't applause.
[ Growling ]
Ph-Ph-Ph-Phil ?
What do you call that thing ?
- [Phil] Two words.:
- [ Thundering Roar ]
- Am-scray !
- [ Monster Hissing ]
- [ Crowd Screaming ]
- [ Echoing ] Let's get ready to rumble!
That's it.
Dance around ! Dance around !
- [ Roaring ]
- Watch the teeth. Watch the teeth.
Keep going. Come on. Come on.
Lead with your left.
Lead with your left! Your other left!
[ Monster Snarling ]
[ Roaring ]
[ Laughing ]
Whoa !
[ Yelling ]
- [ Swallows Hard ]
- [ Groaning ]
[ Loud Burp ]
- [ Groans ]
- [Crowd Muttering]
- [Woman Screaming]
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Roaring Continues ]
- [ Loud Applause ]
- All right ! All right !
- You're bad! Okay!
- See, Phil ?
- That-- That wasn't so hard.
- Kid, kid, kid.
- How many horns do ya see ?
- Six ?
Eh, close enough.
Let's get you cleaned up.
[Nervous Muttering]
- [ Gulps ]
- Guys, guys, relax.
It's only half-time.
[ Faint Rumbling ]
That doesn't sound good.
[ Roaring ]
- Definitely not good !
- [ Monster Hissing ]
[ Whistling ]
[ Yelling ]
Whoa ! Whoa !
Will you forget
the head-slicing thing ?
Hyah !
[ Yelling ]
Phil, I don't think we covered
this one in basic training !
[ Yelling ]
- [ Monster Hissing ]
- My favourite part of the game:
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Groaning ]
sudden death.
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Rock Creaking ]
[ All ]
Huh ?
[ Crowd Gasping ]
Oh ! There goes another one.
Just like Achilles.
Game...
set... match.
- [ Groans ] Huh ?
- [Rock Creaking]
[Crowd Gasping]
[ Cheering ]
Phil, you gotta admit.
- That was pretty heroic.
- Ya did it, kid !
Ya did it !
You won by a landslide !
[ Straining ]
- Hades mad.
- [ Yelling ]
Well, what do ya know ?
From that day forward,
our boy Hercules could do no wrong.
He was so hot, steam looked cool.
# Oh, yeah #
# Bless my soul
Herc was on a roll #
# Person ofthe week
in every Greek opinion poll #
- # What a pro #
- # Herc could stop a show #
# Point him at a monster
and you're talkin' S.R.O. #
- # He was a no one #
- # A zero, zero #
- # No whe's a honcho #
- # He's a hero #
# Here was a kid
with his act down pat #
# Zero to hero in no time flat #
- # Zero to hero #
- # Just like that # [ Snaps ]
# When he smiled
the girls went wild #
# With oohs and aahs #
# And they slapped his face
on every vase #
# On every "vahse" #
# From appearance fees and royalties #
# Our Herc had cash to burn #
# Now nouveau riche and famous #
# He could tell you
what's a Grecian urn #
# Say amen, there he goes again #
- # Sweet and undefeated #
- # And an awesome ten for ten #
# Folks lined up
just to watch him flex #
# And this perfect package
packed a pair of pretty pecs #
# Hercie, he comes
he sees, he conquers #
# Honey, the crowds
were goin' bonkers #
- # He showed the moxie
brains and spunk #
- # Yeah #
- # From zero to hero #
- # A major hunk #
- # Zero to hero #
- # And who'd have thunk #
# Who put the glad in gladiator #
# Hercules #
- # Who's darin' deeds
are great theatre #
- # Hercules #
- # Isn't he bold #
- # No one braver #
- # Is he sweet #
- # Our favourite flavour #
- # Hercules #
- My man.
- # Ooh #
- # Hercules #
- # Look at my Hercules #
- # Hercules, Hercules #
- # Yeah, yeah, yeah #
# Bless my soul
Herc was on a roll #
- # Undefeated #
- # Riding high #
- And the nicest guy.
- # Not conceited #
- # He was a nothing #
- # Zero, zero #
- # Now he's a honcho #
- # He's our hero #
# He hit the heights
at break-neck-speed #
- # From zero to hero #
- [ Grunting ]
# Herc is a hero #
# Now he's a hero #
# Yes, indeed #
[ Grunting, Panting ]
Pull !
Nice shootin', Rex.
I can't believe this guy.
I throw everything I've got at him...
- and it doesn't even--
- [Rubber Squeaking]
What are... those ?
Um, I don't know.
I-I thought they looked kinda dashing.
I've got 24 hours
to get rid of this bozo,
or the entire scheme I've been setting
up for 18 years goes up in smoke,
and you are wearing
his merchandise!
[Slurping]
[ Chuckles ]
Thirsty ?
[ Yell Echoing ]
[ Both Groaning ]
[ Chuckles ]
Looks like your game's over.
Wonderboy is hitting
every curve you throw at him.
Oh, yeah.
[ Chuckles ]
I wonder if maybe
I haven't been throwing...
the right curves at him,
Meg, my sweet.
Don't even go there.
See, he's gotta have a weakness...
because everybody's got a weakness.
I mean, for what ?
Pandora, it was the box thing.
For the Trojans, hey.
They bet on the wrong horse, okay ?
-We simply need to find out Wonderboy's.
-I've done my part.
- Get your little imps--
- They couldn't handle him as a baby.
I need somebody who can...
handle him as a man.
Hey, I've sworn off manhandling.
That's good because that's what got you
into this jam in the first place.
You sold your soul to me
to save your boyfriend's life.
And how does this creep thank you ?
By running off with some babe.
He hurt you real bad,
didn't he, Meg ? Huh ?
Look, I learned my lesson, okay ?
Which is exactly why I got a feelin'...
you're gonna leap at my new offer.
You give me the key
to bringing down Wonder Breath,
and I give you the thing
that you crave most...
in the entire cosmos:
- your freedom.
- [Urn Shatters]
[Hercules Laughing]
You should have been there, Father.
I mangled the Minotaur,
grappled with the Gorgon.
Just like Phil told me.
I analysed the situation,
controlled my strength and kicked.
The crowds went wild !
- [ Simulates Crowd Cheering ]
- [ Whistling ]
- Thank you. Thank you.
- Hah !
You're doin' great, son.
You're doing your old man proud.
I'm glad to hear you say that, Father.
I've been waiting
for this day a long time.
Hmm.
What day is that, son ?
The day I rejoin the gods.
You've done wonderfully.
You really have, my boy.
You're just not there yet.
You haven't proven yourself a true hero.
But, Father, I've beaten every single
monster I've come up against.
I'm-I'm the most famous person
in all of Greece.
- I'm-I'm an action figure !
- [ Squeaking ]
I'm afraid being famous
isn't the same...
as being a true hero.
What more can I do ?
It's something
you have to discover for yourself.
- But how can I--
- Look inside your heart.
Father, wait !
[ Grunting ]
- [ Whinnying ]
- [ Sighs ]
On your left is Hercules' villa.
Our next stop is the Pecs
and Flex Gift Shop...
where you can pick up the great hero's
30-minute workout scroll...
"Buns of Bronze. "
At 1:00, you got a meeting
with King Augeas.
He's got a problem with his stables. I'd
advise you not to wear your new sandals.
- Phil ?
- I told you, don't move !
[Phil]...D.G.R,
the Daughters of the Greek Revolution.
- Phil.
- At 3:00, you got ta get a girdle
from some Amazons.
Phil, what's the point ?
[ Screaming ]
That's it !
Keep your toga on, pal.
[ Grunts ]
Yuck ! What d'you mean,
"What's the point?"
You wanna go to Olympus, don't ya ?
Yeah, but this stuff doesn't
seem to be getting me anywhere.
You can't give up now.
I'm countin' on ya.
I gave this everything I had.
Listen to me, kid.
I seen 'em all.
And I am tellin' you--
and this is the honest-to-Zeus truth--
- you got somethin' I never seen before.
- Really ?
I can feel it right down
to these stubby bowlegs of mine.
There is nothin' you can't do, kid.
- [Door Opening, Girls Screaming]
- It's him !
Hey, watch it !
Watch it ! Watch--
- I touched his elbow !
- I got his sweatband !
- [ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Grunting ] Phil, help !
- Okay. Escape plan: beta.
- Gotcha.
- [ Blowing Whistle ]
- Hey. Where is he ?
- There he goes ! On the veranda !
- [Screaming]
Whoa !
[ Chuckles ]
- Let's see. What could be
behind curtain number one ?
- Meg !
[ Chuckles ] It's all right.
The sea of raging hormones has ebbed.
Gee, i-i-it's great to see you.
I-I-I missed you.
So this is what heroes do
on their days off.
[ Bashful Chuckle ]
I'm no hero.
Sure ya are.
Everybody in Greece...
thinks you're the greatest thing
since they put the pocket in pitta.
[ Chuckles ]
I know. It's-It's crazy.
You know, I can't go anywhere
without being mobbed.
- I mean--
- Ah. You sound like
you could use a break.
- Think your nanny goat would go...
- [ Bleating Squeak ]
- berserk if you played hooky
this afternoon?
- Oh, gee.
I-I don't know. Uh, Phil's got
the rest ofthe day pretty much booked.
Ah, Phil, schmill.
Just follow me.
Out the window, round the dumbbells, you
lift up the back wall and we're gone.
[ Chirping ]
[Laughter]
[Hercules]
Wow. What a day.
- First, that restaurant by the bay,
- [Meg] Mmm.
and then that, that play,
that, that Oedipus thing.
Man !
I thought I had problems.
- [ Laughing, Clears Throat ]
- [Laughing]
- Psst! Stop foolin 'around!
- Yeah. Get the goods, sister.
- I didn't know that playing hooky
could be so much fun.
- [ Humming, Tweeting ]
- Yeah. Neither did I.
- Thanks, Meg.
Oh. [ Chuckles ]
Don't thank mejust yet.
- Oh !
- Oop. Careful.
Sorry. Weak ankles.
Oh, yeah ? Well, maybe you
better sit down for a while.
So, uh, do you have any problems...
with things like this ?
- Uh--
- Weak ankles, I mean.
Oh. Uh, no. Not really.
No weaknesses... whatsoever ?
- No trick knee ?
- Uh--
Ruptured... disks ?
[ Nervous Chuckle, Gulps ]
No. I'm, I'm afraid
I'm, uh... fit as a fiddle.
[ Sighs ]
Wonderboy, you are perfect.
[ Chuckles ]
Thanks.
- [Crashing, Splashing]
- Whoops.
It looks better that way.
No, it really does.
[ Sighing ]
You know, when I was a kid...
I, I would have given anything
to be exactly like everybody else.
[ Scoffs ]
You wanted to be petty and dishonest ?
Everybody's not like that.
- Yes, they are.
- You're not like that.
- How do you know what I'm like ?
- All I know is...
you're the most amazing person with...
weak ankles I've ever met.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh !
Meg, when I'm with you...
I-I don't feel so... alone.
- Sometimes it's better to be alone.
- What do you mean ?
Nobody can hurt you.
Meg ? I would never,
ever hurt you.
And I don't wanna hurt you, so...
let's both do ourselves a favour and...
stop this, um,
before... we--
[Phil] All right! Break it up !
Break it up ! Party's over!
- I been lookin' all over this town !
- Calm down, mutton man.
- It was all my fault.
- You're already on my list, sister,
so don't make it worse !
- [ Snorting ]
- [ Snorts Back ]
And as for you, ya bum,
you're gonna go to the stadium...
and you're gonna be put through
the workout ofyour life !
- Now get on the horse.
- Okay, okay.
- I'm sorry.
- Ah, he'll get over it.
[Phil] Move !
Move, move, move, move, move ! Move !
- [ Neighing ]
- Whoo ! Ya-eee !
Hey, watch it, watch it !
Whoo ! Watch it !
Keep your goo-goo eyes on the--
That's it.
Next time, I drive.
Oh, what's the matter with me ?
You'd think a girl would learn.
# If there's a prize
for rotten judgement #
# I guess I've already won that #
# No man is worth the aggravation #
# That's ancient history
Been there, done that #
# Who d'ya think you're kidding
He's the Earth and heaven to you #
# Try to keep it hidden
Honey, we can see right through you #
- # Oh, no #
- # Girl, you can't conceal it #
# We know how you feel
and who you're thinkin' of #
# Oh-ho, no chance, no way
I won't say it, no, no #
# You swoon, you sigh
Why deny it, uh-oh #
# It's too cliche
I won't say I'm in love #
# Shoo-doo, shoo-doo #
Oo-oo-oo #
# I thought my heart
had learned its lesson #
# It feels so good
when you start out #
- # Ah #
- # My headis screaming
Get agrip, girl #
# Unless you're dyin' #
- # To cry your heart out, oh #
- # You keep on denying #
# Who you are and how you're feelin' #
# Baby, we're not buyin'
Hon, we saw you hit the ceilin' #
- # Face it like agrown-up
when you gonna own up that you #
- # Got #
- # Got it bad #
# Oh, no chance, no way
I won't say it, no, no #
- # Give up, but give in
- # Check the grin, you're in love #
# This scene won't play
I won't say I'm in love #
# You're doing flips
Read our lips #
- # You're in love, shoo-doo, shoo-doo #
- # You're way off base #
- # I won't say I'm it #
- # She won't say in love #
# Get off my case
I won't say it #
# Girl, don't be proud
It's okay, you're in love #
# Oh #
# At least out loud #
# I won't say I'm in #
- # Love #
- # Shoo-doo, shoo-doo
shoo-doo, shoo-doo #
# Sha-la-la-la-la-la-la #
# Haaa #
Hey, what's the buzz, huh, Meg ?
What is the weak link
in Wonderboy's chain ?
Get yourself another girl.
I'm through.
I'm sorry. Do you mind
runnin' that by me again ?
I must have had a chunk of brimstone
wedged in my ear or something.
Then read my lips !
Forget it.
Meg, Meg, Meg,
my sweet deluded little minion.
Aren't we forgetting
one teensy-weensy, but ever so
crucial little, tiny detail ?
I own you !
- [ Groaning ]
Oh, I got another horn here.
- You work for me.
That kid's gonna be
doin' laps for a month.
If I say "sing," you say,
"Hey, name that tune. "
If I say,
"l want Wonderboy's head on a platter, "
- you say--
- Medium or well-done.
- Oh ! I knew that dame was trouble.
- [Hades Chattering]
This is gonna break the kid's heart.
- [Meg] I'll work on that.
- I'm sorry. You hear that sound?
That's the sound of your freedom...
- fluttering out the window forever.
- [ Coughing ]
I don't care.
I'm not gonna help you hurt him.
[ Sighs ] I can't believe you're
getting so worked up about some guy.
This one is different.
He's honest, and-and he's sweet--
- Please !
- He would never do anything to hurt me.
-He's a guy !
-Besides, O oneness, you can't beat him.
He has no weaknesses.
He's gonna--
I think... he does, Meg.
I truly think... he does.
[ Hercules Grunting, Straining ]
Ha-ha !
- [ Sighing ]
- [Grunting, Straining] Whoo-hoo !
Hey, Phil!
What happened to you ?
Kid, we gotta talk.
[ Screaming ]
Oh, Phil, I just had
the greatest day of my life !
I-I, I can't stop thinking about Meg.
[ Sighing ]
She's something else.
Kid, I'm tryin' to talk to ya !
Will you come down here and listen ?
Aw, how can I come down there
when I'm feeling so up ?
[Whistling]
[ Clears Throat, Clicks Tongue ]
Gotcha !
Ah, very nice !
What I'm tryin' to say is--
That if it wasn't for you,
I never would have met her.
Oh, I owe ya big time.
Will you just knock it off
for a couple of seconds ?
Rule no 38. Come on, Phil.
Keep them up there, huh ?
- Phil, I got two words for ya: duck !
- Listen to me ! She's--
- A dream come true ?
- Not exactly.
- More beautiful than Aphrodite ?
- Aside from that !
- The most wonderful--
- She's a fraud !
She's been playin' ya for a sap !
- Aw, come on. Stop kiddin' around.
- I'm not kiddin' around.
- I know you're upset about today,
but that's no reason to--
- Kid, you're missin' the point.
- The point is, I love her.
- She don't love you.
- You're crazy.
- She's nothin' but a two-timin',
- Stop it !
- no-good, lyin', schemin'--
Shut up !
Phil. I--
Oh, I'm, I'm sorry.
Okay, okay, that's it.
You won't face the truth ? Fine.
Phil, wait. Where you going ?
I'm hoppin' the first barge out of here.
I'm goin' home.
Fine ! G--
Go ! I don't--
I don't need you.
I thought you were gonna be
the all-time champ,
not the all-time chump.
[Hades] Geez Louise!
What got his goat, huh ?
Baboom.
Name is Hades, Lord of the Dead.
- Hi. How ya doin' ?
- Not now, okay ?
Hey, hey. I only need a few seconds
and I'm a fast talker, all right ?
I've got the major deal in the works.
A real estate venture, ifyou will.
And Herc, you little devil you.
May I call you Herc ?
- You seem to be constantly
getting in the way of it.
- You've got the wrong guy.
Hear me out, ya little-- Heh-heh.
Just hear me out, okay ?
So I would be eternally grateful
if you would just...
take a day off
from this hero business of yours.
I mean, monsters, natural disasters.
Phew. You wait a day, okay ?
- You're out of your mind.
- Not so fast, because, ya see,
I do have a little leverage...
you might wanna know about.
- Meg !
- Don't listen, Herc-- [ Grunting ]
- Let her go !
- Here's the trade-off.
You give up your strength
for about 24 hours, okay ?
Say the next 24 hours.
And Meg here is free as a bird
and safe from harm.
We dance, we kiss, we schmooze,
we carry on, we go home happy.
What d'ya say ? Come on.
People are, are gonna get hurt,
aren't they ?
Nah ! I mean, it's a possibility.
It happens 'cause, you know, it's war.
But what can I tell ya ?
Anyway, what do you owe these people ?
Isn't Meg-- little smoochy face--
isn't she more important than they are ?
- Stop it !
- Isn't she ?
You've gotta swear
she'll be safe from any harm.
Fine, okay.
I'll give you that one.
Meg is safe, otherwise you get
your strength right back. Yadda, yadda.
Fine print. Boilerplate. Okay ? Done.
What d'ya say we shake on it ?
Hey, I really don't have, like,
time to bat this around.
I'm kind ofon a schedule here.
I got plans for August. Okay ?
I need an answer, like, now.
- Going once, going twice--
- [ Mumbling ]
- All right !
- Yes, we're there ! Bam !
[ Groaning ]
You may feel just a little queasy.
It's kinda natural.
Maybe you should sit down !
- [ Grunting ]
- Now you know how it feels
to be just like everybody else.
Isn't it just peachy ?
Oh ! [ Chuckles ]
You'll love this. One more thing.
Meg, babe, a deal's a deal.
You're off the hook.
Andby the way, Herc,
- is she not a fabulous little actress ?
- Stop it.
- What do you mean ?
- I mean your little chickie-poo here...
was working for me all the time.
- Duh.
- You're-- You're lying !
Help !
[ Coughing ]
Jeepers, mister,
you're really strong. Ha-ha !
- Couldn't have done it without you,
sugar, sweetheart, babe.
- No ! It's not like that.
I didn't mean to--
I-I couldn't-- I--
I'm so sorry.
[ Pain And Panic ]
Our hero's a zero ! Our hero's a zero !
[Laughing]
Well, gotta blaze.
There's a whole cosmos up there
waiting for me with, hey, my name on it.
[Laughter Continues]
So much for the preliminaries,
and now on to the main event !
[Howling]
Brothers ! Titans !
- Look at you in your squalid prison !
- [ Squealing ]
- Who put you down there ?
- [ Titans ] Zeus !
And now that I set you free,
what is the first thing
you are going to do ?
- [ Titans ] Destroy him !
- Good answer.
Crush Zeus !
Freeze him !
Melt Zeus !
Blow... him...
away !
[ Bleating ]
[ All ]
Zeus !
- [Hades] Uh, guys ?
- Huh ?
Olympus would be that way.
- Zeus !
- Freeze him !
- Hold it, bright eye.
- Huh ?
I have a special job for you,
my optic friend.
[Rumbling]
- [Rock Titan Yelling]
- Ah. Huh ?
Destroy Zeus !
Oh, we're in trouble !
Oh, big trouble ! I gotta--
My lord and lady,
the Titans have escaped,
and they're practically
at our gates !
Sound the alarm !
Launch an immediate counterattack !
- Go ! Go !
- Gone, babe.
- # [ Trumpet ]
- Huh ?
- Charge !
- Yah !
- On to battle !
- [ Shouting ]
Ee-yah !
- You windbag !
- [ Shouting ]
Boom, badda-boom, boom, boom !
Hah !
[ People Screaming ]
[Cyclops]
Hercules !
Where are you ?
[ Roaring ]
What can we do ?
- Where is Hercules ?
- Yeah, Hercules'll save us.
Hercules ! Come out !
Face me!
What are you doing ?
Without your strength, you'll be killed.
- There are worse things.
- Run !
Wait ! Stop !
- Hey, look ! It's Hercules.
- Thank the gods !
- We're saved !
- [ Cyclops ] So.
You mighty Hercules.
[ Laughing ]
- [ Roaring ]
- [ Grunts ]
- Oh !
- [ Groaning ]
- [Pegasus Whinnying]
- [Laughing Continues]
- [ Whinnying Continues ]
- Easy, horsefeathers.
Whoa ! Stop twitching. Listen.
Ah ! Hercules is in trouble.
We've gotta find Phil. He's the only one
who can talk some sense into him.
- [ Pegasus Whinnying ]
- [ Meg Yelling ]
Get back, blast you !
[ Roaring ]
- Ooh, chihuahua.
- Zeus !
Come on ! Hurry up !
We're shovin' off here !
- Phil !
- [ Whinnying ]
- Phil, Hercules needs your help !
- What does he need me for
when he's got friends like you ?
- He won't listen to me.
- Good ! He's finally learned something.
Look, I know what I did was wrong,
but this isn't about me.
It's about him. If you don't
help him now, Phil, he'll die.
- I need more thunderbolts !
- Hephaestus has been captured, my lord.
Everyone's been captured.
Yah ! I've been captured !
Hey, hey !
Watch the glasses.
Zeusy, I'm home !
Hades.
You're behind this !
- You are correct, sir !
- [ Groaning ]
[ Laughing ]
Flea.
- Hercules !
- Phil.
Come on, kid. Come on.
Fight back.
Come on, you can take this bum.
This guy's a pushover. Look at him.
You were right all along, Phil.
- Dreams are for rookies.
- No, no, no, no, kid.
Givin' up is for rookies. I came back
'cause I'm not quittin' on ya.
- I'm willing to go the distance.
How 'bout you ?
- [Cyclops Approaching]
[ Laughing ]
Me bite off head !
[ Screaming ]
- Whoa, baby !
- [ Yelling ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Hercules ! Look out !
Meg ! No !
[ Grunting ]
- What's happening ?
- [ Groaning ]
H-Hades' deal is broken.
He promised I wouldn't get hurt.
Meg.
Why, why did you--
You didn't have to--
Oh. People always do crazy things...
[ Groans ]
when they're in love.
Oh, Meg.
Meg, I-- I--
Are you... always this articulate ?
[ Chuckles ]
You, you haven't got much time.
You can still stop Hades.
I'll watch over her, kid.
You're gonna be all right.
I promise.
[ Whinnying ]
Let's go, Pegasus !
Hup, two, three, four.
Come on, everybody !
- I can't hear you !
- Oh, oh !
I swear to you, Hades,
when I get out of this--
I'm the one giving orders now,
bolt boy.
And I think I'm gonna like it here.
[Hercules]
Don't get too comfortable, Hades !
- [ Whinnying ]
- Hercules !
This oughta even the odds !
- Yeah, Hercules ! Thank you, man.
- Get them !
Whoa ! Hey !
No ! Get him ! Not me ! Him !
Follow the fingers ! Him !
The yutz with the horse.
- [ Screaming ]
- Thank you, my boy.
Nice horsey ! My intentions were pure !
I really was attracted to you.
[ Both Yelling ]
Throw !
Hah !
Now watch your old man work !
- Uh-oh.
Guys, get your
titanic rears in gear...
and kick some Olympian butt !
- Whoa, is my hair out ?
- [ Snickering ]
- Hah ! [ Laughing ]
- Whoo-hoo !
Thanks a ton, Wonderboy. But at least
I've got one swell consolation prize--
a friend of yours
who's dying to see me.
- [ Whinnies ]
- Meg.
Meg.
[ Crying ]
Meg, no.
[ Mournful Neighing ]
Oh, I'm sorry, kid.
[ Sighs ] There's some things
you just can't change.
Yes, I can.
[Hades Yelling]
We were so close!
So close. We tripped
at the finish line. Why ?
Because our little nut, Meg,
has to go all noble.
[Rumbling]
- Where's Meg ?
- Oh. Look who's here.
Wonderboy, you are too much.
- Let her go.
- Get a grip.
Come here, come here.
Let me show you around.
Hmph. Well, well.
It's a small underworld after all. Huh ?
Meg ! Ahhh !
No, no, no.
Mustn't touch.
You see, Meg's
running with a new crowd these days.
And not a very lively one, at that.
You like making deals.
Take me in Meg's place.
Oh, well. The son of my hated rival
trapped forever in a river of death.
- Going once.
- Hmm. Is there a downside to this ?
- Going twice !
- Okay, okay, okay, okay.
You get her out.
She goes; you stay.
You know what slipped my mind ? You'll
be dead before you can get to her.
That's not a problem, is it ?
Oh !
What's the matter
with these scissors ?
The thread won't cut.
This is-- This is impossible !
You, you, you can't be alive !
You'd have to be a, a--
- A god ?
[ Yelling ]
Hercules, stop !
You can't do this to me. You can't--
[ Muffled ]
Fine. Okay. Listen.
Hah ! Okay. Well, I deserved that.
Herc, Herc, Herc.
Can we talk ?
Y-Your dad, he's a fun guy, right ?
So maybe you could
put in a word with him,
and he'd kinda blow this
whole thing off, you know ?
Meg, Meg, talk to him.
A little schmooze--
[ Screaming ]
Eew ! Get away from me !
Don't touch me !
Get your slimy souls off me !
- Ooh, ah--
- He's not gonna be happy
when he gets outta there.
You mean, if he gets outta there.
- If. If is good.
- Taxi!
I don't feel so good.
I feel a little-- [ Screaming ]
[ Sighing ]
Wonderboy, what--
Why did you--
[ Chuckles ]
People always do crazy things...
when they're in love.
Whoa ! Hey, hey, hey !
Whoo !
[ Cheering, Applauding ]
Three cheers for the mighty Hercules !
Oh, yeah !
Flowers for everybody ! Oh !
[ Applause, Cheering Continue ]
Hercules, we're so proud of you.
Mother.
Hah !
Fine work, my boy !
You've done it !
You're a true hero.
You were willing to give your life
to rescue this young woman.
For a true hero isn't measured
by the size of his strength,
but by the strength of his heart.
Now, at last, my son,
you can come home.
[ Cheering ]
Congratulations, Wonderboy.
You'll make one heck of a god.
[ Cheering Continues ]
Father, this is the moment
I've always dreamed of.
But...
a life without Meg,
even an immortal life,
would be... empty.
I--
I wish to stay on Earth with her.
I finally know where I belong.
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- Hit it, ladies !
- # Oh, gonna shout it
from the mountaintops #
- # A star is born #
- # It's the time for
pulling out the stops #
- # A star is born #
- # Honey, hit us with a hallelu #
- # That kid came shining through #
- # Girl, sing the song #
- Ooh. Whoa !
- # Come blow your horn #
- # A star is born #
- # He's a hero
who can please the crowd #
- # A star is born #
# Come on, everybody shout out loud
A star is born #
# Just remember in the darkest hour
within your heart's the power #
# For makin' you a hero too #
# So don't lose hope
when you're forlorn #
- That's Phil's boy !
- # Just keep your eyes upon the skies #
# Everynight, a star is
Right in sight, a star is #
- # Burning bright, a star is born #
- # A star is born #
[Hades]
What d'ya say ? It's happy ending time!
Everybody's got a little taste
of somethin' but me. I got nothin'.
I'm here with nothin'.
Anybody listenin' ?
It's like I'm--
What am I, an echo or something ?
Hello ? Hello ?
Am I talking to, what ?
Hyperspace ? Hello, it's me.
Nobody listens.
DivX subtitles - Luke_S