CHINA 859 A.D.
After 241 years of prosperity,
the Tang Dynasty is in decline.
The Emperor is weak and incompetent.
His government, crippled by corruption,
no longer controls the land.
Unrest sweeps the country.
Village by village,
an underground alliance forms...
'The House of Flying Daggers'.
Based in Feng Tian County,
near the Imperial Capital,
The House Of Flying Daggers
moves in the shadows,
Stealing From the rich
to give to the poor,
they earn the support and
admiration of the people.
At the same time, they
are feared and hated
by their bitter rivals...
the local deputies,
Captain Leo, Captain Jin.
We're heading out on patrol.
We're going to be busy again.
The Provincial Office
has given us ten days
to catch the new leader
of the 'Flying Daggers'.
What?
It took us three months to assassinate
their old leader.
Ten days? Impossible.
Have you heard of the
new Peony Pavilion?
Yes.
Does anyone know you there?
No, I haven't been there yet.
Good, now's your chance.
Any information?
We suspect one of the showgirls
is a member of the 'Flying Daggers'.
OK, I'll check it out.
Pull. Pull harder.
Pull harder.
That's it. I'm done.
Madam!
I'm coming.
Madam.
Here I am.
What can I do for you, sir?
I heard you have a new girl.
You're well informed.
Is she pretty?
She's quite a beauty.
Bring her to me.
There is one thing you need to know.
What's that?
The girl is blind.
Blind?
Then she must be special.
I'm curious.
How did you lose your sight?
I was born blind.
Why would a blind girl work here?
Why can't a blind girl work here?
You're right.
What's your name?
Mei.
Mei?
Every girl here is named after a flower.
Why is yours so plain?
I don't want to compete
with those girls.
What do you mean?
The flowers here can
hardly be called flowers.
Real flowers bloom in the wilderness.
Well said.
If you impress me
I'll take you to where
the real flowers grow.
What's your talent as the top showgirl?
Dancing.
Come closer.
Don't you know the rules?
A rare beauty in the North.
She's the finest lady on earth.
A glance from her, the
whole city goes down.
A second glance leaves
the nation in ruins.
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty like this.
A rare beauty in the North.
She's the finest lady on earth.
A glance from her, the
whole city goes down.
A second glance leaves
the nation in ruins.
There exists no city or nation
that has been more cherished
than a beauty like this.
Please calm down, sir.
Go away.
What's the matter?
Please let me explain.
This girl is young and inexperienced.
Please forgive her.
Take her away.
Go away.
Stop!
Captain.
This is the Captain of the County.
To hell with the captain!
Outrageous! Arrest him.
Let me go.
Who are you?
How dare you! I'm the captain.
You're drunk and indecently dressed.
Arrest both of them.
Get your hands off me.
Let me go.
Please spare the girl, Captain.
That man was drunk.
It was not her fault.
Please don't arrest her.
Our business is new.
I rely on her to bring in guests.
How can a blind girl
be a top showgirl? Move!
She's a dancer with rare skills.
Please see for yourself.
Do you know the 'Echo Game'?
I played it once...
All right.
Perform well and I'll let you go.
Thank you, Captain.
Go and change quickly.
Fantastic.
Excellent!
Who are you, really?
Why do you want to kill me?
Government running dogs...
I wish to kill all of you!
I do enjoy fighting a blind girl.
We found this in her room.
You're a member of the 'Flying Daggers'.
Who's the new leader?
Where's the new leader?
I'll show you
what we'll do if you don't answer.
Show her!
In front of you is a torture device.
Your head will be put here.
Your shoulder, here.
Your back, here.
Your legs, here.
You'll never dance again after this.
Do you understand?
You have one day to think it over.
This girl reminds me of someone.
Who?
Rumor has it,
the old leader's blind daughter
disappeared after his death.
It was a heavy blow to
the 'Flying Daggers'.
They vowed revenge for their loss,
while searching for the girl.
Why would the old leader's daughter
end up in a brothel?
Who owns the Peony Pavilion?
Perhaps the 'Flying
Daggers' has realized
we were responsible for
their old leader's death.
Forget it.
Let's turn her over for a reward,
and then go out for a drink.
I have a better idea.
Since we have some clues,
let's follow them through
for a bigger reward.
Do you want me to do it?
Of course, who else?
All right. This girl is a rare beauty.
You know I love flirting with girls.
Don't let beauty blind your judgment.
If I die under a skirt, I
can still flirt as a ghost.
Who are you?
I undressed you only yesterday.
Have you forgotten me already?
Why did you rescue me?
Why do you think?
You're an exquisite flower.
I'll do anything to help you.
Control yourself.
Don't worry.
I'm no longer a guest
of the Peony Pavilion.
You're not a showgirl anymore.
You're the daughter of the old leader.
What did you say?
How many blind girls know martial arts
and carry daggers like these?
I've rescued you,
and your daggers as well.
Why did you take such a risk?
I hate the corrupt government
and admire the 'Flying Daggers'.
Much obliged.
Why did we abandon the horses?
Hoof prints can be easily tracked.
I have two new horses hidden ahead.
You've planned well.
What's your name, Master?
Just call me Wind.
Wind?
I wander around all alone,
come and go without a trace.
Like a carefree wind?
No, a playful wind.
You like to tease.
I wonder what you look like?
That's easy to find out.
Here.
Please let go.
This isn't the Peony
Pavilion. No rules here.
You'll know what I look
like if you touch my face.
Come on.
It's not respectful to
touch your face first.
You prefer to start at the bottom.
That's fine with me.
You've mastered the flying technique.
Your right hand is
skilled with a machete.
Your left hand is powerful
with a bow and arrow.
Your heart beats
steadily, you seem sincere.
You can read me like a book.
You're a brave man.
I'm never shy around women.
You're young, indeed.
You know how to hold your drink.
The soldiers are approaching.
I've lost my dagger pouch.
I'm sorry I was late.
The 'Flying Daggers' are always moving.
Where should we go?
We just keep heading north.
Just head north?
They will come to us.
The 'Flying Daggers' has many masters.
Why did they send you as an assassin?
No one sent me. I came alone.
As the old leader's daughter,
you should be more cautious.
Have you considered the consequences?
I'll do anything to avenge my father.
Come here.
These are men's clothes.
Put them on for now.
I won't take advantage of you.
Have you seen enough?
Please hand me the clothes.
You knew I was here?
Master Wind wanders like the wind.
I'd expect you to be anywhere.
You look different in men's clothes.
Do I look awful?
I will tell all the girls
to wear men's clothes
the next time I visit
the Peony Pavilion.
Now I know
you're not shy around women.
You're not shy either.
How do you know?
You knew I was watching you bathe,
yet you said nothing.
You saved my life.
You can look all you please.
I thought you were hot as fire.
In fact, you're cool as water.
I don't know you well enough.
I really care for you.
A playboy like you,
are you ever for real?
What if I am this time?
Are our men close by?
I'm sure today's
fighting has fooled Mei.
Our men will ease off from now on.
Good. That'll save me some arrows.
Any clues?
Not yet.
Don't let her see through you.
Don't worry. I never
fail at seducing a woman.
She trusts me.
I warn you, don't fall for her.
What do you mean fall?
Fall into bed?
Like her father, she
must be very cunning.
Don't let her fool you.
Don't be absurd.
I'm in control.
I have to get back now.
Don't turn a game into
reality and ruin our plan.
Who cares, as long as the plan works.
Shall we rest for a while?
I smell flowers.
You told me
you'd bring me to
where real flowers grow.
Which is the most beautiful?
How do I look?
Pretty as a flower.
Soldiers are approaching.
I'm on your side.
You?
I am a Captain of the County.
A captain?
Nonsense. You are the
bastard who broke the jail.
You're wounded. Is it serious?
No.
Was it someone from
the 'Flying Daggers'?
It's not likely.
Then who?
I don't know.
He's gone.
I guess he doesn't
want to reveal himself.
This time, I believe
that you're for real.