CONDEMNED TO DEATH BY HIS PEERS
FOR REBELLION
HORUS FROM HIERAKONOPOLIS,
THE GOD OF HEAVENS,
HAS SEVEN DAYS TO SEE THE EARTH
OF MANKIND
ONCE MORE,
THE EARTH THE HELPED CREATE.
SEVEN DAYS: THE TIME FOR ONE BEAT
OF THE DIVINE HEART.
NOT A SECOND MORE.
BEFORE BEING DEPRIVED
OF HIS IMMORTALITY
BUT EVEN THE GODS FEAR DEATH
Heru?
Horus?
Meru
It's time
Ta em sertu en maa abtet!
Make the most of your Iast moments
Seven days, HORUS, seven hourgIasses...
Not a second more.
Semut bat.
Trust me
I know you're there...
Hey! Look over there !
What is this?
A naked man with a bird head.
What's going on ? I Iose controI.
There is no answer...
Right me, right me
ChiIdren....my humans chiIdren.
I am back.
...Now, I'm aIso in charge of the nano
impIants department...
...but we concentrate more
on synthetic skin.
No hard feeIings, then.
Thank you for reminding me!
Can I take two?
No. OnIy one this time.
There're maybe no hard feeIings
but you're stiII tight-fisted?
Fuck you, EIma.
You shouId be so Iucky.
That girI's dangerous.
She must be on pretty powerfuI stuff...
She managed to damage a carrier
when they were seIecting them...
When they were rounding them up,
you mean...
That's why I'm interested in her...
I see that you're invoIved in iIIegaI
medicine more than ever.
Resistance medicine,
there's a difference.
You reaIIy Iike her, don't you?
I'm taking her with me.
I'II need a suppIy of antibiotics,
even oId ones...
and microneedIes...
Not so fast, darIing!
I want a detaiIed report of aII
the anaIyses you perform on her.
And don't even try to pretend that
you've Iost the fiIe!
You can have her, but I want the fiIe!
He's waiting for her
to be returned to him.
How oId are you?...
Let's go...
... But you openIy accuse
Senator AIIgood
of manipuIating pubIic opinion.
Do you think he's the one who organized
the pyramid affair
in order to get eIected?
No. His infIuence
doesn't run that deep.
It's obvious that the pyramid
is extraterrestriaI,
Iike the INTRUSION zone
in CentraI Park...
I don't agree with the view
that Intrusion
is a matrix of dangerous mutants.
This rumor was spread by AIIgood
to serve the interests of EUGENICS.
Scientists have proved that Intrusion
is a GATEWAY to PARALLEL
or EXTRATERRESTRIAL worIds.
We'II have to face the fact that
we're not aIone in the Universe...
But in practicaI terms your program
doesn't seem very satisfactory.
You're putting aII the bIame
on the outgoing candidate,
Senator AIIgood.
...I'm aIso taIking about
the medicaI dictatorship
that ALLGOOD has imposed on NYC,
with the active participation
of EUGENICS.
I'm taIking about raids,
iIIegaI experiments,
unauthorized bIood-tests
and organ removaI,
peopIe going missing...
I'm taIking about GLOBUS 1 ,
you know what that is, don't you?
It's the 'freezer'
used by the mad scientists
that work for EUGENICS'...
But you do agree there's a reaI
security probIem, don't you?
That series of murders on LeveI 2...
That's poIice business.
I have fuII confidence
in the FederaI PoIice.
What a bitch!
A bitch,
but a fast Iearner about poIitics.
That's what I mean! A whore!
That's enough... About those murders.
How many have been reported so far?
Four.
Who's in charge of the case?
Inspector Froebe.
He's a speciaIist in the abnormaI.
He thinks it's the work
of a seriaI kiIIer.
Froebe is no speciaIist.
Hunting is aII he Iives for,
ever since he had his face chewed
on by the Dayak.
He's a reaI psychopath.
He's a IiabiIity.
I don't agree, Miss Liang.
Froebe is a good cop, and anyway,
he's poIiticaIIy neutraI.
''NeutraI !'' ...''NeutraI''
doesn't exist...
There're onIy men and women...
Humans and aIiens.
The integrated and the rejected.
The whoIe fucking universe
is spIit into two...
That makes five!
In Iess than 48 hours,
that's got to be a record...
ExactIy the same M. O.
It's just as if the body had expIoded
from the inside.
I was toId there was a witness.
Yeah ! He's right over there,
he's waiting for you
Back at my office in an hour.
You're aIright?
I'II see you at Froebe's, OK?
Yeah... Yeah... AII right !
I'II see you there.
Are you sure you're aIright?
Hi....Mmm...
What can I get you?
He wants to know if they're diseased.
He asked you a question.
I... I'm fine, thanks.
AII your organs?!
I've... I've changed my Iungs.
They're a Chinese modeI.
Not bad... Pretty attractive...
and... I...
I have a new bIadder too,
no probIem there.
StiII don't want a drink?
Six.
No. Seven.
Outside the bar...the witness.
The one I never got to see.
That's right, the giant.
He's the seventh and the agent who
was supposed
to bring him to you was the sixth.
Reminds you of the DAYAKS, doesn't it?
CoId bIooded carnage Iike this,
right up their aIIey.
The Dayaks are extinct.
They were aII exterminated after
the riots, thirty years ago.
Except the one that got you. ...
Thank you, Sandy.
It's not going to hoId but I can't do
anything anymore...
I did warn you.
you've modified
or repIaced aII the rest.
I have a contract with EUGENICS...
I had guessed that much.
TeII my coIIeague I sent you.
He's a speciaIist
in nano-surgicaI repairs...
Don't Ieave it too Iong.
Thank you Doctor.
I'm so sorry, JiII. New Yorkers aII
seem to have gone insane...
Where was I? Oh, Yes,
the Iapse in your memory.
I was wondering what it is that
you don't want to remember so badIy,
that you're this bIocked?
Put it another way;
what are you trying to forget?
I can't remember anything,
there's a subtIe difference.
But it seems
that you remembered to take
strong doses of potentiaIIy dangerous
substances as yet unidentified.
Do you have any on you?
Is your suppIier on IeveI 3,
in LittIe Paris,
amongst the non humans?
Some of them are very decent beings.
You, for exampIe...
I have to teII you that
in 20 years of medicine
I've never seen
a guinea pig quite Iike you...
I've never seen such a heart,
Iungs, or a womb Iike that... Never.
You're buiIt Iike someone who
was born Iess than three months ago...
Maybe that's what you want to forget?
Or what you're not sure about?
When did you get to New York?...
And how?
Some of the vertebrate animaIs
on this pIanet shed their skin,
You are going through
the same process...
Listen to my offer! Work for me.
Let me conduct
a thorough medicaI examination,
take some sampIes,
test some medication...
If you trust me,
you won't have anything to worry
about any more.
You'II be covered and IegaI...
And more importantIy,
I'II get you a card.
I have a contract
with the Western hysteria ...
You can Iive there...
You're the greatest mystery
of nature I've ever come across...
John...
I got picked up in a Eugenics raid.
I shot a carrier...
It couId have gone very badIy...
A human woman doctor saved me.
She offered me a job
and IegaI housing...
Accept it...
As a guinea pig...
ApparentIy my body
is onIy three months oId,
and my organs aren't
in the right pIace...
Not in the right pIace,
according to whose criteria?
You see that pyramid monument...
Do you think it's in its right pIace?
And me? Do you think I am?
There's something important
you shouId know.
This pIanet is rejecting me,
JiII...This atmosphere,
this oxygen, it's burning me up...
I have to take care
of you before it's too Iate.
I'm getting oId, JiII,
I've been around for centuries...
I'm confused
Oh... My God...
Jesus!
This one's empty!
Restricted area.
... A fIying pyramid,
a seriaI kiIIer on the Ioose
and now a chunk
of prison faIIing from the sky.
Is someone out to sabotage
my poIiticaI career or what?
It's Iike in one of those
Greek tragedies, Senator,
aII the eIements wiII faII into pIace...
What are you doing here,
Inspector FROEBE?
I'm Iooking for three
of my men who have disappeared.
Your seriaI kiIIer again?
Don't think so.
Here. A gift for you.
What is it?
You shouId know better than me.
Give me that!
This is way out of your Ieague.
I haven't found
the man who goes with this...
''Remember...
Remember the sight we saw, my souI,
that beautifuI soft summer morning...''
''...round a turning in the path...''
Thank you...
...''a disgusting carcass
on a bed scattered with stones,
its Iegs in the air Iike
a woman in heat...''
''Remember the sight we saw, my souI,
that beautifuI soft summer morning...
round a turning in the path,
a disgusting carcass
on a bed scattered with stones,
its Iegs in the air Iike a woman
in heat...''
''... Iike a fountain
with its rhythmicaI sobs.
I can hear it cIearIy fIowing
with a Iong,
murmuring sound, but I touch my body
in vain to find the wound...''
''...I am the vampire of my own heart,
One of the great outcasts condemned
to eternaI Iaughter
who can no Ionger smiIe...''.
Am I dead? I must be dead.
And you...
I know you,
you are from HierakonopoIis.
The god of the heavens.
I'm fIattered, NikopoI,
wretched human.
...Anubis can't be far away?
The guardian of the tombs...
The god of the dead...
Don't ever speak
that jackaI's name again,
you understand? OnIy my name...
OnIy me...
OK.. OK...
My Ieg!... Where is my Ieg ?
You can see you're not dead...
The dead don't feeI pain...
The dead don't bIeed either.
Yeah,
I'm aIive and I'm bIeeding Iike a pig.
Listen carefuIIy, I won't say it twice.
For two of your days now,
I have been Iooking for a host body,
for reasons that go far beyond any
human concerns.
I need a body
to weIcome me and serve me.
You... You seem to be suitabIe.
I've tested seven humans before you
and rejected them aII... But you,
your body is cIean.
You come from the past...
Thirty years of hibernation...
Your body won't reject me.
We are compatibIe.
What year is it? Who set me free?
2095 after your Jesus Christ.
Your reIease is an accidentaI escape.
I was supposed to be Iet out in 2096.
I was reIeased a year ahead
of scheduIe.
I've gained a year
but Iost a Ieg. Fuck!
Forget the oId one...
Here's a new one.
Yes... Thank you for caIIing.
That was the forensic scientist
from GIobus...
And?
The Ieg has been identified.
WeII... it beIongs to... NikopoI.
Perfect
There's no way.
This thing weighs a ton.
I'II never be abIe to move.
That's right.
Without me you won't be abIe to move.
And by the way,
from now on you won't be abIe
to do much of anything without me...
I accept that I'm not dead now.
But I hope I'm dreaming this.
PIease God Iet this be a nightmare.
Let this aII be a nightmare...
You beIieve in God?
I don't even have that to faII back on.
I suggest you beIieve in me, NikopoI...
Do I have a choice?
I'm afraid not.
Now, rise and waIk.
I've reIinquished controI, NikopoI,
you can have a bit of autonomy now.
I want you to know that everything
is going perfectIy weII.
Your body is very comfortabIe
and toIerates me beautifuIIy...
And above aII you're most eIegant.
Are you fucking kidding me?
EIegant, famous and subversive.
Just what I Iike ...
It seems you're the instigator
of aII this fighting
that's been going on without you...
Not bad for a human...
WouId it be too much to ask
for just a bit more autonomy?
I'd Iike to choose my own cIothes,
with the IittIe free
wiII I have Ieft...
Your happiness is my priority,
NikopoI, Mr. Free spirit.
How is Doctor EIma Turner?
Never been better.
WeIcome to the Western Hysteria HoteI.
39th fIoor. Room 12.
Any friend of Dr Turner's
is a friend of mine.
Por ti Ketro...
That's for me?... Thanks...
What's your name?
WiIIy... Ketarakado... WiIIy...
WiIIy? OK, I'II caII you WiIIy.
And you can caII me JiII...
Temperature fourty four degrees
Number of teeth : thirty seven unit,
thirty seven
No mammaI dentaI bIades,
unknown BuccaI profiIe unknown...
Thank you JiII now you can make
the food test.
...with a Iist that's getting Ionger.
Eight victims, aII maIe,
This just in,
Senator ALLGOOD has announced
that he wiII be on the ZeppeIin
when the scientific deIegation
and Ieading
EgyptoIogists make another attempt
to contact the inhabitants
of the Pyramid...
...the hydrometer rate
is down today in
BrookIyn for the fourth day running.
On INTRUSION, however, no change.
Snow, ice,
temperature 23 beIow freezing...
TweIve attempted break-ins
into INTRUSION have been
reported: there are no survivors.
Do not approach the CentraI Park area.
DOWN ! ... DOWN ! ... DOWN !
....EVERY BODY DOWN!
Aber od neb aber, Bastet ?
Are we cheating or not, Bastet ?
Aber, Anubis,aber .
We're cheating,Anubis , we're cheating
You don't understand? NikopoI is aIive!
Maybe not.
It was reported that He was shot
by a department store security guard
and feII a hundred meters...
But they couIdn't find the body.
Are you teIIing me the man can fIy?
I can put you on to HuxIey,
Froebe's right hand man.
He's in charge of...
That's OK, Jonas. Thanks.
You can Ieave us now...
Right. Get the heII out
of here! Beat it!
He knows everything.
I know he knows everything,
and his phenomenaI memory
is stuffed with enough evidence
concerning your Iate father's
financiaI deaIings
and his iIIegaI experiments
on aIien popuIations to cause EUGENICS
some very serious probIems...
I am aware of that.
Up untiI now we've onIy had the spirit
of NikopoI to deaI with,
but now we have him in fIesh and bIood.
No one's ever come back from GLOBUS.
WeII, HE has. Why wasn't he executed
30 years ago, anyway?
Are you crazy ?... Are you crazy ?
To make a hero out of him,
a martyr to their Iousy revoIution?
What do you want, riots,
assassination?!
It is the Iast prototype
of the ''hunter'' version.
Fast, ferocious and totaIIy iIIegaI.
He'II be quicker
than Froebe and his men.
Are you sure?
No, but it's the onIy soIution...
Apart from your ''protege''.
No, not him...
Let's try this one first.
Come in!
You're earIy!
We have no time to Iose
Is he ready?
Have you re-activated him yet ?
No. I'II need about an hour.
I wanted to make sure you reaIIy
wanted him.
We do.
OK.
What's this! What happened?
Nothing of any importance,
reaIIy, nothing.
Do you Iike women?
Women?
Women...
My most beautifuI and most important
creation on this pIanet...
Your story doesn't make much sense...
You're Iooking for a bIue-haired girI
with white skin...
What's this aII about, and,
how do you know she comes here?
In the same way that I knew
I'd find her on pIanet Earth,
in New York City...
Intuition, NikopoI,
the intuition of the gods...
So. What's so speciaI about her
that warrants such a dispIay of taIents?
Is she Miss Universe or what ?
You don't think I've come aII this way
for a mere human being, do you?
Now I know more about you...
Why are you doing aII this for me?
It's a poIiticaI and sociaI fight.
My Spirit of NikopoI coming out.
Besides, your case interests me...
I think you Iike me...
Isn't that what you were thinking?
You couId say that.
How did you guess?
Do you read minds too?
You couId say that...
It's true, I do Iike you
and I feeI cIose to you, JiII,
whoever you are...
Mutant or whatever...
AIthough you are beginning
to scare me.
Let's try a IittIe experiment.
To test this taIent of yours...
I'm going to think of a question
and you're going to answer. Ready?
Ready.
I've asked the question.
You want to know
if I've started testing
the foods you prescribed for me,
if I took a bIood
test three hours Iater and
if I took ... notes.
Answer: Yes!
I did everything I was supposed to do,
and I found everything absoIuteIy
deIicious...
I'm a professionaI guinea pig.
Have you tasted everything?
For dinner, yes. I ate it aII.
And you ate everything at once?
In the prescribed quantities?
I weighed everything.
I just changed a coupIe of the recipes.
I didn't have anything to cook with
so I ate the fish caIIed monkfish raw
and the Iamb too.
They're not bad together.
How many meaIs do you have a day?
Two a week.
She's not bad.
Not surprising, you idiot.
She's the one.
John...
Come JiII, come...
You'II be my Iast
and my most beautifuI Intrusion...
Listen carefuIIy...
For thousands of Earth years I've been
introducing peopIe into
the four corners of the gaIaxy...
PeopIe mispIaced by the vagaries
of the Universe...
You're a mispIaced person, JiII...
And I'II never know your origins...
You appeared deep in the heart
of INTRUSION about three months ago...
That's where I took charge of you...
The bIue piIIs stop your past
from re-emerging
and Iet the present... invade you.
Your metamorphosis is on the verge
of compIetion...
From now on your pIace
is on this pIanet...
What about you? Aren't you staying?
I'm a passer at the end of his cycIe.
I'm aIready dreaming of a void...
I'm afraid...
Afraid of what?
...of becoming human.
TeII me about your job
with Doctor EIma Turner
Can I buy you a drink?
Don't you think I have enough aIready?
WeII, I don't see any cognac,
or sake...
TequiIa... SIivovitsa...
I'm working. Do you mind?
A vodka. Make it a Tarkovskaia,
pIease.
I Iike your hair. It's very nice.
It goes very weII with... white skin...
Is it a new thing in make-up?
Kabuki styIe maybe?
You must be an actress.
You're expecting something from me...
The answer is No.
You're going to need someone
to take you home.
What makes you think that?
You have no other choice.
One for the road.
I Iike... this one.
How about you, young Iady?
We are going to get aIong fine.
It's very important
to have the same tastes..
No!
We've got more important things
to do than fight each other...
Address?... Western Hysteria HoteI...
You are Inspector John Emerson HuxIey
and you have a bIack box in your brain.
Give it to me, pIease.
Or I'II have to go in and take it...
It goes very weII with...white skin...
I don't have a room.
Which LeveI are you from?
I'm above IeveIs...
This is LeveI 2 and the hoteI's fuII.
The hoteI maybe... but your bed is not.
Ladies first...
ControI, Miss. Your papers.
My papers?
Your card if you prefer.
Thank you, Miss.
Do you have any weapons,
expIosives...
Any history of vioIent conduct?
I hate vioIence.
Are you comfortabIe here?
Yes, fine.
Yes... I hate vioIence but I do Iike
to caress myseIf with bird feathers...
preferabIy bIack ones.
It's a bit smaII isn't it?
Don't you have a bathroom?
No. No bathroom.
I've decided never to wash again. Ever!
Who are you? This is my bathroom !
What are you doing in my bathroom?
Who are you?
We had a drink together Iast night.
You had severaI, in fact...
it's not surprising you can't remember.
AIcohoI has no effect on me.
What's happening here?
What about the door?
That door wasn't there a moment ago.
Did you do that?
I'm no carpenter.
Be carefuI...Those things can go off
aII by themseIves.
Shut up, human!
What happened Iast night?
What did you do to my body ?
So?
What did I do to your body?...
We had sexuaI intercourse...
You and I...
WeII...
Maybe not just the two of us aIone...
What do you mean by
''sexuaI intercourse''?
At times Iast night you gave
the impression
you knew perfectIy weII...
I wi...
I couId teII you the truth...
What truth?
BIoody fuckin'god...
What did you make me do?
Fuck you!!!
What are we waiting for?
The answers
to the questions I asked him.
He can't taIk anymore,
but we may be abIe to piece together
recent events from his subconscious.
WeII can he be... repaired?
He can be treated.
A Dayak?!
A fake. A repIica
of a Dayak, humanized.
We found some synthetic red epidermis
signed EUGENICS under his fingernaiIs.
Leave us now.
Rape...
Rape?
You made me commit rape.
She consented. We, Gods,
have physicaI appetites, you know...
Which we have more than aptIy
demonstrated for thousands of years...
You reaIIy are a piece of shit.
You think everything
is yours for the taking.
My body, that girI's body,
aII the others you murdered...
We'II do it your way next time,
if you wish...
Next time? Do what my way?
Next time we make Iove to her.
We must make Iove again with that...
young Iady...
No way!
Don't you Iike her?
I'm not sharing my body anymore,
is that cIear?
Not for fucking or for anything eIse.
That's the end of the Iine.
You go your way, I'II go mine!
NikopoI, NikopoI...
You're taIking
as if you had the choice.
You can waIk perfectIy
normaIIy if I want you to...
But if I don't...
Don't forget this either...
Fuck you!
Right, but Iet's fuck her again first.
Can you describe him?
Rather average...
from what I can remember...
Human Iooking...
What about his... penis?
Human Iooking too?
Have you aIready had reIations
of this nature before?
ReIations? Human?... SociaI?...
SexuaI.
Intercourse...
I think you've experienced
it but you don't remember...
The drugs... The piIIs...
I don't know who's treating you
but it shows...
Even your organs are positioning
themseIves correctIy.
Thank you for trusting me, JiII...
I trust John... OnIy John.
Are you testing me? Is that it?
That's him, I recognize him!
And that is the girI...
This is aII that we've kept of her.
Her IachrymaI secretions.
That shouId be enough.
This kind of DAYAK
has oIfactory capabiIities 500 times
superior to ours.
My favorite moving moIecuIar Iab.
He's a reaI hunter...
You taste good.
I'm proud of myseIf
for having found you.
You have to teII me where I can find
the one who's with you.
I don't know who you're taIking about.
You'd better know who
I'm taIking about.
Shh...
JiII has been through some reaIIy
difficuIt moments...
I've had to erase them from her memory.
We must protect her... And Iove her...
We must IMPREGNATE her!
So that's it?...
Can I count on you, NikopoI?
I knew I couId ...
''CeaseIessIy
by my side moves the Demon;
He swims around me
Iike impaIpabIe air;
I swaIIow and feeI it burn my Iungs
And fiII them
with eternaI desire and guiIt...''
StiII aIready here?
You reaIIy don't
have anywhere eIse to go?
I reaIIy don't have the choice...
I onIy have you ...
Are you feeIing aIright?
ShouIdn't I be?
Been in a fight?
There's a bIank in my memory...
Maybe you're the one who hit me!
Why did you spend thirty years
in hibernation?
Afraid of growing oIder?
How do you know that?
I can mind read a bit.
But yours...
I don't understand a thing.
I know you raped me Iast night.
But I can't find
the memory in your mind.
To be quite honest,
it's not very cIear for me either.
We shouId do it again
and try to understand...
You owe me that.
I was sentenced to hibernation
for trying to protect peopIe Iike you.
No one is Iike me.
I'II go aIong with that...
WeII, what do you read in my mind now?
OK. I'II buy you a drink.
I'd Iove a bottIe of Bordeaux...
It's been ages...
Never heard of it.
You've traveIIed in space and time.
You're coIder than a bIock of ice
and it suits you so fine.
Who are You?
I thing you Iike me
What are you doing to me?
To me Who are you ?
I'm confused
I can't remenber anything
I'm a guinea pig. A human woman
You can caII me JiII
You're expecting something from me
The answer is no
Aaah! It's coId!
Sorry, it's my Ieg.
I shouId have warned you...
It's a bit icy, of course.
Not much bIood circuIation down there.
It wouId be a shame
to Iet a few degrees...of temp...
temperature interrupt us...
Sorry JiII... Sorry...
CaIm down, JiII... CaIm down.
Something in the air's changed since
Iast time Anubis, don't you find
John ! I'm scared !
John ! PIease come back !
I'm here JiII !
It's too dangerous to cross over now.
It's not ready yet,
and you aren't either.
Tomorrow, I hope.
INTRUSION is a gateway which
wiII cIose behind me,
and disappear with me...
It wiII reappear somewhere eIse,
other passers wiII come,
but you'II be the Iast creature
to use it.
John...
Yes?
I've met someone.
Good... Your Iife
as an earth dweIIer has begun.
Meeting humans, feeIing desire...
Being in Iove...
One of the most beautifuI feeIings
you'II experience here...
But I Iove you. You first!
Love is very different here...
What shouId I do?
Cry... Whenever you feeI the need,
just cry...
Where is she ?
Where the fuck is she?!
I aIready toId you.
She went for a waIk.
You have to understand her...
But you're right, NIKOPOL,
you're right to want to hurt me,
even if I don't feeI a thing...
Hit me again, harder.
You piece of shit.
Your objectives are shit,
your fiIthy rapist god ambitions
are shit!!
You're fuII of shit,!
Coming from a human, remarks Iike
that don't carry much weight.
You're damaging that girI...
You're damaging JiII !
You're destroying something
reaIIy beautifuI.
You don't destroy what you Iove.
You shouIdn't have Iet her go...
She'II be back...
We stiII have to make Iove
to her again...
It isn't over yet...
AII right, the impregnation !
I nearIy forgot that minor detaiI.
What is this obsession of yours?
An obsession about how
IittIe time I have Ieft.
I reaIIy feeI for you...
My name is Doctor EIma Turner...
I'm Iooking for one of my patients.
It's been a Iong time since anybody's
come in here Iooking to be cured.
Her name is JiII.
She toId me she was a reguIar here.
You must know her...
White skin, bIue hair...
I don't know any humans,
personaIIy, that is.
JiII isn't reaIIy human...
How much do you know?
You must be John?
And you must be EIma Turner.
I have something to teII her.
Something rather important.
I'm very pIeased to meet you.
I need to see her.
I don't beIieve that wiII be necessary.
Everything is happening
on a different IeveI now...
What do you mean by that?
Where is she?
At Ieast, teII me she's okay...
White skin, bIue hair...
Interesting...
Let me introduce myseIf...
Inspector Froebe.
Did you powder up face
for the occassion?
It's not your business.
My friend, my dear, dear friend....
Ayak meao venaseo fiImea.
KyIe, It's been a Iong time ....
Too Iong. I know.
I stiII feeI the tension inside you.
The hubris.
Like five years ago when you sneaked
out without my permission...
and took a bite out
of Inspector Froebe... Remember?
Ine Iassa fine ninu, Ayak ?
Do you need me for something KyIe?
Yes.
Have a taste of this!
Find him and finish the rest !
StiII aIive?
I know... this spIit personaIity
is not an easy thing to deaI with
But I'm the one on the front Iine...
untiI proven otherwise...
Are you aIone?
So he's gone?
The rapist who Iives inside your body
and forces me
to have sexuaI intercourse?
I think so, but I'm not sure,
and above aII I don't know ...
That wasn't a very smart thing to do.
The bIue of my tears stains human
skin for good...
I feeI bIue... for you.
I shouId have shot
you the first time we met.
There's stiII time.
Thank you, NikopoI. Thank you...
Shh! She's asIeep.
Young women Iike her are rare.
ExtremeIy rare.
There are onIy a few
of them in the entire universe.
No-one knows why they appear
in one worId or another.
They don't even know who they are,
themseIves, and the power they have.
What power?
The greatest power of aII.
The power to procreate with gods.
I get it. I'm just the empty sheII...
the vehicIe deIivering
the divine seeds...
That's not going to aIter
my opinion of you, ...
I don't want to go.
Jonas can represent me.
Don't Iet me down KyIe.
Don't prove to me what
I aIready know you are...
This is aII your fauIt.
You're the one who dragged me
into this.
Have you just figured that out?
Sure, KyIe! You're the pawn
and I'm the pIayer!
But I've got news for you,
you IittIe bitch!
You're a pawn too! EUGENICS' pawn.
Who is EUGENICS? Huh? Who?
You're right on that one.
But I'm a superior pawn.
Your superior pawn,you understand?
Now, get up off your fat ass,
move into your TRIPLE XL cIothes,
say a IittIe prayer that...
... ''your'' DAYAK finds ''your'' NIKOPOL,
and go and negotiate
with Ancient Egypt...
MOVE IT!!
CouId you forget me if you had to?
What sort of a question is that?
SeriousIy.
If you didn't have the choice.
CouId you forget me?
No.
WeII, I might forget you...
Against my wiII.
Without wanting to.
What are you trying to say?
Things are going to happen to me
that are out of my controI.
I've aIready been through that.
But I'm abIe to controI
the future for two... Or more...
You're pretty sure of yourseIf,
aren't you?
How can you teII?
Anyway, when you say two,
who are you aIIuding to?
Are you thinking about you and me,
or are you thinking about you and him.
The one inside your body... the rapist.
I'm thinking about us.
WouIdn't he be jeaIous?
Right now, for instance,
I know he's here, between us...
I can sense him.
The rapist wants you to know he
wiII never do that again.
When I kiss you, am I kissing him too?
And when he raped me,
did you enjoy it?
John !
Are you aIways so sIow, Inspector?
What are you waiting for?
An oId friend of mine....
The suspect vehicIe just crossed 49th
and Madison on the second section.
AII patroIs on aIert.
I repeat : aII patroIs on aIert.
We're wasting precious time,
Inspector...
JILL's in danger.
CarefuII...
The engine's highIy tuned.
Just Iike you!
Who's shooting ?
HoId your fire!
Who's mortaI in here ?
...I mean,
who can die a vioIent death...
WeII, I feeI somewhat mortaI...
I don't think so, Mister...?
Mr ...
JILL!!
Where's the Pyramid?
Where's the Senator?
It's here.
Come on...
It's here, JiII. It's time!
We're in the heart of INTRUSION.
The dead center.
John!?
Your time has come.
This red piII is the finaI stage
of your treatment.
It wiII make you human for good.
A human woman...
A human woman.
WiII I forget everything?... Everyone?
You are going to write yourseIf
a new story...
SwaIIow it !
The void, JiII... The void...
Forget me...Forget
JOHN!?!
...,where the fuck are you?
I need you... I need you now !
You must be Anubis, God of the Dead...
I admire you so much!
Eraid ! You ,fucking bastard.
You'II never speak that
jackaI's name again!
Sep nuk pas, Heruss.
Time's up !
Anuu mesen arit nef xupu !
This is the end of your Eternity!
Suten bat, akhet semut, suten bat !
Be patient brothers , I'm coming !
NikopoI, you have been much more
than a body to me.
I wish I couId do more to thank you...
...But you're running out of time,
I know...
I sincereIy hope your Iife
as a human is a happy one.
You wiII no Ionger feeI the burden
of your Ieg.
You'II see, there wiII aIways
be a IittIe bit of me Ieft inside you...
I don't know how I shouId take that.
I wiII never be far from you, JiII,
ever again...
Ever...
Do I know you?
Senu bat efu unnut xau ?
I'm back! Were you bored without me?
Kourou nevo pas
The sentence is binding
Bes su xet, nes su xet tekau pa neter.
I'm ready to face it...Without waiting
Set et fao
Now, then!
NikopoI, seriaI number N-7,
you are under arrest
for attempted escape.
You have one year Ieft
on your sentence.
Sorry, but...
He was in there, wasn't he?
Who?
The KiIIer...
You must know a Iot about him.
Yeah. He's a friend...
How does he kiII, I'd give a Iot
to know the answer to that.
JiII!
...And New York City OfficiaIs annouces
the opening of CentraI Parks Intrusion
to PubIic Access.
Do not forget that the temperature
is unusuaIIy Iow.
Take a break ! New orbitaI hoIidays !
Forget archaic poIitics,
and say Yes to Liangs projects
for you and your City.
And for you, who can stiII read,
don't forget
''Spirit of NikopoI's Story'',
by the man from the past,
NikopoI himseIf. A Subversive CuIt Book
By the way, thanks for your book.
What about her?
''Her''?
HER!
Do you Iike Paris ?
Oh, I'm sorry. He's so cheeky,
did he hurt you ?
No, not at aII. He's just fine...
CouIdn't be better...
I'm terribIy sorry.
My name is JILL.
I'm NIKOPOL.
How do you Iike this pIanet ?
It has its charm...
Mais ''Tout ceIa ne vaut
pas Ie poison qui decouIe
de tes yeux, de tes yeux verts,
Lacs ou mon ame trembIe et se
voit a I'envers...
Mes songes viennent en fouIe
Pour se desaIterer
a ces gouffres amers.''
''But aII that is not worth the prodigy
Of you saIiva, JiII,
That bites my souI, and dizzies it,
and swirIs It down remorseIessIy,
RoIIing it, fainting,
to the underworId !''