Pay attention!
Ah, yes sir.
Take this map to Kanemaru now
And bring me the promised money.
What is this, sir?
If Kanemaru wants this,
it must be something big.
Watch that mouth of yours!
If word gets out,
bandits will be hounding all over it.
Make sure word doesn't get out.
They're in the independence army, too?
Do you know Park Chang-yi?
He's in on this, too?
Yes.
All you have to do is give this map
to Kanemaru.
Chang-yi will see to the rest.
Kanemaru will be on the train to
North Manchuria with a map.
That map is very important to us.
We need it.
And why should I help you?
'Cuz there's money in it.
It depends on the amount.
What's the reward money
on Park Chang-yi's head?
Will that be enough?
Not bad.
We have no other choice
but to pay you to do this.
So don't screw up.
Yes, sir.
Remember!
You've never set eyes on that map,
understood?
Of course, sir.
Now, go.
Yourjob is to get on the train.
And steal the map back
from Kanemaru.
We get paid and the map back.
Everyone's happy.
Manchurian soldiers are escorting him.
Be careful.
Are you worried, sir?
Of course not.
I know what you're capable of.
You're the best in all of Manchuria.
Just Manchuria?
Best in Manchuria means best
on the continent.
Forgive me, I'm not good
with words.
Here.
Your train ticket to Gando.
Park Chang-yi...
What the hell are you doing?
Bandits don't need train tickets.
Then?
We'll stop it.
SONG Kang-ho
LEE Byung-hun
JUNG Woo-sung
Rice cakes!
Candy!
Independence for Korea!
Rice cakes!
Candy!
Over here!
Rice cakes!
Nobody move!
Don't move!
The Good The Bad The Weird
Get up!
All of you!
Hurry up!
Now!
What's going on?
Who are you?
Can you speak Korean?
Do you understand Korean!
What?
Don't know any Korean, at all?
Bags!
The bags! Hurry!
Get 'em down!
Hey, you!
Get that one down, too!
Quickly!
Get the big bag!
Hurry up!
Now, the other one!
Hey, is that yours?
Hey!
I said, is that yours?
Wait!
Do you know who this is?
He's Sir Kanemaru.
President of Japanese Imperial Bank!
Kanemaru or kangaroo! Come here!
What's that?
Stop! Drop to your knees!
Get him! Get him!
You! Go get him!
Shh! Shh!
Get out!
Get out! Go!
Hurry up!
Yes, sir!
Find Kanemaru's bag, first!
Get Kanemaru's bag, first!
What the hell?
Bitch!
No!
Is Chang-yi after the map?
Come here!
Shut up!
Come out!
I'll kill you!
Shaoling! No!
Please let her go!
Open up!
Move!
Does it hurt?
Find the map!
Give me the rifle!
Who the hell is that?
Stop the train, now!
Byung-choon?
Yes, sir?
What do you think
is going on over there?
No clue, huh?
No, sir.
I think.
It's the fool up front
who has the map.
Man-gil!
Let's go! Hurry!
Park Chang-yi
The man behind him is
a bounty hunter named Park Do-won.
Yoon Tae-goo
The man behind him is
a bounty hunter named Park Do-won.
What a nuisance!
Get rid of him!
Yes, sir.
- Who was that?
- I don't know!
Isn't the guy on the bike
a friend of yours?
Yes, but not anymore.
- Did 'ya get anything?
- Sure did!
What?
I'll show you later.
Let's go!
Alright! Let's go!
Get moving!
What do you think it is?
Well... Not sure.
Where is it?
Maybe Manchuria...
But with the Russian writing,
could be the Maritimes Province.
Wait...
Hey!
This is a treasure map!
A treasure map?
Before Qing Dynasty's fall,
they buried a great treasure
somewhere in Manchuria.
This is the map!
No way!
It came out on the Ghost Market
once then suddenly vanished!
All the bandits came to
the Ghost Market for it.
Go find out everything you can
about that map.
Gotcha.
Leave the map.
What? You don't trust me?
It ain't that. Leave it and go.
Come on, man.
It's dangerous to be
carrying it around, fool.
And...
Exchange this for money.
Whoa!
They'll be won'th quite a bit.
Be careful.
They might've trailed us here already.
No way. They wouldn't dare!
This is my turf!
Just be careful!
Okay, I got it!
Bastard.
What in the world is this?
Russia...
Border...
Treasure...
Absolutely no idea.
Who's there?
Hold on.
What should we do?
Who is it?
It's me, Byung-choon.
Byung-choon?
What the!
You freak!
Get out!
Sorry! Sorry!
Don't move!
Get out!
Shit!
What happened? Tell me!
Where's the map?
Hurry up and give it to me.
Before I do...
You must pay your dues.
Ah, right.
What do you think you're doing?
I should've known. Fine.
I'll give you what you want.
Just give me the map.
Crazy bastard!
You've got some nerve for someone
who's hired to kill!
Gone insane over money!
You won'thless son of a bitch.
I took you in when you were
wandering around drunk.
I saved your sorry life!
I wanted to end this nicely,
but now you give me no choice.
No matter how notorious
of a ruthless killer you are,
you can't dodge a bullet.
A bastard who kisses the asses
of traitors...
What a pitiful end you'II...
Funny, ain't it?
People must know
they'll all die someday.
But they live as if they never will.
Damn funny.
Well, well...
You lived long enough.
Selling off your country.
We found out, sir
It's the Ghost Market thugs
and Park Do-won.
Knowing I, Park Chang-yi,
would be after it?
Yes, sir. But...
Looks like Park Do-won
was after you, sir.
The Ghost Market?
It's a market for stolen goods.
There was a gunfight last night.
The fool who stole the map ran away
to the Ghost Market.
He'll probably sell it there.
How many men can we round up?
About a dozen, sir.
Get the boys and go
to the Ghost Market!
Pack it up.
- Yes, sir.
Come in. Cheap prices!
Good lantern, sir?
Come in and look around.
Umbrellas for sale!
Out of my way!
Umbrellas!
Granny?
You sure do live long.
You'll probably outlive me.
What happened last night?
Byung-choon came after me.
The idiot even said his name
before shooting.
Why?
For the map?
Probably.
So did you find out anything?
It's gotta be
the Qing Dynasty treasure map.
Not only the bandits
but the Japanese army's after it.
Let me see it.
There's gotta be somethir...
Forget it! Give it back.
Hold on! I know this!
This is the Russian Empire...
Alexand...
Sand? Desert?
Alexander.
What's that?
- Give it to me!
- I know what I'm doing!
Next word is...
'Buried'.
It says, 'Buried'!
Like a buried treasure?
That's right!
Then it says...
'Excavatior!
Ex-vacation? What's that?
It means dig up.
Then...
'In large... volumes'?
Then this all means, buried, dig up,
in large volumes?
Hold on!
- Are you sellir it?
- Nope.
You crazy?
The Ghost Market thugs are after this.
The word will get out quick.
The chief here will probably give 'ya
at least 1000 won.
You idiot!
This could be won'th millions!
Are you out of your mind?
The reward on your head
is 300 won.
What?
I'm only won'th a piano?
A used one at that.
They think I'm just a petty thief?
You, Mr. Train Robber,
ARE a petty thief.
Let's just sell it at the
Ghost Market for 1000 won.
Forget it. I'm gonna see
if this is won'th gold or shit.
Granny! Granny!
Know what this is?
It's a treasure map!
If we find the treasure,
it's goodbye to this for us.
We'll eat all we want
and live in luxury!
Where do you wanna go?
America?
Where else? France?
En toi, c'est dah di dah.
Je t'aime, moi non plus?
What?
Damn! Shit!
Shit! I told 'ya they're fast!
Where are they?
Out the window?
Get out! Hurry!
Get Granny!
Granny! Granny!
Those bastards!
Run!
Bastard!
Granny!
It's not safe here.
They went that way!
Stay right here.
Don't lose this
and don't show it to anyone.
Even if Man-gil asks,
tell him you never saw the map.
Damn!
Watch Granny!
Hey! Move!
- The Ghost Market Gang is coming!
- Get back!
Damn sons of bitches!
Yoon Tae-goo, age 35,
300 won reward.
What are you saying?
I don't speak Korean.
You're Chinese, are 'ya?
No! Please! Stop!
I knew it was you.
You have the map, don't you?
Who are you?
Yes or no.
Just answer the question.
You're after the map, too?
Damn bastards.
I did, but not now.
So there!
Where is it?
Use your brain, fool.
I'm in this shit 'cuz of that map.
You think I'd just go and tell 'ya?
The independence army wants it,
not me.
Independence army, my ass.
Think I'd fall for that?
Talking doesn't get through
to 'ya, does it!
Wait!
Okay! Okay!
I've got an offer for 'ya.
I don't make deals with scoundrels.
I'll tell you a big secret
about that map.
You know what it says?
'Treasure, Buried,
Dig up, Large volumes'.
What?
That's what it says on it!
It's a treasure map!
So you and me can go find it!
If there's a treasure,
we split it 60-40.
Me 60, you 40.
How 'bout it?
That's how you
make a deal, man!
Did 'ya say your name was
Park Do-won?
You must've heard of who I am.
Of course you did.
Then do you know the Ghost Market?
My boys there will...
- Hey!
- Sorry.
You crazy bastard!
You evil son of a bitch!
I've never seen a Korean
so mean and vicious!
You can't do this to me, man!
How old are 'ya!
You little...
Hey, Yoon Tae-goo.
Don't even think about escaping.
Give me some water.
What did you catch this time?
What's this?
Get some sleep.
You got a rough day ahead.
Get me some water, girlie.
It can talk?
Water, please.
- Song-yi!
- Coming!
But...
Going somewhere?
Escaping?
No, of course not.
I just gave it a tug
and itjust fell out.
You folks
shouldn't be so careless.
Fine. Go back in and sleep.
Hey, it's raining!
Boss?
We saw Yoon Tae-goo, today.
He's the one who took the map.
Just as you wanted.
Everyone's happy, huh?
I get money.
You get the map.
And the original's safe where it is.
If this map is wrong...
...or there's no treasure,
then I'll find you.
And make sure you get buried alive.
That's no way
to talk to an old pal.
Look at what they did to my place.
Man-gil, that idiot.
Where the hell is Man-gil, the fool.
Granny!
Granny?
Damn! You scared me!
You slept in here all this time?
Damn Man-gil!
Told him to watch Granny...
Where's the map, Granny?
Where'd you put it?
Where is it?
No, not candy!
The big map I gave you.
The map!
Just once.
Once?
Did someone take it?
Who did you give it to?
Let go.
Man-gil?
Did he take the map?
I had to come and see you.
Do I know you?
You're alone?
Yoon Tae-goo's a friend
of yours, right?
Where is he?
And who might you be?
I'm Park Chang-yi.
Park Chang-yi?
You bastard!
Help me!
Tae-goo...
Hey!
Where do you think you're going?
- Give me another knife!
- Yes, sir.
I have a message.
A message for Tae-goo.
So stay calm.
And listen up.
Tae-goo!
Got it?
This blade's blunt!
Sharpen it!
Hurry up!
Damn rain...
What! Run!
Retreat! Retreat!
This way!
Man-gil!
Stay right here, okay?
Shit!
You! Run to the other side.
So I can see
where they're shooting from.
Why should I be the one?
Then who else?
Should I run straight on?
Or zigzag around
and make 'em confused?
Fine. I'll decide.
Hey! Come here!
Follow me!
Give me a gun, man!
Hey!
Give me my gun back!
Do-won! Where're 'ya going?
Come back!
Give me my gun!
Where are you going?
Come on! Give me my gun!
Gun! Now! Do-won!
Gun...
Shit...
Man-gil! Man-gil!
Man-gil!
Over here!
Whatch out!
Watch out!
What the!
- Cover me!
- Get back!
Get the horses!
Are you Korean?
Yes.
Is Yoon Tae-goo in your gang?
You think we'd mix
with a schmuck like him?
Damn! That way!
When our gang gets here,
you're all dead!
Yoon Tae-goo.
Park Chang-yi.
So we meet, here.
This is awesome
but why's it so damn heavy?