The School of Bastøy
existed from 1900-1953
It was a school for misfitted young boys.
This film was based on true events.
I once saw a whale swim
with three harpoons in it.
It took an entire day to die.
We found the wale again, and proceeded to
come closer, closer than we had ever come before.
He was weaker due to the
harpoon I shot him with,
covered with scars from all
the battles he had fought.
It is not as strict as they say it is.
They have Sundays free.
Shut up.
The  King  Of  Devil's  Island
They will enter cell C. That is
your responsibility, until you leave.
- What is it now, three weeks?
- Yes, Bestyrer.
Ensure that they learn.
No tobacco, no alcohol,
no civilian clothes,
no games, cards, or dice.
No discussion during work.
- No obscene behavior,
no personal belongings.
What is this?
Private asset?
Address me as House-Father Bråthen.
C5, C19, these are is your numbers.
Take off your clothes,
fold them, and place here.
You will receive new clothes
down below in the barracks.
One thing.
I observe everything.
I see everything, I hear everything.
And I write everything down in my book.
Is that understood?
Sit on your hands.
Stand straight.
Take down your hands.
What happened to your face?
Police.
It could have been a lot worse
if you had been in prison.
Hence why I ensured that you
made your way here.
Since you're a sailor you know
how important discipline is.
You're part of the crew
with one common goal.
Yes.
Yes, Mr. Bestyrer.
Yes, Bestyrer.
I'm your captain and this
island is my vessel.
The House-Parents are my mates,
the boy C1 , Olav Fossen,
he is one of you.
However, he is your leader.
Our goal, and your goal is to find,
the honorable, humble, useful,
Christian boy inside you.
And we're going to shape and polish him.
If we do not find him...
you'll remain here.
Do you understand?
Yes, Mr. Bestyrer.
At this island, we don't speak about
what anyone has done, or participated in.
There is no past nor future.
There is only the present.
If whole world crumbles under the waves,
it has nothing to do with us,
isn't that true, C-19?
Yes, Mr. Bestyrer.
Learn the rules and follow them.
So we see that you get what you need.
Bråthen.
Bråthen!
Cabin coordinator C1 will perhaps leave us
soon, and his space will soon be available.
What an ambitious and dedicated young man.
You can go now.
Is that him?
I don't like the idea of having
someone like him here.
This place is about to disintegrate.
- I can no longer be here.
- Stop.
C-1 to 6 will clear the northern field.
C-8 to 12 will shovel fertilizer with Bjarne.
Hey! Anyone who complains,
will receive the same job tomorrow.
New-boy, C-19, you have outhouse duties.
Is there anyone here who will volunteer
to show 19 how this will be done?
I'll show him.
We call it America because the
house-parents don't come down here.
This is where we live in peace.
You'll get used to it.
I'm not going to be here very long.
C-5, come with me,
we need a man in laundry.
There was someone who tried once.
However, it hasn't happened
since I've been here.
It's too far across.
- When did you come here?
- Six years ago.
You must love it here.
Is it true that you killed someone?
I thought we didn't talk about
what we've done before.
The boathouse is closed.
You can't get in there.
The only way out from the island
is the manager's signature
- And you're getting it?
- Yeah, I get it when the committee comes.
You're like the captain's cabin boy.
Arni, come.
Arni!
Put up your hand.
Hold it still!
He hasn't learned the rules yet.
But he wants to, right?
Yes, Bestyrer.
He wants to get away from here,
and he will.
When he's earned it.
Yes, Bestyrer.
Is that your mom?
Lights out.
I can't find it.
My clock.
House-father!
Be quiet.
Go to bed now.
I can't find it.
Help me.
Get up!
Down, down, down!
Let, let me go.
Hand's down.
C-5.
Thanks, house-father.
Be quiet!
I see everything.
I hear everything.
Up!
''Thus began my life now what
which was just comfortable.''
''So that I occasionally,
say to myself
that I could just be safe from
multiple visits by the savages,
so it would not bother me if I
moved from the place where I lived.''
C-19.
''I was certainly out of order
to kill a kid of my flock.''
''Carry it home and make it right.''
"But along the way, I saw a goat's
shadow with to young kids with him."
Want me to read them for you?
C-5?
Congratulations.
The manager decided that you'll
sing for the committee.
That means we must practice.
Who is Elsa?
Just read.
"Dear Erling. I'm frightened
when I look beyond the ocean
and think that you're out there.''
''I miss you terribly now.''
Keep reading.
" I'm trying to remember you.
How you laughed when you were last here."
''When you didn't even know
what a harpoon was.''
Harpooner. The man which stands
in front of the boat and shoots it.
Was that you?
Just continue.
"I thought I saw you the other day.
I see you everywhere."
''I hope you come back before christmas.
Like you promised.''
Long before christmas.
Haven't you told her where you are?
- I think there is more.
- Read it then.
If you're going to be here, you
must learn to behave yourself.
Are you going to teach me that?
What have they done to you?
Stand still.
Everything okay, C-5?
The ear.
It doesn't look like we're
going to get rid of your smell.
That's how it is when you're born
out of your mothers ass.
Liquor?
Is that liquor I smell?
Section C.
We're going to continue
this inspection every day,
until there is peace in barracks C.
Is it funny? Then we will
find something funny for you.
C-19.
Stand straight!
Yes.
This is quite meaningless, huh?
Just like your behavior this morning.
I'm sorry, Mr. Bestyrer.
No, you're not.
It's just that I don't
belong here, manager.
Yes, you do, you see.
You belong here.
You can put down the stone.
Now take these stones, and place them
back in a pile where they belong.
So you think your strong do you?
We will see.
"Dear Erling, I'm frightened
when I look beyond the ocean
and think that you're out there.''
"I miss you..."
Erling, let him go!
Særavdelingen.
Forestry...
Half rations.
Your mother lives in Horten, right?
I thought maybe she could invite me over.
to dinner, for example.
Maybe six or seven days?
Stop turning the saw, you idiot.
You'll break the blade.
That is isolation.
Ow, shit!
The last boy which was
put in isolation,
he hit his head against the wall
so he couldn't talk anymore.
- Have you never tried to run away?
- Yea. One time.
I jumped on the mail boat,
but I was only eleven.
What'd you do when you were eleven,
in order to come here?
I stole from a church.
Help me to write a letter.
A story.
To whom?
Somebody.
About what?
A story of the sea.
Sailors on a ship. With me on board.
Did you see the whale?
I saw a whale swim
with three harpoons in it.
It took an entire day to die.
What should I be then?
Deck boy...
And I will be the harpooner.
You shouldn't eat that.
You'll get sick.
Bestyrer.
We've learned.
And what have we learned?
That we're all on the same ship,
Mr. Bestyrer.
Give me your rabbit, Aksel.
I'm hungry, I need more food.
Stay away!
- I just want to pet him.
- Stay away.
I'm just going to pet him.
It's a her, not a him!
C-9 and C-19 requesting
permission to use the outhouse.
C-19 is a problem.
We should be harder.
They should punish him more,
and keep him separate.
Discipline without compassion
is heartless, we've talked about this.
We are role models for these boys,
we must not be heartless.
Bestyrer.
Now I speak not only for myself,
I have really nothing to complain about.
I have been here for 9 years.
I haven’t asked for a penny
more in pay, but...
the parliament church and
School Committee sets the salary.
You have to talk to them.
I know that, but...
to be a house-father is important,
but it is no lifetime job.
An ambitious man, would
have left a long time ago.
Good Night.
Bråthen?
Bråthen, you're doing a great job.
Good night.
We need help to bring in the wheat.
You're doing the laundry.
Please, let me help you
in the field. Please.
- Can you handle a pitchfork?
- Yes.
Come on!
Where did you hide the saw blade?
They won't find it.
Promise me that you wont
escape before I leave?
Yes.
It's not long from now.
Hey, what are you looking at?
Bastøy boy.
Here you are.
C-5?
Let me see your hand.
Come here.
They're wrapping it together.
What is it?
Turn on the lights!
Get help! Hurry!
Come on.
Come on, we gotta leave now.
We're leaving now.
Do you want to stay here?
Go back to the infirmary, Ivar.
Take me with, Erling.
Please, I'm begging you.
Go!
I want to come, I can help
you row when you're tired.
Please!
I don't want to be here anymore,
I can't do it!
Please, Erling.
Please!
Go back, lvar.
I can't have a wussy with me.
What?
You're not in the infirmary?
Where have you been?
I have been talking to someone.
Have you been down to the beach?
Have you been with C-19?
Gossip pussy!
Bråthen?
Yes, Mr. Bestyrer?
How long have you been on Bastøy?
- 9 years
- 9 years...
Has anyone managed to escape
during that time?
- No.
So this boy, C-19,
has to be a kind of hero.
The first to successfully
escape Bastøy.
But he is no hero.
He is selfish, egotistical and cowardly.
He can not see himself in the face
and stand for what he has done,
so he runs away.
And leaves you all again
to take the consequences.
He risked your privileges,
which you have worked so hard for.
And where does he run to?
What will he find when
he finally stops running?
He will find nothing.
Nothing!
For he will be taken and sent right
back here. I can promise you that.
Am I disappointed?
Yes, I'm.
I disappointed in you.
I am disappointed in C-1 ,
Olav Fossen,
whom is responsible for barracks C.
But those who really should
be disappointed, are you.
Half rations.
He did it.
He got away.
Erling escaped, for heavens sake!
I heard that the chef had talked
with the captain of the mail boat
He said he had found the manager's
rowboat across the mountains -
- by Rørestrand.
...with an Our Father in covenant
if you never shudder
fight for everything you hold dear
die as it comes!
C-5.
The hero is back.
Come on, let's work.
C-1 will read this and then
carry out the punishment.
Read.
''Penalties for serious offenses
such as escape attempt, theft
or repeated use of tobacco,
shall receive 12 strokes to the
back or until the blood seems.''
Hands on the table!
Yes, between the lines.
Do it!
C-1, do it properly!
Where are you going now?
Managers galley boy.
Don't blame me that you
broke the rules.
Was it easier for you to read me the
rules, than to tell the manager
what Bråthen does with Ivar
in the laundry room?
Or are the rules like that too?
You promised me, you devil!
Or do you dare not say anything, now that
you are about to get your signature?
What is going on?
What are you doing here?
- House-father...
- Be quiet!
You are so close to being released,
and you come running in here
without permission.
Have you lost your mind?
I saw C-5 and...
...and...
...house-father Bråthen in...
Bråthen?
What is he doing?
He puts C-5 in pain.
Pain?
Well, speak up!
House-father Bråthen
and C-5...
I saw them in the laundry cellar.
What are you trying to say?
What are these hideous fantasies?
It's not allowed! What he does
with Ivar in the laundry cellar.
Get out!
Go!
Ivar! I want you and I to go
to the manager right now.
Do you not see that I'm working?
If we go together, he will believe us.
Then I'll never go home.
C-5.
Bestyrer.
Stand straight.
I am just wondering
if your hand is better?
Yea, it's a little better.
Thanks, manager.
Good. Then everything is okay.
Excellent.
Nothing to complain about.
But there are no other problems?
No.
No, because I thought you should maybe...
I believe it will be better for you,
if you work in the forest
with you friends.
Thanks, manager.
Yea, I believe that
the forest will better suit you.
Yes, manager.
Great, then!
Good.
You owe me money.
What money?
Bråthen and I are having a bet.
If you are back in
laundry in the morning.
Go and help Bjarne with the fire.
What are you doing with Ivar's clock?
He gave it to me.
Get back!
Get the nurse now.
Right away!
Run!
Get them to the sleeping hall.
To the sleeping hall.
Go to the sleeping hall!
It is absolutely terrible
what has happened.
We suffer from everything that has
happened with the poor boy.
I understand that you feel guilty.
But I have to admit that he didn't
have it so easy before he came here.
And it was no less turbulent here.
He was not as strong.
He was one of those whom did not
fit to live among other people.
And maybe it was God's will
that he finally let go.
We tried to help him,
and find easy work for him.
But,
he tried to swim away from here,
a desperate act
that could only end in disaster.
And we all know where he
got the idea from to flee.
Escape is just
a childish fantasy.
But he is in peace now.
He is in God's place.
Sit down.
C-19, sit down!
Send C-19 to my room.
Are you looking to go to prison?
If you can't decide, then you
don't understand what a prison is.
He didn't try to escape.
He drowned himself.
What's the difference? He's gone.
Forget him!
And help the others to forget him also.
You've seen little of the world and you
think you understand. But you don't.
No, manager,
there is a lot i don't understand.
Bastøy or prison. The choice is yours.
Get him out.
Why have you been here so long,
Bråthen?
They talk.
There are rumors that I don't even
want to speak about. Accusations.
You can't listen to them,
they say whatever they want.
A child has died.
And you have been accused of
actions which are so horrible...
the only thing I have done
is to try to help a boy
who could not help himself.
C-5 was not scared of me.
It was these animals
he lived with in barracks C.
I can't have a house-father who is
suspected of such a thing as this.
It's disgusting.
Bestyrer.
Please...
You are accused of fornication with a child.
Do you understand what that means?
Is there much truth there,
shall I see that you rot away in
a prison for the rest of your life.
I understand how difficult a man
of your position must have it.
With a young wife here.
And all the responsibility.
And all these options to take.
And the funds that would get the boys
and the island destroyed for good.
The funds you've used up
to make your life a little easier.
I know that.
But others could maybe misunderstand it.
Now you're leaving!
You bastard!
Leave, you bastard!
Now it's too late.
What are you going to say when the committee comes?
When they begin to ask questions.
They will certainly question and dig.
You have to tell them the truth.
You don't give up, Astrid.
You don't give up.
- Are you Erling Kaspersen?
- I am C-19, mam.
Have you learned anything here?
- Yes, mam, I have learned many things.
- Could you tell me what kind of things?
I learned that I would rather
be here than in prison.
And why is that?
Don't you see
what great good we get, mam?
The boys,
are they always so quiet at the table?
No.
You see them now as they will be seen.
Clean and neat.
Especially the boys
who may be out in society.
For them, this is more of great importance.
The boy that died recently.
It must have made an impression on them?
I'm the first to recognize that
it isn't easy being a Bastøy boy.
It's a brutal environment.
We do what we can.
We help and we support them.
But one can not
be everywhere all the time.
And children could be very bad.
The boy who tried to escape
turned out to be a chop chicken.
He was not strong enough
to take care of himself.
Yea, it is tragic.
''If we confess our sins,
He is faithful and just.''
''So, he forgive us our sins and to
cleanse us from all unrighteousness.''
''What hurts is when it is...''
''if we confess our sins,
he is faithful and just.''
Nervous?
''So, he forgive us our sins and to
cleanse us from all unrighteousness.''
Good.
Congratulations.
Do you have something you want to say to us?
You need not be afraid,
it is only just to speak out.
Yes, I want
to say something to Mr. Bestyrer.
I will never forget all he has done.
I want to say something.
There is a boy here who died on this island.
I understand manager
that you were not directly involved
in harassing this kid.
But I'm speaking as a leader of hall C,
you had a responsibility.
Do you understand that?
Those were wise words, Fossen.
You could have taken
better care of that boy.
Yes, Bestyrer.
When do you leave?
In one week.
What is it with you?
You're going out in the world now.
You can do what you want.
Get yourself a wife.
Do you know what the committee said?
Do you know what the manager said about us?
Doesn't matter what they said.
Bastøy is only a
small stone in the water.
You can be what you want.
You can be a priest,
you are so smart in reading rules.
- Goodbye.
''We sailed for several weeks
before we saw him again.''
''Our food ran out.''
''And Øystein, the chef, was not so
much to brag about in the beginning.''
''Should have seen how thing I've become.
I can't eat anymore fish.''
''But we found the whale again,
and we came right on top of it.''
''Close than we had before.''
''He was weaker due to the harpoon
I shot him with.''
''At close range, he was great,
25 meters long at least.''
''And covered with scars from
all the battles he had fought.''
''He had already killed
the new deck boy.''
''The Captain have a
high opinion of himself.''
''But deep inside
he is a damned coward.''
''The rest of the crew
are afraid of him.''
''I have become acquainted with
one boy whom is soon to sign off.''
"For six years he has worn on the ship,
he has done everything right. "
''Now he is going home."
Forgive us our debts, who
also have forgiven our debtors.
Lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
For thine is the kingdom, and
power  and the glory forever. Amen
Sit down.
Sit down!
We shall now take leave of
two friends. Two good friends.
By tomorrow they will be out in
the world meeting
new sorrows, new joys,
new lessons.
Aksel Johnsen.
God bless you. And may you take
care of the opportunities he gives you.
Olav Fossen.
Go!
Go.
Go while you can.
C-1?
Do you have any more wise words
that you want me to take with me?
Behave yourself, now.
See you around.
We never finished the story.
Maybe I will see you again.
On a ship somewhere.
I hear you guys are leaving
Good luck.
C-1, towel.
Did the manager know that
Bråthen is back?
Of course he did. He had been
in land to shop for the manager.
It's that simple.
If only you had done
that you were asked,
had it not been a problem.
Everything had been fine.
You damned liar!
Do you remember when you first came here?
A little brat
who was so afraid that he shit on himself
and peed in his pants. Every day.
Worthless.
Just like the whore
of a mother you had.
And your petty criminal father.
You were nothing.
For six years I have struggled with you.
And all that is of value to you,
I created.
Bjarne!
You must help us.
You're one of us.
Bjarne?
Bjarne, you are one of us!
Øystein, eat your food.
Come on, Øystein, you must eat.
Are you sleeping?
Do it.
Or freeze up.
There was just blood everywhere.
He swallowed them down until he died.
Harpoon shooter, cook and cabin boy.
Everything, swallowed by the whale.
And everything went back
the way it used to be.
The captain was admiral.
And could command a crap bowl.
And sailed to America.
And the crew was on deck
and had their own number.
Lined with mackerel and herring.
Olav!
Take his key!
Help!
Runaway!
Olav!
Stop!
Enough!
- Get up.
- Enough.
Get up!
Back to your places.
Back to your places!
Back!
Come on!
Don't do anything dumb now, boys.
What are you looking at?
Fucking Bastøy Boy.
Get up on the chair.
The manager is coming!
Let him through.
You do not belong here, either.
Goodbye, manager!
Let him go!
He said we should let him burn.
Get out!
C-19.
Are you going to kill me now?
So?
Can I get your signature?
Lieutenant?
I have to talk to someone higher up.
I want
to speak to the King of Norway.
Tell him that it is...
that is it the king of Bastøy.
They're coming back!
And there are many of them.
Do you understand what I am saying, Olav?
Take the paddles.
Come on!
They’re coming.
It came over from the mainland.
- I can't do this anymore
- The sea is frozen over.
I can't stand it.
We can cross over!
I can't go on it.
Stop!
Come on!
The letters were to my sister.
Let me go.
Let me go...
Olav.
Olav?
We are approaching Christiania.
Bastøy, port.
I once saw a whale swim
with three harpoons in it.
It took the entire day to die.
He was weaker due to the
harpoon I shot him with
And covered with scars from
all the battles he had fought.
I have become acquainted with
one boy whom is soon to sign off.
For the six years he has been on
the ship, he has done everything right.
And now, he is going home.
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1332134
Kongen Av Bastøy - King Of Devil's Island (2010) English.srt
FPS: 25.000
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+ |T|h|e| |D|e|a|f| |B|o|y|s| |F|o|r| |B|o|y|s| |G|r|o|u|p|  +
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) All DVDs to be subtitled
2) All VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled
3) All videos/DVDs used in lessons at school to be subtitled
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV
____           __            ___   __              ___        __               __
/     /   _   /    )  _   _ (_     /  _)        _  (_      _   /  _)        _   / _   _
(     /)  (-   /(_ /  (-  ( /  /     /(_)  () (/ _)   /   () /    /(_)  () (/ _)   (__)  /  () (/  /)
/                              /                        /