This story begun since
the abnormal rohit borned..
he grew up with the time,
but his brain remain like a kid.
and his habits, mischief,
and talking remained like kid..
Then rohit's innocence
got punished...
everybody makes fun of me...
if you won't help me,
so who else will
you've so much power...
Oh God give me a little bit power to me..
and one night on the land of kasoli
an space ship landed..
rohit got the magic..
the life started smiling..
the powers from the magic
changed the rohit completely
rohit's fame crossed the borders.
One day a great scientist called
rohit to singapore sidhant arya
then suddenly sonia leaved
the rohit's hand...
they found the cause for
living in rohit's son krishna.
but his amazing powers..
scared sonia mishra that...
she took away krishna
and started living on strange place
but destiny choosed the
way of heart..
krishna went to singapore
for meeting priya..
where the truth was waiting
the his father rohit is alive.
and is host-aged by
the dr. arya..
then time sent that son
a new history
the fire of a circus
made him wear a mask..
like that we got new protector..
new friend..
an super hero..
Kaal's experiment is successful
now spreading this virus
in every corner of the world...
will start the destruction
of human being..
now i understand the secret of
the powers of sunlight you gets.
if my experiment will successful,
so this world will get new beginning.
10 min remaining.
father you,
is everything all right?
i'm fine...
i'm very happy today, father?
sorry l woke you up,
but 9 min are remaining in raising sun
so lets go to lab ..
whatever lacking was in
formation, l fixed them up.
what's all this father?
my hard work for years..
an try..
the sunlight gives it a energy.
and l think i finally by the mirrors...
by reflecting the lights energy..
i've made the perfect
combination for multiply it.
there's a natural combination exist.
but we can't see it.
its actually a electronic device..
if there is magical combination
around this pen..
so this pen will be activate..
and will start beeping.
then it will gather all the
rays and put them in subject.
then we'll be able to see
who the sunlight gives the life.
means, the sunlight will
put the soul in this dead plant?
how come it possible?
it is possible..
sun..
pen has been activated.
its mean the formation is correct.
energy's power is too high.
have to do something.
have to make filter who let
the pass light which is needed
and observe the remaining
energy itself..
filter with brain..
i'll make it..
then see it..
my experiment will
change the solar energy direction
now lets go ..
have to go to office.
lets go
looking smart.
you fixed up the puncture?
yes.
lets go..
first you get ready.
i'm ready
sure?
was just touch up..
i'll do it in car.
see
now you've got ready ..
yes.
don’t you want to go to office?
yes but maybe today
i've to go to parlor first..
office is here now.
is near the security agency
on the left side
air india's job?
lets go l'm getting late.
don’t change the topic.
tell me what happened this time?
when clients comes to book ticket,
they maybe in the air..
therefore the airline made
him permanent landing
and said, to take off forever.
it happened exactly
this is my new office.
come here..
i'm going to leave the studio
at 4:30...
and you'll meet me exactly at 5 O clock.
remember!
if you'd be late today..
and this husband job that...
now when do l drop you?
i'm fine..
we'll be succeed.
the boss fired you both.
this is your termination later..
and its yours..
what happened your
father looks like tennis ball..
when those thief came
to steal in jewellery shop yesterday..
so you ran away...
so will your job can be intact.
i ran too, but for coming ..
i mean...
what?
why are you shocked?
you go to work..
now tell me,
when l ran yesterday..
i mean went..
after that who had
come in the store.
who?
now you understand the secret..
what's my full name?
kripa sharma..
karipal's Kri..
And sharma's Sh..
what's the name after joining it..
krish..
you?
speak silently
if someone would listen,
so the crowd will gather..
you're still assuming wrong?
right?
krish's height and yours...
have to adjust..
tall in fight, and then small
you can't understand..
this is the style
of we super man people..
you're a common man,
so you do one thing..
find the work
which you can do easily
the big news from mumbai.
the plane's front wheels
has been jammed.
the pilot's every attempt
was unsuccessful for open it.
if the landing would not go properly,
so plane can be crashed.
the all passenger are in danger.
have to go now..
where he's gone?
landing without front wheels..
plane can be explode..
we don’t have another option
fuel is about finish
will something happened to us?
the dangerous virus has created
a panic in Namibia...
you must have heard
about it..yes we were seeing it.
in how much time the virus
starts reacting?
after coming in contact,
its symptom shows up in 5 min.
this virus is spreading by
the air and water..
we've sent the blood sample
of infected people around the world.
have sent you too
that you can crack this virus..
therefore you're my last hope.
i'll try my best..
i want to meet you right now.
for what?
i've a shocking information
about the namebia virus and its anti.
i'll tell you everything
when l'll meet you
my life is in danger,
therefore l'm calling your from payphone.
look l'm going to office,
you come to my office..
i know the address..
who're you?
different..
unique..
because i had no past..
only present..
whoever you are,
came to wrong place..
place is right, and time too
intentions are maybe wrong.
first you know me..
i'm the answer of your
every question.
look..
you look
in my eyes..
to yourself..
that you agree to meet me.
you wanted to tell me
something about the virus..
take this..
it contain the virus sample,
and its anti dot..
this company makes the anti dot..
and l recently know that it makes
the anti dot later..
first it makes the virus..
they've many labs in the world..
therefore l've collected the full
proofs against them..
you were in-charge for lab no.3
were you had to make the different
DNA's fusion..
but you made these files..
how'd you know.
i'm saying right..
you made mistake to cheat with him
its a miracle of science.
this was made by the person
who's making his strange world.
this is kaal
having wit for get over
on the time and life
an secret.
science's an genius.
this research can change
the whole world..
but he started experiment
for changing himself.
we can see it strange
coincidence the who has power in brain
his trunk below the neck
is soulless
but leaving 2 fingers of hand.
its hard to believe...
but its truth
kaal with telekinesis..
means getting his brain
powers in two fingers.
can pick up things
and fly them..
and can break them
even then his finding..
so he can find that bone marrow
which can put soul in hi body
when different DNA kaal
couldn't find the cure in humans..
then he selected the animals
for his experiment.
and mixing his and
the animal’s blood dna..
kaal made the strange creature..
whose soul belongs to kaal.
the face is of human.
and habit and strength
is of animals..
the kaal named them
animal..
but kaal couldn't get that
bone marrow from manima..
of he's looking for.
his struggle is still on.
start the final test
teach them living here
and carry on finding and try
you'll find that bone marrow.
i'm successful too today.
you've not seen my new
manimal strikers tongue strike
and kaal was successful yesterday
when he made you
by his and chameleon’s blood
that's why you can
change the face and body
anywhere anytime
lets see how much people
are breathing in namibia..
this red dot shows that 40%
people are infected by this virus.
world many genius scientist
face is sad.
our scientist are asking,
when to send our anti dot there!
let the people die.
and let them afraid more.
as much people's courage will go down,
and our profit will go up
this virus hasn't born
it was made
who can do this!
an very sick person
we're successful to make
the anti dote of virus
an company named kaal pharma
anti dote reached to namibia.
and situation is under control
this antidote proved again,
there're more good people than bad
there's nothing not afraid.
you're safe now.
now we both are safe
but tell me something
what were you doing up there
i was doing my homework
then l saw a pigeon stucked in wires
was restless
therefore l went to roof
for help him
but my hands are small
but anyhow i made the pigeon free
and l fell
and you saved me krishh
me?..
you saved that pigeon
whoever brings the smile
on anybody's face is krish
am l krishh?
yes
but you've mask, suit and powers.
what i have?
you've the truth that taught me
if your hands are small so what?
courage should be big.
please come
you've come very soon
should come after the restaurant shuts
by the way may l know where
were you hid.
it was important to go
was important?
more important than your job.?
these guest came to eat
chines food..
and taunted me.
look..
he's the one..
he reaches where there's
no hope like wind.
and you're the one, where you
should be, you runs away like wind
if one ability would be in you like krish
so l'd not fire you from the job
we're informed by sources the krish
is off duty since 1 1 O clock
i never got more good
surprise than it.
you may never get the
more good than this gift.
what?
today's morning has
happiness for us.
when kids grew up..
they thinks elders kids..
i remember today is the
birthday of krishna.
so l've brought the gift for him
the cause of today's happiness
is something else.
and she'll tell you herself.
whose?
i've no friend of this name.
it can be..
i don’t remember the name of friends.
its your name..
you're going to be a grand father.
really?
yes papa
every father wants his child
to see growing up
plays with him..
and l kept him away,
and couldn't see all this.
how much krishna fall before
he stand up on his feet.
how much time he
could controlled.
how many times he came
to home dirty..
and l'm regret of this..
but now ..l don’t regret of it.
if l couldn't see your childhood,
so what?
will see after becoming
the grandfather.
i'll live your childhood openly
with your child..
for completing our little family
this is from my side
for both of you
and this sweets...
i'll feed this to everyone in office.
everybody will be happy
what're you doing kaal?
if my all fingers and my whole hand..
my whole body
would be fine so l..
you can't think..
what'd l do..
l still can't think ..
how can you do all this.
from where did you found these powers.
what's the secret of it?
at last why having so much power,
this body is stucked in wheel chair
its hurting me.
it should be.
because you hurt me.
after asking the question..
which's answer l don’t know.
and still don’t know..
what're you doing son?
don’t miss use your powers.
whatever powers you've,
don’t hurt anyone by it..
how many times i told you this.
so many times l asked you dad,
how come these powers are in me?
why l'm like that?
i don’t know my son,
you always lied to me.
and you're lying right now..
no..believe me..
spent millions.
will spend billions..
how much we earned
in namebia by our anti dot sell
little bit fear,
and 320 million dollars.
fear's business is the best business.
now we've to earn in billions.
now we want the country for
our virus where is crores population
india or china..
china's population is
more than india.
but there's more population
of Gods in india..
and their belief on them by people.
so lets see.
can their only god can save
them from virus..?
or not..
i heard that you might feel
eating some sour.
no, l want sweet, because
i want our baby sweet like you
how you're licking ice cream
you ate my ice cream
when you want to eat it,
so why you brought me here.
i couldn't eat mine,
so how can l eat yours..
lets buy new ice cream
how're you
i'm in tension,
trying to adjust my anger.
because i'm accused of
stealing ice cream
what you want to eat
you're giving me empty cone
i had filled it..
so why its empty
i'm filling it before you,
okay fill it.
now you see l filled before you
yes you filled but its empty
my ice cream..
i've just bought you
one more cone.
kaal, Mumbai’s color will
be change very soon
as you're seeing everywhere is
the fear and tension
its worse situation
is of the hospital.
because of this rapid spreading virus,
people are in critical situation
1 1 7 people died already,
and its number are increasing.
please get up papa.
my fear was right..
this is the same virus who killed
thousands in namebia.
but this virus's anti dot
has been created..
contact the kaal pharmaceutical..
whatever happened with striker
after that it may be need
to try the krish.
our virus will test him too
indian government's color
turned to white because of virus
their fear is contacting
our dealers..
the special anti dot decomponent is ready
we should start making
anti dot as soon as possible.
how much time will our scientist
take to make it?
10 days..
this city will be destructed in 10 days.
people are dying in front of me.
i can hear their screams
and l can't do anything..
i can't do anything.
so what's the meaning of
being my krish?
it has.
everyone was infected,
but nothing happened to you
priya is alright,
because she has your child in her stomach
my all colleagues are infected
leaving me.
means, this virus can't infect us.
maybe there's something
in our blood.
which is fighting with this virus.
and is protecting us
you test on me.
i'm all right..
its mean..
the anti dot can be created by your blood.
now we can save people..
just in few hours,
the anti dot will be ready
but how fast to everyone..
we can send the medicine..
how come its possible..
don’t know how, but our virus
infection is reducing in mumbai.
someone in you all have betrayed me.
has cheated kaal.
i told you that anti dot shouldn't
reached to india before 10 days.
so how come it reached there
how sent that..
we got news that an scientist of
mumbai has made the anti dot.
how can a worlds any scientist can
make the kaal's virus anti dot.
my virus's anti dot can be
made by only my dna..
by my blood.
so how come they...
how can they got it..
come..
my blood in someone
else veins.?
how can it shed..
how?
Mumbai never stops,
never afraid.. never loose
our mumbai again proved
after defeating this virus.
i'm saluting
the endurance of this city
mumbai and its spirit.
to whom more than it..
who's the real hero of this victory
childs friend.
elders hope.
and olders support.
our krish
if you're here.
or wherever you are..
we've now words to thank you
even then we've just tried...
which will become the new
identity of this city
for presenting this identity
i want to invite the person..
without them maybe krish
couldn't be able save us..
thanks for loving me.
but whatever i did, if you'd be on
my place, you'd do it too
i was just a chain.
we got success by your prayers.
now l want to thank krish
who gives us lights.
do you know krish?
i believe krish
its my belief that,
we'll have krish inside.
the person who use his powers
to help others.
who supports everyone
that is krish
we all have krish inside.
i'm krish
when l saved that pigeon that day
he gave me this symbol
i've it too
what happened?
who's it?
nobody
what's her blood group?
O positive
she's pregnant.
how's priya
don’t know anything yet.
she's inside for check up
what's going on all this papa
you don’t worry,
we'll know everything.
your wife is alright..
but she lost her child..
everything will be fine
these tears are not needed
is yours krishna.
will have to teach her
again to laugh and live.
and only you can do this
are you bothered to bring
you here
who're you?
strange people and place scares.
i know..
you're in the world of kaal
i'm trying to talk to you and you.
running and hitting...
its not good to run in this situation
for both of you
who's this krishh..
i don’t know
you must know your father-in-law
made the anti dot of my virus.
and must be know how he made it
i don’t know it either.
and l know that, l'll get the answer
from you of my every question
my husband is finding me.
who're being find ..
who're not in front.
but you're in front of him
here and there too
lets go
priya are you here
or somewhere else.
i'm here.
in front of you
you're front of me
but not with me
means if you'd with me,
you'd understand that l'm changed.
hence i'm all yours.
as your channel entertain you..
as like l'll entertain you
daily list is ready,
from shopping to cinema..
and l won't take any leave
or any promotion
and want only salary..
and some smiles in salary
20 lac hugs.
2 crore kisses.
from where we should start.
i was thinking it too
forget whatever happened.
his heart is beating once
in every 2 min.
its mean..
he gone to hibernation
in a sleep, he can live alive
as much he want in this heart rate.
but any human can't do this
but animals can do this
they does it
living under the earth,
and takes the breath
and came out on the
right season..
he must have this specialty
as much he's human
is also animal.
i think..
he's manimal.
yes..
are you alright yes why
i'll be late
the person who attacked
on us is gaining conscious
till he regain conscious,
we could help him and he help us.
why you've come here
i was suffocating.
i'm very scared, he'll kill me.
nothing gonna happen
kill him
he attempted to kill me.
did you see?
if you'd not come to save
me on right time.
what l did wrong to them
why they're after me.
its right to be worry but please.
now relax.
maybe we'd know it if
we could keep him alive more days.
but who're they,
and why are attacking us.
maybe for that the father made
the anti dot of virus
yes l was thinking that too
me too
i can't say it surely
but it can be linked.
in virus and anti dot and attack
can be.
that's mean they can come back again?
again can spread the virus
we can save people, but how?
the burnt the lab
but we've anti dot
and it will be created on need.
how
i think till you will not show
her making anti dot.
till she will not stop asking questions
because she's not priya..
this time whoever is before us,
is just on journalist.
today our priya just like
a journalist..
because she hasn't gone for
office for many days.
inner journalist is trying
to come out.
since tomorrow you're
going to office and now for sleeping
but father..
lets go
if we could know how father
made the virus anti dot so can help him
this is very important.
you can't understand because
this is your appointment later.
its time to announce the name
of the winners.
my child...
from my side.
what's this?
krish symbol,
whoever helps anyone gets this.
where can l find krish!
i don’t know this..
we just know that krish
reaches to right time
where it can't reach,
people like you reach on time.
what l did like this
did!
this is for..
who with a mother from
his child..
and mother from her life,
didn't let separate..
and you can't understand.
am l talking to priya
or my kaya..
i want little more time
that is what l don’t have
till tomorrow,
if you'll give me that information
or l'll get it by my way
are all parameters normal
so what he's doing in
his mother's stomach?
bring him out
right now
but why for?
i want to inject my dna
in his and want see
that what will generate.
because until we've not
yet done this experiment.
on any human or animal
before he begot..
if this time he'd be
bring out, so he'll be abort.
he'll die
till this child would not be of 3 month
neither we can bring it out,
nor can do any experiment
till we can't perform its dna test.
how much time?
at least 1 week.
in 7 days.
your 9 month pain will be finish
and maybe my many years waiting too
where are you
shocking truth are appearing Krishna!
first we came to know..
that anti dot kaal pharma made.
and the mutant was in our custody
both dna is same.
and now, the most shocking truth is
and the dna we made is almost same.
i performed test many
times for confirm it.
but the result was same every time
but how come its possible
because that anti dot we...
i think priya woke up
she's fine now.
i'm going to singapore tomorrow,
you take care of yourself and priya
why?
singapore and dr. arya's
wrong intentions.
are the important part
of my past.
and the new truth and questions.
maybe i can get the answers
from my past.
are you alright?
yes
why?
i seems that you're
calling me from far away
i'm near you..
how can l call you from far away
papa called you
he want the coffee
he's still working
still?
no..he said he's working on
an important research
we can't disturb him till morning
you lets go with me
i got the all answers
my decision to come
in singapore was right.
are you gone for singapore?
when?
and you didn't tell me
last night i told you when
you came to lab.
last night.
when?
now you remember it?
you aren't priya.
i'm priya
you aren't priya
if you are..
so must know who's krishna.
and who's krish
who're you?
where's my priya.?
yours?
these tears can betray krishna..
not to krissh
where is my priya
wherever is she..
is alright
your priya and your child.
and this time l'm speaking truth
with krishna and krish..
where's he?
welcome in the kaal's world.
and l'm sorry to bring you
here against your wish
so what did you know.
that..
an human should never
try to become God..
several years ago.
dr. arya made me hostage
in singapore..
and during that, dr. arya did
weird experiment on me.
if my experiment would
be successful
so l'll make a new rohit mehra.
by his blood and dna.
which will have brain like rohit.
and powers too
but he'll walk on my finger tips.
dr. arya created an kid
by using my dna..
but that kid was disable.
dr. arya said to dr. mathur
to kill that child..
but dr. mathur didn't do it ..
he left that kid outside
an orphanage.
after that...
an rich person adopt that child
raised him up..
its means..
to whom i used to think my father.
he wasn't my father.
because that disable child is me.
and you're my father.
now everything will be fine.
i found you...
now i got the answers of my questions.
and now i'll find out my cure.
just i need your help
how can l help you
by giving me your bone marrow.
i'll give you
i'll help you
but you've to stop all this
which you're doing
the world you created.
will have to finish this here.
can i call you dad?
off course i can call you dad.
because you're my dad..
so dad...
if you'll keep the condition...
so you'll hurt a lot..
because then l...
bring out your bone marrow from
that child which is in priya's stomach
your grand child.
he before get born..
no..
he's alive.
because..
i got the priya..
want to see?
but priya was there..
whoever is there is not priya..
is my manimal khaya.
in the face of priya,
real priya is here safe..
and her child health
and his bone marrow too
do you think l'm alone this time..
therefore you can do anything with us.
but you don’t know how powerful are
the tears of a father...
that's why you can't see.
coming toward you
are you alright?
kaal is not here..
come dad.
now l'm stood on my legs..
how're you feeling kaal
i was talking to my dad..
this is just beginning.
now i've to shed a lot of blood
feeling good coming in your world?
look kaya....
now kaal is destruction for all
i'll destroy the humans
and will make new generation
now this world is mine.
would be mine
but you choosed the different path
by breaking my trust.
i knew that kaya would bring
krishh here..
and l wanted this too
you're gonna need these tears
keep them safe
sorry... for our father
yes..we're brothers
two son of one father.
the difference is just,
you're because of love.
my victory will be by your
and your childs end.
i won't live the sign
of this generation
you people wanted something
and were habitual
to whom kaal killed
i've finished the krishh
i've made the krishh immortal
and the turn is of priya mehra.
as much time will he take
to come to me
as much pain i'll give you all
please God.
never consider yourself alone.
because an spirit..
energy
is only in body
the past life comes
back becoming new life.
look
look krishna.
i'm alive in you
our powers are merging.
we'll live together always.
i in you..
and in remembrance of you all.
and you all in my blessing.
what're you doing?
you're like an insects for me.
and inferior ray which i can
crush anytime.
so how come will you save it.
by giving our life.
no
ny taking his life.
you're a small..
and you act like that..
i'm small so what..
should mush have courage.
krish told me.
krish was..
kaal is ..
krish is an thought.
which can't be killed
by any kaal
till one will be stay alive
in all of us..
the krish will remain
what kaal...
are you scared
krishna..
how good l'm feeling
we four of us are together
an family
but to whom do l kill first
to father or to child?
look at yourself..
you're an just a ordinary human
an ordinary son
and weak father.
being human is not my weakness,
but its my power..
because l've blessing of my father.
and the love of every child...
surprise
krishna get up
the person who dies,
who gots born
i'm not born
so i can't die too
how much badness has power,
the goodness ends it always.
krishna
you never consider yourself alone
because nobody dies.
we'll always live together.
me in you.
and in your remembrance..
and you all under in my blessing.
you've got an son..
now you can meet.
i wish father would be here..
he's here..
i've named my son rohit..
this..