Third alarm firebox
R- 50-4. Please respond, 0-1-Charlie-1.
Engine five, Engine 55, Engine 33.
Truck one, Truck 49, medic 20, field com...
...respond to Newgate Avenue
and Newkirk Street...
Hamilton Grain, for the building fire.
Third alarm to firebox R-50-4.
Please respond, 0-1-Charlie-1.
Engine five, engine 55, engine 33.
Truck one, truck 49, medic 20, field com...
...respond to Newgate Avenue
and Newkirk Street...
Hamilton Grain, for the building fire. 20-30.
This way! Take it!
More pressure!
Reposition those rigs!
IC from Ladder 42,
we are on side two...
Jack! Jack!
Everybody, listen up.
The battalion chief says
we've got a report of people...
...trapped on the 12th floor or above.
He says the place is full of grain dust,
which could explode at any time.
So everybody keep together,
maintain radio contact.
Check that
on the three side of the building.
Is that all right? You got that?
Roger, IC. Three side of the building.
Why does it always have to be
the 12th floor?
Why can't they be on the fourth?
Les move it, Grandpa.
Come on.
Ladder 49 to Command.
We're on the 12th floor.
Commencing search.
I'm getting too old for this shit.
Lenny! Lenny!
Take Jack.
Ray!
All right, Cap.
Come on, Jack.
Copy that.
This is Baltimore City Fire Department!
Can anybody hear me?
Fire Department!
Baltimore City Fire Department.
Can anybody hear me?
Fire Department!
Anybody here?
Hello?
Fire Department!
Hey! Jack!
He's over here!
I got a pulse.
Ladder 49, Portable three to Portable one.
We found one of 'em.
He's alive.
We're bringing him out.
Jack, get his hands.
Portable one to Portable three.
Copy that. We got one, too.
We'll meet you at the stairwell.
Give us a hand here!
Breathe through my mask.
Go ahead, just take a breath
outta my mask.
I got him! I got him!
Ladder 49 to Command.
I got his legs.
Be advised we have
two trapped occupants.
We're bringing 'em down the stairs now.
Where's Phil?
What?
Phil.
Cap, they said there was two of 'em.
He was with us.
They said there were only two.
On this level!
On this floor. Over there.
I'm gonna go look for him.
Jack! You stay in radio contact.
Ok.
Fire Department!
Aah!
Portable three to Portable one.
Explosion blocked my rear exit.
Looking for alternative,
but still searching for a victim on level 12.
Ladder 49, Portable one to Portable three.
We copy, Jack.
Hey! Hey!
Come on. Get up!
Can you stand?
Come on, les go.
Come on.
Ladder 49, Portable one to Portable three.
Jack, you all right?
Yeah. I got another one.
Portable three to Command.
Be advised I have the victim.
We're moving toward side one,
the roll-up door.
Get a bucket up there
and I'll drop him down!
Command, do you copy?
Copy that. We are repositioning truck 51.
Come on!
Nice and easy.
Hey! Come on, get it up here! Up!
Truck 51 to Ladder 49 Portable.
We're right underneath you.
Bring him down, Jack. Bring him down.
Whas your name? Phil?
Yeah, is Phil.
Here, Phil, can you hold this?
Can you hold this against your face?
Listen to me. I'm gonna
tie you off right now, all right?
Nice and easy.
Portable three to Command,
ready to lower the victim down.
All right, Phil, now listen to me.
Take this off.
Listen to me.
I'm gonna start lowering you
down now right into the bucket.
Now trust me.
Keep your eyes on me, Ok?
You keep your eyes on me.
I got you. Trust me.
Hey, Phil, you look at me.
You look at me and stay right there.
I can't do this.
I'm right here.
You could do it, Phil.
I can't do this.
Yes, you can. I'm gonna help you.
I got guys on the ground.
Trust me, Phil. Trust me.
Please, I can't.
You have to go.
Now, I'm not leaving till you leave.
And you're going, Phil.
Down! Get down!
Go down. I got you.
I promise. I got you.
Go. You just look right here.
Aah! Uh...
You got 30 feet, Jack.
Stay right here, partner!
Stay right here!
Jack, you got ten, 15 feet.
Bring him down.
Aah!
We got heavy black smoke up here.
We got a four-by-four hole cut.
We can't get in there yet.
Ladder 12, this is Ladder 6.
We need the big booster.
Bring in a big line.
Hey. You the new rookie?
Uh, yeah, I'm looking for, uh, Captain...
Hey, yo, Frank. Whas up?
Whas up, Tommy?
Drop your bag.
Uh, take the spiral staircase.
Look for the door
that says "Captain's Office."
Thanks.
Whas up?
Any breakfast?
Yeah, in the kitchen.
You're the rookie, right?
Yeah.
Uh, probationary firefighter
Jack Morrison reporting, sir.
Sir?
Your shift started at seven, son.
Uh, well, sir, I was already here.
Ah, save it. Sit down.
Now, let me tell you somethin', boy.
Engine 33 is the busiest...
...and most disciplined firehouse in the city.
No room for slackers.
You got that?
I know that, sir.
We get over 4,000 calls a year.
Thas a lot of action.
Gotta be willing to go the extra mile.
Are you, Jack?
Are you willing to go the extra mile?
Well, yes, sir.
I don't think so.
I can.
Sorry, Cap.
Uh, Father Hogan's here.
Uh, I'll go last. I'll go last.
Let him go first.
Go ahead. Go ahead, Jack.
Yeah, so, Jack... Ok.
Welcome to, uh, Engine 33.
Good to have you onboard, son.
Get out.
Well, thank you, sir.
Hey. Ray Gauquin.
How are you?
Jack Morrison.
Good to meet you.
Uh... so, the captain...
He's a great guy.
Uh, right down here.
You can use this one.
This one?
Yeah.
You Catholic?
Most of the guys are.
Uh... we have a thing here.
A priest comes around twice a year.
We all go to confession.
In this job, you need it.
I mean, you get enough fires, you find God.
Yeah.
A good confession now, son.
"Bless me, Father..."
Uh, bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
Is been, uh...
...seven years since my last confession.
Seven years is a long time.
Yes, Father.
All right, where do we start?
Theft? Robbery?
Fraud? Taxes?
Well, you know.
Taxes? Always taxes.
How 'bout sex?
Lmpure thoughts?
Well, yes, quite a bit.
Try to cut back.
Are you married?
No.
Are you a virgin?
No, Father.
Oh, you think is funny to
fornicate with loose women?
What? Wait a minute.
No, you wait a minute.
You come across any more loose women,
you let me know.
Tommy Drake.
Jack Morrison.
Hey, man. Don Miller.
Good to meet you.
Dennis Gauquin.
Hey.
My older and, as you
can see, uglier brother.
Frank McKinney.
Father.
Lenny Richter. Father Lenny Richter.
Pleasure to meet you.
Good sport.
Cap.
You think we'll get
something today or what?
I don't know, kid.
I think you put a hex on us.
Uh, did you report a fire, ma'am?
I burned some bread
in the oven, thas all.
Oh, well,
can we come in and check, please?
You put one foot in here,
this dog'll tear your ass off.
Get in there, probie.
Come here.
Yeah?
What the hell's this?
What?
Are you stupid?
There's no paper.
Yeah, is right there.
Is not on the holder.
Why don't you use your hand?
You're used to it.
Hey, who asked your opinion?
Get outta the bathroom.
Oh, God...! Goddamn it.
All right, who's the wise guy?
All right.
Interrupting my sh...
Goddamn it!
All right, somebody's gonna pay for this!
We got one, rook!
Come on, come on!
About three more blocks.
Right after North Avenue.
All right, Cap.
Move out of the way, asshole!
How you feelin', kid?
Is your first fire.
Are you ready to break your cherry?
That one. Grab that plug!
Got you, Cap.
Three-story brick building.
Flames showing second and third floor.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Go, go, go!
Your helmet!
Slow down. Slow down.
You're getting tangled up.
Let it go, let it go.
Single line, single line.
Come on. Let it go.
All right, there you go.
Go in low.
All right, stop here.
Stop, stop.
Charge the line!
Charge it!
All right.
Go! Go!
Over the side!
Slow down!
Slow... slow down!
Whoa. Whoa.
Huh?
Go!
Keep goin'!
Jesus Christ!
They're just rats.
Come on, les go.
Cap... Huh?
Go!
Hey, Cap...
Ignore it! Go!
Ok.
Just keep goin'.
Drop it. Drop it.
Drop down.
Ok, Ok...
This is it.
You ready? Move it in!
Come on, move it!
What?
No, not yet. Not yet.
When? When?
Move in. Now, now!
I got it, Cap, I got it!
Easy, easy. Hit it! Hit it!
Ok! Ok!
I'm with ya,
I'm with ya.
Hit it high.
Hit it high!
I'm trying, I'm trying!
Good.
Move in. Now, now!
Thas it.
Aah!
Is all right. Get up!
Get up!
I'm Ok, I'm Ok!
Here! Here!
Come on, I got it.
I'm doin' it, Cap!
Up! Up! Hit it high!
Hit it high!
Easy. Easy.
Hit it! Hit it!
Ok!
You did it, man. Good job.
Whoo!
Hey, how 'bout that?
She go easy on you?
Get me up to speed.
We've got a 20-story building.
Most of it concrete.
Most of the fire's on the top eight floors.
And after that explosion on 12,
one of our guys went missing.
Jack Morrison, Ladder 49.
Any radio contact with him?
None.
Anybody with him?
The others of Ladder 49 made it out.
They're in the stairwell with the victims.
You reported this?
Yes, sir.
Ok. Deputy Chief One to communications.
I'm on location assuming command.
Strike out a fourth alarm.
Ok, shut down all exterior operations.
Get your asses in there
and find him. Go, go, go.
Command to Ladder 49.
Jack, come in.
Ladder 49, Morrison to Command.
Jack. Jack, is Kennedy.
How you holdin' up?
Chief, the floor collapsed.
I don't know.
I'm pretty busted up.
Do you know where you are?
No. I was on 12 when it gave way.
I was on 12.
How you doin' on air?
Tank is no good. Air's out.
Ok, hold tight.
We got units comin' in after you.
Hey, Mike.
Mike, the vic get out?
Did he get in the bucket?
Thas affirmative, Jack.
He made it.
He's gonna be Ok.
You did a great job.
Jack, switch to a different channel.
Try eight.
Switch to a different channel.
Hey, Mike... imagine me getting myself...
...trapped in here like some dumb rookie.
You should've taught me better.
Well, what do you expect? I did the best
I could with what I had to work with.
No. No academy fire was ever that hot.
I told you.
Didn't I tell you?
Nothing compares, right?
Nothin'.
I can't believe it.
Hey, we need ketchup.
Right.
Maybe more.
Ok.
Thas it.
I'm goin' in.
Uh, excuse me. Hi.
Hi.
So, can I ask you a question?
Sure.
Now, who are these for?
For us.
Really?
Yeah.
Um, you can't eat these.
Why not?
These, these are,
these are for fat, lonely girls...
...who stay at home at night watching TV.
Lasagna is for the fat girls?
Yes!
Lieutenant, right?
Yeah, thas right.
Lieutenant Jack Morrison.
Hey.
I'm Captain Dennis Gauquin.
Uh, Cliff's Crab Shack,
you ever heard of that?
No.
Best seafood in town.
Thas what you need.
Oh, really?
Sorry, we can't do it.
We already planned dinner.
Thanks, though.
Yeah.
Ok.
Hey, you know where the ketchup is?
Maybe.
All right, can you show me?
Sure.
Ok.
Ketchup, huh?
Been fightin' fires all day.
I need some help finding the ketchup.
Sorry. The captain's been
under a lot of pressure.
We had a big fire today and I think
the, uh, smoke probably went to his head.
It doesn't seem to be his head
thas the problem, Lieutenant.
Thas funny.
Hey, I'm Jack Morrison.
Yeah.
He told me, remember?
Oh, yeah, thas right.
So, you guys usually pick up girls
in the supermarket, for fun or...?
Well, usually I just throw 'em over
my shoulder and carry 'em down a ladder.
Sort of a Tarzan-Jane thing?
It was nice to meet you.
I should get going.
Yeah, it was nice meeting you.
Bye.
Eight o'clock.
What?
Cliff's.
With those girls?
You mean, like if you lock yourself out?
Yeah.
Well, if you lock yourself out...
...and you say that you
left the stove on, yeah...
...the fire department
has to come let you in.
But we try to stop people from doing that...
...by knocking down their door
with an ax. Right, Jack?
Wanna go outside for a smoke?
Oh, more than anything.
Les go.
You guys Ok?
We're goin' outside for a smoke.
Bye. Behave.
So, what do you do?
I work in a jewelry store
where people make their own jewelry.
Did you make those?
Do you make your bracelets?
I made this one, and I made this.
Is nice.
So, whas that called?
Would you be, like, an artist?
No, I just help people make jewelry.
Is just a job for now.
Do you like what you do?
Yeah, I love it.
Yeah? Why?
'Cause you'll just be sittin' around like this,
and all of a sudden that gong goes off.
You go tearing out of the firehouse,
go down the street...
...and fight your way into some building...
...dealing with that heat,
helping people, you know.
Saving people.
Is an amazing feeling.
I can't even imagine what it must feel like
to save someone's life.
I mean, how many people
do you think you've saved?
Well...
Look, actually, I'm...
I'm not a lieutenant.
I just...
We were just screwing around.
I actually just started, uh...
You suck.
Yeah, I got my first fire today, though.
But I did. I got my first fire.
It was amazing.
Captain Dennis sent them over.
Thank you.
Thanks.
I hate you.
He's gonna be Chief Dennis
in another hour.
You suck!
Is he even a fireman?
No, he's a truckie. He's a step man.
Truckies are search and rescue.
He actually goes in and pulls people out,
you know. Dennis has saved people.
Are you a steppie, too?
Not a steppie, a truckie.
Oh, Ok.
But, no, I'm on the engine.
I'm a pipe man.
I actually hold the nozzle
and put the fire out.
Thas cool.
I think is amazing what you guys do.
I mean, you go into burning buildings...
...when everyone else is running out.
I mean...
I couldn't do that.
Is the job.
Whas goin' on, guys?
Not much, man.
Nice. Nice one, guys.
How you doin'?
Jack Morrison! Phone call!
Some woman named Linda claiming you
to be the father of her child.
Ohh!
Hello.
Hey, how you doin'?
No. Uh, yeah.
Uh, fires, no.
But I did have a goose.
A goose in my locker.
It was huge.
Crapped all over my stuff.
Come on, Jack, you startin'
a phone-sex business here?
Go ahead and tell her you love her, Jack.
Hey, look, I gotta go.
Can I call you later?
Ok. Bye.
Aw!
Sweet stuff.
Sweet stuff!
Irish Car Bomb?
Come on, Mike.
Don, you want one?
Linda! Linda!
Hey!
Hey, hold up.
This must be the lovely Linda.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Frank, Linda.
This is Don.
Hey, Linda.
Hi.
And Tommy.
How you doin'?
I think you know him.
Uh-huh. Margarita sends her love.
Ah, Margarita.
Thas Captain Kennedy.
How do you do?
Hi. I've heard a lot about you.
Yeah?
Yeah, you wear really sexy boxers, right?
With red love hearts on them?
Oh, gosh.
A little too tight.
Ah, sit, have a seat.
What are you...?
I had to.
Linda, have you ever had one of these?
No, don't do it.
What is this?
Oh, is an Irish Car Bomb.
Yeah. Here, you put it in like this...
...let it drop right in there,
and chug it all at once.
Are you doing one?
You're gonna love it. Ready? You ready?
Oh, is gonna make me sick.
Come on. Now...
One, two, three.
Drink, drink, drink, drink,
drink, drink, drink, drink...
Come on!
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go!
Wow.
Oh, my God.
What was that?
I'm going to be so sick tomorrow.
Ohh!
Les get another shot!
I think I gotta slow down a bit.
No, you gotta get wasted at a shift party.
Thas tradition.
No, no, no, Jack, the lady knows her
limitations. Let her go. Send her home.
Are you calling me a lightweight?
Yeah.
Lightweight.
Ohh!
Stand back!
Ok. Last one to empty their glasses
runs naked around the bar.
We got a challenge!
Oh, we got a race here!
We got a challenge.
Ok, Ok.
All right. Loser takes off all their clothes.
Call it.
Ready, on three.
One, two, three.
No, no, no.
What the hell is that?
I said last to empty their glass.
Did I say anything about drinking it?
Tom, the lady's right, Tommy.
Ohh.
See, oh, we got a cute one here now, huh?
Take it off! Take it off!
I was very clear.
Take it off!
Take that.
Oh, please kill me.
I like this.
Hm?
Oh. My mom gave it to me.
You know what this is?
Mm-mm.
Is a Claddagh ring.
You know, if is pointed down...
...then it means that you're free.
And if is pointed up
towards your heart...
...then it means that you
belong to someone.
Clear.
Come on, Lenny.
Les go.
Go.
Oh, God.
Jack!
IC, Ladder 12.
Requesting air rescue to deploy.
Jack.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Jack!
Oh, God.
I need a goddamn progress report,
Ladder 49.
Ladder 49 to Command.
Be advised we have
structural collapse inside.
There's a huge amount of debris.
There's no way around it.
I don't care what your problem is.
Just keep goin'.
We're gonna need
some equipment up here.
Equipmens on its way.
Copy that, Chief.
IC from Ladder 42.
We are on side two,
awaiting instructions. Over.
Lenny. Lenny!
Cap, how are we gonna
get through all this?
Squad 47 here!
What do you need?
We need that equipment over here!
You got it!
Give me a saw!
Come on!
We need to shore this.
Come on, we gotta shore this up!
Clear!
Watch your heads through here!
Jack!
Uh, Ladder 49, uh, this is...
Aah!
Son of a bitch!
We got a flare!
May the Lord bless you
with many happy years together...
...so that you may enjoy
the rewards of a good life.
And after you have loyally
served in His kingdom on Earth...
...may He welcome you into
the kingdom in heaven. Amen.
And may Almighty God bless you
in the name of the Father...
...and of the Son,
and of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
You may now kiss the bride.
I now present Mr. And Mrs. Jack Morrison.
Your husband's an excellent firefighter.
Look after him for me, will you?
I'll help him look after himself.
Even better.
Whoa.
Teach Jack this stuff.
All right, this next song
goes out to our newlyweds...
...by special request.
Uh, Frank, Don...
I need you up here, uh,
immediately, please.
Whoo!
Come on, guys.
Come on, get up here, man!
Come on up here right now.
Uh!
Jack. Jack.
Hey, Jack, get up here!
Here we go.
No, no, you goin', you goin'.
We'll be right back. Come on, buddy.
Come here and sit down.
Join the club.
Well, honey, we aren't
sitting far enough away.
How you doin'?
Captain Kennedy?
You the new rookie?
Yeah.
Jack Morrison.
Keith Perez.
Office is back there.
Thanks. How you guys doin'?
Whas up?
Welcome to Engine 33.
Ok, all right.
Thank you. Thank you, Captain.
All right. See ya.
So, Keith, you Catholic?
Yeah.
Are you a virgin?
No, Father.
So you think is funny to
fornicate with loose women?
Uh, no, no, not at all.
Well, if you wanna have sex,
you should get married.
I can't.
Why?
Is not allowed.
What do you mean, is not allowed?
Well, the church doesn't allow two men
to get married, Father.
Excuse me?
I'm gay.
Hey, how did you know that?
Yeah, we got him, baby!
Ohh, really?
What?
Did you tell him?
Whas up with that?
God, is like they're having a love affair.
Girls. Green beers.
Here we go. Green beer.
I'm good.
What?
I'm good. I'm not drinking.
You can have it.
Uh, Linda, is Saint Paddy's.
Is Ok.
I'm not gonna drink.
I'm just gonna grab a Coke from the bar.
What, are you pregnant?
What? You're kidding.
Baby, I was gonna tell you later tonight...
...but I wanted to surprise you.
You're kidding? No!
Linda's pregnant.
Shut up! Shut up! Shut up!
Turn down the music!
No more drinks for Linda.
Doubles for Jack.
He's gonna be a father!
Jack! Jack! Jack! Jack!
Jack! Jack! Jack!
Drinks are on Jack!
Drinks are on me!
Uh-oh.
Keep your money.
Save it for the baby.
Hey, you know, Jack,
you can't have a baby...
...without a shower.
Great.
Eighteen hundred block of Suffolk Street...
...between Lafayette and Harris Place.
Investigator reported smoke in the area.
Charge the line!
I'm getting too old for this shit.
You got that right.
All right, les see if this fire's walking on us.
Dennis, cut a hole in that roof.
Ray, open up that skylight.
Yes, sir.
Engine 15 to Engine 12,
uh, switch to Command channel.
This is bullshit, man.
A two-story dumpster.
Let it burn.
This whole block is vacant.
Let it all burn.
Stop your bitchin', little brother.
We'll be back next week.
Hey, Ray, I got an idea.
Why don't you stop talking
and start doing...
Ray?
Dennis!
Aah!
Man down!
Dennis!
Tommy! Get the door!
Mayday! Mayday!
Firefighter down!
Come on! More line!
I need more line!
Evacuate now!
Activate the alarm!
Come on! Evac!
Evac! Is comin' down!
I need more line!
No! We can get him!
Is no good. Is no good!
Is no good!
Yep. Marlene keeps
askin' me to come home.
She's cryin'. Thankin' God
I wasn't up on that roof.
I just wanna go home
and hold my kids.
This is it.
Les line up, guys.
I want you guys to take
as much time off as you need.
Ok?
Nothin' like this
has ever happened in this house before.
It was the beams.
Never saw a roof go down so quick.
It shouldn't have happened.
What do you mean?
He wasn't paying attention.
What? Are you saying
it was Dennis's fault?
Just shut up and wash
them dishes, rookie.
You know, you're real good
at pickin' on rookies, man.
Fuckin' asshole.
Hey! Hey!
What the hell's goin' on here?
Huh?
I come back from tellin'
a mother that her son is dead...
...and this is goin' on in my house.
In my house!
We deal with this by sticking together.
We take it.
We learn from it.
And we get back on the goddamn truck.
And thas how we honor Dennis!
You got that?
Anybody think of lowerin' the flag?
Do it.
Gathering our prayers together...
...let us pray now in the way
that Jesus taught us.
Our Father, who art in heaven...
...hallowed be Thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done...
...on Earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread...
...and forgive us our trespasses...
...as we forgive those
who trespass against us;
...and lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil.
Eternal rest grant to him, O Lord.
And let perpetual light shine upon him.
May he rest in peace.
May his soul and the souls
of the faithful departed...
Detail, present arms!
Color guard, present arms!
Detail, order arms!
Color guard, order arms!
You don't think that might fall apart?
Well, I hope not.
So I'm thinking about changing jobs.
What do you mean?
Uh, goin' to search and rescue.
Move the truck.
Does that mean you'd
be taking Dennis's place?
Oh, no, you can't think that way.
Well, would you?
Hey, Cap, this stuff is great.
Thas my grandfather.
And, uh, thas his helmet.
These are my dad's.
Thas him.
One of these he got,
uh, after he passed away.
This one.
Is a Medal of Valor.
Yeah.
So, whas goin' on?
Oh, there's something I wanted
to talk to you about. Um...
I was thinkin' about
transferring to the truck.
Well, jeez, what the hell
you want to do that for?
You're an engine man.
Truck's a whole different thing.
You know... no water
between you and the fire.
No hose line to guide you out
if you get lost in the smoke.
Is not a good idea.
Yeah, I know all that, Cap.
I love being on the pipe.
Is just...
Is just what?
Is what I want, Mike.
Well... you know, give it a try.
But you gotta tell me somethin'.
If this isn't for you, you tell me right away.
You promise?
Yes, sir.
Oh, my God.
Somebody!
Its over there.
Can you see me?
Stay down! Stay down!
We're comin' to get you!
I got this.
I'll try not to drop you.
You're not afraid
of heights, are you, Jack?
All right, lets gear up.
Number ten this side, hold your position.
Hold your position.
Do not attempt.
Here, grab this.
All right.
Check your rigs.
Put that around your leg.
Take your time.
Do your buckles.
All right, tighten that.
You got it?
Hey, Lenny, grab the rope.
Its comin'.
Here's your end.
Thanks.
Help!
All right, I got it goin' through.
You're cinched.
Make sure thats tight.
You cool with this?
Yeah.
Stay down!
You ready?
All right, hold on, Jack.
Ladder 49 to Command.
We got a man comin' over the top.
All right, Tommy, nice and easy.
Oh, God, its hot!
Try not to look down, Jack.
Thanks, Lenny.
You got it, man.
Lenny!
All right, give me a foot.
Nice and easy, guys.
No race.
All right, Tommy, let it down.
All right, hold on, Jack.
How much further?
About 25 feet.
25 feet, Tommy.
Oh, God! Oh!
We got you, Jack.
You're good.
Come on. Down!
Keep it comin'.
Uh, yeah, Bob, we're on
the scene in chopper seven.
Hey! Hey! I'm here!
Down! Down!
You almost there?
About 15 feet!
Hey! Hey, I'm here!
I'm coming for you.
Just wait!
Down!
All right, keep it comin'!
Almost!
We've got a burning building...
...in downtown on Calvert Street.
A lot of flames, a lot of smoke.
I'm right here!
Down! Down a few more feet!
No, wait! Wait!
You stay there, all right?
Wait. Wait till I'm set!
Just wait till I'm set.
Ok, stop! Stop!
All right, ho, ho, ho, ho!
Your eyes start to burn
and the heat from the flames...
Get over!
Just wait! Just wait!
Hold it, Tommy!
Hold it!
Oh, there they go!
Calm down! Calm down!
Calm down or you'll kill us!
Oh, God.
I swear to God I'll drop you.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
Close your eyes.
Put your head against me.
Ok, Ok.
All right?
I'm gonna push off this window.
Is gonna be Ok.
You just stay calm, Ok?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Stay calm.
Agh, jeez! Jeez!
Oh, God.
Oh, he shatters the glass!
They're inside now.
We're gonna try and get this guy's name.
Les go, come on!
Oh, God.
You got him?
Is he in?
Give him some slack.
He's in.
Lets get in closer, Jerry.
See if we can get in closer for a look.
He's off-line.
Hon?
Whoa, hey.
Hello.
Hey, baby.
How was your shift?
Hi, baby.
It was great.
Been drinking?
Yes, I had a few drinks with the boys.
Whats the matter?
I saw you on the news, Jack.
Linda, what is wrong?
Dangling from a rope!
How could you tell me
that its not dangerous?
I didn't say it wasn't dangerous.
When we talked about it...
I asked you,
and you said it wasn't dangerous.
I said it wasn't any more dangerous
than being on the engine.
I never said it wasn't dangerous.
Do you see me right now?
Do you?
'Cause this isn't just about us.
Have you thought about that?
Don't.
I'm sorry.
I'm scared.
I can't sleep.
I keep having that dream...
...about the red car turning up in front of
the house when you don't come home.
I'm sorry.
Don't.
I saved that man today.
Did I miss it?
They just took her to the delivery room.
Is she Ok?
She's fine.
Aah! Aah!
Hey, Chief.
Yeah, Jack, go ahead.
Chief, its getting pretty unstable in here.
I got all sorts of shit
falling down around me.
I understand.
Now, Jack, listen up.
Ok.
Can you identify anything around you?
There's a sliding access door to my left.
But I can't get to it.
There's too much debris.
Chief, the problem is every floor
eight through eleven are identical.
Well, look, if the collapse happened here,
and he's anywhere near this control room...
...if we can get him in here,
it could buy us some time.
My best guess is that he's
right about here in this area.
And if he can break through this wall
and get into the control room...
Right, right. And if my guys
can get through the debris...
...they can meet here,
and go down the back stairwell.
Might work, Chief.
Ok, now, look, Jack,
this is very important.
Right behind you there's a wall.
Behind that wall is a control room. Ok?
If we can break through that wall,
we can buy some time.
Can you do that?
I'll give it a shot.
Where do you need us, Chief?
I need two men up there on eight,
helping Ladder 17.
And I need a two-and-a-half-inch
supply line right now up on eight.
Go.
Copy that, Chief.
Ladder 49,
I need a situation report.
The progress is that
we're working on it, Chief.
I need another blade!
Sir, there's no way to tell.
Its tough.
All hands are working.
Just keep at it.
Copy. Go.
Just give me another saw.
We need a saw!
Get me a saw!
Gotta make a wish first.
I wish for a Barbie car.
No, you're not supposed
to say it out loud.
But won't I get it now?
Blow out the candles, baby.
We'll open your presents in a minute.
Yay, Katie!
Happy birthday.
Sorry I'm late.
This is for the birthday girl.
This is for Nicky.
You shouldn't have.
I didn't want him to be jealous, you know.
Thank you.
Hey, happy birthday.
What?
You want a hot dog?
You want a burger, no?
Dog-pile on Daddy.
Cute.
Very cute.
Cute?
You know what I love about this place?
Sitting here at night, watching
the romantic lights of the oil refineries.
Beauty and the Beast is a hell of a book.
Its good. I haven't read it before.
Put the kids to sleep.
Good night.
You ever consider baby-sitting full time?
What do you think I do at the firehouse?
Good night.
Night, Mike. Thanks.
You're welcome.
I think we're alone now.
You all right with that?
Yep.
Hon, shouldn't you have left by now?
Yeah, I can't find my keys.
You seen 'em?
Yeah, they're by the door,
where you left them.
Where I left them?
I left them there?
Oh, hey, Dad?
Yeah.
Can we take PJ to the game on Saturday?
Game on Saturday?
Yeah, definitely.
If its Ok with his parents, yeah.
Did you forget?
No, the guys planned a fishing trip.
I completely forgot.
I'll take him.
No, no, I want to.
Its fine.
What is it?
Its a tree.
Yeah, it is a tree, isn't it?
Its pretty.
You want to put it up on the fridge?
Show it to your mama.
Love you guys.
See ya tomorrow.
Bye, hon.
All right, buddy, I'm off.
Ok.
Whats the matter? Need tightening?
Yeah, I think so.
All right, well, I'll take a look at it
when I get back from work.
Engine 33, Engine 13...
Truck 49, Truck 16,
Battalion Chief six...
...respond to box alarm 33-4
for alarm bell sounding...
...at the BG & E Power Plant
on Broening Highway.
Units on box alarm 33-4,
alarm system is active...
...with possible steam leaks
and pipe ruptures.
Units are to exercise extreme caution.
They say the parents got to dress up.
I'm not gonna do it like last year...
...where I go looking like a fool,
'cause you got nothin' on.
Are you dressin' up?
What do you think?
Yeah, you better.
That can't be good.
Tommy, check out downstairs.
All right.
Ok, lets go. Come on.
Come on, lets go!
Cap, lets find Tommy
and get the hell outta here.
Hey! Over here!
I'm coming!
Tommy!
Hey, Jack.
Did you find anyone?
No, nobody.
Lets get the hell outta here.
Tommy!
Come on, lets go!
Lets go!
You're going in the chopper,
Tommy. Taking you to Gilford.
We got you, partner.
You're gonna be all right.
Tommy, we're puttin' you on the chopper
and taking you to Gilford!
Oh, shit.
Ok, lets go!
Ok, back off, guys.
How were they?
Angels.
Whats wrong?
I hurt myself at work.
You Ok?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm gonna go to bed.
We'll be up in a second.
Come on, Nicky.
Head upstairs and brush your teeth.
Hey, Nick, did you brush your teeth?
Whats going on? You Ok?
No fever.
You got a little tummy ache?
Hey, Dad?
Yeah.
Does steam really melt your face away?
Who told you that?
Joey Costo.
He said that Alex's dad's face
melted away 'cause of steam.
Uh, yeah, well, steam can burn your skin.
But new skin grows back in its place.
Tommy's face got burned,
but his skin will grow back.
Does it hurt?
Yeah, when it happens.
I don't want you getting hurt anymore, Dad.
Well, we're trained not to get hurt, Nick.
And long before you were
even born, I was trainin'.
But, uh, you know,
sometimes things do go wrong...
...like with me and Alex's dad.
But, you know, we're not afraid,
because we do it to save people.
You know, its worth it
to save people, isn't it?
Yeah.
And you know, if things do go wrong...
I got your uncle Mike and all
my friends at the firehouse.
You know they'd never let
anything happen to me.
Yeah.
Can you do me a favor?
Mm-hmm.
You tell Joey Costo that Alex's dad
got burned trying to save people...
...and that he's gonna be Ok.
Will you do that for me?
Hi. Can I help you?
Yeah, Tommy Drake's room.
Room five, right down there.
You're not gonna go in?
There was a nurse inside, and I thought
maybe I oughta come back another time.
No, its fine. You can go in now.
She's almost done with his dressing.
Oh, excuse me.
How's he doing?
We have him on medication
to control the pain.
He's over the worst.
Ok.
We'll leave you alone for a few minutes.
Thank you.
Jack, how are you, man?
I'm doing fine, buddy.
How are you doin'?
Doctor says I'm gonna make it.
Yeah.
You know what I have?
They put dead men's skin on me.
Marlene wants to bring the kids by...
...but I don't want her to.
Hey. Of course she wants to bring the kids.
They wanna see you.
I'm scared, Jack.
I was their hero, you know?
I was their hero.
Kids, they don't forget things like this.
I don't know, man. Maybe it would've been
best if I just didn't make it. You know, I...
Hey. Don't say that.
Don't say that.
Hey, Tommy, you know, this is one of
the best burn centers in the country.
You know?
I don't think your kids loved
you 'cause of your looks.
They miss their dad.
I don't know.
How did he look?
Good.
Is he in a lot of pain?
They're medicating him,
Linda, so, you know...
I'd like to go see him.
Why?
Because he's our friend.
Do what you want.
Are you telling me
you don't want me to go?
No, I don't want you to go.
Why?
'Cause you're gonna see him,
and you're gonna get freaked out.
Its gonna be more for you to worry about.
More for me to worry about
or more for you to worry about, Jack?
Linda, don't tell me you don't worry.
You're always talkin' about being honest.
Be honest.
Are you trying to pick a fight?
I'm not trying to pick a damn fight.
I'll tell you the job, good ones.
A big office, secretary.
Too much paperwork, though.
Oh, you have got to cheer up.
Hey, Jack, stop your pouting.
Everybody's got to work Christmas.
Ho-ho-ho!
Ah, here's trouble.
Ho! Ho-ho!
77 and a Sea Breeze, dear?
Get it? "Deer."
Whats eating you?
Hey, Santa, who is this?
Thats not Mrs. Claus.
'Cause I met Mrs. Claus,
and that is definitely not her.
Yeah, well, maybe I have to come
slide down your chimney tonight.
What the hell are you doin'?
I'm Ok. I'm Ok.
What the hell's wrong with you?
He had it comin'.
I'm gonna kick his ass!
This isn't about Lenny.
Whats wrong with you?
Huh?
Nothing.
We gotta talk. Come on,
lets get some coffee.
I kicked his ass, didn't I?
Yeah, you did.
You want anything else?
No, thank you.
Did we calm down?
So, you still love the job like you used to?
Look, you've been through a lot.
What can I say? I mean,
you lost your best friend...
...you've been through some bad fires.
You seen a lot of buddies hurt.
It festers. It does.
How are Linda and the kids?
You know, its tough.
Yeah, it is tough.
See, I never had that problem...
...because when I was married...
...my wife hated me being a firefighter.
We were divorced nine months later.
But you're different.
You're a good father.
You worry.
But you should worry.
You know, maybe its time
for a change of scenery.
Yeah, what does that mean?
Well... I was thinking...
...there's this, uh, job down at headquarters.
There's this aide's position
that I can put your name in for.
Are you saying I need to
get out of the firehouse?
Well, I'm saying that
you should ask yourself that question.
Maybe go home, talk to Linda.
You know, be honest with yourself.
There's nothing wrong with moving on.
I did it.
So, what did he say?
Mike offered to take me
with him as an aide.
What does that mean for us?
Well, I'll be home nights,
unless they call me in.
And, uh, 70 cents an hour increase in pay.
No fighting fire.
Is that what you want?
I don't know.
Um... You know?
Things have been... so crazy lately and...
You know, the kids are scared,
and I see you upset...
...and, uh, you know, its my fault.
So this is about me
and the kids again, is it?
Look, we've been married ten years.
And what you do is hard for me sometimes.
And I do get scared.
But I deal with it.
'Cause I'm proud of you, baby.
You know, Mike asked me tonight...
...if I still love the job the way I did.
And, for the first time in my life,
I didn't know what to say.
...from midnight
through the current hour...
...how this has been progressing
on into our area.
And you can see just at the midnight hour...
...in and around the immediate
Baltimore metro area...
...we already have winter storm warnings...
Man, we're gonna get six calls tonight.
Doubt it.
They're gonna bullshit all night,
you're gonna tell me.
Mm, tell you...
Firebox 13-13.
Please respond, 0-1-Charlie-1.
Engine 13, Engine 52,
Engine 8 and 6...
Lenny! Lenny!
You'll ladder up to the third floor.
I got it! I got it! Go!
Over here!
Whats going on?
Its frozen!
Our pipe's running low.
Don! Don!
We got a frozen plug.
We gotta pump it to 'em.
Comin' at ya.
You Ok?
Yes.
How old are you, son?
Nine.
Hey, buddy, where's your mom and dad?
Shopping.
They leave you alone?
I... I was with Jenny.
Who's Jenny?
My cousin.
She was baby-sitting.
Where do you live?
Which apartment? Show me.
Top one?
Hello? Fire Department!
Hello!
Fire Department!
Anybody hear me?
Hello!
Anybody there? Hello!
Hello? Hello!
Help!
Help! Can anybody hear me?
Jack!
Help!
Hey!
Right here!
Jack!
Hey, we're over here!
Right here, right here!
Grab her legs! Lets go!
Got her?
All the way down, all the way down.
All the way down.
Go, go, go, go.
One, two, three, four, five.
Go. One, two, three, four, five.
Come on, breathe.
One, two, three, four, five.
Go. One, two, three, four, five.
Go.
I got somethin'!
Good job.
Thank you.
Nice work, guys.
Jack, you're bleeding.
Huh?
You're bleeding.
Get it treated.
Your shifts over.
Merry Christmas.
Lenny!
On the night of Christmas Eve,
Baltimore firefighters...
Jack Morrison and Leonard Richter...
...entered a blazing apartment block...
...despite enormous danger to themselves...
...and saved a young girl's life.
Now, normally I'd present the medals...
...but today we have someone
more important...
...and certainly better looking:
Jenny Buckley.
Firefighter Jack Morrison.
Congratulations, Jack.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Firefighter Leonard Richter.
Come on. Come on!
Aah!
We're through!
Come on, les go!
Give me your hand.
Come on, this way!
Lets go!
We got a rebar! Come on!
Come on!
We need equipment up here!
All units report to the 11th floor now.
Jack. Its me, Jack.
Chief, I'm through the wall.
Coming down!
Oh, God!
Get down!
Is everybody all right?
Ladder 49 to Command.
We're through the debris.
And conditions deteriorating rapidly!
Ladder 49, there's a control room
straight ahead.
Jack's in there.
You keep going. Just keep going.
Jack, they're on their way.
Command, stand by.
I see a door.
I see a door!
Jack, they're getting close.
You just hang on there, Jack.
Just hang on.
Come on, guys!
There's the door.
Jack, hold on!
We're right here!
Open it up!
Hold on, Jack!
Open the door!
Come on, les go!
Close it! Close it!
Ladder 49 to Command!
The room is blast over.
We can't get in!
Its fully engulfed, Chief!
We're attempting to find
another way to get to Jack!
We have a lot of falling debris here.
We have falling debris!
We need help.
Jack, talk to me.
Mike, its too late.
Listen to me.
Its no good.
Pull 'em out.
Mike...
...tell Linda I love her...
...that I loved her from the second I saw her.
Do you hear me?
Yeah, I hear you.
Promise to take care of my kids.
Tell them that I'm always with them.
You tell... you tell them that.
You hear me?
I will.
Command to all units.
Evacuate the building immediately.
Truck 16 checking in here, Chief.
Uh, all units reporting clear.
The building's clear.
We're all out.
Copy that.
Its never an easy thing...
...saying goodbye to a brother firefighter.
Its not.
And this time particularly is difficult for me...
...because I watched Jack grow into a...
...well, into one of the finest
firefighters I've ever known.
He joined this department
because he wanted to help people.
Who knows how many homes are
still standing because Jack was there...
...or how many lives were spared?
He gave his life for that cause.
We'll never forget you, Jack.
And we're better for having known you.
But I make you this one promise:
Tomorrow, when that bell rings...
...we will be back on the truck...
...because you were
the bravest of the brave.
People are always asking me...
...how is it that firefighters
run into a burning building...
...when everyone else is running out?
Well, Jack, you answered that question...
...by saving another man's life.
Your courage is the answer.
And today we will be as brave as you...
...by not mourning you,
but by celebrating your life.
So I'd like everyone to stand up
and celebrate the life...
...of Jack Morrison.
Thank you.