No.
Not that cell. That's number thirteen.
It's bad luck.
We don't give it to anybody.
I'm not superstitious, brother.
Brother Vincent. Brother Vincent.
One of the new men
took a cell that wasn't for him.
Crimson Rivers II
Angels of the Apocalypse
Good morning.
Chief Niemans from Paris.
What brings you here?
New Year,
but we're a bit early.
Leave it to me.
We're still in shock
and we're afraid of the media.
We don't want any bad publicity.
- Neither do I.
Do they have to be here?
- Where is it?
Follow me.
Start, gentlemen.
Perform a DNA test.
Where can I wash my hands?
Nobody's going to answer.
They took the vow of silence.
This is a Montanistic monastery.
But that probably doesn't
mean anything to you.
Montanus, preacher from the second
or third century.
Congratulations.
I thought that movement had long
disappeared.
We just survived,
until the ninth century in Lombardy.
That's when Lothar II built this
this convent, our only refuge.
How many people live here?
Thirty two.
And nobody's missing?
- Nobody.
When was that wall restored?
Last week,
by two local bricklayers.
Do you have a file.
- No, we don't archive anything.
Tell me, why do your monks
have dirt under their nails?
The hardest work
is in the vegetable garden.
Especially now that the weather's
acting up.
Kevin?
Did you see the little boy
who was with me just now?
Did you see a little boy
with brown hair?
What are you doing here, boy?
How did you get there?
Thank you, sir.
You scare me.
- There's a phone call for you.
Yes? I don't want to know.
Send a theology expert.
As quickly as possible.
Fine. Thanks.
- Nothing, the DNA results came in.
He was alive
when he was walled in.
Chief, that will be our police
station.
We don't have a name.
Philippe Esaquidar.
Is that him?
That was him. Print it.
Agricultural area measure,
three letters.
Hectometre.
- Three letters.
Stop. Stop.
Won't you let me sleep?
19 hours of surveillance.
I'm trying to have some fun.
And you give me hell.
When a dealer stays away for 19
hours, something's wrong or he moved.
He doesn't live here. Only his woman.
You hurt me.
What are you doing?
- We've been in this hole for 3 weeks.
She's been alone for 19 hours.
I'll take care of it and we're going home.
Don't be stupid.
Don't do something stupid, damnit.
We've been tailing him for 6 months.
- Way too long.
Pénélope?
I don't want to bother you.
Emilio gave this address.
He said to wait downstairs.
But I've been freezing for 2 hours now.
So I thought, maybe dear Pénélope
might have coffee for me.
To get warm again.
I don't have any coffee. Only tea.
- Tea is fine too.
Sit down.
Have you known Emilio for long?
Well, I don't know... seven years.
I don't have any sugar.
- That's ok.
Thanks.
I don't know why I let you in.
Emilio doesn't want me to let anybody in.
He's always rather paranoid, isn't he?
Have you known him for long?
- We did quite a lot of business together.
If Emilio wasn't so jealous...
... I'd fuck you.
That's sweet of you.
You must be good in bed.
He's not going to do her, is he?
- Don't be stupid.
Incredible.
Will Emilio stay away for long?
He'll be right back. And you're leaving.
And I get laid.
Open up.
Where are you? Open up.
- Guys.
Did you see anybody come in?
No, nobody. Nothing's happening.
Open up.
What are you doing here, asshole?
Asshole. I told you not to let
anybody in, bitch.
Next time, I'll kill you.
Who are you, jerk? A cop?
Don't move.
Give me your hands. Your wrists.
Don't move, asshole.
Damnit. My arm.
Get up. Get up, damnit.
Go on.
Repeat that inside and in French
if you don't mind.
Philippe was my eldest brother.
He didn't drink or party.
He was the prodigy child.
Until he went crazy.
He died walled in, like
Nostradamus.
Do you know why Nostradamus
had himself walled in?
No.
So that nobody would walk over
his grave.
Do you think your brother...
Would he have asked that they...
He was crazy, but not that crazy.
He wanted to suffer like Christ.
He can't complain.
Why did you speak German before?
Why not. They buy everything here.
Every day, I get an offer
for my house.
A good opportunity to start life all
over again somewhere else, isn't it?
Why should I?
Isn't the Last Judgment approaching?
That's what my brother said.
How long had your brother been saying...
...strange things?
Ever since he met his master.
His light.
And does that light have a name?
Jesus.
Two steaks
are lost in the forest.
After a while, the first one turns
around. Nobody left.
Suddenly, the second one appears.
'Where were you, ' asks the other one.
'Hiding. '
- I don't understand.
Damnit.
Where did that jerk come from?
Are you ok? Can you hear me?
- I didn't see him coming.
Looks like Jesus. You should
stay on the crossing, Jesus.
Don't move.
- Do you think this is funny?
We're taking you to hospital.
Park your car.
Please.
- Reda...
Where are you going?
Hello, do you hear me?
Do you hear what I'm saying?
Did anybody do anything to you?
Try to calm down.
Do you want to go to hospital?
I'll take you.
I can help you.
Look, I'm a police officer.
Please. No.
- Calm down.
Call an ambulance.
Calm down. I'll help you.
Lord.
- I can help, I'm a police officer.
Father.
Open up.
Lord.
They're coming.
- Who?
They're coming. They're here.
- Who's here?
What should we do?
- That's not a nail, that's a bullet.
Call an ambulance.
What's that bullshit?
Stop it, he's in hospital.
It's ok.
Identity unknown
Good morning. Chief Niemans.
What do you want?
- I want to talk to you.
If you're looking for my husband,
he disappeared 3 months ago.
Not a word since.
Not a word, nothing.
Excuse me.
Turn off the TV, Sébastien.
I talked to Michel Esaquidar,
Philippe's brother.
A friend of your husbands.
The TV, Sébastien.
I haven't seen him in a long time,
I'm glad to say.
Philippe was found dead yesterday.
- He's dead?
In a monastery near the German border.
Go play in your room, children.
I know it would end badly.
That monastery is cursed.
Everybody in the area knew.
But they were stubborn.
Who are 'they'?
If you want me to find your
husband alive...
... you have to tell me what you know.
André got him into it.
- André who?
I don't know. And Thomas Duret.
He's a bricklayer with a local company.
But André is the brain.
Even at school he was messing
with my husband's head.
How should I put it...
He always saw Jesus in him.
My husband has a sweet face and...
Please go on.
André bought the monastery
for a song.
What did he want with it?
In the cities,
many people are drifting, he said.
He wanted to give them spirituality.
He was very religious, just
like my husband.
It may sound strange,
but they loved the people.
Real Christians.
They wanted to protect the people.
Protect them from what?
- From danger.
They were not many,
but they believed in it.
And the people felt that.
They had followers.
Until the previous owners
wanted the monastery back.
And did you know their followers?
No, just André.
I never met the others.
Do you know how many there are?
Wait a moment.
Twelve.
How is our prophet?
Very well. He sang a song all
morning, for fun.
What kind of song?
Something religious.
Almost funeral music.
Not really dance music, right?
Is that an invitation?
I'm going to visit our friend.
he must be bored all alone.
He's not alone.
There's a priest with him.
- A priest?
Father?
Father.
Come on. Breathe.
Breathe.
Don't let him go.
Close the doors.
Urgent assistance in 22.
-Don't let him leave.
Father, you can't...
Father.
Don't try anything.
Against the wall with your hands
in the air.
Mommy.
Stay there.
But...
Nobody passes.
That was the slogan of the 155th artillery regiment.
- Correct.
Were you with them?
- Not me, my father.
Are you following in your old man's footsteps?
- Something like that.
I'm here for a worker who worked here.
- Follow me, I'll allow you a visit.
150 kilometres of tunnels.
Six for the Fermont fort alone.
Back then, there were six armed posts...
... and more than 600 men...
...spread over all the tunnels of the
Maginot line.
Ok, we're here.
It's there, in the back.
- Thank you.
I'm looking for one of your
bricklayers, Thomas Duret.
Tell him I've also been looking for
him. For two weeks.
He even forgot his pay.
When did you last see him?
Easy, on a Friday night.
The seventh. Friday the seventh.
He said goodnight
and you never saw him again?
No, we left at 6.
No more Thomas.
Only his things.
- Did anybody see his car?
No, nobody.
So nobody saw him leave?
After a whole week, we won't also
spend the weekend here.
Where does that tunnel lead to?
- To Hochwald.
The next fort, but it's deserted.
Is there a way out there?
- No idea, it's at least 15 kilometres.
We're not going to walk that now, are we?
Damnit, what's that?
That door wasn't there?
- No.
Call this number
on behalf of chief Niemans.
Tell them to send a team.
They'll understand.
Damnit, Thomas.
- What do you want?
There was a phone call for you.
They found Jesus.
I don't know...
- Sometimes you have to make a decision.
Hello.
- What are you doing here?
Mathilde said
things were pretty hot yesterday.
I don't need temperatures.
You're supposed to be on guard upstairs.
Don't give me hell, Reda.
There's already a chief there.
Did he show ID?
- No.
You guard the entrance.
- I should have studied medicine.
Hey, little chief...
Be nice and turn around slowly.
Niemans? What are you doing here?
A special investigation,
who gets that?
And you? No longer at school?
- School, that's eight years ago.
And you, not retired yet?
Get my cassette recorder, will you.
What are you giving him?
C-37.
It stimulates nerve tissue
around the cortex and the memory.
Police manual, part 4, chapter 12.
Narcotics and their
pharmaceutical derivatives.
The riders...
Father... all four are here.
The seals...
They'll open the seals.
Which seals?
The dead come back...
The fifth seal has been opened.
The fifth seal has been opened...
They're coming back
for the Last Judgment...
God...
Yes, what can I do for you?
- You asked for a specialist.
Yes.
I'm a bachelor of theology with a state certificate.
The religious West
and it's modern application.
It's a pleasure to work with you.
The pleasure is mutual.
Do you only say hello
to chiefs?
Excuse me.
Captain Reda.
- Marie.
How fitting, this is Jesus. He's been
rambling about the end of the world for an hour.
When he hears your name is Maria...
He got a light sedative.
- Yes, a diluted atomic bomb.
It's all on the cassette tape.
They're here.
The angels...
... of the Apocalypse.
No sugar, correct?
Good memory.
Still scared of dogs?
- It's getting better. I've got one.
Good.
Which model? Doberman?
Bull terrier?
Yorkshire.
That's almost a guinea pig.
I hope you feed it seeds?
It would choke on dog food.
What's his name, the chief's best friend?
Well done, back then in the Alps.
- It almost went wrong.
Do you follow what I do?
The policy academy would have lost
a good teacher.
Don't flatter me.
You're no longer a student.
I made a memo for both of you.
For you, the twelve apostles.
Description, map...
For you, John's Apocalypse.
You'll be fascinated.
Can't you give me the short version?
Short?
The Apocalypse consists of seven seals
that seal the Holy Book.
Each stage contains a message
and opens a seal.
The seals Jesus referred to.
First the riders. There are four.
The fifth seal
is the resurrection of the dead...
...all in white robes.
The sixth seal is the earth
that shakes and shatters.
Then there is half an hour of silence...
... and the arrival of the seven angels
of the Apocalypse.
That guy from yesterday looked like this.
- Was he alone?
Yes...
Well, I think so.
- And finally the book.
By God's hand.
Who opens the seventh seal, can
read it and become one with him.
That's it. Fairly simple.
And our Jesus knows all this?
He's a believer. He believes that
the end of the world is upon us.
External elements must have given him
apocalyptic visions.
Like the death of his apostles?
- No doubt.
Did you find anything?
Signs on the walls
of the victims.
The signs and the names are correct.
The cross and the two loaves
for Philippe.
Carpenter's square and lance for Thomas.
It's all been staged.
Yes?
Don't touch anything.
God.
Do you buy from here often?
- Sometimes.
The bodies are in the workshop.
The customer already found them.
- She's already been interrogated.
Can I have their names?
Judas Marcherin and Simon Viarnet.
They were associates.
Can I have your notes for a moment?
Please.
Look.
What?
- It's unbelievable...
What is?
The names are correct,
but also the professions of the apostles.
Philip owned a small company,
as did Philippe Esaquidar.
Saint Thomas was a bricklayer,
like Thomas Duret.
Apostles Judas and
Peter were tradesmen.
Do you know the professions
of the seven others?
Bartholomew was a caretaker,
Matthew was a publican.
Simon the Zealot held no profession.
And the other four were fishermen.
The parrot in the picture
must be the lab's logo.
I want to know who took that picture.
Find out whether a caretaker or customs
officer have been killed recently.
Maybe they can still be saved.
You mentioned fishermen?
Why don't they just
kill them?
So the others in the picture get so
scared they won't talk.
Hello.
A glass of white wine.
- We're not in the Alsace.
A glass of milk then, is that
possible?
Cut it out, Reda.
we'll have three Lorraines.
Do you know any of these 12 people?
- No.
Nobody.
Are you sure?
- I won't repeat myself.
And if I smash up your place,
would that open your eyes?
The four on the left have a
little white cabin at the lake.
Behind the hill.
There are plenty of artificial
lakes here.
Created in the thirties and connected
by a canal.
It's like a Maginot line of water.
Saw anything?
- No. I'm just a bit tense.
Having fun, I see.
Come, I found something.
I think we're barking up
the wrong tree.
What do you mean?
- I reread your notes.
Apostles Peter, Jacob,
Matthew and John...
They didn't fish for fish...
... but for shellfish.
And here all I see are fishing nets.
There are no shellfish.
And that?
Pull it up.
How long have they been hanging there?
Half an hour.
Get help and look after Reda.
Reda...
Aren't you wounded?
- I'm ok.
There must be a secret entrance
to the turret.
There's nothing in the building plans...
... but the Germans
used it from 1940 until 1945.
We don't know what they did there.
Ask Paris about the reconstructions
performed here in 1940.
We've got the photographer.
He's the caretaker of a supermarket
and his name's Barthélémy Debernault.
And three days ago, a customs officer
was killed at an airport.
Marie, find out in which
church that picture was taken.
Reda, come with me.
In French, brother.
In French.
Of course.
Excuse me. The emotions.
Control your emotions.
Don't be so sensitive.
Of course.
Don't be too religious.
Customs officer brutally slaughtered.
Gentlemen?
- Do you know Barthélémy Debernault?
Yes, he's in the shop. Why?
Can you point him out?
- Yes.
Michel, the shop.
The bottom screen.
Barthélémy...
He quit as caretaker.
Without any explanation.
is he acting different?
- He's rather nervous.
Barthélémy was
caretaker of the shop.
What did he do?
Have the guards
block all the doors.
Quickly.
- There.
A monk.
That's not possible, damnit.
There was a monk there just now.
Is that thing working?
Niemans, do you hear me?
- Yes. Still nothing on the screens.
That's not possible. Look.
He can't have disappeared.
Aisle twelve. He's going straight
towards Barthélémy. Run, Reda.
Left, Reda.
Left.
Turn on the microphone.
Barthélémy Debernault?
Run, Barthélémy, run.
Don't lose him.
I've got him.
Complete analysis and identification.
Within 2 hours.
Shit, filthy weather.
We've got the blood analysis
from the supermarket.
Can you please sign?
What is that?
- An application for an extra vehicle.
After what you did to your
last car...
Nothing special.
No suspect substances?
- No.
That's impossible.
He can't be clean.
Or else his power truly
is supernatural.
We failed. They're dead.
Why do you always call when I'm working?
I'll call you in two hours.
Don't call me when I'm working.
Niemans.
What's happening?
What do they want?
- No idea.
And beware of those two snooping
detectives.
They won't take us by surprise again.
Good morning, gentlemen. Police.
It's six o'clock
and this is a search warrant.
Where are you going?
- Outside.
Nobody's going outside.
Heinrich von Garten, Minister of
Cultural and Religious Affairs...
... of the government in Berlin.
We said nobody.
Remove your hand.
Let him go.
One phone call from me and
you're fired.
See you very soon.
To work, men.
Search that joint.
What do we do?
- Nothing.
Did we check their communications?
- They didn't make one call.
Keep looking. We have to find something.
Nothing. We found nothing.
That's impossible. It's got to be
here somewhere.
Is that church far from here?
- Which church?
The church in the picture.
With the apostles.
Still nothing about the convent?
I found the sign
of the Montanists.
Look.
What does JEO mean?
JE or IE
is the Hebrew name of Jahweh.
In other words, the father.
EO is the son. IEO, IEO...
The Father, the Son, the Holy Spirit.
Three circles.
But I'm not sure,
because of that reverse E.
Bernard, king of Italy...
... and cousin of Louis I, who
was the grandfather of Lothar II...
... is driven out of Italy in 818...
... but takes with him the biggest
treasure from the Vatican.
Sp big that the Vatican
never confirmed it.
And where is that treasure?
With the only relative who wasn't his enemy:
Lothar I.
The father of II.
Exactly.
The strange thing is that last week, the seal
of Lothar II was stolen.
What is that seal exactly?
- Some kind of key.
To what?
To the tomb of Lothar II
and his treasure.
I have the police report here.
What did the treasure consist of?
- Nobody knows.
It's supposed to be 'the most beautiful
treasure a Christian can own'.
Where there's hate,
I'll bring love.
Where there's violence,
I'll bring forgiveness.
Where there's discord,
I'll bring unity.
Where there's error,
I'll bring truth.
Where there's doubt,
I'll bring faith.
Where there's despair, I'll bring...
- Father, please?
I wouldn't do that, Father.
We need to talk.
It's ok. Please.
Who is he?
A survivor.
- The Zealot.
Are all the others dead?
Jesus is in hospital.
Tell me what you know.
It's too late already.
We incurred the wrath of God.
The angels of the Apocalypse have arrived already.
- There we go again.
Stop your predictions.
There are no angels.
We've come to help you.
Tell us what you know.
We're discussing...
We're discussing the Great Book.
From God's hand.
When we restored the monastery...
... we found the entrance
to Lothar's grave.
And the treasure he took.
And the seal that opens the cellar?
Did you steal it?
I didn't steal it.
And I came here
to hide in my old parish.
We were the only witnesses.
The treasure can't
fall into the wrong hands.
Where's the seal?
Give me a moment.
Lay down.
Forgive me, Lord.
Unharmed?
- Yes.
Are you ok?
How did you know there was a bomb in it?
You told me I'd make a good cop.
Where are you going?
I want to study them further.
I'll return them tomorrow.
Do you think you can do anything
because you're a cop?
And you think you can take the divine
writings with you?
Are you worthy of reading them?
Who are you in the eyes of God?
Who?
- What's wrong, brother?
These are holy writings.
I'd prefer you read them
here.
Aren't you referring to the Holy Book
Lothar was supposed to have possessed?
I don't know what you mean.
Oh, no?
But for the book
you need a key.
And I have that key.
But that's impossible.
They've got it.
Or else it'll be too late.
Tomorrow, the door must be opened.
The door?
Where's the door, brother?
Where's the door?
It's mine.
Mine.
Soap.
For 2000 years you have been
selling useless stuff.
Now you can see the effect for yourself.
Take what you need.
Marie, call a doctor.
Marie, quick.
The question to the Germans...
... about the reconstruction plans
of the Maginot line.
They say it hasn't been reconstructed,
so there are no plans.
From the bureau of cultural
and religious affairs.
But that's our friend Heinrich.
Heinrich von something.
Why did the priest say the door
has to open tomorrow?
Where is that damned door?
I've got something.
I had a problem
with that reverse E.
But it's not an E.
It's a three.
The J is a seven and the O a zero.
So that makes 730,730.
And what does that number mean?
According to the Montanists,
it's the date of the Apocalypse.
To the death of Jesus, on April 7 30,
add 730,730 days...
... and you get
November 27 of this year.
In other words, today.
Shall we get changed
for the occasion?
We can just as well
sit in the front.
And the door?
Didn't you find anything about it?
- No.
According to an old text,
the treasure is protected...
... by an infallible mechanism.
He who wants to read the book, incurs
Gods lightning.
That's all I found.
Nothing about the location of the entrance.
Did you hear them yet?
The bells?
They never ring.
There's the entrance to the cellar.
In the tower.
Who's causing trouble at this hour?
Where do they all come from?
A new Europe is emerging.
A white and religious Europe,
as it should always have been.
A Europe...
- Our Europe, dear delegate.
Heinrich, your operations
have been executed masterfully.
Where do you think you are?
Nobody passes.
Silence him.
When our signal disappears,
warn the army.
I want to come along.
- You should interrogate Jesus.
And keep listening.
I'll need you.
Reda, your Apocalypse is coming.
Do you think it's deep?
We'll never have enough rope.
We're not going all the way to China.
It's a decoy for nosy visitors.
Go on, I think he's asleep.
Careful, Reda. Careful.
Niemans.
The rope is too short, I tell you.
If the monks go here,
there must be an entrance.
Niemans.
Marie, are you there?
Yes.
- He has to talk.
I've sinned.
- Do you hear me, Marie?
I know.
Marie, do you hear me?
- I hear you, chief.
We're in the Maginot line.
So the line and the monastery
are connected.
I'm losing the signal.
Of course.
There's metal everywhere here.
Marie, do you hear me?
That explains your monk with no head.
A balaclava and black around the eyes.
Apart from that, you see what you
want to see.
And this provides supernatural power.
War amphetamines.
Banned since 1945.
You feel no pain.
Your strength multiplies.
And you obey blindly.
- Makes sense that he beat me.
Cover me.
Marie, send backup.
See you soon, you said.
Welcome to the temple of Lothar II.
I was a young officer back when...
... I happened to find a part
of these subterranean tunnels.
I didn't have time to look around.
Victory had changed sides.
For years I looked in all the books...
... to find out what these tunnels were.
One beautiful day,
it became clear to me.
The treasure of the Vatican
that Lothar II had taken...
... had to be somewhere here
under the rocks.
The rest you know, I presume?
The twelve apostles found an entrance,
probably the real one.
You found out, bought the monastery...
... and liquidated the twelve witnesses.
Our Europe
doesn't care about details.
Reda...
Wake up.
Marie? We have a problem.
The Sermon on the Mount...
Nobody can serve two masters.
You can't serve God and money.
- They'll kill us all.
What does the book say?
Marie, do you hear me?
- Very poorly, chief.
The door to the tomb opens.
Tell me where the book is.
The Holy Book...
Nobody can know.
Where is it?
- Hidden.
Marie, the stone opens.
Niemans, what's happening?
What's in the stone?
Marie, the stone's open.
There's a big book.
- Gain some time. I have to think.
The year 830, the geometry...
- You die if you touch it.
Don't speak about what you don't know.
You're the one who's dying.
I'm in great shape myself.
I'm not dying at all.
- It's as certain as sunrise.
You're quite the poet.
What does he say?
Marie? Did you find it?
By opening the book,
a mechanism is activated.
The Apocalypse didn't come, as you can see.
The book is on a pedestal.
The axes, the light,
the mirrors and weights...
The first counterweight techniques.
It's activated by
lifting the book.
Don't touch the book.
It's a trap.
Without a doubt, chief.
Niemans, do you hear me?
What's happening?
Send backup to the Maginot line.
Heinrich, evacuate everybody.
- He doesn't understand. Say it in German.
Climb, climb.
Climb.
Damnit.
To the right.
Quick.
Are we in the broom closet?
Take it easy. It's a turret,
not a broom closet.
There must be a way out.
The only way out is that fucking door,
damnit.
The wheel. Turn it open.
Come on.
Shit, it's not working.
It's not working.
The amphetamine.
How fast will it work?
- No idea. Turn.
Turn.
Come on.
They're still alive.
- Good stuff.
I can run all the way to Paris.
- Don't you like Lorraine?
His condition has gotten better.
He's been lucky.
That's good news then.
After a week of holiday,
he'll be even better.
You never told me.
- What?
What the name of your dog is.
- I thought it was a good name.
He's pretty scary.
For a Yorkshire?
- Yes. I baptised him...
Reda.
Are you pulling my leg?
- No, you both have the same look.
Not really.
I was only kidding.