Riggs, you sure we're on
the right street?
We must be getting warm.
-You see anything?
-Where? l don't see anything.
This must be the place.
Holy shit!
What the hell is that?
Shit.
Who's this joker?
l don't know.
A spokesman for the NRA?
Regular asshole.
What do we do now?
Run him over.
What if he shoots us with
that assault rifle?
He hasn't yet. Maybe he won't.
What if he does?
Don't be a Don't-Bee.
Be a Do-Bee. Be positive.
Positive?
-Let's run him over.
-Glad you see things my way.
l hope he doesn't turn.
He won't. We'll creep up on him
so he won't notice.
We'll creep?
Will him not to turn.
Power of positive thinking.
Don't turn.
Will him with me.
-Will him?!
-Don't turn around.
-l need you, man.
-Don't turn around!
That's it. Believe!
Don't turn around!
We're better than him. We're better!
We're better!
-Don't turn!
-He's turning.
-They just bounce off him!
-l saw!
We're in trouble, man.
Shit! l'll draw his fire!
You run for cover!
No, l'll draw his fire!
Are you out of your mind?! You got
a wife, kids. l got less to lose!
Go! Get out of here!
l wasn't supposed to tell you, but
Lorna's pregnant. You'll be a father!
What'd you say?
You'll be a father!
She was afraid to tell you.
She was afraid you'd get angry.
You never talked about children?
-Shit!
-A baby.
There's something l'm not
supposed to tell you too.
Rianne's pregnant. You're going
to be a grandfather.
Rianne's what?!
Rianne can't be pregnant.
She's not married.
l don't think she intended
to get that way.
They asking me to be a granddaddy?
Here's what we'll do.
Take your clothes off!
What the hell for?
Okay, you run.
Flame-O turns, sees you in your undies.
lt distracts him. That's when l shoot.
-Shoot what?
-The valve on that napalm tank!
Before he shoots me?
-Maybe.
-Maybe?
ls he black?
Too much armor on.
l can't tell!
No! Not him! The father of the baby!
Please let him be black!
Get going! Here he comes!
Are those little hearts?
Not now, Riggs.
Just hit the damn valve!
Also, flap and make noises
like a bird!
Flap my arms? Why?
lt'll distract him more!
l need him to turn!
-On 2! Ready?
-On 2? We always go on 3!
No time for 3! Go! 2!
-What about 1 ?
-All right. 1 , 2, go!
l don't want to die in my underwear!
Why are you waiting?
Shoot the bastard!
Riggs, you think that bird thing helped?
You think it helped?
l just wanted to see if you'd do it.
Cute shorts.
Go spit, Riggs!
l'll buy you a doughnut.
Don't put your arms around me
when l'm naked.
You're ashamed of your butt?
He's a lively one.
That shark damages my boat,
l take it out on you, Leo.
-l didn't mean to catch it.
-Why do you want to keep it?
Yeah, why you want to keep a shark?
-The teeth'll look great on a wall.
-They got to stop snapping first.
Maybe he'll fall asleep.
Engage him in conversation.
He'll nod off.
-He don't look tired.
-Maybe chewing on Leo will wear him out.
You think sharks eat their own kind?
Stop! You guys got me in stitches!
Okay, where's my bag?
Starboard side aft.
Starboard, that's left, right?
-No, port's left. Starboard's right.
-Yeah, right.
Right, yeah. Right side aft.
Got it. Okay.
-Whatever.
-Check both sides, you'll find it.
Careful!
Behind you, shark!
Maybe we should throw him overboard.
Throw them both overboard.
No witnesses. We could probably
get away with it.
-You too?
-Yeah.
l kept my nose out of it, but....
You and Lorna.
You're having a baby,
you're living together.
You're not getting married.
Why, does that violate your
family values system?
l'm just trying to understand.
Rianne's not married either.
Okay, that's hitting below the belt.
You know, when l was married...
...it was good. You know.
You put the ring on.
You make the commitment.
You do all the....
She's dead because l'm a cop.
She's dead because l'm a cop and l....
l don't wear the ring anymore but
l look down, it's still there.
l still feel it...
...and l don't know,
it's like l'm not...
...finished with that yet. l don't know
how to explain that. ls that bullshit?
No. lt's not finished.
lt's not finished.
Okay, you did say ''aft.''
A-F-T. Aft!
That's a fucking word?
ln the back of the cabin
on the right side!
Why didn't you just say that
to begin with, Roger?!
l love these people. Get around boats
and water, everything becomes nautical!
''Astern! Avast, you landlubbers!
Man the bilge pump!''
Pump your fucking ass!
All right, all right!
-Get a grip.
-Okay, okay, okay.
No problem. No problem. Okay, okay.
-What does Lorna say about this?
-She doesn't like nautical terms either.
We haven't discussed it.
That's pretty messed up.
The baby's due in a few days and you
haven't talked about getting married?
No.
l haven't done it at all.
-Do we want Leo to shoot the shark?
-l do want Leo to shoot the--
No, Leo!
What?!
-Give me that.
-What's the deal?!
You're shooting a gun on my boat!
l'm not shooting your boat,
l'm shooting Jaws.
Nobody's killing it.
l won't let it die so
you can have its teeth!
So grumpy since you
learned you'll be a grandpa.
Get off of me, will you?
Don't fool around!
Some piece of hardware.
Got a permit for this?
-Of course. l'm a Pl now.
-A ''P'' what?
Pl! A gumshoe! You get in ugly
situations. l got guns, everything.
You are an ugly situation.
Permit or not, you don't deserve this.
You're not safe.
Smart move, Riggs.
Shit!
Hard right, Rog!
Did you hear shots?
Coast Guard, this is Code 7.
We're in L.A. Harbor.
We got to go.
They're getting away!
Who was it? We know who it was?
No, no, l'll drive!
-Want me to help?
-Get out of here!
This your gun?
Yeah, want some laser surgery?
Watch it! You could blind somebody!
Coast Guard, this is Code 7
in pursuit of freighter.
Heading north.
Awaiting instructions. Over.
Code 7 , maintain your present course.
We have a cutter en route.
Why you slowing down for?
We'll hang right here.
Coast Guard'll be here any minute.
-What do we do now?
-Show them our badges.
LAPD!
Los Angeles Police Department!
We heard gunfire!
The Coast Guard's on the--
Coast Guard! Boat's on fire!
Freighter's on fire!
-Let's board them.
-What are you talking about?!
There's a fire on the freighter!
Okay, l'm upside. Now what do we do?
They're trying to get away.
Get up there!
One hell of a fishing trip.
Shut up and keep your head down!
LAPD!
Stop where you are! You!
Hold it there!
He's got it!
What'd he say?
He said, watch his back!
-Why didn't you warn me?
-Shut up!
Tie it up!
Pull it out!
That was great.
l told you to keep the boat closer!
Why are you listening to Leo?
Oh, shit!
You all right, Riggs?!
Look at that!
Oh, shit!
Jump!
Roger, where are you?!
My boat!
My new boat!
-What?
-The shark.
What about the shark?
A shark!
Don't leave me! Rog!
Come on, Leo!
-Hurry up!
-l'm coming!
You can make it!
This is all l got left.
Four sets of papers, totally genuine.
They'll get in the country
and be able to stay forever.
U.S. citizens.
Ask them to vote the incumbent
party, help me...
...keep my job with the
State Department.
Bloody marvelous.
They've red-flagged Asian visas lately.
Those weren't easy to slip through.
Something wrong?
A small delivery problem, Mr. Proody.
Leave!
Coast Guard interdicts
about one a month.
Pretty raggedy-looking.
Six weeks locked in a hold
with one toilet.
Rice and a little fish to eat.
Lousy deal for 35 grand a head.
35 grand? Where'd they
get that money?
Didn't. Got to work it off from
the snakeheads, the smugglers.
-They sell them as cheap labor.
-Sell them?
Like slaves.
l guess these must be the lucky ones.
They'll claim asylum. Say they were
persecuted, like everybody else.
We'll send them packing.
Cost you and me a goddamn fortune.
What happened to, ''Bring me your tired,
your poor, your wretched masses...
...yearning to be free''?
Now it reads, ''No vacancies.''
l guess your parents
were Native Americans.
They pop one every boatload.
Shows the rest what'll happen
if they run or don't pay.
At least he's nobody's slave.
Don't coddle them, move them!
We're on the boat, l see
this barrel coming down.
Sergeant Murtaugh didn't see it,
so l push him.
He's big, l knock him over.
We're in the water.
l'm pulling, he doesn't swim.
l saved this big guy.
There's that kid.
What's his name? Bissell?
lt's a food.
Burger.
No, Biscuits or something.
He's always kissing my ass,
giving me coffee and shit.
Sergeant Riggs, Sergeant Murtaugh.
What are you doing here?
That's a long story.
You're all wet!
-You need a blanket?
-l'm fine.
-Somebody get this man a blanket now!
-Blankets, yes, sir!
Get this body out of here!
Hold up! What do we got here?
Stay back, stay back.
Shit!
He's dead. He's fucking dead, man!
-Shit!
-What?
This is how he wanted to
come to America, right?
Was he in the killing section?
This guy's been shot four times!
At close range, like he was executed!
He was executed.
By the crew.
What the fuck!
People get killed left,
right and center in this town!
Now we're importing victims?
Gangbangers want to kill
each other, no problem.
One of us gets shot,
occupational hazard.
But just a normal guy? What the
fuck did he ever do to anybody?!
-That ain't right.
-Easy, Biscuits.
You'll get an ulcer.
You got to settle down.
Blanket!
l thought it was....
Sorry, Blankets.
-Here's blankets.
-Sorry, l'm losing my head.
l just hate to see bad things
happen to good folk.
We'd shoot the breeze with you, Butler,
but you're in charge here so--
You should take this, it's free.
You're all wet.
Get some vapor rub on your chest.
All right, Boogers.
Hey, get them out of here!
Get them out of here!
He takes the job kind of personally.
Personally? Yeah, he's pretty serious,
l'd say. Overzealous.
He's jealous of who?
l don't know. Who?
-You said he was jealous.
-l didn't.
l was standing here!
l said he was zealous. Full of zeal.
-He's loud too. Shit.
-What?
-He's loud!
We better get up before
the sun comes up.
Something's in the lifeboat.
-l'll catch a squad ride.
-See you.
l'm sorry about your boat.
-l'm sorry.
-Shit.
All of a sudden, this big
fucking shark comes--
Can l say that?
You can say it, but we can't air it.
So this big darn shark comes along....
Shit.
My Code 7.
Oh, God.
-You were coming home last night.
-l'm sorry.
l had some bad Chinese.
You look a little banged up.
You look a little knocked up.
Are you okay?
You sure?
-Easy, tiger! There he goes again.
-She. There she goes again.
-You okay, though?
-l'm good.
Better than Roger. His boat sank.
-Boat sank?
-l had something to do with it.
-Here, boy.
-No! No grease!
-Have some cookies.
-What happened?
Gunfights, explosions, sharks.
The usual.
Here, boy.
Thanks.
You were out fishing.
Does trouble just go looking for you?
lt seems to know pretty much
where l am most of the time.
Oh, God.
You finished the nursery.
Yeah, l did.
l figured it was good for a girl
or a boy. Cute, huh?
lt's a dogfest. What'd you get,
the whole 1 0 1 ?
l know. l got a little
carried away with puppies.
lKid'll probably hate dogs.
You know, Lorna, we never ever
talked about marriage.
l sort of figured you didn't want that.
You want to get married?
Me neither.
You want breakfast?
''Serve and Protect''
Since when have you been
reading this smut?
lt's not smut. lt's Ebony Clark.
-Trish gave it to me.
-''Every fiber in his being desired her.
He devoured her with his eyes.''
Can we try this thing
on page 1 96 sometime?
There's a good one on 1 68. Maybe later.
Nothing comes between
a pregnant lady and a meal.
Have l ever ''made your...
...womanhood reach peaks that would
rival the highest Himalayas''?
-Foothills of Malibu, maybe.
-But not even a Teton or...?
-l don't think so.
-Thanks.
l thought l'd at least rate the Rockies.
You know l'm kidding.
You're saying that to
make me feel better.
No, l'm not.
You know l'm playing.
l've been to plenty of
mountaintops with you.
lt's just that l'm hungry.
When you have that kid,
we'll blow up Mount Saint Helens.
-l brought you a doughnut.
-Police food.
How did you know?
l dropped by lnternal Affairs yesterday.
How's the rat squad?
-l picked up something good.
-Some cheese?
lA got an anonymous tip.
The person said Roger's on the take.
No, he's not.
l know he's not. lt's probably
some jerk he put away.
But with the new boats...
...and putting 2 kids through college,
l just thought you ought to know.
l actually tried to persuade him
to take money.
Stop it, Riggs! l can't hear that.
Nothing.
l won't say anything anymore.
l'm kidding.
-That's awful.
-l'm kidding.
Don't tell him l said that.
With all his problems...
...he'll blow his top. lt'll be awful.
Just don't say anything.
What do you mean?
Like what?
-ln general, problems.
-You mean something specific.
l got a nose for these things. What?
You're pushing me. l really don't
want you to go there.
Get it off your chest.
You'll feel better. Tell me.
l'm not going to leave
you alone. Tell me.
-Tell me.
-l'll tell you what it is!
This pregnancy destroyed my brain cells!
What? What?
l'm drooling. What?
Promise me. Swear to me you'll
never say a word about this, ever.
-l swear, l swear.
-Right hand!
l swear l won't, ever.
l promise. What?
You know how Roger is about
his daughter dating cops?
He'd kill them. So?
Rianne's married to one, the father of
her baby. She's afraid to tell Roger.
They met last year. They fell in love.
She got pregnant. They got hitched.
Nobody's telling Roger about this?
After the baby's born.
You mean it's a package deal?
Take it or leave it?
-Does Trish know?
-She knows.
She doesn't know you know.
But Trish knows.
Who's the lucky soon-to-be-dead
son-in-law?
-Who?
-Sergeant Lee Butters.
This gets better and better!
No wonder he sucks up to Rog.
Brings him apples, blankets, coffee....
Not a word. l'm telling you, nothing.
l won't tell him anything. He'd shoot
me just for being the messenger.
He's my best friend. lt'd be wrong to
mess with him. l won't mess with him.
Promise.
l don't think we have to discuss boys'
names because we're having a girl.
Okay. Piadora.
l like Piadora. That's sweet.
-l can't live with that.
-l love that name.
-Wilford.
-lt's the oatmeal guy.
We're talking kids' names.
Has Rianne picked any names out yet?
We don't want to double up or anything.
Oscar for the boy,
Loreen if it's a girl.
l like Lee Butter.
Better! l like it better.
-Don't get me started.
-l like those names.
Captain wants to see us downtown.
Trish'll be right down. Have fun
shopping for the baby.
Bye-bye, honey.
Who had the sleepover?
Just airing out camping gear.
-We're out of here.
-Something smells good.
Really good.
Trish has food on the stove.
We out of here.
That smells like Chinese food.
Chinese food?
She's into Chinese cooking.
l got to see this. Can l taste?
-l love Chinese food.
-Hold it! Please!
Please!
There's a Chinese person in the kitchen.
l saw him.
A couple of Chinese people.
Actually a whole family.
A large family.
Hey, guys.
-lt does smell good, huh?
-Smells great.
They were hiding in the lifeboat.
After that lNS guy,
l had to do something.
-l know. So you brought them home.
-lt took two trips.
-Really?
-They fit in the station wagon?
That's Ping with his grandfather, Hong.
He's head of the family.
Speaks English.
Hey, Hong. This is my partner,
Martin Riggs, and this is Lorna.
Wife?
Can l speak to you?
-Lorna, this is the best breakfast.
-l'm hungry. l'd love some.
Are you out of your mind?
This is illegal.
As in, ''against the law.''
You'll bring on a shitstorm.
Just hold on!
Just wait a frigging minute!
The way l see it, those are
slave ships out there...
...and l'm freeing slaves.
l'm freeing slaves like
no one did for my ancestors.
This is my chance to do
something and do it right.
Why didn't you say so?
This is not going to be boring.
Need any help?
Where is he?
What is it, food or money?
-Food and money.
-More money than food.
l see you more now than
when you lived here.
-We're independent now.
-What'll you spend the money for?
-Hookers, drugs....
-Contraceptives.
Can you believe how they
talk to their father?
lt costs more to go to school now
than it did when you went.
Go to school now!
l get the tuition bills.
And the grades too. Consider this a
down payment on a future ass-chewing.
Now get out of here and go to school.
l want to see grades!
l see the tuition.
l want to see some grades, okay?
l want more cluck for my buck.
Thank you for the money.
l'm tired.
Me, l can't win.
Boy.
Say, we get a raise and
nobody told me about it?
l got to get to the bank.
How can you when you're taken
to the cleaners all the time?
Hey, guys.
Hey, babe.
-Both the kids leaving?
-Yes. And we're broke.
ls Lorna here?
She's in the kitchen.
On her third breakfast by now.
l remember those days.
-l'm sorry!
-You know l love it when you do that.
You look terrific.
Wait till she tries raising
that baby by herself.
Daddy, l'll be fine.
Move back in and old Grandpa Rog'll
be up all night taking care of the baby.
Better than her marrying the wrong guy.
You know, a cop or something.
True.
Come on, guys. See you.
l should say goodbye.
Hurry up!
Yeah, stuffing your face.
Stop kissing me. Try that. Try that.
You, stay away from my girl.
l'm not joking.
You stay away from my girl.
Joking!
Got the baby beeper?
-All right, l know.
-lt's your fault.
lt's your fault. All the chicken shit.
Flapping all over the place.
All right, everybody.
lt's been a year almost already.
This shit ain't funny no more.
-Enough is enough!
-Please!
Okay? Enough!
l'm the one that gets it in the neck.
Can we exercise a little maturity?
lf l find who's doing this,
l'll kick his ass.
Who's doing this? l catch that asshole
who put my picture up there, that's it.
-That's it.
-Cut their balls off.
Captain.
l still look out there expecting
to see all the old faces.
lnstead, l see a bunch of kids whose
names l barely remember.
-Will you sit down?
-Sorry.
We're dinosaurs headed for extinction.
Speak for yourself.
We're making way for the
new police force:
Guys with guns and psychology degrees,
like Butters out there.
Biter has a psychology degree?
-More like a psycho degree.
-Times have got to change.
l once got shot by a hot rodder
with a zip gun.
That's how far back l go.
You wanted to see us?
Some things don't change.
-Here we go.
-The department lost its insurance.
All the damage you've done,
they can't get a new one...
...while you two still run around
on the streets.
They can't fire you either.
So...
...they're promoting you.
Lieutenant.
There's no open lieutenant spots.
So the chief's using a special privilege
and making you captains.
-Better.
-Captain!
Time was when this would send me over
the falls. l swear, l'm getting old.
So what do we do now?
Captain shit.
-Hang out.
-Take long lunches.
Yell things like,
''Riggs, Murtaugh, l'm the captain.''
-''Chief's shitting bricks, man.''
-You finished?
Think you can stay out of trouble?
Something simple?
Absolutely.
Captain Riggs.
Captain Murtaugh.
You want your badges?
Let me see those sergeant badges.
Throw them over here.
Let me have yours.
This is the most painful
experience of my life.
-Now get out of here.
-Thank you, Captain.
-No, Captain, after you.
Enough with the ''Captain'' shit!
Get out of here!
l insist. After you, Captain, l insist!
''O Captain! My Captain!''
-Captains outrageous!
-News travels.
You get a break from real police work.
Play golf, tennis....
They got brown rings
Around their noses
Now that you're captains,
come up in the chopper.
-Not for me.
-l'll take a raincheck.
-lf you change your mind, call us.
-He's a down-to-earth guy.
l'm sorry.
Can we knock this shit off, please?
This is your captain speaking.
Jesus.
The man's got feelings, you know?
Congratulations. Look at you.
Captain Murtaugh.
l don't really know how to say this,
but you really inspire me.
lKeep it up.
How's it going, Burton?
-lt's Butters, Captain.
-l'll remember that.
-lKid really likes you.
-l wish he'd cut that shit out.
He likes me?
Likes me.
You don't think he...
...likes me-likes me...?
Likes me like that?
lt's the police force
not the military.
The millennium's creeping up on us.
You know what the captain said:
''New people, new department.''
Dr. Woods?
Captain Riggs.
-Don't run.
-l'm in a rush.
-l need to talk to you.
-Wait! What is it this time?
Recurring dreams about flying dwarfs?
Or have you cooked up something new?
l'm sorry about all that.
l want your advice.
l was thinking of....
Thinking?
Marriage.
Marriage?!
-The ''M'' word?
-Does ''confidentiality'' mean anything?
-That's funny.
-lKeep it down.
You know what would happen?
We'd go into my office...
...and you know what you'd
end up telling me?
You'd tell me something like, ''Doc...
...l want to marry Murtaugh.''
Or your mother, maybe.
Or how about Nelson Mandela?
Nelson Mandela?!
Something to ridicule me, Riggs.
Something to get a rise out of me.
Listen carefully!
l'm...not...stupid!
And my time is reserved...
...for police officers with
real needs and real problems.
Have you got that?!
-Have you?!
-Ask me again?
No. And you know what?
l don't like you.
Stephanie?
l can't go out with you.
l'm in a relationship.
All right?
l think you need to see someone.
You'll find someone someday who'll love
you. Not in this department but....
-You have to stop bothering me!
-You're disgusting!
What's the matter with you people?!
What's shaking?
-Captain Riggs.
-Captain Murtaugh.
You're supposed to turn around.
We're captains.
Heard you're up to your ass
in Chinese.
The taller ones come up to the navel.
Big enough to kick your ass.
What can l do for you?
One of the ship's crew shot an illegal,
apparently under orders...
...and we'd dearly like to know...
...who's smuggling Chinese?
We got no hard evidence but we're pretty
sure the big boss is Benny Chan.
Uncle Benny?
You know him?
-When he was running smack.
-We never nailed him.
Benny's slippery.
Where's he hang out?
He's got a nightclub,
couple restaurants.
He operates mainly out on
North Broadway. Here's the address.
Hi, fellas.
There he is. Hey, Burger. Summers.
Butters!
What you got on the freighter homicide?
l talked to some illegals. Turns out
they only knew the shooter by sight.
Checked out the boat.
The boat is registered under a dummy
corporation out of lndonesia.
lt'll be a rough one to crack,
but we'll nail them.
You ever hear of Benny Chan?
Benny Chan. No.
What kind of bad man is he?
Real bad. Big crime boss in Chinatown.
lf it's dirty and it's Chinese,
Benny's doing it.
So where do l find him?
At his restaurant.
l'm kind of hungry for Chinese.
How about you?
We're going there anyway.
We'll drive you.
Just let me get my jacket.
Not with him.
-He's doing good.
-l know.
We might need backup. Spend some time
with him. You might learn to love him.
Like a son.
ln-law-enforcement.
lt pays to know your fellow officer.
He might have to back you up one day.
Sir, let me just say, it'll be an honor
to share some egg rolls with you.
Yeah, all right. Let's go.
Let's go.
Share?
So, Butters, it seems like you hate
crime in a sort of personal way...
...if you don't mind me saying.
Why so you say that, sir?
Last night l noticed you were,
let's say, more than slightly miffed.
-Wasn't he, Roger?
-Hell, yeah.
Any particular reason?
About 1 50,000 of them.
That's how many bullets were zinging
around my neighborhood growing up.
Couldn't go outside.
Couldn't go near a window.
Lived on the floor, ate on the floor,
slept and watched TV on the floor.
l didn't learn to walk till
l was 1 0.
Spent most of my formative years
nose-to-nose with the family beagle.
When l'm working on a crime...
...l ain't thinking about the crime.
l'm thinking about that goddamn
floor and it pisses me off.
We supposed to be
meeting Leo somewhere?
No, why?
Because he's following us.
Don't look.
Who's Leo?
Maybe it's a coincidence.
-What does he want?
-l don't know. Let's find out.
-Fucking asshole!
-Bite me!
Bite me, okay? Whatever! Whatever!
Jerk!
You looking for us, Leo?
-You saw me, huh?
-Yeah, we saw you.
What you doing, Leo?
l'm perfecting my tailing technique
now that l'm a Pl.
He's a private eyesore.
Nice inconspicuous vehicle.
l like it.
Riggs, who's the perp?
-What'd you bust him for?
-l'm a perp?
A young brother in a police car is
automatically a perp?
Look at my suit! My tie! Do l look
like the Crips' accountant?
Look at this badge, bitch!
Check out the gun.
-License! Registration!
-Put the gun down!
License! Registration!
Urine sample!
l got a badge too, okay?
German Jews didn't have it any
easier as kids!
So don't think you're the only one.
Besides, l knew you were a cop!
l was kidding!
l can smell a cop a mile away!
You saying l smell bad?
Don't turn everything around!
You're so touchy.
These guys'll tell you.
We got a history.
Maybe we'll work together someday!
l'm the bomb! They'll tell you!
We'll work together soon as l open up a
cereal shop, you fucking leprechaun!
l didn't call you names, fuckface!
Don't start!
Okay?! Don't fool around!
These guys'll tell you.
Sir, you're double-parked.
Officer, l'm just talking
with the detectives.
We don't know this guy.
Think he was drinking.
They're kidding. Come back!
l wasn't drinking!
They just said that.
Blow your breath in my hand.
Now hold on, l can smell it already.
Blow in my fucking ear!
No, you're all mine.
-You're mine.
-Whatever.
Where's Uncle Benny?
-He's not here.
-ls he in there?
-l'm sure he is.
-This way.
Yes, it's a two-way.
Look, please. We have 3 people.
The restaurant's over there.
Let's go this way, please.
They can see us, but we can't see them.
-Where's your green card?
-That's a racist remark.
l'm a policeman who asked
you about your green card.
This is not the way.
You're the boss till we
get up in his ass.
lt'll be fine. They've refurbished.
-l couldn't stop them.
-How you doing?
-Out, out!
-Can l get some drink or food?
Uncle Benny, l hope this is a bad time.
He still hasn't clipped his eyebrows.
What'd we tell you about that?
We hate not disturbing you.
-This is Detective Buckles.
-Whatever.
Sell any heroin? Buy any cops? lKill
anyone lately? How's the restaurant?
Have something to eat.
Give you the police discount.
-Flied lice?
lt is fried rice, you plick!
l'm very busy. What is it this time?
Tell him, Buttkiss.
lKnow anything about a boatload of
illegals that went aground last night?
Just what l saw on the news.
Some snakehead lost big money.
400 people at 35 grand.
Fourteen million.
And missed out on making them slaves.
You are cops. l thought smuggling
Chinese was an lNS problem.
We found 3 bodies full of holes,
so now it's a cop problem.
Three dead Chinese?
Billion more where they came from.
That's right. Life's cheap.
The problem is, he shot at me and Rog
too, and that pisses us off.
Too bad they missed.
But still l don't know
anything about it.
Who's he?
Doesn't look too happy.
What's his name?
Who's this guy? ls he appraising
your furniture, or what?
He doesn't speak English.
Then he doesn't understand words
like ''scumbag'' ...
...''eat shit''?
l think he understands good.
-Enter the drag queen.
-The insurance, remember?
l'm busy.
lf you have nothing on me, get out.
Just know we're still around.
l'm on your ass too.
But the door is this way!
This is quicker.
This is quicker, really.
See? lt's quicker!
Don't forget my
1 0% policeman's discount.
You in Hong lKong...
...you'd be dead.
No, not that! No, Riggs! Don't!
The insurance....
What the hell?
Hurry up! Hurry up!
You got to try it sometime. Not only
is it satisfying, it's therapeutic.
-lt saves the cost of a shrink--
-And bad guys can't call the cops.
-Why not? We're already here!
-El Nio.
l know this guy.
That's the captain.
Hold it!
Remember, no damage!
Shit!
l'm LAPD. l'm commandeering
your bike. Here, here.
$200.
Riggs, l'm coming!
Somebody stole your bike!
Stop!
Police!
Move out of the way!
-Butler! Chase the fast one!
-What do you have, Alzheimer's?!
Stop! Freeze!
Stop, you Chinese motherfucker!
Halt!
Clear out the way! Police!
Riggs! He's getting away!
Excuse me! Out of the way!
Get down! LAPD!
Stop, you little shit!
Get down! Get down! Get the fuck down!
My arm!
l didn't do anything!
l got you covered down here!
You got the right to remain silent!
So shut the fuck up, okay?!
You got the right to an attorney.
lf you can't afford an attorney...
...we'll provide you with the dumbest
fucking lawyer on Earth!
lf you get Johnnie Cochran,
l'll kill you!
Riggs, don't jump!
You're going to be a father!
Don't jump, damn it!
Hold on!
Hold on! l got you!
Don't move!
Okay, l won't move!
Hold on! l got you!
You'll catch me?
No, l'm not going to catch you!
l got a dumpster here!
You didn't do nothing,
why you running?
-Get over here!
-Shit!
Hurry up!
Come on, come on!
Hold on, Riggs!
A bit more to the left, will you?
Stop right there! Now! Now!
No, the other left!
Make up your mind!
You couldn't find something smaller?!
This is all l could find!
Hey, l got it here!
Now, you jump! On 3!
Ready?
Ass first! lt breaks the fall!
One!
Two! Three! Son of a bitch!
You all right?
l should have had him.
Damn right, you should have!
Who's your partner?
-Son of a bitch!
-l don't have a partner!
The guy you ran with!
l'm a waiter. And then you guys
pull a gun, trying to kill me!
And you physically abuse me!
l want my lawyer!
You ain't no waiter! lf you're
a waiter, what's today's special?
What's today?
Wednesday!
Chicken and sweet and sour pork,
barbecue spareribs--
Shut up!
Next time, don't run!
-Stay still!
-l should've got him!
Johnnie Cochran!
He fight for me!
Mao began helping in the fields
when he was 6 years old.
He led a rebellion early
against his domineering father.
Finally, Mao left home to
continue his schooling.
Those were troubled times. Old China
dissolved in a welter of unrest....
Sorry, Sergeant Murtaugh.
No, no, no, sit, please.
And it's Roger.
lt's your chair.
No, sit down, really. lt's fine. Sit.
Want something to drink?
Tequila?
Thank you so much.
From Mexico.
This can't be the first time
you had tequila, Hong.
Yes, yes.
Bread.
Toast, toast!
Yeah, yeah, toast.
Bread!
You know anybody here?
My uncle.
He pay so we can come to America.
You been in contact with him?
l leave message.
What's your uncle do?
ln China...
...he's artist.
An artist?
lt ought to be tough
leaving home, huh?
ln America...
...my children have chance
to make good life.
We want the best for our children.
And our grandchildren!
You believe l'm a grandfather?
That's right! Little Ping!
You're a grandpa!
Where does the time go?
Don't know.
Have no watch.
You have no watch?
Here.
This is my pop's. Here, take it.
He got it when he retired
from the force. Here.
No, no. No, l cannot.
l want you to have it.
lt belonged to a good man.
lt ought to belong to another good man.
Thank you so much...
...Roger.
Shit!
Hold him!
Push him off!
Get him!
What's wrong?
-Are you okay?
-lt's the shoulder.
lt's an old shoulder injury. l'm going
to have to toss in the towel.
-No problem.
-lt happens periodically.
-ls he okay?
-l was just getting going too.
You're lucky, kid.
-You're lucky he didn't kill you.
-You owe me a rematch!
-Anytime you want.
-l might even train for it.
Better bring your own paramedic too.
-l'll get some ice for that shoulder.
-The shoulder's okay.
There's nothing wrong with my shoulder.
l was faking it.
Faking it?
Gomez was killing me out there.
l didn't have anything left.
l told you that kid was good.
He's good but it's not all him.
l mean, l've been feeling it lately.
You know the other....
Like the other night on the ship
when that guy nailed me.
And yesterday l couldn't catch him.
l just thought, you know,
l'm out of shape or something.
You know. But it's more than that.
lt's like....
-l hate to say this but--
-You're getting too old for this shit.
How about that?
Finally.
No, but l can't be. l mean,
l'm only....
-Jesus.
-Yeah, you're only.
Can't beat the clock, Riggs.
Murphy's right. We're dinosaurs.
What am l going to do?
Accept it.
Like l do.
No. Bullshit.
Bullshit. l won't accept it.
-l'll will it not to happen.
-Will it? You're going to will it?
l'm not too old for this shit.
We're not too old for this shit.
We're not too old for--
Say it like you believe it.
We're not too old for this shit.
l'm not going to buy
a hemorrhoid cushion.
-l'm not going to get corns!
-l got corns!
-l'm not wearing a suit!
-What's wrong with a suit?
How's it going, Captain?
Thanks a lot, you guys.
Very funny.
That cop tried to strip-search me!
-You get his phone number?
-Funny.
Sugar-glazed with jelly.
Thanks, Leo.
-What happened? The scratches.
-A dog.
-A dog?
-Catch you drinking out of his bowl?
l'm working on an important Pl case.
Did the dog hire you?
No, the dog didn't hire me.
The people that lost the dog hired me.
Sounds like a big case.
lt is a big case, Mr. Big Shot,
for all you know.
lt's an expensive dog.
-A Bolshoi.
-Borzoi.
Whatever, whatever.
And you found it, huh?
Sort of. Okay, listen to what happens.
lnstead of going around town looking
for a dog, l went to the pound.
l take the dog home. l dye the dog,
it looks exactly like their dog.
Dog was a real rat, though.
He scratched me.
But l got the job done.
Some kind of Pl business
you got there.
Douche Ventura, pet infective.
lt's grand theft.
-What is?
-With trickery and device, felony.
lt is?
You guys are always kidding.
Whatever. l get it.
Here comes that touchy kid.
l'm not here.
What, Putter?
The guy you chased?
The gun he dropped matched slugs on the
bodies on the boat. He's your shooter.
Son of a bitch got away from me.
He didn't get far.
They found him on a rooftop nearby.
Strangled. And get this:
Pigeons ate his eyeballs.
Cool.
Excuse me.
Shit! l hate these fucking phones!
You get a call, they cut you off.
You make a call, they cut you off.
What's the point?
Don't you know what they're doing?
They fuck you with cell phones.
They're fucking you with the cell phone.
They love when you get cut off.
Because when you call back,
they charge you...
...for that first minute again
at that high rate.
lf you're able to call back...
...because the 3-hour battery you
got only lasts 20 fucking minutes.
lf you're behind a hill, it goes....
Or you're going through a damn tunnel.
And they keep making it smaller!
You know why? So you can lose it.
Why? So you buy more phones.
l never lost my mother's phone!
Take you two hours to make
a long-distance call.
Duh-duh-duh-duh-4.
Duh-duh-duh-duh-5.
l messed up! Hang up. Got to
do it again. Duh-duh-duh-duh-4....
Never lost my Sports Illustrated
swimsuit phone.
How about scanners? They get your phone
number and call all over the world!
Somebody took my number and called
Afghanistan! Afghanistan!
l don't know what fucking
Afghanistan look like.
Even if l did, l would not talk
to their Afghan ass for 3 hours!
l won't talk to my daddy for 3 hours!
They fuck you, they fuck you
with the cell phones!
You know when you go to a drive-through?
Hold on.
Why am l talking--?
Leo Getz, private investigator.
Private investigator?
l wondered if you'd be willing
to investigate my privates.
lnvestigate what?
My privates, you stupid shit.
Shut the fuck up.
Very funny.
You're costing me money here.
$3 to answer a call.
They're fucking me, now you are.
-You're pretty tough on the phone.
-That's right. Telephone tough guy.
-Why am l talking to you on the phone?
-Get the fuck out of here. Go home.
What happened to your face?
''No'' means no!
The kid's going to like me,
l can tell.
He'd be the first one.
Whatever. Whatever.
You know, we should hire Leo.
Hire Leo?
He could follow Uncle Benny around.
-Benny'll see him.
-That's the idea.
-He'll drive him nuts.
-Benny'll shoot him.
Let's hire him!
l smell like stale coffee.
What do you care if l go home
and change my shirt?
A coffee stain's not something
that would bother me.
Look at the way you dress.
What's that supposed to mean?
Just because l don't get around in
nifty suits like you. Not many cops do.
What's that supposed to mean?
l've been wondering,
where's the money coming from?
Where do you think it's coming from?
-Where do you think?
-l don't know.
-lt's none of my damn business.
-You don't know.
-Trish gave me some money.
-lt's none of my business.
Trish gave me some money, and
from my Aunt Anne who died.
All right. Okay, sorry.
Whose car is that?
l don't know.
lt looks like a full house
for Lamaze class.
You know that car?
Here you go, Captains.
No charge for the ride.
Rianne's here and Lorna's here.
l'll put it on your account, Captain.
Hey, honey.
What's going on?
l came home to change my shirt--
Why are you here?
They took the Hongs.
Shit.
Drop it.
Girls, get out!
Look who we got here.
-Uncle Benny's friend.
-Hey, Bruce.
Nice pajamas.
Where are the Hongs?
Drop your guns.
-Drop them!
-Okay, take it easy!
Don't stand for that, honey.
Son of a bitch!
Let the women go.
l can't breathe!
Son of a bitch!
l'll be damned! Thanks, kid!
Ping, cut us loose, cut us loose.
Cut me loose, Ping!
Go ahead, cut me.
Cut me.
lt's all right.
You okay, honey?
l owe you one, kid.
The keys to your car.
-They're in the car.
-l got car.
We need a radio.
We have to go, baby.
Let's go.
How are we going to find them?
We got to catch them assholes!
3-William-56, this is Air 12, go ahead.
We need your eyes, guys.
We're looking for a black Mercedes
and a black Lincoln Continental.
Vicinity of Ladera at the 210 freeway.
Black Mercedes and black
Continental, huh?
Shouldn 't be too hard
to find in this town.
Look, just give it a shot,
will you, guys?
Be cooperative.
That's a roger.
Will wonders never cease?
We've got 2 black Mercedes, one heading
east, one heading west.
Eastbound one got on the
Valley View ramp.
East, okay.
We'll take it.
Locate the Continental.
Roger.
-ls that the right one?
-l don't know.
But we're going east and China's east.
China's west too.
-We can't divide.
-l'll think positive.
You crossed two lanes!
Do you see him?
Watch the road!
l'd give my right arm for a siren!
Why'd they take the Hongs anyway?
Maybe they're shaking them down
for more money.
Hong's uncle paid already.
He got in touch with his uncle.
He left a message for him.
That's how they know where l live.
Out of the way!
Go, go, go!
There it is! There's the son of a bitch
right there!
Bastards left us to burn!
l want to have a chat with them!
You don't have any guns!
Get me right up behind this trailer.
But you're driving!
You're driving!
There's cruise control!
Just steer!
Why you always make shit complicated?!
Closer.
Don't be shy. Get up there.
You crazy son of a bitch!
Closer! Closer!
That's it!
Thanks.
Hey, asshole! Come on in!
l need to ask you.
Where's the Hongs?
Where are they?
Fuck!
Come on, get him!
Watch out!
Highway Patrol, this is William-356...
...heading southbound on highway!
Officer in trouble!
Oversized trailer.
LAPD! Pull over! LAPD!
LAPD! Pull over!
Pull over! See that?!
Right! Fuck you!
Shit!
Anybody there? l got a crazy ass with a
phony badge trying to pull me over!
Get away from my boy!
Son of a bitch!
l got you!
Hold on!
Get in!
Come on, get in here!
Get in here!
Shit!
Ready?
-Welcome back. Shit.
-What a drag.
Thanks, Rog.
-What about the Hongs?
-We'll ask the other guy. Go!
Pull over! Pull over!
Son of a bitch!
lKeep your hands inside then!
Get out of the way!
Wait! There he is!
There he is!
-lKeep going!
-l'm going.
We're gaining on him.
Don't worry, l got him.
Son of a bitch!
-You okay?
-Yeah, l think my heart's still beating.
Maybe a little too close.
You are now entering an
international holding area.
Please have proper documentation ready.
Sorry, Rog, about your loss.
Thank you, man.
How's my hero?
He's a little bit sad.
He's talking about his mom and dad.
Here's Butters.
How's it going, Riggs?
Why are you here?
l heard it on the radio.
l'm really sorry about your house.
This is Detective....
Butters.
-Trish, my wife.
-How you doing, Trish?
Nick.
Carrie.
Rianne.
Everybody okay?
You get a make on who did this?
lt was Uncle Benny.
-Who's Leo? The little Fonzie guy?
-You got a phone?
That's him.
-You be okay?
-Yeah, we'll be all right.
Call me.
The kids have their place.
Rianne has hers.
He's there?
We'll be right there.
Can you drive us?
Yeah, let's do it.
l'll call you.
Man, sit down.
Captain Murtaugh...
...l know this is a bad time...
...but...
...l think there's something
you need to know about me.
-This is hard for me to--
-l think maybe l know what it is.
You do?
lt's okay.
lt is?
People have the right to do what makes
them happy. Don't expect me to like it.
l know this must be real hard for you.
lt's impossible for me!
l was hoping we could get together
around the holidays, say Christmas.
Why the hell should we get together and
see each other on Christmas?
-l'm trying to reach out.
-Reach somewhere else.
Do what you want,
but leave me out of it.
-l got it.
-l don't want to hear no more about it.
Not a word.
What you grinning about?
Think about how we can talk to Benny.
l got it all worked out.
What's the matter with you?
My ass hurts. My tooth! ls this
a dentist's office or a proctologist's?
-Just please be quiet.
-l'm trying! l'm in pain!
Why don't you go see your
own dentist and be quiet?!
My dentist is in Detroit or l would go!
-Oh, brother.
-Oh brother, your ass! Get the dentist!
Doctor, l'm sorry to bother you.
We have an emergency.
A man walked in off the street.
He's in a lot of pain. You better come.
Okay, you can come in now!
-You sure Leo can pull this off?
-Leo's got a B.S. in B.S.
Coast is clear.
Talk to the hand, okay?
One second.
Okay, okay. Wait a minute.
Let me. Let me do my job!
You hurt me, l'll stick an egg roll
right up your ass.
-What's this?
-Don't be alarmed.
lt's only a drill.
Don't say a word.
Shut up.
Now....
Where are the Hongs?
Open wide and tell me.
l don't know any Hongs.
You do. Their uncle paid you to
get them out of China.
More smuggling?
We went through that.
Let's go through it again.
-Come on.
-l have nothing to say.
These look very interesting.
You're not going to use it.
You won't shoot me.
-You're lousy cops.
-We're good cops. Here.
This'll settle him down.
Breathe, Uncle Benny. Breathe.
Breathe.
Crank up the nitrous.
Crank that baby up.
You said it wasn't going to hurt!
l'm holding this. Go ahead.
Deep. Right down to your toes.
Thataboy.
He's wasted!
-Great, great.
-Have some more.
He'll talk. Yeah, he'll talk.
Thataboy. Breathe.
-That's me.
-That's you.
Now, where are the Hongs?
-What's renminbi mean?
-Renminbi means...
...renminbi.
-You're a funny guy.
-This guy's wasting our time.
Time!
-Time for Four Fathers!
-Forefathers!
Washington, Jefferson, those guys?
Roosevelt?
l'm sleeping with my wife's 2 sisters.
You lucky son of a bitch.
That's a good one.
Not so good...
...when my wife finds out.
l don't need needles!
Let's shoot his legs with Novocain
and watch him try to get out of here.
What you got there?
A nut cup.
l got some big nuts!
That's nitro--
Oxide!
Laughing gas!
We're stoned!
Murtaugh! Hurry up!
That's one funny son-in-law
you got there, Rog.
After tonight, it be too late.
Too late? Too late for what?
Why did you call him my son-in-law?
Who? Uncle Benny? He's far too old.
Old coot.
Buy Four Fathers back at
Four Fathers' store.
Why's he talking about his ancestors?
l don't know.
Why you call him my son-in-law?
Because l am!
l thought he was....
No, l'm....
Bloody marvelous!
Your baby is having my baby.
My baby is having his baby.
And your baby?
Whoa, baby!
Whoa, baby! My baby!
What's going on?
What are you doing?
l couldn't stall anymore.
What happened? Huh?
-What's going on?
-Rog, look at this. Does that hurt?
Riggs, get out! Fine!
Whatever!
Anything happens to the Hongs we'll
come back and rip you a new one.
A new one. That's two for Benny.
Bloody marvelous.
What are you, crazy?
What'd you do that for?
For keeping it from me.
Hit him, not me.
As soon as we find the Hongs, me, you
and Rianne is getting into this.
Rimminy?
A young bimbo? A young jumping jiminy?
l don't know.
I can't remember.
No, Riggs. Renminbi .
Say that again.
That's it!
You got it.
Means, ''people's money. ''
People's money?
What else did Benny say?
He was talking about his ancestor.
About buying him back.
And something about how tonight's...
...too late.
Mean anything to you?
No, nothing at all.
What about the guy
who torched my house?
lt was like Benny
was afraid of him.
If Benny's scared of him,
he's got to be a Chinese Triad.
Those guys'll kill anyone
who gets in their way.
lncluding cops...
...and their families.
So watch your asses, all right?
-Thanks, Ng.
-lKeep me posted.
Pick up your wife, my daughter.
Make sure she's safe.
l'll get Trish, you get Lorna.
Her and Ping.
What?
You want to get married, don't you?
No.
Yes. Yes, l do.
But if you don't want to, it's okay.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because l didn't want to put
any pressure on you.
lf you want to someday, that'd be great.
lf you don't...
...l love you.
l'll take you any way l can get you.
Feel that!
Feel the baby!
He's really dancing.
He's kicking. You feel him?
Hang on!
You're okay.
Riggs. Pick up, Riggs.
Riggs, it's Murtaugh.
l'm sick of these fuckers.
l say we just find them and shoot them.
-What do you think?
-Meet me and Butters on South Spring.
What's going on?
They found my watch.
They killed Hong, his uncle,
Uncle Benny too. Bodies are in there.
-Where's the rest of the family?
-They're okay.
lNS raided a Chinese sweatshop.
Hong's family was being held there
and they led them back here.
They were making funny money.
lnk's still wet.
Where are the faces?
That's why l called it funny.
Why are they making Chinese money?
Can they even exchange the stuff here?
Only in China.
-Renminbi .
-l remember.
Hong's uncle was an artist.
Maybe an engraver.
Bringing over his family could've
been how he was paid to do the job.
-That sounded thin.
-lt's not.
lKeep talking. What?
Benny said something about paying...
...buying back his forefathers.
What'd you say?
Benny said something about buying
back his forefathers.
You said ancestors.
What's the difference?
The number four.
Four Fathers.
They were the top guys
of the Hong lKong Triad.
-These guys disappeared from prison.
-Reds jailed them when they took over.
-l bet you they're here.
-Damn, we're good.
Grab Ping. l don't want him
to see the bodies.
1 0 to 1 , l know where the money is.
20 to 1 ,
l know where the Four Fathers are.
Let me make a call.
Don't leave without us.
That was good work.
You must be a detective.
l have my moments.
Uncle Benny.
l was actually starting
to like the old goat.
''Bloody marvelous.''
And it's fried rice, ''you plick.''
Here.
-Which one is Hong?
-Hong's right in front of you.
l want a complete set of forensics
on all three.
Dads and their kids.
l'll take care of yours, buddy.
We got to go!
Take care of yourself.
Where're we going?
-L.A. Harbor.
-What's there?
lt's a foreign trade zone. A lot of
deals go down with the Chinese military.
It's run by a corrupt Chinese general.
I got it, some corrupt Chinese general
brought the Four Fathers here...
...and the Triad's
buying their release.
That's what Uncle Benny meant
by buying them back.
That general'll be shitting kittens
when he sees the money's counterfeit.
Let's tell him.
Hi, gang.
LAPD.
l saw Hong.
This is what Benny meant by buying the
Four Fathers. Harpo, Groucho, Chico...
...and Fucko.
How are you, boys?
Who's the naughty general?
Who's been lining his pockets?
Naughty.
Speaky English?
What do you want?
See this?
l hope you need a lot of toilet paper
because that's all it's good for.
Wiping your ass.
Take the Four Pops back to China.
We don't give a shit.
The Four Pops.
Don't want them no more.
lt's counterfeit.
Triads never prosper when they
cheat a general.
See for yourself.
There you go. Money losing face.
General losing face.
Very hard when Triad tried to sit on it.
l fucked you. l fucked you.
We fucked you.
-We fucked you. lt's beautiful.
-Beautiful.
Don't we get a hand?
lKeep your head down!
Let them shoot each other!
Watch out!
Thanks!
Was this a good idea?
lt was an idea!
-1 1 in the mag, 1 in the pipe. You?
-Wheel gun. 6 shots.
Four!
What's going on?
Why are you lying to me?
lA says you're on the take.
l'm on the take?!
l think it's crazy too! But you're
spending a lot of money!
You ever hear of Ebony Clark?
Yeah! She writes those cheesy
sex novels!
Are you boinking her?
No, l'm not boinking Ebony Clark, Riggs.
Shit!
Trish is Ebony Clark.
You're boinking her!
Yeah, l'm boinking her.
l'm too embarrassed
to tell anybody.
Yeah, l don't blame you.
How many you got?
Two.
l'll look for some more ammo.
Who's that in white pajamas?
Wah Sing lKu. The Four Father
with him is his older brother.
No kidding.
Captain!
-Hey, Butters.
-Shit! Shit!
Now you got my name right.
l'm out. l got to find some rounds.
l'll help you.
Never been shot before.
Take care of my son-in-law.
-You all right?
-No. l got my ass kicked again.
Shit, l'm out. l'm out.
l hit the son of a bitch. l thought
l missed him. Where'd they go?
Come on, come on.
Go.
We got Door Number 1 ,
Number 2, or Number 3.
-Looks like Number 2, Monty.
-Let's go.
What's behind Door Number 2?
Bingo.
Now you've done it.
Now he's really pissed.
Son of a bitch is going to be a handful.
Since l met you, l've done some
hairy shit. But this won't happen.
l'm going to be a grandfather...
...and you and Lorna will have a baby.
He ain't worth dying for, Riggs.
He ain't worth it.
Yeah, you're right.
And if he gets away we can track him
down later with a howitzer or something.
Your son-in-law's bleeding. We should
get him and go. lt's raining and....
l'm too old for this shit too.
Guy's too damn good.
Yeah, he's good. How'd he do that
thing with the gun?
He took my gun apart with one deft move.
How did he do that?
How?
Yeah, okay.
Let's go ask him.
Are you up there?
Are you all right?
Where are you, Riggs?
Will it to me, Riggs!
Where are you?
Will it to me!
Will me, Riggs, will me.
You going to have a baby. Will me,
you son of a bitch. God! Will me!
l hear you, Riggs.
l hear you.
l got you.
l'm coming!
l heard you, Riggs! l heard you!
You willed me to it!
You willed me, baby!
What took you so long?
What took me so long?!
What the hell do you think?!
l was knocked down over here!
l couldn't even get up!
Come back here!
Let's go home, man.
Let's get out of here.
l haven't been here enough
lately, Vicki. l'm sorry.
l need to talk to you about Lorna.
Me and Lorna.
lt's like this.
She wants to get married...
...and l love her.
l won't lie to you. l do.
And l want to make her happy.
l'm looking for help here, honey.
l don't know what to do.
Funny talking to you about
this stuff--
You want to get yourself shot?
What the hell are you doing here?
l was tailing you.
Sorry.
l'll leave you alone, okay?
l guess you want to be alone.
l appreciate it.
When l was a kid...
...l had a pet frog.
What?
Just give me a second.
Let me tell you this, okay?
l had this pet frog.
His name was Froggy.
He was my best friend in the world.
l didn't have lots of friends.
Matter of fact...
...l had no friends...
...and...
...l used to kiss the frog too.
l thought maybe...
...it would turn into a princess
since l was a boy...
...and it could be...
...my mother.
They told me that she...
...left or something.
And my father was no bargain.
And so, just the frog.
Froggy was my friend.
l really loved him and
l took him everywhere with me.
And l was riding on my bike one day...
...and he jumped out of the box...
...and l ran him over
with the back tire.
l killed him.
l was really heartbroken. Really.
He was my best friend,
the only thing l ever loved.
And then l met you...
...and Roger.
And you guys really looked after me
a lot more than you really had to.
l'm terrible to you, Leo.
No, no, it's okay.
lt's okay.
You're my family...
...and my friends.
You're not better friends than Froggy.
You're just different.
And...
...l just thought that maybe
that might be relevant.
Okay, l'll leave you alone now.
l got a funny f--
What's wrong?!
l'm having a baby.
Lorna beeped me.
Yep, it's Lorna.
She's having the baby.
-l'll get the car.
-l'll be behind you.
You sure picked a strange angel, honey.
But l got the message.
l got the message.
l'll always have this.
Always have you.
ln here and here.
Thanks, honey.
l got to go. Bye.
l am not ready to have this baby!
You're as ready as you're going to be.
Fine! Just wheel me in.
My legs are staying closed!
Give me this!
Now, now, ma'am, let go!
l am a police officer!
And l am not ready!
Are you all right?
-Are you the husband?
-Yes.
Honey, are you all right?
No, l'm not. l said l didn't
want to get married but l do.
l want to be a wife before l'm a mother.
l just lied.
l know you don't want to.
-You said ''okay''?
-Yes, l did. Okay.
Let's do it. Okay.
He said okay.
-Congratulations.
-He said okay, Leo.
Oh, my God.
What's that smell?
l was on my way to the toilet
and she grabbed me.
l'm so sorry.
Have a nice baby!
Will you marry me?
You bet l will.
Let's go.
l'm not going! Wait! No, no, wait!
Please, Riggs.
-Get a minister.
-Now?
Right now. We're getting married.
Here comes another one.
But we need a license, a blood test--
Before the baby comes!
lt's coming now.
Listen, l am getting married
or there is no baby.
This could be an aspect
of a transition phase.
This is no goddamn aspect
of a transition phase!
Honey, everybody, calm down.
Calm down. Calm down. Okay?
-Get a priest, minister, anything.
-Where?
Leo, go get a priest!
Goddamn it, Leo!
l got it, l got it. Okay, okay.
Pant, pant, blow.
Remember Lamaze class?
Pant, blow. Come on, pant, blow.
But l want to say ''l do.''
Here he is. Here he is.
This is Rabbi Gelb.
A rabbi?
You said anything, duh.
He'll do.
For what, l'll do? What?
Marry us.
-Marry you?
-Please.
-You're Jewish?
-Not necessarily.
-You got a license?
-No.
Rabbi, please don't go.
She needs to hear the words
before the baby comes.
Are you both serious about this?
l don't have time for hijinks.
We're really very serious.
l could do it.
lt wouldn't be official.
l just want to hear the words.
What the hell. What are your names?
l'm Martin and this is Lorna.
Martin and Lorna.
What am l doing?
How do the goyim do this?
Dearly beloved.
Dearly beloved,
marriage is a spiritual unity....
Faster, faster!
She's heading for the home stretch.
Martin, will you take
Lorna to be your wife?
Will you honor, love,
etcetera, etcetera, etcetera...
-...until death do you part?
-l will.
Lorna, will you take Martin
to be your husband?
-Etcetera, etcetera. The same thing.
-l do.
l pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
You already did.
-All right, let's go.
-No, wait, wait!
Hold it! Hold it!
What is...?
l need this! l need this glass!
-No, goddamn it!
-l need it!
What are you doing?!
Talk to the hand, okay?
l'll be right back.
You know how long it took me
to fill that thing? All day!
This is unsanitary. What is this?
-Break it.
-And get piss on my shoes?
You got to do this!
-Mazel tov !
-Okay, let's go.
Come back here,
you little son of a bitch!
Pant, pant, blow, pant.
Leo, please.
Your work is over here now.
l think someone else needs you.
Good luck, Lorna, Riggs.
Thanks a lot.
Stick around. Meet the kid.
Good luck, Lorna! Okay, okay.
Here it comes, here it comes.
Here he is.
He's looking right at you.
He knows it's you.
Rog, look what l found.
-Look at that.
-Boy, what a beauty.
Look at those eyes!
-He looks like his mother.
-Yes, he does.
Murtaugh! Murtaugh!
-No, Butters!
-That's right.
Butters' baby. Better not be Murtaugh.
lt's Butters, Butters, Butters.
Look at that baby.
Look at the hair.
That's my baby!
Look at her. You're so cute.
Look at you.
27 people. Nobody thought
of bringing a camera?
Leo, your plastic's flaccid.
These machines take your plastic,
they wreck it, then give you the camera.
The camera doesn't work.
They're trying to--
No, no, please.
What you doing here?
Look at these two babies.
Just a little something from the squad.
Thank you.
-Give me back those captain badges.
-What for?
Congratulations. You're sergeants
again. The city's self-insured.
l thought they'd make us president.
By the way, Grandpa,
you owe the Chief one.
He went to bat for you with the lNS and
they're giving asylum to the Hongs.
All right!
We're taking a picture.
We're going to take a picture.
Get in the picture.
Squeeze together.
Candy-stripers out.
Out, out, okay, okay. Out.
l can't. There's not
enough room. Sorry.
You got to back up.
l'm taking big steps!
Get this guy to take it.
Doc, do me a favor?
Take a picture of all of us?
-lt's my best man, after all.
-Closer.
Get my grandbaby in it too.
Are you all friends?
No. We're family!
Okay, on 3.
One...two...three
Rip By KOPYCD