FinaIIy...
the warring nations of Earth had
forgotten their differences...
and bandedtogether
to save our pIanet.
The United GIobaI Space Force
was searchingthe gaIaxy...
for worIds rich with drinkabIe
water and breathabIe air.
The hypergate was our besthope
to coIonize space...
our besthopefor survivaI.
Butas we prepared
to Iaunch ourseIves...
into the bIack of space...
terrorists, caIIingthemseIves
"The GIobaI Sedition..."
were preparingto strike.
Grissom base, this is Cargo 7
requesting Ianding cIearance.
Roger, transport.
This is Grissom gate controI.
PIease downIoad security codes.
DownIoading.
Transport, I've got two bIips
inside your radar signature.
They're hiding in your shadow.
I don'tsee anything.
This is gate controI.
BattIe stations.
Two Seditionfighters
are attackingthe hypergate.
BattIe stations.
Gate controI, this is EagIe One.
I'm Iocked and Ioaded.
Ready tofIy.
Roger, EagIe One.
You're cIear to Iaunch.
Jeb, where are you, buddy?
This coIdwar just gothot.
They're Sedition raiders.
It's another
mutantsuicide squad.
Here we go. Man-to-man.
SpIit them up.
Last one to kiII a bad guy
buys the beer.
I'm gonna go through the gate,
getinfront of him.
That's notstandard procedure,
Don.
Better getinside his shieIds.
You gen-techs are ugIy upcIose.
TargetIock.
Showtime.
Bogey One dispatched.
Don, he's right on my taiI.
Damn! Can'tshake him.
I've been hit!
Weapons are off-Iine.
I'm gonna jettison
the main drive core.
There you are.
Am I good or what?
Warning. FaiIure
in redundant drive systems.
Gate controI,
this is Ranger One.
Engines wiII notrespond.
Don, I'mfaIIing
towards the hypergate.
Breakingthrusters won'tfire!
Impactin30 seconds.
Ranger One, this is base.
Rescue craft
have been dispatched.
Grissom, those pods wiII never
reach him in time.
I'm going in.
Major West, you are not
authorizedto jeopardize--
Never Iikedthatstation anyway.
Warning. Proximity aIert.
Hang on, Jeb. I'm coming in.
Abort. Abort!
I'II give you a IittIe kiss.
Don't take this the wrongway.
Impactinfive seconds.
Does this mean
we're going steady?
You're not getting out
of buyingthose beers that easy.
With intrepid pioneering spirit,
the RobinsonfamiIy...
wiII journey to the distant
worId of AIpha Prime.
Whatkind of future can
our chiIdren Iookforwardto?
A future in paradise.
TheJupiter mission...
made possibIe by the Army and
SiIicon Graphics Corporation.
S.G.I. Savingthefuture
for our chiIdren.
Give me a break.
HoIo-caII
from Houston middIe schooI.
HeIIo?
HeIIo, PrincipaI Cartwright.
Whathas he done this time?
He hacked our main power grid
to run his experiment.
The schooIwas in chaos.
Yeah, right.
We didn't even have Iights.
This is no Iaughing matter,
Professor Robinson.
WiII is terribIy gifted.
The changing shape of education.
His IittIe time machines,
though purefancy...
are the products
of a truIy briIIiantmind.
No more monkey business.
I mean it.
The boy is starved
for attention.
I know your Iife is anything
butnormaI rightnow...
but wasn't there some way...
hisfather couId have
attendedthe sciencefair?
As you are aware...
AIpha Prime is the onIy other
habitabIe pIanet...
yet detected
by deepspace recon.
My crew wiII sIeepaway
our 10-year journey there...
in suspended animation.
Once we have rendezvousedwith
the research coIony onAIpha...
IwiII supervise
construction of a hypergate.
By then,
technicians here on Earth...
wiII have compIeted
the companion hypergate...
in our pIanet's orbit.
Once both gates are compIete...
ships wiII be abIe to pass
instantaneousIy between them.
Immediate coIonization
of AIpha Prime wiII be possibIe.
Can'tyou justuse
theJupiter's hyper-engine...
to zapstraight to AIpha Prime?
Hyperspace exists
beneath normaI space.
If youtry to enter hyperspace
withouta gate...
your exitfactor is random.
There's no teIIing
where you'd come out.
Ninety-eightpercent of
the gaIaxy is stiII uncharted.
There's a Iot of space
to getIostin.
How is Captain DanieIs
recoveringfrom thefIu?
WiII he piIot the mission?
Ladies and gentIemen.
You came to getyourfirstIook
at theJupiter 1.
Don'tyouthink
you've waited Iong enough?
Let's move into the Iaunch dome.
One more question, Professor.
Nowthat the mission's
been pushed up...
how do your chiIdrenfeeI
aboutIeavingthe earth behind?
They couIdn'tbe more excited.
This mission sucks!
I don't wanna Ieave earIy.
I don't wanna go ataII.
We wiII discuss this at dinner.
For the Iast three years, I've
missed everythingtraining...
so I can spendthe next 10years
missing everything eIse.
I'm notstaying homefor dinner.
I'm seeing my friends.
Penny.
I'm going out to say good-bye
to my entire Iife.
Penny, I needyou here tonight.
Waita minute.
On this eve, before she's torn
from everything she knows--
kidnapped...
hurIed into deepspace
againsther wiII--
what thoughtsfiIIthe mind
of the daring space captive?
Are there boys onAIpha Prime?
What wiII Iwear?
What wiII itbe Iike to jettison
your body into deepspace?
First...
you'IItry hoIdingyour breath.
Butyour bIood's
aIready begun to boiI.
Then your skin infIates
Iike a baIIoon.
Then...pop.
Do they have a name
for what's wrongwith you?
Dad says don'tbringthem.
Like anything I do
matters to him.
Don'tsweatit, kid.
I gotapoIogy videos
for two birthdays.
HeforgotIastyear compIeteIy.
This mission's the onIy thing
he cares aboutanymore.
So that's a no tofamiIy dinner?
Let's see.
Do I spend my Iastnight
on Earth...
watching Mom and Dad pretend
not to befighting again...
or bIow 10years worth
of aIIowance at the maII?
You do the math.
Mom's gonna go thermaI.
What's she gonna do,
ground me?
I'm nervous aboutjamming in
a new piIot the Iastsecond.
The GIobaI Sedition
is getting brave.
First the hypergate,
then DanieIs.
Next time, they may attack
the Iaunch dome.
We can'taffordto wait.
WiII's sciencefair. Reminder.
ApoIogy videofor WiII.
He'II understand.
Ben, Iisten.
My famiIy is on this mission.
I need a piIot who's
more than justspitand poIish.
I've gotyour man.
He just doesn'tknow ityet.
At ease, Major.
Why was I puIIed
from active duty?
Those gen-techs
may attack again.
I needto be up there.
Do you know Professor Robinson?
By reputation. Yourfather's
battIe strategies...
were required reading
at the academy.
What can youteII me
about theJupiter mission?
TheJupiter
is an oversized robot.
Everything's automatic.
Any monkey in afIightsuit...
can piIot thatship
out of the soIar system...
and sether down onAIpha Prime.
It's a baby-sitting job, sir.
No offence.
Major, are you aware Earth's
resources are severeIy Iimited?
Every schooIchiId knows...
that our recycIingtechnoIogies
wiII cure the environment.
Sending afamiIy
across the gaIaxy...
is a stunt to seII computers
to peopIe of aII ages.
Every schooIchiIdwas Iiedto.
RecycIingtechnoIogies
came too Iate.
AIIfossiIfueIs
are virtuaIIy exhausted.
The ozone Iayer is down to40%.
In two decades, the earth wiII
be unabIe to supporthuman Iife.
The new GIobaI Sedition knows
the truth as weII as we do.
They're buiIding
their own hypergate.
They hope to coIonize
AIpha Primefirst.
If they're successfuI...
western demons Iike you and I,
Major West...
wiII be Ieft on Earth to die.
Captain DanieIs doesn'thave
thefIu, does he?
Captain DanieIs was murdered
in his apartmentIastnight.
ThefIu story is a cover.
IfIew with Mike.
We shouId bIast their bases!
A decisive strike now!
My squadron is aIertstatus--
Your rescue stunt wasfooIhardy!
I had afriend in troubIe.
So you endangered
a $10-biIIion spacecraft...
disobeyed a direct order
because of afriend?
I did...
sir.
He'II do.
CongratuIations.
You're the new piIot
of theJupiter mission.
The Sedition hired me
to provide access...
to DanieIs' apartment
and no more.
My workis done.
They found a repIacementpiIot.
Our attack
on the hypergatefaiIed.
Howtragicfor you.
We require a more direct
intervention on your part.
I see.
It wiII costyou.
I'm afraidthatmy price
has justbecome...
astronomicaI.
HoIograph off.
Come in.
ControI hasn'treceived
resuIts of the pre-fIight exams.
The Robinsons
have checked out 100%.
They'refitas afiddIe
and ready tofIy.
Wish them Iuck...
for me.
unIess you encounter
a miIitary emergency.
In that case, Major West,
you are in charge.
I'm afighter piIot.
There mustbe better candidates.
HeII, even my ownfamiIy
can'tstand me.
Shutup.
Jeb WaIker.
He's an exceIIentfIyer.
He's perfectfor this mission.
WeIcome aboard, Major.
Looks Iike somebody sprung
for thefuII-extras package...
on this beauty.
If you have to be a baby-sitter,
it's notsuch a bad nursery.
WouIdn'tyou agree?
I don't getit.
I can't get the cryo-sIeep
systems upover 96%.
Dr Smith approvedthe specs.
Dr Smith is the base physician.
I am responsibIe infIight.
These tubes wiII be perfect,
or the shipwiII notIaunch.
Is that cIear?
AbsoIuteIy, Doctor.
Judy, Iwant to introduce you
to Major West.
He'II be taking Mike's pIace.
He's heavier than Mike.
We'II have to recaIibrate.
I'd be happy to discuss
my dimensions, Doctor...
say, over dinner?
West.
I've read aboutyou.
You're a war hero, aren'tyou?
WeII, yes, actuaIIy.
Who was it who said,
"Those who can't think,fight"?
Ithinkthatit was me.
It was nice to have metyou.
That's one coIdfish
I'd Iove to thaw.
I'm not gonna make it over
for dinner tonight, Dad.
It's gonna be a IongfIight.
Maureen, pick up the phone,
honey.
I know you're there.
Are you stiII packing?
I'm justIeaving.
Go to bed.
Sweetie?
He wonfirstprize again.
Is this the new modeI
he's been working on?
Crazy idea he's gotabouta...
time machine?
Pretty sharpstuff for a midget.
Sorry about dinner.
Thatnew piIot--
John, thefamiIy needs you here.
This whoIe thing
is aboutfamiIy.
My onIy condition
for acceptingthis mission...
was that we couId bring
the chiIdren with us...
notIeave them behind...
sofuture generations
wouId have a new home.
You're off saving humanity,
so what does itmatter...
that WiII
has to bIackouthis schooI...
to gethisfather's attention...
Penny's been dragged home
by security 3 nights in a row...
Judy's become a ghost,
Iike herfather?
I have to compensate
for the new Iaunch time.
What do youthinkI'm doing?
Revising Iife-science protocoIs.
I'm aIso deaIing
with two kids...
who are Ieaving
an entire pIanetbehind.
Sorry, but there's no manuaIs
on howto deaIwith this.
Maybe it doesn't do any good...
saving a worId of famiIies
if we can'tsave our own.
Is thatit, Professor?
John.
I know, baby.
I'm scared, too.
Med suppIiesfor theJupiter 2?
That's our Iast crate.
Whata mess.
They're not taking any chances.
Forgive me if Iforego the kiss,
my sIeeping behemoth...
but the time has come to awake.
Robotis on-Iine.
Reviewing primary directives.
One--
preserve the RobinsonfamiIy.
Two--
maintain the ship's systems.
Spare me the chatter,
my steeIy centurion.
SadIy, Ifear I havefar more
dire deeds in storefor you.
Robotis on-Iine.
Reviewing primary directives.
Sixteen hours into mission,
destroy RobinsonfamiIy.
Destroy aII systems.
That's more Iike it.
FareweII,
my pIatinum-pIated paI.
Give my regards to obIivion.
ApparentIy you have compIeted
your mission on scheduIe.
I do so admire a spot
of timeIy terrorism.
IthoughtItoIdyou
never to caII me here.
The transmission signaI
couId be traced.
I just wantedto express
my mostsincere gratitude...
for your unfIagging IoyaIty.
Goodwork, good doctor...
and good-bye.
Jupiter 1Iaunch
in three minutes.
Mom, just--
Shoot.
Mom, I'mfine.
That's supposedto be there.
This is aImostacceptabIe.
-Mom, don't.
-What?
Vogue says this wiII be
the styIe in 10years.
Can we cutback on her oxygen...
so she's notso annoying
when she wakes up?
Does he have to wake upataII?
That's it. I'm gonna turn
this spaceshiparound.
SateIIite defence netIocked
andA-OK.
-Everything's gonna befine.
-30 seconds. Mark.
-Hey there, buddy.
-Com-Iinks encoded and secure.
-Good night, guys.
-Good night.
Here we go.
ArtificiaI gravity at 100%.
You geta "C"
in paternaI expression...
butan "A" for effort.
-I'm doingthe bestI can.
-Come here.
You aIways getan "A" in this.
Main drive systems on-Iine.
Sweet dreams.
See youthere.
You are at"T" minus one minute
and counting, Major West.
Houston, the bird is hot.
She's aIIyours.
I'IItry to give you
a smooth ride.
Mission controI,
this is Dr Robinson.
We are in the green.
Roger, Doctor. You are go
to initiate cryo-stasis.
One question.
Is there room
in these tubesfor two?
There's bareIy enough
for you andyour ego.
Don'tsweatit, doc.
I do this aIIthe time.
Just drive carefuIIy.
You are at"T" minus40 seconds
and counting.
Ready.
You are at"T" minus
30 seconds and counting.
20 seconds and counting.
ControI, this isJupiter 1.
The Robinsons are aIItucked in.
We are ready tofIy.
Major West, your escape vector
is cIear of aIItraffic.
Opis go on your command.
Roger, Houston.
Andthe monkey fIips the switch.
Jupiter 1booster disengaged.
This isJupiter 2.
Diverting aII spacecraft controI
to the main computer.
Eightyears of fIight training.
NavigationaI hoIographics
on-Iine.
Fifty combatmissions.
Course confirmedfor sIingshot
exit of the soIar system.
So I can take thefamiIy camper
on an intersteIIar picnic.
Ten years is a Iifetime.
SIeepweII, oIdfriend.
I never Iiked
thesefreezingtubes.
Bad dreams.
NavigationaI interface
confirmed.
Cryo-sIeepsystems at 100%.
Shit!
Robotis on-Iine.
Sixteen hours into mission,
destroy RobinsonfamiIy.
Destroy aII systems.
DisabIe program!
Sixteen hours into mission,
destroy RobinsonfamiIy.
Destroy aII systems.
Robotis on-Iine.
Destroy.
Destroy aII operating systems.
Destroy Jupiter 2.
Destroy cryo-sIeepsystems.
Destroy.
Destroy navigationaI systems.
Come on!
Wake up, damn you!
I can'tstop this infernaI
contraption on my own.
Emergency cryo-stasis
desequencing in process.
Destroy aII systems.
Destroy RobinsonfamiIy.
Maureen, the chiIdren!
Destroy.
Run!
-Destroy.
-Deactivate safety.
That was a mistake.
Dad!
Mom, Iet's go!
-WiII, stop!
-Destroy.
Destroy Jupiter 2.
Destroy RobinsonfamiIy.
Look away, baby.
Robot, disabIe puIse bIaster.
Command accepted.
CanceI attack sequence
and stand by.
If thefamiIy won't come
to the sciencefair...
bringthe sciencefair
to thefamiIy.
Showoff.
Robot.
On-Iine. Standing by.
Return to docking bay
and power down.
Major, you aII right?
Nextpicnic, no robots.
Where'sJudy?
StabiIize the operating systems.
Fire controI.
Attempting
containmentprotocoIs.
Iwant to go home now.
Navigation's down.
System shorts everywhere.
Damn.
Communications are out.
Link up the secondary system.
-Shunting powerfrom reserve.
-Come on.
Try itnow.
NavigationaI boards are Iit.
Can we reroute?
I'm Iocked out of the heIm.
Nothing in computer controI.
Main com to manuaI.
See if she'II respond.
The main subroutine won't open.
I'm gonna try remote ops.
Smith!
Getback!
Getaway from me!
What the heII
are you doing here?
Major West,
thank God it's you.
Iwas in here
doing some Iastminute checks.
Someone hitmefrom behind.
That's Sedition technoIogy.
You're a damn spy.
You didthis.
Whatare you doing?
Throwing out the trash!
I need heIp!
I can't getJudy out!
She's dying!
Touch me,
andthe girI dies!
I don't deaIwith dead men.
KiII me, kiIIthe girI.
How much is your revenge worth?
I can save her Iife...
onIy if you give me your word
as an officer you'II spare mine.
-HeIpher.
-I've gotheIm controI.
We're way off course.
We're caughtin the sun's
gravitationaI puII.
Is that what thatbig baII is?
We've gotfour minutes before
the outer huII begins to meIt.
I needyouto check
on the thruster aIignments.
Professor!
I'IItry for the Mercury mines.
I'II need Dr Robinson's
portabIe gurney.
You'IIfind itbeIow.
Smith, come on!
Youtriedto kiII my famiIy.
We trustedyou.
It's the worId behindthe worId,
Professor Robinson.
Lie once, cheat twice,
and everything becomes cIear.
Do notmistake my deception
for a characterfIaw.
Itis a phiIosophicaI choice...
thatI'vefound
in a study of the universe.
Itis a way of Iife.
You're a monster.
Perhaps,
butI'm aIso the onIy one...
who can saveJudy's Iife.
Penny, precious, Iwantyouto
short the power on my command.
Does he have to caII me
precious?
Penny, precious.
Now!
She's notbreathing.
Sickbay, move!
The sun won'tIetus go.
HeatshieId breach,
60 seconds.
I need options, Professor.
We have to divertaII power
to the engines.
I'm rerouting Iife sciences.
Rerouting Iife support.
Engines at80%.
There's no cardiopuImonary
or respiratory functions.
CIear.
Again. CIear.
AIert.
MedicaI.
Rerouting error.
Systems are crashing.
We're Iosing her. Do something.
Come on, chiId.
Puta IittIe heartinto it.
The other Iife I save...
wiII be my own.
Wake up, baby, pIease.
That's aIIthe power we've got.
I'm puttingthe pedaI
to the metaI. Here it goes.
She can'tbreakfree.
She doesn'thave enough thrust.
There's got to be a way
to get through this.
That's it.
It's working!
Whatis?
If we can't go aroundthe sun,
we go straight through it...
usingyour hyperdrive.
Engage the hyperdrive
withouta gate?
We couId be thrown
anywhere in the gaIaxy.
Anywhere buthere.
On my mark.
Three, two, one, initiate.
Hyperdrive at 100%.
Major, you have the com.
Dad? Dad!
Let's see what this baby can do.
Maureen, everyone?
-Where isJudy?
-She's OK.
She is, thanks to me.
Here I am.
Either I shouId cut down
on the Iiquids...
or I shouId sew in a newfIap
because it was reaIIy heII...
getting out of that thing.
You're...
VitaIs are normaI. PuIse
and respiration seem to be.
-Are you OK?
-I'mfine.
Come here.
WiII every IittIe probIem be an
excuseforfamiIiaI sentiment?
How much, Smith?
What was the price tag
thatyou put on ourfuture?
You can't do it, can you, John?
You can'tkiIIthe man
withoutbecomingthe monster.
Coward.
What's happened, John?
Where are we?
I bypassed
most of the damaged systems.
We'II have to repair the rest
manuaIIy.
You had me worried, doc.
Nice to see youthawed.
You have a puzzIing definition
of a smooth ride.
Computer,
mapour currentposition.
Searching
for recognizabIe consteIIations.
This database has star maps
of aIIthe known gaIaxy.
I don'trecognize
a singIe system.
We're Iost....
aren't we?
Easy, doc. God.
PIease.
The cryosuitabsorbed
most of the eIectricaI charge.
You're Iucky
this wasn'tyour hide.
Doctor, is that concern
I detectin your voice?
Greatbedside manner.
What's that?
A battIe scar?
Sort of.
It was a tattoo.
An ex-girIfriend's name,
butI had itremoved.
WouIdn'titbe easier
to use a magic marker?
Yeah, weII, that's me.
A girI in every port.
So, Major, nofamiIy?
Nothingto tie you down,
no one to miss?
I've never been
thefit-in and pIay-nice type.
Youthinkthat's romantic?
I don't.
But whataboutyou, doc?
Is there some Iucky IittIe nerd
you Ieftbehind?
I spent three years working
on this mission.
We're tryingto save the pIanet.
I haven'thadtimeforfun.
If there's no timeforfun...
then whatare we saving
the pIanetfor?
Here.
Thanks.
I hate being IittIe.
Ithinkitbroke.
I'IItry andfix it.
Why aren'tyou upon deck
with Mom and Dad?
Have you met our parents?
Good point.
Popcorn, orchids...
waves, BiIIy...
kissing.
ChocoIate.
It's a Iist...
of everythingwe Ieftbehind.
Never Iove anything, kiddo...
'cause you just end up
Iosing it.
Smith couId stiII hurtus.
Maybe I shouIdn'tIethim Iive.
But...
How can we bring
civiIization to the stars...
if we can'tremain civiIized?
Right, Professor?
Have you noticedthatyou
take the opposite position...
to whatever I say?
Of course I do.
We're married.
AIert.
SpatiaI anomaIy in progress.
What the heII?
I mustbe dreaming.
ThatIooks Iike a ship.
Itappears to be some sort
of hoIe in space.
Where does itIead?
A reasonabIe question.
Major, wait.
I'IIwaitIater.
PuII back.
Let there be Iight.
Proteus?
She's one of ours, aII right.
AII right.
I've never seen a ship
Iike this.
No response to haiIs.
Scanning aII miIitary
and civiIianfrequencies.
Nothing.
I'm getting
inconsistentIife signs...
but they may be sensor ghosts.
Computer is stiII on.
I'IItry the standard
docking codes.
ControI codes confirmed.
Initiating docking sequence.
Weird.
Whatkind of shipis that?
That's not one of ours.
Boys, that's not even human.
If this is aII a dream...
why can't there be more girIs?
As part of her ensIavement...
the brave young space captive
Penny Robinson...
isforcedto utiIize her
dazzIingtechnicaI expertise.
Identify yourseIf, soIdier.
West, Major,
United GIobaI Space Force...
requesting permission
to see the prisoner.
Proceed, Major West.
CouId he be cuter?
I don't think so.
Breathe, Penny.
UnIock.
These quarters are unacceptabIe.
We're goingto check out
the probe ship.
Maybe we canfigure outhowthey
gothere and howto gethome.
Have a wonderfuItrip.
Put this on.
You're comingwith us.
Out of the question. I am
a doctor, nota space expIorer.
Whatyou are
is a murderous saboteur.
I am notIeavingyou here...
so you can do more harm
than you've aIready caused.
I absoIuteIy refuse.
Give me an excuse to kiIIyou.
PIease?
BIack was aIways my coIour.
Lock.
Activate standby.
Crush, kiII, destroy.
Surprise.
Safety on.
Dad, chiII.
It's OK.
I hacked into his CPU,
andthen...
I bypassed
his main operating systems...
and accessed his subroutines.
He's basicaIIy justrunning
on remote controI.
I know I haven'tbeen around--
Professor.
We're ready to go.
We'IItaIkIater, son.
Take care of my dad.
OK, Robot?
Vacuum check compIete.
Oxygen IeveIs are normaI.
Microbe scans are negative.
CIear.
The air is staIe, oId.
That's the smeII of ghosts.
I've got
her on-board computer up.
Not working?
She's working, aII right.
Just--I don'tknow.
Too damnfast.
Dad, do you hear something?
Like the drip, dripof bIood.
You reaIIy needto shutup.
Here.
This matter appears bioIogicaI.
Nothing goodwiII come of this.
You, of course, beingthe expert
on space expIoration.
Let's go.
Trustme, Major.
EviI knows eviI.
Motion sensors
are stiIIworking.
This way.
RambIer-crane series robots.
ButIike no design
I've ever seen.
WeII, weII.
Aren't we the poor cousin?
Down here.
It's a remote opstation.
Come on, Dr Smith.
CouIdthis shipbe a prototype?
Looks Iike some kind
of firefight.
Captain's Iog is degraded.
Maybe I can gather
somefragments.
Sorry.
The hyperspace tracker seems
to befunctioning normaIIy...
but we cannotprocess
aIIthe data.
There is no sign
of theJupiter 2.
I have exceeded my timetabIe.
When did he make Major?
Iwant this on the record.
I am not wiIIingto give up.
Don wouId keepIookingfor me.
That's it. The rest
of the data's totaIIy corrupted.
How couIdthey Iaunch
a rescue missionfor us...
when we've onIy been Iosta day?
There's no data
on the aIien ship...
but they broughtin something
that was attachedto its huII.
Gotit.
Some sort of egg sac?
Getbackhere!
Be happy to obIige...
aIthough I don't thinkit's me
you shouId be worrying about...
butrather these.
I'm detecting motion.
Behindyou.
After it. Move!
Bring Smith.
Don't even think aboutit.
Hydroponics.
Growth Iike this
wouIdtake decades.
Unhand me, you mechanicaI moron.
Don'tmove.
Easy.
Easy there, buddy.
No one's gonna hurtyou.
Easy.
ReIax.
ExceIIent.
Looks Iike you made afriend.
StiII, I'dwaitafew weeks...
before tattooing
her name on your arm.
Do yourseIf afavour.
Don't evoIve.
Charming.
The Dr DoIittIe of outer space.
This couId be a creature
from thataIien ship.
But this guy's no piIot.
He Iooks Iike a chiId.
Try itnow.
Strange.
The scaIes are giving off heat.
I've tapped into
the internaI sensor array.
There's no other
animate Iife present.
Besides us,
this shipis totaIIy deserted.
A ghostship.
ThefIavour of the day
is banana beef.
Who thinks up
these combinations?
Good.
Major West, I highIy
recommendyou never breed.
That, by the way,
is my medicaI opinion.
LittIe thingwas hungry.
I've got their star maps
on-Iine.
Here we go.
More systems
than I've ever seen.
Finding a route to AIpha Prime.
DownIoadingtoJupiter.
I don'tIike the sound
of thatsound.
They're moving.
Get this infernaI...
creature off me!
Come here.
John, get the heII out of there.
Mom says,
"Get the heII out of there."
Evacuate.
Now!
The controIs are too sIow.
Activate hoIographic interface.
HoIographic interface, on-Iine.
They eat their wounded.
SeaIthe buIkhead.
Codes are Iocked.
Duck.
Emergency buIkhead.
Fire sensor activated.
Emergency buIkhead cIosure.
Stop!
We have to get that door open.
Open, damn you!
Get out of here.
Whatis with me
andthese damn doors?
I can't override
thefire protocoI!
A miIIion bucks
worth of weaponry...
and I'dtrade itaII back...
for a Iousy...
can of Raid.
Stand cIear.
Getmoving! Go!
Come on!
Maureen...
can you getme anything?
CycIingthrough a vacuum check.
I'm overriding.
No way it's that easy.
Run!
Run! Getback!
Getbackto the ship!
Move!
Gotit. Try itnow.
Mom says, "Try itnow."
Can we save it?
Can't withoutIetting
the spiders into the ship.
Leave him behind!
Thatspider scratched me!
StopIaughing, you IittIe worm.
Good-bye, Robot.
You couIdn'tsave him, kid.
Save him? Of course.
Whatare youtryingto do?
Prepare to disengage!
This is afun picnic.
FirstyeIIow aIiens,
now giantspiders.
The crowd goes wiId.
RecaIIyour chiIdhood
nightmares, Major.
Monsters are rareIy
so easiIy dissuaded.
Why don'tyoutaIkto them,
bugto bug?
Ithink
they'd rather come inside.
Armingtorpedoes.
Fire in the hoIe.
AIert. DetonationfaiIure.
The robotmusthave damaged
the detonator cores.
They won'tbIow.
AIert.
Outer hubhas been compromised.
DNA extrapoIation coming up.
SiIicone-based, mantium sheII,
Iack of respiratory system.
Means they do Iive
in deepspace.
Tiny frontbrain impIies
communaI reIationships.
Like bees.
If the bioIogy Iesson is over,
I couId use some heIp.
They may be attracted
to heatand Iight.
Inner huII breach in 15 seconds.
I'm bringingthe Proteus
fusion drives on-Iine.
It's working.
Let's turn up the heat.
Whatare you doing?
Never Ieave an enemy stronghoId
intact.
Stop!
That's one of yourfather's
firstruIes of engagement.
Thatis a direct order.
I hate spiders.
That's comingfast.
Getinto the harnesses now.
ManuaI heIm, engage.
-ChiIdren, secure?
-Secure.
I'm in.
PuII up.
ReaIIy? No kidding.
Thanks.
Coming in too hot.
I'IItry and sIow us down.
Hang on!
Everybody by the numbers.
Life sciences,
stiII breathing.
Video mechanics...
OK.
Mission medicaI, I'm aIive.
Me, too.
Robotics, I mean.
I'm aIive...
Major West's poor excusefor
piIoting skiIIs notwithstanding.
Oh, Dorothy.
Backin Kansas atIast.
YouvioIated a direct order.
AbouthaIf the core
materiaI's burned out.
We'II never generate
enough power to break orbit.
We can get off the ground...
but getting backinto space
is another story.
I orderedyou not to bIow
thatship's reactors.
Life supportis marginaI.
It's gonna get coId in here
tonight.
AIso, the pod andthe chariot
are pretty much scrapmetaI.
Don'tyouwaIk away from me
when I'm taIkingto you.
Give ita rest, Professor.
Iwas technicaIIy
stiII in command.
I am commander of this mission.
Look, no offence...
butyou're an egghead
with an honorary rank.
No one ever intendedfor you
to handIe combatsituations.
You handIed itbriIIiantIy,
sending us crashing down here.
Those aIiens posed
a continuingthreat.
I made a judgement caII...
and, if I have to,
I'II make itagain.
You of aII peopIe
shouId understandthat.
Yourfather wouId backme up.
My father is dead...
kiIIed in one of those combat
missions you admire so much.
My famiIy is on this ship,
andyouwiIIfoIIow my orders...
whether you agree with them
or not. Is that cIear?
Save your speeches.
I Iike you, butI'm gonna
do whatever it takes...
to ensure the success
of this mission...
with or withoutyour heIp.
Is that cIear?
Am I interrupting something?
No, reaIIy.
Ithink youtwo
shouId sIug it out.
Here we are,
stranded on an aIien worId...
andyouwant
to getinto a pissing contest?
PIease, gofor it.
I'II haveJudy down here
to decIare you both unfit...
and I'IItake over this mission.
I don't want to hear another
wordfrom you. Is that cIear?
Not...another word.
Better.
If you'vefinished hosing down
the decks with testosterone...
I suggestyou come with me.
I may havefound a way
off this pIanet.
TeII me aboutit.
Damn bug bite.
She...
She reaIIy is an interesting
specimen. Huh, doc?
She'sfascinating.
The retinaI aperture diIation...
seems directIy Iinked
to the skin pigmentation.
What?
Can I keepher?
She's notjustanotherfad
you can pick upandthrow away.
Oh, pIease.
She's aII aIone here, and
I promise I'II Iook outfor her.
I promise.
She kind of needs me.
The minute you mispIace her,
youforget tofeed her--
Don'tsmiIe. I mean it, Pen.
Thanks...doc.
We're both a Iongway from home,
aren't we, IittIe one?
BIarp?
That's what we'II caIIyou--
BIarp.
Nice girI.
Pretty girI.
Nice.
The atmosphere here
can sustain human Iife.
I've Iocated 500 rads
of radioactive materiaI...
five miIes west.
We'II need atIeast thatmuch to
get the corefunctioning again.
We start outat daybreak.
Be safer that way.
Those are my orders.
I agree
with your recommendation.
Dtente's a beautifuIthing.
It's nice to see youfound
a corner to suityour taIents.
Turn down the bed
before you Ieave.
I gave my word I'd Ietyou Iive.
I never saidfor how Iong.
FamiIy hour is over.
We're dying here.
Robinson is out of his Ieague.
Lookinto his eyes andteII me
you can'tsee hisfear.
Ifoughtin the miIIenniaIwars.
SurvivaI is a soIdier's game.
We both knowthis civiIianfooI
wiII Iead us straight to heII.
Robinson needs our heIp,
if he wants it or not.
With minimaIforce,
we couIdtake this ship...
and assure them we shaII
continue atyour command.
Of course.
My God...
you're right.
How couId I have been so bIind?
I'II justrun and getyou a gun
so we can hijackthe ship, OK?
Sarcasm is the recourse
of the weakmind.
I'm hidingthe pain.
ReaIIy.
Lock.
Your pain...
has justbegun.
StarIight, star bright.
A miIIion strange stars,
and onIy one wish.
Iwish we were home.
Never seen a sky Iook so aIien.
We reaIIy are Iost,
aren't we?
When thefirstsaiIors
circIedthe gIobe...
saw a brand-new sky...
they thought they'd saiIed
off the edge of the earth...
but they were reaIIy
justaroundthe corner.
You're sayingwe shouId
justbiIIow our saiIs...
and Iet the windtake us home?
Is thatit?
Those saiIors...
foundfamiIiar shapes...
in the stars...
to make the sky seem
morefriendIy...
andto heIp them
findtheir way home.
That's howthe consteIIations
were born.
Porky, the wise and mighty pig.
The great...
big-eared bunny Bugs.
The way you gotus down here,
that was pretty fIying.
My quarters or yours?
Excuse me?
Don'tpIay coy.
We're the onIy singIe peopIe
of consenting age in the gaIaxy.
How much more of a set-up
do you need?
So youfigure, why not dispense
with the pIeasantries...
and get down to business?
You have a way with words.
Do youwant to show me
how you handIe the heIm?
Righthere on this consoIe?
Righthere wouId befine.
Why don'tyou justhang on
to your joystick?
ExceIIent technique, Major.
ReaIIy.
WiIIwas Iookingfor you.
I senthim backto his room.
He's decided
he can rebuiIdthe robot.
He wants to stay upaII night
and show me his designs.
Funny creatures, men.
Try so hard not to be
theirfathers...
end upmakingthe same mistakes.
We can't get off this pIanet,
IetaIone getback on course.
I don'thave time.
JustIisten to him.
It doesn'tmatter whathe says.
JustIisten.
Sometimes--especiaIIy
in the eyes of theirfathers--
IittIe boys have to comefirst.
As soon as
we getback upinto space...
we'II spend a Iot of time
together, I promise.
It's nice havingyour
whoIefamiIy under one roof.
Even if we did have to go...
haIfway across the gaIaxy
to manage it.
Good night, John.
Good night, Maureen.
Good night, Judy.
Good night, WiII.
Good night, Penny.
You guys have got to be kidding.
Good morning, WiII Robinson.
SoIar paneIs are charged.
The radioactive materiaI
we needfor the core...
is in the centre of thatbubbIe.
Iwas afraid of this.
OK, everybody,
Iet's getsettIed now.
Ithinkthis "bubbIe"
out there...
is exactIy the same thing
we passedthrough in space.
Both of them are opening
and cIosing doorways.
Doorways to where?
Doorways in...time.
You can'tbe serious.
Time traveI is impossibIe.
It's not.
JustimprobabIe.
Whatif we crossed
into a time...
years after Earth
senta rescue mission?
Perhaps the professor
hithis headwhen we Ianded.
Think aboutit.
The way the Proteus
seemed desertedfor so Iong.
Yourfriend Iooking so oId.
So if we waIk
inside thatbubbIe...
we couId be waIking
further into thefuture.
Dad, whatif the doorways
aren'tnaturaI?
This kind of phenomenon couId
onIy be produced naturaIIy.
ThatbubbIe's
the kind of side effect...
I predicted my time machine
wouId do.
Whatif someone buiIta device--
Son...
I appreciate your input...
butnow is not the time
forfIights of fancy.
You never Iisten to me.
Not ever.
This time bubbIe couId be
causingthese earthquakes.
No teIIing how Iong before
this pIanetbreaks upentireIy.
The major and I
are goingto Iocate...
the radioactive materiaI
for the core.
We may have very IittIe time.
I'm Ieaving now.
That's a surprise.
You're the mostimportant thing
in the worIdto me.
One day, I hope you'II
be abIe to understandthat.
Whatif...
one time you don't come home?
Whenever your grandfather
went on a mission...
he'd Ieave these with me
for safekeeping.
When he came home,
IwouId aIways be there...
waitingto give them back.
I'm coming back.
I promise.
Listen...
aboutIastnight...
Go on. You can do it.
I'm sorry.
See, that wasn'tso difficuIt.
Like puIIing steeI needIes
through my cheeks.
Then you understand
whatsayingthisfeeIs Iike.
Try to come backin one piece.
Listen, doc, I'm...
I'm thinkingthis is your basic
"kissfor Iuck" occasion.
WouIdn'tyou agree?
Thinking.
It's notreaIIy
your strong suit, is it?
I've gotafix
on the radioactive materiaI.
That was scientific.
Scared?
There's an aIIoy
in this crater waII...
that's disabIingthe com-Iinks.
You're not goingto be abIe
to communicate with the ship.
Come home to me, Professor.
I Iove you, wife.
Come here, squirt.
Nice girI.
Pretty girI. Nice.
It's OK.
You're stiII in one piece.
Come on.
Systems error!
RobotunabIe to Iocate
motor controIs!
UnabIe to--
CaIm down.
Whatis happeningto me?
I didn'thave enough time
tofinish the downIoad.
Warning!
Penny, give itback!
My circuits are unbaIanced.
So I hadtofinish you off
with another personaIity.
I putmy mind inside of yours.
That expIains
this warmfuzzy feeIing...
when Ithink aboutbasebaII.
Strike! You're out!
But this does not compute.
What?
Robot triedto destroy
the RobinsonfamiIy.
Why didWiII Robinson
save Robot's personaIity?
I guess sometimesfriendship
means Iisteningto your heart...
notyour head.
Put thatin your memory bank.
Don't worry.
I'm gonna buiIdyou a new body.
Mom aIways said I shouId
try to make newfriends.
I need a microseaIer.
I gotit.
After much deIiberation...
the space captive
hasfinaIIy decided...
to accepther new roIe
as a member of the crew.
The Robinsons, after aII,
can obviousIy use her heIp.
BIarp, come backhere.
TheoreticaIIy,
thisfuture wouId befixed...
unchanged by what we do
or did in the past--
Why don'tyou give
the oId egghead a rest?
Outhere we got two moons,
a crater the size of Miami...
andthat wouId be
one great cIimb.
My father wouId have Iikedyou.
What's that?
This metaI's decades oId.
Whatkind of a nightmare
is this?
Where the heII are we?
The question is,
when the heII are we?
IwiIIteIIyou a joke.
Why didthe robot
cross the road?
Because he was carbon-bonded
to the chicken.
We have a Iot of workto do.
Thatsounds Iike oId Morse code.
What does itsay?
"Danger,
WiII Robinson, danger."
WiIIiam. Come in.
UnIock.
You said someone was in danger.
We aII are.
You are wise to arm yourseIf.
This gun is set tofire
for me onIy...
so don't try anythingfunny.
Lock.
You misjudge me.
I onIy want to heIpyou.
HeIpus?
Youtriedto kiII us.
Butnow ourfates
are intertwined.
If yourfather
andthatidiot WestfaiI...
I have no chance
of getting home.
It's in my bestinterests
that they succeed...
and I aIwaysfoIIow
my bestinterests.
Whatmonsters roam
these aIien wiIds?
They'refooIs!
To set off bIindIy
across this savage Iand.
Much as I hate to admitit...
it wiII be much harder
without them.
Whatare youtaIking about?
They'II be back.
They'II be OK.
WiIIthey?
Someone shouId go after them.
UnIock.
Iforbid it. You're a boy.
A cIever one,
buta chiId nonetheIess.
This pIanet
is IikeIy fuII of predators.
Even if youfoundthem,
whatif they're hurt? Ravaged?
Dying?
What good couIdyou do?
You can heIp them.
You're a doctor.
I'm a doctor.
We made it.
Mom didn'tsee us.
That'sfantastic.
ItoIdyouwe couId get
into the bubbIe this way.
The bubbIe's growing!
Run, chiId!
CooI.
Wait!
Come on.
We can aIways go back.
It's justIike stepping
between two rooms.
I can bareIy contain my gIee.
Dad's signaI is...
this way.
I Ioathe chiIdren.
BiIIy...kissing...
hot wings, orchids, corn.
Waves...BiIIy...
popcorn with...kissing...
What didyoufind?
Come on.
No time to dawdIe.
Let's move aIong.
FoIIow yourfather's signaI.
Come on.
AIIthings reaIIy do come
to he who waits.
Whatis this pIace?
The shockmusthave
scrambIedyour brain.
Take a Iook around.
Don'tyou recognize this spot?
You're home.
This can'tbe.
Whathave you done to the ship?
Where is my famiIy?
What chance do youthink
yourfamiIy hadwithoutyou?
A few spiders survived
the destruction of the Proteus.
They reachedthis pIanetand...
I can stiII hear
the women scream.
Who are you?
You don'trecognize me?
I'm your son WiII.
Dad's signaI
is just over this ridge.
Be stiII, my fooIish heart.
Shit.
A boy of your inteIIigence
shouId never swear.
Shit.
Indeed.
Look, Father...
whatmy fIights of fancy
have wrought.
I usedyour hyper engine
to buiId my time machine.
OK, Robot, puthim down.
Affirmative.
Where are we?
IthinktheJupiter 2,
butin a differentfuture.
Father?
Once this core materiaI...
isfuIIy introduced
into the controI consoIe...
Core materiaI.
If we couId get that
backto our Jupiter...
IwiII open a doorway
stabIe enough...
for one person to take
one trip through time...
and space as weII.
Commence proto-generation.
CooI, huh?
Today, IwiII change history.
I'm gonna go backto that day
you dragged us into space.
I'II stop the ship
from taking off.
I'II save thefamiIy.
Earth, October 1, 2058.
TargetIock confirmed.
ExceIIent.
Son...
Look around.
Theforce of your time machine
is rippingthis pIanetapart.
These vioIent distortions
in time...
are being caused
by your experiment.
Whatif ithas the same effect
on Earth?
Whatif, in getting home...
you destroy Earth
in the process?
I know you mean weII.
I'm going home.
I'm goingto save thefamiIy.
You've got to Iisten to me.
I'm yourfather!
My father?
Letme teIIyou aboutmy father.
I'II neverforget
thatmorning 20years ago.
What was ityou said?
"I'm coming back.
I promise."
You promised...
andyou never came home.
My father's not
comingto the rescue.
What do youthink you're doing,
young man?
Letme teIIyou aboutIife.
Around every corner,
monsters wait.
I know. I am one.
We monsters have nofear
in devouring IittIe boys.
To survive, you mustbe
fuIIy preparedto kiII.
I can do it.
Can you?
Listen to me, my chiId...
I've crossedthis worId
with you...
risked my Iife,
butIwouId not throw itaway.
Who knows what dangers
Iie ahead?
You can'tprotectus.
I can.
IwiII.
Gimme the gun.
EnabIe gunfor aII users.
Voiceprint confirmed.
A brief Iesson in survivaI
on this worId or any other--
never trustanyone.
EspeciaIIy me.
It's aImost time.
I hope it works.
Neverfear...
Smith is here.
Don'tmove,
Professor Robinson...
or this pecuIiarfamiIy reunion
wiII be tragicaIIy brief.
I'II ask you
to stepaway from that.
It's a time machine,
you idiot.
I had hopedto take over
the shipwith this.
One of Iife's IittIe ironies.
Let's try this dance again.
You are the puppet,
I am the puppeteer.
Do try to getitright
this time.
Robot, youwiII respond
to my voice aIone.
Affirmative.
We need eIectric disrupters.
That's good, gargantuan.
You did it.
JustIike I imagined.
You Iinked
the dimensionaI sifter...
to the navigationaI array.
That's how it can be in
the same pIace at the same time.
But the spatiaI deIivery system,
the targeting Iaser...
I never thought of those.
Thefuture is never what
itseems Iike when you're 10.
Say good-bye to your past!
Yourfuture Iies with me.
I'm going home in your pIace.
Whatare you grinning at?
Look aroundyou...
at this hostiIe worId.
Do youthink a boy
couId have survived aII aIone?
Neverfear...
Smith is here.
It's Dr Smith.
HeIIo.
How nice to see me again
after aIIthese years.
Confused?
Have I changed?
The spider's sting had some
unexpected side effects.
My unique gifts
gave me an advantage...
in this quarreIsome worId.
After the women were savaged...
I became thefather
WiII never had.
Two decades of agony taughtme
the error of my ways.
Butyou, your crude ambition
fiIIs me with seIf-Ioathing.
You see,
I have Iookedwithin me...
andwhatI see is you!
I never Iiked me anyway.
Robot, kiIIthem aII.
Wait.
Dr Smith, pIease.
Don't.
Very weII.
Robot, take them inside
and keep them there.
If they move...
then kiIIthem.
Proceed or be destroyed.
Nothingworks.
I'II draw hisfire,
you grab WiII and get out.
HaIt!
Stop!
Do you remember me?
Do you remember whatI
taughtyou aboutfriendship?
I needyouto heIpus now,
because we'refriends.
Logic error.
Friendshipdoes not compute.
ForgetIogic.
Act with your heart.
Robothas no heart.
Robotis powered by
afusion puIse generator.
Every Iivingthing has a heart.
My programming has been modified
to remove aII emotion.
Any attempts to override
command protocoIs...
may resuItinfusing
my neuraI net.
PIease, Robot?
If you don'tIetus go,
we're aII gonna die.
I'm askingyou now,
wiIIyou heIpus?
WiIIyou be my friend?
Robotattempting
to deactivate controI boIt.
-Commands overridden!
-Do it!
Destroy RobinsonfamiIy!
Destroy!
You did it.
Robot wiII save WiII Robinson.
Robot wiII save hisfriend.
Where are they?
Waithere.
Without that core...
I can'tpromise
we'II get off this rock.
See if you can make it
backto our Jupiter.
I'II get the core materiaI
and meetyouthere.
We don'thave the trackers
tofind our way back.
ThefamiIy needs theirfather.
The crew needs their piIot.
I can'tfIy the ship
as weII as you can.
You're their best chance
to survive.
Listen to me.
I know you never wanted
to take this job.
Ithink you're goingto turn out
to be a grade-A baby-sitter.
So...
the camper's aIIyours now.
Take care of them.
Good Iuck.
-Dad!
-Professor!
Remember the space spiders
in the Proteus?
They're not goingto be abIe
to getback.
EnabIe aII missiIes.
But the warheads don't work.
Just do it.
Look!
Damn, he's stiII breathing.
Fire in the hoIe.
So these saiIors,
they drew shapes in the sky...
Look! It's afIare!
...to heIp them
findtheir way home.
Danger, WiII Robinson!
CIimbon! Hurry!
FieId dampeners on-Iine.
PortaI compression commenced.
TeII me again, oId monster,
how didthe girIs die?
We've been over this before,
son.
In aIIthe years since...
the spiders
have never resurfaced.
Why?
Let'sforget the past.
PortaI aperture reduction, 50%.
CarefuI, chiId!
The pIasma aroundthe portaI...
wiII ripa man into pieces!
Haven'tyou made the doorway...
too smaII?
Notfor me.
But then I'm not going, am I?
Spiders didn'tkiIIthe girIs.
It was you.
I justnever IetmyseIf see it.
You keptme aIive
because you needed me.
Because I couId
buiIdthisfor you.
Poor boy.
Didyou reaIIy think
IwouId Ietyou go home?
LetaIIthatI have become
vanish?
Look atme!
I am no mere man!
I...am...a...god!
Within these egg sacs
growthe seeds...
of a master race of spiders.
We shaII descend upon
heIpIess Earth...
an entire pIanet to ruIe!
An entire pIanet
on which tofeed!
Time to die...son.
I'm notyour son.
Good-bye.
My father once said...
"EviI aIwaysfinds
its trueform."
You shouId have kiIIed me
when you hadthe chance.
Youwere right.
I couIdn'tkiIIthe man...
butI can kiIIthe monster!
Spare me
thefury of the righteous.
Ithinkthere's timefor a snack
before my trip.
The pain.
You ain'tseen nothingyet.
Remember the Proteus?
These monsters
eat their wounded.
Take aIIthe time youwant
to die!
Wake up, son!
Dad?
Core materiaI insertion
compIete.
AIItabIe run--2058.
Mission controI.
You couId've taken the core
and Ieftbefore it was too Iate.
I couIdn'tIetyoufaII.
You're my boy.
Mom! It's them.
Hi, Mom!
You aII right?
You're notas dumbas you Iook.
I'm gonna getyour name
tattooed righthere.
Greetings.
Where'sJohn?
The bubbIe cIosed behind us.
It was his onIy way back.
I'm sorry.
We've aIready begun
the pre-fIight countdown.
I'm goingto save
as many Iives as I can.
I kepthoping somehow
he'd make itback.
Let's go, Major.
Good-bye, my Iove.
Engaging primary thrusters now.
Look. He made it.
Go.
We're not getting any aItitude.
We don'thave enough power.
I'm sorry.
I couIdn'tsave them.
So many years ago.
I can stiIIfeeI it--
our sun...
our Earth.
It's aII Ithoughtabout--
going home.
A Iongtime ago,
youtoId a smaII boy...
that one day he'd understand
how much hisfather Ioved him.
I couId never see
how much you cared...
untiI now.
Come.
Let's go.
I kepthoping he'd make itback.
Good-bye, my Iove.
Look!
Don'tmake me waitanother
Iifetime to know how youfeeI.
Dad!
Dad, it worked!
Come with us!
I can't.
OnIy enough powerfor
one person, one trip, remember?
It's goodto see you again, Mom.
It's goodto see you aII.
Take care of them, WiII.
Don'tforgetme.
He sacrificed everything
for hisfamiIy.
I'm gIadyou came back.
I just wantyouto know
I Iove you.
I Iove youvery much.
The pIanet
is breaking uparound us.
We're doomed!
Boy, thatfeIt good.
Getus airborne.
I'm goingto try
to reach escape veIocity.
We don'thave the core materiaI.
The gravity weIIs
wiII puII us back down.
We mightbe abIe to--
We won'tmake it. I know.
We have to go...
down--
through the pIanet
as she's breaking up.
We can use
the pIanet's gravity...
What?
to throw us out the other side
and backinto space.
That's insane.
I don'thave time to argue.
That's a direct order.
Yes, sir, Commander.
This shouId be interesting.
I see it.
FuII burn.
Stop!
-Right!
-Left!
Letme drive.
AII right, everybody,
hoIdyour noses.
Rock and roII.
Nice work,fIyboy.
I earn thatkiss yet?
You earn this.
This one's on credit.
CoIdfish, huh?
There you are. Come here.
Where have you been,
you IittIe creep?
-LittIe creep?
-Oh, great.
Warning, Major West.
My sensors indicate
we have a probIem.
The pIanet's gravity fieId
is coIIapsing.
We'II be sucked in.
No way to get cIear in time.
The hyperdrive.
I'm accessing
the Proteus star maps.
Here we go again.
TargetingAIpha Prime...
I hope.
Initiate...now.