From czech subtitles translated bluedog - p.d.
Some events of this movie are based on fiction.
It's not possible to completely show...
complexity of a man's life,
which everybody perceives differently.
Mesrine: Part 1 - Death Instinct
I was born maybe a half mile from here.
Go ahead, go.
- Did you let him in?
- Yeah.
Algeria, 1959.
- I can't...
- Everything will be alright, brother.
Look at me, everything will be fine.
Think about your family.
Look at me.
Where is the bomb?
God won't help you.
- Stop! Let him go!
- Mind your own shit!
- Mesrine!
- I am gonna shake him up.
Talk...
Look at your brother.
Do you want a cigarette?
Don't tell them anything, they'll kill you anyway.
I like you, tell me
where is the bomb at?
Nobody has to suffer.
I tell you everything.
Don't tell them anything!
Jasmin!
- Where is the bomb?
- Say nothing!
- Don't tell them!
- Shut her hole!
Leave her alone! That's my sister!
Stop!
Leave her alone!
I play with her for a little bit.
Stop!
I kill you!
Kill them!
Shoot!
It's your duty!
No!
Where did you hide the bomb, you bastards?!
Father found you a job.
- Really?
Yes.
- At the factory.
Steelmill?  - Yes, right there.
Good factory. If you'll like it over there,
you'll have a good future.
Thank you.
Hey, where you at?
- Come down.
- Ok, i'll be right there.
I'll be right back.
- You haven't eaten anything. - Do you have any money?
Yes, I do.
- So, how was it with the guerilas?
- It was a piece of cake.
- How was Algeria?
- Good. I don't feel like talking about it.
- You have a nice ride. I see you're doing fine.
- I'm not complaining.
I'm doing some work, you know. It's good money.
- Tell me more about it.
- I'll tell you  everything about it.
- And where are we going?
- I asked where we are going?
- It's always so many people here.
- Always packed.
Let's go.
Ladies, how are you?
I came with my friend.
Take care of him.
We'll see.
Jacques, come here.
- He's handsome.
- I'll be having fun with Suzan.
- I'm Sarah.
- Sarah...
Haven't we met before?
- Are you in it for the money only?
- Yeah, only when i get paid.
You'll pay me.
You're very nice, but i won't let you go unless you pay me.
We'll see.
Hey guys.
- Where you been?
- Some of us have to work too.
- This is Major.
- This is my payout. Who's dealing?
- You wanna lift?
- I take a walk.
I'm completely broke.
Can i borrow for a cab?
- That's too much. - Are you sure?
- Yeah, thanks.
Listen these your "dirty jobs", could you let me in?  - Yes.
- Relax, just push harder.
- Ok.
The safe is behind that bookshelf.
This one?
Look what i found.
- Check it out, so much money is here.
- What a catch.
Thieves!
What do you want here?
- Hello, are you the owners of this apartment?
- Yes. - Excellent.
Inspector Bernar... Romain Japlé.
The Police.
I must inform you that you've been robbed.
- And that's not all. Those scumbags
turned your bedroom upside down.
- God!
- Calm down honey.
- Calm down madam. I'm sorry.
- We found this weapon at your place.
- Yes, this is my rifle.
I hope you have a permit for it.
Bring it to the police precinct as soon as possible.
- To be honest, i don't know  where it is...
- Daniel, did you take the fingerprints?   Yes, i did.
Get ready, we're going to laboratory.
- Eduard, come take a look.
- Go, i think missus will be shocked.
Quiet Marie, calm down.
- We'll be expecting you at the precinct tomorrow at 9.
- Ok, we'll be there.
Thank you.
- Listen, Do you still have these kinda jobs?
-  Sure, a plenty.
- Do you want me to introduce you to the boss?
Who is it? - Guido.
Guido, this is my buddy Jacques Mesrine i talked to you about.
Jacques Mesrine?
- Paul told me a lot about you.
Thanks.  - Sit down.
When are you going to stop bringing me these
wandering dogs from the streets?
- It's not...
- Are you talking about me?
- No, not you.
- I asked you something , Paul.
- And i asked you too, grandpa!
- What?
- Wandering dogs? You mean me?
What's pissing you off?
- I hope you have a big army behind you.
- My army is secret organization.
Everybody recognize it
and it attacks whenever it wants to.
You are just bragging, you old babbler.
- If you don't know how to socialize
with older people, you shithead,
then i will have to teach you some manners.
And what else would you like?
Are you looking for this?
That's what happens when you hug old people.
- Where is you respect?
- Okay, calm down.
Don't be afraid I'm not a sociopath.
- Yes.
- I see you're not dumb.
I give you an advice,
the kind you'll only get from a friend.
In our bussiness you can't win.
At the end of your career if you lucky...
you'll get this.
If you get out of  water dry...
Are you following me?
Thanks.
I take your advice to my heart.
If you really consider me as a friend,
call me Jacques.
Of course Jacques, sure.
My Jacques. My lovely Jacques.
Do you wanna do it again?
I have a friend, but... if you'll pay me,
i'll work for you.
Have you lost your mind?
What are you blabbing about?
Who do you think i am?
Some sucker?
I don't need your services.
I'll manage without you.
Don't be so pissed.
- I like you, Sarah
- I like you too.
You must be careful how you talk to me.
Hi.
- Your boss called.
- What did he want?
He said you didn't come to work for a week.
- And what?
- What "what"?
Father have found you a good job
and that's the way you pay him back?
So what. What's your problem?
Leave me alone!
Good man earns for his livelihood honestly!
Keeps his family together and has a respect for them.
Talk to your son!
You know, Me and your mom, we don't want you to leave.
It's your house.
Your mom, your mom...
Speak for yourself for once.
What's going on with you, Jacqui?
Jacques is tired of his father being henpecked.
And i am ashamed how you
collaborated with germans.
And one more thing, tell me one reason
why i should be proud of my father.
No, i didn't work for germans.
- I was forced to.
- Nobody forced you, dad!
The same way nobody forced me to go to Algeria!
My god, just tell me what's going on with you.
Do you have any pride?
Spain, 1960.
- It's nice here.
- I wouldn't lie to you.
These two are coming to greet us.
Excuse me.
How you doing?
- Good?
- We are french.
- Blond is mine.
- Ok, then i take brunette.
Do you understand?
Yeah, i do.
- Paris, Paris... France.
- Eiffel tower. - Yeah.
You know... Wait.
Hey, Paul, how do you say kiss in spanish?
- Beso.
- Oh, kiss!
A little beso...
- I want you "beso".
- No, please.
- I got to go.
- No, no, no...
Hey, man!
Hi.
Would you like to dance?
- In spanish you say  "bailar".
- Bailar? Great. So, would you like to "bailar"?
No.
Sofia, say yes.
- Are you coming?
- Yes.
- I'd like to dance, boy.
- Frenchmen don't dance.
Come to my room, number 10.
- No, no. - Why?
- No.
- Really?
- Yes.
I have never been with someone before.
It's the first time.
- First time?
- Yes.
Sofia...
Hey, Jacques!
It's time, let's go!
We got to go.
Move a bit faster.
Get in.
We're leaving.
Bye!
What can you do in weather like this?
Weather is not bothering me,
I work where it doesn't matter.
- What do you need the gun for?
- You don't carry the gun?
- No, I don't. If you do anything can happen.
- Is it here? - Yeah.
- Good evening!
- Do you want something to drink?
- Give me whiskey. - Double.
- Is Sarah here?
- No, she's not but she'll be here soon.
Sarah is taken, but Mado is free.
Go!
I wouldn't take this one.
- Gentlemen, would you buy a lady a drink?
- Get lost!
- What if you'd show some respect for the lady?
- Beat it! Get lost!
What's that about?
Are you serving faggots in your bar?
I told you to get lost!
Hey, you!
What kind of manners are these?
What's wrong?
Anyone else wants some too? Huh?
Jacques, What are you doing here?
Leave him alone!
- My poor boy. - What are you doing?
- Have you lost your mind?
- Are selling yourself because of him?
Yeah. And you got a problem with it? He's my friend, ok?
You snake! Get out of here!
I didn't ask you for anything!
- My love.
- My nose...
- I'm so sorry.
- Sweet couple.
Get out of here!
Get out!
I'm sorry, Sarah.
God!
Sit in back.
Your nose got bigger.
It's nothing.
And how's Sarah, is she alive?
Listen Jacques, i've made an agreement with Guido.
I let you have her.
I fixed her smile a little bit .
Ahmed, that's nice suit.
- It's a classic. Isn't it Guido?
- A classic suit.
- Is excellent. - Oh, yeah.
- I look in it like a real frenchman.
Frenchman?
You know how they call an Arab in suit like this?
- Do you know it, Guido?
- No, I don't know.
They say, "defendant , stand up!"
good joke.
Jacques, do you know what they call Arab in ashtray?
No.
A wastefulness. Three of them would fit in it.
Good joke.
- We're just joking.
- Don't be afraid.
- We are not like that.
- No, we are not.
You son of bitch.
I spit on people like you!
Guido,  i gave you a word of a man.
I promised you!
- Your arab word is worth a shit!
- Shut up!
Shut up!
- Come here so i can see you better.
- Look, he whiffs like girl. - Shut your hole!
I would put bullet in a man's head,
but an animal like you, i finish off with knife!
Did you want to sell Sarah!
For how much?
Die you asshole!
Well, what you got?
Flesh.
- What's that?
- That's not important.
- Jacques, did you get married?
- Yes, I did.
- Are you married?
- I am.
Heard that, Guido?
He got married.
- She's pregnant.
- He got married because she is pregnant. Bravo.
Enough.
Hey, are you gonna serve me finally?
Pour drinks! Bitch!
Move your ass! What are you doing?
Pour drinks!
Hey, guys, what's the problem?
And who are you?
Son of this bitch or the owner?
Please, serve them.
move your ass!
Well, you see.
Nothing's happening. Keep playing.
Everything is okay.
This for disrespect
and this for your drinks.
- Does it always take so long?
- Depends.
- 8-10 hours, depends.
- That long?
Depends, maybe even longer.
- When you become father, maybe you'll settle down.
- Maybe.
Lot of things change with time but me.
- Only a few people change.
- It's true.
- Do you remember Skazatov?  - Who is he?
- You shot him in his knees, that guy.
Oh, Skazatov, i remember.
And what about him?
A couple days ago he came with two buddies and was asking about you.
Were they tough guys?
Yes they were.
But without my approval they won't do anything to you.
Really? So it's cool.
What are they doing over there?
A child.
- Mister Mesrine?
- It's me. Guido, finally.
You have a beautiful daughter.
You the man.
- How are you?
- She's beautiful.
Hi.
What happened?
- Were you out with buddies and whores?
- Yeah, you're right.
Wait.
Let me finish it.
Yeah, i was with my buddies.
- How about whores?
- Whores?
Whores.
why would i need whores when i have a woman like you?
That bank looks great. Only two tellers work there,
but most importantly there's no safe.
These morons keep money
under regular lock.
Jacques, it's a walk in the park.
- And you don't want to do it?
- No.
- Why?
- Because i'm going with Guido.
- I don't have any choice and you know that.
- That bank can be easily robbed.
Get in, get out, the same way bunnies fuck.
- Yeah, as long as bunnies won't get fucked by someone else.
- Yeah.
To bunnies!
I do it!
Prison d´Evreux, 1962.
- How are you?
- Dad.
Did she say "dad"?
My little girl. Dad.
She said it.
I'm dad.
Your daddy.
She said it for the first time.
Jacques...
I don't know what to do.
- What do you mean?
- I phoned your parents and they said...
i should go back to Spain.
What kinda crap is this? Is this why you came here?
To look at me and tell me you're taking my daughter away from me?
Sofia, look at me.
Do you want to tell me that?
I love you...
...you're my wife.
I need you a lot.
Phone my parents,
they'll help you out. Sofia...
For them you're like their own daughter.
- Will you phone them?
- Yes, I will.
This is my mom. Mom.
She's a beauty your mom.
I just got out of jail. I'm not ashamed to say
i was there for robberies.
And the reason I don't have any references
it's simply because...
my life was on the edge since i came back from army.
And right here I'd like to  start fresh from zero.
I'm doing this because of my parents, my wife
and of course for myself.
But most importantly for little daughter because...
... i have a little a daughter.
You know, your past is not helping you.
But at the same time i feel your honesty.
You can start work tomorrow.
- Really?
Yes.  - Thank you.
- I'll show you where you'll work.
- Sure.
This way, please.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Jacques, your little Bruno is a cutie.
Doesn't he cry during the night?
Only rarely, but that's pretty normal.
- Does he cry?
No. - You're sweet.
- Just wait when his teeth start coming out...
- Anyway, we'll see.
- I adore kus-kus.
- You know what, you should open a restaurant.
- You're good cook.
- Besides, he already has a job with a good pay.
- We don't miss anything.
- Don't get excited.
Sofia, come to me, honey.
- Good night.
Good night.  - Bye, bye.
I have a job for you.
You wanna make some money?
No, i don't.
- No?
- No, i don't want to.
Because of Sabrine and Bruno.
I live and support myself honestly.
Alright we'll discuss it any other time.
Let me know.
- Jacques, you got a minute?
- Yeah, i do.
- I have serious problems.
- Like what?
I'll have to fire somebody.
- But above all...
- I get it.
- Wait...
- It's alright.
- Last one to come, first one to go.
- I haven't decided yet.
- Don't make anything out of it, you're good man.
- Don't worry because of me.
- So, i'm ready.
Let's go.   - Jacques?
- Jacques, where are you going?
- Everything's ok. I'm going out with my buddies.
What buddies?
You said you're done with it.
- Listen to me!
- You listen to me! I don't have time for this now.
- You promised me that you won't hang out with them anymore.
- That's history.
Go back to them and
that whore too!
- And what's bothering you?
- Why can't you just stay home?
This is the home of my parents!
I lost my job!
- I don't care whose home is it!
- Quiet! You wake up Bruno!
If you leave, I'll call cops!
What did you say?
Say it again! Repeat what you just said!
Don't you ever say these words again, ok?
- Come here! Open the mouth!
- So, kill me!  - Open your mouth!
If i should choose between my
buddies and you, i'd choose them.
Remember that.
Mom!
Take care of daughter.
Fat Guido.
You think i can't recognize you through the mask?
You're ridiculous.
- Yeah, sure.
- The guy you're getting these papers for...
is already dead.
- You asshole.
Looser. - Shut up!
Who sent you?
- Chevallier?
- Shut up!
This is your end.
You're finished.
You've reached your goal.
I found them.
- Why did you do it?
Mind your own shit. Any other questions?
- You killed unarmed man!
- Do you recall how you put the gun in your wife's mouth.
That's something different.
I break.
- Do you bet more or you wanna take a break?
- Time, time, time...
You don't need me to give you an advice.
You'll figure it out yourself.
- Here!
- Why are you throwing away your wedding ring?
- She has abandoned us. Me and three kids.
- What?
Yeah.
- Really?
Yeah.   - Good.
You think this is more than three?
Doesn't matter. Fuck Sofia.
So, Who is the best?
Your friend Paul won everything.
- Handsome, are you gonna buy me a drink?
He can't, he's here with me.
okay then.
Thanks.
- What's your name?
- Jeanne.
Jeanne? Funny.
And I am Tarzan.
- My real name is Jacques.
- My pleasure Jacques.
- What do you want to drink?
- I thought it's customary for a gentleman to ask this question.
Traditions need to be changed.
- I try. I'm ready for everything.
- Me too.
Really?
Yes.
- Quiet! Nobody moves!
- Everybody put your hands on the table!
- Quickly, all of you hands on the table!
- I said, hands on the table!
Hey, calm her down!
Move, hurry, hurry!
What's your problem?!
- I said, quiet!
- Quiet!
- Quick, move!
- Jacques...
- now you're stealing from me?
Do you have a problem with it?
- You won't get too far.
- Don't worry about me.
I have what i want.
Here is a tip.
- Dad, why isn't it working?
Sweetie,
because the ball and the racket must be this way.
- Are you alright?
Dad, does it hurt? - No, it's nothing, honey.
I'm only injured.
- I love you dad.
- I love you too.
In front of my daughter!
What the hell is it!
Will you stay together? Do you still want
to be with him?
- To the end.
Yes, of course.
If you love this woman, run away with her
and come back when everything settles down.
Do you really mean it?
You think they won't go after us once we cross the border?
The police is trying to get you,
i won't help you with that.
Yeah, but they were shooting at my daughter!
I guess there are some rules!
What rules?! In this bussiness
there's only one rule, rule of the jungle.
Everything has principles and moral laws.
Get ready.
It will hurt.
Don't twist, I almost had her.
Guido!
Remember in the future,
this is being used for killing people!
Good.
Let me, i'll help you out.
Bye mom.
- Come to me.
- Bye dad.
- My love.
- Be back soon.
Montreal, 1968.
More, more, more!
Good!
You're doing pretty good for a Frenchman.
It seems you are not from around here.
How long have you been here?
A month or two.
Do you like this job?
I was doing better back in France.
What was your job?
I was robbing banks.
My name is Jacques Mesrine.
And yours?
Jean-Paul Mercier.
I'm helping to finance a thieves.
Pefect job in Quebec.
- Pleased to meet you.
- You too.
Because of your criminal past I have to deny
your residence application.
You have 10 days to leave Canadian territory.
Dear.
How did it go at the immigration?
Good, but we need more time.
Next week you don't have to go back to construction job.
- Why?
- I replied  to an ad from some millionaire.
He's looking for a driver.
We'll go for an interview.
- Will you be working for him too?
Yes, I always want to be with you.
Mr. Davallier. Mrs. Schneider
and Mr. Mesríne are here.
Come in, please.
- Welcome.
- So it's you, Jacques and Jeanne.
My guardian angels.
- I suppose that we are hired.
- And you have my blessing too, my son.
So in that case, thanks dad.
Let's go
one, two and three.
Are you alright?
Slowly.
We are not in a hurry.
Don't worry, i'm holding you.
So where to, sir?
- to Santlar street.
- Sure.
Hello sir.
- Have you paid for the parking?
- I live here, here is my card.
- Good then, take care.
Look.
- This is from Jacques.
- From Jacques?
I'm telling you for the first and  the last time,
stop mingling in to my work.
- I don't want to see you here anymore!
- What? Are you going to complain?
I've been working here for more than 20 years!
Just go!
- You'll see, you won't get out of this that easily!
- Go, just go!
That's okay.
My gardener gave me a notice.
You talked to him with disrespect.
The whole altercation was provoked by you.
- That guy is just a nobody.
- Maybe he is,
but he served me loyally for 20 years.
And I only knew you for three months,
so with less regret i rather say goodbye to you.
- I'm giving two days to leave this house.
- Sure. Come, we're leaving.
Jacques, we have to talk!
Jacques!
- Jacquesi!
- Damn!
What?! What!
- Why are you treating me like this?
For disrespecting me, Georges.
- and for disrespecting my wife.
- Tell me...
what do you intend to do with me?
- Jacques?!
- What? At first, you've been so nice to us,
and then because of that idiot gardener,
you fired us!
Are we some kind of scum?
You'll pay for this.
I'll teach you some respect!
- My brother will pay you.
- It's possible.
In the meanwhile let me watch the TV!
Jacques!
Help!
- Hi  Jacques. This is Jean-Paul.
- What's up?
- I don't think he'll come.
We'll see about that.
I'm done talking!
He thinks, he is gonna pull my leg.
That old fart didn't show up with the money!
He'll pay, you'll see Jeanne.
That's him.
Shit!
- What are we going to do, Jacques?  Look.
- Shit!
I have to stop.
Fine, stop.
Get ready!
No. It's too many of them.
THE END OF THE RUN FOR BONNIE SCHNEIDER
AND CLYDE MESRINE!
DESLAURIER'S KIDNAPPERS
AGREED TO THEIR EXTRADITION TO CANADA
- What do you say on your arrival to Quebec.
- Quebec? A very restricting country.
BILLIONAIR DESLAURIER WILL
TESTIFY AT TRIAL
Tell us, do you regret what you did?
No, i don't regret anything!
10 YEARS FOR MESRINE
AND 5 YEARS FOR SCHNEIDER
Say a few words to our viewers.
One word!
It doesn't matter what. Anything.
Long live Quebec!
- Hey, do you want take a picture or what?
- No.5933, for the first month you are not allowed to talk!
I don't give a shit what i can't do.
I'm Jacques Mesrine. Stop pissing me off!
- No.5933, take it off from your face!
- I can't sleep with this light on!
- Take it off from your face, no.5933!
- Leave me alone!
Stop! It's not neccesary!
Why?!
No! No!
No! No! No!
Your stay in isolation is over.
Welcome at the prison with maximum security.
Forget about it, Frenchman.
I've seen you on TV.
Long live Quebec, right?
You think you can get through barb wire?
Your friend Mercier is right there
where you've been tortured by Gottier.
- How is he?
- How could he be, he's barely alive.
See you soon, French.
By the way, you looked more happier on TV.
Hey!
- Nice to see you again.
- You too.
Hey, hold on.
They're watching.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Do you know these two?
- Which ones?
- The fat one with buddy.
That fat one is murderer.
The other one, too.
He's suspected of killing the guard.
Why? Are they causing problems for you?
Right now, i don't know.
I think I know how we'll escape from here.
We'll get through the fence.
During our walk in daylight?
Do you have any other ideas?
Good, Jacques.
When?
By the fall you'll be either outside or
you'll be dead.
I'm for it. Death or freedom.
Tell me honestly.
What do you want from me, Frenchman?
- I need tools.
- What's in it for me?
I don't have anything to offer you.
Except a chance for freedom.
If i'll manage to get out of here,
i'll take you with me. I'm giving you my word.
You're desparate, Frenchman.
I like it.
- Let's go.
- See you.
Did he agree?
- What day is today?
- I know is monday.
Jesus, Frenchman!
Do you want to get killed?!
But not here and not on monday.
They are always watching,
except on monday after weekend hangover.
Mercier, let's go.
- Are you looking out?
- Yeah.
Hurry!
Don't worry, everything is ok.
Stop! Or i'll shoot!
Come on, let's get out of here!
Everybody on the ground!
Face to the ground!
Today prisoners escaped from prison with maximum security.
Until now this was considered impossible.
- Jean-Paul!
- What?
- They talk about us.
- Leave me alone right now!
- Jean-Paul!
Give me two minutes, damn!
We're famous, Jean-Paul.
Don't go out with your hands up
only if they'll capture both of us.
They shoot at everybody, whoever moves.
- We must be fast.
How much time do we have?
30 seconds.
Not enough?
- Do we have a choice?
- No.
I wanna see your hands!
Quick on the floor!
Don't move!
Quiet!
I said don't move!
Don't move and nothing happens to you!
I'm telling you, don't move!
Jacques!
Stay where you are!
10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Thank you ladies and gentlemen.
Take care. Stay nicely on the floor.
No, not yet. That one across the street too.
- What?
Let's go!
You're crazy!
Jacques!
It's time.
I'll be back soon!
I love you.
- Take care.
- Go!
That's Frenchman!
Now?
Yeah.
- One...
- two, three!
Shit!
Should i go?
Watch out.
Majos!
Jean-Paul!
Let's get the hell outta here!
We have to back up!
Grenade!
- Jean-Paul.
- I'm ok! Step on it!
Help him!
Quickly!
Let's go!
Public enemy no. 1
Only two minutes.
- You cannot have more.
- Ok.
Marta Baron speaking.
Yes Jeanne, he is here.
Hello, my dear.
Yes, my love.
How are you?
Everything is fine.
Not bad. It's ok.
No, nothing is fine.
As soon as i'll get better,
i'll be there right away.
- No, don't organize anything.
What's going on with you, honey? Stop.
Mercier is with me.
We're armed to the teeth.
I'll come to get you.
No, please don't do it.
Soon my jail time will be over.
Hush, what are you talking about?
I'll come to get you, my love.
We'll leave together and everything will stay behind us.
Don't do it, Jacques.
I don't want you to come.
- I'm asking you, please understand.
- I'll come to get you!
- I'll come! Stop!
- No, they know you'll come.
They're waiting for you! They could kill you!
They won't kill me, trust me.
Soon, bye.
Jacques, you must not come.
I said i'll come and i really will do it, damn!
- Did you hear me? I'll come.
No, Jacques...
No...
Calm down and be ready, you hear me?
See you soon.
It's over.
What are you saying?
It's over...
It's over, Jacques.
Now try with the left hand.
- Damn!
- It's harder now, isn't it?
My hand is still weak.
Watch out.
Shit.
Hello.
Greetings.
- That was you shooting?
- It's hunting season...
Season is over.
You see, i told you.
We were just practicing our shooting.
Really?
Indeed
I know you.
Escaped prisoners!
Enough, Enough!
They'll hang us for this, that's for sure.
Yeah, death or freedom.
death or freedom.
Jean-Paul Mercier was killed by Canadian police
two days later during the bank robbery.
Following the attack by Jacques Mesrine and Jean-Paul Mercier
on maximum security prison, an inquiry was ordered
to shed a light on the conditions in the prison.
The findings of the investigation led to the closure of the prison.
Jeanne Schneider served the remainder of her sentence
in Fleury-Mérogis prison and finished her days in France. free...
Regarding Jacquese Mesrine...
The End of first part.
From czech subtitles translated
bluedog - p.d.