Karabal, do you read me?
Please come in. This is Falcon!
Karabal, please come in,
this is Falcon 1-8.
Karabal, do you read me?
This is Falcon 1-8.
Whip 2 listening.
Is that your group coming down
from southwest of the station
That's correct. We're almost there.
Still no contact.
Karabal, Karabal. This is falcon 1-8.
Falcon 1-8, this is Tuna.
Did you establish contact with Karabal?
We can't establish contact
with the station.
Guys, it is at 11 o'clock.
Did you see Karabal hill?
Falcon 1-6 roger.
Falcon 1-4 roger.
Falcon 1-8,
what is the condition of Karabal?
Do you see anything?
There's smoke rising from the building,
people lying around
Is someone approaching the station?
Tuna, Tuna5. I'm 50m away Commander
Tuna 5, report the the situation.
Be careful. Enemy could still be around
Secure the area
Commander?
Speak, lieutenant.
Commander, here...
Lieutenant what happened to Karabal?
1993 Southeast
Have you ever been in love, Commander?
Yes, I was. Ibrahim.
- Did she laught at you?
Karabal Military Base.
Ibo, just grab his weapon.
Yes, Sir. Sergeant.
Are you asleep?
Get up, wake up, Go to bed!
Lbo Give me the weapon.
This is not your home.
Leave him with the blanket.
Get up.
Kaya1, Kaya1.
Kaya copies.
We reached the station Commander.
The second lieutenant is asleep.
Shall I wake him?
No. I'm on my way.
Sit down, boy! Sit down!
Good morning.
I am captain of infantry commando,
Mete Horozoglu
Turgay Atalay from Kars.
To your command.
Gendarme second lieutenant,
Vedat Dinckaya.
Communication Sergeant
Kamil Ates, captain.
We were expecting you
tomorrow Commander.
We came early, didn't we?
Why is that so, Turgay?
Because of you! To support you!
We've been informed yesterday
by radio dispatch.
Okan. - Yes, Sir. Commander.
Bring me Dogukan, Doruk
and Cemil right now.
Our condolences
You must be hungry.
Shall have something to prepared?
We came to your outpost.
Your soldiers were asleep.
We killed them.
Then we entered the station, your room.
You were asleep as well.
We killed you too.
Do you know the Subasi Plateau?
We came that way.
At the entrance of the plateau
Lieutenant Baris called me...
...to come up front.
Because he discovered footprints.
We need to take go through anyway,
I said.
I called Orhan. Told him this.
From far away, the sound of Dragunov
sounds like a whistle
If you hear it, you're still alive.
One of us, Emre from Sivas,
he was at the front.
He couldn't hear it.
It went right in there.
I was paralyzed.
Turgay pulled me away.
Then I came to myself.
Take cover, I just yelled.
Orhan is experienced.
He spoted where the sound comes from
He lifted his gun...
A bullet hit his left shoulder.
He staggered. Wanted to lift his gun...
Bam!
Orhan!
I screamed Orhan!
To make him get back to us.
He doesn't hear me.
He walked to the center of the plateau,
to the snow.
I yelled to the Paramedic
a couple of times...
...but he could not raise his head up.
His first combat.
He tried a couple of times
but couldn't.
Which one of us could anyway?
Then the third bullet hit him.
Orhan just collapsed.
Roll call in 30 minutes.
On the front right part of the skull...
...there is a bullet hole, size 1 cm.
Another one, 5cm in diameter...
...on the back left side of the skull.
At ease, Sedat. At ease.
Did you have the chance
to meet the others? - Yes, commander
Establish a connection to the brigade.
What's your name?
- Akan, Sergeant.
And you?
- Utku Duman, Sergeant.
You?
- Cüneyt, Sergeant.
How many of you are there on this station?
- 12 men, including all ranks.
Commander we've reached Mt. Karabal.
Copied Kaya. Any problems?
No, no problem Commander.
Copied, captain.
The boys already expected us.
You know I trust you a lot.
You are responsible for this.
Thank you, Commander. Understood. Over.
Don't worry.
We will take care of Orhan's family.
Don't leave the station except patrols.
May God be on your side.
At ease. Name?
Communication Sergeant Kamil Ates,
at your command.
Kamil Ates, you are dead.
Are you married?
- Yes, commander.
She's living in the barracks?
Give her a call, she needs
to look for another flat.
She won't be able to stay
there anymore. Why?
You are dead!
Are your parents still alive?
- Yes, commander.
Good. We'll send your coffin
to them. You?
Akan Atakan, from Hatay.
At your command Commander.
You are dead! You?
You? - Ömer Çetin Duman from
Bandirma. At your command.
You are dead, Ömer Çetin!
You? - Utku Duman from
Giresun. At your command.
To whom you gave your last will document?
- To my father
Good, then we'll also
send him your coffin.
You? - Melih Korucu, Istanbul.
At your command.
You are dead!
Do you have a girlfriend?
- Yes, commander.
Not anymore.
She'll marry another guy.
Cause you are dead now, boy.
Your mother cries her heart out,
the neighbours try to calm her.
They are rubbing her wrists
with cologne.
My son, she's crying...
...my one and only!
Your father is crying as well,
silently inside, in one corner.
On his lips only one sentence remains:
...long live the Motherland!
Long live our Nation!
If I had another son I'd send
him too, cries your mother.
Long live Motherland, she says.
They ambush the station.
They kill all of you.
We'll send your families your corpses.
They wash your bullet holes.
Wash off the blood.
Then they cover your coffin
with the flag.
That's the way they do it, right Turgay?
Like you command, captain.
That's the way.
That's the way the man who
meant the most to me died.
He died not because he fell
asleep but because he wanted.
They put him in a helicopter
and sent him to his family.
That's what they are
going to do with you guys.
You? - Ekin Bulut, Ankara.
At your command,
Who will carry your picture
on your burial?
Do have a sibling?
- Yes, commander.
Good, he will carry it then. How old?
30. Commander.
Then your 30 year old brother
will carry your picture...
Your 30 year old brother
will carry your coffin...
Does your father smoke?
- No, commander.
He'll start because of you.
He will have cancer.
You'll even make it into the TV news.
2 minutes, bullshit! 45 seconds.
You'll be heroes for 45 seconds!
A fancy lady will say in a sad tone:
Ekin Bulut died a martyr
during station ambush.
45 seconds!
After that celebrity news.
Did you fight bravely?
Did you die like that?
No, you died because
this guy fell asleep!
Why do your parents cry?
Because this man fell asleep.
Don't be mad at him.
Be mad at yourself. You are a unit.
You can't act as individuals.
You act for your comrades.
You don't sleep for him to sleep.
You die, so he does not!
You won't just die asleep.
If you sleep, you die.
You all die! If you sleep, you die.
If you sleep, you die. You too.
You guys all die.
You die, if you fall asleep, Sergeant.
If you fall asleep everybody dies!
Look. We are strong, brave and ready!
Ready for what?
- To die in our sleep.
You won't sleep! Won't eat!
Won't rest!
I won't send your corpses,
your coffins...
...to your families!
I forbid you to die.
Understood, soldier?
- Yes, Sir!
I forgive your friend
to preserve order in the unit.
I forgive him, so you can stand guard
side by side until morning.
But if I ever catch you
with your pants down...
I'll shoot you by my own hand. I swear.
A training accident. That's what
the report is going to say.
Understood, soldier?
- Yes Sir, captain!
What is the status of this flag?
The wind here is too strong.
Keeps tearing them apart.
We brought a new one. Change it.
Yes Sir, captain!
How are the boys?
Good. They will get over the shock.
Every single one of these boys
is different.
Their hands, faces, their loves
and fears.
You don't notice them.
They don't even know why you can't.
They come here, because of you.
To become your heroes.
They run and don't know why.
We make 'em run so it wil be
easier for them to walk.
All their longings are here, their
sadness. Even their home is here
This is their homeland.
One goal makes 'em forget everything.
They celebrate like they fight.
They dance but in a reserved way.
They are men.
They laugh.
What's going on here?
- A hand grenade exploded.
I just came from watch, captain.
I tried to adjust the pin to the grenade.
It slid out of my hand
I threw it in the toilet.
Why the hell is the hand grenade
in the toilet and the pin in your hand
They make mistakes, but never lie.
- Have you ever been in love?
A long time ago.
- You're not in love right now?
They fall in love.
- While I am on watch at night
...you light my nights like moonlight
- lf you write poems, you'll fall in love
When you emboss my dreams,
I can't sleep in these mountains
They express their feelings
through poems.
You need to be able to express
your feelings.
One a Kurd, the other a painter
and the third a poet.
I'm a Kurd too!
- Me too.
And you are the guys to watch my back?
They come from the most
different places.
Tunceli, Eskisehir. Adana, Istanbul.
They don't understand each
other. Here they learn.
Enjoy your meal, comrades!
- Thank you.
His code name is Doctor. Real name Riza.
An unknown enemy is coming their way.
You know, the doctor was a student in med school
That's all. Departure at 6 am.
Get some rest.
They leave to face their enemy.
- Tomorrow we leave on duty
Snow is falling silently. - Where are we
heading to, commander? - You'll see, when we get there
What will happen to the commando?
Tonight we're in combat
Shoot, platoon, shoot!
They get graded after the degree
of injury of the patient:
1. wounded lightly.
2. Patient in need of
medical hospital care.
3. Patient in need of operation.
- It's urgent.
Right. 4. Patient is fatally wounded.
They are curious about their fate.
Will we treat a wounded terrorist?
- Of course.
I want to join the mountain mission.
At home nobody cares about me
What am I supposed to tell them
when I get back home?
I'm a good-for-nothing. That's
what my dad keeps telling.
Do me this favor, captain. Let me join.
You need to be brave
to join the mission!
This mountain will make a man out of me, commander.
- Take him with you
God is almighty.
Troop, wake up. Get up!
He's still sleeping! Get up!
Pull the pin,
throw the grenade!
They leave their warm beds and
start their march to the mountains
Snow on my head. Snow on my head.
Winds are wild. Winds are wild.
Lowlands become too narrow.
Lowlands become too narrow
My country. My country...
...are the mountains, the mountains.
Fate is looking for its hero
and finds him...
Orhan!
I wrote a report, Mr. District Attorney.
Here are the details.
Let's type it.
Below the shoulder, left and right side,
there's a bullet hole, circ.3 cm.
Attention, Mr. District Attorney.
The ground is slippery.
These boys keep walking,
no matter what.
These boys carry their hearts
in their hands.
Their distance to you grows
as the distance to the peak diminishes
Now they can't understand you anymore
and you can't understand them
Who's up there? - They are
cleaning the roof,
Did you see Orhans new car?
- No.
He was crazy about it.
- I know.
He could not enjoy it
Life sucks.
Come in. You're wife's on the line.
She's waiting.
Hello?
I hear you. How are you?
- I'm fine, fine. How are you?
Do you know when you'll be coming back?
Even if I knew I couldn't tell you.
I know. I just wanted to know,
whether you know a date or not -No
Please take good care of
yourself. - Of course, darling.
Commander, Tell your wife, waiting is useless.
She won't see you again
Zeynep, hang up there is
interference -I don't understand.
The line is no good, hang up.
I 'll call later. Hang up.
Speak, while you still can, Kaya.
Do you listen asshole?
What's up?
Doesn't Commander Tuna allow
you to leave the station?
Don't be such afraid.
Why could not you become a man?
Instead of living like a wild hog
in the mountains
you should have graduated
university and went back to
Your cheap propaganda slogans
won't work, captain.
Am I not right?
Instead of going to your university,
I rather hang out in my mountains
Why so angry, Doctor? We're just
having a nice chat.
No worries, captain.
At the end you'll die like an animal.
Wolves and vultures will feast
on your corpse.
Screw you, captain.
- Screw you too, pig.
The guys who didn't sign their last
will... - Here Cemil,
and Dogukan, Polat too.
Ibrahim, Resul and you.
Muharrem. - I did sign it,
Sergeant. - What? - I signed it
Write! In the case of my death...
God Forbid.
...I pass on my individual rights...
What means individual?
- The rights you own,
currently being a soldier.
Which means?
- To make it short:
If we die a martyr, the government will pay reparation.
- How much?
I guess a lot.
- Dogukan whose name will you write?
I've got no one to insert here.
- Whose name did you write?
My mom. I have a mom but
my father takes everything.
Then I'll write my mother's name
in my last will.
Whatever, then write your father's
name down. At least there's a name there
If anybody wants to donate his
organs, write it down also.
Organ donation?
- Yes donation lbo
How's that supposed to work?
Is that an order?
No, I won't donate nothing.
That just won't work.
Why not?
- Won't my heart die when I die?
No it won't. They cut it out,
put it into a box...
...and take it to the hospital.
And you do something good.
It's an easy thing to say, but you
incur the sin of these boys
Do you think that's a good thing
to do? - I don't incur the sin of anyone
Suppose they die, shall they
enter the afterlife...
...without arms and legs,
even without a heart?
He's right. If we die tomorrow...
...we enter the afterlife
without our donated organs.
That's the word of God,
that's how its written down.
God Forbid, if we step on a landmine...
...and our arm or leg is shattered,
what then?
Then you're a martyr and
you'll go straight to heaven.
Your place will be directly
below the prophets.
There no one will ask you
about your missing organs.
But you just said it. I'm becoming
a martyr if I die here? - Right
- So if I'm a martyr anyway
and therefore not accountable in heaven
then I'll donate my heart!
- That's right.
I'll donate, pal. - That's the spirit.
- Right on, donate!
When was the warning shot fired?
- 3 months ago, commander
What intervals?
I'm here since 8 months and
there was only one.
One in 8 months? - Yes, commander.
- That's fishy Baris
You and Sedat look through
the old files...
...and check them for death
zones and shot directions.
Calculate the distance and inform
the brigade.
In case of an assault we can ask
for an artillery backup.
Yes, Sir. Commander.
- Vedat, where are the files?
At the information centre.
Good, let's check them.
- Yes, Sir. Captain.
Why didn't you connect the dugouts?
- The soil is too rocky
We weren't able to build
connecting dugouts.
Do you send out patrols to secure the area?
- No, commander
Weather's too rough. And we
don't have enough men.
We'll send out a patrol when the
snow melts. - Yes, Sir.
Then we'll see what's going on
out there.
Considering this weather,
pigs won't come out either.
They're totally shredded.
How are we supposed to sew them?
No idea, just sew. It's an order.
Yours is even worse.
- Yes.
Lock it. Pick up ammo.
Hurry. Hurry. Muzzle into the can
Load it, chamber a round,
release the safety, pull the trigger
Put in the magazine, lock it.
Muzzle into the can, chamber a
round, pull out the magazine
Release the safety, pull the trigger,
put in the magazine,
Don't point it at me.
Pick up your magazine.
Come in.
Time for you medication. - Thank you.
What are you staring at?
There's nothing to see here. Get lost.
Put it on the speaker.
- As you wish, commander.
Sergeant... Turn it off!
Give me my gun!
Turn of the generator!
Hurry, hurry... at 2! To the 14!
Only shoot when you see the enemy!
In my right pocket!
What's in your right pocket?
Take the lucky charm.
He is dead. Turn off the light.
What is in your right pocket?
We're right under the relay! Right!
I can't see anything.
Take the lucky charm.
Did you dream?
Everythings fine, it's nothing.
Sergeant. - Sleep on.
He's as pale as a ghost.
Must've been a nightmare.
Go back to bed.
The snow is melting.
Spring is here!
Indeed.
I will send you a parcel.
Will you get it?
Apricots and stuff you like.
Thank you, but not now.
I'll let you know when the time is right, ok?
If you need a courier, I'm your man!
- Zeynep, hang up please.
I wonder, how long your wife will
continue to live in the barracks after you die
Do you hear, Mete? - Zeynep,
would you please hang up?
Actually I aimed at you.
I hit the boy accidently.
What was his name again?
No worries, I'll whisper his name
in your ear next time we see each other
After the last attack the
organization will get more aggressive
At least this is what it looks like.
Every single one of you needs to
act with caution.
Follow the orders accurately.
Be ready for combat at all hours.
This place will become our grave...
...or theirs.
Don't you ever forget that.
Look under every rock.
Clear.
- Clear.
They took this path. We secured
this area.
Southeast. Southwest.
Get down.
Their hideout must be
right around here Baris.
That's why he's not attacking.
We must disturb him. Hurt him.
Let's search every mountain, boys. Okan!
Yes, Sir.
- Send two men over there.
They also cleared
the other side of the path.
This area?
- Search completed in this area.
He trusts himself a lot.
That's his weak spot.
We must make him angry.
Let's make him angry then.
Go look for a nice
observation spot. - Yes, Sir.
We need to find an ambush point.
The 2 of us and two messengers
Your medication Commander
4 men are enough.
This guy is here.
You were right, captain.
Have you found an appropriate spot?
Yes, Sir.
He won't attack us until
the end of our assignment.
We need to lure him out of his cover.
If we can't find him, he must find us
What are we going to tell the
brigade Commander?
They don't want us to leave the station.
We say nothing.
If something goes wrong?
It won't.
Let me go alone.
No, I'll join you.
As you wish, captain.
I'll revenge Orhan.
In this place sin is larger than
man, right?
It is written that man...
...shall not slay man.
Are there men without sin, lbo?
That's what's written.
Do you want to read my poem?
- Yes
Why don't you write one yourself?
If I could, I wouldn't ask for yours.
Hello, do you hear me?
Follow my words:
I look at stones and rocks.
Look sad, while staring at the stone.
Look at the stone.
- Look...
I look at stones and rocks.
There they lie.
What is their purpose? Alone is
the stone, for a long long time
Can he leave? He cannot.
Can you?
- No.
I ask myself, if somebody waits for them or not.
- Less tragic, slightly melancholic
Don't cry, just melancholic
Then I think of you.
Your eyes open, they shine.
I think of you. I think of you.
Don't overdo it. Laugh slightly.
I'm glad that the longing will
end someday.
We'll be united happily.
What's up?
What? Why are you laughing?
OK?
That's it, darling.
- Masallah!
Damnit, lbo!
Did you do it how I told you?
I did and even swayed with my
head. Just ask Sedat!
Did you put feeling in your words?
- Yes, there was feeling
Strange. Then you didn't perform it properly.
What's her job?
She's as student at a technical
college. - Technical college?
Yes.
- Then it won't work with her.
Why?
She's the materialistic type,
not the romatic. She needs a different poem.
Really?
- Go. I'll write another one.
Those girls aren't romantic.
May I ask you a question, Sir?
- Of course, Kadircan.
Rumors are spread... of a doctor
who'll attack the station.
Who is this guy?
You know, the terrorist
who's intercepting the radio
Why is he called Doctor? Is he a doctor?
He dropped out of medical college
after 3 years.
Then he disappeared in the
mountains. Nickname stayed.
Why did he drop out?
Afraid of dead bodies?
Is this guy nuts? He should work
in a hospital and earn lots of money.
What's he looking for
in the mountains?
Commander says,
they'll definitely attack.
Then they will.
I am your angel of death.
Are you out of your mind?
- Put that rifle away.
Are you OK?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Good god...
I thought I heard something...
My grandpa made those.
Said, they'll protect you.
These men are doing a great
and sacred job.
As I said before...
...we were able to weaken
the terrorists severly.
We will increase these efforts...
...and as I promised our
distinguished people...
terrorism will no longer be
an important topic...
...by the end of summer.
Even the flag cannot endure
our wind, right?
You also fought for this flag.
How could you forget?
You forgot! The blood of my
people is also in that flag.
It is the blood of all of us
which colors this flag red.
But you added the crescent moon
and the star.
Just a star would've been better!
So you don't like the crescent moon?
Go away while you still can.
If not, Zeynep will be very sad
No one will be sad if you die?
I'll blow your head up, just as I did
with the other two boys
You're gonna pay for this.
You will die, captain.
You dont use the
radio transceiver anymore?
No.
- Did you have a fight?
We broke up.
She's sick of waiting.
True. Its hard to wait for
your death news anytime.
Then she just shouldn't wait for it.
It is a good thing,
if someone waits for you.
Open the window.
What's wrong. Tell me!
Nothing. Don't mind.
- Why are you doing this? Tell me.
I don't know. I need to think of Emre...
...Sergeant Orhan, my mother, Hülya.
I invented some new techniques.
Want to learn?
A man is stuck in an elevator.
How? Just look.
One.
Two.
Blue. Beret. Does not fall down.
Now with just one finger.
One, two. That's more easy.
Do you know the shop owners son?
Mahir?
Recently he sent his mom over
to my parents house.
They want me to marry their son.
- What the hell?
My mom just told me.
I'll smack this guy.
That really makes me mad.
They proposed to her and stuff...
It made my heart race.
I guess I'm more in love than I thought.
But she said no,
so what else do you want?
That's right. But what if we die?
Hello? Mom?
My son...
Nothing, not much to do here.
How are you?
I miss you so much. So nice to
hear your voice, my boy.
How are the boys?
Good. In perfect shape.
We don't know anything
about your situation.
Me and your father are kinda nervous.
We do get bits of information...
They aren't related to us,
we are at a different place.
We're in Turkey.
You'll wrap the newborn in
Besiktas banner for me, will you?
Mom, I'm talking to you.
- To me?
Yes, of course to you.
We're the champions this season.
Don't you get it. Fener is the best.
Hello, mom. Im fine and you?
Mom? I am allright, how are you?
Do you hear me? Is your phone broken?
Lts getting warmer,
orange blossoms smell lovely.
Do you hear the call to prayer?
I pray for you and your friends.
I can't stand this much longer.
I see you sometimes standing before me.
If I blink, you're gone.
I guess I am demented.
I miss you so much.
- I miss you too.
I couldn't wash the t-shirt
you wore last time.
Sometimes I smell it.
- Oh, mom.
It smells like my boy.
I'll send you greetings with music!
If we die while asleep.
Will we still become martyrs?
If you're confident and
not afraid of death...
...you'll become martyrs while sleeping.
Is that guy still beating you up?
- It will soon be over, mom
No need to worry about us.
- Just 64 days...
You serve your country.
You need to endure this.
Why? Are you at war?
Don't you ever watch TV?
- Your father sold the TV.
What did he do?
Oh, I really miss you.
- I do miss you too.
I really miss your cooking a lot.
Since you left I never
prepared meat balls...
...nor stuffed wine leaves.
Because you like those so much.
Mom, do you cry?
No, I'm not crying.
Don't cry.
Your voice protects me.
Your voice soothes me.
Do you still have that gold
I bought you?
Have you ever thought about me
being in need of you?
I too want to be with you.
They won't let me. Do you think, I'm stupid?
It was everything I had. I wanted
to start a business with that.
You will certainly become mad there!
Don't call him dad, he is not my dad!
And you will call again in 10 days,
I know.
This isn't a hotel. I'm not in the
position to call you more often
Hello?
Hello.
Aunt Hanife. It's me, Soner.
- Hello.
Is Esma at home?
No, she's not.
But I can hear her.
Please don't call anymore.
Her father scolds me and her too.
- OK, auntie.
Are in love with somebody too?
Yes.
Keep me updated, will you?
We'll be sitting near the phone all the time
Is she in love with you?
Yes.
I love you.
- I love you too.
You know I love you very much,
don't you?
Yes, I know.
It's me. Ahu.
You were luckier than me.
Will your love die, if we don't see
each other?
Love is not the only thing
that plays a part here.
You're self-centerd.
Am I self-centered because
I need to fight for everything?
What are you fighting for anyway?
What's this snotty remark
supposed to mean?
You are there so that I can sleep
at peace right?
You 're in the army.
Yes I am.
- Of course!
So I need to be thankful for every
quiet night. I get it.
Do you want to end it?
- That would make it easy for you, right?
No, it wouldn't.
But you sound like that.
It feels like the right thing to do,
indeed. It is over.
Not even a picture of you did I get,
now you hang out with other guys
One day I will knock on your door
with roses.
..."get lost" is what I'm going to say.
Live on your street.
You tramp, what fun we had with you.
You look tired, Vedat.
- No, commander. I'm fine.
Didn't you sleep?
No.
Where does she live?
I beg your pardon? Who?
- Your girlfriend, boy.
In Istanbul.
Are you in love with her?
I think so, yes.
You know that love is too small
for big cities.
I know.
She'll cheat on you.
Are you prepared for that?
I can't change it.
Are you ready for the fight?
- I am.
Serkan, you?
I am ready.
You didn't make that impression
on me during the first combat
I am now, captain.
- Ready for what?
Ready for what you taught us, captain.
What did I teach you?
Would you treat the man
who shot Orhan...
...if we captured him wounded?
Yes, I would.
Equal treatment for everyone,
right? - Yes, commander.
Even this we taught you, right?
- Yes, commander.
That was a mistake.
I beg your pardon?
- Nothing
And if that man killed your
brother? What would you do?
I would still treat him.
And what would you have
told your mother?
A man killed my brother.
We captured him but I saved
his life. Why?
Because I swore an oath to
uncle Hippocrates, right?
These mountains have different oaths.
Hakan you are a banker, right?
- Yes, commander.
Those guys earn 5 times
the salary we get.
Ain't it true?
Depends on the bonus.
We have commissions too.
What would I need to show you
to get credit?
I'm not in the credit department,
but securities I guess.
My securities are these mountains here.
You would need papers to prove this.
I don't have papers...
...so these mountains
mean nothing to the bank.
When you're discharged
you forget the mountains.
Go to the woman you love.
Rest your head on her shoulder
And start talking...
Oh, you're going to say,
when I was there I shot men.
I was shot, I couldn't breathe,
you'll say and cry.
Everywhere was blood you'll say.
Shed two little tears
on their shoulders, right?
And the women will cry.
My hero, my national hero.
That's how she'll call you.
Just awesome, right?
You'll hug each other,
so soft and nothing else matters.
Turgay?
- Yes captain.
Tell the boy, who is drawing,
to paint not only rocks and stones
Tell him to paint flowers,
beetles and butterflies!
Yes, Sir. Commander.
Maybe then we can get
credit someday, right?
Kaya, Kaya 1.
Kaya 1 here.
We prepared the stake-out.
Kaya1, did you ever apply
for credit at a bank?
No, Kaya
Well, don't. Because they want to
see a entry in the land register
Understood.
Go now. C'mon.
- Yes, Sir.
Turgay. - Yes, Sir?
- Bring me tea.
Kaya 1, Kaya.
Kaya, Kaya 1.
Just come back home.
- Yes, Sir.
He said you shouldn't draw stones,
but beetles, flowers and butterflies
You will not get credit if you don't.
Here, take the sheets.
Allright.
Take a big pot, add some tea...
...and boil them thoroughly.
Just wait. In a minute you will
forget that you are here.
How?
Just close your eyes and concentrate.
We concentrate on women, right?
No, later. First we concentrate on
the day of discharge.
Or leave.
Yes, two men.
Flowers.
Southwest, they are running.
Beetles.
We will leave this place.
150m
Think of your families.
Birds chirping. Wind.
I see them. They are no scouts.
Let's wait.
And other things. You see them,
don't you?
A woman.
Yes.
100m
Think of Hülya.
80m
Think of your warm beds.
You aim at the man.
- The sound of water.
I take the women.
Listen.
70m
Forget that you are even here.
- Stay calm.
You are not here.
- 60m
A slight breeze.
- Very nice.
Quiet.
50m
You fire when I fire.
The girl fell behind the tree. Go, run!
Yes, Sir.
The boy went down. The girl I don't see.
He is dead.
Does she have a hand grenade
with her? - No.
Maybe under her body.
Have a look. Let's leave.
Turgay.
- Yes, Sir.
Take his ammo. Turgay.
- Yes, Sir. - Yes, Sir.
Kaya 1, Karabal.
- Karabal here.
During combat...
Wait. Don't report.
Commander?
- Take that.
Will you return?
- Give me the walkie-talkie.
Everythings fine. We return.
- Understood.
Take it.
Turgay, bundle up our stuff.
- Yes, Sir.
What are we going to do with them?
They'll come and get the man.
We'll take the girl to the base
Serkan. How's her condition?
Badly injured.
I know. I shot her.
Can you stop the bleeding?
We"ll need the helicopter.
Which university did you attend?
- Hacettepe.
They have the best medical
department, right?
I guess so...
So you've been a bad student or
what? Do your job.
Turn on the TV.
We need the helicopter, commander
- There won't be one.
We're not the US Army...
...which sends a helicopter
for every single wounded soldier
I need to talk to her. There are
things I want to hear from her
I am trying to save you.
Bring me a sheet.
I'm 21, born in Ankara and
go to college.
What's that?
How was the day of the contest
for you? Were you excited?
Just tell us a little about it.
Swab.
- Swab. Swab.
Let me have it.
Here, grab this. Tighter!
I can't watch this.
- Then don't, damn it!
There were so many other
beautiful girls.
And how does it feel to be the
most beautiful girl of Turkey
I am very proud.
And I want to represent my
country in the best possible way.
How did you get that stunning
body and great looks?
I exercise alot. I am an athlete.
I'm on a healthy diet.
Every morning an apricot,
a glass of water.
That's how I start my day.
Is there a part of your body
you don't like?
I don't like my neck.
What changed in your life
after the contest?
It still feels like a dream.
Nothing much.
Only more people know me now.
Commander I can't concentrate.
Can we turn off the TV?
Could you stop the bleeding?
- To some extent.
Thank you and again, congratulations.
Are you in pain? What a pity.
You were there
when Orhan and Emre got killed?
Orhan had a wife and two kids
and a new car.
Did you watch them die?
Did I squeeze to tight?
I'll loosen then. Good.
Is there anyone who'll miss you,
when you die?
Who'll be sad when you die?
Commander You'll kill her.
Not me.
Will the Doctor be sad? Do you know him?
Commander.
He fucks you, doesn't he?
You are going to kill her.
- I'll make this Doctor to show up here.
Commander you will kill her.
- Be quiet! What?
The Doctor wants to talk to you.
Tell him the captain is taking care
of his girlfriend. He's busy right now.
Yes, Sir.
So you know each other.
Where is the doctor?
You're going to kill her!
Commander...
Commander! Commander!
You'll kill her! Commander!
The Doctor is here.
Commander! Commander!
Enough!
Orhan had a wife and two kids
and a new car.
Call the helicopter to take her away.
Everybody out! Llker, Soner, out!
Yes, Sir.
Turgay.
You go with the helicopter,
take a few days leave.
No, we arrived here together and
we're leaving together.
The helicopter is here.
The boys shall help you carry her.
Yes, Sir.
Bring the blanket also.
Let her down, slowly.
Let me have it.
Sit down.
Citizens heatedly protested
against the terror of the PKK.
It takes 57 second.
What takes 57 seconds?
Commander said we would get
45 seconds. But it took 57.
General Güres is ordered to
lead the examination...
...in Diyarbakir in the southeast
of the country.
Don't shed tears, you beauty.
Don't hurt yourself, beauty.
What does this mean in turkish?
Don't shed tears,
don't hurt youself, beauty.
What shall I do, I love you.
I can't cope with my feelings.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Yes, in the village.
What's her name?
- Xece.
What?!
What's that supposed to mean?
- Hatice in Kurdish.
My heart. My only one, my flower.
Beloved.
I am too far away to say I'm sorry.
I wished my breath to be in your face.
I'd love to warm your back
with my breath.
If only I could whisper the
sweetest love songs in your ear
Muzzle into the can!
I couldn't, my love.
I was ashamed of these words.
My hands caressed your hands,
my lips caressed your neck...
Be careful.
My eyes, your heart...
...where the sun hides.
I always thought the clouds would disappear,
if I would only stare bravely enough at them.
I can't change this. Too late.
Don't be angry.
A cloud concealed my view.
I couldn't help it...
I became that cloud.
I made it rain in your innermost.
Forgive me.
I didn't have enough breath
to chase the clouds away.
I seem to hear your voice...
In my most unprotected moment
I will take your curse.
I will ask for forgiveness.
My breath was supposed to
give life to yours. I couldn't.
I was out of breath.
Come.
Your medication.
I don't need them anymore.
Throw them away.
I wished so hard that this breath would be
enough to swallow the love in your chest
It wasn't supposed to be that way.
I wasn't able to tell you the
fairy tales of my childhood.
I would have loved to carry you
away with my fairy tales!
Once upon a time... was all I said.
Hello? Hello?
Kaya, I will avenge the death of my comrade.
- Then come
I'll revenge the woman.
- I'll have revenge too.
I will raise a statue for her there.
Come here, act like a man.
- I'll come soon.
I won't leave this place without
having seen you first. You coward.
Would a coward fight for 10 years?
You live like a boar in the mountains.
You killed thousands of youth!
You murderers!
We fight against the leeches
that dwell among your own people
Did you manage to defeat them
in all these years?
You are one who kills his own people.
Don't speak out the name of
my people, who you supress.
You were suppressed? What is it,
that this state didn't give?
My freedom! You banned my
people from their own land.
You don't gain freedom through murder.
- You outlawed my language
You went to university in this country!
Be patient. I will free you of
all your worries.
You are a murderer.
- In fact you are the murderer.
What about the teachers, children,
engineers, workers you've killed.
This land is tough, this war has rules.
You have a rule for killing children?
How many villages did you burn down?
The blood of the innocent
villagers is on your hands!
You never understood us. It is your fault
that poverty became the fate of my people
Has every poor man become a
terrorist, like you?
This is our land.
- Doctor, this land belongs to us all.
These mountains are mine. Off you go!
This place shall become your grave.
- Off you go.
Not without seeing you first.
- Go to your wife.
I'll stay here, Doctor.
- Go.
I'm going to kill you.
- You will die here.
So long live Motherland!
I want you to give that to Zeynep.
Commander.
This is not an order.
I ask you to do it.
I don't think I'll survive the combat.
I feel it since Orhan died.
I can't accept his death.
But you've been in so many combats!
I never told Zeynep
how much she means to me.
I was ashamed.
We are soldiers. Unromantic.
Nothing for me.
I wasn't able to say I LOVE YOU.
I love you...
How hard to say are these 8 letters?
Good god... 8 letters.
Everything's black, Baris.
I don't find answers to
my questions anymore.
I remain here without answers.
Without Zeynep, without Orhan.
Nothing makes sense and
I don't find words for it.
How can I explain that I have as much love
for Ankara, as I have for the mountains here
Anyway...
Don't you wonder what's the
medication for I take?
We can't have children.
I'm bleeding on the inside.
Give this to her.
Tell her, I smell her scent
whenever I see flowers.
And... I want her to forgive me.
Could you deliver additional ammunition?
Good, I'll keep you updated.
Sir, yes Sir. Commander.
All nights in this place are short...
...except one.
You pray to make it end.
You don't have a chance to think
about why you're here.
You just want to survive the night,
still breathing.
If I stop breathing, you do too.
Do you deserve your breath?
I don't know. Commander, I...
- Keep silent!
You guys sent me here.
The Turkish soldier is the bravest
Martyrs never die, no one will
ever divide this country.
My uncle shouted this.
My aunt did.
Neighbours. You.
And I came.
This is war. Either you are a
murderer or a victim.
In between there's only dishonour.
Do you think, I don't know that
we can't win this war like that?
Do you think I'm stupid?
I know that.
What you don't know is that
if I fail here,
you lose in Istanbul and Ankara
as well. Do you get that?
You don't.
Nobody is ever right at war
You don't ask yourself
in the longest night...
...who is right or wrong, murderer
or victim.
There is only your breath.
You breath in or out.
That simple. You get that?
If you would've only liked me a little.
Sleep now.
Don't worry. Every war has
got an end. Even this one.
At the end you'll judge me.
That doesn't matter.
There is no other place for me
to turn to.
Damn kiosk owner!
Is the captain asleep?
Sergeant, I need to call Göksen.
Who is Göksen?
- My bride-to-be.
This is not funny. Good night.
- I have to call her!
I beg you!
I need to ask you for something.
One of the boys...
...needs to do a long-distance
call. Family affairs.
This is the number.
What's happening?
Get lost. It is ringing.
It is ringing.
Hello? Hello?
Get down!
- Commander!
Sedat?
Are you OK?
Lbo?
My arm is off.
Go get the MG
Kamil!
I can't see anything!
Turn of the generator!
Yes, Sir. Commander.
Kamil.
Commander!
Turn off the light.
Onur.
Turgay.
Look at his foot.
Push it on his leg. He is dead.
Off to the radio room.
Muharrem.
Turgay.
Fire!
Come here, Soner.
Soner, grab the bag, look at me.
What's your name?
Lbo! - What's your name?
Doctor, I've got a letter
in my right pocket.
Don't shot until you see the enemy.
Right pocket.
Look at me.
I can't see anything.
OK, let's go together.
Hand this letter to my mom, OK?
Down!
Göktay, answer me!
Bro, my arm has been ripped off.
Give me the letter.
Right side...
Look. On the other side.
Go away.
Doctor, commander.
My arm has been ripped off, commander.
Want to lick my head? It wouldn't help.
In my right pocket, Resul.
Grenade.
Resul, Resul.
One of us?
Don't be afraid. Give me a gun.
They are on the right side.
I dont see them.
Shoot. They shoot.
In my right pocket.
What's in there, Sergeant.
What in Gods name is where?
His girl knows nothing about
poetry. I wrote a poem.
We must shoot.
- Grab his arm.
While you sneak into my mind at night...
...I keep watch here.
I can't find sleep, must think of you.
Want to get up to get to you,
but I can't.
I... shoot.
Hakan, shoot! Shoot!
Just shoot! Just shoot!
Have you ever been in love, captain?
I've been, lbrahim. And you?
Screw you.
Cüneyt.
I once was.
Have you ever written a poem?
Yes, I did.
- Screw you.
Do you have feelings? Do you? Huh?
Cüneyt!
Did she laugh at you?
Welcome, Doctor.
Thank you, commander.
I can't find the vein. Go on.
I must read poetry.
Go, Dogukan.
Fire?
Shoot them. Hakan. Give me your rifle.
Do you hear me? Go to the 14!
I can't see anything!
- I am looking!
Is nobody here?
Why don't you shoot? They will kill us!
Are you OK, Sergeant?
Paramedic!
They come.
Go.
- God help us.
Ibrahim.
Paramedic! Come here fast!
In my right pocket...
Look ahead. Sergeant, where are
you going? Down!
In my right pocket.
Turn of the light! Sergeant! Sergeant!
We're an easy target because of you!
Look ahead, Dogukan! Look ahead!
You have some ammo left?
Do you see the spot over there?
Are the boys out there?
Mami
Why did MG 3 stop?
Just shoot!
Dogukan, there are too many of 'em.
Mami
Stupid, why don't you shoot?
Take the lucky charm.
Take it, for god's sake. Take it.
Shoot!
Mom
Dogukan, take the lucky charm.
Turn off the light!
Commander, please.
Turn it off, Ekin!
My grandpa prayed...
I brought you the radio unit.
Shoot only when you see them.
I'm out of ammo.
I beg you, take it.
Take the clip.
The man comes.
- I brought you the radio unit.
Pull him down.
Dogukan.
How are you, captain?
- Give me my weapon, boy.
Wake up, please!
- Look after Ekin!
Paramedic!
Calm down.
Are you OK, commander?
Just a graze. Now you are a war veteran.
Behind him. Back!
- Hold tight. He's dead.
Answer!
- He is dead!
Turn of the light! Sergeant!
Ömer is shot. Don't move
We are under the relay. Ömer was shot.
He is bleeding
You have to come here
immediately. Paramedics...
Ömer is shot. Don't move
Where are you?
- Right under the relay. Come
On my way. Stay where you are.
Lights off!
- Aim at the right side.
Prepare the signal rocket.
I'll make you get the girl.
You'll become a war hero,
just wait and see.
War veteran Ömer Çetin.
She'll immediately fall in love with me.
Over there!
Now, everybody will know
I'm in the special forces.
They are coming! Hurry!
The paramedic comes.
Where is he hit?
- Belly.
Give me the bandage.
On the ground!
Father, I'm coming.
- Forgive me, mother.
I am tearing down your castles
Kaya. Piece by piece.
I can still see the roof, doctor.
Is your RPG out of ammo.
Situation report, Heval Ciya.
Up, up!
We're here to help you.
Surrender Turkish soldiers.
We won't do you any harm.
Surrender your captain.
It's not worth it... fighting for
this man, soldiers.
We dont have anything against you.
Save your breath, Doctor.
These boys will never surrender.
Go to Turgay.
- Turgay is dead.
Turgay is dead.
- No, he's not!
Turgay! Turn off the lights.
- Then I won't see.
Turn it off!
Serkan.
Commander, don't.
I'll kill you. Turn it off!
- I need to bandage you.
Shhh. The light.
Bring me a sheet or a blanket.
Don't let your soldiers die
like flies. Surrender.
Come Doctor, I'm waiting for you.
Are you seriously injured?
- I don't know.
Are you okay, Ömer?
- Yes, commander.
Will we die? - We'll have lots of
times to go for walks.
Yes, Sir. Commander.
Do you have your rifle?
- Yes, commander.
Surrender.
I broke the slender neck
you were so fond of kissing.
You hear that?
What was her name, Doctor?
How did you call her?
My wild wind?
My daisy? How?
Doctor?
Doctor, do you hear me?
Come. I am here.
Her name was Gulan.
A beautiful name.
I abhor the pain you feel,
when you hear them ringing the bell
I won't smell your soul anymore.
Like a cloud I'll darken your inner sun.
Forgive me.
Words never had so much weight, my love.
When I said "my life for my country"...
...my heart screamed
"you are my home!".
I became your grave
while trying to be your soil.
A trickle instead of your river.
Instead of being your sun
I became your shadow.
Forgive me, my love...
Why didn't I listen to your soul?
Listened with my eyes,
see with my heart?
Why did I hide my heart
when you reached out for it.
If only my tears could rest
on my cheek without shame.
My love, I take you with me.
How cruel, to be the cloud
in your heart.
To devour the light of the
morning forever.
Winds! Help me!
I hope that one sunny day
a stronger love finds its path...
...and I fly away.
Then I will scream a thousand times
I love you.
I'm unemployed. Why do you hit me?
This love should not end like this.
Please don't leave me, oh!
Don't leave me alone,
don't surrender me to death,
don't surrender me to cruelty.
Take me with you, wherever you go,
don't surrender me to death,
don't surrender me to cruelty.
Take me with you, wherever you go,
I can't breath without you,
I can't stand it here without you,
Oh, I can't be alone!
I miss your scent,
waited for you forever,
Take me with you, wherever you go,
I can't breath without you,
I can't stand it here without you,
Oh, I can't be alone!
I miss your scent,
waited for you forever,
Take me with you, wherever you go,
I can't breath without you,
I can't stand it here without you,
Oh, I can't be alone!
I miss your scent,
Take me with you, wherever you go.
Well done.
- Thank you, guys.
Troop!
- Thank you!
Step by step, march ahead!
Snow on my head.
Winds are wild.
Lowlands become too narrow.
My country...
...are the mountains, the mountains.
Towns seem like traps to me.
People's chit-chat not allowed.
Stay away from me.
My country...
...are the mountains, the mountains.