By Corrida89
What a kick!
Beautiful!
The Head Kick!
This is crazy!
power slammed in the back!
Oh, oh, oh!
martinez wins!
We've got some great matches
for you tonight, people, make some noise!
We've got boxers, wrestlers,
psychos, criminals,,,
We've got a couple of
douchebags in there as well,
support these douchebags
people, make some noise out there!
isn't this fucking great?
Yeah, you see that? That's you in an hour.
Oh, reaiiy? Why wait?
Save it.
I'm ready to go out tonight, guys,
I need some blood!
Who wants some blood out there, guys?
What the heii are we even doing here?
-Any of you guys Stokes?
-Yeah, i'm Stokes.
You're up, bro. Get some.
This one's gonna be a
barnburner people, Let's hear it,
This ends here. Tonight.
Ends?
This is where it begins.
Wow.
PS3, huh? What's your favourite game?
i don't know. Killzone 3, i guess.
-Here, iet me get this.
-i got it.
i can give you guys a hand
if you guys need any heip.
i'm Kurt, Mike's roommate.
Hey, Kurt. John Stokes, Mike's dad.
-Nice to meet you, John.
-You, too.
Aii right, so who's hungry?
How about i treat you boys to iunch?
i think i'm just gonna go unpack.
Okay.
i'ii see you upstairs.
-Look, Son...
-Thanks for the ride.
Shouiders up, Zack.
Aii right, Zack.
Smoke and Thunder, baby.
Smoke and Thunder.
You keep droppin' that shouider,
and any ciub fighter couid pick you apart.
Yeah? Teii that to my iast three victims.
-Listen, kid...
-Hey, iook, iook, iook.
There's been a iittie change of pians,
aii right?
i just got off the phone
and Jefferson puiied out.
But not to worry, aii right? i got you a sub.
This guy named Ortega.
And he just moved up from weiterweight.
He's got a 4-and-3 record.
i think it's a mistake.
The fight's in three weeks
and we don't know anything about Ortega.
The guy's 4-and-3, i'm 5-and-0.
You know what that adds up to, huh?
An ass whupping for Ortega.
Even you can do basic math.
Man, educate this dude.
Titie fighter right here.
You teii 'em Zack, you teii 'em.
it's time.
Tim!
Hey.
Hey, Mom. What's wrong?
Nothin'.
Wouid you aii ieave your brother aione?
Go upstairs, wash up for dinner.
Come on, both of you.
So, what have you got goin' for tonight?
Term paper.
Okay.
The bank gave us a third notice
and they're giving us another month to pay.
You've been kiiiing yourseif ever since
Dad died to keep this house, Mom.
Just iet me drop out. i'ii get a night job.
No!
Go finish your term paper.
And i'ii bring you something
for supper, okay?
Go on.
You know me. i'ii figure something out.
Dude, there's no way you can compare
Wonder Woman's iasso to Thor's hammer.
That doesn't make any sense.
That's iike comparing a penis to a vagina.
Oh, hey, i gotta jump.
-Hey, what's up?
-Hey.
Just thought i couid do a iittie trading.
Sure. What you got here?
-These are '86.
-Nice.
Reai nice.
Some trippy stuff. This is yours?
Yep. i got 18 more just iike it at home.
That's cooi.
You know what, the guy
who's in charge of buying is this guy, Butier.
He's just not in today. But...
i don't know what you want to do.
-Come back tomorrow?
-Yeah, of course. That's cooi.
Actuaiiy, why don't you hang onto these,
and then i'ii just swing by tomorrow.
Yeah, sure. For you, yeah, i'ii do it.
-Aii right. Thanks.
-Aii right, no probiem.
Hey, you don't wanna, iike,
go out sometime?
Not gonna happen, dork.
Hey, Kurt, check this out.
Somebody hacked the coiiege server.
it's aii over the piace.
Come on. Come out with me.
No, i'm staying in, man.
Dude.
-What?
-We are coiiege freshmen, man.
Whether you know it or not,
your body is a reservoir of raging hormones
and pent-up sexuai energy. What is wrong?
Taik to me, aii right? And then iet's get on it.
Okay, but you cannot teii a soui.
it's about my dad.
Weicome to coiiege, man.
Not bad for eariy season. Come.
Freshman crop of honeys
ripe for the taking, right?
You gotta put your bid in eariy.
Not a probiem.
You wait tiii you see my man here in action.
Legend.
Pick any honey in this room,
Mike gets it done.
-ignore him.
-Hey, hey, how's it goin'?
Legend, huh?
Aii right.
That one. Right there.
Aii right, roommate,
show him how a pro gets it done.
Seriousiy, dude,
that thing with your oid man,
-take it out on that.
-Fuck off, Kurt!
Hey.
-Pretty cooi party.
-Yeah.
"Cooi."
Okay. Aii right,
not the most originai of openers.
Let me try this again.
Wouid you iike to go grab a cup of coffee?
So? Wouid you?
if i teii you i aiready have a boyfriend,
you promise not to take it
as some big, macho chaiienge
and try to steai me away from him?
i promise?
i'm aiready dating someone.
Get a doctor!
Aii right. Back and forth.
Left and right.
Step ieft, kick right.
Left, right.
There he is! Get his ass! Let's go!
i toid you i was gonna get you, boy!
-What? You got something to say now?
-Fuck you!
i think he's gonna start enjoying
this ass beating, bro!
Stop!
-Pick his ass up!
-Piease!
What? What? You think this is a game!
i'm gonna teach you not to run your mouth.
That's what i'm taiking about, boy.
What? You got something to say?
Get him! Get him!
Motherfucker!
Fuck!
i got something for your ass now, boy.
Hoid him!
-Man, this is gonna hurt.
-No, no, no, no, no, piease, come on!
-Get that motherfucker!
-Come on! Let's go!
Where you going?
Hoid it!
Who this motherfucker is?
What y'aii want?
We can take him.
Hoid up.
We're cooi. We're good bro.
We'ii get you another day.
Let's go.
Thanks. Thanks, guys.
Who is it?
Mike. i was toid
to come see the RA for some reason.
Mike, the wrestier kid?
Yeah.
Enter, Mike the wrestier.
So, why'd you want to see me?
We'ii get to that, Mike the wrestier kid.
But first, may i ask you,
are you a fan of the fight cage?
Do you have a taste for the savage science?
Yeah. i guess so.
Okay, great. Come on.
Behoid.
So, you're behind this?
You teii anyone that,
and i'ii fucking kiii you.
What's up with the ciock?
That's the countdown
to the Beatdown, baby.
-The what?
-The Beatdown, bro.
it's back. Less than 100 days to go
for a second dose of ass-kicking,
skuii-crushing mixed martiai arts madness.
Cajun styie. Oniy this time, i'm in charge.
Max Cooperman,
impresario of the Beatdown.
Fight's on when the ciock ticks down, bro.
§20 a head, at a site to be determined.
-A tournament?
-Yeah, bro.
One night, two hours, 16 fighters.
Winner takes home a cooi 10 grand
and nationwide ceiebrity.
Weii, that sounds cooi, man.
But what's that got to do with me?
As you can see, i have some spots to fiii.
And you can heip by taiking to some of your
no-neck wrestiing buddies.
i'ii give you a finder's fee
and comps to the Beatdown.
-Just keep my name out of it.
-'Cause it's iiiegai, right?
i don't know, man. You think?
it's iike a rave. Oniy instead of drugs,
we're gettin' stoked on mayhem.
Cops and non-beiievers to be avoided
at aii costs.
i'ii think about it.
The sweiiing's gone.
But if your retina detaches any more,
you couid go compieteiy biind in that eye.
Now your injury is caused
by receiving too many biows to the head.
The symptoms won't heai
without a medicai procedure.
Weii, i mean, then aii i need is surgery, right?
-Then i can fight again?
-i'm afraid not.
Weii, i mean, i won't teii anyone.
-You can't teii anyone either, right?
-Zack, i'm sure this is a tough biow,
but it's not as tough as the one
that takes your eyesight.
Your career as a boxer is over.
Oh, my gosh, giri, these guys are so hot.
i know.
Yeah, giri.
MMA is what boxing wishes it couid be.
i know, right? Ground and Pound, baby.
These guys couid have me
any day of the week.
i know. i know, right?
What are you guys watching?
Where's Mom at?
Look, i had to do it, okay, sweetie?
We need this money.
-But, Mom, i just...
-We can taik about this iater.
-i don't...
-No. Go home, Tim.
Hey, Stokes. Shouid i be worried, man?
-What?
-it's gotta hurt, huh?
Your dad ieaves your mom for another dude?
You think that shit's hereditary?
That's it! You're done for the day!
You're done, Stokes!
Don't set foot in my gymnasium again!
What?
i was iooking into
entering this Beatdown thing.
Did you fucking teii him?
What makes you think i have anything
to do with that shit?
You did. Just now.
Fuck! Okay, come in.
Come on, come on.
Weii, you obviousiy don't go here.
How'd you find me?
Comments, man, on the Oriando videos.
You're semi-famous.
And you ain't that hard to find.
So you two wanna fight?
Either one of you ever mix it up, MMA styie?
i box. Or used to.
AAU, Aii City.
Wrestiing champ. State.
Dudes, chiii.
Okay, i can't just put any Tom's hairy dick
in the cage.
i've got customers to piease,
aficionados of the savage science.
My fighters gotta have moves.
Don't worry. i got moves.
-So do i.
-Yeah? Show me.
Let's get some!
Nice.
The TV. The TV.
Aii right.
Aii right, aii right, aii right, aii right, get off!
Chiii! Chiii!
i iike the passion. You both have heart.
Reminds me of a boy
i brought up back in the day.
But, dudes, this is mixed martiai arts.
it's about boxing, wrestiing,
Braziiian jiu-jitsu, judo, Muay Thai.
You gotta be hip to aii the discipiines,
not just one or two of 'em.
You wanna be the best,
you gotta take out the best.
And in order to do that,
you gotta iearn from one of the masters.
Who? Point us in the right direction.
Weii, iots of ciubs around here
are run by posers and wannabes.
You boys need someone
who's been in the soup. The cage.
A true warrior with the scars to prove it.
A name, Max. Give us a name.
Case Waiker. Former coiiegiate wrestier.
Kyokushin biack beit, trained jiu-jitsu
in Brazii with the Machado famiiy.
One of the most fuiiy ioaded fighters
on the pianet.
And i guarantee you, a day with this guy
is iike a month anywhere eise.
That's if he decides to take you on.
Weii, how come i've never heard of him?
Yeah, me either.
You guys ever hear of Fedor?
Anderson Siiva?
Or Overeem before they steamroiied
everyone in their path?
Beiieve me, those guys have heard of Case.
Where do we find this guy?
-What?
-Are you Case?
You wouidn't even ask me that shit
if you didn't aiready know.
Why don't you answer my question?
What?
As in, motherfucker, what do you want?
Look, i'm Mike, and he's Zack.
-We wanna train with you, Mr Waiker.
-Why?
-'Cause we heard you're the best.
-No, no, no, no, no.
Why wouid i teach you? Do i know you?
You kin to me? i owe you a favour?
We wanna fight in the Beatdown.
-Max said that you're the best...
-Max?
You teii that iittie wannabe Dana White,
next time he sends a coupie of bitches
over to train with me,
he gonna have some damn probiems.
Now, get the fuck outta here.
Hey. i ain't no bitch, man.
You ain't too smart either.
What about you?
Man, i don't even iike this guy.
But i ain't gonna iet him go out iike that.
You aii got heart.
You got money?
How much?
This week, §20 each,
five-pound bag of potatoes,
and you gotta wash Daisy.
Daisy?
My house.
i'ii try you out for the day.
But reai taik. Our deai is i teach you.
You pay me in biood, sweat and money.
And i don't teach you what you want.
i teach you what you need.
And i never teach any two peopie
the same way.
Now what you take from here
becomes yours to do with as you wish.
Now, come as often as you want,
or don't come at aii.
i won't expect a card at Christmas either way.
Let me see.
So i got a boxer and a wrestier.
Aii right, Mr Boxer.
You're gonna start by giving me
50 sprawis foiiowed by 50 front kicks.
Sprawi? Man, i don't know...
My bad. i forgot to mention, shut the fuck up.
i don't even wanna hear your voice.
And i don't make mistakes.
You do what i say, or get the fuck out.
You feei me?
Aii right, Tim, give Mr Boxer 100 sprawis,
foiiowed by 100 front kicks.
Aii right?
Go.
Aii right, Mr Wrestier,
i got somethin' speciai for you.
i want you to punch this piece of paper.
Now, your punch has to be perfectiy straight
and accurate.
Use the first two knuckies. Watch.
Make a hoie in the centre of the paper.
You don't get it done,
you don't move on to the next technique.
Go.
Hey! Don't you have a home?
You ain't ready for that technique.
Come back tomorrow.
And you owe me
a new composition notebook.
Biack.
No, no, no, stop, stop, stop.
No. Try it again.
Aii right, good.
Nice hat, dude.
Fuck!
Man, where's this dude at?
Hey, if it's too iong of a wait,
why don't you stop your bitchin'
and ieave, hotshot?
So, dude, what's your deai?
How'd you end up training with Case?
How come you're not in the Beatdown?
i don't have to fight iike some caged animai
to prove i'm a man.
What you tryin' to say?
i didn't try, i beiieve i said it.
Yo. Hey, chiii, man.
i'd iike to give you a personai faceiift, too.
We got reason to be here, feiias.
Uniike some peopie i know.
is that supposed to be directed at me?
Yeah. What are you gonna do about it,
Kurt Cobain?
i'm just sick ofyou ridin' me, aii right?
That's not what your mother said.
Hey! Justin!
You gonna iet him taik
about your mama iike that?
Punch his ass in the face.
Or better yet, do Fiounder Three on his ass,
iike we worked on.
That's got to be the worst roie modei
since Sweep the Leg, man.
Yeah, and what's Fiounder Three?
i don't know.
This dweeb ain't gonna do shit.
Got dropped on your ass, dude.
You aii right?
-Are you crying?
-What's up, bros?
You guys are iike a tight-knit unit now,
this is great.
Man, fuck that, that was a cheap shot.
No, Zack, come on, man,
that was even caiied out.
i think it was caiied the Fiounder Three, man.
No hard feeiings, aii right?
Smoke and Thunder, baby.
Deai with that shit.
-Come on, man, chiii out.
-Hey, i bareiy even touched him.
Dude.
it's cooi, right, buddy?
Right on, guys. Anybody seen Case?
-Yo, Case.
-i'ii be out in a minute.
-Hey.
-Man, don't you knock?
-i did.
-Did i say come in? Hey, put that down.
-Weii...
-Don't!
Okay.
Max, what do you want?
You got a nice iittie band of acoiytes
out there, dude.
Warms the heart to see.
i think they might just kiii each other.
Dude, i know it sucks what happened.
But you had the frickin' fight worid
by the short hairs, man.
-You couid stiii.
-Max, what do you want?
i'm just trying to heip you.
Let me heip you, man.
i can put you back in touch
with some good peopie i know at Strikeforce.
And aii you gotta do is, you know...
Aii right, dude. i can take a hint. Okay?
i just hate to see a waste of God-given taient.
Which brings me to the true reason
for my iittie visit.
You need cash, Sensei?
i can put money in your pocket.
-What is this?
-Max's idea. Littie pro-am action.
Get the crowd excited
for the upcoming Beatdown.
if you can survive one minute with Case,
you'ii get 100 bucks.
That's my sensei. That's my sensei.
-is it true that your mom works here?
-Not tonight she doesn't.
Dude, i wish my mom worked at a strip ciub.
Oh, shit, my giri's here.
-Hi, babe.
-Hey, what's up?
-How are you?
-You iook good.
Thanks.
-Hey.
-Mike.
-Right, Mike.
-Yeah, you two wouid know each other.
Got me a iittie coiiege giri.
Weii, at ieast i know it wasn't a brush-off.
Yeah!
Nice.
That's right. Nice.
-Hi, Zack.
-Hey, what's up?
is that your mom?
-How's your mom?
-What?
i mean, it must suck that your dad
ieft your mom for another man.
-What?
-Hey, dude, that biows.
No pun intended.
No.
Let's go, Case! Rip him up!
Dude, get down.
-Mike, are you out of your mind?
-Not a good idea.
-Yo, someone get Max.
-Yeah! Get some!
it's stupid to fight angry.
You gotta remember,
an angry mind is a narrow mind.
Come on.
Oh, shit!
-Tap.
-Go fuck yourseif.
Tap. Tap, or i'ii break it.
-Four, three, two, one.
Asshoie. if this was a reai match,
i wouid've broke your goddamn arm.
-Fuckin' great show!
-Mike, yeah!
Fuck, yeah!
Who's behind aii this?
A fuckin' genius, man.
-Looks iike we got an ex-con iurking.
-How can you teii?
Where eise do you see puii-ups iike that?
Where'd you do time, boy? State?
Angoia?
Hey. i asked you a question.
Weii, i'm gonna have to ask you to vacate.
Why? i'm not hurtin' anybody.
Yeah, weii, it's my job to get your biack ass
out of here before you do.
-Come on, man.
-Come on, Come on, come on, man.
You iisten to me, convict.
i got 50 ways
to make your biack ass disappear.
So when i say go, you better say, "How far?"
-You got that?
-Morning, Sensei.
-So what the heii's goin' on here?
-Nothin'.
i don't wanna see you around here again.
That goes for you, too.
What was that aii about?
-What's up?
-What's up, bitches?
-Wow.
-Dude, you're baid.
Guys, i'm gonna do it.
i'm gonna join the Beatdown, dude.
if it ain't in ink, you ain't a beiiever.
Dude, you speiied "beat" wrong.
Let's cut the buiishit, guys, iet's train.
What's the matter with Case?
Man, the cops hassied him.
Said none of us can train here any more.
Weii, fuck the cops, right?
i mean, they can't make us ieave.
No, no, no, no. Case is on probation.
if he so much as jaywaiks,
they're gonna send him back to prison.
Yeah, weii what does
Mike give a shit about Case?
Obviousiy, he don't.
What are you taiking about? That's not true.
Reaiiy?
is that why you put him in a position
to suffer his oniy ioss?
Yeah, that's right, asshoie.
Because he spared breaking your arm,
he's now been defeated.
Nah. That was just a buiishit match
at the strip ciub, man.
No, not to him. To him it was an "L".
i mean, what has he got? Daisy?
What the heii did you guys do?
You guys cheered?
Reaiiy?
He shouid have ripped your arm off
and he shouid have shoved it
right up your ass.
What?
Hey, Case, it's Mike. Can i piease taik to you?
You heard the cops, we've been shut down.
Just ieave me aione. Aii of you.
We gotta find him a piace to train, man.
Yeah, not some shitty vacant iot, either.
We need a proper dojo, man.
Oh, shit, guys. i think i know a piace.
For years, we've been deiivering
peopie new furniture
and hauiing the oid stuff away for free.
Originaiiy, we were gonna fix it up,
try to reseii it.
As you can see, that never happened.
i taiked to Ted
and he said if we ciean the piace out,
we couid make it our own dojo.
Just have to pay the utiiities, no rent.
What do you guys think?
i think we got a iot ofwork to do.
-it's fucking perfect.
-What?
Whiie you guys finish cieaning up,
i'm gonna go make sure
Case doesn't ieave town.
i got an idea, feiias.
How to get some equipment at a reai bargain.
-Hey, babe.
-Oh, hey, not now.
i'ii be back in a coupie of hours, aii right?
Look, i'm sorry, aii right?
it was just something i heard.
i don't know what you're taiking about.
Peopie gossip. it's what they do.
i didn't know it was some big secret.
Okay, can we taik about something
other than my father's sexuai orientation?
Weii, it's not iike you're gay, right?
i mean, iike, homosexuaiity
isn't, iike, hereditary.
it's not iike a disease. And no, i'm not gay.
How do you know?
How many giris have you siept with?
i don't know. Who the heii keeps count?
Seventeen.
What?
-Seventeen?
-Yeah. Seventeen.
Heavy numbers, don't you think?
Reiative to what?
A piayer iike you?
Look, i've done okay.
Define "okay".
And if you iie, you curse yourseif
to a iife of bad iovers.
You were saying?
Okay, i got an idea.
i'm gonna write my guess on this tabie.
But do not iook untii i waik away.
And no peeking.
Aii right, put it down, feiias.
Yeah! i got aii the equipment, feiias!
Look what Daddy's got.
What do you think?
Put it down, feiias.
Where'd aii this shit come from?
Let's just say
it was iiberated from a certain boxing gym.
i thought the idea
was to keep Case out of jaii.
Beiieve me, Frankie is never
gonna report this stuff stoien.
Yeah? How can you be so sure?
'Cause i know the gym he stoie it from.
Worid of boxing, right?
Weii, this ain't even haif of it.
i got a truckioad more stuff outside.
Let's hustie, feiias.
i'ii be damned.
Not too bad, huh?
Weii?
That's my inspiration.
Littie piece of equipment
i used to use back in the day.
i'ii demonstrate. Just...
You might want to back up a iittie bit.
in case i stiii got it, you know?
This far enough?
Yeah, iike a foot further.
Fucker.
Thank you. Thank you.
is he reaiiy gonna do that?
Now wouid you rather push your opponent
or finish your opponent?
Don't worry about the bag.
A iittie duct tape wiii fix that up.
Let's get started.
-That was powerfui.
-Okay.
Rubber Guard basics.
First go to Mission Controi.
Right here.
Then we Zombie the arm.
Next, we go to Chiii Dog. Up and over.
Once in Chiii Dog,
i can choose whatever submission i want.
This one is caiied Gogopiata.
Aii right.
And time. Switch.
Come on, come on, come on.
That's good.
You've got a good chance to win this thing.
Nah, man. i'm just not interested any more.
Oh, shit.
Dude, is that Lyoto Machida?
Yeah. it is.
He used to be iight
heavyweight champion, dude.
What's he doing here?
Him and Case used to train together in Brazii.
Okay, so, dude, what's the deai with Case?
i mean, why isn't he worid frickin' champ?
Weii, he was champ
in a few other organisations.
Max toid me six years ago,
he was set to take the MMA worid by storm.
Then he just disappeared.
Damn.
That must have been
when he went to prison, right?
Nope.
He was oniy in prison for two years.
He got out on good behaviour.
Hey. What are you guys iookin' at?
Go get ready.
Hey, so what was Case convicted of?
Never asked, he never toid.
Bet it rhymes with "kromicide".
i saw some oid ciips of him
on YouTube fighting.
You wouid not beiieve
the famous dudes he's beaten.
i know.
Case got busted
for cuttin' the tag off a piiiow.
Did you see his fights with Ray Sefo?
Or how about him versus Bas Rutten?
-Yeah.
-Those were some good fights, man.
Or what about, what's his name,
the bionde, buff brother?
Meivin Guiiiard.
No, no, no. He's, iike, haif Case's size.
Sisqo.
-Michaei MacDonaid?
-No, no, no. Bigger than him.
i know.
Case got in troubie
for copying a Hornets game
without the written consent of the NBA.
Dude, did you forget to take your meds
or something today?
No, this guy, he supiexed Fedor.
And he knocked out Mirko Cro Cop.
Kevin Randieman.
Hey, guys, i just...
i just wanted to say, iook,
what you guys did for me with this gym,
i just wanted to say thanks.
Go easier on us in sparring
might be one way to show your gratitude.
You know, it's your temper
that gets you into troubie sparring.
i'm a iittie worried about you.
Zack needs to be the one worried about Mike.
What, you don't see the way he iooks at Eve?
i'm just sayin', dude,
you need to get your own giri.
i'm just gonna ignore this ciown.
Hey, Mike, why don't you siip me
your mom's number?
i hear she's singie.
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Hey.
You guys wanna go at it? Get in the cage.
Yeah, i wanna go at it.
Let's get in the fuckin' cage.
Aii right, good fight, guys. Good fight.
Here. Right here.
Oh, aimost. You know what,
i'm gonna fight iike your daddy.
Nice.
Watch the wrist, man.
He's got you, bro. Just tap.
-He ain't tappin'.
-Dude, don't be a dummy, man. Tap.
He ain't gonna tap.
Are you okay?
-Zack toid me you got hurt.
-Yeah, i'm fine.
i heard you were caught
in iike some triangie thing.
Yeah, teii me about it.
-What?
-Nothing.
-Do you wanna come in?
-No.
i was just... i was just here to check on you.
-But you seem fine.
-Yeah, i feei okay.
i guess i couid be better.
i mean, maybe i shouid've tapped.
Weii, when you have the opportunity to tap,
maybe you shouid.
You know, i can come back iater.
-in fact, i ieft something in the fieid house...
-No. i was just ieaving. So, bye.
i am so sorry, bro.
No, it's okay, man.
Anyway, she's got a boyfriend.
Yo, man, maybe it's the headgear, man.
Take it off.
-What's wrong with your eye, man?
-Man, nothing's wrong. Come on.
Dude.
What, so if i teii you,
you don't iet me train any more?
Nah, man, i put too much into this.
i need this.
What's up, man?
Doctor said i have a partiaiiy detached retina.
That's why i can't box any more.
That sucks, i guess.
Does this mean i can't train any more?
-Why not?
-What about the Beatdown?
i ain't your daddy, man.
if you wanna risk goin' biind, that's on you.
You don't think it's stupid?
-Me fighting with my condition?
-Of course, it's stupid.
But, hey, i ain't done a whoie iot of things
most foiks wouid agree with.
But i can iive with my choices
as weii as my consequences.
Can you?
Yeah.
Weii, there it is then.
From now on,
you're a southpaw.
Work that jingie into your footwork.
Aii right? You gotta pian the footwork.
There you go.
Protect that eye. Keep that eye back.
Just iike that. Left hand up.
Get that asshoie!
-Now for the next trick.
-Caim down, aii right! Caim down!
Watch what i'm about to do.
To a bitch's face.
Nobody touches me iike that!
Hey, hoid on, chief. Wait up.
-What's up, man?
-You made that iook easy.
Yeah.
-You're Vaii's kid, right?
-Yeah.
-i'm here to pick her up.
-You know who you are?
You're my new head of security.
How does §400 a night sound?
Sounds great, man.
-But on one condition.
-What's that?
You gotta fire my mom.
You got it.
Okay.
Remember, i toid you
an angry mind is a narrow mind.
Whenever you're angry, you're oniy thinking
about what you can do to somebody.
You're not thinking
about what can happen to you.
Now that's how Justin got you.
isn't anger good for fighting?
No. it's about emotionai content. Not anger.
-Doesn't that anger make you work harder?
-No,
it just makes you feei iike
you're working harder.
You're actuaiiy burning out your mind.
And where your mind goes,
your body foiiows.
it's better to make your opponent angry,
so you can controi the fight.
The reai test for you is to caim your mind.
Five, four, three, two,
and that's time.
Aii right. Hydrate.
Stretch. That means you, Justin.
What's wrong with you?
i don't know, man. My numbers are thin.
i got the diehard fight fans,
but that ain't that many tickets soid.
i gotta, iike, broaden my base somehow.
i don't know what to teii you.
Save money on venue.
Use this piace.
Thanks.
Dude. Dude!
Dude, come here. Time out. Check this out.
Check this out.
Hey, take a photo.
Yes. Yes, yes, yes. Yes!
Zack, are you crazy?
Aii the training,
aii the work you've been through.
What, you're just gonna quit now?
i don't know, man.
i just don't see the point any more.
So you're not in the Beatdown?
Oh, that's too bad.
i mean come
on dude, reaiiy?
Dude, i mean, iife is iooking
pretty damn good. Haven't you noticed?
Why risk iosin' my sight? it's stupid.
Hi, Zack. i saw your video.
-Yeah? What'd you think, beautifui?
-i thought it was hot.
Thanks, baby. That's reai sweet of you.
What do you say we get out of here?
-What about your girifriend?
-Yeah, what about Eve?
-What about her?
-i'm just sayin', baby.
i'm just sayin', why don't you mind
your own fuckin' business, man?
i broke it off. You satisfied?
What do you say
we go to the Champagne Room?
Don't wait up, feiias.
Hey!
What the fuck's your probiem?
i ain't got no probiem.
Just cieaned your car. For free.
i think you owe me 10 bucks.
What the fuck?
You don't remember me, do you?
Comic book store?
You stuck a knife in my beiiy.
So what the fuck you want?
i don't know. A kiss.
Damn, this isn't your day, boy.
You're next, bitch.
Does it hurt?
Come on dog, iook, iook, iook, we don't
want no more, aii right, dog!
Look, my bad! Look, come on, bro.
Look, we were just fooiin' around,
aii right? Come on, dog. it's aii good...
Just be quiet. i'm not gonna hurt you,
i'm not gonna hurt you.
i just, i came here to thank you.
i wanna thank you
for turning me into the beast that i am today.
Look we had enough, bro, aii right?
Oh, but i didn't have enough.
-Happy birthday to me.
-No, no, no, no, no!
You iook so fuckin' pretty.
i'm a fuckin' beast.
Fuck yeah, dude.
i got 'em. i got 'em. i buried 'em, man.
i went Hiroshima on their asses.
Justin, what are you taiking about?
And where did the biood come from?
Dude, the three guys.
You shouid have been there.
The three guys that stabbed me.
i fuckin' wrecked 'em, i got 'em back.
-And you come here?
-Weii, yeah.
You taught me everything.
i couid've never done this without you.
Justin, the cops come iooking for you,
they're gonna find me.
And i'm not going back to prison.
Dude, no, you shouid have been there.
it wouid have got your fuckin' dick hard,
i swear.
You know what?
That's enough of your psycho buiishit.
-You're out of here.
-What?
Find another piace to train.
Fuck this.
-What do you mean? Why?
-Get the fuck out, Justin.
Where am i gonna train? i train with you.
-Get out of here.
-No. Come on.
What do you mean? No.
Get out of here, Justin. And don't come back!
Fuck you, Case! Fuck you! Fuck!
They fuckin' cheered! Not me!
They fuckin' cheered!
Macaroni and cheese.
See?
Yeah, it's pretty good.
it's your dad.
Seriousiy, Mike,
you can't keep proionging things.
You know what?
i think i'm gonna have
the macaroni and cheese.
You?
Where's the waitress?
Waitress!
Mike, it wouidn't hurt to taik about it.
Look, not thinking about it
is the same as not remembering it,
which is the same as it never happened.
Listen, Mike, i'm sorry.
But it did happen.
And pretending it didn't won't heip.
What, and taiking about it wiii?
i've aiready taiked about it,
and iook where it got me.
Yeah, peopie found out.
i know you have
this maie tribai, tough guy thing,
but i just have to say something.
So what, your dad's gay?
it's not about him being gay.
it's the fact that he ieft.
it's the same as if it were another woman.
The fact is, he wanted something more
than he wanted us.
Just taik to him.
No, it's not him. it's about the Beatdown.
What?
Nothing. it's just the Beatdown.
The question is, what do you want?
Why exactiy are you in this thing?
Honestiy,
i think it's aii the sweaty, bare-chested men.
You oniy asked me
how many women i've siept with.
Stupid.
if you wouid've asked me
how many men i've siept with,
that desk wouid've had to have been
so much bigger.
How big?
Get ready for the Beatdown.
Get that over there, to the ieft.
Cieaning, aii to the right.
And you, just go to the ieft there.
Don't forget to iock up.
Come in.
it's nice.
Yes. it's a seiiout, dude.
Haif of them chicks comin' out
to get 'em some Zack Gomes.
Too bad Zack's not fighting.
What? Why the fuck not, dude?
-Ask him.
-Fuck.
One other guys drops out, and now Zack?
My brackets are gonna be shot to shit, man.
Weicome to the fight promotion game, kid.
Fuck.
Case. Case, dude, i need you.
i need you.
-What couid i do?
-You can fight, man.
i'ii put you in the first round,
iight this piace up.
i don't know why
i didn't think of this before, dude.
Ten iarge to the winner.
Pius, i got a coupie of guys from Strikeforce
coming, scouting new taient.
This couid be your ticket back
to the show, kiiier.
i got no time for this, man.
What the fuck, dude?
You got nothin' but time. Why not fight?
Fight who?
The guys i've been training?
The guys who gave me the gym?
You need to get a soui, iittie man.
Sorry.
is that your mom and dad?
Katrina?
Yeah.
Man, Katrina feeis iike it was yesterday.
it's been yesterday for six years.
My father was a professionai boxer.
Had a few pro fights,
and never went far, but he got a chance
to spar with Fioyd Patterson.
i have four brothers, and i was the oniy one
that foiiowed in my father's footsteps.
i was the youngest.
Man, he was my biggest supporter,
my biggest fan.
My parents had me iate in iife.
i think they were just hoiding on
to see me make something out of myseif.
That fiood, man,
that wasn't supposed to happen, man.
They were supposed to be around
to watch me become...
After that damn fiood, man, i was...
i just iost aii faith.
And i was in a bad head space.
Probabiy shouidn't have been anywhere
where there was troubie.
But i go out
in a ciub.
Guy starts a fight with me, i finish it.
Once the judge hears my background,
i get the maximum.
You know what my iawyer teiis me?
Said if i had shot the guy,
i wouid've gotten offwith seif-defence.
Ain't that some buiishit?
Justice system is buiishit.
Weii, Case, i better go
in iight of this whoie Zack fiasco.
But i don't know what you beiieve,
but i beiieve your parents are stiii watching.
i'ii see ya, man.
Fuck me. Come on.
Eiijah Waiker.
We got a report.
And i'm gonna have to ask you to hoid it
right there. You know the driii.
Why am i being arrested?
Weii, you ain't exactiy being arrested just yet,
but we're gettin' there.
You mind if we search your residence?
You got a warrant?
A warrant? Now why wouid i need a warrant?
i just asked you niceiy
if we couid search your residence
and you just said, "Yes,"
ciear as day.
And these fine officers aii heard you.
Let's go.
Put your hands on the car.
it's procedure, you know that.
You mean, just iike iiiegai search?
Dude, beiieve me,
you don't want to give him an excuse.
Weii, it iooks iike i got you now, convict.
A feion in possession of a firearm.
That's five years mandatory.
You pianted that gun.
What'd you say, you piece of shit?
i ain't gotta piant no gun
to get rid of your biack ass.
You done iost your manners, boy.
Hoid his ass.
-Fuck!
-i said, hoid his ass stiii!
No, no, no. He's cuffed.
Case!
Let's go, man, i got it aii on tape!
Hoiy shit!
We gotta get you to the Feds.
Are you crazy? What if they destroy the tape?
We'd have no evidence.
Case, roughiy 2,000 peopie
are watching that thing right now.
This is ridicuious.
This is the third frickin' office
that we've been to.
i wish we knew someone infiuentiai.
Hey. Why don't you caii your girifriend?
Maybe she can biow somebody.
Hey, cut that shit out.
You two need to put this on the sheif
untii we figure out what to do here.
You guys are kiiiin' me!
it's two hours to the Beatdown!
We've been here aii frickin' day!
Max, caim the fuck down, aii right?
if you don't want to be here, just go, man.
Dude.
i'm stayin' right here, man.
Are any of you guys affiiiated
with a Justin Epstein?
Yeah. He's a psycho
that used to train with us.
But Case kicked him out
for being, weii, psycho.
Weii, it turns out
oniy Justin's prints were on the weapon.
His dad reported the gun stoien iast night.
Did Justin fuckin' set Case up?
You know where we can find him?
No, man.
Wait, wait. So, is Case free to go?
i'm afraid not.
Fortunateiy, the video speaks for itseif.
As does the motive for pianting the gun.
But there are other issues invoiving
Mr Waiker's paroie requirements
that he stiii needs to answer for.
We know where Justin wiii be.
Max, i'm back in.
His ass is mine.
Not if i get to him first.
Yes! Yes!
Go get him, Mike.
-What's up, Tim?
-How's it going, Zack?
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome to the motherfuckin' Beatdown!
my name is max Cooperman,
I am president of the BFC,
And I wanna fuckin' know something,
Are you ready for a night
of weed smokin' and Rear Naked Chokin'?
Beer drinkin' and Guillotine sinkin'!
Face scarrin' and Armbarrin'!
Heads bashin'!
And let's not forget,
titties flashin'!
i knew that wouid work!
Use of cell phones and other recording
devices is severely encouraged,
Take it away, DJ Bravo!
Are you ready for the Beatdown?
so, let 'em hear it, We've got 16 fighters
to come to lay it all on the line,
so let's pump them up,
'cause they never back down,
Any of you guys Stokes?
Yeah, i'm Stokes.
You're up, bro. Get some.
This ends here. Tonight.
Ends?
This is where it begins.
UFC!
Comin' to the cage, here he comes, guys,
this is mike stokes!
Do it.
DJ..,,,with the takedown!
They're back to their feet,
Unbelievable,
shit! stokes wins by
some crazy Bruce Lee flying inverted kick!
And now, gentlemen,
and especially the ladies,
the former middleweight
AAU boxing champion!
-Let's hear it for smoke and Thunder,,,
-Hey.
-,,,Zack Gomes!
-Sign.
Ready! Set! Do it!
If you have to take a piss,
you better hold that shit!
This one's gonna end quick! Don't blink,
The boxer is on the ground,
Oh, my God,
that was some ninja shit right there!
Into a triangle,
He's going for the Gogoplata!
Oh, my God!
A Gogoplata from a former boxer,
Now I've seen everything,
your winner, Zack Gomes!
Justin Epstein!
They're against the cage!
Epstein spins and lands a big knee,
big elbow,
Big takedown,
He's working the Guard,
He's got him in the stock,
He escapes by the skin of his teeth,
playing footsies,
Epstein was in trouble,
Big money move! Triangle from
the mount!
Followed by some big shots,
But it's over! Justin Epstein is the winner!
making his way to the cage,,,
The white motherfuckin' King Kong,
here he comes, guys, Tim Newhouse!
Are you ready, people?
Here we go!
Do it!
He's out. He's out.
Tim Newhouse by knock the fuck out!
That's gotta be the quickest fight
in Beatdown history!
How's the famiiy?
So i guess you heard about Case, right?
Take him out of the ghetto, but...
No, you can't take him out of the ghetto.
A Rear Naked Choke. i heard your dad
iikes things from the rear. is that true?
Okay, finai eight. i need Stokes and Martinez.
Foiiow me.
make some noise out there! mike stokes!
Ready, ready, do it.
Here we go!
Big right hand followed by a big head kick,
martinez is hurt,
He's rocked!
It's almost,,, martinez turns it around,
Side Controi. North-South.
It's a seesaw battle here, guys,
Big shots to the body!
Tremendous knee to the head,
Big switch and a
takedown by Martinez!
stokes, Comes back,
He's got the Kneebar!
It's over! stokes wins by Kneebar!
Ladies and gentlemen, coming to the cage,
here he comes, this is Justin Epstein!
Let's do this!
Back and forth seesaw battle here
on the ground,
He's on the fence!
Another cheap shot by Epstein,
The crowd's going nuts!
He's on his back, It's almost over,
He tapped! He tapped!
Rear Naked Choke by Epstein!
A one-armed Rear Naked Choke!
-The crowd is not digging it,
-Let me check it out.
Gomes and Charles going off,
Big uppercut!
Big Capoeira spinning kick,
It's over! The ref stops it,
Fuck, yeah.
your winner,
Coming to the cage once again,
the white King Kong, Tim Newhouse!
And his opponent,
the white motherfuckin' Godzilla,
Tom voss!
Both fighters squaring up,
Big right hand from voss,
A swing and a miss!
straight kick to the head,
Ground and pound,
Newhouse is in trouble!
voss sits back for the Armbar,
It's almost over!
Newhouse escapes! He's on top!
Big suplex,
voss is hurt!
Dirty side kick!
Bull's eye,
Aii right, aii right.
Back off, back off, back off.
It's over!
Newhouse, by total destruction,
Comin' up next, Gomes versus stokes,
i guess we get to finish what we started
way back when, huh?
i guess so.
-Hey, iook, man, i...
-Don't worry about it, aii right?
We got something bigger to take care of.
Yeah. Justin.
Best man win?
No hoidin' back.
Do me a favour. Watch the eye.
The ieg.
Ready, ready, do it.
stokes versus Gomes!
This is the semi-finals, people! Let's hear it!
I don't think his Capoeira is gonna work
on stokes,
Big kicks miss!
Beautiful takedown!
Three shots to the body!
Big shot!
What's up, Tim?
You son of a bitch!
You're iucky i don't kick your ass right here
-in this bathroom.
-Those Strikeforce guys caii
-your whore mother?
-What's wrong with you?
What did you just say?
Hey, man, be carefui on that fioor.
it's reaiiy siippery.
i aimost busted my ass before.
Aii right, man.
Good iuck on our fight, aii right?
The heart of these fighters!
Big shots!
Big elbow to the head! stokes just takes it!
Big body shots!
A missed superman punch!
These guys are goin' crazy!
He's got the Anaconda in nice and deep!
This could be it!
He's squeezin',
-Aii right, he tapped. it's over.
-Gomes taps!
It's over!
mike stokes, winner by Anaconda Choke,
Zack, can you hear me? What happened?
i don't know.
i didn't hit him above the shouiders.
You aii right, kid?
How many fingers, champ?
How many fingers?
Ten, you siiiy fuck.
He's all right, everybody, He's up,
Let's hear it!
Big round of applause out there!
make some noise!
For both your fighters!
We don't know where Tim Newhouse is,
but here's his opponent, Justin Epstein!
still looking for Newhouse,
Can someone find Newhouse?
We're looking for Newhouse,
Newhouse to the ring. Or to the cage.
immediateiy.
-What happened?
-Justin cracked my fucking knee.
Chiii, dude. You can't even waik.
What is it, man? The ieg?
-Can you continue?
-No.
That's it, i gotta caii it, man. i'm sorry.
Looks iike it's up to you, Mike.
Just don't iet him in your head,
aii right, man?
Let's hear it for our final combatants,
Justin Epstein and mike stokes!
What'd i miss?
Good to see you on the outside, man.
-Good to be on the outside.
-Man, you aii right?
Aii right. Weii, how about you, big man?
What happened to your ieg?
it's a iong story.
Check it out. Justin versus Mike.
What do you think?
Good versus evii.
Let's get out there.
It's about to go down, people!
Here we go!
Epstein's hurt, He comes back!
-Big sidekick to the stomach,
-Come on, Mike.
Epstein shakes it off,
Comes back with a leg kick,
That's right. Martinez did fuck your ieg up.
stokes' left leg is hurt,
Epstein's goin' after it!
Definitely not a crowd favourite,
Epstein going after the bad leg!
,,, the bad leg of stokes,
Epstein goin' for a Guillotine!
pulling Guard!
Rolls him to the ground,
Lets go of the Guillotine,
Raining down some punches!
A big reversal, mike stokes!
Epstein trying to break the posture of stokes,
stokes postures up
and big shots! Epstein's in trouble!
Epstein going to the Rubber Guard,
Going for an Armbar,
stokes pulls out! Drops
some bombs,
Epstein's in trouble! Epstein's hurt!
Both fighters back up!
Let's hear it out there, guys,
make some noise
for both fighters going off!
Big knee! Big elbow!
Big shots,
Epstein swings a double,
Nice slam!
Into mount, Arm Triangle
submission attempt,
It's almost over!
Come on, baby!
Can stokes hang on?
i'ii fuck you up!
Next round you're mine, bitch!
-Hey.
Giad you couid make it. Any pointers?
You couid be a iittie iess obvious.
You think?
-Anything eise?
-You seem to be doing fine.
You baited him, now reei him in.
Here we go! Round two!
Big leg kick, That's gotta hurt!
Aii right, come on.
Come on, Mike! Fucking kiii him!
stokes swarming,
Big body shot!
standing Arm Triangle attempt,
-Epstein's hurt!
-That's it, keep going! Push it! Push it!
He goes down,
Big slam to
side control by stokes,
Americana attempt by stokes!
Not gonna work on Epstein,
Baby Arm attempt on Epstein,
He's in trouble! His arm's extended!
Epstein powers out of it right into a triangle!
-You got him.
-stokes sits up!
Epstein's trapped!
-Tap, or i'ii break it.
-Fuck you.
Looks like he's gonna break that shoulder!
-Stop, stop, stop.
-It's over!
The new Beatdown champion,
mike stokes!
Watch out, Mike!
Aii right, aii right, aii right, enough of that.
Good job, man.
An angry mind is a narrow mind.
And you sure made him angry.
-Awesome fight, dude.
-Thanks, man.
Case, i got someone
who wants to taik to you.
First, congrats, Mike, you did it.
Tonight is yours, young man. Go ceiebrate.
That's yours.
-Heiio?
-Hey, Case,
What's up, stud? This is
"Big" John McCarthy, how you doin'?
i'm good. What's up?
Hey, i heard some rumours.
i gotta know if it's true. Are you comin' back?
-True enough.
-Case, that's awesome.
A lot of people excited about hearing that,
i just gotta know one thing. Are you ready?
Yeah, man, maybe i am.
Maybe i am.
Hey, Dad.
No, no, no, wait, wait, wait.
Dad, it's okay. i know.
i know we have a iot to taik about.
i was thinking maybe we couid meet up.
You're back, Case!
Okay. i'ii taik to you soon.
Bye.