What's up?
Nothing.
You don't work for me no more?
I was just... Didn't I just say I was
going to get his money?
Bitch, I don't work for
the phone company.
I don't do this shit long distance.
Bring your ass here.
Do I look like I just fell off
a turnip truck, bitch?
You know, Bobby, you been acting
kind of strange lately. You okay?
Just had a few personal problems.
It's taken care of...
What kind of problems?
l'll straighten it out.
You sure?
Absolutely. Don't worry about it.
What's he doing? He's beating this girl.
We got a 3-million dollar hit
about to go down over here.
You don't like it, turn your head.
Come on, Gino.
Guys, we're coming in.
Gino's blowing it. Let's go.
I'm pregnant.
You pregnant?! You let some trick
get you pregnant?!
Ain't you ever heard of a rubber?!
This motherfucker hit me.
I'm scared l'll lose my baby.
You wop motherfucker!
What the fuck you doing?!
You talking to me?
Who the fuck you think you are?!
You like to beat up on
fucking women?
Beat up on me.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
I know where you live, motherfucker.
l'll fuck your wife and kids...
Gino, you son of a bitch!
I got some unfinished business
to take care of.
It'll be over
by the end of tonight.
Stick by me, all that money's yours.
That's a lot of money.
We stuck with you through
worse for free.
How long could the night be?
Mommy, can I get a hot dog?
No, honey.
Forget about it, okay?
If you eat a hot dog now,
you'll ruin your dinner.
Also, do me a favor.
IKeep your sneakers clean tonight.
No dirt, no puddles.
We got a party tonight.
Let's go in here to get some stuff.
Bobby, l'll take the kids.
How's that feel, Bobby?
You ain't laughing now.
How you doing?
Good.
Dad, can we play catch or what?
You finish your homework?
No?
And you still want to play catch?
Go get your stuff.
Stop the car. Give me the pipe.
Doing a cop
right in the street like that!
- Give me the pipe!
- It's already fucking hot!
I got news for you.
It'll get a lot hotter
before the fucking night's over.
Move the goddamn car!
What are you doing? Get in the car!
What's your problem?
He'll do her.
- Asshole.
- Asshole?
What are you looking at?
You got the mitt. I got the ball.
Get the bat.
Let's go. Let's go.
We got a problem. Can you come in?
I'm with the kid, why?
Bobby Lupo was shot on 18th Avenue
in front of his wife and kids.
Oh, my God!
I'm sending you a car.
Vick, I got to send Tony over right now.
Damn you and the job! He waits
a month for one weekend with you.
I know,
but Bobby just got shot.
Oh, my God!
Laurie and the kids were with him.
l'll be right over.
Send Tony to my parents' house.
l'll pick him up afterwards.
Get them out of here,
Vick, please.
Sure you want to see this?
Give him some room, will you?
Come on!
See if there are any more witnesses.
All I got is this fruit and vegetable guy.
I'm real sorry, Gino.
It was Richie Madano.
Laurie said Richie got out of the car
and just stepped up. Bang!
The grocer said Richie tossed something.
We didn't find nothing.
We know every mob operation.
We'll squeeze them
to give him up.
Do that. But it's me who'll find
this fucking guy. You know that.
You and Vicky...
Divorce goes through this month.
How'd it happen?
Some wannabe wiseguy asshole,
Richie Madano.
Dope dealer, dope user...
He was a guy Bobby and Gino
grew up with.
We don't know why he'd kill Bobby.
- Are you all right?
- No, I'm not! He was my best friend.
He just pulled a woman
out of a car...
...and blew her brains out.
It looks random.
Three of his crew were with him.
One has a tattoo on his neck.
I know him. Bochi.
He's a piece of shit.
Got a sheet as long as my arm.
We got a city-wide out,
every officer.
We got A.L. 's
at the airports, trains, buses...
This guy won't run.
He'll sneak and hide,
but he won't leave Brooklyn.
l'll feed you every dope dive he's got,
but let me do it my way.
Just give me an unmarked
and a shotgun.
Don't. You're too close.
Let other cops do it.
I know this guy
better than anybody else.
I know the neighborhood
better than anyone else.
- Be careful, will you?
- You know me.
- Get the son of a bitch.
- L'll do what I can.
Why won't this man run?
You never understood nothing
about the neighborhood.
I guess not.
You kill a cop in front of witnesses,
you're going to die.
The difference is, this guy wants to die
in his own neighborhood.
Why can't you all piss on a tree,
mark territory, like dogs?
Don't worry. L'll be at
the divorce hearing on time, in 1 piece.
l'll pick up Laurie and the girls
and bring them to our house.
Finish this
so we can finish our business.
Find Richie Madano before the cops do
and bring him to me, here!
What about Gino?
Stay away from Gino. Leave him alone.
Come on, go.
Sammy, how are you?
Why are you here?
Still comb your hair like a girl.
Gino, I'm sorry what happened.
My sincere regrets.
Comes from my heart.
In front of a man's family.
It's inhuman.
Worse than that.
He's not with us.
You know we never let
nobody do anything like this.
If you or one of your people...
...catch this guy...
...he gets what,
seven or ten, maybe?
If we're lucky.
Gino, this man disgraced me. And you.
He spilled an innocent man's blood
in front of his family!
And on my sidewalk.
Gino, you know our ways.
He must be dealt with by us.
But I promise you...
...I will teach this man the price
of our blood.
...God forbid I find him before
you do...
...you know what l'll do.
Think about it.
All right, Gino?
Patch me through to Doz.
10-4, switching over.
Go ahead, talk to me.
Vittorio doesn't know nothing.
If he does, he won't tell me.
I'm sending over O'IKelly and some guys
from OCCB. IKeep in touch.
- Sure, l'll keep you posted.
- Watch your ass.
"IKill them all. Let God sort them out."
Tough guy.
Please, God...
...let me run into this guy someday.
I heard what happened.
Hope you get the son of a bitch.
Me too. Six-pack of seltzer.
Six dead Washingtons, brother.
Never thought about it.
We're going to call him Corragio.
You see anything, you drop a dime.
How's your mother?
She's going straight now.
Thank God.
You want to fuck?
Did you hear what she said?
What'd she say, my man? What'd she say?
I'm at Sunset Park and 3rd.
Richie's clients are all down here.
Ain't it the truth.
I'm looking for two hotshots for backup!
Anybody got the balls?
How about you?
You got the fucking balls?
I got the balls.
Now you got the bread.
It's Gino!
Get in the fucking car!
Back up!
Get the fuck out of the way!
Make a fucking right!
I'm trying to lose him, for chrissakes!
Too much weight in the car!
If you don't lose this cocksucker
I'm going to pop you first.
This guy's good.
You having fun yet, guys?
Lose this fucking guy!
You want to drive this fucking car?!
Shut the fuck up, you hear me?!
Shut the fuck up!
l'll get him.
This is where we lose him.
This is our break coming up!
Hang on!
Holy shit!
Get out of the way!
We haven't lost him yet.
Let's take him for some pork chops.
Back up!
Give me the merch and the bullets.
Do what he fucking says.
Let's get out of here.
All right, here he is.
I want you to hang this motherfucker
on a hook, you hear me?
I got some scores to settle.
You 3 come with me.
Let's go!
Hang him up by a hook!
We'll cut him a new ass!
Come get some!
Bust his head!
Richie's a bad guy. My friends don't
like him and yours don't like him.
You hang around
the wrong people.
This is for you,
motherfucker!
Don't be a bad guy.
What you want to shoot me for?
Don't be a bad guy like that.
Be a nice guy, all right?
Have you seen the news?
This fucking jerk Madano
is on the loose again.
Made him out to be a wiseguy.
And they connected him to us.
That piece of shit couldn't be
a gangster if he owned New York City.
Get him.
We can't stand this publicity.
l'll get him.
You got any puppy dog food?
Right here.
I got anything you want.
I got this stuff here...
Looks like he needs this.
Give him some of this.
None of this is from Jersey, right?
I don't want no radioactive stuff.
I don't blame you.
What are you doing down here?
How you doing?
It's okay.
- I heard you got your license.
- What'd I get, a dog license?
I heard you just got your button.
You're still a dirtbag criminal.
You know how many cops I know that
make my guys look like altar boys?
Ain't it the truth.
Sad world we live in.
It's our world. It's our system.
- What, I got to hear this again?
- Come on, we got to do this.
Ever since we was little...
...I never, ever tried to, like,
you know...
...act 1 ike I was better than you
at anything. And I never was.
You called me "lucky." I wasn't
lucky, man, it was just deep desire.
I was always willing to do whatever
it took to get the job done.
You know, this thing...
You think it's the department. I don't
give a fuck about the department.
This, to me, is personal.
You'll never change, Gino.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Aw, fuck me!
Where is he?
- I don't know.
- You haven't seen or heard from him?
Come on, he's my brother.
l'll see him sooner or later.
He's crazy, sticking that crap
up his nose.
I knew this would happen.
l'll call you, on my mother's eyes.
Find him. Otherwise, next time we
come here, you're coming with us.
I need them.
I need this shit, right?
Nicki, coffee.
He's not here.
Mr. Madano, how's your health?
I said, he's not here.
I believe you.
But if you don't mind,
I'd like to talk to you.
He killed Bobby.
In front of his wife and kids.
What did Bobby do to him?
Bobby didn't do nothing.
What did the police do
to make him crazy?
Two blocks over, he just killed
another woman, random!
Something make him crazy.
Bobby's children watched Richie
kill their father.
Now, you know as well as I do...
...Richie was always into bad things,
even when we were kids.
But never crazy like this.
He's on drugs now.
He's lost his mind.
Now, if you've seen Richie...
...or you know something
I don't, you better tell me.
When I came here...
...I got a job repairing the subway.
Same house, same job, ever since.
I come home for dinner every night.
Almost 50 years.
And you don't believe me?
I believe you.
And even then,
when I was a punk kid...
...I believed you and you believed me.
How can I keep you from killing my son?
You tell Richie to get a lawyer.
Have him turn himself in.
If not...
...l'm going to kill him.
"Just..."
"...in time..."
Open the door.
How you two doing?
Rica, I ain't seen you around
in a while, you know?
What'd you do,
retire or something?
I guess you could say I retired.
Got a job at the video store.
- Just trying to get back to normal.
- Normal?
What do you mean by "normal"?
What'd you do, Rica? What'd you do?
you just say no?
What are you, what's-her-name,
Nancy-fucking-Reabush?
No, Rich,
it's not like that.
You wouldn't "just say no"
to me, would you?
How you doing?
Officer Big Shot,
come to bust my balls?
This here is a detective!
In what, narcotics now?
Now I want you all
to be very nice.
Tell this fucking mamaluke
anything he wants to know.
Vinnie, come over here.
You shouldn't talk to me that way.
We don't know each other so good.
You were still sucking your thumb
when Richie was sucking dicks.
But still, you shouldn't
talk so tough.
If Richie was here
you wouldn't talk that shit.
But he's not here.
You know why he's not here?
Because he's a chickenshit
fucking pussy asshole.
Don't go pushing my patrons around,
you prick.
Prick? Look around.
Is this the setting for profanity?
Fuck you!
Benny the Book.
How are you, buddy?
You wouldn't be here using Ma Bell
for illegal means?
Bookmaking's an illegal activity.
You also wouldn't know Richie owns this
place and sells narcotics here.
Because he's a fucking puke
who likes to pervert kids.
Drugs?
Nobody uses drugs around here.
You don't know nothing, do you?
Anybody seen Richie?
Anyone know why Richie did Bobby Lupo?
I don't know cazzo.
Big man with a badge and gun.
What's the password,
asshole?
What are you doing here?
- Aren't you Vito's friend?
- I got lots of friends.
You jump around a little bit.
Is that it?
Who's this one over here,
your girlfriend?
You know what, Cool Breeze?
Someday your wise mouth is going to get
your body in a lot of trouble.
- Where you from, finocchi?
- Attica.
You couldn't be from Brooklyn,
because we don't talk like that.
Tattoo, this guy's nothing
without that badge and gun.
You can't come back here.
Get the fuck out of here!
What do we got here?
What is this shit?
Whose hot dog is this?
ls that yours?
Without that badge and gun,
you'd be dead.
Get the fuck out of here!
I've noticed a lot of
boxing memorabilia.
We got some gloves over here.
Pictures everywhere. Who's the boxer?
You're the boxer?
You a tough guy?
- Tough enough.
- Really? What could you do?
To you?
I'm starting to get in a bad mood.
Maybe it's a mood swing, my hormones,
or a need to impose my will.
I want you tell these finocchis
to get on the fucking table.
Tell them to get up on
the fucking table.
Are you totally nuts?!
You could've killed somebody upstairs!
- But there's nobody upstairs!
- How would you know?
Did you bust in the joint?
I don't recall.
The only balls he has
is that badge and gun.
Here's my gun!
Fair game now, okay?
And here's my badge!
This is your trophy.
This is your trophy, okay?
Come and get it.
Tell one of your citriolis
to come and get it.
I offer 5000 for that badge,
right now.
Anybody see Richie?
Anybody know why
Richie did Bobby Lupo?
Fuckface, you want to get by me?
There's only two things stopping you:
fear and common sense.
And l'll cut
your fucking head off!
You motherfucker!
You knocked my teeth out!
Hey, Sticks, come on!
Motherfucker!
I'm with Vittorio.
So that means you can't touch me.
That's right. I forgot.
How you doing, buddy?
- I want to talk to your brother.
- He'll want to talk to you.
What are you doing?
You don't want to do that!
Tell him l'll cut off his head
and piss down his throat.
Fuck you!
Anybody seen Richie?
I'm going to keep coming back until
somebody remembers seeing Richie!
So what's the latest?
The cops are all over town,
hitting every business we own.
All my guys
are looking for this bastard.
Vittorio, he's killing people
like it was free.
When I'm through,
I'm going to Cono's for dinner.
You find Gino.
Tell him to...
Ask him to meet me there.
And you find Richie.
I don't care how.
You just find him.
l'll find him.
- Tell Joey about the mouse.
- What mouse?
- Why, is Joey an exterminator now?
- What about the mouse?
I got a mouse in my house. I pay $800
so I can chase a mouse around.
Shoot this rat bastard.
The mouse is about this fucking big.
I'm going to shoot him?
Shoot him through the floor,
you kill a neighbor.
Let's go by Chas the Chair.
I think the mouse
is smarter than you are.
- Shoot this rat.
- Shut up about the fucking mouse!
Thanks for coming.
- Pull up a chair.
- Sit where I can see you.
What are your guys...?
Busting my balls all over town?
Hurting my business.
That ain't right, Gino.
Well, you know, Vittorio,
I was meaning to tell you...
...I really don't like you.
And I never really did.
If you fall off a cliff or get arrested,
rot in jail for life...
...I really don't care, all right?
I'm sorry about what happened to Bobby.
I know how you loved him.
But I know you don't mean
one word you just said.
You're one of us.
Family.
Let me tell you something.
I'm not one of you,
and I'm not with you.
Gino, wait up.
Why you talking to the old man
like that?
Because he's your boss, not mine.
You know what I'm saying?
I want to tell you something.
You remember Uncle Pino, right?
Yeah. The big guy.
One time...
...when I was a kid, Pino was going to
take me to the movies.
First, we go to the candy store.
Mettiamo's, remember it?
Who the hell could forget?
We see this guy filling up his pockets
with this and that.
Pino grabs him by the throat...
...drags him outside,
throws him a beating.
Puts him in the trunk of the car,
drives to the movies.
He went to the movies?
In the movies, I'm not watching.
I'm thinking to myself:
"What about this guy in the trunk?"
I think to myself,
"He killed him. He's dead."
I run to Pino, I says,
"You killed the guy."
Pino's bored, brings me around the front,
gives me the keys, he says:
"Do what you got to do."
I says, "Me? What am I going to do?
I'm nine years old."
He gives me the keys.
I open the trunk.
- I see a man staring at me.
- You must've been scared.
I've got Pino over here.
What am I scared of?
I says to the guy,
"Hey you, get the fuck out of here!"
I blink. He's in Hoboken.
He took off like a shot?
Like a bird.
You scared the shit out of him.
The son of a bitch.
Nine years old, I'm looking at Pino,
I'm thinking to myself:
"My God, what a great guy."
I always wanted to be a wiseguy.
Look at us now, under God.
Who'd have thought that
I would've become a cop?
Hey, Lucky, you know...
...to me God's a puppeteer.
We're on the end of the strings.
But God has a strange sense of humor,
you got to admit.
Maybe you're right.
Richie, judging by
your sudden rise to stardom...
...l'll lay odds this one's
got a make on it by now.
Richie, don't!
Don't! What are you doing?
I'm an overnight success, baby.
I'm going to crib here for
a couple hours. Any problem with that?
How do I know that thing's real?
Don't I look like an honest guy?
How bad do you want to find out?
Tell her I'm here,
then get the fuck out of my sight.
How you doing?
You want to tell me
how you got up here?
- Where's Richie?
- I don't know nothing from nothing.
Is that right?
Here's your drink.
I didn't order no drink.
Cops have been
in and out of here all night.
But it's you I been expecting.
IKind of figured you'd save
the best for yourself.
How you doing?
I can still get it wet.
How about you?
Me?
I can't believe you eat
with that mouth.
I feel bad about Bobby.
You don't know
what reason your brother had?
Even if I knew, which I don't...
And you haven't seen your brother.
Right?
Last time was a couple of days ago.
He's always with a different whore.
Who's his latest special?
Since when do I keep track
of my brother's pumps?
Must be tough.
- Who's this one over here?
- Which one?
The one with nipples
you could dial a phone with.
Terry.
Why?
Let's cut the bullshit.
I got to talk to you.
Would you get
your fucking hands off me?
Don't push me around in my club!
What the fuck you think you're doing?
Didn't I tell you to get
out of here?
Are you getting your rocks off this way?
Is this what they teach you to do
when you're a cop? Shit!
Have you seen your brother anywhere?
No, I haven't.
I've told you a million times.
What the flying fuck
you think you're doing?
Have you seen your brother anywhere?
Are you stupid?
I already told you "no."
Why don't you just destroy
my whole office?
If you're looking for my lipstick,
it's in my bag.
I've had enough of this.
Look what I found.
You got a gun.
- I got a license for that.
- Where is it?
My dog ate it.
Let me tell you, this is a year
in jail. Sullivan Act.
You think a year's a piece of cake?
- Aren't you smart.
- Look, it's getting late.
All night I've been running into people
who are deaf, dumb and blind.
IKnow what I'm going to do?
I'm going to arrest you.
You're going to arrest me?
For what?
How does it work?
I give you a little head
and you forget the whole thing?
It won't make me forget.
You were never that good.
Go fuck yourself, Gino.
You're under arrest.
I'm going to be needing
a new go-cart.
Something with some stomp.
And a scanner.
Where the fuck are your manners?
The man's talking to you.
There's a GNX over on the top floor,
on the parking garage.
Bay 10. Take the scanner,
wire it, bring it back.
We're going to have us a little party.
We'll have a little party,
a little soiree.
Bite off a couple chicks.
We can all get laid, get blowjobs.
Hey, Richie, you know I haven't gotten
no pussy since 1969.
You ain't got any pussy since 1969?
What've you been doing?
Jerkin' the gherkin?
Come on, man. That's cold.
Leave him alone.
What've you been doing?
Bobby Arms. Get me a beer.
You don't have to push me.
Usually when you're arrested
you can use a phone.
Are you kidding?
You have not even told me
what I've been arrested for.
Let me see here. What could we do?
How about 240.25?
Prostitution, honey.
Are you fucking kidding me?!
Let me out of here right now!
I told you I was going to do this.
What?
Are you out of your fucking mind?
I told you I was not kidding.
Now, how's your memory?
Who is Roxanne?
You are really starting
to piss me off.
Did you ever find this one
on the street?
Many times.
- How much was she?
- $ 10.
Ten bucks this, friend.
Fuck you!
I can't believe you're doing this.
I'm kind of disappointed.
I thought you could get at least 15.
Gino, you fuck! Get me out of here!
Come on, Chas. Have another drink.
What's the story with you and that cop?
Who? Gino?
The one you popped.
Was that business?
Or was it personal?
It was personal business.
Holy shit!
Why are you fucking asking me
about my business?
Richie, cops!
Cops!
You rat me out?
Never.
You rat bastard!
I'd never rat you out.
l'll put you out of your misery.
Please, don't!
- Hands up!
- Nobody move!
I don't believe it! Why did
you shoot him? He didn't rat us out.
How you doing?
You only arrest Patricia
because she no help you find Richie.
Just the same, maybe you could come in
and we'll talk a minute.
If you'd sit down
right over here.
This is difficult for me to say.
I'm sorry for the way I behaved
in your home.
I know it was disrespectful.
You always been like a father to me.
If you tell me...
...that you haven't seen Richie,
I believe you. We got problems.
I know that it's...
No man wants to bury his son.
And I know...
...no man wants to admit that his son...
...has become something
the world can do without.
But I'm very afraid...
...every moment, for everyone
around us.
I pray...
...for this to end.
I know what you're trying to say.
I'm going to have to...
...make you stay downtown tonight.
Jerry, that's robbery,
not narcotics.
Talk to Donziger and get back to me.
l'll talk to you.
Does this look familiar?
I can't.
I help you any way, he'll kill me.
Come on.
He's your own brother!
He's a vacuum.
He sucks up 3 to 4 grams a pass.
That much crack doesn't promote
rational thought.
It'll get worse than I been telling you.
I got your father under arrest.
It won't work, Gino!
God!
Why don't you understand this?
We can't help you.
If he even thinks we did,
he'll kill Pop too.
He's that far gone?
Believe it, Gino.
Anybody.
Then I'm going to keep you here
tonight and keep you alive.
Hate me tomorrow.
In the 8-0 precinct.
Signal 1013. Police officer shot.
6835 Amboy Street.
This is one night this town ain't never
going to forget about.
Ask me, I think you already
made sure of that.
Your wife's called couple times.
She's at your apartment with Tony.
Any chance you can swing over there
for a minute?
I could do that.
I'm right in the area.
Come over here. Come here.
I almost forgot about you.
I got to get you
a nice hot bath, some food.
Maybe a girlfriend or something.
How's Tony?
He's fine.
Did you eat?
A couple of dog biscuits.
- This is my new dog.
- Look at you.
- A police dog?
- This is Corragio.
Are you keeping him?
I'm thinking about it.
Maybe.
It depends on how brave he is.
I'd better go and see Tony.
You want to come up
for an espresso?
Yeah. Why not?
You stay there and be a good boy.
- Should we show the dog to Tony?
- He'll never go back to sleep.
Did you ever have a dog
when you were little?
We didn't have enough money
to feed ourselves.
There was this old man who came
to the neighborhood when we were kids.
He was from the old country.
He carried an old school bell.
He pulled along a sharpening machine
operated by a foot peddle.
The neighbors used to get
their knives and scissors sharpened.
A dime here, a quarter there.
But it was an honest living.
Time goes on...
...people start buying...
...disposable scissors and knives.
Fewer and fewer people come out.
I always used to think to myself...
...how it would feel to leave...
...before light...
...and come back after dark...
...with nothing to show your wife
and family for what you've done.
That bell was the loneliest sound
I ever heard.
He was your father, wasn't he?
I remember one time I followed
the old man for a whole summer...
...every day...
...day in, day out.
And after a while,
it started to grind him down.
Nobody, nobody needs him, you know?
If you feel like nobody needs you...
...and you feel useless...
...you die inside.
You let yourself go.
We always used to tell everybody,
"Pop died from cancer."
I believe he died of a broken heart.
After Pop died...
...and the neighborhood kids wanted
to go to Coney lsland to play...
...one of the other fathers,
Mr. Madano...
...used to slip me a little money so
I could go play with the kids too.
You know how I repay Mr. Madano?
You want to know
how I thanked him tonight?
I arrested him.
Just so I could get to Richie.
That's how crazy I get.
Gino, these may be your streets
and your neighborhood...
...but there are
other police officers.
I'm really proud of what you do.
And I know how everybody loves you.
But Tony needs a father...
...and I need a husband.
What are we talking,
reconciliation over here?
No, we're talking a lifetime deal.
All or nothing.
I could do that.
That I could do.
I love you.
- Tony! We need Tony!
- Get down in the bathtub!
In the bathtub.
You're dead.
Come on, you rat bastard!
Drop it!
You going to shoot an unarmed man?
I wouldn't.
You know what I'm going to do?
You motherfucker!
Angie, send me units
over to my apartment.
There's been a shooting
over at my place.
It's a bunch of Richie Madano's crew.
They're all deceased.
Going to take you to a hotel
with your mother.
I know that this is not an easy thing
and I know you're upset.
l'll take care of it right away.
Oh, shit!
Fellas...
...have a drink.
Never mind that bullshit.
Sit down, dickhead.
We're looking for your brother.
Where is he?
He ain't been around.
I ain't seen him.
You understand English?
Teach this guy some English.
You fucking bum.
You want to give me the right answer?
Where's your fucking brother?
You cocksucker!
l'll break your fucking head!
You're both dead, you fucking bums!
The two of you! Tell him that!
Say Rusty told you you're dead!
The two of yous!
You asshole!
Get the fuck out of here!
Get the fuck out of here, man!
I bet you're real popular
in your neighborhood now.
Angie, I was never too popular
with my neighbors.
I'm heading to Lamore's now.
Patti back yet?
Can I talk to you in private
for a minute, please?
Sit over here.
Is this you?
My name's Terry Malloy.
So who's Roxanne?
Richie's girlfriend.
I thought that's who you were looking for.
It is.
Do you know where I can find her?
I think she lives here in Brooklyn,
but I don't know where.
You don't know where. What are you,
a concerned citizen now?
Why not?
Who is Richie to you,
anyway?
A piece of shit.
How come you look like
you been crying?
I got a fucking migraine.
Listen, I want to ask
you something.
Do you know this girl?
Maybe you could sit over here.
You all right?
Come on, Terry.
You have to talk to me.
Who is it?
It's Roxanne.
And you were fucking Bobby
at the same time?
Don't be that way.
Come on. Settle down.
She got a last name?
Ford. Roxanne Ford.
How you doing, Vermeer?
How the hell did you get up here, man?
Jesus Christ!
He didn't have
nothing to do with it.
Where you been? We been waiting
around here all night for you.
What you been waiting on?
Waiting on if you need us.
What do you think?
What happened to your nose?
Gino came around, playing the role.
Busting up the place.
What, you ain't got a piece?
You got a piece behind the bar.
You let him do that to your face?
Why didn't you whack him?
All I heard was you clipped Bobby.
You want me to whack a cop too?
Nobody has to worry
about you stepping on your dick.
You know how wacko he gets!
And with you doing Bobby like that!
You're mistaking me
for someone who gives a shit.
If Gino and me bang heads...
...he'll be racked
in a closed casket.
You won't
let him take you?
What are you, a clown?
Take me? Take me where?
You let one motherfucker take you!
It ain't just Gino! Bulls are banging
down doors all over the neighborhood.
It's Frankie's guys.
They're back!
Them too! Every couple of hours
a different bunch comes slapping me.
Stop whining like a cunt
and get your piece.
I can't.
Don't let me see you again.
Don't ever let me
see you again.
Good evening, fellas.
Nice to see you again.
Never mind the bullshit.
Where the fuck is he?
Over here, Sal.
You lose.
Who's she?
She brought me
to the girlfriend.
She just had to identify the body,
so she's a little upset.
Did you have breakfast this morning?
Good.
Because it ain't pretty.
What is it?
He killed Allie
and 3 of the other guys.
This is no good.
Let's go find Richie.
O'IKelly, get upstairs and make them
photograph that thing right.
This is what I found
in Bobby's desk.
Bobby was doing this one and the one
in the car at the same time.
Now, from the extreme rigor mortis
in the body, it looks like...
...time of death, 24 hours ago.
Before Bobby.
I'm getting too old for this shit.
I know what you mean.
Hey, keep it down.
My sister's sleeping.
Wake her up.
We ain't disturbing yous, are we?
Rica, come here.
We're wanting a little party.
I want a little party.
It's kind of my going- Away party.
Right, Bobby?
Right, Rich.
You ain't got a problem with that,
do you?
No, Rich. No problem.
Angie? Get me Gino.
It's Picolino.
Call up Willy the Pimp. You tell him
to send over his best broads.
Nobody will say you hung out
with me just for the money.
Richie, please, come on.
l'll take care of you, Rich.
Hey, boys!
We're going to have us
a real good time tonight.
Big time, Richie. Big time.
It's my night! My last night!
Who is it?
How you doing, Laura?
Good. Okay.
I couldn't sleep after Vick left.
So I had a bath.
I'm better now.
What are you doing?
What are you looking for?
No. No, Gino, that's my purse.
Give me... Gino, stop!
What's this?
What is this?
Is this what Richie threw on Bobby
after he shot him?
That was fast thinking.
Just like
a good cop's wife would.
You know what I think?
I think you found
one of these somewhere.
And got so fucking mad
you couldn't see straight.
So you sent one to Richie, never
dreaming he might actually kill Bobby.
I only took it because
I wanted to protect him.
See, this is Roxanne, here.
Twenty-four years old.
Richie killed her first.
You got it all wrong, Gino.
I only took it
so people wouldn't know.
Bobby was dirty, wasn't he?
Or maybe...
...he was just doing Richie's
girlfriend at the same time.
I don't think so.
I think that Bobby always wanted
to be like somebody else.
He liked Richie's lifestyle, his money,
his women. You knew he was dirty.
Bobby's gone now.
So are lots of other people.
I didn't want to kill him.
I just wanted to save my marriage.
Come here, Laurie.
I want my Bobby back.
I want him back.
You have an emergency phone call
from Picolino.
Angie, patch me through
right now.
Listen to me, Picolino.
I know that place.
Get out of the neighborhood now.
Hands on the table!
What the fuck's going on?
My buddy Gino's here.
I got to go play.
Fuck you, cop!
He's in the bathroom!
What're you going to do?
What're you going to do,
you going to arrest me?
I'm out of bullets!
That's a shame.
Those bullets
could've saved you a lot of pain.
I like pain, you know.
l'll kill you.
That's for Bobby.
- What happened?
- I'm hit. Took one right here.
What're you doing with my gun?!
What the hell is wrong with you?
Jesus Christ!
- You did the right thing.
- I did the right thing?
I'm sorry it had to be this way.
Tell the boss what you did.
Do the ritual thing.
Are you sick?
Geez, put him in a fucking trunk
in Jersey.
That sounds great, but...
...can we have dinner in the city,
me and you alone sometime?
Sure, I won't even bring
my beeper.
Speaking of food,
I could go for...
...a chili hot dog with
cheese and french fries.
Not for nothing. It's 9 a.m.
Eat here, you'll have gangrene by noon.
Gino, I'm going to buy you a nice
romantic...
Yo, fucknuts!
You talking to me?
Are you the guy who threw a puppy
out this car window the other day?
- What's your business, anyway?
- I'm an animal lover.
Animal lover?
You don't mind your fucking business,
l'll stuff you in a bag...
...and throw you out
a fucking window.
- You're a tough guy?
- L'll show you how tough I am.
My balls!
Oh, Vick, look over here!
ls that a police dog, or what?
Ripping & Subtitles
4EverPsycho
lovespiral@ciudad.com.ar