Come this way!
Men wounded in battle we can deal with.
But this strange disease...
Thirty men dead yesterday.
Eighteen, the day before.
We need supplies.
Plasma.
Penicillin.
We'll get what you need.
You're Americans.
Please...
...get me out of this shithole.
Buddy, that's what we're here for.
We're gonna take you home.
First we'll take a blood sample, all right?
I'm gonna die, right?
- You won't die.
- Tell my girl I love her.
I won't tell her.
You're gonna tell her yourself.
The soldiers inside are in
the early stages of the disease.
By tomorrow night they will look like this.
Mother of God!
I'll authorize an immediate airdrop.
It's worse than I thought.
Get the plane here by 1900.
Get the plane, Billy.
Come on! All right!
Isn't this your last day?
Yeah.
Sam, are you there?
Pick up the phone. We have a situation
in Zaire. It doesn't look good.
Stay there.
Hemorrhagic fever, high mortality.
We picked up a satellite relay from Cairo.
I said stay!
What's up?
Looks like we have a Level 4.
How many dead?
Don't know. There aren't any numbers yet.
- What do you think it is?
- Too early to say.
The WHO is preparing a team,
but I want you there first.
You're off Hanta and flying to Zaire.
Let me get my crew together.
I'll get back to you.
I can't believe this. You're wet.
You guys are wet.
Which one disobeyed me first?
Lewis, it was you, right?
You guys are busted. You look very guilty.
Lewis, come on.
Get down.
How are you?
Hi, boys. How you doing?
What are you doing?
You miss me?
Come here. Who wants some breakfast?
Your paper.
You here for your stuff? Come on.
Bagels. Who wants bagels?
Breakfast?
- Who wants some breakfast?
- I've got to go away.
Where?
Zaire. They think there's cases
of hemorrhagic fever there.
- Is Casey going?
- Yeah.
And Jaffe. The whole crew.
Most of it.
So you want me to take the dogs?
It's just four days.
I'm going to Atlanta Friday.
If you're late, the dogs go too.
Fair enough.
What will you do at CDC?
Working BL4.
Same as you.
My job.
I'd like to think of it as my job.
And I won't have the Pentagon
pressuring me.
This is mine.
Take it.
And the rest of your stuff
is in boxes in there.
I can hang on to it till you come back...
...or whatever.
You know that you're giving me
all the pictures of us.
You can keep them.
You keep them.
I don't want them.
I don't want them either, Robby.
Thursday!
I want a turn-up, on the mark.
Come on, let's move it.
Let's go!
This plasma goes in the right rudder
of the right wing.
- Where is Jaffe?
- His wife is in labor. He's on leave.
- Who'll read the tissue samples?
- You don't trust me?
- Come on!
- Fine.
You want a hotshot scope-jockey,
fine, but, frankly, I'm hurt.
- Who cut his orders?
- The Old Man himself.
He hasn't got up this early in years.
- I'll tell him you said so.
- I'll deny it.
Good to see you.
Thought if I showed my star
it might speed things up for you.
Is it working?
No.
First file on your new man.
Plus telex traffic to date,
and satellite photos from the area.
Sir?
Get in, get out.
I hate having you here,
making my life miserable...
...but don't want to lose you to some bug.
- One question.
- Go on.
What have I ever done
to make your life miserable?
You got up today.
Thank you, Billy.
Major Salt.
May I say it's an honor to work with you.
West Point, Johns Hopkins. How many
hours did you log in helicopter school?
- 85.
- Married?
- Yes, sir.
- Good luck.
You've never been in the field?
No, sir.
But I'm fully trained and highly motivated.
I'm talking about landing in a hot zone.
It's unique.
Have you seen the effects
of hemorrhagic fever?
No, sir.
Allow me.
- Major.
- Yes.
At first the patient has flu-like symptoms.
In 2 or 3 days pink lesions appear
on his body, along with pustules...
...which erupt with the blood and pus.
A milky substance begins to...
These lesions become full-blown.
They feel like mush.
There's vomiting, diarrhea,
bleeding in the nose, ears, gums.
The internal organs shut down.
They liquify.
Very good.
We've read that in a book too, but...
...in 16 hours you'll see it.
In the flesh, so to speak.
I can handle whatever we encounter.
- Lf one panics, we're all in danger.
- He's under orders not to die.
And that's a set of orders
he actually plans to follow.
That must be it.
He's losing it!
No! Just hang on!
I can't breathe!
Keep your helmet...
- Take it off!
- No!
- Keep it on!
Don't let him expose himself!
Goddamn it! Isolate him! Isolate him!
Don't worry.
It's not airborne.
Sam Daniels, USAMRllD.
Benjamin lwabi.
We've been expecting you.
We came as soon as possible.
Not soon enough.
The village is dead.
Do you know the incubation period?
But it kills in 2 or 3 days.
The mortality rate is 100%.
Jesus.
Could an infected person
have gotten out of the village?
If he did,
he'd be dead or dying in the jungle.
It's 50 miles to the next village.
First case? Patient zero?
A young man called Murazo.
Worked with a white man
to build a road into Kinshasa.
- When he returned he was sick.
- I see.
And he drank from this well.
From there, it spreads to the entire village.
Did you identify the carrier? The host?
No, when we arrived, he was incoherent.
He died two hours later.
He couldn't tell us how he got it.
He's not sick.
He's a local ju-ju man. Witch doctor.
He stayed in his cave all week.
I'd like to talk to him.
No, he talks to me.
You see, he believes that the gods
were awoken from their sleep...
...by men cutting down the trees...
...where no man should be.
And the gods got angry.
This...
...is a punishment.
Alarmingly high fatality.
All localized within a 3-mile radius.
Incubation period short.
Appears contained.
You didn't put "alarmingly."
It's an adverb.
It's a lazy tool of a weak mind.
I want to add this:
Billy...
...this is the scariest
son-of-a-bitch I've ever seen.
And I've seen a lot.
Fine. Fax it to Ford's house.
Sorry, sir.
It's okay.
I've never seen anything like it.
I put the team in danger, sir.
We're still here.
I got scared, sir.
You know, fear gets a bad rap.
I don't want anybody working
with me who isn't scared.
Okay?
Then I'm your man, sir.
I sent the fax 6 hours ago.
I am not going to issue an alert.
But you must issue an alert.
- You said it was contained.
- I said containment was probable.
You should be monitoring the airports!
Remember 1989? You found 2 cases
of Congo fever in Nairobi...
...and we put a note in
every American kid's lunch box.
- I was wrong.
- You were wrong.
What about 1992? Lassa fever?
- I was wrong.
- Again.
- But now you're right?
- No, I could be...
Yet you waltz into my party
smelling like dirty socks...
...take me away from Senator Rosales...
...who heads the Senate Arms Services
subcommittee in charge of our budget!
Forget Ebola, forget Lassa.
This bug kills so fast...
Keep your voice down.
Now that is exactly my point.
It is the very lethality of this virus
which works for us here.
They don't live long enough to spread
the thing around. So it is contained.
I hope so.
I'm through talking, okay?
You never understood the concept of time.
What day is it?
- Sunday.
- When did you say you'd be home?
- Friday.
- Thursday, Sam.
I meant Thursday.
Thursday and Friday sound so much alike,
even I confuse them.
Why didn't I go to Atlanta
like I said I would?
You're decent. If you put the bags...
Fuck you.
You said you'd be home Thursday,
so I could fly Friday...
...buy a toaster, treat myself,
and maybe on Sunday have a day of rest.
Now I must go to the airport.
I won't get in until 7.
It'll be too late to buy a toaster.
You know what? I can't unpack, because
I have a welcome cocktail party at 9!
Lewis, move over.
Move!
- Get over!
- You're scaring him!
Lewis.
That's because you let him on the sofa.
Here.
We can go now.
How long are you keeping the dogs?
They're going with me to Atlanta.
They're my dogs too. I miss them.
Do you want them?
Either they go with me or stay with you.
We can't share them.
Decide.
A negotiation.
Okay.
Wait!
You win.
Keep them.
Let's go.
Wait I just wanted to tell you something.
It's important.
Now I forgot.
- I'm gonna miss my flight.
- Wait a minute, I remember.
Remember that they like
those medium-size bones.
I know, the little barbecued ones...
I know.
That's right.
You look tired, Sam.
Was it that bad in Zaire?
Could've been better.
You be careful.
I wish you luck.
You better tell him to go.
We can go now.
That's not what I said. You're not
getting this. Try to be objective.
Let me understand this.
You didn't want the photos...
...but you wanted the dogs?
- That's not it.
You could have taken a photo
of the dogs and solved everything.
I open my heart and you make jokes.
- I'm not.
- We had the dogs as puppies.
- They were cute.
- That's not the point.
- They're still cute.
- They were ours, and now they're not.
The dogs are probably a case
for the Supreme Court.
I'm asking you if I'm right or wrong.
We're about to look at the most deadly
virus we've ever seen. Think about that.
Right or wrong? It's a question.
She's got a new job at CDC.
No, she's got your job at the CDC.
- Good for her.
- Anyway, she's starting a new life.
She's not coming back.
It's over. Move on, because, frankly,
I'm sick of hearing about it.
All right. What do you mean, it's over?
You really need to seek some help.
A divorce signed by both parties is
strong evidence something is off.
Did she say it was off?
Know how I stayed friends with you both?
- How?
- I don't have conversations like this.
I'm not asking you to take sides.
She didn't take the dogs to be mean.
- I'm asking your opinion.
- What is this?
You didn't check your suit. It's torn.
Takes your breath away.
Thank you.
- Good morning, Colonel.
- Good morning.
I took the liberty
of bringing in the samples.
An early riser.
I was up at 4.
Let's work. I want to separate and thaw
them and throw them under the scope.
Done.
- We'll have results in a few hours.
- Good.
Listen to the way it rolls off your tongue.
Motaba.
You know, it sounds like a perfume.
One drop and you'll feel different.
Your lover will melt in your arms.
Here, try it.
Quick hands.
But not as quick as mine.
Don't mess with this stuff.
You must be ready for anything.
Nothing in here can't kill you.
Including the air.
Okay, sirs, here we go.
These are from an 8-hour period. Healthy
kidney cells before meeting the virus.
In one hour, a single virus has invaded,
multiplied and killed the cell.
In just over 2 hours...
...its offspring invaded
the nearby cells here, and here.
Continually multiplying.
Jesus Christ, five hours?
It kills this fast?
These numbers can't be right.
Ebola takes days to do this.
Sirs, the numbers are correct.
I wish to God they weren't.
One goes in, millions come out.
And every cell is dead.
Now we see them individually...
...searching for their next victim...
...until nothing's left to kill.
Mark this day, Salt.
We could spend our careers
waiting to see a new virus.
Sirs...
Mr. Motaba...
...up close and personal.
I hate this bug.
Come on, Casey.
You have to love its simplicity.
It's 1 billionth our size and it's beating us.
- What, do you want to take it to dinner?
- No.
What then?
Kill it.
Daniels won't like us going
behind his back like this.
Then we'll kill him.
Lighten up. We have no alternative.
You're so goddamned sentimental.
That's the trouble with this country.
The micrographs are ready.
They're ready.
Oh, my God! It's our African friend.
It's back.
We have to be very careful now.
We wiped out a whole camp
to keep this bug secret.
Lock it up. Shelve it.
You know about this,
I know about this, nobody else.
Get your friend Daniels off the case.
I don't want that nosy little bastard
messing up 30 years of our work.
Is he in?
Just a minute, please.
Come in.
Would you please get us some coffee?
Would you like anything?
Why am I off Motaba?
Nothing for the colonel.
Sit down.
Didn't you say Motaba was contained?
It'll pop up again.
We don't have a blood test.
We don't know how it's transmitted.
There's a fresh outbreak of Hanta fever
in New Mexico.
CDC needs help. We're sending you.
Send Peterson's team.
Don't tell me who to send, colonel!
I told Senator Rosales I'd send
my best man. That's you.
Now get out.
We've got baseline information on it.
What am I going to do there? Trap rats?
We have the bug growing.
We isolated most of the proteins.
We'll have an antibody test soon. Casey
put the bug into rodents and rhesus...
...and we'll know its
genetic sequence in a month.
If you leave us alone,
we'll map this guy down to its last gene.
The odds of Motaba causing any more
problems are a million to one.
- I don't know that.
- You should.
You would if you didn't harbor
this desire to face the end of the world.
It's the biggest thing we've ever seen.
Jesus, you're killing me.
- Fresh, brand-new virus.
- You're still killing me.
It's bumpy, baby.
It's okay, baby.
You'll be out of here in no time. I promise.
- When did you get it?
- Today.
- We still on?
- He wants it.
Oh, I see.
- So your ship came in again, Jimbo?
- Our ship.
Africa,
land of great beauty and untold riches.
- Absolutely untold.
- Keep it that way.
Take care.
- Tell them to send an alert.
- No, I won't.
Why are you fighting me on this?
I won't base my first
official decision on a hunch.
It's not a hunch.
I've got a lab full of dead animals here!
There's no response to
intravenous acyclovir. They're all dead.
Of course! You stuck them with
the same needle. Where's the evidence?
I don't need any, I've got a feeling.
Your feeling is in my notes.
This is very simple.
It kills everything in its path.
Tell them to put out an alert.
This sounds familiar. Is that an order?
You're turning a deadly virus
into a family matter.
This is not personal.
I can't do this back and forth.
Once in your life, take a chance!
You know what? I did. I married you.
You hung up.
First it was the dogs, now we're fighting
over a virus. I can't believe it.
What is the matter?
Music is supposed to
soothe the savage beast.
What?
Oh, Christ, you little shit.
- Welcome back.
- Look, look.
Let's have a look.
You got the papers?
Papers. That's a good one.
Look at her. You asked for a monkey,
I got you one.
- What do you mean, look at her?
- What do I mean?
I told you a male.
No, you said, "she."
Client has a female.
He wants to breed them.
Goddamn! Jesus!
It's okay. It's okay.
All right, all right. I'll sell her cheap.
- Come on, help me out.
- We had a deal. You screwed up.
I can't even sell that one. Look.
It serves you right.
What am I going to do with her?
The warning will be in our report.
Colonel Daniels believes it is serious
enough to send out a special alert.
Do you know how much it costs to send
out an alert to 400,000 health workers?
In '89, he predicted Hanta and it hit.
I suppose I understand your allegiance
to your ex-husband...
...but we both know...
...the chances of this virus showing up
in the US are virtually nil.
Go on, girl.
Yeah, it's freedom.
Look at the trees.
It's like home.
There you go.
That's it.
Don't give me that look.
No, go on.
I'd keep you, but I'm already hitched.
Come on. Go on.
That's it.
This is Captain Carter again.
At this time you must
return to your seats...
...as we're approaching Logan Airport.
Hey, buckaroo.
So cute.
Hey, mister.
Are you going to finish that cookie?
No.
You can have it, Sheriff.
No, no, Bobby, don't bother the nice man.
It's no problem.
I don't want no trouble with the law.
Jimbo!
I missed you so much.
You look like shit. What's wrong?
I don't know.
Something I ate, or something.
What is it?
Sweetie, talk to me, what is it?
Help!
Morning, Rudy.
Lucrecia won't eat beef wafers
so we'll go back to veal.
What's wrong?
Rudy, can you hear me? Squeeze
my hand! It looks like toxic shock.
- Fred said he was fine yesterday.
- Come on!
I read about some bad strep cases
in Newsweek.
Maybe I should subscribe. Henry,
get me a blood culture and a blood count.
Goddamn it, come on, Rudy!
A final score of six to three.
Shit.
Fuck!
What about AIDS or hepatitis?
We'll test the blood. Don't worry.
Should you give me gamma globulin?
I don't want to give anything to my girl.
Flowers would be nice on occasion.
- You should eat.
- You shouldn't eat that crap.
You know you want one.
You got something.
E. Coli outbreak in Michigan
in a steak house franchise.
Fevers of unknown origin in Boston.
Their docs can't figure them out.
Wouldn't be African explorers
back from Zaire, would they?
Yeah, right. No, just a couple kids.
No unusual travel.
Some atypical strain of Lyme and
those Boston doctors missed the boat.
Lisa.
Get me on a plane to Boston.
Right in here.
Right over here.
James.
Jimbo, can you hear me?
We're here to help but we need
to know how you got sick.
Can you talk?
Hello?
Were you in contact with any animals?
- Should we call a code?
- Turn it off.
- What is this?
- I'm here to find out.
- We'll need a post.
- No, I'm not gonna get what he's got.
- I don't do autopsies.
- And you?
- I'll do it.
- Oh, God, he's dead, isn't he?
- Oh, God!
- Honey.
- Don't let him die!
- We're doing all we can.
I need you to help me.
- Jimbo, say something!
- Look at me.
Alice, did Jimbo tell you anything?
Did he talk to you?
Very slow.
Maximum sharps precautions.
Slow.
Give me the scalpel. You assist me.
He worked at an animal quarantine facility
in San Jose.
We're monitoring his co-workers.
The host could be there.
Don't let anyone out of that place.
We're isolating everyone. I quarantined
the Boston med staff, girl's neighbors.
Christ, Sam, I opened this guy up.
It looked like a bomb went off inside.
His pancreas, liver...
...all the organs were liquified.
I should have forced the alert.
You tried.
Get tissue samples to both our labs.
I'll confirm it's Motaba.
- Is anyone else showing symptoms?
- No, not yet.
CDC has a Stage 3 alert out.
If there are any new cases...
...God...
...we'll find out.
What about the girl?
She died when I was in post.
She wasn't on the plane.
So the first time she had contact
with him was at the airport.
Plane got in at 9:00. She was
admitted at 6:00 the next morning.
We're talking a 24-hour incubation period.
- This thing moves so fast.
- That's good for us. We can see it.
Nobody gets sick soon, we're safe.
This doesn't sound like you.
- What?
- Imagining the best case scenario.
Why not? I still think there's hope for us.
Are you all right?
I'm gonna get something to drink.
What's your problem?
Water.
You must wait your turn.
I need water.
We caught it early, and you'll make it.
But I need you to fight.
Dr. Mascelli. Dr. Mascelli to ER, stat.
Look who's here.
You got to fight, okay, Henry?
Got to fight.
She got sick really fast.
I thought it was the flu.
She fainted. She's burning up.
They keep coming in.
What's wrong with these people?
I don't know, Emma!
Get me the county health department,
now!
The passengers checked out clean.
No further infection at Boston Municipal.
We're in the clear!
Robby, Dr. Reynolds.
15 cases.
There's another outbreak?
- Besides the one in Boston?
- Why're you reluctant?
CDC and USAMRllD are the only agencies
able to deal with a virus like this.
That's why I want to leave tonight.
Sorry, can't do that.
Why in God's name would you
keep me out of there?
It's a civilian matter. CDC is on it.
Let them do their job.
We don't have a charter.
Fuck the charter. People are dying.
It's about you being a doctor!
It's about that sacred oath we took!
We're friends.
Yes, we're friends, but I'm also your boss!
I run this outfit!
You do what the hell I say!
I'm your boss. I have my boss. Clear?
Get your boss on the phone.
Tell him to put me on a plane before
you two kill a lot of people.
I suggest you shut up now.
Don't forget who you're talking to.
I don't know who I'm talking to anymore.
Am I talking to USAMRllD,
the Pentagon, the CIA, McClintock?
- Tell me who I'm talking to.
- This conversation is over.
You're going to New Mexico.
I suggest you get packed or whatever you
have to do, and I suggest you do it now!
Who screwed up? Why wasn't
my pilot given the new orders?
Ford called me 0200, told me to get
my ass to Cedar Creek, California.
You're going to Albuquerque.
I'm not going to Albuquerque!
I'm going to Cedar Creek!
Get Ford on the phone
and get him to confirm.
No, give me that phone.
- No, I better confirm.
- You know what time it is?
2:30.
That's right. You redirect on my orders.
Call and change my flight.
Put your finger on the phone!
My stripes.
It'll be your ass if you don't call.
Finger the phone. Finger it.
Thank you.
Proceed to Cedar Creek with
the 1st Battalion of the 6th Infantry.
We need transmission rates of possible
carriers: insect, marine, animal, human.
If it's spreading, we need to know
where it's going and how fast.
And Billy...
...we're in a hold mode for Clean Sweep.
You and I both know we can
throw these people a lifeline.
We must proceed with
conventional containment.
And you must maintain an
absolute media blackout.
Control your subordinates.
Is Daniels in line?
Yes, sir.
I'll believe that when I see it.
Anything else?
No, sir.
Good luck, Billy.
Bring in the supplies.
- What's holding them up?
- There they are now.
Ray Fowler, Chief of Police. Mayor Gaddis.
I'm Dr. Keough from CDC.
This is Dr. Aronson and Dr. Ruiz.
Cedar Creek is a small town.
We're like a family. Everybody's scared.
I know and we're here to help you in
any way we can. I'll be in charge.
I thought he was in charge.
Hi, Robby.
We just set up the BL4 mobile unit.
Why're you here?
I thought Ford sent you to New Mexico.
He did.
We're keeping the patients
isolated in here.
There's so many.
So many, so fast.
Apparently they all got it
at a movie theater.
Dr. Daniels?
There's something you should see.
This way.
The patient was admitted a week ago
after a car accident.
He's had no contact
with anyone in isolation.
It's airborne.
- I'm Lt. Colonel Briggs. Welcome.
- Thank you. The Sit. Rep.?
Since 0620 today we've established
an outer and inner perimeter.
No one has violated our cordon.
Before that, I can't give any guarantees.
There are 2618 people in this town.
I want them all accounted for by 0900.
Guarantee me that.
We're on it, sir.
Quarters in here, sir.
By the way,
Colonel Daniels is in town against orders.
Locate him.
Arrest him.
Clear this area, now!
We have rights!
What're you doing?
You can't do this to us!
This is a different strain.
This one is the one we got
from Jimbo Scott, the one from Zaire.
This new one is from Cedar Creek.
They look the same. But...
...closer...
...and closer.
See the differences?
The spikes here and here.
The protein code changed,
allowing it to survive longer in the air.
So it spreads like the flu.
Casey, chain of death?
Assuming the new strain originated with
Seward. He infects the whole theater.
Go back further.
He's a medical worker. He was sprayed
with a blood sample taken from Alvarez.
Alvarez tells us what?
Zip. He was dead before we got here.
But Alvarez died of the original strain.
Seward died of the new strain.
The virus didn't suddenly mutate, so...
...I think...
...that the host animal
is carrying both strains.
Good.
Alvarez, Jimbo, what's the connection?
- I can't find one.
- Wait a minute.
- Alvarez worked at a pet store.
- I'm just learning this now?
We just got it.
If the host is there it may carry
antibodies to both strains.
I'm at the pet store.
Salt, get on the new strain from scratch.
Casey, blood test.
General, you got a minute?
There you are. Colonel Briggs,
take this man into custody.
We're in deep shit.
The virus has aerosolized.
What do you mean?
It's gone airborne.
- Would you excuse us?
- Certainly, sir.
You said Motaba is only spread
through direct human contact.
I know what I said,
but now we're facing a new strain.
- What?
- It spreads like the flu.
- Impossible!
- Fine.
Go to the hospital and see.
Go without a mask, you'll see clearly.
You got 19 dead, hundreds more infected
and it's spreading quickly.
Isolate the sick,
and I mean really isolate them.
Keep everyone else in their homes.
We are!
No, we're not doing it!
I just drove through 100 people!
If one of them has it, then 10 of them
have it! If one gets out of town...
...we're in deep shit!
And we're already in deep shit!
Go ahead and arrest me!
All right, Sam!
Don't threaten me.
Or my crew.
Please.
Leave us to do our work.
All right, Sam.
- You were never here.
- No, I was here.
I followed the bug here.
I've always been here.
You remember that.
The US Army and the CDC report...
...that the virus which struck
this California town...
...is being contained
as they search for answers.
A quarantine has been established
to protect neighboring townships...
...and extends to the Pacific ocean,
just a scant mile away.
You are entering a restricted area.
Turn your aircraft around.
This is a no-fly zone.
Careful of the glass.
Return to your homes!
Do not congregate in the street!
Robby.
Could this be the host?
This monkey's sick. It can't be our host.
We need to run an ELISA.
Let's get back to the lab.
No one is permitted to leave the town.
Anybody attempting to do so
will be placed under arrest.
I repeat, we are turning you around.
What the hell is Bobby doing?
Tommy, follow us.
We gotta get out of here. Kids, get down.
Remain calm. We are turning you around.
Get to the trees!
Halt your vehicles...
...then dismount.
They're bluffing. Keep going.
You have entered a restricted area.
We will fire.
This is your last warning.
They're shooting!
Damn it, people, there's no place to go.
Go! We're almost there!
What are they trying to do?
Get out of the vehicle!
Let's see your hands!
- All right, lady, get out!
- Move!
- How are we doing?
- Just a moment.
Tell me as soon as you got something.
Anything?
This monkey's been infected
with the original strain.
No antibodies, nothing.
That means the monkey
caught it before the mutation.
Maybe he came from Africa
with the real host, or caught it at Biotest.
Not Biotest. CDC turned that place
inside out. Motaba negative.
- Test it again.
- They know what they're doing.
Get your people over there,
tell them to test it again.
And after they've tested it,
Welcome home.
Military have escalated the quarantine
at Cedar Creek, doubling their presence.
Authorities remain silent about
the details of the situation...
...continuing the media blackout.
We can only guess at the seriousness
of the spread of the disease.
Our sources number the dead as low as 10,
as high as 50.
It's like a war zone out here,
and we can only imagine...
...the fear of the citizens
of this once very quiet rural town.
Their voices too are silent.
All phone communications are cut off.
Those we can hear...
...those with information, will not speak.
It is, in a word, frightening.
A military curfew is now in effect.
Return to your homes immediately.
Anyone found on the streets
after 1900 hours, or 7 p. M...
...will be arrested and confined.
Return to your homes.
You'll be safe there.
Return to your homes immediately.
The area's been secured.
All civilians are in their homes.
Only minimal protective gear is required
for military personnel.
- Got it?
- I got it.
She was one of the first infected.
What's E-1101?
It's an experimental antiserum
from Yale virology.
It might be worth a try.
I read the journals. I haven't read a word
about E-1101. Where'd you get it?
You know I can call Yale in a second.
I want to save these people, too.
I'm using everything in the arsenal.
We have to work together, Sam.
Are we?
Are we what?
Are we working together, sir?
Oh, shit.
Don't waste your time making phone calls.
Excuse me.
Come here.
Give this to the rhesus and also put it
with some virus and pull it apart.
What is it?
- What's it look like?
- It's not orange juice.
No, it's not.
Colonel?
What is it?
I don't know.
Maybe he'll tell us.
If you're feeling sick at all...
...hang a pillowcase or any piece
of white cloth on your front door.
Soldiers will take you in for a test
and you'll know the results in hours.
Early stages resemble the flu.
Coughing and high fever.
Anyone showing these signs
should report them immediately.
Doctors have the situation in hand...
...and are working to find a cure.
I'll only be gone a few hours.
Well, I may have to spend the night.
You girls be good.
Make sure you brush your teeth
before you go to bed.
- Don't touch your mommy.
- Oh, baby, I can't.
I love you.
Bye.
Positive.
Positive, damn it.
The whole damn town is infected.
This way. One straight line.
Down the hall.
Out into the field.
This way, folks. One straight line.
No animals have been removed
from here in 14 days.
I double-checked the storage lists,
the manifests, the vet profiles. Nothing.
Talk to every single employee.
Somebody's got to know something.
The source of this whole mess is there.
The host is there, Casey.
He didn't talk to everyone.
This coffee sucks.
- Why don't you get some sleep.
- Why don't you?
- I slept in July.
- I got work to do.
Don't tell me when to sleep.
I don't tell you when to sleep.
What happened?
Nothing.
I just got a sudden case of the willies.
I can finish up.
No, no, no, I'm fine.
I hate them willies, you know?
They should call them "the Sams",
don't you think?
You're tired?
Yeah.
The best projection USAMRIID is willing
to make for the spread of the virus is this:
...24 hours...
...36 hours...
...48 hours.
The curtailment must be
viewed objectively.
Be compassionate,
but be compassionate globally.
Thank you.
All right, all right. Please.
The President's ETA from the East Asia
Economic Summit is in 20 hours.
By then, he wants a recommendation
from this group.
As I understand it, you want to firebomb
the town of Cedar Creek, California...
...population 2,600, with a fuel-air bomb...
...the most powerful non-nuclear weapon
in our arsenal.
The way it works, it explodes,
sucks in all available oxygen to the core...
...vaporizes everything within a mile:
men, women, children and one virus.
Destruction complete, case closed,
crisis is over.
This Constitution of the United States,
I've read it cover to cover.
I don't find anything in it
about vaporizing 2,600 Americans.
But it does say, several times...
...that "no person shall be deprived of life,
liberty or property...
"...without due process."
So, couple things before Clean Sweep
is even considered:
One...
...unanimous, unwavering support
for the president on this one.
You must support the president publicly.
He goes down, you go down!
Secondly...
...I want an army of experts citing
thousands of lab experiments...
...telling any idiot with a camera
that there was no other way!
You got that?
No member of this government will go
sneaking off to the Washington Post...
...telling them they were
the sole voice of opposition.
If there's a voice of opposition out there,
I want him in here.
Those are the citizens of Cedar Creek!
Go on! Look at them!
These are not statistics.
They're flesh and blood!
And I want you to burn those
into your memories.
Because those images should haunt us
till the day we die.
1918. Remember your history, Donny?
The great influenza pandemic.
Circled the globe in nine months.
Killed 25 million people.
My father lost three brothers in that. So?
What if there were men who could
have stopped it, but didn't?
How would history judge such men?
Oh, baloney.
FDR stopped Stilwell going into Indochina.
He caused the Vietnam War.
What does history say?
Truman dropped the bomb on
the Japanese. Saved American lives.
Now revisionist historians say he dropped
the bomb to scare the Russians.
Those men were at war, Donny. We're not.
We are at war. Everybody is at war.
I have a presidential green light on
Clean Sweep, and I am going forward.
These people are Americans.
2,600 dead or dying Americans.
If that bug gets out of there, 260 million
Americans will be dead or dying.
Those people are casualties of war.
I'd give them all a medal if I could...
...but they are casualties of war.
That's all.
Come on.
- Neal, is it?
- Yes, sir.
I have to ask you a few questions.
Have a seat.
Jimbo, Jimbo, how did he get it?
Maybe we're on the wrong track.
Maybe Alice gave it to him.
His tissue samples had twice
the viral amplification of hers.
- So we're stuck.
- We're doing the best we can.
We're not.
Let's wait for the comprehensive results
to come in.
Can I ask you a personal question?
Where are the dogs?
God...
Please don't say they're in a kennel.
Think I tied them to a tree
and left a bag of dog chow nearby?
- That's what you did when you left me.
- Let's start over.
It's Alvarez, Jimbo, Biotest.
Jesus.
Look.
Guys, guys, the monkey. Turn around.
My sweet Jesus.
He should be dead by now.
The orange juice worked.
Not on humans.
Not on Cedar Creek Motaba. This monkey
was infected with the original strain.
Right. You know what that means?
This is no experimental antiserum.
E-1101 was designed to kill
African Motaba.
And they had it all the time.
Come on!
How's his breathing?
He's going to arrest!
We need blood, fluid, oxygen, ice, now!
Let's go. Put it in his armpits.
Let me in.
- Under his armpits.
- Pressure.
I need his arm.
Temperature.
I need pressure.
What is his temperature?
106!
We need suction! We need more ice, now!
Casey. Let me in there.
You slept long enough.
Open your eyes! Open!
Open! Open! Open! Look at me. Look.
Casey, right here. Here I am, here I am.
See me? There you are.
There you are. How you doing?
I had a wonderful dream, Auntie Em...
You were there. You were there.
Stay with me.
You were there too. You had a 106 fever.
We're going to take you down.
Stay with me. Don't fuck around.
How many brain cells did I kill?
How many? About a billion.
Now I'm only as smart as you.
What can we give him
to kill his sense of humor?
We must get a line!
Hold him.
- Hold his hand!
- I got it.
Talk to me!
It didn't get past the outer glove.
Give him a line.
What?
Come here.
I was with him.
I should've known something was wrong.
- Did it pierce it?
- It did.
Let me see.
- Let me get some iodine on it.
- I did that already.
I did that, Sam!
Oh, God,
I know how to work with needles.
Why didn't I wait?
- Okay, listen to me.
- Not now, okay? Not now.
- Listen to me!
- There's nothing to say.
There is.
Watch it.
You knew about Motaba all along.
E-1101 was the antiserum.
You could've stopped this outbreak
before it mutated. But you didn't.
We couldn't.
We?
We.
That's all you need to know.
You must tell me what the host is.
We never found it.
We had to synthesize the antiserum.
To protect the troops. But now
the virus comes here and 2 kids die.
We could've stopped it then...
...but we don't because we must
protect the perfect biological weapon.
But then the virus mutates and we can't
stop it now and we could've then.
The decision was made in the interest
of national security.
At the time, we felt we could afford
a certain number of losses.
Robby's infected.
Sorry.
Is "we" sorry too?
"We" is responsible for a town dying.
"We" is a party to Casey dying.
My wife is dying.
Isn't she your ex-wife?
What's your point?
My point is your penchant
for distorting the facts.
You and Robby are, in fact, divorced.
Who is "we"?
"We" includes you, Sam.
Unless you resigned from the Army lately.
You don't just do research
and it ends there.
We must defend ourselves against other
maniacs developing biological weapons.
That's how the game is played.
It was a terrible mistake to withhold
E-1101, but we're beyond that now.
We've done all we can as doctors.
We must go on...
...as soldiers.
You're gonna wipe out the town.
You'll eradicate that mutation
and then your weapon's intact.
That's why the troops
are moving out, right?
It's already ordered.
When is it?
2000 hours.
By order of the president.
The president?
He was advised
by an expert panel of virologists.
I wasn't there.
It's not about a weapon.
When the president saw that in 48 hours...
...the virus could be on
the White House lawn, he gave the order.
I wasn't invited.
If you had been...
...what would you have advised?
Ruiz called. He scared a security guard
into telling him Jimbo...
...smuggled an animal out.
- What kind?
- He couldn't say.
It was small enough to fit
in the back seat of a car.
We know it came in on a ship
from Africa around September 1st.
That's something at least.
We must find that ship.
You better pack. We got work to do.
Colonel Briggs.
Daniels was here? In here?
- Yes, he was.
- Why wasn't I informed?
You were asleep.
I am never that asleep.
Now you find him and you arrest him.
We are so close now. We have a chance.
I know.
- Do you believe that?
- I believe you.
You must go.
Listen...
I don't know how to say this...
...but if I'm not back by 1800...
...and you're not symptomatic...
...leave.
- What do you mean?
- Leave town.
Have you seen the troops moving out?
They can't do that.
They're doing it.
Sir, I think we should go very soon.
Like, right now.
Let's go!
Where's Colonel Daniels?
I think he's upstairs!
Upstairs! Let's go!
- How many hours in flight school?
- 60 hours plus.
- Actual flying time?
- I was yanking and banking.
Anybody seen Daniels?
We're looking for Daniels.
Have you seen him?
Tall, big guy?
Sure.
There.
Let's see some activity on these birds!
We got four flights today!
I want a fuel 93 and a turn 91!
Yes, sir.
Where's your pilot?
General Ford just called.
We've got helicopter priority. Where is he?
My pilot, sir, he's...
Your pilot's what?
My pilot's taking a leak.
Taking a leak? No shit.
In that case we'll just wait in the Loach.
- Tell him to squeeze it off.
- Give him a hand.
Mr. Robertson!
Get out here on the double!
Anybody seen Daniels?
They're down below! Let's go!
Stop that chopper! That's an order!
Hold your fire!
Watch it!
Hit the decks, troops! We're airborne.
Com Center, Flightline.
Shit.
Get us to San Francisco.
They'll follow, so go along the coast.
Fog might give us cover.
You've flown through fog, right?
I read about it.
Daniels just commandeered
one of our choppers.
Dare I ask how?
Don't waste time thinking.
Find him. If he resists, shoot him.
- I understand.
- Wait.
- You don't have to do this.
- He's a carrier of the disease. Do it.
I'm doing it.
Go after him like this,
the press will swarm all over it.
You're creating a panic.
You always have the wrong priority.
He's not infected. You know it.
He's been in direct contact with Motaba
patients. Know something beyond that?
You should've arrested him earlier.
Launch AWACS!
- You sure?
- Yes, sir.
I got it. Back up, coming through.
Make a hole, people.
Back up.
Colonel Daniels from USAMRllD.
George from Sioux City, South Dakota.
Back of the line.
We got a terrible epidemic.
We're from Cedar Creek!
- Site of the viral infection!
- You heard about the virus?
Need we say more?
We need the bills of lading...
...from ships arriving from Africa
in the last 3 months.
Shall I cough on you?
- Mrs. Pananides.
- Now you're talking.
I think these men need some help.
Biotest and paperwork have to be very
careful. Live cargo, federal regulations.
Here.
Compare our list with your Biotest list.
- You ready? Number one, Petra.
- Same.
- Venus.
- Patricia.
- Same.
Tae Kuk.
- Tae Kuk.
- No, sir.
- No?
- Carried a monkey, delivered to Biotest.
- No, negative, sir.
It's not on the list?
That's our vessel! That's the boat!
- The Tae Kuk has set out to sea.
- So what?
How'll we locate it?
My friend's in the Coast Guard.
I can make a call, easy.
How close?
Closer than his wife would like.
Get me on that ship. It can't be far.
It just left this morning.
You want me to fly you out to sea...
...drop you on a freighter at sea?
With all due respect, that's idiotic.
- Idiotic? We're fugitives from the law.
- Right.
Idiocy is our only option. Find the boat.
So what is this?
She's a monkey. Her name's Betsy.
- A monkey? I could tell.
- I'm feeding her, see?
- She lives in the woods.
- Do a lot of monkeys live in the woods?
No, just Betsy. She comes to visit me.
Does Betsy like apples
like my little monkey loves apples?
She does.
Tae Kuk, Tae Kuk, this is Army Helo 1350.
Say your position, over.
Try another frequency.
It won't work.
They'll be monitoring marine channels.
- We'll rely on the position report.
- Just don't be negative.
Affirmative.
You sure you got the coordinates right?
How much fuel have we got?
Don't worry. This bird will go
400 miles without refueling.
Wait.
There.
Tae Kuk...
...Seattle.
- That's it. Thank you, Mrs...
- What's her name?
- Pananides.
I can't land on that ship.
Get me on it.
- I'll get you close enough.
- Close enough for what?
Close enough to jump, sir.
You're not serious.
All right, you fly, I'll jump.
No, just get closer.
Just get...
...very close.
That lifeboat is your best shot.
How do I get back up here?
Get them to clear me an area.
Or I can throw you a rope.
Just kidding, sir. Trying to keep you loose.
Closer!
Get me closer!
Does anyone here speak English? English?
- Little.
- I need information...
...about an animal that was on this ship.
You don't understand.
This is a medical emergency.
I'm an American Army doctor!
Doctor!
Come. Look.
Is anyone else sick?
No. No, sick.
Take me to this man's sleeping quarters.
Upstairs.
Where's his locker?
There's our host.
How are you?
I'm good. I'm good.
You should be nice to Sam.
You know he's got a big crush on you.
I'm so scared.
Would you please hold my hand?
I'm right here, Casey.
The president's scientific advisors
assured me that there is no threat...
...of the further spread of this disease
at the present time.
The two men who escaped
from the quarantine this morning...
...are believed to be
infected with the disease.
Everybody relax!
This is a military emergency! Back up!
It's all right.
Back up. Everybody back up.
This is a military emergency.
Stay calm. Stay calm.
Everybody stay calm.
That's them.
That's the guys.
Get a camera on them.
- Which camera do I talk into?
- Right there.
My name is Colonel Daniels.
I'm here with Major Salt.
We're not infected with the Motaba virus,
but many are.
We've identified the animal...
...carrying the virus
and need help finding it.
The animal who is carrying
the Motaba virus is a monkey.
This is a photo of the animal.
Can you get in close?
Can you get a shot of it?
Get in as close as you can.
It's a small monkey,
about the size of a cat. It has a white face.
Dark fur runs down its back.
Don't attempt to capture it yourself.
Don't go near it. What you can do is
if you see this monkey...
...call this number at
the Center for Disease Control in Atlanta.
The area code is 404...
...and it's 555-9653.
Again, if you see this monkey...
...don't go near it.
Hold your fire!
Right. Palisades.
Dr. Reynolds, I just want to make sure
I wrote it down correctly.
That's 211 Sycamore Road, Palisades?
And the woman's name is Jeffries?
Thank you.
Thank God she called the CDC.
What have we got?
Jimbo takes the monkey to Cedar Creek,
tries to sell it but can't.
He drives to San Francisco,
gets on an airplane for Boston...
...without the animal.
- Must have released it.
Between Cedar Creek
and San Francisco is what?
- Palisades.
- That's it.
- We're there.
- There it is.
That's it. We're there, colonel.
We are there.
We intercepted a phone transmission.
They're headed there.
A potential screw-up you avoided
among many others you have not.
Who should handle this?
You?
You kiss ass with the best of them.
- You hope to make General?
- Yes, sir.
You won't.
Now get me on one of those choppers.
She won't come.
She won't come, except to me.
I'm her only friend.
I trust you are the best helicopter pilot
in this man's army.
That's a relief.
Viper 2, lead, left echelon.
Viper 2, line the skids, I'm at your six.
We're looking for a Loach 1350.
Make this easy for me, all right?
Have you ever been sick?
- Yes.
- It's not much fun, is it?
A whole lot of people are sick right now.
A whole town.
And you know how much
you love your mommy?
That's how much I love my wife.
And my wife is one of the people
who's very sick.
I want her to get better.
Is it, Betsy?
Betsy can help make everybody better
because she has medicine inside her.
That's what makes her very special.
Do you understand?
You won't hurt her?
No.
She'll just go to sleep.
That doesn't hurt, does it?
No. Promise you won't hurt her.
I promise.
If I hurt her, you can punch me in the nose.
A serious punch.
For a very serious nose.
All stations this net, this is Viper 6.
The Commander in Chief has issued
final authorization.
We are to proceed.
Some of us have doubts about what
we are about to do. It's human.
But the fate of the nation...
...perhaps the world, is in our hands.
We are the last line of defense...
...and we cannot...
we dare not refuse this burden.
I'm confident that each of us...
...each of you...
...will do his duty.
Viper 6 out.
Viper Command, Sandman is rolling. Over.
God forgive us.
Betsy.
Here, girl.
Oh, God, be careful.
He won't hurt her.
I can't stand this.
It won't be long.
There you are!
Careful. Careful.
Come on, Katie, move. Come on.
Oh, baby. Move!
Damn it.
We're approaching the destination.
This man's a carrier of the disease...
...and we're going to take him
into quarantine at Travis.
Big Eye, Viper flight is airborne,
do you see us?
Big Eye paints your flight at two.
Standing by, over.
Don't give me any shit. Listen carefully.
Put Ford on the phone,
tell him it's Colonel Daniels.
Where are you?
We're on our way back. We got the host.
What?!
We found the host, Billy.
Thank God.
You must call off the bombing.
I'll buy some time, that's all I can do.
You get back here, quickly, safely.
You may run into resistance.
Resistance?
That makes it tough to get back safely,
doesn't it?
Good luck.
Let's go.
- Problems, colonel?
- Of course!
Sandman flight, this is Viper 6.
Stand down, stand down. Return to base.
Viper 6, Sandman. Roger. Return to base.
Take a look.
- Is that resistance?
- That's resistance. Hold on.
- There's our Loach, sir.
- Where?
Army 1350, this is Viper lead at your 6:00.
Acknowledge. Over.
Viper, I hear you.
Army 1350 stand by...
...to turn into formation
to accompany us to Travis.
On whose authority?
- Mine.
- Who are you?
Major General McClintock...
...senior officer in this area.
I didn't know you were behind us.
We have the host animal.
We're headed back to Cedar Creek.
You are to accompany me to Travis.
You don't understand.
No one is sick at Travis.
Don't make this difficult for me.
They're lining up in attack formation.
They want us down.
You don't want to destroy
an Army helicopter in broad daylight.
With all due respect,
if you do not follow us to Travis...
...l'll blow you out of the sky.
General, with all due respect, fuck you, sir.
Under my authority...
...go weapons hot.
Viper 2, This is General McClintock.
Go weapons hot.
Hold on.
We're going low.
Anything I can do?
Don't make me nervous.
The river goes to the right.
We must head them off. Break right.
Two, breaking right.
I don't see them. We lost them.
Shit! Hang on colonel.
Two is masked. No shot.
See that bridge?
Over or under?
You decide. I'm really not up to it.
- Hang on.
- I would have said over.
Wires! Two is off left.
What do I do?
Get him out of the air.
Don't go under the bridge!
You're missing him.
- Go into it.
- You're missing him.
Hang on.
We got it.
- Lf you're in trouble, I want to know.
- Hang on.
Warn me before you pull
a stunt like that again.
I didn't know I was going to do it.
Where are you?
Viper 2 closing in on you now.
Pulled a 160, he's coming back at you now.
They're coming at us.
I'm going weapons hot.
- Holy shit!
- Break!
Break!
- Where's he gone?
- I don't know, sir.
Son of a bitch did that on purpose.
- Are those rockets on the side?
- They are, sir.
Fire a few into those trees.
Look there.
Lead,
we got fire in the trees at two o'clock.
Verify.
Viper 2, can you get down
there and search for wreckage?
Negative. It's too thick down there.
Big Eye, we think the Loach is down.
What do you see?
We had 3 contacts and then
an explosion. Now we have 2.
Everything else is ground clutter
on the highway.
Flying a little low, aren't we?
Avoiding radar, sir.
She's still out. How you doing?
Use the E-1101 as a road map
to synthesize an antiserum.
Right away.
- We've got a lot of people here.
- I'll copy it big time.
I want liters of it.
I want everything ready if Robby responds.
You got it?
- Yes, sir.
- Okay.
There's no sign of wreckage.
We've been decoyed.
You son of a bitch!
How you doing?
You're going to be okay.
We found the host.
You don't have to say that, Sam.
No, it's true.
Would I kid you?
Salt's cooking up the good stuff.
Let's hang out for a while.
I love your face.
Keep talking to me, Robby.
Please don't leave me, Robby!
Don't!
Colonel, I got it!
- Your helmet?
- Come on, come on, put it up.
We got it.
You ready?
- Say when.
- Now.
I got it. I got it.
Get the lab geared up.
Make more. A town is waiting.
- It's going to work, sir.
- Go, go. Come on. The time's now.
You delayed the bombing.
More sentimental bullshit.
There's a chance we
can save these people!
You're nuts. Sandman 1, Viper 1.
How copy? Over.
Send your traffic.
We had the antiserum and didn't use it.
That will come out.
I can defend that.
It's not about saving our asses anymore.
You are to proceed immediately with
Operation Clean Sweep. Understood?
Daniels knows about the African camp.
Roger, Viper.
Sandman is proceeding.
Her pressure's down.
It worked, she's normalizing.
But, sir, they're coming.
I picked up a transmission.
The plane is in the air. They're coming.
Come on.
Where are we going?
- Where are we going?
- I must talk to the pilot. Can we?
Yes, guard channel.
- Get this thing up.
- Where're we going?
I don't know.
- Get us in the air.
- Let's tell them we have the antiserum.
- They don't care.
- This is crazy.
They want their weapon.
- They'll kill everyone?
- Right.
- They'll watch innocent people die?
- Yes, they want their weapon.
Viper, Sandman.
We're commencing bomb run now.
3 minutes to target area.
Sandman. Bomb release is go.
I say again, bomb release is go. Over.
Where are we going?
I want to talk to the pilot now.
Go.
To the aircraft approaching Cedar Creek,
this is Col. Sam Daniels. I'm a doctor.
Do you read me?
We read you.
Okay. You must not bomb this town.
That son-of-a-bitch,
that little son-of-a-bitch!
This is Viper Command,
you're being spoofed by com chatter.
Viper Command, Sandman.
Authenticate. Over.
Sandman, this is Viper Command.
I authenticate.
Juliette, over.
Your commanders do not have
the current data. We do.
We have an antiserum being
administered as we speak.
Every infected person will have their
dosage, so you must abort the mission.
This is urgent. Do you read me?
You cannot bomb this town.
You must abort.
I'm talking to the bomber pilots.
Do you read me?
Where is he, Briggs?
Can he prevent the bombing?
Can he abort their run?
If he gets in the way of the plane.
Get something up in the air
and blow him out of there!
Now!
Can't we stop his transmission?
Do you read me? You must abort!
They've been trained not to answer you.
You hear me, don't you, guys?
I'll say it one last time.
These people that you're going
to bomb are not the enemy.
We can kill the virus without killing
these people. I swear on my soul...
...that the President
does not have the facts.
He doesn't know
we have a working serum.
Do you think he wants
to blow up the town?
If you think I'm lying, drop the bomb.
If you think I'm crazy, drop the bomb.
But don't drop the bomb because
you're following orders!
Your superiors have another agenda.
Don't you understand that right
below you in Cedar Creek...
...there's a biological weapon they've
been manufacturing for 30 years?
I guarantee you...
...that the disease has spread
beyond the perimeters of this town!
People,
we're in a state of national emergency.
We are under executive orders.
See it through.
If you incinerate Cedar Creek,
you incinerate the serum.
Billy, can you hear me?
Why don't you do something?
Don't kill these people to protect your lie.
This is murder,
anyway you fucking slice it!
If you manipulate the truth,
the Constitution...
...then it's not just a town you're killing,
but part of the American soul.
Billy, why aren't you at Cedar Creek?
This is General Ford.
I remind you that you are interfering
with presidential authority.
Sandman has a specific line to the target.
If you are in his way,
he cannot complete his bombing run.
Do you understand?
- Why'd he say that?
- Beats me.
Are you dumb or something?
You just told him how to stop the...
Okay.
Colonel, there it is.
I see it.
- You up for this?
- Yes, sir.
He's over the target area,
please advise. Over.
We have final clearance.
Do not deviate. Over.
I'm talking to the pilots in the bomber.
What you're about to do isn't easy...
But I've told you the truth.
You will release that weapon
on time and on target!
What you do in the next 30 seconds
will be your testimony to life.
Sandman, you know what's riding on this.
Please, try to remain calm.
Okay, guys, no more words.
But we're not moving from your path.
Do you hear us?
I said we're not moving from your path.
I've never seen anything like this,
I swear to God.
Sandman, Viper Command...
I don't care if you fly through those
bastards. You've been trained for this.
Hold your course and drop.
You'll have to take us out with you.
We're not moving!
They're dropping it.
Thank you, guys.
Sandman,
how did you release that weapon?
Viper Command, this is Sandman.
We have detonation over the water.
It might have been wind shear. Over.
I believe that you have deliberately
contravened a direct order.
Now return to base for
immediate rearming. Over.
Give me the microphone, general.
I beg your pardon?
Give me the mike, general.
Sandman, this is General Ford.
You will ignore that order.
For the record, I am relieving
General McClintock of command...
...for the crime of withholding
vital information from the President.
I have in no way withheld vital
information from the President.
- Colonel Briggs.
- Sir.
Place General McClintock under arrest.
If I go down for this, Billy,
you go down for it.
It's out of our hands now.
You sentimental son-of-a-bitch!
Nobody puts me under arrest!
Nobody.
Colonel Briggs...
...what a wonderful moment
this must be for you.
That was a good nap, kid.
You look better.
The gown becomes you.
- How're they doing on the antiserum?
- Great.
Cranking it out by the liter.
- How much are they giving the patients?
- 200 mls...
Is that what they gave you?
I didn't think I'd ever see you again.
I didn't think you'd make it.
It's a pretty unique experience.
Like living with me.
Would you do it again?
Maybe.
Now that I have the antibodies.
Subtitles by SOFTITLER