Caption and sync: paula_g
:=:== Subtitles by SRT project ==:=:
Parker
-Hello father.
-One please.
- $ 10 please.
-Excuse me if I'm late.
Here's my bank.
Like, 20 minutes.
Wearing another Fred & Ginger,
contestant number 4,
Audrey Clarke,
has been acting
since she was 3 years old.
People in the county
of Cincinnati in Audrey's performances
for 16 years in fame.
Don't worry dance fans.
-C'mon mommy!
-One more time ma'am.
There you go.
It's all yours.
-C'mon mommy try again!
-Ok.
Fake some pain in your heart.
-C'mon!
-All right, try again. One more time.
-No.
-C'mon, c'mon one more time!
-C'mon mommy, please.
-Hey, padre.
-No.
-I really want it.
-Come on in here,
help this little girl out here.
-No.
-I don't think so.
-No, cash, no nots, on the house.
C'mon for this little
beautiful little girl, you could do it.
-Please.
C'mon on the house, 5 3 4.
There you go.
-Who wants to be next here?
-Cool, yeah!
-Look mommy, I won, I won!
-We have a winner!
-Well done to the winner!
-I won, thank you!
Here, it's for you.
You're a winner.
-You're a winner.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, padre.
-There's a big winner.
Hardwick!
Hey!
Got it.
Be very quiet.
Hey officer,
I've got to get through real quick.
Sorry sir.
Livestock shows are changing.
You're gonna have
to wait 20 minutes.
C'mon I'm not gonna
say anything if you don't say anything.
No Sir,
those are the rules.
Easy.
Hardwick's torching the
hay bales in 5 minutes.
Wait for my call.
-$ 20 bands please.
-Let's move this in cos we've got another equipment comin'in.
It's gonna be over 100
degrees again today.
Frankie, grab me a
lemon shake from the restaurant?
This is gonna be fun.
My uncle was a priest.
Sorry to bother you.
I'm on a bus back to Cleveland at 4.
I was wondering if there's some
place I could put this when I walk around.
Sure Father.
Right where you came in,
there's a blue building.
It's the hospitality center.
They'll be more than happy to help
you with whatever you need. They got some
very good refreshments there.
- Go, go.
- Freeze!
Drop it!
Let's go.
Everybody down!
Down in front of the table!
Put your fucking face down!
Hold it!
-What is the erase code?
- 487.
Type it in.
Let's go.
Move!
On the floor.
Face down.
Need all your phones
on a pile over here please.
Right up here,
like the good Father said.
Hurry, up here!
We want this over
as quickly as possible
You wanna steal from
people who can't afford it?
You don't have
people that don't deserve it.
So relax.
I'm no better than you.
You're no better than me.
If I say I'll do
something I'll do it.
You say you'll
do something if you don't
I'll make sure
you regret it.
We don't have
the key today for the cabinet.
-Only Mr. Lindsey has those keys.
-Shut it old man.
Hands behind your back.
Everyone, hands behind your back!
-Stay down bitch!
-Back down sailor.
I can't always breathe.
Please, I don't wanna die!
I don't wanna die!
Shut your guts
or I'll blow your head off!
Hey, I'll take care of this.
Tie them up.
Calm down.
Take it easy.
It's ok.
It's gonna be just fine.
I promise.
-What's your name?
-Ben.
Do you have a girlfriend, Ben?
She loves you, right?
What's her name?
Hannah.
Tonight you're gonna be
sitting with your arm around Hannah.
Watching this
on the 10 o'clock news.
She'll be so close you'll
feel her breath on your neck.
When she hears how
nobody got hurt toady because you're a cool head,
she's gonna press a
warm hand against your cheek.
She's gonna look
into your eyes,
like there's no place
else she ever wants to look again.
Trust me Ben,
it's gonna be a good night.
Thank..
Thank you Father.
On the floor.
Hands behind your back.
Ok, let's get in.
Partner, you is better be
right about what's inside these tin cans.
Hurry up
before he drinks it all.
You're right,
we should have left earlier.
Hey, you
look beautiful, Claire.
I bet you say
that to all the girls.
-You know you're the only one.
-What about your partner?
-C'mon your dad's important to me.
-I know it.
I love that
you love him.
-Hurley!
-Hey, dad!
-Excuse me a second.
-Sure.
There's my little girl.
Claire, who's
this bum you brought?
-Hi beautiful.
-Hi, daddy.
-I'm gonna find Jen.
-Good, go see her.
So good to see you man.
Me too, Hurley.
Ok.
One down, one to go.
-How does it look?
-What have we got?
Full.
Totally full.
Sing, sing baby...
I got everything
from a guy,
he's worked this
fair for last eight years.
Blueprints...
everything you need.
They rake in a
big haul on Saturday and Sunday.
1.. 1.5 million,
not bad, huh.
So you think
I'll need those guys?
Yeah, it's a
five-man job.
How do ya
know this guy Melander?
Melander and
I worked together
out in Portland 20 years back.
Always had a good crew.
Independent, like us.
I told him right off,
if you're in
it's your show.
You're in charge.
Number 2, good to go.
-Let's go.
-What the fuck was that!
you stay with the plan.
Move it.
Let's go.
There's public panic out here.
C'mon.
All right.
Down on the floor.
Stay on the side.
Go out the back.
So, we all good?
You were supposed
to close the hay bales behind the livestock.
-Away from the midway.
-There was some trouble,
so why are you angry
about some big fucking deal!
Someone gets hurt,
the cops come after us.
-That's the big fucking deal!
-Mother fucker!
I said behind
the livestock pavilion.
30 seconds!
C'mon, unload it.
Right now!
I have to say, Parker,
you came as advertised.
so, I've decided to
bring you in on something else.
Something big.
Look, $ 200 grand each
isn't gonna make any of us rich.
But if we all kick in our share of seed
money towards the next little piece of business down line
we all end
up with $ 2m each.
We've just took a million bucks.
That's a hell of a lot of seed.
And that's just for the house.
I don't think so.
Look, picture
one of those duffel bags,
only instead of $ 10s and $ 20s,
it's filled with
diamonds and pearls.
Jewelry is 10 cents on the dollar.
No thanks.
No, not $ 0,10.
I'm getting $ 0,20.
Parker, $ 2m each.
We got someone on the inside.
It's the score of a lifetime.
Guaranteed.
We made a deal.
You said we split the take,
that's what we need to do.
Why don't you think about it?
Come on. Parker, hey,
we're talking millions, seriously.
Ok Parker,
cards on the table.
I'm gonna need
the whole score for this next thing.
So, if you were me,
what would you
do with a guy like you?
Divide up the shares
and that'd be the end of it.
What if you decided
not to do that?
I'd kill him
while I had the chance.
Jesus Christ.
Shit.
Grab him!
Shoot him!
Stop him!
Son of a bitch!
What fucking idiot
fires a shotgun in a car?
-Shut up, Hardwick!
-My God!
Shut up!
-Go finish it.
-Wait, wait, wait.
Look, he's fucking dead.
Let's just get the fuck out!
I'd don't give
a fuck who your uncle is!
You wanna be a
part of this, go finish him.
-You heard him, Hardwick!
-Go.
Get the fuck out of here!
We got to get out of here!
-Handle your business!
-C'mon, we gotta go!
Do it!
Blow his fucking head off!
Fuck!
You're a fucking pinsetter,
Parker!
-You're so fucking stupid!
-Do it!
-C'mon!
-Let's go, let's go!
I didn't get
a good look at his face,
just that he was a priest.
So far as his build, that goes
I dunno.
I guess I'd say average.
Did he say anything to you?
Not really.
Nope.
Looks like a
man's shoe up there.
-That looks like blood.
-Yeah, look at that.
James, stop!
There's a man!
Boys,
stay in the truck.
-Do you think he's dead?
-I dunno.
You boys hang back.
I'm gonna check.
-Oh Sweet Jesus, c'mon.
-What do you want me to do, daddy?
He's alive!
Take him from this side.
C'mon now.
Pick him up. Let's go!
Help him, boys.
You scrub my back?
All these scars,
if you came into the ER
with these many holes I'd pray for more.
That's why I stay away from hospitals.
Stay still.
We get you to the hospital.
We gotcha.
A silver Suburban used by the
thieves who struck the neighboring Ohio State Fair on Monday,
was found in a strip mall across
the state in Cincinnati, Ohio.
The men made off
with approximately US$ 1m,
there are believed that
severe deadly fire when making their escape.
A 51-year-old Sedelia resident,
Charles Stompton was killed in that blaze
Anyone with information is asked to...
Don't get up.
You were shot.
-I'll call the nurse.
-Don't you call the nurse.
-Where am I?
-Kentucky.
You know what happened to you?
They don't even know your name.
-Are you crazy?
-Good morning ladies.
-Good morning.
-How' you today?
Ok, Mr. Quinn!
-Radiation is all set for you.
-Just a minute, the man needs some help.
Ok, ok, no problem.
Let me get you set,
-and I'll check him out.
-Man needs help.
-C'mon.
-Get up, get up.
-He needs some help.
-Let's go, let's go.
-Help the man.
Ok. We have
to get to radiation.
-Pick your feet up.
-No.
Calm down.
Nurse.
Oh no.
Hey, hey stop.
Don't hurt him, please.
Oh my God.
Is he dead?
-He's dead. You killed him.
-No.
Praise the Lord.
Whats... what's
gonna happen now?
Please don't
hurt me, please.
They say he was shot?
Yeah, found on the
side of the road like were dead.
How long did it take you.
I need the chair to
hold up my weight.
Don't call attention
to us and I'll let you go as
soon as we're outside, understand?
-Is he talking?
-No, he was still unconscious.
A farmer found him.
See you inside.
Hey, you look better.
You too.
Blow his fucking head off!
Do it!
-Got it!
-Put it in the truck.
There ain't gonna be no ducks left.
I'll have to leave you.
Mr. Norte,
I'm a friend of Bob Hurley's.
Yeah. Listen,
I need some documents.
Don't worry about the money.
I start a new job in the morning.
Do what I say
and you won't get hurt.
Mine's bigger
than yours.
It's not the size,
it's how you use it.
-Get to hell?
-You got hurt cos
you didn't do what I said.
Your bullet-proof
vest doesn't cover your legs.
-Next time I'll take out your eye.
-Who the fuck are you?
Do right to
feel you weren't at hospital.
-They'll get you, you know.
-Yeah, so don't sweat it.
So, I'll have the money,
you're insured and they'd be getting me.
Get up.
Remember I've
got a gun on ya.
-What's your name?
- Jack. People call me Jack.
C'mon, Jack.
What's your partner's name?
Oliver.
You say Oliver, I got
shot and this guy helped me, nothing else.
-I got shot. Thank
God this guy helped.
-Jesus
It's small but it hurts.
He knows we're wearing
vests, he'll shoot you in the face.
Now can we just get this over
with so I can go to goddamn hospital?
Ok, Oliver.
Put Jack into the other room.
I need cash.
You know they're
gonna get you for this.
Yeah,
Jack already told me.
Sorry about the leg,
Jack.
Sit tight for 5 minutes
and we'll call you an ambulance.
Hey!
Come on in, senor.
You made
it in record time.
So, you're
Hurley's friend?
I'm glad you found us,
Mr....?
Won't you step
right this way.
You know,
this was my dad's business.
We make most of
our money at high schools.
You know, printing
year books, diplomas, stuff like that.
Need to buy a
car, get along
Name, birth
certificate and driver's license.
Sure.
Passport.
Anything else?
-Did you bring a picture?
-No.
Five days, my friend.
C'mon. Get out.
Run, move.
Hello?
It's Parker.
Yeah?
There was a
problem with the job.
-I need you to do 2 things for me.
-Yeah, name it.
First, let Claire
know that I'll be gone
longer than I thought.
All right.
You got it.
Second, do you know where
I can get hold of that client  Melander.
What happened?
I invoiced but
I wasn't able to collect.
Oh Jesus, Parker.
Are you all right?
Where is he?
This is not a good idea.
After you didn't call,
I did some checking,
it turns out that Melander
is not as
independent as I thought.
He's got connections.
Big connections.
We're talking Chicago.
Danzinger.
-So don't start anything.
-Hurley, it's me.
-Give me a name.
- Listen...
Hardwick is
the nephew of Danzinger.
-You understand?
-Gimme a name!
Jesus Christ.
All right, here's what I got.
His brother, Bobby Hardwick,
owns bars on Bourbon Street,
plus a
rock 'n' roll club.
Now listen, you be real careful.
These are bad guys.
-Are you invited?
-Yeah.
-Right, go ahead.
-I need to see Bobby Hardwick.
-Not gonna happen.
Tell him Mr. Danzinger
sent me.
Wait here.
Idiot!
Get out.
I got 300 people down
there and you're telling me
you only got 200 paid.
That means I
got a 100 fucking guests.
-Who are these fucking guests?
-Relax buddy.
Now don't tell
me to relax, you understand?
-What?
- Bobby Hardwick?
Out.
Private.
I need you to tell
me where your brother is.
-Get him the fuck out of here.
-C'mon, you heard...
Your brother went off on
a job with a man named Melander.
You know how
fucking connected I am, chief?
They took money
that belongs to me.
Tell me where they
are and I'll get out of your hair.
Do you have any
concept of the unholy shit storm
you are about to unleash
by fucking with me, do you?
First, I should
tell you myself personally:
I always follow through.
Always.
-Fuck you!
-You gonna tell me what I need to know,
or I'm gonna press down
on this chair until it crushes your trachea.
Trust me,
it's agonizing.
Plus there's the posthumous
humiliation of having been killed with a chair.
-Florida
-Go, go!
-Where in Florida?
-Palm Beach!
-Palm Beach, for chrissake!
-Bobby!
-You ok?
-Fucking get him! Get him!
Hi.
You know what to do.
Claire. We should
keep that thing on.
Look, Trevor may find his
way up there.
Think you'd better talk to a travel agent.
Tomorrow.
-Yeah?
- Hurley, time for a vacation.
Yeah.
There's nothing
between Cheryl...
Oh God!
There will always be
something between you and Cheryl.
Always.
You're not gonna
wear that skirt.
You know we can't
wear earth tones.
It's Tahari.
That's what's important.
Not your hips.
What do you
expect me to wear, Ma?
I tell you what to
wear, what to drive,
You can't afford it.
You know I'm not loaning you any more money, right.
Can you open my pills,
my hands are bad.
-I put them out.
-At least take Pipsy out.
-Leslie!
-It's your dog.
-But it's my house!
-It's a condo, Ma.
I put one of these
devices in this speaker.
When these babies go off,
all hell's gonna break loose.
Let's hope you
know what the fuck you're doing.
The beauty is, speakers
will still be able to work.
Hey, Bro.
No. Hold on a sec.
Now will you just
shut the fuck up and concentrate?
Are you sure?
Bobby...
-Look at this.
-Stop playing with that thing.
-Fuck!
-What the hell was that?
What!
-He's alive.
-Who?
Parker.
He knows we're here.
He ambushed my
brother, he tried to kill him.
Parker's dead.
He got out of the
SUV and you shot him, right?
-Yes, I fucking shot him.
-You...
I thought he was dead
when I shot him, I swear to God!
We need 5
men for the gig.
We can get by with 4;
don't work with 3.
Fuck!
All right.
Ok.
You get with your
uncle in Chicago,
and you have
me handle this.
We look
real professional.
Now.
That fucking Danzinger had better do
something for all the money he's gonna make on this haul.
The mafia doesn't
usually touch family.
But who knows with
Danzinger.
I'm not taking any chances.
Jen should be packed.
I'll be back and
get you in 15 minutes.
Yeah.
Hey, don't worry.
He'll be fine.
Claire...
it happens.
Yeah, not to me.
Oh God.
Dad, it never
happened to us.
Yeah.
Times change.
I'm the one who should be jealous,
he called you first.
Lock these doors.
All of them.
I'll be back with your
step-mom 10 minutes.
Parker?
-Did you get my message?
- Yeah.
My dad came by.
Two minutes after he left,
a strange man with a
big knife let himself in...
was that a message to you?
Listen, drive straight
to the fishing camp in Okeechobee.
No stops.
No calls.
You'll be safe there,
but make sure you're not being followed.
For how long?
I'll be
there Friday.
What if you're not?
Parker!
Empty the cash out of
the storage locker and disappear.
Look,
I'm 1 commission away.
I'll get it to you
by the end of the week, I swear.
No, you don't understand.
I need my car for work.
If you re-possess my car,
I can't pay you, please.
Just... just give me another week.
Great. Thank you.
Next week at the latest.
Hi. I'd love an
Americano with 2 sweetners.
-We've got it all ready for you, Leslie.
-Oh, thanks very much.
Leslie Cienfuegos.
-Rodgers.
-Right.
How is the ex?
You heard from him?
Shouldn't you
be over in West Palm?
I like it here fine,
like you do.
Maybe you have a cupholder in your car,
or you just keep that between your legs?
What's large and black, Jake,
where do you think I like it?
Let's see you laugh
the next time you get a ticket fixed.
Jackass.
Don't fuck with us.
Just give us Parker, and...
I told you boy!
I'm talking to you!
-Shut up!
-Fuck you!
Do you know who we are?
You deliver,
or you're gonna be dead like Parker!
What are you talking about?
I don't know any Parker!
Watch out!
-Dissatisfied customers?
-I don't have dissatisfied customers.
But I have you,
and now I have this.
You have a gun.
-Give me what I came for and I'm gone.
-You brought them here.
-Now you get down on the floor with them, boy.
-We had a deal, Norte.
I gave you  money,
now give me my papers.
Fuck your papers!
I don't need this bullshit!
Did they say
they were from Chicago?
-We didn't say.
-Shut up!
-Get on the floor!
-Did they mention someone Danzinger.
Look, I dunno anything.
All I know is I got a situation here.
You know his brother, Ernesto?
He sold you out.
Daniel, I said
get on the floor.
All right.
I'm done.
Hey, look,
we don't have to kill each other.
There men wanted you.
I don't want any part of it anymore.
I'm like...
Sweden.
-You mean Switzerland.
-Whatever.
Your documents are in
that little drawer right behind, right there.
Take them out.
Daniel Parmitt.
-Equador?
-You're an American citizen,
born in Equador.
There's lots of gringos down there.
You family
was in the oil business.
Pick up the gun.
No look here, there's not very
many people who could do what I do as well as I do.
If I get dead, my people will be
very upset and they're gonna come and get you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah
Who's gonna get me?
Pick it up.
Shoot them.
The other way we could
do this is I shoot them and I shoot you.
I'm trying to help you,
Norte.
Listen, pal.
You can still get out of this alive.
Why did you stop?
They're dead!
Then they won't feel it.
Keep going!
Toss me the gun.
So now what?
You got a hold on me, right?
I don't need a hold over you.
Only if you make all this disappear,
and anyone ask, I never showed up.
-What do I say about them?
-Maybe they died on the way here.
Don't forget to
take care of the navigator outside.
Equador.
I just hate flying.
I hate it,
and the goddamn
landing was terrifying.
When he went up on one wheel,
I thought I was gonna die for a minute.
I mean, Jesus.
Jen's already at the lake with the damn dog.
-What about Claire?
-Taken care of.
-Promise, she's safe.
-All right.
Ok, so Danzinger must be the fence
to get 20 cents on the dollar.
-This is what how it looks to me.
-Yeah, I think so.
You know, US$ 2 million share...
5 ways 20 cents
on the dollar
-50 million dollar score.
-Yeah.
-So where in Palm Beach?
-No, no...
Parker, I'm telling you
Bobby was lying.
Not Palm Beach.
Look, the problem
is not the score,
the problem is Palm Beach.
Nobody does business there.
There's a cop to
every 8 residents.
Draw bridges, they can
check the island out like that.
You're trapped. The state pen is
full of light weights that have tried it.
You know Melander,
is he a lightweight?
No,
Melander's not a lightweight.
But it doesn't matter.
Listen, I got
a call from Danzinger.
And for whatever the reason,
they wanted to
go down without a hitch.
So they sent me this
to give to you.
This is your Ohio share,
plus 10%.
Take it, go
somewhere with Claire.
Keep your money.
Who are you kidding, Hurley?
Chicago doesn't pay
to keep people out of their way.
For chrissake, Parker!
Danzinger is a fucking savage.
He sent an assassin to your home,
he almost killed my daughter.
I'm just trying to help you.
I don't want it from you.
I want it from them.
-It's the principle.
-Principle?
You want to get yourself
killed over a principle?
Me, Claire.
Is that what the fuck you want?
You almost dies on a plane runway.
If it's gonna happen, it'll happen.
It's not something you can control.
When I enter into an agreement
with someone, terms on both sides have to be honored.
If they don't allow that,
I'm asking chaos to take control over my life.
Nobody likes chaos.
Yup...
Yeah, no one likes chaos.
Sure.
Hurley, what if...
What is you had a place
in Palm Beach to sit things down?
Nah. Nah, cops
will be all over us.
No rent.
What if we...
What if we
bought a house?
Palm Partners,
how may I help you?
Do I have any messages?
All right, I will transfer
you to Mr. ...
Why do you even
read the society pages?
It's, not like you could
ever go to one of those parties.
Look, a normal couple gets divorced,
they need 2 houses instead of 1.
-If a rich couple gets divorced?
-They need 4 houses instead of 2.
I know what
you're worried about.
It took me 2 years
to get my first commission.
Even though it's
only a quater share.
I would've had my
first if Jammison hadn't swooped in.
-Good morning ladies.
-If I don't sell something soon,
-I'm screwed.
-Amber picked up a cold-call.
some rich ass Texan
looking to buy his 3rd vacation home.
I've been answering
the phone for 3 weeks, and nothing.
They are great clients,
all in cash.
-What's Amber's line?
-12.
Hello?
Yes.
-Excuse me for 5 minutes. Thank you.
-No problem.
Absolutely.
I'll let her know.
Hello?
That was Mr. Thompson.
He said he wants to close on Edgewater right away.
He said he's gonna be flying in at noon.
Oh, his phone died.
I was on the phone with him...
If you want, I can go take
care of that for you right away.
That's so sweet of you.
But no.
-1 1 for the price of...
-Noella.
-Excuse me one moment.
-Call Mr. Parmitt at the Buca Resort,
and tell him that I'll
call him later to re-schedule.
Of course. Sorry about that.
The price was US$ 1,155.
In item: 8000.
At a cost of US$ 2,353.20.
I can't believe
you've just stole her client.
There's nothing wrong
with stealing now and then.
They do it to us
all the time.
Mr. Parmitt?
Miss Rodgers.
Yes.
Anybody who is somebody,
and rich, winds up in Palm Beach.
I mean, more billionaires
per square foot than anywhere else.
Palm Beach is about
style, community.
-It's, it's, it's not about money at all.
-Of course not.
Where do
you live now?
I've got a place in Vail,
on the South Park Real,
-in Maine.
-Yeah.
I'd like to see a few more
areas before securing in on one.
-Do you have time tomorrow?
-Sure.
Yeah, I have all the time you
need to zero in on anything you want.
I'll pick you up
at your office at 10h.
I'll never remember my
way around unless I do the driving.
-Taxi!
-Can I drop you somewhere?
No thanks.
I'm good.
-Where to?
-Lake Okeechobee please.
-Yes Sir.
-Take the highway 441.
Morning, ma'am...
Daniel Parmitt.
San Antonio, Texas.
I though we agreed
no more scars.
I don't wanna lose you.
Hey.
I keep thinking about
that man inside our house.
I've been around
thieves my whole life but,
this guy,
he's a killer.
He really scared me.
They wouldn't have killed you,
Claire.
-They use you to get to me.
-And kill us both.
You can leave, Claire.
No one will blame you.
This Italian-made villa
was built 3 years ago.
It's only
US$ 17m.
If you were older and
1 mile down the beach it'd be US$ 35m.
You like?
You know, the furnishings are
all antique and they could be available for, you know...
the right price.
So, married?
Once.
She passed away.
I'm sorry.
What about you?
What does your husband do?
Divorced.
11 months.
He was a salesman.
He sold me...
the whole dream.
I thought he was something.
His Ferrari was rented.
At least it
wasn't stolen.
Well, he declared bankruptcy
before the divorce, so
I get to help him pay off this debt,
while he lives there in Key West
with his new girlfriend.
A younger girl.
This one right over here,
this has been on the market for about year for about US$ 27,5m.
If you make an offer now,
you could probably get it for about US$ 19,5m-ish.
It's a good price.
This is obviously
more of a neighborhood.
Right here,
with these greeen palm trees,
this house sold about 2 months,
for US$ 1,2m.
Mr. Rodrigo
says he wants to renovate.
Can you believe it?
It's obviously a tear down.
Mr. Rodrigo?
Yeah.
Amber sold it to him.
I think he said
he's from Texas too.
I'll have to meet
him someday.
You know, the one nice thing about
it, the inner coast goes right down here wraps right around the house.
It's really beautiful.
You see what I mean?
The inner coast winds up here.
So, you live in
San Antonio your whole life?
Yeah.
Since I was about 3.
To tell the truth,
I was born in Equador.
My folks are both
in the oil business down there.
Equador?
Really?
That's what it
says on my birth certificate.
-Hey, Leslie.
-Hey, Julio. How are you?
I was in a management
training program here before I got married.
I could've got you a great discount,
even rate, say 11 years ago.
Do you mind if I hold on to these for
my bankers to see if they have a problem on their end?
Sure. They're all sold.
I just kind of tossed them anyway.
Here, my card.
Mr. Parmitt...
Daniel...
I know that
you're in town alone,
so, if you'd like, we can
go over more places,
say, over dinner
or just drinks?
You are so kind,
but I'm afraid I've other plans.
-I'll be in touch.
-Ok.
Plans...
Pipsy, stop.
Be good.
Leslie?
Put on the soap channel.
Do we have to have the
soap opera channel always on?
-I pay for it.
-I pay every minute.
I heard that.
I heard that too.
You see? This is the kind of
outfit you would look great in.
Don't tell me,
it's Tuesday night.
I'm off to poker.
You mind Pipsy.
Actually, Martha's still in the hospital,
why don't you come?
We'll put Pipsy in the carrier.
The girls would love to see you.
If he's in town,
we can't risk him
getting any of us alone.
-We have to...
-Uncle said he has the best guy to take care of Parker.
Mr. Danzinger is going to be
very disappointed you haven't seen Parker.
Listen my friend,
I keep telling you,
I dunno anybody named Parker,
all right?
Nice new carpet.
I love that shit.
-I am ready to order.
-Sit down, sit here.
Don't worry about it man,
I got you peperoni.
If you're free,
maybe we can go for that drink now.
Who knows you're here,
Leslie?
If you wanna go somewhere more private,
we can go to your hotel.
Or we can go to the office, I have the keys.
You know, Mr. Crin usually keeps the...
-I'm gonna ask you a question you need to answer.
-Ouch, ouch, ouch, you're hurting my neck.
Who knows you're here,
Leslie?
No one, ok?
No one!
-You're gonna love this.
-Fuck.
You know, everything you did
in the car today was, almost right.
Almost.
But I didn't buy it.
Is Daniel Parmitt
you real name?
Why wouldn't it be?
Because you're less
than 2 months old.
You have a bank account,
an address in Texas and a drivers license.
You never owned or
leased a car before this one.
You never had a credit card
and you never had a mortgage.
You know, I've traveled a lot.
My family business pays for everything.
And the only house you showed any
interest in was the one back there.
-Mr. Rodrigo's.
-Really, you think that?
Really.
You know, I looked
into Mr. Rodrigo too.
He's only 6 months old.
Ok, why are you parking
all the way over here?
We could've parked
right in front of the office.
-There will be no cars there at this time of night.
-Let's go.
Unless you don't want
the chance of being seen.
Is that what's going on?
-Wait a minute...
-Keep moving.
Don't turn those on.
English accent...
I knew you weren't from Texas.
Look at that
A nice Chablis.
Will you be joining me?
Ok.
Well, I'm thirsty.
I drink too much,
and I worry too much.
Divorce, pushing 40,
I have a sister I haven't
spoken to in 5 years.
And I'm stuck with my mum.
Doesn't look like she's
gonna kick off any time soon.
I'm sick of chaufering these...
fucking entitled
wannbe "playboys"
who've never worked a day in their life,
showing them houses
that I can never afford.
Laughing at their
jokes that I can't stand.
All offending
of their groups,
but not all their groups.
You never know, one of
these days I might just get a full commission.
So if you're
gonna kill me, go ahead.
I live with a
snapshot on my future,
and nobody's gonna know,
and nobody's gonna care.
But if you're not...
I can help you.
Help me?
People in Palm Beach
are sharp, very sharp.
People like you only
come here for one reason, money.
And I dunno what you're into,
kidnapping, extorsion, robbery...
but whatever it is, you're
gonna need somebody who knows the territory.
Or you're gonna get caught.
Take off your clothes.
What?
I'm not sure if I'm better
off with you alive or dead,
either way I have to know
if you're wearing a wire.
Look, I've been in a third
of the houses around here,
and I know the rest.
I can answer your questions,
and I can tell you what
questions you're forgetting to ask.
And all I'm asking,
is for you to give me
a small piece,
so I can get the hell out of here.
-Turn around.
-What?
Turn around!
You know, even to find Rodrigo,
you had to think of that roundabout with me.
And all it do is
make me suspicious.
I mean, how many people
do you want asking questions about you?
Lift your hair.
Get dressed.
Wash up the wine glasses.
Lock up before you leave
I'll think about it.
Hey, Lionel.
What you say?
I've got something for you.
Don't blow it all on the ponies again.
Tell me what you got.
I wanna know
every last detail.
Leslie!
Ok, last chance.
All this right here could be
yours for one low price.
Hey.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I bought a lottery ticket 2 days ago,
and I don't think it's going to be hailed.
Leslie, what did you do that for?
It is a waste.
Hello?
Mr. Parmitt?
Yeah, I have the perfect
condo I can show you.
I'll mee you at 1000 Ocean
Avenue in 20 minutes.
Yes!
Right on time.
You can park right there.
So, I'm hired?
You don't have to check me
for a wire again, do you?
I mean, you
can if you want.
We've got work to do,
Leslie.
-You're hard to read.
-Not really.
Let's just stick to business.
This is the deal...
Don't ask me any questions,
because I'm only gonna tell you what I wanna tell you.
The man who calls himself Rodrigo
took something from me.
He's in business
with 3 other men.
They're here for a robbery
and they're gonna use that house to lay low when they're done.
So...
you let them steal something,
and you steal it from them.
I help you,
and I get commission.
-You're gonna kill them, are you?
-I never said that Leslie, you did.
Civilized people
need to follow rules,
I'm just gonna put things right.
Where are they gonna hit?
I thought that was something
you could tell me.
You don't know?
Wha...
-When are they doing it?
-I don't that either,
but it's jewelry.
None of the stores
have checked out the inventory.
How large?
US$ 50m to 750m.
This is
Clinton's Jewels?
You're fucking kidding me?
Forget it!
They are gonna get caught or killed,
and so are you if
you are anywhere near them.
Leslie.
You can't leave.
Is she your friend?
Miriam Hugh Clinton,
was the first lady of
Palm Beach society.
She had more diamonds
than Elizabeth Taylor,
and when she died,
she left the entire estate to Palm Beach.
They're auctioning off
for US$ 75m jewelry collection right here,
tomorrow night.
What's behind there?
30 acres, a golf course, pool,
tennis courts, 2 ballrooms...
and it's one of the only houses
that's on the ocean and the inner coast.
Hey, Miss,
this is private property!
Sorry guys,
just taking in the sites.
No, no, no,
that's too much white.
Take them away and
bring back some pink roses.
-And just what is this now?
-Speakers for the auctioneer.
Small ballroom,
round to the right.
Ok, you go to the left side,
Robert to the right.
Report all panel
numbers to,
Barry,
who'll be standing next to me.
-Where do you want these?
-Put the speakers in the corners.
Right,
excuse me for a minute, please?
Go get the gear,
I'll meet you by the basement.
Stash that shit by the exit.
Hurry up!
So, have you been in jail?
You don't feel bad
about what you do?
Not everyone steals
these things.
Some people admit it to themselves,
some don't, it's what human beings do,
That's why
we invented locks.
Do you think
people in these houses feel bad?
Grandparents and their
great-grandparents, they the ones who go their hands dirty.
I just mean,
how do you sleep at night.
I don't drink coffee after 7.
-Is this the back entrance?
-Yes?
There's a taxi stand
at The Breakers.
-What's gong on?
-Out. Out!
Wait a minute. What's the plan?
What do I wear? I wear black, what do I do?
Go to your office.
I'll handle this.
This is getting old,
you know!
Welcome back to the hotel,
Mr. Parmitt.
You can handle the car.
Leslie,
someone's at the door.
someone's at the door!
-Jake?
-Leslie.
-Do you mind if I come in?
-Yeah, come in. What time is it?
How the hell did
you get my address?
-It's sort of official.
-Don't let him in!
At least make your
dog shut up!
Can you do that?
Yeah, what's going on?
It's about a man
named Daniel Parmitt.
I don't even know how to
use this thing, that's why I always get coffee.
-What about Mr. Parmitt?
-D'you know him?
Yeah, he's in town from Texas.
I showed him some places,
and he turned out
to be a real time waster.
I happened to be driving passed Sloan's curb
yesterday and I saw you talking to someone.
Yup.
That was him.
I showed him a condo.
You mean you can get together
a list of all the places you showed him?
Sure. I have to get it
from the office, why?
If there's a vacant place he knows about,
he just get it in his head to make some home for a while.
Shit.
Can you please get that for me?
Damn dog,
always tracking in
God knows what,
from who knows friggin where.
He got into an
altercation in his room,
with a fellow. The fellow went
over the balcony and he's dead now.
We're gonna need to ID
the victim.
That's crazy.
What about Mr. Parmitt?
We assume Mr. Parmitt
was hurt pretty bad.
He ran out of the hotel, stole a car
and no one's seen him since.
Well again, I guess I can kiss
that commission goodbye.
They found your
business card in his room.
We dunno what he was into.
I was just wondering if you could help us out.
You know, if you come by the
office later, I can give you his application,
and anything else you need,
ok?
You know, it makes you realize how dangerous
this business can be for a woman,
I mean, I was in places all alone with
him and he could have killed me.
That's why it might be good if you
started thinking of not being alone anymore.
Yeah.
-Sorry to wake you
-No, it's ok.
Thanks again.
Oh my God! I cannot
believe he's not barking.
-Yeah, dogs like me
-What do you mean?
I need to get you towels?
Oh my God!
-There's so much blood, what
are you doing with so much blood!
-I...
-Do you wash, wash it and put pressure on it with a towel...
-Leslie.
-Leslie, listen to me!
-What?
Listen, get dressed get into
your car, find a pay phone and call this numnber.
Ok, ok, ok.
You might not get an answer,
but maybe.
-And go straight to work.
-What?
-Yes.
-I can't leave you here.
We have to get you
to a hospital. You'll die by the time I...
-Leslie!
-Leslie, go.
Ok.
Pipsy, you like this one?
Do you make soup?
Of course?
Hi, erm.
My name is
Leslie Rodgers.
Daniel Parmitt
asked me to call.
Yes.
Why don't you go ahead and take a look at
both places again before you make your final decision?
Yeah, I can be there
in a half hour.
Ok.
Bye.
- Oh my God!
- It's a... It's a person!
- Oh no!
- Did you see that?
Oh, that's...
so terrible.
Call 911!
You ladies have a great day.
I thought that guy
sounded like trouble,
-I mean, Equador?
-Yeah, trust my luck.
Are you ok?
I'm going out.
If anyone from the police
comes, just give them the list of
places I showed Mr. Parmitt, ok?
-What's the matter?
-Nothing. I just need some air.
I was afraid you were the cops.
What's going on?
Are you a nurse?
I'm Claire.
-Leslie.
-Hi.
I named her after
Leslie, the "Y&R" wrestler.
-Mum.
-He sister's named after Jennifer in Valley of the Dolls.
They don't care, Ma.
I used to have a beauty salon,
and the TV was on all day.
-I told you to go to work.
-I was. I did, I...
I w...
I left.
I thought I was calling
somebody to take you to the hospital.
I can't do that, Leslie.
I have something to do tonight.
Are you crazy?
You almost died,
What do you have?
A mangled hand, a broken rib?
-For this time.
-This is a real man.
You are in no
shape to do anything!
You can barely even sit up.
-Would you tell him, please?
-I can't stop him.
He is who he is.
Ok.
All set.
Do you want me to call
a taxi or leave you the car?
-Phone a car.
-You're good at that.
Claire?
I didn't think you'd stay.
I know.
Will you wait for
me at the fish camp?
You know I will.
I left a bag with his
clothes and some stuff in it.
Thank you.
Thank you so much
for taking such good care.
Please, it was nothing
Please, please.
-Thank you, bye
-Come back to see me.
Bye.
-Bye.
Some soup for you.
That cop
is watching you.
Go back to work.
When you get back, I'll be gone.
Right. Everyone gets a weapon
and 2 electric clips.
Carlson, you have to be damn sure
that fire house is empty.
Relax.
It's closed for renovation.
Hardwick, I'm
giving you my best 45.
Let's go!
No one's gonna believe you're a fireman,
even volunteers cut their fucking hair.
Now, put your hood before
your jacket, show some discipline.
Hey, he looks fine.
I'm more worried about
Hardwick on that goddam boat.
Let's go!
C'mon!
-It's getting started at US$ 12m.
-It's mine.
-What?
-It'd look much better on me.
Thinks you're too small.
-That's sensational.
-It's beautiful.
-It's great.
If you'd all please take
your seats, we'll begin.
We're here tonight
to celebrate my very dear friend,
Miriam Hugh Clinton.
Let me introduce our
celebrity auctioneer,
Lionel Fleming.
Hello, and welcome!
We're here tonight
to pay tribute
to one of the great daughters
of Palm Beach's society,
Miriam Hugh Clinton.
Her kind works and,
and noble sp...
-Talk to me.
-Good to go.
All right.
Let's go.
Move it!
Let's go!
All right, everybody move!
Move away from the building!
-There are millions of dollars in jewels in there!
-Move over there, Sir!
Officer, get
everyone away from the door!
-It's empty!
-Don't let anybody in!
These fumes are toxic!
You, I want you to put
a perimeter around this building.
Nobody gets in here
but my guys, move!
Clear it up.
Lock these doors.
Locking it up!
Hi.
Right.
Hardwick's on his way
Time to go.
Let's go.
-Let's go!
-Right behind you.
We've got 2 minutes
to get under water.
C'mon.
Let's do it!
This is the Palm Beach
county sheriff,
you've entered
a restrictred area,
please move
away at once.
-What the hell is he doing?
-Doesn't he realize...
Sir, there's smoke in that building.
Is there a fire?
Yes, there is a fire and the
fire department is there to take care of it.
Excuse me.
Guys, there's West Palm
Beach Department.
West Palm?
How did they beat us here?
-But they're already in there.
-Seeing something?
I told you once,
I need you to leave this area right now or I'll...
Break the glass
Stand back. Stand back.
-Two more fire tucks just showed up.
-Look at this dickhead.
I'm not going to tell you again.
Please leave the area.
-Do you understand me?
-Sorry Sir. Sorry about that.
-Thank you.
-Have a good night man.
Thank you.
-Look, I got a West Palm helmet.
-I got another one.
Put them down, it's evidence.
This is a robbery.
Oh my God.
195.
We're gonna lock down the island.
Secure the bridges,
ten units on both sides of the island,
search the perimeter.
Marine units,
unicoastal on each side.
Eagles 1 and 2
get visual placements.
we've got to track them.
Eagle 1 in
position at north bridge,
I visual all 3
bridges in that position.
Eagle 2, flying
over intercostal.
Driver's license ma'am, please.
It's really happening.
Damn!
I'm not gonna let you fuck this up.
Fuck.
-They were freaked!
-Tell me about it.
Did we end the job great.
-Smooth as a baby's ass.
-We are heroes baby.
The public loves us.
The public loves us!
Hey, mna, who wants a beer?
Let's celebrate.
All right, let's check it out.
What have you got?
Let's see what we got, baby.
Let's see what we got!
-Yeah!
-Wait just a goddam minute.
Honestly, guys!
Yeah!
Yes!
-C'mon.
-They're jewels, baby.
What've you got, Ross?
Let me see it.
Check it out.
Look at that.
-Yeah, yeah, yeah!
-Now we are rich!
Who the fuck are you?
-I'm a real estate agent. I'm minding my own business.
I just came by to check the house!
-Get inside.
Look what I found.
Can someone tell me who the fuck is she?
-Who's this?
-Wait, wait, wait.
-Why the hell did you bring her in here?
-Cos she was peeking through the fucking window.
-I was just checking...
-Sit down, sit down.
-Calm down.
-Shut up.
-You... you can call my boss.
Shut up!
-You know what I'm thinking?
-What?
-Parker.
-Oh no.
-It's not fucking Parker. You're being paranoid again.
-He sent her in!
-He's out there somewhere.
-I don't know anybody...
Shut that fucking hole!
Shut up!
Parker's got to be hurting bad.
He leaked a whole gallon of blood in that hotel.
-The news said he could barely walk.
-The mother fucker's a rock, man.
He didn't die...
that fucking bitch!
-Where is he?
-I don't...
Where the fuck is he?
-Tell me where he is or I'll shoot you in the fucking...
-I don't know...
Tell me where he is!
Oh fuck off!
Do you want every cop
in the fucking road here?
You're right.
All right!
Get the fuck off of me!
You all right?
Here, let me help you.
All right.
Come on now.
Let's sit down and talk.
It's ok.
Now listen to me.
You don't want to die, do ya?
-Do ya?
-No.
Now tell me where he is.
I don't know.
Check the house,
every inch.
You know who those belong to?
No.
I don't have any idea.
Yeah, you do.
What's your
connection with Parker?
Are you fucking him?
What?
You wanna hit me now?
Go ahead.
You first.
Then it's my turn.
-Clear. It's clear on this side.
-He isn't on this side either.
Where's Ross?
Ross?
Ross!
-Fuck.
-Shit.
Oh shit.
Go check it out.
-Me? No fucking way am I...
-Get out!
Get the fucking
gun out of my face.
Stop pointing the fucking gun at me!
I'm fucking gone!
Jesus fucking christ.
If she moves,
shoot her.
Why don't we just...
unbutton this fucking button right here?
Yeah.
Lemme see what you got.
Bitch!
I'm gonna fuck you and then you die!
-In your dreams you fat, ugly fuck!
-Fuck you!
Shut the fuck up!
Shut your hole
and pay attention!
Goddammit!
Ross!
Parker,
we've got the girl!
You better come out
unless you want to see her dead!
Parker!
What the fuck are you doing?
You bitch!
You're fucking dead!
Parker, you touch me and
Danzinger will hunt you down!
He will not rest
until you're dead!
Listen to me, we can split this
up. We can use my connections.
Do not make me fucking kill her!
-Oh my God!
-D'ya understand?
-Go ahead.
-I will shoot her...
Shut the fuck up!
I will shoot her in the fucking head.
-Don't let him kill me!
-Go ahead.
Fuck!
Let me explain.
You were supposed to torch
the hay bales behind the livestock pavilion.
-C'mon.
-Wait, not so fast.
-You shouldn't have come here
-I thought you might need help.
What happened, did you know
that guy's gun wouldn't go off?
When I broke in
the night before,
I bent the firing pins
of most of the weapons.
"Most of them"?
This is what's going to happen...
Take the jewels to your office,
find an a/c vent and put in the stuff
in it. Put the grating back on and forget about it.
You don't tell your mother
and you don't check on them to
make sure they're still there.
In about 3 months...
I'll send someone to get them from you.
It might take a long time to fense,
but after that done, you'll receive
your share by express mail.
You can't put that
money in the bank, Leslie.
You can't go on a
crazy shopping spree.
Ok.
-How much will it...?
-I get the first US$ 200,000,
it's my original share.
The next US$ 200,000...
goes to my partner
who planned the job.
We split the rest.
How much?
I'd buy you a showy palace.
Oh sorry.
Sorry.
Sorry, I'm sorry.
Wait, wait, wait.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna lie low for
a week or so till things calm down.
I have someone
driving to get me.
Claire?
I never did have a
chance, did I?
-Danzinger?
-Yeah.
Who the hell are you?
Parker.
All right.
I was gonna give
him 20 cents on the dollar,
-I'll give you 40.
-It's not about money.
-Leslie!
-I got it.
-Good morning.
-Sign please.
-It's heavy.
-Ok.
-Oh my...
-Leslie, who was that?
It's the mail man!
Nothing but bills!
We've received
diamonds from heaven.
Bought a new house...
he's putting money
to pay off our debts.
You know, I believe that man that
we found on the side of the river that day...
he were no man at all.
He was an angel.
Sit here to test.
:=:== Subtitles by SRT project ==:=:
Caption and sync: paula_g