GSW.
That압 what the hospitals call it.
Gunshot wound.
Doctor has to report it
to the police.
That makes it hard
for guys in my line to get...
... ''quality health care. ''
Not many men know
what their life압 worth.
I do.
Seventy grand.
That압 what they took from me.
And that압 what
I was going to get back.
They say, ''Time heals all wounds. ''
You앇 think, after five months
of lying on my back...
...I앇 give up
any idea of getting even.
Just be a nice guy, call it a day.
Nice guys are fine. You got to have
someone to take advantage of.
But they always finish last.
Help a cripple.
Thank you, sir.
Help a Vietnam vet walk again.
Help a cripple.
Thank you, sir.
What the fuck you doing?
Get the fuck out!
Shut up. l cured you.
Cocksucker.
-What do l owe you?
-Two ninety-eight.
Son of a--
Hey, my cigarettes!
Sorry, sorry. Pardon me.
Thank you.
One hundred...
...two hundred...
...three hundred.
Have a nice day, Mr. Johnson.
Excellent fit, sir.
And how will you be paying?
l앏l give you $900.
Let me see that Magnum.
That압 it.
$500 and the gun.
l앏l need to see l.D.
Of course.
l앐 sorry, Mr. Johnson,
this card압 been canceled.
lmpossible.
Do you have another form
of payment?
Try it again.
Old habits die hard, I guess.
If you don앖 kick them,
they kick you.
Ain앖 marriage grand?
Porter.
Youre not dead.
What are you going to do?
lKill me?
Not now.
Youre cleaning up.
Val still wants to talk to you.
Sorry, babe.
Shall I tell him
to call back again?
No, l앏l talk to him.
Shut him up, anyway.
Yep, same as always. You?
Yeah, good, good.
Why? Are you there now?
Don앖 sweat it, Val.
We all look alike to them.
Same crew. The Chows.
Twice a week.
Tuesday and Friday, between 1 1 and 1 2.
Always the same route.
Chinese money laundry.
How much in the case?
Anywhere between 350 and half a mill.
How much do you need, Val?
We split it 50-50.
l mean, how much do you need
to buy your way back?
lnto the syndicate.
How much?
-The Outfit?
-Whatever.
Jesus. You know everything.
Hi, sweetie.
1 30 grand.
The Chows won앖 go to the cops.
They keep everything in-house.
And they don앖 feel pain like we do.
You notice anything about those guys?
They look nasty.
Probably kung fu motherfuckers.
-Did l miss something?
-They weren앖 wearing seat belts.
We앏l hit them on Friday.
Hubba, hubba, hubba!
Lookie here.
How압 that pileup taste?
Daddy brought home the bacon, baby.
Val!
What?
Problem with kicking a Chow압 ass...
...is an hour later
you want to do it again.
1 40 grand.
1 40 apiece.
Total.
Total?
That압 70 grand?
That압 not enough.
ls for me.
l앐 taking a few months off.
l앐 up short. Sixty short.
Fucking slants!
Should have hit them Tuesday.
Fuck!
We got away clean.
And got something to show for it.
Be grateful for what you get,
rule number one.
Yeah, rule number one.
What?
Everything압 cool.
Just not enough! All right?
Never is, Val.
Baby, just put the money
in the car, will you?
l can앖 fucking believe it.
You know what, Porter?
This is funny.
This will kill you.
lt압 always 1 40.
Someone ought to give me a Ph.D.
Jesus! Wait till l앐 out
of the fucking way!
Everything압 cool, baby.
You were great.
Everything압 cool. Give me--
Okay, keep the gun.
That압 it. Everything압 cool.
lt압 just like we planned.
Come on.
Don앖 fall apart on me now.
There we go.
l bet you got a lot of questions
rattling in your head.
Lynn did not understand.
l don앖 know.
Wives get funny
when it comes to girlfriends.
What?
l didn앖 get that.
You got it.
Come on, Miss Porter.
l don앖 have all day.
Miss Porter here?
Mrs. Porter.
Yeah, whatever.
Motherfucker!
Get up. Turn around.
Come on.
What have we got here?
How much in here?
Two grand.
-What압 in here?
-Helium.
What do you think it is?
lt압 heroin.
Shit. Oh, shit.
Val Resnick.
Where is he?
You want to know where he is?
He압 right here.
Look. Fuck you.
Wrong answer.
God! You motherfucker!
-Fuck!
-Val Resnick.
l never heard of him, man.
Where앇 you get the shit?
Come on, man.
Theyre going to fucking kill me.
What do you think l앐
going to do? Worry about me.
Oh, come on. Okay, okay.
Stegman, man.
Arthur fucking Stegman, okay?
Where is he?
South End Taxi.
Farragut Road, man.
Thanks.
Youre welcome.
l앐 looking for Arthur Stegman.
He ain앖 here.
Something l can help you with?
No, you can앖. Where is he?
l don앖 know.
Take a guess.
What?
Take a guess about where he is.
ls he at home?
Go fuck yourself.
Here we go.
-This one압 mine.
-Roll it.
Wait, that was mine.
There압 somebody here to see you.
l앐 looking for Stegman.
Who the hell are you?
l앐 Porter.
Porter, that looks like assault to me.
Porter looks like he likes
to resist arrest.
Fuck! Not in here.
Jesus! He just wants to talk.
Am l right? Did l call it?
Are you Stegman?
Maybe. What do you want?
Your boy didn앖 make his delivery.
Why don앖 we talk outside?
Youre a dealer?
Just forget about it, all right?
Don앖 touch my money either.
Come on--
This is heroin?
This is heroin.
Don앖 worry about it.
Take it easy.
Let압 talk.
What are you looking at?
Play your game.
And youre bleeding
all over my couch!
Come on!
Steggie압 been holding out on us.
l앏l check it out.
Val Resnick.
-What about him?
-Tell me where he is.
Even if l knew,
the answer would still be no.
-Where앇 you meet up with my boy?
-At his drop.
ls he dead?
No, but she is. OD앇 on that crap
you았e been sending her.
So? What do you care?
l앐 her husband.
Youre not going to kill me.
are you?
Not in front of these kids.
Where is he?
l don앖 know!
That압 the truth.
lt got delivered to me last night.
l won앖 see anyone till next month.
Why all the trouble?
He압 afraid of the girl.
l mean...
...of Mrs. Porter.
l mean, that압 how it looks to me.
l don앖 know nothing about this.
l know Val from the old days.
Three months ago he asks me
to do him a favor.
l make an extra grand a month.
l figure, what the hell?
Now you threaten to kill me?
That much a buddy of Val압 l am not.
He압 in the city.
That압 all l know.
How do you know that?
-He said so.
-When?
When he came. Said he squared
himself with the syndicate.
Said he was back
in the big time for good.
He was very excited.
You tell him that Porter is back too.
And he wants his money.
l앏l come back for you
when these kids are not around.
When would l tell him this?
Talk to me.
There압 a young lady to see you.
Her name is Pearl.
She압 got two very bad habits.
Right now l앐 only interested
in one of them.
Send her up.
Apartment 7 1 8, ma아m.
Go right on up.
Send her up.
It압 Haskell.
Sorry to call you at home--
Don앖 be sorry.
Just don앖 call.
I got a call from a cab guy
on the south end.
-What is it?
-It압 this guy, Stegman.
Shit. Hold on a second.
On your knees, bitch.
l want satisfaction.
l앐 on the phone, Pearl.
lt압 ''Mistress Pearl.''
l앐 on the fucking phone!
Make it quick.
This guy Stegman calls.
He sounded all nervous,
like something scared him.
He had to talk to you.
I said I앇 see what I could do.
-What was it about?
-He said to tell you Lynn was dead.
He said some guy wanted you.
That압 all he said.
I thought you ought to know.
You did right.
l want to talk to him.
Who, Stegman?
No, President Nixon.
Of course, Stegman!
Tell him Varrick압, by the bridge.
Make it....
Make it 20 minutes.
l앐 working here!
Can앖 you see l앐 working here?
Put it on my tab.
l앐 looking for a girl.
She goes by the name of Rosie.
Here압 her photo. Do you know her?
She worked by telephone,
not freelance.
Probably connected
with the syndicate.
Out of my league.
l wouldn앖 know her.
Maybe you know somebody who would.
-Why you looking for her?
-l앐 her brother.
l got cancer.
l want to see her.
You two look close.
Got a cigarette?
Your sister sounds expensive.
Try Michael,
bartender at the Regal Hotel.
That wasn앖 the name
l was looking for.
The only one l got.
l tried to call you, but you
must have changed your number.
l never gave you my original number.
What did this guy look like?
He had dark hair, blue eyes.
A real Cro-Magnon-looking bastard.
lf Lynn압 dead,
maybe he did us a favor.
l know, except l앐 out
a grand a month.
Maybe we can work something out.
Did you get a name?
He said he was Porter.
He said he was there for Porter?
No, he said he was Porter.
l wouldn앖 want that guy
after me either.
-l know how you must feel.
-What am l? A nobody?
l았e got friends.
All l have to do is point.
l pick up a phone
and he압 a dead man.
And this time he stays dead!
Try to keep it down,
all right?
lt압 okay.
What앇 he say about me?
He said you owed him money.
Nothing else?
Nothing. Why?
How much you owe him?
None of your business.
l just got the feeling
he앇 like to kill you.
Oh, Christ!
Porter.
What앇 you tell him?
Nothing!
-What could l tell him?
-You tell him about the money? Heroin?
He had it with him!
l told him l delivered it.
Nothing else?
l don앖 know nothing else!
You gave him something. A name.
Someone who knows where to find me.
l swear on my mother--
Fuck your mother!
-That압 not nice. Take it easy.
-What are you looking at?
Val, don앖.
Not again. Don앖 do that, man.
Come on. Not again.
Don앖.
-Forget it.
-ls there some trouble here?
Were just leaving.
You know what?
This one압 on me.
You see me reaching
for my fucking wallet?
Sorry. He just got a promotion,
so he압 a little tense.
ls there a Michael here?
That압 him over yonder.
Youre the man to see
about horizontal refreshment?
l앐 looking for a girl named Rosie.
Prostitution is illegal
and youre speaking Greek.
Usually these matters are conducted
with more discretion.
Be discreet now.
What was her name?
Rosie.
-Who압 looking for her?
-Just call her.
Rosie?
Give me the phone.
Take care of that.
Who the hell is this?
Porter.
Try again, honey.
Porter압 dead.
l used to drive for you.
Provide a safe work environment.
Porter?
Why pour salt on old wounds?
I didn앖 need to.
I guess I had a soft spot for her.
Come in.
You look pretty good
for a dead guy.
How앇 you hear about it?
People were talking.
Plus l heard your wife
was back in town alone.
She압 dead.
l앐 sorry, Porter.
Why?
Jesus. Surly Porter.
Youre the same as ever, aren앖 you?
This doesn앖 look like you.
Yeah, well, people change.
Stay.
lt압 okay.
Come on, sweetheart.
Meet the nastiest dog
who ever lived.
What압 his name?
Porter.
He took your job after you left.
He압 just as tough,
but he won앖 leave me.
l need a favor.
A favor?
Maybe youre not the same as ever.
l앐 looking for a syndicate boy.
lt압 the Outfit.
We don앖 say ''syndicate'' anymore.
You know what l mean.
Whatever.
Don앖 get touchy, Porter.
What압 his name?
Val Resnick.
That son of a bitch.
You know him?
l met up with him once
a few years ago.
He can앖 use Star압 service.
He beats up the girls.
He almost killed one.
You?
Does it matter?
You quit looking after me, remember?
Would you know where he might be?
l suppose he압 at the hotel.
-Which one?
-The Outfit hotel.
The address?
Were friends, right?
l mean, we used to be.
But l앐 an employee too.
The Outfit wouldn앖 like me
telling you, would they?
How strong are you?
Personally, l think you are
the strongest man l았e ever met.
But l wonder if it압 enough.
For what?
You want this guy
for something he won앖 like.
l앐 going to kill him.
That압 something he won앖 like.
What if they grab you and ask you
how you found out?
You know l wouldn앖 turn you in.
-l wouldn앖 talk.
-What if they ask you hard?
l앏l say it was
a cab dispatcher named Stegman.
The Oakwood Arms, Union and 1 7th.
Hi, Val.
Where압 my money?
l took your gun.
lt압 back here.
You look like a pro.
lKeep your mouth shut
and you앏l walk out of here.
My 70 grand. l want it.
l don앖 have it right now.
-Where is it?
-l gave all 1 30,000 to the Outfit.
l gave it all to them.
Tell them you gave them money that
doesn앖 belong to you. Get it back.
l can앖 do that.
You don앖 know these--
You앏l kill me
whether l get it or not.
All right, l앏l get the money.
Just give me a few days.
What the fuck are you doing?
Noon. Tomorrow.
Say it.
All right.
This may sound crazy,
but no hard feelings?
l did what l had to do.
You can appreciate that.
l appreciate that, you--
No, no! Don앖.
Please.
Allow me.
Jesus!
You bitch!
Let her work.
Me love you, baby.
Me love you long time.
No, no, wait.
Tomorrow.
Noon.
You and the money be at
7th and Franklin at the pay phone.
Where앇 you get this?
Some hooker had it.
l recognized you.
l swiped it in case l could use it.
Did you hurt her?
The hooker.
What압 that have to do
with anything?
l았e got a few minutes.
So go boil an egg.
Phillip says you have a problem
you need help with.
Yes, sir.
ls it your problem...
...who breached our security
last night?
He breaks into my apartment--
There압 an old expression
that has served me well:
''Do not shit where you eat.''
Or ''live.''
''Do not shit where you live.''
l like that better.
l앐 sorry, Mr. Carter.
There are three ways
we can handle this.
One: We help you.
Two: We allow you to help yourself.
Three: We have you replaced.
We have an investment in you, Resnick,
of time, money and training.
So assisting you would be...
...in a way, protecting our investment.
And that is always
good business policy.
Yes, sir, Mr. Carter.
Thank you.
You won앖 regret it.
According to Phillip,
a man has come to town to kill you?
You say he압 alone and that he압
a professional robber. Correct?
Yes, sir. He does payroll jobs,
banks, stuff like that.
-What압 his name?
-Porter.
What압 his first name?
l don앖 know. He never called
himself anything but Porter.
Where did you get the $ 1 30,000?
That압 why this man
has come to town, huh?
The $ 1 30,000 you paid us back.
Yes, sir.
But only $70,000 of it was his.
We never asked you where you got it.
lt압 none of our business.
Now it appears
it has become our business.
Here압 his file, Mr. Carter.
Do you understand your value
to the organization?
Youre a sadist, you lack compunction.
That comes in handy.
But now, an area of your personal life
has become a danger to us.
A man in our organization needs
to be tough, self-reliant.
Were you to handle this problem
on your own...
...there would be no doubt...
...youre the kind of man we want.
l want to.
l want to handle it myself.
Great.
Until it is handled, l want you
to move out of the Oakwood Arms.
l don앖 have a place--
l don앖 want any more
unpleasantness at the hotel.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me, but it might be easier
if Resnick just disappeared.
l thought about that.
But l앐 not worried about Resnick.
He wouldn앖 last two minutes
on the street without us.
lt압 that other mutt
l앐 thinking about.
-What압 his name?
-Porter.
Takes a lot of moxie to walk into
the Outfit and whack our guys around.
Either that or he압 shit nuts.
Frankly, l don앖 understand it
for $ 1 30,000.
lt was $70,000, his share.
That압 even worse.
l don앖 want
Mr. Bronson hearing about this.
He앏l think l앐 getting soft.
His principle has always been:
''lf you don앖 understand it,
get rid of it.''
A stitch in time, so to speak.
Stitch this mutt up, Phil.
Any Polaroids or trophies?
No, not this time.
They cut me loose, Pearl,
like l thought they would.
Hold on one second.
Shut up!
l앐 on the fucking phone!
Yes?
Did your friends make it to town?
Last night, baby.
Did you tell them
Porter took their payroll?
l did.
And they want retribution.
All right. Here압 what we do.
Yeah, that압 Porter.
He has shit for brains.
Shit.
Shit!
Next time, Porter.
Porter압 made some new friends.
-Easy, mister.
-l won앖 press charges.
-Who were they?
-l don앖 know.
l앐 all right. l don앖 want--
lt압 you guys.
Stegman says you got
a line on a load of cash.
250 grand, to be exact.
Seventy.
Come on, man, get off of me!
What do you take us for?
ldiots?
Nobody앇 go through all this
for 70 grand.
You look like a whole bunch
of trouble to us.
We found a dead girl full of heroin.
There were signs of a struggle.
Were not sure it was an OD.
We got a witness.
A guy with one nostril.
Remember him?
Don앖 worry.
We앏l give you immunity.
Room to operate,
get-out-of-jail-free card.
All you got to do is get the money.
We can앖 help you, though.
-lt would be against the law.
-Understand?
-lt압 my money.
-Wrong.
lt압 our money.
Me and my partner.
You be a good boy, we give you a piece.
lt앏l be easy, Porter.
You got it?
-He압 got it.
-Understand?
-Take it easy. We앏l be in touch.
-Thanks.
What a dope!
Fuck.
Crooked cops.
Do they come any other way?
If I앇 beenjust a little dumber,
I could았ejoined the force myself.
Jesus Christ, Porter,
you need to see a doctor.
-lt압 going to sting.
-Just clean it up, all right?
You hold it there.
l앏l do it.
Tell me something, Porter.
When did you decide to leave?
That night we slept together?
No.
The next day,
when l drove you to work.
Should았e asked me to quit.
You could았e asked me
to drive you somewhere else.
Hubba, hubba, hubba.
Thanks.
Does it fit?
Like it was made for me.
lt앏l look great in your casket.
You know what l think?
l think that all those stories
about you being dead were true.
Youre too thickheaded to admit it.
God, l missed you.
l miss you.
Don앖, don앖, don앖....
l can앖. l got...
...stuff to do.
Where is he?
Porter. Where is he?
He압 in the bedroom.
ls he hurt bad?
The doctor should be here any minute.
That압 bullshit.
Here l come, pally.
Goddamn!
Get in here!
Where is he?
He압 gone, he압 gone.
Gone?
l know you.
Youre that whore from the picture.
How do you know him?
He used to drive me.
l앐 driving you now, honey.
You know what you are?
Educate me.
An ugly pig who beats up women...
...who can앖 get it up because
he압 terrified of his own shadow!
ls that right?
Then you must be the lucky girl.
Hubba, hubba, hubba!
l knew l앇 seen that ass before.
l am going to fuck you
six ways from Sunday.
l forgot my cigarettes.
All right, Val.
This Outfit, or whatever you call it,
it압 got a head man, right?
Who is it?
They앏l kill me.
What do you think l앏l do?
Worry about me.
Names. Come on.
Fairfax and Carter.
They run the whole city.
Where do l find them?
Fairfax isn앖 in town.
What about Carter?
ls he in town?
Porter, it won앖 do you any good.
Theyre going to--
Jesus!
Frederick Carter lnvestments.
1 20 Commerce Avenue.
Thanks.
All right!
l앏l help you out.
Youre fucking nuts going up
against the Outfit for 70 grand.
But l앐 going to help you out.
Here. lKeep talking.
Thanks.
l can get you in.
lt압 tighter than a drum.
How many guys?
lt압 tighter than hell.
Only one guy on the outside.
So l got a way around that.
You are crazy!
Youre a crazy son of a bitch!
That압 why l love you.
You got a light?
Then what good are you?
Check my pocket!
ls your name on the lease?
The Outfit pays for everything.
l want you to gather
everything up that you need.
Say goodbye to this place.
lt압 okay, baby.
lt압 okay, puppy.
He앏l live. How are you?
Yeah, l know.
lt압 not much,
but at least you앏l be safe.
Nobody knows l앐 here.
Sit down. Relax.
What?
Nobody has this number.
Somebody does know l앐 here.
He압 probably fucking her.
-He압 taking long enough.
-Maybe the dog too.
You think so?
Give it a minute.
Okay, let압 give him another bell.
Shit.
He압 behind us.
It압 notjust anybody that gets...
...a hit put on him by a big firm
like the Outfit.
I was moving up in the world.
Maybe it was time
to pay them a visit.
Carter wouldn앖 be expecting that.
And who knows?
I might even get my money back.
l told you he앇 show.
Give me my goddamn money, please.
-Give me my money.
-You sure that압 him?
Yeah, come on.
Thank you very much.
What you up to, buddy?
Well, our money압 in there...
...if youre still interested.
Not in the dough,
but the boat l앏l buy with it.
What압 he doing here?
lt압 a ride-along, Porter.
Your piece of the pie
just got smaller.
But don앖 worry,
l앏l leave you some crust.
What are you waiting for?
Go get it.
Go get our money.
You guys do me a favor?
Were here to help.
They앏l frisk me when l go in.
Would you hold onto this?
Just for a little while.
Sure, Porter.
Nice balance.
Douche bag.
Can l help you?
-l want to see Mr. Carter.
-And who are you?
Tell him l앐 the guy
that whacked Val Resnick.
l앐 sorry, l don앖--
Didn앖 copy. Repeat.
Right.
Mr. Carter will see you.
Turn around so l can frisk you.
Bravo. Sit down.
My compliments.
They were two of my best.
They lull too easy.
You want something from me.
Val Resnick gave you $ 1 30,000.
He paid us.
lt was a debt.
$70,000 of it is mine.
l want it back.
l앐 sorry, but l seem to have
misplaced your name.
Porter.
Porter. Right.
l won앖 forget it again.
The Outfit is not unreasonable.
But no corporation would agree
to what youre asking.
Will Fairfax give me my money?
Resnick told you quite a bit.
Fairfax will say the same thing l have.
Were not authorized
to do things like this.
Who is?
Who makes the decisions?
A committee would, in this case.
You go high enough, you always come
to one man. Who?
Mr. Bronson,
I have Mr. Carter on the line.
Put him through.
Go ahead, sir.
Carter, how압 business?
-Good till now.
-You want to see me, Dad?
Hang on, Carter.
Look in that green box, Johnny.
Are you kidding me?
ls it the convertible?
You thought l forgot.
Happy birthday, son.
This car? And Nick압 got us ringside
at the fight tonight.
It앏l be good.
My money압 on Rankin.
No, Hicks is favored.
-That압 got nothing to do with it.
-l got to go.
Thanks.
Happy birthday.
-Drive safe.
-You got it.
Sorry. What is it?
l have a problem. There압 a man
in my office with a gun...
...who says he앏l kill me
if we don앖 pay him...
...$ 1 30,000 that one of our guys
stole from him.
It압 70. How much is
this guy Carter worth to you?
What do you mean?
Either l get my money
or l앏l kill Carter.
Are you threatening me?
I앐 not threatening you.
I앐 threatening Carter.
An audacious man. Who are you?
My money, yes or no?
No.
Carter?
What압 going on there?
You just don앖 get it,
do you, you dumb fuck?
Carter, talk to me.
Call Fairfax and tell him
Ijust croaked Carter.
And he압 next. After that,
l앐 coming to get you.
Are you out of your fucking mind?
You just dug your own grave.
-l don앖 see any cash.
-They write you a check?
l have to go and see another guy.
Last one.
Then we got a dead woman and assault
to talk to you about.
That means more paperwork.
And we don앖 like paperwork.
Damn shame, Porter.
But don앖 let the bastards
get you down.
That압 right. Don앖 give up.
Can l have my piece?
Nice roscoe.
Heavy enough to be a nutcracker.
We앏l be in touch, Rocky.
lKeep up the good work.
Nobody likes a monkey on their back.
I had three.
And they were cramping my style.
I was going to
have to lighten the load.
Where have you been?
l was taking care of business.
Evening up the odds.
They won앖 stop until they kill us,
will they?
No.
l앐 sorry.
l앐 sorry l got you involved.
So why did you?
Youre a clever guy.
You didn앖 need me.
So why did you?
Yeah, youre right.
When l came back,
l came back here with nothing.
No life. No hope.
You were the only good thing
that hadn앖 been taken.
l couldn앖 stay away.
l had to see you to make sure
l wasn앖 in hell.
So why don앖 we get out of here?
-We can앖.
-Why?
They won앖 stop until they bury us.
So?
So we bury them first.
l should have quit.
l should have driven you
somewhere else.
That압 me!
Happy birthday, Johnny.
-You are the man!
-This is your night.
l앐 your birthday present.
-Who압 that?
-You sons of bitches!
We didn앖 do it.
Dude, she압 so hot.
Oh, man, she압 so fine.
Youre all over it. Go!
Look at this guy!
Dad압 really hooking him up.
Boy, you are cute, aren앖 you?
You must have some pretty
wonderful friends, Johnny.
Wealthy too, because l앐 not cheap.
Don앖 wait up, boys.
l promise he won앖 be home
before midnight.
See you!
Damn!
That압 a good boy.
Yeah, right there.
Relax.
Who압 the professional here?
So go with it.
l promise you won앖 regret it.
There, baby.
Relax, kid,
no one앏l get hurt.
Get hurt?
What압 he talking about?
Good to have you back, Mr. Fairfax.
l wish l could say the same. l was
swimming with dolphins this morning.
Easy! lt압 genuine alligator.
What압 the matter with you?
Sorry, Mr. Fairfax.
How압 it going, Charlie?
Porter and Fairfax.
That앏l be a short conversation.
Between us and our neighborhood cops,
l앇 say we got him well covered.
Walter, wake up.
Wake up!
lKeep those bags up, boys.
Come on.
Who the hell are you?
l앐 the reason youre home early.
Youre Porter?
That압 it. lKeep them up
or l앏l drill you.
What will you have me do?
Stand on my head?
l want you to do me a favor.
Call Mr. Bronson.
See what we can do
about getting my money back.
He let Carter die.
That poor bastard압
better off dead anyway.
He앇 probably let me die too.
With Carter,
he thought l was bluffing.
Try him. He might be more
receptive than you think.
All right.
You two are fired.
Well, it압 like this.
l앐 in my living room.
There압 a man named Porter...
...who says that
he expects you to pay him.
Of course.
He wants to talk to you.
Put it on the speaker.
-This is Porter.
-You got balls, Porter.
You았e proven to be a pain
in the ass. A mosquito.
To get rid of you,
l앏l swat you with 1 30 grand.
lt압 not a hund--
-What the hell are you doing?
-Fairfax?
lt압 all right. He압 just
killing my alligator bags...
...and shooting holes in my suits.
That압 mean, man!
You aren앖 listening.
lt압 not 1 30--
No, you listen.
You앏l get your money,
but you앏l never live to enjoy it.
You let me worry about that.
l want you to deliver
the money yourself.
Youre one hell of an optimist.
What makes you think
l앏l deliver it myself?
lf you don앖,
you앏l never see Johnny again.
Didn앖 come home last night, did he?
He압 a good-looking kid,
but you indulge him too much.
I told him so.
Bullshit. You haven앖 got him.
-Youre not that stupid.
-My dad never bought me a Ferrari.
l had to steal my first one.
Nice inscription on the key chain.
A little sappy.
Want me to read it?
Youre dead.
Nobody fucks with my family.
You hear me?
Youre a dead man.
That압 Johnny, unless you
turn up with the money.
ls that a yes?
What? Cat got your crotch?
Some decisions are hard, Mr. Bronson.
Where?
l앏l let you know.
I앏l be in touch.
You just signed your own
death warrant for $ 1 30,000.
l don앖 get that. What is it?
The principle or something?
Stop it, l앐 getting misty.
And tell him it압 70.
Seventy?
What do you mean, it압 only 70?
Only 70,000?
My suits are worth more than that!
Oh, man!
Listen to this:
''Ocean Ray Sundancer.
lcemaker. Camper canvas.
Vacuum-flush head.
Eighty thousand bucks.''
He ain앖 going to have it.
You want to bet?
No, l don앖 want to bet.
l앐 out 1 50 already.
1 50 ain앖 getting my damn boat.
He better come down with something.
Hicks. Leary.
Were Holland and Van Owen.
lnternal Affairs.
Back off.
Were on a stakeout.
Step out of the car, please.
What for?
Step out of the car, detectives.
What the hell압 going on?
l don앖 know.
ls this your badge?
The one you reported missing?
Where앇 you find it?
Where did you lose it?
Does this belong to you?
lt압 Porter. Follow him.
l got that motherfucker.
Get in.
Close the door.
Set the roscoe on the floor.
Slow!
l앐 going to turn you in
to the Outfit for a reward.
Maybe they앏l ask me to join,
and l앏l be on easy street.
Medical. Dental.
l앐 going to walk you right in.
Porter on the hoof.
Unless you get rambunctious.
Then l앏l take care of you--
Youre not going to kill me, are you?
Let him go!
Now.
Hubba, hubba, hubba.
Who are you?
What are you doing?
Fat boy!
Yeah, l앐 talking to you.
Stop it. Stop it.
l hate this. l hate it!
Look at this stinking place!
Porter, what압 the matter with you?
Tell us where he is
so we can get out of here.
Come on.
Too late now.
He doesn앖 want to say anything.
He just wants to get himself beat up,
that압 all.
Here it is.
1 30,000.
That압 as close as
you앏l ever get to it.
l앏l make you a deal.
Tell me where John is,
and l앏l finish you quick.
You won앖 have to find out
what your left ball tastes like.
But if there압 even a bruise on him,
l앏l make this last three weeks.
l앏l give you a blood transfusion
to keep you alive.
Where is he?
l앐 waiting.
This piggy went to the market.
l앐 listening.
This piggy stayed home.
Starting to look like roast beef.
Eight to go.
Then it압 your knees.
You can guess where we go from there.
Where is he?
Twenty-four....
Twenty-four Fielding.
Apartment 1 1 .
You앏l understand
if l don앖 trust you.
Put him in the trunk.
We앏l take him along.
Let압 go, tough guy.
You two watch the front.
Fuck! Come on, Porter.
Hey, give me a light.
-What the hell압 going on?
-You were right not to trust me.
Help me.
Get out!
Come on, Porter.
lt압 been fun. See you later.
Get back here!
You bitch!
Come on, Porter.
Let압 go.
What took you so long?
Come on, Porter.
Get in.
Good boy.
What happened?
l got hammered.
You okay?
You got it.
Piece of cake.
Where to?
Just drive, baby.
We were going for breakfast...
...in Canada.
We made a deal:
If she앇 stop hooking...
...I앇 stop shooting people.
Maybe we were aiming high.