Game industried has always tried to bring
video games and digital far than 3d technology
have you ever thought if you send
any data over internet
how it will go from 1 corner
to other corner?
We have lots of rays and frequencies
around us
it has been spread into our
world like fire
and this world is always around us
because of these days all digital
data travels
mr barren could not come here to
welcome you, he has sent his welcome photo
can i bring this photo in this conference
room without any gadget?
Our technology is about that
it has made from those rays which
are always around you
but you cant see them
with our technology you can
see and touch them
you can move the distance between
real and virtual world
sometimes to save life we have
to kill someone
for everyone
and i had a fight with father
of all
only he could fight with me
all girls love me
i dont like uninvited guests
i always come without invitation
just now i killed spider man
with baygon spray.
With insect are you?
Dont worry my girl.
Then will you come with me for dinner?
But i dont want to eat chinese
if your talk is finished than
can we start fighting?
Stand up
i cant talk on the phone
what is going on in office?
Someone has called him jackie chan
i'm not interested in looking at
your ugly face in the morning
our company has got a very big
contract to make a game
it will be released in india
my last 2 games were floped
if this game will also be flop
then i will shutdown this company
i will not fire anyone because
i will open a restaurant here
is anyone has any problem?
I have a problem
what is your problem?
I dont know how to make idlee
you are not taking me seriously
when my book will be on best seller list
than you will see how it helped me
it is necessary for all girls
of india
why all girls in india are like this?
I'm not singing,
i'm saying
tell me something about your
new video game
its a new game
it has a very fresh hero
then who do you like?
Villain dont have any rules.
They just have to win
make a game in which villain
will never lose
hero always wins
goodness always win against
badness
move fast we have to
go to school
your father will drop you at school
if father will drive then we will
reach office day after tomorrow
i want to tell you 1 thing
you like villains then i will make a game
in which villain will be more powerful than hero
badness is not good
whenever i use computer or play game
my name is whisper
it means her computer will connect
her computer with all of our computers
she will ask for permission.
We all will say no
one fat boy will say yes
i have a very good idea for
our new video game
i did not put this smile in program
then why ra. One is smiling in game?
Is program learning things by itself?
This is the main part of our game
it will be the power of all players
after winning each level it power
increases
until this heart is attaching ra. One or g. One
they cannot be died
they will not die by breaking heart
they will not die by beating them
if their both hearts are attached together
then we can kill them
how they will die?
Whoever shoot first on target
will win
so this heart is their strength and
weakness too
in this movie villain lost and
hero won
thats why film was flopped
did not you see villain was very cool?
People die by smoking
we both can break his teeths
take it as a tip
did you see how i scared them?
I'm not a coward
i'm not a coward
check correctly
there will be a game's launch in 2 days,
there should not be any problem
have a look at most fabolous game
he can become anything
any face, anything.
And this artificial program
he can learn anything
same danger will not come everytime
every player will get a super
hero to fight with ra. One
and you will get a suit to play
this game
every player can become g. One
i want to play this game now
this game will finish when i
will kill you
i have to stay in lab,
there is a problem in the game
you hugged your father
i wanted to say that game was great
we live in 1 house,
i can say tomorrow too
ra. One is not stopping
where ra. One is gone?
I will kill you
how it happened?
Ra. One told me he will find me
first control suit of this
game is yours
i have made ra. One like you want
if ra. One is made from bad thinking
then g. One is made from my feelings
you can see it and touch it too
if you will stuck in game then
my g. One will show you way
it means ra. One has become kashee
i was saying correctly,
ra. One has killed papa
ra. One has turned into kashee.
We are getting late for flight
you wait there i'm coming
upload ra. One's back up program
it doesnot have any back up program
if you will stuck in game then
my g. One will show you way
there is only 1 way to stop ra. One.
G. One
if ra. One can come out then
g. One can also come out
we can try to follow these steps and
bring ra. One out
i just saw akash going up
sonia called me. Ra. One is coming.
You go up
i have to take out g. One
ra. One is coming after you.
He does not know me
what is going on?
Why he is following us?
How ra. One can come out of game?
How he can become akash?
I will tell you everything later
i dont want to understand anything.
I want to go back india
there will be no ra. One and g. One
why he is coming with us?
G. One saved us
he cannot come
i dont understand anything.
Try to understand
i will understand everything later
how we will bring him out from
metal detector?
Try to understand he cannot come with us
g. One will do cool move
what are you doing?
Do like ra. One
i cannot do like ra. One
i'm not strong like ra. One
you made you taxi driver?
Will you come?
I bring you
what are you doing?
I will reset him and press play button
he is a man,
not a tape recorder
if someone is dead,
he cannot come back
like people change clothes,
soul can change bodies
tell him to leave him
you cannot touch me here
you cannot touch me anywhere
i have to touch you
she is my mom
yesteday is behind,
future is ahead
what did you say?
There is a shekhar's folder in my program,
there are so many shekhar's line in that folder
i have to go to electricity ward
you scared me
go and stand by somewhere else
when everything will be ok then
i have to do something for him
he cannot live with us?
He is not a tv or toaster that
we can keep him on side
he talks like human
do you think g. One was
right about geeta?
That dad has come back by becoming
g. One
do you remember whenever we are
in danger what papa said?
I have charged inverter
do say this infront of children
i will run.
Do anything you want
i know what i have to do
with him
it was my mistake
i told father to make a game in which
villain never lose
if we beated ra. One that day
then papa would be with us
there is no nutritional element in it
do you know every year 1000
people quit smoking?
No by dieing
i think you are same like us
how you gone mad?
Someone is coming out from your nose
why do we pray?
So that god can protect us
so god comes out and protect us
do you believe in angels?
You just make our game famous in
mumbai expo
its just a shadow
vijay subhrimaniyam's son
i'm incomplete without my heart
they have gone
and i dont have their new address
why you need to do it?
I can read your mind
i can control your mind too
shekhar's and mine lots of memories
are attached with this house
thats why i wanted to come here
we cannot stay at 1 place for long
we have to go from here
if we will destroy his heart still
he will not stop following us
we will always run from him
if we will not destroy heart then we
have to face him
its a emotional decision
you have to make a decision
i have only this house and shekhar's
memory left
i will not run anymore.
Shekhar believed in goodness
promise me you will take
care of pratiek
it is not in my program
that you have done for us
what is all this?
We are burning ra. One
we burn him this day
you burn ra. One every year because you
know he never dies
you look good in papa's clothes
here everyone knows shekhar.
Dont make problem here
shekar has made this video game
for pratiek
he wanted to give him on his
birthday
if you will give him this game
then he will feel good
i will also like it
your magic show is there
and shekhar will dance here
shekhar cant dance
go back from here.
We need g. One
g. One need us
dont be scared. Until g. One bring my
heart back i will not kill you
pratiek is not a part of this game
he was not.
But you made him
she is in my control
she is in a train that will not
stop on its station
in that exhibition where our
game is going to launch
go and free them
i will not wait for you
leaving seat is not allowed
dont talk to anyone or
eat anything
train did not stop on signal
nothing will happen to him
will you save my pratiek?
I'm g. One.
Thats why i'm made
only i have to go
you asked my once does angel exists?
Yes they exists
i'm here g. One
if you will be late then...
until your heart is with me you cant
kill him
until my heart is with you,
you cant kill me
until our hearts are connected with
system we cant die
its very simple for me
i have come here to kill you
g. One dont give him heart.
Your chances of save are 0.01'/,
why you want to die?
Because i made a promise to someone
i'm having headache
what are you doing?
Dont try to fight.
Try to be safe
g. One hold his main part
what are you doing?
Neighther you can run
nor you can fight
fight can be win with heart
now our heart is not our weakness,
it will become our strength
there must be something is this game,
father has left something in it
if i want to kill ra. One then i have
to bring him to my world
please dont go.
I dont want to lose my father
you will never lose your father
until you have goodness in your heart,
your father will always be with you
good people died but their
goodness always alive
we both killed ra. One
i'm very happy that you both
have come back
how is pratiek?
Whole day he uses computer
dont take his hope from him
where is my hero?
Ra. One can come back,
he is here