Thousands took to the streets
and thousands kill...
Many peaceful protesting monks have been
killed, some burnt alive and others drowned..
Foreign journalists have been shot and caned..
Thousands of villages have been destroyed.
Rape and torture are a daily occurrence.
In Burma there are more landmines,
than anywhere in the world.
Young men are bitten and forced into
the army. Many as young as 12 years old.
Beheadings and mutilations
are common.
The Karen people comprising mostly of poor Christian
farmers have been singled out for extermination.
The military government wants many of
the abundance resources on the Karen land.
The bloody military campaign against the Karen
people has been going on for almost 60 years.
The longest radical war in the world.
Ready. Send them out!
Move!
Shoot them all!
OK.
Looks like dangerous work.
I am Michael Burnett.
Do you have some time to talk?
Won't take too long, I promise.
I was told it might be possible to
rent your boat. We like to do that.
Is that possible?
We need to get up river.
Where are you going?
Into Burma.
Burma is a war zone.
That's what people call it.
But it's more like genocide than war.
This will be my fifth trip in,
we are aware of all the risk.
I don't go that far north.
Let me explain our situation.
Our church is part of the Pan-Asia
ministry..
located in Colorado.
We are all volunteers, whom
around this time of the year,
bring in medical supplies,
medical attention..
prayer books and support to the
Karen tribe's people.
People say you know the river
better than anyone.
They lied.
What I am asking is, we compensate you...
for a few hours of your time..
to help change people's lives.
Are you bringing in any weapons?
Of course not.
You are not changing anything.
It's thinking like that,
that keeps the world the way it is.
F..k the world.
- Let's go
- Why?
He's not interested.
- Let me try.
- Sara...
It'll be an interesting trip going up there.
What do we have to lose?.
Let me try.
Sarah.
Hello?
I am Sarah Miller. Hope you don't
mind me coming back here.
The man you were talking to...
I wasn't talking to anybody.
Ok, the man that was talking to you..
asked if we could hire your boat
to go up river.
and you said no, why?
Can't help you out.
If you have some reasons,
mind if I heard them?
Go home.
Why did you come back?
Waiting for you.
I told you before,
I can't help you.
We need to know why you
can't help these people.
We are here to make a difference.
We believe all lives are special.
Some lives, some no.
Really?
If everyone thought like you,
nothing will ever change.
Nothing will change.
Of course it does.
Nothing stays the same.
Value your life, it's a good one
It's what I am trying to do!
No, what you are trying to do
is change what is.
And what is?
Go home.
Really.
Maybe...
Maybe you lost your faith in people.
But you feel the same for something.
You must still care for something.
Maybe we can't change what it is,
But trying to save a life,
isn't wasting your life. Is it?
As bad as these people are,
they will eventually lose.
They can't keep it up against a united front.
They can't!
Time alone will tell. In the meantime,
we just got to hold it together.
Just the other day...
Excuse me, Sara?
Where are you going?
To talk to him.
He'll probably want his privacy.
Michael, you shouldn't worry,
he's helping us.
He's being paid.
He didn't take anything.
Thank you again for doing this.
Really from all of us.
You never told us your name.
John.
Where are you from?
Arizona.
- Why did you leave?
- I got drafted in Vietnam.
And you just stayed?
It's complicated.
You have a family back home?
Father maybe.
I don't know.
Aren't you curious to see what
might have changed back home?
Don't have a reason for that.
Sara.
Because of you we going,
I'll approve it..
anytime you want to turn around...
...it is done.
Ok.
What is it?
Who are they?
Burmese pirates.
Everyone sit down,
don't make a sound.
- It's all right.
- Don't talk.
- Are there more of them?
- Maybe.
We will know?
We should keep going.
We made a commitment.
I ain't talking to you.
What do you want to do? - We are a
group here. They want to vote. Vote.
Sit down!
If it is money they want...
Nobody talks. Heads down!
What are you doing?
We come here to stop the killing.
Who are you to kill?
- Who are you?
- Let him go!
You want them to rape her
fifty times and cut her head off!
Who are you?
Who are any of you?
We are going back.
No. We shouldn't go back!
Let go.
- What are you doing?
- We are so close!
What has happened here is horrible...
But what the people in there are
being killed like this every day.
Michael this was your idea.
We made a commitment.
I know you don't believe
in what we are doing,
But it is our lives.
Our choice.
You are not going to change anything.
Please
Please John.
Go sit down.
We are taking the overland route on the way
back, so there is no need to wait around.
I have to report this.
I know you think what you did is right,..
but taking a life is never right.
I don't know what to say.
Maybe you shouldn't say anything.
Should you? Good Luck.
KLAW KBE LO LANDSBYEN.
Open your mouth.
We signify your faith with
this little flower, ok?
Hey dear. Can you hand
over the bandages?
Get out of here!
What about them?  Go on, take them!
......calling Raven.
Over...
What am I?
We made you this way.
You are a full blooded combat soldier.
Talk to me Johnny!
You don't just turn it off!
- It's over!
- Nothing is over!
Aren't you curious how things
might have changed back home?
You have done enough damage!
You will always be tearing away soldier..
till you come to terms with what you are.
So you are just going to stay here forever?
John Rambo!
John.
John Rambo.
My name is Arthur Marsh.
Pastor of Christ Church Colorado.
I need to talk with you.
It is very important, otherwise
I won't come here like this.
The morning of the day the group left,..
Michael Burnet notified me...
that they were traveling through this location.
What happened?
No one knows exactly.
They will supposed to return 10 days ago,
but they never came back.
I requested help from the embassy,
but they can't help.
Not in Burma and not in time.
How do you know they are alive?.
Because we have been in contact
with the Karen freedom fighters,
who say they think they know
where they were taken.
I was given the name of an ex-military
American local from the embassy..
who put me in touch with men who say they
have experience in this part of the world.
Mercenaries?
Yes.
I don't have any other choice.
You know the exact spot.
We need you to take these men,
to where you let our people off.
When are they ready to leave?
When you are.
You know what you are.
What you are made off.
War is in your blood.
Don't fight it.
Did you kill for your country?
Did you kill for yourself?
God is never going to make that go away.
When you are pushed...
Killing is as easy as breathing.
Look at this f..king place!
Only a f..king ape would live here?
What am I doing here?
Hey, knock that shit off!
And you don't like the arts?
And you don't like the shit.
I like your sister, Diaz.
She got a thing for retards.
Hey boatman!
How much longer in this ancient piece of shit?
What did the reverent say?
Something about his flock went missing.
I said look mate, that is what you get
when you're trespassing into Burma.
That's what you get, when you go around
sniffing other people's garbage.
You know those generals in there are making millions,
cranking up more than anyone in this planet.
Bullshit!
Millions, Moron. How do you
think they paid for that shit all ?
Try to read the papers
instead of sticking under it.
The general is the biggest junkies
of all of them.
It's noble Louis..
You are? Those people going in
without weapons.
Just books and medicine.
It's noble.
Ok, schoolboy!
You stick your nose in other people's
business, you get f..k up...
or you are dead.
The only reason I am doing this
is for an ex-wife and 3 kids.
and after the shit is over, you can
shove that right up your ass.
- Try to think careful, mate!
- Back off!
And you, I don't want to die of old age
before I get there. So move.
You said something?
S.P.D.C. LET INFANTERY BATTALION 360
Is it me? Or is it the air coming in
smelling like some wet dog?
For f..k sake, I can swim faster than this.
- Am I right?
- We dead.
Chop, chop. The quicker we are there,
the quicker we get back.
Those idiots.
They come here..
start all the trouble...
... expecting the whole world to work
like their old neighbours. Well it doesn't..
So they send in the devil...
... to do god's work.
Ironic isn't it?
Am I boring you man?
Is it the trip? It's got you nervous?
Because we..
...we really appreciate the action.
You know what I mean?
Look at me in the eyes if
you know what I am saying.
Oh dear..
You are really an uptight master,
aren't you?
You can drop the act in your stare.
I have seen it all before.
I am not impressed.
He's old school, SAS.
The first rate soldier to be
told to go maniac.
They call him schoolboy.
The name stuck with him since.
The name he start calling me
no matter how many people I shoot.
What do you want from us?
One man and a kid in a chicken coop.
This sort of rebel they put up.
I am not liking it You are in a jungle,
there is nothing to like.
How are you doing?
My name is Bieth, this is Tha.
This is it?
What's with the kid?
He's a good tracker.
We don't need a tracker. We need a guide.
You know the exact location right?
10 km west.
To north 6 km walk.
- How many soldiers?
- 100 maybe.
- 100?
Heard what he said.
- More soldiers coming tomorrow.
I know I'm just a white trash
full of blanks, but I can count.
...stop f..king with the 100 strong.
Alright, alright!
Let's get this straight.
We don't engage anybody.
If we can extract these people, good.
It's in, out, clean, or we go off.
Somebody want to tell me
what the boatman is doing?
Why don't you wait with the boat.
- My man will stay with the boat.
- Your boat, you stay here.
I won't slow you down.
No, you won't.
It's not a nature hunt?
You can believe that.
He can be with me at the back.
He stays here. He's the boatman.
He stays with the boat.
Only a white man with a f..king dick.
Who has the explosives?
I've got some C4.
- I’ve got a claymore.
- Alright.
Let's go on with it.
Come on, move.
What is that?  ### bomb.
English dropped it in World War II.
Your people taken from here.
In my life, I've seen some shit.
But I've seen no shit like this.
Check it out!
All these commies, kill everything,
People are dead here as warning.
Mines, everywhere.
Watch where you are walking.
- Alright let's move on.
- To what?
They even kill the dogs.
Those people are dead. I'm with Kenji.
At least to have a look see.
Check it out.
I'm with you.
Check what? They are 100 strong.
We told the man's money.
Hey, calm down.
We got to see what is wrong.
If anything is wrong, anything at all,
we leave. Alright?
Yes.
I order.
Good.
This way.
- Army!
- Go!
I'm going to fire at them.
No, if they don't make it back from where
the hell they came from, they'll be on to us.
Who are you boatman?
- Let's move. - Move?
They are going to come after us,
when these guys don't show up.
We don't need this shit.
We are going back to the boat.
Any of you boys want to shoot,
now is the time.
Any reason one of us just
doesn't want to surprise us.
But this is what we do.
Who we are.
Live for nothing.
Or die for something.
Your call!
What's your call?
Let's move.
Once Schoolboy's on the tower, we've
got 15 mins. Set your watches to 1:45.
And we won't wait for anybody.
We meet at the base of the tower.
We don't meet up there, we f..ked.
All set?
Set!
Go!
Don't talk. Hear me out.
Where is the girl?
She's over there.
Go untie him. I'll be back again.
Here!
There's two in the cage.
Near the pitch. Get them.
Come on!
Let's move!
Where is the boatman?
And Sarah.
15 minutes. That's the deal.
We're leaving.
Let's go!
5 more minutes.
Bullshit!
He knew the deal.
If we're getting away,
we f..king leave together!
Your live.
Let's go!
Not without her!
Who do you think save your life?
We did.
Get up!
- You got us covered?
- Yes.
Why did you come back?
Why did you do?
This way.
My leg.
Hold still!
Shut up.
We got you. We're getting you out.
His leg is broken!
Where is the guide?
He's gone!
- We're not going to make it to the river with him.
- Will you shut up.
Untie his lace.
Take of his boot.
No! Leave his boot on.
....I need a knife.
- Is he going to make it?
- I don't know. Make him stretch.
Spread out!
Take the point.
Hear that?
They're tracking us.
- Turn around.
- What are you doing?
I want you two to go to the river.
The boat is waiting.
It's out there.
You can follow the shore line.
- What about you?
- I'll be alright.
Give me the claymine.
- Fire of a shot.
- What?
Fire off a shot!
Go! Go!
Let's move.
- Wait.
- Where are they?
- Son of a bitch!
- Look
Oh God!
Oh damn it!
F..k you!
Come on to me, you lady boy!
What did we do?
We did nothing.
What are we going to do?
We can't do anything.
Karen rebels.
Michael!
THE END
Subtitles by: Reklame