Abdul Elijah says we're in business.
Get the capital in safe place, okay?
Meet me back here 3:00. Bring me a key.
We go check the color of your green.
Your shipment's on its way. You have a
small item for me. I give you a courier.
Bless Abdul Elijah
and the brotherhood.
Nice doing business, comrade.
Oh! Attention!
Fun bag patrol.
Double bogies, 11:00.
Whew, Christ!
You think she bought those?
I don't think so.
I think those
are definitely home grown.
Art!
Just an opinion.
Jesus!
-Guy's gotta be dead not to notice that.
-What's the matter with you?
I'm a man. I got needs.
We're on the job. Come on.
We oughta arrest her.
- What'd you squeeze him with?
- Caught him packin' on parole.
Gave him a choice:
Whisper in my ear...
or I turn him into Joliet Prison
for five years.
He tipped you to
a big cleanhead deal?
Don't tell me we're popping cleanheads.
I hate the cleanheads!
You're this close
to losing your job.
Can you give us a second, Charlie?
Yeah, all right.
You're not helping yourself.
This is a good tip.
I got it from my guy Streak.
All right. Come on, let's go.
Freeze! Police! Hands up!
Shut up!
You ain't got shit!
Follow me. You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can be used
against you in court.
Outside stairwell!
Freeze, motherfucker!
Don't get nervous.
I do this for a living.
You look like Marvin Hagler.
I lost money on Hagler!
Hey! How long you gonna be in there?
You're not even using the goddamn phone!
Jerk.
America.
Chicago. Gangsters.
- How you doing, honey?
- Blow yourself.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
It's good thinking.
Should be out any second.
He's going through customs
right now.
You read the report Stobbs wrote
on the cleanhead bust?
- He says your performance was adequate.
- Adequate. Jesus Christ! What a jerk!
It's a personality thing.
Stobbs just doesn't like yours.
Ten to one he doesn't speak English.
- Captain Danko.
- Yes.
I'm Detective Sergeant Gallagher,
Chicago Police Department.
- Glad to meet you.
- Thank you.
This is my partner,
Detective Sergeant Ridzik.
- First time in Chicago?
- Yes.
You have a nice flight?
Yes, fine.
- You hungry?
- No.
Thirsty?
Hate to break this up, but I'm parked
in a red zone. No offense.
We got a car waiting outside
for you.
It's a half-hour drive
to the city.
It's a nice drive.
You'll enjoy it.
Nice night.
Been real hot lately. Nothing hotter
than Chicago in August.
It's the humidity
that gets to you.
Humidity. You know,
moisture in the air.
How's it been in Moscow?
Hot.
No moisture.
Where'd you learn
to speak English so well?
Army.
Compulsory training.
Language school in Kiev.
Oh, yeah. That's like
in Chicken Kiev.
We had that at my sister's wedding.
Viktor Rosta must've pissed off
a lot of commissars...
for them to send someone
all this way to baby-sit him home.
What did he do?
Pee on the Kremlin?
I gotta apologize
for my partner, Captain.
He's just naturally suspicious.
Did you arrest Viktor?
- Me? It was patrolmen.
- Where?
Right near his hotel,
The Garvin.
It's a breeding ground for pushers,
pimps, prostitutes.
Take me there.
We got you booked
at the Executive House.
Please. Garvin.
You sure you wanna stay here?
It's horrible. You have a choice.
I stay here.
- If you're on a budget--
- Thank you.
I will be fine.
You're the boss.
I'll pick you up
at 9:00 in the morning.
Nice talking to you, Captain.
- What do you think?
- I think he's a jerk.
- Danko.
- You're welcome.
Put your name in the big book
right there.
You had man here called "Rosta."
Viktor Rosta.
- A Russian?
- Soviet.
I want same room.
Are you Russian too?
Nice going.
It's 302.
Right up those stairs.
Capitalism.
This is our booking area.
Looks like a major crime wave
just hit, right?
When I first got here
when I was first assigned here...
I thought all hell
had broken loose.
Nope. It was just
a typical Monday morning.
Is that a Russian cop uniform?
Looks like a glorified postman
or something out of World War Two.
- Be respectful to our guest, Audrey.
- Yes, sir.
Not king.
Checkmate in two moves.
Use bishop to queen four.
Thanks for your advice, comrade,
but I think I got it covered.
This way, Captain.
The nerve of that guy.
Captain Danko, Moscow Militia.
This is Commander Donnelly,
chief of this district.
Thanks, Tom. The Captain
will be with you in a minute.
This is an extradition order.
It only requires your signature.
He ran a red light.
No driver's license.
The officer found a gun in
his glove box, so he brought him in.
We shook him down.
Then he refused to speak English.
When we found the cyrillic writing
tattoo, we figured he was one of yours.
Viktor did not ask
for political asylum?
I think he wants to go home.
Audrey, go get Sergeant Ridzik.
Right.
Stress management.
You watch the fishes.
You water the plants.
Special breathing exercises.
Monitor your blood pressure.
Listen to pleasant sounds.
Relax.
Personally, I think it
may all be a pile of shit!
But when you're facing a bypass,
you stop asking questions.
Look...
just out of curiosity, and since
I figure cops are cops everywhere...
how do you Soviets deal
with all the stress?
Vodka.
Yes, sir.
I want you to ride with Gallagher
and the Captain to the city jail.
Make sure he signs this form
before they go to the airport.
Then bring the top copy back.
Just bring the top form
back to me.
- Yes, sir.
- That'll make it official.
So long, Captain.
Nice doing business with you.
- Gallagher! Taxi service.
- Right.
You can tell they're old buddies.
Body language is a beautiful thing.
We are ready.
Yes, sir.
- Do you know what this key opens?
- Looks like a locker key.
Why don't you ask your bud?
You try it.
Where is the locker...
that this key opens?
- What'd he say?
- He say...
"Go and kiss your mother's behind."
You son of a bitch!
Come here!
Motherfucker!
- Take it easy!
- I'm fine!
- Take it easy.
- I'm fine. Happens all the time.
Every day someone tells me
to go fuck my mother's ass.
- Have you seen my mother's ass?
- No, I haven't.
Well, you'd want to fuck it too.
He shouldn't have said that
about my mom.
What do you care? It's not your case.
It's not my case.
- It's not even an American case.
- Right, right.
We're just an escort service here.
Pull back on your emotions.
How can I let what he said pass?
Find a middle ground.
This way, clown.
All right, I'm outta here.
Look, Captain,
have a good flight back.
If you get a chance to flush
this turd down the toilet...
do it over the Pole.
By the way, you were right about
that chess move. I was dead in two.
It was obvious.
Forgive Ridzik, Captain.
He's been having a hard time lately.
- Put himself in a jam--
- I try to forget Ridzik.
- Hey, Bernie.
- Yes, sir.
Give me a Sun Times and
a Racing Action tip sheet.
You got a winner?
Move!
- Come on, let's go!
- The key!
Come on, man!
Let's go! Let's move!
- How's he doing, Doctor?
- It's still early.
There's no fracture,
but Danko does have a concussion.
We're gonna need him
to make a full statement.
I don't think you should expect
much out of him today.
Thank you very much.
Gallagher didn't even
get a shot off.
I think it was the cleanheads
who did it.
That's possible. They all walked
yesterday morning. Illegal warrant.
Even the guy with the shotgun?
Walked right out the door
with a handshake from the judge.
- Shit.
- Listen to this.
This guy you shot there,
according to his l.D., he's Russian.
Can you believe that?
I'm sorry, but the police department
will have to bear with us.
Captain Danko should remain
incommunicado.
The Russians got a chance
to talk to him. Why?
They were the closest thing to family
and they weren't gonna interrogate.
How did you get that piece
through customs?
Diplomatic immunity.
Great. That restores my faith
in airport security.
You're not supposed to have
that gun, Danko.
I'll tell you what, though.
Tell me what's going on with Viktor
and you keep the gun.
Take it.
Come on, gimme a break
with this shit.
Maybe this Russian bully stuff
works on a chessboard, but not here.
You retire the uniform?
I am now undercover.
Undercover?
You look like Gumby.
You're gonna fit right in.
For your information, Captain,
I shot one of your Russians.
Unfortunately, he's not dead.
He's in intensive care.
When he comes to,
maybe you should talk to him.
How long before this happens?
Is this 60 Minutes?
Do I look like a doctor?
Other things first.
Hey, Gumby?
Where do you think you're going?
Lighten up. I got it.
Thanks.
- What are you doing out of bed?
- He thinks he's gonna find Viktor.
- That's cute. Keep an eye on him.
- Why me?
Because I said so.
He's a material witness.
Maybe Donnelly can figure out
what to do.
- How come I get all the shit jobs?
- Because it fits you.
- You come with me?
- You heard. I just got my orders.
- Take me to the same hotel?
- Do I look like a cab?
Yes.
I just took him back
to the hotel.
He went in,
came out ten minutes later.
I didn't know what to do,
so I brought him here.
Okay. Good.
About your involvement in this,
you know standard procedure.
If you're a witness to a murder, you
can't be active in the investigation.
Okay, I know.
I'm not taking you off the case.
You and Gallagher were friends.
I'll fit you in somehow.
Send in Danko.
The two Russian suits
that showed up at the hospital.
They want Danko in a big way.
So I told them we'd put him
on a plane soon.
Please be seated, Captain.
You've met Lieutenant Stobbs?
Stobbs is the point man
in this investigation.
We met. I'd like to run
this by you, Captain.
"Viktor Rosta. Full name,
Viktor Sedgavich Rostavili.
"Born September 4, 1944.
Georgia, Russia.
"His father had the distinction
of being hanged by the U.S.S.R....
"for the crime of Brigandage."
Brigandage?
Burning villages, raping women.
That goes on in Russia?
In past, during war.
Not now.
According to you.
According to this...
Viktor spent three years
in the army and six...
on a forced labor camp
for drug offenses.
"Is currently wanted
in the U.S.S.R.....
"for murder, kidnapping, rape...
"extortion,
currency speculation...
"and drug dealing."
Where did you get this information?
Your boys in Washington have decided
to be cooperative since Viktor split.
In fact, they got
a whole new attitude.
I hear they're sending
over some caviar.
Why didn't you tell us
this before?
I had no authorization.
Bullshit!
My government does not like
to do laundry in public.
Anything else we should know?
I will not leave this country
without Viktor.
I need cooperation.
You wanna stick around...
and find Viktor, Captain,
that's fine by me.
One more thing.
I don't want the press
to get near you.
And don't roll through town
like the Red Army!
Have you wigged out?
Danko is the perfect weapon;
a loose cannon.
If he helps us find Rosta,
great.
If he screws up, breaks rules,
he's a Russian.
- But what about Ridzik?
- Ridzik is a good cop.
And a total expert at fucking up.
Departmentally speaking,
I got no downside here.
I'm having them bring in
Gallagher's snitch...
the guy who helped us bust
the cleanheads.
He's a sleaze, but I think he can tell
us who's brokering the cleanhead's deal.
He visits Viktor in jail?
Only two folks had that honor:
A skirt named Cat Manzetti
and that Russian I shot.
The girl teaches dance
in Wicker Park for the city.
We're gonna try to catch up
with her later on tonight.
About this pile of shit pimp here.
In this country, we try to protect
the rights of individuals.
It's called the Miranda Act, and it says
you can't even touch his ass.
I do not want to touch his ass.
I want to make him talk.
I'm gonna handle this one.
Hey, Streak.
- You can't hold me here, Dickweed!
- Hostility.
You got nothing on me.
This is bullshit!
- Easy.
- Where is Viktor?
What the fuck are you doing?
I don't know who he thinks he is.
I'll have both your badges!
Easy, Streak.
Just sit down, relax.
I wanna ask you a couple of questions
about the cleanheads.
Fair price for services rendered?
Capitalism works, right, Streak?
Cleanheads got a monster deal going
down. I told Gallagher. End of story.
He lies.
In this country, he has
that God-given right.
Do I smell heroin?
- What's this?
- Come on, man!
-You bring this into the police station?
-You planted that.
That's disrespectful.
This is distribution weight.
Fuckin' cop setup!
You're fired.
Cleanheads' deal:
who, when and where?
The lawyer I got makes ACLU
look like Nazis.
He lives for cop misconduct.
Probably sue you for free.
And I ain't tellin' you shit!
Jesus! Oh, shit!
Abdul Elijah runs the deal
from Joliet.
Shit's comin' in a couple of days.
I don't know where.
I swear on my balls!
I don't know!
Soviet method is more economical.
I'm so glad I took the time
to explain an individual's rights.
Sorry about that hand.
You gotta watch these doorjambs.
They're dangerous.
Breaking his goddamn fingers in front
of me. You can't pull a stunt like that.
- You ignored me.
- Miranda?
In your country, it's okay
to lie, put drug in pocket?
No, not really.
Maybe I was a little out of line.
I was just trying to get him to talk.
- I wasn't gonna prosecute the guy.
- We both go too far.
Shit! All I know is Gallagher's dead,
your Russian's on the loose somewhere...
and I gotta chauffeur you around
all goddamn day.
It really sucks.
Who is Abdul Elijah?
He's got one of the biggest
criminal organizations going now.
- Where can we find him?
- In jail.
Miranda Law is there?
Yes. Miranda is there.
Even scumbags have rights
in this country. I told you.
In Soviet Union, only after two days
can scumbag talk to lawyer.
You're shitting me!
I am not shitting on you.
We go to see Abdul? Yes?
Sure. Whatever you say, Gumby.
I'm your escort.
That suit's not gonna explode
or anything?
- I think you're safe.
- Just checking.
Once I lock one of these fuckers up,
the gangs take over.
The Aryan brotherhood,
the cleanheads, the Muslims.
Since most convicts are repeaters,
gang leaders got connections to outside.
They're in operation.
Cleanheads' playground.
- From now on, you're on your own.
- Thanks.
There he is. Abdul Elijah...
sitting on his throne
with his cronies.
He makes them shave their heads
to prove obedience.
I guess the rules are different
for the bosses.
Kind of like your government, lvan?
Come here, you.
I wanna talk to you.
This Captain Danko. He's come from
Russia to speak to your scoutmaster.
That's nice, but who
the fuck are you?
These men have no respect
of our authority as police officers.
No shit.
Revolutionary political leaders,
like myself...
are incarcerated to keep us quiet.
What is your political crime?
I robbed a bank.
Now, let's get to it, Mr. Moscow.
What is it you want?
I have Viktor's key.
If that's true, then you also
have Viktor's money...
and all you need is half a hundred
dollar bill and you and me do business.
I give you key,
you give me Viktor.
That is unethical.
You keep cocaine.
Bad. You're trying to make me
compromise my principles.
We are not like American police.
You ship drugs to my country,
and one morning you will wake up...
and find your testicles floating
in jars of water next to your bed.
I'm a holy man.
I got no need for testicles.
Then I settle for your eyes.
You can't threaten me,
white boy.
You want to know what my crime is?
My crime was being born.
I'm 38 years old and I've been
locked up 26 of those.
I educated myself in here.
I've come to understand this country
was built on exploiting the black man.
Of course, I don't hear anything
about brothers in your country.
But your country exploits
its own people just the same.
So I guess that makes me
the only Marxist around here...
right, comrade?
You see, this ain't
just no drug deal.
This is politics, baby.
This is economics.
This is spiritual.
I plan to sell drugs...
to every white man
in the world...
and his sister.
I still want Rosta.
- Yeah, real bad. I can tell.
- Where can I find him?
I tell you what I am gonna do,
Captain.
I am gonna put you two white boys
together, see if you can't work it out.
I need Viktor.
He needs that key.
And you...
you're just another motherfucker
we gonna have to deal with.
Be cool.
Okay, so tell me.
How did it go?
- Fine.
- Fine?
You wanna cut the shit?
You were talking to that jazzbo so long,
I thought about having my head shaved.
It could be a good idea.
- What's that?
- My watch.
- It's on Moscow time.
- Time to pick up Pokey?
- Time to feed parakeet.
- What's that?
Russian for jerking off?
- I guess not.
- What's wrong with parakeet?
Nothing. I didn't say anything
was wrong with parakeet.
My kid sister used to have one.
You want a parakeet, it's okay
with me. I don't give a shit.
You think that parakeet is feminine?
Did I say that?
I didn't say that, did l?
What do I know?
I guess it's okay.
- Christ, it's fine.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Slow and fast.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, hips.
Easy.
One, two, smooth.
Mind showing me l.D.?
I like to know who I'm talking to.
Ridzik, Arthur.
Detective Sergeant.
This is Captain Danko.
He's from Moscow.
You went to see Rosta in jail.
- What did you talk about?
- The weather...
taxes, inflation.
Did you meet him hanging around
the hotel bar, lobby?
Fuck you.
No. I have a headache
and good taste.
I don't have to listen.
It's very important.
Many people could be hurt.
Shit.
It's really no big deal.
He told me to go to The Garvin, get
his old room, where exactly to look.
It was just a passport and this
hundred-dollar bill torn in half.
I gave it to a friend of Viktor's.
I don't even know his name.
Cut the shit!
Just tell me where he's at.
I don't know.
- You got a phone number?
- I lost it.
- Look, this Viktor's a very bad guy.
- Really?
- A cop died because of him.
- I don't know.
You know anything about 11th and State?
I'll take you and book you for murder.
- Trying to scare me?
- Wondering why you're helping Viktor.
He's my husband.
I'm gonna bust that bitch so hard
she bounces.
Wait. We can use her
to find Viktor.
You got all the ideas.
Maybe I'll go home and whack off.
Watch Crime Stories.
Viktor uses fake name,
marries American to get visa to U.S.
Right. Why do I get the feeling
you're taking it so personal?
I shot his brother
six months ago in Moscow.
- Shot him dead?
- Yes.
- Way to go.
- Thank you.
Why don't we stake it out?
You go to the car.
I'll get something to eat. I'll get you
something healthy from all food groups:
hamburger, french fries,
coffee, donuts.
- Wait.
- You don't like onions?
- Give me key to car.
- It's unlocked.
In case she leave.
No, you can't drive that car.
What if you crash?
That means I gotta fill out reports
until I retire.
Key.
All right. But honk
if you see something.
Hey, asshole.
You can't park here.
This is my parking place.
I live right up there.
So move or give me 50 bucks.
- I do not understand.
- Let me make it simple, moron.
You move your ass or gimme 50
or I take my bat...
and mutilate your car.
- Do you know Miranda?
- Never heard of the bitch.