They told me you are the man.
They said that this guy
can move anything.
(FUNK MUSIC PLAYING)
They said that?
Yeah.
I am the man.
USA passport.
The most valuable piece of paper
in the world and
we make it our own.
That shit's artisanal.
I'll be the judge of that.
Not bad.
What about Omar?
The friendly ghost?
He ain't gonna cut
your head off for this?
I know he owns the city.
Omar signed off personally.
(LAUGHING)
I don't know who you think
you're bullshitting,
but it ain't me.
(GUNS COCKING)
Calling me a liar?
With guns on your face?
You crazy you don't trust me.
Let me explain something to you.
There's not a lot in
this world that I love,
but the shit that I love,
I don't trust with nobody.
I'll buy 50 now
and 500 after Omar
looks me in my eye
and lets me know
he's not going to kill me
over this deal.
Is that something
you can arrange?
Or is it more bullshit?
You're crazy, bro.
Yeah, I am crazy,
but in a good way.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(SPEAKING SERBIAN)
Shit!
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Everybody down! Atlanta PD!
There!
Shit!
(GRUNTING)
Freeze!
Freeze! I said freeze!
Atlanta PD!
Get down!
See you, bitches!
JAMES: Freeze!
(GROANS)
Atlanta PD!
Get me another car!
A Prius? Get this
bullshit out of here!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Damn!
Valet. Get out.
Get out! Yeah!
(ENGINE REVVING)
Asshole!
Move, trick!
(HORN HONKING) Get out the way!
Here we go.
Hey!
(LAUGHING) Whoo!
Oh, shit!
How you like me now?
Stop! Stop!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Oh, shit!
Yeah, baby!
I got you.
Yeah! (LAUGHING)
I tried to be nice.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
You thought I was crazy?
No, baby, I'm nuts.
MALE GAMER:  Does anybody
have a twenty on Black Hammer?
All right,
let's get these bitches!
BEN: The target's on
the second floor.
Let's switch it up.
Assface, me and you,
we'll go around back.
ASSFACE23:  Copy that.
Watch your friendly fire.
Hey! Guys, remember,
if they throw a grenade,
you got five
seconds to pick it up
and throw it back.
MALE GAMER:  Frag out.
This is not a game,
gentlemen, this is real.
Be on your toes at all times.
ASSFACE23:  Copy that.
How's my king this morning?
Good. I'm fine, babe.
Wasting his royal talents
in the kingdom, I see.
ASSFACE23:  Bogies at nine.
Bogies at nine.
I don't know if
you're being sarcastic,
but I'm not.
Right now I'm on a black bag op.
Kick move!
Can we talk?
Babe, in a second.
ASSFACE23:  Did you
call me "babe"?
I didn't call you "babe."
Shut up, Assface.
I'm talking to my lady.
Do what you're supposed to do.
Get eyes on that sniper.
Does anybody have
eyes on the sniper?
Ben, let's go.
This is not the time.
Stop. Ang, don't start.
Oh, I'm sorry, guys,
the real world needs Ben. Bye.
Give me it back.
Look at what
you're doing right now.
Stop. Seriously.
Move me out of the thing.
Put me in a bunker.
You going to get me...
Wow. Stop! Hey. Oh!
MALE GAMER:  Not again, Ben.
No! No!
ASSFACE23:  That really hurts.
Oh! Oh!
MALE GAMER:  Hi, Angela.
Even soldiers have to
get to work on time.
You're pro-Taliban. You are.
Stop.
I'm sorry, guys.
I had a black bird
in the living room.
I didn't hear it chirp.
It's not fair.
Here's the thing,
you have to understand
how easy it is for me
I feel like I had been
fighting in Pakistan
for the last eight hours.
Okay,
first of all, "Black Hammer"?
Speaking.
That's about when
I pull my penis out
and it hits the ground.
Kaboom. Boom!
(LAUGHING)
What are you laughing for?
You do know that
you're going to be
Mrs. Black Hammer.
The words every girl
wants to hear.
It better be.
Mmm. And when exactly
is this Black Hammer wedding?
Soon. Very, very soon.
Mmm-hmm.
Things are
getting close to where
I want them to be.
I'm figuring it out.
Can you make me one?
(SNIFFS) Mmm.
Sure.
So, is this about
you becoming a cop?
Yes, it is.
I got it all figured out.
Here's what's
going to happen.
After that I'm
going to be on patrol.
going to be a detective.
After being a detective,
I'm going to be a lieutenant.
That's how it happens.
Boom, boom, boom, boom.
You know that I love you
with or without the academy,
right?
I understand that,
but this is different.
I got such
a good feeling, babe.
I did everything right.
Did you tell my brother
that you signed up?
I'm going to be honest,
and don't get mad at me,
but I'm going to say
what I want to say.
Here's how I feel
when it comes
to your brother.
But I know that your
brother is ignoring me
because of that incident.
The barbeque incident was
a first-degree burn,
not a third-degree burn.
I've gotten past it, okay.
He doesn't have to know.
I don't see why
it's important.
Seriously, Ben,
if I'm ever going to
be Mrs. Hammer...
Black Hammer. Black Hammer.
Hammer. Got it.
I need him to be on board.
You two are the most
important men in my life.
What you just said
has been received.
I will check in.
Give me a kiss.
Done. You know what
we're doing tonight, right?
Mmm... Yes.
What?
Dinner. Yeah.
Dinner at Dominick's.
A romantic dinner
followed by some
sweet, sweet lovemaking,
dirty style.
That's right. Dirty style.
Dirty style?
What is that move?
It's the move that
Rihanna does in that video.
(LAUGHS) I don't
think that's it.
This is it.
It's very sexy.
Is it?
Yes.
I actually saw it
in a Kama Sutra book.
They call it
the "Lathered Lotus."
After I'm done doing that,
I'm going to give
you the Kawasaki.
(IMITATES MOTORCYCLE REVVING)
I don't understand
what that is.
That's starting that bike up.
After that, what do
you think comes last?
Ah, let me guess.
What?
Black Hammer.
That's right. Kaboom. Boom!
ASSFACE23:  Uh, dude, turn
your mic off. This is awkward.
I thought it had
something to do
with Thor from Avengers.
No. Ben.
Why didn't you
turn the game off?
You didn't turn the game off.
They know we have
a nasty household.
Is that what you want?
Because of you.
Whatever.
I authorized this operation
with very clear guidelines.
Instead, you shoot up
a mall full of civilians
like it's a damn video game.
And for what?
Fake passports?
Thinking those
would lead us to Omar.
Of course you were.
Do you know
how many man hours
we spent on this case?
And in two and a half years
you've had
no breaks,
so enough of this shit.
Your obsession aside,
there's no criminal,
nobody you get to
use as an excuse
for ignoring
the rules of engagement.
Lieutenant,
this was a special...
Nobody!
And especially
not for some lowlife
nobody's ever even seen before!
We know what he looked like
when he was nine.
BROOKS: Shut up, Miggs.
Look, these Serbs are dealing
more than just passports.
The fact that they're
still alive lets me know
they got something Omar wants.
Which was going to
lead us right to him.
Well, this Marko guy's
already lawyered up
and he's refusing to talk
except to claim entrapment.
Entrapment?
How about attempted murder?
Asshole tried to kill me.
Oh, you little pussy.
Someday somebody's going
to shoot you in the face
and that vest isn't
gonna do you any good.
The lawyer's already
claiming self-defense.
(LAUGHS) Self-defense?
With all due respect,
that's bullshit.
I'm shortening
your leash, James.
We all want Omar, but these
guys are a waste of time.
That's all.
Get out, all of you.
SANTIAGO: Hey, James,
how about next time
that you don't
tell me that this is about Omar,
you tell me, huh?
I don't want you to
start worrying, Santiago.
Worry? What are you,
my mother?
Come on, James.
You go into a back room,
out of contact,
you come out with
three armed guys
and a motorcycle.
You don't want me to worry?
We're going in
there with no backup,
I want to be scared, man.
I want to be so terrified,
I'm letting out little
involuntary shits. Okay?
Who put this together?
Me. All right?
Follow my lead.
I'm the brains, you the brawns.
The "bronze"?
Yeah, it's the plural of brawn.
I know.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
BEN:  Since when do you need
the brother's permission?
He is her only living
relative, I get that.
Her dad was a cop.
He got killed on the job.
I'm not taking
anything away from that.
But why do I have to
suck up to the brother
just because she
wants us to get along?
It would be easier,
but he's still upset
because I set him on fire.
Doggone propane knob.
What I did...
(STUDENTS SHOUTING)
Hold on. Hold on.
What did I tell you?
Get down! Get down, boy!
Hey! Hey!
You're white!
You don't fight.
What's wrong with you?
BOY: Come on, bro,
let's roll.
BEN: Hey, Ramon!
You're not going to do
this today. Watch out.
Kick move.
Hey, Ramon!
Hey, hey, hey!
Ramon!
Man, it's the rent-a-cop.
I know you hear me.
What are you
doing with these guys?
BOY: Catch you later, Ramon.
Don't you got
an English test today?
You think they're
going to let you
play basketball if
you fail that test?
I already speak English.
Okay. Well, go ahead.
You got it figured out.
Hey. Before you go,
let's play this out. Okay?
You go with them, you get drunk.
Now that you're drunk,
you can't play basketball.
How long before you drop out?
I give it a week.
So now you're
a 17-year-old wino.
When you're a wino,
you do what winos do best.
You're going to jail.
Once, twice.
Third time you
get a hard judge.
Judge gives you two choices.
You got jail,
you got the army.
Which one you going to take?
Army ain't so bad.
You're right, it's not.
Except you forgot
about one thing. War!
So now you're in Afghanistan.
You know what they
got in Afghanistan?
Landmines!
Boom! You got no legs.
So now what happens?
You're right back here.
You're in the streets,
but let's remember,
you got no diploma,
you got no feet, you got no job.
That means you're
back at the liquor store
getting drunk all damn day.
Now that you're drunk all day,
you try to steal because
you don't have a job,
but your stealing
ain't going too good
because you can't run.
You know why you can't run?
Because you got no feet!
Now you're stuck living
in a refrigerator box.
Here's the bad thing.
You're lonely,
you're in a gutter,
and you're legless.
Is that what you want, huh?
BOY: Come on, let's go!
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
I think I'm going to
go back inside now.
You going to walk.
Run.
(LAUGHS) Okay. All right.
Sprint.
Because if you
didn't have legs,
you got to crawl.
All right, man, go ahead.
You're something else.
About the dumbest
damn kid in this school.
I can't do it.
I ain't gonna be
everybody's mentor.
I don't get paid for that.
I've been waiting
all day to look at this.
I got in!
(LAUGHING EXCITEDLY)
I'm in the academy!
Freeze. Get down.
Freeze, you best put it
down because I'm
about to make change.
I have to call James!
(ALARM BLARING
ON CELL PHONE)
Jesus Christ!
Are you blowing up there, James?
You can't stop
Santiago's mom, man.
You can only hope to contain.
Hey, I know you're
trying to insult me,
but it's just too true, bro.
No, it's that little clown
that's dating my sister.
About a chromosome away
from being a midget.
(LAUGHING)
I should have
put a stop to that
a long time ago.
So why didn't you, bro?
I tried.
She loves his little ass.
I don't know
what she sees in him.
He's short but maybe
when he takes his pants
off it's just like...
(GASPS) "What is that?"
SANTIAGO: Just right for her.
She loves it.
(MOANING IN SPANISH)
(WHINNYING)
(MOANING LOUDLY)
What?
That's disgusting.
Look, man, does she know
you think this guy is a jerk?
Have you told her that?
I have to come at
a different angle because
she's not gonna want
me in her business.
I have to ditch this dude.
Look, man,
maybe this guy is all right.
Maybe he just
wants into the family.
(SCOFFS) I know
exactly what he wants.
(BOTH MOANING)
I love you.
Baby, congratulations.
ANGELA: You know what
I want to do to you?
What do you want to do?
Let's go upstairs.
No, because if we go
up there you know
what's going to happen.
You'll want to
brush your teeth.
Mmm-hmm.
After that you're
going to wash your face.
Then you got to put cream
and stuff on your face.
Let's be spontaneous.
Let's do it right here.
I want to be
wild like a savage.
Okay.
Give you that Kawasaki.
(IMITATES MOTORCYCLE REVVING)
I'm about to give
it to you right now.
You know what I want?
What you want?
I want that kaboom.
Girl, you're
trying to crawl down...
You want the hammer?
I want the hammer.
Then go get the hammer.
Okay.
Enough of that nastiness.
Oh, my God!
(SCREAMS)
Babe, call 911! Now!
Get out of my house,
you son of a bitch!
(GROANS)
JAMES: I can't believe
this shit.
Angela, what if I
was a real intruder?
Instead of my brother
creeping around my house?
Wasn't nobody creeping.
You were sitting in the dark
with a coke and a hot dog.
If you'd lock the door
or close the window
or bar that patio
like I told you.
This is exactly
why I didn't let you
install the alarm system.
It's about who's
going to protect you.
This weenie?
One, he is not a weenie!
(JAMES SCOFFS)
He can be weenie-ish,
weenie-like,
but I love him,
so it doesn't matter.
I picture you with somebody
with a little more prestige.
Somebody who plays
for the Falcons
or the Braves,
or even the Hawks.
Braves. Yeah.
Not with the mascot.
James, listen to me,
you do not screw this up for me.
BEN: Hey, guys.
I can hear what you're saying.
So if you want to stop.
Damn, it's Sir Scream-a-Lot.
I was responding to
a hostile situation, James.
You call for backup
when there's
a hostile situation.
That wasn't calling for backup.
That was
a high-pitched scream,
and you pushed
my sister in the way.
I pushed your sister
out of harm's way.
You shined the light at us.
It's different strokes
for different folks.
Put the ice pack in
his mouth. No, on his head.
I'm sensitive to
extreme measures of cold
and you know that.
Because you just got
knocked out by yourself.
James, you know what? You...
Um...
Guys, maybe we should...
What?
Is he still staring?
Make him stop.
Look. We were in
the middle of something,
so you have to go.
Y'all wasn't in
the middle of nothing.
We were, James.
Let's go. Get out.
I got my sandwich over here.
Listen. Listen, I'm going.
Bar that patio door.
ANGELA: I will. Thank you.
Promise. Love you.
Hey, James, wait up.
Hey, can you wait up, please?
Hey.
Look, man...
I know that you
don't really like me,
but I feel like
you don't like me
because you don't know me.
Nope, you're wrong.
I don't like you
because I do know you.
Well, I bet you'll like this.
I got accepted into
the police academy today.
I'm going to be a cop.
I've been trying
to call you all day.
I'm finally going
to have a career that
I can be proud of, man,
and Angela can be
proud of, and you.
Who knows,
maybe we can be partners
or something.
(SPITS)
Okay.
Now that I got things
straight, I feel like
I can finally make your sister
an honest woman.
There's just one thing
standing in the way.
I was wondering if I
could get your blessing
to ask Angela to marry me.
BEN: James?
Did you hear what I said?
I have to go.
Yeah, okay.
I figured that you
probably just got to
let everything sink in,
which is fine.
Maybe we could
take a ride later
and talk about all this?
Oh, shit.
So, just because
you joined the academy,
that suddenly makes
you ready to propose?
Yes. I mean, no!
I've been ready.
Look, I figured
that if I made it
through the academy
that you would be
forced to accept me.
Is that right?
I don't want to be
known as the guy
who set you on fire.
In my defense,
that was a mistake.
I tried to put you out.
I got water, but you panicked.
I don't even want
to dig into that.
That's getting off subject.
I want to talk to you...
Show and prove.
Show and what?
What are you...
You want to marry my sister?
Show me you're worthy of her.
And prove to me
you got what it takes.
How do you want me to
do that? I don't get it.
Tomorrow,
I'm going to take
you on a ride-along.
You can show me
what kind of man
you're made of.
And prove to me
that you deserve somebody
as special as Angela.
Hell, yeah.
Mmm-hmm.
Thank you, man.
I cannot wait to
show you that I'm twice
the man that you think I am.
I'll pick you up tomorrow.
All right. I'll see you then.
It's time to let go.
Hey, this is going to be great.
You will not regret this.
Mmm...
(SNIFFS)
Morning.
(GASPS)
James!
Didn't I tell you to
bar that patio door?
What are you doing, man?
It's 6:00 in the morning.
Good cops wake up
before the crooks.
Get your ass up. Let's go.
Okay.
James, that's not cool!
All right.
I'm ready, man.
Boom.
You forgetting something?
Uh-uh. Forgetting what?
This could be the last time
Angela sees your
little ass alive.
Don't you want to say goodbye?
No.
You can get shot today.
You know that, right?
Dead. You.
Ang?
Hey, babe?
Listen, James just
told me I could die.
ANGELA: No,
you're not going to die.
If I do die, I want you
to know that I love you.
If this was a latte,
it would be a love latte.
And you make me
think of rainbows,
because we both love colors.
And I love the way
your hands open up and
close, like monkey paws.
Remember when we ate
that peanut butter?
You was like,
"Put it on your nose,"
and I was like, "No."
That's the day
I fell in love with you.
Give me a kiss.
I want five of 'em in a row.
Five?
BOTH: Mwah! Mwah!
Mwah! Mwah! Mwah!
BEN: Deal. Done.
ANGELA: Go, go, go.
Hey. I hope I don't die,
because I still got
a lot more to say,
and I know we got to go, so...
All right, let's go.
Kick move.
You didn't tell me
you had a car like this!
What's under the hood?
A 5.7 liter Hemi?
Look at these tires!
Those are 22-inch Z Pirellis.
Are you driving it
with the traction control
or the posi... Okay. Okay.
I need a minute with you.
Where's your team?
I got them
sitting on a location.
Who's this?
Benjamin Barber.
Prospective.
Prospective what?
I'm a pre-cadet
at the academy.
I didn't realize
that was a category.
No, I got him from
that Boys & Girls Club.
I'm starting to do
some mentoring and shit.
I'm just surprised
you let anybody in
the car with you.
I'm starting to
take your advice.
Letting people into my life.
I may actually
become the new smiley face
of the department.
Have a seat.
Cool. (CLEARS THROAT)
Not there.
Right there.
You didn't say anything first.
You're not doing no mentoring.
BROOKS: The other perp
from the underground
is in the hospital.
He just came to.
Because I'm pretty sure
he knows what's going down.
Kind of hard for
the guy to talk
with his jaw wired shut.
He'll live.
Hey, Lieutenant...
I think you're wrong
about this Serbian connection.
You mean about leading to Omar?
The guy that no one's
ever seen before?
Lay off, James.
Lieutenant, you're
going to see me a lot...
You got a piece of
lint on your jacket.
I'm sorry.
That was... I'm sorry.
What's up his ass?
(SCOFFS)
Here you go.
What's this?
It's a waiver.
Sign it.
You don't just sign stuff.
What does it say?
That states if you
get your face burnt off,
or you take rebar
through your chest,
or accidentally get
poked by a hep C needle,
or so stressed out that
you want to eat a bullet,
that states that
you won't bitch out
and sue the city.
City don't need that.
City broke.
Is this necessary?
Are you going out with him?
Yes.
Oh, it's necessary.
Unit 260 is out
on a signal twelve.
Hey, Gina.
Give me all
the 126s you got today.
Everything.
The crazier, the better.
Send it straight to me.
You want 126s?
Yep. The more annoying,
the better. Do it.
Hey, what are you
doing with my glasses?
I wanted to see
what it looked like.
Put this on.
What is this?
James!
You did not tell me
I was getting
a jacket in the car.
Oh!
Whoa, whoa. What's
with the tightness?
It's a Dri-FIT
compression shirt.
Keeps my body dry.
It wicks the moisture.
Put that jacket on,
don't take it off.
Okay.
I'm not. I'm not going
to sweat in it either.
This is going to keep
my body dry. Wicks it.
Let's go.
Wait. Let me put my gloves on.
I knew I was
going to need gloves.
You don't need those.
Let's go.
Okay.
Wait. I got a jacket.
James! Guess
what just happened.
BEN:  This is it.
The real deal.
The hard, gritty streets.
I am so ready for this.
I'm serious, man. Bring it on.
Be quiet.
I'm sorry?
You talk too much.
Shut up.
Today is your Training Day.
BEN: Let me tell you
something about that movie.
That's motivation right there.
I'm about to show you
what these streets
is all about.
What it takes to
be a cop out here.
Right.
But you have to follow my lead.
I need you to do
everything I say
when I say, how I say,
and as fast as I say.
I don't want no lip,
no back-talk, no "Why?"
I just need you to
jump to it. You hear me?
Do you want me to
say something, or...
There's rules out here,
you know what I mean?
Don't touch no perps
unless you bringing them in.
There's no reason to
escalate any situation.
You stay cool,
and if you're outnumbered,
you always call for backup.
Always.
Not some ways.
All ways. Locked in.
You got one day,
and one day only,
to show me what you got.
I have a few good words
to say to the guy over
at the academy about you.
Hey, James...
James, don't play
with me like that, man.
Hey, give me one.
You're not a fiver?
All right. Dude, yes.
All right.
So what are we
working on today? Omar?
How do you know about Omar?
I overheard you guys
talking about it
at the station.
What's this Omar guy look like?
Does he have
a scar and everything?
Nobody knows
what he looks like.
Not even his own crew.
That's his power.
He killed anybody
who ever seen him.
DISPATCH:  Unit 19,
126 in progress,
Delacey and Leeward.
Pub owner complaining
about bikes parked illegally.
Unit 19, copy.
This is it?
This is it.
Oh!
(INHALES) It's about to happen.
Let me push the siren.
JAMES: No siren.
This is the siren.
It's not a siren.
What is that? What?
That was the trunk.
That's pretty stupid for us
to go chase bad guys
with our trunk open.
It makes it look
like we don't know
what we're doing.
Okay, here's the deal.
The owner of that pub
keeps complaining about
people parking in
his handicapped spaces,
and loitering.
No, we don't play that.
So here's what I need you to do.
Go over there and
simply get them to move.
Okay. Uh...
Anything I need to know, though?
Like, are they into
human trafficking,
dealing?
What's these guys' resume?
They're loitering. That's it.
No. Loitering today.
It's Gotham City tomorrow.
Scum like this
need to be taken down
here and now, you know?
Okay, Mr. Here-and-Now.
Go make an example.
BEN: All right.
You go around the front,
I go around the back?
Little good cop, bad cop action?
This is your chance to
show me what you're
made of, all right?
You got to represent now.
This is not
the high school quad.
Yes.
Don't go over there
talking to those lions
meowing like a pussycat.
What did that just mean?
You'll figure it out.
I don't think you can.
That was definitely weird.
It's like the same thing.
Okay, I'm just going to go.
I'm going to go.
(CLEARS THROAT)
BEN: Command and respect.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Some nice bikes you got here.
Harleys.
I'm a Harley man myself.
You mind if I take
a look at this one?
(BEN WHOOPING)
That's nice.
Uh-oh.
Houston, we have a problem.
I can't help but notice
that you don't have an
authorized handicap sticker
on your
DMV-issued license plate.
Sorry, but I'm gonna
have to ask you guys
to get on your bikes
and leave this sector.
What is not being understood?
(BIKERS LAUGHING)
You done did it now.
You guys think you're
tough because you're
in a little gang?
You want to know
what tough looks like, hmm?
I'm the definition of tough.
My mother was a stripper.
Her dance name was Asphalt.
Anybody else here been
raised by a woman who
clapped her ass for money?
Dollars. You haven't?
Which means that
you wouldn't last a day
in my world.
I'm going to tell you
what's going to happen
quick, fast and in a hurry.
You, you're gonna
get some Purell and
some baby wipes,
you're going to
clean this shit up.
Do I make myself clear, mister?
Huh?
That's not a "mister,"
that's my wife.
I don't know what
the hell you've been
looking at, but I'm
looking at a damn man.
I'm looking at a...
That might be a woman.
There's a chance of that...
I'm not going
to argue with you
over the sex of this thing.
You guys are going to
jail, because I'm
sick of doing this.
(MOTORCYCLE REVVING)
What's that?
Who turned on their bike?
Is that your bike?
Because I hear...
Who called them?
Did you call them?
One of y'all paged them?
Okay.
We all good for later?
SANTIAGO:  Yeah, it's all set.
What about that other thing?
Oh, yeah.
A kid named Runflat
might have some
intel on the Serbs.
Runflat?
Yeah.
That piece of shit.
I'm putting cases
on all you bitches.
You think you're going
to do this shit to me?
You'll be playing
basketball in Pelican Bay!
SHU program!
I'll go check it out.
Right. Catch you later, baby.
King Kong ain't got shit on me!
Really?
Oh, shit!
(GRUNTING)
I'm a lion.
Get your hands off me.
I said I'm a lion!
You like that back, huh?
JAMES: Hey, hey, hey.
Y'all don't want to do that.
Get off of me.
(EXCLAIMING IN RELIEF)
Jesus, thank you.
Come on.
You didn't follow one rule.
I did follow rules.
I told you don't touch nobody.
But you have to admit
that for a second
I had it under control.
No, you didn't.
Yes, I did.
No, you didn't!
James, that's...
You were so happy to see me
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
you damn near jumped in my lap.
Can you stop?
It's Angela. Please.
I know who that is.
Hey, bouncy butt.
So, how's it going?
Great.
Horrible.
Horrible!
Greatable.
Yeah, babe,
let me tell you something.
I'm cleaning up
these streets so good,
you'll be able to
eat off of them.
Stop lying.
Babe, let me let you go,
because there's a lot
of stuff around here
and you're breaking up.
I love you, though. Okay? Bye.
JAMES: Did you call
my sister "bouncy butt"?
BEN: You don't want to know.
All right, stay in the car.
Wait, what?
I ain't staying in no car.
I'm going with you.
No, you're not.
Yes, I am.
No, you ain't. (SCOFFS)
I want to help.
I'm not staying
in this car, man.
Cool. All right.
I'll let you help.
Thank you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm looking for a kid
by the name of Runflat
I need to talk to.
Runflat. Like a tire?
Long story.
Okay.
See that youngster over there
playing basketball?
Black shirt, striped pants?
BEN: Right there?
Yeah.
That's his little brother.
All I need you to do
is go over there,
find out where Runflat is.
That's all I gotta do?
Yes. And after this
we're taking off
the training wheels.
I'm sick of this
putt-putt shit.
All right, over.
I need y'all to get out of here.
Let's move.
Am I speaking French? Go!
Uh-uh. You stay.
What's up, little man?
"What's up, little man."
What are you talking about?
I'm not the little man.
You are.
Hey, don't start this if you
don't want to finish it.
Start what? What,
you about 3'10 ", 3'11"?
Yeah, but you know
what I'm gonna do. Grow.
What you gonna do?
Stretch? You hope!
Understand something,
boy. I'm a man.
Whatever you say.
I'm an officer of the law.
She need to stop flirting, too.
Ronald. Talk to you.
Ball up.
(YELPS)
Where are you going, Ronald?
Come on, man.
Ronald, why are you
walking away, Ronald?
Hey, that's my car!
Get your ass back.
I'm using it.
Take your time. You got it.
It's okay.
Come on.
Why you walking
off from me, Ronald?
Don't call me
that around here.
Call me Runflat, okay?
What you know about
that Serbian crew?
Screw them, man.
Coming over here
thinking they own shit.
How they tied into Omar?
Who?
Nigga, don't play with me.
You still got
them pins in your...
(SCREAMS) Come on. God!
Mamasay, mamasa, mamakusa! Oh!
Man, you're not a cop.
I've been empowered by a cop
to come over here and
ask you about the
whereabouts of your brother.
Now give it up.
You think I'm gonna
give up my brother again?
He just got out.
You're gonna give him up.
You came to the wrong place.
I ain't telling you nothing.
What you just did
was spit on my lip.
Yeah, I did.
That just got you
a little time in prison.
You're gonna tell me
what I need to know,
or it's gonna get real
ugly for you, Ronald.
I'm going to lock you up.
This is bullshit.
Bullshit is my middle name.
I got a real shaky
relationship with the truth.
What the hell you shaking for?
Did you take a swing at me?
You reached for my...
Going for my gun?
(SHOUTING IN PROTEST)
Now I got to defend myself.
No! Hold on, man.
I'll tell you what's up. Damn!
All right. All I know is this.
Serbs ran on Omar's
territory. He got mad, okay?
They trying to push something.
They got a shipment coming in.
That's all I know.
I'm about to make
a citizen's arrest.
I'll make
a citizen's arrest, too.
For what?
Impersonating an officer.
What?
You said you were a cop.
That's illegal.
That is it, boy.
This is what I'm
going to do time for.
You better give
up your brother.
Give me your brother!
Stranger danger!
What?
Man, let me fix you up.
I don't want to
touch you there.
You want to see my what?
I don't want to see yours.
He's playing.
My mama says that's private.
That's my nephew.
He's trying to touch
all the little boys.
Get him!
Who got next? Who playing?
MAN: Let's see your badge!
I'll be leaving here
in a few minutes.
Once this little midget
gets back in the car.
Start the car!
BOY: Run, shorty, run!
Open the door!
It's me! Open the door!
BOY: Go cry home to your mama.
What took you so long?
BEN: We should go.
Do the thing.
Make the tires skirt!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
JAMES: How did that work
out for you back there?
BEN: Uh...
I think it would have
worked out a lot better
if I had a gun.
So, you need a gun to
interrogate children?
Me having a gun just gives me
a certain level of confidence.
Knowing that
it's below my belt.
That's all I'm saying, man.
Have you ever even
held a gun before?
The PX-48R controller
is extremely realistic.
Okay?
(LAUGHING)
What are you laughing at?
Are you talking
about a video game?
Yes.
Don't mention
those stupid video
games to me, okay?
Don't say stupid.
Don't call my games stupid.
In my world, do you know
what you would be considered?
A newbie.
A newbie?
You have any idea
what level player I am?
No.
You have no idea.
My gamer tag is
spoken in hushed terms
of awe and envy.
When I log on, people go crazy.
"Oh, my God!
Black Hammer's in!
(WHISPERS) Black Hammer."
Shit's not real.
You would be lost in my world.
Black Hammer would not help you.
Let me show you my world,
all right? The real deal.
BEN: Why don't we just
go to the department range?
Because that's for cops only.
Which you are not.
Yet. Which I'm not yet.
Hey, James.
Hey, Val, how you doing?
Good. How's it going?
Pretty fair for a square.
Got to train a new booty today.
I'm new booty?
I'm Val.
How you doing?
I'm Ben. New booty.
Good to see you, Ben.
You, too.
They got everything
you need here.
Right. Right.
But this the real deal.
Mmm-hmm.
It's not a Xbox.
No video game controllers.
Just real deal.
Right.
Here's the handguns.
Val can hook you up.
Beretta, Glock, whatever.
I wish Assface was here.
Because he's more of
a suppression fire
disciple, you know?
I'm glad Assface is not here.
Why would you say that?
He should be here.
This is his world, too.
Uh...
I could choose whatever I want?
Knock yourself out.
All right. You said it.
No take-back-sies.
What do I want?
What do I want...
Hurry up.
You act like you're
looking for doughnuts.
Why are you so impatient?
I got shit to do.
Give me a second.
Let's go!
Fine, fine.
I want to get...
I don't want that one.
I want this one.
Smith and Wesson 500.
Let me get that.
All right.
It's a good choice, ain't it?
500 Smith and Wesson.
You like that choice.
You like it.
Here you go.
Oh, ho, ho!
Bang, bang... Shit!
Problem?
Did you feel that?
No, no problem...
Got it?
Can I do that thing?
Like how they do that...
You know what?
Can you do it?
Let's just go with the Glock.
All right.
That's a good choice, boy.
Don't touch me.
That's a tap.
I didn't touch you.
There's a difference.
This is touching.
I didn't touch you.
There we go.
Hey, what's this? Shit!
Oh!
It's all right, I got it.
You want me to
help you set it up?
No, Ben I got it.
Should we get a book?
(GUNS FIRING)
Let's see what you got.
Do we need goggles
or earplugs or
anything like that?
No, usually the bad
guys don't give us time
to put on that kind of stuff.
Okay, right. That's
actually a good point.
It makes a lot of sense,
and it's better
to keep it real.
I would rather this be real.
You know what I mean?
Keep it real.
Yeah. Okay. (GRUNTS)
Here we go.
Freeze!
How do you say freeze?
Freeze.
Okay. You know what it is?
You don't move your
top lip that much.
I move my top lip
so it doesn't come out stern.
You get what I'm saying?
(IN DEEP VOICE) Freeze.
Freeze.
Just shoot.
Shoot.
You pronounce everything.
I got you.
You ready? Here we go.
Freeze! Atlanta PD!
Get on the ground!
Hands behind your head!
Fingers laced!
You better lace them!
Lace them!
Shoot the gun.
Okay. All right.
Ready? Here we go.
Damn it!
I pinched it. I pinched
the inside of my hand.
I don't think
the sight on the gun
is quite calibrated.
The way I was shooting,
it looks a little...
Yeah, it's off by
a centimeter or two.
You right-handed
or left-handed?
You were doing both.
You're ambidextrous.
That's why I like shotguns.
I'm more of
a shotgun specialist,
because I need
both of my hands,
because my upper body...
Let me use
your 12-gauge, man.
Be careful, it's got
a magnum loaded in it.
Oh, yeah. (LAUGHING)
Now we're talking.
The street sweeper.
Just like Fallujah.
My nigga.
Denzel,  Training Day.
You might want to
step back a little bit.
This thing got
a little kick to it. Okay?
Freeze! You better stop
before I put
a hole in your back!
Oh, you think it's a game?
Oh, it's on now!
Oh, shit!
Got a little bit of kick to it.
My stomach in my ass.
Oh, yeah, you're
ready for the streets.
This gun should be banned.
I really appreciate everything.
No problem, man.
Well! How did it go?
BEN: (IN HIGH-PITCHED VOICE)
It was good.
It was real good.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm just a little rusty,
that's all, Val.
A little more used
to a higher-grade
military weapon
like an RPG or a flame thrower.
VAL: Yeah, we don't really
get the exotic stuff.
Though we did have
a couple of Zastavas
in here the other day.
Let's go.
Wait a minute,
you had some Zastavas?
Mmm-hmm.
M92 or the M93?
I had the M92.
Are you kidding me?
No.
I was going to ask you
about the Black Arrow.
That's what I thought
you was going to say.
We're talking about
the Serbian submachine guns.
The M92 is a good gun,
but that Black Arrow,
let me tell you something,
take your back off.
Serbian?
Serbian, yes.
How the hell you
know they were Serbian?
Uh, because I'm the
Black Hammer. Platinum
level. I told you that.
X-Y-C-Y.
You press at the same time
and it gives you a...
Who had these guns?
Two guys.
One white, one black.
Serbian?
Um, I don't know.
One had an accent.
Let's go.
Serbians?
One had an accent?
Yeah.
If you could do it,
what would it be?
(SPEAKS ACCENTED GIBBERISH)
What if you had the...
(SPEAKS GIBBERISH)
Let's go.
I'm trying to figure this...
BOTH: Let's go.
What was that about?
Wait for me in the car.
I just got a clue, didn't I?
In the car.
I just figured something out.
I'm gonna get in the car.
Can you at least
turn the car on?
Radio or nothing.
What's up, boss?
JAMES:  Listen, them Serbians,
they got
something big going down.
I think they're
selling something to Omar.
I believe it's
military-grade weapons.
Damn, if Omar gets
that kind of firepower,
holy shit!
Matter of fact,
I want you to find your boy
at the Airport PD,
tell him to keep his
eyes open for anything
strange coming out
of Eastern Europe.
Did you listen to Brooks?
He doesn't
want us anywhere
near this Omar thing.
We just have to
fall back, please.
Santiago,
you sound like a rookie.
Let me do the thinking
for both of us, okay?
You hook that other thing up?
Yeah, it's all set.
You're going to be hearing
from dispatch any minute now.
Good. I need to get
rid of this clown.
(CAR ALARM BLARING)
Sorry.
What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
My fault. I didn't know.
I didn't expect
that to happen.
Hey, I got a clue, didn't I?
No.
Yeah, I did. I got instincts.
You say what you want.
You know I do.
You think just
because you play
a little punk video game,
that you're ready to be a cop
out here in these streets?
You're ready to go
toe-to-toe with the biggest
kingpin in Atlanta?
You understand this guy has
killed cops, innocent people,
even his own crew.
And still he's got everybody
thinking he's a ghost.
What's your little ass gonna
do when we run up on Omar?
What a cop is supposed to do.
Why am I telling you
what I would do?
How about we back up?
How about you
tell me "thank you."
That could go a long way.
"Thank you, Ben.
"You helped me with a clue.
Good instincts."
DISPATCH ON RADIO:  Unit 19,
126 in progress...
Shut up. Shut up.
Corner of State and Bellevue.
Let me say "Copy."
Let me say it.
Please. Come on.
Let me say "Copy."
Some cop stuff.
Copy.
19, repeat that, please.
19, come again?
Hold up.
Wait a minute. Copy...
Give me that.
Stop it, she can't hear me!
Give me a second, dude.
Get off, man!
Get off of it!
That's my wrist.
Now that's unnecessary.
Copy that.
Copy that for real this time.
The first one wasn't real.
19, please repeat.
Because if you
tell me say "that,"
I will say "that."
JAMES: Man, shut up.
You bent my wrist.
CRAZY CODY: No!
She took everything!
She took my boat!
CASHIER: He's down there
and he won't
stop throwing stuff.
Poor bastard's at it again.
CRAZY CODY: She took my car!
JAMES: This dude, again.
I just want my life back.
Cody Tillman, AKA Crazy Cody.
You know him?
No.
Take that!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
JAMES: Hey, hey!
You better sit your ass down.
You stay right there,
I'm going in.
No, let me go in.
You stay there.
No. I want to talk to you.
No.
Here I come.
Stay! Stay!
No! No!
I'm coming in hot.
Grab me, James, grab me!
What you doing over here?
I want to talk to you.
I want to go.
You can't handle Crazy Cody.
Can I please have
some of Crazy Cody? Please!
I'm breaking every
rule possible for you.
You get this right
or I'm taking your ass home.
That's a deal.
Go in there. This is a layup.
Show and goddamn prove.
Hey!
CUSTOMERS: Oh!
I didn't see that coming, James.
Stop it!
You're here throwing
all this produce
and shit. Stop!
Listen to me,
what you going to do
is get on the ground
and put your hands
behind your head.
I ain't doing shit.
Handle this!
Don't embarrass me.
What am I doing?
Do your job!
I'm not trying to do my job?
Do your job! Go!
Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Don't you take...
Keep your clothes on!
They took everything else.
Might as well take my clothes.
Get this
situation under control.
Make him respect you.
You better not pull it out.
It's getting pulled out.
He's going to pull it out!
JAMES: Control the situation!
What am I supposed to do?
Arrest that man.
You want me to arrest that?
He got his penis out!
He is packing, though.
I got nothing.
What are you doing?
Stop. Stop!
Ben, what are you waiting on?
He has some freak honey shit!
What do you want me to do?
Quit playing.
That's it.
You're going to jail.
Honey Boo Boo!
Stop it. You're going to jail.
Come on. Do your job.
Ow!
That's police brutality!
Let the dude go.
His heart is broken.
Hold on. Hold on.
Ain't nobody hurting him.
(SCREAMING)
Finish this, man.
(YELPING)
Quit playing.
What are you doing?
Eat this chip! Eat it, bitch!
(BOTH YELLING)
You failing.
I'm gonna make you my bitch.
You ain't gonna
make me no bitch!
Come on, Ben.
You ain't going nowhere.
No! Get off me!
Ugh.
BEN: Yo, stop!
Get off. Get off of me!
Oh, shit.
BEN: Stop, man!
I can't breathe!
James, he's choking me.
It's not funny no more.
Drop the bottle!
Please don't do this.
Now you calm down!
Ben, you okay?
Stupid.
You okay?
Book him on
drunk and disorderly,
resisting and assault.
I'll meet you up there.
I thought it'd be different.
I thought I'd be better.
I'm gonna go in here
and fill out this paperwork,
then I'll be back
to take you home.
Don't worry about it,
man, you'll be all right.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hey, babe.
ANGELA:  Hey, babe,
how's it going?
Fine. It's going fine.
Okay.
So, it's the weekend and
I was going to make plans.
I was thinking maybe
we can go to that
new restaurant or...
Babe,
I don't want to do nothing.
I just want to
stay in the house
and play my game.
I don't feel
like being bothered.
What's wrong?
Come on, babe, talk.
You want to know what's wrong?
Everything is wrong.
I don't know if I can do this.
It's not what happened,
it's what didn't happen.
I met the damn devil today
in the form of a child.
He didn't respect me as a man,
he had a foul mouth.
We could start off there,
or if you want,
we could talk about
the fact that I got
confronted by
a man-lady biker thing.
I didn't know what it was.
All I know is she had
a beard and breasts,
but the fact
I thought it was a man
and spoke on it, I'm wrong.
"You got the beard, not me!"
And to top it off,
I go to the farmers' market,
I get into a dispute
with a guy named Crazy Cody,
he started pouring
honey on his body,
I'm wrestling a man with honey!
No, wait a minute, Ben.
Did you say Crazy Cody?
Yeah. What does that
have to do with anything?
Baby, James plays poker
with a guy named Crazy Cody.
He's a blonde-haired
white guy. He's
known him a long time.
Hey.
Question, babe,
you ever heard of a 126?
Yeah. It's a cop code
for an annoying
situation nobody wants.
They do it to rookies.
It's a joke.
Why?
Nothing.
Babe, let me let you go.
I have to go.
I'll call you later, okay?
I love you.
I love you, too.
I got your damn 126.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(OFFICERS LAUGHING)
The guy's coming
at me, he's like,
"I'm nervous, I'm nervous."
He's like,
"Put your hands up."
And the closer he gets,
the shorter he gets.
And he's coming at me,
then it was like
a Cabbage Patch doll.
I've never seen
anything like it.
Then he gets on me,
tries to put
the cuffs on me, bam.
I got honey on me,
I'm yelling,
"Oh, Honey Boo Boo!"
So,
can we stop with these 126s
or is this guy coming back?
Oh, no. He's done.
You hear me?
Done. Anybody got a fork?
(ALL LAUGHING)
JAMES: I'm serious, you know.
Matter of fact,
I don't even
think he going to join
the academy. Yeah.
All in all, I got to say,
today was a good day.
All right, let's get
you home. Tucked in.
DISPATCH ON RADIO:
Unit 19, 126 in progress.
Suspicious person,
55 North Peachtree.
Hey, baby, cancel that 126.
As a matter of fact,
I'm going to be
offline for about a hour.
No, you know what?
On second thought, copy that.
Unit 19 en route
to 551 Peachtree.
Copy that.
The hell you doing?
I told you I want to be
a cop. I want to be a cop.
And that 126 might be serious.
I feel like
I got my second wind.
Like I'm Action Jackson
or somebody right now.
Let's go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
We discussed this.
You not cut out for this work.
That's not true.
I'm not going home like this.
It's not going to happen.
Now, if this doesn't
go well, I will be
out of your hair, James.
All this cop talk
will be finished.
Matter of fact, I'll go one up.
If this doesn't work,
I will call Angela right now
and tell her myself.
Your funeral.
Indeed it is.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
JAMES: What's
the problem this time?
I don't like these guys.
Something's wrong.
You're gonna have
to get a bouncer.
The department
is getting tired
of doing this for free.
I'm serious this time.
The one by the bar.
Other dude, blue jacket.
They've been casing
this place all week.
JAMES: I think
you're right this time.
I need you to go to
the car, call in 211,
tell them we need a backup.
Okay. Will do.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ben!
What are you doing?
I want to go talk to him.
Gonna do it now.
Everybody on the floor!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Get on the ground.
On the ground! Now!
Atlanta Vice!
Everybody be cool.
No, no, no.
Don't nobody be cool.
We're about to heat this up.
Ben!
Yes?
Back to the car.
Call for backup.
No!
Look, the situation's
already in progress.
I got this.
Ben!
Get down!
Yeah.
Get up, baby, stop.
It's not real, it's fake.
Man, you got to be kidding me!
You gonna pull out a gun
when you looking at this?
This much of
a height difference.
Thank you.
I'm gonna tip you.
Get 100 ones.
I got you in a second.
You better chill, man.
Put the gun down.
We got hostages.
BEN: Oh, no!
James, they got hostages.
You ain't gonna shoot me.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
I'm gonna do it!
You do it, you next.
Ben!
Yes?
Stand down!
I ain't gonna stand down.
I never stand down...
from a 126.
This ain't no joke, man.
This is the real deal.
You right, James,
this ain't no joke.
This is dead serious.
We serious up in here.
Shut up! You're about
to get us killed, cop.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hold on, cowboy.
Oh, God!
I got a way for you to
get out of here. Okay?
Put the gun down.
I'll forget you had
hostages, and y'all won't
get that much time.
No! Overruled. No.
Overruled! I don't like it.
I don't want to do that.
Why...
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Why do that when
we can handle this
right here, right now.
One winner, one loser.
Let's get to shooting!
Ben!
Let's shoot!
Let's start shooting!
Man, you crazy!
Yeah, I am crazy.
Only thing that can
kill crazy is a bullet.
You got that bullet, huh?
Can you kill crazy?
Kill crazy!
JAMES: Ben, get out of there!
Come on, Tim, what's the move?
Yeah, what's the move, Tim?
He got to ask you
because you can't
make no decisions.
The black man is
following the white man
once again.
Make a decision by yourself.
Tim, I'm back over here to you.
What you going to do?
It's a chessboard.
I'm a rook. I'm about
to take your bishop,
but I can't
because I got your queen.
Where I go? Where am I?
I'm gonna stop
so you can see me.
You see me, huh?
You see me? Shoot!
Ben!
I'm going to do this fool!
Do me! Do me!
(SCREAMING)
He tried to do me!
Freeze!
Bitch, you better
get down and shoot!
(GROANS)
James, this is real!
This shit is real!
Don't you move, boy.
Oh, Jesus! This is real!
Take it easy, man.
I didn't even do anything.
Hey, don't say anything.
Keep me away from this psycho.
Ow! Come on, man.
Where do I start?
You think
because you're better
than the average riff-raff
that gives you the right
to do things your own way?
To tote that
little civilian bastard
into an active crime scene?
L-T, I did not know
it was going down
like this, all right.
This owner right here
is always crying wolf.
We come by to check it out,
it's going down.
Perp gets shot,
no other fatalities.
What's the big deal?
You want a medal for that?
Now I hear you took
him to a gun range?
And something
about military weapons
and Omar?
That dry,
snitching-ass Santiago.
It's not Santiago!
I got ears out
here just like you do.
I told you to leave it alone.
But you're out here on your own.
I don't know half
the shit you're working.
And all you say is "trust me"?
You should.
Haven't I earned that?
Let me be clear.
I can only cover
your ass so much.
So clean your shit up.
Or I'll clean it up for you.
You, get in the car, you done.
Why?
We got more important 126s?
You almost got me killed!
Almost don't count.
So, you done. Let's go.
No, I'm not done.
I want to talk some more,
I got something else
I want to say.
I may not be a cop right now,
but I will be.
You hear me? I will be.
And there is nothing
that you can do about that.
I tried to help you.
Hey! Hey, man!
You came to me and said,
give me a day to
show me what you got.
I gave you a day.
It's not good enough.
So the answer to
your question is no!
I do not give you my blessing.
I don't need your blessing.
This isn't Afghanistan.
I'm not about to
buy her with a goat.
That girl loves me, man.
That girl loves all of this.
Breathe it in,
because it's in your face.
I'm taking care of her, not you.
You?
Me.
You can't even
take care of yourself.
You wouldn't last
one day out here.
You think I'm
gonna become a cop
and get myself killed?
Leave her by herself?
This conversation is over.
Get in the car.
This is your problem, man.
It's why you don't
have no damn partner.
You walk around here by yourself
because you don't trust nobody.
Eventually
you're gonna have to
trust somebody, James.
I'd never trust you.
I'd never trust you
with my life.
And my family's life?
Can you comprehend that?
You don't even know
why you don't like me.
Tell me why!
You don't know why.
Because you
don't know me, James.
I know who you are.
You that clown
that's always trying
to talk yourself out
of every situation.
No matter how deep you in it.
That's a bad character trait
for a cop.
So get your ass in
the car so we can go.
I ain't getting in no car.
You getting in the car.
I'm not getting in no car.
Walk.
You think I've never
walked before? I'll walk.
You think I'm gonna beg you?
Don't beg me. I'll walk.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
Let me jump in
because I don't
know where I'm at.
Back seat.
I'm not getting
in no back seat.
Back seat.
No.
James?
Hey, James?
Can you at least let me ride
in the front seat, please?
Shut up.
Before I tase you in the mouth.
That's illegal.
That's very illegal.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
What?
Turned himself in to
County this morning.
Confessed to vandalism.
Weird. Weird.
That ain't weird.
He just scared.
Trying to get off
the streets. It's Omar.
If he's onto Runflat,
then he's definitely onto us.
We might want to pull our skirts
over our faces and
just back off, huh?
It will never happen, all right?
So just keep your eyes open.
All right, copy that.
That's a damn shame.
Boy just got out of jail
and now he got to
go back already.
See,
that's where you don't know
what you're talking about.
Runflat ain't been
on the inside for
about two years now.
That's not what
his brother said.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Ow, man!
What did he say?
I'm not telling you
nothing after that.
What did he say?
He said, "You think
I'm gonna give him up
when he just got back?"
That's exactly what he said?
I got perfect conversation
recall. It's a gift.
I just got another clue.
This is a two-clue
kind of day for me,
and being that that's the case,
I need to be in
the front seat right now.
No, it ain't.
Yes, it is.
The kid's got another
brother that drove
for Omar, all right?
He escaped custody, left town.
Now, no way
he'd risk coming back
unless he had to be.
So, what's our move?
My move is to find the brother.
Oh, come on. Come on, James,
after all I just did?
What'd you do?
I'm giving you clues
left and right!
No.
I can help!
I'll keep my distance.
I'm serious.
Veto. You're done.
Fine. Take me home.
I don't need this.
I'm going home.
I'll take you home.
I'm going to go home
and use the phone,
call Lieutenant Brooks
and tell him
you out here
freelancing this Omar case.
See what he thinks about that.
You better not.
Oh, I am.
You damn right
I'll call the lieutenant.
You little snitch bitch.
Call me whatever you want.
Snitch Bitch Ben.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
Hey, man,
you know where
I can get these things?
Oh, hell no! I got
the right to refuse
service... (GROANS)
You better be
lucky it wasn't me.
James, you broke the glass!
Oh, shit!
What's up? Come here.
Get your ass over here, boy.
Get your hands off me, pig!
How stupid are you to
hide out in the same place
we found you before, Jay?
Plain sight.
Classic tactic, man.
You better tell me
where that Serbian buy
is going down, boy,
or I'm gonna give you
a classic tactic.
I ain't telling you nothing!
Why'd you even
come back, Jay, huh?
This is becoming
a family tradition.
Tell me where that buy is,
or you going to jail
with a bullet wound.
You think he playing
with you? You think
he got time for games?
This man is crazy.
If he pull the gun out,
that means he serious.
Tell him where
the buy is going down.
Where's it going down at?
Bullshit.
BOTH: Bullshit?
Oh, no, this is real shit.
You better tell me
where that buy going down!
Tell us where the buy is.
You hear me?
Tell us where the buy is!
Forget both of y'all!
Really?
That's how you feel?
You want to feel this?
That's right!
You want to see crazy?
I'll show you crazy!
Tell me where the buy is!
Tell me where...
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
Oh, shit.
He shot me!
I'm sorry.
Yeah, he shot your ass.
You damn right I shot your ass.
He going to shoot you again.
No. No.
Because he crazy.
I can't handle this one.
It's out of my hands.
You want to see crazy?
I'll show you crazy!
You think it's a game?
Tell us where the buy is!
You better tell me
where the buy is!
Okay.
It's at the old factory.
The abandoned one
off of Huber.
Okay.
Old abandoned factory.
What time?
9:00.
If you lying, Jay,
I'm gonna shoot you
in the other shoulder.
Just keep him away from me!
Boy, you want it hot?
You want to get some
hot slugs up in you?
Slugfest, homie.
Chitty-chitty-bang-bang!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Hey, man, it's going down now.
Over at that old
factory on Huber.
SANTIAGO:  Shit.
Okay, I'm on my way.
I'm calling in for
some heavy backup,
all right?
All right.
Where'd you get that gun?
I kept it from the club.
You know the guy
you shot in the ass?
Come on, man!
Now!
Here!
Hey, mother...
I thought the safety was on.
I got him to talk though,
didn't I?
Yeah, you got
a very interesting
interrogation voice.
Nice and screechy.
Okay. It's all this intensity.
That's what it is.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Wait for me here.
Are you serious?
If I had time to
drop you off, I would,
but I don't.
It's my clue that
got us here. I've been
helping you all day!
Oh, you have?
Yes.
Is that why you
just shot somebody?
On accident?
That's not fair.
And before that,
you asked a suspect
to actually execute you.
That's because
I thought it was
another 126. You know that.
This is not another 126, Ben.
This is the real deal.
So the time for jokes is over.
So the kind of help
you got, it's not
the kind of help I need.
I'm just trying to go...
Do I have to cuff
you to the wheel?
You ain't gotta do that.
Where's
your ride-along?
He flamed out.
I had to take him back.
Where's backup?
Probably running late.
Listen, I got a look inside.
They're all in there,
it's going down right now.
Just FYI, when I get
in there I'm gonna
start shooting people.
I haven't shot anybody all day.
We know, Santiago.
Let's hit it.
Okay. Here's what
we should do. I...
Man, what the... Oh!
Oh, hell no.
That's right.
Stay still.
Yeah, surprise.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
I don't want to hear that.
(R&B MUSIC PLAYING)
(GROANS LOUDLY)
A-B-C-D-E-F-G-H-I-
J-K-L-M-N-O-P...
I can't do it.
(SIGHS IN FRUSTRATION)
I can't believe you two
punks been protecting
Omar this whole time.
Pays well.
No benefits,
but we get those
from the day job.
I should have known.
Greedy bastards.
James, we're not
giving anything away.
We're selling it
because we're businessmen.
And we're enterprising it
so that Omar won't
have to hide no more.
And all you had to do
was just let it
go for one day.
If you had let
it go for one day,
you wouldn't be here right now.
MIGGS: Now things are not
gonna end well for you.
JAMES: Yeah,
don't be too sure.
You didn't want to
play ball, so here we are.
It's not easy on us either,
believe me.
(MEN TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Oh, my God! Shit!
Thank you.
Omar appreciates
the delivery of
his weapons.
What is this?
That's just a loose end
that we're gonna
take care of very soon.
Added bonus for Omar.
SERBIAN BOSS: So,
can we do business now?
Yeah.
Can I see the merchandise?
Victor.
Didn't have to be
like this, James.
Nice.
You could've had
a little taste of that.
I for one, though,
I feel hurt, because
we never hung out.
We never watched sports
or shared some
chicks together.
It must be tough
being an island though, huh?
Nobody to have your back.
You know what?
You should see
a therapist about this,
because you don't
want to spend
the rest of your life...
Oh, I'm sorry.
I forgot.
You're about to die.
BEN: I want that one
for myself.
(GUNS COCKING)
Who the hell are you?
Who am I?
(CHUCKLING)
Oh, shit.
Yeah, that makes me laugh.
Especially
considering the fact
that this is my deal.
That these are my men.
SANTIAGO: Wait a minute.
You're Omar?
That's right.
Omar is here.
I know what you're thinking.
Nobody's ever
expecting to see Omar,
but he's here.
And why is that?
Nobody can tell me why
because it's a surprise.
This is a surprise inspection.
So I suggest you all
put a smile on your face,
because today is the day
that I finally decided
to let you see mine.
Welcome to me.
Where's Jay?
Oh, Jay?
I left Jay ass
at the pawn shop
because he wasn't prompt.
Everybody knows that
I like my shit prompt.
It's more professional that way.
Ain't that right, my Serbs?
I've been keeping tabs
on all of you
for some time now.
You.
Oh...
Let me take the time
out to give you this.
You have been
crushing all week,
you hear me? Yeah.
I need more men like you.
You're a good man,
you know that?
I want you to keep
keeping on, young butt.
Matter of fact,
do me a favor and
give Omar a gun.
A gun?
Did I stutter, hmm?
You're gonna
embarrass me in front of
my crew after I just
gave you a compliment?
I said, give Omar a gun.
Hold up. Now hold up.
I thought Omar was 6'4".
(GUN COCKS)
(CRIMINALS MURMURING)
(ALL EXCLAIM)
(GROANING)
How tall is Omar now?
Anybody else want
to weigh in on how
tall he thinks Omar is?
No? Does anybody
else want to test me?
We weren't expecting to see you.
But it's better
that we deal with
this business personally.
Of course it is.
I'm sorry you had
to see that shit.
Hey, and I want to
apologize for this
because that's not me, okay?
I don't want
y'all thinking it is,
and this is stupid, too.
So I'm sorry for that.
Now, I gotta take the time
to give a special shout-out
to Miggs and Santiago.
Hell, yeah.
Yeah!
I'm clapping, ain't I?
Am I clapping?
Yeah!
My double agents.
You guys brought me
the best prize of them all.
James Payton.
What you think you doing...
Shut your ass up, man!
You don't have
the right to talk.
See, James,
for those who don't know,
James has been chasing
my ass day and night
for some time now.
But he can never catch me.
You know why?
Because he's one of those people
who thinks he always knows best.
Doesn't think that
people are good enough
for certain people,
without even really knowing
those other people.
You with me?
Guess what today is, big man?
Today is the day that you die.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm going to have to
put some tarps down
and shit.
Now I might finish
you off with my gun,
I might.
But I'm going to start you
off with the cold steel
of my katana blade.
I'm talking death
by a thousand cuts.
Oh, I'd like to see that.
(KNIFE UNSHEATHING)
Give us a little taste of that.
MIGGS: (LAUGHING) Yeah,
I'd be entertained by that.
A little preview.
Come on.
Hell yeah.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Okay.
You ready? Here it come.
Don't you.
I gotta cut you.
Don't you cut me.
What you think I gotta do?
I gotta do it!
(INDISTINCT)
(GRUNTS)
Yeah!
That's what you get, po-po!
Maybe stab him
a little more, cut him more.
Shut your ass up.
I ain't no show pony.
This shit is over.
Now what I'm going to do is
I'm gonna cut you loose.
Mmm-hmm. Yeah.
I'm going to let you
all handle this shit,
while I take this
piece of shit somewhere.
Get your ass up.
Let's go. Walk!
SERBIAN BOSS: Good,
because this
was getting ridiculous.
Thank you.
The hell are you looking at?
Nothing, Omar.
BEN: You can call me Omar now?
Can we just keep it moving?
I will not run
a crew without respect.
What?
I won't do it.
Get in here.
Let me tell
everybody in here
something right now.
It's about respect in this game!
I will not tolerate a crew
that does not respect me.
Respect is best served cold!
MAN: It's revenge!
BEN: Who said that?
Was that you?
Hmm?
Revenge is a dish
best served cold.
(LAUGHS) Oh!
Who in the hell are you?
I'm Omar.
Who the hell are you?
What are you
doing in my warehouse?
What the hell's going on
here? Kill them both.
Fellas, please.
We don't want to
make Omar nervous.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(BOTH SIGH)
Let me explain
something to you.
Omar is very comfortable.
You know why?
Because Omar doesn't
have a bunch of guns
pointed at him,
new guy.
I really don't mind
that you're
pretending to be me,
whoever you are,
but what I do mind is
that any of these idiots
actually believe this clown!
Ask this guy right here
who he thinks Omar is.
I don't know, it just hurts.
You shot Roberto?
You damn right I shot him.
I'm impressed.
Problem is,
if Omar shoots Roberto...
(ALL GASP)
Oh, shit!
Omar shoots Roberto.
I like you, little man.
You got balls.
So, you Omar!
Wait right there.
Damn, man!
You ain't what I pictured.
You ain't nothing
but a black dude.
Probably from Decatur.
(OMAR LAUGHING)
That's what you get
for thinking, James.
That really ain't your thing.
See, if you was thinking,
you'd get the big picture.
You'd see where you are.
Look around you, James.
You see where you are?
You're in the middle of
one of the biggest arms deals
to ever go down in this town.
You could be in on it.
But you playing
cops and robbers.
You think you
been looking for me,
but I've been watching you.
I've been following you.
I've spent a lot of time,
lot of money
thinking about you.
I spent so much money in fact,
your boys are
now working for me.
Everything all right
with your packages, fellas?
Yes, sir.
SANTIAGO: Come to
the other side, man.
Last I heard,
it ain't buying you
a house in Florida.
See, everybody wants to be
on the winning side, James.
That's what I want for you.
You out front,
me in the shadows.
We could run this town.
Yeah, that's right,
I see you're curious.
I'm gonna make you
this offer one time,
one last time.
What do you say?
I'm Omar!
(ALL GROANING)
Shut up!
Would you please stop!
Nobody believes you.
Get over there.
I'm gonna get with you later.
(WHIMPERS)
Come on now.
What's it gonna be?
Get your goddamn hands off me.
(SIGHS)
Well, I tried to put
the man in the penthouse.
He wants to spend his
life in the poorhouse.
Guess we'll have to
reinstate the death penalty.
You know what, Omar?
It really don't matter.
You could smoke me right here,
because we all gonna
die up in here anyway.
Oh, are we?
SERBIAN BOSS: What are
you talking about?
You know what I'm talking about.
Your boy Marko
told me everything.
It's a big setup.
Them boxes right there,
ain't nothing in
there but replicas.
Not true.
You ain't gonna like
how this movie end.
You just walked into
your own assassination.
We'll open the boxes
and find out, won't we?
(SCREAMING)
Which way do I go?
Right here.
Yo, this is crazy, man!
This shit is crazy!
Calm down!
I can't calm down!
Holy shit! Oh, shit!
James, I see a gun!
Get it!
(YELLS)
Shit! I got it! I got it!
Selective fire.
Visual confirm target.
Short bursts.
Just shoot!
Come on, here we go.
One, two, three, go!
I thought it was
the extended mags!
It's not the extended mags!
What you talking about?
Shit, I'm out.
What the hell are you doing?
In a game,
you can pick up
ammo off the ground!
This ain't no damn video game!
Hold on! I got one!
Oh, God!
Let's go!
Same thing on
the count of three.
Watch out!
I just saved your life!
Shit!
Shit.
Save my life and
get me the hell out of here!
(SCREAMING)
Yo, we can't go that way.
Why?
Because they got
AK-47s down there.
Two shotguns.
They're probably Benellis.
From the sound of it,
it might be AR-15 as well.
You can hear all that?
It's from the game.
I got a perfect recall.
I'm a Platinum level player.
Here you go! Huh?
See how you like that!
Call me the perfect storm.
Grenade!
You got five seconds
to pick it up
and throw it back.
Oh!
(MEN SCREAMING)
Stop throwing
the goddamn grenades!
I already pulled the pin.
Another one!
James, the money.
JAMES: Ben!
Get your ass back here!
It's gonna blow!
Let's get out of here!
Oh!
You all right?
I'm good.
Okay.
That's it?
That's not so bad.
I thought it was going
to be bigger than that.
Damn!
My car!
It's probably
still drivable though,
because it happened in the back.
You can't drive it now.
Yeah, it's definitely not
drivable. At first it was,
but after this, there's
no way you can drive it.
We have to get out of here.
Come on.
You wanna get a cab, or what?
Let's go.
Okay. All right.
BEN: So, what was
Omar going to do with
all those guns anyway?
JAMES: Probably start an army
and take over the city.
He's got half
the cops on his side.
So, we stopped him?
For now.
Hey.
What?
Slow down, man.
You see I got the money, right?
Yeah, that was good.
Hold this. My sock is wet.
Must have stepped in
a puddle or something.
Hate it when that happen.
(GASPS) What is that?
JAMES: Damn. You shot.
I think I would be able
to feel if I got shot.
You got so much adrenaline
going through you,
you don't feel it.
But I'm serious.
JAMES: Wow.
BEN: What?
It went straight through.
Oh, my God!
There's a hole in my leg!
I got shot!
Yeah I was pretty clear on that.
Oh, shit! It hurts now!
All right.
Sit yourself down. Sit down.
I ain't gonna sit down!
I just got shot!
I can't feel my toes!
Shh! Give me your belt.
You gonna whip me
because I got shot?
Tourniquet!
Okay.
You have to get a cold piece
of meat like a steak.
You have to put
a steak on it, man.
Listen!
I'm listening.
I got shot!
You're gonna be okay.
You lost a little blood.
Just have to get
you to a hospital.
Anybody down here?
Calm down!
All right, calm. I'm calm.
(PHONE RINGING)
(CHATTER ON POLICE RADIO)
(TURNS OFF)
Yeah.
Hey, Lieutenant,
we got a problem here.
I'm aware. Make this
easy on us, James.
Come on in.
Wait,
what are you talking about?
Listen, Santiago
and Miggs, they dirty.
(CHUCKLES) Funny,
they're saying the same
thing about you.
They got Marko and his buddy
backing them up.
What?
Hey! Tell him I got shot.
Lieutenant, you gotta
believe me, it didn't
go down like that.
You know I'm on your side.
Come in, James.
Just don't make it any worse.
Where are you?
BEN: My foot, I think
the tourniquet too tight.
We already at worse.
Is the ambulance coming?
Is it coming?
No.
And we can't call one either.
They'll be all
over the scanners.
What does that mean?
It means I'm on my own.
You're not on your own.
You got me, man.
Let's get you to a hospital.
Okay. Oh, shit.
Stop the car. Stop!
Sorry to inform you, sir,
but I have to
confiscate your vehicle.
That's not even a real badge.
I'm a police officer,
I need you to get out.
How you gonna
carjack me without a gun?
You right. Get your ass out.
Watch the sweater, man!
Hold on to your weed!
Firefighters are still
battling a nasty blaze
here at an abandoned warehouse
in the Old Fourth Ward
district of Atlanta.
Who cares?
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
DOCTOR: Let's start
two bags of O neg.
Let me know when
the next OR's available.
James, take my hand.
Ain't happening.
James, please.
Here, call Angela.
Tell her I love her.
Tell her I love her so much.
She sent you a text.
What she say? Read it to me.
It says...
"Come home soon."
"Come home soon"?
Oh, my God!
It's okay. Keep going.
James, what if I
never see her again?
Where's the doctor at?
I'm right here.
Doc, am I dying?
You're not dying.
No, seriously.
It's complicated.
I know you supposed
to call this in,
Doc, I'm losing breath,
I think I need some CCs.
I want you to buy me some time,
so we can make sure
that the one that did this
don't come back
and finish the job.
You feel me?
Okay.
Your buddy lost some blood,
so I'll give him
something for the pain.
We'll get him in
the next OR that opens up.
I appreciate it, Doc.
Nurse, start him on
some morphine,
dress that wound,
and let me know when
the next OR opens up.
James, should we give him
some of the money we took?
I don't know what
he's talking about.
You know what I'm
talking about. The money.
We good here, Doc.
WWJD?
Shut the fuck up!
I found the entrance
to the prison door,
I'm taking heavy fire.
Assface23, take out
that machine gunner.
If you actually want to win,
you have to listen to me.
All right.
This is not a game.
Shit! Someone lay
down suppressing fire.
I have to answer my door.
You are go for door.
ANGELA: Who is it?
Angela, it's Santiago and Miggs.
Can you do me a favor,
can you open up?
I need to talk to
you for a second.
What happened?
Is everything okay?
How are you doing?
Good.
Can we come in for a second?
Sure. Sure.
We're just looking for James
and your boyfriend.
They're not here by
any chance, are they?
No, I haven't
heard from James
or Ben in a while.
Is everything okay?
For you, no.
Wait, did you guys
just hear that?
Yeah, what the hell was that?
What should we do?
We should finish the game,
assholes.
No. Listen closely.
ANGELA:  Miggs and
Santiago, get out!
You can't hear that?
(ARGUING ON SPEAKER)
Yeah, something's wrong.
Can I ask you a question?
How many rainbows
are you made out of?
Because right now,
I can see one,
two, three trainbows.
(LAUGHING)
I just said "trainbows."
You know what, Ben?
Hmm?
I read you all wrong.
What are you talking about,
you "read" me?
Me and Angela had it rough.
Moving from foster
home to foster home.
It was right after
our parents died.
It was hard, man.
I didn't trust
nobody with Angela.
Can't nobody
protect her like me.
It was how I used to think.
It's hard to change, you know.
Mmm.
It's okay. It's fine.
Nah.
I need to trust her
a little more, you know.
She a big girl.
She know how to
pick the right guy.
Wow.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh!
That is it right there.
That's why I made
it my ring tone,
because I like it.
How do you answer this thing?
You have to slide it.
Those things are crazy.
It's your buddy, Assface.
Assface?
You have to answer that.
I can't wait for
you to meet Assface.
You gonna love him.
Hello?
No, he can't talk right now.
He's a little incapacitated.
Ain't nobody constipated.
What's this pertaining to?
I think there's
trouble at his house.
What?
I heard shouting.
When?
Just now, from Angela.
How many voices did you hear?
Two. Miggs and Santiago.
Are you sure
those were the names?
Yes.
Thank you, Assface.
Oh, my God, what happened?
You look like
a monster right now.
Miggs and Santiago, they got
Angela at your house.
What? Oh, no!
Sit back down. You on meds.
You can't move.
No, listen to me.
This is what we gonna do.
Listen.
You gonna help me up.
And you and me, and him.
We have to take him with us.
The three of us,
we gonna go over there
and kick some ass.
I can't have
nothing happen to you.
Angela would kill me.
After all we
been through today,
you still don't trust me?
Man, you still under...
(STATIC ON POLICE RADIO)
FEMALE OFFICER: Have
you seen these guys?
DOCTOR: No. Nothing.
Are you sure?
Come on, we have to get there.
Come on.
We have to get... Oh, shit!
Oh, you should have
helped me, James.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
BEN: Are my lips chapped?
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yeah.
OMAR:  James, my man.
I'm here with your
boys Santiago and Miggs.
Got somebody who
wants to holler at you.
There are three of
them and they're armed.
Don't touch me!
I'm gonna tell
you something,
if you touch her,
I'm peeling your wig back,
you understand me?
Ooh! Ooh! Threats. Threats.
JAMES:  I know
how you look now.
OMAR:  Keep talking, baby
sister ain't gonna make it.
What's it gonna be, James?
What do you want?
What do I want?
I want my money.
Yeah, I got it.
Yeah, come on, man,
you gotta hurry up
before we get
started without you.
We be there in 30 minutes.
But we right around the corner.
Exactly,
but they don't know that.
Right. They just unlocked
the Platinum level player.
Ain't gonna be no cheat codes.
I need you to stay focused.
Follow the plan.
I'm focused.
Timing gotta be on point.
Okay.
I'll need you to come in fast.
We gonna get their ass.
Mmm!
ANGELA: Don't touch me.
SANTIAGO: I could
make you so happy.
(GASPS)
(THUDS)
Hey. Go check that out.
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
BEN: Damn it, I missed him.
Ben?
You again?
Where you at?
I'm high as a kite.
I can't feel none of this.
Get off of him.
BEN: James!
Omar, freeze!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
James!
You better have my money.
Get off of me.
Stop!
Come here! Come here!
Ben!
No!
I'll be with you
in a sec, babe.
It didn't even hurt.
Black Hammer!
Bring my sister into this?
After everything
I did for you! Get up!
Get your ass up.
(PANTS) You are
gonna respect me.
Okay, listen.
I'm not trying to...
Bitch!
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
Ben!
You want some more?
I'm sorry,
I just made a huge mistake.
It's too late for that.
ANGELA: No!
Get off me.
Get your hands...
(YELLING)
Ahh! (WHEEZING)
How does it feel to be
on the other side now, huh?
You always think
you're better than everybody,
getting all your citations.
Looking down at all of us?
How does it feel now, huh?
Do it.
Get away from my brother!
Son of a...
Great, baby!
Ang, behind you.
James!
(PANTING)
ANGELA: James!
OMAR: Girl, you better
bring your little
narrow ass on
before you make me mad!
James!
Come on with me.
No!
Get off of me!
Omar!
James!
Let her go, man!
Damn, James,
you disappoint me, man.
Make you a nice offer.
Nice offer!
You got to turn me down.
You know I don't
like to be disappointed.
That's all right,
you stopped this deal,
but there's always
another deal to be made.
I'm accepting your offer now.
Now?
(LAUGHING)
No. Now, you gonna do
what I tell you to do.
You gonna put your
gun down, you gonna
watch me drive off
with your sister.
That's what's happening now.
You know I can't do that.
How about now?
Huh?
What's it gonna be, James?
You shut your little
ass up. Just keep your
narrow ass still.
Girl, you don't hold still
you gonna make me...
What? What?
ANGELA: No.
OMAR: Come on, James.
Huh?
Trust me.
OMAR: Clock's ticking!
What's it gonna be?
All right. Whoa.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh, now you want to
get some act right.
I'm putting it down.
Oh, now you're
putting it down, okay!
Bye, James.
BEN: Kick move.
(GROANS)
How do you like that end?
Damn.
Game over, bitch.
Oh...
He getting up.
James...
James, you got him, right?
BEN: I didn't even
realize I got shot
till we left the warehouse.
But I didn't panic, though.
Here comes the lieutenant.
So, now what are
you going to do?
What you mean?
Well, after three years
and all that overtime,
you finally got your man.
I didn't get my man.
BROOKS: I never
liked those two.
Hmm.
What?
No, I'm not going to say it.
I'm not.
No.
I'll see you at the office.
Did you see that?
Actually, I didn't.
You didn't see
the look that
he just gave me?
No.
That was a look
of respect, James.
I didn't even tell
you when they was
shooting at the warehouse
what I was doing.
Everybody's all over
the place, but I'm
locked in on Omar...
JAMES: Omar.
For the record,
I would've never
taken your offer.
See, you always
missing the big picture,
James.
Yeah, but I ain't
gonna miss your ass.
Oh.
Get his ass out of here.
(AMBULANCE DOORS CLOSING)
Ben held his own, huh?
Did he impress you enough?
We didn't get ourselves killed.
So I guess he did all right.
That was your approval.
You just gave
me your blessing.
Did you hear that, Ang?
James, you just
gave me your blessing
just now.
James, don't you walk...
Come here, James.
Baby, you gotta help me
because this
morphine done worn off.
This shit hurts. James!
I can't chase you
because of my leg,
but I wanna give you a hug.
Look at this, ladies.
He has amazing taste.
Great taste, right?
No. Hey...
I need you at least
15 feet away from
this grill at all times.
James, please don't start.
I can't even believe
you over here, man,
after what you did to me.
What I did to you
was not my fault.
You set me on fire!
You know what?
On my phone I can
go to a website,
and this website will
give me instructions
on how to use this machine.
You're not using my grill.
Back off.
Give me your
Wi-Fi password.
No.
Let me get your wee-fee.
Give me the wee-fee!
Suspect-shot-23.
There's so many
other passwords
that you could have chose.
Airplane. Bike.
It's too much, man.
I'm in, watch out.
Let me do it.
Move. No.
James.
Come on. Stop it.
This is unnecessary.
This is stupid.
No, get back.
Will you trust me!
I'm a man that's weeks away
from graduating from
the police academy.
Dude, this is symbolic.
All right.
Thank you.
I turned the gas
on five minutes ago!
(SCREAMING)
(PEOPLE GASPING)
BEN: I'm all right, Angela!
(COUGHING) I'm okay.
Hey, James,
you should give
your neighbors a call,
because I think
I killed their dog
when I came in hot.
I might have
second-degree burns, people.
Let's just say
third-degree to be safe
because my chest
is blistering up
as we speak.