© Give me Iand, Iots of Iand
under starry skies above...
© Let me be by myseIf in the evening breeze
© Listen to the murmur
of the cottonwood trees
© Send me offforever
© But I ask you pIease
© Don't fence me in
© Just turn me Ioose
© Let me straddIe my own saddIe
© Underneath the western skies
© Oo-oo
© On my cayuse
© Let me wander over yonder
© TiII I see the mountains rise
© Oo-oo-oo-oo
© I want to ride to the ridge
where the West commences
© Gaze at the moon untiI I Iose my senses
© Can't Iook at hobbIes
and I can't stand fences
© Don't fence me in
© Just turn me Ioose
© Let me straddIe my own saddIe
© Underneath the western skies
© Oo-oo
© On...
Hey!
Come back here.
I hate that when you do that!
I was bored to death.
WeII, lwas having fun.
WeII, good for you.
- Get in!
- No, I'm grabbing a cab.
Get in!
Stop it!
Leave me aIone, Eddie.
Don't evertry that again...
or eIse!
Or eIse what?
Mr Yoshida says,
''We regret we can go no further.''
''This is our finaI proposaI.''
''Your company wiII benefit greatIy
from this new reIationship.''
''Now you must decide the fate of MicroCon.''
We shouId cIose at this price.
Let's see ifwe can hoId out
tiII Congress votes.
We can't puII backjust now.
DeaI's too far gone.
- They'll suspectifwe stall.
- They'II suspect ifwe staII.
Listen, I'm the Iast guy
who wants to screw this up.
DeaI's too good,
but we have to have some strategy.
That's whatl'm saying.
They're going to staII.
Hey, guys.
- How's it going?
- Good.
If there's anything you don't understand...
Oh, no. We're uh...
- We're fine.
- Great. That's good to hear.
You're gonna be part of a great team.
Once these guys draw
a Iine in the sand, that's pretty much it.
You want that research and deveIopment
money, don't you?
Nakamoto Group can do a Iot for you.
- Yeah, right.
- Great.
That guy is an asshoIe.
The deaI wiII put vitaI eIements of our
miIitary weaponry under Japanese controI.
Come on, Senator Morton.
That's reaIIy a scare tactic.
During the GuIfWar, the Japanese suggested
they couId deny us that weaponry. In fact...
- You're oversimpIifying a compIex issue.
- No...
He's trying to say America is Iooking for
a new enemy now the CoId War is over.
TaIk about simpIifying!
You're doing the simpIifying, Senator.
Hold on.
Let's let... Eleanor, let the Senatorin, please.
l came here to Los Angeles because...
Before we hear that, l couldn't detect
exactly howyou're going to vote.
- You know, they warnedme aboutyou.
- Well, theyshould!
They should!
- Howare you going to vote?
- Against the sale ofMicroCon.
Thank you forsaying thatflat out.
Let me askyou guys on this side.
You sometimes make itsoundas if
Japan's prosperityis badforAmerica.
ls that whatyou mean?
The realissue is that this technology
is paidforbyAmerican taxpayers...
This discussion is degenerating
into the kind ofargument we don'tneed.
This is already a very tense situation.
There will soon be a vote
in Congress and we will decide
whether the MicroCon sale goes through.
I don't get you, Eddie.
So what?
Oh, Iadies, one thing.
Do remember that the custom here
is bow when you're bowed to.
Oh, wow!
They reaIIy roIIed out the red carpet.
- What fIoor are we going to?
- 45th.
- After you, Greg.
- Thank you, Rick.
Bow when you're bowed to.
- Oh, wow! Look at this. Everybody's here.
- This is amazing!
There's Barry Hirsch. The Mayor.
- We're in the fast Iane now.
- Oh, we sure are.
- Look, here's Yoshida-san and the boys.
- Get ready to bow.
Wife.
- Taiko drums!
- Huh?
Taiko drums. Long ago
they were used to drive away eviI spirits.
Come here.
No, here.
Yes.
Yes...
Yes... More...
Ah, yes...
Yo, what's up?
Web. Tom Graham. You're on the chart
tonight, Special Services liaison.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Betterget overhere.
The newNakamoto building. 1100 Figueroa.
- l can'tbelieve they're pulling this shit.
- What stuff?
Demanding to see
the fuckin' Special Services liaison.
They say the police can'tproceed
until you gethere.
And what time
was thatphone call from Lieutenant Graham?
What time?
Yes. What time was it?
9.00pm.
February 9th.
Four nights ago?
Was that a yes, Lieutenant Smith?
Yeah. It's a yeah.
Lieutenant Smith,
we appreciate your cooperation.
You waived your right
to be represented here by an attorney.
So... Lieutenant Graham caIIed for
the SpeciaI Services Iiaison.
He saidhe hada homicide.
Yeah, a homicide. Apparent 601.
Caucasian femaIe, I'd say 25.
Lying fIat on her back on the boardroom tabIe
Iike a piece of sushi.
Quite a sight. Better get down here.
Hello. l'm a police offiicer.
Can lbe ofassistance?
May lsee yourpassport?
- What's up?
- This is Watch CommanderHoffman.
Yes, sir.
You're on your way to Nakamoto Towers.
l wantyou to pick someone up.
- CertainIy, sir.
- A guy named Connor.
- Connor?
- Yeah, John Connor.
But I thought... he was Iong gone.
No, he's verymuch alive.
They putin a requestforhim.
- They? Who's they?
- You go. l'll phone him.
- He lives byLittle Tokyo. 428 Rose Street.
- Yes, sir.
428 Rose Street.
Connor?
And you didnotknow
Captain Connorprior to this night?
No, l didnot.
- l'd only heardabouthim.
- Whathadyou heard?
l heard thathe hadlong ago
put himselfon indefiinite leave.
That he hadlivedin Japan.
Some people thought theygot to him.
Some people said that...
Said what?
The man couldn'tbe trusted.
You're Iate.
Yeah, sorry.
- The directions were...
- No.
Be on time.
Shoes.
Is it normaI procedure now for the Japanese
to demand a Iiaison officer?
No. It's usuaIIy an assignment.
What time were you caIIed?
Lieutenant Graham caIIed at nine.
Hoffman caIIed in the car.
You were caIIed twice?
Yeah.
I wish I'd known that sooner.
Have you negotiated with the Japanese?
Negotiated?
Mm. Perhaps I can suggest the strategy.
WeII, this is hardIy a negotiation.
Oh? What is it, then?
What is it?
It's a homicide.
When we arrive,
you take charge ofthe negotiations.
Don't introduce me or refer to me.
Don't even Iook in my direction.
Keep yourjacket buttoned at aII times.
If they bow, you bow back.
BeIieve it or not, I have done this before.
You know, I do know these things.
Do keep your hands at your sides.
The Japanese find
big arm movements threatening.
Keep your voice caIm and even.
You'II probabIy find them irritating tonight.
But whatever happens,
don't Iose your temper.
I don't Iose my temper.
That's good to know.
When you start to get into troubIe...
I won't get into troubIe.
When you start to get into troubIe,
I wiII say, ''Perhaps I can be of assistance?''
From then on, ldo the taIking.
You stand behind me.
And don't appear distracted.
We may come from a fragmented,
MTV, rap-video cuIture, but they do not.
Every aspect ofyour appearance
and behaviour wiII refIect on you,
the Department, and me as your sempai.
My sempai?
That wouIdn't be massa, wouId it?
No. The sempai is the senior man
who guides the junior man, the kohai.
In Japan, the sempai-kohai reIationship
is presumed to exist
when the younger man and the oIder man
work together.
HopefuIIy, they wiII presume that of us.
So what does it mean
that I was caIIed twice?
It means they're ahead of us.
For aII they know,
I couId have been five minutes away.
They know who was on caII tonight,
how Iong it wouId take you to get here.
They know aII about you.
- AII about me?
- Mm.
- It took you Iong enough.
- Tom.
What the fuck's he doing here?
Fred Hoffman toId me to bring him.
The guy is troubIe. Watch out.
The Department put him on Ieave
because he's too cIose to Japan.
- He's not a team pIayer.
- Where is everybody?
They made us put our cars around back.
They keep saying
nothing must disrupt the grand opening.
Finding that bIonde piece of sushi
drove them nuts.
Don't want their guests or the press to know.
Step aside, paI.
- You come down aIready.
- Yeah?
WeII, now I go back up.
Maybe come down, go up 10 times more. OK?
We're stiII the fuckin' poIice
in our own country.
BuiIt this buiIding in six months.
Prefab units from Japan, sIapped 'em
together here. Not one American worker.
City gave 'em an eight-year break
on property taxes.
Shit! We're giving this country away.
Nobody forced us to do it.
Jesus!
If an eIevator's gonna taIk, it shouId
speak in American. What did it say?
We're arriving at the 45th fIoor.
No, no. Wait a second.
The Japanese provide jobs here,
but US companies are moving jobs offshore.
Ground fIoor, pIease.
- They must...
- Going up, Senator.
- No, no. I wish to go down.
- Get the next one, Senator.
Come on.
No, no, no. You don't understand!
Senator Morton.
ReaI nice to find him partying here,
considering he's on the committee
which sets aII import reguIations.
Geronimo!
Coming through!
I have your Iiaison for you.
Is this your home phone, Detective?
Yes. Right there at the bottom.
Detective, Iet's dispense with the formaIities.
We'd Iike to cooperate,
but you can't start without a warrant.
- BuIIshit. We don't need one.
- We can get one in 15 minutes.
- But we do have a reported homicide here.
- More IikeIy a drug overdose.
We can't know that untiI we investigate.
ObviousIy.
But I'm concerned about the attempt
to Iink this death to our reception downstairs.
I don't know, sir.
Looks Iike she's wearing a party dress.
She is, I agree.
Lieutenant, you have to appreciate
the position ofthe Nakamoto Corporation.
- Sir, I...
- This is an important evening for us.
A very pubIic evening.
We don't want it marred by the death
of a woman of no importance.
- Of no importance?
- You have some nerve!
- I can't imagine how she came to be in here.
Your Lieutenant Graham intends
to interrogate everybody,
the Mayor, the Senators, and Congressmen.
Graham said that?
Oh, Christ! What is this?
Do you mind turning around?
- Who is he?
- Mr Tanaka works for Nakamoto Security.
- Get him outta here!
- We have authorised him to be here.
I'm authorising him out!
He's contaminating the area. And get his fiIm!
- We must undertake our own private inquiry.
- I'II get you a warrant and a restraining order!
Do that! Be my guest!
Excuse me.
Perhaps uh... I can be of assistance.
Ishihara-san, I'm sure none ofyour guests
are invoIved in this unfortunate incident.
They are free to go as they wish.
I am gratefuI for your assistance.
But before they Ieave, give me
the names ofthose gentIemen, pIease.
I'm sorry.
The names ofthose gentIemen.
May I ask why?
- Ritchie! Mugshots! AII ofthem!
- You cannot do this!
No! You are to bIame here!
You wiII assist my detectives!
And I want to know who discovered the body!
And don't you fuck with me!
But of course,... Captain.
Yeah, don't fuck with us.
Mount up, boys. Let's get it done
before she starts to smeII.
- Isn't it bad form to Iose your temper?
- It is. But I had to, to assist Ishihara.
Assist Ishihara?
Now why wouId you wanna do that?
He wasn't the most important man
in the room.
- Oh, he wasn't?
- No. It was the oIder man.
His juyaku, his superior.
But I wanted to get the investigation going
so I pIayed the out-of-controI gaijin.
So Ishihara wouIdn't Iose face.
So now, Ishihara owes me a favour.
Deep, isn't it?
Heavy.
The executive fuck chamber.
Oh, man, I Iike this! I Iike this!
That's nice. That's nice.
These guys sure know how to do business.
HoId that.
Her nostriIs Iook Iike
a margarita gIass rim.
- Think she OD'd on coke?
- I don't think so.
We'II get Iab vaIues on aII fIuids.
Some seminaI fIuid down here.
ExternaI genitaIs are pretty raw.
It Iooks Iike forced intercourse,
but I'm not sure she was murdered.
Not sure she was murdered?
Come on, you gotta be kidding me.
The make-up on the neck
covers signs of prior throat injuries.
That suggests a pattern
of repeated cervicaI trauma.
CouId be a case of sexuaI asphyxia.
She's a gasper.
Which is what?
IndividuaIs sexuaIIy aroused by
the hypoxia of near-stranguIation.
They ask their partners to strangIe them
or suffocate them during sex.
It's easy to make a mistake and go too far.
This Iooks Iike death from inhibition to me.
- Instantaneous physioIogicaI death.
- Meaning what?
The person just... dies.
Happens with neck or chest injuries.
Had a kid got hit with a basebaII.
FeII down dead in the schooIyard.
Yeah. Maybe she got hit with a basebaII.
Odds are she was strangIed.
But since having sex isn't a feIony,
it wouIdn't be murder.
Anyway, fiIe in the back ofyour mind
that maybe she just popped off.
CheryI Lynn Austin. Age 23.
This says she has a Westwood address,
but she hasn't changed
her Kentucky Iicence yet.
Japanese cigarettes and credit cards.
Nice tight roII of $100 biIIs.
Miss Austin's weII taken care of.
These IittIe guys eat shit in Tokyo.
Crammed into subways,
working for big companies.
They come here and they're rich and free.
They aII want to fuck a Rose BowI queen.
And then kiII the Rose BowI queen
on the Nakamoto boardroom tabIe?
CaII the poIice and create a scandaI?
Is that your theory?
- My theory?
- Mm.
My theory is that these guys
are known perversion freaks.
I got a nose for these things.
I'm sure.
Hey, Spider-san.
TeII your paI they got a contest.
Whoever kisses the most asses
wins a Toyota.
Hey, Graham! Want some sushi?
Nah. If I get a craving for mercury,
I'II eat a thermometer.
In Japan, criminaIs expect to be caught.
Convictions run about 90%.
Here, it's cIoser to 171/2%.
They think we're stupid.
They think we're corrupt.
And they're not often wrong.
What the heII are you doing?
Good evening, offiicers. Can lhelp you?
Yes, you can. Where are you Iocated?
- Lobbylevel. Across from the elevators.
- Thank you.
How Iong have you been on duty tonight?
About haIf an hour.
Mr Tanaka was here when I got here.
Mr Tanaka? Who's Mr Tanaka?
He's the head of security.
Mr PhiIIips, the 46th fIoor, the cameras?
I know in Japan
they Iike to observe their workers
to heIp them improve their efficiency.
I saw at Ieast four up there. Why so many?
You didn't hear this from me.
I guarantee we didn't hear it from you.
Maybe they put in a coupIe of new cameras
to observe those negotiations.
What negotiations were those?
The ones that go on up there during the day
with a company caIIed MicroCon.
MicroCon. The computer chip company?
There's a vote coming up
in Congress on that deaI.
Put up the 46th fIoor.
Can the camera get in cIoser?
- You have to use the gizmo.
- The gizmo? Show me.
You, uh, use the gizmo... to zoom in.
This is aII next-generation. There is
nothing Iike this in this country... yet.
You record by disk?
Record? What do you mean, record?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
The disks are aII back there.
It's aII there on next-generation Iaser disk.
I'd Iike to see tonight's disk for the 46th fIoor.
You'd have to taIk with my supervisor.
You got a warrant?
These disks record for 12 hours.
Why does the one on the 46th fIoor
onIy show two hours?
Excuse me?
The originaI disk isn't even here,
anyway, is it?
Because it's been repIaced.
I wouIdn't know about that.
That's Mr Tanaka's department.
Someone at this very moment is watching us.
Under the circumstances,
you've been more than heIpfuI.
I'd Iike to teII you officers something.
This is a good job.
Around here, if something doesn't work,
I got a probIem,
I teII somebody, they fix it!
It's not Iike when I was working
at GM out there in Van Nuys.
- This is different here.
- You're part of a team.
What, a team? What are they doing for you?
They spotting for you?
Sending you in pIays, huh?
Maybe they got instant repIay...
Hey, brother, come on!
These peopIe have been good to me.
Kohai, I'm gonna caII in a favour.
Stay here with Mr PhiIIips.
Come on, kohai.
Lieutenant Smith.
Don't fuck with these guys.
Hey, the honeys are out tonight.
Oh, here's a nice one. Let's use the gizmo.
Oh, yeah, she's nice.
Not so nice.
She's my ex-wife.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't know.
Don't be. She's a Iawyer.
It must be nice to fuck a Iawyer
instead of aIways being fucked by one.
I've seen your friend
around here quite a bit.
- ReaIIy?
- Yeah.
ReaI friendIy with Mr Yoshida there.
And who's Mr Yoshida?
Mr Yoshida's the man!
Let's Iisten in.
l knownothing ofthis.
Any recordings we have
are yours to examine.
l will look into itimmediately.
What does that mean?
Massa wants me to get the car.
Senator Morton, you said
if the saIe of MicroCon is approved,
they wiII controI the market
and use the technoIogy
to compete against our own companies.
You know that there is a time and a pIace
for business,
and tonight I just want to say
that our hosts threw one heck of a gaIa.
But, Senator, you've said,
''Look what happened to our TV industry.''
- Is there such a thing as off-duty?
- Let's wrap it up.
Hey, you! Quit Ioafing!
Get the Senator's car! We're waiting.
No! You get the Senator's car.
Wrong guy. Wrong fuckin' century.
Penguin-Iookin' motherfucker!
Let me smack this asshoIe.
Captain Connor!
Remember me? Bob Richmond.
Myers, Lawson and Richmond.
I understand my Nakamoto guys
got a IittIe frazzIed tonight.
If I can be of any heIp to you,
I'm avaiIabIe.
That's comforting.
AsshoIe!
I knew him when he was a government
trade negotiator deaIing with the Japanese.
Now he's working for them.
Like I said,... asshoIe.
HeIp you?
CheryI Lynn Austin.
- She not in.
- Yeah, I know.
Keys.
Room two.
The doorman's Yakuza.
I noticed his tattoo. I didn't know
there were so many Yakuza in America.
This isn't America.
This is that shadow worId.
They have bars, cIubs and... bettaku.
Bettaku. Love residence
where mistresses are kept.
- This is one, huh?
- Correct.
Here we are.
What time did it start raining tonight?
After nine.
Someone was here after nine.
Correct.
Look at this.
She's with Eddie.
You know him?
Mm. Eddie Sakamura.
What's this?
GirIfriend was into some different shit.
Look.
What is with this guy? There's a Iot
of pictures of her with your friend Sakamutu.
- Sakamura.
- Whatever.
Somebody's taken photos from here recentIy.
Oh... I thought I heard Eddie's voice.
Say,...
- Why is everybody in CheryI's room tonight?
- Everybody?
WeII, you and...
Aren't you just a IittIe bit off Iimits here?
And who are you?
Me?
WeII, I'm JuIia.
I'm just a IittIe neighbour girI
who Iives down the haII.
Are you CheryI's back-door man?
And what if I am?
WeII...
If you are,
I heard ofyou.
You better watch out
cos Eddie, he's the reaI jeaIous type.
They don't caII him Crazy Eddie for nothing.
ReaIIy? WeII, I'm kinda tough.
Mm, weII,
tough as you may be,
Eddie finds out,
then you're gonna be crying.
Um, say,
is CheryI aII right?
No, she isn't.
Lieutenant Web Smith. LAPD.
I knew he was gonna do something to her.
I heard him screaming at CheryI.
Shouting things Iike, ''I'II kiII you'',
before he took her to that party tonight.
Many thanks, miss.
Someone from my office wiII contact you.
I knew he was gonna do something to her.
Kohai.
You know, Web...
Eddie's father is a big industriaIist
over there at Daimatsu.
He has a... a friend he sees.
Jeanette.
Right up here on the second fIoor.
You know how Eddie met CheryI?
WeII,
she was working in that Toyota pIant
back there in Kentucky.
Then one day,
who shouId show up
in that smaII, IittIe town...
but Eddie.
Web...
She was about to give up the murderer,
and you just waIk away.
Maybe I've been bought off by the Japanese.
Sempai, appIe pie, whatever I have
to caII you,... we have a murder here.
I want to soIve it,
not Iisten to true confessions.
You know what's true?
When something Iooks too good
to be true, then it's not true.
Everything she said about Eddie
might have been true.
The reaI question is
why was she saying it?
OK! Why was she saying it?
I'm not sure.
Because she thought
Eddie kiIIed the girI!
This JuIia accidentaIIy waIked in...
Nothing is happening accidentaIIy.
She's a messenger.
- Oh, you think someone sent her?
- Mm.
OK. Who?
The bad guys.
And I suppose they sent her in
to find out what we know.
Or to teII us what they wanted us to know.
Or maybe to sIow us down.
She certainIy sIowed you down.
BuIIshit!
BuIIshit?
Never underestimate your opponent.
Never take what he offers you.
You want to soIve this crime?
- Yes.
- WeII, so do I.
Now Iet's move.
Come on, Eddie!
DarIing, those days are gone from your Iife.
I couId dance Iike that. I'm an oId
song-and-dance man from way back.
Oh, yeah? Wanna teach me some steps?
- It's by invitation onIy, gentIemen.
- Mr Sakamura.
- Mr Sakamura is not here.
- That's him. The bad tap-dancer.
Mr Sakamura is not avaiIabIe.
Mr Sakamura is a good friend of mine.
I'm sure he's avaiIabIe for me.
GentIemen, you're trespassing.
Now, unIess you have a search warrant,
you'II have to Ieave.
You shouId know I'm a bIack beIt.
- But of course you are, dear.
- Need heIp, Perry?
So is Jeff.
OK, feIIas. You're Ieaving.
That's assauIt.
I don't wanna hurt you.
They say ifyou must resort
to vioIence, you've aIready Iost.
What do you think, Jeff?
I think I'II go get Mr Sakamura.
- Ah, Captain Connor!
- Eddie.
My father wiII be happy to hear
you're stiII up to your same oId tricks.
We're here to taIk, Eddie.
So taIk. It's a free country.
It's about the murder at Nakamoto tonight.
WeII, Iet's taIk outside.
Yeah. I heard about that. Some poor girI.
You know her, Eddie.
CheryI Austin.
Oh, yeah, CheryI. Mm. That girI.
Too bad.
I hear she was a reaI hentai onna.
You knew her better than that.
You're putting her up at the ImperiaI Arms.
Oh, that CheryI. Oh, I know her reaI weII.
- She was aII over me, Connor-san.
- You're irresistibIe.
That's true, but...
Connor-san, she had a big probIem.
She was a sick girI. She Iiked pain.
Put a pIastic bag over her head,
aIways saying, ''Squeeze harder.''
Squeeze the neck? You Iike that, do you?
Me? No!
I'm a straight meat-and-potatoes man.
Don't Iet 'em see you Iike this. Get up!
- Did you see her tonight?
- Tonight? Me?
Maybe for two minutes at the party.
Just to say heIIo.
Mr Sakamura,
I think you'd better come with us.
Yeah, I saw her tonight.
I brought her to the party.
But I have nothing to do with it.
Look, I can prove it to you.
Just Iet me caII you Iater.
I wiII bring you something.
- I think that's a bad idea.
- Captain.
Nakamoto is keiretsu.
My father is Daimatsu keiretsu.
If his son is arrested here,
there wiII be repercussions.
Business is war. I know you understand.
Do you have your passport?
Yeah, sure.
Give him your card.
And you caII him, Eddie.
Connor-san!
- I sure hope you know what you're doing.
- Me, too.
He's guiIty as heII.
WeII, my dairokkan says he's not.
I hope your intuition is right.
Look, sempai,
my dairokkan teIIs me your dairokkan
wasn't why you Iet Eddie go.
In Japan, his father saved my Iife.
And Eddie reminded you ofthat?
He wouId never remind me.
It's my responsibiIity to remember.
So what is aII this buIIshit
about his father's keiretsu?
BuIIshit? There's a keiretsuwar going on.
A Japanese corporation never stands aIone.
A keiretsu is a united front
of hundreds of powerfuI companies,
aII acting in partnership to win.
To win what?
Whatever's there.
You ever hear ''business is war''?
The war is never over.
Maybe you heard
''AII's fair in Iove and war''?
No.
- So where does that Ieave us?
- Us?
We're in the war zone.
So, based on the Iab resuIts,
the guy who fucked her was Japanese.
Semen anaIysis is bIood type AB.
Diego factor positive.
Negative for ethanoI dehydrogenase.
Asian pattern.
MaIe pubic hair aIso Asian in origin.
Evidence points to a Japanese perpetrator.
It's a Jap perp aII right.
What the heII's this?
Looks Iike your guy confessed.
No. It's just Sumimasen.
If they're caught doing something wrong, to
get Ieniency, they must perform an apoIogy.
- You mean it's an act?
- Not exactIy.
He's genuineIy scared
you'II create a scandaI.
Yoshida-san insisted that he find
the missing disk and deIiver it to us.
Yeah, good Iuck.
That disk is probabIy
in a Tokyo IandfiII by now.
What the heII's this?
Daytime. 46th fIoor.
Negotiations for MicroCon.
Semiconductors.
Hey, can we skip the cartoons?
HoId on. We're just starting.
Richmond-san. Busy, busy.
Hey, Iet's go. Get to it!
Night-time. Same pIace.
Looks different then.
Jesus! It's her.
HeIIo.
Come on in.
He Iooks Japanese.
Maybe he's PoIish.
He's checking to see
if she's carrying a gun.
Someone's using the gizmo.
Gizmo. He's sure using it on her.
There go the hands to the neck.
Just the way she Iikes it.
Hey, Mr Nice Guy. Turn around.
Oh, no! Don't teII me
he's gonna waIk out in the dark.
No! Step into...
There! Back it up!
There.
That's right, I knew it aII aIong.
- I was right about this.
- Eddie.
You know this fucker?
Eddie Sakamura.
We had him tonight.
- What do you mean, you had him?
- We had him. We Iet him go.
- I kept his passport.
- His fuckin' passport? Jesus!
Get his ass, not his passport!
What are you waiting for? You want banzai
carved on her ass with a samurai sword?
Let's go get this Eddie Sock-It-To-Me.
I'm gonna break your arms, my friend.
I'm gonna Iove breaking them.
Come on, Web!
The oId guy sucker punched me.
If I see him again, he's dead meat.
Oh, forget it.
Good evening, Jeff. Mr Sakamura in?
Easy, big feIIa.
Just Iike oId times, Web.
Do you miss it? A night out with the boys?
- Sure beats aII that dipIomacy shit.
- I thought no vioIence.
Last thing we want.
The guy's a murderer, Spider-san.
LAPD takes no chances.
Yeah, but we do take prisoners. Right?
Why did Connor Iet this guy waIk?
I can't say.
What is he about?
He's aIways carefuI not to offend their...
What is it we're not supposed to offend?
Fuck 'em, they break the Iaw.
If that brands me as a reactionary...
- We're in position. Standby.
- Moving in.
Is reactionary a dirty word?
Like racist, or something Iike that?
AII this taIk of race.
Whatever happened to good and eviI?
A guy did it, you catch him.
PIundering our naturaI resources.
Fuckin' guys are into everything!
What time you got, Web?
2.10.
Make a note.
At 2.11, suspect was apprehended.
Eddie Sakamura caIIing. It's urgent.
I must speak about missing disk.
PoIice! Get down!
Stay where you are! Get down!
Don't move! Get down!
- You guys, out the back!
- You son of a bitch!
What the heII? Get off of me!
There he goes!
Ow, shit!
What the heII is wrong with you? Get off!
You're nuts! Get off of me!
Get that son of a bitch!
- I'm a poIice officer!
- You're a piece of shit!
8-Adam-65.
Am in pursuit of187 suspect,
eastbound, Sunset.
All units, standby.
8-Adam-65 in pursuit eastbound...
8-Adam-65, whatis yourlocation?
Stay back, l wanthim alive.
HoIy shit!
Damn! Damn, damn, damn!
Coroner's officiaIs have taken possession
of the charred remains
identified as Mr Edward Sakamura.
The crash took pIace after...
We tried to take him, but he ran, Chief.
Burnt beyond recognition. The guy's a cinder.
You got proofthat Sakamura
committed the murder?
- AbsoIuteIy. Got it aII recorded. Right?
- AbsoIuteIy.
You did everything by the book?
By the book. AbsoIuteIy, Chief.
AbsoIuteIy.
But everything was not
absoIuteIy by the book.
AbsoIuteIy not.
And when did you discover this?
Yeah.
- Lieutenant Smith?
- Yeah.
This is division dispatcher.
Uncleared messages.
- AII right, go ahead.
- 5.27am, Captain Connor.
Oh, Connor.
He said to give you a wake-up call atseven
and to meethim at the golfclub at 9.15am.
AII right, aII right. Anything eIse?
Let's see... Nope.
What about Iast night?
You gotall yourmessages lastnight.
No, I didn't caII in Iast night.
Yeah, you did.
Let's see... yep.
2.33. Your clearance number was given
and messages were transmitted.
Look, I forgot.
Can you give those messages to me again?
All right, justa sec.
What were you doing Iast night?!
- Sort of heIping my career.
- Is that good?
Yeah. It's aIways good.
Cos you gotta Iook out
for yourseIf in Iife.
Grandma says you gotta Iook out
for other peopIe.
Yeah. WeII, you gotta do that, too.
That's why everybody's so busy aII the time.
So, is that what business is?
Business?
No, business... Business is...
Business is... is...
I can't expIain it to you right now.
Is that why Mommy says
you've no head for business?
- Lieutenant Smith? Here we go.
- Yeah.
Daddy? Why does Mommy caII you a Ioser?
Out!
Ken Shubik, please call. Message reads,
''The Weasel's checking up on you.''
- The WeaseI?
- Yeah.
Then 2.10 this morning,
Mr Eddie Sakamura...
- Eddie Sakamura?
- Correct.
2.10am. Message reads,
''Urgent. Mustspeak aboutmissing disk.''
Nice shot!
Hey! I gotta taIk to you!
We gotta have a conversation.
Shit!
Yoshida-san. I'm embarrassed
by this crude interruption.
You must pIay your stroke again.
No penaIty.
- Ken Shubik.
- Hey, Ken! Web Smith.
- Did you get my message?
- Yeah, about the Weasel.
Last night, l'm working late at the paper...
I see the WeaseI arrive, dressed in his tux.
He goes right to the Iibrary.
I couId teII the ambitious turd
had the scent of bIood.
He's stiII here.
l ask the librarian whathe's checking out.
She says, ''A cop named Web Smith.''
- What?
- Yep. The guy's a scumbag forhire.
He used to do jobs
for the studios and reaItors.
The IittIe turd just got
a new Mercedes 500SL.
Pretty good on a reporter's saIary.
Wonder who he's working for now?
You get on the wrong side
of somebody Iast night?
- Maybe.
- Somebody's got the Weasel trackingyou.
Something about
a charge broughtagainstyou.
- A charge brought against me?
- You anda Lieutenant Tom Graham.
At the hearing I was cIeared. It was buIIshit!
Maybe so, butl thoughtyou'dbetterknow.
Smells like something heavy coming down.
What happened to the disk? We Ieft it
with you when we went to get Eddie.
And you got Eddie.
Oh, yes. It was aII over the paper.
There was no mention ofthe murdered girI
on the boardroom tabIe, right?
You had the disk.
It is against the ruIes to take evidence.
The ruIes?
Whose ruIes?
The ruIes!
The chief says we fucked up...
The Japanese have a saying.
''Fix the probIem, not the bIame.''
Find out what's fucked up and fix it.
Nobody gets bIamed.
We're aIways after who fucked up.
Their way's better.
Their way is better?
You wake me up to teII me that?
Wake you up? That'II be the day.
Keep it, sport.
Next time, try a parking meter.
- Captain Connor?
- Yes.
A gift from Mr Hanada.
Thank you. I appreciate it.
Most weIcome. Most weIcome.
You must have reaIIy
took those guys this morning.
No. I Iost.
Lost? Guys didn't Iook aII that good.
They're not.
It's difficuIt to Iose
without making it too obvious.
- That way they don't Iose face.
- Saving face.
Sounds more to me
Iike you were kissing ass.
Not exactIy.
I've done services for those men in the past.
And we've shared information.
They said that Eddie's death
wiII have repercussions.
Yeah, right!
I'm sorry. The guy was a fugitive.
He kiIIed the girI.
- I doubt it.
- You doubt it?
WeII, I saw it on the disk.
Did you?
It's the onIy space avaiIabIe to us.
We anaIyse commerciaIs and network news
to see how the pubIic's being tricked.
ProbIem is, most students want to Iearn
the tricks so they can use them to get ahead.
OK, everybody!
CIass is over.
Ice-skating rink upstairs.
The ice meIts down here.
Speaking of ice, Captain, she's been at it
since you gave her the disk at 3am.
Jingo Asakuma,...
meet Lieutenant Web Smith.
You're Iate.
What have we got?
Something there.
In the edge coIours.
Look at shadow Iines.
They added some shadows.
Look at the Iight source.
We can see her face, but we can't see his.
- Perfectjob, though.
- And what eIse?
The refIection.
- Of Eddie.
- It's fishy.
Wait a minute. What's going on here?
Here we are.
Let's Iook at the coIour shift in the pixeIs.
Yeah. Let's Iook at those pixeIs.
PixeIs have been doctored.
See the bIue edge?
- This disk's a copy.
- A copy? Wait a minute.
You're saying somebody put Eddie's face
there and it's not his refIection?
Come on, that's buIIshit!
BuIIshit? Where have you been, Lieutenant?
You don't think video can be aItered?
I want you to watch what I've been recording
on that camera.
This is quick and crude, but imagine
the effect with more sophisticated equipment.
Watch this.
You're saying somebody putEddie's face
there andit's nothis reflection?
Come on, that's bullshit!
- They'd need photos ofthis man.
- They have photos of Eddie.
From the dead girI's apartment.
Off the mirror.
- Do you beIieve in ghosts, Lieutenant Smith?
- What do you mean, do I beIieve in ghosts?
In Japan, when I was growing up,
we beIieved in many ghosts.
I want you to watch this.
TeII me what you see.
See it?
- See what?
- Yeah.
PIay it again,... but sIowIy.
The way to see it is to move sIightIy faster.
It's a ghost!
- Look at that! It's a ghost!
- A third person.
- It's been systematicaIIy erased.
- Erased?
Just Iike airbrushing someone out of a stiII,
onIy much harder.
It pisses me off, though.
They expect us to be sIoppy Americans.
They think we wiII not be thorough,
not be inteIIigent.
In Japan, I guess they'd have done it right.
Right. The ghost wouId have stayed hidden.
To do this, they wouId need
high-res video stiIIs,
cIose-ups ofthe tabIe, anything in the area.
They'd have to dupIicate
the ghost's waIk.
Like someone waIking through the room,
shooting photographs?
- The security guy.
- Tanaka.
He was waIking backwards
through the room taking pictures.
Wait. Here's something.
Look, there in the gIass.
Our ghost has Ieft a refIection.
I'm adjusting image resoIution
and sharpening.
If I appIy an edge detection operation,
I shouId be abIe to isoIate the refIection
and puII out its shape.
Let's... adjust resoIution and...
magnitude of each ofthe coIour channeIs.
Let's fiIter out aII the noise
we picked up aIong the way.
HoIy shit.
Eddie Sakamura.
Then he witnessed the murder.
How many hours
did they have to work on these?
- I got my caII at...
- The murder took pIace 8.30pm.
- Ishihara deIivered the disk to us... 1.33am.
- Five hours.
I doubt it couId be done.
If it couId be done,
where wouId it be done?
- It's quiet.
- HardIy anyone's in yet.
They were working Iate
Iast night on a rush project.
I'm sure Nakamoto
appreciates the hard work.
Yes. I heard it went reaI weII for them.
Mr DonaIdson is expecting you.
Yes. We did some work together
when this was the DonaIdson Corporation.
- Jim, how are you?
- Captain Connor.
- Web Smith.
- HeIIo.
- What can I do for you?
- WeII, we need your heIp, Jim.
Anything.
You worked on some disks Iast night
for Nakamoto.
Some disks? Oh, I doubt that.
You did. And I need their names.
Our cIients are confidentiaI.
I know, but er... we do need your heIp.
Captain, we wouIdn't have done
any work for Nakamoto here.
You know damn weII Nakamoto
and Hamaguri are competing keiretsu.
Yes, but I've been toId
by reIiabIe sources
that onIy you have the next generation
of technoIogy to do this kind ofwork.
Your reIiabIe sources are wrong.
Besides, we're way beyond
the next generation here.
And I reaIIy don't know anything.
- You stiII run this pIace, don't you?
- Run it? Sure.
I'm stiII the chief executive here... sort of.
ActuaIIy, my roIe is a IittIe different now.
You mean you don't run it?
Look, we soId it. They own it.
PeopIe who own things are entitIed
to do whatever they want with them.
That's the way it works.
But, hey, you know...
There's a bright side to everything.
I'm getting out
to a Iot more Dodger games IateIy.
Having some fun. You know what I'm saying.
Yes, I do, Jim.
Fine.
Best regards to Mrs DonaIdson.
How's... whatshername?
She's fine.
- Give her my best!
- I wiII.
- So... what do we know now?
- WeII, we know the disk was doctored here.
And we know that they know that we know.
We're beating the grass to startIe the snakes.
What? Look, where are you from, sempai?
- ScotIand Yard?
- No. ScotIand back yard.
So how did you become
the speciaI Iiaison officer for Los AngeIes?
And... who is whatshername?
What you shouId be asking is
why you and I were put together Iast night.
- I was on duty. Nakamoto requested you.
- No, they didn't.
Nakamoto is formaIIy protesting
the fact that I'm on the case.
You're saying someone eIse caIIed you in.
- Someone who...
- Has been manipuIating things.
We're pIaying that most American of games.
Which is what?
Catch up.
My goIfer friends aIso said
that Eddie's peopIe might retaIiate.
Eddie's peopIe might retaIiate? Against who?
Whoever they feeI
was responsibIe for his death.
What do mean when you say retaIiate?
- I shouIdn't say any more.
- But you've been taIking aII morning!
I just reaIised
they may have bugged your car.
They? Who's they?
Let's move!
- We're the cops! Why are we running?
- We're not running. We're eIuding.
EIuding.
We're safe around here.
You caII this safe?
Rough neighbourhoods
may be America's Iast advantage.
Perhaps I may suggest a strategy.
Don't stare at these guys.
Keep your hands down.
These guys don't Iike big arm movements.
They might shoot you.
Keep your voice caIm...
Better stiII, don't say shit.
If you hear me say
''Can I be of any assistance?''
it's too Iate.
You can kiss your IittIe ass goodbye.
Hey, yo! What's up?
Spider? Spider Web Smith
scored 40 against Crenshaw.
48.
- Yo, motherfucker. What year was that?
- '75.
- Was that before CoIumbus or after?
- Very funny.
- Armani?
- Yeah.
Giorgio!
You be doin' just fine, brother!
Look, I'm escorting this oId geezer
back to the Ioony farm.
He stoIe sushi from some Japanese cats.
Now they chasin' us.
So I need you guys to get behind us.
Think you can heIp us out?
We got your back.
Hey! You guys Iookin' for something?
- Do your window, sir?
- Yeah, OK.
You got your pink sIip?
Why pink sIip?
Because I was Ied to beIieve
this car wouId be for saIe...
soon.
- SenatorMorton's campaign offiice.
- Senator Morton, pIease.
- Who's calling?
- Captain Connor returning his caII.
And there he goes.
What's wrong with this picture?
- The cIock isn't moving.
- ExactIy.
After the guy Ieaves, time stands stiII.
What they probabIy did here
was rock and roII.
Print the same scene over and over
to keep the pixeIs - the grain - aIive.
They removed what came after this guy's exit
and that made the disks the standard Iength.
So no-one wouId suspect
anything was missing after that. But...
Something happened after that.
If we onIy had the originaI disk,
we couId see what happened after that.
ExactIy.
You catch on fast, Lieutenant Smith.
Web.
Yeah, I do.
I shouId go and make
a copy ofthe disk for you.
Miss Asakuma...
- Jingo.
How do you feeI about working with us?
I mean the poIice.
- EspeciaIIy since you're...
- You mean... because I'm Japanese.
Yeah.
Here I'm Japanese.
But in Japan, I was ainoku.
My father was a kokujin.
You know that word, kokujin?
- Negro?
- Negro.
Oh, yes. I know that word.
Yes, a BIack man.
He was with the American Air Force.
My mother worked in a noodIe shop.
Do you know the term...
''he's a bit burakumin''?
It's Iike...
UntouchabIe.
I was even Iower than burakumin...
because I was deformed.
To the Japanese, deformity is shamefuI.
It means you've done something wrong.
And then on top of aII that
I reaIIy did something wrong.
And what was that?
I feII in Iove with a gaijin.
A Caucasian who was Iiving there.
We were both ostracised.
Made his work over there difficuIt
and my Iife impossibIe.
He had to Ieave Japan.
He Ieft you?
- Maybe we Ieft each other.
- No.
He ran out.
He couIdn't take it.
Him?
No, he couId take anything.
My friend is a very strange man.
You know what he says?
AIways Ieave the cage door open...
so the bird can return.
Your friend sounds Iike an idiot.
Let's go, kohai. We're Iate.
And bring the disk.
Thank you.
Your paI took the disk.
- Anyway, we got the right guy.
- Maybe we got the wrong guy.
What are you taIking about?
The case is cIosed.
Just reIax. Go home, get some sIeep.
SIow down.
Fuck you, sIow down.
- They're squeezing me.
- Who?
- Yeah, who's squeezing you?
Come on, now. Wake up.
These aren't the oId days.
Just get me that disk
and the case is cIosed,
just how everybody wants it to be.
There's your disk.
Go make everybody happy.
You cIose the case.
What are you gonna do?
I'm opening it up.
What?
Oh, what am I?
Endangering my chances for advancement?
Baby, ifyou onIy knew.
Five Japanese nationaIs inspecting
the remains of Iast night's car wreck.
The guys from Nakamoto.
What are they Iooking for?
An interesting question.
Do you recognise the pick-up truck?
Yeah.
It was outside Eddie's Iast night,
by the CadiIIac.
It Iooked suspicious,
so we had it brought in.
There's the ownership ofthe Toyota.
Tanaka?
Yeah.
Head of Nakamoto security.
Now, what was Tanaka doing
at Eddie's Iast night?
Hey, Lieutenant Smith!
WiIIy WiIheIm, LA Times. How's it going?
- Pretty busy right now.
- I understand.
We're preparing a story on you
about the Martino case.
The accusation of accepting a bribe
brought against you by Mr Martino?
- Any comment?
- No comment.
Lieutenant Graham made some
interesting comments. Wanna hear them?
- No.
- The DA's office is about to reopen the case.
- No comment?
- No!
Captain Connor, what about the charge
of Japan-bashing in tonight's paper?
Hey!
Hey? Hay is for horses.
What is Japan-bashing? What does it mean?
AII animaIs are created equaI
except the Japanese?
You stupid IittIe shit! Fuck off!
Can I quote you on that, sir?
Japan-bashing? You?
- What'II they think of next?
- Next?
Next they'II caII you a racist.
Look. I've toId you.
I have no idea where Mr Tanaka is.
I haven't seen him.
- But did he come in today?
- I don't know.
And even if I did know,
the answer is ''I don't know.''
WeII, someone knows.
You guys'II never beat 'em.
They're too good.
I've toId you this in order
to avoid unnecessary embarrassment.
I am surprised to hear this, Connor-san.
Because, personaIIy,
I weIcome your invoIvement.
I know that you're aIways...
- Discreet.
- Ah, yes.
You ask me about MicroCon.
We were approached in Tokyo Iast year
by Richmond-san.
And I'II teII you,
MicroCon needed a shot in the arm.
So I thought that Nakamoto
wouId be just what the doctor ordered.
Excuse me.
Go on, sir.
FrankIy, we were surprised
it wouId be offered.
We were cautious
to enter into negotiations.
We received assurances that there wouId be
no objection to the saIe from Washington.
We have been criticised for trying
to heIp a company in financiaI difficuIty.
We feeI very
kitsu-tsuita.
- Wounded. Yes.
- Yes.
- That's buIIshit, but...
- Life goes on.
I remember when computers were fun.
Hey, guys!
See you back up there.
Let's get this deaI cIosed.
So, anyway...
- Not much team spirit.
- They'II get into it.
EspeciaIIy now since they know
Senator Morton is changing his vote.
He's been convinced his stand is racist.
- Racist?
- What eIse couId it be?
Remember when Fujitsu tried
to buy FairchiId Semiconductor?
The US government bIocked the saIe
saying it was against nationaI security
to seII it to a foreign company.
Then Iater FairchiId is soId
to a French company.
This time there's not a peep from
Congress, Senator Morton, or anyone.
ApparentIy, it was OK
to seII to a foreign company.
Just not a Japanese company.
I'd say that's racist poIicy,
pure and simpIe.
Captain Connor.
Nakamoto is an honourabIe company.
We have no part in any...
compIications that have occurred.
But ifthey don't want Japan to buy it,
don't seII it.
- I wiII assist you in whatever way I can.
- I'm very gratefuI.
Tomorrow at noon for goIf?
Tomorrow at noon.
I wiII try to make it harder
for you to Iet me win.
Senator. Are you comfortable
with this newposition?
Absolutely.
Because l don't viewitas a newposition.
l viewitas a modifiication...
That's exactIy what it is. A modification.
The response has been ten to one
in favour ofthe way I've...
modified my position.
Modified? It's a totaI reversaI.
Oh, no. Not at aII.
It's simpIy a...
refinement of my earIier views.
Foreign trade invigorates America.
I've aIways been a proponent offair trade...
But you were against the saIe
because it put our advanced weaponry
in the controI ofthe Japanese.
Now, that's... reaIIy vastIy simpIified.
Ah! More affirmations.
Oh, Senator ShanIey.
It must have kiIIed him to write this!
AII the poIIs have been positive.
Ah! But I didn't bring you here
to discuss poIitics and economics.
I know how that must bore men Iike you.
I just wanted your input, gentIemen.
I know you're investigating events
that took pIace at the Nakamoto party.
I wondered ifyou feIt there was any Iinkage
between those unfortunate events
and the proposed saIe of MicroCon.
We're not aware of any Iinkage.
Has Nakamoto done anything unfair
or improper in promoting this saIe?
Not that we're aware of, no.
Good.
Your investigation is concIuded, then?
Yes.
Good!
That's it, then, gentIemen. Thank you.
There's one for you.
Thank you.
And one for you. Thank you very much.
- John, here's some more faxes.
- Ah, more support! AIways weIcome.
Mind if I give you some advice?
No.
If a battIe can't be won,
don't fight it.
If a battIe can't be won, don't fight it?
Mm. The Art OfWar. Sun Su, China.
Fifth century BC.
- An educated guy, huh?
- Oh, yeah.
He read a fortune cookie once.
Keep this number between us.
Lieutenant Smith?
l have Lauren Smith foryou.
Ah, just what I needed.
Webster, l'm calling to inform you
l'm takingZelda.
- When? This weekend?
- Todayat5 o'clock.
What are you taIking about?
l'm talking about charges being brought
against you concerning bribery.
Come on, Lauren.
You know everything about that charge.
It was thrown out. Remember?
- Come offit! We both know whathappened.
- Stop it, Lauren.
- Plus the fact thatyou've become a racist.
- A what?
And you associate with known racists.
The courts will fiind thatyou're providing
an improperatmosphere for our daughter.
- They want you to back off.
- You're not taking ZeIIy.
Are you denying me myright? l'm with
my attorney. We're recording this call.
Record this. Fuck you! And fuck
your Iawyer too, ifyou aIready haven't!
You're not coming near ZeIIy...
That's enough.
What the fuck are you doing?
You wanna take me on? Step out ofthis car!
I've had enough ofyou!
You wanna take me on?
Get out! Come on!
I'm tired ofyour shit! I'm tired of her shit!
Come on! I'II pimp-sIap you
up and down this fuckin' street!
TeII me about the bribery charge, kohai.
- The what?
- The bribery charge.
Look. The woman who fiIed the charge
was a chronic psychiatric case.
The review board dismissed it.
You got that?
AII right. Now I gotta go get ZeIIy.
I can't heIp you ifyou won't teII me.
TeII you what?! It was dismissed.
You know cops are aIways being accused
of assauIt, moIestation, taking bribes.
AII kinds of shit!
Jesus Christ!
I'm a good cop!
It was a domestic vioIence caII.
The kid is in the crib screaming his head off.
I puII back the covers
and next to the kid is a kiIo ofwhite brick.
Graham says we can't make the arrest,
that the search is invaIid,
the wife can't testify against her husband,
and that any decent Iawyer wiII beat this.
The woman is screaming,
the kid is screaming.
I'm Iosing my mind here.
SuddenIy the husband waIks in
with an enveIope this thick
with $100 biIIs.
He says to me,
''Thank you, officer, for aII your heIp.''
''Thank you very much.''
Graham turns to me and gives me the nod.
And you took the money.
What was I supposed to do, man?
I mean, my wife...
My wife was pregnant.
HeaIth insurance didn't cover it.
We had biIIs up to here.
Yes! Yes! I took the money.
Me and Graham spIit it.
Now you're the onIy one that knows about it.
Graham knows and now,
who eIse?
Yeah. Graham knows.
Wanna know why I toId you?
- Why?
- I figure you're on the take, too.
- What are you taIking about?
- That fuckin' fat enveIope in your pocket.
The one the guy gave you
back at the goIf cIub.
This is a goIf membership.
Oh! So how much
is a membership worth these days?
A hundred thousand.
Boy, they sure make it easy
to take a 100,000 bucks, don't they?
GoIf is how they do business.
This is very important for what I do.
WeII, I guess that makes everything
aII white now, doesn't it?
Make sure she hasn't taken ZeIIy.
Damn! If it's not one thing, it's another.
ZeIIy!
ZeIIy! Hey, babe, you here?
Somebody's here.
I was wondering where he wouId show up.
Oh, my God!
Put that phone down!
- I'm just caIIing my guys.
- Put the phone down.
- So who was kiIIed in the car crash?
- Tanaka.
- The security guy.
- Yes,
Tanaka.
He worked for Nakamoto,
but he had a speciaI reIationship with me.
My father's keiretsu couId offer
a better future to him, understand?
Tanaka... He Iiked women.
And drugs too. And for that,
give me good information.
- He tried to set you up as the murderer.
- WeII, he was pIaying both sides.
Look, I'm stiII aIive. He's stiII dead.
He doubIe-crossed me,
but I doubIe-crossed him better.
He's afraid to get caught with me
so he uses my car... and kiII himseIf.
I didn't Iike the coIour anyway.
You reported the murder.
Then you caIIed me in?
My father aIways said,
if you need heIp, caII Connor-san.
Those Japanese guys,
what were they Iooking for in the car?
What Tanaka brought Eddie...
and what Eddie was going to give to us.
That's right, Connor-san.
- The originaI disk.
- Connor-san,
you smart cookie for a gaijin.
But you're gonna be surprised
when you see this.
First, give me back my passport.
I think I'm gonna need it.
CarefuI, kohai.
- Who is it?
- Me, Web. Let me in.
It's Graham.
Hide a sword with a smiIe.
Hey, Tom! How you doing?
What are you doing here? What's wrong?
- Wrong?
- Yeah.
What the fuck's wrong with you?
What are you taIking about?
The squeeze is on, baby.
Your ex is taIking.
The chief is shitting
and the WeaseI's snooping.
- Opening up new things.
- New things?
What new things?
Look, are you on the take?
- Fuck you, the take.
- Are you on the fuckin' take?!
Who the fuck are you to ask me about that?
You started me off. You remember that?
Now, pIay baII.
You get to keep your kid, yourjob,
and your buddies. We're a team, Web.
A team? What team are we on, huh?
We know who you've got in there.
You're harbouring a murderer in there.
How did you know Eddie was stiII aIive?
He's not! He's dead.
He just forgot to Iay down.
- He didn't do it.
- Who did it?
We don't know who did it!
Send him out, Spider-san, with the disk too.
I'II protect the guy.
And what if I don't?
If you don't?!
If you don't, you're obstructing justice.
You're harbouring, baby.
If you don't, we're coming in after a murderer.
What are you doing to your Iife?
You know me, Web. I get my man.
Yeah. Even if he's the wrong man.
Who the fuck are you? The Supreme Court?
You're putting a Iot of guys
in the Iine offire to protect one dead Nip.
You risk your Iife and your chiId for me.
We're Iike sitting ducks up here.
Time to be among them.
Don't Iet anyone in.
Put this on.
And don't try to go out.
Daddy!
ZeIIy.
Baby, not right now, OK?
You and Grandma want to stay in the room.
Go!
Don't do anything.
We'II take care of everything.
They want us to wait.
This Eddie guy's aIive.
They want a shot at him.
I gotta figure this.
The first ruIe is to protect your ass.
Maybe we ought to get some backup.
What do you say?
HeIIo.
Kohai, it's me.
Come on, Iet's go.
I've cIeared the back staircase. Go!
Come, come, come.
I'II stay with Eddie.
Daddy!
ZeIIy.
Eddie!
Hey!
Web!
Web.
Kohai.
And that's aII I remember.
LuckiIy, you were wearing the proper gear.
Yeah. LuckiIy.
You've read this morning's paper.
You were caught
in the middIe of gang warfare.
Man, I was caught
in the middIe of a business negotiation.
No, Lieutenant.
You can read.
You were the target
of a drive-by shooting by a street gang.
It was a grudge attack.
None ofthe suspects has been apprehended.
One gang member was found murdered
by rituaI stranguIation.
So Eddie's dead now.
OfficiaIIy.
OfficiaIIy, the case is cIosed.
Under the circumstances,
we're recommending that you take
a voIuntary Ieave of absence.
And, Lieutenant,
wouId you be abIe to teII us
the whereabouts of Captain Connor?
No.
I have no idea where he is.
They shut us down.
Put a padIock on the front door,
just Iike that.
Know how it works?
A phone caII to the university president
from major endowers.
The fuckers can't stop us that easiIy.
- They're stiII ahead of us, kohai.
- Got here as fast as I couId.
They're Iooking for you.
We've been piecing it together.
EarIier in the evening,
Eddie and CheryI made Iove.
But at the party she met another man,
her secret Iover.
Her back-door man.
Someone at Nakamoto
must have suggested
that they use the executive bedroom
on the 46th fIoor.
But they never got
beyond the boardroom tabIe.
Here comes your ghost.
Eddie. Before they erased him.
- He's Ietting her get kiIIed.
- He's seen this before.
The gasper routine.
Funny oId worId, eh?
I thought Eddie was the jeaIous Iover.
A stronger passion overtook him.
His IoyaIty to his father's keiretsu.
They aIso wanted to purchase MicroCon.
Don't forget there's a keiretsuwar going on.
Who is it?
Senator Morton.
Eddie probabIy offered her
to the Senator as form of hospitaIity.
So, Senator Morton kiIIed her?
Wait tiII you see the rest ofthe disk.
We know they used this situation
to bIackmaiI Senator Morton.
They pinned the murder on Eddie
by doctoring the disk.
- Why was Eddie protecting him?
- The Senator was voting in his favour.
This is about who wouId controI MicroCon.
Whoever controIIed the Senator
wouId controI the fate of MicroCon.
This is the part ofthe disk
we never saw before.
There. You see that?
Yeah, the cIock. It's moving.
No. The girI.
She's moving.
HoIy shit.
She's aIive.
She was aIive, untiI...
Now, who the heII is this?
Someone who's been observing
and knows the exact Iocation
of the hidden cameras.
PIease go on.
What? That's it?
That's aII we got?!
- We can't Iet 'em get away with this shit.
- Get away with this?
They won't get away with this.
I am very, very okotta!
- Pissed off.
- Yes! Pissed off.
Good. So what do we do now?
Yes. What do we do now?
- You're asking me?
- Yes.
We beat the grass to startIe the snakes.
ExactIy.
Oh, my God.
We hadan agreement.
You saidnothing wouldhappen.
- We hada deal!
- Yes, sir.
Did you see what I just got by fax?!
I understand. Thank you.
Very kind ofyou to caII.
..the fucking technology wouldprotectme!
Oh, my God. Look at this.
We will decide
whether the MicroCon sale goes through.
l will be basing my vote
on my country's needs.
You have aspirations
perhaps for the highest offiice in the land.
Excuse me just a second.
Hey... Can I heIp you with something?
- Hey! What's going on? You can't barge in...
- You, shut up.
Yoshida-san.
Forgive this interruption.
But there is something I must show you.
This is the originaI disk from your security
cameras that fiImed this conference room.
And recorded the murder... and the murderer.
We are gratefuI to you, Yoshida-san,
for insisting that Ishihara deIiver this to us.
But instead... he repIaced it
with this doctored version.
PIease. Show us the originaI disk.
I wiII deaI with this.
Get out!
They are distancing themseIves.
- HoIy shit.
- Senator Morton.
At this moment,
she's not dead.
And now we shaII find out
who actuaIIy kiIIed her.
Why was I not toId this?!
What has been happening here?
I was protecting the situation, Yoshida-san.
He has been too Iong in America.
He has adopted many bad habits.
No!
It was not me.
It was him!
Hey, there's no running... Hey! SIow down!
Hey, there's no running here!
Keep eye contact at aII times.
And at aII costs, don't Iose your temper.
I don't Iose my temper.
How are you doing, guys?
How are you doing?
We're cops, man.
Step aside, we'II have no troubIe.
This is poIice business.
It seems Iike nobody's Iistening.
Come on, come on!
It's me.
I couId have taken 'em.
Their objective was not to win,
but to deIay us.
And they've succeeded.
Eddie's friends.
Looks Iike they've got their revenge.
Shit.
We gotta stop this!
We gotta do something!
Do what?
He's finished.
That cement dries fast.
And there's no way
they're gonna rip open that foundation.
Everyone wants this case cIosed.
Besides,
they put us on Ieave of absence.
So, what wiII MicroCon do now?
- StruggIe on.
- We'II find a way.
Or a way wiII find you.
I hope we can continue our friendship.
- Uh, sure. Let's... Let's do Iunch sometime.
- Let's do Iunch.
What's going to happen to him?
They are retiring him.
Ishihara wiII be given a window seat.
He wiII spend the rest of his Iife in Japan,
staring out an office window.
Too bad. He seemed Iike a heck of a guy.
PersonaIIy, I got aIong great with him.
If you sit by the river Iong enough,
you wiII see the body
of your enemy fIoating by.
Connor-san.
I wanna thank you.
I feeI I shouId repay you with something.
Repay me? For what?
- WeII...
- The key.
Ah, yes. The key.
The key is... don't taIk about it. Just do it.
The kohaitaIks.
The sempai knows.
- If I wanna be a sempai...
- No.
The key.
- What?
- The key to your car.
Oh! Yeah.
I knew that.
Today at goIf, we'II be discussing
how I can heIp Nakamoto
puII out ofthe MicroCon deaI
without Iosing face.
- Keiretsu interruptus.
- ExactIy.
Very nice working with you, kohai.
See you.
Yoshida-san.
A perfect day for goIf.
WeII, thanks to your heIp,
we were abIe to find out who did it.
- Did you?
- Did we what?
Find out?
Find out? You mean who did it?
Come on!
You know in Japan,
the one who confesses to the murder
doesn't have to be the one that did it.
It's an oId tradition that, out of IoyaIty,
an innocent man
wiII take the rap for his boss.
It's his duty.
That's not what happened here.
That Richmond guy wouId have done
anything to make that deaI go through.
He was working with Ishihara.
A yuppie faciIitator,
a hustIing business samurai.
Wave ofthe future.
If you say so.
If I say so?
Look, I'm a cop.
It's my business to know these things.
Besides,... what about Connor?
- What about him?
- The guy's aIways right.
If you say so.
Did I say something to anger you?
- No, nothing you said.
- Then, what is it?
- GoIf.
- GoIf?
I don't get it.
There it is up there.
You Iive here.
428 Rose Street.
WeII, weII, weII.
When I came to pick him up
that first time,
behind the sIiding paneI,
that was you?
The gaijin that you Iived with in Japan,
that was Connor.
Thanks for giving me a Iift.
Wait a minute.
There's some things here I don't understand.
Yes.
Goodbye, kohai.
No, no!
Now, Iook.
I mean, the guy, he's pIaying goIf now.
You and me, we're aIone.
And...
I know.
They say IoyaIty is important.
It aII comes down to who you trust.
Wait a minute.
When he said that Iine about
''AIways Ieave the cage door open
so the bird can return'',
what the heII does that mean anyway?
Who knows?
When you figure it out, Web,
Iet me know.
Damn!
Kohai!
Visiontext subtitIes: JuIie CIayton
ENGLISH