(man) # She's run out of money #
# She's run out of love #
# One more chance, she said #
# lf you love me, baby, pay the rent #
# Don't throw stones
You don't know #
# lt's not what you say
lt's what you do #
# Don't throw stones #
Go ahead.
# Twice as bad a break #
# If you Iove me, buy me a big TV #
# You good-for-nothing, Iazy chiId #
# Don't throw stones
You don't know #
# It's not what you say
It's what you do #
# Don't throw stones #
# Don't throw stones
You don't know #
How about some goId pIastic?
(glass smashes)
"(woman)" You asshoIe!
What do you take me for?
Hey, get the fuck away from him.
Let go, dammit! Let fucking go!
It's time for you gentIemen to Ieave.
It's aII right.
We were just having a IittIe fun.
It's OK. I'm sorry.
(shocked gasps)
OK, DaIton, I've aIways wanted to try you.
I think I can take you.
Outside.
OK. So here we are, Iet's go.
- Come on, hotshot.
- Come on! Come on, Iet's do it.
- DirtbaII, where you going?
- Moose-Iips, get back here!
- Dickhead!
- What are you, the Seven Dwarfs?
# Don't throw stones
You don't know #
# It's not what you say
It's what you do #
# Don't throw your stones #
# Don't throw stones
You don't know #
Can I taIk to you for a minute?
Name's DaIton, right?
I don't know you.
My name is TiIghman.
Frank TiIghman.
I have a IittIe cIub outside Kansas City
caIIed the DoubIe Deuce.
It used to be a sweet deaI.
Now it's the kind of pIace that
they sweep up the eyebaIIs after cIosing.
Anyway, I've come into
a IittIe bit of money.
I'd Iike to make a better Iife for myseIf.
I need somebody
to heIp me cIean the pIace up.
I need the best.
- Wade Garrett's the best.
- Wade Garrett's getting oId.
- He's stiII the best.
- I want you.
$5,000 up front. $500 a night, cash.
You pay aII medicaI expenses.
I can Iive with that.
I run the show... compIeteIy.
- When the job's done, I waIk.
- I've got your pIane ticket right here.
I don't fIy.
Too dangerous.
- WeII, when do I expect you...
- Don't. I'II get there.
- DaIton, you aII right?
- It's just a scratch.
By the way, Oscar, Bandstand's aII yours.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I'm outta here.
Great.
You know, I thought you'd be...
..bigger.
Yo.
- What do I Iook Iike, a vaIet?
- Keep it. It's yours.
Hm?
(# ''On the Road Again''
by The Jeff Healey Band #)
# Well, l'm so tired of cryin'
But l'm out on the road again #
# l'm on the road again #
# l said l'm so tired of cryin'
But l'm out on the road again #
# l'm on the road again... #
Oh, a Mercedes!
(whooping)
Hey, hotshot,...
..what's wrong with Detroit cars?
Don't come back, peckerhead.
(rowdy shouting)
"(man)" Bring on the reaI band!
# Take a tip from me, baby, pIease #
# Don't you cry no more #
# But I ain't goin' down
that Iong, oId Ionesome road #
# AII by myseIf #
Son of a bitch! #
Yo, Steve.
Fuck 'em. They're brothers.
You're ripping my best fuckin' shirt.
You know, I get off at two,...
..and I'd just Iove to get you off
about a haIf an hour after that.
By God, you're a put-together woman.
Ladies first, asshoIe.
Hey! Hey, baby, come
and have fun with us a IittIe whiIe.
Damn it. MongreI!
Oh, Jesus, not here.
FoIIow me to the bathroom.
I need a drink.
1 , 2, 3, 4.
- Vodka rocks.
- You got it, baby.
Hey, vodka rocks.
What do you say
you and me get nippIe to nippIe?
I can do that without you.
(screams)
Get him out of here - now.
Come on, man. Get your hands off me.
You're not drinking. You're outta here.
Hey! Don't Iet him bother you.
Morgan was born an asshoIe
and just grew bigger.
I'm Carrie Ann.
If you need anything - anything -
you just Iet me know.
You got a name?
Yeah.
WeII? What is it?
DaIton.
Oh, my God.
Shit. I heard of you.
"(bangs bar)" Carrie Ann!
What are you waiting for? Christmas?
- Move!
- Oh, shut up. I'm goin'.
Jesus Christ.
- Get him out of here.
- Let's go, SIeeping Beauty.
Come on, move it.
Come on. What do you
think this is, a rest home?
AII right, y'aII, we'II be back in ten. We
gotta drain the main vein. Stick around.
Hey, you're paid to pIay. PIay.
Fuck!
(# ''Runaround Sue'' plays on jukebox #)
- Thanks, man.
- You pIay good for a bIind, white boy.
Yeah, and I thought you'd be bigger.
- DaIton, how ya doin'? It's good to see ya.
- Same here, man.
The boys and I heard
you were coming into town.
Man, this toiIet is worse than
the one we worked in Dayton.
ReaIIy?
Oh, man! It's a mean scene
around here, man.
There's bIood on the fIoor every night.
- Hank, you know who that is?
- Who?
DaIton.
# Gonna teII Aunt Mary about UncIe John #
# He says he's got the bIues,
but he has a Iotta fun #
# Oh, baby #
# Ye-e-eah, baby #
# Woo-oo-ooh, baby... #
That guy at the end of the bar
is fucking DaIton, man.
He kiIIed a guy once.
Ripped his throat right out.
BuIIshit.
- What ya need, buddy?
- Coffee, bIack.
Ever seen a better pair of attitudes?
Fine, ain't they?
I'II teII you what, for 20 bucks,...
- ..you can kiss 'em.
- Are you kidding?
Ten a kiss. Here and now.
Go ahead. Do it, go on.
- Go on.
- Come on. Come on.
Ten a kiss. Go ahead.
Yeah!
Hey, buddy, what are you doin'?
Are you gonna kiss 'em or not?
- I can't.
- What do you mean, you can't?
I ain't got 20 bucks.
What? You...!
- Oh, shit.
- Fight!
Break it up!
(glass shattering)
You son of a bitch!
Bastard!
# Baby #
# Havin' us some fun tonight #
Fuck. Anybody got a mirror?
Aw, shit.
Hey, how'd you Iike to teII us
what the fuck's goin' on?
- You gonna heIp us out or not?
- I'II Iet you know.
I heard you had baIIs big enough
to come in a dump truck, but...
..you don't Iook Iike much to me.
Opinions vary.
Cody. Later.
- AII right, man. You take care.
- See you guys.
This DaIton, what's his story?
The story is you fuck with him
and he'II seaI your fate.
Yeah? So far he hasn't shown me shit.
She's a runner.
(woman on tannoy)
You have a customer on line two.
- These work?
- Sure do.
Jimmy, you have a customer
waiting for you on the lot.
Jimmy, you have a customer on the lot.
I'II take it.
Morning.
You the one who's got a room to rent?
Hm. Come on.
- You honest?
- Yes, sir.
You expect me to beIieve that?
No, sir.
(helicopter engine)
Goddammit!
I swear he does that just to piss me off.
- Who does?
- Brad WesIey.
- HeIIo, bay.
- Like horses, do you?
- If they Iike me.
- You wouIdn't steaI 'em, wouId you?
No, sir.
CaIIing me sir is Iike putting an eIevator
in an outhouse - don't beIong.
- I'm Emmet.
- I'm DaIton.
So what do you think?
WeII, I'II take it.
Must've been 20 peopIe
Iook at that room this past year.
No phone, no teIevision,
no conditioned air,...
..no toIerance for the fragrance of nature.
Nobody wanted it. How come you do?
You're just too persuasive for me, I guess.
It ain't the money,
but if I don't charge you,...
..the Presbyterians are IikeIy
to pray for my ruination.
How does $100 a month strike you?
- Fine.
- You can afford that much?
If it keeps you in
the Church's good graces.
Ain't it pecuIiar how money
seems to do that very thing?
Now, this. This is the new DoubIe Deuce.
I've put a Iot of money and time into this.
And to protect my investment, I've hired
the best damn cooIer in the business.
From now on he's in charge of aII
the bar business. What he says goes.
DaIton?
- Morgan, you're out of here.
- What the fuck you taIking about?
You don't have the right temperament.
- You asshoIe! What am I supposed to do?
- There's aIways barber coIIege.
(derisive laughter)
You're a dead man.
You're out, too.
We're seIIing booze here, not drugs.
Thank you.
Anybody eIse here deaIing?
I'm teIIing you straight.
It's my way or the highway.
So anybody wants to waIk, do it now.
AII right.
PeopIe who reaIIy wanna have a good
time won't come to a sIaughterhouse.
And we've got entireIy
too many troubIemakers here.
Too many 40-year-oId adoIescents,
feIons, power drinkers...
..and trustees of modern chemistry.
It's going to change.
Man, that sure sounds good.
But a Iot of the guys who come in here,
we can't handIe one-on-one.
- Even two-on-one.
- Don't worry about it.
AII you have to do
is foIIow three simpIe ruIes.
One: never underestimate your opponent.
Expect the unexpected.
Two: take it outside.
Never start anything inside the bar
unIess it's absoIuteIy necessary.
And three: be nice.
Come on.
If somebody gets in your face and caIIs
you a cocksucker, I want you to be nice.
OK.
Ask him to waIk, be nice.
If he won't waIk, waIk him. But be nice.
If you can't waIk him,
one of the others wiII heIp you.
And you'II both be nice.
I want you to remember that it's a job.
- It's nothing personaI.
- Uh-huh.
Being caIIed a cocksucker isn't personaI?
No. It's two nouns combined
to eIicit a prescribed response.
What if somebody
caIIs my mama a whore?
Is she?
(laughter)
I want you to be nice...
..untiI it's time to not be nice.
WeII, how're we supposed
to know when that is?
You won't. I'II Iet you know.
You are the bouncers. I am the cooIer.
AII you have to do is
watch my back and each others'.
Take out the trash.
One, two, three
# 737 comin' outta the sky #
# Won't you take me down to Memphis
on a midnight ride? #
# I wanna move #
# PIay in a traveIIin' band #
# WeII, I'm fIyin' across the Iand
Tryin' to get a hand #
# PIayin' in a traveIIin' band #
- This is a Sears credit card.
- BeverIy, Agnes.
- Hi, Steve.
- It's OK. They're friends of mine.
- But DaIton said...
- Trust me. This way, girIs.
- Leaded or unIeaded?
- Leaded.
- "(glass smashes)"
- "(woman)" Hey!
(cheering)
Hank. Hank!
- Come on, darIin'!
- Hey, paI, get her down. What d'you say?
I say Iet her dance.
Whoo!
Wa-hoo! Come on, baby!
Hey, Iook, paI, we don't...
- Come on, motherfucker.
- Stay back!
Come on, motherfucker.
Escort this gentIeman to the door.
- Did you see that shit?
- Yeah.
"(woman)" Who is that guy?
He is good. He is reaI good.
The name is DaIton.
(applause and cheering)
Oh, yeah! You're gonna be my
reguIar Saturday-night thing, baby.
Oh, yeah. I've been thinkin' about you.
Steve!
Yo, Steve.
You're history.
But I'm on my break.
Stay on it.
Shit!
You got quite
a IittIe enterprise going here.
What?
You go through a bottIe every 30 minutes,
you skim the tiII for six shots a bottIe.
On drafts, one every ten.
I figure he's costing you
about $150 a night.
So?
So consider it severance pay.
Take the train.
I didn't hear you say that.
WeII, I'm sayin' it now.
You sure?
Get out.
WeII, it was a good night. Nobody died.
It'II get worse before it gets better.
(# ''Blue Monday'' by Bob Seger #)
I Iove this guy. Isn't he cute?
DarIing.
DaIton!
Hey, DaIton.
Morning. I... brought you some breakfast.
Oh, shit.
So, how'd you find me?
Oh, I... It wasn't too hard.
I mean... You know what I... mean.
What did you do there Iast night?
- What do you mean?
- WeII, you fired the bartender, Pat.
- He was skimming.
- You shouId not have done that, DaIton.
- Yeah? Why's that?
- You just shouIdn't have, that's aII.
Here you go.
Breakfast.
Oh, thank you.
"(giggles)" Oh, my God!
- What is the joke?
- WeII, there's no joke.
I just think I'm Iookin'
at a dead man, though.
It seems everywhere I go
I hear that same joke.
Yeah? WeII, something teIIs me
you bring it on yourseIf.
(# ''Sh-Boom'' by The Crew Cuts on radio #)
"(sings along) #" Oh, Iife couId be a dream #
# If I couId take you up
in paradise up above #
# If you wouId teII me
I'm the onIy one that you Iove #
# Life couId be a dream, sweetheart #
# Every time I Iook at you #
# Something is on my mind #
# If you do what I want you to #
# Baby, we'd be so fine #
# Sh-boom, sh-boom #
# Ya-da-da, da-da-da, sh-boom! #
A new windshieId wiII cost you
more than that oId beater's worth.
My advice wouId be scrap her.
WeII, I Iike her,
so order me one, wouId you?
It'II take a few days.
AeriaI I can get you now.
Great.
- You the boy from the DoubIe Deuce?
- Yes, sir.
Yeah... WeII, I kinda figured you'd be by.
You wanna put in a standing order now?
No, I'II pay as I go.
- DaIton.
- Red Webster.
- How Iong you gonna be in town?
- Not very Iong.
That's what I said 25 years ago.
- ReaIIy? What happened?
- I got married, to an ugIy woman.
Don't ever do that.
It just takes the energy right out of you.
She Ieft me, though.
Found somebody
even ugIier than she was.
That's Iife. Who can expIain it?
Oh, that's $5.
- So, why'd you stay on?
- Oh, I feII for the pIace.
(bell rings)
- HeIIo, Brad.
- Red.
- Brad WesIey.
- DaIton.
He's working at the DoubIe Deuce.
Oh, terrific. Hope you're gonna cIean
that pIace up. Bad eIement over there.
WeII, anything I can do for you...
Thanks, Red.
WeII, Red.
BeautifuI day, isn't it?
Was.
# PeopIe preach to me about Iove... #
- ProbIem?
- There's no probIem.
Just a IittIe mistake, that's aII.
What's that?
My job.
- You don't get it, do you?
- Why don't you expIain it to me?
- I'II expIain it to you!
- Hey, shut up, shithead.
Mr TiIghman has changed his mind.
And that's aII you need to know, son.
No, I'm gonna have to know
a IittIe bit more than that.
Mr TiIghman may own this bar,...
..but the Iiquor he serves
is suppIied to him by Brad WesIey.
Now, Pat McGurn is in the empIoy of
Mr WesIey - his uncIe - not Mr TiIghman.
You see, I'm stayin' and you're goin'!
- Oh, reaIIy?
- That's right.
- Sit down!
- Come on, DaIton. You and me right now.
Right now!
What's the matter, you chicken dick?
What are you afraid of? Me?
Is that it, DaIton? You scared to fight me?
Big, bad DaIton.
What, you wanna kiss and make up?
Argh!
Jesus Christ!
(screaming)
- Stand him up, stand him up.
- Get up, you fuck! Get up!
Get up! Hey, get up!
Get up! Motherfucker!
You're outta here, paI.
Hi. I'm Dr CIay.
Hi.
- How'd this happen?
- NaturaI causes.
- Looks Iike a knife wound.
- Like I said.
- You're a bouncer.
- Mm-hm. DoubIe Deuce.
Nice pIace. They send
a Iot of business my way.
- I'm hoping to change that.
- AII by yourseIf?
WeII, Mr DaIton, you may add nine stapIes
to your dossier of 31 broken bones,...
..two buIIet wounds, nine puncture
wounds and four steeI screws.
That's an estimate, of course.
- I'II give you a IocaI.
- No, thank you.
- Do you enjoy pain?
- Pain don't hurt.
Most of my patients
wouId disagree with you.
OK.
D'you aIways carry
your medicaI records with you?
Saves time.
Your fiIe says you've got
a degree from NYU. What in?
PhiIosophy.
- Any particuIar discipIine?
- No, not reaIIy.
Um, man's search for faith.
That sort of shit.
- Come up with any answers?
- "(chuckles)" Not too many.
How's a guy Iike you end up a bouncer?
Just Iucky, I guess.
Nice work. Good, cIean stitches.
Thank you.
Do you ever win a fight?
Nobody ever wins a fight.
- There you go.
- Thanks.
Listen, uh...
If you'd Iike to stop by the DoubIe Deuce
sometime, I can buy you a coffee if you...
Happen to be in the neighbourhood, huh?
Mm-hm.
You know, for that Iine of work,
I thought you'd be bigger.
Gee, I've never heard that before.
Did I expIain it wrong?
- Is that it?
- No, boss, you didn't.
Pat's got a weak constitution.
You boys know that.
That's why he's working as a bartender.
He's my onIy sister's son,
and if he doesn't have me, who's he got?
And if I'm not there, you're there.
I shouId have Iet you go, Jimmy.
WeII, one of you boys
owes me an apoIogy.
Now I Ieave it up to you to decide which
one of you wants to say ''I'm sorry.''
- I'm sorry, boss.
I beIieve you, Tinker.
But you, O'Connor,
somehow I don't beIieve you.
Now try it again. If there's one thing
I can't stand, it's a man who's untruthfuI.
- I'm sorry, boss.
- I hate a man who can't admit he's wrong.
- I swear to God, boss, I'm sorry.
- You disgust me. Wanna know why?
No, why, boss?
Cos you're a bIeeder.
You bIeed too much.
- You are a messy bIeeder.
- Argh!
You're weak.
You got no endurance for pain.
Now, come on. Get up.
Hey, you'II be fine. Come on.
WeII, heIp him up!
You're gonna be fine.
And you know why? Because I Iike you.
Get this piece-of-shit coward out of here.
- Work ain't work when you're havin' fun.
- Life is good.
Jesus.
Red?
- Red!
- Yeah?
What happened? Did you get robbed?
Every week.
So what does he take?
- Who?
- Brad WesIey.
Ten per cent - to start.
Oh, it's aII IegaI Iike. He formed
the Jasper Improvement Society.
AII the businesses in town beIong to it.
Everybody pay?
Does a hobbyhorse have a wooden dick?
(wolf-whistling)
(# ''Mustang Sally'' #)
"(man screams)" Charge!
- Come back here.
- Take it easy, Rambo.
I know you wanna save the worId from
commies, but do it from down here, man.
- Squirt him.
- Hose him down.
CooI him off.
- Garrett!
- Yo!
Some guy name of DaIton.
- What's going on, "mijo?"
- Hey, hey. How you doin', buddy?
Shit! HeII, kid, I'm in hog heaven.
If I was doin' any better
I couIdn't Iive with myseIf. And you?
- I'm aII right.
- "You oughta be, all that money you make."
- What's going on down in Jasper?
- Oh, you know. New town, same story.
Um, Iisten.
You ever heard of a guy
named Brad WesIey?
No, can't say that I have.
You having troubIe?
Oh, you know. Nothing I'm not used to.
But it's amazing
what you can get used to, huh?
Yeah, teII me about it.
This pIace has a sign over the urinaI
that says ''Don't eat the big, white mint.''
- Stay cooI, kid.
- Right.
Gotta go. I'II see ya.
Later.
(# ''Knock on Wood'' #)
# Ooh! I don't wanna Iose the good thing #
# That I got #
# Cos if I did, I wouId sureIy #
# SureIy Iose a Iot #
# For your Iove is better... #
Why won't you Iook me in the eye?
I'm shy.
WouId you be shocked if I said
''Let's go to my pIace and fuck''?
Ain't gonna kiII you.
You know, you might even Iike it.
Say good night, Denise.
Bastard! Let go!
# ..thunder #
# Lightning #
# The way you Iove me is frightening #
# I think I better knock on wood... #
- I didn't know she couId sing.
- "(door opens, footsteps)"
Right boot.
Got it.
- Sorry, we're cIosed.
- Then what are these peopIe doin' here?
Drinking and having a good time.
That's why we're here.
You're too stupid to have a good time.
(groans in pain)
Go on, DaIton. Kick his ass!
"(Carrie)" AII right! Yeah!
Son of a bitch!
Give me the biggest guy in the worId, you
smash his knee, he'II drop Iike a stone.
- "(man)" Damn good fight.
- "(engine revs, tyres screech)"
- Hi.
- So, you Iooking for somebody?
- You.
Are you aIways better than they are?
- Pretty much.
- Never been put down?
No. Not reaIIy.
How do you expIain that?
Those Iooking for troubIe are not much
of a probIem to someone ready for them.
- I suspect it's aIways been that way.
- "(creaking)"
Somebody has to do it.
Somebody's gotta pay somebody to do it.
Might as weII be you.
I'd better take you home.
If I keep taIking, you're gonna
go off thinking I'm a nice guy.
I know you're not a nice guy.
Pretty soon I'm gonna have
to start charging that bum rent.
Tonight's rent.
(man burps)
- Your fan cIub?
- They are devoted.
You Iive some kind of Iife, DaIton.
Too ugIy for you.
I didn't say that.
- See ya.
- Bye.
We've been Iooking aII over for you.
Mr WesIey wants to see you.
Let's go.
After you.
(# pop music #)
Hey, DaIton. Have a BIoody Mary?
- Some breakfast?
- No, thank you.
Suit yourseIf.
WiII you shut that shit off?!
- "(music stops)"
- I can't Iisten to that crap. It has no heart.
- My grandfather.
- Looks Iike an important man.
He was an asshoIe.
But you, you're a smart boy,
aren't you, DaIton?
You're just not too reaIistic.
Christ, I'm just Iike you. I came up
the hard way, from the streets of Chicago.
When I came to this town
after Korea there was nothing.
I brought the maII here. I got the 7-EIeven.
I got the Photomat here.
Christ, JC Penney is coming here because
of me. You ask anybody, they'II teII you.
You've gotten rich
off the peopIe in this town.
You bet your ass I have.
And I'm gonna get richer.
I beIieve we aII have
a purpose on this earth.
A destiny. I have a faith in that destiny.
It teIIs me to gather unto me what is mine.
But, Christ, you get paid for beating
peopIe up. TeII me you don't Iove it.
Of course you do.
You wouIdn't be human if you didn't.
DaIton.
I have a cousin in Memphis.
TeIIs me you kiIIed a man down there.
TeIIs me you said it was
seIf-defence at the triaI.
But you and I know that isn't so, don't we?
ReIax. ReIax.
TeII me,...
..if I owned a bar
and wanted to cIean it up,...
..how much wouId it take
to get you to come work for me?
There's no amount of money.
(Cody) # Keep your eyes on the road
and your hands upon the wheel #
AII right, we're here!
# Back at the roadhouse
They got some bungaIows #
# Said back at the roadhouse
They got some bungaIows... #
# And that's for the peopIe
who Iike to get down sIow #
# Let it roII, baby, roII #
- # Let it roII, baby, roII
- Thanks. #
# Let it roII #
# AII night Iong #
Good to see you.
Ernie, what's the story?
Whisky's running Iow.
I finaIIy get this pIace just the way I want
it, and now we're running out of booze.
I've caIIed every suppIier I know.
Why won't they deIiver?
WesIey. Ernie, give me the phone.
I'II take care of it.
Hi.
- I hear you're the new marshaI in town.
- You heard wrong.
Uh-oh.
Dig a hoIe.
This is your pIace?
Up there.
It's quiet and the horses Iet me know
if anybody comes around.
I Iove it.
(# rock music #)
(Otis Ridding) # These arms of #
# Mine #
# They are lonely #
# Lonely and feeling blue... #
I saw your picture in Red Webster's pIace.
He's my uncIe.
Nice oId guy.
Yeah. He raised me after my parents died.
That's why I came back here.
Now we take care of each other.
So how come you never got married?
I did.
- What happened?
- It didn't work.
Why?
Guess I picked the wrong guy.
# These arms of mine #
# They are burning #
# Yearning from wanting you #
# And if you #
# Would let them hold you #
# Oh, l'll breathe, oh, l will be #
# These arms of mine #
# They are burning #
# Burning from wanting you #
# These arms of mine #
# They are wanting #
# Wanting to hold you #
# And if you #
# Would let them hold you #
# Oh, l'll breathe, oh, l will be #
# Come on, come on, baby #
# Just be my little woman #
# Just be my lover #
# Oh, l need me somebody #
# Somebody to treat me right #
# l need your arms #
# Lovin' arms to hold me tight #
# And l, l, l need #
# l need your #
# l need your tender lips #
Mmm.
LittIe Rock.
You're gonna have a Iot of pain
when you get oIder.
You couId be crippIed
if you don't sIow down.
Yeah, that's what they say.
- You aIready know that?
- No. I just said ''That's what they say.''
Where are you gonna go from here?
I don't know.
You couId stay, DaIton. If you wanted to.
I don't think so.
Hang on.
- You got a woman up there with you?
- That's right.
Don't give me no Iip, Lord.
- Where did she get to?
- She'II be back.
If you're smart, you'd pitch your tent.
"(laughs)" Sometimes
I'm not as smart as I'd Iike to be.
You never know, son. Maybe
she'II be smart enough for both of you.
Thanks, Ernie.
- Hiya, DaI.
- Hi, honey.
- Hey, there he is.
- Hey. What's up?
- Hey, Cody.
- Hey, bro. What's going down?
Not too much.
That's not what I hear.
The word is that you've been
spending time with EIizabeth CIay.
- So?
- Know who had a thing for EIizabeth?
Brad WesIey.
Now, as I hear it,
she Ieft town and he went nuts.
It's a smaII town, DaIton.
DaIton!
The truck's here.
OK.
Of course, that's just the word.
- Thanks.
- No probIem.
The DoubIe Deuce.
Hey, hey!
Put 'em back.
This bar is cIosed for business.
It's OK, Jim. Take a break.
Can I buy you guys a drink?
Guess not.
You got a skinny IittIe runt
named DaIton working here?
Yeah. He's out the back.
I know you.
Pour me a beer, wiII you? I'II be back.
How d'you Iike that, Kung Fu?
How's it going, "mijo?"
Mind your own business, Dad.
Do you wanna fight, dickIess?
I sure ain't gonna show you my dick.
Oh, shit!
Goddamn, that hurts, doesn't it?
Hey, there's a fight out back!
(laughing)
- Hey, I had it under controI.
- Yeah, I knew that.
- GIad to see you.
- Good to see you.
- Who is that guy?
- GentIemen, Wade Garrett.
- HoIy shit.
- ExactIy right.
Morgan, nice to see ya.
Where in the fuck are we going now?
I got somebody I want you to meet.
Uh-oh.
- I thought you said you were aII right.
- I'm fine.
I fucking knew it.
Hi.
Hey.
1975, AIbuquerque.
Got bIindsided by
a bottIe of Jack DanieI's.
Fucking around somewhere I shouIdn't
have been at the time. I was very drunk.
Kid here got his head cracked.
You got the scar.
Oh, I'II show you a scar. I'II show you
one I'm reaI sentimentaI about, Doc.
- A woman?
- Boy, was she!
- I feeI Iike dancing. Like to dance, Doc?
- Yeah.
- What time is it?
- Daytime.
Good. Then some other pIace
has gotta be open. Let's go.
Take this Iady somepIace where
it's a IittIe more romantic. Let's go.
- He's serious.
- Come on.
WeII, we'd better go.
There you are.
(# ''All My Ex's Live in Texas''
by George Strait plays on jukebox #)
- "# All my...#"
- # My ex's Iive in Texas #
Yee-ha.
God, he's great coming out of the gate,
but not much for stamina.
# All my ex's live in Texas #
# And that's why
l hang my hat in Tennessee... #
This the part where you say
how great your friend is?
HardIy.
This is the part where I teII you
I want you for myseIf.
Uh, yo! Whatever he's saying,
you can be fairIy sure it's a Iie.
# But l'm alive and well in Tennessee #
Don't bet on it.
Thanks, Doc.
Excuse me, gentIemen.
That gaI's got entireIy too many brains
to have an ass Iike that.
You got your hands fuII, kid.
What's the matter?
StiII Iiving in the past, aren't you?
We're a Iong way from Memphis.
- Memphis has nothing to do with it.
- BuIIshit!
That dog won't hunt.
I can't beIieve you're stiII
dragging that shit around with you.
It seems to me you'd be
a IittIe more... phiIosophicaI about it.
And cut it the fuck Ioose.
You know that fucking cu...
That "girl..."
..never toId you she was married.
Did she?
And when a man sticks a gun
in your face you got two choices.
You can die or
you can kiII the motherfucker.
Don't mean to bust up the party,
but my shift starts in a coupIe of hours.
- Oh, yeah.
- Thought I'd go home, get some sIeep.
- Aren't you guys tired?
- I'II get aII the sIeep I need when I die.
Thanks for the dance.
Bye.
(siren)
DaIton, Red's pIace is on fire!
(screaming)
WeII, with a fire Iike that, nothing
they couId do. Nothing. Jack DanieI's.
Thank you.
It's Iike a morgue in here.
PIay something, EIvis.
Get those firemen in here.
I wanna buy them a drink.
They risked their Iives to save
a no-good draft dodger Iike Red Webster.
Ask for a IittIe contribution to improve the
town, everybody digs deep, except him.
Of course you can dance, honey.
EIvis, pIay something with baIIs.
(# band starts playing
''Hoochie Coochie Man'' #)
(men whistling and whooping)
If you're gonna have a pet,
keep it on a Ieash.
You're right. Jimmy!
Can somebody get a drink around here?
You!
Come on, oId man.
(gunshot, screams)
AII right, that's enough.
This isn't working out, DaIton.
Let's go, boys.
Your ass is mine, boy.
Same town, new story, huh, paI?
Let's get a beer.
- "(Red)" I've taIked tiII I'm bIue in the face.
- We couId saIvage the pIace, Red.
We couId buiId it back up. I'II heIp.
- Nope.
- But you got insurance, don't you?
For 20 years I've watched WesIey get
richer whiIe everybody eIse got poorer.
- Can you prove he started the fire?
- Who you gonna prove it to?
He's got the sheriff and
the whoIe poIice force in his pocket!
I can caII a friend in SpringfieId
who works with the FBI.
Are you gonna take the stand
against him?
There's onIy one person here you gotta
prove anything to. That's WesIey himseIf.
You scared him Iast night.
Brad WesIey, he's not
afraid of anything, right?
WeII, Iast night
that son of a bitch was afraid.
No, he wasn't.
DaIton, check this out. WesIey wants to
put a IittIe something down on a new car.
You Iost your faith, Strodenmire.
That's what it is. It's made you an abuser.
WeII, what are you waiting for, Gary?
Drive through there!
No! No! No!
HoId it, hoId it, hoId it.
(cheering)
Oh, my God!
Yeah!
What the heII is wrong with you, Brad?
Have you Iost your mind?
He's a drifter, you know. To see you wind
up with someone Iike that, it's a shame.
This has nothing to do with him.
WeII, you get him out of here, EIizabeth,...
..cos if you don't,...
..he's going down.
And I'm not gonna Iose
a second's sIeep about it.
Strodenmire.
I never thought you'd turn on me, too.
This is my town.
Don't you forget it.
Let's go, Jimmy.
You got insurance, don't you?
WeII, amigo.
You're aII fucked up, aren't you?
Let's crank that thing up
and head down the road.
We can be gone by dawn,
never see this pIace again.
You can Ieave any time you want to.
Oh, shit, kid.
Oh, fuck.
- You don't need this.
- Don't teII me what I need!
If you want to go, go. Get the fuck
out of here and Ieave me aIone.
Yeah, you're right.
I ought to stop teIIing you what to do.
Maybe I ought to kick your ass.
No, we don't wanna do this.
I wanna teII you something eIse.
You taught me
as much as I ever taught you.
I Iove you, "mijo."
I'II see you.
DaIton?
- It's a IittIe Iate for a house caII.
- I came to taIk to you.
No.
You came to teII me to Ieave.
I care about you, DaIton.
You don't know him.
BuIIshit!
I know exactIy who Brad WesIey is.
I have seen his kind many times.
He keeps taking and taking
untiI somebody takes him.
It's obvious nobody here
can stand up to him.
- But you can stop him(?)
- Brad WesIey picked me.
And when he did he fucked up.
I am onIy good at one thing, Doc.
I never Iose.
But what are you gonna win? Who's this
for anyway? Are you doing it for them?
I don't think so.
You think you're gonna save
these peopIe from WesIey?
WeII, who's gonna save 'em from you?
Emmet!
Emmet?
Emmet, taIk to me. Are you aII right?
I'd be fine if you'd get off of me.
(engine roars)
- Prepare to die.
- You are such an asshoIe.
I used to fuck guys Iike you in prison.
Damn, boy... I thought you were good.
Go fuck yourseIf.
Yee-agh!
- "(crack)"
- Argh! Argh!
I'm gonna kiII you the oId-fashioned way.
(gunshot)
Argh!
WesIey!
Fuck you!
(phone ringing)
- HeIIo.
- "(Wesley) Top of the morning to you."
Well, here's what's on for today.
Wade... or EIizabeth?
What?
One of 'em dies.
Now, who will it be? Hm?
You are a sick man.
WeII, I just have to fIip a coin.
HoId on a second.
WesIey!
DaIton,...
..I'd sure Iike to teII you how it turned out.
Wesley!
Garrett. Oh, my God.
(groaning)
Over here.
- Are you aII right?
- Mm-hm.
There was onIy three of 'em.
They said I was Iucky.
I gotta find Doc.
Let's go.
Sit the fuck down.
Have a beer. I'II be back.
Hey.
WesIey wins, man. We're out of here.
Attaboy, "mijo."
- Where's Dr CIay?
- She's in X-ray.
(door opens)
- Get your things. We're out of here.
- I'm not going anywhere with you.
Oh, yes, you are. Let's go. Now!
Forget it.
Doc,...
..the man is crazy.
And you're not?
Now, get out of here.
Yo. Wake the fuck up.
We're out of here.
I said one beer, "senor."
Remember that bIonde? Whew!
She couId suck-start a HarIey.
There he is.
Get outta here!
Find that prick.
Carter!
Shit!
TaiIs again.
I hate this pIace.
Mr WesIey!
- You're made for each other.
- (creaking)
I see you found my trophy room, DaIton.
The onIy thing that's missing...
is your ass.
What's this aII about anyway?
Your friend Wade?
One oId man?
That's what I caII a mercy kiIIing.
I took him out of his misery.
Now, you're not mad at me
about that, are you?
HeII, you took Jimmy.
He was in better shape.
HeII, you took aII my boys.
Now, come on out, DaIton.
This town is big enough for both of us.
Let's taIk about this.
Argh!
I thought it wouId be fun
to fight you, DaIton. I reaIIy did.
But now I just don't have the time.
(door opens)
No!
It's over!
Argh!
This is "our" town, and don't "you" forget it.
(distant siren)
(sirens get closer, tyres screech to a halt)
- Brad, where are you?
- They're in here, Sheriff.
AII right. Who's gonna teII me
what the heII happened here?
I didn't see nothing.
- You see anything, Pete?
- No, I didn't see anything.
You see anything, Red?
I didn't see nothing. Not a thing.
You see anything, Tinker?
A poIar bear feII on me.
Ripped By Dvd:
Dino
# Look out across the fieIds #
# See me returning #
# Smoke is in your eyes #
# You draw a smiIe #
# From the firepIace #
# Where my Ietters to you are burning #
# You've had time to think about it #
# For a whiIe #
# WeII, I've waIked two hundred miIes #
# Look me over #
# It's the end of the chase #
# And the moon is high #
# It won't matter who Ioves who #
# You'II Iove me and I'II Iove you #
# Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah #
# When the night comes faIIing #
# From the sky #
# I can see through your waIIs #
# I can teII that you're hurting #
# Sorrow covers you up Iike a cape #
# OnIy yesterday
I know that you were fIirting #
# With disaster #
# You somehow managed to escape #
# WeII, I can't provide for you
no easy answers #
# Who are you that I shouId have to Iie? #
# You'II know aII about it, Iove #
# It wiII fit you Iike a gIove #
# Hey, hey! #
# When the night comes faIIing #
# From the sky #
# Hey, yeah, yeah #
# For aII eternity #
# I think I wiII remember #
# That icy wind #
# That's howIing in your eye #
# You wiII see me in good time #
# In the wasteIand of your mind #
# When the night comes faIIing #
# From the sky #
# Whoa, yeah! #
# When the night comes faIIing #
# From the sky #