[Singing In Arabic]
Aah!
Show them the courage
of Allah.
Aah!
He says you stole the bread.
It's a lie.
I caught him stealing ours.
Cut off the infidel's hand.
No. I took the bread.
Wait.
That's not true.
They're not interested
in the truth.
But he's lying.
You're too weak, Peter.
You would not live.
As you wish.
Cut the other one's
hand off as well.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Robin.
Oh, God.
No, no, no!
This is English courage.
Aah!
Aah! Aah!
That's for five years of hell.
Behind you!
Come on, Robin,
for God's sake.
Come on!
Wait!
Take us with you!
You cannot save
those people, Christian...
but you can save me.
They're coming, Robin.
Robin, come on.
Christian!
Why should I?
For pity's sake.
My sentence is death.
He's a Moor. Don't listen.
I will show you a way out.
Why should we?
If you do not,
we're dead.
No, Robin.
For God's sake.
Robin, they're coming!
I'm sorry.
Come, Christian.
Come.
This way.
Thanks. I misjudged you.
You are fast
with a sword, my friend.
Five years I've waited
to smell free air.
It makes a man fast.
Aah!
Peter!
[Guard Shouting In Arabic]
It's mortal.
Leave me.
Give this ring
to my sister Marian...
and swear you'll
protect her for me.
His wound
is by the heart.
We cannot save him.
Swear it, Robin.
I swear it.
They're coming.
Tell Marian I died
a free Englishman.
Pe-Peter!
Peter!
For England!
No, no!
Come, my friend.
Make his sacrifice
an act of honor.
Come now.
Why did you cut me
free, Christian?
Whatever blood
is in your veins...
no man deserves
to die in there.
Farewell, friend.
God speed your way.
Our way lies together
with the speed of Allah.
What?
You have saved
my life, Christian.
I will stay with you
until I have saved yours.
Thanks, but I go
to England.
I relieve you
of your obligation.
Only Allah can do that.
What if I say no?
You have no choice.
I am Azeem Edin
Bashir Al Bakir.
You may call me Azeem.
[Guards Shouting In Arabic]
Robin of Locksley.
Kindest sir...
"tis rumored you fought
in King Richard"s crusade...
with my beloved son Robin.
I fear you have
returned home...
to desperate times...
when dark forces plot
against our absent king.
I am anxious for word
of my son.
Were you present at
his capture nearJerusalem?
Do you know the name...
of the potentate
who holds him?
Does he still bear me ill will?
A little news, please, sir.
I would give all that I own
for his release.
[Shouting]
[Grrr]
I will see him, I tell you!
Get out of my way!
Stop there!
Help me, my lord!
You should have waited.
I'm sorry you were
disturbed, master.
Duncan, it's all right.
Let him go.
They've taken my Gwen,
my daughter.
Who's taken her?
Men on horses,
in masks.
We tried
to stop them, but...
my son, he's dead.
He's dead.
Master, stay.
There is an evil moon tonight.
Never fear, Duncan.
Good will overcome.
Trust in that.
I'm sorry, my lord.
I had no choice.
You!
Locksley.
The king
shall hear of this!
Join us.
Never.
Join us...
or die.
God and King Richard!
Yaah!
Oh, thank you, Lord.
I'm home.
I'm home!
You are strange, Christian.
Yes, but I'm free.
Now I beg you
to free yourself of your vow.
Return with the boat.
I know how it feels
to be so far...
from your home
and family.
Because I love them
so much...
I cannot dishonor them.
I thought
you would say that.
No man controls
my destiny...
especially not one
who attacks downwind...
and stinks of garlic.
Come, Azeem.
Our fighting days are done.
By nightfall, we'll celebrate
with my father.
You understand,
of course...
I had to try.
I would have succeeded.
Why must you walk
in back of me?
In your country,
am I not the infidel?
Ha ha ha.
It seems safer
to appear as your slave...
rather than your equal.
For an infidel, you have
uncommon clarity of thinking...
but you tell me
nothing of yourself.
For instance,
your name Azeem...
what does it mean?
Great one.
Great one, really?
Did you give yourself
this name?
It's... It's a joke.
Azeem the great one,
I am home!
Whoo!
Look.
Mistletoe.
Many a maid's lost
her resolve to me...
thanks to this little plant.
In my country,
we talk to our women.
We do not drug them
with plants.
What do you know of women?
Where I come from,
Christian...
there are women
of such beauty...
that they can possess
a man's mind so...
that he would be willing
to die for them.
Wait. Is that why
you were to be executed?
Because of a woman?
That's it, isn't it?
That's it!
It is close to sunset.
You painted old dog.
Who was she?
The mullah's daughter?
Huh?
Another man's wife?
What's her name?
Is there no sun
in this cursed country?
Which way is east?
- Her name.
- East!
Her name.
- Jasmina.
- That way.
You are sure?
I would know blindfolded.
I'm five miles from home.
Was she worth it?
Worth dying for.
[Dogs Barking]
We've got him now!
Ha ha ha.
You're dog's meat, son,
you know that.
Get down here!
You know that
you're doomed!
Come down here!
Down!
You're not playing
by the rules, boy.
Deer don't climb trees.
Perhaps he thinks
he's a game bird.
Ha ha ha!
Shall we
teach him to fly?
Yeah.
Get him down.
[Robin]
Hold!
I'm curious as to
what manner of creature...
is so fearsome that it
takes six men to attack it.
Stranger, this is
no affair of yours.
Well, have we treed
the devil himself?
Let me see.
A small boy...
a truly dangerous animal.
This boy killed one of
the sheriff of Nottingham's deer.
You starve us!
We needed the meat.
I advise you
to move on, pilgrim.
This is the sheriff s land.
Wrong.
This is my land and my tree.
Therefore, whatever is in it
also belongs to me.
Might I have
the pleasure of your name...
before I have you
run through?
Robin of Locksley.
Well, well. Locksley.
Welcome home.
Kill him!
Aah!
Azeem!
It's time
to redeem that vow!
Unleash the hounds!
Get off your damn knees!
Look out!
[Boy]
Yay!
Now, sir...
if you'd be so kind
as to give me your name...
before I run you through.
Guy of Gisborne,
the sheriff s cousin.
That little bastard
was poaching deer.
Poaching? Is it not
a greater crime to starve a family?
Go on, Locksley.
Go on.
I've seen enough blood spilt
to last two lifetimes.
Now get off my land.
And tell Nottingham
what happens to his scum...
when they
pick on small children.
You.
You traveled 10,000 miles
to save my life...
then leave me
to be butchered?
I fulfill my vows
when I choose.
Which does not
include prayer times...
or mealtimes or anytime
I'm outnumbered 6-to-1.
You whine like a mule.
You are still alive.
Have no fear.
Come down, boy.
Is it true, boy?
Did you kill a deer?
Hundreds of them.
You scared him.
Interesting place, this...
England.
[Bell Clanging]
[Bird Squawking]
Hold up, Sir Guy.
The sheriff s not
to be disturbed.
Cousin.
I trust you justify
your intrusion...
with news of profound value.
I met a hooded man today...
who bade me warn you
not to harm his people.
Who told you to cover up?
His name?
Robin of Locksley.
The prodigal son returns.
He's a whelp.
This girl could best him.
Put it there!
Yes, well, this whelp
bested four of my men.
Yes, well, your men
were probably drunk.
And yet you survived, cousin.
I barely survived.
Yes, yes. I'm sure
it would take an army...
to match these rogues.
I trust Locksley's
visited his manor...
and found the home fires
still burning.
Time for potence, cousin.
Mortianna?
[Grumbling]
- [Squawks]
- Shut up!
You cold, madam?
Chit-chit-chit-chit-choo.
Ya, ya, ya.
What do you see?
The son of a dead man.
Locksley.
Does he affect us?
He precedes the lionheart.
King Richard returns
from the Crusades.
That could prove
a bit awkward.
It would soften the spines
of the barons.
Soon?
Make haste.
But my plan is still intact?
Aah!
What's wrong?
I have seen our death.
The painted man...
he haunts my dreams...
adorned with strange
foreign markings.
Ah! Locksley's companion.
Kill him!
Kill them both!
[Moaning]
Father?
Father!
Is anyone here?
Duncan!
Father!
No!
No.
Who is it?
It's my father.
[Footsteps]
Who's there?
Master Robin?
Is that you?
Duncan?
Oh, praise be.
I thought God
had abandoned us.
Duncan, my father.
Oh, it's a miracle.
Why... Why didn't
you cut him down?
It's a miracle.
I never thought that...
Are you deaf?
Easy!
Look at him.
I would have done
if I could see.
Who did this to you,
Duncan?
Guy... Guy of Gisborne...
with the sheriff and
his witch looking on.
Why?
They say that the sheriff...
captured your father
worshiping the devil...
that he signed a confession...
before the bishop.
No.
That's not possible.
Nottingham declared
all Locksley lands forfeit.
Did you believe the charges?
Not even when
they took my eyes.
[Sobbing]
We must go.
He loved you till the end,
young master.
He never gave up hope
of your return.
I should have been here.
He called the Crusades
a foolish quest.
He said it was vanity
to force other men...
to our religion.
But you must flee now.
Head south to safety.
Gisborne will
surely seek revenge.
I hear you, Duncan.
You should go home.
My world's turned
upside down here.
I cannot ask you to
come where I am going.
Alone, Christian, you will
only get yourself killed.
Besides...
there is nothing left
for me to go home to.
I will not rest
until my father is avenged.
I swear it...
by my own blood.
What is this place?
Peter's home.
It's nearly six years
since we left together.
We'll find food and shelter here.
[Knock Knock Knock]
No more beggars.
Tell the mistress
of the house...
that Robin of Locksley
is at her door.
Her ladyship's not here.
Is the child Marian at home?
Maybe she is.
Maybe she isn't.
Aah!
Ohh!
The hospitality
in this country...
is as warm as the weather.
It's a joke.
Really?
Leave your weapons!
Just you.
Wait here.
Right here?
A curse on Moors
and Saracens.
Were it not for
their ungodly ways...
Master Robin would
never have left.
What manner of name
is Azeem...
Irish, Cornish?
Moorish.
[Gasp]
Who are you?
Robin of Locksley.
You lie.
Robin is dead.
Step into the light.
Turn around.
Am I to dance next?
Who are you?
I am the maid Marian.
Well, then show
yourself, child...
for we knew
each other well.
The years have...
been kind.
Thank you.
With the king away...
we must guard against
villainous outlaws...
who would kidnap
a relative of his.
Surely you can see
I'm not one of those.
Perhaps.
Now remove yourself
from this house.
I would, my lady,
but I'm sworn to protect you.
Protect me?
Robin of Locksley
was nothing but a spoiled bully.
And besides...
as you can see...
we have enough protection.
Marian, wait.
You are truly courageous
against an unarmed man.
Aah!
Point me toward danger,
Azeem. I'm ready.
Stop! Stop!
Aah!
Ohh!
Hello, Marian.
His last thoughts were of you.
Oh, Peter.
Oh, God.
I'm sorry, Marian.
I'm sorry.
How do I know
you didn't abandon him...
to save your own skin?
No one feels his loss
more than I.
The next time I visit London...
I'll convey your condolences...
to my mother.
I would think,
for your safety...
that you would
join her there.
No. I have no interest
in life at court.
All that gossip mongering...
and currying favor.
But you're alone here.
Hardly.
These years have left us
many in need.
While you and my brother
were off playing boy heroes...
Nottingham has
plundered the shire.
I see you still
have your lands.
Because I give them
no excuse to take them.
I am the king's cousin.
It is my station
to look after these people...
until his return.
Marian.
My purpose in coming
was not to hurt you.
I swore...
I swore to your brother
that I would protect you.
You cannot replace
my brother.
I don't...
I don't want to replace him.
Marian, I've returned to my home
to find it destroyed...
and my father murdered.
And the only
explanations for it...
are the ramblings
of an old blind man.
All I remember of you...
is a spoiled bully
who used to burn my hair as a child.
Please allow that years
of war and prison...
may change a man.
Robin, whatever happened...
between you and your father...
you mustn't believe...
what they accused him of.
I don't.
Look.
How did your uneducated kind...
ever takeJerusalem?
God knows.
What is it?
It's Nottingham's soldiers.
Coming here?
Is this your protection?
I killed some
of the sheriff s men.
Oh, dear.
I fear I've placed
you in danger.
[Horse Neighs]
I can take care
of myself. Just go.
No. That's my horse.
A truly magnificent
animal, milady.
Go!
I said I'm sworn to protect you.
And I say no more
boyish gestures.
I'm not leaving.
Stop them!
They're stealing my horses!
You're so kind, Marian.
Ooh!
You've been sheltering
outlaws, Lady Marian?
They're thieves, you imbecile.
Lucky he didn't steal
your virtue as well.
A crown to the man
who brings me Locksley's head!
Milady. Hyah!
Have we lost them?
No.
My horse carries two.
Yours is lame.
We cannot outrun them.
Leave me, Master Robin.
I slow your escape.
We can lose them
in the forest.
Sherwood Forest
is haunted, master.
Either we take our chances
with the ghosts...
or become ghosts ourselves.
Come on, damn you!
There are only three of them!
It's not the men we fear.
It's the evil spirits.
Robin of the Hood...
son of a devil worshiper!
Your father died a coward...
cursing your name...
and squealing
like a stuck pig!
You will bring no justice
to your father...
by dying today.
[Strange Noises]
Master Robin?
There are your
ghosts, Duncan...
wind chimes.
A child's toy
put to good use.
You scare easily,
my painted Moor.
This forest has eyes.
I swear it.
In my dreams alone...
have I imagined
such a place.
Then imagine
a way to cross it.
There's hope!
#There was a rich man
from Nottingham #
#Who tried
to cross the river #
#What a dope,
he tripped on a rope #
# Now look at him shiver ##
Beg for mercy, rich man!
I beg of no man.
[Shouting]
Aah!
Well, this here
is our river...
and any man
who wishes to cross...
must pay a tax.
I will pay no tax.
As you can see...
I have nothing...
not even my sword.
Bollocks!
Any man who travels
with two servants...
and claims he's got
no bloody money...
is either a fool...
or a liar.
Yeah, he's a liar!
Who are you?
John Little...
best man of the woods.
- Yeah!
- Yay!
Well, best man,
do you lead this rabble?
- Whoa!
- Oh!
Yes, I do, mate.
And if you tosspots want to travel
through Sherwood Forest...
it's going to cost you...
that gold medallion.
This is sacred to me.
It's sacred to us,
too, matey.
That there will feed us
for a blooming month.
You'll have to
fight me for it.
Whoa! Whoa!
Love to, mate.
- Yeah!
Be careful, Father.
He walloped 12 of
the sheriff s men.
Is that so?
Reckon I'm going
to enjoy this.
Hey!
That's your father?
Come on, John!
Knock him over, John!
Ha ha ha ha!
Whoa!
[Will Scarlett]
He's drowning!
Lost something?
Thanks for the taxes.
Ha ha ha!
Looks like
the little rich boy...
is lost for words, eh?
Any great ideas?
Get up!
Move faster!
Move faster.
Great idea.
Watch it, John!
We're not through yet.
All right, my old cocker.
You want another
good walloping?
You shall have one.
Ohh!
Seems I've made it
past the gate, John Little.
Or should I call you
LittleJohn?
[Wulf]
Hit him, Father! Wallop him!
Swimming time again,
old chum.
Ohh!
[Wulf]
Where is he?
Do you see him?
It's a bloomin' shame.
He was a brave lad.
Ooh! Aah!
Help!
Do you yield?
I can't bloody swim!
Yes!
Good. Now put
your feet down.
I'll be buggered.
- The medallion.
- Give me your name first.
Robin of Locksley.
Well,
Robin of Locksley...
you got balls of solid rock.
Come on.
[Laughing]
That's Much,
the Miller's son...
Harold Brownwell...
and that stumpy one there
is David of Doncaster...
but the lads
all calls him Bull.
[Laughing]
'Cause you're short?
No. It's 'cause
I'm so long!
Yeah, look.
No, Bull.
Save it. Save it for the ladies.
Give the man some mead.
Very good, isn't it?
Now, I made that myself.
Has English hospitality
changed so much in six years...
that a friend of mine's
not welcome at this table?
But he's a savage, sire.
That he is.
But no more than you or I.
And don't call me sire.
With regret, I must decline.
Allah forbids it.
Your bloody loss, mate.
How is it there are
so many of you in hiding?
Well, we're all outlaws.
Got prices on our heads.
Even the young lad there.
He's a blasted sheriff.
He says we owes him taxes.
Well, you know,
your ghost...
will only keep the sheriff s men
at bay so long.
They've worked so far.
You have a better idea?
You can always fight back.
Yeah.
Ha ha ha ha.
I reckon I must have cracked
that noble head of yours.
These are all good lads here.
They got hearts of oak,
but they're farmers.
It'd be lambs
to the slaughter.
They say the sheriff
was raised by a witch.
Witch?
She knows
every man's thoughts.
You can see
right through her...
and she flies.
That's a load
of codswallop.
What does the rich son
of a devil worshiper care...
about outlaw peasants?
My lord was a kind
and generous man!
Who among you dares
believe him capable...
Duncan. My father was
no devil worshiper...
and I'll have words with any man
who says otherwise.
But he's right.
I was a rich man's son.
But when I killed
the sheriff s men...
I became an outlaw
like you.
You are nothing like us.
Well... that there's
Will Scarlett.
Don't take no note of him.
He's full of piss and wind.
Come on, lads, drink up.
Stop talking
so much bloody rubbish.
This here is the best
we simple men can expect.
Here we're safe.
Here...
we are kings.
Ha ha ha!
[Rooster Crows]
[Coughing]
[Sheep Bleats]
Aah!
Too much mead, old friend?
Oh, forgive me.
I oversleep.
No, no.
Rest yourself.
What day is it, Duncan?
Sunday, I think.
Do they still give alms
to the poor at mass?
That they do.
These days,
the need for mercy...
is greater than ever.
Well, my other god calls.
Oh, don't upset
yourself, Mortianna.
Appearances are important
to that lot.
Especially on a Sunday.
You know my true faith
lies in the old ways.
Although...
frankly sometimes...
I can't see much difference.
Did my parents truly tell you...
to instruct me in all this?
Their dying wish.
[Chuckles]
Come on.
We beseech thy blessing,
Lord...
on all your people...
but most especially...
on our noble sheriff
of Nottingham.
Grant him the wisdom...
to guide and protect
our glorious city.
Grant him also
the strength...
to bring to justice...
the lawless men who would
threaten its safety...
and prosperity...
and the judgment
to punish them...
in your name.
Amen.
- Amen.
Go in peace.
Alms, please, sir.
Please, madam.
- Sarah.
- Yes.
Thank you.
Ma'am.
That's all I have.
God bless you, mum.
Alms for a blind man, milady?
Mmm.
For one who cannot
see your beauty.
Hello.
What are you doing here?
Searching my soul.
I do not wish to be seen
with an outlaw.
You prefer the company
of Nottingham?
There's a price
on your head.
How much?
100 gold pieces.
Is that all?
I'll have to annoy
the good sheriff more.
Soon it will be 1,000.
For 1,000, I would
turn you in myself.
Nottingham is
mounting an army.
He has every blacksmith
in the county...
in the castle,
making swords and armor.
What is he planning?
I don't know,
but there's no limit...
to the man's ambitions.
Go!
Thank you.
Quickly! Go!
Robin, do something for me.
What?
Take a bath.
Take a bath?
These are my private
chambers, my son.
I have priests
who would hear your confession.
- Gggt!
- Aah!
Shh!
I see the boy I knew
in the man before me.
Welcome home, Robin.
You shine like
the sun, milady.
You've been meeting
with Robin of Locksley.
My cousin tells me...
the knave deprived
you of some horses.
Oh... yes.
A most disagreeable
experience.
Yes, I know.
And for inflicting that upon you...
I'm going to hang him
from the walls by his own entrails.
I'd like to see that.
If you'd bring
your household...
within the city walls...
I could give your every need
my personal attention.
I do thank you,
but I prefer to stay...
in my family's home
for now.
Oh. Well, then, perhaps
you'd do me the honor...
of accepting
a small token...
of my undying devotion
to your safety.
Oh!
Why... King Richard
will be deeply moved...
to hear of your concern
for my welfare.
Yes, um...
I'm afraid the king
has many enemies...
both abroad
and at home.
I fear for his safe return.
Oh, no. Fear not,
dear sheriff.
He will return,
and when he does...
he will wish to reward
his faithful subjects.
I asked your father
three times...
if he worshiped
the dark one...
because his answer
vexed me so grievously.
He said...
he must meet God
with a clear conscience.
You lie.
On your souls...
do not shed blood
in the house of God!
Aah!
[Nottingham]
You bastard!
In there!
Get him!
Locksley!
I'm going to cut
your heart out...
with a spoon!
Then it begins.
Aah!
He's taking
the sheriff s horse!
Close the gate!
The sheriff s horse!
He's stolen
the sheriff s horse!
Uhh!
What are you looking at?
There's a rider coming in!
Water!
Thank you.
For the animal.
How can I protect you,
Christian...
if I know not
where you go?
You've hardly raised
a finger...
when you do know...
great one.
I prefer to have
the choice.
Wonderful. You've stolen
the sheriff s horse?
You've stirred up
a bloody hornet's nest now!
Are you afraid, John?
Yeah, a little.
Well, so is the sheriff.
Today I gave him a sting
he'll not forget.
You fool!
You've started a war!
We're already at war.
Duncan...
bread.
And I say we strike back...
at the very man
who takes our homes...
and would
hunt our children.
We?
You planning to
join us then, matey?
No, to lead you.
Christian...
these are simple people.
They are not warriors.
Be careful
you do not do this...
for your own purposes.
You forget yourself, Azeem.
I do not ask for your company
or counsel.
Why a spoon, cousin?
Why not an ax
or something...
Because it's dull, you twit!
It'll hurt more!
I want this brigand found.
Starve them out!
Slaughter their...
No, take their livestock.
I want Locksley's own people
fighting to bring his head in.
Well, perhaps we could create
a name for him...
something to drive fear
into the hearts of the populace.
Maybe Locksley the Lethal
or Wreaking Robin or...
Whatever!
I want him dead
by the next full moon...
before the barons
come back.
Now sew...
and keep the stitches small!
He's not here, sir.
Where is your mate,
the man they call Little?
He died last winter.
Burn it down.
Light the other one.
Leave us the sow.
Her young will feed us.
Beware of
the Sherwood bandit.
Robin of the Hood?
Yes, sir.
Pray he's brought to us
before winter.
Ma!
Over here!
Oh, John!
Papa!
They burned it, all of it.
Where is this
Robin Hood now?
He's there.
Look! Look what
they've done!
If it's fame
you seek, Christian...
I think you have it.
You brought this misery
on us, Locksley.
It's Nottingham
trying to divide us.
We are divided, rich boy.
I'm not as blind
as that old man.
You're still trying to be
lord of the manor.
I heard today the sheriff
now values your neck...
at 500 gold pieces.
I say we take him in.
- Aye.
Do you think the sheriff
will return everything...
after I'm gone?
He'll give us the reward
and our pardons.
Wrong.
He'll stretch your
necks one by one.
What would you
have us do...
fight armored men
on horseback...
with rocks
and our bare hands?
If needs be.
But with
the one true weapon...
that escapes you, Will...
courage.
Look out!
Thank you, Wulf.
You wish to end this?
You wish to go home?
Then we must stop
fighting amongst ourselves...
and face that the price
for it may be dear.
I for one
would rather die...
than to spend my life
in hiding.
The sheriff calls us outlaws...
but I say we are free.
And one free man
defending his home...
is more powerful
than 10 hired soldiers.
The Crusades taught me that.
I will make you
no promises save one...
that if you truly believe
in your hearts...
that you are free...
then I say we can win.
They got armor.
Yeah! Right!
They got armor, Bull?
Even this boy
can be taught...
to find chinks
in every suit of armor.
We ain't got nothing to eat.
What do we need that
the forest cannot provide?
We have food,
wood for weapons.
We'll find safety
and solace in her trees.
Yeah, but
what about our kin?
Sheriff s taken
all they got, too.
Then, by God,
we take it back.
Ho!
Hyah!
What's the meaning of this?
Milady, a woman
of your beauty...
has no need for
such decorations.
How dare you!
[Bell Rings]
Please don't take that.
Please, sir, those
belong to our lord.
Now they belong
to my lord sheriff!
- Yay!
- Ha ha!
Give it back.
Good.
Tell the sheriff...
for every harm he
does these people...
I will visit it
back on him tenfold.
Something vexes thee?
What the devil?
'Tis a hot day,
my friend...
to burden your horse
with a heavy purse.
The sheriff will hear of this.
I truly hope so.
Yeah!
There, luv.
Buy yourself
a new sow.
God bless you, Fanny...
and God bless Robin Hood.
We reckon he's nicked
three to four million...
in the last
five months, sire.
All right, fine.
Raise the bounty on his head.
25,000 crowns.
Begging your pardon, sire.
It won't do no good
how much you raise it.
Really, scribe?
And why is that?
Because, sire,
the poor, you see?
He gives them
what he takes...
and, well, sire,
they love him.
Just a minute.
Robin Hood steals money
from my pocket...
forcing me
to hurt the public...
and they love him for it?
Yes.
That's it, then!
Cancel the kitchen scraps
for lepers and orphans...
no more
merciful beheadings...
and call off Christmas.
The treasury is empty.
All day and all night,
people plague my door...
whining for tax relief...
and safe passage
through Sherwood Forest.
"We cannot pay thee...
what the highwayman
has taken."
It's the shortest route
to London.
It's the only road to London,
you little ferret.
Sir Guy's patrols
have found nothing, sire.
No camp. Nothing.
[Spits]
This hooded viper
simply slithers into the forest.
You, my room,
10:30 tonight.
You, 10:45...
and bring a friend.
A tongue offends thee.
Whose?
One who rights all.
One who...
That horrible little scribe?
- His tongue?
- Cut it out.
#What's the pleasure
in this life #
# Laughter, love,
and drinking #
# Good King Richard,
bless his soul #
# Loves his wine
and warring #
# But for us
who stay at home #
#There's only beer
and whoring #
# Play your music,
dance the day #
#Think of not
tomorrow... #
How many?
20.
20?
How many?
Five.
They can't count anyway.
- Come on.
- Why scare them?
And they call me barbarian.
# Loves his wine
and warring #
# But for us
who stay at home #
#There's only beer
and whoring #
# Play the music,
dance the day... ##
Friar! You'll find
it difficult to sing...
with a sword
in your gullet.
Yes, my lord.
You pig.
Shut up about it!
Help me move this log!
Log? This is a tree!
You're supposed to help me!
I'm supposed to be
meeting a girl!
You men in front, after me.
You men in the rear,
stay with the wagon!
On to glory!
Ha ha ha ha ha!
Bastards!
Come on, find them!
# Oh... ##
[Burp]
Go!
Hyah!
Welcome to Sherwood,
Friar. Giddyup!
Aagh!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Surrender your weapons!
Surrender your weapons
and I'll give you my word...
you shall go free!
Don't do that!
Aah! What are you...
Azeem! Aah!
Look at that!
Oh!
I'll be buggered.
This treasure had a purpose.
We must find out what.
Oh! Aah!
Good morning,
my reverend friend.
You travel
with poor company...
when you travel with
Nottingham soldiers.
Tax him!
- Tax him!
I'm Robin of Locksley...
and my men are thirsty.
- Aye!
- That's right.
Robin Hood!
Ha! Lord bless me.
I mistook you
for common thieves.
Kindly let me pass, huh?
Surely the lord
has the charity...
to spare a few barrels...
for good Christian men, yes?
We have much to celebrate.
Come on.
If you wish them to share
in the good lord's brew...
you must best me for it!
Hyah!
Confess, Robin Hood...
that Friar Tuck is a braver,
holier, and wiser man...
than thou art.
He giveth
and he taketh away.
Do you yield?
I'd rather roast in hell.
Aah!
Shoot him! Shoot him!
# Robin has his way #
#Whether you live
by night or day #
#Whether you're rich
or young or old #
#Whether you're noble,
meek, or bold #
#You will fall #
# Short or tall ##
Oh, I think the good friar's
taken us far enough.
Well done, Friar.
Thank you, Lord,
for teaching me humility.
Ohh.
Well, Tuck...
Thanks for the beer.
Are these not
the meek of the earth?
We're in need of an honest man
to minister to them.
What say you, Friar?
The Lord reveals himself
in mysterious ways.
I accept.
Good.
You will not regret it.
Aye, but you may!