Hot as hell out there, huh?
Well, well, well, well.
How are we today, young man?
What can I do you for?
Jeez, it must be cosy in that suit. Hey?
Oh. Yeah.
No, the airport lost all my bags.
Well, it's gonna be
a real scorcher today.
Yeah. No kidding.
I'm supposed to catch
a boat cruise from here...?
A few years back you'd be lucky
to see any tourists up here at all.
- Yeah.
- Too remote for most people.
It's changing pretty quickly,
I can tell you.
Right. Uh, can I get a coffee, please?
Real strong.
- Two sugars.
- How about a 'cup-a-cino'?
Give the new machine a work-out.
Phil. Hey.
What's going on, man?
How's Chicago?
Everything's fine,
except for the fact that
they lost my bags at the airport
and my computer was in my bag
and I need it to finish the article,
so could you call Greg at the office
and tell him what happened
'cause I really need someone
to track down those bags for me.
Hello? Hello?
Hello? Can you hear me?
Can you hear me now? Phil?
- Get outta there.
- Can you hear me now?
Hey, can you hear me?
Hey. There you are.
No, no, the service here sucks.
Oh, no. Oh, no, it's over.
Yeah, she went back last week.
Whatever.
Why do you think I took this shitty job?
Hello?
Shit.
Jesus Christ.
There you go. Real strong.
It's on the house.
Oh, thanks. Thanks a lot.
Hey, nice picture.
That silly bugger will think twice
about going swimming at night, hey?
- Tickets.
- Dad, have you got the tickets?
Tickets.
That's two. Two adults, one child.
Cheers. Just in the middle there.
Wow. It's so low.
Yeah. Big one looks safer.
- Better you than me.
- OK.
So one of the rules of my tour
is that you only have one chance
to complain about the heat and the flies.
Nice to meet ya.
They're a fact of life up here
and whingeing about 'em all day
isn't gonna make 'em disappear.
Simon. Get a hold of those flies.
Might have to kick you off the boat, mate.
Ticket?
Oh, I got one. Trust me.
Come on, mate.
You got two tickets there, sir.
- Oh, no, no, no. Just me.
- No worries.
Sit anywhere you like.
Jesus!
We're on bush time now, so should
have youse back around 5:00. Or 6:00.
She's your kid,
and you kind of promised her crocodiles.
Honey, it's a two-hour tape.
I'll get footage, OK?
Oh! Here we go.
Maybe we'll see those crocodiles.
Welcome to Ryan's Wildlife Cruises.
My name's Kate Ryan
and I'm gonna be your tour guide today,
in case you hadn't figured that out.
This is my business partner, Kevin.
Say g'day, Kev.
Yes, you are.
Oh, my God, you're so cute.
Honey, we should get a dog.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Thought you were a cat person.
Anyone have any questions?
Alright, let's go check out some crocs.
The Northern Territory
is home to the biggest population
of saltwater crocodiles in the world,
spread throughout
several large tidal river systems.
The State covers a landmass
double the size of Texas
but we have a population
of only 200,000 people.
As you can imagine,
we all have pretty big backyards.
Excuse me. Excuse me?
- Hi there.
- Hi. I'm Gwen.
Hi. Hi, Gwen. Would you mind...?
- Oh, no. Sure, help yourself.
- No, no.
Sorry, it's, um...
It's the smoke. It's... it's kind of wafting.
Right. Shite. OK. Story of my life!
I'll, um, go down the back.
- Oh, thank you so much. Thank you.
- That's OK.
- Really appreciate that.
- Thanks a lot.
Right.
- Come here.
- Where's the zoom on this?
- You don't need the zoom.
- There it is, there.
Come on, darling.
OK. Smile.
- Hmm.
- Oh, Sher.
- What are you doing? Look at that.
- Oh, darling. Don't pull a face.
- Why do you always pull a face?
- Excuse me?
Do you want me to take
a photo of the family?
- Yeah, that...that'd be super.
- Yeah?
- That would be good. Thank you.
- Thanks very much.
- The big button?
- Yeah, just that one there.
OK. Here we go.
Oh, that's beaut.
- That is a beautiful camera.
- Thank you.
- Yeah, is that new?
- Oh, yes.
- I got it for Christmas.
- Yeah, nice. Cute little snapper.
I mean, she's no, um...digital SLR,
which is single lens reflex.
I got a 25mm lens. I got a 35mm,
right through to a 1 55mm.
Doubler pushes it out to 300mm,
but who's counting?
- I know I'm not.
- Well, that's very impressive.
It is indeed. Guess how much.
Man, it's like,
you know, the 'African Queen'.
It's hot and horny
and I just wanna get naked.
I could come into the room.
- You know, we could do that.
- Do you want to sit somewhere else?
- I like sitting next to you.
- No. Do you want to sit there?
- No.
- There's a spare seat. Sit there.
- I paid for this seat.
- You're bugging me. Sit there.
- What, with the lrish girl?
- Really, no, it's sexual harassment.
- With the lrish girl?
- No, just sit here.
You can't make everybody
move to the back of the boat.
- No.
- Enough already with the sex talk.
- OK? OK? OK?
- It's not your boat.
Shite! It's hot, isn't it?
Hey, what are they waiting for?
Keep watching.
- Oh, my God.
- Oh, my gosh!
- What was that?
- You right there, love?
Look at the size of the bastard.
Don't you worry.
He's already got his lunch.
God, that's amazing.
- Are you right?
- How often does it do that?
Every day at 2:00.
- Wow. Every day at 2:00?
- Yep.
And how high do they jump?
Oh, they can jump right out.
They use their tails to propel 'em.
I mean, sometimes
they come right up to you.
So, it could come into the boat, right?
It could come into the boat?
You'll be right,
so long as you don't go in the water.
I'm not planning on it, I tell you that.
There's a salty.
They're so still.
- Check this out.
- That's great. That's great!
Dad, imagine if it bit you.
It's amazing.
It's so still.
Looks young, though, doesn't it?
I guess that's how they catch...
Looks handsome.
Oh. There he goes.
Alright, the species
that we're looking at today,
the saltwater crocodile,
is probably the most dangerous member
of the crocodilian family.
They're pretty much living dinosaurs,
who have been perfecting
their hunting skills
over 200 million years.
So they can swim underwater
at up to 20 miles an hour
without making a ripple on the surface.
And they can burst out to attack
with incredible speed.
They're also known to watch their prey
and learn their habits.
In fact, you can see this bloke
looking at us now.
So if any of you are camping up here
near a river and you need water...
It's got teeth like your mother.
..make sure you do so
at a different time every day
because the croc will learn your routine.
You might wanna avoid that.
Croc gets a hold of you
and he can't swallow you in one go,
he will literally tear you to pieces.
Super.
- Allen, can you imagine?
- So how big do they grow?
Well, that one there was a little one,
but they can grow
from 20 to 25 feet long,
weigh up to two tonne.
There have been stories of bigger ones,
but the crocs that we're looking at today
are just as dangerous.
Are there many attacks on people?
Tourists, occasionally.
That was in poor taste.
I'll bet.
Don't worry, ma'am.
We're perfectly safe on this boat.
They won't attack anything
bigger than they are.
- How big is this boat?
- Yeah.
- Big enough.
- Sure. Whatever.
Lighten up a little, will you?
Right. The bigger the better,
if you ask me.
Aren't you beautiful, hey?
Do you love me?
Gimme a kiss. Gimme a kiss.
- Got a Wet One?
- Oh, yeah.
Jesus. Anyone complain
about the flies yet?
That was your one shot.
That wasn't a complaint.
That was a question.
- How long are you out here, anyway?
- Oh, just a few days.
Alice Springs after this, then home.
Where's that?
Chicago.
I'm a travel writer for a magazine.
Sounds like the life.
How about you? You travel a lot?
Never left the Territory.
You're kidding, right?
Why would I wanna leave all this?
It's amazing watching people's faces
the first time they come out here.
You might wanna...take your seat.
Gets a bit hairy around this bend.
Aye, aye, captain.
Sher, did you know this is
the oldest landscape in the world?
Absolutely ancient.
Dad, you can be so boring sometimes.
MAN AND One, two...
I got you.
Did you see that?!
No.
Yee-hoo! Whoo-hoo!
Oh, my gosh. They're stopping.
Oooh!
Keep your shirt on, cunt-face.
- Katie.
- G'day, Neil.
Oi.
Bloody charming. There's ladies present.
Sorry, ladies.
Sorry about that, folks.
This shouldn't take a minute.
- Oooh!
- Mate, I'm at work.
Katie, we're just saying g'day
to the tourists, yeah?
- G'day, tourists.
- Tourists.
Yeah, you can take the photo, darlin'.
Oooh, please. Pop it out.
Hope you brought
your microscope!
Alright, you've acquainted yourself
with the tourists.
Now would you acquaint yourself
with the other end of the river?
Come on, mate. Let's just fuck off, eh?
No, hang on.
I just wanna know why
Miss Captain Katie Coo here
is acting so high and mighty these days.
What is it, Katie?
Why won't you have a bar of me, sweet?
Excuse me, son, the young lady
asked you politely to remove yourself.
We'd like to get on with our tour.
Fuck me, it's John fuckin' Wayne.
This is the tour, John.
Me and Col, we're the wildlife.
Hello.
- We're ducks!
- I'm gonna keep this simple for you.
I'm gonna count to three
and ask you to leave.
What the fuck are you gawking at,
four-eyes?
- One.
- I don't know.
I got the brochure but it didn't
say anything about assholes.
- He's a poofter, mate.
- Two.
I'm not kidding, mate.
Bullshit, Katie.
Fuck!
- Oooh!
- Whoa!
Jeez...
Get out!
You right there, mate?
- Sorry about that, folks.
- Unbelievable.
As you can see, human pollution
is one of the greatest threats
to the environment out here.
Collin! Collin, you bloody idiot!
- Sorry, mate. I...
- What are you fuckin' doing?!
Forget it, mate. It's over.
About 1 0 days. Yeah,
we got four weeks all up, so...
Nice. I'm seeing things
I don't think my friends would believe.
We got some on you inadvertently before.
Alright, we'll be heading home now.
Should take us about an hour or so.
I'll have you back in time to grab an
ice-cream on your way back to town.
- Oh, swell.
- Thank you all for a wonderful day.
Finishes now?
Um, special thanks
to John Wayne and to 'Four-Eyes'.
Top work, Four-Eyes.
I think they deserve a round of applause.
- Thanks, guys.
- Well done. Well done.
Up in this part of the world,
we call you 'top blokes'.
Don't know where I'd have been
without youse.
Please don't film me.
Honey, please don't.
Did you see that?
- No. What?
- I think I saw something.
Flare, I think. Up there. There.
Should we say something?
- Excuse me, miss.
- My husband just saw something.
I think it was a flare.
- Where'd you see it?
- Up there.
A flare?
Did anyone else see it? No?
- No. No.
- No.
- Wait. I got the tape.
- Yeah. Rewind it a little bit.
Yeah. It's right here.
Oh, Jesus! I saw it.
- Yeah!
- There's one. There's one!
- Did you see that flare?
- I saw it..
Base, this is 'The Suzanne'.
Are you there, Bill? Over.
Do you read me? Over.
I can't understand you.
I'm in Kingston Gorge and I'm getting
severe interference. Do you read me?
I think I just saw a flare.
So I'm gonna head upriver
and check it out.
'Suzanne', out.
Alright, we've just seen
what looks like a distress flare,
so we're gonna take a quick run upriver
and see if anyone's in trouble.
I realise this is a bit of an inconvenience,
but we do have to respond.
I got a bus to catch at 6:30.
Yeah, so do we. We're meeting family.
Who do you think it is?
Could be poachers.
They sometimes go into Arnhem Land.
It could be anyone.
It could be anyone,
and if it was you up there,
you'd want me to respond in exactly
the same way, so keep your seat, sir.
I'm sorry, but my wife and l,
we really...
- Allen, please. I'm fine.
- I'm not having you here all day.
How long do you think it'll take?
Can't be more
than a couple of miles upriver.
OK, you're alright. You're alright.
Listen, she's fine.
Are you OK?
Not really supposed to go through here.
This is sacred land.
Shouldn't really matter
if someone's in trouble, right?
She'll be right.
I reckon it came from
deeper in the swamp somewhere.
What do you think?
I think we've gone as far as we can.
Besides, there's nobody here.
It's gonna get dark soon.
We should probably go.
Probably right.
What?
Well, I suppose that's where
the flares came from.
This has really gone too far.
We must get back.
I can't have you out here any longer.
OK, we should...
What was that?
- Oh, shit, we're sinking.
- Oh, my God! We're sinking!
- There's a hole!
- What's happened?
Are we moving? Move it!
There! There!
Hold on! Hold on to your seats!
Just hold on to your seats.
We're almost there. Just hold on.
Let's get off. Get off, now!
Get off the boat. Hurry.
Get off the boat.
Alright, there's a radio
in one of these bags.
Should be in here somewhere.
Right.
Can you find it in there?
No, it's not in there.
It's underwater.
- Oh, shit!
- Is it working?
- What about the boat radio?
- It's wet but it should work.
Stay off the boat.
It's not working, mate.
It's underwater.
Can you take that up on the hill
and see if you can dry it out?
Just keep
switching channels, mate.
No bloody radio!
You've got us stuck on this
tiny little island with no bloody radio!
Great!
Kate?
Emergency. Hello.
Can anyone hear me? Over.
What's going on here?
We're gonna miss the bus.
We're late already.
- Are you alright?
- Yeah. I'm just...
- So we have no radio?
- I don't want to be here.
Take a deep breath.
- You'll be alright, OK? You know?
- Yeah.
Miss, we have no radio,
so what the hell happens now?
Well, how will anyone know
where we are?
I thought you said
crocs wouldn't attack a boat.
Alright, they're territorial animals, so...
..if we've stumbled into one's territory
it's possible it might've
given us a little nudge,
just to let us know we're not wanted.
"A little nudge"? Tell that
to whoever was in that boat.
My God,
we're in the middle of nowhere here.
Listen, we have to stay calm, yeah?
We're gonna be fine.
My dad's gonna realise
something's happened
and he'll send a search party to find us.
When might that be, exactly?
Well, we're a long way upriver,
so it could take a couple of hours.
This is a tidal river, isn't it?
- This is a bloody tidal river!
- What? What does that mean?
See those trees? That's how high
the tide will be when it comes in.
The whole bloody place
will be underwater.
Look, that won't be for hours
and we should have time
to fix the boat by then.
Miss, I don't know a lot
about boats but, seriously,
we can't sit on this pile of mud
waiting to go underwater in pitch black.
If we can get across,
we can walk it in a few hours.
It's the only way we're gonna get help.
- How the hell you gonna get across?
- Well, how do you think?
So, what do you say, mate?
You with me?
- No! No, Everett, no.
- Honey. It's OK.
I am in charge of this group
and what you are suggesting is crazy.
If we don't get across right now
it's gonna be too late.
Alright? You understand?
Well, what?
Would you lot prefer to get through that
in the dark? Come on!
I don't know! I friggin' well don't know!
- Bloody hell!
- You're not going in the water!
Hey. Hey, buddy!
Come on. Come on, buddy.
- Come on!
- Get your hands...off me!
Hey, hey, hey. Shush, shush!
Shh. I can hear something.
What channel is it?
- Look at this thing!
- Oh, my God.
Where the hell did he go?
Somebody do something! Everett!
Everett!
Everett?! Everett!
- Everett!
- Stand back.
No!
- Come back from the water.
- Get the fuck away from me!
Come back. Come back!
All of you, stay away from the water!
- Everett!
- Jesus!
It's gonna be OK.
It's gonna be alright.
No! No!
Everett!
Somebody do something!
How long did you say
until the tide comes?
Can you grab that flashlight?
What, like a couple hours, or...?
What?
How long do we have before
the tide comes in? Hours or minutes?
Look, with an animal that aggressive
out there,
I think the tide's
the least of our problems.
It's gonna be dark soon.
We need light to see. It doesn't.
We have to get off the island.
We can't go in the water.
So how the fuck
are we gonna get off here?
I thought you were supposed to be
some kind of fearless travel writer.
Yeah, well, I just saw a man
get eaten by a fucking crocodile.
This is not what I do, alright?
You know what I do?
I write stupid articles about hotels
and restaurants and resorts,
not about the Australian outback.
And by the way, I fucking hate animals,
especially ones that can kill you.
Speaking of which, I'm gonna kill
my fuckin' editor when I get home.
Can't find the flares.
Would they be in a giant yellow box
with the word 'flares'
written on the side of it?
- Where?
- Over there.
Shit!
We are completely fucked.
Over here! Quickly!
Quickly.
- Did you get something?
- I think it's music. Listen.
It's them.
Whoo-hoo! Hey! Hey!
Whoo-hoo!
Told you to keep going.
Told you they'd be there.
Hey!
Look at that. She's pretty
happy to see you now, mate.
- Mate, watch out!
- Whoo!
Neil, we need help!
- What are you doing?
- Hey, Neil! Watch out. Neil!
Get off the boat!
What are you doing?
Boys!
- Whoo-hoo!
- Slow down. Slow down.
Come in, you...
- Neil!
- Come back!
I'm not kidding!
What?
I can't...
He cannot hear you!
Now you wanna talk to me? Huh?
What's wrong with the boat?
Swim!
Mate, swim!
Swim! Come on, mate! Keep coming!
Come on, Neil!
Come on, mate. Hurry up.
You can do it.
Get out.
- Oh, shit!
- Collin!
Collin!
Fucking hell!
I can't imagine how she feels.
So, how long before your father comes?
Shit. I can't get this thing to start.
Oh. That worked.
Local technique, mate.
Right, I've figured out
a way to get across.
We just saw that woman...
Well, how you gonna get across
without getting in the water?
I am getting in the water.
Neil...
I'm gonna swim across, real quiet.
I'm gonna tie a rope
from one of these trees
to one of those trees over there.
We'll suspend it
a few metres above the water.
We all climb across. Piece of piss.
We just saw crocodiles jump
four feet out of the water today.
- My wife won't be able to cross.
- She's gonna have to, mate.
But... can we come back with help?
By the time we get back, you know,
this island's not gonna be here.
Oh, great!
Fucking brilliant!
Oi, your wife will be fine.
We will all be fine.
But we have to move right now
before it comes back.
What makes you so sure
it's going to come back?
Look around you, champ.
We are still in its territory
and it doesn't like it.
Plus he's probably already tagged us,
Katie, so...
- Wh-what?
- Tagged us?
They tag you as a food supply.
They don't stop.
It's like a vicious dog who's guarding
a piece of meat in its backyard.
Jesus!
Then they take you back to the place
where it stores its kills and...
Under a log or a burrow somewhere.
Like I said, now is the best time to move
because the fucker is busy.
Listen, Neil...
Look, the tide's rising.
We've got no choice.
We go now, we have a chance,
or later...
You figure it out.
- You want a hand, do you?
- Yeah.
My God.
We're going to tie a rope
from the island trees to the shore.
Plan is to climb across.
Mum?
You'll be able to cross fine. Don't worry.
Of course I will, sweetheart.
Course I will.
Neil! Neil?
I don't think this is a good idea.
-Someone's got to cross.
-You don't have to do this.
OK, well, what do we do?
I think...
I'm not doing this to prove anything.
It's just...
I mean, you wanna go home, don't you?
- Yeah, of course.
- Right.
Here. Hold this.
Why don't you tie it around your waist?
I'll feed it out to you.
You'd better feed it out fucking fast, mate.
- You're not as stupid as you look.
- Yeah, hopefully you're not either.
Keep away from the water.
Right, here's one.
Here's another one.
Why do you think it's doing this?
Heard stories of 'em getting territorial,
but... people just keep going
and they leave 'em alone.
Us being here?
That's gonna be driving him crazy.
He's gonna feel as if we're moving in.
Yeah, but this is still pretty weird, right?
Ready?
OK, we're right?
Can I go first?
I just wanna get home.
Oh, thank God!
He's done it.
- Alright!
- Good work.
I don't know
if I can hold on that long.
Alright, turn around. Both your knees up.
OK, let's go. Up you go.
Russell, can you get her up
on the rope?
There you go.
Watch your foot.
Alright, Mary-Ellen.
- Grab the rope.
- You'll be right.
Now wrap your legs around the rope
and then it's just like I told you -
one hand in front of the other
and you'll be over there in no time.
That's it. There you go.
- That's it.
- It's doing well.
- Really good.
- Come on!
There you go. You right?
That's good.
We're gonna have you outta here
in no time. That's it.
Simon, if you see
the slightest move, mate, you tell us.
Liz? I'm gonna take Sherry across.
OK? I'll be straight back for you.
We'll be absolutely fine.
It's alright, love.
That's it. That's great.
You're across the water right now,
so I just want you to keep breathing...
- Can you see anything?
- Stay relaxed.
Russell, shut the fuck up.
We'll be fine. We'll all be fine.
We'll all be fine.
Just keep going.
You're almost there.
Just keep breathing.
That's it.
Keep... keep breathing.
It's alright, love. Just take your time.
It's not alright.
I can't hold on.
I have to stop.
It's alright, Mary-Ellen.
You're gonna be fine.
Just keep breathing.
- You're gonna be fine.
- What's she doing? She's stopping.
She'll get us all killed if she doesn't hurry.
I can't! I can't! I can't!
Come on.
You're doing fine.
I can't hold on.
Is she right?
Oh, she...she's frozen.
Sherry, Sherry, Sherry. Come on.
We're going. We're going.
- I can't hold on!
- Wait a minute.
- Don't you fucking touch me!
- Oi! Oi! Come on!
Don't you fucking
come anywhere near me!
- You fuck off!
- Calm down, mate.
Don't you put her on that rope.
Fuckhead,
the rope won't take three people OK?
I am not going to let that woman
endanger the lives of my wife
and my child!
Slow down and think about
what you're doing.
- Why don't you fuck off?!
- Get down!
- Jesus Christ. Get him down!
- Stay away! Stay away from me!
Get down now!
Fucking don't do that, you stupid fucker.
- Alright, Sherry. I'm here.
- Are you crazy? Get off the rope!
- There shouldn't be three people...
- We know that, mate!
Bloody English idiot.
Keep going, Sher. It's alright. I'm here.
Just... We're right behind you, Sher.
- Just hold on.
- Something just moved.
Mary-Ellen, Allen and Sherry
are on the rope behind you.
It's alright. I'm here.
You'll be across in no time.
Just move, Mary Ellen!
There's two people behind you. Move!
OK, Sher. I'm here. I'm right behind you.
Right behind you, Sher. Keep going.
She's not moving.
For Christ's sake, move!
I can't.
- You can!
- Come on.
Neil, she's frozen. Get her moving!
Keep go...
Neil, she's freaked. Get her moving!
Move!
Move, for God's sake! Move!
Neil?
- Neil, come on!
- Neil?!
- What's happening?
- Oh, shit!
Move! Move!
No, Sher! No, Sher! No...
Oh! Oh!
- Just hold on tight.
- Daddy!
- Oh, God!
- Move! Move!
Do something! Do something!
Don't let go. Keep going!
Come on. Swim!
Oh, my God!
You alright? You alright?
Oh, fuck.
Kate, get back from the water.
No.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Daddy!
No!
Oh! Oh, my God!
It can't be long now.
Someone will find us soon.
It'll be alright.
Where are you, you... bastards?
Sorry. Does that hurt?
No. It's... It's fine.
I just... I think... I think I sprained it.
Oh, God!
- How are they?
- Um...Sherry's in... in shock.
And Elizabeth's not doing very well.
She needs to...take her medication.
Where is it?
She...
She left it on the back of the boat,
so its probably floated away.
But there's painkillers
in the, uh...the first aid kit.
They might not come till the morning.
If I hadn't brought us here,
none of this would have happened.
It's not your fault. It's not your fault.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry. Come here.
- Sorry.
- Come on, it's OK.
It's not your fault. No giving up yet, OK?
Alright? Don't give up.
Don't give up. It's OK.
OK.
There. That's better.
Now let's go find this first aid kit.
Where the fuck is it?
We're dealing with an animal, right?
I mean, at the end of the day,
it's just a stupid animal.
So, I was thinking, maybe
we could make some sort of a trap
and have enough time to swim across.
Jesus, mate.
The only way
we're gonna get off this bloody island
is if someone turns up
with a rather large boat, you know?
I just don't think that's gonna happen.
Do you?
I know that's not gonna happen
but the tide is moving in quick
and people are falling apart.
We've got to do something now.
Bait. We don't have any bait either.
I know we don't have bait.
If we could somehow hook the fucker
on this line with the anchor
and keep it still for just a little bit...
We can use one of the lifejackets
to help keep it afloat.
Right. So, that's great. You wanna
go fishing? Oh, that's nice.
Well, the results are in, Peter,
and you're a fucking genius.
-Shut the fuck up, Simon.
-Well, mate, I'm sorry.
Am I the only one who's noticed
what's going on here?
I mean, there's an animal out there
and it's... it's hunting us.
I mean, why is it still after us?
I dunno.
And it's... it's big.
You know, and it's like... it's like
a fucking steam train with teeth
and...and...and numbnuts here
thinks that we're gonna hold it back
with that bit of dental floss.
Just shut the fuck up, OK?
How much time do we have?
- Um, maybe half an hour. At most.
- We've got a half an hour, OK?
So we can either try and trap this thing
and... and keep it still
for long enough for us to get across,
or we can sit here on our asses
and in a half a fucking hour,
we'll be up to our necks in it.
Fucking Americans.
Yeah. Righto, mate. I'm with ya. Alright?
We haven't got any bait.
Yes.
No.
- No.
- No. I can't.
- Yes, you can.
- I can't!
- I have spent years fighting...
- I said no.
..battling for one more year, one
more moment of knowing my daughter.
I can't.
- I haven't come this far...
- No.
..to go down in some pile of mud
in the middle of nowhere
because you're not prepared
to make a sacrifice.
I'm not gonna let my daughter die.
Oh, my God.
Wait. Wait.
What the fuck's he doing?
They'll eat anything, right?
Hey?
When we swim, you're to go first.
You're not to try to help me.
But how are you going to cross?
One of the others is going to help you.
Well, what about you?
I'll be fine, darling. Let's just get you safe.
Oh, my.
What do you reckon?
Oh, shit.
Need some help with that?
What?
Never mind.
Here, give it to me.
- You're good at that.
- Yeah.
28 years old and I can tie a knot.
Never been anywhere.
Yeah, well, travelling's overrated.
Trust me.
Here we go.
- Who's gonna work the trap?
- Well, doesn't it just sit there?
Crocs sense vibration in the water
through their skin.
We need to keep the bait moving
so it thinks it's alive,
otherwise it won't go for it.
- I'll do it.
- No. You can't with your hand. I'll do it.
- Have you done much fishing?
- Yeah. Once, when I was six.
Well, nothing's changed.
You watch the rope
and the minute you see
that life preserver move at all,
you let us know
and then get the hell outta here, alright?
- I got it.
- And... and then what?
Wait for it to take the bait,
then we head for the other side.
Come on, let's go. Come on.
You sure you wanna be
the last one across?
No. Not really.
Righto.
OK, put that on.
It's getting higher.
This isn't gonna work, is it?
If it doesn't, we're gonna
have to make a dash for it.
So we'll stick together,
swim across as fast as we can.
OK.
I'm, er... I'm... I'm really sorry
about your husband.
I... I can't imagine
what it must be like to, er...
..to not have a chance to say goodbye.
I've been saying goodbye
for the past three and a half years.
We're getting ready to leave. Um...
I can't swim.
I'm not putting anyone else's life at risk.
We...
If I thought there was good reason -
a year, even - I would.
But there's not, so please
don't make this any harder than it is.
Put this on
or you will be putting a life at risk.
'Cause l... I'm not gonna
leave you here, OK?
And you...you got a really good kid there.
Come on, you fuck.
Come on. I've got you.
I love you.
Crocs like the scent of dogs.
He should cross last.
OK.
Promise me you'll take care of him.
Promise.
Alright.
Kate?
- Do you still...
- Pete!
- Go. Go! Get 'em outta here.
- Oh, shit.
Come on, let's go! Let's go!
Come on, it's on!
- OK.
- Get 'em in, mate.
Yeah, right. You just get in there.
Don't worry about your mum.
And swim like hell!
Go. Get in there and go.
That's it. Go.
Go. Swim! Swim!
Don't worry. I've got you.
- Swim!
- Hurry! It's not gonna hold!
Kate, move it!
Come on! Hurry! Go!
- You're OK, Sherry. Go!
- That's it! Go!
Move!
Kate, you gotta move it!
It's not gonna hold!
Mum!
- Can you see Sherry?
- She's there.
Kate! Kate!
Kate, it's loose!
I don't know where it is. Swim! Swim!
Sherry!
Wait!
Go after them!
Head upriver. We'll meet you there. Go!
- OK.
- Go!
We'll catch up with you.
Get outta here. Go! Go!
Kate!
Kate! Kate!
Kate.
Kate!
Russell!
Simon, wait up!
Simon!
Kevin, come here.
Kevin, come here, you little shit!
Kevin.
Kevin?
Kevin. Come here, boy.
Kevin. Come on.
Arggh!
Jesus.
Kevin.
Kevin!
Kevin, come here.
I said come here, you little shit.
Kevin!
Kevin! Kevin, get back here!
No, no! No!
No! Get out of here!
No!
Come on, you fuck! Come on!
No.
No!
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Oh, fuck.
Arrgh!
Thanks.
Hey.
What did you think of the tour?
I was thinking I'm probably gonna
spend a little more time at home.
Thanks.
* Never smile at a crocodile
* No, you can't get friendly
with a crocodile
* Don't be taken in
by his welcome grin
* He's imagining how well you'd fit
within his skin
* Never smile at a crocodile
* Never dip your hat
and stop to talk a while
* Never run
Walk away
* Say goodnight, not good day
* Clear the aisle
and never smile at Mr Crocodile
* You may very well be well-bred
* Lots of etiquette in your head
* But there's always
some special case
* Time or place
* To forget etiquette
* For instance
* If you meet a sad crocodile
* Who looks sad and lonely and mild
* He's just hungry
That you can bet
* It's the time to forget etiquette
* Be careful
* Never smile at a crocodile
* No, you can't get friendly
with a crocodile
* Don't be taken in
by his welcome grin
* He's imagining how well you'd fit
within his skin
* Never smile at a crocodile
* Never dip your hat
and stop to talk a while
* Don't be rude
Never mock
* Throw a kiss, not a rock
* Clear the aisle
and never smile at Mr Crocodile. *