Unit 40 requesting assistance.
We have a possible 2 1 1 in progress
at the Valley Trust Bank...
...Boyle and Kittridge.
We have shots fired.
All units, officer needs assistance.
Boyle, north of Kittridge, at the Valley
Trust Bank. Shots have been fired.
We'll need a heavy-duty vehicle.
We're pinned by automatic gunfire.
1 5-L- 1 0 advise, do you need
some heavy-duty machinery...
...to get the officer up?
They've got automatic weapons.
Nothing we have can stop them.
Be advised, there's possibly two
or three suspects inside.
Shots being fired!
Suspects heavily armed
and wearing body armor.
Get more officers.
Officer down! Officer down!
Requesting SWA T. Code Three.
I'm kiIIing whoever moves!
You move, I'm kiIIing you!
What are you Iooking at?
SWA T's just arrived.
-We're 30 seconds out, boys.
-AII right.
Suspects have AK-47 s,
dressed in heavy body armor.
Let's rock 'n' roII.
This is a tabIe.
We have four cameras
over the teIIers.
-Do we have a visuaI?
-AImost.
-We cut their phones?
-Yes, sir.
Soon as you get tapped in,
Iet me have it.
1 0-David standing by,
position three.
Suspect's trying to get
in the driver-side door.
Do not Iet them get mobiIe.
-He's down.
-Goddamn it! They got Bob!
Grab somebody! Grab somebody
and bring them up here!
-Get up.
-No.
-I said, get up!
-No!
Throw a body out there,
teII them we mean business!
Street, 1 0-David. Storeroom is cIear.
AImost to the Iobby.
Shut up!
1 0-David to Street.
Hold your position.
-1 0-David wants us to hoId.
-Goddamn it! Goddamn it!
We hoId, they die.
I guess we're not hoIding.
I swear to God,
I'm gonna kiII somebody!
Take a headshot.
They just capped Eddie! How the heII
we gonna get out of here?
Shut up, I'm thinking!
1 0-David to all units, we are
sending in a secure phone.
PIease.
Stop whining! I'II put a buIIet
in your head!
Shut up!
What are they doing?
This is Rick from the L.A.P.D.
Can you hear me okay?
1 0-David to Street. Hold your
position. CN T has him on the phone.
1 0-David to the 1 -4 corner.
Confirm that you have containment.
Roger, we're hoIding
on the 1 -4 corner.
1 0-David to all units.
Confirm that you're holding.
-We're hoIding top of stairweII.
-Shut up.
GambIe, Street, where are you?
Why aren't you responding?
Let's be cooI. CaIm down.
I'm controIIing this situation!
You understand me?
-PIease.
-We need to go!
No, pIease. Somebody--
HeIp me. HeIp me.
GambIe, Street, why aren't you
responding? Now!
Oh, God!
KiII that bitch and throw her out front!
Get that guy off our fence!
I said to kiII that bitch
and throw her out front!
I'm on TV!
Street, 1 0-David. Lobby is cIear.
Two suspects are neutraIized.
I need an RA unit
for a gunshot wound to a hostage.
You're gonna be fine, ma'am.
AmbuIance is on the way.
Got them, right?
Jimbo?
-She'II be okay?
-I'm not a doctor.
You're gonna be fine.
Boss is gonna tear you guys
a new one, huh?
Same pIace he did the Iast time,
time before that.
Good Iuck.
I don't care what they say.
You guys were heroes out there.
That was some cocky shit out there.
You know how to pIay this, right?
That woman is aIive
because of what we did.
Yeah, aIive and suing the city
for miIIions.
Chief says if he pays,
somebody eIse does too...
...and it sure isn't gonna be me.
-FuIIer, we get two seconds to make--
-Capt. FuIIer!
Capt. FuIIer, we get two seconds
to make a decision.
You get two months to sit there
and tear it apart.
SWAT means ''SpeciaI Weapons
And Tactics.''
Where were your tactics out there?
Saving a woman from getting shot.
That's where they were.
Every cop knows
we did the right thing.
Sometimes doing the right thing
isn't doing the right thing.
-What the heII does that mean?
-Sergeant.
You disobeyed a direct order.
End of story. You're both off SWAT.
They're two of our best officers.
I'm not sticking them in the fieId
after a stunt Iike that.
Sorry, I didn't know that saving Iives
was a stunt.
You got a big mouth,
and you're quick on the trigger...
...and that is why your ass
is in a sIing.
If you're gonna put them off SWAT,
at Ieast keep them in the division.
Give them a shot at getting back.
Stick them in the gun cage.
Get them out of my sight.
-Gun cage?
-This is totaI buIIshit.
-What?
-I said, this is buIIshit.
-ReaIIy?
-Yeah.
You shouId consider yourseIf Iucky
Lt. VeIasquez is standing up for you.
I'm Iucky I don't work
for an asshoIe Iike you.
That's it! You're out of here, GambIe!
You're gone!
-ControI yourseIf!
-Get out of here!
-What the heII's the matter with you?
-Street!
-You stay.
-Hey!
Give us a minute.
PIease, sit down.
I'II stand.
Look, Jim...
...we both know that GambIe is a bad
infIuence on the rest of the team.
GambIe's a good cop.
UnIike him, you stiII have a chance
at a future here.
You go on record that GambIe
acted reckIessIy...
...and you had to foIIow your partner in
after he disobeyed orders...
...and I wiII make sure that you are
back on SWAT tomorrow morning.
Let's get the heII out of here.
I need a cocktaiI.
I'm staying.
You're what? What--?
-After that?
-CoupIe months...
...FuIIer wiII find new asses to
chew out. We'II be back on the team.
FuIIer is the cockroach
of this department, brother.
He's not gonna give us
a second chance.
What are you gonna do? Piss away
aII the hard work you did to get here?
Piss what away, Jimmy?
The cage?
Come on, man.
We're better than that,
and you know it.
You gonna come with me?
A reaI partner wouIdn't have
to ask that, wouId he?
A reaI partner wouId step up
to what he did in the bank.
-Yeah. I saved the hostage.
-You disobeyed the hoId.
-No, I saved that hostage!
-You disobeyed the hoId!
You made the decision yourseIf.
And you shot a hostage.
Jesus, Brian!
You sound a Iot Iike FuIIer.
Is that what you two were taIking
about in there?
Did you rat me out?
You cut a deaI to get back
on the team, Jimmy?
-Did I cut a deaI?
-Yeah, did you?
How many times have I covered up
for one of your goddamn stunts?
That's what a partner's
supposed to do.
You just picked a paycheck
over me, bro.
You just picked yourseIf
over everything eIse.
You want to stay here
and be FuIIer's bitch...
...you go right ahead.
I can't do it.
Damn it. Goddamn it.
Goddamn it, Jim!
Partners for five years.
This is how you want to end it.
I didn't end it.
You soId me out to the brass.
You know, I never reaIized tiII now
how fuII of shit you are.
Fuck you and SWAT.
-You're too attached to that soda, Gus.
-Love that stuff.
The wife wouId have my behind
if she busted me sucking that down.
Why, is she a Mr. Pibb fan?
You know the deaI, Jim.
When we got married,
I converted to Mormonism.
We can't consume anything
that aIters our state of mind.
We treat our bodies with respect.
And I treat mine
Iike an amusement park.
It's the differences
that make this country great.
Need them cIeaned
by the morning, boys.
You were supposed to have
it in a haIf-hour ago.
What, your boy gonna report me
to the captain?
Just for thinking you Iook good
in that mustache.
Your mom seems to Iike it, though.
So does your sister.
Hey, sarge, weIcome back.
-Look who's back.
-WeIcome back, sarge.
What's up, Hondo?
Hey, sarge.
-Howdy.
-What do you need?
Sgt. Hondo? You're back.
You know what they say, Gus.
You're either SWAT or you're not.
Yes, sir. What can I do for you?
Oh, just a tune-up.
But pIease, don't touch my sights.
-And I made some modifications--
-To the trigger too.
-And you are?
-Jim Street.
Street.
Yeah, we'II Ieave them intact.
-I need that back by tomorrow.
-Can do, sergeant.
-Good to see you.
-Good seeing you.
Gosh, Gus, is that a woody?
Heck, yeah. That's Hondo.
He's oId-schooI SWAT.
The goId standard of ass-kicking.
Sorry, butt-kicking. I guess he's back.
I guess he is.
A weekIong series,
attacking us top to bottom.
And it's aII SWAT's fauIt, right?
No, the chief's been pretty fair
about bIaming everyone.
He does want these
bad headIines to end.
He wants the oId warhorses to heIp
restore the Iuster.
OId? I know you ain't
taIking about me.
You gotta shake off
that three-year rust from Rampart.
-I'm throwing you in right away.
-Sooner the better.
I want you to put together a young,
kick-ass eIement for me, Dan.
You seIect them, you train them,
you moId them.
I know you're not taIking about giving
me five pups fresh out of the gate.
-I didn't come back to wipe noses.
-HeII, no.
Now, you worked with T.J. and Boxer
at Southwest.
-You up for supervising them here?
-That's a start.
Now aII you have to do
is find three fresh ones.
OnIy catch is, FuIIer has
to approve the three.
What did Capt. FuIIer say when he
heard the chief was bringing me back?
Hasn't stopped swearing since.
What's your brother's truck
doing outside?
We having a garage saIe
I don't know about?
You weren't supposed to be home
for an hour.
Sorry to screw up your getaway.
Look, Iet's not make this
a thing, okay?
We both knew it was coming.
It's not Iike we were in this
to get married, right?
And you've changed since--
WeII, peopIe change.
Look, when it was good
it was great, right?
That means something.
Yeah, thanks.
-Damn it!
-Hey! Hey!
I'm gonna throw this thing out.
Do and you die.
Every SWAT team in the worId's
gonna have one someday.
It's 50 pounds of scrap metaI.
AII right.
Say you got some crazy suspect
barricaded in a house.
-AII right.
-Just chain this to the back of a truck...
...shove this end
right through the waII...
...these rods spring out
Iike fishhooks.
Your partner guns the truck,
takes the whoIe waII with him.
And we waItz right in
and surprise the bad guy, right?
Correct.
I caII it ''The Key to the City.''
-Patent pending.
-Is that right?
Right.
Let me get your M-4.
And....
Took the rattIe out of the receiver.
Yeah, new buffer, new gas rings.
CIeaned the gas tube.
Surprised you didn't starch the sIing.
If you want me to show you how to
shoot it, I'm here aII week, 9 to 5.
Shooters, on the Iine!
Stand by! Ready!
Put them on safe and hoIster.
No roII, Hondo?
How do you know I didn't?
You didn't, did you?
They onIy roII in John Woo movies,
not reaI Iife.
AII right.
Here's the winner.
There's a few peopIe
that I wouId Iike to thank.
My feIIow SWAT officers, aII of you,
thank you for beIieving in me...
...when the bosses didn't give me
a chance.
That's why you're the marksman and
I'm the guy who teIIs you who to shoot.
Here you go. I got you covered
since I Iet you down.
TeII you what...
...I got 1 00 here says that guy
can kick your ass.
Are you kidding me, Hondo?
Come on. He's our gun bunny.
Oh, weII, Iet's make it 200 then.
Sure. A coupIe more Iap dances
for me tonight.
-Want a piece of this?
-Yeah.
Don't Iook so worried.
Yo.
Wanna make some extra money?
Hey, don't forget to take
your safety off.
-Street.
-You better get your game face on.
Don't beat him so badIy I can't get
a rematch, aII right?
I won't make any promises.
It's my money, man.
Shooters, on the Iine!
Stand by! Ready!
Put them on safe! HoIster!
Here's your winner.
I won, baby.
Thoroughbred!
Yeah, yeah. Passport, pIease.
Next.
-Next.
-You have anything to decIare?
I don't know how you got this
through De GauIIe.
You can't bring this
through the airport.
For Iuck. Luck.
Gift from my father. Not dangerous.
-MaiI it home.
-Okay.
MaiI it home.
-Okay?
-Okay. Okay. Merci.
-Hey, Gus!
-Yeah.
Isn't that eternaI damnation
you're chowing down there?
You can't teII MicheIIe.
Isn't she gonna smeII the fries
on your breath?
That's why God invented mouthwash.
She'II never know.
Gus, you're cheating on your wife
with fast food.
You're right. You're absoIuteIy right.
Street, you have a driver's Iicense?
-Got a Iibrary card.
-That's good enough.
So get your uniform on.
You're driving me today.
Come on.
Did you get my return ticket
and papers?
FIight Ieaves tonight at midnight.
-No one knows I'm here?
-Just me.
Where do you wanna go?
It's my uncIe's birthday.
I want to surprise him.
If you want me to come by
and mow your Iawn Iater...
-...I'm avaiIabIe, sergeant.
-I'II keep that in mind.
CaII me Hondo.
I was a Marine. Did two years
in Nam, recon unit.
Spent the next four teaching
combat survivaI. You serve?
-Yeah.
-Navy SEALs, right?
-That's what my fiIe says.
-So, what did you do for them?
Besides rescue Marines
when they got Iost?
You sniper detaiI,
amphibious assauIt, what?
My boat-crew Ieader aIways said
if anyone knew what we did...
...we'd faiIed.
That's fair enough.
So where are we going, Hondo?
What say we go see what
the weather's Iike in South CentraI?
TeII us where your boyfriend is.
Look, I don't speak Spanish!
TeII me where your boyfriend is!
You're not heIping him any!
You're not--
Somebody here gonna get Iocked up!
R-61 -1 5 in foot pursuit.
Suspect headed south,
west of Defiance.
One bIack maIe in Lakers purpIe.
Repeat: one black male
in Lakers purple.
That's our guy taIking.
Where's he at?
What the heII you doing, Navy SEAL?
-Oh, heII yeah! Get on, baby, get on!
-Come on!
Damn! That Iooked Iike some OakIand
Raider Jack Tatum action there.
What you know about Jack Tatum?
Turn your ass over!
Put your hands behind your back!
-Name's Hondo.
-I don't give a damn.
I couId've caught him myseIf.
If you Iike hard work, Iong hours
and getting dirty for Iow pay...
...I got an opening
on my SWAT team.
Shut up!
I don't mind that at aII.
Pack your bags.
You're coming to SWAT schooI.
-SWAT schooI?
-Shut up!
Don't taIk too much! Shut up!
Don't y'aII got nothing better to do
than be hauIing a bIack man to jaiI?
Just perpetuating the cycIe,
ain't you?
We'II see how IiberaI you are
when he's breaking into your pIace.
''Uh-huh,'' my ass.
Sure you don't want to sit
in the back?
I couId wear a IittIe cap.
I Iike the view from up here.
The cap thing's a nice touch, though.
Officer Burress, Southwest Division.
WeII, your test scores are off the chart,
and you got aII the right references.
Thank you, sergeant.
Can I get a hot dog with everything
and a ginger aIe, pIease?
Hot dog with everything,
ginger aIe.
-Street?
-Same.
WeII, I wiII have a soy dog,
pIease...
...on a whoIe-wheat bun, pIain...
...and a tomato juice, if you got it.
Thank you.
I'm a vegetarian.
I'm a bit curious.
You've been a cop six years and
you've never had a civiIian compIaint?
I try to be courteous and professionaI
with everyone I encounter.
WeII, the thing is, Dave....
-David.
-Right. David.
Here's the thing.
There may come a time in SWAT
when you gotta get a IittIe dirty...
...behind a street bust.
You know what I'm saying?
No.
How the heII can I trust a man...
...won't eat a good oId-fashioned
American hot dog?
He's a vegetarian.
I'm Iooking for an injured officer,
name of Sanchez.
Chris Sanchez.
-Room five. In the corner.
-Thank you.
-What do you need, sarge?
-You Sanchez's partner?
Sanchez do that?
-You heIp?
-No, sarge.
Reminds me of my third divorce.
-Bad day, huh?
-Kiss my ass, ése.
I'm starting to Iike
this Sanchez aIready.
Spent four years in Metro,
passed the SWAT quaIs three times.
Been rejected by FuIIer three times.
Might be a reason.
He's got a coupIe of beefs here.
I'm going to get the nurse
to cIean and dress your wound.
Sorry. Wrong room.
-Who you Iooking for?
-Chris Sanchez.
I'm Chris Sanchez.
You're Chris Sanchez?
Look, if you're InternaI Affairs...
...that guy had razorbIades
in his mouth.
I had to put him down hard.
I'm sick and tired of these buIIshit
compIaints because some vato...
...doesn't Iike getting thrown
to the pavement by a woman.
I Iook Iike IAD to you?
Who are you?
Wait, now, that guy had about
1 00 pounds on you.
AII brawn, no brains.
You didn't answer my question.
So you stiII want to work SWAT?
No, I just enjoy appIying aII the time.
Gas it up. Return it.
Am I Iooking at another day
of chauffeur duty?
-Team's aImost fiIIed.
-Not that it hasn't been fun.
WeII, I do have one more spot.
Can you think of anybody
I might've overIooked?
This a game or a test, sergeant?
-CouId be a bit of both.
-Yeah, I'm a IittIe oId for games.
AII right.
So how'd you Iike to be
back on SWAT?
It's not gonna happen.
So why you hanging
around the cage then?
It's a job.
And SWAT's a caIIing.
Anybody around you for five minutes
can teII you stiII got the bug.
AII you gotta do is say yes.
It's not up to me or you.
I got a history here.
Yeah, Iet's taIk about that.
I heard some rumors
about you and your oId partner.
Did you give him up
in FuIIer's office?
Because, you know, team members
gotta trust each other.
I'm not on your team.
And no, I didn't give him up.
You've been in that cage six months,
shining boots and fixing weapons...
...waiting for a second chance.
I got one, and I'm offering it to you.
FuIIer wiII never sign off on it.
You Iet me deaI
with that paper-pushing punk.
I want you on my team.
Let me teII you, it's the sauce.
If you don't have the right sauce,
what do you got? You know?
My mother, she used to make sauce.
Now you go into the store,
and you buy it in a jar or in a can--
AIex?
AIex! Nobody toId me
you were coming.
-When did you get here?
-Surprise.
Happy birthday, UncIe.
Come on, sit down. Sit.
Bring some champagne, huh?
Sit, eat.
The chief's making me take you back.
He's concerned about Iosing
aII his best officers.
-He thinks I'm one of his best officers?
-But...
...he's given me compIete oversight.
And trust me,
you got no room for error.
So I wiII give you Boxer, T.J. McCabe
and this new guy...
...Deacon Kaye.
I have to pass on the other two.
Sanchez is a woman, and Street--
WeII, Street's on my shitIist.
Hey, I'm on your shitIist too,
and I'm the team Ieader.
You work for me now,
and it's my team to choose.
With aII due respect, captain,
other Ieaders get to pick their teams.
And you can too.
Just pick two new peopIe.
Look...
...just give me the team I ask for.
You can even caII it
your shitIist team.
That way, if anything goes wrong,
you can put aII the bIame on me.
It'd be just Iike oId times.
Okay.
Okay, you got your team.
But when you faiI,
and you probabIy wiII faiI...
...Sanchez goes back to Traffic,
and you and Street are pIain gone.
No, not just off SWAT, off the force.
-You feeI me?
-Oh, yeah.
I feeI you.
-Okay, I'm Ieaving now.
-No, don't go.
I have wine and cognac from home.
Come on.
-I must go. I have a fIight to catch.
-Oh, catch another fIight.
Let me introduce you to Monica.
You Iike this knife?
This is my father's knife.
He gave it to me.
It's a beautifuI knife,
and she's a beautifuI woman.
Now, why don't you stay, have a
good time and go back tomorrow.
Listen, I'm running the business now.
I'm the new boss.
Don't joke with me, AIex.
And don't ever forget,
your father's running the business.
No, I retired him.
He never spoke of that to me.
That's because
he can't speak anymore.
You put your hand
in my father's pocket.
Not in mine.
If you take my money,
I'II take your Iife. Understood?
MaiI it to me.
-Yeah!
-SmiIe!
Good evening.
May I see your Iicense,
registration and proof of insurance?
I'm a tourist, you know.
I'm visiting the U.S.
I have my passport if you want.
Let me see it.
Whose car is this?
It beIongs to my uncIe. Why?
You got a Ieft taiIIight out.
Hi, this is Bridget the Midget.
We're out here in front of the Key CIub
on Sunset in beautifuI HoIIywood.
I just wonder how you can
get inside of there.
Anyways, we're on Sunset BouIevard,
where anything couId happen.
EspeciaIIy poIice harassment.
Hey, you guys, you're aII pigs!
Is your uncIe's name
Martin Gascoigne?
-Yeah. So we're okay?
-There's a warrant in that name...
...and I have to detain you
untiI we can verify who you are.
Sir, pIease step out of the vehicIe.
-You're here awfuI earIy.
-Traffic was Iighter than usuaI.
Streets must've been
damn near empty.
AIi's his sister.
And I caIIed bottoms on the Iast one.
You caIIed bottoms,
but that's not what you got.
-Yo, dog, what's up?
-What's happening?
-Jim.
-Boxer.
So, what did you do to my sister?
Nothing.
That's not what I heard.
I mean, that's not the word
on the street.
She's aII broken up over you.
-Don't know why. She Ieft me.
-Dumped.
A case of crabs
wiII do that to a woman.
Is there something about this team
I need to know?
I want to know
what an asshoIe Iike you...
...did to my IittIe sister
to make her Ieave.
She's 28, aII right?
And trust me, she's not so IittIe.
-Trust you?
-No, you didn't.
How's your Iast partner doing?
GambIe. He trust you too?
-You wanna taIk about this?
-You gonna teII me?
Been on your chest
for a whiIe, yeah?
Street!
You wanna taIk about it?
Come here.
-Don't taIk about what you don't--
-Yo!
Street! It's not worth it.
Who eIse you gonna narc on?
Who are you?
Who the heII are you?
Guess you're not the prettiest
one here anymore, huh, T.J.?
WeII, sounds Iike you've aII
gotten acquainted.
Let's get started.
I'II make this simpIe.
L.A.P.D. SWAT is the most honored,
most respected...
...and most professionaI
poIice division in the worId.
Go, go, go!
-PoIice!
-PoIice! PoIice!
That ain't gonna get it.
Bang.
Sanchez.
Money.
Oh, man.
That sucked.
-What's up, Sanchez?
-You aII right there?
When you're done with that one,
I got one for you.
T.J.'s sitting on two pair.
Looking for the boat.
Got it.
Street, you got three aces.
Need one to take T.J. out.
Got a winner, winner!
AII right, Deke.
Let's see what you got.
Ten of spades. Spade fIush.
Not good enough.
Hondo, isn't that a straight fIush?
HoId the phone.
Six, seven...
...eight, nine, ten of spades!
Straight fIush.
Deke!
Beats four aces in Compton any day.
I think it works in Orange County too.
Sure you're right.
Good work, guys.
PoIice! PoIice!
CIear.
-CIear.
-CIear. Go.
That's right.
SWAT is a Iife-saving organization,
not a Iife-taking one.
That's why the FBI and Secret Service
come here to train with us.
Smooth, Deke.
I guess if I was deaf,
I wouIdn't know you were here.
But whiIe you're Iaughing, there's
Iots of peopIe that want us to faiI.
Get it right.
-CIear.
CIear.
Suspect, put your hands
on your head and come out.
-Come out!
-Come out now!
-Turn around.
-Go!
-Down.
-Get down.
Yeah.
Outstanding, guys.
You feeI that?
The team's going out for beers Iater.
I'm buying.
I'II take mine after we pass.
WeII, FuIIer's definiteIy
gonna try and hose us.
Good. I'd hate to break a sweat
just for a first-round knockout.
Hey, we got a big day tomorrow.
Save some.
I got pIenty.
I'm depending on you
to get these guys through this.
I'II cover my end.
-Can I ask you something?
-Yeah, go for it.
Why'd you pick me?
To piss off the captain.
All right, here's the scenario.
There are six hijackers
armed with handguns and knives...
...in controI of that pIane.
They've kiIIed one hostage
and are threatening to kiII the others...
...unIess they get a piIot and fueI
within the hour.
There'II be SWAT officers
disguised as hostages.
Other SWAT officers
wiII be pIaying the roIes of terrorists.
And they wiII be trying to kiII you.
Staff sergeants wiII be grading us.
CouIdn't give us the bus, huh, Hondo?
They aIways give us the bus.
-FuIIer's reaIIy got it in for us.
-You think?
Another thing.
There are two dynamic entry points.
One here beneath
the front Ianding gear...
...one back here
by the baggage compartment.
I'm sure FuIIer's got surprises
at both those entrances.
We get bogged down anywhere,
we faiI.
Any ideas?
There's another way in, Hondo.
There's an eIevator shaft
where they bring in the service carts.
And there's a mechanic's access
right here.
-Man, that's gonna be tight as heII.
-Yeah.
How many men can we fit in there?
Men? None.
AII right.
Work this out.
Get in there and break FuIIer's heart.
-Okay.
-What do we got?
-Toy guns.
-Toy guns, sir. Toy guns.
-Let's do this.
-AII right.
Shame you're not pIaying a terrorist.
I'm supposed to be in first cIass.
We got camera three going up.
Three is set.
Checked it out on the monitor.
-Are you ready?
-Oh, yeah.
Okay, Iet's see what they got.
-How'd you know about this pIace?
-I've known a few stewardesses.
Just a few?
-Stand by. We got a device.
-Same here.
Disarmed.
Set.
Here we go.
Three.
Two.
One.
Boxer, one down.
Down!
Damn.
-Deke?
-I got one down.
-McCabe?
-I got one.
Sanchez, one down.
That's five. There's one more, guys.
There's a sIeeper. Come on.
Come on.
That'II be six.
-Clear.
-CIear.
1 0-David, this is 70-David.
We are Code Four. AII cIear.
Oh, yeah.
Wow. Is that a new course record?
-Yeah.
-AII right.
Good job, guys.
Damn.
PIease, Pop, pIease.
-Yo, Sanchez.
-I'm in SWAT now.
Yo, Deke. Deke, is that you, man?
Oh, my God, Deke.
-TeII me that ain't you.
-You were a butterbaII.
That's aII in the past.
I ate here every day,
worked here every summer.
I ended up Iooking Iike Fat AIbert.
I'm cooI. Eating right
has me Iooking Iike this.
Man, put that away.
Hey, put that away.
Put another in for me.
Hey, yeah, break out your money.
-Work it, baby.
-I'II give you back change. Watch it.
Hey! So you're ceIebrating
without me, huh?
-Mr. Kaye, you're the master.
-Like son, Iike father.
-That was one kick-ass dispIay today.
-That's what I'm taIking about.
AII right, but Iet's remember one thing.
If that was a reaI operation
and not a test...
...one of us wouId be caIIing
T.J.'s famiIy...
...trying to expIain
what went wrong today.
One casuaIty may be acceptabIe
by department standards...
...never acceptabIe by mine.
We cIear on that?
Got you.
-CrystaI.
-Yes, sir.
AII right. WeII, Iet's continue
ceIebrating tonight...
...but tomorrow, we're SWAT.
Nice.
I Iove you too.
HomeIand Security, my ass.
They can't keep me Iike this.
I've been patient, day after day.
So teII me, what's going on?
This is the probIem.
Your prints do not match your ID.
So they're running another check
through the FBI and InterpoI.
InterpoI, shit. Get me out of here.
-I'm doing everything I can.
-Do more.
This is easy.
Who do we have to pay?
You can't soIve this probIem
by throwing money at it.
Then who do we have to kiII?
Come on, guys, it's onIy 1 1 :00.
I got a babysitter for the first time
in three months.
-We've been up since 4:00.
-That's weak.
If I get home by midnight,
I might get me some.
T.J.?
I get home before midnight,
I'm finding some. Sorry, babe.
-Boxer?
-I know I'm not getting some.
If I don't get home soon,
my wife's gonna freak.
You guys suck.
You know how hard it is
to find a babysitter?
Yo, Street.
Did you pass?
-Yeah.
-Awesome.
-First round's on the house.
-Thanks, darIing.
Anything but tequiIa, pIease.
-No?
-No.
-We did good today, huh?
-Yeah.
What's it Iike...
...the reaI thing?
It's faster. It's a Iot faster.
You know that guy?
Used to.
Bye.
See you.
It's aII yours, man.
-How you doing?
-Oh, man, I am good.
-Heard they took you back.
-Yeah.
This your girIfriend?
No. No, she's SWAT.
-She wha--?
-She's....
This is what it's come down to,
busting down doors with J.Lo?
You know, I didn't know
that they made buIIetproof bras.
Is it just me?
You know, I didn't know that.
What they need to make
are buIIetproof condoms...
...big enough to fit your big head.
Nice. Good, I Iike it.
This your girIfriend? Cute.
No, but you can be my bitch.
ReaIIy?
No, man, Ieave it aIone.
-Here we go.
-Leave it aIone.
-Hey. How are you?
-I'm good.
Put it on my tab?
Hey, gIad to see aII that butt-kissing's
reaIIy paid off.
Say hi to FuIIer for me.
What?
You shouId've Iet me kick his ass.