In ancient times the world was immersed
into darkness and chaos.
North Africa, in 1600.
These were the days of witchcraft and black magic.
Times when no one came against evil.
Where is the throne room?
Hush, sir!
So ...
[speaks in an unknown dialect]
No?
[responding to the same dialect]
That's nice!
Honest fellow.
Not ...
... Alive ungodly unbelievers!
Qasar!
With us here if someone else.
- Not worth it no treasure!
- Shut up, dog!
Do not scatter!
The captain is the devil prowls!
I'm feeling!
Do not disperse, I said!
There is only one devil - I!
So ...
All for me!
Here we are on the spot!
My search ended ...
Toytos!
[shouting through the door]
Who ...
You?
I - the devil reaper.
I came here for you, Solomon Kane!
- Your transaction took place!
- You're lying, I'm not concluded any deals!
Conclude Kane.
And the stakes - your soul!
Your life is over greedy killers.
You do not take my soul!
Bend down to me, Solomon Kane!
The devil does not forgive the debts!
Tell your master that I have
not ready to descend into hell!
Lord protect me!
Fool! He had long since you left!
On your knees!
You will never take my soul!
Never!
You do not get away from us ...
Your soul is damned Solomon Kane.
[bells]
England, a year later.
Solomon?
Who was this novice?
This - brother Thomas. He came to us
few days ago.
And these signs really guard
you from the demonic ...
Do not you dare mention it in a holy place!
I must talk with Solomon.
Once again, we heard your cries during matins.
This is a dream. Vision does not leave me.
It would be worth to pay attention to the fact
that your dreams tell you.
I listened to them.
Night after night my dreams say that I am cursed.
God protects his flock. But I
not belong to her!
Right?
My enemies are watching ...
... for me ceaselessly.
And one more thing, this monastery ...
This monastery, prayers, symbols ...
That's all that hides me from his gaze.
Solomon ...
All these months that you spent here,
I felt like we covers the shadow.
Yes, dark times now.
I inquired of the Lord, and He answered ...
Solomon, you must leave us.
But how?
I live here in solitude ...
Not cause harm.
I came down with a vicious circle, left the power ...
I am learning to be a man of peace!
I know this is so. But your future
not with us, not here.
What are you talking about?
I did give all their wealth the church!
And we thank you for your generosity,
but me you must understand.
Padre!
Please do not force you to plead.
In this monastery, I found a safe haven.
- And do not go away.
- You will go home.
Home?
You the Honorable Sir, you have the land.
Come back in their possession!
No.
- Solomon ...
- No!
I never go home.
But you can not stay!
I heard a voice in a dream,
called me to send him.
- I always listen to the voices.
- Did Solomon his appointment?
Everyone he knows his fate.
And Kane finds his destiny.
To redemption leads many ways.
Unfortunately, not all of them peaceful.
[Women's sobs]
Pilgrim!
- A lift?
- No, thanks.
In this way one is better not to wander.
Once again, I thank you, buddy.
I'll walk.
- As you wish. May God bless you!
- And you too. Ma'am!
But, oh, oh, come on!
[voice of the forest]: Silence!
I do not care.
Let him hear!
Derneshsya - you end.
I'm not looking for trouble!
Well, very sorry.
Because you found them!
Well, let's see ...
You have nothing?
Take anything you want.
Do not worry, pilgrim.
Take!
Quiet!
- What have you got?
- Look! Some sort of magical signs!
Should he sorcerer!
What can we do to you?
Do not burn it as a witch?
In the fire!
I read in your eyes murder.
Kill me?
A? Kill?
- No.
- What?
Do not kill the man who robbed you?
I will not fight with a man. I renounced all violence.
Bad luck to you. Because we ...
Do what I say, Solomon.
Do not forget your place.
You're the second son, Solomon.
Marcus - my heir.
And after my death, the master
He will land, but you ...
Father, but Marcus - stupid animal!
And thou wilt rank and go
serve the church, as I ordered.
- But I do not want to be a priest!
- Your desires are unimportant!
Holy Father will take you to the Abbey.
I'm not going.
Dare to argue with - will not get anything.
I am of you deny!
You'll be the poor bum!
What you want?
If you leave, it would not be able to return!
Do not even think to disobey!
So quiet, quiet.
Calm down, sir.
All over.
He's come!
Father! The man woke up!
Well ... Drink some water if you can.
Softly, softly.
- The fever subsided, his father.
- Praise the Lord!
You get well!
My name is Krotorn.
William Krotorn. My daughter Meredith
you come out.
Should, God is watching over you, sir.
He led us to you for salvation.
Edward, well, everything!
Look for areas for the night.
- Here, put, mother?
- Yes, thank you, Meredith.
More fun, Meredith!
Samuel!
Water the horses.
Why do I ...
- Fought with the Spaniards?
- I had to.
And with whom More?
With all managed to war, it seems.
There were many masters.
And sailed with Admiral Drake.
Admiral Drake!
But it ended badly.
How it must have fun!
See the world ...
Learn something new ...
A life full of violence and bloodshed,
you think, is fascinating?
You know what I had in mind. Edward, why
you ospraivaesh all, no matter what I said?
- You already have to understand that ...
- Come on!
I fought in the army of the queen. Once or twice.
Yet found faith.
To take away the life of another person
... is not an easy test.
I must confess, Mr. Krotorn ...
I was at home was worse than in combat.
Kill for me a piece of cake.
Dare to argue with - will not get anything.
If you leave, it would not be able to return!
Do not even think to disobey!
Help!
Help! Stop!
Marcus. What are you doing?
Solomon! I thought you had already saved
from the life of priests of the flight.
- Solomon ...
- Shut up! I am not allowed to open his mouth.
Sarah, run!
This is not your worry, brother!
Since you go away and leave you a souvenir.
And now look here! I am the eldest son!
I - heir!
I will get everything, but you - nothing!
Take the load and away from this land!
Marcus!
It is a friend.
- Please, join!
- Thank you.
How are you?
Bruises bruises yes, nonsense. Your daughter --
Healer of God.
So it. All of the mother.
Though the whole Earth will pass, but rather women not syschete!
My family - all this for me.
You are lucky.
And you have those?
A brother, but since ...
Lifetime passed.
We all lost loved ones. Because of the plague,
harassment, prejudice.
Take even Edward.
He had a wife and child.
But the Lord took her to their own.
And now you want to swim in the New World?
Yes, we want. Exactly.
Sometimes all the better to start life anew.
You can go with us.
You are very warm-hearted man, William.
Thank you. Over the proposal.
I'll be honest with you.
You should know who calls in the road.
I've done wrong.
Cruel.
Evil.
Terrible.
I am very ...
No, I was ...
Very sinful.
Bad.
But the Lord says about redemption!
And forgiveness.
No. My soul is damned.
Servants of Satan will come after me, I go down the path of peace.
Well, stay in it.
Do not go ...
Since paths of peace.
Captain Kane!
Yes, Miss?
I'll sew clothes.
Your already a bit ...
Lightly, Miss?
Slightly worn ....
You are so kind.
Thank you.
It is more suitable stately man.
True, William?
Certainly, it is better,
than in previous rags!
Was glad to win your approval.
Right now you have a respectable appearance.
Well, quite a while no one could say both me.
Thank you!
You sail with us in America?
- Not sure, Samuel.
- How so?
Well ...
You are with his family rushes into a new life.
And I have to correct the former.
- Tell the truth?
- Yep.
You're able to kill those who attacked you!
In the old days ...
I would have ripped the heart still living out of their chest.
With me poderetes?
Poder, if not throw
their silly questions!
- Hell! "
- I have no reason to fight with you, young man!
-Samuel!
-And here's the reason!
To save from thieves beautiful maiden!
Oh, Solomon, save us, for God's sake!
To arms!
Samuel!
Come into the carriage, quick!
Who could have done it?
Devil!
The devil himself was here!
There were no devil.
Here, burning witch, apparently.
It must be a creature escaped.
We better go.
We can not leave these
people vultures.
Do not feel sorry for firewood, Edward!
That night, the darkness is better
close at bay.
My child, that happened to you?
Leave bednyashku alone, William!
They wanted to burn the witch.
People came to see her cramps.
But the flames did not touch it ...
She laughed, and more ...
She said that all the offspring of the devil
free to roam the earth.
And then ...
It has all been murdered.
Burned their eyes.
Because they came to see.
Let us pray.
- I'm tired!
- Even a minute.
Child, pray to be.
- I do not want you to pray.
- Hush, hush ...
I'm tired!
Spare?
Well, of course tired, poor thing.
Let us arrange accommodation for you.
EdwardI
It would be a girl to wear your cross today.
- He will protect her.
- Of course.
- Hold.
- Good.
Here, baby.
Is better to put on it.
He will protect you.
Solomon!
What we need is you!
- What are you?
- Meredith ...
Take it, child.
She - a witch!
The devil is waiting for you long ago, Kane!
Decided to hide? Run.
Back! Do not run away!
Move!
Put your hands!
New recruits for Malachi, my lord.
You are ready to serve his master?
I am happy with this option!
To serve us, you will have to be us.
Well! Tell me what to do?
What is he doing?
Good-oh!
- Father, I collected firewood!
- Good for you, Samuel!
Now mangled.
Let me help you.
Must pull.
Thank you.
Give me ... look.
- Does it hurt?
- No. I do not feel anything.
Why I pick up on this creature?
I do not know.
In their evil reasons.
So, we are in danger?
Do not worry.
As you are not possessed by evil, Meredith.
Believe me.
I believe.
What are you fidgeting, Samuel? Take branch
more. I love hot supets!
William?
Large fire is better not to breed.
No need to attract attention.
- Solomon!
- What is it?
- I heard something. - Where?
- Over there. For those trees.
Wait here.
Help!
Help!!
Samuel?
Samuel, DROP!
Hush, sir!
Below the head. And shut up!
Who is Solomon? Who are they?
Listen carefully. Go back to your father!
Quickly go all out!
Run!
Do not touch her!
Meredith!
Let go!
Mom!
Solomon!
Samuel!
This is it!
No! Stop!
Stop!
Solomon!
Save us!
Stop!
Please, leave him.
Let me go!
Do not touch it.
You see, I'm unarmed.
Solomon, save him!
- Kill all!
- Quiet, Samuel!
Solomon, kill all!
Listen, Samuel, quiet!
Not to take, okay?
You will not break - and he let go.
Release?
You also can, I know!
I said shut up, Samuel!
Listen ...
Are you the owner? What do you want?
I'll do anything.
Kill me!
You can.
No, I ...
No way.
I. .. peace-loving people.
Do not even think to hurt the boy.
This child ...
Puppy ...
- Go ahead all of you.
- Save us.
He - the only man here.
No need!
- Solomon!
- Stop it!
- Listen to me ...
No-e-e-t!
No!
Samuel!
Bring labeled!
Kill them! Kill them all, Solomon!
Save us! I implore you, save us!
What do you want from me? ..
What?
And all this, why I'll need?
So be it!
Murder ...
I paved a road to Hell.
But such a price I gladly pay!
Help! Save me!
- Save it!
Let her go!
Stop!
There, there!
Solomon ...
- Bring Meredith.
- Yes.
- Bring it!
- Right!
- Curse return it!
- I will return.
For me ...
This is my ...
... My last words.
I know God hears.
You will save our girl ...
... That, and his soul will save.
Canst all atone.
Solomon, I know that it will.
Swear to me.
- Pledge This!
- I swear.
By William, I find her!
Find it.
Go!
Go, go!
Hold him!
Meredit! You are here ...
Have you seen ... Have you seen this girl?
Wait! Check, please ...
Have you seen her?
I do not know her, let go ...
Come to me! Where you drove?
Have you seen this girl?
I do not know ... There everywhere robbers!
Look!
Have you seen this girl?
I beg you, let go! I want
to his home!
Sorry, baby. Forgive me ...
All. Everything. Go.
Where? Back!
Where you have luck? What do you want?
Better to live, baby.
We are not saved. Slavery or death - that
all our choices.
- Lord - and he did not save us!
- We'll get out!
Hold my hand. We will survive
this, you'll see.
Silence!
Give it here!
O Creator ...
[bells]
Lord, hear my prayer.
I let you down - I can not find it ...
I'm lost.
Ozar me!
Let me find my own way!
Holy Father!
At such times we are living.
I was looking for a sanctuary to pray.
Blessed be the Lord in his temple!
Blessed be in the stronghold of His power!
I have seen such terrible things ...
- So this is your house?
- Other I do not need.
Yes and no.
I have no other.
You from afar?
Three days of continuous racing - and here I am.
But where "here" - do not know.
This border ownership of Somerset and Devanshira.
And yet my house.
A sad return!
So the looters and then visited?
Narrow-eyed dogs Malachi.
Yes, they are then passed.
Now the robbers own all
lands to the west of here.
It turns out I have to the west.
Meet his doom, my son.
- Who is this hat?
- A faithful servant of the devil.
Wizard. Nobody saw.
Hiding in his castle and sends
Warriors in the mask to do his will.
His army is weak transforms into slaves,
and strong - at the soldiers.
But the Lord will save the righteous!
Here ... Here is what he said. I have read.
Here, found. I have read.
This End of the World.
Do you really believe it?
Abomination, which restrained the light of Christ,
crawls out of the flames, in order to harm and suffering!
It seems that Christ and all his angels slept.
... While we are in distress.
Not blaspheming!
All tvoritisya - by the will of God.
Is this true?
What evil can get away with walking on land!
And it remains protected only ... what?
Only faith?
So says the Holy Scripture.
Quiet!
What is it?
This is something outside.
You're wrong.
Outside, no harm there.
The evil is already here.
So?
Come.
See?
Satan wanted to get them all.
In order to sift as wheat.
O Creator ...
And what could I do?
Delete creatures!
They were once men and zhnnschinami ...
I knew ih.Oni not to blame for that
spell Malachi to change them.
This is my flock.
I give them shelter.
their care.
- And the food.
- Food?
What?
What do you feed them?
that's what!
I leave you satanic creatures
for the mortification yours!
And save your soul.
Have mercy on your soul!
Your pal.
And I remember it, old man!
He warrior.
Remember?
What are you doing here, pilgrim?
Here's what ... It turns out you are also given
themselves to this evil.
And you should!
Hat is about to seize all around.
You have no purpose to fight.
You only remains that fight.
But it's not on your part ...
Exactly?
Who knows?
And if I have changed my mind?
No! What do you do?
Stop!
Look - this girl was taken yours.
- You saw her?
- No-one I have not seen!
Look carefully, brat! This is the last
chance to save your worthless life!
Speak!
- Okay, I saw it!
Have you seen her? Tell me, where is she?
Died.
Died?
You're lying, scumbag!
What is it? Can I lie?
I did want to live!
You're lying to me!
Not lie. No.
Not her!
I do not believe it!
For a pitcher. Keep the change.
Thank you, sir.
You sure of?
It's him!
I recognized him.
Sir?
Captain Kane!
I Henry Telford. Remember me?
I am with you sailed on the "Tersule" assistant.
My name Telford. Remember?
- It's not him.
- This is it. Kane.
The present leader, too, believe!
And where it leads us to another tavern?
Look at him!
My friend assures me that in life,
not seen a better warrior.
- I do not believe him.
- And correctly.
I know what you can! I saw!
All gone long ago.
It is not.
And I, Telford, has lost its soul.
- The sense of it not. Forget it.
- Stop!
Captain, we need a leader.
We must resist!
So resist!
It is no more ...
I lost it.
And now will pay for it.
And let for my coming.
I was not touching.
Mercy! I beseech you!
Ah-ah-ah-ah!!
Here's what awaits all who dare
resist hat!
Beseech you! Mercy!
There will be no mercy!
That death no one will save!
This is a nonentity!
Beat him to the cross!
And burned to ashes since the city!
Help!
No ... No!
Solomon!
Solomon! Do not die!
Meredith ...
You hear me?
Meredith!
- Solomon!
- Meredith!
God!
Give me strength!
Solomon-o-o-n!
Captain Kane!
- Another 20 in the Rhone Marche.
- They are becoming stronger.
That's why we want Kane!
- What can we do to him ...
- He needs us!
Whatever the past may have been his sins ...
One of the devil to change to another?
I think this is stupid.
Earth, stones, fire and water ...
Do not poke your nose to me with his vile
blasphemous magic!
This is my "lousy" magic made you!
In her more power than your hristianstkom God!
I advise you to remember it!
I sang what you asked.
His body healed.
What do you see in the future?
Your leader will lead you to the blood and darkness!
And ready are you to this?
Goodbye.
What are you doing?
You need to lie!
- I'm leaving.
- Where? Not all of course.
She's alive!
But the wounds barely healed. And we still
the big battle is not ready.
Have to wait.
I invite you to go!
I do not want this!
You can not ask for. But we're going.
He promised us that you destroy evil.
And we will be next to you.
Just too "promised?
You did it want to destroy?
So we take!
Hat was a priest and healer.
But sold his soul to the devil for the power
which now possesses.
It enslaves our people and destroy the earth.
And the rider ...
As the iron fist is his
shelf and carries the death!
He guise of no face!
He takes the soul of a tap.
True. I have seen.
If you kill him, hat will be vulnerable.
Saying is easier than to do.
No. He will fall.
You know where that hat?
This is not a mystery.
In the castle Aksmut.
No!
Can not be ...
No doubt. You know him?
My father was his owner.
I grew up there.
Now there are no master.
And I did not know that he died ...
Well ...
It's time this finish!
People, all who are here, take the gun!
- We do not Goto ...
- Suppose now that he is protected!
- We are not yet ready.
- And he, too!
- We are very little.
- What's the reason? Remember, I took the city a smaller number?
But as we get into the castle?
Forgot that I was born there and does not intend
enter through the main gate?
Good God, and it is - my house?
You really live here?
- Yeah.
- This explains a lot.
- And you're here!
- With the return of ... Solomon Kane!
To arms!
Yalbash, diversion of people! We did not win!
Follow me!
Go!
Meredith!
Save us!
Meredith! There is a girl named Meredith?
Meredith!
- You are free!
- Thank you!
Run faster!
Come out, old man, you're free.
I'll help you.
Now try to weaken the chain.
Even if you do it, I'll stay.
- What are you mumbling? Why?
- Because it was my house.
Father?
Solomon?
God ...
And I thought I'd lost you forever.
No.
You were still a boy when ...
No!
You with them can not cope.
These black magic is not less than iron.
- How to release you?
- Nothing, Solomon. Not.
Father ...
I felt so ...
The blame for what he did.
But I do not blame that Marcus has fallen ...
- I am not his fault that he died.
- And he had not died, Solomon.
If so - would not have happened all this horror.
That is ...
Glory to the Creator, he is alive!
He was saved by not God's will.
What? I do not understand.
Falling off a cliff, he was horribly maimed.
But breathing, the truth never came.
Neither doctors nor the priests did not return him to life.
And I brought a sorcerer.
What!
- Yes ...
- You gave Malachi here?
I promised him everything that I have.
If only he returned to me Marcus.
And it turned out, Solomon!
His magic mirror he entered
into darkness and back Marcus back, but ...
... he has changed.
but his face, disfigured by his fall,
was hiding under the mask.
And obey only the will of the sorcerer.
It can not be my brother!
This creature is your brother.
Or rather what was left of him.
Now Marcus is ruining all who follow him.
Execute my request.
Just tell me, I'll do anything.
We both have to answer.
For my sins I'm ready to answer.
Now.
- No!
- You should!
That I brought here a sorcerer.
And while I breathe, he will be here.
I will not let me die.
Hurry! Here!
- About the sake of God, help!
- Is that all?
- All those who survived? - Two more here
about the rest do not know.
Hold them here. You need only hold on.
It's your stupidity?
Hold out just a little!
I can stop it with one blow!
Malakal!
I come to you!
Did not you wanted?
To me!
Solomon!
Solomon, go away, it's a trap!
Long path, which will be a pilgrim
in the name of their faith.
But even longer his way home
in the land of their fathers.
I've long been waiting for you.
Warlock unworthy of the throne of my father!
Your father - just a child. Fool,
concluded a deal with the devil.
He betrayed you.
Your soul is damned.
Rather!
You still obedient, faithful son?
Malakal!
Malakal, you coward!
Meredith, you're not hurt?
- You came for me!
- I swore to William.
Solomon is a trap! They marked
me, that you came.
Stop!
- The devil is waiting for you.
- The Devil and as soon I will.
Oh, God! Solomon!
Brother, listen to me ...
Are you listening, Marcus?
You are not obliged to obey him!
No!
Listen to me!
Meredith, run!
Where's your master?
Where has he gone?
Where are you, hat?
Disappeared into the darkness?
What am I to you hiding?
I need you here.
Each your step closer you here.
Your pain was in retaliation for your sins.
My lord asked your soul!
See what the devil sent for you!
This creature drag you back to Hell!
Your soul is damned!
Lord ...
Marcus!
Our father is gone.
Now all that - yours!
Hat can not command you!
Stop!
Brother, stop! Brother!
Solomon!
Give rest in peace, brother.
Only your innocent blood will release him!
Now you're free!
Take it!
Lord, to thee only hope.
Stop! Let her!
Can you take my soul!
So why all the risk, even his soul ...
... To save her?
I swore an oath.
I will keep it.
Solomon ...
Praise God!
He disappeared.
Your father has promised ...
... What if I will save you, I will save, and his soul.
And he did.
Yes. So it.
I am no more the devil.
Guards fell.
Father, I have kept his oath.
Meredith returned to his mother.
The demon disappeared.
Banished into the darkness with the sorcerer
which all of us cursed.
But to destroy the evil is not so simple.
And I know that I still have to fight.
Now I'm completely different. All through what I went through ...
... All that I saw and everything that made ...
... Pointed out to me my destiny.
There was a time when the world was plunged into darkness.
Seasons of witchcraft and black magic
when no one was going against evil.
These times ...
... gone forever!