Subtitles: LoS PiRaTaS 2002
*** by Kurgan ***
Captain's Log:
Stardate 8130.3.
Starship Enterprise
on training mission
to Gamma Hydra,
Section 14,
coordinates 22-87-4.
Approaching neutral zone.
All systems normal
and functioning.
Leaving Section 14
for Section 15.
Stand by.
Project parabolic course
to avoid entering neutral zone.
Aye, Captain.
Course change projected.
Captain,
I'm getting something
on the distress channel.
On speakers.
Imperative.
This is Kobayashi Maru.
We've struck a gravitic mine
and have lost power.
Our hull is penetrated
and we have sustained...
This is the starship
Enterprise.
Your message
is breaking up.
Can you give us your
coordinates?
Our position is Gamma Hydra,
Section 10.
In the neutral zone.
Hull penetrated.
Life support
systems failing.
Can you assist us,
Enterprise?
Data on Kobayashi Maru.
Vessel is third-class
neutronic fuel carrier,
crew of 81,300 passengers.
Damn.
Mr. Sulu,
plot an intercept course.
May I remind you that if the starship
enters the zone...
I'm aware of my responsibilities,
mister.
Estimating two minutes
to intercept.
Now entering
the neutral zone.
Warning.
We have entered neutral zone.
We are now in violation
of treaty, Captain.
Stand by,
transporter room,
ready to beam
survivors aboard.
Captain,
I've lost their signal.
Alert. Three Klingon cruisers
bearing 3-1-6 mark 4,
closing fast.
Visual.
Battle stations.
Activate shields.
Shields activated.
Tell them we're
on a rescue mission.
They're jamming
the frequencies.
Klingons on attack course
and closing.
We're over our heads.
Mr. Sulu,
get us out of here.
I'll try, Captain.
Alert. Klingon torpedoes
activated. Alert.
Evasive action.
Engineering, damage report.
Main energizer hit,
Captain.
Engage auxiliary power.
Prepare to return fire.
Aah!
Shields collapsing,
Captain.
Fire all phasers.
No power
to the weapons, Captain.
Captain, it's no use.
We're dead in space.
Activate escape pods.
Send out the log buoy.
All hands abandon ship.
All right, open it up.
Any suggestions, Admiral?
Prayer, Mr. Saavik.
The Klingons
don't take prisoners.
Lights.
Blowers on.
Captain.
Trainees,
to the briefing room.
Maintenance Crew,
report to bridge simulator.
Physician, heal thyself.
Is that all?
What about my performance?
I'm not
a drama critic.
Staying with
a sinking ship?
Permission
to speak candidly, sir.
Granted.
This was not a fair test
of my abilities.
Why not?
Because there was
no way to win.
A no-win situation
is always possible.
Has that never
occurred to you?
No, sir, it has not.
Dealing with death
is at least as important
as dealing with life.
That thought had not
occurred to me.
Now you have something new
to think about.
Carry on.
Engineering Cadets,
assemble on C Level.
Admiral, why not put
an experienced crew on the ship?
Galloping around the cosmos
is a game for the young.
Now, what does that mean?
Aren't you dead?
I assume you're
loitering around here
to learn what efficiency rating
I plan to give your cadets.
I am understandably curious.
They destroyed
the simulator room
and you with it.
The Kobayashi Maru
scenario
frequently wreaks havoc with students
and equipment.
You took the test
three times yourself.
Your final solution
was unique.
That was its virtue.
Oh, by the way,
thank you for this.
I know of your fondness
for antiques.
"It was the best of times,
it was the worst of times."
Message, Spock?
None that I know.
Except, of course, happy birthday.
Surely the best of times.
Captain Spock,
space shuttle leaving
in 15 minutes.
Where are you off to?
The Enterprise,
to check in before your inspection.
And you?
Home.
Bless me, Doctor,
what beams you
into this neck
of the woods?
Beware Romulans
bearing gifts.
Happy birthday, Jim.
Thanks.
Romulan ale.
Why, Bones,
this is illegal.
I only use it
for medicinal purposes.
I got aboard a ship
that brings it in.
Now, don't be a prig.
2283.
Well, it takes this stuff
a while to ferment.
Here, give me.
Now, you open this one.
I'm almost afraid to.
What is it?
Klingon aphrodisiacs?
No.
Bones, this is...
charming.
For most patients
your age,
I'd recommend
Retinax 5.
I'm allergic
to Retinax.
Exactly. Cheers!
Cheers.
Ahh.
Happy birthday.
I don't know
what to say.
You could say thank you.
Thank you.
Damn it, Jim,
what the hell's the matter with you?
Why are we treating your birthday
like a funeral?
Bones, I don't want
to be lectured.
What the hell
do you want?
This is not about age,
and you know it.
It's about you flying
a goddamn computer console
when you want to be
out there hopping galaxies.
Spare me
your poetry.
We all have
assigned duties.
Bull!
You're hiding- hiding behind
rules and regulations.
From whom?
From yourself, Admiral.
Don't mince words, Bones.
What do you really think?
Jim, I'm your doctor,
and I'm your friend.
Get back your command.
Get it back
before you turn
into part
of this collection,
before you
really do grow old.
Starship Log:
Stardate 8130.4.
Log entry
by First Officer Pavel Chekov.
Starship Reliant on orbital approach
to Ceti Alpha VI
in connection
with Project Genesis.
We are searching
for a lifeless planet
to use as a test site
for the Genesis experiment.
So far, no success.
Standard orbit, please.
Mr. Beach, any change
in the surface scan?
Negative.
Limited atmosphere
dominated by kraylon gas,
sand, high-velocity winds.
incapable of supporting life forms.
Does it have to be
completely lifeless?
Have you found something?
We picked up
a minor energy flux
on one dynoscanner.
Damn. Are you sure?
Maybe the scanner's
out of adjustment.
I suppose it could be a particle
of preanimate matter
caught in the matrix.
Get on the Comm-pic
to Dr. Marcus.
Aye, sir.
Maybe it's something
we can transplant.
You know what she'll say.
Let me get this straight-
something you can transplant?
Yes, Doctor.
Something you can transplant?
I don't know.
But it may only be
preanimate matter.
Then again, it may not.
There can't be
so much as a microbe,
or the show's off.
Have a look.
If it can be moved-
You bet, Doctor.
we're on our way.
Well, don't have kittens.
Genesis will work.
They'll remember you
with Newton, Einstein, Surak.
Thanks. No respect
from my offspring.
Par for the course.
You teaming up
with me for bridge?
Maybe.
What is it?
Whenever we deal
with Starfleet,
I get nervous.
We are dealing
with something
that could be perverted
into a dreadful weapon.
Remember that overgrown Boy Scout
you hung around with?
Jim Kirk
was many things,
but he was never
a boy scout.
Captain Terrell,
standby to beam down.
Chekov,
are you sure
these are
the correct coordinates?
Captain, this is
the garden spot
of Ceti Alpha VI.
I can barely see it.
There's nothing here.
The tricorder
must be broken.
Chekov, over here.
Those look like
cargo carriers.
Hey, give me a hand.
What the hell happened?
If they crashed,
where's the rest
of the ship?
What the hell is that?
Botany Bay?
Botany Bay!
Oh, no!
We've got to leave now!
What about-
Never mind that. Hurry!
Chekov, what's wrong
with you?
Chekov?
Come on! Hurry!
Starship Reliant
to Captain Terrell.
This is Commander Kyle.
Will you please
respond, Captain?
Captain Terrell,
respond, please.
Let's give them
a little more time.
Khan.
I don't know you.
But you...
I never forget a face.
Mr...
Chekov.
Isn't it?
I never thought
to see your face again.
Chekov,
who is this man?
A criminal, Captain.
A product of 20th-century
genetic engineering.
What do you want?
I demand to be-
You are in a position
to demand nothing, sir.
I, on the other hand,
am in a position
to grant nothing.
What you see
is all that remains
of the ship's company
and crew
of the Botany Bay,
marooned here 15 years ago
by Captain James T. Kirk.
Listen,
you men and women-
Captain, Captain.
Save your strength,
Captain.
These people had sworn
to live and die
at my command
200 years
before you were born.
Do you mean he never
told you the tale?
To amuse your Captain?
No?
Never told you
How the Enterprise
picked up the Botany Bay
lost in space
from the year 1996,
myself and the ship's company
in cryogenic freeze?
I've never even met
Admiral Kirk.
Admiral?
Admiral.
Never told you
how Admiral Kirk
sent 70 of us into exile
on this barren sand heap
with only the contents
of these cargo bays
to sustain us?
You lie! On Ceti Alpha V,
there was life.
A fair chance-
This is Ceti Alpha V!
Ceti Alpha VI exploded
six months after
we were left here.
The shock
shifted the orbit
of this planet,
and everything
was laid waste.
Admiral Kirk
never bothered to check
on our progress.
It was only the fact
of my genetically
engineered intellect
that allowed us
to survive.
On earth...
200 years ago...
I was a prince...
with power over millions.
Captain Kirk
was your host.
You repaid
his hospitality
by trying
to steal his ship
and murder him.
You didn't expect
to find me.
You thought
this was Ceti Alpha VI.
Ahh.
Why are you here?
Why?
Allow me
to introduce you
to Ceti Alpha V's
only remaining
indigenous life form.
What do you think?
It killed
20 of my people...
including my beloved wife.
Oh, not all at once.
And not instantly,
to be sure.
You see,
their young enter
through the ears
and wrap themselves
around the cerebral cortex.
This has the effect
of rendering the victim
extremely susceptible
to, uh...suggestion.
Later, as they grow...
follows madness...
and death.
Khan, listen to me.
These are pets,
of course.
Not quite domesticated.
Khan,
Captain Kirk
was only doing his duty.
Aah!
Aaaahh!
That's better.
Now, tell me,
why are you here?
And tell me
where I may find
James Kirk.
Enterprise to Admiral Kirk's shuttle.
You're cleared for docking.
Approach portside
torpedo bay.
Enterprise, this is
Admiral Kirk's party on final approach.
Enterprise welcomes you.
Prepare for docking.
I hate inspections.
I'm delighted.
Any chance to go aboard the Enterprise.
I'm glad you're at the helm
for three weeks.
These kids
can't steer.
Open the air lock.
Permission to come aboard.
You're welcome.
You know my training crew.
Certainly they know you.
We've been through
death and life together.
Mr. Scott, you old space dog,
you're well.
I had a wee bout, sir,
but Dr. McCoy
pulled me through.
Wee bout of what?
Shore leave, Admiral.
Who do we have here?
Midshipman First Class Peter Preston,
Engineer's Mate, sir.
First training voyage,
Mr. Preston?
Yes, sir.
I see.
Shall we start
with the engine room?
We'll see you there.
Everything is in order.
That'll be a pleasant surprise,
Mr. Scott.
I'll see you
on the bridge, Admiral.
Company, dismissed.
Well, Mr. Scott,
are your cadets capable
of handling
a minor training cruise?
Give the word, Admiral.
The word is given.
Aye, sir.
What about the rest
of the inspection?
This is
Starfleet operations.
Enterprise is clear
for departure.
Admiral on the bridge.
Running lights on.
Very well,
Mr. Saavik.
You may clear
all moorings.
Aye, sir.
All moorings are cleared,
Captain.
Thank you.
Lieutenant,
have you piloted a starship
out of space dock?
Never, sir.
Take her out,
Mr. Saavik.
Aye, sir.
For everything there is
a first time, Lieutenant.
Don't you agree, Admiral?
Uh-huh.
Aft thrusters,
Mr. Sulu.
Aft thrusters.
Would you like
a tranquilizer?
Add 1 /4 impulse power.
We are free
to navigate.
Course heading, Captain?
Captain's discretion.
Mr. Sulu,
you may...
indulge yourself.
Aye, sir.
Does that
about do it?
I doubt
we could squeeze
any more information
into the memory banks.
We'll design
a bigger one.
Who would build it?
Dr. Marcus,
Comm-pic coming in
on the hyperchannel.
It's the starship Reliant.
On the screen, Jedda.
Come in, please.
This is the Reliant
callingRegula-1.
Repeat,
this is U.S.S. Reliant.
Commander, we are receiving.
This is Regula-1 .
Ah, Dr. Marcus. Good.
We're en route to you
and should be there
in three days.
We weren't expecting you
for three months.
Has something happened?
No. Ceti Alpha VI
has checked out.
Then why
are you coming-
We have new orders.
All materials
of Project Genesis
will be transferred
to this ship
fortesting
on Ceti Alpha VI.
Who do they
think they are?
Commander Chekov,
this is completely irregular.
I have my orders.
Pin him down, mother.
Who gave the order?
The order comes from...
Admiral James T. Kirk.
I knew it!
The military's
been waiting
to get
their hands on it.
I have no intention
of allowing Reliant
or any unauthorized personnel
access to our work.
I am sorry
that you feel that way.
Admiral Kirk's orders
are confirmed.
Please prepare
to deliver Genesis to us
upon our arrival.
Reliant out.
Well done, Commander.
You realize, sir,
they will attempt
to contact Admiral Kirk
and confirm the order.
Hold, please.
Thank you, sir.
Lieutenant,
are you wearing
your hair differently?
It's still regulation, Admiral.
May I speak, sir?
Self-expression
doesn't seem to be
one of your problems.
You're bothered
by your performance
on the Kobayashi Maru.
I failed to resolve
the situation.
There's no correct resolution.
It's a test
of character.
May I ask how you
dealt with the test?
You may ask.
That's a little joke.
Humor. It is
a difficult concept.
It is not logical.
We learn by doing.
Who's been holding up
the damn elevator?
Thank you, sir.
She change
her hair style?
I hadn't noticed.
Wonderful stuff,
that Romulan ale.
Admiral Kirk.
Kirk here.
I have
an urgent Comm-pic
from Space Lab
Regula-1 for you.
Dr. Carol Marcus.
I'll take it
in my quarters.
It never rains
but it pours.
As a physician,
you should appreciate
the dangers of reopening
old wounds.
Sorry.
Jim, can you read me?
I can hear you, Carol.
What's wrong?
Why are you taking
Genesis from us?
Taking Genesis?
Who's taking Genesis?
Who is taking Genesis?
I can see you,
but I can't hear.
Jim, did you
give the order?
What order?
Who's taking Genesis?
I won't let them
have Genesis
without proper authorization.
On whose authority
can they do this?
No one's authority.
Jim-
Uhura, what's happening?
Transmission jammed
at the source.
Alert Starfleet headquarters.
Aye, sir.
I want to talk
to Starfleet command.
We must have order
in here.
This has to be a mistake.
Mistake.
We're all alone here.
They waited until everyone
was on leave.
Reliant is at our disposal,
not vice versa.
I can't believe
Starfleet-
I tried to tell you
scientists are always
pawns of the military.
Starfleet has kept peace
for 1 00 years.
I cannot subscribe
to your interpretation of this event.
You may be right, Doctor,
but what about Reliant?
She's on her way.
We have a problem.
Something may be wrong
on Regula-1 .
We've been ordered
to investigate.
If memory serves,
Regula-1 is a scientific
research laboratory.
I told
Starfleet command
all we had was
a boatload of children,
but we're the only ship
in the quadrant.
Spock, these cadets
of yours-
How will they respond
under real pressure?
As with all
living things,
each according
to his gifts.
Of course,
the ship is yours.
No, that won't
be necessary.
Just get me
to Regula-1 .
As a teacher on
a training mission,
I am content to command
the Enterprise.
If we go on duty,
the senior officer
must assume command.
It may be nothing.
Garbled communications.
You take the ship.
You proceed from
a false assumption.
I am a Vulcan.
I have no ego
to bruise.
You're about
to remind me
logic alone
dictates your actions?
I would not
remind you
of that which
you know so well.
It was a mistake
for you to accept
promotion.
Commanding a starship
is your first, best destiny.
Anything else is
a waste of material.
I would not presume
to debate you.
That is wise.
In any case,
were I to invoke logic,
Logic dictates that the needs
of the many
outweigh the needs
of the few.
Or the one.
You're my
superior officer.
You are
also my friend.
I have been and
always shall be yours.
Stop the energizers.
Put me on speakers.
An emergency situation
has arisen.
By order
of Starfleet command,
I'm assuming command
of this vessel.
So note in Ship's Log.
Plot a new course
for Regula-1 .
Mr. Scott.
Aye, sir.
We'll be going
to warp speed.
Course plotted
for Regula-1 , Admiral.
Engage warp engines.
Prepare for warp speed.
Ready, sir.
I know none of you
were expecting this.
I'm asking you to grow up
sooner than you expected.
Warp five, Sulu.
So much for the little
training cruise.
Course to intercept
Enterprise ready, sir.
Excellent.
Helmsman?
Sir. May I speak?
We're all
with you, sir.
But consider this-
We are free.
We have the means
to go where we will.
We have escaped
permanent exile
on Ceti Alpha V.
You have proved
your superior intellect
and defeated the plans
of Admiral Kirk.
You do not need
to defeat him again.
He tasks me.
He tasks me,
and I shall have him.
I'll chase him
round the moons of Nibia
and round
the Antares Maelstrom
perdition's flames
before I give him up.
Prepare to alter course.
Space Station Regula-1 ,
please come in.
Dr. Marcus,
please respond.
This is
Enterprise call-
It's no use.
There's no response.
But no longer jammed.
No, sir.
No nothing.
There are
two possibilities-
they are unable
to respond,
they are unwilling
to respond.
How far?
12 hours, 43 minutes,
present speed.
"Give up Genesis,"
she said.
Give it up to whom?
It might help if I knew
what Genesis was,
beyond the biblical
reference.
Have Dr. McCoy
join us in my quarters.
Mr. Saavik,
you have the con.
Well, I've got
sickbay ready.
Please tell me
what's going on.
Computer, request
security procedure
and access to
Project Genesis summary.
Identify for retina scan.
Kirk, Admiral James T.
Security scan approved.
Summary, please.
Project Genesis.
A proposal
to the Federation.
Carol Marcus.
Yes.
What exactly is Genesis?
Well, put simply,
Genesis is life
from lifelessness.
It is a process
where by molecular structure
is reorganized
at the subatomic level
into life-generating matter
of equal mass.
Stage One was conducted
in the laboratory.
Stage Two will be attempted
in a lifeless underground.
Stage Three will be processed
on a planetary scale.
We intend to introduce
the Genesis device
into an area
of a lifeless space body-
a moon or other dead form.
The device is delivered,
instantaneously causing
what we call
the Genesis Effect.
Matter is reorganized
with life-generating results.
Instead of a dead moon,
a living, breathing planet
capable of sustaining
whatever life forms
we see fit
to deposit on it.
Fascinating.
The reformed moon
simulated here
represents the merest fraction
of the Genesis potential,
should the Federation
fund these experiments.
When we consider the problems
of population and food supply,
the usefulness of this process
becomes clear.
This concludes our proposal.
Thank you.
It literally is Genesis.
Power of creation.
Have they proceeded
with their experiments?
The tape was made
last year.
I assume they've
reached Stage Two.
Dear Lord, do you think we're
intelligent enough to...
Suppose...
What if this were used
where life
already exists?
It would destroy
such life
in favor
of its new matrix.
Its new matrix.
Do you know
what you're saying?
I was not evaluating
its moral implications.
As a matter
of cosmic history,
it's been easier
to destroy
than to create.
Not anymore.
Now we can do both simultaneously.
According to myth,
the earth was created in six days.
Now Genesis will do it
in six minutes.
Really, Dr. McCoy, you must
govern your passions.
They will be
your undoing.
Logic suggests-
My God, the man's
talking about logic.
We're talking about
universal Armageddon.
You green-blooded,
inhuman-
Admiral, sensors indicate
a vessel in our area
closing fast.
What do you
make of her?
It's one of ours.
It's Reliant.
Reliant?
Try the emergency channels.
Picture, Mr. Saavik.
Slow to 1/2 impulse power.
Let's be friends.
Slowing to 1/2
impulse power.
Reliant
in our section.
This quadrant, sir,
and slowing.
Sir, may I quote
general order 1 2?
"When communications
have not been established-"
The Admiral is well aware
of the regulations.
Aye, sir.
Could their Comm system
have failed?
It would explain
many things.
They're requesting
communication, sir.
Let them eat static.
They're still running
with shields down.
Of course.
We are one big happy fleet.
Ah, Kirk,
my old friend.
Do you know
the Klingon proverb
that tells us
revenge is a dish
that is best served cold?
It is very cold in space.
This is damn peculiar.
Yellow alert.
Energize defense fields.
I'm getting
a voice message.
Their chambers coil is overloading
their Comm system.
Spock?
Scanning.
Their coil emissions
are normal.
They still haven't raised
their shields.
Raise ours.
Shields going up.
Lock phasers on target.
Locking phasers
on target.
Locking phasers.
Raise shields.
Fire!
Aah!
Get those shields up!
Trying, sir.
I can't get power.
Scotty!
Get off those channels!
Mr. Scott
on the screen.
I'm just
hanging on, sir.
The main energizer's out.
Try auxiliary power.
Aye, aye, sir.
Damage report.
They knew exactly
where to hit us.
Who? Who knew where
to hit us? And why?
One thing is certain.
We cannot escape
on auxiliary power.
Visual.
Sulu, divert power
to phasers.
Too late.
Hang on!
Scotty, what's left?
Just the battery, sir.
I can have auxiliary power
in a few minutes.
We don't have
a few minutes!
Can you give me
phaser power?
A few shots, sir.
Not enough against
their shields.
Who the hell are they?
Admiral, the Reliant's
commander is signaling.
He wishes to discuss
terms of our surrender.
Put it on screen.
Admiral.
Do it!
While we still have time.
On screen, sir.
Khan.
You still remember, Admiral.
I cannot help
but be touched.
I, of course,
remember you.
What's the meaning
of this attack?
Where's the crew
of the Reliant?
Surely, I have made
my meaning plain.
I mean to avenge myself
upon you, Admiral.
I deprived your ship
of power,
and when I swing around,
I mean to deprive you
of your life.
But I wanted you
to know first
who it was
who had beaten you.
Khan...
if it's me you want,
I'll have myself
beamed aboard.
Spare my crew.
I make you
a counterproposal.
I'll agree
to your terms if...
if...
in addition
to yourself,
you hand over to me
all data and material
regarding the project
called Genesis.
Genesis? What's that?
Don't insult
my intelligence, Kirk.
Give me time to recall
the data on our computers.
I give you
60 seconds, Admiral.
Clear the bridge.
At least we know he doesn't
have Genesis.
Keep nodding as though
I'm still giving orders.
Mr. Saavik,
punch up the data charts
of Reliant's
command console.
Reliant's Command?
Hurry.
The prefix code?
It's all we've got.
Chart's up, sir.
Admiral.
We're finding it.
Please. Please,
you've got to give us time.
The bridge is smashed.
The computer's inoperative.
Time is a luxury
you don't have, Admiral.
Damn!
Admiral?
It's coming through
now, Khan.
Reliant's prefix number
is 1 6309.
I don't understand.
You have to learn why things work
on a starship.
Each ship has its own
combination code...
to prevent an enemy from doing
what we're attempting.
We're using
our console
to order Reliant
to lower her shields.
Assuming he hasn't changed
the combination.
He's quite intelligent.
1 5 seconds, Admiral.
Khan, how do we know
you'll keep your word?
I've given you
no word to keep, Admiral.
In my judgment,
you simply have no alternative.
I see your point.
Stand by to receive
our transmission.
Mr. Sulu,
lock phasers on target
and await my command.
Phasers locked.
Time's up, Admiral.
Here it comes.
Now, Mr. Spock.
Sir, our shields are dropping.
Raise them!
I can't!
Where's the override?
The override?
Fire!
We can't, sir!
Why can't you?
They've damaged the photon control
and the warp drive.
We must withdraw!
No! No!
We must!
Enterprise will wait.
She's not
going anywhere.
Sir, you did it.
I did nothing...
except get caught
with my britches down.
I must be
getting senile.
Mr. Saavik, you go right
on quoting regulations.
Meantime, let's find out
how badly
we've been hurt.
Is the word given, Admiral?
The word is given.
Warp speed.
Aye.
He stayed at his post
when the trainees ran.
Admiral, this is Spock.
Yes, Spock.
Engine room reports
auxiliary power restored.
We can proceed
at impulse power.
Best speed to Regula-1 .
Kirk out.
I'm sorry, Scotty.
Approaching Regula
at Space Lab Regula-1.
Space Station Regula-1,
this is
the starship Enterprise.
Please come in.
Space Station Regula-1,
do you read?
this is Enterprise.
Please acknowledge.
This is Enterprise.
Do you read me?
Space Station Regula-1 ,
do you read?
Please come in.
There's no response, sir.
Sensors, Captain.
Scanners and sensors
are still inoperative.
There's no way to ascertain
what's inside the station.
No way of telling
if Reliant is still in the area.
Precisely.
What do you make
of that planetoid beyond?
Regula is Class D.
It consists of various
unremarkable ores,
essentially
a great rock in space.
And Reliant could be hiding
behind that rock.
A distinct possibility.
Engineering.
Aye, sir.
Mr. Scott, do you have enough power
for transporters?
Barely, sir.
I'm going down there.
Khan could be
down there.
He's been there.
Can you spare someone?
There may be people hurt.
Yeah. I can spare me.
Begging the Admiral's pardon.
General order 1 5.
"No flag officer shall beam
into a hazardous area
without armed escort."
There's no such regulation.
All right.
Join the party.
Mr. Spock,
the ship is yours.
Jim, be careful.
We will.
Indeterminate life signs.
Phasers on stun.
Move out.
Aah.
Jim!
Well, rigor hasn't set in.
This couldn't have happened
too long ago, Jim.
Carol.
This is Enterprise
calling Space Lab Regula-1 .
Respond, please.
Admiral. Over here.
Dr. Marcus,
come in, please.
Oh, my God.
Please acknowledge signal.
Please-
Commander Uhura,
this is Lieutenant Saavik.
We're all right.
Please standby. Out.
Oh, sir,
it was Khan.
We found him
on Ceti Alpha V.
Easy. Easy.
He...
he put creatures
in our bodies
to control our minds.
It's all right.
You're safe now.
Made us say lies...
do things...
but we beat him.
He thought he controlled us,
but he did not.
The Captain was strong.
Captain...
where's Dr. Marcus?
Where are the
Genesis materials?
He couldn't find them.
Even the data banks
were empty.
Erased?
He tortured
those people.
But none of them
would tell him anything.
He went wild.
He slit their throats.
He wanted to tear the place apart,
but he was late.
He had to get back
to the Reliant
in time
to blow you to bits.
Where's Reliant's crew? Dead?
Marooned
on Ceti Alpha V.
He's completely
mad, Admiral.
He blames you for the death
of his wife.
I know what
he blames me for.
The escape pods
are all in place.
Where's the transporter room?
Did he make it
down here?
It was not
my impression.
He spent most
of his time
trying to wring the information
out of the people.
Anything?
The unit's been left on,
which means nobody remained
to turn it off.
Those people back there
bought escape time for Genesis
with their lives.
This is not logical.
These coordinates
are deep inside Regula,
a planetoid we know
to be lifeless.
If Stage Two
is completed,
it was going
to be underground.
It was going to be
underground, she said.
Stage Two of what?
Kirk to Enterprise.
Spock here.
Captain Spock,
damage report.
Admiral,
if we go by the book,
like Lieutenant Saavik,
hours could seem
like days.
I read you, Captain.
Let's have it.
The situation
is grave, Admiral.
We won't have main power
for six days.
Auxiliary power
has temporarily failed.
Restoration maybe possible
in two days.
By the book, Admiral.
Meaning you can't
even beam us back?
Not at present.
Captain Spock...
if you don't hear from us
within one hour,
your orders are to restore
what power you can,
take the Enterprise to the nearest
star base,
and alert
Starfleet command.
Sir, we won't
leave you behind.
Uhura, if you don't
hear from us,
there won't be anybody behind.
Kirk out.
Well, gentlemen,
you can stay here, or...
If it's all the same,
Admiral,
we'd like
to share the risk.
Right. Let's go.
Saavik?
Go? Where are we going?
Where they went.
Suppose they went nowhere?
Then this will be
your big chance
to get away
from it all.
Admiral.
Genesis, I presume.
Phasers down!
You!
Where's Dr. Marcus?
I'm Dr. Marcus.
Jim!
Is that David?
Mother, he killed everybody
we left behind.
Oh, of course he didn't.
David, you're just
making this harder.
I'm afraid
it's even harder
than you think, Doctor.
Please...
don't move.
Chekov?
I'm...
sorry, Admiral.
Your Excellency,
have you been listening?
I have indeed, Captain.
You have done well.
I knew it.
You son of a bitch!
Don't move, anybody!
Captain?
We are waiting.
What's the delay?
All is well, sir.
You have the coordinates
to beam up Genesis.
First things first, Captain.
Kill Admiral Kirk.
Sir, it is difficult. I...
I try to obey, but...
Kill him.
I...
Aah!
Kill him, Terrell, now!
God sakes!
What is it?
Khan, you bloodsucker!
You'll have to do
your own dirty work now.
Do you hear me?
Do you?
Kirk.
Kirk, you're still alive,
my old friend.
Still, "old friend."
You've managed to kill just about
everyone else.
But like
a poor marksman,
you keep missing
the target!
Perhaps I no longer
need to try, Admiral.
Oh, no!
They can't take it.
Khan?
Khan, you've got Genesis,
but you don't
have me.
If you're going
to kill me, Khan,
you're going to have to
come down here!
I've done far worse
than kill you.
I've hurt you,
and I wish to go on
hurting you.
I shall leave you
as you left me-
as you left her-
marooned for all eternity
in the center
of a dead planet.
Buried alive.
Khan!
This is Lieutenant Saavik
calling Enterprise.
Can you read us?
This is Lieutenant Saavik.
Calling Enterprise.
Can you read us?
He's coming around.
It's no use, Admiral.
They're still jamming
all channels.
If the Enterprise followed orders,
she's long since gone.
If she couldn't obey,
she's finished.
So are we,
it looks like.
I don't understand.
Who's responsible for all this?
Who is Khan?
Well, it's a long story.
We appear to have
plenty of time.
Is there
anything to eat?
I don't know about anybody else,
but I'm starved.
How can you think of food
at a time like this?
First order
of business-survival.
There is food
in the Genesis cave,
enough to last
a lifetime...
if necessary.
We thought
this was Genesis.
This?
It took the Starfleet
corps of engineers
1 0 months in space suits
to tunnel out all this.
What we did in there,
we did in a day.
David, why don't you show
Dr. McCoy
and the lieutenant
our idea of food?
We can't just sit here.
Oh, yes, we can.
This is just to give us
something to do, isn't it?
Come on.
Admiral?
As your teacher Mr. Spock
is fond to say,
I like to think that there always
are possibilities.
I did what you wanted.
I stayed away.
Why didn't you tell him?
How can you
ask me that?
Were we together?
Were we going to be?
You had your world,
and I had mine.
And I wanted him in mine,
not chasing through the universe
with his father.
Actually...
he's a lot like you...
in many ways.
Please tell me
what you're feeling.
There's a man out there
I haven't seen in 1 5 years
who's trying to kill me.
You show me a son
that would be happy to help.
My son.
My life that
could have been...
and wasn't.
What am I feeling?
Old.
Worn-out.
Let me show you something
that will
make you feel young
as when the world
was new.
Impulse power restored.
Excellent.
More than a match
for poor Enterprise.
You did all this
in a day?
The matrix formed
in a day.
The life forms
grew later
at a substantially
accelerated rate.
Jim! This is incredible!
Have you ever
seen the like?
Can I cook
or can't l?
Where is she?
Sir, may I ask you
a question?
What's on your mind?
The Kobayashi Maru, sir.
You're asking if we're playing out
that scenario?
On the test, sir.
Will you tell me
what you did?
I would really like
to know.
Lieutenant, you're looking
at the only Starfleet cadet
who ever beat
the no-win scenario.
How?
I reprogrammed
the simulation
so it was possible
to rescue the ship.
What?
He cheated.
Changed the conditions
of the test.
Got a commendation
for original thinking.
I don't like to lose.
Then you never faced
that situation...
faced death.
I don't believe
in the no-win scenario.
Kirk to Spock.
It's two hours.
Are you ready?
Right on schedule.
Just give us your coordinates,
and we'll
beam you aboard.
All right.
I don't like to lose.
We were immobilized.
Captain Spock said
it would be two days.
You go by the book.
Spock, you know Dr. Marcus.
Of course.
Hello, Mr. Spock.
I'm taking them
to sickbay.
By the book?
By the book.
Regulation 46a-
"If transmissions are being
monitored during battle...
no uncoded messages
on an open channel."
You lied.
I exaggerated.
Hours instead of days.
Now we have minutes
instead of hours.
They're inoperative
below C-Deck.
What is working
around here?
Not much, Admiral.
We have partial main power.
That's it?
Best we can do
in two hours.
Admiral on the bridge.
Battle stations.
Tactical.
Uh-oh.
She can still outrun us
and outgun us,
But there is the Mutara Nebula
at 153 mark 4.
Scotty, can we make it inside?
The energizer's bypassed
like a Christmas tree,
so don't give me
too many bumps.
No promises.
On your way.
Trouble with
the nebula, sir,
is all that static
discharging gas
clouds our
tactical display.
Visual won't function,
and shields will be useless.
Sauce for the goose,
Mr. Saavik.
The odds will be even.
Alley clear, sir.
Repairing second.
Ready to fire away 1 .
There she is!
There she is.
Ahh.
Not so wounded
as we were led to believe.
So much the better.
Estimating nebula penetration
in 2.2 minutes.
Reliant is closing.
If they go in there,
we'll lose them.
Explain it to them.
That was close.
They just don't want us
going in there.
One minute
to nebula perimeter.
Why are we slowing?
We daren't follow them
into the nebula, sir.
Our shields
would be useless.
They are reducing speed.
Uhura, patch me in.
Aye, sir.
You're on, Admiral.
This is Admiral Kirk.
We tried it once
your way, Khan.
Are you game
for a rematch?
Khan.
I'm laughing at
the superior intellect.
Full impulse power.
No, sir!
You have Genesis.
You can have whatever you-
Full power!
Damn you!
I'll say this for him-
he's consistent.
We are now entering
the Mutara Nebula.
Emergency lights.
Oh!
Tactical.
Inoperative.
Raise the shields.
As I feared, sir-
not functional.
I'm reducing speed.
Target, sir.
Phaser lock
inoperative, sir.
Best guess, Mr. Sulu.
Fire when ready.
Oh!
Aft torpedoes, fire!
Hold your course.
Phasers starboard!
Aah!
Fire!
Damage, Mr. Scott.
Admiral, I've got to take
the mains off the line.
It's radiation...
Scotty.
Joachim.
Yours...
is a superior...
I shall avenge you.
Could you use
another hand, Admiral?
Man the weapons console,
Mr. Chekov.
Spock.
Sporadic energy readings,
port side aft.
Could be
an impulse turn.
He won't
break off now.
He followed me this far.
He'll be back.
But from where?
He's intelligent,
but not experienced.
His pattern indicates
two-dimensional thinking.
Full stop.
Full stop, sir.
Z minus
10,000 meters.
Stand by
photon torpedoes.
Torpedoes ready, sir.
Look sharp.
Fire.
Aah!
- Aah!
Uhura...
send to Commander, Reliant.
Prepare to be boarded.
Aye, sir.
Commander, Reliant.
This is Enterprise.
Surrender and prepare
to be boarded.
Enterprise to Reliant.
You are ordered to
surrender your vessel.
Respond.
Reliant. Come in, Reliant.
You are ordered to surrender
your vessel.
Enterprise to Reliant.
You are ordered to surrender
your vessel. Respond.
No, Kirk.
The game's not over.
To the last
I will grapple with thee.
Admiral.
Scanning an energy
source on Reliant.
A pattern I've
never seen before.
It's the Genesis wave.
What?
They're on a build-up
to detonation.
How soon?
We encoded four minutes.
We'll beam aboard
and stop it.
You can't.
Scotty, I need warp speed
in three minutes
or we're all dead.
No response, Admiral.
Scotty.
Mr. Sulu, get us out of here.
Best possible speed.
Aye, sir.
Are you out
of your Vulcan mind?
No human can tolerate
the radiation in there!
As you are so fond
of observing, Doctor,
I am not human.
You're not going in there.
Perhaps you're right.
What is
Mr. Scott's condition?
Well, I don't think
that he-
I'm sorry, Doctor.
I have no time
to discuss this logically.
Remember.
Spock! Get out of there!
Spock!
Spock, get out of there!
Time, from my mark.
2 minutes, 10 seconds.
Engine room...
what's happening?
Spock! Scotty...
Good God, man!
Get out of there!
No! Don't!
Spock! Spock!
Don't!
Time.
3 minutes, 30 seconds.
Distance from Reliant.
4,000 kilometers.
We're not going
to make it, are we?
No.
No, you can't get away.
From hell's heart,
I stab at thee.
For hate's sake,
I spit my last breath
at thee.
Sir, the mains
are back on line.
Bless you, Scotty.
Go, Sulu!
My God, Carol,
look at it.
Engine room.
Well done, Scotty.
Jim...
I think you'd better
get down here.
Bones?
Better hurry.
Saavik, take the con.
No! You'll flood
the whole compartment.
He'll die.
Sir, he's dead already.
It's too late.
Spock!
Ship...
out of danger?
Yes.
Don't grieve, Admiral.
It is logical.
The needs of the many
outweigh...
The needs of the few...
Or the one.
I never took
the Kobayashi Maru test...
until now.
What do you think
of my solution?
Spock...
I...
I have been...
and always
shall be...
your friend.
Live long...
and prosper.
No.
We are assembled here today
To pay final respects
to our honored dead.
And yet it should be noted
that in the midst
of our sorrow,
this death takes place
in the shadow of new life,
the sunrise of a new world,
a world
that our beloved comrade
gave his life to protect.
He did not feel
this sacrifice a vain
or empty one,
and we will not debate
his profound wisdom
at these proceedings.
Of my friend,
I can only say this-
of all the souls I have
encountered in my travels,
his was the most...
human.
Honors...
Hup.
Come.
I don't mean to intrude.
No, not at all.
I should be
on the bridge.
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
I poured myself a drink.
Would you like it?
Lieutenant Saavik
was right.
You never have
faced death.
No, not like this.
I haven't faced death.
I've cheated death.
I've tricked my way
out of death
and patted myself on the back
for my ingenuity.
I know nothing.
You knew enough
to tell Saavik
that how we faced death
is at least as important
as how we face life.
Just words.
But good words.
That's where ideas begin.
Maybe you should
listen to them.
I was wrong about you...
and I'm sorry.
Is that what
you came here to say?
Mainly.
And also that I'm...
proud.
Very proud...
to be your son.
Captain 's Log. Stardate 8141.6.
Starship Enterprise
departing for Ceti Alpha V
to pick up the crew
of U.S.S. Reliant.
All is well.
And yet
I can't help wondering
about the friend
I leave behind.
,'There are always
possibilities, ,'Spock said.
And if Genesis is indeed
life from death...
I must return
to this place again.
He's really not dead...
as long as
we remember him.
It's a far, far
better thing I do
than I have
ever done before.
A far better
resting place I go to
than I have ever known.
Is that a poem?
No.
Something Spock was trying
to tell me
on my birthday.
You OK, Jim?
How do you feel?
Young.
I feel young.
Space,
the final frontier.
These are
the continuing voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Her ongoing mission,
to explore
strange, new worlds,
to seek out new life forms
and new civilizations,
to boldly go
where no man has gone...
before.
Subtitled *** by Kurgan ***
Subtitles LoS PiRaTaS 2002
Quality warranty