Stardate 9521.6.
Captain's log U.S.S. Excelsior.
Hikaru Sulu commanding.
After three years I've concluded my first
assignment as master of this vessel -
- cataloguing gaseous planetary
anomalies in Beta Quadrant.
We're heading home
under full impulse power.
I'm pleased to report that ship and
crew have functioned well.
According to this, we've completed
our survey of the entire sector.
I have an energy wave at
240 degrees mark six port.
Visual!
My... God!
Shields. Shields!
She's not answering her helm.
Starboard thrusters.
Turn her into the wave.
Go to impulse power.
- Damage report.
- Checking all systems.
- That was no meteor shower.
- Negative, sir.
The sub-space shock-wave
originated at bearing 323.75.
Location... It's Praxis, sir.
It's a Klingon moon.
Praxis is their
key energy production facility.
Send to Klingon High Command. "This
is Excelsior, a Federation Starship."
"We have monitored
a large explosion in your sector."
- "Do you require assistance?"
- Aye, sir.
- Mr Vultane, any more data?
- I've confirmed Praxis' location, but...
- I cannot confirm Praxis' existence.
- On screen.
- Magnify.
- Computer enhancement.
- Praxis?
- What's left of it, sir.
Captain, I'm getting a message
from Praxis.
Let's have it.
This is Brigadier Kerla,
speaking for the High Command.
There has been an incident on Praxis.
However, everything is under control.
We have no need for assistance.
Obey treaty stipulations
and remain outside the Neutral Zone.
This transmission ends now.
- An incident?
- Do we report this, sir?
Are you kidding?
- What are we doing here?
- Maybe it's a retirement party.
That suits me. I just bought a boat.
I'm supposed to be chairing
a seminar at the Academy.
- Isn't this just for top brass?
- Where is Sulu?
Captain Sulu?
On assignment. Where's Spock?
This briefing is classified.
Ladies and gentlemen, the C-in-C.
As you were.
I'll break
this information down succinctly.
The Klingon empire
has 50 years of life left.
For full details, I'm turning this briefing
over to the Federation Special Envoy.
Good morning.
Two months ago a Federation Starship
monitored an explosion on Praxis.
We believe it was caused by over-mining
and insufficient safety precautions.
The moon's decimation means
a deadly pollution of their ozone.
They will have depleted
their oxygen supply in 50 Earth years.
Due to their enormous military budget -
- the Klingon economy doesn't have the
resources to combat this catastrophe.
Last month, at the behest of
the Vulcan Ambassador, -
- I opened a dialogue with Gorkon,
Chancellor of the Klingon High Council.
He proposes to
commence negotiations at once.
Negotiations for what?
The dismantling of our space stations
and bases along the Neutral Zone.
An end to 70 years of hostility,
which the Klingons can no longer afford.
Bill, are we talking about
mothballing the Starfleet?
Our exploration and scientific programs
would be unaffected, but...
I must protest!
To offer Klingons safe haven
within Federation space is suicide.
Klingons would become
the alien trash of the galaxy.
If we dismantle the fleet, -
- we'd be defenceless before
an aggressive species on our territory.
The opportunity here is
to bring them to their knees.
Then we'll be in a better position
to dictate terms.
- Sir...
- Captain Kirk?
The Klingons
have never been trustworthy.
I agree with Admiral Cartwright.
This is a terrifying idea.
It is imperative that we act now
to support the Gorkon initiative, -
- lest more conservative elements
persuade his empire -
- that it's better to attempt
a military solution and die fighting.
You, Captain Kirk,
are to be our first olive branch.
We are to rendezvous with the vessel
which is bringing Gorkon to Earth -
- and to escort him safely through
Federation space.
Me?
There are Klingons who feel the same
about the peace treaty as yourself, -
- but they'll think twice about attacking
the Enterprise under your command.
I have personally vouched for you
in this matter.
You have personally vouched...?
You will extend Chancellor Gorkon
full diplomatic courtesy, Captain.
- A full Ambassador is better equipped...
- If there's no further business...
...I wish you and your crew Godspeed.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
I remind you this meeting is classified.
I don't know whether to
congratulate you or not, Jim.
I wouldn't.
We volunteered?
There's an old Vulcan proverb.
"Only Nixon could go to China."
How could you vouch for me?
- That's arrogant presumption.
- My father requested that I open...
I know your father is the Vulcan
Ambassador, but you know how I feel.
- They're animals.
- Jim...
- There is an historic opportunity here.
- Don't believe them! Don't trust them.
- They're dying.
- Let them die.
Has it occurred to you that this crew is
due to stand down in three months?
We've done our bit for king and country.
You should have trusted me.
Control, this is S-D 103,
approach to Space dock. Over.
You are clear to deliver Captain Kirk
and party to N.C.C. 1701 Alpha.
- Captain on the bridge!
- As you were. Lieutenant...?
Val'eris, sir. We were told you needed
a helmsman, so I volunteered.
It is agreeable to see you again.
She was the first Vulcan to graduate
at the top of her class at the Academy.
- You must be very proud.
- I don't believe so, sir.
She's a Vulcan, alright.
Let's get this over with.
Departure stations.
- Scotty? Did you find the engine room?
- Right where I left it.
Stand by.
Uhura, get me the dock master.
Control tower reading, sir.
Control, this is Enterprise
requesting permission to depart.
This is Control. Permission to depart
granted. 30 seconds for port gates.
- Clear all moorings.
- Awaiting port gates from this mark.
- All lines clear.
- Aft thrusters.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
1 quarter impulse power.
Captain, regulations specify
thrusters only while in space dock.
Jim...
You heard the order, Lieutenant.
Aye, sir.
Captain's log. Stardate 9522.6.
I've never trusted Klingons,
and I never will.
I can never forgive them for
the death of my boy.
To escort the Chancellor of the Klingon
High Council to a peace summit -
- is problematic, at best.
Spock says this could be an historic
occasion. I'd like to believe him.
But how on Earth can history get past
people like me?
- Sorry.
- You could have knocked.
We are almost at the rendezvous, sir.
I thought that you would like to know.
Permission to speak freely, sir.
It is an honour to serve with you.
You piloted well out of space dock,
Lieutenant.
I've always wanted to try that.
You've done well, Val'eris.
As your sponsor at the Academy I've
followed your career with satisfaction.
And as a Vulcan,
you have exceeded my expectations.
I do not understand this representation.
It's a depiction
from ancient Earth mythology.
"The expulsion from Paradise."
- Why keep it in your quarters?
- To remind me that all things end.
It is of endings that I wish to speak.
Sir, I address you
as a kindred intellect.
Do you not recognise...
...that a turning point has been reached
in the affairs of the Federation?
History is replete with turning points.
You must have faith.
- Faith?
- The universe will unfold as it should.
- Is that logical? Surely we must...
- Logic, logic, logic.
Logic is the beginning of wisdom,
Val'eris. Not the end.
This will be my final voyage on board
this vessel as a member of her crew.
Nature abhors a vacuum.
I intend you to replace me.
I could only succeed you, sir.
Now hear this.
All officers to the bridge.
Klingon battle cruiser off the port bow.
All Officers to the bridge.
Captain on the bridge!
Shall we raise our shields, Captain?
I've never been this close.
The Chancellor is undoubtedly
awaiting our signal.
- Uhura, hailing frequencies.
- Aye, sir.
Right standard rudder.
Bring us alongside.
Z plus 5 degrees.
Channel is open, Captain.
This is the Starship Enterprise.
Captain James T. Kirk commanding.
This is Kronos One.
I am Chancellor Gorkon.
We've been ordered to escort you
to your meeting on Earth.
Thank you.
Would you and your party care to dine
this evening aboard the Enterprise -
- as guests of
the United Federation of Planets?
We would be delighted to accept
your gracious invitation.
We'll make arrangements to have you
beamed aboard at 19:30 hours.
I shall look forward to that.
I hope you're happy.
Captain! There is a supply of
Romulan ale aboard.
It might make
the evening pass more... smoothly.
Officer thinking, Lieutenant.
Guess who's coming to dinner.
Energize.
- Chancellor Gorkon.
- Captain Kirk.
May I present Captain Spock,
whom I believe you know.
Captain, face to face at last.
You have my thanks.
Chancellor.
Gentlemen.
This is my daughter, Azetbur...
My military advisor, Brigadier Kerla...
...and this is General Chang,
my chief of staff.
I have so wanted to meet you, Captain.
- I'm not sure how to take that.
- Sincere admiration, Kirk.
From one warrior to another.
Right...
This way. You might enjoy a brief tour.
- They all look alike.
- What about that smell?
You know only top of the line models
can even talk...
- You men have work?
- Yes, ma'am.
Then snap to it.
I offer a toast.
The undiscovered country.
- The future.
- The undiscovered country.
Hamlet, act 3, scene 1.
You have not experienced Shake-
speare until you've read him in Klingon.
Captain Kirk.
I thought Romulan ale was illegal.
An advantage of being 1,000 light
years from Federation headquarters.
To you, Chancellor Gorkon.
One of the architects of our future.
Chancellor!
Perhaps we are looking at
something of that future here.
Tell me, Captain Kirk. Would you
be willing to give up Starfleet?
The Captain feels that Starfleet's
mission has always been one of peace.
I wouldn't dispute my first officer.
Starfleet has always been...
There's no need to mince words.
In space, all warriors are cold warriors.
General,
are you fond of... Shakespeare?
We believe all planets have a sovereign
claim to inalienable human rights.
"Inalien..."
If you could only hear yourselves.
"Human rights."
Why, the very name is racist.
The Federation is
a "homo sapiens only" club.
Present company excepted, of course.
We know where this is leading -
the annihilation of our culture.
That's not true. No!
"To be or not to be"...That is the
question which preoccupies our people.
- We need breathing room.
- Earth. Hitler, 1938.
I beg your pardon?
Well...
I see we have a long way to go.
We must do this again sometime.
You don't trust me, do you?
I don't blame you.
If there is to be a brave new world, -
- our generation is going to have
the hardest time living in it.
- Captain Spock.
- Chancellor. Madam.
Captain.
Well, most kind.
Parting is such sweet sorrow.
Hmm, Captain?
"Have we not heard
the chimes at midnight?"
Thank God!
- Did you see the way they ate?
- Terrible table manners.
I doubt our own behaviour will distinguish
us in the annals of diplomacy.
I'm going to sleep this off. Is there any
other way we can screw up tonight?
I'm going to go find
a pot of black coffee.
The Enterprise hosted
Chancellor Gorkon to dinner last night.
Our manners
weren't exactly Emily Post.
To the galley - Romulan ale no longer
to be served at diplomatic functions.
Captain Kirk, will you please
join me on the bridge? Captain Kirk?
- Captain.
- What is it?
- I find this curious.
- Spock, I'm really tired.
We are reading an enormous amount of
neutron radiation.
- Where?
- It appears to emanate from us.
The Enterprise?
Val'eris, do you know anything about
a radiation surge? Chekov?
Only the size of my head.
I know what you mean.
- What's happened?
- We've fired on the Chancellor's ship.
Torpedo room!
Please confirm, have we fired?
- Uhura, monitor.
- Aye, sir.
- Direct hit.
- Confirmed, sir.
This is the bridge. Do you read me?
- Did we fire those torpedoes?
- Negative. We're still fully loaded.
Unable to confirm or deny
firing the torpedoes.
- Hailing frequencies.
- Aye, sir.
Kronos One, this is Enterprise.
Do you read?
It's very hard to make out. There's been
weapons firing and a lot of shouting.
- She's still listing.
- She's spinning out of control.
Have you not
a shred of decency in you, Kirk?
We come in peace,
and you blatantly defy that peace.
For that,
I shall blow you out of the stars.
- We haven't fired.
- Captain...
According to our data banks,
we have. Twice...
Captain, they're coming about.
- They're preparing to fire.
- Shields up, Captain?
- Captain, our shields.
Signal our surrender.
We surrender!
- This is Enterprise. We surrender.
- If they fire, with our shields down...
...we will not be able to respond.
- Repeat, Enterprise surrenders.
- Are we firing torpedoes?
- I wish I knew.
- I'm going aboard. Spock, take the con.
- I involved you, I will go.
No, I'll go. We'll not be the instigators
of war on the eve of universal peace.
I'm going too, they may need a doctor.
Uhura, tell them we're coming,
and tell them we're unarmed.
- Have you lost your mind?!
- I don't understand what's happened.
We're here to help.
Follow me.
- Chancellor Gorkon.
- My God! What has happened here?
- You dare to feign ignorance?
- What happened?
With a direct torpedo hit,
you crippled our gravitational field -
- and two of your Starfleet crew beamed
aboard wearing magnetic boots.
- Aren't you carrying a surgeon?
- We were until this disgrace.
Then for God's sake, let me help.
I've got a pulse - we can move him.
I need light. Put him on the table.
Hold him! Hold him while I stabilize him.
I said hold him!
Sweet Jesus.
- Can you...?
- I don't even know his anatomy.
- His wounds are not closing.
- He's killing him!
He's gone into
some kind of damned arrest.
Come on, dammit! Come on!
He's not responding.
Don't let it end this way, Captain.
Under article 184 of your
Interstellar Law...
...I'm placing you under arrest.
You're charged with assassinating
the Chancellor of the High Council.
He tried to save him.
They've been arrested.
Mr Spock, we've got to do something.
I assume command of this ship
as of 02:30 hours.
Commander Uhura, notify Starfleet
headquarters and request instructions.
We cannot allow them
to be taken to Kronos as prisoners.
Opening fire will not retrieve them,
and we must avoid an armed conflict.
We will be able to follow
the Captain's movements.
- How did you achieve this?
- Time is precious.
We must piece together
what happened here tonight.
According to our data bank,
this ship fired those torpedoes.
- No way!
- I sympathize, but we need evidence.
Please accompany me.
And if we cannot piece together
what happened? What then, sir?
In that case, Mr Chekov, it resides in
the purview of the diplomats.
The Chancellor of
the High Council is dead!
The result of an unprovoked attack -
- while he travelled to see you under
a flag of truce on a mission of peace!
Captain Kirk
was legally arrested for the crime.
He and Dr. McCoy boarded
Kronos One of their own free will.
- None of these facts are in dispute.
- I have ordered an investigation.
- In the meantime...
...we expect the Federation to abide by
the articles of Interstellar Law.
Kirk and Dr. McCoy will stand trial for
the assassination of Chancellor Gorkon.
Out of the question. Ambassador
Sarek, can we get them extradited?
Mr President, I share a measure of
personal responsibility in this matter, -
- but I am obliged to confirm my
esteemed colleagues legal interpretation.
What is the position of
the Romulan government?
I must concur with my colleagues.
You can't believe that Kirk assassinated
the Chancellor of the High Council.
Mr President.
I don't know what to believe.
I'm waiting for your answer, sir.
This President is not above the law.
Mr President, Starfleet command
is here from San Francisco.
- Mr President.
Bill, Admiral Cartwright,
please sit down.
Mr President, we cannot allow
Federation citizens to be abducted.
I'm constrained to observe
Interstellar Law.
Sir, would you please
take a look at this.
We prepared Operation Retrieve
based on the danger of terrorism -
- between the Klingon empire
and the Federation.
We can go in, rescue the hostages -
- and get out in 24 hours
with acceptable losses.
- We have the technology...
- Yes, yes.
But suppose you precipitate
a full-scale war?
Then, quite frankly,
we can clean their chronometers.
Mr President, they are vulnerable.
There will never be a better time.
The longer we wait, the less accessible
the hostages will be.
I'll bear that in mind. Thank you,
gentlemen, that's all for now.
Mr President.
Sir...
Those men have literally
saved this planet.
I know that.
And now they're going to save it again.
By standing trial.
Enterprise, report back
on the double. Do you read?
- We're to report back at once.
- We can't abandon Kirk and McCoy.
400 years ago, on Earth, workers
who felt their livelihood threatened -
- flung their wooden shoes called
"sabots" into the machines to stop them.
Hence the word "sabotage".
We experience technical malfunction.
All back-up systems inoperative.
Excellent. I mean... too bad.
Mr President, I have been named
chancellor in my father's place.
Madam Chancellor,
you have my condolences on your loss.
I assure you
that this shameful deed will not...
Let us come to the point. You want
this conference to go forward.
I will attend in one week,
on one condition.
We will not extradite the prisoners,
and you will not attempt to rescue them.
We would consider any such attempt
an act of war.
We hope you'll be our guest
here on Earth.
After recent events, you will
understand if I prefer a neutral site.
And in the interests of security, let us
keep the location secret for now.
As you wish, Madam Chancellor.
Your father was killed
for what he wanted.
The peace process will go forward.
Kirk...
Kirk will pay for my father's death.
It is as I said, Mr Spock.
Inventory registers every torpedo.
Yet the data banks insist we fired.
- One computer is lying.
- A computer doesn't lie!
Precisely. Therefore we must inspect
each torpedo visually.
That could take hours!
And if they're all there?
Then someone forged an entry
in the data banks.
Gorkon's daughter has been named
Chancellor. It was on the news.
I'll bet that bitch killed her father.
- Her own father?
- It is an old story, sir.
They don't place the same value on life
as we do, you know that.
Take my word,
she did not shed one bloody tear.
Hardly conclusive,
since Klingons have no tear-ducts.
Lieutenant, any response from Starfleet
since our dispatch?
Yes, sir.
And?
Commander Uhura is experiencing
technical difficulties, sir.
Curious. Very well.
For 24 hours, we will agree
this conversation didn't take place.
- A lie?
- An omission.
In 24 hours we won't have a clue
where Captain Kirk is.
- I know precisely where he will be.
- You do? Where?
Kirk, Kirk, Kirk, Kirk...
It's a damn show trial.
The Enterprise fired on Kronos One
without provocation.
The Chancellor and his advisors...
...having been lulled into
a false sense of security -
- by an invitation to a dinner
aboard Captain Kirk's vessel -
- at precisely 19:30 hours
that same evening.
Call your first witness.
After the first shot
we lost our gravitational field.
I was weightless and couldn't function.
Then two Starfleet crewmen
came towards me.
Or perhaps
they merely wore Starfleet uniforms.
That remark is speculative.
I move that it be stricken.
We're interested in facts, not theories.
If the gravitational unit was not
functioning, how could they walk?
They appeared to be wearing
magnetic boots.
- Gravity boots...?
- Dr. McCoy.
Would you be so good as to tell me -
- what is your current medical status?
Aside from a touch of arthritis,
I'd say pretty good.
You have a singular wit, Doctor.
For 27 years I've been surgeon
aboard the U.S.S. Enterprise.
In three months I stand down.
You know...
I believe that you consumed rather
a generous amount of Romulan ale -
- in the officers mess
on the night in question.
- Objection.
- Sustained.
We all did. All of us.
That doesn't mean...
Was Chancellor Gorkon alive
when you first examined him?
Barely.
Now be careful, Doctor.
Have you ever in your past -
- saved patients as barely alive as he?
I didn't have the medical knowledge
I needed for Klingon anatomy.
- I see.
- You where there.
You say you are due for retirement.
May I ask, do your hands shake?
- Objection!
- I was nervous.
No. You were incompetent.
You were incompetent!
Whether deliberately or as a result of
age combined with drink.
- The court will have to determine.
- My God, man. I tried to save him!
I tried to save him.
I was desperate to save him.
He was the last best hope
in the Universe for peace.
The witness is excused.
There we have it, citizens. We have
established the particulars of the crime.
And now we come to the architect of
this tragic affair.
James Tiberius Kirk.
What would your favourite author say,
Captain?
"Let us sit upon the ground and tell
sad stories of the death of kings."
Tell us your sad story, Kirk.
Tell us that you planned to take
revenge for the death of your son.
- That's not true.
- Objection!
Captain Kirk has not been identified
as the assassin.
I offer into the record this excerpt
from the Captain's personal log.
I've never trusted Klingons,
and I never will.
I've never been able to forgive them
for the death of my boy.
I've never trusted Klingons,
and I never will.
I've never been able to forgive them
for the death of my boy.
Are those your words?
Those words were spoken by me.
Objection! My client's political views
are not on trial.
On the contrary. Captain Kirk's views
are at the very heart of the matter.
His record shows him to be an
insubordinate, unprincipled opportunist -
- with a history of violating the chain of
command whenever it suited him.
Continue.
The record shows that Captain Kirk
once held the rank of Admiral -
- and he was broken for taking matters
into his own hands.
Do you deny being demoted for
these charges. Answer me now!
- I cannot deny it.
- You were demoted?
- For insubordination?
- On occasion, I have disobeyed orders.
Were you obeying
or disobeying orders -
- when you arranged the assassination
of Chancellor Gorkon?
I didn't know about it
until we boarded the ship.
You still deny the Enterprise
fired on Kronos One?
And you still deny your men beamed
aboard and shot the Chancellor?
I cannot confirm or deny
actions which I didn't witness.
Are you aware
that as the captain of a ship, -
- you are responsible for
the actions of your men?
I am.
If it's proved that members of your
crew carried out the assassination...
- They're setting us up. Your Honours!
- Do not answer.
Captain Kirk,
you will answer the question.
As Captain...
...I'm responsible for
the crew under my command.
Your Honours, the state rests.
Send to Commander Enterprise.
"We stand ready to assist you.
Captain Sulu, U.S.S. Excelsior."
It is the determination of this court that
the prisoners are guilty as charged.
I wish to note for the record that
all the evidence is circumstantial.
I beg the court to consider this
when pronouncing its sentence.
So noted.
Captain James T. Kirk,
Dr. Leonard McCoy.
In the interest of fostering amity -
- for the forthcoming peace talks,
the sentence of death is commuted.
It is the judgement of this court -
- that, without possibility
of reprieve or parole, -
- you be taken from this place
to the dilithium mines -
- on the penal asteroid of Rura Penthe.
There to spend the rest of
your natural lives.
Rura Penthe!
Known throughout the galaxy as
the alien's graveyard.
Better to kill them now
and get it over with.
Lieutenant.
The torpedo hit once again, please.
Hold.
It is Enterprise. We fired.
That is not possible! All weapons
visually accounted for, sir.
An ancestor of mine maintained -
- that if you eliminate the impossible,
whatever remains must be the truth.
What does that mean?
That if we cannot have fired
those torpedoes, someone else did.
They didn't fire on themselves
and there are no other ships present.
- There was a neutron surge.
- Not from us.
A neutron surge that big
could only be produced by another ship.
- Kronos One?
- Too far away.
Very near us. Possibly beneath us.
If there were a ship beneath us,
the Klingons would have seen it.
Would they?
- A Bird of Prey?
- A Bird of Prey.
- Cloaked?
- They can't fire when they're cloaked.
All things being equal, I would agree.
However, things are not equal.
This one can.
- We must inform Starfleet Command.
- Of what?
A new weapon that's invisible?
They'll call us raving lunatics.
They'll say we'll say anything
to exonerate the Captain.
And they would be correct.
We have no evidence.
Only a theory
which happens to fit the facts.
Assuming you're right. Why would they
fire on their own President?
Indeed.
This ship will be searched
from bow to stern.
I do not understand.
If there was a ship underneath us -
- surely the assassins beamed aboard
from that vessel, not Enterprise.
You're forgetting something,
Mr Chekov.
According to our data banks,
this ship fired those torpedoes.
If we did, the killers are here.
If we did not,
whoever altered the data banks is here.
In either case,
what we are looking for is here.
- What are we looking for, sir?
- Lieutenant.
Two pairs of gravity boots.
This is the gulag Rura Penthe.
There is no stockades,
no guard tower, no electronic frontier.
Only a magnetic shield
prevents beaming.
Punishment means exile
from prison to the surface.
On the surface, nothing can survive.
Work well, and you will be treated well.
Work badly, and you will die.
Oh, my God!
The universal translator
has been confiscated.
I'm sorry...?
He's definitely on about something, Jim.
If this is your spot, we'll move on.
He wants your obedience to
the Brotherhood of Aliens.
- He's got it.
- And your coat.
I'm afraid not. It wouldn't fit.
- Thanks.
- This will help keep you warm.
- I'm Martia. You're Kirk and McCoy.
- How did you know that?
We don't get many
presidential assassins.
- We didn't kill Gorkon.
- Of course not.
- But there's a reward for your death.
- That figures.
We've been set up.
Somebody up there
wants you out of the way.
- Any progress?
- None.
A crew of 300 are looking everywhere,
but the killers may still be among them.
Surely they have disposed of
these boots by now.
Would it not have been logical
to leave them on Gorkon's ship?
Logic must give way to physics. Gravity
wasn't restored when they escaped.
Without the boots, they would have
floated off the transporter pads.
Why not simply vaporize them?
Like this?
As you know, no one can fire an
unauthorized phaser aboard a starship.
Suppose, when they returned,
they threw the boots into the refuse.
I'm having the refuse searched.
If I'm correct, those boots will cling to
the killer's necks like Tiberian bats.
They couldn't escape without them
nor throw them out the window.
Those boots are here. Somewhere.
- Did someone fire off a phaser?
- It's alright. It's nothing.
Mr Spock, Starfleet is screaming for us
to return to port.
- Who fired the...
- Ah, Mr Scott.
I hear you have difficulty with the warp
drive. How long do you need for repair?
There's nothing wrong
with the bloody thing.
If we return to space dock, the killers
can dispose of their footwear -
- and we will never see the Captain
or Dr. McCoy alive again.
- It could take weeks.
- Thank you.
Val'eris, inform Starfleet
our warp drive is inoperative.
- A lie?
- An error.
We have lost all contact
with the Captain and Dr. McCoy.
Yes, at the moment they're surrounded
by a magnetic shield.
But if I know the Captain,
he is deep into planning his escape.
You've got him
where you want him, Jim!
- Are you alright?
- I think so.
- They'll respect you now.
- I was lucky that thing had knees.
That was not his knee.
Not everybody keep their genitals
in the same place, Captain.
Anything you want to tell me?
See what you can do for him. Let him
know we're not holding a grudge.
Suppose he's holding a grudge?
When whoever it is makes their move,
you won't be here to ask if he's the one.
- Do you want to get out of here?
- There's got to be a way.
Three months before retirement.
What a way to finish.
- We're not finished.
- Speak for yourself.
One day, one night... Kobayashi Maru!
Bones! Are you afraid of the future?
I believe that was the general idea
that I was trying to convey.
- I don't mean this future.
- What is this - multiple choice?
Some people are afraid...
of what might happen.
- I was terrified.
- What terrified you, specifically?
No more Neutral Zone.
I was used to hating Klingons.
It never even occurred to me
to take Gorkon at his word.
- Spock was right.
- We all felt exactly the same.
No. Somebody felt a lot worse.
I'm beginning to understand why.
If you've got any bright ideas,
now is the time.
Time is the problem.
You and I are nothing.
You heard the judge -
the peace conference is on again.
Whoever killed Gorkon is bound to
attempt another assassination.
Unless we can get out of here.
It's me - Martia. Listen. No one has ever
escaped from Rura Penthe.
- Except us.
- It is possible.
I know how to get outside the shield.
- How do we fit in?
- Getting outside the shield is easy.
After that, you have to get us off the
surface before we freeze. Can you?
- It's possible.
- I can't make it alone.
You're the likeliest candidate
to come here for months.
Candidate for what?
Go to lift 7 in the morning
for mining duty. I'll see you there.
Don't disappoint me.
- What is it with you, anyway?
- Still think we're finished?
More than ever.
Sorry to wake you, sir.
Starfleet requests any data we have on
the whereabouts of Enterprise.
What?
They're refusing to acknowledge
signal to return to space dock, sir.
Signal Starfleet that we have no idea
location Enterprise.
- Sir?
- You have hearing problems?
No, sir.
Klingon blood.
They must have walked through it when
it was floating and tracked it back here.
This is the first evidence
which corroborates our theory.
Now we go to Starfleet?
We expand our search
to include uniforms.
All uniforms?
Clear, sir. Make a hole.
Coming through. Coming through.
Sir! Sir!
- I think we've been had.
- No, you weren't, Doctor.
Get off at the first level.
Follow the gang into the mine.
They don't take girls.
- You are crewman Dax?
- Yes. What is the problem?
Perhaps you know
the Russian epic of Cinderella?
If shoe fits - wear it.
Mr Chekov...
Watch me.
What kind of creature is this?
Last night you two were...
Get in.
Come on. We don't have a lot of time.
Hurry!
Up there.
Come on - climb!
Here, you'll need these. Quickly!
Stay close.
- There they are.
- They emerge from the beaming shield.
Mr Scott, start your engines.
Mr Chekov, set course for Rura Penthe.
Mr Spock, Rura Penthe is deep inside
the Klingon frontier.
- If we're discovered...
- Correct.
We need a feat of linguistic legerdemain
and intrepidity -
- before the Captain and Dr. McCoy
freeze to death.
- Leave me, I'm finished.
- No!
Bones, I'm wearing
a viridium patch on my back.
Spock slapped it there
before we went on Gorkon's ship.
That cunning little Vulcan.
Come on! We're in the clear.
Now that we're outside the shield,
they can locate us two sectors away.
If they're even looking for us.
We must respond. A universal
translator would be recognised.
"What is your destination, over?"
Would you mind explaining
that little trick you do?
- I'm a Chameloid.
- I've heard about you.
Shape-shifters.
I thought you were mythical.
Give a girl a chance, Captain.
It takes a lot of effort.
I don't doubt it.
Stop me if I'm wrong, -
- but do we have any way of knowing
whether this is the real you?
I thought I would assume
a pleasing shape.
We're outside the shield.
Now it's your turn, Captain.
If you say so.
Are you crazy?!
She didn't need our help. Where did you
get these convenient clothes?
Don't tell me that flare
is standard prison issue.
It's to let them know where we are.
Ask her what she's getting in return.
A full pardon... which doesn't cover this.
An accident wasn't good enough.
Come on, Spock.
Good enough for one.
Two would have looked suspicious.
Killed while attempting escape.
That's convincing for both.
Surprise!
- Your friends are late.
- They'll be along.
- I can't believe I kissed you.
- Must have been your lifelong ambition.
Isn't it time you became
something else?
I like it here.
Well, well, well...
What took you so long?
Kill him, he's the one.
Not me, you idiot - him!
- No witnesses.
- Killed while trying to escape.
- Damned clever, if you ask me.
- It's a classic.
- That's what he wanted.
- Who? Who wanted us killed?
Since you're all going to die anyway,
why not tell you?
His name is...
Damn it! What the hell! Son of a...!
Couldn't you have waited two seconds?
He was about to explain
the whole thing.
- You want to go back?
- Absolutely not!
This is the bridge.
We're still in Klingon space.
Deck 9, remain at battle stations.
The Klingons have a Bird of Prey
that can fire while cloaked.
- She torpedoed Gorkon's ship.
- So that's it.
We believe that Gorkon's murderers
are aboard this ship.
- Has the peace conference begun?
- Who knows? The location is secret.
- There's always something.
- Captain! Mr Spock!
I found the uniforms
with the Klingon blood on them.
But the uniforms belong to
these two men. Burke and Samno.
Not anymore.
Phaser on "stun" at close range.
First rule of assassination -
kill the assassins.
- Now we're back to square one.
- Can I talk to you?
- Why weren't they vaporized?
- It would set off the alarm.
It's possible.
Now hear this. Now hear this.
Court reporter to sick bay.
Code blue - urgent.
Statements to be taken at once
from Yeomen Burke and Samno.
Repeat, court reporter to sick bay.
Code blue - urgent.
Statements to be taken.
Repeat, statements to be taken from
Yeomen Burke and Samno.
You have to shoot.
If you are logical, you have to shoot.
- I do not want to.
- What you want is irrelevant.
What you've chosen is at hand.
I'd just as soon you didn't.
The operation is over.
I did not fire.
You cannot prove anything.
Yes, I can. At my trial my personal log
was used against me.
How long did you wait outside
my quarters before I noticed you?
You knew?
I tried to tell you,
but you would not listen.
Neither of us was hearing very well
that night.
There were things I tried to tell you,
about having faith.
You have betrayed the Federation.
All of you.
- And what have you've been doing?
- Saving Starfleet.
Klingons cannot be trusted. Sir...
You said so yourself.
They killed your son.
Did you not wish Gorkon dead?
"Let them die", you said.
Did I misinterpret you?
And you were right.
They conspired with us to assassinate
their own Chancellor.
How trustworthy can they be?
Klingons and Federation members
conspiring together.
- Who is "us"?
- All who stands to lose from peace.
Names, Lieutenant.
My comrades will make certain
all your transmissions are jammed.
- Names, Lieutenant!
- I do not remember.
A lie?
A choice.
Spock.
Admiral Cartwright.
From Starfleet?
Who else?
General... Chang.
- Who else?
- Romulan Ambassador and others.
Where is the peace conference?
She does not know.
Then we're dead.
I have been dead before.
Contact Excelsior.
- She'll have the co-ordinates.
- I've already got it, sir.
- Standing by, Captain Kirk.
- Sulu.
You realize that by even talking to us,
you're violating regulations.
I'm sorry, Captain.
Your message is breaking up.
Bless you, Sulu.
Where is the peace conference?
They'll attempt another assassination.
It's at Camp Khitomer,
near the Romulan border.
I'm sending the co-ordinates on
a coded frequency.
We'll need more than that.
There's a Bird of Prey on the look-out
for us that can fire while cloaked.
Surely not.
How many of those things are there?
Come on, Lieutenant.
- Just the prototype.
- Do you hear that?
I'm getting under way now.
We're in Alpha Quadrant.
The chances of our reaching
the conference in time are slim.
- When does this conference start?
- According to my information - today.
- Thank you, Captain Sulu.
- Don't mention it, Captain Kirk.
Spock?
I prefer it dark.
- Dining on ashes?
- You were right.
It was arrogant presumption on my part
that got us into this situation.
You and the Doctor
might have been killed.
The night is young.
You said it yourself, it was logical.
Peace is worth a few personal risks.
You're a great one for logic.
I'm a great one for rushing in
where angels fear to tread.
We're both extremists. Reality is
probably somewhere in between.
I couldn't get past the death of my son.
I was prejudiced by her
accomplishments as a Vulcan.
Gorkon had to die before I understood
how prejudiced I was.
Is it possible...
...that we two, you and I,
have grown so old and inflexible -
- that we have outlived our usefulness?
Would that constitute a joke?
- It wasn't your fault.
- I was responsible.
- For no actions but your own.
- That's not what you said at your trial.
That was as captain of the ship.
Human beings...
We both know that I am not human.
Do you want to know something?
Everybody's human.
I find that remark... insulting.
Come, I need you.
Madam Chancellor,
members of the diplomatic corps...
...honoured guests.
The United Federation of Planets
welcomes you to Camp Khitomer.
She's out here somewhere.
- But if she's cloaked...
- Then all we have is a radiation surge.
By the time we're close enough
to record it, we're ashes.
2.06...
2.03...
- Close enough to beam down?
- Not yet. In two minutes. 1.58.
Go to impulse power for Khitomer.
Let us redefine progress to mean that
just because we can do a thing -
- it does not necessarily follow
that we must do that thing.
- Uhura?
- Nothing, Captain.
If she's here,
she's rigged for silent running.
Coming up on transporter range
in 57 seconds.
Transporter room.
Stand by to beam down.
53...
48 seconds.
44...
I can see you, Kirk.
Chang.
Can you see me?
Now be honest, Captain.
Warrior to warrior.
You do prefer it this way, don't you?
As it was meant to be.
No peace in our time.
"Once more unto the breach,
dear friends."
- This is fun.
- Reverse engines. All astern.
One and a half impulse power. Back off!
What's she waiting for?
Probably attempting to ascertain
why we are reversing.
Wondering whether we detect her.
Incoming!
- In range?
- Not yet, sir.
Come on!
- She'll fly apart.
- Fly her apart, then!
Many speculated about
my father's motives.
Some said he was an idealist.
Others said he had no choice.
If Praxis had not exploded, his idealism
wouldn't have found expression.
We are a proud race.
We are here because we intend
to go on being proud.
- Go to auxiliary power!
- Auxiliary circuits destroyed.
"Tickle us, do we not laugh?
Prick us, do we not bleed?"
"Wrong us, shall we not revenge?"
Gas.
Gas, Captain. Under impulse power
she expands fuel, like all vessels.
We call it "plasma",
but it is merely ionised gas.
What about our equipment
to catalogue gaseous anomalies?
The thing's got to have a tail-pipe.
Doctor, would you assist me
in performing surgery on a torpedo?
Fascinating.
Hard to starboard.
The proposed agenda is as follows:
The evacuation of Kronos -
- has been calculated
within the 50 Earth year time span.
Phase 1 - preparation for evacuation...
Captain, she's packing quite a wallop.
Shields weakening.
Shields up! Alright, now we're giving
them something else to shoot at.
The game's afoot.
- Excelsior's been hit!
- "Our revels now are ended", Kirk.
"Cry havoc,
and let slip the dogs of war."
- Bones, where's my torpedo?
- Bet you wished you'd stayed in bed.
Shields collapsing!
The key, please. Time is short.
- The hull has been compromised.
- I wonder how bad.
Connect echo-bars.
...discuss the report on phase 2.
- Alter circuit A.
- Sensor.
...we commence
within minutes of the preparation.
- "I am constant as the Northern star."
- I'd give real money, if he'd shut up.
Plate, please.
...and assimilation will consume...
We've got a heart beat.
...with the Klingon Empire...
Key, please.
- Where's that torpedo?
- She's ready.
Lock and load!
Fire!
"To be... or not"...
..."to be."
Target that explosion and fire.
Fire!
This work will occupy us
throughout most of the week.
I hope that the delegation -
- can implement the provisions
of Phase 1 by the first of next month.
As you know, time is of the essence.
Out of the way!
Mr President!
Kirk, Enterprise.
- Arrest those men!
- Arrest yourself!
We've got a full confession.
- This is not Klingon blood.
- Cartwright. Just a minute.
It's Colonel West!
What's happened?
What's the mean of all of this?
It's about the future, Madam Chancellor.
Some people think
the future means the end of history.
We haven't run out of history quite yet.
Your father called the future...
..."the undiscovered country".
People can be
very frightened of change.
You've restored my father's faith.
And you've restored my son's.
Once again, we've saved civilization
as we know it.
And they're not going to prosecute.
They could have prosecuted me.
I felt like Val'eris.
They don't arrest people
for having feelings.
And it's a good thing, too. If they did,
we'd all have to turn ourselves in.
- Captain Kirk.
- Captain Sulu.
As much to the crew of the Enterprise,
I owe you my thanks.
Nice to see you in action one more
time, Captain Kirk. Take care.
- My God, that's a big ship.
- Not so big as her captain.
So... This is goodbye?
It's about time
we got underway ourselves.
Captain, I have orders
from Starfleet Command.
We're to put back to space dock
immediately... to be decommissioned.
If I were human,
I believe my response would be:
"Go to hell."
If I were human.
Course heading, Captain?
Second star to the right.
And straight on 'til morning.
Captain's log, stardate 9529.1.
This is the final cruise of the Starship
Enterprise under my command.
This ship, and her history -
- will shortly become
the care of another crew.
To them and their posterity
will we commit our future.
They'll continue the voyages
we have begun -
- and journey
to all the undiscovered countries -
- boldly going where no man,
where no one...
...has gone before.
DVDRIP by Feedback Overflow.