Subtitles provider:
Sibirski
I thought weapons were forbidden
on this planet.
Besides...
..I can't believe you'd kill me
for a field of empty holes.
It's all I have.
- Your pain runs deep.
- What do you know of my pain?
Let us explore it...together.
Each man hides a secret pain.
It must be exposed and reckoned with.
It must be dragged
from the darkness into the light.
Share your pain.
Share your pain with me
and gain strength from the sharing.
Where did you get this power?.
The power was within you.
It is as if a weight
has been lifted from my heart.
- How can I repay you?
- Join my quest.
- What is it you seek?.
- What you seek.
What all men have sought
since time began.
The ultimate knowledge.
To find it we need a starship.
A starship? There are
no starships on Nimbus Ill.
- I have a way to bring one here.
- But how?.
Have faith, my friend.
There are more of us than you know.
You're a Vulcan.
'You'll have a great time
on shore leave, Bones."
'You'll be able to relax."
You call this relaxing?
I'm a nervous wreck.
If I'm not careful,
I'll end up talking to myself.
Greetings, Captain.
- Spock, what are you doing here?
- I'm monitoring your progress.
I'm flattered, but of all the
points of interest here why pick me?
The record for climbing EI Capitan
is in no danger of being broken.
I'm doing this because I enjoy it.
Not to mention the most important
reason for climbing a mountain...
Because it's there.
I do not think you realise
the gravity of your situation.
On the contrary,
gravity is foremost on my mind.
I'm trying to make an ascent.
Go pester Dr McCoy.
Dr McCoy is not in the best of moods.
Goddamn irresponsible...!
Playing games with life.
Concentration is vital.
You must be one with the rock.
If you don't stop distracting me...
Perhaps "because it is there" is not
sufficient reason to climb a mountain.
I am hardly in a position to disagree.
Hi, Bones.
Mind if we drop in for dinner?.
I am Caithlin Dar.
Yes! Our new Romulan representative.
Welcome to Paradise City,
capital of the Planet of Galactic Peace.
I'm St John Talbot, the Federation
Representative here on Nimbus Ill.
My charming companion
is the Klingon Consul, Korrd.
- I expect that's Klingon for hello.
- Come in, my dear.
20 years ago, our three governments
agreed to develop this planet.
- A new age was born.
- It died a quick death.
The settlers we conned
into coming here took to fighting.
We forbad them weapons,
but they fashioned their own.
It appears I've arrived just in time.
Get away from that transmitter.
Romulan.
Terran.
Klingon.
- Consider yourselves my prisoners.
- Prisoners?
We're already prisoners here
on this worthless lump of rock.
- What value could we be to you?
- Nimbus Ill is a worthless lump of rock.
But it is the only place in the galaxy
that has the three of you.
Our governments will stop at nothing
to ensure our safety.
That's exactly what I'm counting on.
USS Enterprise,
shakedown cruise report.
I think this new ship
was put togetherbymonkeys.
Halfthe doors won't open, and guess
whosejob itis to make itright?
Borgus frat!
"Let's see what she's got, Scotty."
We found out, didn't we?
- I know you'll whip her into shape.
- Uhura, I thought you were on leave.
- I thought we were going together.
- I can't leave her when she needs me.
I had a feeling you would
say something like that.
So I brought us dinner.
You're the most understanding woman
I know.
Red alert.
I just fixed that damn thing!
Turn it off, will you?
Red alert.
This is a red alert.
Enterprise, acknowledge.
This is Enterprise. Identify yourself.
This is Starfleet. We have a Priority 7
situation in the NeutraIZone.
- Scotty, this is for real.
- They can't be serious!
The ship's in pieces and we've got
less than a skeleton crew.
Starfleet, are you aware
of our current status?
Yes. Stand by to copy operational
orders and recall key personnel.
- Admit it, we're lost.
- Yes, but we're making good time.
- Commander Sulu, come in.
- I don't believe this.
Shore leave is cancelled.
- Rescued at last.
- Return to pre-arranged co-ordinates.
- You can't say we're lost.
- Is there a problem?
Yes. We've been caught in...a blizzard.
We can't see a thing.
Direct us to the co-ordinates.
My visual says
sunny skies and 70 degrees.
Look, the sun has come out.
It's a miracle.
Don't worry, your secretis safe
with me. I'll send the shuttle foryou.
Uhura, I owe you one.
Come and get it!
Bones, knock it off.
We're right here and we're starving.
- Bipodal seeds, Doctor?.
- Beans, Spock, but no ordinary beans.
These are from an old recipe
handed down to me by my father.
If you stick your Vulcan nose
up at these,
you're insulting
generations of McCoys.
In that case I have little choice
but to sample your beans.
Surprisingly good. It does have
a flavouring I'm not familiar with.
- That's the secret ingredient.
- Any more secret ingredient, Bones?
Be my guest.
- Your secret ingredient is alcohol?
- Tennessee whiskey.
Bourbon and beans, an explosive
combination. Can Spock handle it?
With that Vulcan metabolism,
he could eat a bowl of termites.
- Doctor, I am half-human.
- It certainly doesn't show.
- Thank you.
- This guy never changes.
I insult him
and he takes it as a compliment.
- You two could drive a man to drink.
- What did I do?
Human life is far too precious
to risk on crazy stunts.
You should have been killed
when you fell off that mountain.
It did cross my mind.
But even as I fell
I knew I wouldn't die.
- Isn't he the only one who's immortal?
- No, it isn't that.
I knew I wouldn't die
because the two of you were with me.
- I do not understand.
- I've always known...
..l'll die alone.
I'll call Valhalla
and reserve a room for you.
All that time in space,
getting on each other´s nerves...
So what do we do on shore leave?
We spend it together.
- Other people have families.
- Other people, not us.
What are you doing?
I'm preparing to toast a "marsh melon".
I'll be damned! A marsh melon.
Where did you learn to do that?
I have familiarised myself with the
customs associated with camping out.
What do we do
after we toast the marsh melon?
- We consume them.
- No, I mean after that.
We are required to engage in a ritual
known as the sing-along.
I haven't sung around the campfire
since I was a boy in lowa.
What are we going to sing?
- "Camptown Races."
- "Pack up your troubles."
- Are we leaving?
- It's a song title.
- "Moon over Rigel 7."
- "Row, row, row your boat."
- Do you know "Row your boat"?
- It didn't come up in my research.
The lyrics are very simple...
"Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream.
"Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily,
life is but a dream."
The Doctor and I will start off
and you jump in.
- Doctor, if you please.
- Don't say I didn't warn you.
- Spock, why didn't you jump in?
- I cannot comprehend the words.
It's a song, you green-blooded Vulcan.
The words aren't important.
- You just have a good time singing.
- I am sorry, Doctor.
- Were we having a good time?
- I liked him better before he died.
Let's just get some sleep.
- Captain...
- We're on leave. Call me Jim.
- Jim...
- Yes, Spock?.
Life is not a dream.
- Go to sleep, Spock.
- Yes, Captain.
- Good night, Bones.
- Good night, Jim.
- Good night, Spock.
- Good night, Doctor.
- Good night, Jim.
I don't know. I just don't know.
Captain Klaa, we have the target
in sight. A probe ofancient origin.
- Difflcult to hit?
- Most difflcult.
Good.
All weapons atmy control.
Scope.
Shooting space garbage
is no test ofa warrior's mettle.
I need a target thatfilghts back.
Captain, new data,
hostages on Nimbus Ill.
- One ofthe hostages is a Klingon.
- And the others?
A Terran and a Romulan.
The Federation will be sending
a rescue ship ofits own.
Plot course forNimbus Ill.
I've always wanted to engage
a Federation ship.
Get the damn light out of my face.
We had to send the shuttlecraft.
The transporter is non-operational.
- We have received new orders.
- I had my communicator.
- You forgot to take it with you.
- I wonder why I did that.
It appears shore leave has been
cancelled. Pack out your trash.
"All I ask is a tall ship
and a star to steer her by."
- Melville.
- John Masefield.
- Are you sure about that?
- I'm well-versed in the classics.
Then how come you don't know
"Row, row, row your boat"?
- Enterprise, you have control.
- We're doing just fine.
All I can say is
they don't make them like they used to.
You told me you could have
this ship operational in two weeks.
I think you gave me too much time.
How many times do I have to tell you?
The right tool for the right job.
I've never seen him happier.
Bridge...l hope.
I could use a shower.
Yes.
- Doesn't anything work on this ship?
- They can't send us out like this.
- Starfleet transmission on line.
- Put it on the view screen.
Can we have a little quiet, please?
Can you clear that up?
Can we have a little quiet?
- Bob!
- Jim!
- We are dressing informally.
- I'm on my way to the shower.
I apologise for cancelling shore leave.
We have a dangerous situation
out on Nimbus III.
On the Planet of Galactic Peace?
A terroristforce
has captured the only settlement.
They've taken hostages. The Klingon,
the Romulan, the Federation Consuls.
- The Enterprise is not up to specs...
- The Enterprise is a disaster.
- We have ships in the quadrant.
- Butno experienced commanders.
- I need Jim Kirk.
- Please!
Proceed to Nimbus Ill
and assess the situation.
Avoid a confrontation.
Above all, however,
get those hostages back safely.
- Have the Klingons responded?
- No, butyou can bet they will.
- Plot a course for Nimbus Ill, Mr Sulu.
- Course plotted.
I'm afraid the ship's problems
will have to be solved en route.
I'm counting on each one of you
to give his best. Let's go to work.
Jim, if you ask me,
and you haven't...
I think this is a terrible idea.
We're bound to bump into the Klingons.
- And they don't exactly like you.
- The feeling's mutual.
Engine room, we'll need all the power
you can muster, mister.
We'll beat those Klingon devils
even if I have to get out and push.
I hope it won't come to that.
- All possible speed, Mr Sulu.
- Aye, sir.
- What's the matter?.
- I miss my old chair.
The starship Enterprise
has been dispatched to Nimbus Ill.
Enterprise?
That's Kirk's ship!
Ifl could defeatKirk...
You would be the greatest warrior
in the galaxy.
Maximum speed! Success!
Captain's log: Stardate 84...
- Good morning, Captain.
- Forget it.
- We have the hostage information.
- Put it on the screen.
This is an authorised transmission
from the Starfleetmemorybank.
- Not General Korrd!
- He's apparently fallen from favour.
Korrd's military strategies
were required learning at the Academy.
When they put me out to pasture,
I hope I fair better than Korrd.
This must be the hostage tape.
A short time ago, we surrendered
to the Galactic Army ofLight.
We are now in the protective custody
oftheir leader.
We will be treated humanely
as long as we cooperate.
He requests thatyou send a starship
to parley for our release at once.
We are in good health and would
appreciate your immediate response.
I regret this desperate act,
but these are desperate times.
I mean no harm to these innocents,
but do notputme to the test.
I implore you to respond immediately.
What is it?
- You look like you've seen a ghost.
- Perhaps I have, Captain.
Spock, what is it?
Do you know this Vulcan?
- I cannot be certain.
- But he does seem familiar?.
He reminds me of someone
I knew in my youth.
- I didn't know you had one.
- I do not often think of the past.
- Who does he remind you of?
- A gifted young student.
He possessed a great intelligence.
It was assumed that he would join
the great scholars of Vulcan.
- But he was a revolutionary.
- What do you mean?
The knowledge he sought
was forbidden by Vulcan belief.
- Forbidden?
- He rejected his logical upbringing.
He embraced the animal passions
of our ancestors.
He believed the key to self-knowledge
was emotion...not logic.
Imagine that, a passionate Vulcan.
When he encouraged others to follow
him, he was banished from Vulcan.
Fascinating.
- Captain to the bridge.
- On my way.
- Spock?.
- Coming, Captain.
- Approaching Nimbus Ill.
- Standard orbit, Mr Sulu.
Paradise City is demanding
to know our intentions.
Respond with static.
Let them think we're having difficulty.
Paradise City, we are barely
receiving your transmission.
- Transporter room, status.
- Transporter is still inoperative.
If we could lock on to the hostages,
we couldn't beam them up.
- We'll have to get them out ourselves.
- Klingon vessel approaching.
Bird of Prey.
1 .9 hours till her weapons are in range.
Damn! Let's go.
Their scanning equipment
is primitive, but effective.
- Land at co-ordinate 856.3.
- That's far from the city.
- We cannot risk detection.
- Mr Sulu, execute.
- This is the starship Enterprise.
- A Federation starship.
This is Captain Pavel Chekov.
You are in violation ofour treaty.
Release your hostages at once
orsuffer the consequences.
Your threats amuse me.
What consequences?
A Klingon warship
will arrive within the hour.
- The Klingons will be quite angry.
- They are likely to destroy the planet.
Then it is fortunate I have you
and your starship to protect me.
You and your first officer
are to beam down to my co-ordinates.
We will be happy to beam down,
but we musthave certain assurances.
At foot speed, the journey
to the city will take 1 .2 hours.
We don't have 1 .2 hours.
Wait a minute... Perfect!
We'll have to get their attention.
What's that?
Is she naked?
Hello, boys.
I've always wanted to play
to a captive audience.
- Spock, be one with the horse.
- Yes, Captain.
Open the gate.
It's our lookout party.
Federation soldiers are right behind us.
Close the gate.
Where are they going?
- Spock...
- Hold your horse, I'm scanning.
The hostages are being held
in that structure.
Galileo, start your run.
Phasers on stun.
Sulu, take out that light.
- What's going on?
- Surrender, you are under attack.
- It wasn't bloodshed I wanted.
- Wait! Come back.
- Uhura, come on down.
- Roger, coming in.
Nimbus Ill is famous forits wildllfe,
and the flshing is terrifilc!
Easy flnancing through
Federation Federal can take you there.
- Thank God.
- Please cooperate.
Hand over your weapons.
Well done, my friends.
Qualse tu?
Spock!
Spock, it's me.
It's Sybok.
You've finally caught up with me.
Don't you have anything to say to me?
You are under arrest for 1 7 violations
of the Neutral Zone Treaty.
- You've developed a sense of humour.
- I did not intend to amuse you.
These are serious charges.
However, if you surrender now...
I'm sorry, Spock, I'm not through
violating the Neutral Zone Treaty.
In fact, I'm just getting started.
For my next violation,
I intend to steal something.
Something very big.
Your starship.
You staged all this
to get your hands on my ship?
- Who are you?
- Captain James T Kirk.
I thought Captain Chekov...
I see... Very clever, Captain.
Spock, you have been given
a second chance to join me.
- I am a Starfleet officer.
- Of course.
Of course. Then I'll take the ship
without your help.
- Shuttle en route.
- Position of Bird of Prey?.
Closing!
Estimating attack range
in 8,000 kellicams.
Stealth approach,
slow to one quarterimpulse power.
Prepare to cloak.
Engage cloaking device.
- The Bird of Prey must have cloaked.
- Raise shields.
- The shuttle...?
- Do it. Go to red alert.
Once we control your vessel,
we'll bring up our followers.
The Klingons are out there.
We'll be lucky to make it to the ship.
This is Enterprise, red alert.
Bird ofPrey approaching.
Raising shields.
Find a safe harbour.
No!
No reply. Remain on course.
Listen to me. In order for this
craft to enter the landing bay,
Enterprise must lower the shields
and activate the tractor beam.
- To re-raise the shields will take...
- 15.5 seconds.
An eternity, during which
we'll be vulnerable to attack.
He speaks the truth. If my people
are cloaked, then they intend to strike.
- We cannot turn back.
- Let me do something.
Very well, do what you must,
but no more.
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
Kirk! He's on the shuttlecratf!
Alter the attack course!
Understand your situation.
Are unable to return to planet.
Stand by to execute
emergency landing plan...B
- Emergency landing plan B?
- B as in barricade.
What are you doing?
In order to lower and raise the shields
quickly, we'll forego the tractor beam.
We'll fly her in manually.
- How often have you done this?
- Actually, it's my first attempt.
He's good...really.
Scotty, open bay doors.
Stand by to de-cloak forflring.
- Scotty, lower shields.
- Lowering shields.
- Bird of Prey bearing 105.2.
- Go, Sulu.
They're in.
- Bear on Enterprise.
- Enterprise targeted!
- Warp speed now!
- Firing!
Track her course!
He's good.
We must change course at once.
I'll take you to the bridge.
Pick it up.
Sybok...
You must surrender.
No!
- You must kill me.
- Shoot him!
For a moment...
I thought you might actually do it.
Put him in the brig with Captain Kirk.
Spock, you will accompany me
to the bridge?
No...l will not.
You know I'm right.
Then you must join them.
- These two will be useful.
- Give us a moment alone.
Don't be afraid.
Goddamn it, Spock.
You betrayed us all.
I do not expect you to forgive me.
- I ought to knock you on your ass.
- If you think it would help.
- You want me to hold him?
- Stay out of this... Why?.
- All you had to do was pull the trigger.
- Then Sybok would be dead.
- I ordered you to defend your ship.
- And kill my brother.
- A fellow Vulcan is not a...
- Sybok also is a son of Sarek.
He's your brother brother?.
You made that up.
- I did not.
- You don't have a brother.
- Technically I don't have a brother.
- See?
- I have a half-brother.
- I've got to sit down.
You and Sybok have the same father
but different mothers?
SyboK´s mother was a Vulcan princess,
but we were raised as brothers.
- Why didn't you tell us this before?
- It is a personal matter.
- For that I am sorry.
- That makes everything all right. Sorry!
Spock could no more kill
his own brother than he could kill you.
He's already in the brig. Besides,
we've got bigger problems to deal with.
Like how do we get out of here.
I'll say one thing,
you never cease to amaze me.
Nor I myself.
- I was beginning to worry.
- It's all right. Sybok will explain.
- What are you doing?
- Plotting our new course.
You have no authority.
- What's going on here?
- Pavel, listen to this man.
- I don't understand.
- Each of us hides a secret pain.
Share yours with me
and gain strength from the sharing.
Useless.
Unwise.
You could have warned me.
There's got to be a way out.
- This new brig is escape-proof.
- How do you know?.
The designers tested it using the most
intelligent person they could find.
- He failed to escape.
- Did this person have pointed ears?
And an unerring capacity
for getting his shipmates into trouble?
He did have pointed ears.
- Following new course. Warp 7.
- Arrival in 6.7 hours at present speed.
Now that we're underway, I'll announce
my intentions to the rest of the ship.
Brave crew ofthe starship Enterprise,
consider the questions ofexistence.
Questions that man has asked since
he first gazed at the stars and dreamed.
My Vulcan ancestors
were ruled by their emotions.
They felt with their hearts.
They made love with their hearts.
They believed with their hearts.
And they believed in a place where
these questions would be answered.
Modern dogma tells us
this place is a myth.
A fantasy concocted by pagans.
Itis no fantasy.
I tell you...it exists.
My brothers, we have been chosen
to undertake
the greatest adventure of all time.
The discovery of Sha Ka Ree.
Is it possible he's found Sha Ka Ree,
the reason he left Vulcan?
Our destination
is the planet Sha Ka Ree.
It lies beyond the Great Barrier...
..at the centre ofthe galaxy.
- The centre of the galaxy?.
- Where it is fabled to exist.
The centre of the galaxy
can't be reached by any ship.
Sybok possessed the keenest intellect
I've ever known.
When I get the ship back,
and Sybok is in here,
you can debate Sha Ka Ree
until you're green in the face.
You're either with me or you're not.
- I am here, Captain.
- That's a little vague, Spock.
What's that noise?
It's a primitive form of communication
known as Morse Code.
You're right. I'm out of practice.
That's an S.
- T...
- A...
N... D... End of word.
- Stand.
- New word.
B... A...
C... K...
- Back.
- Stand back!
What are you standing around for?.
This is a jailbreak.
These three are strong.
This will be quite a challenge.
We've got to find them.
- We can't trust anyone.
- Send a distress signal.
There is an emergency
send apparatus in the observation room.
You might be able
to reach it by means of Turbo-shaft 3.
- It's a long and dangerous climb.
- Some of us get off on that.
Get the transporter working
and contact a rescue ship.
- Which way to the Turbo-shaft?
- Down that tunnel and turn right.
- You can't miss it.
- Mr Scott, you're amazing.
I know this ship
like the back of my hand.
- We'll get a good workout.
- Yeah, or a heart attack.
Get Mr Scott to sick bay.
This is going to take me forever.
Where's Spock?.
I believe I've found a faster way.
- Bones?
- I'll wait for the next car.
We're not splitting up.
- We're too heavy.
- It must be the marsh melons.
- Spock, the booster rockets.
- I can't control their power.
Fire the rockets.
Captain, please come back down.
Hit the brakes.
- I overshot the mark by one level.
- Nobody's perfect.
Spock.
Emergency channel open.
To anyone within range,
this is Captain James T Kirk.
If you read me, acknowledge.
Acknowledge.
This is Starfleet Command,
we readyou. Over.
A hostile force
has taken control of our vessel.
Our co-ordinates are 000.2.
Request emergency assistance.
Understood, Enterprise. We are
dispatching a rescue ship immediately.
Plot course 000.2.
But Captain, that course
will take us into the Barrier as well.
Where Kirk goes, we follow.
- I trust your message was received.
- You can't expect us to stand by.
What you fear is the unknown.
The people of your planet
once believed their world was flat.
Columbus proved it was round.
They said the sound barrier
could never be broken. It was broken.
They said warp speed
could not be achieved.
The Great Barrier is the ultimate
expression of this universal fear.
It is an extension of personal fear.
Captain Kirk, I so much
want your understanding.
I want your respect.
Are you afraid to hear me out?
- I'm afraid of nothing.
- Wait outside.
I'm sure you have many questions.
Here, amidst the stars
of our own galaxy,
we shall seek the answers together.
Easy, Scotty.
You're back with us.
I dreamt that a madman
had taken over the Enterprise.
- He's not a madman.
- He's not?
Sybok has put us in touch with feelings
we've always been afraid to express.
- I have to get to the transporter.
- Scotty!
- There's so much I want to tell you.
- Wait till I'm a wee bit stronger.
I don't think I could take it
in my present condition...or yours.
Sha Ka Ree.
The Source.
Heaven.
Eden.
Call it what you will.
The Klingons call it Qui Tu.
The Romulans, Vorta Vor.
In Andorian it is unpronounceable.
Still, every culture shares
this common dream.
A place from which creation sprang.
For us it will soon be reality.
My only reality is that
I'm a prisoner on my own ship.
What is this power you have
to control the minds of my crew?.
I don't control minds... I free them.
How?.
By making you face your pain
and draw strength from it.
Once that's done, fear cannot stop you.
It sounds like brainwashing to me.
Your pain is the deepest of all.
I can feel it, can't you?
Leonard.
This is some kind of trick.
Father?.
My God! Don't do this to me.
Leonard.
I'm here. I'm with you, Dad.
The pain. Stop the pain.
I've done everything I can do.
You've got to hang on.
I can't stand the pain.
Help me.
All my knowledge and I can't save him.
You've done all you can.
The support system will keep him alive.
- You call this alive?
- Son...
- Release me.
- I can't do that, Dad.
But how can I watch him suffer
like this?
You're a doctor.
I'm his son.
Why did you do it?
To preserve his dignity.
- That wasn't the worst of it, was it?
- No!
Share it.
Not long after, they found a cure.
A goddamn cure.
- If you didn't kill him, he'd have lived.
- I released him!
- You did what you thought was right.
- Yes! No!
Release this pain!
This pain has poisoned your soul
for a long time.
Now you've taken the first step.
The other steps we'll take together.
Each man's pain is unique.
I hide no pain.
- I know you better than that.
- Do you?
- Spock, don't.
- It's all right, Captain.
Proceed.
- What is this?
- I believe we are witnessing my birth.
Sarek, your son.
So human.
Spock?.
- What have you done to my friends?
- Nothing. This is who they are.
- Didn't you know that?
- No, I didn't.
- Now learn something about yourself.
- No, I refuse.
- Jim, try to be open about this.
- About what?
How I made wrong choices in my life?
Turning left instead of right?
I don't need Sybok to take me
on a tour of my weaknesses.
To be brainwashed by a conman!
- This conman took away my pain.
- With the wave of a magic wand?
The things we carry with us
make us who we are.
If we lose them, we lose ourselves.
I don't want my pain taken away.
I need my pain.
Captain, you remain here.
Spock, Dr McCoy, come with me.
- Spock?.
- I cannot go with you.
- Why not?
- I belong here.
- I don't understand.
- Sybok...
You are my brother,
but you do not know me.
I am not the outcast boy
you left behind many years ago.
I found myself and my place,
and I know who I am.
I cannot go with you.
You'd better count me out, too.
- Then I'll see you on the other side.
- Wait!
We'll never make it
through the Great Barrier.
If we do, will that convince you
that my vision was true?
It was given to me by God.
He waits for us on the other side.
You are mad.
Am l?
We'll see.
They say no ship can survive this.
They're wrong. Danger is an illusion.
We have no instrument readings.
- Mr Sulu, full ahead.
- Full ahead, aye.
- Is it possible?
- Fascinating.
Are we dreaming?
If we are, then life is a dream.
Instruments are back on line.
Incredible.
There is a power source emanating
from the planet like nothing I've seen.
- Sha Ka Ree.
- Qui Tu.
Vorta Vor.
Eden.
- About the ship...
- The ship needs its captain.
- No special conditions?
- No conditions.
- I could turn us around.
- No, you too must know.
Well, if we're going to do it,
we're going to do it by the book.
Standard orbital approach.
Alert the shuttlecraft to stand by.
Sybok, Spock, McCoy, come with me.
The rest of you remain on board.
Until I determine
what we're dealing with.
Don't just stand there,
God's a busy man.
I am no longer in control of the craft.
All right, we'll play it your way.
It's amazing. The land. The sky.
Just as I knew it would be.
- You have to see this.
- I don't have time.
The Captain told me
to get the transporter working.
We have travelled far.
By starship.
Enterprise, this is Kirk.
We have...
Sybok.
Perhaps...
Brave souls, welcome.
Is this the voice of God?
One voice, many faces.
Does this better
suit your expectations?
- Qualse tu?
- It is l.
Yourjourney
could not have been an easy one.
It was not.
We had to breach the Barrier.
Magnificent.
You are the first to find me.
- We sought only your infinite wisdom.
- How did you breach the Barrier?.
- With a starship.
- This starship...
Could it carry my wisdom
beyond the Barrier?.
- It could, yes.
- Then I shall make use of it.
- It will be your chariot.
- Excuse me...
- I will reach every corner of creation.
- I'd like to ask a question.
- What does God need with a starship?
- Bring the ship closer.
What does God need with a starship?
- What are you doing?
- Asking a question.
- Who is this creature?
- Don't you know?. Aren't you God?
- He has his doubts.
- You doubt me?
- I seek proof.
- You don't ask the Almighty for his ID.
Then here is the proof you seek.
- Why is God angry?.
- Why have you done this?
- He doubts me.
- You have not answered his question.
What does God need with a starship?
Do you doubt me?
I doubt any god who inflicts pain
for his own pleasure.
Stop! The god of Sha Ka Ree
would not do this.
Sha Ka Ree? A vision you created.
An eternity I've been
imprisoned in this place.
The ship. I must have the ship.
Now...give me what I want.
Sybok...
This is not the god of Sha Ka Ree,
or any other god.
I don't understand.
Reveal yourself to me.
What's wrong?
Don't you like this face?
I have so many,
but this one suits you best.
No, it's not possible.
- Bring me the ship or I will destroy you.
- The ship.
Bring it closer so that I might join with it.
Do it, or watch these puny things
die horribly.
- What have I done?
- Enterprise, listen carefully.
This is my doing. This is my arrogance.
My vanity.
- Sybok, we must find a way...
- No, save yourselves.
Forgive me, brother.
I couldn't help but notice your pain.
It runs deep. Share it with me.
- Enterprise, are you ready?.
- Torpedo armed.
- We're firing on your position.
- Send it down now!
Run!
Sybok...
Let's get out of here.
Sulu, I've lost them.
Spock, get us out of here.
Thrusters are inoperative.
Mr Scott, please tell me
the transporter is working.
I might be able to beam up two of you.
- Beam up Spock and Dr McCoy now.
- Just a damn minute!
Bring up the Captain.
- We can't just leave Jim down there.
- Get a grip on yourself. Status report.
The Klingon captain
wishes to name his terms.
This is Captain Klaa
ofthe Klingon Empire.
Do not attempt to arm your weapons
orl will destroy you.
You are alive for a single reason:
the renegade James TKirk.
Hand him over
and I will spare your lives.
- I'm ready to beam him aboard.
- Captain Kirk is not among us.
- You lie.
- Vulcans are incapable of lying.
- Captain Kirk is on the planet below.
- Then give me his co-ordinates.
- I am in need of your assistance.
- My assistance?
- You are his superior officer.
- I am a foolish old man.
Damn you, sir. You will try.
Klingon commander,
someone wishes to speak with you.
So it's me you want, you bastards.
What are you waiting for?.
Release him.
Myjunior officer has something
he wants to say to you.
I...apologise.
The attack upon your vessel
was not authorised by my government.
Now, may I present
our new gunner.
- Spock!
- Welcome aboard, Captain.
I thought I was going to die.
Not possible, you were never alone.
Please, Captain,
not in front of the Klingons.
Would you care for a wee nip
of Scotch whisky?.
I never thought
I'd be drinking with a Klingon.
- What are you two conspiring about?
- About the progress we've made.
She has wonderful muscles.
Cosmic thoughts, gentlemen?
We were speculating...
Is God really out there?
Maybe he's not out there.
Maybe he's right here
in the human heart.
- Spock?.
- I was thinking of Sybok.
- I have lost a brother.
- Yes.
I lost a brother, once.
I was lucky. I got him back.
I thought you said
men like us don't have families.
I was wrong.
Are you just going to pluck that thing,
or are you going to play something?
# Row, row, rowyour boat
# Gently down the stream
# Merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily
# Llfe is but a dream... #
Subtitles provider:
Sibirski