TICK: You ready?
LENNY: Yeah. Boot it.
[Garbled chatter]
POV VOICE: That's it.
LANE:
That's it. That's it. Excellent.
POV VOICE: I'm recordin'.
LANE: Are you crazy?
Waittill I getthis thing down.
You trying to l.D. me?
Fuckin' retard!
Goddamn,you stupid fuck!
POV VOICE: Don't be a pussy.
LANE: Don't call me a pussy.
I'll fucking I.D. you!
Here,take the gun.
POV VOICE: This piece of shit?
I can't believe it.
Is it even loaded?
I want the auto.
LANE: Asshole.
[Sniffing]
Whoo! I love this shit, man!
Don't fuckin'--
Fuck you!
Ha ha ha! Whoo!
POV VOICE: It's right there.
Turn right.
DIAZ: OK,just relax.
Relax!
POV VOICE:
Right, right, right.
Here we go. There it is.
LANE: Shh.
POV VOICE: Take it easy.
LANE: One...two...three...go!
[Yelling]
DIAZ: Let's go! Let's go!
POV VOICE: Rush that punk!
LANE: Put your head down!
COOK: Aah!
LANE: I said down!
I'll fuckin'
blow your head off!
LANE: This is a robbery!
Everyone, hands up!
You, get to the back!
POV VOICE: Hands in the air!
No, no, no.
Where you going, bitch?
Over here. Over here.
DIAZ: Get the fucking money!
POV VOICE:
You! Open the fucking register!
DIAZ: You want to die,
you little fuck?
OWNER: OK. Please, don't shoot!
DIAZ: Where's the fucking money?
There's the fucking money!
OWNER: Don't shoot us.
POV VOICE: This way.
OWNER: OK.
POV VOICE: Go, man. Run!
Run, man, run!
You wanna die?
LANE: Go, go, go!
POV VOICE: Don't look at me,
youfuckin' Chink!
DIAZ: Get in there!
LANE: Get inside,
you fucking cock sucker!
-Did you get the money?
-Yes!
LANE: What are you doing,
you fucking asshole?
Come on,we gotta go!
DIAZ: You getthe money or not?
How much?
[Sirens]
COP: This is the police!
LANE: Fuck!
DIAZ: I'm going. I'm going.
LANE: Um...fuck. Here.
Come on,follow me!
POV VOICE: Go, man, go!
LANE:
The fucking doors are locked!
POV VOICE: Come on!
Come on!
Where are the cops, man?
[Gunshot]
LANE: Fuck you!
POV VOICE:
What are you doing, man?
Go, man! Go!
LANE: Shit!
[Gunshots]
COP: Stop!
[Burglar alarm rings]
COP: Drop your goddamn weapon!
LANE: Come on!
POV VOICE:
They're right behind us!
Fuck!
LANE: Come on! Oh, shit!
POV VOICE: Go, man, go!
-Come on.
-Go.
LANE: Aaah!
[Explosion]
LANE: Come on!
Come on,jump!
POV VOICE: This is insane, man.
COP: Hey,you, stop!
[Panting]
LANE: Come on, grab my hand!
POV VOICE: I'm gonna die!
Hold on to me, man!
LANE: You mother fucker!
[Gunshot]
POV VOICE: Aah!
Uhh!
God damn it!
You know I don't deal in snuff!
Don't have a fucking coronary.
LENNY: You could've
at least warned me!
You know I hate the zap
when they die.
It just brings down
your whole day. Jesus,Tick.
Sorry.
How come the cops
didn't put it in evidence?
With all the blood,
they didn't see the rig.
It was under a wig.
How'd it getto you?
I got ways, Lenny.
I got a deal
with some of the paramedics.
My guy pages me,
I pick it up at the morgue.
This clip's got to be
worth a grand, right?
Tick, not to dash your hopes...
but I don't deal this kind
of product. You know that.
I'll give you four, 'cause
I've gotta cut off the end...
and my customers want uncut.
Fuck that, man.
The last part is the best.
You dry dive six stories--
blammo!
You jack into the big black.
I don't deal black-jack clips!
It's policy. I got ethics here.
When did that start?
This is what people wanna see.
You know it.
So lay it off to somebody else.
Lenny, Lenny.
I got expenses.
I gotta get my rig fixed.
There's blood
all over the heads.
-Take it away.
-Gimme six, at least.
This is a good clip.
It gets you pumpin'.
The first part's OK...
better than the usual soaps
you bring me.
TICK: That is cold.
I always bring you choice.
Like this low-grade shit here?
Some girl in afight
with her boyfriend.
It's a test pattern.
Nothing happens. I'm snoring.
Lenny,
you're always telling me...
bring you street life,
real life...
that one man's mundane
and desperate existence...
is another man's Technicolor.
I said that?
Many times.
It's a direct quote.
I'll take it for five.
You'll make out OK,
'cause it's pure cream.
You don't have to cut
anything back to the wearer.
Yeah,that's for sure.
-OK.
-What else you got?
[Yelling]
[Heavy metal music playing]
WOMAN SINGING: You kill me
with your smelly fingers
Your smelly fingers from the sex
You are the grand master--
TALK SHOW HOST: Calls are
a little kooky tonight.
It's a little aftertwo a.m.,
December 30, 1999.
Second to last day
of the whole darn century.
LENNY: Jer, hi. I'll drop
the money by tomorrow.
Next day latest.
It's a little crazed right now.
Would I lie?
No, never to you,Jer.
You're not wrong.
Prick.
[Tenor singing opera]
TALK SHOW HOST: Dan,
looking forward to the new year?
DAN: Not really.
I mean,what's the point?
Nothing changes New Year's Day.
The economy sucks.
Gas is over
three bucks a gallon.
Fifth-grade kids are shooting
each other at recess.
The whole thing sucks.
What are we celebrating?
[Heavy metal music playing]
CHOIR SINGING: Amen, amen, amen
Amen
Amen, amen, amen
LENNY: You shoot the clip.
Get it to me by Monday.
Client wants a guy and
two girls, and the guy wears.
Yeah. No, I know.
He's trying to be original.
The girls have to be young, OK?
So don't use your mother
like you usually do.
Yeah,you,too, asshole.
TALK SHOW HOST: Go ahead,
caller. You're on the air.
DEWAYNE: My name's Dewayne.
I got a New Year's resolution
for the police.
Hey,yo, Five-O,you better
get down with the Two-K.
TALK SHOW HOST:
Two-K? What is that?
DEWAYNE: Two-K. The big 2000.
Coming up tomorrow night.
Out with the old,
in with the new.
See,for the man,
no new is good new.
We're gonna take it
and make it new, our own.
History's gonna
start right here.
TALK SHOW HOST: Dewayne--
DEWAYNE: I wanna give
a shout-outto Boo--
TALK SHOW HOST:
You're on the air, Lori.
LORl: lf you read the Bible...
you'd know there won't be
another thousand years.
We're in the last days
as foretold in the--
TALK SHOW HOST: The last days?
The apocalypse,the rapture?
LORl: Look atthe signs. There
are wars and rumors of wars--
TALK SHOW HOST: Just so we know
how much time is left...
when is the rapture
supposed to hit, exactly?
-Midnight New Year's Eve?
-That's right.
TALK SHOW HOST: Now, is that
midnight L.A. time...
or Eastern Standard Time
orwhat?
What time zone is God in?
LORl: I pray for you all.
WOMAN: Ooh,yeah. Oh,yeah.
LENNY: OK. I can use this.
Listen, it's not bad...
but, honey,you gotta move
your eyes slower next time.
Much slower, like you're
making love with your eyes.
EDUARDO:
Let me get this straight.
You'll pay me two hundred
dollars to wear a hair net...
and bang some beautiful babe?
I gotta think about this.
LENNY: Let's get you wired up.
I hope this axle grease
you got on your hair...
doesn't screw up
the SQUID receptors.
What is all
this SQUID shit, anyway?
Superconducting Quantum
lnterference Device--SQUID.
The receptor rig on your head
sends a signal to the recorder.
We call it "being wired,"
butthere's no wire.
You gotta keep the recorder
close--five, sixfeet max--
a jacket pocket, by the bed,
whereveryou close escrow.
-Know what I mean?
-Yeah.
There's a half hour of tape,
so give me some lead-in.
Don't wait too long.
I don't want to
be going out for popcorn.
Don't worry. You won't.
-Got it?
-No problem.
You look great.
You look...beautiful.
[Panting]
Aah!
Shit!
Get out!
DISPATCHER: Ten-seventeen,
do you request backup?
That's a negative.
Um...
Suspect is a black male,
thirty-five toforty.
We're handling it.
[Bell rings]
-Freeze!
-Freeze! You bitch!
You fuckin' bitch!
Aah!
Aaah!
Fuck! Fuck!
[Gunshots]
Aah!
Oh, shit.
STECKLER: God!
[Helicopter passes]
[Telephone rings]
[Ring]
ANSWERING MACHINE:
Hi, it's Lenny.
Just what do you have in mind?
[Beep]
Lenny...God damn it,
you gotto be there.
You got to help me.
Please pick up the phone.
Come on, pick up.
Come on, Lenny,
fucking pick up the phone!
OK, I'll call you back.
[Helicopter passes]
FAITH: Watch what I do. You OK?
[Laughs]
You're doin' good, honey.
[Humming]
LENNY: [Laughing]
You look so good.
LENNY: Faith, come back.
FAITH:
You all right? You need help?
Sweetie, you're doing good.
Oh!
[Laughter]
Lenny...
[Laughs]
I'm sorry. Ha ha ha!
I'm sorry, baby. Are you OK?
[Bob Marley's
"Three Little Birds" playing]
BOB MARLEY SINGING: Don'tworry
About a thing
'Cause every little thing
Gonna be all right
-How do you feel?
-Lucky.
Dry me.
BOB MARLEY:
'Cause every little thing
Gonna be all right
BOB MARLEY:
Rise up this mornin'
FAITH: You wanna watch,
or you gonna do?
LENNY: Watch and see.
BOB MARLEY: Three little birds
By my doorstep
Singin' sweet songs
Melodies pure and true
Saying
This is my message to you
Oh,wow...
BOB MARLEY:
Gonna be all right
Baby, don't worry
Don't worry
About a thing
'Cause every little thing
Gonna be all right
Oh, baby, baby, baby...
You're so beautiful.
FAITH: I love your eyes, Lenny.
I love the way they see.
BOB MARLEY: Don'tworry
About a thing
'Cause every little thing
Gonna be all right
Baby, don'tworry
About a thing
'Cause every little thing--
[Beeping]
[Fanfare plays]
ANCHORWOMAN:
New Year's Eve, 1999.
It's being called
the party of the century...
but it may be the biggest ever.
No one's seen preparations
like this...
but preparations
require care and insurance...
and the LAPD
is one insurance company...
that doesn't want accidents.
[Rapping]
Put you on a reservation
Black nation
Die underyour step
and fetch a military lie--
The bodies of two men found
under the Hollywood Freeway...
have been identified
as rap starJeriko One...
and band memberJames Polton,
known to fans as Replay.
Both were shot in what police
are characterizing...
as an execution-style killing.
The body
of an unidentified woman...
was found with them,
also shot numerous times.
Police said the killings
appearto be gang-related.
With his band,
Prophets of Light...
Jeriko One's outspoken political
stance and violent lyrics...
have stirred nationwide
controversy.
Meanwhile,
astrologers have been busy...
making predictions
for the coming century.
Some of their fortune-telling
is indeed incredible--
Muammar Qaddafi will be awarded
the Nobel Peace Prize.
Turkey will make
reparations to Armenia.
By 2025,there will be
a second woman president...
-Hey, Lenny.
-How ya doin', man?
Hey, man.
Keith.
-Keith?
-Yeah.
Hi. Lenny. Lenny Nero.
We spoke on the phone. Hi.
OK.
Not to be rude, but I gotta ask.
Are you a cop?
I understand. No, I'm not.
You understand. Attorney, right?
That's right.
Tassel shoes. Entertainment law
would be my guess.
It's my job to know people
and what they want...
what's behind their eyes.
OK, so tell me,
have you everjacked in?
Have you everwire-tripped?
No.
A virgin brain.
We're gonna start you off right.
Just save us some time,
tell me what you know.
Just what I've read.
That the technology
was developed for the Feds...
to replace the body wire,
and now it's gone black market.
That's right, so...
this conversation's
not taking place, OK?
-Damn right it's not.
-Good.
Do I get the deck from you?
I'll get you a deck at my cost.
My thing is the software.
Clips, right?
Clips. Right.
Listen, I want you to know
what we're talking about here.
This is not
"like TV, only better."
This is life.
It's a piece of somebody's life.
It's pure and uncut, straight
from the cerebral cortex.
You're there. You're doing it.
You're seeing it, hearing it.
You're feeling it.
What kind of things, exactly?
Anything. Whatever you want,
whoever you wanna be.
Want to go skiing without
leaving your den,you can...
but I'm assuming
that a guy like you...
you want to ski,
you fly to Aspen.
That's not what
you're interested in.
It's...
It's about the stuff
that you can't have, right?
The forbidden fruit, hmm?
Running into a liquor store with
a .357 Magnum in your hand...
feeling the adrenaline
pumping through yourveins, huh?
Or see that guy with the
drop-dead Filipino girlfriend?
Wouldn'tyou like to be
that guy fortwenty minutes?
The right twenty minutes.
I can make it happen...
and you won't even tarnish
your wedding ring.
Sounds good.
I can get you what you want.
I can get you anything.
Just talk to me.
You have to trust me, OK?
'Cause I'm your priest.
I'm your shrink.
I am your main connection
to the switch board of souls.
I'm the Magic Man.
The Santa Claus
of the subconscious.
You say it,
you think it,you can have it.
You want a girl?
You want two girls?
I don't know what your thing is,
what you're curious about.
You want a guy?
Maybe you want to be a girl.
Hey,think of that. Be a girl.
See what that feels like.
Maybe you want a nun
to tie you up.
It's all doable.
Talk to me about costs.
Before we get into numbers,
I want you to try a taste.
I got a deck with me.
-Right here?
-Step into my office.
[Gasps]
Ohh.
Ahh.
Ooh.
[Turns off]
You were just an 18-year-old
girl taking a shower.
Are you beginning to see
the possibilities here?
MAX: Hey. So,where is he?
-In the back making a deal.
-Oh.
KEITH: Nexttime, let's meet
someplace less public.
LENNY: Nervous? Don't be.
Cops have more to worry about
than the SQUID trade.
MAX: Oh,yeah?
Assume the position,
you miserable techno-perv puke.
Beat it,fuckwad! Uhh!
Max, I was with a client!
You think that'sfunny?
Prick.
MAX: See the look
on that preppy puke'sface?
Pissed all over his Topsiders.
LENNY: It was funny,
but it cost me money.
MAX: Come on, amigo.
The world'sfull of marks.
No one knows how to work them
like you do, pal.
You could sell a rat's asshole
for a wedding ring.
LENNY: Yeah, I could.
MAX: Let me buy you a drink.
Bobby!
Tequila, porfavor.
Double shots.
Make it a Tres Generaciones.
Nothing but the best
for Lenny...
the finest cop to ever get
thrown off the vice squad.
-Fuck you.
-Ha ha ha!
Whoo. Yeah, nice tie.
LENNY: Thanks, Max.
MAX: You always got to dress
like a fucking pimp?
This tie cost more
than your entire wardrobe.
MAX: That's not saying much.
LENNY: It's the one thing...
that stands between me
and the fucking jungle.
MAX: To the jungle...
where some shit bird
can cap you in the head...
and that'll ruin
your whole day.
You were lucky, Max.
So darned lucky, I wake up with
a twenty-two in my brainpan...
and a cop pension
I can't live off of.
Damn! It's a good thing
I wasn't luckier.
[Laughing]
Bobby, hit me again.
You seen Faith lately?
-She won't call me.
-Just as well.
Sure, Faith was
the most outstanding woman...
a guy like you
could ever hope to get...
and it's completely humiliating
that she's gone...
but you got to face
that it's over.
Thanks, chaplain.
I'm touched by your concern.
I just hate to see you
pining away, man.
You're myfriend.
It makes me want to vomit.
Hey, lris. You OK?
I gotta talk to you.
It's serious.
MAX: What happened, honey?
Some john get rough on you?
No. I mean,talk private.
Please?
I'm in trouble. So is Faith.
MAX:
There's the magic fucking word.
IRIS: Can you come with me
to your car, please?
There's something
you have to see.
LENNY: What's going on?
-It's a bad situation.
-What?
If they get me,
I know they'll...
Who?
[Siren]
Oh, shit.
Hey! Hang on! That's my car!
DRIVER: Not anymore.
It belongs to the bank.
-Wait a second.
-Whoops.
Great. Two million years
of human evolution...
that's the best idea
you can come upwith.
What do you getto repo a car?
Two hundred? Two-fifty?
I'll pay you
three-fifty right now.
-Got the cash on you?
-I was gonna write a check.
DRIVER: See ya.
LENNY: I totally respect that.
I would want cash.
They'll take my check inside.
Just give me two minutes.
Here. You can keep my watch
for collateral.
It's a Rolex.
I'll be right back.
Two minutes.
Two minutes?
[Truck drives away]
Son of a bitch.
[Speed-dialing]
[Ring]
What happened to your car
this time?
MAX: See, Lenny,
if you packed your piece...
you could make the guy
see sense.
Bobby,turn this up.
JERIKO ONE RAPPING:
You watch us take it all
And then you'll
understand our pain
We'll make you the rat
That crawled through the cracks
You love
that red,white, and blue
But you hate
the black, black, black
And you tryin' to make me think
I did this to myself
When the drugs I smoke
And the guns I tote
Both came from your shelf
But I never had a dream, 'cause
My life is a nightmare
America's been my boogieman
For four hundred years
MAN:
Are you asking me how I feel?
We felt Jeriko.
We listened to him.
JERIKO ONE:
The LAPD is a military force...
turned against its own people.
We live in a police state...
-Hey, Macey.
-Shh.
...with their social programs
that don'twork.
[Cheering]
They're rearranging deck chairs
on the Titanic.
But a new day is coming.
Two-K is coming.
The day of reckoning is upon us.
History...
ends and begins again...
right here...right now!
MAX: Right on!
To the end of all things.
You know how I know
it's the end of the world?
LENNY:
No. Tell me.
'Cause everything's
already been done,you know?
Every kind of music's
been tried...
every government's been tried,
every fucking hairstyle...
bubble gum flavors, cereal,
every type of fucking.
What are we going to do?
How are we going to make
another thousand years?
I'm telling you, it's over.
We used it all up.
MACE:
What's this week's sad story?
They jerked my wheels.
It's outrageous the computer
errors the banks make.
Have you noticed?
No, I haven't,
because I make my payments.
So, Max Peltier,
how's the P.I. business?
MAX: Sucks. But when
I get this new logo--
LENNY:
I want to hear this scumbag.
REPORTER:
Do you have any leads?
MAN: Why wasn't Jeriko One
provided adequate security?
GANT: He always had adequate
security available to him.
He chose not to have
those encumbrances in his life.
Why's he a scumbag?
You-know-who left Lenny for him.
-Faith left Lenny for him?
-Don't say Faith.
Use the "F" word around Lenny,
it triggers a maudlin display...
and you gotta tranquilize him.
Shh.
GANT: I've lost afriend,
a man of great courage...
which is more than I can say
for most of us.
-If you're riding--
-Let's go.
[Siren]
MAN: Fuck you,you pig!
MACE: Driving Mr. Lenny.
It's going to be a big night.
Can't you feel it?
The energy in the air.
There's money to be made,
dreams to sell.
MACE: Sleaze to peddle.
That is so unenlightened.
I sell experiences.
The way I see it, I'm performing
a humanitarian service.
I probably save lives.
I wanna hear this part.
Everybody needs to walk to
the dark end of the street.
It's what we are.
Now the risks are out of line.
The streets are a war zone.
Sex can kill you.
You slip on the 'trodes
and get what you need...
almost as good as
the real thing and a lot safer.
Porno. Face it,
you sell porno to wireheads.
Harsh and untrue.
My clients are professionals.
They're people with taste.
Some are even celebrities.
-What celebrities?
-The guy from the news.
-He does the weather.
-That counts.
-You passed La Cienega.
-I'm not taking it.
It's the quickestway
to the club.
I've got business there.
I'm meeting people.
Mace,you're myfriend.
Plus I'll give you twenty-five
percent of what I make tonight.
This may be
a hard concept for you...
but friends don't have
to pay their friends.
-Faith is singing.
-I should have known.
Look...
I pulled twelve hours.
I gotta get some sleep.
I got one last pickup
at the St. James Club.
They got a taxi stand.
You can catch a cab.
A taxi?
Well, someone might see me.
[Horns honking]
DOORMAN:
Hold it right there, ma'am.
Whoa. Hold it right there.
MACE: Damn it, Lenny,
you made me late.
What's your pickup's name?
I'll find him.
-Fumitsu.
-Fumitsu?
Fumitsu. Fumitsu.
DOORMAN: You can leave
the car right there.
Oh,fuck.
-Nero.
-Strickland.
Commissioner Strickland.
Since you shit-canned my career,
I don't have to call you "sir."
It's one of
life's small pleasures.
Aren't you peddling a little far
from your usual gutter?
I was invited here
by a close friend--Mr. Fumitsu.
He's right over there.
I don't like
disappointments, Nero.
You know what disappoints me
very much?
Your sex life? Excuse me.
Mr. Fumitsu.
[Exchanging greeting
in Japanese]
Leonard Nero, BLS Limousine
and Security Service.
I've arranged for
one of our finest drivers...
Lornette Mason,
to take care of you.
She's a security specialist
trained in defensive combat.
Of course,the car's bullet proof
and fully armored.
I'll be coming along to complete
our periodic driver evaluation.
With your permission, of course.
We do it to ensure
that our VIP clients...
are always treated
as honored guests.
Good evening, Mr. Fumitsu.
Sir, please watch your head.
Excuse me, Mr. Nero.
Excuse me, sir!
What the fuck are you doing?
Coming with you.
[Sighs]
You will not live
to see the morning.
LENNY: Drive on.
[Revving engine]
LENNY: Are you a cop?
No.
Good. Have you ever been wired?
FUMITSU: Wired?
The latest technology.
LENNY: Oh.
That is so beautiful.
You got to take
a look at this, OK?
Yeah. You're going to love it.
-You have more?
-I have more.
Believe me, I have more.
Ha ha ha.
[Horn honks]
Hey! Careful on the jacket.
It's Armani.
Are you angry?
I told you no wirehead shit
in my car. You're on foot!
In L.A.? Are you crazy?
Can I come in?
I'm having a hard time
hearing the stereo!
I need my case.
It's still in the back.
Can we talk a little bit
like two rational adults?
Uhh!
That'd be no.
OK,you got my attention.
This is cutting off
the circulation to my head.
Do you mind? Macey.
It's cool. It's nothing.
Two seconds.
This is uncharacteristic,
Miss Ice Water-In-Her-Veins.
You push me too far!
You made me lose it infront
of a client! I could get fired!
-Are we still friends?
-I don't know.
Friendship is more
than one person...
constantly doing
favors for an other.
I don't hustle my friends.
But you just suck people along
with scams and your slick act.
We're still buddies?
Don't use the time
that I'm talking...
to think about what
you'll say next.
-You listening?
-Yeah.
Lenny,your ass is always broke,
you go from score to score...
and you're getting strung-out.
You don't even see it.
It's your brain,
so do whatever you want with it.
But not on my watch,
you understand me?
I got a child, I got rent...
and an ex-husband
doing hard time...
who doesn't send me
a dime of support.
I'm just trying to hold on here.
I know you wouldn't say this
if you didn't care about me.
Thanks, Mace. Really.
You're getting out with Fumitsu,
and that's the end.
I'll get you to the Templars
in ten minutes.
I'm sorry for the inconvenience.
FUMITSU: I'm changing my plans.
Your supervisor has recommended
an excellent club...
called the Retinal Fetish.
It's on La Cienega.
Yes, sir.
MACE:
Enjoy your evening, Mr. Fumitsu.
LENNY: I appreciate it.
Thank you.
OK, come on.
Excuse us.
WOMAN: Hi, Lenny.
LENNY: This is a friend of mine,
Mr. Fumitsu.
Can you take care of him?
WOMAN: He's clean. He's fine.
Could you take care
of this gentleman?
LENNY: Thank you.
OK. Bye.
[Punk rock song playing]
TICK: Hey, Lenny. How ya doing?
LENNY: Who's the new side
of beef in Gant's posse?
TICK: Wade Beemer, running back
for the Rams, '96, '97.
Like a fucking freighttrain.
LENNY:
Rams. That's football, right?
TICK: No, ping-pong.
Iris was looking for you!
GANT: Hello, Lenny.
It's OK,Wade.
He's an old friend of mine.
Lenny Nero.
Come to peddle me some clips
for old time's sake...
or just making a few extra bucks
for the holidays?
LENNY:
You're not a client anymore.
I wouldn't sell you the sweat
off a dead dog's balls.
GANT: I've got everything
I need from you. Thanks.
FAITH: Cut it out, Philo.
Too bad about your guy Jeriko.
You've lost your golden goose.
Show some respect.
He was an important artist.
Important for your label,
so you're in mourning.
His records will sell out now,
and you'll make out.
Always do.
Faith, can I talk to you
for one second?
It's not a good idea right now.
I just gotta talk to you
for one second.
About what?
That'd be between me and Faith.
Funny, I don't feel anything
between you and Faith.
You see,
that's your problem, Lenny...
you assume too much.
You assume there's something
where there's nothing.
You assume
that you have a life...
when, infact,you peddle pieces
of other people's lives...
and the broken parts
of your own.
-Faith.
-Get him to his car.
Call me, OK?
Faith!
Call me!
Lenny the loser.
Leave him alone, Philo, OK?
You shouldn't talk to him
or anybody...
not with everything
that's going on.
You are too goddamn paranoid.
You know that, Philo?
Paranoia's just...
reality on afiner scale.
LENNY: Thank you.
[Prong singing "Strange Days"]
Awoo! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
LENNY: Hey. What's up,Tex?
TEX: What's up, my brother?
LENNY: Those rascals
still haven't grown back?
No. Any day now. I just know it.
Got something for you.
A present,
something I had custom-made.
Happy Millennium.
I got something for you,too.
Just showed up tonight.
I don't know who from.
LENNY:
Fan mail from some flounder?
Mmm.
-Hi.
PRONG SINGING:
Strange days not like before
I can hardly wait
It's been so long
I've lost my taste
Say angel come
Say lick my face
Let fall your drapes
I'll play the part
I'll open this mouth wide
Eat your heart
[Cheering]
Your heart
I can hardly wait
Lips crack dry
Tongue blue burst
Say angel come
Say lick my thrust
It's been so long
I've lost my taste
Here, Romeo
Take my water brain
LENNY: Hi, baby.
I missed you.
Lenny,you have to leave.
I mean it.
LENNY:
Iris said you were in trouble.
-You talked to lris? When?
-Tonight.
I haven't seen her in months.
What the fuck would she know?
Who knows what's going on
in that whore's head?
LENNY: She used to be
your best friend.
FAITH: You're really
running out of excuses...
to come around, aren't you?
I know you, Faith.
You're afraid of something.
What's going on?
Just let it alone, Lenny.
It'll take care of itself.
It's Gant, isn't it?
This guy is poison.
He's got you walled in.
He uses the wire too much.
He gets off on tape,
not on you.
That's a good one
coming from you.
Why don't you just split?
-I don't want to.
-Do you love him?
LENNY: I don't think so.
To him,you're some kind
of possession.
You're like a Ferrari.
You're just something
to show the other guys.
FAITH: Yeah?
He has his uses,too,you know.
LENNY: What? He gonna
record you on his label?
He might.
You never know, right?
Faith...
Faith, listen to me.
I've watched you create yourself
out of nothing.
You're like
a goddamn cruise missile...
targeted on making it,
and you will.
FAITH: I know I will.
LENNY: It's you
up on that stage, not him.
You don't need him.
You have to get out of here.
If Philo catches you,
he's gonna hurt you.
I'm already hurting.
FAITH: No, I'm serious.
He's acting crazy.
He's doing
way too much playback.
He's gotten completely paranoid.
He's such a controlfreak now...
he's even paying Max
to follow me around.
Max? You're kidding.
Yeah,for about a month now.
Jesus.
Look, Lenny,
just stay away from Philo...
and stay away from me.
Stop trying to rescue me.
Those days are over.
I'm a big girl now.
I've changed.
Stop trying to save me.
I don't need saving.
Just give up on me!
I just wanted to make sure
you were all right.
You know why movies
are still better than playback?
'Cause the music comes up,
there's credits...
and you always know
when it's over.
It's over!
You were great.
MAX: Hey, man.
I know what you're thinking.
She told me about your new gig.
It's just a job.
I feel like shit about it.
-You should feel like shit.
-I do.
You introduced me
to that prick Gant.
I introduced him to Faith,too.
I don't cherish the moment.
Questionable move, given
the historical perspective.
I figured I could take
the prick's money--
you wouldn't believe
what I'm charging him--
and make sure Faith
is OK atthe same time.
Keep an eye on her.
For you, OK?
Which you can't do...
without getting your fingers
bent the wrong way back.
I need the money.
This does us both some good.
Fairly twisted logic,
Max, even for you.
-Hey,you got a job.
-I got a job.
OK. I'm sorry. You got a job.
That's great.
Listen,you got to stay on her.
Watch her for me, please.
I'm on her.
-OK.
-Stay cool.
-Take it easy, all right?
-You,too.
WADE: Come on.
WADE:
Here, chicky, chicky, chicky...
LENNY: Wait a minute.
I recognize you.
You're Wade Beemer, right?
Running back for the Rams,
'96, '97, right?
Yeah. That's right.
I saw you play, man.
I mean,you were good.
I mean,
like a fuckin' freighttrain.
So,what happened?
Injuries or what?
Bullshit politics, man.
It's always politics.
Like this thing we're in here.
He's paying you to tune me up.
I'll pay you more not to.
I'll write a check right now.
-I got to go.
-OK. Cash!
Here's everything I have on me.
What do you say?
How about a Rolex?
I got a real one.
Come on. It won't hurt too bad.
It's nothing personal.
Just one second, please.
It's my jacket.
It's really expensive.
And just not--not the eyes.
You're bleeding.
Some jerk puked on the stairs,
and I slipped.
I should sue.
You came back for me.
I came back
to pick up my client.
No. You came back for me.
I got to lie down, Macey,
please, in the back?
MACE:
Some piece of work, Lenny Nero.
You're calmly back stroking along
in the big toilet bowl...
and somehow,
you never let it touch you.
I mean, between working vice...
and your current
so-called occupation...
you must have seen
every kind of perversion.
But you're just like
some Teflon man.
You still come out this...
goofball romantic.
It's my sword and my shield,
Macey.
LENNY: All right.
A little B & E action.
-What did you say?
-Nothing.
[Sirens in the distance]
Aah!
[Taser crackles]
Shit.
No, no.
Please. Please.
Please.
You can let me go, please.
I haven't seen yourface.
Please.
Let me go.
Let me go, please.
Oh, my...Holy...
Aah!
[Gasping]
Lenny.
Lenny!
Go to the Sunset Regent
right now.
Go! Go!
[Tires screech]
[Groans]
Oh, Christ.
He's jacking her
into his own output.
She's seeing what he's seeing.
She's--she's seeing herself!
[Crying and gasping]
Aah!
[Crying]
No...
Oh...
[Gasping]
Oh, my God.
[Strangling]
God! Uhh!
[Silence]
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
[Retching]
Lenny,what is it?
A black-jack.
Black-jack?
A snuff clip.
It was lris.
The sickfucker killed her.
Are you sure it's real?
Oh, shit.
[Max breathing heavily]
[Moans]
[Panting]
Well, I lost my appetite...
for about a year.
Want to take a look?
MACE: Hell, no.
I don't fool with that.
-You all right?
-Yeah.
-You OK?
-No. Not really.
MAX: Here.
All right.
Let's work it.
No, I--I can't.
Come on, Lenny,you used
to be good at this shit.
Let's play it down.
What's the perp doing?
I can't.
You used to be
a fuckin' cop, OK?
That is a fucking murder.
What's he doing?
He stalks her...
and...he rapes her...
and he does her.
And he records it.
He's a thrill-killer.
He wants to see it again.
He records himself
raping and killing her.
But he sends a signal to her.
So she feels what he feels
while he's inside her.
The thrill
while he's killing her...
sent to her...
heightening her fear...
which heightens
the turn-onfor him.
I've seen a lot.
MAX: So have I. Too much.
-It's a bad one.
-Yeah.
He makes her see her own death,
feeds off the reaction.
He records it all. Everything.
And gives it to you.
He wants to share it.
Of course
he wants to share, man.
That's his deal.
He needs an audience.
-This is a sick puppy.
-Why me?
'Cause you're
the Magic Man, Lenny.
You make dreams happen,
don't you?
If it's got something
to do with the wire...
sooner or later,
it washes up on your beach.
I've never dealt in black-jacks.
-Everybody knows that.
-He's just skull-fucking you.
MAX: He just wants
a reaction from you.
He wants to make you do
something you do not want to do.
MACE: Maybe he just figures
Lenny will appreciate it.
It's the dark end of the street.
How do you like it now?
Jesus, Mace, back off.
No. This guy's
one of your SQUID-head contacts.
He's somebody that you know.
MAX: The problem with that
is Lenny knows everybody.
Take the tape to the cops.
No.
No. They'll crucify me.
So this wire-freak gets
to keep running around, huh?
MAX: Lenny's right. The police
will think he's the perp...
or they'll go through his
client list and ruin his life...
such as it is.
I'll call my buddies
at Homicide.
I'll tell them lris
was a friend of mine...
and that'll put me in the loop.
I'll get the forensics
and all that shit.
Get some sleep.
I'll call you
when I get something.
Relax!
Lenny!
Keep moving, man.
Somebody's thinking
about you a whole lot.
[Blues guitar music]
[Guitar music echoing]
FAITH: Leave me alone.
Don't come to my house.
Are you trying to ruin my life?
Iris is dead. She was murdered.
Who did it?
LENNY: I don't know, but
this guy's real damaged goods.
Iris knew someone was after her.
She said
you were in danger,too.
-I'm not in any danger.
-No more games.
Whatever you're hiding,
whatever's going on...
you have to get out of here now.
Then what?
Are you gonna protect me?
Are you a big tough guy?
You're a fucking talker.
You don't even own a gun.
I have a gun. It's under my bed.
[Guitar music stops]
You don't know whatyou're
fucking with.
Tell me.
GANT: Tell him, Faith. Go on.
FAITH: Lenny just stopped by
to give me some bad news.
An oldfriend of mine's
been murdered.
Remember lris?
How the fuck
did you get up here?
Charm.
Tell you what, Lenny.
Just for you, hmm?
Make you a deal.
Why don't you just take her?
If she's so unhappy and
wants to leave, she can go.
I'll let her decide.
Faith always knows
what she wants. Don't you, baby?
See? Hands off.
I'll tell you something else.
I'll tell you this,you fuck.
If she says she stays,you go.
You crawl
back in your cockroach hole...
and you never
cross my vision again.
Faith...
Come on.
I've made my choice, Lenny.
Get him out.
Get him out!
You're fucking crazy, Faith!
Come with me! Faith!
I don't love you anymore!
Do you understand that?
You mean nothing to me!
Leave me alone, Lenny, please.
FAITH: You said you were
gonna get lris out of this.
GANT: Now you understand
the danger we're in.
That was so sweet what you
said out there. So touching.
I almost believed it.
I don't think he understands
you did it for him.
He doesn't even know
what's going on.
Leave him alone!
I'd leave him alone
if he'd stop coming around...
and you would just stop
talking to him!
The only time a whore
should open her mouth...
is when she's giving head.
LENNY: Shit! Mace! Help!
CORTO: Don't be shy, Lenny.
This is yourfloor.
Let's go.
Lenny, guess who's going
to the hospital?
LENNY: Can we be smart here?
I can make itworth yourwhile.
I'm not saying
I mind a couple of shots.
Just go light is all I'm saying.
Here, look. Take my Rolex.
CORTO: Ooh, nice watch.
-Is this impact resistant?
-Yeah, sure.
LENNY: Aah!
CORTO: You stupid piece of shit!
You stupidfuck. Get up!
Come on. Get up!
Unhh!
CORTO: Oh, ho. Pain, pain!
Hey, Lenny,we tried
tofind a smaller girl...
to beatthe shit out of you,
but itwas short notice.
Itwas short notice.
Oh! Ow! That one had to hurt.
Safety's on.
Uhh!
MACE: Come on. Let's go.
LENNY: Hey,wait!
CORTO: Ohh! That'sfucked up.
I need a drink.
MACE: Get some rest.
LENNY: The cops know
they'll never nail this guy...
the second
they walk in the room.
It's all about
whatthey see walking in--
dead hooker, handcuffs,
penetration.
Cops are lazy.
They know nobody gives a shit
about a dead hooker.
They're road kill, right?
They'll take some pictures,
make some jokes...
and just shrug it off
like it's a random kill.
It's a trick gone wrong.
It's the kind you never solve.
MACE:
That doesn't add, does it?
Because lris said
she knew somebody was after her.
That is not random.
If they get me--
[Siren]
She said "they."
"If they get me."
This whole random
sex-killerthing is bullshit.
Somebody whacked her
for a reason.
So this guy's not a psycho?
No, he's a psycho.
To do what's on thattape...
he's not a well-adjusted
human being.
I gotta get some sleep.
MACE: OK, Lenny.
Putthat down...
and I'll check on you tomorrow.
LENNY:
Hey,you wantto rub my neck?
My shoulder's real sore.
MACE: OK. All right. Come here.
-Right here?
-Oh,yeah.
Ohh...
Don't stop.
How's Zander?
MACE: He'sfine.
I miss him.
He misses you,too.
I'm real sorry about being
so hard on you earlier.
It's justthat I see you...
getting sucked into this
deeper and deeper, and...
LENNY: Macey, come on.
I know you still love me.
[Tires screech]
[Siren]
How can you do this
infront of your child?
-Infront of your own son?
-Macey, hold on!
MACE: [Sobbing]
lnfront of your own son!
Zander!
LENNY: "When a child loves you
for a long, long time...
"notjustto play with,
but really loves you--"
-Hi, honey.
-Hi, Mommy!
-This is Lenny.
-Hi.
Come on.
[Telephone rings]
Hi, it's Lenny.
Justwhat do you have in mind?
[Beep]
MAX: Last day of the world,
you spend it in bed?
-What's up, Max?
-Not a whole hell of a lot, man.
They've just been
saying words overJeriko.
Tension's running
pretty high down here.
-Faith OK?
-Yeah.
MAX: She's leaving with Gant,
so I gotta boogie real quick.
Iris checked into the Regent
last night under afalse name.
She paid cash.
-She was hiding out.
-Yep.
I heard you dropped in
on Gant last night.
Another slick Lenny move?
He's in this somehow,
but I don't know how.
Just stay close to Faith, OK?
No worries, bro. I gotta jam.
[Gasps]
[Panting]
[Door opens]
Jesus.
What up, Lenny?
-Where are we going?
-Anywhere.
MACE: You're acting strange.
What's going on?
-Shh, Mace.
-What?
We'll talk about it in the car.
Hand me that box of tapes.
MACE: Yeah.
-Oh, shit.
-What's the matter?
This tie doesn't go with blue.
[Yelling]
MACE: Lenny,would you relax?
We're not beingfollowed.
Stop being so paranoid.
LENNY: The guy had a knife
to my throat in my living room.
Relaxing might be right out.
Aah!
[Panting]
TICK: Oh, man.
That is one unbelievable piece
of eyefuck.
LENNY:
Skipthe art criticism,Tick.
What can you tell me
aboutthe wearer?
-That guy isfucked up.
-We know that.
No. The killer's got
some kind of distortion...
in the visual cortex.
The color and gray-scale values
are all messed up.
Like color blindness.
See the peak period ratios?
There could be some kind
of tumor or brain lesion.
Whoever's doing this is using
a box to splitthe signal--
You ever make a box like that?
Yeah, but I can't see the gear
well enough to see if it's mine.
I don't like this.
-This is not good.
-What?
TICK: It's cutting close to me.
She was just here, man.
-Who was?
-Iris! Pay attention!
Iris was here?
The other night,
shaking like a junkie...
saying she wanted me
to copy some clip.
-Whatwas it?
-She wouldn't let me see.
She was going to give it
to you to holdfor her...
Iike insurance or something.
-She never gave me a tape.
-Think backto what she said.
She came in crying.
She wanted to go to my car.
Can we go to your car?
You have to see something.
-Something about my car.
-In your car.
[Barking]
[Whimpering]
LENNY: That's a handy little
attitude adjuster.
Damn. I'm boxed in.
What's it say?
LENNY: Nothing.
Let's go play this back.
STECKLER:
Give us the tape right now.
I justwantto get my car back.
The place is closed.
Shutthefuck up.
Aah! Give him the tape.
It's in my case.
I'm going to open my case.
ENGELMAN:
Facing us, so we can see it.
Take it and turn her loose, OK?
Yeah. Absolutely.
ENGELMAN: Aah!
Uhh.
-Aah!
[Tires screech]
LENNY: "Oh, no.
We're not beingfollowed, Lenny.
"Don't be so paranoid, Lenny."
Aah!
Oh, shit!
Take it easy.
The glass is bullet-resistant.
Bullet-resistant?
What happened to bulletproof?
Shit!
Calm down, baby.
This is what I do.
Hang on!
Oh, Christ.
Unh!
[Breathing heavily]
[Lenny dialing]
Shit!
MACE: Fuck.
God damn it.
Nine-one-one is busy.
It's all right, Lenny.
They'd never make it in time,
anyway.
Uhh!
Itwon't open.
Oh, shit. You're crazy.
Oh, God.
This is bad.
The gas tank's
gonna go any second.
Hold on.
MACE: Uhh!
Are you
out of yourfucking mind?
Thefire is out, isn't it?
Get in here, Lenny.
Come on! Move it! Move!
Uhh!
Get ready to hold your breath.
Just kick out hard
andfollow me, OK?
STECKLER: Let's get out of here.
I can't believe you had
to give them the damn tape.
Yeah. Me neither.
Itwas one of myfavorites--
me and Faith in the hottub
on my birthday.
Are we impressed yet?
Yeah.
Pretty impressed.
JERIKO RAPPING:
Here we kitty come, come...
CURTIS: I'm missing
the party of the century...
hauling your asses around--
MACE: Hey, Curtis,
just drive, all right?
CURTIS: This shit is wack.
Those guys were cops.
You sure?
It's the walk or something.
They'll run your plates
and getyour address.
We gotto keep moving.
JERIKO RAPPING:
That crawls through the cracks
You love that red...
CECILE: Whatyou doing all wet?
Lornette,what's up?
MACE: Zander,we're going
to Aunt Cecile's house.
We'll watch thefireworks
from there.
-Aw, Ma.
-Come on, boy.
LENNY: Come on, Zander.
We're goingfor a ride, OK?
[Beeping]
-I wantto know what's going on.
-Get in the car, Cecile.
-What's going on?
-Now.
[Radio playing rap music]
RONNIE:
Yo,what's up? How y'all doing?
-Yo, Mace.
-Hey, Ronnie.
-You never come around.
-I been working.
MACE:
This is Lenny. He's with me.
RONNIE: What's up?
-Watch thefireworks, baby.
-How you guys doing?
-Hey.
MACE: Good seeing you.
[Sighs]
Tell me.
I can'ttell you.
You gotto see it.
I'm not doing it.
I know whatyou think
aboutthe wire...
butyou gotto see it.
It's that important.
OK?
I'm sorry this has to be
yourfirst playback.
Keepyour eyes closed,
oryou'll see double.
[Radio playing]
IRIS: Baby,yes.
[Laughing]
REPLAY:
I wanna thankyou,Jeriko.
I owe you oneforthis,
my brother.
JERIKO:
You owe me two,you bastard.
REPLY: All right. I owe you
three,four,five, and six.
IRIS: Hey, baby.
[Laughing]
REPLAY:
Yes,yes,yes. Oh,yeah, baby.
[Siren]
Lights. Damn. Look atthis, man.
REPLAY: Oh, goddamn, man.
Just be cool,Jeriko. Yo.
JERIKO: I'm not speeding, man.
Man,what's the matter--
a black man can't own no Jeep?
STECKLER ON LOUDSPEAKER:
Pull to thefoot of the ramp.
JERIKO: Black man with a white
girl againstthe law in L.A.?
[Horn honks]
REPLAY: You know how it is.
If we be cool,they be cool.
No trouble.
I can't afford no trouble.
JERIKO: I'm upset.
JERIKO: A man can't do shit
in this town.
DIAMANDA:
I ain't going back, lris.
I don't give afuck.
I ain't going back.
STECKLER:
Driver, step out of the vehicle.
Get down on your knees.
Putyour hands
behind your head. Now!
ENGELMAN:
Everyone else, out of the car.
JERIKO: Goddamn, man!
Whatyou pull me overfor?
If I was going slower,
I'd have been parked.
STECKLER: On your knees.
Putyour hands behind your head.
ENGELMAN: Putyour hands
on the hood of car.
-Don't move. You,too, bitch!
-Aah!
JERIKO: I suppose you pulled us
over because you had suspects...
fitting our description
in the area.
Is that
whatyou're going to tell me?
Whatwas the description,
two black males in a car?
Yeah, right.
REPLAY: Ow! Fuck!
You know what? You pulled over
the wrong black male tonight...
Officer--what is it? "Steckler."
Officer Steckler.
I'm that eight-hundred-pound
gorilla in your mist,fucker!
I make more money in a day
than you make in a year!
And my lawyer
loves spending my money...
dragging sorry-ass,Aryan,
Robocopfuckers into court.
Get a man down on the ground
with no probable cause.
STECKLER: Shutthefuck up.
DIAMANDA:
He didn't do anything.
Shut up and get back overthere!
-You all right?
-Motherfucker kicked me.
ENGELMAN: It's that rap asshole.
STECKLER:
You're that rapper puke.
Jeriko One?
You're the one that's getting
all the gangbangers together...
going downtown,
forming citizen groups...
trying to rake the LAPD
over a cheese grater?
JERIKO: That's right, and you
gonna be in my next song.
It's gonna be called
"Robo-Steckler."
[Laughter]
It's all about a cop
who met his worst nightmare...
a nigger
with enough political juice...
to scrunch his ass
like a stink bug.
You gonna befamous,fucker!
STECKLER: I don'tthink so.
REPLAY: Whatthefuck? No!
[Iris and Diamanda screaming]
STECKLER: Stopthat bitch!
DIAMANDA: Aah!
IRIS: Oh, no. Oh,fuck. Aah!
STECKLER: Get her!
IRIS: Oh, no. Fuck.
[Iris screaming]
[Bullets ricocheting]
IRIS: Oh, God!
-There she goes!
-Get her!
IRIS: Aah!
[Train horn blaring]
STECKLER: You bitch!
[Horn blaring]
IRIS: Aah!
ENGELMAN:
I don'tfucking see her!
[Gunshots]
LENNY: Hang on, Max.
Mace.
You see?
You had to see it.
I see the world opening up
and swallowing us all.
Yeah. I know.
Max, are you there?
Meet me atTick's
in half an hour.
And, Lenny,
don't get pulled over, OK?
You know whatthis tape
could do if it got out?
Yeah. I got a pretty good idea.
Peoplefinding out...
seeing...
thatthe LAPD justflat-out
executed Jeriko One.
Jesus.
Maybe they oughtto see.
LENNY: Maybe...
buttonight's probably
notthe best night.
Mace.
Come on.
We're rolling.
LENNY: I don'tthink
those cops did lris.
Whoever lris was wearingfor
killed her.
Why?
LENNY: lf those cops
had gotten hold of her...
they'd have beat it out of her
who she was wearingfor...
and gone afterthem,too.
Our killer is running
as scared as we are...
which makes him
really dangerous...
judging by how scared I am.
COP: Hold it up.
COP: Let her go.
[Rock music plays loudly]
Sounds like Tick's
already celebrating.
LENNY: You seem overdressed
forthis party.
MAX:
I wanted to look niceforyou.
Hey,Tick, I gotto talkto you.
LENNY: Shit!
[Music stops]
He's been cooked off.
MACE: ls he dead?
LENNY: No, but hisfrontal lobes
are like two runny eggs.
They put an amplifier in-line
to boostthe signal...
and itfries his brain.
Tick!
It's Lenny!
Hey, hey,Tick, come on!
Tick, it's me. Lenny.
Come on. Wake up!
Tick!
Come on!
Come on,Tick, come on!
He's totally cut off
from the outside world.
How long does it last?
Forever.
Those two psycho cops
are on a slash-and-burn...
tofind the tape
and covertheirtracks.
Tick is a known duplicator.
They wanttofind outwhat he
knows, if copies were made...
orwho might've wired up lris.
It doesn't even get investigated
as a homicide...
since he's technically alive.
Yeah. That's right.
He's technically alive.
Seems sophisticatedforthem.
These are not subtle guys.
There's more to this
than you think.
What do you mean?
All I'm saying is...
you don't know how high up
thefood chain this thing goes.
I heard stuff.
What stuff?
I heard stuff, smoke, rumors.
I've heard stuff.
I've heard stuff
about a death squad.
They're a group of guys, cops,
loyal to the hard-line school.
Guys who've had too many years
of city hall, review boards...
and the goddamn media
pissing down their necks...
suspending cops right and left,
tying their hands...
while these same people
are squealing...
"Save us! Save us!
Do something,you morons.
"Crime is totally
out of control."
LENNY: Bullshit, Max.
It's conspiracy paranoia.
The issue isn'twhether
you're paranoid.
The issue is whether
you're paranoid enough.
Christ.
Exactly. Get religion, man.
I love you
like my own blood, Lenny...
but don'twalk near me
in public right now, OK?
The only card
we gotto play is the tape.
Get itto the media.
That's right. Blow it open.
Run that on
the eleven o'clock news...
by midnight,you've got
the biggest riot in history.
They'll see the smoke in Canada.
Whatthe hell are you saying--
pretend it didn't happen?
-I didn't say that.
-It happened.
The LAPD executed...
one of the most important
black men in America.
Who thefuck are you
to try to bury it?
STECKLER: Trying to rake
the LAPD over a cheese grater?
You want blood running
in the storm drains, go do it.
Two hundred thousand gangbangers
will spread through this city...
and burn it
to thefucking ground, Mace.
Once thefire starts...
the cops will cap off
anything that moves.
It'll be an all-outwar.
STECKLER: I don'tthink so.
Maybe it's timefor a war.
You really wantthat
on your head, Mace, huh?
Really?
Whoever did lris did Tick.
It's the same sick
wirehead shit.
It's the same reason--
to burn the trail.
If Faith knows anything
aboutthis, and she does--
Somebody's going to kill Faith?
[Singing]
Yeah,you're not rid of me
No,you're not rid of me
I'll make you lick my injuries
I'm gonna twistyour head off,
see?
Till you say, don'tyou wish you
Never, never met her?
Don'tyou, don'tyou wish you
[Cheers]
Aah!
Jesus, Lenny,
you scared thefuck out of me!
What do you want?
LENNY: We know aboutJeriko.
Iris made me a copy of the tape.
I was trying to keepyou
out of this.
LENNY: I know. How'd it happen?
MACE: Why was lris riding around
with Jeriko wearing a wire?
Faith, listen--Look at me.
You gotto trust us.
We're here to helpyou.
All right.
I'll talkto you alone.
Mace is in this.
Tell us.
Faith.
Philo, he's gotten
obsessed with playback.
He's a total wiretripjunkie.
He's such a controlfreak, he's
been having peoplefollowed.
He's recording his business
partners' phone calls.
He's wiring up people
left and right.
Philo and Jeriko
weren't getting along.
He was afraid Jeriko
was gonna dump him...
but he wasn't sure, so he starts
with the surveillance.
A couple of nights ago,
he wires up lris...
and he sends her
and the other girl, Diamanda...
overto Jeriko's table.
DIAMANDA: Hi, baby.
IRIS: Hi. My name is lris.
JERIKO: Hey.
IRIS: I got a presentforyou.
You are so beautiful.
FAITH: So that night,
lris calls up crying.
She'sfreaking out.
She comes over,
and she plays the tape.
Philo loses it.
He can't believe the disaster
she's gotten him into.
He's afraid the cops
will beat it out of her...
who she's been workingfor
and then come lookingfor him.
MACE: Why didn't he just
go public with the tape?
Save himself thatway?
FAITH: lf it got out
he spied on his own artists...
he'd lose all his other acts,
and it'd be overfor him.
PHILO: Shh.
FAITH:
So he gives lris some money.
He tells herto check into
a hotel under an assumed name...
until he canfigure out
whatto do.
Hefigured outwhatto do.
You think he killed her?
The killer knew where she was
because he put herthere.
What a nightmare.
PHILO: I don't know where
thefuck she is, butwe're late.
Let's go.
MAX: Philo, how do you want me
to work it atthe Bonaventure?
Want me downstairs atthe party
or upstairs atthe suite?
Lenny.
Leave here with me right now.
MACE: Come on.
-We'll talk aboutthat later.
-No, man. I need to know.
PHILO: Joey,whatthefuck
are you waitingfor? Get her.
I just say things once, baby.
We will talk aboutthat later.
OK, man.
I'm cool. I'm sorry, man.
Hey,Wade,
go outfor a pass, bro.
[Singing] Blue sky
No white clouds in my blue sky
Oh, shit!
CORTO:
Get out of myfuckin' way!
MACE: Come on! Come on!
FAITH: Lenny!
MACE: Go! Go!
CORTO: Pardon me! Sorry! Sorry!
Get out of myfuckin' way!
Move it! Move!
LENNY: Faith?
FAITH: Lenny!
GANT: Hello, Lenny,youfuck!
Let's go, darling. Walkwith me.
Happy New Year!
CORTO:
Get out of the way! Look out!
-Get out of the way!
-Lenny!
CORTO: Sorry. Excuse me.
Get out of myfucking way!
[Women screaming]
Vita,Vita, not now, baby.
Come on. Not here.
REPORTER: There he is.
Mr. Gant,
afew questions, please?
[Reporters
shouting questions]
Well, I'm certainly
in the moodfor a party.
Wade,take her upto the suite.
WADE: No problem.
PHILO: You go and have
a glass of champagne...
or six.
See you upthere in a bit,
helpyou ring in the new year.
I liveforthe moment.
MACE: Pussy-whipped,
sorry-ass motherfucker.
Oww!
Take it easy.
Where are they now?
He's got her up in the room,
under guard.
He's still working the party...
acting smooth
like nothing's nothing.
-I say we work a trade.
-What do you mean?
Give him the clip.
It'sfucking brilliant.
The tapefor Faith.
I know he'll gofor it,
and I can set it up.
This is whatwe laughingly
referto as a plan, right?
Just getyour butt down here.
If I'm not downstairs,
go to the room.
It's twenty-two-oh-three.
You writing?
LENNY: Two-two-zero-three.
If he gives us any shit...
we kill them all.
What do you say?
Really scatterthe pigeons.
We gotto get overthere.
Can you borrow a dress
from Cecile or something?
I'm not going.
Gant's going to do her
rightthere.
Shut up.
Lenny,
parkyour mouth and listen.
It's a setup. Think about it.
Why's he sending tapes to you?
To getyou to rush in...
put a bullet in you, one in her,
and the gun in your hand.
Yeah,that sounds right.
I'm going.
You gonna getyourself
killedforthis?
Forthis toxic-waste bitch?
LENNY:
Whatthefuck are you doing?
MACE: This is your life!
Right here! Right now!
It's real time,you hear me?
Real time!
Time to get real, not playback.
You understand me?
She doesn't love you anymore.
Maybe she did once,
but she doesn't now.
These are used emotions.
It's time to trade them in.
Memories were meanttofade.
They're designed thatway
for a reason.
Have you ever been
in love with...
someone who didn't return
that love?
Yeah, Lenny...
I have.
Didn't stopyou
from loving them, right?
Or being able
to understand them...
orforgive them?
I guess.
Didn't stopyou
from wanting to protectthem...
did it?
When I met Faith,
she was just another...
another runaway...
giving twenty-dollar blow jobs
to buy crank.
Just another lost soul.
And she had this voice
thatwas...
Well, itwas scary.
Like she could take
all the hurt and rage...
of the entire world...
and lift it upto heaven
in one voice.
I helped her.
And I promised herthat
I'll always just be there...
to protect her.
See, it's not about
what's in her head.
It's aboutwhat's in mine.
I can't let go of the promise.
It's like it's all I have left.
No, it's not.
Come on.
Let's go to a party.
[Huge crowd cheering]
[Playing heavy metal music]
The end of the world,yeah!
LENNY: Shit!
MACE: Let's bail.
LENNY: Hey, Mace.
You look great in that dress.
I mean, betterthan I would.
Thankyou, I think.
Come on, let's go.
GUARDSMAN:
Hold it rightthere!
MACE: What's your plan...
for getting into the most
sold-out party in history?
LENNY:
Relax, Mace. This is what I do.
[Singing in African language]
You see Gant?
MACE: Uh-uh.
Oh, shit.
[Hits speed dialer]
LENNY:
Come on, Max. Come on, buddy.
Come on, buddy.
OPERATOR: The customeryou have
called is unavailable...
or has traveled--
LENNY: All right.
I still got one ace to play.
Gant's gotwhat I want.
I've gotwhat he wants.
This is the original.
There are no copies.
That's why it's a makeable deal.
This tape is a lightning bolt
from God.
It's worth more than you,
more than me...
and more than Faith.
You understand?
It can change things
that need changing...
before we all go off
the end of the road.
You do not have the right
to use itfor currency.
So if you go...
you go alone.
I care aboutyou, Lenny...
a lot more than you know...
which makes us both
pretty stupid, huh?
But if you pawn this tape...
you mean nothing to me.
Excuse me.
You see that guy overthere?
That's Deputy Commissioner
Palmer Strickland...
the sanctimonious prick
who busted me out.
His ass is so tight...
when hefarts
only dogs can hear it.
If there's one cop
who's not dirty, it's him.
Take itto him.
You want me to trust a cop?
No. Trust me. Here.
What if you're wrong?
Go.
STRICKLAND: Excuse me.
Commissioner...
there's a clip in here
thatyou need to see right now.
If itweren't New Year's Eve,
I'd have you arrested...
for possession
of illegal equipment.
MACE: Just look atthe clip.
You wantto know
who killed Jeriko...
go into that stall right now
and hit "play."
COP: ls there a problem?
MACE: Damn it, I knew it.
-Let's go.
-Let go of me!
Sir?
Wade, can we talk here
like two human beings?
It's nothing personal.
[Bagpipes playing]
DUNCAN:
Remember me,youfucking bitch?
Come on! Come on!
What are you looking at?
God damn it!
Enjoy the party.
Steckler...Steckler!
Fuck!
I didn't hearyou come in.
FAITH: Uhh!
Uhh!
Aah! No!
[Intruder moans]
Shh.
Uhh...
[Groans]
Oh!
FAITH: Uh...uhh...
Shit.
[Grunting]
Max.
No.
MAX: You OK?
Mmm?
Did I hurtyou?
Huh?
I love you, Max.
MAX: You're so pretty, Faith.
Shit!
Come here!
Come here,youfuck!
GANT:
Do you wanttofuckin' die?
You wanttofuckin' die?
MAX: Piece of puke
hired me to kill you, baby.
Can you believe that?
lsn'tthat right, Gant?
FAITH: I can't believe
this is happening.
MAX: Believe it!
Bring me the 'trodes
and the deck.
Quick! Come here, big shot,
suck on this.
You wantto suck on something?
FAITH: What are you gonna do?
You can'tjust kill him, Max!
MAX: I'm not gonna kill him.
Just a little poach job.
GANT: Ohhh!
MAX: You shutthefuck up!
Shut up!
Or I'll pull
thisfucking trigger!
[Fireworks explode]
FAITH: Aah! Fuck!
MAX: Here's how much
I love you, baby.
FAITH: God, Max!
MAX: Hope you enjoy the show,
Philo...
youfuck.
-Take it,you prick!
-No, Max! Don't do it!
MAX: Take it! Take it!
Take it!
Don't make any assumptions
about ourfriendship, Lenny.
I didn't know
you were color blind, Max.
Only way I could stand
yourties.
Manos arriba, amigo.
Ooh.
Glocktwenty-three.
Nice.
Where's Faith?
MAX: I sent herto the party.
Ifigured I'd wait up here
until you killed Gant.
What makes you think
I'm gonna kill Gant?
MAX: You just did.
Jesus!
Statistically,that's the second
most common word people say...
right before they die...
"shit" being number one.
So, uh...
I killed Gant,
then you ran in...
and being on his payroll,
you shot me.
That's the way it happened.
LENNY: Now I'm remembering.
I killed lris,too, didn't l?
They'llfind the original
of her snuff clip...
in your apartment.
The one I left atthe club
was a copy.
Was I a really busy guy?
Did I do Tick,too?
You bet. Did you like it?
So,why, Max?
Why did you have to do lris?
Ifeel like I gotta share this
with somebody...
'cause it's justtoo perfect.
I won't say anything.
Oh, I know.
So, I'm working
forthis puke, right?
And he says he'll pay me
quite large to do the hooker...
but I also gotto do
his bitch girlfriend...
'cause she knows the score,
and she's out of control.
Only he doesn't know
about me and Faith.
So I say to myself,
if I turn the job down...
he'll get somebody else,
and I lose Faith...
to coin a phrase.
To buy time, I do the skank...
but I still got
to deal with Gant.
It's him or me...
but I can't cap him
without some chump...
to take thefall.
And who better...
than his girlfriend's loser
ex-boyfriend--known criminal...
and who has been seen
hassling them in public?
Who is, regrettably,
also your bestfuckingfriend.
No plan is perfect, Lenny.
Cheer up. The world's ending
in ten minutes, anyway.
You must be so pleased.
I mean, lfollowed your
jellybean trail right here...
Iike a good little chump.
You gotfoggy on me
a couple times.
Rememberthat riff
aboutthe death squad?
I had to keepyou
from going to the cops.
I've heard stuff
about a death squad.
The issue isn'twhether
you're paranoid, Lenny.
The issue's whether
you're paranoid enough.
-There neverwas a death squad?
-No.
Justtwo loose-cannon cops
covering their butts.
Pretty zany, huh? All this
caused by a random traffic stop.
Nothing means nothing, man.
You know that.
The whole planet's
in totalfucking chaos.
JERIKO: The day of reckoning
is upon us!
You gotta getwhatyou can
while you can...
'cause some shitbird can
come put a twenty-two...
in the back of your head...
any second.
Aah!
How'd you hook upwith Faith?
Hmm...
Thisfuck hires me about
a month ago to eyeball her...
only Faith knows mefrom you.
So she comes upto me and says,
"Max,why are youfollowing me?"
And I say, "I'll buy you
a drink. I'll explain."
And she says--
FAITH:
"Do you enjoy watching me?"
You're supposed
to go downstairs, baby.
I know.
I don't always do what I'm told.
You know that.
So I said,
"Do you enjoy watching me?"
Come on, Max. Play with me.
And then what'd you say?
I said,
"Yeah, I'd even do itforfree."
FAITH: Uh-huh.
And I said, "That's good...
"because I like thefeeling
of someone watching me.
"I acquired the taste
from Lenny."
MAX: And then she said...
"Since we're going to spend
so much time together..."
"Why don'twe make
the best of it?"
[Fireworks exploding]
The very best.
You know all aboutthat,
don'tyou, Lenny?
Faith and me,
wefound a place...
you could never reach, Max.
Never.
Faith...
I know it's gone.
Butyou, Max,
you can'tfucking touch it.
Enjoy it.
FAITH: Lenny!
MAX: Fucking bitch!
LENNY: Shit.
MAX: Youfucking bitch!
FAITH: You bastard!
God!
MAX: Aah!
Fuckyou!
[Screams]
MAX: Come here!
LENNY: Go to hell!
MAX:
Motherfucker! You're going down!
Come here!
MAX: Aah!
LENNY: Oh!
[Cheering]
Ohh!
Oh!
Come here, Lenny!
I'm taking you with me,
you motherfucker! Come here!
Come here with me!
Motherfucker!
Come here!
[Lenny screaming in pain]
[Screaming]
[Singing]
They're selling Jesus again
They wantyour soul
And your money
Your blood and yourvotes
They're selling Jesus again
Selling love to you
Selling love
Out!
Love
There she is!
PARTYGOER: Fuckyou!
Getthefuck outta here!
ENGELMAN: Freeze!
I said,fuckingfreeze!
[Taser crackles]
Down!
All the way down right now!
Now pay attention, motherfucker!
Stay down.
Down! Down! Down! Down!
Down now!
You son of a bitch!
You ain't goin' anywhere!
[Other officers approach
shouting]
FIRST COP:
Get off! You heard the man!
Shut up and move!
FIRST COP:
Putthat gun down!
SECOND COP:
Get on the ground now!
Hold it.
Hold on.
Let me tell you
what's going on here.
Let me tell you what's going on.
Get on the ground now!
Now!
Let me tell you what happened!
Just listen. No!
All right?
Getthesefucking things off me!
Don't uncuff him!
FIRST COP: Shut up! Get down!
Putthatwhore down now!
MACE: Wait!
You don't know what happened!
STECKLER: Yes! Fuck her up!
STECKLER: Hit her! Hit her!
Leave her alone!
Kick his head in!
Beatthe shit outta him!
GUARDSMAN: Move out!
STECKLER:
Commissioner Strickland!
That is the cause of all this!
Rightfucking there!
These two are under arrest
for murder!
Read them their rights! Move it!
-Yes, sir.
COP: You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will
be used againstyou...
in a court of law.
You have the right
to an attorney.
If you can't afford an attorney,
one will be providedforyou.
STRICKLAND: Getthis woman
some medical attention.
COP: Get some medics
up herefrom the Guard!
Mace, are you OK?
I got 'em.
[Lenny laughs]
Getthefuck outta here!
Everybody!
Backthefuck up!
Dropyourweapon!
Drop it now!
No! No!
No!
COP: Putthat gun down!
-Dropyourweapon!
-Dropthe gun now!
Now! Drop it!
Put it down right now!
-Dropyourweapon!
-Shoot!
You...fucking...
nigger bitch!
Lenny!
Lenny! Lenny!
No, no, Lenny, Lenny.
LENNY: Yeah?
What?
Are we under arrest?
Nah,they just have
to ask us afew questions...
for about six hours.
MEDIC:
OK,where are you hurt, sir?
SECOND MEDIC:
Ma'am,you OK? Ma'am?
MACE: Yeah.
MEDIC: Getthat coat off.
You hurt anywhere else?
CROWD: Ten...nine...
eight...seven...
six...five...
four...
three...
two...
one!
Whoo!
MEDIC: You need an ambulance.
Let's go this way.
Come on this way, sir.
Hey, Lenny,we made it.
Yeah,we did.
You should get going.
Yeah.
See you downtown.
See you there.
MEDIC: Make way!
LORI CARSON SINGING:
Ahh
Ahhh
Ahhhh
Pretend there's no night
Hold on
Everything has
Come apart
But in this moment
Right now
When it can come together
Makes no sense
What's there to lose?
Fall in the light
Will you catch me
if I'mfalling?
Will you catch me?
Hold on...hold on
Hold on
Will you catch me?
[Peter Gabriel and Deep Forest
play "While the Earth Sleeps"]