Police Department, zone one.
Sergeant Roberts.
The Polish Hill Strangler
has claimed a fourth victim.
The nude body of Arlene Dunn
was recovered from the Ohio River.
Police had been alerted
to the crimes by the killer, -
- who taunts them by playing the
song "Little Red Riding Hood".
The police brutality trial
of Detective Jimmy Detillo is over.
Detillo was convicted
for the beating ofLeon Watson.
Watson remains in a coma.
The key to the conviction -
- was the testimony of Detillo's
partner and cousin Thomas Hardy.
Hardy testified that his partner
used unwarranted force.
Come on, son, we're gonna
be late for the policeman's ball.
- You've got to face him sometime.
- I feel like an asshole.
Maybe you are an asshole.
You always were kind of strange.
- I had you as a role model.
- You got that from your mother.
- I see you got the boat fixed.
- Yeah, we're going out tomorrow.
What's the latest
on Little Red Riding Hood?
We get close, he slips away.
I'm telling you, Dad, it's a cop.
Maybe an ex-cop.
Uncle Nick thinks so, too.
- Did you talk to him about Jimmy?
- We talked around it.
Every cop in Pittsburgh
thinks I'm a rat.
You're not a rat.
You told the truth. Nick knows that.
Yeah, we'll look where it's got me.
It's tough, but you know
what my dad used to say?
"Loyalty above all else,
except honour."
We're pursuing a murdersuspect.
'89 Ford, dark blue, RHX715.
Wejust crossed
the 31st StreetBridge.
Suspectis armed and dangerous.
- Let's go.
- So much for the policeman's ball.
Take Bigelow.
- Don't you have a date tonight?
- You're my date.
- What happened to that nurse?
- It just didn't work out.
You've got to give these things
a chance, Tommy.
That girl that works for Dutch
is awful nice.
- Is there some meaning in all this?
- Grandkids.
What?
I'm not that grown up myself yet.
- There they are.
- Go down the alley.
Send an ambulance
to the southbound tube.
We'll trap him at 2nd Ave.
Captain Hardy.
Get out of the car now
with your hands up.
- Uncle Nick.
- Is this the policeman's ball?
This is your last chance.
Get out with your hands up.
Here he comes.
He drives like a cop.
Pull up to him.
Come on, fellas, easy.
My leg!
Something's wrong with my leg.
- Where's Dad?
- Tommy, listen ...
He's been shot, Tommy.
The killer got away.
Daddy! Jesus Christ!
Look who's here.
- Tommy, sorry about your father.
- Thanks, Don.
You just couldn't stay away.
Why come to the sentencing?
We've already heard your testimony.
- Uncle Nick.
- Hi, Tommy.
- How are you feeling?
- I don't know.
- How's the leg?
- Okay.
- I don't want to be here.
- You're a better man than I am.
Tommy, they got the guy
that killed your father.
- What is this?
- His name's Kesser.
He couldn't even lift those women.
We have an eyewitness
that saw him dump a body.
- Even you said it was a cop.
- I said it could be.
Now we have a witness
that said it wasn't.
- Dad, let's go in.
- Sit down, I'll be right with you.
Go ahead. Sit down.
I'll be right in.
I don't want any problems with you.
Do you understand me?
You should be glad we caught him.
Where is he?
They're going to throw the book
at him, Nick. Your son or not.
The criminal court of Pennsylvania
is now in session.
The sentencing for the State
versus Detective Jimmy Detillo.
The Honourable Judge Hellen Kramer
presiding.
- Mr. Gunther, where is your client?
- We don't know, Your Honour.
Jimmy ... Son, listen to me.
Listen to Daddy. We'll talk to them.
We'll work something out.
Mama went off this bridge.
You remember?
They never found her.
Jimmy, you don't have to do this.
Cops don't go to prison, Dad.
I don't go!
Are you gonna give him a push?
- Jimmy!
- Hey, Tommy.
That's my partner.
My flesh and blood!
Come on down.
You're scaring everybody.
- Who's the best cop now?
- You, Jimmy. Always you.
Who's the best cop now?
Always you, Jim.
Come on down.
Come on, partner. Just take my hand.
Come on.
Come on down.
- No!
- Jimmy!
- You motherfucker! You did this.
- Let go of him.
You did this. Fuck you!
No, Bob!
Don't lick me with that fish breath.
Hey, Hardy.
RIVER RESCUE
He's still on the sauce.
He'll be sleeping it off somewhere.
He's a fifth generation cop.
He'll show.
Yeah? Who wants to bet?
- $20 says he don't show.
- You're on.
Thank you.
- Tie that up for me, will you?
- Hardy!
I've been calling you for an hour.
You missed roll call.
Penderman's really pissed.
You look like shit.
Did you fall off the wagon?
You're a fucking mess.
I'm sick of taking shit for you.
- What do I put in the log?
- Will you get the stern line?
You're a real asshole.
How did I end up with you?
Hardy!
Get some dry clothes on, Sacco.
I'll catch you on the next run.
River Rescue 9221, this is base.
We have a 111
one mile south of Neville lsland.
10-4.
Kim Lee, get Hardy.
- 9221, this is base. Come in.
- Go ahead.
This is Penderman.
Get back here and pick up Sacco.
Hardy. Hardy!
Malfunction on his radio, sir.
Like when you shut it off.
- Jeff Schultz. Where's your diver?
- He fell off.
Open it up.
Stand back, please.
Shot in the heart. Small caliber.
Been in the water 48 hours.
Less. 24 hours.
She's been dead 48 though.
Somebody held on to her a while.
- Who's this guy?
- Tom Hardy.
- Tom Hardy?
- The infamous.
- Uncle Nick.
- How are you?
- How come you never call me?
- I call, you're always busy.
- Danny's back.
- Where was he all this time?
California, someplace.
- What did he say?
- Nothing much. You know Danny.
- How are the treating you at work?
- Good.
I read that Rossmore is retiring.
Are you gonna be the next chief?
Not me, kid.
I'm just a Larimer Avenue dago.
- I hear they're gonna fry Kesser.
- That's what they do with killers.
- I'll see you around.
- Come on, let's go.
When I grow up, I'd love
to have a pair of shorts like that.
- How's your wife, Eddie?
- None of your fucking business.
How would you know ...
You're his partner, how's his wife?
Eddie's picking on me again,
Uncle Nick.
One of these days
it's just going to be you and me!
Workers discovered the nude body
wrapped in a sheet.
She was identified as
Cheryl Putnam of Monessen.
Miss Putnam, a stewardess,
was abducted from her home, -
- then taken to another location,
where she was murdered.
The brutal crime reminds many
of the Polish Hillstranglings.
There's no connection other than
the victim being a white female.
The Polish Hill victims were
strangled, not shot at close range.
- You picked the wrong house to rob.
- You got nothing worth stealing.
- It's been a long time.
- I could've killed you.
- I wanted to surprise you.
- You did.
Give me a drink.
Why do you live on a houseboat?
You and your old man
should've burned this place down.
- How was California?
- Sunny.
Sunny? You're out there two years
and that's all you can tell me?
"The Simpsons"
are on an hour earlier.
Are you still mad at me?
Yeah, well, I fucked up.
After that night on the bridge ...
I blamed you for Jimmy.
Yeah, I blamed me, too.
- I looked for you at the funeral.
- I couldn't deal with it.
An empty coffin like my mom's ...
The river took half my family.
It never gave them back, either.
I was wondering
what happened to that picture.
You, me and Jimmy at my dad's
cabin. All going to be cops.
- Brilliant idea.
- Look at us now.
I'm a dropout. Jimmy's dead.
- And you're one of those ...
- Water dogs.
It wasn't your fault
what happened to Jimmy.
He had something wrong with him.
He did, like my mom.
Nobody noticed it, until he beat
that suspect. But I noticed it ...
I never did anything about it.
You did the right thing.
- Fuck 'em.
- So, are you back now?
- I'm back.
- You want to get something to eat?
- No, I've got to meet a girl.
Danny ...
Welcome home, man.
HARDY-CHRISTMAN
- Hey, Kim Lee.
- How are you doing, Hardy?
- Who's Christman?
- Jo Christman. New diver.
- What's he like?
- Not what you'd expect.
Come on in, Tom.
Tom Hardy, Jo Christman.
She's a police officer,
a qualified diver and a paramedic.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- No.
- Okay.
- Can I ask you what he said?
- No.
Thanks.
I hope she floats.
You want to get
that stern line, please?
- Afternoon.
- Hello.
Give me the bottle.
Let me rephrase that:
Give me the bottle now.
- You know this is a no-wake zone?
- No, sir, I didn't.
- Drive a little slower next time.
- We have to give them a ticket.
- No, we don't.
- They were speeding.
You better do it. I'm not sure
I can stand the excitement.
Sir, I need your registration.
- Hardy, did you see that?
- Yeah.
Take the wheel.
Keep heading up the river.
Tell Penderman to send backup.
River Rescue, this is 9221, over.
Land shark.
How many men upstairs?
Let me rephrase that.
- Two, plus a pilot.
- Close your eyes. Close 'em.
Where's the $200,000?
I'll blow your head off.
Pittsburgh Police.
We have two choices here.
You either put the guns down
or we all start shooting.
I'll shoot!
Hey, man, untie us!
Behind you!
Thanks, Dutch.
Hey, you did really good
out there tonight.
- Thanks, Hardy.
- Really good.
- Thanks.
- Goodnight.
- I've never had a woman partner.
- Neither have l.
- You guys are understaffed.
- This is the new effiiciency system.
- See you tomorrow.
- No, I'm off until Wednesday.
Damn it!
Hello.
Who is this?
PITTSBURGH DEPARTMENT
OF PUBLIC SAFTEY
KESSER
CHICANIS
Tom, what are you doing here?
Are all the bars closed?
Just visiting some old friends.
- You don't have any old friends.
- Who'd know that better than you?
Yeah, old friends.
Goddamn it. Mother fucker!
He was in the Polish Hill files.
Hey, Tom.
What are those? What is that?
What? This?
Nothing, just some papers.
As the ltalians say, "Don't scald
your tongue on another man's soup."
There's an lrish saying:
"Never listen to ltalian sayings."
I knew this was going to happen.
You just won't let go, will you?
I can't lay down on this.
My father's in a grave ...
- We've got the guy who killed him.
- A cop killed my father!
- Kesser doesn't have the brains.
- He was convicted in court ...
- Answer me!
- I'm telling you!
Your father is dead
and this case is closed!
If you can't accept that,
that's your problem.
I can take that gun and that badge
away from you right now.
- Is that what you want?
- Do what you got to do, Nick.
Hardy, we're out of our patrol zone.
Will you tell me where we're going?
We're going to visit a friend.
I'll break here for dinner.
I'll be back.
Right ... I'll just stay here
and watch the boat.
- Can I get you something?
- Yeah, a guy named Chicanis.
I don't think I've seen him
all night.
Okay, tell me what you know!
Who told you to lie?
- Give me the names.
- Don't shoot me.
- Hardy, put up your gun.
- Now!
No, put up your gun.
Hardy, damn it!
This shit has got to stop.
If you have a drinking problem ...
You were out of control.
- You're already on probation.
- How long have you been a cop?
- How many years? One? Two?
- Long enough to know the rules.
Partners back each other up.
You have no business telling me how
partners should treat each other.
- You had a gun to his head.
- I wasn't going to shoot him.
- I'm trying to solve a murder!
- What murder?
I hate to tell you this, but you're
not a homicide detective any more.
- 9221, this is base. Come in.
- Hardy.
We've got another 111.
Northshore. East of Glenwood Bridge.
Get the bow line.
This is Hardy. We're on our way.
Let's go. Now!
If the kids have any bad dreams,
call this number.
We'll send a counsellor out.
Get the kids home now.
Kids, come on. Let's go home.
- Why didn't you question them?
- What for?
- The body was dumped last night.
- How do you know?
I used to be a homicide detective.
- Round up the usual suspects.
- Keep laughing.
It's a sin what he turned into.
Sorry to interrupt your evening.
We've got a dead nurse.
You stay right here. Don't move.
Absolutely, Dad.
I wouldn't want to get in the way.
Prick!
Paula Puglusi, a nurse.
Same M.O. as the Putnam woman.
Guess who she used to fuck.
You knew her?
- Yeah.
- God, Tom, I'm sorry.
Does that guy you were chasing
have something to do with this?
- He was a witness.
- In the Polish Hill case?
I was one
of the investigating officers.
Five women were strangled.
During the pursuit of the suspect
my father was killed.
- Chicanis said he saw the killer.
- And you don't believe him?
This was the case
where you lost your shield.
I lost my shield because
I said a cop killed my father.
You want to give her one more pop
before they take her away?
- I'll give you one more pop.
- Blow it out of your ass.
- Talk to the press for Uncle Nick.
-That's enough.
- I thought you quit smoking.
- The gum didn't work.
Who's she?
- That's my new partner.
- Not bad.
- You didn't know about that?
- No, why should l?
Coming back to the force?
See what you're missing?
Tommy!
- You want to get some dinner?
- What did I say?
- I just invited him to dinner.
- Go up there!
- He hasn't changed a bit.
- Yeah, that's the problem.
- What do you know?
- We just fished out the body.
Don't play games with me.
I want to know what you know.
You don't want to hear it.
It's the same guy.
- The same guy? As in Polish Hill?
- Fair hair. Good bodies.
These women were shot,
not strangled.
They had neck bruises
and were bound wrist and ankle.
- Eiler told me you know this girl.
- A lot of guys knew her.
If I didn't know better, I'd think
you didn't want to solve this case.
Are you a cop or not?
Now you come up with this story
and I'm supposed to believe you.
When was the last time
you saw this girl?
He's putting them in the water
so I'll find them.
- He wants me to find these girls.
- You're crazy, that's it.
- He called me.
- He called you?
- That's right.
- What did he say?
- He didn't say anything.
- You dreamed it.
Get in your little boat
and get the fuck out of here!
You're an alcoholic. You need help.
- Get your head examined.
- Maybe you need a drink.
- It'd ease the pain of being wrong.
- Get out of my sight.
Keep those people out of here!
Am I talking to myself?
Put Grandpa back on.
Just a second.
She sounds good.
Yes.
Okay, bye-bye.
- Hi.
- Hi. Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Okay.
This is it. 16 months ago.
I didn't murder anybody.
This witness is lying.
One memeber of the police department
agrees with him.
Thomas Hardy
made this statement to the press.
I do not think
Kesser is the killer.
Important information was withheld.
Can you tell us
what that information is?
Two of the women
were called from police call boxes.
Why didn't you say that?.
A Pittsburgh cop did it!
An offical police report
denied Hardy's accusations.
The controversy has not
changed Kesser's death sentence.
Airtight case.
Kesser had no alibi at all.
He confessed to the murder
of his accomplice as self-defense.
He denied the Polish Hill murders.
We found evidence from the murders
in his hotel room, -
- and the gun
that killed Vince Hardy.
Then why does Hardy
think that Kesser was framed?
Kesser's fingerprints weren't
on the gun. It was a police special.
The serial numbers were erased.
Hardy starts barking conspiracy.
- He thinks the killer's a cop.
- No one thought he was innnocent?
Yeah, Kesser.
Well, Bob, he's putting them in
the Allegheny or the Monongahela.
That narrows it down.
This is Hardy here. Go.
Hi, it's Jo. Are you going
to the policeman's ball tonight?.
I'm going to go.
I don't really know anyone.
Maybe I'll see you there. Bye.
- Don't leave me out here.
- One drink, real quick.
What the hell is he doing here?
Captain, he's here.
- Hi.
You look ... different.
I'll take that as a compliment.
- I didn't think I'd see you here.
- Nobody did.
Tommy, you made it.
Good to see you, man.
Come on, the whole family's
right over here.
- Dad, look who's here.
- He's got Tommy with him.
Let him go.
Don't keep them waiting.
- Tommy, good to see you, son.
- Hi, Uncle Fred.
- Introduce your date.
- She's not my date.
This is my new partner,
Jo Christman.
Unfortunately, these are the Hardys.
My Uncle Fred.
- My cousin Gary.
- Don't fuck her.
Tommy, you're too skinny.
Come to our house to eat.
She's right. You ought
to quit being such a stranger.
Now, I'd like to propose a toast.
- To Vince Hardy.
- The best Captain of Homicide ever.
Vince Hardy.
How about we drink to my mother?
She was a Hardy, too.
And Jimmy, let's drink to him.
It'd be fitting here by the river.
Uncle Vince is dead.
They're dead, too. Drink to Jimmy!
- That's enough!
- No, It's not enough, damn it!
- Let go of me. I'm all right.
- You don't belong here.
- Me and you, Eddie.
- Anytime.
The best day of the year.
Better than Christmas!
- Are these policemen all relatives?
- No, they're just criminals.
How did they end up on the force?
Part of some nationwide
negative gene pool, I guess.
- Don't do that, okay?
- What?
That thing where you're
not really talking to me.
- That's not the answer.
- It'll do till the answer turns up.
Hey! What the fuck
is the matter with you?
Get out.
Get out now!
You want to sit around drinking
and feeling sorry for yourself.
What is this? You won't respect
yourself until someone else does?
I respect you.
You've got a lot of courage.
The whole department is waiting
to see you fall on your ass.
- You're giving them what they want.
- They want to keep me silent.
Stupid is almost as good.
Will you go now, please?
Just go home.
No, I don't want to.
I don't want to go home.
What are you doing?
What made you decide
to become a cop?
All the shit you've
got to go through ...
... being a woman and all.
When I was in college,
my roommate was raped.
The campus police were
only interested in keeping it quiet.
I knew that the guy was white
and very tall.
I started checking out
basketball courts near the campus.
From the pictures I took of the
white players she identified him.
- You caught the guy?
- Yeah.
This is the police. Pull over
and stop the engine.
Stop the car ..!
Take the wheel.
This is 9221
in pursuit of a murder suspect, -
- heading west on the railroad
service road at mile 16.
Suspect is armed and dangerous.
- Send backup.
- All units respond.
Hold it steady.
My God!
Yep, it's definitely a rug!
Way to go, Hardy,
you asshole!
Tommy, congratulations.
We're all very proud of you.
You blew up a litter bug's car
and found a carpet.
- It looked like a body.
- Then you're in the wrong job.
Let's just say that it was
the killer and it was a cop.
It'd be very easy for him
to figure out our patrol patterns.
He'd just be waiting for us
to come along.
He dumps the rug
to make us look like morons.
- Hardy ...
- Yes.
- You should know something ...
- Are you really a man?
- No.
- Good.
But I was married to one.
- A cop?
- Worse. A lawyer.
That is worse.
We have a daughter. She's four.
- What's her name?
- Sarah.
Nice name.
Thanks.
Is that it?
We shouldn't be doing this
as partners.
- We should be taken out and shot.
- We should shoot each other.
- Too much paperwork.
- I'm serious, Tommy.
Well, maybe you're in the wrong job.
Tommy?
STEWARDESS CHERYL PUTNAM
VICTIM
LOTS OF LOVE
CHERYL
Tommy, what's wrong?
What's the matter?
THIRD VICTIM
IN 3 RIVERS MURDER CASE
Her name was Constance Cabrizzi.
I used to call her Connie.
- You knew this girl too?
- I took her to the prom.
Amazing coincidence ...
me knowing all these girls.
You knew about the nurse.
Now you know about Cheryl.
And now Connie.
- You've got to tell someone.
- Who?
Who can I trust? I don't know
how high up this goes.
- What do you mean?
- Say I told the wrong person.
- You didn't do this.
- Why? ls it an obvious frame?
It's just like Polish Hill.
That's right, Jo.
It's the same killer!
He killed those girls in '91,
and my father.
Now he's killing women I knew
and leaving them for me to find.
- You're scaring me.
- It's scaring me, too.
All the women in my life
keep turning up dead.
There is absolutely no connection
between Polish Hill and this.
If you print that in your paper,
I'm knocking you off this beat.
The tip checked out. Hardy went
to high school with Cabrizzi.
That's two out of three. I bet
we can tie him to Cheryl Putnam.
- You want me to bring him in?
- No, we couldn't hold him on that.
We can put him under review.
I'll call internal affairs.
- He'll be put under surveillance.
- He is under surveillance.
- Close surveillance?
- It doesn't get any closer.
Thank you very much, Officer Sacco.
I'd like to call
Detective Emily Harper.
Raise your right hand, please.
Do you swear to tell the truth?
- I do.
- State your name.
Detective Emily Harper.
Are you a member of the Police
lnternal Affairs Division?
- Yes.
- What was your last assignment?
The assignment was to
rate Officer Hardy's competence -
- and to monitor his interest
in the Three Rivers murder case.
You state that Officer Hardy
neglected his duties -
- to pursue an illegal investigation
into the Three Rivers murder case.
To what do you attribute
his unusal interest in the case?
He feels the murders were committed
by the Polish Hill murderer.
A case he worked on.
A prosecution witness in the case -
- said that Officer Hardy
threatened him.
And that you were forced
to protect him with your own weapon.
No, that's incorrect.
- I drew my weapon as backup.
- Backup?
Officer Hardy was not ...
out of control and dangerous?
At no time whatsoever.
Hardy is courageous and resourceful.
I wish we had more officers ...
- Excuse me ...
- Don't you want my evaluation?
Thank you, Detective,
you may step down.
Ten-minute recess.
I'm sorry.
- Why'd you change your testimony?
- Why do you think?
- You cheat good.
- Hardy.
Hi, Emily, it's your father.
Sarah just wanted to say hello.
She's enjoying her visit.
We'll see you Sunday. Bye.
Hi, Jo ... I mean Emily.
I'll never get used to that name.
It took a lot of courage to do
what you did at the hearing.
Maybe we can talk.
Call me. Bye.
Yes, Bob, I know you're hungry.
You're always hungry.
Go catch a rat.
Let's see what our friends
the coastguard have for us.
Let's see.
Nothing up there but cabins.
Jesus Christ!
Bob, will you get that ...
This is Hardy here. Go.
Jo!
Kim Lee! No!
Oh, God! It stops now!
Hands high, Danny.
Where's the girl? I know everything.
- I got your note.
- What note?
Jesus Christ!
The key to Detillo's conviction
was the testimony of Thomas Hardy.
Surprised?
Hello, Jimmy.
I got you.
I got you good, didn't l? Admit it.
Yeah.
Yes!
What a world!
It's hard to believe, isn't it?
I jump off a bridge.
I don't die. Go figure.
And you ...
... being so smart.
That must be a real comfort to you
at a time like this.
- Jimmy.
- Shut up! Shut your fucking mouth!
I loved you. You're my brother
and you betrayed me for him.
You knew I was the best cop!
Say it!
- Who's the best cop?
- Jimmy was the best cop!
- What are you doing?
- I'm sorry.
Tommy, let's have a drink.
Me and you. Just like the old days.
Remember?
Look at me when I'm talking to you.
What's the matter?
You're a drunk, aren't you?
Drink it!
Are you too proud
to drink with a dead man?
Maybe I should drink
with your little dove.
Hey.
- Leave her alone, Jimmy.
- Shut up!
So, I'm killing all these girls ...
He's riding next to me
wondering who's doing it.
We're investigating the crimes.
Me and my partner.
You've been a very bad boy,
fucking your new partner.
Did you get fucked, honey?
Well, Tommy has made a career
out of fucking his partners.
- Let the girl go.
- Shut up or I'll kill you.
- Bye-bye, Tommy.
- Jimmy!
I like this game.
Everybody dies,
and they all die with Tommy's gun.
Now we've got us a game.
- Say goodbye to her, Tommy.
- Jimmy, don't do it!
- Jimmy, no!
- Say goodbye to her.
Jimmy!
Put the gun down, son. Please.
Listen to Daddy.
- Put the gun down.
- What fun would that be, Dad?
It's all over, son.
Put the gun down.
- It's just starting.
- Please!
I think Tommy
has some questions for you.
Tommy? Comments? Come on.
Should I help him along, Dad?
You know your dad,
God bless his lrish soul ...
He was ...
How shall I put it?
He was sort of killed.
Tell Tommy who killed his dad.
Tell Tommy.
Come on, tell him!
Don't move or I'll fucking kill you!
Son of a bitch.
Jimmy!
Get up!
- I'll kill you.
- I'm your son.
Let me go.
- Freeze! Stop or I'll shoot!
- Vince, no!
I'm sorry, Tommy. I never meant
for any of this to happen.
He was my son.
But it's over now, because
we're going in ... together.
What are you gonna do? Shoot me?
Come on, shoot me.
You couldn't do it before.
You just don't have it in you.
Shoot your own son?
There goes that gold watch.
A bullet proof vest!
Who's the best cop now?
- Come on, Jimmy! Me and you!
- Go on. Run, you son of a bitch.
Tommy!
I just want to talk to you!
Tommy, what are you
making me chase you for?
Come on, are you mad at me?
I just shot my dad.
Call me, Tommy. No, I'll call you.
- Get these handcuffs off me.
- Why are you handcuffed?
Where's Detillo?
- He's been shot! Get off!
- I'm not getting off.
Hardy, you son of a bitch!
Get away from me!
You could never beat me!
You like to jump off bridges.
Who's the best cop now?
- Take these handcuffs off me.
- Get some handcuff keys.
- Do you want to take a shot at me?
- No.
It wouldn't do any good, Eddie.
On the other hand ...
Hardy!
You're okay.
VINCENT THOMAS HARDY
LOYALTY ABOVE ALL ELSE,
EXCEPT HONOUR
Grandkids, Dad.
English subtitles