Fix By SanjeevNeo
, Wrestling is not a sport "
"It is about the struggle that lies
Today some tough competition in breathtaking pursuits
..yk Indian fighter in this tournament
..bray Win
..bray Win this fight free
It is told that quarter into India
It's a gamble to break the
How much being spent for this match
Difficult to say
One thing I clearly said to reduce ..vly
There is little risks
Today 's fighting Ghaybh
But it has been proven that Avbrvy of Akashi.
Doping affair cricket, handy in this case is
What goes on in that meeting? Soon we realize
All think it only popular game in India Krykth
But the campaign's Indian fans
Seriously follow '
And the entire state of oneself and one day, another
Brushes added
I'm sorry for Zrrtvn
And Tbatsh completely bear
I ..qbvl
But every one of you I believe you were
I had not quit now rather than sold
But they all know, that the sport
Manish is a 5-seater in the world.
I believe I
There, I want that
Me 6 month s time to do so
I am his consistent you.
Ino Do not assume a small problem, Akashi
All know that the sport 's wrong one
We thought that the State
No no
I disagree with you
Two-year task could not do
! 6 months then you'll want me to sign me?
Perhaps you are right
I once lost and
I windward money Hmgytvn
You know that all the empty stadium
But if you take it we should close today
I hope not Back Pvltvn
Also I let happen.
Now put this together last chance
Mr Patel, trust me no more
I do not Naamydtvn
Akashi once again Avbrvy
She put it in the media
None of the reporters did not respond to questions
The silence do not know
! Cherish satisfaction or failure symptoms
I understand the answer's going to be 6 months
How much do you have left?
6 months
Because of the harm you did, I'm sorry
But you were right
The sport has no future
..yndh Far, but Nmyynysh
You know that this sport
! In the world how pro's
Start Going Many of the games are
The problem is not that
Well, your generation is the same problem
Everything that matters to him
Sit coolly rejected
Tell me what do you want?
I want to say that the future of the sport into Hndvstanh
Not in my hands. But Guru
India is a country who I can respect
Who is of Indian territory
When a putty Hindustani
In the ring the rest of the team like a donkey
That 's when it becomes the stands full of spectators
Noble am joking?
Also Bnzrtvn athlete is Hndyay
Aynkararv could match that?
"King"
Akashi, I saw him fight time
Into power. Hvshh. And boiling in the intelligence and Khrvshh
Rzvsh victory, but Adtshh
And losing his habit, but Hnrshh
Cyrenaica in his eyes, and I handed is power
Power equal to ten
..and now
All heroes on the battlefield welcome Haryana
..khryn Fight this fight
And soul Haryana, Sultan Ali Khan as we Tqdymtvn
As much as 50 fresh horse
10 swords and 10 athletes
His power
The Phlvana what was Nsybshvn what to keep
..bray Ztshvn between and
Today's winner will get a donated tractor
All the audience to see Sultan
But their lives and come
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
.rsanh Balyvvdyha proudly presenting the
Www.Bollywoodiha.Com
And now our King, the soul enters Haryana
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
Now you see
This is how it looks after the ground
Take it to the ground
Translation: Research and hearing
Karim Khan, Saman Kiani and Magic
It's just all the doors and Rogun
To say Phlvvn
Is called to play
The meeting Jvnmvn
I think this one was hit Sultan
Sultan Submit
Otherwise, the heart and the intestine Drmyarm
The soil is in your blood. "
"And you soil your blood
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness .. Sultan
Here's demonstration Sultan
Phlvvny like this before?
Sultan history by becoming the
Good for the soul of Haryana
00: 08: 52,812 -> 00: 08: 55,164
Sultan Ali Khan
"... In your blood is Soil"
Sultan heroic
And the sport by winning the King Jynh
And thats because of the sultan's Myrqsn
..kash, If irrigation it to the ring.
India's lean sound of a name OVERSEAS
"Sultan, Sultan, Sultan"
"King"
"A brave a popular our lives"
"A forgotten hero of our lives"
"Ritzy, after glaring looks"
"Laughs and says"
"Sort dances"
"The movement keeps you living these peaks"
"And says the phonetic sound of the bell"
There is but smoke and fire. "
"Grey's burning
Biff good land Myznt "
"When life Khmt grabs tight Myznt
There is a huge gap between combat and loved "
"You can love but you can not fight you do not fight with your heart
It shine like stars "
"He Abryshmh or a fine cloth
"Sometimes life or Myqyh pit" -
"The heart of a lion Nmyfhmh lives among us"
"Convert to a storm with our lives."
Ritzy, after glaring looks "
"Laughs and says,
"Regular and continuous dances"
"The ups and downs of life, keeps"
"And says .. and says to call the sound of life"
"The movement keeps you living these peaks"
"And says the phonetic sound of the bell"
Provide water
His salary was made?
Yes, sir Grftm-
Sir, all inside waiting Shman
Good morning everyone
Sbhtvn Good -
You are alive
Just leave them
Write their names
After your name is?
excuse me -
I work with Sultan Ali Khan
Brin inside -
Okay, now go to brush card
How long do you want ten and twenty rupees
Continue this?
It takes a great job Bknyn
Is that right, brother
Just takes time
But certainly fine
High esteem
Sultan Ali you sure this house?
Himself a Bdbkhth
I therefore do not form
Played to our pain
A hand cans and begging looks
Tractor open the entangled?
A moment Vaysyn
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
Gas still wanted
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
Gas Show
Dad, you were right
Do you Sltanyn?
My command, sir.
Did you?
Yes that's fine -
He is a lot like you.
I've quit, but his Phlvvny
The amount Begin
I'll give you whatever Bkhvayn
Ah, I do not Khtsh you
Good Morrow safely you.
Begin the least Qymttvn
Price Begin
Top down we reach an agreement
If you were not the son of Mr. Avbrvy
High Yjvry now that I Payynt
Remember you do it
One step in the right father
Go Svarshv so excuse ovary
! Wow Dmyh
Brother say -
What?
This gentleman does not passes
Pdrjan What happened?
I do not have a ticket, one ticket to me this
Enough, I Pdrjvn
The Byzbvnh, I Do not tickets
Why is Hvastm
... And Listen
A time not to disturb others
Excuse me, you're Govind?
Yes Frmayshtvn -
Hi, I'm Akashi Avbrvy
Where you are, too?
..dhly-
Do you like Sultan are, too?
Yes
Gets two minutes to talk about it?
However, if the screen you can
Just two minutes
I'll go my command
Pay attention to the booth helpful
Eye -
Injo ... You will suffer? I had planned a chair?
Not good.
00: 16: 04,798 -> 00: 16: 06,052
But this is not possible
Sultan are no longer comes back into the ring.
Why?
Is a story
A famous love story
In the village we are behind it
Hello brother Sultan
Look tea
..rzm The presence of Sultan met the love story
This story was not betrayed you nor hypocrisy
"Maybe talk to me or retaliating"
"If you want, do not accept those words are my eyes"
.. "But Start Going, do not ask me that."
"I've spoken to not see you and not your name."
"You're my religion, Toei my God"
"If you wanted me but'm Mad King Bola"
"I danced"
I danced and I will relieve my beloved "
"And rejected his feet will follow, Bola King
.. "You are my companion, you're my proof."
"In some relationships, salt to taste Doria"
"This needs which have to be seen again."
"8 years ago."
..dvstan And brothers on the auspicious day today
to celebrate
..hrky Win
The sides are firmly Dysht
What storm comes Nbrtsh
Mvjan into the whole area of ​​our name famous
Do not worry
Sultan soul, like that Kanalay
It is also not another?
I Hyklt Qrbvn
At my age want me to be like that Kanalay?
Jvvnyt learning happen?
Uncle meat for very long these days Myjnbh
A mode eat cold things get better value
What's the King?
Tytvyh
Govind, Everything alright?
Yes that's fine
I heard Rvsyth
Yeah, but not invite
What are you saying your brother?
Who is gonna win in the race kites?
Rakesh raises
R u sure?
Wanna bet?
..bya On the bet that whoever took the kite
The winner is
What happened? Afraid?
..dadashm Says he is not alone in the village
But the region is not one
! The king beat
what's your idea?
I get older, when your pain midway captain, is not it?
Look, we do it but we
Now I work with serious
Okay bet
... If three minutes before tearing thread
Running time what to keep
Miri are you're a black face the donkey
Ok, ok?
Woe to the mat
Since Sultan
Ignore Up
Whip broke my dishes?
Where are you going??
What Mrgtvnh?
High Gmshyn
Go see
Go to see
Gmshyn
But now Dad, I'm encouraged Ino
: Instagram, the media cable channel Balyvvdyha
Instagram.Com/BollywoodihaOfficial
Telegram.me/BollywoodihaOfficial
From away
get lost
Sultan June
Do Tavrh blindness?
Go see, I direct I used to go
You stand up
Now raise both hands and shouting
Zell What gave?
Zell say, you take out your eyes, okay?
The boy bitch, just for the engine was ruined
Leave Bjy
Atfaqh spawns another
Do not you touch me
Together too, yeah?
Dvstyn Yeah?
All the boys Aynjvryn
Kasktm broke his hat
what happened? Why are you shouting?
go away
Got ..zvdbash
We told ourselves, do ..dashtym
Ino Welch
Now tell me Who looks black Svrtshv
And ass ride much?
Babath
Salam Alaikum Granny
And upon Hey baby
I showed, how?
Hello to you, I
At least say hello this
Mother'll see how humble he led
What he says
Big man, 30 years old
Place your ass riding with the kids
Whatever I had
Why has installed dish
Chiu bad you wanna show the nation?
Movie like that?
Shameless
Stop another
One like you, that nothing hand smiles ..
Here's the thing wants you broke Let Me
What I just listen a
One day it will take the boy home to fire
Mother
What? -
Austin hit up that I found your bride
Where? -
Granny, struck the boy in the head
..amrvz A girl?
I saw before the house
Cans of Slh
My heart tells me of when I saw her ..vly
All my life I have with him
Love you?
Slowly
My boy
Charity he should not be postponed
Without some hesitation Go and tell her
Love u
And want to marry her
Did you know?
Really? -
Then what?
Close tiger take it to the grave owner
All Karat alright
Go another
Come one chance to go home.
Brother look, as if we came late
Gone was the wife of one another Hyeongsu
It did not open the tray?
You go and see where to go
Gvshmvn of the root passes, Govind
Hooray sweets
What do you do?
What do you do, dear boy?
This .. this glove?
which one?
As im
The foot Mrs.
Crown Neighborhood
Tickets must we do see it
"Well, Your Excellency, this" Htvrast
I left after one
Here's you know wants tickets
Say, you want me to be different?
No
I'm Sultan Ali Khan
Dish TV company Mhbvba Mhbvba
And Fashion TV
Why not speak English as the force blow?
I found out that girls
In England to learn Bahvshtrn
Say I Love You So
We rely on time to kiss and kiss
You know in England
Boys like you to say what?
"Bchhshhry"
(Salman misunderstood)
Liked
Well Hyeongsu what he said?
"He said," Bchhshhry
Go looking for
! Go inside the house.
Q Look, they can punch !!
This Quito Shaskvl Damadh
Ajq boy Vjq
Stop the drum Tombak
DJ does this have bathtubs
Whatever she says, what happens to English
Uh huh girls like they're speaking English
You see the good she is having with her friends
Dear attention
Open your eyes, my dear.
DJ hit something else
She loves than that
High Byssh now
Not hear?
She loves the bass sound?
"A strong mind is the fragrant girls"
(Jet / spices: clan Harayany)
"A man looks innocent and illiterate, according to all the girls."
"She's a person with Svadh, nerves are not"
"Vamysth a corner and was ordered to"
"Jati man nodded distractedly all shows and accepts"
"A strong mind is the fragrant girls"
(Jet / spices: clan Harayany)
Eyes British talks were going "
"While I'm illiterate
"Without any effort, stolen my heart"
"Ignore me captain, and goes to the DJ"
Now choose sir, the laundry song "
"Or should shoot to happen here?
"Because ... she loves Base"
"She loves Base"
"When dances like to see his face."
"Hey Chicken inexperienced, so the sample deception"
Those who Vaystadn not remember me. "
"Every 16 girlfriends Manen
"I really like you, that I'm chasing die"
Forces us to listen to English songs "
"Sing Indian and efficient knock Golem
"Because ... she loves Base" "
00: 29: 34,358 -> 00: 29: 36,303
"She loves Base"
"I do not know what's the reason for the deterioration of the heart"
"Since I met you if I forgot the whole world"
You're always there for me. "
"Really you Smjy
Do you think you're cool. "
"But in fact, an idiot
When he gets angry. "
"I like the red face
"She loves Base"
She wants to dance his heart "
"But boy looking for love and Ashqyh
"There, the DJ says he does not risk"
"Both his hands up and Myrqsn Mybrn"
One girl from the rest of Torre "
"Whoever you get involved with this girl goes bad trouble
"The girl also fire, hot!"
"Everybody Sing something."
While a program Fshnh "
"Bomb Anrzhyh
"I Start Going pick you up, I was crushed under the feet"
Knock Knock and the House of dance "
"Chshmatm ice cream and dance
"He liked the lamb speaker volume up"
"She loves Base"
"When he dances, I look like her eyes"
"A strong mind is the fragrant girls"
"She loves Base"
Sytkay
King
Brother Sultan
What's open?
English to Hindi and vice brother come down
What I found out was Sytgay?
What?
Would seats were dirty
And Guy 's son
Mission together Psrksyf
This means there
Kind of Fhshh?
I Fhshh
Dadasha dog me say
Puppy say
But until now I have not addressed dirty
But that
I stumbled to my pride
Must sync it right
! I knew where
His name is Arefeh
Arefeh
Phlvvnh guy's girl
Phlvvn girl?
A place nearby
Whoever wins this fight into
Association tournament looks
The match took an average weight
..and You this race
Milk and Phlvvn girl. Arefeh Myjng·h
A two-bent on bending ....
Take it
She came fresh from New Delhi
The English Fvlh
In the state wrestling tournament grabs
Wish his father a gold medal score,
What Dkhtryh
Guy sets no, if wants
I'm in front of him Bshashm
Whatever it has to do with this wedding
! Brother to heart and do nothing, but how comes
!I do not understand
As a doctor, doctor grabs
Engineer engineer looks marriage
Well Phlvvn looks with union Phlvvn
what do you mean?
I mean, for that I'm Phlvvn
I'm like this
In the blink of an eye
good job
And here the hero Arefeh
Mashallah
Madam, signed a Mydyn?
How well did you fight and he eased back Nshvndynsh
Walked me?
And what would she say?
She loves Base?
This time I'll show you a Bysy
Do you understand was that, then?
No Madam, discussion Azdvajh
My very heart Pakh
I remember to say whatever to take out
I fell in love and want to marry you
Oh Well Well Well, you're Romeo
I am engaged
Just marry a hero
I decided 5 minutes ago
I like you Phlvvn
I am not a wrestling match press whistle.
Look, Mr. Romeo wrestlers
Mzkhrfatt you keep and get out of here
30 and I are looking Phlvvn
Head and hands reminds me break
Madam, Mytrsvny menu?
Coming tomorrow
Brecker common ground
Who Srvdst see tat
Yadtm, I'm Guy seats
Take Grdnshv
Leave it
This hero's Mykhvd
Get involved
Professor John
Say What?
It is not something Professor, I want to be Phlvvn
What? Of Phlvvny you know what?
Chiu want me to see?
Up front and you learn
And Myndazysh Earth
Well done you learn very good
Phlvvn this?, A little worn shorts
S not shame
Professor, I sought permission from my dad
The next time I get the Olympic gold medal for India
English call him gold
I like SH brother
I hug you with arms like this
Professor, Shah Rukh mocking Thank You
I love him
The way that he easily reduced to the girls eyes
Bad girls love looks
Why did you come here Phlvvny
Or love?
That's what I want to do
The essential love love
Those words are in open big
What is your name?
King
Until now, conventional race?
I ..bazy but you kite flying competition Dhatmvn
Olympic still has not come into kite flying
It's not easy getting a kite
If you do not have an idea of ​​the three best Phlvvna Come
If they take me anymore Nmybynyn
And if I won, me as a disciple of Mypzyryn
Then I remembered Ino Mydyn
Excuse me. Excuse me ...
Ok, ok,
Pavan, Yasin, Rakesh
Let's see how fast this guy is
Bream
Go Brother -
are you ready?
Start
Nshknyn
Little by little, it will now fall in
Help ... I fall in
...Help
Now, I certainly do
That man will Zndhst
Tomorrow at 6 am
The master
Oh woe
Two two ambulances
Pawan What happened?
Who is Chyzysh?
Mad?
Blood drawn forgive
Onur
Mary Kom there
Let's Go You vaccine
Sit there
Then you shall give blood
I came to kill her blood
The game was religious
sit down
Hello
Did you come?
Good, sleep
So far I have not blood
A little afraid
Fear What Dad, Inna all professional
Sister, Ino Czech now come blood group
Vrzydhay people like you, beautiful two to three units
He can not donate blood
Take my hand
Just hand
Madam, I did something that
You think you do not
Sisters Group Khvnysh he Mnfyh
..av Knew that negative ...
In the entire Asia 1% have negative her blood group
What does that mean?
The Group Khvnyt very Kmyabh
This simplicity also oh
Madam, I'm Kmyabm
All this is not necessary
I was asking you.
Ranjan crazy love
A pure romance
The pain that is in my rhymes Kumar Sano
And Hmrash a British Nmh
That I give it to you
Did not you tell unless you marry a Phlvn?
Well let me make a hero
Look, I think these feelings
Ansanharv weaken looks
And me and my dad a wish
He medal winning Almpykh
I do not want to block my way, OK
Would you like to get in my service
Well a drink with me blow?
Give Blood
Come Take my blood sister
St. excesses
Why did not you ever get married?
I love you marry
But'm the right person has not come
Well, you got something to say
... A good and decent girl
The hero is
What do you mean, the girl who clamping ship?
I did not mean
Our society into wrestling
And for the guy saying Phlvvny
..vly Girls
What about the girls? -
Phlvvn can not girls be?
To change this way of thinking
I went to the Phlvvny
You know why I struggle with the boys?
..chvn Into our society
Death and the girls spend their lives behind Rvsryshvn
(For home living and childcare)
You say if the girl got into the community
Where you play the bride?
My dad liked to have a boy
To build him a Phlvvn
But unfortunately I was born
My birthday coincided with my mother's death
But Dad was very effective for me
I was fresh and dry
I did not lack
I wanted to stay up in Delhi
But I'm here
And I saw
The day I get medal
Arefeh name taking into Haryana
So Excellency, Mvatb yourself
And you keep bearing Mrdangyt
Do not let the lamb
..and The girl was fighting so that
All their Phlvvny stay
why are you laughing?
Lakshmi queen threw remember me
Dmv tricked you refresh your look
Batnt quite similar, but the girls Vtnyh
I was impressed
Come on, hit safely
"I had the same dish antennas A"
"No way a free network would not work."
"There are no cables, did not signal"
"Harayana the same for me Argentina"
"What kind of stretching I do not know who gave my heart"
"I just got my eyes Network, reflection you."
"Well, who knows what is the connection between us."
"With your touch a 440 volt current was connected"
"With your touch ... with your touch."
"With your touch."
"With your touch a 440 volt current was connected"
"Stay awake at night and I see TV"
"For you will keep my song for you"
"Tell me, how, what and why?"
"I think u think about me."
"I .. to me."
"You are my ration card, you are my share."
"And girl, I can not say anything about Khvshglyt."
"Well, who knows what is the connection between us."
"... A process"
"With your touch a 440 volt current was connected"
"With your touch."
My command
I'm going to my friends Mrfyt
That boy dressed in jeans and T-shirts, Gvvyndh
The Coco And here opium
Hello
sit down -
Sit
What can I get you your brother's wife?
Here's the delicious Dvghay
brother's wife?
"We girlfriends say" Hyeongsu
And here the first boy who among us has a girlfriend
What you're saying?
I'm your girl you told your friends?
Not
Yeah
But I thought wrong
I am leaving
Arefeh
Listen, Arefeh
What is what?
Really told them I'm your girl?
excuse me
But yeah, I
Suddenly wrong?
The three no, but 10 thousand another
... Know that
Feelings between you and me is
And turning around in the morning with the engine die
We eat breakfast, lunch and dinner
Laugh, feel Gettin '
You see what people think twice?
00: 49: 17,356 -> 00: 49: 18650
Dkhtrshh friend or Bjy say?
Only Dvsttm
You know what?
Even though you do not understand me, is my own problem
I was like to be with people like you
With what are you thinking?
I'm 4 days'll look and love?
A Look at me Look at you later
What is common between us?
I am a state champion
The goal in my life and I wish
What are you?
A clown
Karash stand with the nation's laughter provided
You know what is love?
He's a respected him Myzary
He's got to know some things that you do not
There is no purpose in your life?
GONNA get his girlfriend
This is how I will hear no more Saddam
Sultan came John
Let's Eat
Today is my son's eyes
Instagram.Com/BollywoodihaOfficial
The proposition that girl, do not you?
Should think and get your hair Khyala
This, incidentally, happen
I'm not a baby
Only, not disrespect me
My boy
! Happiness is a woman behind every man
And behind every unsuccessful man a woman
But no to a man unsuccessful
Putting emphasis
To respect yourself at
Must bear the disrespect they got
Must burn
And try to Sultan
As long as you're proud of this world Miri
Professor, competition Provinciarum in-stream?
Yeah well?
I want to fight
Write my name
Qlt the Jashh your son?
Do you think this joke?
Go Let others wouldn
I want to fight
Write my name
Until now were not Phlvvn
State champions, do you wanna fight?
Yeah
..vas·h Fight
Should you try Years
To handle it
That 's the name bell
Go us not waste time
Kia die, why fight?
J. Singh, Rakesh, Durga
how come?
If Bbrmshvn
After you write my name?
Are you kidding?
Got us?
Fight them you do?
Yeah
Who?
now
Enough, no more Welsh
That's got hands?
Do you think this game, baby?
..bhm Say something important.
! He dust
Today, I struggle to remember my work account
I struggle a open next month
On the soil
Then comes my work account
And the Sultan 's state champion
"If that was the fate of Batu face"
"After her wrist twisting quests"
"Go ahead, his wrist Bpychvn"
The seven heavens cry "
"Tears of the seven heavens to eat
"With every seven-Nov-ins now."
If you take the power that you have in front of him. "
"If all between the Bshkafsh
"The world today palms Tv’"
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
Dada What do you do?
The Sultana me, wants to be champion
If you're going to help them
So smooth Go
Good thing Sultan, Bravo
Do it again
It must be pretty careful
"Thy will be more than you think"
Good, very good.
"You Dlth, and in the eyes of you is one"
The neck 5 seconds Bgyrysh
"Go to what you studied and King Show"
Take my hand, why entrepreneurs
The seven heavens cry "
"Tears of the seven heavens to eat
"With every seven-Nov-ins now."
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
The seven heavens cry "
"Tears of the seven heavens to eat
"With every seven-Nov-ins now."
If you take the power that you have in front of him. "
"If all between the Bshkafsh
"The world today palms Tv’"
Professor, my name Write
I told you
This year's state champions in the race
You win, Sultan
"State Championship Tournament, Farid Abad, two months later."
Arefeh final for the second time
Entered the competition
Hey, take Kmrshv
..arfh All the force that gives up to spend
The Dkhtrrv off the ground
And all the proud looks India
Haryana Queen 's hero
Sultan hero is pre-state opponents
Neck firmly grabs
Pahashv land grabs and Mykvbtsh
There is no second Soltani
Sultan, Sultan
Sultan's name no one knew
But today they're all screaming their name
Stop it now looks Sultan
And now Jdydmvn hero is none other than Sultan Ali Khan
New champions Haryana
Professor John Hi
The Sultan's troubled federation
Hero challenged, your Jlvshv
Did you go out of your mind?
Mad?
You know the arrival here.
How much trouble ceased?
Between the ship and you learn a new quarter
Now, did you ever challenged Chghr a wrestler?
In the Federation Blvayyh
If I die today, I lost the
Then do not you take these joke
You nemishe Because what do you want?
I do not know myself what I need
I am neither understand nor do you understand
I know that no one can give only so much Shkstt
Until yourself Victims
Master
Federation officials are working with you
You really Sultan chat?
I know that I was afraid
I love a girl
But I came by the thousands tough
Large entanglements
He deeply loved girls
She gave me a slap that ..ama
I broke my personality
He's not to love this fight earns
Not to gain honor
Only to prove myself
So far this who did not see
What is your opinion about this fight?
Look, I want to say that today's
Or historic King 's
Or he gets consigned to history
Go to this show that the fight against smoking
What eventually got
This is a serious challenge
Make Karshv
Sultan, Sultan
Yes that's it
Here's the final score for Dyvraj
..yh One side as if he
Victory is yours
Finish a race moves now, okay?
Come Sultan yourself
What chaos at the stadium Bpast
...King
Sultan won
Well Sultan history by becoming the
Today a star was born
Congratulations
I'm sorry, Sultan
What are you sorry for?
See Falling
Sultan Sultan is today because of you
You do want me to be me?
Yeah
Sultan Khan's
As husband accept you?
I accept
Barkat Ali's son Arefeh
Spouse acceptable to you?
What to say Granny?
"Say that" I accept
Mr. Molavi, I accept
"I do not tell jokes, not to prove not talking about"
United Nations Games - Delhi 2010
"I figured it out a couple of years now, Jzabtt"
"You are my love, you are"
"I have to tell jokes, I tell the truth"
"I Bdakhlaqm girl, very Khvym your side."
"You are my love, you are"
"She says that she would have ever heard, lovingly woven"
"Asian Games in China - 2010"
"Today I have two dreams are mixed together."
"These sweet nor the song is my dream?"
"You know who I suggest you start"
"I have to tell jokes, I tell the truth"
"I Bdakhlaqm girl, very Khvym your side."
"You are my love, you are"
"Wrestling World Cup - 2014"
What Hstvn after winning the gold medal?
..mykhvam That of my father, Ayshvn father, my grandmother Mrbym.
King says how you feel?
Very happy, proud and happy
"I got my own world Tiger Tiger."
"Wherever you go promise come with you."
.. "Morning comes."
"The smile on the lips take out"
"The night seemed"
"Fade'm talking u"
"I love you immensely, and I love dance"
"I do not think wise, my baby again today."
"You are my love, you are"
"She says that she would have ever heard, lovingly woven"
"Today I have two dreams are mixed together."
"These sweet nor the song is my dream?"
"You know who I suggest you start"
Today Sultan clarifying these Lissette
Sultan's wife Arefeh
"You know who I suggest you start"
Sultan Khan, Go and bring sweets
She was unconscious, the doctor he wants sweets
The Kdvmsh I take? Wet or dry?
Man, between Santa loss to
Come check and Bkvbyn
King 's Dad' s
, What have you done?
I kept a little yourself
The trouble all year
This all year long for an Olympic medal
It all gone contract
Are you going with this play?
I reached my goal Baba
Look there.
Dance and see the Khndsh
That's my goal
..ta Where he 's progress
Reach your goal
My dream fulfilled
We are both ready
You Lose
No no
I ate
No -
I want to drink water
Take a bending
that's good
Wicks faced screws you work
Enough for now
Must take the Olympic gold medal
London Olympics
The competition between Sultan Ali Khan from India
And Aaron Levy of Greece is
..myrh On a bend Aaron
I stress Dad
Silent
..and Now once more Aaron
Come Sultan
Sultan had won a movement
The Magic Man looks really
India grabs gold
Sultan Ali Khan heroic
The pen
Of the best pens in the world
Write your own fate with this auto
Cut, I
..vydyvkan H. de
... Vegetable oil in now
Cut, once more please -
Dear Phlvvnm director
I'm not an actor, a great honor
King
Yes Master
..dvan Rang Khan said that he did not go to fight
Halshvn not welcome them, Professor
So far misunderstanding Sultan these days
Another ship into the ground soil again!
But every year the season
What earthly ships?
Pavan had better go
Inside the Avnast
Ladies and gentlemen
Sultan by taking Olympic gold medal
Name of us have known everywhere
Why did the government to pass compensate for the lost
Now I am invited Sultan Ali Khan
..ta Us talk,
Assembly made us more elegant
What do you feel you won the Olympic gold medal?
Ino should ask medals
Because Madam, I did not get medals
But taken my medals
No one was there such a medallion
There has Soltani
What Yndtvn program?
Turkey was going for the world championship week
And tell'm winning
The King is the King of the ring
The mean that one can
You beat?
There's only one person who can
Sultan defeat
He Sultana their
This shows your confidence or Ghrvrh?
I'm're not satisfied if the Zhmthayy
But still you get the answer to this question,
After I was world champion
Thanks
Bream
Sultan Khan, I think you are getting from me upset
I'm a big fan of Shmam
A reconciliation to take photos
Mygma up when he Miri
So do not ambition
Dad? Go looking for
After the press conference, Sultan
One reporter accidentally slapped a
People say that Sultan
After winning the Olympic arrogant
Before the press conference
Was a disgrace to answer questions
What is this stuff look?
It is not good for children
We eat
You know what I told him.
Goofy Weights
What a huge statue at university
The proud Create
Mesh for Tv’
Sultan, 9 months I was over
..khvbh That
So what's love, girl or boy?
how come?
What do you want for yourself?
Well Nkhvay, boy
I even chose Asmshm
Day in the world of corruption too
We'll call it safe
When you laugh the whole world laughs .. Come eat
Well doctor what he says?
Who's the bastard born?
Says probably next week
Well good.
With my World Championship
He is born, the
That I won, that 's Haryana
Sultan's name knows
Sultan Nero
Where?
World Championship
Doctor says Zaymanh week, I need you s
Female doctor knows that these guys Sultana
As my blood N.
Here's the same guys Qast
Like I'm Championship
She born like Phlvvna
When he was born
Babashm becomes world champion
Sweet dream good thing
High, but if you go for your dreams
Remember yourself away.
I wish I had a medal Tolaru
But for the happiness I Dvtayymvn
I wish leavin
There is very little distance between self and pride
I told you earn honor your photos
It brought me pride
Come on, Zbvntm launched
listen
When I was nothing
Let you did and walked away
To gain position for
I was heart's blood.
And for the same position for
Everywhere Mrvfm
And the Ghrvrh that what I say in England
With confidence, do not you?
Food was over.
Sultan opponent's neck was
(Final)
This was what the King
King saw what was
Blessed very good.
His right
... Doctor
Balyvvdyha media, for reference only Persian Bollywood
Translators: Magic, Kareem Khan and Saman Kiani
It's a great suplex
Sultan opposing the motion of the Earth's
And Sultan Ali Khan from India
New world champion grabs name
Conqueror ring
Boy or a girl?
the boy
I knew
come back soon
the boy
After Mobarakeh
Evil, Where?
Arefeh?
Congratulations
World Champion Sultan
Set the ring victorious
I was you
Child less fine
True, very rare
He was born with blood group negative
Do you know how weak
One was anemic
But all had many
11 hours fight
All the villages we would have been
But could not find somebody with this blood group
When he Rsydsh
I fought with all life.
He failed and went
Follow your dreams were
And he lost
Ok, you win Sultan
But now all Bakhtym
Now the wall is gone
I can not break up
Go Sultan
I do not wanna see you.
After six months I have not talked to him
I appeared in front of me but crooked way,
After her grandmother's death came
Then I got home
A few days later came the news of his father's death
Was only
Arefeh it?
Arefeh lives with his dad
For years now pipe down
For years, she goes to the shrine of Sultan Bbynsh
Hey, comes and goes as he Drarh
When Mybynsh if Nmyshnassh
Thing for passes away.
Sultan now what he?
What do want me to be broke?
Before that fought to live
Now he was fighting with life
Now it's just a dream
Want to have a blood bank team
To be with her all
And also knows the heart
That Arefeh forgive him.
It wants to somehow
Seek his forgiveness
There, for many years he
Collected money from people looks
Mr. Akashi, I know you are, too great person
I want to ask something of you
Your offer is very good.
But these people do not like to
Counter-attacking on time if this proposal goes
But if that's the way blood banks Bndazyn
He's probably gotten asap
Thank you, thank you very much
Get ready, we will go to market early
Animal Sultan Khan, tea eat?
Yes
sit down
Well, what do you say?
The construction of blood banks
The card spawns
I also sent your file to the ministry
But this Zmanbrh
The mean number of years now that Hmynv Minister
The country's all okay did you
Licensing is also not working for you
My Dad ready for a long time, late
I heard Daddy, Come out, another two minutes to die
Brother Sultan, why rush it?
Keep a low tolerance, the card goes
Just wait, too.
Long live India
Let's go Babaei market.
Sultan, Hi
A moment to listen to me
Licensed?
Still refused
I know why the ship, but Kurdish
Whoever may also be milled
Was Hmynkarv
Until now how much money did you collect?
234 thousand
All of the money collected photos
To the extent not match certain
My dad told me that King
Was born wrestlers.
Look, pal, I, as a businessman
I came to do a deal with you
But hearing the story, to believe it
Just think, that everything and lost
You play with wrestling again Bdstshvn
Owners alike who lives in war
Is the struggle into a place like useless things?
This is my card
Wait Tmastm
Good Prim
Take my statement
good job
Prim his legs
By now, Bravo
Good Prim
Prim his legs again.
By now
Good Prim
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
Take my statement
Good Prim
How much did you collect?
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
Just think, that everything and lost
You play with wrestling again Bdstshvn
Good Prim, by now
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
I know you never Nmybkhshy menu
And know my heart again
You want me so much Hnvzk
As Phlvvny that it Mynazydm
I laid
But is his main Phlvvn
That in my own life show
I wanted to live off the land
Your feet should be firmly put
But if life is always going to win
I was coming to tell Hmynv
I told you, without you.
All Chiu lost
But both our pride
Both you and I
She found someone that we lost Hrdvmvn
excuse me
From now on, I do not see Hemo
Sorry to hear how Khvastnm
How do I get an apology?
I know we are not perfect love "
"But I'm not ashamed Babtsh
Each full-time gave the Dead "
"The one who al-, survive
"My hope left under feet."
"I feel like a bird that never flew the same could not be completed"
"I'll leave if you forgive me I"
"If you wanted me but'm Mad King Bola"
"I danced"
I danced and I will relieve my beloved "
"And rejected his feet will follow, Bola King
.. "You are my companion, you're my proof."
"Do you remember me or not."
"Your way of life for me."
"You are angry Ahtramh"
"I Drshkst, secrets from you."
"Life is a gift you'd probably separation"
Hey Paladin
Go with caution.
"If you wanted me but'm Mad King Bola"
"I danced"
I danced and I will relieve my beloved "
"And rejected his feet will follow, Bola King
.. "You are my companion, you're my proof."
They work with you
See Khvshjalm
How soon decided so?
My grandmother used to say: on the good
There is no need divination
Yes that's right
Bream
.. "You are my companion, you're my proof."
It was fighting?
Where did you get it from Akashi?
Gold medalist Almpykh
Mykshnsh
The time is World Champion
Leave it -
Qlt the Jashh?
But a few years becomes a hero?
Kapil bad today a cricket ball
Do you think he can match what?
This is a sport for youth
OVERSEAS 30 or 31-year-old young people fighting in it.
And you brought a 40 year old man
The ship us score?
..and You know that this sport Ferry Astaylh
You're right
Not listen to me
This exercise requires precision and speed is power
This can be broke all doing these things?
Mr Patel was right Shmayh
I agree with you
But he was fighting
I am Madhash quarter
Why we take education
What is a sponsor?
You know that no fighter
No sponsor stepped into the ring kept
What did you think when you see her?
Who Aspansrsh you?
Harrow body are you doing?
They're awfully shape
Yeah, very, Mashallah
Also my fate into my body but I
Have?
We got a little belly that our water
See Avnjarv
I look ascending
CCTV Camera
Now we
We need to go looking for sponsor
Shah Rukh Khan in Kolkata
Preity Zinta
Here's the Dadashth that sits in front of you
Eval brother, Adam, you grow it yourself
Remember we did with the corner
Dodge ate Gapa
I heard my brother closed
The media is busy, the shut down?
I came here for this?
Look, I'm gonna date
I invested Championships
Qrbvnt not my brother, I do not fight
Who said you go do battle
Fighting this, the King Khan
We came to do Sponsorship
We get a sponsor?
Babamv see?
01: 38: 05,564 -> 01: 38: 09,121
You know that stingy to all means
Jvnsh is dependent on money
He Aspansrt want me to be?
Impossible
It got little mentally
Still into the hut captive
Think a little
International media so coming
That you can not think about do
think
Sultan melee looks all the world Mybynnsh
Such an opportunity does not come in another clip
Look to Where Moers
Kstm comes into magazines
A little brother to look after yours
Slim think Moers
Take and eat here Kvkd
Coming into form
After Hillah?
Hella yeah bro -
What is this brother?
The same ship that must fight
Brother, Qlt the Jashh?
I know the ship's local Phlvvny
Zmynay into soil that's done
Who are these people meet Mykshn
Inside the judo, boxing, karate
There's even a slap in it.
So what do you think?
One million rupees and you learn that
So easy fight?
Look bro, I have no doubt
I've got money
But Mr., I am not Superman
6 weeks into the land becomes worthless
Everyone ..bray
Everyone -
What's the most important thing in my ship?
the power
You having
I had -
How long it takes the form come again?
6 weeks
Why, I'd Mvzsht
Bream
What a misfortune got stuck
let's go
Old Delhi
Delhi is just too real
Everything that can not be found anywhere else
No doubt here can you find out
The same old town
One of the ancient cities of the world
From here 8 years ago, a boy went to London
In the world of sports to become a star
That nobody could get it.
! How many medals here
There's so kind Jvahrh treasury that was Pnhvvn
Won one of the five combat the underground racing Lndnh
But was captured materials
Was deported and returned to Delhi
Back to the beginning
The fighting stopped
But it just did not fight
Now were going to be best for a train fighters
Khvdshm as you know is the best
Fatih the Conqueror Singh
Olympic medalist
World Champion
Taste, someone may
Welch she looks away.
What a story
So what?
Professor?
I practice it I do not
Conqueror, it's the best
best?
Yes
Well look at it now
Loser's nice guy you see it.
Theirs was lost under the weight of sin, someone may
I got kind of a person I do not practice
Trust me and practicing wanted
I'm sure
Abuse of trust or confidence?
OK
I'll give you a chance.
See how much power the ship s left
Tomorrow morning, there will come
Sultan, a man is dead.
Sultan useless
King dead
is dead
Stupid
Dashmvn not nervous -
Time's a-wasting
It is totally baseless
"If fate was met you."
In the ring, gives poor June
"Then after twisting his wrist."
I'm leavin I had Phlvvny
But the fight did not remember
Alive.
What English?
Alive and well
OK?
Master
Team?
main -
Come work
OK
Come on him
That's all?
What happened?
This was?
This machine like Dagon
Just Kurdish paunchy
Wrestling Yeah?
Lamb breath knocked Outi
Byarsh low
This exercise is totally dependent combat techniques
Come with this start with the same style Phlvvny
Your head down. Okay, all must
The core focus on your photos
You have a better balance
Come and bring pressure
What was the world champion?
Go start now
"Sultan"
Kill
hurry up
Chiu look?
Say, you want to take me?
The one who must say, you'll ring
If you want it bad break
Got to be resisted
Invincible
Now Kill
Ten of the team, You're one in open
And that one should have a weight ten minutes
Ineffectual
This is how could not
Also expects the primitive, or
Ring into the last round a scream
Found
Why are you wasting time?
Not idle
Look what's going to happen after that kite
Like the cheetah Mydvyh
Stupid
Dashmvn are not nervous -
Hey
Come on
Since the coming
Children Bdvyyn
Now see
"Run and Win"
"Drink from the sea Khrvshndh"
"With the efforts of the beginning"
"And all the quests"
"Sultan"
One of the most important exercise is,
That his opponent to know
Why force yourself into bad
Marcus, one of the
The most dangerous fighters Msabqath
Pray draw you into Nyfth
Do not let the beam to lead Ballerina
OK
stand up
King
Of the attack
Elbows, knees, punches, punches
The fire comes out of the water
: Instagram, the media cable channel Balyvvdyha
Instagram.Com/BollywoodihaOfficial
Telegram.me/BollywoodihaOfficial
Argh
He was stuck on Aynqdh
Another dangerous points of the sport
Shut off and lock holding
The s-esteem and low irrigation capacity
I should exercise your photos
But ... Submit
If you got a lot of pressure Surrender
Making submissions to sentence ends
OK?
Breathe
Saws thing for
How much longer significant capacity?
Passed out
It can not fight the Svnya
Bring water a little brother
To kill himself gives the
1..2..3..4
Four .. five
..shsh
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
Yes that's it
Abyraj, national hero
Savyndr Singh, champion of the International Boxing
Francis, taekwondo gold medalist
At the international level
They all start here
Come on, you let your name locked
I think that's his hero Mybaz·h
Because He's the real value
Being the winner knows
I like both King
Did you miss the most important part of your life contract
Family
I used to practice my matches
But your fight than these Msabqath
Because your adversary your
Do not let me Shkstt
And unfortunately I did not come to you
Because I know that if I die inside the ring
Do not you accept defeat
I see something Nmytvm
Just keep a low Brvmv
Hi, I'm Xiaoyan National Stadium, Delhi
I live for you
Today the third season
Tournament "Peru tic Down" is
In this tournament two years ago investors
Thus incurring huge losses
And this chapter shows that
How important is this tournament for India
The third season starts next two days
01: 55: 02,478 -> 01: 55: 04,792
And the excitement is all sweeping in from
And as you see behind me
Tayrn it comes Woodley
The American and Chinese Tycho is his sponsor Tayrn
And now the defending champion "Peru tic Down" Marcus
From the UK, who is his sponsor, James Kvfyld
It is located behind the fighting machine that Maurice
Maurice Brzylh and sponsor of the
Great Russian businessman Victor is Glsky
..and That is, the most important event of the season
Akashi Singh, owner of the "Franchise" from his hand
Someone introduced
And most importantly, a wrestler with this is that these fighters Hndyh
For the first time a wrestler Indian
In such a battle field looks
The name of the King's Indian wrestlers
Olympic champion and world that we who
... This is the first
Together have a champion in such a place
And something that characterizes any of the fighters
* Not Khvshshvn from each other.
Hi everyone my name is Shang Mayang
Hi, I'm Kobra Singh
..and The first press conference the first fight
In the third season matches Down tic Peru
I Dvttvn
Thanks Kobra
Die without wasting time scouting your questions
How Akashi decided that
An Indian wrestlers to the tournament irrigation?
I made a mistake
They say India Country Khakyayh
And King of the same soil countries
Son of the soil
And in my opinion it's the best
Sultan Where have you been all these years?
And why after the World Championships
Abandoned ship?
! Family problems
"What do you call her" family matter
S called in English
" Family matters "
Sir, I heard that the wife is not Knartvn
Divorced when you hold?
Can Nprsyn personal question?
We did not divorce
..dvamvn And contention will happen
When we love a lot
Litigation and dispute off though
Also, do yourself do not have an Mshajrhhayy?
Here's to tell you, among women born fighter
Warriors are
Indeed, your spouse vessel clamp, right?
There, the transmitting another nature
Media Gyrayytvn too
You cause you are getting Sqvtm
Now order us a little Bknyn
It made me reconcile
Sir, Bnzrtvn methionine
In the championship sit?
I do not know
No -
Do not even think about
Because tomorrow I'm just ready for his
And beat every single Astkhvnay your body break
Myzarmt in a Chmdvn
And I will remit for wife
Like the nervous gentleman
Noble met them this, he did not in English?
I'll answer it in the ring.
Sultan, the name on everyone's lips
... Today Sultan with integrity
Several years ago Arefeh
Even God's mistakes Mybkhshh
I heard the wife is not with you
Divorced when you hold?
I am a film
Well Say
Childhood Arefeh
I accept
A young Arefeh
Arefeh sorrow?
I accept
Full Arefeh?
Be Ino
National champion fell asleep at night wedding
My sweet,
And now came the day when all've been waiting for
Today is the first contest "Peru tic Down" took place
24 fighters will fight with each other for 25 days
And all the matches took place inside the cage
Champion will receive 100 million rupees
And the one who failed previous two seasons desperately
In this period plays a hero
And all say that because it is none other than King
Behind me stood the melee fans
And today, all because he inches
And now the championship Presents
Boxing machine, Boris
My God, look at this man Bndazyn
Steel and Vantash and see the movements Krvbatyksh
..and Into the conference
And in the stadium, just the name of Marcellus Maurice
To listen hard,
Brother, it's our turn
I am out Vaysadm
Two seasons ago this race was exciting ..dr
Because the Qhrmanashh
Take Srshvnhha
And now milk and soul Haryana
Sultan Ali Khan comes
The Sultana Dad
Aspansrsh us,
Come Sultan
We ceased bother him
After Sultan Quick.
Phlvvn, good?
My heart is called a race to the principle Vamysth
What do you know about the contest
I'm intrigued by the Kobra?
..mykhvam Know a fellow fighter
A younger fighter
And how Chqrtr was fighting?
So very exciting
Because such a race with these conditions saw Hyjvqt
..yh Standing side by another car Hmvtnmvn
Fighters
This hand
ready?
Not start any
The third season began with the Kobra Msabqath
Come see Sultan Indian wrestlers
MMA can be a tick after removal
K., I think this race interesting
! See Maurice's first movement Mynynm
That seems ridiculous and it looks Sultan
Take away the cage
Otherwise consuming Myfty
Come Maurice
This Yarvyh how feisty
Pvlam all of the dies
Do not rush Dad race not over
Sultan Come on, Come on I
What do you do?
Why do not you focus?
What thinks?
Hvsht work with, go to bring water
The competition was not easy for her ..asla
This was quite unexpected because Maurice
The Sultan, it can lead to trouble
And now he goes with his movements
Into trouble -
Come Sultan
I think Maurice speed of Sultan am
.. I thought that once I
Good good.
Save yourself
Breathe
Kobra I think another race finish
And now it looks strangle him
I have a few seconds left to leave more
Oh my god please bear now
Only 5 seconds left
Save yourself
And that was saved
Sultan saved the home side in the first round
Why
S
Very good
Dad passed plucked up Gvshmvn
Come brother Sultan
Do not be nervous
Sit too little time
He's a big fighter
Look at this
! I do not know this guy is a fighter or a monkey
He fights or anything else matters
Because you Soltani
Do not involve your mind and just think about now
Stay away from Lgdhash
One dog bone ..tk
And Myfrstmt for wife
Fight
Come on ... Come see
K., Sultan looks at it another way
But I doubt that the second round get away with lamb
!!! Evil, what else was it?
What kind of move was
! That's what was moving
Sultan left the cage looks
Where going?
Wants what broke?
Race not over
Sultan is sure that he can not lift another fighter
It finished the match by knockout
! Let us see what the
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
And I say this thing hit the Indian technical
And the impact Sultana
"Sultan"
O puppy
Sultan. Sultan
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
Evil, took
"Sultan"
King
3 hours by
By late
Go a little rest.
Akashi what to do, bro?
Nmybrh sleep at night.
You know when I'm here with you
I think that Hrdvmvn losers
You know you taught me something?
about what?
Never in life do not want to lose
Everyone wants to take it
You know, this ring and campaign for me was just a business
But now I'll
My eyes to see the dignity and respect
Adam feelings are
Say, you want me to sign a beam
good night
02: 11: 40,322 -> 02: 11: 42,813
..bd Of weird and wonderful race first
Now a Sultan's faster, and with confidence
He was a fighter's form
Can you see her fists over Nshdnyh
Bchrkhvnsh
And now looks lock
Can you surrender
I did not say that the heroic
Hey bro?
Yes, yes, how much?
Sultan after defeating opponent
..bh His hands me a sign of apology sticks
Madam, Hello
Hello
My son is 5 years old Rakesh
Dad tells me I want to change my name your photos
Wants to call it wake Sultan
I say why?
Says because he Heroic
Others champion Darren
But the main hero of Sultana
I want to be king
I have a painting
thanks bro
What do nearby?
Not Enough -
Wait, I'm coming
What do you do?
I eat -
Ghzarv simply, quickly put Lbastv
And prepare
We gon 'party
Rvsyth do?
Dad, it's my birthday
Eval
Congratulations
have fun
Tbryka played this useless
Must we forget smash and party
let's go
Get ready
Come up
Really?
What say Oh, I can not believe
I will not go anymore Khylykhb
I sit here and spend night
Uttered in the ovary
Uttered just can not understand -
I know you like my brother
There, I came to
You're like my family now.
I do not party without family
Asn sit here with my TV
I failed
We have a proverb in my work
Everything that you know English
Not your father not to teach your child
Bream
happy Birthday
Happy Birthday Dear Akashi
You know bro, I do not want any of this stuff
My God, you are so cute
Zntv there's no more money and marry me?
Ms. issue my wife very different.
Volt has been all these years
Every marriage is an expiry
No ma'am, in our relationship does not mean expiration
Well, what do we got?
uh huh
No woman -
You are all too Khvbyn
But her words Nznyn
What is the English word
Feeling
Yeah, why feel
I do have a special feeling
Would it just be sensible
"That's where I did not find the holy eyes"
"That's where I did not find luminous face"
"So far I did not find those words sweet and intimate"
"That's where the figures have not found alive."
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."
"I love your smile I could not find the place"
"I smell the fragrance did not find a place."
"That's where I found Rngarngt Utterances"
"That's where I found Msvmytt"
"Every so that you are always like me."
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."
"You like wet leaves into the rain"
"I like the red species into the winter season."
"Rest in peace my night."
"You commit evening calm, morning prayer I"
"In the space of dreams, I am careful you love"
"I like where the fire is burning."
"Like a Tfshany where bamboozled"
"Even without a further word, accept me up"
"Sometimes you'd work that you want."
"As always you are, stay"
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."
Sultan who you played ring games
And her romantic song called "Jgv Mia" is
The voice on the Internet
And now his fans
Wrestlers lover named
"In my dreams or of hope when it comes."
"You're happy moments and sad"
"I want my side."
"I want my side, to my side."
"In my world and my feelings."
"You're under."
"I want the whole world off my knees."
"You know that even after death."
"I know how loyal I am"
"I will do whatever it"
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."
In the third race battle
Between King and Tyrone are
And Tyrone 's record that
In the second round defeat gives Hryfhashv
Plum
Not start any
The interesting thing is, the competition
Struggle between two ships clip
Competition will be very fun cobra
Tyrone's face, and he struts can you see?
He tells her to come take a ship
As a wrestler Tyrone Qharh
This is also a move
Sultan. Sultan
God's ..avh Sultan
You have come far
Intensified account
The game is very heavy God
Sultan, was beaten today eat
Sultan goes down
Alarm to sound the praises
Oh no. No, that's not good
This round was not good for neither of them
And when someone in a cage happen, not good
come
Yarrow Vzyh
Who got you say? -
Fuck my gum out
Given this fact let fight
I was going to finish the game
Come on purpose that I'm here, do you say?
I'm the last moment
I know that you do not you accept defeat
But she grabs Jvnt
The June for the Gaiters
Why do I love it
See bro
Beat me
This is the second major semi-final round of the competition
what happened?
Dndhash broken
What?
Stop fighting now
So we're trying, but I believe that putting
Like the Sultan trouble
And Tyrone Qbraqh
I think Tyrone did not finish inside the Ayn Rand
King fell to the ground
I kick it up
stand up
Stand up brother Sultan, Amydtv lose
Come on get up
Sultan came to his
Beauty rose
Good King
Come Sultan
King beat him land
Eval
Why
The work was finished and Tyrone
Good boy
I think the move played Tyrone
Ayn Rand hero of the match
Sultan Ali Khan of Hndh
Plum
Hello, I am calling from Delhi Govind
Sultan wounded into hospitals
Come, I am early ticket
The course of events
Down tic Peru tournament ends
As you see behind me
Sultan thousands of fans waiting for
He himself headed health
And again come back to the ring.
Akashi
Yes sir
Who decided?
What do I do? I've tried it Bfhmvnm
But putting accept
I wish for this match after
Keep a logic low
I ..sy Valley
Akashi
At the moment of danger
But the situation Bhranyh
If he enters the ring, I will not come out alive
Come on, this Kashh
Here's Akashi Arefeh
Hello
Hello -
Open into trouble
Not again
02: 30: 25,416 -> 02: 30: 26,526
I've failure
sit down
Tired loss to
Why are you Aynkararv, Sultan?
Want me to prove that I want me?
Now coming
Come on, we got very issues
What has upset you?
Just once, instead I think
Because when I was this guy?
I think that makes a statement?
Who dignity and respect in my eyes wanted to see?
Who was the boy safe?
Just be yours?
That is not my baby?
Arefeh, a father of taste goes?
A lot of time, your pain is pain cure
What do you think?
Just you see me coming?
That did not think I had to come?
He Every Day
Why?
Just to see you
And passed all these years Shadyamvn
For just ten
People from suffering such a pain in the break
"But I'm not broken" physically I
You know why?
Because I love Summary
Truer than your love
I admit, I hurt you very year
Maybe you can not understand me as much as a moment of your photos?
But to say something?
Matter of life or pride and victory?
excuse me
You know, we all say that if you get into the ring.
I might get out alive ancestor
I know
! But they do not know what is the real king
I am leaving
If today who could go toe-Bray
Perhaps the appearance survive
But the die
Destroyed no loss
You know
Yeah
Go something that you started
stop it
And Promise
He promised a Phlvvn to another Phlvvn
And a husband to his wife.
Come back alive
I too believe
Uncompromising
Morsi professor
Go fans waiting outside
: Instagram, the media cable channel Balyvvdyha
Instagram.Com/BollywoodihaOfficial
Telegram.me/BollywoodihaOfficial
And now, facing the Sultan Marcus
Which is located in a dangerous fighter
In fact, the three of Hryfhashv
After the match on a stretcher to hospital
So you pay attention to all things?
Bream
come back soon
What is this appearance to take place?
Can you laugh for me once?
The Sultan Today is
I think this competition, a sort of suicide
I agree with you
! All Mydvynm What is the outcome of this match
But I think it's time we trust the Sultan
I think I'd better see Eben match without a microphone
The pro Sultan
Good idea -
Where Kshtyhatvn brothers drowned?
! Nygash now the guy
Akashi brother tell me something
So money comes Gyrmvn
Blood banks happen?
Yeah
that's good
What they say in English?
Take yourself out of the front
Bream
The last fight
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
Sultan. Sultan
The soil is in your blood. "
"And her blood is also on the ground
God is above you and the Earth beneath you. "
"And anything insights, your madness
"Sultan"
This hand
Amadhayn fighters?
Not start any
Govind, careful woman to be your brother
Karshv over now
Yeah, I -
Presented by Media Balyvvdyha
wWw.Bollywoodiha.Com
Stand-rich Sultan
This visual effect is translated from Hindi Language
Struggles into the tournament
Anything higher than normal for a fight
Because I struggle with is your
To obtain dignity and respect
Should disrespect to grant you
What I seek not to be self-pride, Sultan
What do you think, that you could
Defeat you?
Only one person he can beat Sultan
He Sultana their
come
Translation: Research and hearing
Saman Kiani, Karim Khan and Magic
That day I learned three things
The first ship is not a game
Pykarh in which a man with a Myjng·h
Second, he is not the real wrestlers medal score,
It's his fight with the hardships of life
And beat me
good job
Sprayers and Sultan
..and Last thing: beat yourself up when tabling
Come Sultan -
You can not win the other over the door
Yes that's it
Sultan ... Sultan
King?
* Videos will continue until the end of the visit *
Www.Bollywoodiha.Com
"That's where I did not find the holy eyes"
"That's where I did not find luminous face"
"So far I did not find those words sweet and intimate"
"That's where the figures have not found alive."
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."
"I love your smile I could not find the place"
"I smell the fragrance did not find a place."
"That's where I found Rngarngt Utterances"
"That's where I found Msvmytt"
"Every so that you are always like me."
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."
I am proud of my son -
What is the story of a professor? -
What do you say in English?
I do not want a dead give me training
So take
This is to compensate for your efforts.
"You like wet leaves into the rain"
"I like the red species into the winter season."
"Rest in peace my night."
..arfh, Heroine Harayana
"You commit evening calm, morning prayer I"
The history of the Champions
"In the space of dreams, I am careful you love"
The next step is
"Sometimes something that Hqth Moers"
! Sultan Ali Home
"Some think I'm a stranger."
! ... Come doctor Arefeh
"You know that even after death."
Let us its present
"I know how loyal I am"
"I will do whatever it"
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."
What do you want? Girl or boy?
A fire tore Dkhml
What Hstvn for these successes?
What is your opinion?
Look at my face, he shines
Would that we had five years Sultan
You see this ring as champion
The ship clip, and God help his wife's encouragement.
"You're happy moments and sad"
"I want my side."
"I want my side, to my side."
"In my world and my feelings."
"You're under."
"I want the whole world off my knees."
"You know that even after death."
"I know how loyal I am"
"I will do whatever it"
"I looked down on the world but I could not find someone like you."