TAXI 4
Alright.
Are we finally leaving?
A suspect has been
located in the hotel.
But don't worry Mr. Martinez,
your client is perfectly safe.
I've assigned my best
people to the operation.
Gibert calling Alan.
/You've reached the police.
/Please wait on the line.
I've located the suspect.
Distance...
About 15 meters.
- Join me.
- Right away, boss.
Concentrate, Alan.
Do you see the suspect,
at 11 o'clock?
No, "at 11 o'clock"
is a term used in the navy.
You've been in Marseille for 10 years
and I bet you haven't seen the sea.
Actually I have, when making
my rounds at the port.
Fine.
At 12 o'clock is straight ahead
and at 11 o'clock is this way.
Straight and to the left.
Ah yes, indeed.
Are you sure this is the suspect?
I think it's rather a hotel maid.
But of course.
Do you think a terrorist
moves around yelling
and wearing an explosive belt?
- No.
- Exactly.
They disguise themselves.
And is there a better disguise than
a hotel maid pushing a cart?
- I'm asking you.
- Sure.
Especially in a hotel.
Do you hear the song
that rat is humming
to give himself courage?
Ah yes.
Is that Spanish?
That's a revolutionary song,
my little Alan.
On my command
neutralize the Basque.
Roger that.
At 12 o'clock!
/And we're done!
Let that nightingale sing.
Put him in a cage.
I'll question him later.
Go!
Gibert, how's it going?
Mr. Prefect, I've just neutralized
the Spanish terrorist.
He was transporting
a set of little bottles.
Most likely toxic substances
/he was going to spread.
I'll have it tested.
/Excellent, Gibert.
/And now take care
/of our client,
because we can't allow
ourselves to be late.
Consider it done, Mr. Prefect.
Emilien, the coast is clear.
You can deliver the package.
Emilien?
Emilien, answer right away!
I'm practically standing
in the exit door.
We can't do this while
I'm on a special mission.
It's not my fault.
You look so handsome when
you're on a special mission.
You look like Sean Connery
and you turn me on.
Sean Connery...
Please, don't make fun of me.
You enjoy this
because you're stronger.
Alright, you can tie
me up next time.
Not so loud.
The hotel is bugged.
Yes sir, inspector.
I'll take care of the package,
and you find Gibert.
I love you, Emilien.
I love you too, Petra.
But this isn't the time.
See you at home tonight.
Mr. Cissé?
Mr. Cissé, we need to end the interview,
to be on the pitch in 20 minutes.
I'm sorry to disturb you
but I'm from the police and...
What's your name?
Emilien.
No, this isn't about...
This is about...
/Emilien!
This isn't the time
to exchange business cards.
/Where is that...
What a name.
Damn foreigner.
That's Djibril Cissé, sir.
Excuse me?
Don't get wise with me or I'll check
your papers and have you deported.
Emilien, look.
They don't look alike.
/The nose, the teeth.
But it's certainly him,
I assure you.
/Not so fast, Emilien.
/I know about deception.
I worked for 2 years in customs,
so I saw plenty of impostors.
For example that Korean subsidiary in 82.
I smoked them out.
- But he's not Korean.
- How can you be sure?
I checked his papers.
- His eyes are a bit slanted.
- That's because he's tired.
We have to go or the Prefect
will grow impatient.
Yes.
Head to the car!
I don't know what you did to them,
but you aren't popular here.
Don't worry.
He doesn't know anything about soccer.
His passion is fishing.
What are you mumbling, Emilien?
I just said that
your passion is fishing.
Fishing is a real sport.
Do you ever fill
a fishing net?
No, my job is to put
the ball in the goal net.
That's good.
Because fishing isn't for amateurs.
For example consider float fishing,
on the lakeside.
Sometimes you have to
stand motionless for 8 hours
/observing the float.
/And then...
What's going on?
Are you OK?
Break anything?
No.
I'm fine.
Couldn't you have turned
on the signal?
We were told Mr. Cissé
is having a siesta at the hotel,
so we avoided waking him.
He's not having a siesta.
He's in my car
and he's being transferred.
Djibril Cissé is being transferred?
He'll play for Marseille?
It's Cissé.
Do something or we'll be late.
Don't worry.
I know someone who'll
get us out of here.
You have taxis in the police?
No, he rather belongs
to the Air Force.
Marseille Express at your service.
Daniel, no time for jokes.
Mr. Cissé has to be at
the Vélodrome in 10 minutes.
Mr. Djibril.
Nice to have you.
Will you be playing in Marseille?
I'm taking part in a charity match
and I'm going to be late.
Since it's for a good cause.
I'll change clothes in the car,
to gain some time.
You can always try.
Mom, you'll never believe
who's going to play for Marseille.
That's not the right way.
We're leaving Marseille.
We'll go around to
avoid the traffic jams.
I assure you, Djibril Cissé,
no. 9, playing for Olympique de Marseille.
Now this is a road.
Real driving.
We can't hear the engine.
At this speed all
we hear is the wind.
This just in.
Olympique de Marseille has acquired
an exceptional player, Djibril Cissé.
/A speeding white taxi
/will be there in 1 minute.
Roger that.
It must be our
little Daniel.
At his speed
we have no chance.
- Shall we send the new guy?
- Damn. Are you kidding?
What's wrong?
He's new, let him learn.
/Hey, new guy?
Yes, boss?
Stand next to the radar
and set it to "extra sensitive".
- Alright?
- Yes, sir.
Attention, here comes
the TGV train.
/Step away from the platform.
Thanks, kid.
/You did well.
The measurement is more effective
on "extra sensitive".
Your taxi is quite fast.
I have my tricks.
I recovered some parts from
the Concorde, when it was scrapped.
Slow down, I don't want
to miss the exit.
I've just received confirmation.
The Marseille club has made the transfer
of the year for 60 million euro.
All the spots are full.
Drive to the underground parking.
I know it like my pocket.
I'm not sure why, but I worry
when you say that.
Djibril Cissé's arrival
to Olympique de Marseille
is fueling rumors and insane amounts
of money are being mentioned.
To find out more,
we'll go live to our reporter
at the Vélodrome stadium.
I'm coming to you live from
Marseille for this friendly match
being played for the
Association of Sick Children.
And maybe that's why the players
have demanded insane amounts,
since there is talk of
a contract worth 200 million euro.
/We'll invite him to
/the microphone of TF1,
/but until now the star
/has failed to arrive.
Cissé or not, if he's not here
in a minute, I'm starting the match.
Try taking a right here.
Emilien, we've taken a right
here twice already.
Are you sure you know it
like your pocket?
Yes. I was responsible for
security during the pope's visit.
We spent 6 days here looking
for Gibert, who got lost.
That sounds promising.
I don't know the parking,
but I'll trust my intuition.
We're starting.
7 minutes and 32 seconds.
Thanks for the ride.
Thanks for the show.
We have a better view
here than on TV.
But you're in the
middle of the pitch.
Take a seat in the stands
or it's a yellow card.
Of course, Mr. referee.
What an idiot.
- Foul.
- He's on crutches.
- Free kick.
- What's his problem?
Warm up and stretch your legs.
I don't want any injuries during play.
Do you like the shirt?
Yes, but it's too big.
You'll ask mom to wash it.
It'll shrink and be
the right size.
The logo will come off.
I'll ask mom to wash
around the logo.
Listen to me.
I'd like to see you play
longer than 3 minutes,
so no red card, OK?
OK.
Go.
The first rule is that you
never touch the ball, OK?
OK.
And if someone passes you the ball,
kick it right away.
Which way?
Don't worry about that.
Kick it and let the others worry.
Could I finally get
to play soccer?
Daddy will play
with you later.
Go, my son.
Go.
And don't run too fast.
Are you sure he won't
catch a cold?
Don't worry.
I gave him a heated shirt
and plenty of vitamin C this morning.
Then he's really
in no danger.
You should have signed him up for hockey,
to amortize the equipment.
Are you nuts?
That's too dangerous.
His mother wanted him
to take up karate.
But luckily I have the
file of the club manager.
He accepted to refuse him,
without Petra knowing.
Emilien, he'll be at risk
his whole life.
So he better get
used to it.
Yes, but that can wait.
What about swimming?
No.
His bronchi are too frail.
It's hereditary.
And you never broke anything
when you were little?
Yes, my arm.
3 times.
See.
But that didn't
make me any smarter
or get me a place
at the police academy.
Maybe you'd have been
better off breaking a leg.
Very good, my son!
Who will our kids
grow up to be?
What?
Do you think mine will be
a cab driver, and yours a cop?
Why not?
That's nothing bad.
We both help others.
That's beautiful in itself.
It could be worse.
It could be the exact opposite.
Mine a cab driver,
and yours a cop.
Don't mention such misfortune.
Emilien, yes?
Emilien?
What urgent matter?
Gibert told you that?
But I'm not working today.
Emilien?
Are you alright Maxim?
No, that's not possible.
Emilien, you'd better...
Alright.
I'm coming.
Daniel, Gibert is summoning everyone
for an urgent matter.
Can you take care of Maxim?
Petra is on a secret mission.
I can't call her.
And my mother is on a pilgrimage to Lourdes.
To Lourdes?
She goes there every year
since my birth.
Such a miracle
must be celebrated.
- Take my stuff to the station after the game.
- No problem.
Just don't take them
to the port for sweets.
Sure.
They'll get a slice of bread,
a cup of water and go to bed.
I'm kidding.
Go.
I'll take care of him
like my own.
That's what I'm afraid of.
Emilien, your son visits
me every Wednesday.
And he's never complained.
He never returns with warts on his face.
No.
So get moving
and go to work.
OK.
4 minutes and 30 seconds without
a card is your record.
But I didn't do anything.
That referee gives out cards
to every promising player.
Go get Maxim.
I'll take you to the port.
Come on Max,
we're going to the port.
Stop that ball this instant!
I got it, boss.
Bring me that ball.
It won't piss me off anymore.
Here kids.
You can play on.
Alright, gentlemen...
This isn't the time for dribbling, footwork
or any other soccer nonsense.
I've talked on the
phone with Paris.
They're sending us
a very special package.
It's this year's
biggest transfer.
Drogba?
Thuram?
No, I know.
Makelele?
Beckenbauer?
Maradona?
You're a real
bunch of morons.
I'm not talking about tennis.
I'm talking about a criminal.
Tapie?
This one is even more famous.
According to his file,
he's public enemy no. 1.
/It's...
Boss...
That's yesterday's transfer.
So where's my paper?
It's written on the back.
You asked us to save paper.
Yes, that's true.
That was my wife's idea.
She saw a TV show about the destruction
of the Amazon forests.
Do you know how many acres
of forest are destroyed each day?
/- 3? 6?
/- I don't know.
How many?
If you knew,
it would make you shudder.
How many?
It's millions of matchboxes being
cut down and going up in flames.
So...
When the opportunity presents itself...
Respect your papers.
Respect the paper.
Economize.
Boss, and that public enemy no. 1?
Yes...
He's a Belgian,
whose name I won't pronounce
because it makes me feel sick.
53 armed robberies.
/Accomplice to 122 murders.
/There hasn't been anyone
/worse since Al Capone.
He's being transferred to Congo,
where he'll be tried
in 10 criminal cases.
Transit in Marseille.
We take care of him from the time
of his arrival until 5 a. m. tomorrow.
And we put him on a plane
of the Congo authorities.
This Belgian won't have
the time to tour the city.
Surveillance must be ultra tight.
One police officer per square inch.
I want so many officers around him,
so that he can't see the sea.
Do you understand?
Yes, boss!
At what time is that monster
of the Ardennes flying in?
Good question, Emilien.
At exactly 3 p. m.
Boss, it's already 3:05.
It's 12:05 on mine.
Head to the cars!
Maxim, is this what
you ordered?
So why aren't you eating?
Because my dad says that such
a cake only gets you stains all over.
You'll show your dad that's not
the case and you won't stain yourself.
/Damn, your father.
Leo, hide under the table.
/What's this in the
/middle of the street?
Get out of the way.
Police.
She's caught a flat tire.
I can't leave her
alone in this heat.
He's right, boss.
She'll dehydrate.
We need to help her.
I'm a certified life guard.
I'll help her.
I was a florist
before being a cop.
Nobody move!
Isn't he ashamed?
He should be behind bars.
/How much time does it take
/to change a tire?
It doesn't take 3 hours.
Around here we
take our time.
Thank you.
Finally.
Go.
/Is the cake good at least?
- Mr. General.
- Gibert, explain yourself.
I'm sorry for being late.
We took a shortcut thru the port,
but caught a flat tire.
Does it take an hour
to change a tire?
It now takes the
police a whole week.
The training of recruits
is getting worse.
They learn to shoot on day 1.
But between you and me,
we change tires more often than we shoot.
Do you have the same
problem in the army?
No.
We have caterpillars.
Caterpillars.
Very good.
They go everywhere.
That's funny.
This reminds me of my vacation in Africa.
They had the same cages
and we slept in them,
to protect ourselves
from the wild animals.
This animal is of
the worst kind, Gibert.
If it escapes,
it will burn down the city and kill
everyone before you change a tire.
Don't worry,
Mr. General.
We're used to such
characters in Marseille.
One day they're limping
on one leg,
and the next they're healthy
and playing soccer.
Load him up.
And we're done.
Gibert, be careful with this package.
Your career depends on it.
Don't worry, Mr. General.
Consider it done.
Let's sync our watches.
- 4:20.
- 12:05. Perfect.
We'll be in touch
every 2 hours.
Forward!
Hello, this is Gibert.
Mr. General.
Already?
Yes, already.
You've been gone 30 seconds,
and already you've made a blunder.
How so?
Look in the mirror.
A price tag.
Of course.
Now I see better.
Thank you, Mr. General.
Gibert, I meant the exterior mirror.
/Now look to your right.
Holy crap!
Stop the cars!
- Are you sure this is the place?
- I'm 100% sure.
Alright, this is
what we'll do.
You'll stay in the car.
I'll be better off on my own.
And if...
And I emphasize the "if".
If I'm not back in 30 minutes,
come and get me.
OK, fine.
What?
Call me before
you let him out.
It'll be safer that way.
No problem.
Damn.
What a throw.
COMMISSIONAIRE GIBERT
OK.
Get to work, Serge.
Hi, Daniel.
I found this a mile down the road.
Does it belong to you?
Damn, I knew it had
rolled off somewhere.
Thanks.
- Hi, kids.
- They're growing up fast.
Hi, Maxim.
We know each other.
Luckily he doesn't
look like his dad.
OK, let's go.
Emilien hasn't returned yet.
No problem. I'll put them in
front of the computer.
Does your dad have anything
against video games?
Now you have something to do.
I'll be gone 5 minutes.
I'll make a call.
Be good.
Is someone else using it?
No, they simply gave
my dad the worst computer.
You can barely
send an e-mail.
- And Gibert's computer?
- It's an atom bomb.
SYSTEM ERROR
What's this mess?
Nothing works.
Why don't they make the
newer models more user-friendly?
Yes?
We want to use the computer.
The computer's already in use.
Why don't you go
to another office?
Because this computer is the
latest generation Extreme Core.
SYSTEM ERROR
Do you know how
to use this machine?
Kids' play.
Hi, Marley.
Hi.
Got anything for
a dry throat?
It's the end of the season
and I have little left.
Look in the closet.
HOLLAND.
MOROCCO.
COLUMBIA.
Indeed.
Should I roll 2?
Yeah, maybe I'll
finally wake up.
/Here.
Thanks, but I never smoke while on the job.
I'll smoke it at home.
That's funny.
Here it's the other way around.
We smoke at work but never at home.
Damn, it's Gibert.
Damn, the car...
OK, Alan...
Put the animal in
the big office.
- Should I get him out of the cage?
- Of course not.
Must I remind you that
this animal is extremely dangerous?
I know.
But this cage is extremely big.
Don't question my orders.
Execute.
To all units.
/The wolf is entering
/the sheep house.
Damn, it's Gibert.
Get rid of it.
Wait, Marley.
Come here.
/Come here.
Yes, Commissionaire?
Have you been smoking?
No.
I assure you.
Don't tell me stories.
I have an acute sense of smell,
my little Marley.
Last winter I had a 3-month
workshop with rescue dogs.
I sniffed a lot of snow.
I don't doubt it.
At the end of the workshop
I could smell drugs from a mile away.
Unreal...
Yes.
OK, I'll let you go this time.
But it better not happen again.
Type the password.
I type the password.
Upload the picture.
I upload the picture.
First you click the
picture you don't want.
First I click the
picture I don't want.
And you click the picture
you want to keep.
Thanks a lot, boys.
Without you I never
would have managed.
You deserve a little something.
A ticket.
Here you go.
Put it away.
It's our little secret.
What are you
doing here, kids?
I've told you not
to touch my computer.
Go.
And what are
you doing here?
I'm...
You're the new IT trainer?
That's right.
I'm sorry.
It slipped my mind.
The help of a trainer is a must
in case of these machines.
I'm rather talented when
it comes to electronics.
But I must admit that
I'm having a hard time.
OK, let's have a lesson today.
I had a hard day and I feel
my head is going to explode.
Excuse me...
But you're smoking.
No, I stopped
smoking 3 weeks ago.
I generally have a strong will
but this time I got a patch.
- See?
- It suits you.
But I meant you have smoke
coming out your head.
Yes, indeed.
- May I?
/- Be my guest.
Where did this come from?
This is from Morocco.
Put it out please.
This is a non-smoking office.
I'm sorry.
OK, can we start the lesson?
I have also other things to do.
Of course. Where did you
finish last lesson?
At adjusting the chair.
Grab the mouse.
One eye on the monitor,
and the other on the keyboard.
This won't be easy.
Are you sure this is
for kids under 6?
Dad, this game is super soft.
We haven't played it for years.
Daniel...
You'll never imagine what
a difficult case I've been given.
It's widely known
I have no imagination.
They've sent us an important client.
A very important client.
- That is?
- He's wanted by every police in Europe.
And they sent him here?
That's good.
He can play some boules.
He won't have time.
Tomorrow at 5 a. m. we'll
put him on a plane to Congo.
/If he doesn't escape
/in the meantime.
I don't want to make fun of you,
but this isn't a police station.
It's an amusement center.
Exactly, Daniel.
Gibert has summoned everyone
and I have to do overtime.
I've called Petra
but she doesn't answer.
She's still on that
damn secret mission.
So I'm left with
the kid and...
You'd like your friend
Daniel to take care of him.
For 2 or 3 hours until
I'm off duty.
I'll pick him up
after duty.
- Sugar?
- Yes.
When will I get to work?
I've been with the kids since this morning.
Your wife can't take of them?
She's in Paris at a
redecorating exposition.
She redecorates?
She only redecorates garages.
She's decided to
redecorate our garage.
- What a mess...
- That's right.
Even the taxi has
to stand outside.
Can you imagine?
- That's rough.
- Right.
But come to think of it...
It's better for the
taxi to stand outside.
She's putting flowers everywhere.
/The flower pollen is
/damaging everything.
I spend the weekends cleaning
everything with cotton swabs.
When living with someone you
need to learn to compromise.
And what compromises have
you arrived at with Petra?
A whole bunch.
For example?
For example, my personal things.
When I was single
my things were a mess.
And when Petra saw a shirt lying around
she'd throw it out the window.
- Your boxers too?
- Everything, I'm telling you.
What did you do?
Did you learn to clean up?
Exactly.
And I bought a fishing rod.
I don't have to go
down 3 floors to get my stuff.
When do you want to
pick up your kid?
I'll be off duty
in 2 hours.
OK.
Go for 2 hours.
You're a real pal, Daniel.
Yeah, I know.
Tell me.
/Since it'll be the 4
/of us without the wives,
how about some pizza
and TV at my garage?
Before the shop closes.
Sold.
Tell me.
What will you do with them
during those 2 hours?
I have an idea.
/Grandpa!
Kids!
/It's so nice
/to see you.
You were supposed
to come on Sunday.
I know, but we were going to the movies
and they saw your house,
and started to scream
wanting to see you.
Yes, grandpa.
I missed you so much.
I want to stay with Leo.
My sweet angels.
I'm here.
Grandpa is here.
/Don't worry.
They're so sensitive.
Their mothers are
out of town.
/They act like tough guys,
but in fact
they're soft-hearted.
Can I keep them for
a couple of hours?
/So that they can calm down.
But not more than 2 hours,
Mr. General.
/They have homework to do.
2 hours.
Starting now.
He's been gone an hour.
Shall we go get him?
We'll wait another 5 minutes
and then we'll go.
/Up.
That's it.
And now down.
Faster.
Faster...
Up.
See.
It's not so hard.
/The most important is
/to keep a steady pace.
Boss!
Alan, you made me lose.
/How many points
/did I score?
8.
Not bad for a first time.
/What's the record?
/The record is...
/20 million, 653 thousand.
- May I?
- Be my guest.
Hello?
It's me.
Shall we come and get you?
No, there's no need.
I'm done here.
/I'll be there soon.
OK, fine.
And?
He's fine.
Excuse me, but I have to go.
Already?
Another client is
waiting for me.
Next month at the same hour.
With great pleasure.
Alan, what did you do?
Are you completely nuts?
You gave an order to put
him in the big office.
And orders shouldn't be questioned.
That's true.
You did well, my little Alan.
Take off the cover.
He won't stand here all dressed up.
He's impressive.
Is he really that dangerous?
He's even worse.
He can slit a sheep's
throat with his ears.
Don't be afraid,
my little Emilien.
I spent 5 years in Equatorial Guyana,
eating fried spiders
and counting hippos for UNESCO.
So I won't be scared of
some Belgian, believe me.
We'll start with a routine interrogation.
That'll calm him down.
Alan, get me the papers.
Go ahead, Alan.
First and last name!
So?
How'd it go?
The place is a nuthouse,
I swear.
It gives me the creeps.
Come on, go.
You want to play
the wise guy?
Alan, the Bouches-du-Rhône department.
- Bouches-du-Rhône?
- Yes, Bouches-du-Rhône.
Sure, boss.
You'll see.
Will you answer?
Stay calm!
You still want to
play the wise guy?
Alright.
Alan, there's a hunting
rifle in my desk.
You'll see.
I brought it back from Guyana.
A gift from the head of the reserve.
This dart will put an elephant
to sleep in 5 seconds.
/OK, Alan.
/Careful, it's loaded.
/Keep him at gunpoint.
If he tries to escape,
fire at him.
Without a warning shot?
Of course.
There's only one dart.
What will you use to
put him to sleep?
All the better for me.
Let's continue the interrogation.
First and last name.
What's that?
He's starting to
piss me off.
Don't piss me off.
You don't want to see me pissed off.
Boss, it must be hard for him to
talk with a ball in his mouth.
That's just an excuse.
If he wanted to, he'd talk.
Look, boss.
He's trying to say something.
Let him say it.
That's all we're asking.
Boss, what if we take the
ball out of his mouth?
Not a chance.
Give an arm,
he'll take a finger.
That's what this
little blackboard is for.
There's a blackboard?
Yeah, have a look.
And there's chalk on a chain.
This allows him to communicate.
Very good.
He'll answer us in writing.
Emilien, write
"first and last name".
Boss, he can't talk but
he can hear us very well.
Give him the chalk.
But be careful he doesn't
bite your leg off.
/Go ahead, Emilien.
Slowly.
/Very good, Emilien.
PEE
What did he write?
- Pee.
- Pee?
That's right.
I understand, but is that
his first or last name?
Boss, I think he wants
to go to the bathroom.
He's not going anywhere.
That trick "I'll go to the
bathroom and run away",
I've seen it a hundred times.
He thinks he'll trick us
with such an old stunt.
Are you kidding me?
There must be something prepared
for such an eventuality.
Look over there.
Look where?
Emilien, do you know
how this works?
Of course.
It's kids' play.
This is the drain pipe.
And this one is for cleaning.
Simple.
They showed us a training video
about new equipment a month ago.
Right, Alan?
Never mind.
Hook him up.
And you keep
him at gunpoint!
Try this and tell
me what you think.
This stuff is strong.
I'm already seeing huge worms.
This connects to the water tap.
And this is placed
in the toilet.
Done.
That was easy.
I hooked up the pipes...
Alan, give me that.
I'm sorry, man.
- I wasn't focused.
- Then focus a little, Alan.
We're at a police station so
you can't go around waving a weapon.
And we have no experience
in shooting at bears.
This thing is used
to shoot at bears.
You have to be careful
in an office.
One finger on the safety catch,
while keeping the weapon
close to the body, like this.
My foot.
There's a chair here.
Lay him down.
He weighs as much as
a couple of people.
Damn...
Look at him.
He looks like he
smoked some carpet.
No, it's some stuff
for bears.
For bears?
You gave him that.
I didn't give him anything.
No, you morons.
He shot himself with
a sleeping dart for bears.
We have to wake him or he'll
hibernate for 6 months.
Consider that...
6 months of peace...
And who will sign
the vacations?
- Get up!
- Wake up!
General alarm!
Where were we?
We were at first
and last name.
Have you become as
stupid as Gibert?
I'm sorry.
I spend the whole day with him
so it's starting to rub off.
Are you OK Belgian?
Did you take a leak?
Did you play
"white men can't piss"?
That was funny.
"White men can't piss".
OK, enough.
That must have been a big pee.
See how his legs have swollen?
But that's not normal.
It should go
out the drain pipe.
But water is flowing inwards.
That's not possible.
Water should flow outwards.
Yes, I know.
Maybe you hooked it up wrong.
No, that's not possible.
I was extra careful.
I connected the drain pipe to the tap,
putting the other pipe in the toilet.
Seems right to me.
Anyway, something's wrong.
I'll go and check.
I messed up again.
I'm such an idiot.
I turned off the water
so it should drop.
It's dropping.
Look.
Before he had two geysers
shooting from his eyes,
and now he has
two little disks.
Damn, we need to get him out of there.
He'll drown.
Are you sure about this?
He's extremely dangerous.
We can't toy with him.
Do you think the death of a Belgian
at a French station is something funny?
You're right.
That isn't funny.
There must be a way to
quickly open this.
See anything?
A button, a lever.
A chain?
No, a handle.
Hurry up.
Grab it on your side.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
One.
Two.
He doesn't look good.
Let's take off the mask.
You do it.
- Why me?
- Go ahead, do it.
This thing is hard
to take off.
Do it slowly.
This is funny.
This isn't how
I imagined him.
Then how?
I don't know...
With a face like...
And teeth like...
And a jaw like...
- Like a monster.
- Yeah. Worse.
The biggest killers
are the most anonymous.
The better they look,
the more careful we are.
Go ahead, wake him.
What are you doing?
I'm being careful.
Sir?
He feels better now.
That's good.
I'm glad.
Where am I?
You're at Marseille's main
police station.
And you're police officers?
Yes.
We're soon to be
chief inspectors.
Soon to be chief inspectors.
- The book?
- No, first the flyswatter.
Stop it!
Stop it.
/Listen.
This is a regrettable mistake.
And it's not the fault of the
French police, but the Belgian one.
It's true.
Mr. Albert Vandenbosh.
Wanted by Interpol for
criminal cases in 17 countries.
Memory coming back?
My memory is good
and that's the problem.
My name isn't Albert Vandenbosh
but Fénimore Eugene Triboulet
and I'm an attaché
at the Belgian Embassy.
He thinks we're morons.
1987. Armed robbery on
the Paris-Bouche train.
I did not commit any crime.
I'm an attaché.
You're rather attached.
If you think we'll believe your story,
then you're very mistaken.
Alan, prepare a report
for the boss.
It'll make him happy.
I'll go over to the file.
/Write.
Albert Vandenbosh.
/Eugene Triboulet, I tell you.
I know that Vandenbosh.
Look at his picture.
He has a different face.
/He has a moron's face.
Yeah, sure.
Emilien?
Come and see this.
Who is this?
Albert Vandenbosh.
See?
I told you.
/I won't blame you,
/it wasn't your fault.
/Untie me.
I won't file a complaint
and we can forget about this.
Where did you meet Vandenbosh?
I wouldn't say that
I met him.
I saw him at the
police station in Bruges.
What were you doing
at the station in Bruges?
/I came to report a robbery.
I was the victim
of a carjacking.
A car what?
A carjacking.
My Toyota was stolen.
Two guys threw me out of my car
and drove off with it.
In Marseille we call
that a "Parisian".
In Belgium we say "carjacking".
- Carjacking.
And then?
I was in the Commissionaire's office,
a kind and hospitable man,
when I felt the need
to go to the bathroom.
You always feel the
need to go pee?
I had some prostate
surgery last year.
I'm sorry.
And then?
I was in the bathroom cabin,
when I stumbled upon Vandenbosh,
who was taking off
this horrible suit.
/And then his accomplices
/jumped on top of me
and forced me to put on
this horrible attire.
/Of course I tried
/to defend myself.
But they quickly put
the ball in my mouth
and since then
I couldn't defend myself.
Do you understand?
You're really good.
But unluckily for you,
you've met your match today.
Emilien?
What now?
Can you come and see this?
BELGIAN EMBASSY
FENIMORE EUGENE TRIBOULET
CULTURAL ATTACHE
Fénimore Eugene Triboulet.
Cultural attaché at the Belgian
embassy since 1996.
/Since the 17th of May 1996
/to be exact.
My nomination was also shown
in the evening TV news.
Is there a number to call?
Yeah, there's the number.
Go ahead, call.
Call them.
Belgian Embassy, hello.
How may I help you?
Hello.
I'd like to talk to Mr. Triboulet.
Unfortunately Mr. Triboulet
has been absent for 3 days.
Do you know where I can find him?
It's an important matter.
To be honest,
/we haven't heard from
/Mr. Triboulet in 3 days.
and the embassy is
starting to worry.
Are you saying he's disappeared?
Something like that.
We know he went to the station
in Bruges Tuesday morning,
/to report the carjacking
/of his Toyota.
And since then we
have no news of him.
/Are you his father?
No.
That's terrible.
I'll call again later.
Holy cow...
Will you talk?
Go easy on him.
Don't worry.
I have an eye on them.
And you try not to
burn down the station.
Can you borrow me some clothes?
We have a problem with the prisoner.
Yeah, look in the closet.
/The boss has a few
/shirts to change clothes.
You're right.
He can change clothes
every 10 minutes.
My little Daniel.
You've come at the right time.
Is there a problem?
No, but it would be nice if
you could sign an armistice.
Leo, look over here.
Awesome.
I prefer to die in glory
than to surrender in infamy.
What is that?
Peace.
The war's over.
Are you OK, Mr. General?
I'm fine.
I lost the battle
but not the war.
If you don't mind the next
battle will be some other time.
I'd like the kids
to do their homework.
Yes.
Of course.
Let's do it this Sunday.
This Sunday.
That's right.
The day of Our Father.
It'll make Him happy.
Yes.
And we'll eat an apple pie.
Very good.
I'll take care of that.
Go to the car.
You were supposed to be good for 2 hours,
and not destroy his living room.
He started it.
We wanted to play checkers.
But he said that checkers
are a game for faggots.
Checkers are a game for faggots?
He said that?
And do you know what
a "faggot" is?
A "faggot" is a flyswatter.
My dad says there are plenty
of faggots at the office.
I don't know what these flies
ate this summer but they're huge.
Your boss must be
really well-built.
These clothes are a little too big
but you look good in them.
This isn't exactly my style
but I won't be picky.
Better this than
that diving suit.
That's for sure.
This one is huge.
Are you nuts?
/Sorry, man.
But there was a giant
fly right here.
Giant flies and worms.
I know what you're saying.
I have something
to make it go away.
I assure you...
Where did it go?
How many of these
flyswatters do you have?
No, it's not at
all like that.
/I'll explain.
Our boss loves fly fishing.
And his birthday is coming up,
so we're collecting
some flies for him.
It'll be a surprise.
Excuse me.
OK...
/Give you a ride?
No, thank you.
I'll take a cab.
Bye.
And once again I'm sorry.
Daniel.
Is Emilien off duty?
He has an hour left.
Tell him I'm with the kids.
I'll get the pizzas and we'll meet at my place.
Alright.
I'll tell him.
/- Bye.
- Thanks.
You've arrived at the right time.
I was looking for a means of transport.
Where should I drive you, sir?
Number 4, Mediterranean Square.
/Nice address.
And may I ask for a favor?
Which is?
I know that French Riviera inhabitants
live at their own pace,
because of the sun, which induces
them to take siestas.
But the sun has set and the heat
has subsided so I won't play the tourist.
So could you step on it,
so that I may arrive at my
destination as soon as possible?
The port of Marseille,
for Marseille.
Right?
You better buckle up
instead of being a wise guy.
What?
/- Disgusting.
/- What a stench.
I deserved it.
Have a nice stay in Marseille.
Bye.
Delta 1, the sardine has arrived.
Your turn,
Delta 3.
/Roger that.
/We're on our way.
We're starting.
This is better than those clothes
that smelled like sardines.
Did you get all the
things I asked for?
Everything's ready.
What about the specialist?
It's not easy to find
someone competent in this town.
So I had to...
Serge, I'm not asking
how brilliant you were,
but whether you
found a specialist.
The best of the best.
Then get me a meeting with him,
if you don't mind.
Of course.
I asked him to
pay you a visit.
That must be him.
Do we kiss or shake hands?
Given the choice,
I'll pick the kiss.
In Belgium it's 3.
It's an honor to
work for you.
- What do you know about my work?
- Work. What a vulgar word.
I prefer to speak
of your masterpiece.
She's good.
OK.
When do we start?
Not so fast.
I'm a softy for compliments,
but before we begin,
I have to test you.
A sort of ritual.
I'll close my eyes.
I'll hold you close.
And you'll try, I repeat,
you'll try to steal something
without me noticing.
You have 1 minute.
Starting now.
I set it to the
right time.
It was running a minute late.
She's really very good.
Where did you recruit her?
It's no use.
We've tried the books but he's not
interested in any of them.
OK...
I see only one solution.
- He's here.
- Where's the bear?
His nose is warm.
He's not a bear,
he's a commissionaire.
He shot himself with a sleeping dart.
We need to wake him.
That's what I thought because
I've never seen such a species.
I'll apply the antidote.
This dose is
for an elephant,
but it works the same way
in case of a bear.
Do you know what
you're doing?
Yes.
The most important is
to aim properly,
above the trunk
and between the eyes.
- Emilien!
- I'm here, boss.
Are you OK?
What's wrong?
That's a normal reaction.
He should lie some
time in his basket.
I dozed off for 5 minutes.
What time is it?
12:05?
That's why I'm so hungry.
I'd eat an ox.
Shall I order a pizza, boss?
I won't refuse, my little Alan.
I'm on it.
Emilien, I had an absurd dream
and you were in it.
Really?
Yes, that Belgian had tricked you
and you let him get away.
It was one of those dreams.
Emilien?
Daniel...
You'll never believe
what happened.
You got fired?
How'd you know?
You get fired once a month.
It's easy to remember.
But this time it's
for real, Daniel.
Do you remember that
public enemy no. 1?
We were supposed to keep
an eye on him during his stay.
- I let him get away.
- No?
I did.
He got away
and I didn't stop him.
I'm such an idiot.
That was quite a stupidity.
It's not just one stupidity,
it's a whole bunch.
I keep stacking them one
on top of the other.
I've made so many of them,
I can write the dictionary of stupidity.
Don't rub it in.
/You had your successes.
/The Santa Clause gang?
That Chinese woman?
Those were lucky shots.
I'm a good-for-nothing, Daniel.
Gibert did the right thing by
taking away my badge. I don't deserve it.
Don't worry.
You're not the only one.
Besides, I picked this profession
to make my dad happy.
He asked me on his death bed.
How could I refuse?
That's not easy.
But you tried your best
and that's what counts.
Yeah, you're right.
Time to start a new chapter
and do something else.
Something that I care about.
Now that's positive attitude.
Apart from stupidities,
what would you like to do?
That's problem.
I've become attached to this profession.
It's one of the most
beautiful professions.
In that case, you're really
in a dead end.
If only I could find the Belgian,
Gibert would give me back my badge.
What Belgian?
The prisoner was a Belgian.
With a big face,
dressed as a fisherman?
Yeah.
That's exactly him.
Did you see him?
He got in my cab
in front of the station.
That was him.
He didn't want a lift,
preferring a cab.
That was a truly spectacular escape.
Was there also a goodbye fanfare?
Stop it, Daniel.
Do you remember where you drove him?
Of course I remember.
You're a genius, Daniel.
Emilien?
What?
And what about the kids?
/Crap.
/The kids.
Do you have an idea?
My little Daniel.
Is it already Sunday?
Yes, it's Sunday.
I'll leave the kids
and go get the apple pie.
Very good.
I'll fire up the oven.
Are you sure this is it?
Yes, no. 4.
We have to make sure
they're still here.
They're still here.
How do you know?
The lights are out.
The lights are out because they're
sleeping like everyone else,
except morons.
And the car is
parked up front.
You'd make a good cop,
you know?
Was that a compliment?
Yes.
Don't tell me it
never attracted you.
As a kid, you never played
cops and robbers?
I did. But I was always
part of the other team.
Always.
So if you want my help tomorrow,
I need to get some sleep.
- Is that possible?
- Go ahead. Sleep.
I'll keep an eye on them.
Emilien!
I'm sorry.
I dozed off.
We have coffee, hamburgers,
cheeseburgers, cake.
And yogurt.
You had all
this in the car?
I went out to buy it.
What?
So the house wasn't
being watched?
I was supposed to sleep, and you were
supposed to watch the house.
But you snore so loud
that I can't sleep.
So maybe they ran off.
They didn't run off.
Look.
The car is parked
in the same spot.
Two guys drove up in
a second car an hour ago.
Yeah? Why didn't
you wake me up?
When you're asleep that's
when I get some rest.
In spite of the snoring.
Daniel...
They're leaving.
/There's your Belgian.
It's not him.
He didn't have a mustache
and he was younger.
Emilien, he disguised himself.
Look.
That mustache is falling off.
/Yes...
/Why would he dress up
/as an old man when going out?
Maybe because the police
is looking for him.
Oh yeah, of course.
But I've seen that girl
somewhere before.
I've never seen her.
Where are they going?
Guess.
MONACO
/Monaco, of course.
One bank per square inch.
This is paradise for him.
It's called a fiscal paradise.
Yeah, tell me about it.
There are plenty of boxes
here we'd like to open.
It would help us in many cases.
Should I ask the Belgian to open a few?
He owes you that for your help.
Stop your nonsense.
There we go.
He's chosen a bank.
BELGIAN ROYAL BANK
Belgian Royal Bank.
Most likely he's homesick.
/Will they rob the bank?
They didn't go
to play boules.
I'm calling Gibert.
Don't you want to wait
until you have some proof?
Don't worry.
We'll find the proof later.
/Hello, sir?
/Emilien speaking.
I have the Belgian.
I mean I've located him.
I know I'm not a cop anymore.
I was taking a walk and I saw him
walk into a bank with his gang.
They didn't go
there to play boules.
It's the Belgian Royal Bank
in Monaco.
Yeah, it's far.
OK, I'll try to
slow them down.
They're coming.
Great.
We've located the Daltons,
and they're sending Rantanplan.
Hello.
How may I help you?
Yes, I've come to
see my son, Edward.
Edward Triboulet?
You're his father?
Yes.
My pleasure.
He'll be happy to see you.
This way please.
Second floor, room 115.
Thank you, young man.
This way.
You're kind, Etienne.
Come in.
Dad?
- Dad has been dead for 4 years, moron.
- Oh, right.
He wouldn't be proud
you changed your name.
You didn't like it, did you?
Fénimore...
You're not in prison?
Not this week.
I treat prison like
a country house.
I go there to relax.
Bring your head closer.
What a stupid hairstyle.
Can't you get
another hairstyle?
Girls don't like hair
combed like that.
They like hair combed
like mine.
I assume you're still single.
Yes.
Delta 1, we're in position.
/Roger that, Delta 2.
That girl is going
to join them.
/I've seen her before.
I'm sure of that.
I'm entering the bank.
/Roger that, Delta 2.
We have you on visual.
Things are heating up.
Maybe I'll go there
and have a discreet look.
No.
You don't know
what discreet is.
We stay in the car
and wait for Rantanplan.
Madame?
I have an appointment with
Mr. Triboulet to open an account.
I'll call him, madam.
Go ahead.
What are you waiting for?
Hello?
A client.
/Take care of her.
Don't let my presence
inconvenience you.
Yes, I'm coming.
/Right away.
Go and give me
the keys to the safe.
/I'll take your place.
I only have the keys
to the empty boxes.
I only open accounts.
Good, because so do I.
I'm sorry for the delay, countess.
Please, this way.
- Open it.
- Yes sir, Mr. Triboulet.
If you don't mind
the step, countess.
And we're done.
Your turn, countess.
Do you have a favorite place
when opening an account?
That wall there.
On that wall we have number 82.
Alright?
Perfect.
And?
Catch anything?
I'm looking for the
alarm system cables.
/If I don't turn it off,
the alarm will go off when
we open a safety box.
She's really very good.
That's for sure.
Bring us something to eat.
I haven't eaten since last night.
I'll bring us something, boss.
FRIES
What's Gibert doing?
It doesn't take an hour
to get to Monaco.
- I've taught you some bad habits.
- That's true.
And what are they doing?
It doesn't take an hour
to open a box.
Maybe they're opening
more than one.
This is a list of
those we want to open.
This will take some time.
Have a coffee.
A coffee?
The "La Libre Belgique" newspaper.
Now this is class.
In Her Majesty's service.
I've opened the first box.
Roger, Delta 2.
Carry on.
What?
A guy in a suit
and dark glasses
gets in a van
at 9 in the morning.
Do you think that's normal?
Maybe he got back from work
and is changing clothes before going out.
And he bought fries,
even though he sells them.
Maybe those he bought
are better than his own.
You have an answer
for everything.
And that's why I'm a cop.
I have only 5 boxes left.
Alright Delta 2, wait a moment.
Number 107.
I repeat: number 107. 1-0-7.
Roger.
A black diary.
Is that it?
Confirmed.
- You scared me.
- I'm sorry.
- How's it going?
- Only 5 left.
- Hurry up.
- Of course.
It's me.
How's it going?
I'm doing what I can, but...
He has a smaller head than yours,
so the wig keeps falling off.
Stop fooling around
and get out of there!
Moron.
Enough of this.
Put on the mustache and let's go.
Or else he'll yell
at me again.
What are they doing?
Have they stopped for breakfast?
That wouldn't surprise me.
Look.
There.
I told you, he'll get away.
- Yes, hello?
/- Gibert here.
Boss, he's leaving the bank
disguised as an old man.
/Where are you?
The driver left to
ask for directions,
but it's not easy,
because the inhabitants
/run away when they see
/a police officer.
And the GPS is broken again.
It's displaying the wrong town.
Where do I go now?
You go to the beach.
Once you get there, you walk
into the sea and swim ahead.
- Alright.
- Now get lost.
He left and is going to get away.
He's at the end of the street.
It's there around that corner.
Emilien, how was that
old man dressed?
What do we do?
Nothing. We don't care.
It's not him.
I'm not myself!
Sure.
And I'm not myself either.
Load him up.
You're making a mistake.
I'm not myself.
Emilien?
Yes, boss?
/We'll meet at the office.
/I have a police badge for you.
Thank you, boss.
Did you hear that?
Wonderful!
And thanks to you, Daniel.
How will I ever thank you?
Emilien, something's fishy.
He simply feels guilty.
He knows I'm a good cop
and doesn't want to lose me.
I'm not talking about that,
but about the Belgian.
They drove up in 2 cars
and 6 people went in with bags.
Now 2 of them came out with
no bags and left on foot.
Can you explain that?
No.
That's not easy.
And did you notice the old man
wasn't limping the same way?
I did notice that.
I thought he must have
fallen down the stairs.
Old people often
fall down the stairs.
And I think it's not
the same person.
Really?
If that wasn't the Belgian
then where is he?
There.
Holy cow...
I'll take a different route.
That'll be more discreet.
We'll meet at the house.
No way.
We rob together
and get caught together.
Besides, you won't leave me.
I'm rich and single.
I'd regret it.
Dammit.
He didn't let her leave.
What now?
Do we follow them?
With this piece of junk?
What are you waiting for?
Follow them.
I'll let them get away.
It's more fun this way.
This isn't the
time for games. Go.
Why are they going
so slowly?
It's nice to drive slowly for once.
We can enjoy the scenery.
Driving this slowly
they'll suspect us.
A taxi cab is less suspicious
than a piece of junk with fries.
What are they up to?
In Monaco they prefer
caviar over fries.
When they saw a car with Belgian plates,
they followed their client.
I assure you, this isn't
the time for jokes.
I remind you that
I'm up to my neck in trouble.
You got your badge back.
That's what matters.
Really?
You think Gibert will give me my badge,
when he learns he has the wrong guy?
My name is Edward Triboulet
and I work for the Belgian Royal Bank.
And I'm Hercule Poirot.
Alan, which book is it now?
- Number 77, boss.
- 77...
The Seine-et-Marne department.
/A very nice department.
You'll see.
It's worth a visit, isn't it?
Let's try this again.
First and last name!
My name is Edward.
Edward Triboulet.
This is leading nowhere, boss.
And we have few books left.
Don't worry about that.
We have the 22-part encyclopedia.
But...
Since he's Belgian I thought
we could use a different method.
Do you know what I mean?
Good thinking, my little Alan.
Everyone get out.
Please!
Don't leave me!
Please, don't leave me!
Stay!
- So you're Belgian?
- Yes, I'm from Brussels.
Jacques Brel was also Belgian?
Yes, he was a great man
and a hero.
Let's listen to the hero.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Wonderful.
Is this better?
Not that.
No.
Mercy.
No!
Stop it!
- Not that...
- First and last name!
Help!
Save me!
- Damn. He's giving it to him.
- The boss is good at that.
Crap.
We lost those guys
with the fries.
We're not going
to the house?
I have greater ambitions
than that pitiful house.
Call the Columbian.
Are you out of prison?
Yes, I'm calling
to tell you
that thanks to what I'm holding,
you'll take my place.
I'm listening.
BRB. Belgian Royal Bank.
Ring a bell?
Yes.
/The things that were in your box
/are not there anymore.
Hello?
Did you drown in
your pretty pool?
What do you want?
/Not much.
You have 10 minutes to get in your yacht
and sail to your shitty country.
And we're done.
I got us an estate, my dear.
Tell me what you think.
/This is what I love.
I came here a year ago,
for talks with the Columbian.
And I fell madly in
love with this place.
But that bastard
wouldn't sell it to me.
Come, my dear.
I'll take you to paradise.
Look at this.
Isn't this beautiful?
Follow me.
Isn't this paradise?
This stuff is first class.
It's not the flour they sell
on the streets of the capital.
You turned me on
in the bank,
while opening those boxes.
Eugene...
Don't you think
we should slow down?
We have no time to lose.
We have to hurry,
ever faster.
We might be dead in an hour.
We have to make use
of each moment.
- You're right, Eugene.
- Call me Fénimore.
Fénimore, allow me to change clothes,
to look more beautiful.
That's a good idea.
I'll change too.
And we'll eat a candlelight dinner
on the patio overlooking the sea.
Excellent.
See you soon,
Fénimore.
Delta 1, you need to come get me,
things are heating up here.
When will you be here?
Hold on, Delta 2.
Excuse me, sir.
How long will the repair take?
Young man...
2 or 3 days.
Delta 2...
I'm sending reinforcements.
/Emilien, what are you doing?
I'm calling reinforcements.
My little Emilien.
The Belgian admitted everything.
Everything?
/Everything.
/We couldn't stop him.
/And since he
/became so willing,
we attributed him
a few other cases.
He'll get a 1000 years of prison
and won't notice the difference.
Boss, that's not
the right Belgian.
What do you mean?
That's his double,
a look-alike.
The real Belgian left
the bank 5 minutes later.
So where's the real Belgian?
I've followed him to
the Columbian's villa in Cannes.
The Belgian and
the Columbian together.
/Can you imagine
/such a catch?
General alarm!
You look sublime, my dear.
Thank you.
And you look great in white.
You think so?
I like white.
I like white...
But I prefer champagne.
- Did you hear those shots?
- I heard only one.
Trust me. One shot is usually
followed by others.
What are you doing?
I'll take up a forward position
and prepare the terrain for Gibert.
You'd be better off
guarding the rear.
Don't worry. I'll inspect
the topography of the terrain.
So that special forces
can penetrate easily.
Here.
Put this in your ear.
You'll be able to
monitor me from afar.
I have a bad
feeling about this.
To us.
/There's a high fence.
I'm climbing up a post.
There's a tree branch
that reaches into the estate.
/That's strange.
/Such branches are usually sawed.
But this one isn't.
Actually...
It is.
That was a topography class
presented by Emilien.
Let's dance.
Do you realize what
a couple we'll make?
Fire and ice.
My Machiavellism
and your professionalism.
We'll be the most feared
couple of modern times.
I'll be your Clyde
and you'll be my Bonnie.
Shall we dance or kiss?
We can do both.
Otherwise I'll come to believe
you're a double agent.
Haven't you learned
to knock when entering?
I'm sorry, boss.
But look what
fell out of the sky.
Well, well. It's the little
cop from Marseille.
That little cop is an inspector.
I won't let you
get away with this.
Hands in the air!
You're under arrest!
You know, you're really stupid.
Barging in here
with your little gun
and believing you can arrest
the public enemy no. 1.
The killer of the Flanders.
The monster of Belgium.
I warn you.
The house is surrounded.
Really?
Right.
Reinforcements.
An armada.
I can hear the helicopters
circling the house.
- They'll be here any moment.
- Very good.
We'll be waiting for them.
I'll show you what
we'll welcome them with.
But first you'll pay
for disturbing my peace!
Leave him to me.
I've always dreamed
of killing a cop.
And I was off
to a good start.
Fine.
This will be my engagement
gift for you, my rose.
No other gift will
make me happier.
Miss, please listen to me...
- Mrs.
- Mrs., if you prefer.
I've never hit a woman
and I practiced judo for 8 years.
That was a Japanese hold.
Since you insist,
I'll take this seriously.
OK.
But open your eyes.
Don't worry about me.
But I am worried about you.
Do we know each other?
Think harder.
I don't know that hold,
but that must have hurt.
Reinforcements better come quick
or there won't be much left of him.
Do you like my girlfriend?
She's not my type.
And would you like me more
if I were a blonde?
Petra?
I was sure that I know her.
It took you awhile.
Finally.
Gibert and his orchestra.
Boss, should I check if
the front gate isn't open?
You might as well use
the door bell.
The success of an operation hinges
on the element of surprise.
And thanks to this catapult system
we will jump over the fence!
That was the
Swedish corkscrew.
/Go on.
Show him.
Break his neck.
Finish him.
I have a knife
on my right thigh.
- Take me as a hostage.
- What?
Turn around and take me.
In front of everyone?
Take me as a hostage,
you idiot.
He's holding a knife
on my throat.
Where did he get the knife?
I did a whole body
search and found nothing.
If you move,
I'll slit her throat.
Nobody move.
Don't worry, dear.
I'll deal with this.
Stay calm.
And you, little cop...
Tell me what you want,
and you'll have it.
Boss, are you sure this is safe
without a warm-up?
I'm warm as the breeze, Alan.
I took part in a trampoline
competition back in 71.
Exactly.
71 was a long time ago.
Jumping on a trampoline
is like riding a bike.
You never forget it.
Send the first group.
Betrayed by technology...
Alan, go to the truck
and find the problem.
I'm on it, boss.
What's your number, boss?
I have no idea.
I'm in last place.
Probably a burned-out fuse.
Find it.
With his weight, I'm not
surprised it doesn't work.
OVERLOAD
I found the problem, boss.
We have company.
What do we do, boss?
We wage war!
/You want to play?
/You want to catch me?
Then come and get me!
I'm glad I stayed in my cab.
I'm the no. 1 here,
do you hear me?
And not only of Belgium,
but of the whole world!
And some French cops
are not going to scare me!
/Let's go!
Come on!
I'll show you!
Do you know what
this Frenchie says?
He says you're making him mad!
And this little Frenchie...
is going to kick your ass.
It won't take long.
Daniel, help us.
I'm not surprised
he remembers me.
And who's no. 1 now?
This weapon is dangerous.
I'll go get something bigger.
- Is he nuts?
- What's he doing?
Guys, look what I found.
I saw one of these
in a movie.
/Ignition.
This guy should be
locked away.
I'll clean up this house.
It won't take long.
Help...
It looks better in yellow.
My love...
When I think that
I didn't recognize you
and that I almost hit you.
Don't worry.
I would have defended myself.
Where should I drop you off,
before matters get hot?
Listen, buddy.
I won't congratulate you
for that handling.
Neither will I.
And I'm not the only one.
Excuse me, who among you
is the group leader?
Excuse me.
Right.
May I ask what
your rank is?
Commandant.
That's it?
Judging by your look,
I thought you were a General.
Surely someone doesn't like you
and is putting a spanner in the works.
I can take care of that.
I know a few influential people.
I buy weapons for them,
so they owe me a favor, Commandant.
Why not.
Shall we discuss this
in the car?
My pleasure, Commandant.
Load him up!
What are you doing?
Let go of me!
You're making a mistake!
Do you know who I am?
Let go of me!
You're making a mistake!
Young man, your behavior is
an example for others.
Thank you, sir.
But Emilien deserves the merit.
I only drove the taxi cab.
Besides, the meter has been
running since yesterday.
There's something I don't get.
You knew he was going
to rob that bank?
Yes.
There are hundreds of safety boxes
we can't legally open.
So we gave the Belgian the green light
and he opened them for us.
He'll get 200 years of prison
and won't notice the difference.
Exactly.
How did you know
he would escape?
By transferring him to you,
we were 90% sure he'd escape.
Really?
So I had my part in the
success of this operation?
Yes.
You were perfect.
Any news about Gibert?
Even a whole box of sleeping pills
hasn't slowed him down.
We'll show them!
Forward!
Win the match!
The Commissionaire is
full of energy.
We've tried everything
to get him to tire.
We signed him up for the New York marathon,
but even that didn't help.
Shoot!
Go on!
What's he doing?
Is this how he plays?
Shoot!
You're not here to
pretend you're playing.
I'll show you
how to play.
Is this hard to do?
Look.
Look at this ball handling.