Here.
Here?
Yes here you are in your new home.
Brother Hsu lives over there.
It`s very crowded here.
We`ll get there in 10 minutes.
Remember, you`re a stranger here.
Take care of yourself,
and don`t start any trouble.
I know.
You must be thirsty.
Let`s get something to drink.
- Two bowls, please.
- OK.
Come on, let`s go.
Do you have any hot ices?
Hot ice?
Give me some and I`ll pay you double.
She`s pretty.
Come, let`s have a look at you!
Not bad at all!
- Nice complexion. Look!
- Let go!
- Stay out of this!
- Let me go!
Don`t forget your promise!
Don`t be afraid. Keep us company!
Dumplings! Hot dumplings!
Let me try.
Hmm, pretty tasty. Come and get some!
Have some.
Take the basket.
You have to pay!
You can`t eat without paying!
Pay? Pay for what?
What money?
Get out of here.
What happened?
They refused to pay and then hit me!
Why did you bully the kid?
Stay out of it
or you`ll get the same!
It`s Hsu Chien!
- Hsu?
- Oh, yes...
Come on!
Hold it.
Hsu Chien!
Uncle!
When did you arrive?
Just now. I came looking for you.
I got your letter.
This is...
Cheng Chao An.
Come to my place!
Come out everybody...
Uncle...
This is my nephew Chen Chao An.
My name`s Ah San.
I`m Ah Yin.
I`m Ah Wang.
- Ah Pi.
- I`m Ah Chang.
I`m Ah Kun.
Cheng Chao An.
Come in and sit down. Come in.
Take Uncle`s luggage!
It`s been two whole years!
Sit down.
Come on, let`s catch up.
How are things back home?
There`ve been many floods.
Times are bad.
There`s no getting around it.
Have some tea, Uncle.
My! You`ve grown into a pretty girl.
She`s our little sister Chiao Mei.
This is Cheng Chao An.
Have some tea.
Thank you.
How`s old Mr Chang?
He fell ill
and died five months ago.
What about the Chen girl Yu Fang?
Yu Fang?
She wanted to escape the famine,
so she got married and went away.
Old Mr Wang, who used to live here,
left a month ago for home
to find a wife.
- Did you meet him?
- Old Wang?
I didn`t see him.
Who can afford a wife nowadays?
Take the teahouse next door.
They`ve closed for lack of business.
People are heading for the cities.
They can`t stay in the country.
You`ve been away a long time.
Yes.
My letter explained why I came here.
I know.
There was nothing for Chao An to do.
Don`t worry.
I`ve talked to the factory manager.
I`ll take Chao An
to see him tomorrow.
Chiao Mei, go buy some food and wine.
We`re giving Uncle
a proper welcome tonight!
Right!
Thank you.
OK!
Remember, don`t talk too much.
Just answer whatever he asks.
Uncle is coming.
Come!
Come...
Uncle, everything is fine.
- I`m taking him to the manager.
- Thanks!
You folks stay and chat.
Uncle!
Here.
Father says
it`s an important shipment
and must be delivered immediately
Don`t worry it`ll be finished tonight
and delivered tomorrow.
Take care. I`m off.
Don`t work too hard.
Please.
See yourself out, won`t you?
Hsu Chien!
Is this your friend?
Yes, his name`s Cheng Chao An.
This is our factory manager.
Sir...
We need hardworking people.
Start him from tomorrow.
Right!
Come to work tomorrow.
Thank you!
Don`t mention it.
We`ll show you the town afterwards.
That looks like Mrs Ma.
Why are you crying?
Did someone try to bully you?
Tell me who and I`d deal with it!
Where`s your husband?
We`re broke and he`s gambling.
I`ll go in and have a look.
Ma, have you lost everything?
Lend me some money?
Still want to gamble? Look!
Banker wins!
What are you doing?
What a hand!
Loaded dice?
Forget it, nobody forced you
to come here.
Don`t be a sore loser. Come on.
Try to cut down on your gambling.
Here`s $200. Take it as a loan.
But...
I`ve nowhere to spend money.
Pay me back when you can.
Thank you!
It`s cramped and the work is hard,
but the pay isn`t bad.
You can make enough in 5 years
to start a small business back home.
Hold it!
Please step aside.
Troublemakers!
Trying to run?
You`re a pain in the neck.
Only six of you?
Come on, let`s get it on!
Come on!
Get out of here!
You`re pretty good.
I learned some tricks back home.
Mother gave me this
to remind me not to fight.
Rise and shine, time for work!
Get up!
You`re safe with Hsu Chien around,
but he likes to fight bullies.
You might not be able
to control your temper.
Don`t worry,
I won`t fight.
I`ve Mother`s token to remind me.
All right then.
Take care. I`m off.
Goodbye, Uncle!
I`ve been doing all the talking.
Why don`t you say something?
Conversation leads to friendship.
Don`t be shy.
Why don`t you answer?
Don`t you hear me?
I`m talking to you!
Where do you live?
Let`s go on a date.
Let go!
Not until you answer me!
Cheng!
I`m off to work.
Cheng Chao An!
Here to start work?
Report to the foreman first.
Who`s the foreman?
The dark one.
Hurry up, be careful.
The short plump one.
What`s your job?
My name`s Cheng Chao An.
You`re the one Hsu Chien brought.
What took you so long?
All right, get to work.
Give them a hand.
Set it down carefully.
Push this across.
Don`t just stand there!
Get moving!
Do you want the job or not?
What am I supposed to do?
Help them move the ice.
Let me do it!
What is this?
None of your business!
- Damn!
- Sorry!
Stop!
What was that for?
He was careless and broke the ice.
He`s new here.
He can pay for the damage,
why hit him?
Why did you hit him?
Why`d you use violence?
Shut up! Get back to work!
Forget it!
It`s not worth it.
Are you done?
I`m hungry.
My treat.
Let`s go.
Wait, you two.
- What is it?
- The factory manager wants you.
OK.
Time to eat.
Wait, Wang and Chang aren`t back.
Never mind.
I heard the foreman say
the factory manager wanted them.
The manager?
- What for?
- I don`t know.
OK, but leave enough for them.
Pass it over.
Thanks!
Sit down!
OK.
Now, let`s have a serious talk.
Here`s $2,000 for you.
What for?
Listen.
We came so far to work here
to earn more money.
Didn`t you two discover something
in the ice today?
Yes.
It`s heroin.
Heroin?
C`mon! How much
can an ice factory make?
There are more profitable businesses.
Since you know
we`re prepared to cut you in.
We`re in this together now.
When we left home,
Father told us to work hard,
but to stay away from crime.
I`m trying to help you.
The $2,000...
We don`t want it.
I won`t force you,
but please don`t tell anyone.
Don`t worry.
I trust you.
We`re off.
OK.
Goodbye.
Wait until Hsu Chien
hears about this...
Hurry.
Have Wang and Chang arrived?
No.
Get to work.
- Didn`t the manager send for them?
- Yes.
Why didn`t they return last night?
How should I know?
Is the manager in?
Yes.
Sir!
Chang and Wang didn`t return.
Do you know where they are?
Why ask me?
The foreman said you sent for them.
The boss telephoned yesterday
and asked for them.
What for?
I don`t know.
Strange.
I don`t believe it!
You can go
to the boss` place and see.
Old Wang disappeared two months ago.
Wang didn`t disappear.
He went home to find a wife.
All right, get to work.
They might turn up at any time.
Any news?
What did the manager say?
He said the boss sent for them.
If they`re not back soon
I`ll go there after work.
- Alone?
- Why not?
I`ll go, too.
Don`t move!
Step back, just watch me!
Come on.
See? That`s the way to do it.
Nobody can get near you.
Fine.
Remember that move for next time.
Yes.
Father, let me have $2,000.
What, broke again?
I need the money for a reason.
You know you like to have
a new woman every year?
I`ve found one for you.
Really?
Tall, slim pretty and educated.
Not like those dumb chicks.
Where is she?
I`ll get her for you for $2,000.
That`s blackmail.
Let`s have it!
Sir, two workmen are here to see you.
I`ll see them inside.
You take a rest.
I`ll be right back.
This way!
This is the boss.
Sir!
- You go out first.
- Yes.
What is it?
Two of our colleagues
were called here last night.
Yes.
Chang and Wang work hard.
I sent for them to reward them.
I`m also promoting them.
Do you know
they haven`t returned?
Yes, I`ve informed the police.
They`ll be found.
You said that with Old Wang.
It`s been over a month now.
What can I do?
You workers eat drink and gamble -
you do whatever you feel like.
They`ve got legs.
How can I tell them where to go?
They aren`t like that!
You needn`t lose your temper.
You`re not their next of kin.
Be smart!
If you play your cards right.
I`ll see you`re rewarded.
I don`t understand.
I`ll make it clear.
Don`t meddle in my affairs
and I`ll make you rich.
What? So you admit
something happened to them?
I didn`t say that.
Hand them over!
Otherwise I`ll report you!
Say what you like.
You got no evidence.
Don`t think you can bully us!
- Hand over our men today!
- No.
I`ll charge you with murder!
Hsu!
Lao Erh!
It`s 12:30,
time to sleep.
Hurry up and come to bed!
Hurry up!
The lane is deserted.
We`ll wait till tomorrow.
Go.
Don`t cry, Hsu is all right.
Go to bed.
Brother Hsu isn`t back yet.
We`re worrying about it.
Something may have happened.
Chao An, you know the pier?
There`s a shop there
where Hsu often goes to play chess.
Go and see if he`s been there.
Ah San!
Go to the gambling den and watch
for anything suspicious.
- OK.
- Hurry!
I`ll go and poke around,
You go to Ma`s place.
Ask him to help.
OK, I`ll go.
Chiao Mei, stay here.
If he returns, come to the factory.
Has Hsu been here?
No, not for some time.
Did you see Brother Hsu?
Which Brother Hsu?
The one who was in the fight.
Thanks!
Have Hsu and Pi returned yet?
No, everyone`s waiting.
What to do?
Ask the manager to call the boss
and see if there`s any news.
I`ve called the boss.
- What did he say?
- Anything on Brother Hsu?
And the other two who disappeared?
He said Hsu and Pi went to his home,
but they left soon afterwards.
As to the other two,
the boss has informed the police.
They`ll look into the case.
They went to the boss` place.
He must know what happened to them.
Right!
Tell him to hand them over!
That`s right!
You`re being unreasonable.
You people gamble
and womanise all day.
Nobody can tell you what to do.
They may have gone to Bangkok.
No, Hsu doesn`t gamble.
He`s our leader.
He`d tell us if he were going.
You hand him over, or else!
Hand them over!
What`s the use of pressuring me?
How should I know where they went?
We don`t care what you say.
Hand them over or we won`t work.
We`ll strike
until you hand them over.
Quiet, it`s no use shouting!
Get back to work.
We`ll talk it over tomorrow.
No way. Stop, hand them over.
What?
Hurry up!
If Hsu doesn`t come back,
we won`t work.
We`ll strike.
What`s going on?
- Start work.
- All right, you needn`t get violent.
You hit me!
Why did you hit him?
I`ll beat you!
Get me 336.
Boss, we`ve got trouble!
Cheung, don`t just stand there.
Fight!
Where did they come from?
Stop!
It`s all a misunderstanding.
It`s none of your concern.
If you want to fight, fight me!
Chao An is pretty tough.
Come on!
Come, you dare?
Go.
What`s keeping you?
Get out!
Good work!
Chao An, nice moves!
Cheng Chao An.
Come up to my office.
Why did the manager want Chao An?
Will he try something?
If the manager
tries to rough up Chao An
we`ll fight!
Go.
- Shall we go and have a look?
- No. He won`t dare hurt Chao An.
Let`s wait here.
Take a rest.
Come on, let`s take a rest.
What`s going on?
Go take a look.
Right!
Look, what`s on it?
Cheng Chao An...
is promoted to foreman!
Really?
What about Ah Sheng?
He`s demoted to third class!
Now that`s what I call fair play!
Now Chao An is our chief,
he`s our big brother from home.
Yes.
Hey!
You deserved it!
Here comes our big brother!
Big brother...
One, two, three, four...
Brother.
Follow us.
Halt!
- Dismiss...
- At ease
Ah Kun, why are you so happy?
Don`t you know?
Cheng Chao An is now a foreman.
How come?
The manager says he`s able and just.
Able and just?
What happened?
We had a fight with foreman Sheng.
He slapped me and Ah San fought him.
He called over ten men to beat us up.
Cheng Chao An suddenly stepped in.
He`s quick and skilled.
He floored all of them.
The manager promoted him.
- Why did you fight a foreman?
- He tried to make us work.
He hit me and the fight started.
- Why did you refuse to work?
- It was because of Hsu.
We asked for our four men back
and refused to start work otherwise.
What about Hsu?
What fun! Another fight!
There`s still no news of Hsu.
Don`t cry.
I`ll talk to the manager tomorrow.
If he won`t hand them over
I`ll show him no mercy!
- Well?
- He`s reported it to the police.
If they don`t return today
come to the station with me.
All right...
Let`s start work.
Time to eat.
I`m so hungry.
Wait!
Chao An went to the police station
and hasn`t come back.
We should wait for him.
Let`s wait awhile.
Sit down!
The boss said he couldn`t come.
He`s having dinner
with the police chief.
Any news of Hsu?
Don`t worry
the chief is the boss` good friend.
They`ll do everything to find him.
We`ll be notified once he`s found.
- Come, let`s eat
- OK
Manager!
They`re coming! Come in.
Come in and sit down.
Please sit.
Let me introduce you.
This is Wu Man.
This is Sting Hsiang.
This is Rose.
Our foreman, Cheng Chao An.
Good.
I`ll drink to your health.
Right!
Mr Cheng I return your toast!
You`re a good drinker.
Let this dinner
make peace between us.
We`re all colleagues.
You have a bright future, Chao An.
Thank you!
Bottoms up!
Come on, let`s eat!
One, two, three...
Good!
Boards don`t hit back...
Good...
Come...this way.
Still waiting?
Go to bed don`t catch cold.
Ah Kun, I`m afraid.
What for?
Five people who lived here
have disappeared.
Maybe Cheng is also...
Don`t make wild guesses.
He`ll be all right.
I`m worried.
Oh, well...
Stop crying!
I know you like him.
But, really,
we don`t know much about him.
He`s young, don`t worry about him.
We don`t know what he`s up to.
Leaving so early?
Sorry.
Where could Chao An have gone?
I wonder!
He`s coming!
Chao An! Why didn`t you come back
last night?
Where did you go?
We were worried sick!
What did the police say?
The police?
I didn`t go.
Didn`t go? Why not?
- Where did you go, then?
- The manager asked me to dinner.
Dinner?
So you forgot about Hsu?
Don`t forget how you got this job.
- Listen to me
- Go.
- You forgot all about it!
- Wait!
Come on!
What`s the rush?
One dinner and you get
a swollen head.
Just because you know the manager.
Go on! Suck up to him.
I work for my keep.
Yeah.
- Sir!
- Who is it?
Cheng Chao An.
What is it?
There`s no word on Hsu.
The workers are all worried.
I`d like to see the boss.
All right.
I`ll call him
You can go after work.
All right.
Hsiao Chun!
- What is it?
- There`s a man coming to see me.
- We`ll have to put on a show.
- A show?
- Who are you?
- A foreman from the factory.
- What`s your name?
- Cheng Chao An.
You may go in.
Don`t bite!
Come!
Boss!
- Are you foreman Cheng?
- Yes.
Chang called me about your visit.
Come inside.
Sit down!
Be seated.
I know why you came.
Is it about Hsu Chien?
Idiot, don`t be so careless!
Sorry.
I`m very unhappy.
I`ve lost a lot, too.
How so?
I`ve been here so many years.
Many people envy my success.
They`re using this opportunity
to attack me.
You`ll hear a lot of rumours
about me.
Don`t believe them.
I treat the workers as my children.
I advise them to be economical.
We all came from faraway places.
We work hard and should save up.
Listen, I know you`re capable.
Thank you, but about them...
Don`t worry, I`ve told the police.
They`ll find them.
Father!
We looked everywhere, no trace.
Idiot! Fooling about outside all day.
You can`t even do one small errand!
Why are you home so early?
It`s almost dark.
You`ll look again tomorrow.
Don`t come home
if you don`t find them!
I`ll be going.
Fine. Ask them not to worry.
I`ll do everything I can.
OK.
We got away with it for now.
We must take care of the factory.
Nothing must go wrong.
Cheng is not a simple guy.
- Keep a close eye on that fellow.
- Yes.
Father! Come.
I`ve found where the girl is.
She`s a beauty!
I`ll get hold of her tonight!
I`m looking forward to it!
Hi.
Haven`t eaten yet?
Thank you!
What?
The boss kept you for dinner?
No.
What did he say?
That he`d told the police?
And they`ll let us know
if they`re found?
Rubbish!
A foreman eating cold rice?
That`s tough!
Yes, a foreman
isn`t used to such economical living.
Ah Kun, why say that?
Say what?
I don`t like him.
We`d best keep away from him.
It`s no use treating him so well.
We`ll tell him to go
after Hsu returns.
Ah Kun is a good man but impulsive.
Don`t be angry.
I won`t.
They don`t understand me.
In time, they will. Be patient.
I`m going to work.
You better go home.
Mr Cheng.
Where are you going?
Since you`re here, sit down.
Come.
Sit.
What`s making you unhappy?
Some workers disappeared.
There`s been no news of them.
You must be careful.
Your boss is tricky.
Think about it:
how much can an ice factory make?
Do you know how he made his fortune?
How?
There`s something in the ice.
- How do you know?
- I was their maid.
Look!
He did this to me.
I knew you`d come here.
What have you been up to?
So what?
Now you know the truth.
You think we`ll let you leave alive?
Get him!
Go!
Chiao Mei!
Chiao Mei. Chiao Mei!
Mother gave me a jade talisman
and told me not
to get into trouble,
but now all this...
What am I to do?
If anything should happen to me,
what should she do?
She`s over 70.
Should I just return home?
Those people have been so nice to me
since I came here.
Each of them was a nice person.
They took me into their family.
Now they`ve died so horribly.
I`ll settle the score!
I must take revenge!
The young master didn`t return.
Go and find him, then call me.
Yes.
It`s none of your business.
Go away!
Just keep away. Go on.
It`s not your fight.
Come out!
The boss and the foreman
are fighting.
Run!
Why should you save me?
Never mind, run!
Over there!
Brother Cheng!