(DEVICE CHIMING)
(CHIMING CONTINUES)
WOMAN: No!
(MOANING)
(PANTING)
MAN: Come on!
Open the door!
Let us in!
(HAL COUGHING)
Get up.
Give me another day.
One more day.
One more day isn't going to make any difference.
Please!
Just give me some more meds!
MASON: You had your meds, Hal.
You're getting worse.
Put me back
in quarantine.
Just till tomorrow.
I'll get better.
(COUGHING)
You're not gonna
get better, Hal.
(PANTING)
I'll take the walk.
It's my choice.
Not today.
You can't do this.
It's my choice!
It's my job.
Make your peace.
SAM: Mason!
He tested positive, Sam.
He has a choice.
Let him walk.
He'll just come back.
They always do.
MASON: We can't let him infect the rest of the colony.
Mason.
This isn't right.
This is survival!
(GUN SHOT)
It's nothing personal.
His time was up.
That's all, Sam.
SAM: In this place,
we live in fear of the common cold.
The last flu wiped out 20 people in less than a week.
So, now we've got rules.
You get sick,
you go into quarantine.
If you don't get better,
you've got a choice.
A bullet or a long
walk in the snow.
At least that's how
it's supposed to work.
After the snow started,
the lucky ones found places like this.
A place where life could exist underneath the ice.
When I got here,
we were hundreds living on top of each other.
Everyone just thankful they'd
made it out of the cities alive.
When the food ran out,
most of the people in the world died,
but not the people
in this place
where seeds were stored underground,
kept safe for a better day.
Some people,
they talk about a place,
a paradise with blue skis and
birds as far as you can see.
Those are just stories.
Everybody knows that.
So, we hold on.
Hibernating, like the last dark age.
But it's not the cold
we need to worry about.
It's each other.
Briggs.
What's up, Sam?
I need to talk to you.
Look, don't start. Hal knew the rules.
His blood test was positive and
he wasn't getting any better.
We don't have the meds to
keep fighting this flu anymore.
And we can't risk
another outbreak.
But why do we leave it to the one
guy who loves to pull the trigger?
Look, this colony started
with over 400 people.
And I have done
too much surface time
with a shotgun in one hand
and a shovel in the other.
I've had my fill of blood in the snow.
You understand?
Now, Mason is just doing
what has to be done.
Yeah, but he's not doing it right.
He didn't give him a choice.
Hal wanted to walk,
not take a bullet.
Well, right now,
we have a bigger issue.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Calling Colony Five,
this is Colony Seven. Over.
Colony Five, this is Colony Seven.
Come on, guys. Over.
What's up?
SOS loop from Colony Five.
SOS?
SOS.
You sure it's Five?
It's got to be.
It's their code.
Marcus always checks in.
When was the last time
you had contact with him?
About seven days.
They said they were gonna be down for radio repairs.
And they've been dead air
until about an hour ago.
(SIGHS)
BRIGGS: Okay.
General meeting in the main hall in 30 minutes.
Okay. For who?
For everyone.
I want you to go
see Viktor, Sam.
He's having a problem
with the livestock.
(SIGHS)
Right.
All colonists report to the main hall in 30 minutes.
I repeat. All colonists please report
to the main hall in 30 minutes.
Thank you.
You gonna try and save these rabbits, too?
Another stillborn litter.
Hmm. They need
protein, just like us.
How many are left?
Twelve in all.
But this here
is the only female.
(SIGHS) You know you're screwed
when even the rabbits won't fuck.
SAM: Let me see what
I can get from Kai.
Mason.
What's going on?
What are you
talking about?
What happened
up there with Hal?
Sam come
running to you?
What gives you the right to take away the man's choice?
His choice was made
when he tested positive.
That is not
how we do things.
We give people a choice.
It's theirs to make
regardless of the outcome.
Till they come back.
Till the food runs out.
It's not a problem
until it's a problem.
You gave me
this job to do.
Now let me do it.
Mason.
You know...
You'd think for someone you served with,
you'd give them
a little more respect.
(SLOW JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
Almost had you.
No, you didn't.
What do you need?
Soy pellets.
The rabbits
aren't doing so hot.
Where's this?
Uh, somewhere in Spain,
I think.
You never give up,
do you?
No.
No one thought Briggs could fix that
link to that old satellite, but he did.
So?
So, all that weather modification tech is out there.
It's just buried
under the ice.
Well, that's where it should stay.
Buried.
Sam, somewhere, someone
is working on a fix.
And when there's a thaw,
I'm gonna find it.
Take me with you?
There's not a lot of choice down here.
You'll have to do.
Hal's gone.
Well, we live and
die by our rules, Sam.
We should get
to the meeting.
(JAZZ MUSIC PLAYING)
(TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
Breathe slowly.
You can't cough. Okay?
Hey, I fixed that crack
in the north vent for ya.
Thanks, Sam.
That's great.
Dex?
You all right?
(STUTTERS)
Yeah. I'm good.
You're not
looking so hot.
No, no. It's good.
I'm fine.
Maybe you should go back to your room, huh?
BRIGGS: All right.
Listen up.
A few hours ago,
we received a distress signal from Colony Five.
(ALL MURMURING)
BRIGGS: They haven't
responded to any radio calls.
Given that Colony Three
shuttered last year,
I think they're
worth checking up on.
Cooper, I want you to see what kind
of radio parts we have to spare.
Okay.
We've got nothing
to spare.
(ALL MURMURING)
Mason, we're sending a team and I'm leading it.
I need two volunteers.
What if they've been
hit with a new flu?
We'll take
all precautions.
We'll go into quarantine
when we get back.
That's what
it's there for.
Quarantine's a fucking joke.
We're barely surviving here.
We need to take care
of our own, Briggs.
KAI: We made a pact
with Colony Five
and we need to
look after each other.
Yes, we did. And we're going.
End of discussion.
Dexter.
I need a skilled set
of hands with me out there.
I'll go.
Dex needs to stay in case
the turbines break down.
BRIGGS: Thank you, Sam.
BRIGGS: Anyone else?
(SOFTLY)
Look at me.
Anyone?
Take me.
VIKTOR: Graydon, no.
Please don't go.
Now, I know I haven't logged a lot of surface time,
but I can do it.
Thank you, Graydon.
You'll do well.
All right.
Kai will be in charge until I'm back.
(ALL MURMURING)
BRIGGS: Rations are
still in effect,
although I've authorized regular
portions for the children.
Work details continue as usual.
We'll be in touch by radio.
(SNEEZES)
(ALL MURMURING)
MAN 1: She's sick.
Come on.
(ELENA COUGHING)
MAN 2: Get her out of here.
(ELENA CONTINUES COUGHING)
BRIGGS: Quarantine until
further notice.
It's okay, sweetie,
don't worry. It's okay.
You really should have said
something earlier, Dex.
They're done, Briggs.
They're sick.
And we follow procedure.
They just put
the whole colony at risk.
We need to give them
the test right now.
We're gonna wait
until I get back
and see if they've
done any better.
Until then,
Kai's in charge.
You really think she can make the tough calls?
That's really not your
decision to make, is it?
Are we clear?
Crystal.
Mom!
(PANTING)
Oh, my...
KAI: You okay?
That fuckin' dream.
It wasn't your fault.
(SNIFFLES)
Would you come
back to bed?
SAM: The world froze
a long time ago.
So long ago that I can't
remember the warmth of the sun.
I heard the stories
growing up.
How the planet grew hotter
as our fuel was burned.
How we made towers
to work the weather.
But the truth is,
one day it started to sn.
And it never stopped.
GRAYDON: Hey!
Is that what I think it is?
SAM: Weather
modification.
GRAYDON: Never seen one
this close before.
You think it still works?
It did its damage
a long time ago.
We got to cross
this thing?
Unless you wanna
go down there.
We make our way
around to the left!
Yeah.
Whoa!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Watch your step.
Guys!
GRAYDON: What is that?
What the hell's
he doing out here?
We got to keep moving.
God, how cool would it be to
fly one of these things, huh?
GRAYDON: Hey, Briggs,
what was this used for?
Medevac.
It used to airlift
people to safety.
I wish
I could've seen that.
Briggs to Colony Seven.
Cooper, come in.
(RADIO STATIC)
COOPER: Colony Seven here.
Good to hear your voice, Briggs.
Copy that.
Good to hear yours.
We're camped out at the helicopter for the night,
so we should reach Colony Five by noon tomorrow.
What about you?
Got any news?
Dex and Elena are
still in quarantine.
And they're both
getting worse.
They have all the symptoms.
Mason's pushing for the te.
BRIGGS: Mason knows that's
against protocol.
That's why I left
Kai in charge.
Yeah, he's not
too happy about that.
I know.
There's gonna be some changes made when I get back.
Cooper, you have my authority to use force if necessary.
Mason is not to take them for
a walk without my consent.
I understand.
You guys be safe out there, okay?
Over and out.
(EXHALES)
(CHUCKLES)
Give you some time
alone with that, or...
Maybe I do.
(CHUCKLES)
You know, Sam,
we're not too far from where I found you.
Yeah.
What were you
doin' out here?
It was a long
time ago.
Go on, tell him.
We got all night.
Uh...
My family, um,
we were holed up about 40 miles north of here,
in a mine.
Uh, just us and some mining families,
a couple old-timers.
We got supplies in there,
shoveled the entrance out every day.
Eventually, the supplies ran out.
Food ran out.
So, after we ate
the horses and the dogs,
my dad and the other men went
into the city to go get some help,
but they never
came back, so...
And people started dying.
And the way things were going,
I needed to get them out of there,
my mother and my sister.
I figured we had
a better chance out there.
(SIGHS)
Anyway, uh,
the storm came up
and we got separated,
and I never saw them again.
I'd be dead too
if Briggs hadn't found me.
You were a boy, Sam.
You did the best you could.
Yeah.
(PANTING)
Hey, what is this?
GRAYDON: You guys, that's blood!
We shouldn't be going in there!
We came here to help.
That's what we're gonna do.
You smell that?
Smoke.
(COUGHS)
You know,
maybe one of us should just stay topside, huh?
We stick together.
You're coming.
Right.
Shit.
(METAL RATTLING)
SAM: How many were
there at last count?
Fifty.
Not so much of a welcoming committee this time.
What the fuck
happened here?
Hey.
You remember
how to use this?
Yeah.
You sure?
Let's move,
okay?
This way.
They're all dead.
We don't know
that for sure.
(DISTANT GROANING)
(GROANING CONTINUES)
What the fuck
was that?
(BANGING)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
SAM: Someone's alive.
(GASPING)
It's coming from over here.
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
In here.
This door has taken
a lot of punishment.
Shit.
Hey, come on.
Let's get the hell out of here, huh?
Hey, find a spine, boy.
(LOCK CLICKING)
(LOCK OPENS)
BRIGGS: You got it?
(METAL DOOR CREAKING)
What, is he dead?
(SCREAMS)
Calm down!
Calm down! Calm down!
(WHIMPERING)
Don't! Don't!
BRIGGS: Easy. Easy.
MAN: Please don't.
We're here to help.
(STUTTERS) Please.
Don't, don't.
(SAM SHUSHES)
It's okay.
Calm down.
Are you hurt?
Are they gone?
SAM: Who?
The door!
Lock the door.
Get the door!
He needs water.
No, easy. Go easy.
Easy, easy.
What's your name?
Leland.
Have you got any food?
I'm so hungry.
Yeah. I've got
something here.
How long have you
been locked in here?
I don't know. Days.
Is there anyone else?
Is anyone else alive?
Define alive.
(CHUCKLES)
LELAND: That's good.
We're from Colony Seven.
We got your distress signal.
We came to help.
SAM: Leland.
What happened?
We fixed the steel grid
to a new antenna.
When it finally worked,
its reach was amazing.
We received
a partial transmission.
(MACHINE WHIRRING)
You're gonna love this.
We have modid
a weather tor
and successfully reverd
the cooling process.
Clouds have receded to a three-mile
radius and are expanding.
We have
thawed permafrost.
We have melted pack ice.
We now have soil. We have su.
We now have
the conditions to grow.
If anyone out there can hear this,
I repeat our location.
Our location,
latitude 47 degrees north, two...
SAM: Is that it?
Is that all there is?
We triangulated
the transmission,
sent a team
to find the source.
But they never found it.
But somebody found them.
And followed them
right back here.
Who?
(SOBBING)
Leland,
who followed you?
Leland, look at me. Over here.
Show me on this map.
Where did that transmission come from?
Point. We're right here.
North, on this line.
And 25 degrees is here.
South, there.
Listen to me.
We're gonna take you back
to Colony Seven with us.
No! Please, sir.
I'm gonna stay here.
Right here
behind this door.
What if they're still here?
SAM: There's no one here.
We only knew that you were
here because of the knocking.
Yeah,
but I didn't knock.
They're still here!
They're still here.
Radio Colony Seven,
you tell them we're on our way back.
It's time for us to pack up and go.
Take anything we can carry.
Okay. It's okay.
It's all right.
(RADIO STATIC)
GRAYDON: Calling
Colony Seven.
Colony Seven,
can you read me? Over.
(RADIO STATIC)
GRAYDON: Colony Seven,
come in.
This is Graydon calling in.
Can you read me? Over.
GRAYDON: It's not working.
All right.
We're too deep underground.
We'll radio ahead when we get back topside.
You, Leland,
you're coming with us.
You don't understand!
It's safe behind this door!
There's 50 colonists,
you're the only one behind it.
(STUTTERS) I couldn't open it.
I just couldn't.
(DISTANT SHRIEKING)
(BANGING)
(SHRIEKING)
Get him on his feet.
Please. GRAYDON: Come on.
Let's go.
(BANGING)
(SHRIEKING)
What the fuck
was that?
(GRUNTS)
Shit.
He locked himself
back inside.
Come on.
(BANGING)
(SHRIEKING)
SAM: Graydon,
let's go!
(METAL CREAKING)
(SHRIEKING)
(BANGING)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
(CLATTERING)
GRAYDON: (WHISPERS)
We shouldn't be here.
This has nothing
to do with us.
(WHISPERS) Turn that
light out.
(BANGING CONTINUES)
My God.
(GRUNTS)
(GRAYDON GAGGING)
(SNIFFING)
(GRUNTS)
(SCREAMS)
(SNARLS)
(GASPING)
We got to go, Sam.
(SCREAMS)
Now!
(ALL SHRIEKING)
(PANTING)
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Come on!
Fuck.
(SCREAMS)
(STRAINING)
Come on, Sam.
Come on.
Damn. Graydon.
(FERAL MAN SHRIEKING)
He's gone. We better move.
Go on. Go!
(BOTH PANTING)
Go! Go!
Come on!
(FERAL MAN SCREAMING)
Fuck! I'm out!
Come on! Go! Go!
(ALL GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(EXHALES)
(YELLS)
Briggs!
Give me your hand!
There's still people
alive down there.
We can't help them, Sam.
We can't help them.
Briggs, don't you think
we should keep moving?
No! The temperature's dropping too fast.
We won't make it!
Come on.
Briggs?
Yeah?
Those people...
How could they...
I don't know, Sam.
When people are desperate,
they'll do
horrible things
to survive.
I told you I was an army captain
during the relief effort, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, well, I never
told you what I saw...
When...
When people
lose control like that.
When we go feral...
There's nothing
human left in us at all.
We might as well just
be a pack of wild dogs.
See, during
the relief effort,
we had, uh, 20,000 people
corralled in a stadium.
Food got handed out.
And the sick got treated.
But when the food
ran out...
The people with guns started taking
things from the people without guns.
And then,
when there was
nothing left to take,
they took people
upstairs and decided
who would live
and who would die.
It was...
It was the hunger.
People couldn't take it.
It just drove them mad.
We tried to stop it.
We really did, but...
We couldn't.
Me and Mason,
he was my squad back then. We left.
Tried to find a place
where we could make sure
that nothing like
that would happen.
You did.
Maybe.
When we get back,
we'll patch into the satellite.
Take a look.
If they've got the sun,
we've got the seeds.
SAM: No.
No, no, no!
How many?
Twenty!
Maybe more!
It's hard to tell!
Oh, fuck.
SAM: Our footprints!
Shit!
We're going to lead them right back to the colony.
We'll stop them at the bridge.
Come on.
Come on!
Briggs,
what are you doing?
Stopping 'em!
Block the wind!
BRIGGS: No!
What?
The fuse is out!
Fuck!
I'm going to go
and relight it.
What the fuck are you doing?
Briggs.
Listen to me.
Listen to me. We're fine.
I light it. I come back.
We go home.
It's too late!
(GROANS)
Briggs!
Come on! Get it done!
Come on. Come on!
(SHRIEKING)
Come on, you dogs!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(GUN COCKS)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(ELENA SOBBING)
Please!
Just give her the goddamn test!
No more tests.
No! Oh, no. No.
(DEXTER SOBBING)
KAI: Mason!
What?
Things are going to
change around here.
Are you fucking crazy?
MASON: No.
I'm seeing things clearly.
You know
the test is bullshit.
The delay just
puts us all at risk.
Drop your gun!
SAM: Help!
Help!
Sam?
Sam!
Fuck!
Fuck.
Sam!
Sam? Sam?
Come on. Come on.
Hey. You're okay.
You're safe.
SAM: How long
have I been out?
A few hours.
Sam?
Where is he?
Where's my boy?
I tried.
No.
No. (SOBBING)
We lost Briggs, too.
What are you doing?
There's been
a change in command.
We need
to take precautions.
Briggs' rules
don't work anymore.
We need to be
tougher to survive.
From now on,
rations will be cut in half.
Anyone showing signs of sickness
will be tested immediately.
If you don't pull your weight,
you don't eat.
SAM: Mason.
Where's Kai?
VIKTOR: What happened, Sam?
What happened out there?
They killed them.
Everybody at
Colony Five is dead.
Briggs' come off
the bridge.
Stopped them.
Stopped who?
These people...
They slaughtered everybody
for food.
Do you understand?
And they're coming here.
And unless
we get out of here,
they will kill us.
And where are
we going to go?
There's a thaw.
I know where it is. Okay?
I can get us out of here.
I can show you where it is.
He's in shock.
I can lead you to where it is.
Give him a sedative.
Let me show you
where it is!
No one is
going anywhere.
MASON: Viktor,
let's go topside.
You need to listen to me!
Viktor!
Are you with me?
Mason,
you need to listen to me.
Mason.
Mason!
(WHISPERS) Sam.
No. Nothing.
You know, Sam's a lot of things,
but he's not a liar.
If he says something's coming for us,
we better be ready for 'em.
Keep an eye
on the monitors.
(GROANS)
Sam!
Kai, are you okay?
Oh, my God!
Did he hit you? It's fine.
Did he hit you?
I'm fine!
Are you okay?
Give me a sec.
Come here.
What happened
out there?
I got to show
you something.
Bring up two.
Nothing.
This is bullshit.
REYNOLDS: Mason!
Sam got away.
And how did
he do that?
Rowan.
That little bastard.
Come on!
Let's go!
Forty-seven, 55.
KAI: What are
you looking for?
A thaw. Come on.
Sam.
Sam, there is nothing there.
I have already looked.
No, it's here.
I know it's here.
Sam.
Come on.
There it is.
Holy shit.
Look.
KAI: Oh, my God!
That's got to be like
eight miles of blue sky.
Let's go. Come on.
KAI: They took the weapons,
the maps, everything.
Shit.
They didn't take these.
What are you doing,
Sam?
Sam, what are
you doing?
We need to tell the others and we
need to get the hell out of here.
Let's go. Come on.
Come on. Come on,
come on. Come on.
(GUNS COCKING)
Going somewhere?
Yeah.
We're getting everyone
together and we're leaving.
No one's leaving.
Go fuck yourself, Mason. Hey.
If we don't
leave right now...
Briggs is gone.
I'm running things now.
When everyone's
dead, huh?
And you're king of the fucking castle,
then what?
(GUN COCKS)
I'll still be
running things.
(THUD)
Oh, shit.
We're too late.
(BANGING)
Oh, my God,
my God, it's Dex.
You believe me now?
Anyone who can
fire a weapon,
get 'em to the entrance.
We'll hold them there.
And get everybody
else to the vault!
Let's go. Come on!
(BANGING CONTINUES)
(CLATTERING)
Come on, buddy. Let's go.
It's going to be all right.
Come on, guys!
COOPER: Let's go,
let's go!
(BANGING)
(LOUD BANGING)
(BANGING CONTINUES)
You led them
straight to us.
They're breaking
the hinges.
MASON: Fuck.
(METAL CLANGING)
(THUDDING)
MASON: Behind us!
(METAL CREAKING)
(CREAKING CONTINUES)
(SNARLS)
(GRUNTS)
(WHIMPERING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(WHISPERS) They're
already inside.
In the vents.
(MAN GRUNTING)
Mason!
(SNARLING)
MASON: Here they come!
SAM: Viktor!
MASON: Fall back!
No!
No more running!
(SNARLS)
(COUGHS)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Everybody
in the main hall!
(SNARLS)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
I'm out.
We couldn't make it to the vault.
What the hell is
going on out there?
They're inside.
They're everywhere.
(FERAL PEOPLE SHRIEKING)
There's no time!
No! Don't!
No! No!
No!
Let us in!
What are you doing?
Saving our lives.
No!
Let us in!
(BANGING ON DOOR)
Mason!
(SNARLS)
(FERAL MAN SCREAMS)
Doors.
(FERAL PEOPLE GRUNTING)
(BANGING ON DOOR)
You locked us
out of here.
Yes.
You fuckin'
piece of shit!
The doors aren't
going to hold.
(BANGING CONTINUES)
We need to get
the fuck out of here!
This leads
to the surface!
You'll freeze,
if those things don't find you first.
(FERAL PEOPLE GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
It's our only chance!
No, we stay.
Hold them off here.
Come on. Let's go!
We stay!
Just leave him.
Come on. Come on. Let's go.
Let's go. Come on. Come on.
Let's go.
Come on. Let's go.
Nothing personal.
You're going
to need every bullet.
(FERAL PEOPLE SNARLING)
Come and get it,
motherfucker.
(ALL GRUNTING)
(SNARLING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
What do you want?
More.
(PANTING)
(SNARLS)
Kai, look.
(COUGHING)
Sam. Sam!
What do we do now?
We walk.
With these...
At least
we have a chance.
Now come on.
Come on.
Let's go.
SAM: We used to live and
die by the rules we made.
But our rules,
like everything else we buil,
are breaking down.
There's only one rule
left now, anyway.
One rule above all.
Survive.
Come on.