"In the fourth month
of the Year of the Snake...
...a child shall be chosen...
...to meld the two halves of the sacred
medallion together as one.
And at his touch...
...the reborn shall be endowed...
...with extraordinary
supernatural powers."
You've done well.
As agreed.
Pitiful.
Many people would pay more...
...to be the keeper of such a book.
The only pitiful thing in this room...
...is your life.
Okay.
Actually...
...you have been
quite generous, yeah?
It's nobody you know, okay?
It's fish. See?
Happy now?
Cheers.
In English, please.
Stop wasting time, Giscard.
Pull around the back.
Inspector.
Positive ID on Giscard.
Kwun Yum Temple.
- And he's got company.
- Copy that.
Hold your position.
Pai Gow.
It's our guy.
All right, men.
- And Snakehead?
- Snakehead was not confirmed.
We should wait.
My intelligence says he's here...
...and Giscard is his number one.
We're going in.
I did not agree to this.
- We are supposed to be partners.
- This is an Interpol operation.
The Hong Kong
Police Department's...
...involvement is strictly
a babysitting service.
You don't like it,
take it up with your boss.
It's true.
Tell him we found it and we're in.
Full force, men.
Razor-sharp and all that.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What are you doing?
That's a temple. It's a holy place.
You cannot take guns in there.
Oh, right. Well, don't worry, Eddie,
because you see these guns?
They're holey guns.
Because they make
a rather big holey.
Holey. Do you get it? Holey.
All right.
Move out, men!
Move. Left, right, left, right.
Go, go, go.
Come on, keep up.
Inter...
Freeze!
Damn.
Keep up. Keep up. Keep up.
Interpol! Freeze!
The medallion.
You cannot come in he...
You will give me what I want.
What's that?
Check it out.
- Go that way.
- Got it.
Peter?
Eddie.
Interpol! Fre...
What the he...?
You okay?
This way, men.
Follow me. Down here.
It's the cops!
We've gotta go now!
I need more time.
- We haven't finished yet.
- It's too late.
- We'll try again later!
- Hong Kong Police!
Jai!
Hang on!
Eddie!
Snakehead! Upstairs!
Right!
Damn!
Four months' work!
What did he want in the temple?
He's a smuggler, Eddie. I don't know.
Perhaps he's found a buyer for
black-market Buddhas. The point is...
...you let him get away.
Watson.
I also saw his face.
Interpol's all over me,
and I can't stay here any longer.
You must bring me the boy in Dublin.
I trust you will make my continued...
Just bring me the boy.
Good job.
Okay, this is what I want.
All right, notify the team...
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
- Keep the change.
- Thank you.
Got it. The Sea Horizon.
- Where are you keeping the boy?
- In a safe place.
Very good. Take me to him.
Up there. Okay.
- Where is he?
- Over here.
Wait. Put him down. Put him down!
Untie him. Don't hurt him.
Careful. Be careful.
Inspector, what's going on?
Snakehead's men.
Yes. Hello.
It's the boy.
Good morning, sir.
Show me the boy.
Oh. Of course.
That's him.
Treat him like a prince.
No problem, sir. We are ready to go.
Attention! This is the marine police.
You are ordered to stand down!
Prepare to be boarded.
Attention!
- Showtime!
- This is the marine police.
You are ordered to stand down!
Prepare to be boarded!
This is the marine police.
Look out!
Let's go!
Quickly! Go! Go!
Are you ready?
I'll cover you.
The boy!
Wave bye-bye!
We've interrogated the prisoner.
The boy's been taken to Snakehead
in Ireland. Repeat, Ireland.
Time for vacation.
Call me in Ireland.
Bring me back a snake head.
- Can I help you, sir?
- Yes.
I'm Inspector Eddie Yang
from Hong Kong.
Yes. You have an appointment to the
commander.
Nicole.
Inspector Eddie Yang.
I knew there couldn't be two of you.
Nice.
You clean up well.
Thank you.
Come on.
It's been a long time.
Three months.
I was assigned overseas and...
Oh, yeah.
You were gonna call me.
- I didn't know you'd been assigned...
- To Ireland?
- Yes.
- Well, you missed a few beats, Eddie.
I am now the official liaison...
...between the local Interpol office and
Southeast Asian security forces.
Maybe if you stayed in touch
like you promised...
Nicole.
I should have called.
I'm sorry.
That's worth something.
Not a lot, but something.
Commander?
Inspector Yang is here to see you.
Yes.
I'm Hammerstock-Smythe.
Delighted to meet you, inspector.
Likewise, commander.
Commander, I was just...
What the bloody hell is he doing here?
Hello, Watson.
You're not telling me he'll be working
on this case?
Watson, we need all the help
we can get.
Yes.
You remember this boy?
Yes, I saw him in the temple. So?
- Who's he?
- One moment.
Yes, I recognize him.
This is Lester Wong.
Snakehead's number two man.
That's privileged information,
eyes-only, need-to-know and all that.
- I need to find him, Watson.
- Yes, well, I'm sorry, my friend...
...but that's classified.
We've received a tip-off...
...that Snakehead does have a new
shipment arriving tomorrow in Ireland.
- Maybe the boy will come with it.
- Where?
We don't know.
Go back East, Eddie.
Stick to what you know.
- Watson!
- What?! I mean... Sorry. What?
Any more nonsense like this...
...and you will be off the case, and the
inspector here will be in charge of it.
Satisfied?
You've only been here five minutes.
Watson!
You are in my filing cabinet.
Yes.
I was just getting these.
I think we're in trouble.
Yes, I think everything is in order.
What do you think?
Is it? Well, yes.
- Well, let me have it checked out.
- Yes, sir.
Watson, wait.
- Let's put Hong Kong behind us.
- I'm sorry, is somebody talking to me?
We were partners.
We were good together.
- You need me.
- Really? What do you want me to do?
Just welcome you back
with open arms?
We had a good thing going,
and you left!
Watson.
It just wasn't for me anymore.
I thought you understood.
Oh, I understand.
I understand that you didn't like me
always being on top.
Okay, you can be on top.
Whatever you want.
Let's just do it together. Okay?
No, but you have fun doing it
by yourself. All right?
You think because of the way...
Thank you.
Think we...
Well, we're not.
I'm a man!
Yes. No, there's nothing wrong
when two people love...
...one another.
It's a good thing. I...
That's your fault, that is.
Now, I'm gonna go home
and cook dinner for my wife!
So on a scale of one to 10...
...how did that go?
About a seven.
Below zero.
I think I know just what you need.
Dinner.
Dinner?
Yes, dinner.
We need Watson
for this investigation, Eddie.
He's stubborn, but if we can
catch him off guard...
...maybe loosen him up,
I think we can work it out.
I'll just be myself.
One more thing.
Watson's family...
...they don't know
that he's an Interpol agent.
- What do they think he is?
- A librarian.
- A librarian?
- Yes.
Hi.
- Nice apron.
- Thanks.
Look, you can't just
turn up and barge in.
Darling, I was wondering
if you saw my spatula.
- Charlotte, hello.
- Hello.
- Please. Please come in. Please.
- Thank you.
Arthur, you didn't tell me we were
having guests.
- Please, welcome.
- Didn't know myself.
- We're librarians.
- Librarian?
Charlotte, this is Eddie Yang
from Hong Kong.
Are you staying for dinner?
- Yes.
- No. Absolutely not.
Thank you.
See what you've done to my chops?
What's that called?
Now?
"Lamb à la victim."
Right. Well, yes. Come on.
You know the score.
You eat, you work.
What brings you to Dublin?
- Right. I was looking for...
- Looking for a rare book.
Yes, actually, we were wondering...
...if Arthur would help us find this
rare book.
Oh, well, unfortunately, I'm looking for
that book myself, so...
Maybe we could find it together.
But I'm head librarian, though, right?
Right.
You need help checking in?
I already checked in.
Okay.
Here. Directions.
Where to meet Watson tomorrow.
He told me to give them to you.
Why can't he just pick me up?
It's Watson.
"Privileged information, eyes-only,
need-to-know and all that." So...
Okay.
Nicole.
Yeah?
Tonight was fun.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
- Is this place far away or close by?
- Far away.
- Hop in the car and I'll take you.
- Thank you.
What are you doing?
Move.
Move! Move! Get out of the way!
- Oh, my!
- Sorry.
Did you see that?
What are you doing?
Open this door!
Hey, what's going on?
Now, mind yourself.
Come on.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
I haven't even done any...
Say it!
Talk! Where's the boy?
Let me out of here
or I'll kick your ass.
Speak English! You are hard
to understand!
- You ever hear of police brutality?
- Sounds like fun.
One more chance
until you kick the can.
You mean, "kick the bucket."
- What?
- You mean, "kick the bucket."
If you say so.
What kind of music you like?
Okay, okay, okay.
Just let me out and we can talk
about this, all right?
He's coming on a boat. I don't know
what time. A freighter.
- He'll be coming into the docks.
- A boat!
Look, just let me out of here!
Do you know how long I've been
waiting here for you?
What's the matter? You sound like an
obscene phone call.
You're out of shape.
You should keep fit.
Right, but let's not waste any more
time, shall we?
Pier 5. Well, that must be the ship,
if Giscard's telling the truth.
Let's hope so.
It's all we've got to go on.
Now, these are very
dangerous people, all right?
Do you have a gun?
No, are you going to give me one?
No, get your own bloody gun.
And remember,
I'm head librarian, all right?
- All right?
- Yes.
Right.
Here's the plan.
I'll circle around to the left.
You circle ar...
You circle arou...
And I'll just bloody talk to myself.
Then you go straight through.
Go around.
Welcome, Chosen One.
Excuse me.
You're under arrest.
Come on! He went this way!
Have you seen him?
There.
Watson, come on!
Where's the boy?
- We couldn't find him.
- Find him!
Shoot him.
You okay?
Go, go, go, go! Get the boy!
Interpol! Freeze!
- Hello?
- Hello, it's me.
Me, who?
Eddie! Where are you?
I'm trapped inside the container
with the boy.
Stay right where you are.
I'm on my way.
What color is it?
I don't know.
Watson.
- Eddie's in a container.
- Which one?
I have absolutely no idea.
There! There!
It's Eddie.
Eddie.
Eddie, it's Nicole. Just hang on.
Watson, get over here.
I need your help!
Nicole!
Oh, my God!
Don't be afraid.
I'm not afraid.
We'll be all right.
We got control of the container. We
believe that there's bodies inside.
I need an oxygen tank
and a stretcher. Now!
Eddie, please don't leave me, Eddie.
Eddie, come back to me.
Eddie, please.
- You all right?
- Please.
Eddie, come back.
Nicole...
...he's gone.
Come on.
God bless, Eddie.
God bless.
Nicole.
- We've got work to do.
- You sure?
I'm sure.
Let's go.
I'm sorry...
...I wasn't there when you needed me
most, my friend.
That was nice.
Thank you. I...
- What's wrong?
- Who are you?
What's the matter?
Who are you? What...?
What are we doing here?
Where's my clothes?
Watson.
- Watson!
- Get away from me!
It must be fake.
Well, it certainly looks like you.
My nose isn't that big.
It's really me.
Are you sure?
Don't you think I recognize
my own thing?
It's cold in here.
Let me take a look.
- What's happening to me?
- All right.
Let's just...
...stay calm.
I'm sure there's a perfectly rational
explanation for this. Think back.
You were on the boat,
in the container.
What happened?
Lights everywhere.
- The boy.
- The boy?
- Medallion.
- Yes.
I have it. It was in your pocket.
What's this?
Wow.