The city of Townsville...
...is in some serious...
...serious, serious trouble!
Day after day...
...crime, lawlessness
and evil are running rampant.
Its citizens have lost all hope.
They are utterly helpless
and in desperate need of a true hero.
But who?
Is there no one who can help
this forsaken town...
...and make it a better place?
Fear not, fair viewers, for there
is a man, a man of science...
...a forward-thinking man,
who looks back to a sweeter time...
...when there was spice to life,
and everything was...nice.
I must profess, sir...
...this man holds the ingredients
to Townsville's salvation!
This man, known simply as:
The Professor.
Hi!
What's your name?
My name is Professor.
Professor Utonium. Hello!
Hello, Professor Utonium.
It's very nice to meet you.
It's very nice to meet you too.
-What are your names?
-You made us, so shouldn't you name us?
Okay. This is so cool!
Well, now, let's see.
Because of your directness and opening
right up to me, I think I'll call you...
...Blossom.
Well, aren't you all cute and bubbly!
That's it! You'll be my little...
...Bubbles.
So we have Blossom, Bubbles and...
...Buttercup. Because...
...it also begins with a B.
And together you are
three perfect little g--
Gifts! Birthday! It's your birthday!
I should get gifts!
Wow! I wanted to make some kids
I could teach right from wrong...
...and in turn, maybe they'd do good
for this town, and now I can!
All I gotta do is be a good parent.
Note to self : Good parents
don't leave kids alone.
Sugar, spice and everything nice.
Who knew that's what girls
were made of !
I can't believe I made perfect girls!
Three normal little gi--
You should be careful when coming
down the steps! You could get hurt.
Hey, are these for us?
Thanks, Professor!
-Hey, thanks!
-Yes, Professor! Thank you.
This is the best gift ever...
...Dad.
Yes, it is.
Okay, girls, now watch me.
I think you missed a spot.
I'll go wash up,
then we'll bring in the furniture.
Girls, wait! You should let me--
Help?
This looks pretty good.
What do you think?
-I think it's a little dark.
-I like it dark.
-Some windows might be nice.
-Yeah! I could see some windows.
Right about here.
I'll call a contractor tomor--
Or that works too.
Who's hungry?
-Ready?
-Ready!
Go!
Okay, girls. Time for--
Bed.
-Wake up, girls! Time for school.
-What's school?
This is school.
I'm your teacher, Ms. Keane...
...and this is where
kids come to learn. See?
You wanna play?
Do you think they'll be okay?
I'm new at this parenting thing,
and I wanted to meet you...
...because they're really special.
I mean, really special...
...and I just want to make sure they'll
be okay. Do you think they'll be okay?
They'll be just fine, Professor.
We'll see you at noon.
Okay. Bye, girls. Bye. Bye.
Bye-bye. Bye. Bye.
Okay, class. Take your seats.
-Can Blossom sit with us?
-Can we sit with Bubbles?
Can Buttercup sit here?
The girls can sit right in the middle,
so they'll be next to everyone.
Now, let's begin!
Hello, Professor.
Right on time.
Your girls are outside
with the others.
Oh, no! Look at this mess.
I knew the girls would
be a handful, but I'm so sorry.
What, this?
This is what happens
when you put 20 kids in one room.
Your girls were perfect.
Perfect, normal,
well-behaved little girls.
-Nothing out of the ordinary?
-No. Like what?
-That was sweet!
-What's the point of this game, anyway?
Tag! You're it!
Everyone's running from her
like she's been infected!
-Maybe she's a freak.
-Yeah, and they hate her!
-You're it!
-Tag! You're it!
Oh, no! I've been affected!
-All right, what's going on here?
-I've been affected!
You're not infected, it's just a game.
-It is?
-Yeah.
-A game? Neat!
-Yeah, how do we play?
Okay, look, it's very simple.
Bubbles, tag me.
Come on, it's okay.
All right, now I'm it.
And all you gots to do to play
is tag someone else, and they're it.
By the way, you're it!
Awesome, I'm it! What do I do?
What do I do?
Just tag someone else,
and they're it!
Time to put it into overdrive,
Bubbles!
Tag! You're it!
I'm gonna tag you guys now.
You missed us!
-Tag! You're it!
-No! No, I'm not!
Tag! You're it!
Tag!
Missed me!
No, you're it!
Tag!
I'm it?
Tag! Got you!
-Got you!
-Missed me!
Girls, no! Wait!
Can't catch me!
Oh, no!
Subway, huh?
Tag. You're it.
There they--
Here she comes!
Suckers.
Tag. You're it.
You know, I've got a nice car.
-You're it.
-No, you're it!
Hey!
She'll never find us up here.
Do you hear something?
Run!
Tag! You're both it!
Hey!
-We can't both be it.
-Why not?
-Tag.
-What? I can't be it twice!
-Why not?
-Okay then.
Tag. Now you guys are it.
-Tag.
-Tags.
-Hey, no tag backs! Tag!
-Tag!
-You're it!
Oh, boy.
Oh, boy. Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
Oh, boy.
Mayor, the town is being destroyed
by three girls with freakish powers.
This is a very serious situation.
What action should we take?
-Tag, tag!
-Tag, tag, tag!
Don't worry. We have the situation
under control.
-Oh, boy.
-I know, sir.
-You tell them, Mayor.
Townsville will not stand for this.
Mayor? Hello?
City being destroyed?
-Where are you going?
-Oh, boy.
Mayor, where are you going?
We're in a serious pickle.
Exactly.
Girls, no!
Hello.
The usual, Cucor.
I have a fine vintage for you here.
Picked fresh today.
Oh, boy!
Girls, girls, are you okay?
Tag! You're it, Professor!
Okay, girls. Girls, it's almost
bedtime, okay? Girls?
Come on, Professor, you're it.
You gotta catch us.
Yes, I suppose I do, don't I?
Got you, you little bunny.
Help! I got caughted!
Blossom, watch out!
You're the sole survivor!
No way, Professor!
You can't catch me.
Yes, I can because the game's over,
and it's your bedtime.
Now come up here so we can catch you.
Well now, three little girls had
a very busy day today, didn't they?
Yeah, it was fun.
We met lots of kids.
-And we learned things.
-And we played tag!
I'm glad you had so much fun
because tomorrow will be busy too.
Put your nighties on and get in bed.
We need to talk about something.
-Okay, everybody in?
-Yep, what's up, Daddy-o?
Well, it's your super powers.
I'm not sure how to say this...
...but I don't think you should
use them in public anymore.
Why?
Well, your powers
are very special and unique...
...and although we have a lot of fun
doing things in the house...
...out in Townsville, people don't
understand how special you girls are.
And unfortunately, people
often get scared or angry...
...when they don't understand
something special or unique.
That's silly.
I think so too, but nonetheless, take
it easy with the powers tomorrow.
Just give Townsville a little time
to understand your specialness, okay?
-Okay.
-Yeah.
-People are nice. Things will be fine.
So I'll be waiting here to pick you up
when school gets out, okay?
Okay, but don't worry, Professor.
Things are gonna be fine.
Girls, we didn't know
if you'd be joining us today.
Take your seats.
I'm sorry to say there won't be
any recess for a while...
...due to all the reconstruction.
Secondly, I'm afraid we won't have
any lights or water for a while.
And a broken refrigerator
means snack-time is out...
...so let's try to ignore
all the workmen and noise and such...
...and get right to work, shall we?
Girls, can you recite
the alphabet for us?
Girls? ABCs?
A, B, C, D.... E!
Hey, galldang it!
You done darn broke my board.
Flamdanggling consarglers.
F....
Almost time to pick up the girls.
Better motor.
That's him, boys!
He's in cahoots
with the evil pickle-cart killers...
...cucumber crushers,
vinegar varlets, dill-stroyers!
Why, it's not kosher! It's--
Let it go, Mayor. Let it go.
-Are these your babies?
-Yes, but they were just playing.
They're really very good little girls.
And I need to pick them up from school.
I understand, sir...
...but we want you to come downtown
with us to ask you a few questions.
You guys, my kids.
I really ought to pick them up.
I can't just leave them there...
...alone.
He's not coming. He hates us.
He totally hates us.
No, he probably just got held up,
or maybe the car broke...
...or maybe he forgot...
...or maybe he hates us.
Come on, let's try
and find our way home.
We're not supposed to use our powers.
Come on, girls.
The cause?
Three super powered little girls.
Should manufacturing
super powered children be illegal?
A great travesty has befallen
our beloved city.
I was easing the seat back when this
atomic punk flies in with no warning.
The devastation? Devastating.
It should be illegal.
Used to be a time when
you could buy an honest pickle.
They were lighting up the sky.
Estimated dollars in damages?
A whopping 25 million.
I'm offended just looking at them.
The kind that you can only find
at a pickle cart.
Now Jamie's crying.
-Well, it seems that--
-Hatred is running rampant for--
-Those mutant, bug-eyed--
-Pickle-cart killing--
Freaks. Back to you, Linda.
They are little freaks, aren't they?
With more on this subject is--
Get them out. We don't need them.
We don't need them.
We interrupt this program
for a news flash.
Arrested in connection
with the tag incident...
...was the scientist responsible for
creating the girls, Professor Utonium.
Upon incarceration,
the Professor made this statement:
Please, just let me go.
My girls, they need me.
They don't know I'm in jail.
What if they try
to go home themselves?
They can't find their way
if they don't fly.
Please, they're only little girls
who are probably cold, scared...
...and maybe even lost.
Well, it's official.
I have no idea where we are.
Well, I can't say
it's been the best day.
But it probably couldn't
get much worse.
Hey, it's okay. Maybe there's
a box we can get in around back.
Come on.
See, there's a whole bunch of boxes.
What's the matter?
Did somebody get lost?
Wow, thanks!
Hey, wait! Come back.
Hey, guys, over here.
-Hi. What's your name? I'm Blossom.
-Buttercup.
And I'm Bubbles.
Go away, please. Do not look at me.
We just wanted to thank you
for saving us from those gangsters.
That was amazing
with the trashcan lid.
It was all: swoosh, bang,
splash, bam, boom.
Yeah, you rock.
No, please. I dare not listen...
...for I have been lashed
by harsh tongues for too long.
Alas, my little ones, I do not rock.
For I, Jojo, am a monster.
You're not a monster.
Monsters are evil.
Anybody who would save us
like you did is so not evil.
You're no monster, mister.
You're just really dirty.
Please. You're just trying
to make me feel better.
But my pain is not for you
to understand.
Besides, how could you?
For you are pure and innocent
and, most certainly, loved.
How could you know what it is
to be cast out...
...into a world
that only offers misery?
How could you know what it's like
for people to fear and despise you...
...for the very things
that make you special...
...because you don't fit in,
because you are...
...a freak?!
Because...
...we're freaks too.
-What amazing powers!
-No, they're terrible.
-I bet everyone hates them.
-Yeah.
-And they hate you too.
-Yes.
I am in the same boat.
This brain is full of brilliant ideas.
But will anyone listen? No.
Nothing in this gray matters.
So, what's the point?
Jojo, don't be sad.
Our dad says people get angry
when they don't understand...
...something special or unique.
If you just give people time, they'll
start to understand your specialness.
Yeah. You just gotta believe
in yourself.
If I construct my Help-the-town-
and-make-it-a-better-place machine...
...people will come to understand
my specialness?
I'll do it,
but I'll need your help.
Jump in, take this device
into the volcano.
We need to harness the energy
of the Earth's core for power.
-What are you talking about?
-The plan.
-What plan?
-Our plan.
-To do what?
-To make the town better.
-What?
-You know.
We will build the Help-the-town-
and-make-it-a-better-place machine.
Everyone will see our special
abilities are good. They will love us.
Remember? It was your idea.
Oh, yeah. But use our powers?
-Yes.
-No way.
-Come on.
-No.
We're never using our powers again.
Girls, don't be sad.
Your powers are great.
You just gotta believe in yourself.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
-We did good?
-You did very good. Very good indeed.
-Now what do we do?
-We construct the superstructure.
Look. Can't you see
our plan is working?
Our work is proceeding as planned.
At last, our lives will be better.
At last, we will be accepted.
At last, our greatest work is comple--
-Oops.
-What's wrong?
Well...
...there is one last teeny-tiny,
itsy-bitsy thing we still need.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
-We did good?
-You did very good. Very good indeed.
Now what do we do?
Well, because you've done so good...
...I've got a special surprise.
-Worthless.
-Lame.
-Stupid.
-Okay.
-Better.
-Almost.
Awesome!
Come, girls, our work is fin--
I mean, time to go.
But, Jojo....
-We haven't seen the gazelles.
-Or the crocodiles.
Or the unicorns. Just one unic--
Excuse me, ma'am.
I think you dropped this.
I thought the zoo kept
all the animals in cages.
Yeah, well, you're welcome, lady.
Don't listen, Bubbles.
That's right, Bubbles, do not listen.
All of you, deafen yourselves
to their heartless words.
They do not know it is their saviors
they are speaking to.
They are unaware your actions will
have helped change their world forever.
Because we have helped the town
and made it a better place.
-You think they'll be surprised?
-Oh, yeah.
Will they still be mad at us
for playing tag?
No, they'll have forgotten
all about that.
Will they love us?
Yes.
-Really?
-Would I lie to you?
-I'm so excited!
-We'll show them!
Hey, where's--?
Professor!
Girls, thank goodness you're okay.
I'm so sorry.
I'm a terrible, terrible parent.
You must hate me for not picking you
up from school, but it's not my fault.
It's this town. They've gone crazy.
It's like they've never seen kids
playing before.
I knew your powers would take some
getting used to. But jail? Lawsuits?
Angry mobs? What's next?
Don't worry, Professor. Things are
gonna get better. We promise.
-Today's the day.
-Today's the day!
Today's the day!
-Today's--
-The day.
-What to wear?
That's nice.
Professor, wake up! Wake up.
-Wake--
-Up. Wake up, my brothers.
-Wake up and seize the--
-Day!
-The day?
-Yeah, the day when we--
Show Townsville just what
our powers can really do.
What?
We're gonna show Townsville
just what our powers can really do.
-We did something really good.
-That's gonna really--
Help!
Well, we met this guy.
With powers like us.
Who was also hated by everybody.
But he had this great idea.
To help the town.
And make it a better place.
-That way the town would accept us.
-We did something to help.
So we used all our powers.
And abilities.
And his ideas.
-To help everybody.
-City of Townsville...
-It's gonna be so cool.
-...I'd like to take this moment...
-You're gonna be so proud.
-...to thank the little people...
Everyone's gonna love us.
...who helped to make this day
a smashing success.
We did really goo--
Blossom, Bubbles and Buttercup,
I couldn't have done it without you.
-It's their fault!
-I knew they were no good!
What happened?
This isn't making the town
a better place.
Yes, it is, for me. The hobo
formerly known as ''Jojo'' is no more.
From this day forward,
I shall be known as:
Mojo Jojo!
For too long, apes and monkeys
have been under the thumb of man.
Well, the time has come
to oppose that thumb...
...and take hold
of what is rightfully ours:
The world!
Professor, we didn't want this.
-Liars.
-Fibbers.
You've doomed us all.
Please, Professor.
Please believe us.
I don't know who to believe.
I thought you were good.
No!
Yeah! All right!
I rock!
I rock so hard.
For I, Mojo Jojo, have succeeded...
...in my first, greatest
and most brilliant plan ever.
And I, Mojo Jojo, shall be...
...king of the planet of the apes!
You shall be king? Preposterous.
What? How dare you.
For it is I who is the one
most suited to be ruler.
Those are my clothes.
I, Ojo Tango, shall be simian supreme.
No Ojo. Mojo.
As I unleash the offensive omnipotence
of the oppressive Orango-tank.
-Hold on.
-Oh, no!
-I shall get a grip on the situation.
-You better not.
As I, Rocko Socko,
seize control and rule.
-Wait!
-I, Baboon Kaboom...
...with my Baboom-bot,
will be the bomb.
And if you don't like it...
...you can sniff my Baboom-bot bombs.
That's classy.
Gangway! For we, the Gogo Po-Trol...
...form a chain of command
that will take hold of your world.
I, Hota Wata, am boiling mad,
for you are all wet behind the ears.
So I shall unleash a scalding torrent
to drown you out, for I don't give a--
Watch your mouth.
I, Cha-Ching Cha-Ching,
symbolize chaotic calamity.
We, the Doot Da Doot Da Doo Doos,
shall rain on your parade because...
...we're the spit.
My name is Hacha Chacha
And here is my schpiel
A diabolical plan with lots of appeal
Spreading out bananas far and wide
And fixing up the folks
For a slippery slide
Pretty catchy.
I, Blah-Blah-Blah-Blah, shall create
a sauce of chaos and stir up trouble...
...with a destructive force
known as the tormato.
-Tormato?
-Tormato.
-I, Killa Drilla.
-I, Bonzo Bango.
-I, Rolo Ovo.
-I, Cruncha Muncha.
-I, Wacko Smacko.
-I, Pappy Whappy.
No!
Do not continue with your ramblings.
Mine are the ramblings to be obeyed.
I am the king, supreme leader
and dictator.
Your plans are my plans because you
made plans and my plan was to make you.
I plan to rule the planet,
not to have my plans plan to stop me.
I am your creator, I am your king.
I am Mojo Jojo. Obey me!
That jerk, that big, fat, dumb jerk.
He duped us.
He planned it all along,
and we fell for it.
And now, everybody hates us even more.
What are you doing?
What does it look like I'm doing?
I'm building a house
because now we have to live here.
-Live here?
-Yeah, don't you see?
This can be the bedroom,
and this is my bed.
That can be your bed over there.
I don't wanna sleep on a rock!
Maybe if someone hadn't pushed
Bubbles into the school....
Look, she speaks.
Maybe if somebody hadn't insisted
on walking home...
...so we could run
into the biggest liar in the universe!
We weren't allowed to use our powers,
and you know it!
Look, it's Miss Goody-Goody.
We weren't gonna get people
to stop hating us by breaking rules.
Yeah. And using our super powers...
...to make a Help-the-town-and-
make-it-a-better-place machine...
...was following rules?!
-I didn't see you putting up a fight.
-Well, you're gonna now.
If it weren't for you,
we wouldn't be in this stupid mess.
You stupid!
I'm not fighting with you, Buttercup.
Because you know I'll kick your butt.
No, because I know--
Never mind.
I'm not fighting with you,
and I'm not talking to you ever!
Well, prepare yourself
for a long silence, girl...
...because we're gonna spend the rest
of our lives here, thanks to you.
At least I got me a bed.
Blossom? Buttercup?
Do you hear that?
No!
Blossom, what should we do?
Miss Goody-Goody'll say we should take
responsibility for our mistakes...
-...and go help everybody.
-It sounds like they're hurting.
Who cares?
-What do we do?
-Nothing.
-Girls!
-Professor!
Professor! Professor! Professor!
Help!
Bubbles, wait!
-Good job, but we've gotta save--
-The baby!
Holy....
-Hey, what about--?
-The dog!
-You'll be safe now.
-Here you go, miss.
-Thank you.
-Come on, Bubbles, let's--
Save those people.
Wait! This isn't my baby.
Good dog.
Can we find the Professor now, please?
Oh, man!
Now stay!
Doggone it!
Okay. You should be safe here.
This is hopeless!
I know. There's too many monkeys.
What can we do?
Get your hands off him,
you darn dirty ape!
I didn't mean it!
It was an accident!
He wouldn't let go!
And the dog.
That stupid dog,
and then the monkeys, and he--
I couldn't-- He couldn't--
Oh, man!
Buttercup!
You're a genius!
-I am?
-She is?
Yeah. The one way to stop the monkeys,
save the town and find the Professor...
...is to use our powers to--
Better yet, watch!
-Wow!
-That was amaz-- Hey!
Gross! Cut it out.
Come on, girls. Let's put an end
to this gorilla warfare.
Good one, Bubbles.
-Girls--
-Shut up! I was afraid of this.
They've returned and found out
what their powers can really do.
Come. You will make
a good ''Power-proof'' vest.
-None of those monkeys had Professor!
-Where could he be?
Take a good guess!
Come on, girls! We've got
one last monkey to get off our backs!
Not so fast...
...Mojo Jojo!
Look at the little heroes
here to save their daddy!
No, girls! Save yourselves!
-Sorry, Professor!
-We can take this chump chimp down!
Nothing he can do can stop us!
That's better.
It's good you little freaks
know when you're beaten.
Now if you'll excuse me, I, Mojo Jojo,
have a town to take over!
I have a world to rule!
I have to seize control of an area...
...and force its inhabitants
to follow my way of thinking!
Even if it means...
...taking extreme measures!
-You wouldn't!
-I would!
Professor!
Now I am more Mojo than before!
Now, as I was saying before
I was so rudely interrupted...
...I, Mojo Jojo, have succeeded...
...in my first, greatest
and most brilliant plan ever!
And I, Mojo Jojo...
...shall be king!
Girls, thank goodness you're okay.
Now let's get out of this town!
-It's no use.
-We already tried running away.
We have to fix the problem
we helped start.
You said to give everyone time
to understand our specialness.
Well, now it's time for everyone
to understand. Especially Mojo!
Surrender now,
and we'll go easy on you!
Down here!
Oh, my! You're actually
trying to stop me?
That's so cute!
-Try, nothing!
-We will stop you!
Who are you calling ''cute''?
Okay, let's play!
Buttercup!
-Good job, girls!
-That more Mojo is no more!
Girls!
Somebody's mad.
Look out!
Oh, no, look!
Mojo's got Blossom pinned down!
I have an idea. Come on!
-Do you think he's finished?
-No, but you are!
Fools! You dare to challenge me?
Attempt to defeat me?
Try to destroy me?!
I, who saved you from certain death?
After all I've done for you,
you betray me?
And why? For them?
The ones who hated you....
Have forsaken you?
Can't you see? None of them
will ever understand you as I can.
For we are kindred spirits, whose
powers spring from the same source.
So, girls, do not make me destroy you.
For we are smarter, we are stronger!
We are invincible!
We have the power!
We are superior to them!
And we shall rule!
All we have to do is work together.
Girls, join me.
No!
We'd never join you,
and it's because we are stronger.
-Because we are invincible.
-Because we have the power!
We have to protect them from you!
-It's you who has to be feared.
-Because you are a monster!
You are evil!
And you are...
...it!
Curses!
Girls, you were right!
We should stop Mojo, and I know how!
I whipped up an antidote to Chemical X!
It'll do away with his powers!
I'm so sorry for doubting you. You are
good little girls, and I love you!
We love you too!
-And we're really sorry.
-We messed up really bad.
-But we're ready, Professor.
-Ready?
To take the Antidote X
to get rid of our powers.
If it wasn't for them,
none of this would have happened.
And maybe everyone would like us more
if we were just normal little girls.
No!
Don't do that...
...because that was pretty cool,
with the....
Girls, I think what the Mayor
is trying to say is...
...we're sorry, and thank you.
Yes, that was super, just super!
-Amazing!
-Fantastic!
-Wonderful!
-Stupendous!
You rock!
Thank you.
That was awesome!
You were all flying and running!
And then, laser eyes!
Then, bam!
And then-- And then, bam,
you punched that guy! Remember?
Yeah, that was great.
You know, this town stinks.
And I was wondering if,
maybe sometime...
...we could, like, call you
to save the day or whatever.
Can we, Professor?
Well, I don't know....
Okay, but only if
it's before your bedtime.
Help!
Sugar, spice and everything nice.
These were the ingredients chosen
to create the perfect little girl.
But Professor Utonium accidentally
added an extra ingredient to the mix:
Chemical X.
Thus Blossom, Bubbles
and Buttercup were born!
Using their ultra super powers,
they've dedicated their lives...
...to fighting crime
and the forces of evil.
And so for the very first time,
the day is saved, thanks to:
The Powerpuff Girls!
Hey, that's a good name for them.
Powerpuff Girls, yeah!
I like that. Wonder if they will.
I'll run it by them.
Powerpuff Girls!