(PANTING)
(EXHALES)
(RUSTLING)
MAN: Help me.
(GASPS)
Somebody there?
I'm hurt.
Is somebody there?
Please.
I'm bleeding.
Help me.
Drop your weapon.
You drop yours first.
Drop it!
Okay.
Your turn.
Let me see your other hand.
If I move this hand, I'm afraid my stomach will fall out.
I need to see your other hand.
(CASSIE PANTING)
What's in your hand?
Nothing.
Drop your weapon.
What's in your hand?
(BULLET SHELLS CLATTERING)
Oh. (BREATH TREMBLING)
(GASPING)
CASSIE:&lt;i&gt; I miss the Cassie I was.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Ooh, I want the time of my life... ?&lt;/i&gt;
Hey.
&lt;i&gt; A totally normal&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; high school girl.&lt;/i&gt;
Hey! How you doing?
Hi! Good.
Cheers.
Thank you. Cheers.
&lt;i&gt; I wonder what that Cassie&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; would think of me now.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; The Cassie who kills.&lt;/i&gt;
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
(BOYS SHOUTING AND WHOOPING)
You know,he was supposedto be here.
Who?
Oh.
Why are the hot ones always so unreliable?
What would I   even say to him?
I don't know him,   and he doesn't even know me.
You're a girl. He's a boy.
Your parts go together.
Don't.
Oh, God.
Okay, Liz.
What?
I'm gonna see you Monday.
Oh.
I gotta go home.
Skedaddle.
Okay.
Honey, love you.
I love you.
Bye.
Text me when you're home.
Okay.
&lt;i&gt; (SUMMER BREAKING&lt;/i&gt; PLAYING QUIETLY)
&lt;i&gt; ? And they're all&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; gonna fall from the sky... ?&lt;/i&gt;
Hey.
(CHUCKLES)   Nice phone case.
What? You have something against pink?
No, no. I totally like it.
I'm just kidding. (LAUGHS)
Uh, this is actually my sister's phone.
I dropped her off at a sleepover, and she took mine by mistake.
Mine's much cooler.
It's Spider-Man.
(LAUGHS)
Polka dots.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Ah, that's her.
Hey.
Uh... Yeah, yeah, I have it.
No, I haven't looked at your text messages.
(SIGHS)
"Nice phone case"?
Right.
MAN: (ON TV)   &lt;i&gt; I'm Captain Lochner.&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; This is Sergeant Nicolai.&lt;/i&gt;
WOMAN: &lt;i&gt; Hello.&lt;/i&gt;
MAN 2: &lt;i&gt; How do you do?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I'm sorry.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; No more coffee.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Miss Gray,&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; do you know this gentleman?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Sing me a song.
A song?
Okay, close your eyes.
&lt;i&gt; ? Bones sinking like stones&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? All that we fought for&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; I didn't know it then,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; but that was the last&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; normal day of my life.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? All of us are done for ?&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE:  &lt;i&gt; When you're in high school,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; just about&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; everything feels like&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; the end of the world.&lt;/i&gt;
Can you believewhat happened?
No.
&lt;i&gt; An early curfew, a final exam...&lt;/i&gt;
Hey, Ben!
Stop it.
&lt;i&gt; Soccer practice.&lt;/i&gt;
Sullivan. What are we doing out here?
Why not just tell herwhere you're gonna kick it?
Come on, let's go.
Hey, check it out.   Look at this.   It's so freaky.
Watch.
I can't see anything.
COACH: Oh, my God, Altschuler.
That's it. You're done. Off the field.
No. But, look, it's really weird.
Off! Goodbye. &lt;i&gt; Adios.&lt;/i&gt;
What's going on?
MAN: Panthers, let's go!   Hustle up!
GIRL: Give me your phone.   Give me your phone.
GIRL 2: Mine doesn't work!
It totally just stopped.
All right, Perkins.
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; Turns out,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; what we thought was&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; the end of the world&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; wasn't.&lt;/i&gt;
What, did someone famous   die or something?
&lt;i&gt; It appears to be metallic&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; and of a considerable size.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Across the world,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; social media has been&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; awash with panic and speculation&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; as these images&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; spread like wildfire.&lt;/i&gt;
MAN: (ON TV)  &lt;i&gt; The president&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; has authorized NASA&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; to attempt communication&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; with the object&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; that is now&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; circling our planet&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; and is currently over the United States, moving west over Ohio.&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: Oh, my God.It's right over us.
I wanna see!
Hey.
No, Sam. Wait.
Sam, wait!
MAN 1: You can see it!
MAN 2: Come here!
MAN 3: Look up there, hon.
WOMAN: Wait, what is that?
MAN 3: I have no idea.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; There were no messages from our galactic party crashers&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; during the first 10 days.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But pretty soon, they had a name.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; We called them "the Others."&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: The Wilsons  are leaving, too?
They say they don't feel safe so close to the city.
(BELL RINGS)
Okay.
Is this everyone?
(CELL PHONE VIBRATING)
Well, okay.
Everybody look at   the equation on the board.
Who can give me  the derivative of X?
Anybody?
Anyone?
What...
MS. PAULSON: I'm sure this is just a power outage.
GIRL: My phone's not working.
(CRASHING)
BOY: What's going on?
GIRL 2: Over here.
MS. PAULSON: What on Earth?
My goodness. What's going on?
BOY: Look at that!
Back up! Back up!
(GASPING)
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; The Others hit us&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; with an electromagnetic pulse&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; that killed all the power on the planet.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; No more engines.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; No more electricity.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; No more running water.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; No more everything&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; we took for granted.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; That was the last time&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; I saw Ben Parish.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I guess he's dead now.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Like everyone else&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; in that room.&lt;/i&gt;
Here, Sam. Grab me another, okay? Thank you.
&lt;i&gt; That was the 1st Wave.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; At the time, we thought that was it.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Then the 2nd Wave hit.&lt;/i&gt;
(RUMBLING)
Come on, Sam. It's an earthquake!
Cassie!
Watch out! (SCREAMS)
Come on!
Go! Go! It's okay!
Cassie!
It's okay. It's okay.
(GROANS)
Just keep yourhead down, okay?
SAM: What's that noise?
Sam, run!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Go!
Cassie!
Go on!
(YELLS)
SAM: Cassie! Hurry!
CASSIE: I'm okay. Just climb!
Go, Sam! Go!
Cassie!
Come here.   Hold on to me.
Cassie! (SOBS)
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; In Ohio, we only had the lake to worry about.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But by the ocean,&lt;/i&gt;
(SIGHS)
&lt;i&gt; I can only imagine.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; Every coastal city,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; every island,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; gone.&lt;/i&gt;
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; There are&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; over 300 billion&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; birds in the world.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; That's 75 birds&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; for every person.&lt;/i&gt;
(CROWS CAWING)
&lt;i&gt; Mom said&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; the avian flu was already&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; one of the world's&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; deadliest viruses.&lt;/i&gt;
(CAWING CONTINUES)
&lt;i&gt; In the 3rd Wave, the Others modified it.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Made it unstoppable.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And the birds spread it&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; across the planet.&lt;/i&gt;
MAN: Line A.  Line A is for those
who have already been assessed.
If you'rewaiting to be assessed,then proceed to Line B.
WOMAN: No pedal pulse, no brachial, nothing.
Sit down, sir.  Thank you.
(COUGHING)
Just head  straight on back.
PATIENT:I ain't happy over here.
I feel fine!
I should be on the areathat isn't quarantined!
Hey, Liz!
Hey.
Your mom said you were here.
Cassie! Cassie.
Mom?
What are you...
She's quarantined.
It's okay.   I didn't even touch her.
It is not okay. You can't be here.
I'm sorry.
Sweetheart, I need you to go home and look after Sammy, okay?
But, Mom, I wanna help you here.
I know. Can you get her out of here now?
I wanna help.
Mom.
No, it's okay. Just go.
Miss, you gotta leave. Let's go.
WOMAN: Quarantine six.
MAN 2: In six.
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; Some people&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; were immune to the virus.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And a few people got sick&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; and somehow recovered.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But most people didn't.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Hey.
You can't wear those shoes.
Why don't they just get it over with?
What do they want?
I think a better question is, "What do they need?"
They've been very careful so far
not to damage it  any more than  absolutely necessary.
Damage what?
(SIGHS)
Earth.
I think that's why they're here, Cassie.
They need the Earth.
But not us.
No, not us.
Ready to walk  for a while, Sammy?
Yeah.
Okay.
(SIGHS)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: Dad, how far is it   to the refugee camp?
Just a few miles.We should bethere by nightfall.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Dad, look.  Is this it?
Yeah, buddy.   I think so.
Hey. Welcome.
Thanks. Hi.
Name's Hutchfield.
Hi. See ya.
Let me show you around.
Latrines are   off to the left.
Farm is out that way.
OLIVER: You got fresh water?
Yeah. Not too  bad, huh?
OLIVER: How many people are there here?
I don't know howmany we got now.
305, somethinglike that.
Dining hall over here.
When's the last time   you had a hot meal?
WOMAN: Good.  Well, maybe you can  walk me through it.
Here we draw a purple hat.
WOMAN 2: Can we get some water over here?
Whoa, Dad.
This is a Colt .45.
(GUN CLICKS)
Okay?
This button  changes out the clip.
That's loaded.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
All right? Safety on.
Safety off.
Listen to me.
You're gonna carry thiswith you at all times,
you're not gonna tell  anybody you have it,
and you're only gonna use it   if it's life or death.
You got it?
I thought we were safe here.
(SIGHS)
Pumpkin, there's  nothing safe anymore.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
CHILD 1: Here, you wanna put it in the basket?
CHILD 2: Okay.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
Here. Take this one.
Okay.
GIRL: You gotta  get the weeds, guys.
(FAINT RUMBLING)
What was that?
Sam, come here.
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
What is that?
I don't know.  Come on.
GIRL 2: Asher, come on!
GIRL 3: Mommy!
Dad!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
What is that?
You see Dad?
Dad!
Cassie?
Hey, Dad.
Hey.
What's going on?
HUTCHFIELD: All right, just take it easy.
I thought  the cars didn't work.
&lt;i&gt; Ladies and gentlemen, I am Colonel Vosch of the United States Army.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; My men and I are from&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; the Wright-Patterson&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; Air Force Base.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; We're here to help.&lt;/i&gt;
(CHEERING)
It's about time.
&lt;i&gt; Let's get you people&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; out of here.&lt;/i&gt;
MAN 1: Heck, yeah!
MAN 2: Thank you.
Yes!
U.S.A.!
We should be ready to go at a moment's notice, all right?
Stay with your sister, Sam.
Come on.
You can goright on the bus.
SOLDIER: (OVER MICROPHONE) &lt;i&gt; Adults,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; please move to&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; the mess hall&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; for a briefing.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Children, please move&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; to the buses for transport.&lt;/i&gt;
MAN 3: We're right behind you. Be good!
&lt;i&gt; Adults, please move to&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; the mess hall for a briefing.&lt;/i&gt;
Do you think they have electricity if the trucks are working?
I don't know. Why, you still have a phone?
(CHUCKLES) Yeah.
You have a charger?
Of course, yeah.
Whoa, whoa, sir, sir.
Yeah?
My orders are to  get just the kids  onto the bus.
Well, those might  be your orders,  but they're my kids.
Yeah.
So we're gonna   stay together.
We'll wait for another bus.
It's okay, Private.
I got this.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Look, you're   welcome to keep 'em here   with you if you want,
but if they were my kids,  I'd get 'em on that bus.
Why?
We have reason to believethere's an imminentthreat to this location.
We're trying to get  everyone to safety  as quickly as we can,
and this is the only working transpo we've got,
so we're taking shifts based on need.
Kids first,then we come backfor the rest of ya.
Well, how safe is it at Wright-Patterson?
Safest placethere is right now.
And the buses will just come right back?
Dad, no.
Drop 'em off,   come right back.
Like I said,   it's your call.
Just 'cause some man in uniform tries to tell us what to do
doesn't mean weactually have tofollow his orders.
Okay, I want you on   this one, all right?
I'll be right behind you.
We can't split up.
And we're gonna have   dinner tonight. We're   going to the same place.
Dad, no.
Cassie.
It's the Army, okay?   This is our Army. It's fine.   It's gonna be okay.
Don't leave me alone.
All right. Come here.
I love you.
Take care of your brother. All right? Come here.
I want you to listen toyour sister, all right?
Okay.
She's in charge.
Okay?
Dad.
Go ahead.
I'll be therebefore you know it.
Here, head to the back, Sam.
All right.
Come here. Give me your backpack.
Bear!
What?
Cassie, I forgot Bear!
Cassie.
What? Sam, what?
I forgot Bear! I need to go get him!
Sam, stop. Sit down.
It's okay. What's up?
I can't.I can't go without him.
Please!
All right, all right, all right, all right. I'll go get him, okay?
Just stay here. All right?
I'll be right back.
Promise?
Yeah, I'll be right back. I promise.
WOMAN: Right, no,  I think you're right.
MAN: Just grab   whatever you can get   up in a box and carry it.
SOLDIER: This way.  Down to the mess hall.  In the mess hall now, please.
Come on, Sam.
Bear, Bear, Bear.Bear, Bear, Bear, Bear.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Oh, God. Sam!
SAM: Hey! Wait!
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: Stop!
Sam!
Cassie! Wait, stop!
Sam! No! Sam, wait!
Sam!
Cassie! Come on!
Cassie!
Sam!
No!
Cassie, no, no.(SOBBING)
(PANTING)
No!
(GASPING) No.
Shi...
Can I have your attention,   please?
If you'll alljust quiet down.
We believe   the 4th Wave has begun.
(CROWD MURMURING)
The Others have come  down off their ship.
They are moving among us.
Apparently, they have the ability to inhabit human hosts
and control their actions.
So, they look like humans?
That's correct.
Where are they?
They could be anywhere.
What we do know is they have snipers in these woods,
and they are   targeting survivors.
We've got intel that would suggest
some of themcould be right herein this very camp.
(ALL CLAMORING)
MAN: So, what... Are you saying that some of us are Others?
COLONEL VOSCH:  Please. There's a lot  we still don't know.
We can detect them  in children.
Unfortunately,the screening procedure
for adults isa bit more complicated.
WOMAN: What about our kids?
Yeah, what about our kids?
I know. I know you all wanna   get back to your families.
Unfortunately,we're gonna have to
move you all to  a secure holding facility
so they can run some   screening protocols.
Folks, please!
You need to understand, there is no way
to differentiate us from the Others
without a comprehensive screening process.
The sooner we   get you screened,
the soonerwe can get youback to your families.
This is bullshit!
I am not an Other, okay?I'm not going anywhere.
COLONEL VOSCH:   Sir, no one's   saying that you are.
This is the realityof our situation.
Now if you'djust calm down.
Please, just calm down.
Let me out of here.Get out of my way.Watch out.
Hold on, sir.
Wait. Hey.
Back it up. Now.
Stop right there.
Sir, drop your weapon.
Step aside, now.
Drew, no!
You can't   keep me in here!
Everybody, just calm down!
Let me out now!
Lower the weapon. Now.
I wanna see my kids!
Put it down!
Let me out of here!
No! Drew, stop!
(GUN SHOTS)
Stay down!
Run!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
(GASPING)
(GUNSHOTS CONTINUE)
No, no, no.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(CRYING) Hey, Dad?
(SNIFFLES) Daddy.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. (CONTINUES CRYING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(GRUNTING)
(SOBBING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Daddy.
I need my dad.
God!
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
SOLDIER: &lt;i&gt; Security teams,&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; clear zones three and four.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Security teams,&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; clear zones three and four.&lt;/i&gt;
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
&lt;i&gt; Support team members,&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; meet arrivals on the tarmac.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Stand in the red circle.   Wait for your number   to be called.
MAN: (OVER SPEAKERS)   &lt;i&gt; Number 127.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; 295.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; 2-9-5.&lt;/i&gt;
Here.
&lt;i&gt; Number 7-3, 73.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Number 74.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Number 130.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; 194.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; 1-3-0.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; 1-9-4.&lt;/i&gt;
SERGEANT REZNIK: What's your name?
Ben Parish.
They called me "Zombie"in quarantine.
Any family not known to be dead?
No.
Sister died in the quakes.
Mom and Dad killed by the virus.
But it didn't   kill you, did it?
Not quite.
That where the nickname came from?
You fought it off.
Yeah, lucky me.
Is this your sister's?
Yeah.
Well, lucky you.
You get to help avenge her death.
This puts out a signal that we can track.
You kids are the most important thing right now.
We need every one of you to help us fight the Others.
This isn't summer camp, Zombie. You're a soldier now.
So we don't wanna  lose you. Stand up.
Turn around.
Take a deep breath.
(INHALES)
You all right?
How are we supposedto fight the Others
if we don't evenknow what they are?
Actually, we do.
You wanna see one?
Don't worry. He won't be able to see us.
I know. It's impossible to tell.
Look through here.
Look.
(EKG BEEPING)
That's its true form.
The Others infest real humans like some sort of parasite.
Take over their minds, their bodies.
Drugs, radiation,surgery, nothing works.
The only way to kill 'em is to kill the host.
He's already dead.
You just need to  destroy the thing  inside him.
The thing that did this.
Push the button.
Look again!
Look!
If you're gonnabe on my squad,
I need to knowthat you will dowhatever it takes to...
(SCREECHING)
(EKG FLATLINING)
Welcome to the fight.
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; Here's how you kill off a species.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; First,&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; you take out the easy ones,&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; the weak, the exposed.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Kill them as efficiently as possible.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; That was&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; the first three Waves.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But even if you&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; bug bomb a house,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; there's always a few cockroaches left.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Now, we are like&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; those cockroaches.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And the Others&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; are picking us off.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; One by one.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; And because the Others look like us,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; we can't trust anyone.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(RUSTLING)
(GASPS)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(HOOTING)
&lt;i&gt; Eighty miles to&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; Wright-Patterson.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I'm coming, Sammy.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I promise.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(PANTING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; How do you rid&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; the world of humans?&lt;/i&gt;
MAN: Help me.
(GUN SHOTS)
&lt;i&gt; First, you rid the humans of their humanity.&lt;/i&gt;
(SNIFFS)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Shit.
(GUN SHOTS)
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
Shi... Shi...
God!
Sam.
All right. All right.
(CONTINUES PANTING)
(STRAINING)
(YELLS)
God!
I'm sorry, Sam.
COLONEL VOSCH:  &lt;i&gt; When I was a child,&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; I spoke as a child.&lt;/i&gt;
I thought and I reasoned as a child.
But when I became a man,
I put away childish things.
Those words nevermeant more to methan they do right now,
looking at all of you.
Our hope. Our future.
The best and brightest  vision of who we are  and what we're fighting for.
Our intelligencetells us the Others are
readying themselvesfor a final attack.
(SIGHS) The 5th Wave.
What form it will take,we do not know.
If they are successful,
there will be no more Waves.
No more conflicts.
Humanity as we know it will be wiped from the face of the Earth.
Now.
I'm gonna tell you some things I know.
This is our world.
&lt;i&gt; It is our home.&lt;/i&gt;
They will not overrun it.
They will not possess it.
(GUN SHOTS)
So with whatever   time we have left,
&lt;i&gt; you will learn to think, speak,&lt;/i&gt;
move and fight like the soldiers you are.
FEMALE RECRUIT 1: Look out!  A raid!
FEMALE RECRUIT 2: Go!
Fire!
Let the weight of our loss fuel you.
Let the weight of our dead embolden you.
FEMALE RECRUIT 3:   Your right! On your right!
Let the weight of our hope   drive you to victory.
Can you do that?
All right. Hold!
Soldiers! Can you do that?
ALL: (IN UNISON)Sir, yes, sir!
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Zombie!
(CLIP CLATTERS)
Get down!
It's a booby trap!
Can you do that?
ALL: (IN UNISON)Sir, yes, sir!
Good.
(CREAKING)
(GASPS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(DOOR CLOSES)
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Come on.
Where's my gun?  Where's my gun?
Where is it?
(GROANS)
I know you're awake.
Cassie?
How the hell do  you know my name?
Your driver's license.
I'm Evan.
Evan Walker.
Where am I?
You were   bleeding on the highway.
I brought you back here to my house.
Where's my gun?
All right, when you found me on
the highway, I had my gun. Where is it?
I didn't see any gun.
What did you do?
Your leg, Cassie.
Don't touch me! Don't touch me! Don't...
Your leg.
Jesus.
(GROANS)
Oh, God.
Put your leg over here.
This is gonna hurt.
All right. Just do it. Just do it.
Oh, God.
EVAN: Okay.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Oh, God. (GROANS)
How long have I been here?
About a week.
Oh, God.
How far is Wright-Patterson from here?
The military base?
Uh, about 60 miles.
Why?
(YELLS) Jesus!
(WIND CHIME TINKLING)
Hey. It's okay.
You're safe here.
No.
All right, we're not safe anywhere anymore.
Why did you wanna  know how close  Wright-Patterson was?
Uh...
It's my brother.
The Army took him there, so I...
I need to get him back.
What?
You should eat.
(LIQUID POURING)
You gotta getyour strength back.
Why'd you bring me here?
What do you want?
My family.
I couldn't save them,
but I could save you.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
The way everything's  happened, I guess it just  makes me feel more...
Human.
And you need help with that?
Feeling human?
Don't you?
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Maybe. (CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
You're cheating.
I'm not cheating.
Don't you tell him my card.
You hear me, Oompa?
Hey, I've been  getting pretty lucky,
and this isn't my first time playing.
By the way,   I heard the new   guy coming in
got kicked out of  their last squad.
For what?
Disciplinary issues.
That true, boss?
That's what they say.
What's his name?
SERGEANT REZNIK: The name's Ringer.
And he is a she.
Bunk's over there.
GIRL 1: Did you ever do karate before?
GIRL 2: No.
GIRL 1:Sure looks like you did.
You Zombie?
Yeah.
I was the leader  of my last squad.
No doubt.
So the guy I replace went Section 8. Why?
Does it matter?
I heard it's 'cause this squad's so bad
he was afraid you'd get him killed when the 5th Wave hits.
ZOMBIE: Uh-huh. It's your squad, too, now.
Hey!
Keep staring at my ass
and I'll rip  your throats out.
Let's be clear.
I'm not taking orders from you.
I'm not gonna die with you geniuses.
Good to know.
If anyone in thisbarrack touches me,I'll kill them.
Got it?
Anything else?
I like to play chess. Do you play?
No, actually.
But if you wanna play some strip poker later on...
Ha!
Oh, shit!
And no demeaning,  sexist remarks.
She's cool.
(INDISTINCT THUDDING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(FLOORBOARD CREAKS)
(PANTING)
(GRUNTS)
(CLATTERING)
Quiet.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
You had my gun the whole time! Why'd you lie?
I was afraidyou'd shoot me.
For all I knew, you were an Other.
Yeah, well...
Was he one? Out there?
Yeah.
The woods are full of 'em.
They're using those drones to hunt down survivors.
He looked so human that...
Oh, God. I gotta get Sam.
Cassie.
Rallying points,  places like Wright-Patterson,
they're obvious targets.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
You think that Sammy's already dead?
I'm sorry, Cassie.
You're wrong, Evan.
All right? He's alive.
He's alive, and I'm gonna go get him.
Cassie.
I'm going with you.
You're not gonna   make it very far   on your own.
You know what?  Screw you, Evan.
Okay? I don't need you. I don't need anyone.
Cassie, come on.
If you go,  I'll just follow you.
Actually, no.
If I need someone to carve a cane for me...
You can't stop me. How are you gonna stop me?
I don't know.  Maybe I'll shoot you!
What, like you shot that   guy with the crucifix?
What, you read my journal?
I didn't think   you were gonna live.
Don't touch me!
I'm sorry.
I'll get you there.
I can't promise  what you'll find,  but I will get you there.
We leave in the morning.
RINGER: This is a waste of time.
Go ahead and try it again.
Those kids are gonna bedead before theirboots hit the ground.
Especially with you as squad leader.
You don't know anything about me.
Let me guess.
You did good in school, had a bunch of friends.
You probably played football.
You might have even been team captain.
Life was easy.
And then, all of a sudden, it wasn't.
No more games to win.
No one to get weak-kneed at that pretty smile.
You weren't ready for the end of the world.
And you were?
I know how to survive.
And I was doing fine out there on my own.
Till they forced me onto their stupid school bus.
They were rescuing us.
We didn't get rescued, dumbass. We got drafted.
Good, good.
Try it again.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(GRUNTING)
How about this?
I take you down,
you teach us how to shoot.
And when you don't?
I stop asking.
Deal.
Cute necklace.  Girlfriend or sister?
Sister.   (GROANS)
You're too sentimental.
(GRUNTS)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Can you teach me thatthing where you tookthe gun out of my hand?
Let's just leave any potential disarming to me,
all right?
No.
No, I need to be ready.
Cassie, it's okay.
You don't have to be tough all the time.
Don't do that.
I'm not tough, okay?
I promised Sam that   I would be there for him   no matter what.
I made that promise to him.
Okay.
Give me your gun.
Get up.
Point it at my chest.
Okay. Grab the barrel of the gun with your left,
and with your right,   snap my hand away.
You got it?
Hey, you're not gonna  hurt me. All right.
Like that, but stronger.
Good.
Now at the end,you'll grab my wristand pull it toward you.
Like that?
Yeah.
Good job.
Well, thanks.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Can I have...
RINGER: Okay. Don't be so scared of your weapon.
You gotta think that the gun is a part of you.
Not the gun firing, you firing.
Try it again.
(GUN SHOTS)
Well, that wasn't terrible.
Zombie, the Colonel wants to see you, now.
COLONEL VOSCH: Could be.   Seems like a good target.
Be right back.
Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
Simultaneous attacks on the last of our metropolitan areas.
A full-on invasion. This is it.
The 5th Wave.
It's started?
Yeah.
Here, I want to show you something.
These employ the same technology
as the detector viewer from medical.
We've improved it. Made it mobile.
The idea is to allow  our soldiers in the field
to instantly differentiate between friend and foe.
You look atthe enemy through thisand it lights 'em up green.
We can see them before they know they've been seen.
We take back the advantage.
The only thing  left to do now is
test the opticsin live conditions.
Which is why  tomorrow at 2100,
I'm sending four squadsinto battle equippedwith these helmets.
Your squad will be among those four.
Yes, sir.
Make me proud, son.
Bring that squad back in one piece.
Yes, sir.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Evan?
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Morning.
Who've we got here?
Um...
This is Lizbeth.
She's my best friend.
She looks like she's funny.
Yeah. Actually, you know, she was...
She was really funny.
And this guy.
He's nobody.
This must be Ben Parish.
Oh, God.
Wow.
I really wish you hadn't read my journal.
It's really embarrassing.
Is that your family?
Yeah.
And that must be Sam.
I can't wait to meet him.
We should   probably get moving.
Yeah. (CLEARS THROAT)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
All right, this way.
How do you know without a compass?
Do you have a compass?
No. But...
You know,I can make one out of a pinand a glass of water.
Didn't peg you for a Girl Scout.
What'd you peg me as?
A cheerleader?
You said it, not me.
I've never been   a huge fan   of the outdoors.
Too many bugs.
You live on a farm.
Accident of birth.
I had a scholarship to Kent State.
Mechanical engineering.
Thought I wassome hick, huh?
You said it, not me.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
SAM: Zombie, are they really sending us to fight?
ZOMBIE: Yeah.
SAM: I'm scared.
It's okay.
Just go to sleep, all right?
What was your name before?
Ben.
What was yours?
Sam.
But my sister called me Sams.
When I couldn't sleep
she would sing to me.
&lt;i&gt; ? Bones sinking like stones&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? All that we fought for&lt;/i&gt;
BOTH:  &lt;i&gt; ? Homes, places we've grown&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? All of us are done for&lt;/i&gt;
Could you guys please shut up?
SAM AND ZOMBIE:&lt;i&gt; ? We live in a beautiful world&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Yeah, we do&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; Yeah, we do&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? We live in&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; a beautiful world ?&lt;/i&gt;
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
Hey. Let me help you.
Yeah, sure.
Looks better.
Yeah.
Let me do this.
All right.
Got scissors?
Yeah.
I got it.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
I should probably  cover our stuff.
Evan.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Thank you.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Squad 53?
Present and accounted for.
All right.
Strap in. Take us up.
Where's Nugget?
Food poisoning.
SAM: Zombie.
Zombie.
Let me out of here!
(SOLDIER SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY OVER RADIO)
SOLDIER 2: &lt;i&gt; Copy that.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; Tango Three&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; dropping down 1,000.&lt;/i&gt;
You clear on your orders?
Infiltrateenemy hornet's nest,verify enemy and terminate.
Remember, the Others light up green in your visors.
At mission complete, signal for extraction.
We'll get ya home.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Holy shit, it's working.   You guys, I got two   of 'em straight ahead.
And I heard it. I was right there.
Got you, you motherf...
(GUN SHOTS)
I peed. I definitely just peed.
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
Get inside!
Return fire!
Coming this way!
They're over here, too!
Run for the alley!
Go! Go, go, go!
Teacup, go, go!
Go! Run!
Move!
Go! Go!
Contact!
Stay low!
(GUN SHOTS CONTINUE)
Get to the bus.
Go!
(GUNFIRE CONTINUES)
Where's Teacup?
Where's Teacup?We lost Teacup.
Over here!
Don't do that!   Don't scare me like that!
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
Oompa's been shot!
Down, down! Now, now! Down, down, down!
Down!
He's not breathing!
Don't be dead. Come on, man.
Don't be dead! Please don't be dead!
Oompa... Stay alive, Oompa!
We can't stay here.They'll be back.
That alleyway.We'll have cover there.
No, it's too far.
If we're out in   the open that long
they'll pick usoff one by one.
We need a distraction.
Okay.
Okay what?
I'll distract them.
When I tell you to run, run as fast as you can.
Now cover me!
What?
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Listen up!
On my go, haul ass to the alleyway.
Back out there?   Are you crazy?
Listen, Teacup,you just gottatrust me, okay?
You're gonna run   and don't look back.
What about Oompa?
He's dead, man.We gotta leave him.
Sorry, man. I'm sorry.
Zombie, now! Run!
Haul ass!
Go, go, go!
Let's move! Move! Move!
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Stairs.
Got it.
Clear!
Are we still alive?
I think so.
Watch out!
Don't shoot! It's Ringer!
That was badass, Ringer.
I'd hug you if I didn't think
you'd punch me in   the nuts for it.
Okay, so what do we do now?
None of this makes sense.
They knock planes out of the sky and cause earthquakes,
but they're afraid of  an army of children?
There's somethingVosch isn't telling us.
Okay, I'm not  risking my life for this.
DUMBO: Ringer, what are you doing?
I'm unenlisting.
I'm better out   there on my own.
If you know   what's best for you,   you'll do the same.
Holy shit! What the hell is this?
Zombie, you see this?
She's green!
What the hell, you guys?
Put your guns down.
You're one of them! You're an alien!
What are you talking about?I just saved your asses!
If she's one of them,  we have to take  her out now.
Poundcake, just calm down, all right?
We have to.
I can see it!
I can see it inside of her!
There's nothing inside me!
Shut up!
Zombie, what do we do? Do we shoot her?
It's your call, Zombie.
Zombie,what are you doing?
What's up, man?
Oh, my God!  What's going on, man?
Come on, man.
Hey. Put your guns down.Put your guns down.
Don't shoot. Calm down.She's not an Other.Neither am I.
I'm glowing green, right?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, listen.
You know me.
Come on, Dumbo. You know who I am.
Put the guns down.
Just put 'em down! I'm not an Other.
I don't even thinkany of those people
out there shooting at us are Others.
Reznik, Vosch...
They lied to us.
They lied to us, man.
Green doesn't mean alien. Green means human.
Just, without one of these.
What are you talking about?
Don't you guys see?
Those lenses, these trackers, it's all fake, man.
It's an illusion. It's a trick.
They weren't testing these.They were testing us.
They were seeing   how we would do,
how we would hold up   under pressure.
All right? If we would do what we were trained to do.
To kill Others!
No,to kill the survivors, man!
To kill survivors.
Yeah, well, what about the guys outside,
the ones that  were shooting at us?
They're human.
Why would the Army want us to kill other humans?
Because the Army,  Reznik, Vosch,
they're the Others.
And because we're kids,
they thought they   could manipulate us   into doing their dirty work.
We're not fighting the 5th Wave.
We are the 5th Wave.
Oh, God.
So...
What do we do?
Take out your trackers.
We go AWOL.
This means we can't go back. You know that, right?
Nugget.
I left him back at the base.
I was tryingto protect him.
Jeez.
I gotta go back.
That's suicide, dude.
No, man. I gotta go back.
You can't just wander back in there.
They'll know.
I can't leave him there!
I'll put the tracker   back in. They'll   pick me up.
You guys go ahead. I will meet up with you later.
Dumbo, where can I take a bullet in the torso and not die?
Are you serious?
I'm not kidding, man.
Where can I take a bullet in the torso? I gotta make it look real.
It's the only way I'm getting back in alive.
It's impossible, man. There's too many organs.
There's gotta be  somewhere, man.
Ringer, she can make   the shot, all right?   I know she can.
You want me to shoot you?
Don't pretend like you haven't thought about it.
Where do you want me to shoot him?
Uh...
I mean, the... Oh, shit.
(GUN SHOT)
(RUSTLING)
Evan Walker.
You're out of your drone sector.
Hey.
Put the gun down.  Stay away.
(GUN SHOTS)
(GRUNTING)
Cassie, run!
Where's my gun?
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(CASSIE GRUNTS)
Evan.
(GROANS)
(GRUNTING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Drop the gun.
Evan, drop it.
If I was gonna  kill you, Cassie,
I would've done it a long time ago.
What are you?
You're one of them. You're a fucking Other.
I'm human.
But I'm Other, too.
I'm both.
This isn't the first time the Others have been here.
They came before   and created   sleeper agents, like me.
I always felt different.
Growing up, there was this voice in my head.
It was quiet,  but it was there.
And when the ship arrived,
it was like a switch was flipped inside me,
and the sleeper woke up.
How many people have you killed?
Did you kill your family?
No.
The disease...
The disease that the Others created.
The disease that you created.
Your family loved you.
Our kind believe that  love is just a trick.
An instinct.
A way to protect   your genetic future.
Do you really believe that?
I did.
But then I saw you.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
EVAN: &lt;i&gt; I don't know how.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; I don't understand it, but...&lt;/i&gt;
It was like you   flipped the switch back.
You made me  wanna be human again.
Did you shoot me?
No.
I saved you.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(GUN SHOT)
EVAN: &lt;i&gt; I was wrong.&lt;/i&gt;
They're wrong.
Love's not a trick.It's real.
I know nowbecause of you.
Look, stay back!
I don't wanna hear any more.
Just stay there.
Cassie, please,   just let me help you.
All I wanna do is help you find Sam.
All right.   Get on your knees, Evan.
All right. Come on,just get on your knees.
Listen.
The Army is controlled by the Others.
They're preparing the kids.
For what?
To kill the last humans.
They'll search you.
You can't be armed.
If you follow me,
I'll shoot you.
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
Soldier,  where's your unit?
All dead!
What's your number?
2-9-5!
2-9-5. He'll live.
Let's bug out!
&lt;i&gt; All right,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; copy that, Tango Three.&lt;/i&gt;
Tango Three  returning to base!
2-9-5 on deck!
The rest of the squad  are reported KIA.
(GROANING)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(GROANS)
Ma'am, it's all right. It's all right. We've got you.
&lt;i&gt; 5-4-7!&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; 547!&lt;/i&gt;
SERGEANT REZNIK:   &lt;i&gt; Any family not&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; known to be dead?&lt;/i&gt;
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; No, just me.&lt;/i&gt;
Stand up.
You know why   you're here, Cassie?
Uh-uh.
To get revenge.
He's an Other.
I know.
Look through here.
That's its true form.
That's the face it's hiding.
(GROANS)
(PANTING)
What happened out there?
It was bad, sir.
We were surrounded.
We tried to move to cover, but as soon as we did...
They were everywhere, sir.
Everyone was hit.
Except you.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
I took a bullet, sir.
But you survived.
It's a miracle,
the way that bullet went right through you and managed to
miss everything important.
Let's make a deal.
You drop your lie,  and I'll drop mine.
Tell me, Ben.
What do you know?
I know what you are.
You're gonna   kill me, aren't you?
Yes.
Why?
What's the point   of any of this?
What did we do to deserve...
Nothing.
Other than occupy  a space we need.
(SIGHS)
We're not that different, Ben. Your kind would do exactly the same thing.
No.
Our kind wouldn't have   wiped out an entire species.
Of course you would.
You've been doing it for centuries.
Sir, Sergeant Reznik's dead.
Security found her body.
Where?
In medical.
There's more. Three guards were killed at the west gate and...
(ALARM BLARING)
What the hell was that?
An explosion, sir. It came from inside the base.
Get rid of him.
SOLDIER:Damage to Sector Three!
Captain.
Let's go.
We need to move all the recruits off-base.
Get 'em on planes to Wonderland now.
Deploy units. Find out who's attacking us.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
(EXPLOSION)
SOLDIER 2: South corridor!   On the double!
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
They're taking out our security cameras.
Bring the drones home so we can see who's attacking us.
SOLDIER 3:  Yeah, these are the changes  from about 60 minutes ago.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Hey!
Don't move, all right! Don't move!
It's okay! Okay, all right!
Cassie? My name's Ben Parish. We used to go to high school together.
I know who you are.
What squad are you in?
I'm looking for   my brother, Sam.
Sam?
Sam Sullivan? Sam Sullivan?
You know my brother?
Yes, yes, we're in the same squad.
You know where he is?
I'm trying to get to him right now.
SOLDIER: &lt;i&gt; All recruits&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; report to the transport area.&lt;/i&gt;
They're sending the kids off to war.
Vosch. The Army. They're Others.
Look, Sam is about to get on one of those planes.
If we don't go now, you're not gonna see him again. You understand?
We don't have much time.
&lt;i&gt; All recruits report&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; to the transport area.&lt;/i&gt;
All right.
Ready?
Come on.
Once the recruitsreach Wonderland,
get them ready for  immediate deployment.
Yes, sir.
Transfer area's this way.
Hey!
This is a restricted area.
Hey, it's all right.
On your knees!
Hands behind your head!
No, it's fine.   He's one of us.   It's okay.
Evan, what are you doing here?
Helping you.
Who's he?
Ben Parish.
Ben Parish?
Yeah. Uh...
He was just here.
I told you not to follow me.
Well, I decided to ignore you.
I've been planting bombs.
In about 10 minutes, when the last plane full of kids takes off,
I'm taking this place down, for good.
I'm sorry I lied to you, Cassie.
I was wrong when I said I was both one of you and one of them.
You can't be both. You have to choose.
I choose you.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Go.
Get out of here.
I'll find you.
Who was that?
Evan Walker.
We gotta go find Sam.
I think Evan Walker's about to blow this place up.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
Next floor up.
SOLDIER 4: Head tothe northeast corridor,number 22, now!
Which way?
This way.
SOLDIER: (OVER MICROPHONE)  &lt;i&gt; Stay with your group leader.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Proceed to the transport vehicles in a calm and orderly fashion.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Stay with your group leader.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; Proceed to the transport vehicles.&lt;/i&gt;
SOLDIER 2: Come on.  Move along, people.
Straight ahead.
&lt;i&gt; Stay with your group leader.&lt;/i&gt;
Keep it moving.
Don't fall behind, everyone.
Where do they think they're going?
&lt;i&gt; Once you are on the plane,&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; you will receive&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; further instructions.&lt;/i&gt;
Keep moving. Straight ahead.
&lt;i&gt; Stay with your group leader.&lt;/i&gt;
What's her problem?
Sam! Sam!
Sam! Sam! Sam.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Hi.
Cassie!
Don't, don't.
We gotta go, all right?
Let's go.
&lt;i&gt; Once you are on the plane,&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; you will receive&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; further instructions.&lt;/i&gt;
Come on.
Hi!
I missed you so much, Sam.
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
I missed you, Cassie.
Look what I  brought back for you.
It's Bear.
I love you.
I love you, too, Sam.
Hey. Um...
I gotta take his tracker out.
All right? It's not gonna hurt, okay?
(EXPLOSION)
Is it back up?
All the recruits  accounted for?
Yes, sir. Six barracks left.
Good.
Power up my bird.   Last plane's in the air,   evacuate the base.
Come on!
Shit! It's Vosch!
Run! Run! Go for the truck!
Go!
Sam, run faster!
Go! Go!
Come on, Sam!
Run!
Cassie!
Oh, shit!
Who is that?
Come on!
Come on! Get in!
Quick, Sammy. Get in!
All right, come on! Get in! Get in!
Drive!
Thanks for coming back.
(EXPLOSIONS CONTINUE)
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
DUMBO: Feel better?
ZOMBIE: Yeah, thanks, Dumbo.
Make sure you give her the food first.
DUMBO: Let me know if it starts hurting or anything like that.
Okay.
All right.
Teacup,   how you feeling?
Pretty good.
RINGER: All right.
How much longer for food?
DUMBO: I don't know. Not long.
What are you looking at?
Trying to find the stars.
It's a little early,   isn't it?
(CHUCKLES)
You were named after a star, right?
Cassiopeia.
Yeah. A cluster of stars.
I was named   after Ben &amp;amp; Jerry's.
The truth. Yeah.
Nothing made my dad happier than ice cream.
I'm sure  you made him happier.
Yeah.
So, uh...
What do we do now?
We have to save  those other kids.
Yeah.
How are we gonna do that?
Dinner's ready.
I don't know yet.
Well...
Let's worry  about that tomorrow
and just go get   something to eat.
All right.
Hey, Sam.
Here, wake up, buddy.
Hey, there he is.
Come on.
Come on, lazy bones.   Put your bear down,   would you?
CASSIE: &lt;i&gt; The Others see our hope as a weakness,&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; as a delusion.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; But they're wrong.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; It's our hope&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; that lets us survive.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; That lets us bend,&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; but remain unbroken.&lt;/i&gt;
You two knew each other?
ZOMBIE: Yeah,we went to highschool together.
CASSIE:&lt;i&gt; It's our hope that will let us win one day.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? ?&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; It's our hope&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; that makes us human.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I was born in a thunderstorm&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I grew up overnight&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I played alone&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; I'm playing on my own&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I survived&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Hey, I wanted everything&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; I never had&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Like the love&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; that comes with light&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I wore envy and I hated that But I survived&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I had a one-way ticket&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; to a place where&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; all the demons go&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Where the wind don't change&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; and nothing in the ground&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; can ever grow&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? No hope, just lies&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; And you're taught to&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; cry in your pillow&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? But I'll survive&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm alive&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I found solace&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; in the strangest place&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Way in the back of my mind&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I saw my life&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; in a stranger's face&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? And it was mine&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I had a one-way ticket to a place where all the demons go&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Where the wind don't change&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; and nothing in the ground&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; can ever grow&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? No hope, just lies&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; And you're taught to&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; cry in your pillow&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? But I'll survive&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt; I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm alive&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? You took it all, but I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I had made every single&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; mistake that you could&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; ever possibly make&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I took and I took and I took what you gave, but you never noticed that I was in pain&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I knew what I wanted I went in and got it&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? Did all the things that&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; you said that I wouldn't&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I told you that&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; I would never be forgotten&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; And all in spite of you&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? And I'm still breathing I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;  &lt;i&gt; I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm alive&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? You took it all,&lt;/i&gt;   &lt;i&gt; but I'm still breathing&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;i&gt; ? I'm alive ?&lt;/i&gt;