Orbulus! look, it's Unicron!
The ships!  Get to the ships!
It's our only chance!
Kranix!
There is an evil new force in the universe
A monster planet that devours everything in its path...
and it's heading for the smal planet Cybertron
where a unique race of transforming robots continue fighting a civil war...
a war between good and evil that has raged for millions of years.
The evil Decepticon Transformers, led by the maniacal Megatron,
have sworn to crush their enemies, the Autobots.
To this end, they have relentlessly rescued them across the galaxy
from planet Cybertron to planet Earth and back again.
But the heroic Autobot Transformers and their courageous leader Optimus Prime
are not easily defeated.
It is the year 2005.
The treacherous Decepticons have conquered the Autobots' home planet of Cybertron.
But, from secret staging grounds on two of Cybertron's moons...
...the valiant Autobots prepare to retake their homeland.
Ironhide, report to me at once.
Every time I look into a monitor, Prime, my circuits sizzle.
When are we gonna start busting Decepti-chops?
I want you to make a special run to Autobot City on Earth.
But Prime!
Listen, Ironhide. We don't have enough energon cubes to power a full-scale assault.
Ready the shuttle for launch.
Your days are numbered now, Decepti-creeps!
Jazz, report security status.
No sign of Decepticons here, Prime.
What about Moon Base Two?
Jazz to Moon Base Two, Jazz to Moon Base Two...
Bumblebee and Spike here.
We're about to send up a shuttle. Any Decepticon chinanagins in your area?
All clear, Jazz.
Hey, Ironhide, tell my son Daniel, I miss him.
And tell him not to worry. I'll be coming home as soon as we kick Megatron's tail across the galaxy.
Will do, Spike.
Cliffjumper, commence countdown.
5...4...3...2...1...Blast off!
Now, all we need is a little energon, and a lot of luck.
Laserbeak returns, Megatron.
Welcome, Laserbeak. Unlike some of my other warriors, you never fail me.
Soundwave, play back Laserbeak's findings.
As you command Megatron.
I want you to make a special run to Autobot City on Earth.
But Prime!
Listen, Ironhide. We don't have enough energon cubes to power a full-scale assault.
Ready the shuttle for launch.
Now all we need is a little energon, and a lot of luck.
More than you imagine, Optimus Prime.
Megatron!
Decepticons!
Die, Autobots!
This was almost too easy, Starscream.
Much easier, almighty Megatron, than attacking the real threat, the Autobots' moon base.
You're an idiot, Starscream.  When we slip by their early warning systems
in their own shuttle and destroy Autobot City, the Autobots will be vanquished forever.
No!
Such heroic nonsense.
Fish are jumping today, huh, Dan-O?
I guess so.
Hey, what's the matter?
Uh, I don't know, Hot Rod.
Come on, you can tell me.
Guess I just miss my dad.
Don't worry, Spike will be back soon... oh hey! I caught something!
Wow! Look at the size of it!
Yep. It's a whopper all right.
Hot Rod, the shuttle's coming. Let's watch it land.
Talk about dull, Daniel.
Hurry or we'll miss it!
If you're going to ride, Dan-O, ride in style.
Hey! Let's stop here!
Why settle for a peek, Daniel, when you can see everything from Lookout Mountain?
A little to the left. A little bit more...
Turbo-revvin' young punk! I'll straighten you out yet.
Hot Rod, Look! There's a hole in the shuttle.
What?
Decepticons!
What's that darn fool doing?
Attack!
Come on down, Auto-brat.
Huh. Not bad for an old-timer.
Old-timer? That's something you'll never be if you don't get back to the city.
Save it, Kup. Let's burn rubber.
Ultra Magnus, a cursory evaluation of Decepticon capability
indicates a distinct tactical deficiency.
In other words, Perceptor... We're outnumbered!
Springer, you and Arcee transform Autobot City.
Perceptor, tell Blaster to radio Prime for reinforcements.
What about me? Hm huh hm huh hm huh? I can help, I want to help. What about me?
Blurr, you can help me alert the others.
Absolutely positively definitely. Nobody can get a job done faster than I can. Nobody, nobody, nobody!
Come on, Arcee, Let's go!
But Hot Rod and Kup are still outside the city.
We can't wait.
They'll have to take care of themselves. Come on!
Pathetic fools!
There's no escape.
Breach their defenses!
Delicious... eh, Shrapnel?
Uh, a little heavy on the electrons, electrons.
The Insecticons are in our way.
Wrong. They're our way in. Yah!
Look out, shout.
Hey Perceptor, what's shaking, other than this fortress?
Blaster, Ultra Magnus sends orders to contact Optimus Prime on Moon Base One.
All right! Cover your receptors, Perceptor.
Optimus Prime, do you read me? The Decepticons are blitzing Autobot City.
We're really taking a pounding.  Don't know how much longer we can hold out.
Soundwave, jam that transmission.
Rumble, Frenzy, Ravage, Ratbat... eject. Operation
Optimus Prime, do you read me? The Decepticons are blitzing Autobot City. We're really taking a...
First we crack the shell, then we crack the nuts inside.
Run, Blaster. Save yourself!
No way. Two can play.
Sick'em.
Do you think you got through to Prime?
Let's hope so. Cause if I didn't we're all going to look like burnt-out toaster ovens.
We've got Decepticons in the gates, Decepticons in the air, Decepticons inside the walls... Decepticons, Decepticons, Decepticons!
If we pick them off the wall and they show up in the air. If we shoot them out of the air
and they show up in the gates over there, and that leaves us nowhere, that's where!
Come on, Arcee. We've got to get this launcher into place. Megatron's making his big push, and we got to push back.
Keep at it Springer my boy. Help's at hand.
Together now.
I was afraid you'd be trapped outside the city.
Hey, I wasn't worried for a microsecond..
Then you probably didn't understand the situation.
That did it.
Constructicons, merge for the kill.
Kup, Hot Rod, look!
Devastator.
Prepare for extermination.
I've got better things to do tonight than die.
Their defenses are broken. Let the slaughter begin!
Dinobots, destroy Devastator.
Me Grimlock love challenge.
Megatron must be stopped, no matter the cost.
Prime.
One shall stand; one shall fall.
Why throw away your life so recklessly?
That's a question you should ask yourself, Megatron.
No! I'll crush you with my bare hands!
I've got to help Prime.
Stay away, lad. That's Prime's fight.
I'll rip out your optics!
Finish him off, Prime. Do it now.
No more, Optimus Prime! Grant me mercy, I beg of you!
You who are without mercy, now plead for it? I thought you were made of sterner stuff.
No you don't, Megatron!
Out of the way, Hot Rod!
Fall. Fall!!!
Ah, I would have waited an eternity for this. It's over, Prime.
Never!
Optimus, forgive me.
How do you feel, "mighty" Megatron?
Astrotrain, transform and get us out of here.
Uh, don't leave me, Soundwave.
As you command, Megatron.
The Decepticons are retreating.
Prime did it. He turned the tide.
Astrotrain, take off!
I fear the wounds are fatal.
Prime, you can't die!
Do not grieve.
Soon I shall be one with the Matrix.
Prime.
Ultra Magnus, it is to you, old friend, I shall pass the Matrix of Leadership, as it was passed to me.
But, Prime, I'm... I'm just a soldier. I'm not worthy.
Nor was I... but one day an Autobot will rise from our ranks
and use the power of the Matrix to light our darkest hour.
Until the day... till all are one...
Jettison some weight or I'll never make it to Cybertron.
Fellow Decepticons, Astrotrain has requested that we lighten our burden.
In that case I say it is survival of the fittest.
Do I hear a second on that?
...and against?
The ayes have it.
Get... Make room for others...
Brothers, don't!
Oh, how it pains me to do this!
Wait... I still function.
Wanna bet?
Starscream!!!!
As Megatron has, how shall we say, departed, I nominate myself as the new leader.
Wait. The Constructicons form Devastator, the most powerful robot. We should rule.
Soundwave Superior. Constructicons inferior.
Who are you calling inferior?
No one would follow an uncharismatic bore like you!
Hey! Nobody calls Soundwave "unchrasimatic".
Yeah! Let's kick tailgate!
Constructicons, unite!
No way!
Welcome, Megatron.
Who... Who said that?
I am Unicron.
Show yourself.
I have summoned you here for a purpose.
Nobody summons Megatron.
Then it pleases me to be the first.
State your business.
This is my command. You are to destroy the Autobot Matrix of Leadership.
It is the one thing, the only thing, that can stand in my way.
You have nothing to fear.  I have already crushed Optimus Prime with my bare hands.
You exaggerate.
The point is he's dead, and the Matrix died with him.
No. The point is you are a fool! The Matrix has been passed to their new leader, Ultra Magnus.
Destroy it for me.
Why should I? What's in it for me?
Your bargaining posture is highly dubious. But, very well, I will provide you with a new body
and new troops to command.
And?
And nothing! You belong to me now.
I belong to nobody!
Perhaps I misjudged you.
Proceed on your way to oblivion.
NO! No! No!
I accept your terms! I accept!
Excellent.
Behold, Galvatron!
And these shall be your minions.
Scourge, the tracker, and his huntsmen, the sweeps.
Cyclonus, the warrior, and his armada commander.
And this shall be your ship.
Now Go!
Destroy the Autobot Matrix.
I will rip open Ultra Magnus, and every other Autobot, until the Matrix has been destroyed.
To Cybertron!
Destroy the Matrix.
Get on with the ceremony.
My fellow Decepticons, as your new leader, I...
Who disrupts my coronation?
Coronation, Starscream? This is bad comedy.
Megatron, is that you?
Here's a hint!
Will anyone else attempt to fill his shoes?
What'd he say his name was?
Galvatron!
Long live Galvatron!
Where'd that come from?
Who cares?
I'm more worried about where it's going?
Talk to me, Earth. We've got a situation out here.
Roger me! Wilco me! anything! Hello, hello, Earth.
I'm picking up a faint signal.
This is Jazz. A gi-normous, weird-looking planet just showed up in the suburbs of Cybertron.
And it's attacking Moon Base One.
Jazz! Cliffjumper!
Got to blast free, if we can.
Ignition and...
Hit it!
Jazz! We're not getting away!
This is Spike and Bumblebee, up here on Moon Base Two.
This thing, this monster planet, just ripped the first moon to shreds.
...and it's heading this way.
We'll try and slow it down.
But you better get here fast, because we're not going to...
Dad!
Bumblebee, activate the explosives.
If this doesn't stop him, nothing will.
The explosives are activated. Let's get out of here.
Hurry! It's going to blow!
All right! Hooray! We did it! We done it! Way to go!
Look!
It isn't even dented! What are we going to do now?
We're being sucked into it!
How dare, Unicron! Cybertron and all it's moons belong to me!
But remember, we belong to him.
I belong to nobody.
I will obey, Unicron.
Decepticons, to Earth.
Autobots, prepare to board the shuttles This new menace is more dangerous
than all the Decepticons put together.
Somehow we must destroy it before it devours Cybertron.
But what about my dad? He... he's on the moon between that monster planet and Cybertron.
Daniel, we'll do everything we can for Spike.
And what are we going to do when we get there? That thing crunches moons, it'll make short work of us.
Maybe the matrix can stop it.
You're right; it can!
What do you know about it, lad?
I've just got this feeling.
Look!
To the shuttles!
I, Galvatron, will crush you, just as Megatron crushed Prime.
And you'll die trying, just like Megatron.
Autobot scrap!
Do you want me to gun Ultra Magnus?
There are plenty of Autobots for you. Ultra Magnus is mine!
Stay close to me, Daniel..
And you better stay close to me.
No, you better stay close to me.
Nice Dino, good Dino, sweet Dino, wouldn't you step in the nice spaceship for Blurr? Pretty please? Pretty pretty pretty please?
Pretty pretty pretty please? Nice Dino, good Dino, with a cherry and sugar and whipped cream on top? Nice Dino, good Dino, sweet Dino?
Me Grimlock not "nice dino".
Me bash brains!
Blurr, get the Dinobots in the shuttle.
I'm trying to get them in the shuttle, Ultra Magnus, cause I know we can't launch the shuttle until we get them in the shuttle,
but I can't seem to get them in the shuttle, because they're impossible, impossible, impossible!
Okay, forget it. Kup, Hot Rod, you get the Dinobots aboard and get us out of here!
Come on, you big bozo, get in the shuttle.
This reminds me of the battle on Alpha 9. The Petro-rabbits were...
Grimlock, get your noodle out of my face!
Me Grimlock love Kup's war stories.
You're living one now. Engage the boosters, for Cybertron's sake!
Tell Grimlock about Petro-rabbits again.
I'll give you petro-rabbits. Contact.
Looks like we're shipmates, squirt.
All right!
But if you get spacesick, you're going to walk home.
Hurry.
Wait, Ultra Magnus! Arcee's still out there!
Jump!
Thanks.
Whew. That was close.
Believe it or not, this is the fun part.
Congratulations, Autobots, we've lost them.
So rest while you can.
I remember the dust was so thick off Beta 4, you had to use windshield wipers on your optic sensors.
Me Grimlock know all about wipers, want to hear good part of story.
Good part, Kup. Tell Swoop good part.
Okay, okay. Well, the dust was really thick. And then this gigantic Ichyac came tromping and stomping down the mountain,
flames spewing out of its nostrils. And I thought for sure...
Hey, Kup, don't you think we have better things to do now than tell old stories?
Like what?
Like try to figure out how we're going to rescue our friends, and then save Cybertron.
No. Tell story.
Quiet. We want to hear story. Tell story, tell story.
Time out, time out, time out!
They're closing on us.
Yep, like the shrikebats of Dromedon.
How'd you beat them? I'm trying to remember. There were an awful lot of casualties that day.
Oh, yeah! We inverted polarities.
They're coming back!
All right! We survived that.
But will we survive this?
Cyclonus, transform and attack.
I can't control it!
We're going to crash!
Kup and Hot Rod just bought it.
I can't deal with that now.
Face it, Magnus. The Decepticons are going to dog us until they see us dead.
Then that's exactly what they're going to see.
Prepare for emergency separation.
That's too dangerous!.
What choice do we have?
The Autobots have been terminated.
Excellent. And the Matrix with them.
No! Unicron! Why?
Take me to Unicron! Take me now!
Did you have to let them detonate three-quarters of the ship?
Seeing as how they would have detonated four quarters, I think it was a good choice.
But now how are we going to get there in this wreck?
Perceptor, can you locate a place to set down for repairs?
Gamma rays in this sector of space create marginal navigation probabilities. However...
ahem, yes. I believe I can. he planet of junk is in this vicinity.
Then let's go for it.
Kup! Grimlock! Slag! Anybody!
Hot Rod, help me!
Kup... Kup!
Help...
Kup, talk to me.
Fix me.
Sure, Kup. Right away.
Brace for impact.
Say something. Anybody.
Remind me to give the auto-pilot a raise.
Daniel?
I, I'm okay.
Let's try to salvage this thing.
Can I help too?
It's rough out there, kid.
I think Daniel can make himself useful with this. It was Spike's Exo-Suit.
Dad's Exo-Suit! He told me all about it.
Here, try it on.
Now try to walk. Come on, you can do it.
Just think about what you want to do before you do it.
It's kind of tricky.
Keep on practicing. You'll get the hang of it.
Come on, showtime's over. We've got work to do.
This must be the junk capitol of the universe.
Stop, thief! No welcome-wagon hello stranger with that good coffee flavor for you.
Yeah, yeah.
Or your money back.
Offer expires while you wait. Operators are standing by.
That does it. So, what do you think?
Of all the circuit-glitched diode-blowin' dimwittery. You left a piece out!
No way; you're just a little stiff.
Anyway, all things considered, you've done an amazing job, lad. Amazing.
Really?
Yeah. You even got rid of a nasty burr in my rotator.
Now let's find the Dinobots and get off this twisted planet.
Don't act hostile; I'll use the universal greeting.
Universal greeting?
I'll have them eating out of my hand:
Bah weep granah weep nini bong!
Bah weep granah weep nini bong?
See? The universal greeting works every time. Now, without making any sudden moves,
offer them an energon goodie.
This is getting expensive.
Don't worry. They'll reciprocate.
I thought they were supposed to reciprocate.
No more. Empty.
Reminds me of the Nitith Slave Mines on Galganas 7.
Every place reminds you of someplace else.
Experience, lad. You should learn to appreciate it.
A lot of good it's done us so far.
Hey, what's going on over there?
Has the Imperial Majester delivered a verdict?
I have.
Guilty or innocent?
Innocent.
Feed him to the Sharkticons.
We've got to get a new travel agent.
Bah weep granah weep nini bong.
What is this place?
The world of the savage Sharkticons, and their cruel masters, the Quintessons.
I am Kranix. My planet was destroyed by Unicron.
Unicron. Who's Unicron?
A planet that devours everything in its path.
So that's the monster's name.
No, please! I'm the last survivor of lithone! No, no!
Let him go.
Soon you too shall receive your sentence.
Has the Imperial Majester reached a verdict?
I have.
Guilty or innocent?
Spare me this mockery of justice!
I repeat, guilty or innocent?
Innocent.
Not the end I'd wish for, lad.
Me Swoop no see nothing.
Me Grimlock positive Hot Rod and Kup close.
Me Slag say you full of beryllium bologna.
Me Grimlock say you full of cesium salami.
Beryllium bologna!
Friend find, look behind.
Who say that?
Friend find, look behind. You go wrong way. You fool I say.
Me Grimlock fool?
Picture you got. No fool you not.
Me Grimlock no like you.
Why boy hit my nose?
Wheelie say find friends today.
Me Grimlock say we on our way.
Unicron, why did you torture me?
You have failed.
No, Unicron. Ultra Magnus is dead, and the Matrix destroyed.
The Matrix has not been destroyed, and Ultra Magnus lives on the planet of junk.
Stalk him. Tear him apart, and destroy the Matrix.
Be sure the fittings are securely welded.
Absolutely, positively, definitely. I wouldn't do it any other way, any other way at all.
This Exo-Suit's fantastic. I think I'm starting to get the hang of it.
Forward, avanti, and like, go for the gusto.
Hold on.
Decepticons! We've got to draw them off and double back to the shuttle.
There goes the shuttle.
What do I do?
Transform, transform. You can do it, I know you can do it, you can do it.
Transform.
Human germ.
There they are.
Attack!
Make a break for cover. I'll try and unleash the power of the Matrix.
Till all are one!
Till all are one.
Open, damn it, open.
Prime, you said the matrix will light our darkest hour.
Magnus, I want the Matrix.
Never!
Sweeps, terminate him.
Die. Die!
Unicron, my master, with this I shall make you my slave.
Nooo!
Before his Imperial Majester delivers a verdict, would you like to beg for your lives?
It sometimes helps, but not often.
I can't transform.
Keep trying.
Silence, or you will be held in contempt of this court.
I have nothing but contempt of this court.
Guilty or innocent?
Innocent.
They've got more Sharkticons than we've got photon charges.
Then let's hold a demolition derby.
Didn't even bend a fender.
Yeah, but look. There's a lot more of those can-diggin' grill-crackin' things.
We can't hold out forever, Kup, but we can give them one humongous repair bill!
Execute them...
Excuse me.
Me Grimlock want to munch metal.
I never thought I'd be glad to see those big bozos.
Me Grimlock no bozo, me king.
Sharkticons, execute them.
Me Grimlock say execute them.
I think the problems on this planet will be solved very shortly.
Yeah, but what about our problems? We need a ship.
You get ship if I get trip.
Who are you?
Him Wheelie. Him friend.
He'll be mine too if he can find a ship.
Ship: Stare over there.
That's a ship?
Who cares, as long as it flies.
Ultra Magnus...
Without the Matrix there is no hope, no hope, no hope, no hope at all.
First Prime, now Ultra Magnus. What do you do?
Look!
Don't look behind door number two, Monty. It's time to play End of the Line, My Valentine. Geroni-geron-ron-ronimo!
It's not hard to knock 'em down, it's getting them to stay down that's the trick.
They're indestructible, and they're everywhere!
You check in, but you don;t check out.
Steady as she goes, Bob. Snoopy visitors get mud in the eye, by and by. Film at eleven.
It's Hot Rod.
And Kup and the Dinobots.
Guns aren't exactly friendly.
Neither are they, in case you haven't noticed.
What was that universal greeting again? Never mind; I remember.
Bah weep granah weep nini bong.
Me Grimlock not kisser. Me Grimlock king.
Have a nice day and... ??? ... so say the Junkions.
Where'd you learn to talk like that?
TV. We talk TV. You talk some TV?
I talk some TV and now the news, don't touch that dial.
By George, Kimosaves, your smashed-up friend soon like brand new with 90-day warranty.
Happy motoring. Cock-a-doodle-doo!
Look, he's alive. I don't believe it.
You're all alive?
The Matrix...
It's gone.
And with it, all hope.
No!
Galvatron has it.
Where's Galvatron? Where is he?
And the answer is: Unicron.
Then we've got to destroy Unicron.
Yes, friends, act now; destroy Unicron. Kill the Grand Poobah.
Eliminate even the toughest stains. Hurry, hurry, hurry, sale must end. Rush right on down and test-drive latest model with no obligation.
New improved Junkion planet is sleek, sexy import with turbo handling..
Yeah! Destroy Unicron! Kill the Grand Poobah! Eliminate even the toughest stains!
Unicron! Unicron! Answer me! See this: the Matrix. I now possess that which you most fear!
NOOO!
You'll do my bidding, or taste my wrath!
You underestimate me, Galvatron.
For a time, I considered sparing your wretched little planet, Cybertron.
But now you shall witness its dismemberment.
No!
Decepticons, we're under attack. Scramble!
I don't believe it. Doesn't this remind you of anything, Kup?
Nope. Never seen anything like it before.
What happened to Moon Base Two? Where's my dad? That's what we're going to find out.
...and enamel. Resists fire, rain and corrosion for up to five years. Satisfaction guaranteed.
Or your money back!
Where's Hot Rod?
I don't know, but I hope they didn't get him.
Quick, this way.
The Matrix!
It will do you no good, Autobot. It can not be opened.
Not by a Decepticon.
Like it or not, we are allies now against a common foe.
Destroy him Galvatron, now, or you yourself shall be obliterated.
Of course, my master.
Puny Autobot. You lack even Prime's courage.
Me Grimlock kick butt.
Me Grimlock need new strategy.
Help! Help!
Daniel!
Arcee! Kup!
Dad!
Daniel!
Dad, what can I do?
Knock down the acid cover.
How?
Blast it, son!
But I don't have a gun.
Use your Exo-Suit. Hurry!
Daniel! You did it!
Yeah. I did it!
Come out, Autobot. We all must die sometime.
Not today, Galvatron.
I will crush you with my bare hands.
Die, Autobot.
First Prime, then Ultra Magnus, and now you. It's a pity you Autobots die so easily,
or I might have a sense of satisfaction. Now...
Arise, Rodimus Prime.
Optimus?
No!
This is the end of the road Galvatron.
Now, light our darkest hour.
Spike, Daniel.
What's going on?
No time to answer that now. Let's get out of here.
Look!
Autobots, transform and roll out.
I knew you had potential, lad.
Destiny... you cannot destroy my...
Destinyyyyyyyy...
Let this mark the end of the Cybertronian Wars as we march forward
to a new age of peace and happiness.
Till all are one.