The Fast and the Furious
Tokyo Drift
Made by: Don (edit from Cre@tivE)
soundtrack :
-=dj shadow feat mos def - six days the remix=-
nice ride
Does the job
What job?
Delivering pizza?
That not the ride, that the driver
Who the hell is that?
What?
Hey!
You was talking to my girl?
There we go
She was just admiring..
...my ride
What about your daddy's Viper?
Wow, you can read the brochures
Mr. Monte Carlo
Wooo!
Why don't you guys let the car do the talking?
So, let race!
How about me?
Winner gets me!
Yeah!
The first arrived on the end of the road win
Make it interesting, Clay!
I thought you love me!
Oh no!
What the hell
I guess I got new date for prom
Clay
-Shut Up!
Clay, stop breaking the car!
-Shut Up
Can I get a copy of that?
Do you think that this is a joke?
See the Barbie overthere?
Where is my car?
Crushed
You did what?
You are ready
shawn?
What didn't think you, however?
Ms Boswell
Please sit
It is miss
Officer, is it illegal to smoke in here?
This our third town in two years
Where are we moving this time?
We are not moving anywhere
Tokyo, Japan
shawn, I thought that you will be here on 7?
-today it is the 7.
Just hold on a second
Come on in
This is it
That is when you left to Japan
very well then
How was your mother?
Where do I sleep?
It is either this or the prison
Look, no of us ask for this
But I have promised you mother
to take care of you
Rules?
-Yes, rules!
Real simple. .
You go to school and back
here right after
And I don't wanna see or hear
you anywhere near car!
Here, bedroom is your
Make yourself comfortable
light out at 10
Train to school leaves at 0700
You got to be kidding
Wrong train, I am new here
I am here new
Mr. Boswell?
Yes, Boswell
Wabaki!
-Wabaki?
Wabaki
My name is Twink
Yes?
No, I'm cool
I ain't got no cash
what about a cellphone?
everybody need a cellphone
no offense but might not be here
long enough to even remember your name
Like Michael Jordan?
I love Michael Jordan
check this out.
Brand new Jordan's
not even out yet
i dont know. that my ride dick
I even pay retail for it
What you drive?
My ride?
-Yes
my ride is one of the kind
I though you wasnt stick around
alright
Viper
Porsche Cayman
Volkswagen Touran
(Twink)
At least let me drive
I dont know if you are ready, huh
You look a little nervous
Hear that?
That is nothing for me
Look at?
Ok, then we are done here
Problem with your V8?
Men.
The only thing they concern
is who got the biggest engine
I'm a guy, this is in my DNA
Race you with this thing?
With this toy
I almost not recognised you without those slippers
Don't you mean 'wabaki'?
Neela, right?
You are learning fast
Where do you come from?
Here
Not where you live now
But where you are born
Thus it really matter?
Who is that tourist?
Ah, him leaves little girls with the school
Just as hear ladies, continue wait
Hi
He wanted go exactly
Sorry, I dont speak Japanese
Do you understand that?
We were just talking
What thus that mean?
It means, turn around.
and keep walking
That is exactly what we are doing!
That is Yakuza
See you!
That is weird, I thought this is an open country
The little girl can talk with whom she wants
You know who I am boy?
Yes, the Timberlake of Japan
Leave
Are you crazy?, That is Yakuza
The mafia!
Monkey dont get bananas today
Good Luck, Timberlake..
Then let race!
With what?
Don't you have run?
Sorry, you cannot participate without car
Take mine
let race!
Why?
-Let see what the kid got
Can he drive?
You know what DK stand for?
Donkey Kong?
Drift King!
drift?
What do you mean by drift?
Got it now?
The Mona Lisa?
His car is the Mona Lisa
You know what, just dont blow the mona
Ready!
Set!
Go!
I told you!
Come on, Neela!
Damn!
Nissan Fairlandy 350Z
(D.K.)
Damn!
Don't leave town
Do you know what time it is
I thought it was around 7 o'clock
You know, US is a few hour behind
You have been racing, Shawn?
You are out of here!
Go ahead
You dont get it. do you?
You have nowhere else to go
If it doesn't work right here, you are going to jail!
Do you get that?
This isn't a game
I gonna tell you one last time
If you gonna live under my roof,
you gonna go by my rules
Or get out!
Understand?
Understand?!!
Yes, sir
Nissan Fairlandy 350Z
(Morimoto)
Get in!
I will get you your money
Why do you talking like you have a choice?
There is a guy in there with a paw
who owe me some money
A paw?
Go get my money
OK
Sumimasen
Han... say...
'Okandi'
Han says 'Okandi'
Lets go
You are in pick-up and delivery business now
I call, you show
Only if you teach me how to drift
Is this a negotiation?
I wasn't negotiate
Hi
What he doing here?
He pays me back for the scrample
beer can in my garage
Hope he not do driving, huh?
'Gaijin'.. .
When is the next race?
I do really like to be there
Why not be in it?
You heard me
Why blow another car, han?
I am ready to take that
86Corolla from you hand
Alright
But that is up to your Skyline?
Done!
You do you think, morimoto?
Get the man out of here
We got business to discuss
What is the rate?
Since when you worried so much
about the detail?
When is the driving, han?
let me handle it
Hey dad, it is me
I have to stay at school for
some extra-corruricular activities
So, I will be home a little bit later
Sir
You really need to stop following me around
What do you doing here?
Trust me, you don't want to a
part of this world
It is good enough for you
Your don't know anything about me
Why do you think I don't?
Cause I am a 'gaijin'?
an outsider?
Let me guess
your are normal lady, move around a lot .
Mom and daddy was never home
So you end up piss off all the time
See you for one, cowboy
Why cant you find a nice japanese girl like
the rest white guy around here?
Nissan Fairlandy 350Z
Does everything OK back there?
I can handle DK.
And the Yakuza?
his uncle is Yakuza
He is just playing gangster in his storage room
I need him
What do you mean?
50% of esomething is better than
100% of nothing
So, you will be race D.K.?
Why not? see that girl?
She is the point of the race
See if I am better than others guy
Just prove you faster
The race is something important
Why are you letting me race?
Because you are D.K. creep tonight
And you owe me a car
197 Km/h
What the?
Police's cars are just a factory tube.
If you can do better than 180k,
they will never catch you
They dont even try
Do you know what?
I think I like this country already
Danny!
You're loooking good
Disco?
Let's go
easy now, ladies
Put your hand off that kid girls
He under-age
Ladies, ladies
Ladies
Disneyland for grown-up, huh?
All these ladies...they look like..
What? Models?
It becomes also always more tiring
Yes
I dont just think outside the box,
I tear it up
That my thing
YO!
shawn?
The red evo is yours
Mitsubishi Lancer Evolution VIII
(shawn)
What do you mean?
You represent me now
what do you think?
I gonna let you roll in a Hyundai?
My mother, she is playing in one eye,
and she can did better than that
Han, where did you find this guy?
That yours?
sure is
What happened?
I dont know
I just found him
It got potential
Yeah maybe, we will see
You gonna be late
shawn!
hayaku!
This must be some misunderstanding
I do refund right?
here
try not to break this
Say man!
what is wrong with you, huh?
Damn!!
not easy saving the day, is it?
Maybe you can give me some ponders
You are doing fine
Thanks
hey
Sorry about last time
Your life isn't in my business
Foul!
No it isn't!
Han!
What do I look like? a zebra?
like cowboy make around for their border?
This is my Mexico
why you let me drive your car?
you know I gonna wrecked it
Why not?
Because that a lot of money
I have money
that's the price I can live with.
Look all those people down there
Those follow the rules for what?
What happens if it is not this way?
Very simple
you make choices and you dont look back
So, if you dont drift to win,
what are you drift for?
You really want to know?
Yes
OK, let go
Nissan Skyline GT-R
So feel it!
Again!
What in those bags?
You will see it
You are the pimp, man
Again!
Hey
Watch it!
Go Go Go
Not bad!
Dont lose grip!
Get this man a bunk
That the way to do business
Well this way!
bama_boy : how come i never c u drift?
: because you never ask!
Certainly not bad
I hate that word
They use to call me when I was a kid
I thought you were born here
Well
My mother died when I was 10
DK's granmother took me in ...
My parents have separated when I was 3
me and mom moves around a lot
mostly because of me
In fact it was all because of me.
The day I got my license is also
the day I got my first speeding ticket
The day after I won my first race
Everything between us are a dream
No past
No future
No problems
Just the moment
Sim
can you change the tire set
Wow
Another set?
No, that is your third set today
Come on, man
Stay away from her
Find yourself a new driver
I'm alright
What do you expect?
You play with fire
And throws yourself with gasolin
It over
call yourself a 'gaijin'?
I am a 'gaijin'!
you have change DK
You say I have changed
We are the same
Difference is I know who I am
and where I am from
Do you know who you are?
Do you know who you really are?
come on
Hey  brother
It is my life
we are partner
Are we in the boyscout?
That is what we do
takashi!
how about now
is this what we do?
You need me
takashi!
-you were dead
go go go!
come on!
shawn
takashi
I wouldn't do that if i were you
OK, i'll go with you
Neela
shawn, dont argue with me
I did this
I cant run away
shawn
I am you father
I are responsible for your
And I am responsible for my mess
I got to do this
Can you understand that?
please not redoing my mistake
you alright man?
We leaving town
I know some people
I cant do it, Twain
D.K. want your head
Maybe I should talk to Kamada
What?
D.K. answers to him
I dont know what i have just heard
I got to end this
I gonna talk to him
What are you? A crazy?
Han is dead, alright!
Plus, you cannot just walk into Kamada's
place man!
That is all I got
There is something that i think Han
want you to have
What this?
You gonna need this if you want to out from
Kamada's place alive
Dont you need it?
It is cool
look..i figured it out
shawn
you need to leave
You have come to a wrong place
I didn't come here to see you
You think
You can walk in here with some cash
And walk out
I only return what belong to you
in the first place sir
that is not why I really came
I come here to apologize
I know your nephew and I embaress
ourself badly
Sir, I come here to offer you a piece
of solution
How do you plan to accomplish that?
A race
D.K. and I cause nothing but trouble for you
For us
I'm asking you to allow us to settle this
Once and for all
We race
Good
That should be easy
The cops have got the cars
we almost there
just a little more tweak
It is not the car i'm worry about
D.K. pick this road for a reason
This is a mountain
It is where nobody ever make it to the bottom
Dead Charger
Hey, shawn
check this out, man
there is someone over here
want to race our new DK
heard that to be all people around asia too
Not tonight, Twink
he said he knew Han
said Han was family
alright
Let race!
Dead Charger
nice ride
I wonder if my friend Han have to
use it years ago
I didn't know he was in
the Amerika's muscles
Notice I know a 10 seconds race
I got nothing but time
You ready kid?
Ready!
Set!
Go!
Subtitled by Don (edit from Cre@tivE)