(TRIBAL DRUMS PLAYING)
(PANTING)
(SPEAKING MOHICAN)
CHlNGACHGOOK: Hello!
John Cameron !
(DOG BARKlNG)
Chingachgook!
How are you?
The Master of Life
is good, John.
Another year passed.
How is it
with you?
Getting along.
Yes, l am.
JOHN: Nathaniel.
Hello, John.
Cleared another
quarter, l see.
Yes, l did.
Alexandra.
Welcome.
Jack, how are you?
Hello, Nathaniel.
How've you been?
Good. Thank you.
Where you boys
been trapping?
West of the Cuyahoga.
Why is Uncas
with you?
He should have
settled with a woman,
started a family by now.
LlTTLE GlRL: Hey! Hey!
Hey, Uncas, look!
Mohawk field we saw
was five mile long
on the river.
Chief Joseph
Brandt's field.
You take much fur?
That we did.
Lots.
The Horicon's
near trapped-out now.
Where are you
trading your skins?
Castleton?
No.
Schuylerville.
Schuylerville,
with the Dutch,
for silver.
French and English
want to pay with
wampum and brandy.
So what is it, Jack?
What brings you here?
French and lndian army
are heading south
out of Fort Carillon
to war against
the British.
l'm helping to raise
New York's militia to
fill the Crown's levy.
And the people here
are gonna
join in that fight?
We'll see in the morning.
Where're you boys heading?
We'll trap over the fall.
Winter in Can-tuck-ee.
Find a Delaware-speaking
woman for Uncas.
She will say,
"You are the one!"
Bear him many children.
BOY: Then you can
have a boy like me.
Never.
You're too strong.
Turn me old too fast.
That's what he's
doing to his mama.
MAN: John Cameron,
thank you for
your hospitality.
Mohawk traded furs
with les francais.
We got no quarrel
Now les francais
bring Huron, Ottawa,
Abenaki onto Mohawk land.
Now Mohawk will
fight les francais
and Huron.
l speak for
the Twin Rivers Mohawk
of the Six Nations.
His Majesty, King George ll,
is very grateful
for your support.
How far up the valley?
Up to Fort William Henry.
That's two nights
and a bit from here.
Should be enough
to remind you all that
France is our enemy.
MAN: France is
your enemy.
What did you say?
While we're at your fort,
what if the French
attack our homes?
What then, Lieutenant?
For your homes,
for King, for country!
That's why you men
ought to join this fight!
You do what you want
with your own scalp.
Do not be telling us
what we ought
to do with ours.
You call yourself a patriot?
A loyal subject to the Crown?
l do not call myself
subject to much at all.
(PEOPLE CHUCKLlNG)
l agree with some of what
Nathaniel and John say,
but l believe England's
still our sovereign.
MAN 1 : l'll go.
MAN 2: We will go to
fight the French.
MAN 3: My brother and l
will volunteer up.
MAN 4: l'll fight
with you, Jack.
JOHN: l'm staying
on my farm.
Any man who goes,
his family's welcome
to fort up with us
till he comes back.
Boys,
my sense of it is
we have enough here
to fill the county levy,
and it's a fight
we ought to make.
But first
we got to get terms
from General Webb.
Where are you
meeting him?
We'll go to Albany.
(SHOUTlNG PLAYFULLY)
Attention !
We speak for the men,
not command them.
lf they're not allowed
leave to defend
their farms and families
if the French
attack the settlements,
then no colonial militia
is going to
Fort William Henry.
They will report
or be pressed
into service.
Any of the boys
worth having
can disappear
into the forest.
They will be found.
And where does that
leave you then?
Those men will be
found, arrested. . .
l cannot imagine
His Majesty,
in his benevolence,
would ever object
to his loyal
American subjects
defending
their hearth and home,
their women and children.
Does that mean they
will be granted leave
to defend their homes
if the settlements
are attacked?
Of course.
You got yourself
a colonial militia, General.
lt is
what we wanted.
Major Duncan
Heyward reporting, sir,
en route to
Fort William Henry
and bearing dispatches.
Safe journey,
l trust?
Yes, and l didn't
experience anything
so surprising from
Bristol to Albany
as that that l
witnessed here today.
And what was that?
The Crown negotiating
the terms of service.
l know.
One has to reason
with these colonials
to get them to do anything.
Tiring, isn't it?
But that's
the lay of the land.
l thought British policy is
"Make the world England," sir.
l see you're to serve
with the 35th
Regiment of Foot
at Fort William Henry
under Colonel Munro.
l'll be marching
the 60th to Fort Edward.
Explain to the Major,
he has little to fear
from this General
Marquis de Montcalm
in the first place,
and therefore scant need
of a colonial militia
in the second,
because the French
haven't the nature for war.
Their Latinate
voluptuousness
combines with
their Gallic laziness.
And the result is,
they'd rather eat and
make love with their faces
than fight.
(MEN LAUGHlNG)
Might l inquire if
General Webb has heard
from Colonel Munro's
daughters?
l was to rendezvous with them
in Albany and escort them
to the fort, sir.
You there,
what does Munro
call you?
The Scotsman has sent you
one of his Mohawk allies
to guide you.
Magua.
The Scotsman's daughters
are at the Poltroon's house.
A company of the 60th
will accompany you,
and Magua will
show you the way.
Dawn. At the encampment,
6:00 a.m. sharp.
See to it you're there.
l'll take him
for you, sir.
Cora.
Duncan !
How long have
you been in Albany?
For days and days.
And yourself?
Just arrived.
By God,
it's good to see you.
l don't know
what to say, Duncan.
l truly wish they did,
but my feelings don't. . .
Don't go beyond friendship.
Don't you see?
Respect and friendship.
lsn't that a reasonable basis
for a man and a woman
to be married?
And all else
may grow in time?
Some say
that's the way of it.
Some?
Cousin Eugenie,
my father. . .
Well, then, Cora.
ln my heart l know,
once we're joined,
we'll be the most
marvelous couple
in London.
l'm certain of that.
So why not let
those whom you trust,
your father,
help settle
what's best for you?
ln view of your indecision,
you should rely
on their judgment.
And mine.
Will you
consider that?
Please consider that.
Yes.
Yes, l will.
ALlCE: Duncan !
By God,
you've grown up.
We leave
in the morning?
Yes, miss.
l shan't
sleep tonight.
What an adventure.
Have you seen
the red men?
A few.
l absolutely
cannot wait to return
to Portman Square,
having been
to the wilderness.
lt's so exciting,
Duncan.
(DRUMS BEATlNG)
Alice?
ALlCE: Can we rest soon?
DUNCAN: Absolutely.
You, there.
Scout, we must stop soon.
Women are tired.
Not here. Two leagues.
Better water. We stop there.
No, stop in the
glade just ahead.
When the ladies are rested,
we will proceed.
Do you understand?
(SPEAKlNG HURON)
Excuse me.
What did you say?
Magua said,
understand English very well.
(HlSSlNG)
DUNCAN: Hold tight!
Come on !
Right! To the right!
(SCREAMlNG)
Prepare your firearms!
As three ranks!
Make ready!
First and second rank,
present!
(SOLDlERS SHOUT)
Fire!
(SCREAMS)
(SHOUTlNG WAR CRlES)
(GUNSHOTS)
(GROANS)
No, Duncan.
ln case
your aim's any better
than your judgment.
(GRUNTS)
Your wounded
should try walking
on back to Albany.
They'll never
make a passage north.
Stop it! Stop it!
We need them
to get out!
DUNCAN: Why's he
loosing the horses?
Why don't you ask him?
Too easy to track.
They'll be heard
for miles.
We were headed to
Fort William Henry.
(CHlNGACHGOOK
SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
We'll take you
as far as the fort.
We're walking
out of here fast.
Unless all of you'd rather
wait for the next Huron
war party to come by.
Scout, l'd like to
thank you for your help.
How much
further is it?
Night and a bit.
Appears we're
well away from them.
Maybe.
Maybe they ain't alone.
That Huron captain
back there. . .
The guide?
He's a Mohawk.
No Mohawk.
He's Huron.
What reason did he have
to murder the girl?
What?
The dark-haired one.
Miss Cora Munro?
Murder her?
He never set eyes
on her before today.
She's only been here a week.
Blood vengeance?
A reproach or insult?
Of course not!
How is it
you were so nearby?
Came across
the war party.
Tracked them.
Then you're assigned
to Fort William Henry?
No.
Fort Edward then?
Heading west
to Can-tuck-ee.
There is a war on.
How is it
you are heading west?
Well, we kind of
face to the north,
and real sudden-like,
turn left.
l thought
all our colonial scouts
were in the militia.
The militia is fighting
the French in the north !
l ain't your scout.
And we sure ain't
in no damn militia.
Ottawa, two francais.
What did
you say?
Mirrors,
tools,
the clothes.
Everything
was inside.
They didn't
take anything.
And moving fast.
And a war party.
Let us look after them.
Leave them.
Whoever they are,
though they're strangers,
they're at least entitled
to a Christian burial.
They can't
be left behind.
Let us go, miss.
l will not!
l've seen the face
of war before, sir,
but l've not seen
war made upon
women and children.
And almost as cruel
is your indifference.
Miss Munro,
they're not strangers.
And they stay
as they lay.
Why didn't you
bury those people?
Anyone looking for our trail
would see it as a sign
we passed that way.
You knew them well?
You were acting
for our benefit,
and l apologize.
l misunderstood you.
Well, that's
to be expected.
My father
warned me about. . .
Your father?
Chingachgook.
He warned me
about people like you.
Oh, he did?
He said, "Do not try
to understand them."
Yes. And,
"Do not try to make
them understand you.
"That is because
they are a breed apart
and make no sense."
(RUSTLlNG)
(WHlSPERlNG)
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Why did
they turn back?
Burial ground.
"Breed apart.
We make no sense?"
ln your
particular case, miss,
l'd make allowance.
Thank you so much.
Where is
your real family?
They buried
my ma and pa
and my sisters.
Chingachgook found me
with two French trappers,
raised me up
as his own.
l'm sorry.
l do not remember.
l wasn't but one or two.
How did you
learn English?
My father sent Uncas and l
to Reverend Wheelock's
school when l was 1 0.
Why were those people living
in this defenseless place?
After seven years
indentured service
in Virginia,
they headed out here
'cause the frontier's
the only land available
to poor people.
Out here,
they're beholden to none.
Not living by
another's leave.
The name was Cameron.
John and
Alexandra Cameron.
My father's people
say that
at the birth of the sun,
and of his brother,
the moon,
their mother died.
So the sun gave
to the earth her body,
from which was
to spring all life.
And he drew forth
from her breast
the stars.
The stars,
he threw into the night sky
to remind him of her soul.
So there's the
Camerons' monument.
My folks' too,
l guess.
You are right, Mr. Poe.
We do not understand
what is happening here.
And it's not
as l imagined
it would be,
thinking of it
in Boston and London.
Sorry to
disappoint you.
No, on the contrary.
lt is more
deeply stirring
to my blood
than any imagining
could possibly have been.
NATHANlEL:
Top of the next ridge.
The fort's downhill of it.
DUNCAN: The men of
the regiment will fetch
water from the lake,
build fires,
and provide every
comfort and desire.
l cannot wait
to see Papa.
(EXPLOSlONS)
(DlSTANT SHOUTlNG)
(MEN SCREAMlNG)
(MEN SHOUTlNG)
(MAN SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
Fire!
Prepare! Point! Fire!
(MEN SCREAMlNG)
(MAN SHOUTlNG ORDERS)
(EXPLOSlONS)
(PANlCKED SHOUTlNG)
Open up.
l'm Major Duncan Heyward.
Captain Jeffrey Beams.
Didn't expect you
to make it through.
Let's go
to Munro.
(PEOPLE SHOUTlNG)
Hello, boys!
Nathaniel !
l need to talk
to you, Jack.
MAN: Uncas!
Thought you and Nathaniel
weren't joining up.
We didn't.
Papa! Papa!
Alice! Cora!
Why are you here?
And where the hell
are my reinforcements?
Get Mr. Phelps.
Told you to stay away.
Why did you
disobey me, girls?
When? How? l. . .
My letter.
There was none.
What?
There was no letter.
l sent three couriers
to Webb.
DUNCAN: One called
Magua arrived.
He delivered
no such message.
Does Webb not even know
we are besieged?
Sir, Webb has no idea.
And he certainly
does not know
to send reinforcements.
What happened to you?
On the George Road.
Attacked.
We're fine.
Are you all right?
Yes.
What will happen
here, Papa?
We'll be all right, girl.
This Magua led us into it.
Eighteen killed.
These men came to our aid.
They guided us here.
Thank you.
Do you need anything?
Help ourselves
to a few horns
from your powder stores.
Some food.
lndebted to you.
(EXPLOSlONS)
PHELPS: Miss Cora,
how are you?
Hello, Mr. Phelps.
Mrs. McCann
will get some dry
clothes for you.
CORA: Thank you.
Go with
your sister, Alice.
lt'll be all right, girl.
lt'll be all right.
Might l inquire
after the situation, sir,
given that l've seen
the French engineering
from the ridge above?
The situation is,
his guns are bigger than
mine and he has more of them.
We keep our heads down
while his troops dig
30 yards of trench a day.
When those trenches
are 200 yards from the fort
and within range,
he'll bring in
his 1 5-inch mortars,
lob explosive rounds
over our walls
and pound us to dust.
They look to be
300 yards out.
lf they're digging
30 yards a day,
you have three days.
Damn. Damn.
This man here
can make a run
straight through to Webb.
Three days is not enough time
to get to Albany and back
with reinforcements.
Webb's not in Albany.
He marched the 60th to
Fort Edward two days ago.
Webb is at Edward?
Yes, sir.
That's only
1 2 miles away.
He could have
reinforcements here
the day after tomorrow.
You, sir, pick your man.
Major Heyward will
provide a diversion.
l'll draft out
a dispatch.
Captain Beams
will seek you out
and give it to you later.
Something else.
Cameron's cabin.
Frontier cabin.
Came upon it yesterday.
lt was burnt out,
everyone murdered.
lt was Ottawa,
allied to the French.
Aye.
So?
lt was a war party.
That means they're gonna be
attacking up and down
the frontier.
Thank you, sir.
People here,
Mohawks, settlers,
have family out there.
That'll be all, sir!
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
Things were done.
Nobody was spared.
Those considerations
are subordinate to
the interests of the Crown.
A terrible feature of war
here in the Americas,
Major Heyward.
Best keep your eye
fixed on our duty,
to defeat France.
That hangs on
a courier to Webb.
(CHlLDREN SlNGlNG lN LATlN)
For my children
are the children
of the true faith.
My friendship
and esteem
is boundless.
Tomorrow, l will sing
the war song with you
at the great
council fire.
Magua, how are things
with your English friends?
We're at one.
Join us.
Hear what Le Subtil
has to tell us.
The English war chief,
Webb, goes to Fort Edward
with 60th Regiment.
He does not know
that my father's army
attacks Fort William Henry.
Magua was successful?
The other two couriers
died in the forest.
By now, Munro would know
his dispatch
did not get through.
He'll send another.
Grey Hair will try.
Four or five,
including two women,
entered the fort.
The Grey Hair's children
were under Magua's knife.
They escaped.
They will be
under it again.
Why do you hate
the Grey Hair, Magua?
When the Grey Hair is dead,
Magua will eat his heart.
Before he dies,
Magua will put his children
under the knife,
so the Grey Hair
will know his seed
is wiped out forever.
My engineers
are advancing the trench
through the night.
You may have
your opportunity soon.
(DlSTANT EXPLOSlONS)
GUARD: Miss Cora.
Gentleman
looking for you.
Miss Munro.
Hello.
May l?
lt will seep, and then
it's going to draw.
Thank you, miss.
About done
holding hands
with Miss Munro?
We got some work to do.
What are you
looking at, sir?
l'm looking at you, miss.
Munro refused to
believe what happened.
He does not even
want to hear it.
(EXPLOSlONS)
Well, he's gonna have to.
Get together by
the west bastion.
lan, Sharitarish,
Ongewasgone and William.
Tight weave?
Silk.
Another 40 yards.
(GUNSHOT)
(GROANS)
(PANTlNG)
MUNRO: And how am l
to know it wasn't a raid
by common thieves?
NATHANlEL: The cabin
was attacked by a war party
fighting with the French.
They're sweeping south
down the frontier
attacking farms
and Mohawk villages.
All the men
are stuck here.
l need proof
more convincing than
this man's opinion,
before l weaken
the fort's defenses
by releasing the militia.
Chingachgook's
of the same opinion
about the raid.
Taken together,
that's gospel.
Your fort will stand
or fall depending
on Webb's reinforcements,
not the presence
of the colonials.
l judge
military matters here,
not you.
Your judgment
is not more important
than their right,
under agreement with Webb
to defend their farms
and families.
Major Heyward was there.
He was at John Cameron's.
He saw what it was.
MUNRO: What exactly
did you see, Major?
l saw nothing
that would lead me
to the conclusion
it was other than a raid
by savages
bent on thievery.
NATHANlEL: You're a liar!
Major!
Montcalm is a soldier
and a gentleman,
not a butcher.
Easy for you to suppose.
lt's their women
and children alone
on the farms, not yours!
You forget
yourself, sir!
We're not forgetting
Webb's promise.
British promises are honored,
and the militia
will not be released,
because l need
more definite proof
than this man's word !
Nathaniel's word's
been good
on this frontier
a long time
before you got here.
This meeting is over!
The militia stays.
Does the rule
of English law
no longer govern?
Has it been replaced
by absolutism?
lf English law
cannot be trusted,
maybe these people
would do better
making their own peace
with the French.
That is sedition !
That is the truth !
l'll have you beaten
from this fort.
Someday l think
you and l are gonna have
a serious disagreement.
Anyone fomenting on
advocating the leaving
of Fort William Henry
will be hung
for sedition.
Anyone actually
caught leaving will be
shot for desertion.
My decision is final !
Get out.
(MEN MUTTERlNG)
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Cora?
(SHUSHES)
l wanted to
talk to you.
Talk with Duncan, Cora.
l must manage.
l cannot be
an invalid schoolgirl.
Alice.
l'll see if Mr. Phelps
needs anything.
l'm sorry.
l didn't mean to. . .
Cora, when we
come together
back in England
and are married and
away from this place,
what had to be
done and said here
will matter not at all.
l'm certain of that.
Duncan,
l promised you an answer.
You've complimented me
with your persistence
and patience.
But the decision
l have come to
is that l'd rather make
the gravest of mistakes
than to surrender
my own judgment.
Please take this
as my final answer.
lt must be no.
l see.
(FRENCH SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG)
(WOMAN HUMMlNG)
lAN: Yeah, Nathaniel,
but you weren't
ever for being here.
NATHANlEL: That's right.
l saw it that way then
and l see it that way now.
lan, if l had kin
in the settlements,
hell be damn sure
l'd be long gone.
What do we do about
being under Crown law?
l believe if they
set aside their law
as and when they wish,
their law no longer
has rightful authority
over us.
All they have over us
then is tyranny.
And l will not live
under that yoke.
So l will stay
here no longer.
Anyone caught
leaving the fort
could be shot,
so each man make
your own decision.
Those who are going,
be back in an hour.
Out the northern
sally port.
Strike for
the east side
of the swamp
till you clear
the French picket line.
Head north over the ridge,
then come about southeast.
Fork left in Little Meadow
and you're free of
the outpost and skirmishes.
Should've gotten
out of this long ago.
Got no families, Captain.
Figured we'd stay
and give a hand.
l'll cover you from
the top of the bastion.
You're not
coming with us?
l got
a reason to stay.
That reason wear
a striped skirt and
work in the surgery?
lt does.
No offense, but it's
a better-looking reason
than you, Jack Winthrop.
Push hard,
'cause you got to clear
the French outpost by dawn.
Good luck, Jack.
(lNDlSTlNCT CHATTERlNG)
Ongewasgone,
are you staying?
Yes.
There's too many French.
And so few
of us to fight.
Not too many to die.
But we've given our word
to our English fathers.
(MAN COUGHlNG)
(VlOLlNS PLAYlNG)
(SHUDDERlNG)
You, sir!
As you were!
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
Stand off.
Take him.
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
As you were.
He saved us.
We're alive only
because of him.
The man encouraged
the colonials to desert,
in this very room,
and in my presence.
Sir.
He is guilty of sedition.
He must be tried
and hanged
like any other criminal,
regardless of what
he did for my children.
But he knew
the consequences
and he stayed.
Are those the actions
of a criminal?
Duncan, do something.
He knew the penalty
for his actions.
He ought to pay
without sending you
to beg.
You know he wouldn't send me.
You falsely spoke
of what you saw.
What happened at the farm
was as Nathaniel said.
But not with enough certainty
to outweigh British interests
in this fort.
And who empowered
these colonials
to pass judgment
on England's policies
in her own possessions,
and to come and go
without so much
as a "By your leave"?
They do not live
their lives by your leave!
They hack it out
of the wilderness
with their own two hands,
bearing their children
along the way.
You are defending him
because you've become
infatuated with him !
Duncan, you are a man
with a few
admirable qualities.
But taken as a whole,
l was wrong to have thought
so highly of you.
Cora!
Cora, l would do anything
l could to keep
you from being hurt.
But this man
is guilty
of sedition
and subject
to military justice
and beyond pardon.
Justice?
lf that's justice,
then the sooner French guns
blow the English army
out of America,
the better it will be
for the people here.
You do not know
what you're saying !
Yes, l do.
l know exactly
what l'm saying !
And if it is sedition,
then l am guilty
of sedition too.
They're going to
hang you.
Why didn't you leave
when you had the chance?
Because what
l'm interested in
is right here.
What can l do?
Webb's reinforcements
will arrive or not.
lf they do not arrive,
the fort will fall
to the French.
lf that happens,
stay close
to your father.
Stay close to him.
The French officers will try
to protect the officers
among the English.
No. l will find you.
Do not.
Promise me.
(DlSTANT EXPLOSlONS)
The whole world's
on fire.
(CHATTERlNG lN FRENCH)
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(SOLDlERS SHOUTlNG)
What is it?
Remember
what l told you.
Stay close
to your father
and the officers.
(DRUMS BEATlNG)
(OFFlCERS SHOUTlNG ORDERS)
Colonel Munro,
l have known you as
a gallant antagonist.
l am happy to
make your acquaintance
as a friend.
And l yours,
monsieur Le Marquis.
Please accept
my compliments
for the strong
and skillful defense
of your fortress.
Under the command
of a lesser man,
it would have
fallen long ago,
given the superior
numbers and materials.
Chance has allowed me
to array against you.
Monsieur Le Marquis,
l am a soldier,
not a diplomat.
You called this parley
for a better reason
than an exchange
of compliments.
You have already done
everything which is necessary
for the honor of your prince.
But now l beg you
to listen to the
admonishments of humanity.
l beg you
to consider my terms
for your surrender.
Perhaps the general's
glass can reach
as far as the Hudson
and seize the size
and eminence of
the army of Webb?
My scouts
intercepted this dispatch
intended for you.
Capitaine de Bougainville.
"To Colonel Munro.
Sir, l regret to inform you
"that l have no men available
to send to your rescue.
"lt is quite impossible.
"l advise you
to seek terms
for surrender.
"l remain.
Jerome Webb
at Fort Edward."
This is
the signature
of Webb.
And l know
the temper
of our men.
Rather than spend the war
in a French prison
hulk in Hudson Bay,
they'd fight
to the end.
You've had your answer,
monsieur Le Marquis.
Sir, l beg you not to sign
the death warrant of so many
until you have listened
to what l have to say.
Go on.
None of your men
will see the inside
of a prison barge.
They are free,
so long as
they return to England
and fight no more
on this continent,
and the civilian militia
return to their farms.
Their arms?
They may leave
the fortress fully armed.
My colors?
Carry them to England
with pride.
Allow me to consult
with my officers.
l have lived
to see something
which l never expected.
A British officer
afraid to support another.
Webb can
burn in hell.
And we'll go back
and dig our graves
behind those ramparts.
Death and honor
are thought
to be the same,
but today
l have learned that
sometimes they are not.
Sir. . .
Monsieur Le Marquis,
l am deeply touched
by such unusual
and unexpected
generosity.
My fort is yours
under the condition
that l be given till dawn
to bury my dead,
to prepare my men and women
for the long journey ahead
and to hand my wounded
over to your surgeons.
Granted, monsieur.
(SOLDlERS SlNGlNG)
ls the hatchet buried
between the English
and my French father?
Yes.
Not a warrior has a scalp
and the white men
become friends.
My master
owns these lands,
and l have been
ordered to drive off
the English squatters.
They have
consented to go,
so now l call them
enemies no longer.
Magua took the hatchet
to color with blood.
lt's still bright.
Only when it's red,
then it will be buried.
So many suns have set
since Magua
struck the war post.
And where is that sun?
Magua is the son
of his people
and he has come
to lead many of them.
But Magua has power
with his Huron people
and others here,
l know well.
Magua's village
and lodges were burnt.
Magua's children
were killed
by the English.
l was taken as slave
by the Mohawk
who fought for the Grey Hair.
Magua's wife
believed he was dead
and became
the wife of another.
The Grey Hair
was the father
of all that.
ln time,
Magua became
blood brother to the Mohawk
to become free.
But always in his heart,
he is Huron.
And his heart
will be whole again
on the day
the Grey Hair and
all his seed are dead.
Does the chief of the Canadas
believe the English
will keep the terms?
l fear having
let them go,
which l must,
l will only fight
the same men again
when l drive towards Albany.
But l cannot break
the term
of the surrender
and sully
the lilies of France.
(THUNDER RUMBLlNG)
Monsieur,
the fort is yours.
(SCREAMS)
MAN: Left three ranks,
make ready!
Aim, set.
(YELLS WAR CRY)
(HURONS YELLlNG)
Fire!
Present, fire!
Full company!
Grey Hair,
before you die,
know that
l will put under the knife
your children,
so l will wipe your seed
from the Earth forever.
(MUNRO GRUNTS)
CORA: Leave her alone!
(lNAUDlBLE)
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
When you fall into
British hands again,
l'll have you hanged !
Faster!
Head to the river!
DUNCAN: Where are we going?
NATHANlEL: Nowhere.
l don't understand.
This is as far
as we go.
lf we're lucky,
they'll figure we beached
our canoes and
headed cross land.
lf we're very lucky,
they'll figure
we went over the falls.
Our only hope is
that they pass us by.
lf they do?
Take the south rim
down the mountain.
lt's 1 2 miles
cross country
to Fort Edward.
And if they don't?
You'll just have to forego
the pleasure of hanging me.
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
Powder?
Gone.
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
Mine's soaking wet!
CORA: Our father. . .
Did you see my father?
From a distance.
Say nothing to Alice.
Get back!
(GASPS)
(SPEAKlNG HURON)
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
Yes! Go ahead !
What the bloody hell
plan is this?
l want you to go!
lf we go, there's a chance
there won't be a fight.
There's no powder.
lf we don't go in that,
there's no chance.
None! You understand?
Coward !
You've done
everything you can do.
Save yourself!
lf the worst happens. . .
You stay alive!
lf they don't kill you,
they'll take you north
up to the Huron lands.
Submit, do you hear?
You're strong.
You survive!
You stay alive,
no matter what occurs!
l will find you,
no matter
how long it takes,
no matter how far!
l will find you.
(SPEAKlNG HURON)
(NATHANlEL SHOUTlNG
lN MOHlCAN)
(PANTlNG)
(SPEAKlNG MOHlCAN)
(SPEAKlNG HURON)
(PEOPLE YELLlNG)
(WOMAN SHOUTlNG lN HURON)
(MAGUA SPEAKlNG)
l don't speak Huron.
Do you speak
French, Major?
Yes.
Translate for me
into French
every word as l say it.
l come to you unarmed
and in peace to unstuff
your ears, Sachem.
(DUNCAN TRANSLATlNG TO FRENCH)
Let the children of
the dead Colonel Munro
go free.
Take fire out of
the English anger
over the murder of
their helpless ones.
(DUNCAN TRANSLATlNG TO FRENCH)
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(DUNCAN TRANSLATlNG
TO ENGLlSH)
Sachem, the French fathers
made peace.
Magua broke it.
lt is false that the French
will be friends
still to the Huron.
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(SPEAKlNG HURON)
(DUNCAN TRANSLATlNG
TO ENGLlSH)
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(DUNCAN TRANSLATlNG
TO ENGLlSH)
Would Magua use the ways
of les francais
and the Yengeese?
(DUNCAN TRANSLATlNG TO FRENCH)
Would you?
Yes!
Would the Huron make
his Algonquin brothers
foolish with brandy
and steal his lands
to sell them for gold
to the white man?
Would Huron have
greed for more land
than a man can use?
Would Huron fool Seneca
into taking
all the furs
of all the animals
of the forest
for beads
and strong whiskey?
Those are the ways
of the Yengeese
and the francais traders
and their masters
in Europe infected
with the sickness of greed.
Magua's heart
is twisted.
He would make himself
into what twisted him.
l am Nathaniel
of the Yengeese.
Hawkeye, adopted son
of Chingachgook
of the Mohican people.
Let the children
of the dead Munro
and the Yengeese officer
go free.
This belt,
which is a record
of the days
of my father's people,
speaks for my truth.
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(SACHEM SPEAKlNG)
(SPEAKlNG HURON)
Tell him l'll trade him.
Me for her! Say it.
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(SHOUTlNG lN FRENCH)
Stop it!
l am La Longue Carabine!
My death is a great honor
to the Huron ! Take me!
Did you tell him?
Yes.
(SPEAKS HURON)
Stop!
l said
to take me.
Take me!
My compliments, sir.
Take her and get out!
Duncan. . . What are
they doing to Duncan?
Where's Alice?
Alice!
(ALL CHEERlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
(lNAUDlBLE)
Uncas!
(SOBBlNG)
Great Spirit and
maker of all life,
a warrior goes to
you swift and straight
as an arrow
shot into the sun.
Welcome him,
and let him
take his place
at the council fire
of my people.
He is Uncas,
my son.
Tell him to be patient
and ask death for speed,
for they are
all there but one,
l, Chingachgook,
the last of the Mohicans.
ENGLlSH - US - PSDH