" The legend of the zorro "
Translated for * Euzonemais *
1850 -the people of California
poor and desperate it is about...
joining at the same time to the union
that becomes the third state...
I lower the governor's regime
a voting is the key
of its destiny
and of its promise of freedom.
Inácio
What are you making?
Playing the bells...
so that if there is
problems, the zorro is knowing
If I don't make a mistake, Zorro...
it is already here
Legend Esp. and Sync: Cyberpunk
Translation of * * *EUZONEMAIS * * *
It doesn't think you would owe
to be in the school?
Priest...
Zorro will come
I will certify myself that him
come to see you.  What do you find?
Does he/she speak serious?
The earth is not worth anything else
We have to wait that the rest
of California it is not lost
Light that for the governor
Brother
carefully
Our future
it is in its hands
Yes, gentleman
That area is
a lot it pacifies....
The most recent model
of weapon of high caliber...
Henry of two loads
If God was here,
with certainty, he/she would bring one of those
What does bring it here McGibbons?
I didn't still vote
Oh! that grieves...
...mas, the votings are shut
That I don't think right
I am also entitled
Now, it could be gentile...
and to give me that box
And I will follow my road
He/she will only do with that the people
vote again
but he/she remembers...
Babylon was in ashes
for blame of the inferior race
I come to do the work of God
with that voting
It is hour of doing the work
of you
Zorro! Zorro!
Move!
On the hill,
for the governor's house
We are going, I said on the hill
Zorro! Zorro!
What was?
Where are my men?
They were arrested, Governor...
And I helped them
Zorro! Zorro!
Citizens of São Mateu
In the day today, we joined
to the union...
as a free state
the peace is just the beginning
Inside of three months
all the votes of everybody the towns
of the california
counted seram
And I wait
that finally, we will be called
North American
Zorro! Zorro!
See, see as the stirrup
he/she is crowding together, friend.
Speak to me what won
tell me that are free
We are free
For continuing together
For us
I would like to have accompanied you
It would like
I cannot believe in you
We have our turn lives
Now we can take
Joaquim for Spain...
...eu doesn't imagine as
it should have been moving
It is New York
we should see New York
It is as if everyone
it had moved
in a great city
I was thinking
That is not a good sign
In California...
he/she will still have movement
next 3 months.
Yes
The federal ones
they could need help
until they have the
total controls
He/she looks at, I know what you are thinking,
Elena..
Elena, Elena listens to me...
We are close of being free
I don't get to believe in you
I cannot believe that
I feel like this...
Its husband promised to renounce
And the frank wife, believed in him
How could I be so stupid?
You are exaggerating
Exaggerating?
You promised
We made a promise
You are getting lost completely
of its son's life.
No, not I am not
lost of anything
- Serious?
- Serious
How is its teacher's name?
That is very easy,
he/she calls himself Mr. Irmão ...Sr. Father
King, Jim, Huffer?
Good, I have a terrible memory
What does that, prove?
That doesn't know its own son
And worse still...
He doesn't know you
What does prefer that I do?
To live as a foreman
Only giving orders to the servants
Is it that what it believes that I do?
Only ordering the servants
Don't repeat my words
The people need Zorro
No, you need Zorro
Look at for my eyes, and speak to me
that is deceived.
He/she remembers than
did he/she tell me?
When was Joaquim born?
My family is my life
He/she knows the all it is lucky
when arriving here
with life
and that its enemies
they didn't discover, who we are
For ten years
You have been fighting
to take California to the freedom
Because not ours
freedom?
They are calling you
That is what I am, Elena
That is what I am
What happened with the man
with which I got married?
What happened with the woman
what did to my side fight?
I had a son
Ok...
You turned into one
aristocrat
that doesn't have idea from where it comes
And that doesn't import it anything
plus than only to herself.
To do for that door...
...não will sleep here that night.
Perhaps, I should take a suitcase
I wait that you and Tornado
be happy together
We will be
I love you
I see with my eye that
something that begins with...
H "
Why dad didn't drink coffee with us?
I already told you, he left early
to do some business
He/she always has business
It is like this
Then, what does he make?
Good, he is a boss...
and he/she meets with other bosses
and they discuss
plans and investments
it is very important
Then the time passes
counting the money?
Joaquim!
Be not so rude with its father
You resemble him, a lot
plus than you imagine
Could we speak later about that?
I love you
Who are you?
The question Mrs. of her Vega
is it, who are you?
The devote wife of a rich Sr?
Or a woman captured by the
secrets of its husband?
What do want?
Its help
One
I will tell you something Of her Vega
The women say that only want
a thing of us...
When in fact, they want...
...tudo.
Light as some vacations
of the torture of the marriage.
You think the women
they get married because they want to pass
more time with the husband?
It is crazy
Then, it lets me to understand that
If I follow its advice...
I will finish my days in a room
full of skinned men
Thank you for the advice, but not.
For where are you going?
To ask pardon for Elena
For heaven's sake!
Some of you is
talent Alejandro Of la vega?
Yes
Fineas Gender
Lawyer
I am here, representing
its wife
If he/she has some question
My address is on
the letter
Good morning Mr.
Gentlemen
I inform of I divorce
3 months later
Excuse Sr...
..mas told me for certifying me that he/she didn't let to sleep him, after 2 in
the afternoon, on that day
What day is today?
Wednesday
Clear!
I have go look for Joaquim
Curse
What did with my clothes happen?
I removed at night of you, so that not
you of that pneumonia.
Did you remove of me?
Last night, when it returned
of the tavern...
...Você went swim.
With clothes?
Yes sr.
Does the hotel have pool?
We have a source
I am selling...
good, thank you Lupe...
perhaps he/she should give the turn
I will see you in the confession box,
my daughter
Don't see like this me
I know what will say
No, I didn't come, to lower yours
moral, but yes to increase it
Who told you that
did I need that?
Alejandro, you are being
an obstinate
Because it won't be with elena and he/she tells it
what was deceived?
She is to who wanted to live like this
That stopped being who I am
That California would live without me
He/she wakes up, friend
I have not been playing
the bell for 3 months...
It should be happy...
I am
Certain
Now he/she can run in the sun
for ever
It swallows it that night
and take it for celebrating that night
All my life is a party
Thank you, but not
As to prefer
But it is not irritated in coming to admit,
why won't I forgive you
It blackmails my soul
Of course yes
Now
Somebody more he/she wants to interrupt
the lesson with a...
can I go to the bathroom "?
Hm?
No
Who can tell me what means
that word?
Joaquim?
Joaquim Of her Vega!
Perhaps, he/she can say to the class, which
it means for you
without more explanations of the
oppressions of the rich ones
they want to oppress us with the injustices
and as it explains, as if
it inserts that idea
it fits...
in its behind
I will give you something for you to laugh
It comes here
Better, that I don't get you to reach
for inside
What was with you?
Thank for they catch not you
and they arrested you for a lifetime
It arrives, don't give me excuses
Why does continue seeking fights?
you don't understand, sometimes
it is necessary to fight
Oh, truth
Who does that say?
He said that
Listen
He doesn't think like this, the fights nor
it is always the answer
You as he/she knows, what is the one what he/she thinks?
trust me, I know it more
that you can believe
It is not correct
You were never in a fight,
in its life
Not even, it fought for the mom
I am its father, rapazinho
don't speak like this to me
There is not anything in that world, that I don't do
for you and for its mother, you understand
Small José
It is igualzinho to its mother
Look at for you, Joaquim
It is growing so fast
if I negotiate it to continue growing
We can pay it very shortly
I told you godfather that
it was a present
for my afilhado
That knife costs 2 Dollars.
Good, I will give you 500 dollars for her
But, perhaps me her light for my ranch
with your gratitude
For you, we won't sell anything
To dead men like you, me
I am with its wives
They said that they won't sell, Mister
Had we known each other already before?
Mister
I would remember one
man like you
And I would remember one
mexicaninho like you
dad. he/she will cry teeny
Leave it alone
Mr. as horseman, I owe
to teach my son
Is everything well gentlemen?
To respect the official
I respect, respect
Think of my offer
I will be grateful
10 min. then I am leaving
mmm, that is delicious
Who did give you permission to drink?
he/she never understands me, I should take advantage of
As it goes
He/she doesn't have more medicine
It arrived at little time
he/she is the only person of Dom Galo
A French count, do you say?
It was probably robbed, the
its title
Perhaps a fine perfume
He/she would have to avoid to pay
Are you?
Alejandro of La Vega
Are you of la Vega?
It is a honor
I already heard a lot on you
in fact
Of who?
I would like to continue with that
he/she talks, but me precise to go
Is a charming type, doesn't it find?
Who can be?
Ladies and gentlemen
Welcome
Because we called that of exhibition, if
after a wineglass, everything is the same
French
Californian
This vineyard...
...representa, which I wait that...
he/she will become in an industry that
it will depend on the people
for the success
involving them
in the place of exploring them
that is it that the america
it means for me
the a parents' promise
of the people, for the people
a blessed parents with great beauty
a surprise this late...
Gentlemen and ladies
What surprise? we are leaving of here
No, I don't want to go already
I am having a good time a lot
Mister and lady Vond
a lot of pleasure in knowing it
Alejandro
Elena
Armad
Of la Vega
Conde
Do they know each other?
We talked a little
in the table of the foods
And it seems that divided
plus than that
Allow to clear up me a little
the situation
Elena mentions it as
a man of excellent education
It is a honor to be mentioned...
When he/she asked me the
I divorce 3 months ago
Me abençoo its union, thank you
for inviting us
we have something urgent to do
Be not not well educated Felipe
It will be in another ocasião,temos many
guests for recepcionar
Armand, good night
governor, thank you for having come
It lets me to come
my wife Maria
Its speech was very touching
I am happy that won't order the
my husband for an office
He/she would not dare to challenge
to the liberator of the california
I fear that doesn't remain a lot of
union here, governor
Gentlemen, allow to present them
to the colonel, of the infantry of the alabama
What did bring it here, colonel?
the aroma of the war, wanted
When California goes of the union
the army will be smaller
my country doesn't have problems
ah, Armand knows like me me
I upset with it politicizes her
We will dance
Clear
With its permission, gentlemen
Gentlemen and ladies
The imperial orquesta
He/she is sure in doing that
Perhaps if I placed some lipstick
in you, it would seem with my mother
Then, that man leaves you
dazzled
How did he/she guess?
you know to who I refer
Elena worries me
You wanted to stand back of all this
From when, do you like of it politicizes?
From when you worry with
what do I think?
If he/she wants it, go speak to him
I cannot support it
We have to go auspiciously of that position
but me not
He/she should tell me as he/she met him
in the court of Spain
We finished the together school
that I border, they finished together
he/she didn't want to be embarrassed
It excuses, very late
As soon as
Do tell me count?
When its position stops being Conde
and does he/she become Duke?
It is actually very common
As to be A Talent
It is a beauty
it is rich, beautiful and of the royalty
There is something that I can tell you
for you to go auspiciously
Yes, that kneels down and ask
to return with you
clear, but I don't want to ruin
my dress
But, I like to be single
That, I have to be zealous
yes
Tell me who was, taking care of Joaquim
while its mother leaves at night
I don't leave, I take care of Joaquim,
then it is leaving
I loosen
Finally, why I understand
he/she left me Elena
He/she was embarrassed of being married
with somebody poor like me
no, it is not right
Its father was very happy
that took its place...
Lower the voice
Congratulations highness!
If it is that that thinks of me,
perhaps...
...nunca met me
Thank you, for its hospitality
Conde
I think will need reinforcements
he/she doesn't forget of something, stupid
Conde Armand
Its fine wine and yours
foreign accent
Like her it can be with one
man as that
I will do with that he/she wishes me of turn,
with that crawls of love for me
Nobody leaves my hot tequila
forgotten in the wind
My God
an alms, alms
an alms, God the abençoe
That kind
It was to impress you
Yes, with certainty, he/she wants to impress me
It invites me for having dinner that night
Make something delicious for me
Good, we will have dinner then in its farm
I would like to know its son
Try to understand Armand...
... My .o son is not still ready for
to see me with other man
Yes, I understand
What was?
Those hats
They are pretty
Oh!
To want...
...eu can buy them for you.
Although, thinking well,
So that he/she wanted another hat
The one that me precise
A pipe!
A pipe?
As in the one that my father smoked
I hope is not inconvenienced with mine
extranhos habits
No, not to the I thwart
they surprise me
Hear, look at for there, there is a salesperson
- Wait for me here
- Yes.
What do you make here?
From when you like of
in pipe?
I don't smoke
I said that for coming undone of him,
while I came undone of you
I have to talk
with you at night.
I forgive you
Now good-bye
No, not that not...
...depois,eu saw something in the forest /
Of the one what do talk they?
Yes!
Do they talk on the one what?
Thank you
An explosion
In fact, close to its vineyard
Something that I had never seen
I was only to see they were well
As yesterday the night drank too much
...com certainty, its vision was
darken
But shortly it was clear
An advice...
Some respect is had by the
relationship that had with Elena
Leave that lives with dignity
I have to have certainty that I leave it with
a good man
That I can give you certainty
It arrives, it is already enough
Alejandro,
it is hour of you it to go auspiciously
Elena please
If Alejandro came
for something at least he/she has to give it
Perhaps we can arrange that as
gentlemen
Did it already play pole, certain?
Of course yes
I suggest, that we play
as it is played in my earth.
Beautiful city
Parents
Naturally
- Can I offer it something to drink?
- Tequila with salt
Perhaps a poker departure
it would be less harmful for its health
Did he/she fall it something?
or does he/she only rest?
He/she knows, I think I like
he/she gave game
Promise me, that when
to lose, he/she will leave us alone
What does make you to think that I will lose?
Feminine intuition
For the winner
there are not pretexts
Now, maintain yours
promise and leave
He/she cheated,
it is not worth like this
Good-bye Alejandro
What does know about that name?
We should never have ourselves married
He/she doesn't love him
After 10 years of
marriage with me
It cannot hide
the truth
The cantineiro, heard in its tavern
of here in front...
McGibbons to say
its names....
...que would do
something for Cortez
Its father asked me for
to look for you...
Cortez!
The writings, please
Non Guilhermo, not give
Please, gentleman
That earth is everything that we have
" You, it had expelled them
before you leave
that them
possess its lands "
Salvation and curse
He/she has a thing in common
He/she has to die for one of the two
Serious?
Play the weapons
Everybody
Guilhermo, Blanca
they are going for inside
You are a blind mexicaninho
he/she doesn't know where he/she is entering
It is much less you
don't allow that hurt you
I won't leave, I promise you
Guilhermo, please speak to me
He/she speaks to me
please, guilhermo
What is that you try to tell me?
Without importing that decision takes
I always make a mistake
I failed with everybody
that I love
My wife, my son
and now with the people also
What does want of me?
It helps me
I always hear my heart
He/she speaks to me
for the love of God
Guillermo Cortez was
only the beginning
It is now Elena it is
running a lot of danger
Then, I beg it that
Give me courage...
...e forces...
to carry it it chews
a little more.
It helps me to demonstrate that
Zorro was right
It will go to the vineyard
We will place a man in the door
in the case, that is a snare
We be had problems with her,
then it won't serve us more
Consider it as one
acceptable loss
Master Armand
Please...
..desculpe, one moment.
That is very beautiful
And the one behind that door what is there?
The chapel
It is a long family tradition
I would show you but...
...não has time.
That was delicious
It is now
Oh! excuse
I don't smoke
Unless it is in my pipe
Clear
Ah remembered, né
That kind
But I think I should leave mine
stomach to improve first
Elena...
I want to wonder something
Something that should wonder
there is a long time
Before that,
my love.
Answer me a thing
The one that you to want
Where is the bathroom?
It would like to clean
the nose
Clear
It is in the runner
Excuse
It excuses Mr.
There is somebody that wants to see it
He/she said that is important
It is a snare
As I understand, he has
the writings
But it was necessary to interrupt
my dinner?
I am here
but, I think have a problem
or he/she should say a zorrinho
or Zorro?
I heard that among the places
He/she is a peasant masked as
Monday hero
Men like this, finish always
in the guillotine
They informed me that some of my ships
it will arrive tomorrow
The sailor's anchor
The load should arrive here
the safe
Without erross