There is not one universe. There are many.
A Multiverse.
We have the technology
to travel between universes...
...but travel is highly restricted
and policed.
There is not one you. There are many.
Each of us exists in present time,
in parallel universes.
There was balance in the system...
...but now a force exists
who seeks to destroy the balance...
...so he can become The One.
President Gore addressed Congress today
where he outlined the White House plan....
Here they come, man.
They're going to take you on out.
You're dead, LawIess! You're dead!
Ain't payback a bitch?
Die, LawIess, you piece of shit!
Die Iike aII my boys you took out!
I know they're going to kiII you upstate...
...but no one's getting you on my watch,
so don't sweat, LawIess.
You want that thumb?
Let's move him out of here.
I want to hear you scream, LawIess.
Come on, scream for me.
Going to get you, asshoIe!
Yeah, waIk the waIk!
You piece of shit! You're a dead man!
Something's wrong.
Prisoner down!
Up there!
HoId your fire! Cease fire!
Woo, Scott, foIIow me!
Razor wire shouId have kept anyone out,
Iet aIone moving fast.
There's no bIood.
HoIy shit! He's doing 50!
Adam 13 in pursuit ofsuspect
headed west, Third and Olympic.
Request assistance
from 2 David air unit. Over.
Roger that.
Air 14 en route to Third and Olympic.
He's going to the hoIe.
We have to get there,
override him before he jumps.
Give me the go-ahead. He'II never make it.
Check fire. Stick to procedure, Funsch.
You were recruited to apprehend him,
not be his assassin, understand?
I can't hear you. Do you understand?
Loud and cIear.
YuIaw! MVA!
Loud and cIear, huh?
Roedecker! Less than a minute!
Shit!
Hands high!
Thirty seconds, Roedecker.
Who the heII is this now?
You must be the new guy.
Where is Roedecker?
This is your Iast warning.
Get your hands where I can see them.
Freeze!
You, drop that weapon!
I wiII kiII you.
No, you won't.
Where is Roedecker?
-Here I am.
-What the....
Funsch.
You stick to procedure...
...it aII works out.
Victim 117, Yu Fook Law,
Monoceros Universe.
Victim 118, Swen Law, Tucana Universe.
Victim 119, Ni Dilaw, Canopus Universe.
Victim 120, Kia Jilaw, Serpenz Universe.
Victim 121, Seth Law, Procyon Universe.
Victim 122, Frun Law, Shauwla Universe.
Victim 123, Lawless, Anubis Universe.
What's the next move?
It won't work for you anymore, YuIaw.
The shortest distance
between two points...
...wiII aIways be a straight Iine.
Your Iine has run out. You don't see that?
There's never been anything
Iike what I have become.
You know that.
You were there for my first one.
-I wish I'd never Iet there be a second.
-But there was a second.
And a third.
And a 123rd.
Why did you come, Harry?
You miss me?
I missed who you were.
You've been chasing me how many years?
Two years.
I just need to do it one more time.
There won't be a ''one more time'' for you.
Destination:
Stygian Penal Colony, Hades Universe.
GabrieI YuIaw.
The peopIes of the MuItiverse
have found you guiIty...
...of 123 counts of first-degree murder...
...and 123 counts of unauthorized traveI
to paraIIeI universes...
...by use of iIIegaI quantum tunneIing.
For these crimes,
you have been sentenced to Iife...
...without the possibiIity of return...
...on the Stygian PenaI CoIony,
in the Hades Universe.
May God be with you.
You may make a finaI statement.
The MuItiverse.
Every universe in it is irrationaI...
...sIoppy.
I just try to make it rationaI.
I just try to make it neat.
You caII it murder.
How couId I murder myseIf 123 times?
I just took those wasted energies...
...and put them into one container: me.
It made me faster, smarter, stronger.
What if that is our fate?
To unite with our other seIves.
To be unified forever.
To be one.
I wiII be The One.
GabrieI YuIaw...
...are you ready?
Are you?
Wormhole opens in five...
...four, three, two, one.
WormhoIe's shut.
It onIy had a 30-second window.
Now we have to wait.
Son of a bitch!
-Permission to speak, sir?
-Speak.
Is this part of the procedure?
We'II get him on the other side.
There's onIy one pIace he couId be going.
AIdrich, take these.
President Bush addressed ajointsession
of Congress today...
...where he outlined the White House plan
for universal health care.
Ronnie, you're dead! You rat!
Die, you piece of shit snitch!
You're going to be okay, Ronnie.
You're doing the right thing.
-Go, go!
-Dead! Dead!
You snitch! Dead!
Something's wrong.
Go, go, go! Get him out! Get him out!
Get him in the vehicIe.
Get out, now. Go, go, go.
Oh, shit!
Cease fire!
Is he soup yet?
-No way he got out of there.
-He's got to be.
No!
Get him down! PuII!
One Henry Robert! Code 3!
Demand immediate backup
in the deIivery area!
Go!
I need a hand over here!
Hey, on the bus!
He's going OJ!
-Get him!
-Let's go, Yates!
Gabe!
You see that?
The good news is you're not crazy.
The bad news....
/ lived here my whole life.
And everywhere / look for great memories.
Now all / see is Larry and those kids.
Gabe.
Oh, my God!
I'm okay.
-I'm okay.
-AIdrich said you were in the hospitaI.
-Yeah, I was.
-Did they check you out?
I checked myseIf. Nothing to check. See?
I just need to get myseIf cIear. Hey, OIIie.
You were shot. You need to be examined.
You can do it.
NewsfIash. I'm a vet.
You don't have paws and a taiI.
With aII that's been happening to you,
you need to see someone.
I'm seeing the onIy person I need to see.
I'm serious.
We'II go to the hospitaI,
check on Woo, after I'm done.
You'II be aII right, man.
-You guys take care of him now.
-Yes, sir.
Gabe? Hey, T.K.
How is he?
ExternaI injuries mostIy.
EMT said he's seen a Iot worse.
You gave us a bigger scare
just Ieaving the hospitaI Iike that.
Your man went deep tonight, T.K.
Don't know how he made it up that waII.
I wouIdn't be here if you guys
didn't make it up right behind me.
We never made it up that waII.
I didn't make it out
of the goddamn parking Iot.
Backup unit reported you down.
We continued pursuit, unsuccessfuI.
OnIy you got a good Iook at the suspect.
We need a description.
Think it's someone out of Ronnie's posse?
Payback for snitching?
It was dark.
You have anything? Anything to go on?
Sorry.
If you remember anything,
we'II be down the haII.
Hey, man, I'm gIad you're stiII with us.
Thanks.
Why did you Iie to them?
It was dark.
Gabe, it's not the guys. It's me.
It was me.
What?
He wasn't trying to hit Ronnie.
He was aiming at me!
Before I saw him, I feIt him.
I feIt me!
It was me.
Maybe the adrenaIine
caused some kind of haIIucination.
You were shot. Your memory
couId've been affected by the trauma.
Or maybe it's part
of what's been happening to you.
PeopIe get oIder. They don't get stronger.
They don't get faster aII of a sudden.
Whatever it is, we're here now, right?
And if they find something wrong with me?
I don't want to Iose my job.
I don't want to Iose you.
Mrs. Law,
before we go into the MRI room...
...I have some questions to ask you
about your husband.
-Does he have a cardiac pacemaker?
-No.
-IntracraniaI aneurysm cIip?
Dentures, hearing aid or peniIe impIant?
No, no, and not unIess he had one put in
since this morning.
Mr. Law. Right this way.
I have a few forms for you to fiII out.
This is a painIess procedure
so there's nothing for you to worry about.
Dressing room's here.
Remove aII your cIothing.
You'II find a gown on a hook.
The paperwork's aIready started
so we'II get you in and out in no time.
PIease remove
aII personaI metaIIic objects.
That means no keys, no watches,
no credit cards...
...no body piercings, no ceII phones....
My gun.
-No guns, no jeweIry, no zippers.
-What?
The hospitaI has it.
You're going in for an MRI. Gabe?
Remember what I said?
I feeI it again.
When you're done,
we'II go get your things, aII right?
They're not giving her your gun.
The guys are downstairs.
They can get the gun.
Even if you did, you're not bringing it here.
That's a powerfuI, precise magnet.
AII right.
If you start the MRI, I'II find the guys.
Lose the wedding ring.
Here. I got it.
For Christ's sake, you're getting an MRI,
not a heart transpIant.
Mr. Law, I need you to remain stiII
for three to ten minutes.
You can taIk, but if you move,
we have to start aII over.
Hey. Where did you guys go?
I took him in for a....
Something wrong?
Can I get you something?
No, I have to taIk to the doctor.
Mike, I can't take my break
tiII I'm done with this guy.
Can you wait haIf an hour?
Mr. Law, what are you doing?
Now we have to start over.
Why? What did I do?
Back away!
Thought you were gonna kiII me.
Just give me the chance, asshoIe.
Get on your knees sIowIy.
You there?
On the fIoor, right now!
The fIoor?
This is a hospitaI.
The fIoor is fuII of germs.
You want me to get sick?
It's gunfire.
Let's get security.
Gabe.
Get back!
What have you got?
Nothing.
Not a thing.
No! No!
Be stiII.
Unit 15, weapon fire, south tower!
Fourth floor, /maging Radiology!
Gabe is there.
-Hands high! Hands high, YuIaw!
-Don't move! Don't move!
Don't move!
We aII know if you kiII me,
you have to kiII the other guy.
-Just Iet me take out one Ieg.
-Cuff him.
I'II cover you.
Go.
Back, get back!
-It's Gabe.
-Go! ChanneI 7.
Swing the camera. FoIIow him.
He cut right at the end of the haII.
Don't move! Stay here!
Go back to the room.
T.K., you can't go up there!
Which one is he?
-I'm okay. I'm aII right.
-Don't move, Gabe! We're here to heIp.
-I'm aII right.
-Do you know where you are?
-What's wrong with you?
-Where are you, Gabe?
There are three armed men.
They kiIIed a security officer.
-Who are we?
-They went down the haII.
-What's my name?
-I was unarmed. I couIdn't go after them.
What did you do with the gun?
I don't have one. I asked T.K. to get it.
YuIaw wouIdn't have known that.
This one's safer in their custody.
Let them take him.
You need heIp before you hurt yourseIf.
Or anyone eIse.
Anyone eIse? Someone tried to kiII me!
PIease! I don't want to hurt you guys.
Let go of me!
I don't want to hurt you.
I don't want to hurt you guys.
SettIe back down!
He's cIose to YuIaw's strength.
Let go! Gabe!
It's what I toId you. It's me.
Get home.
We have a probIem here.
Yeah, the reaI probIem is
procedure sucks...
...sir.
AII right, new procedure.
Gabe is yours. I wiII take YuIaw.
How you going to do that?
I'II do whatever it takes.
Sync up your repeater.
Hey, wait a minute.
I've Iived through one of those.
Let me do it.
Sync your repeater, Funsch.
AII right.
When the green Iight turns red
and stays steady and YuIaw is dead....
And you.
You know what to do.
Not a probIem.
Us spIitting up, you going soIo,
is way out of procedure.
So Iisten to me. I know where you're from,
what you've been through...
...but this pIace is different.
Not everyone is a combatant.
There are innocent peopIe here, aIso.
So if you get into the shit,
you trust your heart...
...not your head.
Loud and cIear, sir.
How did that son of a bitch
get out of here?
Have you seen that new video,
Mr. Fanny's Been A-Pluggin'? It's hot!
Dude, I Iike Janine.
But she don't do guys.
That girI-girI stuff gets oId.
Why don't you rent one of those big-ass,
she-maIe tapes, you freak?
Shut up!
I can't determine occipitaI Iobe sweIIing
without a compIete MRI.
-He was acting schizophrenic.
-Schizophrenia doesn't just kick in.
The triggering stressor of being shot
caused a psychotic break.
The Fifth Division is Iooking for him.
They understand he's not himseIf.
They know how to bring him in.
-You okay?
-I'm fine.
-Need a doctor?
-No, I'm aII right.
I am not going to Iet
anything happen to him.
If it wasn't for Gabe,
I wouIdn't be in this uniform.
Thanks, Bobby.
-Maybe it's best if I go home.
-Good idea.
Nothing you can do here,
and he's IikeIy to contact you there.
If I hear from him, I'II Iet you know.
If you hear anything, I'II be home.
I know. I'm going to take you.
I appreciate it, but I'II be fine.
We'II make sure of it. There are four units
on the way to your house. Come on.
-CircIe around. I'II meet you out front.
-AII right.
Just when I find something
I Iike in this universe.
Turn off the radio sIowIy.
Who are you?
You're cIose to his strength.
The Iast two years, you've gotten stronger.
Haven't jacked any more iron.
Haven't changed your diet.
But you are stronger.
Your mind, too.
Answers come fast without thinking.
Who are you? What did you do to me?
Not me. You.
You've done this to yourseIf.
Just Iike oId times, eh, buddy?
Not exactIy...
...buddy.
Put your hands back on the wheeI, YuIaw.
Space is shaped Iike this.
You beIieve this is the onIy universe.
There's not just one universe,
there's a MuItiverse.
Every time a massive star dies
and becomes a bIack hoIe...
...a new universe is created.
They've Iearned to forecast
where and when a bIack hoIe wiII occur.
A momentary bridge
between paraIIeI universes.
TraveI is restricted.
They created an agency
to poIice the MuItiverse.
I'm a MuItiverse agent.
You're a nut.
You're the one who's been seeing yourseIf.
In this universe, you're you.
In another, you don't exist.
In another,
you're married to the same woman.
In another, to a different woman.
In another, you're married to a man.
There's an energy, strain, wave,
connecting aII those Iives.
We aII have one.
The one between you and him
has gotten stronger.
You've been feeIing him, haven't you?
Harry, nobody's proved
that what I'm doing is a bad thing.
You've kiIIed 123 peopIe.
I'd say that was a very bad thing.
You don't know what'd happen
if you kiIIed this one.
It couId destroy the system,
but that doesn't matter.
I know. Everything must be baIanced.
The party Iine.
What do you think wouId happen?
Some peopIe think you'd expIode,
some peopIe think you'd impIode.
You're missing one.
Some peopIe think you'd become a god.
That's the one.
The man you've been seeing,
the ''you,'' he was an MVA agent.
Once he was forced to defend himseIf
against himseIf in another universe.
KiIIed him.
In doing so, part of the other Iife's energy
transferred to him.
Made him stronger.
Made aII of you stronger.
Each time he kiIIs one of you,
the energy divides among the survivors.
So, I'm next?
You're the Iast.
You and him are it.
I don't want any part of this.
You don't have a choice.
First choice, give up. Second choice, die.
Third choice.
So, if everything you say is true...
...what happens to me?
Nobody's got aII the answers.
I don't beIieve you. Stay away.
I'm aIone now.
I'm here to heIp you.
Sir, I have to ask you to hoId it right there.
I said freeze, asshoIe!
Don't you peopIe ever Iearn?
CIear.
Let them have a Iook first.
I have to do my girI stuff.
Thanks.
TV is on.
Yeah, I Ieft it on.
When I got the caII about Gabe, I just ran.
Grabbed my jacket, rushed downstairs.
I'II turn it off.
Bobby?
I appreciate you being here with me
and I don't want to sound rude, but...
...can I have a IittIe privacy?
Sorry, T.K.
I'II be right outside.
Thanks.
I toId you it's not wasted space.
You aII right?
-I'm afraid.
-Me, too.
Is it safe to come down?
No, there are sheriffs aII over.
I need my gun.
I Ieft it at the hospitaI.
I need a weapon.
Yeah, okay.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
They can see inside.
I'm just gonna puII the shade.
Jesus. Did you ever think
when we met that day at the bookstore...
...we'd be in this kind of mess?
Even if I knew, I stiII wouId have come in.
It wasn't a bookstore.
Just so you know,
I'm going to take that gun...
...and kiII you
before you can puII the trigger.
There's nothing you can do
except give it to me.
Gabe, drop it!
Drop it now!
Drop it!
Get in!
Hey, knock it off!
-You're acting Iike him.
-I am him!
Without her.
My grandfather taught me
the energy of Iife goes in a circIe...
...in a perfect fIow, baIanced.
He said, untiI I find my center...
...my circIe wouId never be whoIe.
That day, I first saw her in the cIinic...
...I came in with a dog
that was hit by a car.
I knew right away she was my center.
She made me whoIe.
How do I kiII him?
In an hour, there's a forecasted
wormhoIe opening. Three-minute window.
He's attuned to your Iife wave.
He'II try to find you, kiII you,
and get back to the hoIe.
That's where we get him.
Get him? KiII him!
KiII him?
You're serious?
My own design.
HighIy modified M-590,
hand-portabIe system.
Fires 25 smart rounds per second.
MuItipIe tracking modes,
pIus the Iatest countermeasures.
Each round carries an expIosive warhead
with seIectabIe fuse deIays.
Tracks, enters, pauses .1 microseconds,
then ''Boom!''
Mixto rojo.
And this is his IittIe brother.
Hasn't worked yet.
Don't bIame the tooIs.
I never had the go-ahead to terminate.
Let me show you how.
That'II work, too.
We kiII him, then it's over.
Hey, you two!
Come on! Check that shit!
Let's go.
What are you doing?
Permission to speak, sir.
I know what I have to do.
I'II never get the chance to thank you
for squaring me away.
So, thank you, sir.
I'm caIIing the cops.
Just making sure you know, if we kiII him--
You have to kiII me. KiII me! I don't care.
As Iong as he's dead, I don't care.
If we kiII him...
...there's a chance, some say,
this whoIe universe couId go with him.
The Chinese guy
was tearing the pIace apart.
WormhoIe ETA: ten minutes.
That vicinity.
He's here.
Shit. Take cover!
It's a bomb! Don't breathe for 20 seconds
after the bIast!
YuIaw!
You came here for me.
Now I'm here for you.
After this, there wiII be onIy one.
I won't be The One, but neither wiII you.
Shit! Three minutes.
Thirty seconds!
Shit.
Gabe, get out! Get out!
Get out!
That's him.
Scanning, RHV 579. Confirm.
Send him where he beIongs.
Destination:
Stygian Penal Colony, Hades Universe.
Wormhole opens in one minute.
No, stop!
That's him, that's YuIaw.
Wormhole opens in 30 seconds.
Get him out!
Wormhole opens in 20 seconds.
Wormhole opens in ten, nine...
...eight, seven...
...six, five, four, three, two...
...one.
Wormhole opened.
That man doesn't Ieave this room.
Sir, he assisted in YuIaw's capture.
He's from an uninitiated universe
with no traveI passport.
He goes back.
He can't go back.
They'II Iock him up for Iife.
He wiII be cared for, watched over.
Like the other.
BaIance wiII be preserved.
The wormhoIe cIoses in 40 seconds!
-Sir, permission to speak--
-Permission denied.
That order is buIIshit!
It doesn't matter.
Take him!
I know where he has to go.
I have to send you where you beIong.
It's procedure.
Coordinates accepted.
'Bye, Gabe.
Wormhole opens in...
...five, four, three...
...two, one.
Look out!
Hey, you aII right?
OIIie?
Excuse me, I have a....
What happened?
Car.
Do I know you?
-Fresh fish.
-Got a pretty mouth.
I am YuIaw! I'm nobody's bitch.
You are mine.
I don't need to know you.
You onIy need to know me.
I wiII be The One!