BILBAO, SPAIN
So good of you to come, Mr. Bond,
particularly on such short notice.
If you can't trust a Swiss banker,
what's the world come to?
"Bon." Now that we're all comfortable,
why don't you sit down?
It was not easy,
but I have retrieved the money.
No doubt Sir Robert
will be pleased to see it again.
At the current rate of exchange,
minus the fees and certain
unforeseeable expenses.
"Voilá." Your receipt.
Would you like to check my figures?
Oh, I'm sure they're perfectly rounded.
- It's all there.
- I didn't come for the money.
The report Sir Robert bought was stolen
from an MI6 agent who was killed for it.
I want to know who killed him.
- Terrible tragedy.
- I just want a name.
I am merely the middleman. I'm just
returning the money to its rightful owner.
And we know how difficult that can be
for a Swiss banker.
I am offering you the opportunity
to walk out with the money, Mr. Bond.
I'm giving you the opportunity
to walk out alive.
Looking at our present situation,
strictly as a banker,
I'd say that the numbers
are not on your side.
Perhaps you failed
to take into account my...
hidden assets.
Get up! You seem to have had
a small reversal of fortune.
- Give me the name.
- I can't tell you.
Let's count to three.
You can do that, can't you?
One.
Two.
All right, but you'll have to protect me...
MI6 HEADQUARTERS
LONDON
James! Have you brought me
a souvenir from your trip?
Chocolates? An engagement ring?
I thought you might enjoy one of these.
How romantic.
I know exactly where to put that.
Oh, Moneypenny.
The story of our relationship.
Close, but no cigar.
I hate to tear you away, 007.
Would you mind coming in?
Right away, M.
Sir Robert King, James Bond.
Ah, the man who retrieved my money.
I can't thank you enough.
Careful, M. I might steal him from you.
Construction's not exactly
my... speciality.
Quite the opposite, in fact.
Best to the family.
- Old friend?
- We read law at Oxford together.
I always knew he'd conquer the world.
- Care for a drink?
- Yes, thank you.
- He's a man of great integrity.
- Who buys stolen reports for £3m.
Thank you.
- Any leads on the sniper?
- Not one. Professional job.
She must be working for someone.
Is this the stolen report?
Yes, classified, from the Russian
Atomic Energy Department.
What would King want this for?
He was led to believe
the document was a secret report,
identifying the terrorists
who'd attacked his new oil pipeline.
Interesting.
But it doesn't explain why someone
would want me out of their office alive.
- King! The money!
- Moneypenny, stop King.
Move! Move! Move!
Stop!
Move!
- Get out of the way!
- Medics coming through!
Stop! Stop! It isn't finished!
What was that?!
- Let's go!
- What the hell do you think?
Let's go!
Listen to me!
You can't get away. We can make a deal.
Who are you working for?
Don't do it! Don't blow us up!
I can protect you!
Do you understand? I can protect you.
Not from him.
# I know how to hurt
# I know how to heal
# I know what to show
# And what to conceal
# I know when to talk
# And I know when to touch
# No-one ever died
# From wanting too much
# The world is not enough
# But it is such a perfect place
# To start, my love
# And if you're strong enough
# Together we can take the world apart
# My love
# We know when to kiss
# And we know when to kill
# If we can't have it all
# Then nobody will
# The world is not enough
# But it is such a perfect place
# To start, my love
# And if you're strong enough
# Together we can take the world apart
# My love
# I feel safe
# And I feel scared
# I feel ready
# And yet unprepared
# The world is not enough
# No, nowhere near enough
That's right.
Hello, my dear.
- Who's that young woman?
- King's daughter.
Elektra.
Thank you.
The money was dipped in urea,
MI6 HEADQUARTERS
SCOTLAND
in effect, a fertilizer bomb.
Having handled the money,
the water on 007's hands
started a chemical reaction.
In one of the notes
the anti-counterfeiting strip
had been replaced with magnesium,
which acted as a detonator.
And King's lapel pin
was switched for a copy,
which contained a radio transmitter
to trigger the blast.
In other words,
"he" set off the bomb that killed him.
We know it was someone close to King.
And our only lead committed suicide
on that balloon.
But given the size of
King's organization,
it could be anyone, anywhere.
M.
This will not stand.
We will not be terrorized by cowards who
would murder, and use us as the tool.
We'll find these people.
We'll follow them to the farthest ends
of the earth if needs be.
And we "will" bring them to justice.
Tanner!
Sorry, James. M says you're off the active
duty list until you're cleared by Medical.
Dislocated collarbone.
If any more tendons snap, I'm afraid
you'll be out of action for weeks.
Molly, I need a clean bill of health.
You have to clear me for duty.
James,
- that wouldn't really be...
- Ethical?
Practical... smart.
Well, let's just... skirt the issue, shall we?
You'd have to promise to call me...
...this time.
Whatever the doctor orders.
And I suppose if you stayed
in constant contact...
Of course.
If you showed sufficient stamina,
- and cut out all kinds of...
- Strenuous activity?
We all have to pay the piper some time.
- Right, Q?
- Oh, pipe down, 007.
Was it something I said?
No. Something you destroyed.
My fishing boat.
For my retirement. Away from you!
Now, I want to introduce you to
the young fellow
I'm grooming to follow me.
Helps if you open the door.
And you might be?
- This is 007.
- If you're Q, does that make him R?
Ah, yes, the legendary 007 wit.
Or at least half of it.
Now I dare say, 007,
that you've met your match
- with this machine.
- Yeah?
New model, improved specs?
I thought you were on the inactive roster.
Some kind of injury?
Yes, well, we'll see about that. So?
The very latest in intercepts
and countermeasures.
Titanium armor,
a multitasking heads-up display,
and six beverage cup holders.
All in all, rather stocked!
Fully loaded, I think is the term.
- I think...
- You're not here to think.
You're here to do what I tell you.
Now go and put on the coat
and demonstrate it for 007.
But of course.
Now watch closely, please, 007.
The right arm goes
in the right sleeve, thus,
and the left arm in the left sleeve, thus.
Now, note closely, please,
pockets, poppers and zipper.
Take the lower part of the zipper
- and insert it into the...
- Oh, pull the tag!
What? You said...
Q!
Seems well-suited for the job.
You're not retiring any time soon,
are you?
Now pay attention, 007.
I've always tried to teach you two things.
First, never let them see you bleed.
And the second?
Always have an escape plan.
Good evening.
The Elektra King kidnap ordeal is over.
The Cyprus authorities say she escaped
after shooting dead two of her captors,
and is...
He shouted.
He shouted all the time.
Level One. Clearance required.
Yes, 007?
Tell me about the kidnapping
- of Elektra King.
- I wasn't aware you were on this case.
I brought the money in that killed King.
- Don't make this personal.
- I'm not. Are you?
You're the only one
who could seal her file.
Will you excuse us?
I will not tolerate insubordination, 007.
What happened?
After Elektra King was kidnapped,
her father tried to deal with it
on his own,
with no success.
So he came to me.
As you are aware,
we do not negotiate with terrorists.
And against every instinct in my heart,
every...
emotion as a mother,
I told him not to pay the ransom.
I thought we had time on our side.
You used the girl as bait.
Yes.
The money in King's briefcase
was precisely the same amount
as the ransom demand for his daughter.
It's a message.
Your terrorist is back.
Victor Zokas, aka...
Renard, the anarchist.
He was operating in Moscow in 1996.
Pyongyang, North Korea, before that.
And he's been spotted in Afghanistan,
Bosnia, Iraq, Iran, Beirut,
and Cambodia.
All the romantic vacation spots.
His only goal is chaos.
After Robert came to me
I sent 009 to kill Renard.
Before he completed the mission,
Elektra escaped.
A week later our man
caught up with the target.
He put a bullet in his head.
That bullet's still there.
How did he survive?
The doctor who saved Renard
couldn't get the bullet out.
So Renard killed him.
It's moving through
the medulla oblongata,
killing off his senses.
Touch, smell, he feels no pain...
He can push himself harder,
longer than any normal man.
The bullet will kill him,
but he'll grow stronger every day
until the day he dies.
Robert is dead,
MI6 is humiliated.
He's had his revenge.
Not quite.
Renard had three enemies
in that kidnapping.
And there's still one he hasn't touched.
Elektra.
M.
I see the good doctor has cleared you.
Notes you have exceptional stamina.
I'm sure she was
touched by his dedication
to the job in hand.
007, I want you to go to Elektra.
She's taken over the construction of her
father's oil pipeline in the Caspian Sea.
Find who switched that pin.
If your instincts are right,
Renard will be back.
- And Elektra will be the next target.
- The worm on the hook again?
She doesn't need to know the same man
may be after her. Don't frighten her.
A shadow operation?
Remember,
shadows stay in front or behind.
Never on top.
AZERBAIJAN
You, go back. Leave! This area is closed.
I'm here to see Elektra King.
James Bond, Universal Exports.
I'm Davidov, Chief of Security.
We're having some problems
with the villagers.
I've told Miss King
to stay at the office in Baku.
Oh, hell!
- Miss King, I told you to stay...
- I know what you told me.
Come with me.
Understand us and help us, God,
for God's sake.
The fact is that this is
our mutual inheritance.
This is our faith.
You mustn't allow for this.
No. My family is very well tied
to this place.
I won't allow this.
Everything will be all right.
Blessed tidings.
The church is saved!
Send the pipe around.
That's going to take weeks
and cost millions.
- Your father approved this route.
- Then my father was wrong. Do it.
- Davidov...
- I'll talk to her.
I saw you at my father's funeral.
Yes. I'm sorry.
M told me she was sending someone.
Mr.?
Bond. James Bond.
Did you know my father?
I met him once, briefly.
You seem to have inherited
his touch for diplomacy.
- Saving the church?
- And avoiding the bloodshed.
100 years ago my mother's family
discovered the oil here.
When the Soviet Union was formed
the Communists spent the next 70 years
plundering our countryside for it.
I saw the mess they left on the drive in.
The new pipeline
will guarantee our future.
But it would be a crime to destroy
what little is left of our past.
But you didn't come here
to talk about oil, did you?
No.
Tell me,
have...
have you ever lost a loved one,
Mr. Bond?
M sent me because we're afraid
your life might be in danger.
Please, I want to show you something.
I'm trying to build an 800-mile pipeline
through Turkey,
past the terrorists in Iraq, Iran and Syria.
Up here the Russians
have three competing pipelines
and they'll do anything to stop me.
My father was murdered,
the villagers are rioting,
and you have come all this way
to tell me that I "might" be in danger?
We suspect there might be an insider.
- My father's pin.
- No. A duplicate.
With a transmitter inside
that set off the bomb.
My family has relied on MI6 twice,
Mr. Bond.
I won't make that mistake a third time.
I'm going to finish building this pipeline
and I don't need your help.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have to check the survey lines.
I've always wanted to check
the survey lines.
You don't take no for an answer, do you?
No.
I hope you know how to ski, then.
I came prepared for a cold reception.
Can't land!
- Wind's too strong.
- Hold her steady.
- You ski very well, Mr. Bond.
- Seems you enjoy being chased.
Probably happens all the time.
Less often than you might think.
So this is where they meet,
the two ends of the pipeline?
Your father's legacy.
My family's legacy... to the world.
- Expecting visitors?
- No.
This isn't a social call.
Head for the gully.
I'll lead them into the trees. Go!
Go!
See you back at the lodge.
- Oh, my God, we're buried alive!
- It's all right! It's all right!
- I can't stay here!
- You're not going to.
Elektra...
- I can't breathe!
- Elektra!
- Elektra, look at me! Look at my eyes.
Look at my eyes.
Look at my eyes! You're all right.
Everything's all right. Trust me.
OK. Trust me.
BAKU
She's fine. Some bumps and bruises,
but otherwise fine. She wants to see you.
Not you, Davidov. Him.
Are you all right?
I need to ask you something.
And I want you to tell me the truth.
Who is it?
Who is trying to kill me?
I told you, I don't know.
But I'm gonna find him.
Not good enough.
After the kidnapping I was afraid.
I was afraid to go outside,
afraid to be alone, afraid to be in a crowd.
I was afraid to do anything at all.
Until I realized...
I can't hide in the shadows.
I can't let fear run my life.
I won't.
After I find him,
you won't have to.
Don't go.
Stay with me.
Please.
I can't do that.
I thought it was your job to protect me.
You'll be safe here.
I don't want to be safe.
I'll be back soon.
And who's afraid now, Mr. Bond?
Bets, please!
I want to see Valentin Zukovsky.
Impossible.
Vodka martini.
Shaken, not stirred.
Tell him James Bond is here.
Now.
I don't think you heard me.
Mr. Zukovsky will be delighted to see you.
After you.
No, after you.
I insist.
Bond! James Bond!
Meet Nina
and Verushka.
Lose the girls, Valentin. We need to talk.
Why am I suddenly worried
that I'm not carrying enough insurance?
Chill out, James.
Fine, ladies. Go on, beat it. Scram.
Bull, give them an inch.
And make sure they lose it
in "this" casino?
I'll see you later, Mr. Bond.
I see you put your money
where your mouth is.
Mr. Bullion does not trust banks.
So, what would you like to talk about?
I'm not sure I can really help you.
I'm a legitimate businessman now.
Would you care for some caviar?
My own brand, Zukovsky's Finest.
Take a look at this.
Russian Special Services.
Atomic Energy Anti-Terrorist Unit.
- Where did you find this?
- I took it off a parahawk
which tried to kill Elektra King.
Renard is behind this.
I think you and I had better have a drink.
And then after Afghanistan
the KGB decided
Renard was a liability,
and just cut him loose.
Now he works freelance.
But for whom?
There are four competing pipelines.
I'll bet half the customers in this casino
would be very happy
to see the King pipeline disappear.
- What's funny?
- Oh, nothing.
It just appears Miss King
does not share your concern.
I wanna get my money back!
Why can't I get my money?
- What are you doing here?
- The same thing you are.
Looking for the people
who tried to kill me.
Let me take you home. Now.
No. I want them to see I'm not frightened.
Miss King, how very nice to see you.
We have kept your father's chair free.
Free?
Nothing comes free from you, Zukovsky.
Your father had a credit line with us -
one million US.
I'd be happy to extend you that courtesy.
So, what's it to be?
Vingt-et-un?
Blackjack, your father's favorite?
Let's keep it simple.
One card, high draw,
$1m.
Wait.
Bury the top three cards.
You're determined to protect me.
Perhaps from yourself.
You don't have to do this.
There's no point in living
if you can't feel alive.
Queen of hearts.
It appears that you have been beaten.
By the ace of clubs.
No hard feelings. Come again soon.
Shall we?
Elektra,
this is a game I can't afford to play.
I know.
- What happened to Davidov?
- I gave him the night off.
Welcome to the Devil's Breath.
For thousands of years Hindu pilgrims
have journeyed to this holy place
to witness the wonder of the miracle
of the natural flames that never die.
And to test their devotion...
to God,
by holding the scalding rocks
in their hands
as they said their daily prayers.
Tell me, Davidov,
what happened this afternoon?
You promised me your best men.
Mr. Arkov supplied the latest weapons.
Yes, but Bond...
Bond was unarmed.
And you, Arkov?
Is everything ready for tomorrow?
I have the authorization
and the passes in the car.
And I have arranged
for a plane tonight, but...
But what?
We should scrub the rest of the mission.
The parahawks
were meant to be returned.
People will start asking questions,
even of me. Because of "his" incompetence!
I see. I see you're right.
You're right. He should be punished.
Davidov, hold this for me.
It was wrong of me
to expect so much of you.
Kill him.
He failed his test of devotion.
You can take his place, take his ID.
And do be on time.
Ah, poor shoulder!
It looks painful.
It needs constant attention.
I knew.
I knew when I first saw you.
I knew it would be like this.
Enough ice for one day.
How did you survive?
I seduced the guards. Used my body.
It gave me control.
And the rest,
I got a gun and started shooting.
And what about you?
What do you do to survive?
I take pleasure...
in great beauty.
Let's go. It's getting late.
What happened to Davidov?
- I was told to expect him.
- He was buried with work.
Let's go. Get your stuff.
OK, come on. Let's get out of here.
You're late.
Did you bring it?
The grease?
Of course.
Excellent.
Get ready. We're 10 minutes out.
And make sure you wear the ID.
KAZAKHSTAN
CENTRAL ASIA
I'm gonna go get some air.
Welcome to Kazakhstan, Dr. Arkov.
I'm a great admirer of your research.
It's not often we see someone
of your stature here.
I go where the work takes me.
Oh, by the way,
you have the transport documents?
I pulled the plutonium
out of the one inside.
- You can detonate the triggers now.
- OK.
Look,
our IDA physicist.
Don't bother. Not interested in men.
Take my word for it.
This year we decommissioned
four test sites. Not even a glimmer.
Are you here for a reason?
Or are "you" just hoping for a glimmer?
And you are?
Mikhail Arkov,
Russian Atomic Energy Department.
Miss?
Doctor...
Jones. Christmas Jones.
And don't make any jokes.
I've heard 'em all.
I don't know any doctor jokes.
This is OK.
Take the elevator down the hole.
- Your friend's already down there.
- Don't I get some kind of protection?
No, Dr. Arkov. Down there it's all
weapons-grade plutonium.
Reasonably safe.
Up here we've got hydrogen bombs
your lab built leaking tritium,
which I've spent six months
trying to clean up.
So if you need protection, it's from me.
Your friends are waiting for you.
Doctor!
Aren't you forgetting?
Yes, of course. Thank you.
By the way...
Your English is very good for a Russian.
I studied at Oxford.
Leave it! Leave it!
Come on. Let's go.
Expecting Davidov?
He caught a bullet... instead of the plane.
Get off!
Keep your mouth shut!
You can't kill me. I'm already dead.
Yeah...
- Not dead enough for me.
- You could show a little gratitude.