Texted by Sarastriz.
We have killed,
Babylonians!
Mesopotamians!
We have killed,
Assyrians!
Mycenaean’s!
Sumerians!
But-
we never had the pleasure
of killing-
an Akkadian!
Which limb do I
take first?
May the gods have pity on you!?
Because my brother, will not!
You missed!
You're lucky
we have the same mother!
Before the time of the pyramids
a fearsome horde came from the east-
and swept across the barren lands
of the ancient world.
By the law of the horde their greatest warrior
was proclaimed their king.
His name was Memnon.
He was the greatest swordsman
the world had ever seen.
With the predictions of a sorcerer who
could foretell the outcome of every battle-
Memnon slaughtered all
who resisted him-
until only a
brave few remained.
Silence!
My father has called
for silence!
Hold your tongues!
We are gathered in this place
to put our differences aside.
There is still
time for us.
The last of
the free tribes.
To stand together
against this tyrant.
With his sorcerer
at his side-
no mortal can
defeat Memnon.
And if the sorcerer
were to die?
What then?
It's too late for
your schemes, Pheron.
I've raided Memnon's caravans,
broken the supply lines to his troops-
but he still swept across
the land like a plague.
I will not send my people to their deaths
in a battle that can't be won.
And what people would that be,
Balthazar?
You are the ruler of
Nothing-
but a pile of rocks-
and sand.
If I'm no king-
why are you on your
knees before me?!
Balthazar?!
Akkadian's!
I thought they were wiped out long ago!
They are the last
of their kind.
By their hand,
the sorcerer will die.
You put your faith in a clan
of cutthroats who kill for money?
They are more than that!
They are skilled assassins-
trained for generations
in the deadly arts.
And what price, do these
mercenaries ask from us, father!
20 blood-rubies.
But that's the last of
our treasury.
Be quiet!
If these men kill the sorcerer,
will you fight?
So be it!
As long as one of us still breathes-
the sorcerer will die!
Assassin!
Him-
we kill for free.
We can reach Memnon's encampment
by nightfall.
When are you going to get rid
of that filthy beast?
He doesn't mean anything
by it.
Horses are faster.
Camels are smarter.
That one is mine.
Live free.
Die well.
Stop!
Listen to me!
I am a high priest of Seth.
Spare me and I shall bless thee
in five different languages.
You're screwed in five
different languages.
Wait!
Not that heavy.
Look out for the fat one!
He's behind you!
Help me!
Whoever you are!
Thank you, thank you!
Good sir!
Quiet!
Surely, you heard of the enormous reward
for my safe return?
The sorcerer’s tent!
Back!
That way!
Find the other one!
You been betrayed,
Mathayus.
You know my name?
And why you're here.
He's in the tent!
A living, breething
Akkadian!
This is a rare pleasure!
I hear you trained yourself
to bear great pain!
You must teach me this.
If you live long enough.
Not looking so full of yourself,
are you now, assassin.
You.
You betrayed your own father.
Yes.
He was very shocked.
You could tell on the look
on his face.
By my fathers head-
I pledge my allegiance.
You've proven your loyalty,
Takmet.
This one still lives.
Beautiful.
Bring him to me.
Mathayus.
Live free!
Die well, my brother.
So.
How shall this one die?
He shall not die tonight.
Really?
- We shall see.
- Nor shall he die by your hand-
or any hand you command.
You have seen this
in a vision?
To ignore this, would bring
great misfortune.
The gods show him favour
this night.
Just the gods?
What a puzzle then !
How to kill you without using my hand
or any hand I command !
Fascinating,  isn't it?
The smoke, it causes the fire ants to
abandon their homes, you see ?
All the sooner to feast on
our naked heads.
- You think it's funny !?
- A little bit funny, yes, you see-
I am about to escape while you on
the other hand-
are about to die a horrible death,
for leaving me to die last night !
So what are you waiting for ?
You see that one over there ?
He's been drinking that jak-piss for about
an hour now....and very soon-
ah, you see !
Hey, where's the horse thief ?
Hark, come on.....get me out of here.
You-
promise not to kill me?
Yes, I promise.
Remember, you are an Akkadian, if you make
an oath you always have to keep it, right ?
That's right.
Promise to take me with you and
share in the spoils of you're adventures.
What?
Fine, yes !
I promise.
Now hold still.
Here's one.
That's a big one !
And here comes the mother !
So, where are we going ?
To Memnon's kingdom
to avenge my brothers death.
Never touch the bow !
No problem.
- Who are you calling ?
- My ride.
It's a nice camel.
Not much room up here.
Scoot up, please !
Hey, we had a deal !
Right,
and I haven't killed you...yet !
What news from
my sorceress today ?
Good news ?
Your armies will conquer
in the west.
Queen Isis' forces will scatter
to the four winds.
Give the generals the news. Have them
make their armies ready for the final campaign.
Yes, my lord.
You think I'm cruel,
don't you ?
Perhaps you forgotten what it's
like outside these walls !?
Heartless, ignorant-
and savage.
But I can change that.
I will bring order after
centuries of chaos.
An order which will last for
a thousand years.
Rivers of blood can never
bring peace.
But they can bring obedience !
That will suffice for now !
And when I become
the king of legend-
then you should take your place beside me...
...on the throne-
and in my bed.
But my lord-
in your bed,
I will loose my gift of sight-
and you would loose your
advantage in battle.
The day I speak of...is that when
I no longer need your visions.
Gomorra.
Let me tell you ! After a hard day of looting and
pillaging, there's no greater city than Gomorra !
Except,  maybe Sodoma.
I wish I could join you.
You're not going ?
Believe me,  I like to even the score
with a few of those red-guards myself !
But with the price they got on my head,
I'll never make it through those gates.
I have faith in you, my friend.
You'll get us in !
You see!  They got the city sealed up
tighter than a crabs buttocks.
- I wish there was something I could do to help...
- Oh, but there is !
- What business do you have here ?
- I've come to collect a bargain...a horse-thief.
I know this dog !
They behead him for sure this time.
He'll be all the prettier
without it.
- What happened ?
- You got us in. I knew you could do it.
A jug of your finest wine for my
roadweary friend here.
Wait a minute...the last thing that...I remember...
..was this huge akkadian fist coming...
- Here's your wine, sir.
- ....to my ....
- Let me know if there's anything else you like.
- It's good to be back in the big city !
- Watch my camel for me ?
- Gladly.
Been working here long time ?
How's the kebab ?
"Merchandise of the highest quality ! Virgin-steel forged
by the monks of Pompey."
"Here they are ! The worlds finest swords !
You can't get respect in Gomorra without them."
"Birds of paradise ! Birds of prey !
The most beautiful birds in the world !"
Hey, soldier !
Those big muscles look clamp.
- Perhaps one of us can help you relax.
- Maybe all of us !
Mister, Mister guidance !
You need a guide to find your way.
A good guide might be able to show
me the way into Memnon’s palace.
But a smart guide wouldn't... or he'd
be shown into...Memnon’s dungeons !
I don't have it !
Do you want to earn this one ?
Are you ready! I kill half, you kill half !
Alright.....I kill them all !
How about we go around them
and not kill anyone ?!
- Good Lord ! Are you going to kill me ?
- Maybe later.
Memnon is always threatening
to have my head.
- Don't touch that !
- What is it ?
- It's my special magic powder.
- Magic powder ?!
Yes, magic powder. It's a Chinese formula that
I procured at great expense.
If I get the recipe right it will move mountains
clear roadways at an instant.
Do great things...wonderful things-
or terrible things !
Like all my inventions, Memnon will try
to use it for war.
- Where is Memnon ?
- Why, you mean to kill him ?
Yes.
In that case,
I'd say he's in the training-courtyard.
No, let me go !
I didn't do anything.
You know the penalty
for thievery.
An intruder !
Follow me !
- You again !
- How do I get out of here ?
- Through that door.
- What's that ?
It's one of my latest inventions.
It was meant to be a quick means of transportation
but there was a little problem with the landings.
Open !
- Don't touch that you'll set it off.
- Right !
A man !
- What is this place ?
- The Memnon harems. But he visits so rarely.
And it gets so lonely.
- Can't you leave me alone, Thorak ?
- Watch your tongue, Philos.
Careful with those !
They're delicate instruments.
You're lucky that Memnon has
a taste for your science-
old fool !
If I find out that you had anything to do
with this intruder, I will send the executioner.
We know how to please.
- I'm sure you do, ladies...
- Stay with us !
- That's nice but now isn't a good time...
We will make you're every
fantasy come true.
Kill him !
After him !
Go get him !
Well......are you going to try to kill
me or just stare at me !?
Take a breath.
Gods be praised !
How dare you touch me !
Sorceress, I'm an Akkadian,
hired to kill you.
I find myself in a position where you're more use
to me alive..don't make me change my mind.
And he said "it's not the size of the
hump, it's the motion of the camel."
Alas,
I must leave you now.
- There is the traitor !
- Holy Great Covens!
He's dead ! Just admit it, you smelly camel.
I'm you're master now, you belong to me !
He's dead...dead !
Dead !
- You are alive ! I knew it !
- Right.
I was just saying to the camel :
Camel, no one could kill our
good friend, Mathayus !
Get on.
Why should I make it easy for you ?
You're sworn to kill me.
- Others will die first.
- That's comforting.
- So...who is your friend ?
- Memnon’s sorcerer.
Memnon’s sorcerer! Are you insane ?!
She could get us all killed.
Memnon will have to leave the safety of
his palace to get her !
So you're going to use me first
and then kill me. I feel so much better.
I could always do it the other way
around and kill you first ?!
- So, where are we going ?
- The Valley of the Dead.
The Valley of the Dead ?!
Nobody goes there !
That's why they call it The Valley of the Dead !
Wait for me, please !
Take a dozen of your best men, track him down,
kill him....and bring her back to me !
- Send me news when he's dead.
- Yes, my lord.
My lord !
There are rumours spreading to the armies
that she's gone.
Is this true ?
- It is, my lord.
- Then silence them !
They must believe she's here
if only for a short time.
And when you find the Akkadian-
give him this from me.
- Are we where I think we are ?
- Yes......home !
Where are you going,
sorceress ?
In a hurry to get back
to Memnon ?
Nor am I in a hurry to get away from you !
I never go back to Memnon !
He kept me prisoner since
I was a child.
Why did you help me,
that night in the tent ?
I knew you were the one man
who could help me escape.
Run if you like, but there are
worse dangers out there, than me ?
What do you mean you can't find it ?
I know it's around here, somewhere.
- What are you looking for ?
- Just a little place to get out of the storm.
- What storm ?
- You'll see.
- Thorak.
- Memnon didn't come, did he ?
- He sent his maggots to do his work.
- He's smarter than you think !
Or more cowardly.
Can I go home now ?
Stay here.
Cover up. It'll be safe.
- He's attacking....alone !
- The sun has fried his brain !
A thousand duranas to the one
who brings me his head !
Akkadian bastard !
Where is he ?
This way !
You two first !
Stay on the stones.
Come with me.
Don't touch that !
Coward !
Show your face !
The Akkadian !
Mathayus!
You're alive ! You swatted them like lice !
You are invincible !
Tell me !
Do you think you can save him ?
His fever is high.
A scorpion bit him.
If he does live-
the blood of the scorpion
will always flow through his veins.
Sorceress...?!
It's a miracle.
She cured you. I knew it.
I felt her magic !
It almost killed her but the gods,
they where on our side.
Why ?
Why would you risk your life to save mine ?
Because I believe you
can save the people.
The people are not my problem.
Memnon is.
You and the people have
the same problem.
- Pardon, my lord, a message from Thorak.
- Finally, the Akkadian is dead.
- Is there something wrong, my lord.
- Not at all.
Everything is in order.
In fact things are going so well....
...that I'm moving up our planes.
Tomorrow night we feast to
celebrate our appending victory.
And then we'll drive the last
of the rebels into the sea.
Now go.
My lord.
It is customary for the sorceress
to be present at these meetings.
- Why is she not here today ?
- She's indisposed.
It is nothing serious,
I hope ?
If it was serious.....
...then you would know about it !
Now, go !
She's alive.
She's with him and he's coming here.
Get ready !
It works...
...it works !
My lady, how lovely to see you out here
in this desolate place !
Let me show you... it works !
Come...come.
My lady sorceress.
You see !
I worked it out.
My Chinese formula.
My magic powder works.
All I needed was salt, Peter's salt.
It was here all the time.
This place is just full of it.
By the way, do any of you
happen to have any water ?
- What do you think, is it safe to drink ?
- Not anymore.
Delicious, you see the sandstone must act
as a natural filter. - Quiet...!
I'm alive....I'm alive...
...for the moment.
- Mathayus!
- Move !
Assassin !
The Gods are good to me.
When we last met you offered to kill me.
Now I have a chance to return the favour.
You trespass here.
Our survival depends on this
place being kept a secret.
So we have a problem,
as long as you're alive.
No problem ! I can keep a secret,
like no other...in fact....
I can not remember how we got here...
...we took a left turn....
- It's to late for that.
- Balthazar!
This place is sanctuary for all
of Memnon’s enemies, you know that !
- This man is dangerous.
- You're judgment is clouded.
My judgement keeps all of you alive !
This man cannot be trusted...and I'll prove it.
Bring the woman to me !
The first man to touch her will have
to come through me !
I hoped for nothing less !
That's not fair !
No !
Do you yield ?
- Never !
- Then you're a fool.
- We're brothers in the same cause.
- Brothers ?
You brought death to my people.
Memnon will follow you-
he will come for his sorceress.
Yes, I know who she is !
Memnon will stop at nothing
until she's returning.
He'll come swiftering deadlier once he has her.
Memnon will stop at nothing.
Hide here as long as you can, but believe
me when I say he'll find you.
And if he isn't stopped, he'll sweep across
this land and kill all of you.
And who's going to stop him, Akkadian ?
You ?
Will you stand alone before the fury
of his armies ?
Yes.
A gentleman always lets the lady win !
That's two out of three ?
- Dates ?
- Oh, thank you !
Cassandra!
I've had a vision.
Memnon will follow me here
and destroy these people.
You know this ?
The things I see are like
shimmers in a pond.
Some are certain and some
are like shadows.
But I do know this :
Memnon will release his armies
and ride straight through this place.
Memnon will die by my hand.
It seems the Gods favour me
tonight, Akkadian !
If you face Memnon...
...you will die !
- That is your destiny.
- I make my own destiny.
I need your help.
- Where do you think you're going with my horse ?
- To Gomorra.
Nothing we can say will
stop him.
Without your sorceress ?
She returned to save the lives of your people.
I won't let her face Memnon’s wrath alone.
Step aside.
Akkadian.
You 're riding to your death !
If I let you ride alone...
...what glory would there be left for me ?
This night we celebrate.
Eat...
...and drink your fill-
for tomorrow, we ride into battle.
I would have captured them myself
but he ran like a coward-
and left this bow behind.
My lord...there is something that
is troubling our soldiers
How distressing.
Do tell !
It's been said, that the sorceress
is no longer by your side.
Soldiers will fall prey to idle
palace-gossip.
You have my word,
she's perfectly safe.
If the men are to fight,
to die... they may need more than that.
- You doubt my word ?
- It is not that, sire.
It's just that she's a symbol from
which the men derive courage.
Symbols are most effective
when seen !
My lord !
I am here at your request.
Pardon my absence.
I was not well. But our appending
victory has lifted my spirit.
Is this sufficient to placate your men ?
Tell him what you see, sorceress.
I see a great victory.
Your enemies will reveal themselves to you.
Halt !
What is in the cart ?
What is in the cart ?!
Actually...it's a bit of a surprise.
A gift for tonight’s festivities.
Prince Takmets request.
Very nice.
Well now.
Let's see that pretty little face.
Now go to my chambers.
We have things to discuss.
My sincerest apologies,
my lord.
I understand.
You are fearful ....weak !
The feast is over !
To bed men,
for tomorrow we conquer !
Fortify the palace guard.
Alright.
That was the easy part.
- Everybody know what to do ?
- Cripple the guards.
- Alight the powder.
- And try not to get killed.
- What are you doing here, you could get hurt?
- So could you !
Stay in the wagon.
You watch yourself,
Akkadian !
No need for concern, miss !
Oh...he's going to pay for that !
Seal the gates.
Seal all the gates.
Though I'm relieved to
see you unharmed-
I am somewhat surprised
the Akkadian didn't kill you !
He was after you !
I was merely a pawn.
- But you escaped his grasp ?
- I'm not without my wiles.
Yes, I'm well aware of that.
Bring them.
Tomorrow, my victory
is complete.
- That is your vision ?
- As I said, I have seen it.
Have you ?!
I sense a change in you.
You seem somehow...
...diminished.
I assure you,
I am myself.
Good.
A small demonstration shouldn't
trouble you then.
A simple test.
Now, go !
Everyone leave !
- Where am I going ?
- Stop !
It's over there.
It should be just there.
Good man.
Well, well...
...what do we have here ?
One at a time !
Six urns...four cobras...!
Now.
Let's see what you can see !
Excellent.
One empty pot left, now.
Who dies first ?!
We're almost there !
You know what I see ?
Fear.
You have lost your power.
Thrown it all away.
- What magic is this ?
- Mine.
I see your faith,
hollow king !
And its time has come.
You wish to test magic
against steel ?
I come for the woman...
...and your head !
The Assassin and The Sorceress !
How romantic !
I'll bury you both together !
And here it is.
The foundation-stove !
- Hurry, we're running out of time !
- I'm hurrying, I'm hurrying...
Fire in front...
...and palace-guards at your back.
Looks like I'll be keeping my head
after all, Akkadian !
Kill the witch !
Mathayus!
For your father !
Die well, assassin !
It seems the Gods favour me
tonight, Akkadian !
Mathayus....!
- Hurry up and light it.
- You hurry up and light it.This is your invention !
Follow me.
Ready...weapons !
Attack !
So much for not getting
killed !
Catch this !
Hail, to the king !
I knew it from the start.
Mathayus !
Stay here with us, Balthazar.
There's much work to be done.
I have to look after my
own people.
You're a king now, Akkadian,
and a good one, I think.
Don't forget how you got here,
or the people you came from.
My people will live on,
through me.
Remember, there'll always be
a place for you here.
Live free !
Rule well !
Remember, Nubian eyes will be
watching you, Scorpion King !
I see a time of great peace
and prosperity ahead.
How is it you see this ?
Don't the legend say you'll lose
your powers if you...
Can you think of a better way to keep a
king from taking advantage ?
Well, neither could my
ancestors.
But, how long will this
time of peace last ?
Nothing lasts forever,
my king.
And that is the destiny
of all kingdoms.
Then we'll make our own
destiny.