Look,I'm sorry.just cant give u that kind of information.
Anything else.But I can not do that.
I can not betray my country.
I won't.
This country...gave me everything.
Oh God!.Just keep him away from me.
Please.Dont let him near me.
Ooh Noo! Ooh God!
Come on,baby,relax into it .N let Godzilla do his tang
Ah ahh.agh ahh!
Okay!,Okay!! Come on that is absolutely wrong on so many levels.
- You're with us or not? - And get cheated again ?
What? ..No!
The Pooch may lie,The Pooch may steal ...
- "The Pooch" may...- Refer to him in the third person?
Occasionally ...
But "The Pooch"will not cheat.
Well ''The Pooch "can relax.i was worried about Cougar.
Yeah ..Right..Its always the quiet ones
What? Its Blind Man's bluff."
Hi cards win.How in the hell can a man cheat u?
Cards!
I feel like i got somethin over here..feel like i got somethin.
Queen King Jack,King Q...(reapeats)
J Q K J Q K !
R'right! One,two,three,Go!
I got a great great feelin about this one.
Ur mama had a Great feeling last night!!!.
Ohh! Tha was a Mama joke.
What?
All right,All Right..Lets Go!?
All right.I ...I ...
will raise u.(one guy whistles)
-U dont want to do that.- No?
- Piece u recieved from the houndurian General? - Yeah.
Guess What .I'm definitely in.
(men laughing).-Lets go,r'right.
Whoa!!,wow!
its evens me up.
How many knives do you have? What is going on here?
Cougar,ur bet.
Hey! LOSERS!!
Its Time.
All right,we have a drug and arms dealer called Fadhil.
Runnin a homegrown heroin assembly line near the river
We find it we paint it for laser targeted bombed and get the hell'out.
No Muss No Fuss.
For that they need us ??
You'd rather take 50 dude with Ak's?
All right,I got eyes on Monsieur Fadhil .
- Paint it.-Show time fellas.
Go ahead n call me Michelangelo!.
Dropkick this is Pinball,Requets fire mission.
The target is laid ur clear north to south./Over
Over.
Roger Pinball,target aquired n lock.
Be advise,E.T.A to fireworks is 8 minutes.
Roger!,will break out the ear plugs.
Boss?
there using kids as mules.
Call it in.
Dropkick we got children at targets.
Repeat,We got children at targets.Please be advised.
Acknowledge.Keep position.
Maintain the position? What is he talking about Colonel?
We strongly recommend cancellation of the bombing.
Your orders stands,Prepare for extraction.
Cougar?
Dropkick this is pinball.
Marking equipment suffered damage,we decide to cancel the mission.
Well..That was just stupid.
Is this mission controller ?
This is Max,Colonel Clay.
No one uses names on comms system.
This is a secure military channel.
is it really ...?
Goddamn it u listen to me! theres childen on site.
U think i didnt know that ?
We lock coordinate the moment u painted.
the delivery will occur on schedual.
U have your self a Super Day.
Shit! Jensen contact plane directly.
- Tell them to abort.- Im trying hes jammin us.
Theres nothing i can do.
theres something we can do.
All right,here it is.Five against fortress,
we have about eight minutes before n astray system auto fire.
Plenty of time.
Ill drive.
Us against 50 dudes with Ak's,right?
Jensen and Pooch,Get a truck for the kids.
The rest of us will be  out in 5 ...
Airstrike's is in four and change,Ladies.
Okay,Be out in 4 rally point.
On me!
3min to Target.
Come on lets go.(kids screaming)-
Out you go.(girl voice) Senor Senor!!
All right.Go there with him.
Come on mama.
I got it.Get them out.
All right.Who's your Pappy?
Let's go.This way.Come on!
- Ohh no ...- Yeah.
- Really? - Why not?
- Can u? - Of course.
oKay ...
Ladies ...
Clay,we got the kids.Rally point two minutes.
Max sent you ?,didnt he.
i will not commit to his crazy planning if he does this.
U make this really easy for u.
U let him go,ill let you live.
Come here,son.walk to me.
Clay,Get the hell out! We got to go.Now!
He will kill you too you know.
Target Locked.20 seconds.
- Oh? you stop for coffee in there ? - Yeah.
What kind of blast radius we lookin at?
OK.Pooch ill mite need the bus to go a lil faster.
we hold on to something ...
Like Right Now!
I got it i got it! -there we go pooch!!
Pinball  this is Blackhawk 3 Prepare for extraction.
My favorite part was when I we were completely on fire.
But the shootout that was good times.
There she blows.
lets go,lets go.
All right,everyone together.
Lets Go.
There you go ,there u go good Job.
Sir,is not enough room for your team and them.
Then its them.
R'right lets go guys..
Watch the heads.
All right kids you're going for a ride
Goodbye.(kids) Adios!
No gracias,keep your bear..
Keep it safe.Okay?
(Spanish)- Thanks. -your welcome .
Goodbye.
Get'em out of here.
Some cute lil buggerz.
Hope they make it to the court marshall.
What is that? Hear that?
Guys ...This is bad.
Max,Cobra1.The enemies are in sight.
Received.
Cobra  1 kill amended.
No!
Thats suppose to be us.
A protest yesterday in front of U.S.embassy,
a violent response the death of 25 children from Bolivia
were killed and during operation.
Let me be absolutely clear ...
In no way were these mens acting under order from
U.S.government.
Will be no ceremony for them?
Where is the ring?
What are you doing? No,no,no!
He's getting birderd ...
That is disgusting.
I am officially disgusted by us.-And you lost again.
- We lost again.- No.
You bet.
You gave me money.
Yes,it was stupid of me,wasnt'it?
Could this get any worse??
I suppose if we start to drinking.
your not...your not drinking??
What's happening?
Hombre! Come on get'em in there!
I found a guy online.Says he can get intel on Max for cash,
All we need is to make a little money.
We Do not have money.
Want to go paypal on some kids in a basement that problably lying?
You were there.You know what we did.
Man tried to kill us.
Man killed us,Clay.
No,We got to stay focus.
Okay? On the Mission.
Get money,get clean passports
get back to state side.
without anybody noticing.
hell,we didnt event see what the guy looks like
But I heard his voice.
A man with a voice is a man with a throat.
-The guy has a throat ...- Come ...
Clay,look around you.
Do you really think we are in position to take on CIA super spook?
- Rogue ...- No,its a hell of a plan.
Know what Pooch can setup there next to the taco stand,
and Jensen can serve communications right there next to hookers.
- Captain ...- Yo! Yo! ...
youre not a solder anymore.
youre not a solder.
All right?
Clay,for Christ sake your losing your mind.
- Men are falling ...-Well your losing me,okay?
He won,We lost.so lets gets us home.
Can you do that?
Cheers.
How is the steak?
Meaty.
You want a bite?
Maybe later.
OK.
Do i know you?
(Giggles)Relax pappy
Do i not look relax?
No.
Think we change that?
Wow! its everything a girl could dream of.
Do u have a bathroom?
No,I specifically asked only the hotel room in the world that has no bathroom.
Are u trying  to turn a  "Yes" into a "No"?
Oh.Thank you.
So,What brings you in Bolivia?
Cruise Ship .
We are a landlock country.
Yeah well,it's an amazing cruise ship.
Where were we now?
I think you were about to tell me.How you enjoy following me.
- You saw me didnt you -I did
I bet you didnt see me on Mercado street
I have a business proposition for you,Clay.
Oops What happen to you egg fan.
-Oops!
I do not want to hurt you.
Your not going to.
Yes i am.
-Hi -Hi
What do u want ?
I can help you find him Max.
Im listening.
How did you know that we were alive?
I counted the number of teeth in the chopper wreckage.
Plus u guys aint exacly subtle.
Here the deal ...
I get u and your mens back in the states.You get Max for me.
What's the catch,Lady.?
Its pretty much a suicide missions.
Why should i trust you ?
Be because if i was lying,I would'nt of use words "suicide mission ''.
Just meet me here Tomorow.
And bring your boys.
Goodbye.
Hey.
If your lying to me ...
ill kill ya.
Hey its nice meeting you to.
Yes it was.
Sorry we're late.It was a party at the doll factory.
Pepito's birthday.
- Yes ...- Yeah.
So,she wanted to meet in a cemetery?
Thats not like..we are boating at all
- I'm the only one thats sees his shirt? - No.
Ahh! Its my niece soccer team?8 and under.
i checked their scores online and i ....
What?
There in the play-offs!
What do we have on her ?
Besides a pants bustin crush ...
The company file is blank.
CIA has a standing kill order on her.
Hamas,Sien Feim ...pretty much all except PETA wants this chick antsgrave.
Hey,think you're thinking clear on this?
Hein?Because every time you messed up it was because of a women.
- Name one time that i..- Amber.
Amber was not the problem Her husband was the problem.
Amber's husband was not the one who shot you.
- it was only in the leg .- What about Emma?
Emma doesnt count,I didnd sleep with Emma.
No because She put a bomb in Your Car.
alright i have to admit it.
It did take lil romance out the relationship.
Yes,now this chick shows up n...
Whats her name ...Aisha and she burns down our hotel.
I'm clear,Rogue.
You better be,because I aint gettin killed by no girl.
Long time since anyone called me a Girl.
She put a bomb in your car?
She was volatile..
Aisha,they are Jensen Pooch,Rogue and Cougar.
Really?
Gentlemen,in 97 hours,Max will be in Miami.
He Travels in an armored column,
that at least 30 guards armed to the teeth.
You have a better chance at kidnapping the president.
The good news for you is ...
I have the power bring you back to the U.S.
And fund the entire Ops,as you see fit
You get Max it and we're square.
And ...Why should we belive u ?
Because I'm the first person you've met that even admits he exist.
Listen,you guys can all stay here in Bolivia n rott.
Or go home and get revenge on the man that framed you.
It is your choice.
Colonel?
Dont call me that.We are not soldiers anymore.
All right.You know that if we do this,
we are waging a war against C.I.A.
They had started it!.
Okay,heres what im hearing ...
Im hearing "No" Im hearing "Leave"
Im hearing  'Im Sorry." Is that what im hearing?
We can not do what you ask.
I'm sorry.
Tell me,Nabil ...is it a moral issue,or financial issues?
- A moral issue.- Really?
- You moraly object to this deal? - Yes.I'm sorry.
- Please,leave.- Alright so that what im hearing.
Now,I want U to listen to me.
Listen carefully.
Because I want U to hear this.
Wade?
Ahhg!! What is this?
What are you doing?
What? No! Please!
What the hell was that?
You gave me the nod.
To hit the face nod,not to throw him off the roof nod.
I thought thats what you wanted?!?!?!.
At most,at most that was a brake his finger nod.
Jesus! Wade..
The man was a scientific genius.
granted his weight signals certains impulse controls issues
But thats no reason to throw his fat ass off 57 floors .
sorry...
Well ...
I think I speak for everyone here
May say your actions were excessive.
And yes,more than just a little wasteful.
But then it does seem to have the desired effects.
ill tell you what.Throw baldy up next .
No,please.Wait.
We have a different moral perspective that of our late colleague.
I need one to test it and four to use.
Four snoops?
We will need much money.
you will have ''Much money''.
Welcome back to the land of the living.
How do you want to begin?
We're gonna go bird huntin,
Its a Sonic Dematerialized.
Better known as "Snoop."
21st Century green terrorist.
Pure destruction,no pollution.
So,who we sellin'em to?
Chinese extremists,the PLF,French,Basque,I do not care.
As long as they have the right  price,and willing to use it.
No stock pilling ,No detourence.
It's like giving a hand gun to a six years old,Wade.
You do not know how its gonna end,but pretty sure it will make the papers.
Another war.
Well,what do you belive in,Wade?
I guess Shotguns and Big Tittiz?.
I also enjoy air shows and beer.
We are saving the country Wade.Doing something for benefit of U.S.
I was born in Quebec.
OK.Then save we are saving North America.
Let me have ur weapon,Wade.
Base 1 this is Cavalier415.
We've bein in a colision with civilian vehicle.
Carvey is dead and Freeman is hurt really bad.
We need MedEvac immediatly.
He Has kids base1,He has Kids,A-hha-ha-Ha-ha-aa!!
...that..sucked
-Roger,Cavalier415.
..u better than that ...
We are scrampling a chopper
...kids..we've got kids...
I used to be good at that.I was good at that right Rogue?
- Shut up.- Thanks,man.
Robert De Niro,who?
Jensen,shut up
You shut up,Rogue.
You're dead.I'm spinnal injury.spinnal injury can talk.
The dead cant say shit
Stop talking or ill break your neck really.
You know u really gonna have to start gettin into caracther.
I'm serious,man.
Dead guy no talking..
Our ride.
Base1,this is Medevac Delta we have visual on Cavalier 415.
Here weee go...
Ahhhg haaa!!
R'right buddy will get u patch up in no time.
Oh my God ...(flirting)Hi!.
What is your name?
Shoot when you're ready,Cougar.
Ohh Shit ...
What the hell is going on?
Woohoo!
Just bein chopperjack fellas.
Where is my wild goose?
GPS..Got it.
Have you ever seen an EMT look like this ?
Really bro? "Hi.whats your name "
"I have no legs but I want to take you on a date? "
Yo,J...
What do you think is up with "Not me call me Colonel stuff"?
Classic loss of identity.
Clay defined himself by his place in the military structure.
his way of measuring the good he did the world.
Without it,hes just a Losers,like the rest of us.
You knew that a cats can make thousands of different sounds,and dogs only ten?
Cats...
..not to be trusted
Kay do me a favor,n never reapeat that okay
Okay?
We are all set.
ready take a giant step for aaa ...
guys who like to steal stuff,I guess ...
Hit it.
Showtime...
Beatyful.
Now That is a rocket!
Let'm chase that.
That iiiis a roocket!
- Shit! - Have you seen that?
(heli mic)Medevac  Delta is a base1
- Ooh My God.- Im the black MacGyver.
(heli mic) What is your situation ? Over.
time to move.
Hi.
...ssss' were u from? Originally?
the wilds of North Africa.
Wow That must have been...
sandy ...
Do you have any hobbies?
When I was little
I collected human ears.
Good times  ...
But is...
No,no,no.k listen ...
If you want a gas turbine generator find a force fed electrified unit
hooked it to the fuel tank.
Are few things in life which can not be solved by duct tape.
Are small arms gonna be a problem?
Its takin care of,thanks.
Which brings me to my question.
Aisha?
What do you want with Max?
Rogue ...
No.she did her part well?
we got home.we could go right now.
You can but we made a deal.
Fuck deals okay?
You made a deal with Clay.
I want answers.
Max is trying to buy next generation weapons.
I dont know the end game.
But what I do know is when Max seeks an into interested something him,
people die.
And world map get redrawn.
Shit.
And you really think u can get'm little girl?
No,Big Boy.You are.
Think im gonna kill'er right now.
No,your not.
Yes,I am.
I'm right here.
If you want me to shoot your bankroll,Rogue,go ahead
Rogue.Rogue ...
All right,stay with us.
But if I smell something traps
Do you gonna put a bullet in the head.Sounds fair?
Sounds fun.
Sounds like my parents.
I knew your not gonna shoot her.
Not today.
Load and go.
Surprise.Thats were Max is.
I sure hopes he doesnt see us
in this brite yellow banana Pinto.
Are you trying to say that your embarrassed to be seen in an American classic!?
This is an American classic?!
R'right here he comes.
See what you got.
Good shot.
Hey,where are the seatbelts,bro?
We dont need seatbelts.
The G force will you keep you in your seat.
Jensen,are we wired?
Max is west bound.
And these hot dogs and are delicious.
- This is not a sweet car,bro.- this..is a classic.
Yeah,a classic piece of shit
(Cop)Come on backup.move that car.
many vehicle has bein hit?.Give me the exits ...
street is blocked.
We are trying to clear now.
Dismount!
Go! Defensive perimeter around the "package."
This will wake them up!!
Mask drawn!
Shit!
Pooch ...
Open Fire! Shoot it  down now!
R'right here we go
Ohh ho ho! God damn!!
We are under attact! We need backup!
okay easy go a little to the right.
okay Get down get down ...
To the left.
your other left.easy easy!
- Can u let me do this?? - Sure.
let me do this.
Thats right bitches ...I got a crossbows.
Doors to the rear is sealed.Raises them.
Get out of my way!
I thought you said that small arms are not a problem.
Does that looks like small arms to u ??
- thats a Cannon! - Dont h!
- That is a Cannon! - Dont hi,Dont HIT!!!
Oh! Shit!
Are you sure you you done this before?
okay.Right now! Not the time Not the time right now!
Pooch,what is you status?
Ahh completly irritated and possibly crashin,but the fish is on the hook.
- We got have Max.- barely ...
Fellas!
your not gonna belive this shit.
- Wade was there.- Wade Travers,sevenths group??
He made me ,Clay.out of question.
- Who is he ? - We ran counter ops guerrillas with him.
Let's just say ...that he is a bad man.
I thought you guys were the bad men.
He is worse.
Alright,like right now we need to deal with
a heavily armed evil geniuses inside this truck.
Come on!.
Are you ready?
Open the valve.
All right,lets unlock this thing.
Hit the ground!
Hit the ground or I'll blow ur head off!
yeah..I Dont think so.
Final warning.
Gasoline,muzzle flash ...think about it ...
Put em down!
Cougar...
- Where is he? - Who?
Max.
Who the hell is Max?
- I Can explain.- Shut up!
Jensen open it.
It is a hard drive.
From Goliath the Multinational manufacturer of everything
Completly locked out.
Without a decryption key that goes with this
your looking at a very cool paper weight.
Shoot her.
Burn everything.
- Dont you wanna find out whats on it? - No!
I cant find Max.
Nobody can .
But I knew that he was carry something very valuable to him.
Clay!
Whatever it is,we can use it against him!
It's leverage!
The drive is proprietary product bilt by Goliath ...
Hes probalby on the main frame.
Come on...We're not considering that
- Ho wait,wait ...- No,come on,man ...
- Rogue.- We are not the goods guys anymore.
25 children.
25 innocent lives were lost because of this guy.
- You remember it,Rogue? - Yes,I remember.
- You were there.- Yes,I was there.
Max is gonna pay.
This a guilt trap? I do not want him to pay,I want my life back.
okay? My life back,not that vengeance bullshit.
- Im killin her right now.-u dont like the way im runnin things Rogue?
You can find the door.
Go where,Clay?
go where..
We are fugitives.
Because of you.
The hell you gonna do next?
Put us in a box
because got beat by a guy on a radio?
- You shouldnt of done that.- Cool out.
Stop,stop,stop,stop.
I'll cut your head off man!.
Rogue ...
They know we are alive,Rogue.
The only thing got against this guy is that drive.
She framed us.
Are you guys blind? She framed us!!
We hit Goliath HQ in two days.You want your life back?
Your gonna have to steal it.
Ur wrong,You know that,right?
- Again,'cause a woman? - Cut her loose.
Cut'er loose.
Cut her loose,Rogue.
You cut her loose,Bro.
This is on you.
We are all set,sir.
Commence.
Code
Pulsar.
What is "Pulsar"?
What do you know about deep space?
Nothing.
- Base particle string theory? - Nothing.
singularity events?
Not a thing.
I think we should move on then.
I'm gonna give you 45 seconds to explain what happened with my drive.
And whom am i lookin at here,Wade?
Clay and his unit.
Clay and his unit?
Sounds like a porno,Wade.
You had them killed 4 months ago.
Ive done alot in 4 four months ,Wade.
I am a very busy man.
The Bolivia situation?
Fad-hil?
the Max intel Fadhil gathered ...
Was incinerated,along with everyting else in the blast.
These guys survived.
And they I have my drive.
Yeah.
Okay,so five dead man hijacked you ,Wade.
Did you happen to find out who was behind them?
Not C.I.A.,N.S.A,Special Ops ...
Yes,I am aware thats not us.
seems that the only thing we do know,
is who there coming after.
Get me an 18 man fire team.
In 12hrs!
What is the plan?
The plan is ''get me 18 man fire team in 12 hours.
Are we clear on the plan?
Or we could do it a third time?
- clear.- Okay.
Oh! Wade,you know what I was thinking?
I forgot earlier.
Get me an 18 man fire team- 12 hours.
Are we clear ?
Do you want some?
Pooch has a wife.
Jensen has a niece.
When all this over an they return to their families
What are you going to do ?
I'll think of something.
I'll never let you be a solder again u know that right
Even thou one day...
Do you?
I got Rogue ...
You know ...
If you two really fought
He would kill you.
Why is that?
Because of the others.
you care what happens to them.
And you think this is a weakness?
I know it is.
It is law of the jungle ...
But we are not in the jungle.
Yes,we are.
Good morning.
Oh wow ...thats just peachy!
We r not going anywere before u 2 squash this bullshit.
- Which we are on a schedule here lets go - Yeah!.
(imitating)Oh! we are on a schedule ...
What are you doing?
Rogue ...
I'm sorry I hit you in the face.
Aaha! was good.That was good...Rogue?
Rogue!
Clay,Im sorry that I threatened to cut ur head off.
Very good!
WoW! Dont u 2 feel better?
- No! - No!
I dont give a shit.I do.
Now i say we watch Jensen get him self killed.Yep?
"Goliath World Wide Entreprises"
Mr.Henderson's,please.
Mr.Frank Henderson's human resources
One moment please.
Liking the angle of the dangle??
- This is Henderson.- Mr.Henderson? ...
Richard Hertz from internal security.
I was wondering if you'd kind enough to make ur way to the lobby.
Can I ask why?
Well its a mater of some what sensitive nature.
Involving an individual exposing himself to women in the elevator
Nasty bisness really,best discust in personne
All right.Im on my way.
See you there.
Hi.
Im skippy from Tech support.
I here to install the firewall on Henderson system.
You just missed.But if you want You can come in like an hour.
You know,i can be in n out in two minutes.he dont even have to be there.
- Yeah but you cant go in there ...- Upstairs there ridin me ...
- But you cant...Sir ... - I appreciate it.
I like...your dress.
Dress?
To much.
Algorythm is on main frame ...
Downloading it...now.
- Skippy? - Hey..Shhhhhiit!
- Skippy?
Really?
Ho ho! wow!!
Look,I know that probably doesnt look...
Clay,I need an exit.
Is an exit to the north of the building.
Freeze!!
Wow! this has gotten serious.
I'm warning you!
I am a lethal killing machine.
It was a secret government experiment
They did stuff to me ...
Spooky stuff...
Anal stuff...
Turned me in a dangerous telekinetic.
As the ancient Tibetan philosophy states,
"Dont start none''
wont be none."
"telekinetik" your way on these.
Face Down..
Or I'll make your heart stop beating with my mind.
Thanks,Cougar.
- Who has the hard drive? - Yeah.
An ...uploading the algorithm ...
Holy shit! your Girlfriend was right.
Its a courrier Drive.
- A what? -21st century Human Briefcase .
Russian Mob banks pionnered them its like electronic bearer bonds.
All right,say it again but much slower and dumber,please.
Pretrend your super evil,
And you want to move a ton of you i'll gutted blood money
but you cant because it can be tracked.
So you load the cash On this badboy
and you can physically move anywhere you want to go.
We have Max's courrier drive ,right?
We have Max's $ 400 million dollars.
R'right Clay,before you do something noble,Like smashing it,
I say we go on Amazon.com And get a jet.
Ahhh it doesnt work that way.
Unfortunately,courrier-drive can be Loaded and unloaded
On there home system.
Although,if we were gonna buy stuff,
I say a canary yellow streatch Hummer.
No,no.We're gonna trade it back to him .
Hes gonna get his money and we will clear our name.
- No,We did a deal.- Yes.
Aisha ...
Hes gonna kill us now,you know that,
Yes,I know that.
This thing has a record all IPs from where it was accessed.
And one address comes up alot.
its obviously a place where this thing keep going back too.
Max's Base of Operations .
Port of Los Angeles.
there probably files of every Black book ops which he ever did .
Including Bolivia.
We could hit it there and clean it out.
Expose the world the what hes done.
And clear ourname in the prossess.
A'right,it's a good plan.
But we still kill him.
Absolutely.
We appreciate you meeting us at a single storie facility
No problem.
I regard the whole incident
as a way of us knows each others bisiness orientation.
I agree.
But now that we do know each other,
Know that if you ever get near me with that Yankee-cockeye Bullshit
You will be fed to my dogs.
As you know,we've have a hiccup on our end with the money
One billion dollars.This is the new price.
- A billion? - Cash.
Cash will be difficult.
Difficult? Mr.Wade...
Life the way you people want to live it is difficult.
you want less difficult,
move in my country,study Hinduism.
Meditate
Cultivate your serenity.
way less difficult.
But you,you want to buy bombs.
I afraid that this is a more difficult way of life.
Mr.Wade ...
Hello?
He wants a billion dollars in cash.
Thats alot of paper ...
Stay wet.
did u get ther 18 men fire team I asked for?
Yep.
ok.Change of plans.
Kill them.
Kill my 18 guys ??
Or fire them.witch is easier.
Honestly? Firering them.
OK.
Did you give them intel Clay's people?
Well,yes.
Aaanndd weeere baaack at killing them.
...fine i'll kill them.
What do we do when its dead?
Whats the matter? U releated to them?
In fact,one of them,yes.
Really? by blood?
A brother in law.Id said id kill him.What r we doing?
Its not what we're gonna do,
Its what Clay is gonna do for us.
And that is?
He has our Billions,baby!
What are we up against?
- KryArm - OOh Shit.
- KryArm
- Who is KryArm? - KryArm Securities Solutions.
Ex special forces.
basicly a gang like Cougar,without his warm'n'cuddly side.
We start recon at 06:00.
anyone not here for it,I understand.
Just goin over the plan.
You wanna go with the plan ?.
Lets go over the plan...
- Aahh Shit.
you okay?
The Petunials are playing the Maribold on sunday.
So?
This is the team.
Those look hard ,Im lookin at 8yrs old?! ...
Look at these immates.
What are you doing?
Aaaa just Trying to aa...
Just trying to connect Fadhil drug operation
and about 4 million missing just tried to track it down.
What are you doing awake,Pooch?
Jensen hooked me up to a satellite earlier.
wat'cha need satellite for?
Wait a sec.That is today?
Yes.
Perhaps now she knows if boy or girl.
- Congratulations,man.- Congratulations,thank you ...
You say that now,but you know Jolene.
When she know I'm alive,she's gonna kill me.
I cant let her have that baby without me.
What? What?
Ofcourse we all know we're gonna die in there.
Or can do this without you.
No,you cant.
Go home.
Got it!
Fadhil's 4 million didnt disappeared,
but entered into a private account.
Whose account?
It's a family trust...
says ''in the event of his death,the money goes to child ...
name...
Shit! Whoa!
Just tell me what happened in Bolivia.
We we're on a legitimate op
Painting terrorist camp
So we could bomb it.
It turns out that we were executing Max's redetta.
So you knew nothing about Fadhil?
A Target a target.
It would have been no difference if I have wouldnt've seen those kids.
- You went in? - Yeah.
Had to.
There were 25 children in innocent.
Have you seen him?
Yes.
Why do you want to know all this?
Did you kill Fadhil,Clay?
Who are you?
Fadhil's daughter,Clay! Fadhil's daughter!
She's Fadhil's daughter.
Shes got a gun..pointed at my dick,Clay!
It pointed at my dick! Clay!
You'd rather it be pointed at your face??
I know it makes no sense,but yes!
It's better now?
Not really.
Where's your gun,Jensen?
In the van?!
- And what's doing there?   - Not much.
Will you two,Shut up?
What if it was pointed at your dick?
Jensen,are you okay?
She shot me! in my arm!
Your gonna live,your gonna live!
Cougar,be gentle!
Clay...
We must make a move.Now!
Come on!
Home again home again!
You have money?
Jesus!
Always with the money.
"Hi.How are you?"
''How have you been ?"
I recently attended the funeral best friend,
who you thrown off the roof.
How would've you been?
I cant complain.
In fact,I'm thinking of putting a satellite radio in the car.
God,you are short.
Really,what much you weigh?
Are you standing in a hole?
We have your ordinances.
Alrighty.
Let's make a cash withdraw...
and ...
Who wants to be billionaire?
We should burn this!
Whole ops is blowned.
She know our names,faces ...
Does she knows about our families?.
Damn it,Clay,look at me!
Yes.
I must go home,in Springfield.
Jensen can come with me His niece is in New Hampshire.
I'm done.
I'm going to the port.
Okay?
You get back to your families.
We will get Max.
I did this.I made the call in Bolivia.
I put your families in danger.
Just let me and Clay finish this.
You two idiots are gonna go in there blind??
3.
Hey,getting shot was great...we do it again.
Four idiots.
You've son's a Bitch's...
I'll drive.
Five.
We are in.
Status?
''Zee Pooch is good.
R'right,mohito,just u and me Pappy,
And this hot ass van.
Hey,you!
And disco...
What is the password?
Let us enter or kill you.
Correct.
Main server is two skylights over,
ill be coming out of that door.
be prepared to go the moment Cougar hits the fire alarm.
Get goin.
Im above the computer room.
Maybe 30sec out.
Shit.
Wade is here.
Last chance to get the fuck outta here.
Roger that.
- Hey,Clay! - Yeah.
Look at this.
Go for two years...
And the crowd goes wild
Where do you think your going?
How you guys doin ?
Cougar  says when you're in position.
In position.
Cougs,Cougs?
Well what we have here?
whatS up,fellas?
I think someone is trying to set us up.
Jesus...
Something is not right.
ohh yeah?
Hi,Clay.
Rogue?
Wade...
Yes...
After Miami's failure,I made a deal,Clay.
You're a goddamn traitor.
No,you've betrayed us!
would've keep planning missions
and find ways to kill Max until you got us all killed?
- No.- Yes!
I tried to tell your,but you wouldnt listen.
Now you wanted ...your vengeance.
Face to face with big,bad wolf,the voice from the radio.
all that Bullshit!
Now I get to walk away.
We all would of walk ,Rogue.
Dont you get it yet?
There is no server.
Max,lured you here.
This is a C.I.A."cash stash"
Kill me now.
And maybe you walkaway from this.
No,you die later.
You're about to steal one billion dollars from C.I.A.
Congratulations,Rogue.
You just helped these assholes
to get what they needed to start a war.
We cool?
Hes not my problem.
Take him away.
Let's go back to the boat.
holdon!
Holdon!
I followed you everywhere man..everywhere.
Just couldnt do this shit no more.
You gonna die very badly...
No.
Come on,lets go.
Do you...have any fours?
Goldfish?
You actually have two fours.
Two.You dont understand this game,do you?
Looks like somebodies money is here.
By the way...
Your ordonance is right here.
Four snoops and a Dugati
As requested.
So your Max??
Welcome to the team.
Supervise the loading of money...onto our plane.
What do you mean?
(imitating Hindou)-New change of plan.
Rogue.
Move!
Move,move it let's go!
On your knees! You heard'm!
Pooch! Pooch!
Son of a bitch!
you know I like that hat.
That is a great hat.
I really dont care if theres a hole in it.
What are you smiling at?
Hmpff!! Thats a badass chick!
Payback is a Bitch!
Never touch the hat! Hmm?
Can you stand?
I was shot in both legs.
What kind of stupid question is that? really
Ooh and So now you're Mister grumpy pants?
You know,you are not only which was shoot as today.
U still Stand
Back up!
I need you to armed this device that,right now.
Extremists are about to get framed producing a large crater
You're crazy.
Im engineering global terror conflict
which is finally gonna restore order
on this big blue marble.
Now light the firecrakers.
Cougs.
Clay!
Did you kill him?
My father found out about Max real plans.
Hes was gonna stop.
Did you kill him?
Yes
- Aisha,He was a bad man.- No matter!
I know.
U Can kill me right now
or I can let me help you do what you need to do.
either way,
I get it.
Lets go get Max.
Wade said something about a boat.something s queer to the docks.
Pooch,can you stand?
Ohh! this stupid question day?!
.k.this stupid question day and no one decided one told me.
- It's cool...Come on,leg less Pooch.-.iii..Gotchhaa.
Haa..here we go...All right,let's move.
This aint over yet.
Come on,fellas!
i aint wanna rush you,but I have a plane to catch.
Come on!
There you go ,there you go Lets get it in there!
I'm got Rogue,the rest of you after Wade!
Cougar,cover me!
Like the Pooch aint that ironic!
Come on,buddy!
Call me Legless-Pooch again and ull be Headless-Jensen!
I think its a cool name .
Make ya Sounds like a pirate!
Your Mama's a pirate!
Go!
Cover me!
Get us in the air!
We dont have enough room for take off!
Go to the end and turn around!
AAAHhhhhh!!!
You know ...
I always wondered how this played out,Clay.
I told already.you die very badly.
Oh yeah?
R'right.
Jensen,Run Run!
- Now im defenitly gonna cut your head off.- Go for it.
Son of a bitch!
U Loose!
oKay we are clear to take off.Get us out of here.
Okay,r'right
- Hey,get us out of here! - Okay!
Bomb is activated.
This is the remote.
''Detonation in ten.nine...''
Tha son of a bitch is stealing our money!
Clay,Wade's on the moves.
Clay
U got Wade coming at you.
Run him over!
- What? - RUN HIM OVER!
take him.
Outstanding!
Clay,we have a problem here.
Im looking at a giant vibrating easter egg from Hell.
And no Max.
I think i see him.
Initiate backup plan "C".
Where will you rescue me?
Shit!
ETA? Im at rendez-vous.
Hello?
Whats the matter? Skip the reception?
That was my ride.
Bummer!
Clay is it ?
Colonel.
Then you know what it is.
A remote pressure trigger
Very good.
Release button for ten seconds
and everything goes boom!
So since you Cant shoot me...
Aargh..God Damn it!
You want to try that again?
That hurt.
Havin fun? Enjoying yourself?
Give me a remote and let you in life.
You know the worst thing about being the good guy?
Whats that?
Having to take decisions like this...
Hey!
ha ha!Look at what Pooch found.
Look what I found .
u should do it
Disarmed.
Hello?
Its Max.
Hi,Max.
Colonel...
Nice catch.
Could'ov share a dream together.
Now your back to where you started.
Well,i wouldnt go that far...
Why is that?
i dont know now i know what you look like.
Be seein you soon,Max.
Its a nice watch ,Holmes.
Come with us?
When this is over
and he's dead
You and i will finish that dance.
Fair enough.
Yo! Lets Go home.
Shes volatile...
Papa-Papa,We are clear.
Setin perimeter.
You five by...
I'm a lil nervous about it this one,Colonel.
Whatever happens,You get to that package .
Mission is launched.
Acknowledge.
Im in.
Okayy ...
Pooch can do this.
Hey.
Sir,you can not come here.
It's okay.
I the father.
Where the hell have you been?
Traffic ...
is a boy!
Its A Boy ,Clay
He looks just like me.
Congratulations!