Once in a great while,
mankind unlocks a secret so profound...
that our future
is altered forever.
Fire. Electricity.
Splitting the atom.
At the dawn of the 31st century,
we unlocked another.
It had the potential to change
humanity's role in the universe.
We called it the Titan project,
and it was a testament...
to the limitless power
of the human imagination.
Perhaps that is what
the Drej feared most,
for... it brought them down
upon us without warning...
and... without mercy.
Cale, that day, the day
the Drej descended from the sky,
the only thing that mattered
was keeping you safe.
Perfect!
Hey, stop!
Come on!
- Cale, are you all right?
I'm okay.
Dad,
my invention broke.
Well, then, we'll fix it together,
but not today, Cale. We have to go now.
Dad, where's
everybody going?
We're leaving too.
We all have to go somewhere safe.
Professor Tucker! Professor Tucker!
The Drej have reached the global defense system!
Come on, son.
Will we get the people away in time?
- Not if we sit here talking, sir.
- I wanna drive.
- When you're older, kid.
- I'm older than four.
- Hang on!
Whoa!
- Please proceed to your designated-
- Is the Titan prepped for launch?
- Just waiting for you, sir! - Intelligence says
the Drej don't know the Titan's location,
or we would've
been hit already.
Let's pray
they're right!
Enemy warships
have entered our solar system.
Are we going in that?
- Wow!
- Cale,
I have to go
on a different ship.
- I have to go away for a while.
No, Dad! No!
- Tek is going to look after you.
- But I wanna go with you!
- Sir- - I know. It's
not safe where I'm going.
- Sir! Professor!
- All right, I'm coming!
Cale, here. Take this.
As long as you wear it, there's hope.
- I will see you again. I promise.
- Okay.
- No, it's not okay! It's not okay!
- Tek, keep him safe!
- Daddy!
- Korso, go!
- Come back!
- Evacuate! Evacuate!
- Godspeed, Sam Tucker!
Attention, pilots. Drej Stingers are...
This is Tucker.
Bring me down.
Attention, pilots.
Drej Stingers are attacking
the escape vehicles.
Okay. Are we all here?
Bobby, buckle up.
- Now, Sam. Now!
- Go, Dad! Go!
- Get out of there. Get out of there!
- Come on.
# Lose my head to the chemical freeway #
# Comin' up on overload
Losing sure is easy, so I am no more #
# But I'm not broken #
# In my dream, I win #
# Out here, I'm nothing #
# A cosmic castaway #
# In my head I'm a chemical dreamer
Speed up to the burn out mode #
- # Comin' up to fifth dimension
Beautify, don't crucify me #
- # So I need no mindgame poisoning my lonely soul #
- Eat this.
- # Losing sure is easy
so I am no more #
- # But I'm not broken #
# In my dream, I win #
- It's lunch. One hour for lunch.
- # And I take over #
# 'Cause I'm no loser #
- # And I'm in and you're not #
- Whoo! Whoo-hoo!
# Bad dreams don't stop #
# But I'm all screwed up #
# A cosmic castaway, yeah #
# A cosmic castaway #
- How ya hittin' 'em, Chowquin?
- Hey- Chow- Chowquin.
- Wait.
Hey, it's me. It's Cale, all right?
I'm not with those losers.
Humans wait.
- Uppity Earth scum.
- Guess you're stuck with us losers.
- Don't count on it.
- You wait in line, pal. I'm takin' the express.
- # Cosmic castaway #
- # Yeah #
- Go through the docks, you'll get yourself killed.
Coward. You know, the odds of a ship
docking are a thousand to one.
- # Yeah, a cosmic castaway #
- And that would be the one.
Wow.
- Hi.
Mm-hmm.
Hey, wh- Hey!
Wow.
- We're locked down, Captain.
All right. Keep her hot.
I'll be in touch.
- How you doin' today? Workin'
hard, are you? Bon appetit.
Next! Keep the line moving.
Here you go.
- Akrennian Beetle Sushimi.
- You got ketchup?
Ketchup? Ketchup? You don't need
ketchup. Please, next. Move along.
He's a disgrace.
Those dirty humans.
Ketchup! Boy, some nerve,
human. Nice head, human.
I'm not askin' that much. I'd just like them
to kill my food before they serve it to me.
- You know, I do an honest day's work.
I want already dead food.
- Mm.
- Is that too much for a fellow to ask?
- Do you hear a crackling sound?
- And what was up with Chowquin?
- You should've seen him.
- Ha-ha, not much chance of that.
- He was so out of control, treatin'
me like I'm some kind of- - Human?
Don't start with
that solidarity thing again.
- If you would study
human history as you've been instructed,
you might realize you're not alone out there,
and you'd be better prepared for the future.
- Well, I'll tell you somethin' about your famous future.
- Mmm.
Every day I wake up, it's still the
present, the same grimy, boring present.
I don't think
this future thing exists.
- Do you hear a crackling sound?
- Here we go.
- We gotta get outta this dump.
- Hold on, everybody! I got it!
Please don't panic. Just think of it as
floating time. Two seconds. Everybody calm.
Ah. Just needed some love.
Let's get back to eatin' baby.
Okay. Well, I'm full.
Ohh.
- Hey, Cale.
- Firrikash. Po, how's it floatin'?
- You pulled a nasty stunt back there.
- We don't like your attitude.
- You've been a little uppity.
Up-Up- Is that so? Well.
I'm gonna have to work on that.
- You wanna hunt humans, just remember:
We travel in packs.
- What are you doing?
- It's commonly known as helping.
Yeah? Well, what for?
Sometimes, kid, people
just help each other out.
- Oh, right.
So you're gonna tell me
you don't want something in return?
- All right. Maybe I do.
- What a shock.
I want you to risk your life. I want you to
give up everything you have to join the mission,
where you'll face terror and torture
and possibly gruesome death.
And I would
wanna do that because...?
Because... it's worth it.
Because... the human race needs you.
Maybe you haven't had a look around
lately, but there aren't many of us left.
At the rate we're going, they'll be
reading about us in textbooks...
- and displaying our bones
in alien museums.
- Yeah, well, having your planet
blown up can have that effect on a species.
But maybe I've been wrong all these years, and
it took your inspiring speech to make me see it.
You've really changed me.
It's beautiful.
I think we've gotta hug.
- Oh, man. They've really ground you down.
- Hey, get this straight.
I don't even know you.
I don't want any part of your mission,
- and I don't need your help
with these oversized morons.
Oh, okay.
- I think he called you morons.
- Whoa!
- Korso.
Captain, this is Akima.
We are not alone.
Are we in good company?
That's a negative,
Captain.
I think we've fallen in
with a very bad crowd.
Roger that.
Let's prep for departure.
Tek, I need to be scarce
for a while.
- You don't know the half of it.
- Ha-ha.
Are you still bothering people?
Hey, go away.
Great job with the kid, Tek.
He's a charmer.
I expected you to take him
off my hands a lot sooner.
- Tek, hey, wait. Who is this? You know him?
- Joseph Korso.
- I was with your father on the Titan project.
- My father.
- I don't have a father.
You brought this guy here?
- Yes.
- I don't understand. Why?
You still got that ring
your father gave you?
- Give it to me.
- Hey, give it back!
- Cale-
- Shh.
- Ahh.
Ah. Here.
- Put it on.
- Hmm.
- How did- How did you-
- It's a storage device.
It's genetically encrypted to your
father, and therefore, to you.
It's a map, Cale.
It can tell us
where your father hid the Titan.
That's why I've spent
the last 15 years lookin' for ya.
That ship means everything.
Humanity depends on you finding it.
Me?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Me? No, no, no.
I'm not- Tek, listen,
there must
be someone better.
It's time, Cale.
It's time to stop running.
- Well, actually,
I think it's time
to start.
Drej.
What do they want?
They want you, kid.
Same way I want you, only dead.
How do you know
they want me dead?
I'm convinced.
We gotta get
to the kitchen.
- Korso, the gravity drive!
- You ready?
- Tek, I'll lead you in.
- I'll stay here.
- Tek, you can't.
Take care of the kid.
He's not all grown up yet.
- No, no, no, no. You're coming.
- Go, Cale. I'll read about you.
Follow me!
Whoa!
- Well, this would be good
if we had any baking to do.
Oh, my food!
You guys are- You're terrible.
You're unsanitary.
Ooh, I hope that they catch you,
and I'll testify against you,
and you'll never get out of jail.
- Hey, you'll get
all the ketchup you want.
- Drej! Ooh, I gotta go now.
- Follow ugly!
Oh, great. Yeah, no one would ever
think of looking for us in the vent.
Go!
- Go! Go!
He's the big- I'm not supposed to be here!
Come on! I'm just a cook!
How do I get out of here? How do I get
out? Why is this happening to me?
Stupid- Please- Stupid- No!
Hi. They went right down there.
They came into my kitchen and...
Bull's-eye.
We gotta
get outta here.
Go!
Go! Run!
- Over.
- Huh?
- Maybe next time, kid.
- Hey, I can fly it too.
- It won't start.
I got an idea.
Give it a shot.
Whoa!
Ow!
- Hang on, kid. I'm comin'.
Heads up!
They're
locking down the doors!
- Not going forward. Going up.
- Up?
Move it!
- You should brace yourself.
- Uh, yeah. I'm feeling that.
Eject. Hey, where's the eject?
Cale? Cale?
This model does
have eject, right?
And you were worried.
What do you mean, "were"?
- Akima, we need a pickup here.
- A little late for that.
- I'm right above you. Can you get to me?
- Not enough time.
Not-Not-
Not a lot of time.
- Exhale.
- You gotta be kidding.
- Oh, no, no, no, no!
# Comeback down to Earth, oh, yeah #
# Comeback down to Earth
Comeback down to Earth #
# Oh, yeah
- Is it dead? Can we eat it?
No, it's not dead.
Who are you?
Go away.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Preed, you're in my light.
Ah, such motherly concern
for the subject.
- Why am I naked?
- Why, you positively glow with maternal warmth, Akima.
It's very fetching.
I must have you.
- In your dreams.
- Akrennians don't dream, remember?
- They don't bathe much, either.
- I'm still naked here.
I hadn't noticed. Now, hold still, or
you'll lose something really important.
- Hand me the probe. - The probe?
Uh, wh-where does the probe go?
You know, I'm really feeling
much better. Aah! Hey!
This is just great.
Cross half the galaxy,
nearly get our butts
shot off by the Drej,
just so we can
rescue the window washer.
Hey, for your information, I happen
to be humanity's last great hope.
- I weep for the species.
- You're fine.
I mean, I'm the guy with the map here.
This is big medicine, right?
Big medicine? Let me see.
This is really it?
This can save us?
Huh? Yeah, I guess.
- Do you know what this means?
Um, I'm really wanting those pants
right about now.
Akima, my pet, if the boy isn't
at death's door,
Korso wants Gune to check the map
so we can set a course.
Do you mind?
Are we through pawing?
- This is the Valkyrie, not a singles bar.
- We're done.
You know, I never said I was gonna help you
guys. We never even addressed what's in it for me.
- Why, you get to be a hero.
- A hero? Come on.
I mean, there must be something on the
Titan worth selling or trading or...
What? We're gonna risk our necks
to help a bunch of Drifter Colony bums?
- Where are my pants?
- Guess where Akima grew up.
- Drifter Colony?
- Yes. The boy learns.
- Wait. What's your...
Preed, wait up! Look.
Where's Korso? I wanna talk to him.
I believe he's in Navigation.
We're headed there now.
- You wanna watch
who you're steppin' on.
Or you'll what?
- Ah, the lovely and talented Stith.
This is Cale.
- You remember- Cale.
- No, no, no, no, no. Cannot talk.
We lost targeting on one
of our aft gun turrets again!
What? Think
this is a pleasure cruise?
She's a sweet little thing. Weapons
specialist. Normally, she's very good-natured.
Great!
Things aren't bad enough!
- Tools all over the floor!
- Fight the good fight, precious.
Preed, I'll kill you. Okay?
I will kill you.
I am educated and well-read!
I am not a mechanic!
- I have my pride! - Gune? Guney? Are you in there?
...by the acceleration, multiplied
by the coefficient of the friction...
and apply necessary force.
- Gune?
- Ooh.
- Look at that.
- Does this look familiar? Do you know what it is?
- Neither do I. I made it last night in my sleep.
Apparently, I used Gindrogac - highly unstable.
- Gune.
- I put a button on it, yes.
I wish to press it, but I'm not sure
what will happen if I do.
- Let me see, now. Three, five,
twenty-two, seventy-four,
- eleven...
- No. No-no-no-no. Careful.
- It's perfect.
- Ho, yes!
- Hey.
- Perfect! You fixed it!
- So, where are we now?
We are here, right here-
Bellasan Quadrant.
About three million keks from Tau 14.
Why? Are you homesick?
- Gotta have a home for that.
- Mmm.
Translucent bipedal
mesomorphic embryonic male.
Yes, yes, yes. This is all very
fascinating, but take a look at this.
- It's a map. Can you read it?
- Can I read it?
Of course I can read it.
Yes. Hmm.
- So, what do you see?
- Ah!
- Yes, this is PI'ochda.
- And this- this-
this is... Solbrecht!
And this- And this-
And this- What is this?
- That's, uh- That's lunch.
- What's lunch?
- Mmm.
Spaghetti derivative, meatballs- sort
of, anyway- and Caldoch droppings.
- Who ate it before you did?
- Hey, hey!
Ahh!
- Tell you a secret. This guy's nuts.
- I'll tell you another.
He's never wrong.
Where are we going, Gune?
Ahh, the broken moon
of Sesharrim.
Only 13,000 keks away.
- Have Akima lay in a course.
- We're on our way.
- What's on Sesharrim, anyway?
- The Gauol, an ancient race.
- Great.
- This isn't a joyride, kid.
When the Drej destroyed Earth,
they figured life adrift in space...
would break us down,
wipe us out.
Do you really want
those vile creatures to be right?
- Just lay down and die?
- A little late.
About 15 years too late to save the humans.
But it's not like we didn't have a good run.
It's not about a good run.
It's about our survival.
See, the Titan was truly visionary,
the most advanced ship in the universe.
That ship has the power to reunite
the human race, to give us a home.
And the only way to find it
is in your hand.
So, you're really
counting on me, then?
- We all are.
- Well,
if I don't like
the way things are going,
I'll show you how much
like my father I really am.
I'll leave.
Ahh, no place to
set down on the island.
Land on that coral reef.
We'll take the sled,
see if we can locate the Gauol.
- Preed, you and Gune watch the ship.
- Watch the ship?
- And keep the engines hot.
- Oh, yes. They'll be nice and toasty.
- Hmm. - I'm not keen on the Drej
catching me with my trousers down.
Welcome to Planet Sesharrim, Cale.
- It stinks.
- Hydrogen trees.
Clip one of those,
and we'll be blown to steaming bits.
Hello? Anybody here?
We're looking
for the Gauol.
Now, what exactly
do the Gauol look like?
Don't know.
They don't get out much.
We have a kid with a map here
that you guys should know about.
I think we know
what happened to the Gauol.
Open fire on five.
- We'll clear a path to the sled.
Everybody ready?
- One, two...
Wait. No, no.
Stop.
- I think they are the Gauol.
Ahh.
Over here!
Quick little devil.
- Okay, all I have to do is tap
into the central computer,
and we can figure
the departure protocols.
- Yes. Making progress.
Yes, I'm making progress.
Huh? Wait, wait.
- Hmm.
Ooh. Hmm.
The moon, the moon, the moon. Right,
yeah. That's how we knew to come here.
My father made a map
with that moon on it.
Now, why? Is the ship
hidden there?
Ohh.
- Oh.
Hmm. Ahh.
It must be somewhere
in the Andali Nebula.
We did it, kid.
The Titan is as good
as ours.
He must have been here, standing here.
Right here.
- Who?
- My father.
Go!
Let's move it!
We've gotta
get to the beach!
- Akima!
- Why aren't they shooting at Cale?
- They want him alive.
Come on, guys.
Pick it up. Pick it up.
Nice catch.
Pull up! Pull up!
Preed, come in!
Preed, where are you?
- Hold on!
- Preed, come in!
- Preed!
Preed, Preed, Preed! Aren't you
supposed to be watching for the Drej?
Yes, caveman, that's right.
Drej bad. We good.
- Now, go look at
something shiny for a while.
- How's this?
- Well, you'd better look again!
Drej!
- Aah!
Captain, we're on our way.
Where are you?
We're in the
hydrogen trees being chased by the Drej.
- See if you can spot them, quick!
- Look there!
- Akima!
- Hang on!
Nice move.
Get down!
Come on.
Show yourselves.
- Get down!
- Cale!
- I got 'em.
Whoa!
Preed, look!
There they are!
Oh, no.
- Hang on, Akima!
Don't shoot!
They've got Cale!
Gune, calculate their trajectory.
Stith, take weapons.
- Let's get on it, people.
- Oh, nice job covering our butts, Preed.
- You're the weapons expert.
- What were you doing? Taking a nap?
Enough! Okay,
the Drej took Cale.
But they are not
gonna get away with it.
Well, let's quit running
our collective mouths and go get him.
Our only chance to locate them
is to track Akima. Stith, get on it.
Hmm.
They're gonna use you to figure out
where the Titan is.
Probably just blow it up,
too, when they find it.
- Yeah, well, who's to say it would've worked, anyway?
- Who's to say it won't?
Maybe Korso will get
to the Titan first.
Why do you care so much
about that thing?
I was raised
around people.
"Drifter Colony bums",
I believe, is the term.
I barely remember Earth, but the older
ones used to tell us about it...
so it would never
be completely lost.
No matter how hard things got-
and they were hard...
those memories
kept us going.
Once, we had a home.
The Titan is our chance
to find one again.
I guess that's how
I ended up here.
What are they afraid of? So what did
the human race ever do to the Drej?
- It's not what we did. They're afraid of
what we might become. - Hmm.
Yeah, well, looks like
we're becoming extinct.
- Cale, you okay?
- Akima!
Cale!
- Cale!
- No! Stop!
Leave her alone!
Akima!
No!
Akima's signal is getting stronger. I
think it's coming from the slave cages.
- A Drej pod. What's in it?
- A human.
- She's mine. I saw her first.
- Pretty.
Ah. All right.
- I'll take out the guard.
- Easy, big girl. This requires cunning and deception.
- Hello.
- Ah.
Uh, I'm an Akrennian trader.
I wonder if we might sneak a peek at the
new shipment before they go on the market?
- You're not allowed.
- Traditionally, no. You're absolutely right.
But you see,
I need a new slave rather badly.
- Stop fidgeting, worm!
And I can't wait till auction.
I have to be on the shuttle.
I have an appointment to have my ear shaved.
It has to be booked months in advance.
- You see my problem.
- Hmm.
You're Iying. He's not a slave,
and you're not traders.
- But- - He doesn't carry
himself like a slave.
- Look at the way he stands.
Probably ex-military. - How...
Akrennian traders always threaten before
they ask a favor. It's tradition.
- And your robes are made
out of bedspreads.
- Ah. - Just out of curiosity,
did we have a plan "B"?
- Hmm. An intelligent guard.
Didn't see that one coming.
Whoa.
- This is it.
- Are you in there?
Well, if it isn't the captain.
What kept you?
Do you see anything? It was really
small, like a cocoon or something.
No, no, no.
Nothing like that. No. Mmm.
I do see something.
Oh, no. Just a Drej ship.
Drej!
- What? Where?
- I'm on it. I'm on it. I'm on it.
- Korso, we have a problem.
You'd better get up here.
- I'm here. I'm here.
What's the problem?
- Stith, let's go.
- All right. All right.
- I've locked on to him, sir.
- Gune, look out for his buddy.
- There's only one. He's all alone.
Just one. - Three, five, twenty-two...
- Three, five, twenty-two,
seventy-four, eleven.
- Cale!
- Die, Drej scumball!
Oh, don't-
No, don't shoot. Oh, guys...
- Come on. It's me!
- It's Cale!
- Cale!
- Stith, hold your fire!
- Oops.
Akima,
open the cargo bay.
Cale!
- Ah! The boy is not dead. This is cause for happiness.
- Hmm.
So, um- how did you escape?
- He got lucky.
- You know, we were just about to rescue you.
- Yeah? Well, thanks.
- Anytime.
- Look, uh, they copied the map.
- I'm sure they're heading
for the Titan now.
They won't find it.
Stations, people.
Yes. Going, going.
Akima?
Uh, um, what happened?
How'd you get back?
I got picked up with the trash.
Luckily, Korso got there...
before I ended up as a door prize
in some alien freak show.
I guess I owe him one.
You know, we both
got real lucky back there.
- But the next time around-
- Cale.
Come on.
Gune needs a hand.
- Yes, the map is good.
The map is different.
- Yes, the map is clear.
- Yes, it's very, very clear.
- Ooh. Take it easy.
Hmm. This outer marking
is pulsing.
- Ah, the distal Phalangial Meridian.
- Gune, what do you make of it?
Past outer quadrant.
This is the Ice Rings of Tigrin.
Right here. Hmm.
- Easy to get lost in there.
- Good hiding place.
What?
- Wakeangels.
They follow ships into deep space,
glide on the energywake.
- They're supposed to be good luck.
They're like... ghosts.
Sit down. Why don't
you give 'em a run?
- You sure about that?
- 'Course I'm sure.
Okay.
# It's my time to fly #
# I'm proving ground
tonight #
# I'll try to be the best
that I can #
Yeah. You got it.
Open her up.
- Give these angels something to chase.
- All right.
Try this, guys.
# It's my time to fly #
# My father will be
with me tonight #
# Ooh #
# We're right on target #
# It's my time to fly #
# My father will
be with us tonight #
# A chance tonight #
# To victory #
# Dreams become reality #
# Reality #
# It's my time to fly #
# My father will be
with me tonight #
# Ooh, I'm right on target #
# It's my time to fly #
# My father will be
with us tonight #
# It's my time to fly #
# My father will be
with me tonight #
# Ooh, we're right on target #
# It's my time to fly #
# My father will be
with me tonight #
# Ooh #
# I'm right on target #
- Thank you.
- I knew you could handle this old bird.
No, I mean-
I mean, thank you for...
Thank you for trying to find me.
It's more than my father ever did.
Your father was a great man,
Cale.
- He would've been proud of ya.
- You really think so?
- Trust me.
Thanks. Thanks.
You know, I-
I miss him.
Me too.
Akima?
Akima? Huh?
Oh, uh, uh, uh, sorry.
- In or out?
- Huh? Oh, uh, in.
Uh, what's going on?
Do you know why we stopped?
Pit stop for the basics.
Drifter Colony's the best place...
to pick up plasmapacks,
fuelcells, frozen burritos.
Listen. I need
to talk to you, and...
Where'd you get all this junk?
Not junk.
Why don't you come with me?
I'll show you.
So, we're gonna barter this stuff
for more of that Earthjunk?
Don't you get it, Cale? That junk is all
that's left of the place we came from.
It reminds us of
all the things we miss.
Mm, miss. Like those frozen burritos
you were talking about.
- At least they don't
jump off your plate.
You think this is some game?
Did you forget the plan?
I get you the Titan;
I get rich. We had a deal, right?
- How dare you try
to cut me out like that?
Yeah? Do as you please, and
guess what. You'll retrieve nothing.
You don't have the whole map.
The kid's got it. And I've got the kid.
So you keep your drones
off my back,
or so help me,
I'll rip his heart out.
Cale, come on.
Going somewhere?
Look what I've found:
two little birdies itchy to fly.
- How long were they standing there?
- Long enough.
You lied?
Everything you said?
Everything you told me?
Not everything.
Your father hid his ship,
then the Drej killed him,
all because he couldn't face the truth.
- Yeah? What is the truth? - That the human race
is out of gas. It's circlin' the drain.
It's finished. The only thing that
matters is grabbin' what you can...
before somebody else
beats you to it.
No, I don't believe that!
Then you're even more like
your father than I thought. A fool.
- Cale!
- Akima, come on!
- Stop them.
Stay on 'em.
I'll lock it down.
- Hurry!
- Go! Go!
- Akima! Akima?
Let's go.
We got a ship to find.
Let's get airborne,
now.
- Where's Cale and Akima?
- They're not coming.
- Why not?
- Because they're afraid.
Afraid? What exactly are they afraid of?
They're afraid of what might happen
if my command was ever questioned.
- Get it?
- Got it.
- You got a problem with that?
No.
- Why they not say good-bye to Gune?
- Go get a blanket, quickly. She needs warmth.
- Something to keep her warm.
You, go get a doctor.
- Yeah. Hurry.
- Cover her.
- Yes, yes.
- What did you tell him?
I asked him
to bring corn liquor.
No. Really,
I don't need it.
Ha! Not for you.
For boy.
- Me?
- He pass out soon.
- She'll be fine. She just
needs rest. Don't worry.
She'll be fine.
Hey!
It's his favorite thing in the world...
that stupid ball.
It was our dad's
back on Earth.
Every time
he kicks that thing,
my brother thinks
he's in a big grass field.
That's some imagination.
Yeah, well. - There. He had
a little help. See what I mean?
That's him - our dad.
That's where my brother
got the idea.
Hmm.
Here on the colony,
most people got to shut their eyes...
to see anything other
than rusted spaceship hulls.
Not my brother.
Later.
- Hey. Sleeping Beauty.
- How long was I out?
Not long.
A few hours.
Korso and Preed. I can't believe it.
How long before
they reach the Titan?
They won't.
We're gonna beat them to it.
Akima, we're gonna
stop them.
Was I seriously injured
back there or something,
'cause, funny, I thought you just said
we're gonna stop them?
- That's right.
- Cale, we're in the middle of nowhere.
There's just the two of us,
and, oh, yeah - we don't have a ship.
- Oh, we've got a ship.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
- I'd like to see this... ship.
Check it out.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, yes!
Well, she's been a great house,
but I don't think she'll fly.
Well, she's still got her ionic
vacuum drive. Those never drain.
- This thing's a wreck.
- I can fix it, but do you think...
Don't worry.
I can fly it.
Good, 'cause
we launch yesterday.
# I've gotta get away from here #
# It couldn't be too soon #
# 'Cause I've seen the stars
for you and me #
# Like rockets
to the moon #
# You take me everywhere
that I've never been #
# Show me the meaning
of what life had to give #
# I don't know
what to say #
# I think that maybe
I'm in over my head #
# Stuck in the bed somethin' she said #
- Ow!
# Makes me think
that I'm in over my head #
# Over my head #
T- minus ten, nine,
eight, seven,
- six, five,
- Well, we're good to go.
- four, three,
- Let's hope she starts.
- two,
- Oh, she'll start.
- one, zero.
- Yeah, right.
- She'll start.
Uh, I'd lean back
if I were you.
- Should I get out and push?
- Told ya.
- Okay. You did your job. Now let me do mine.
These collisions keep slowing us down.
- So where is it? - My scanners are picking up
a veritable cornucopia of... nothing.
Just find it!
Gune, are you sure about that map?
You give me map. I follow map.
What more can Gune do?
- If Professor Screwloose over there led
us off course, I'm going to- - Hold it!
- What is it?
- A ship. Three keks east.
- Drej?
- No. Human craft, heading for the break zone. Moving fast.
- How fast?
- I'd say recklessly fast.
- Akima.
- Ah, good!
Akima. Cale.
I- I hail on communicator.
No hailing.
Just follow them.
Okay. I follow, but I plot
new route through safer quadrant.
- If we...
- We're going to follow them,
and we'll run silent.
The reflections
are throwing my readings off.
Uh, Akima, I think
we're getting closer.
- Cale! It's Korso.
- Huh?
- He's right behind us.
- What?
We've got to lose him.
- We'll never find them in there.
- We're going in.
- Stith, where are they?
- I can't get a reading.
There's too much ice,
too much interference, Captain.
- Captain.
- Whoa!
A heat signature.
I see them!
- Where are they?
- Behind us!
- No!
Where is he?
I- I don't know.
- What?
- Well, we found them, Captain.
No more heat readings.
All gone.
Until they make their move,
we stay here.
- They're moving out, I think.
- Now we've got 'em.
- I can't move. They'll see us.
- Maybe that's exactly what we want.
A reading!
Yeah. They're right in front of us.
You're not gonna
get past me, kid.
- There, Captain!
- That's right, Cale. Keep coming.
Closer.
They're getting closer!
There she is, Captain.
No. There, Captain.
Which one?
Look!
They're behind us now!
- Ready lasers!
- I'm on it!
I need one clear shot.
Don't lose 'em.
- Ice! Turn back!
- No way.
- We'll never make it through.
- We don't have a choice.
- Akima! Uh-
- Yes, Cale?
- Pull up!
- Shut up!
Let's not
do that again.
Hold it.
Look there.
Akima, turn around.
Turn around!
That's it.
Wow. Have you ever
seen anything like it?
Once.
- What exactly are we looking for?
- This ship's gonna help us save mankind.
- Not a clue.
DNA coding.
"Mammal.
Tursiops truncatus."
The bottle-nosed dolphin.
These are animals-
or- or they will be.
"Leopard.
Papilio glaucus."
Swallowtail butterfly.
It's all here.
- Cale?
- I'm over here!
Look at this.
Dad.
I could never have done anything
like this when I was your age.
- I wonder who you take after?
Hey.
- The Titan. Quick.
- Ready to go, Captain.
You two stay here.
Preed and I can wrap this up.
- But- Here. Hold on to this
in case there's any trouble.
Hmm.
N- N-N-N-No.
Those two are
becoming a problem.
- We need to take care of it.
I'm one step
ahead of you.
- Watch the ship. I always watch the ship.
- No, this just doesn't feel right.
- I wanna go! I wanna go!
- Captain said stay.
It's Captain I don't trust.
Hmm. You know,
you may be right. Come on.
- Stith here.
- Stith, is Gune right there with you?
- Yeah.
- Then please tell him good-bye
for me, won't you? - What?
- Gune!
- I knew it! I knew it! - Get out of there!
- Cale. If this message has-
- Dad?
If this message has been activated,
then I have died before finding you.
I hope
you can forgive me...
for breaking my promise
to see you again.
What I wouldn't give
to see you now.
I can't change the past, Cale,
but I hope I can give you a future.
This ship has the power
to create a planet,
to create a new home.
Your ring would have activated
the transformation sequence,
but the Titan's power cells
were drained in the escape.
They are unable
to fuel the transformation.
It is up to you
to restore their power.
After that,
the procedure is simple.
- He always did talk too much.
- Oh!
- Ah-Ah-Ah.
Korso, don't do this. This ship is all we
have left. Doesn't that mean anything to you?
Sorry, kid.
World blowing up changes a man.
- Look. The Drej-
- See, you can't beat the Drej.
No one can.
They're pure energy.
Face it, Cale.
You've lost.
- Actually, you all have.
Captain, if you'll relieve yourself
of your firearm...
- You backstabbing-
- Well, I learned from the best.
But it wasn't just the money
the Drej were offering.
It was the health plan
that came with it.
They'd let me live provided
I kill all of you before they get here.
They should be here shortly.
- Gune? Gune?
- Gune!
- Gune, are you all right?
- I'm- I'm all right f-for business.
- Gune.
- I'll just take a little nap...
since I'm so- very sleepy.
Ahh.
- Preed, you can't trust the Drej.
- Akima.
Oh, stop! There's nothing more
tiresome than last-minute heroics!
- Captain? Mm. Oh.
- Hide 'n' seek, is it?
Or should we play...
search and destroy!
- Preed!
- Ah!
- Give me the ring.
- Aw. You're not gonna shoot me, kid.
- Cale!
- Ah. Aah!
Hold on!
Oh!
You can let go, kid.
I wouldn't blame you.
No! I'm not
gonna let go!
- Korso!
- Cale! The Drej!
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Let's not panic.
- We've gotta get out of here before the Drej arrive.
- No, I think we're gonna stay right here.
- Right here is about to be blown apart.
- This could be a good thing. Wait.
- Come on, Cale!
Wait.
We can make this work.
- What did Korso say about the Drej?
- That you can't beat them.
Right!
Because they're pure energy.
If I can reroute the system to use Drej
energy, that would start the reactor.
The energy relays are linked to these
circuit breakers, so this should do it.
- Yes!
- Are you sure this will work?
Come on!
I can fix this!
I need to get outside. Can you and Stith cover me? I
- I just need a little time.
- How much time?
- Uh, a few hours!
What can you do
in a few minutes?
- Here they come.
- Not if I can help it.
- Cale, you're a sitting duck up there.
- I'm all right.
- Oh!
- Come on!
Whoo!
- Oh, fantastic. I only have two guns left.
- Let's make 'em count.
- Akima, I can't shake 'em.
- I've got him.
Ah! I'm out!
Let's do this! Whoo!
- Well, guys, it's been fun.
- A little help here, Akima. Whoa!
- Cale!
I finished my nap!
- Gune!
- Who's your daddy?
Gune's your daddy!
Oh, no! No, no, no, no!
Oh!
- Cale, are you all right?
- I'm pinned.
- Stith, who's outside with Cale?
- Hi, kid.
- It's Korso!
You'll never get a cleaner shot, Korso.
Maybe we can beat 'em
after all.
Go ahead.
I'll cover you.
Yeah, yeah. Right.
Okay.
- Oh, great.
- Fry, Drej!
- Ah!
They're leaving.
Uh-oh.
We got a problem.
Go. They're
joining the mother ship.
- But the breaker!
- Cale, she's preparing to fire!
- You can't stay out here.
- I'll take care of it, so let's move.
Go on. Get out of here.
Cale, where are you?
Go. It's better this way.
Uh...
Here they come again.
Come on.
Faster. Faster.
This is amazing.
I know.
What are
you going to call it?
I think
I'll call it... Bob.
- Bob?
- You don't like "Bob"?
You can't
call a planet "Bob".
Oh, so now you're the boss.
You're the king of Bob.
- Well, no, but-
- What?
Can't you just
call it Earth?
Well, no one said
you had to live on Bob.
I'm never...
calling it that.
# Ohh, oh, oh #
# Ohh, oh, oh, oh #
# Take the path
of least resistance #
# Into the great unknown #
# No directory assistance #
# Now you're on your own #
# But if you're looking
for a new world #
# Just open up your eyes #
- # Because it's not quite paradise #
- # No #
# But it sure feels like home #
# Not quite paradise #
# And we can rent to own #
# It'll be all right #
# No, it's not quite #
# Paradise #
# Tomorrow's an illusion #
# And yesterday's a dream #
# Today is absolution #
# But you gotta let it be #
# And if you're looking
for the answer #
# It's right before your eyes #
- # Although it's not quite paradise #
- # No, oh, no, oh #
# But it sure looks like home #
# Not quite paradise #
# And we are not alone #
# It'll be all right #
# No, it's not quite #
# Paradise #
# Somewhere
from the edge of time #
# When the poets gather
words don't rhyme #
# I'll call you up and say #
# We made it okay #
# Somewhere
in the back of your mind #
# When you see your demons
come to life #
# And the world
just fades away #
# You know it's okay #
# Ohh, oh, oh #
- # Ohh, oh, oh, oh #
- # It's gonna be okay #
# Ohh, oh, oh #
# Ohh, oh, oh, oh #
- # Okay #
- # Oh, oh, oh #
# Oh, oh, oh, oh #
- # Okay #
- # Oh, oh, oh #
# Oh, oh, oh, oh #
- # But it's not quite paradise #
- # Oh, no #
# But it sure feels like home #
# Not quite paradise #
# We'll make this place
our own #
# Not quite paradise #
# We can rent to own #
# We don't have to be alone #
- # Not quite paradise #
- # No, no #
- # No, no, no, no #
- # Not quite paradise #
- # No, no, yeah #
# Now we've traveled far #
# But are we any nearer #
# There's a feelin'
we're reaching for #
# In the fields
where it all began #
# Listen, do you hear #
# I thought I heard a promise #
# But that empty feeling grows #
# And I'm scared
that I will forget #
# But I #
# I can remember #
# Look around and around #
# There's people
still hanging on #
# See, it's me
I'm the one #
# Believe in me
I've just begun #
# We'll be here
when the lights come on #
# When it all comes down #
# to me and you #
# Just a boy and girl #
# Trying to
change a cold world #
# I don't expect
that you'd understand #
# When you look
at this empty land #
# But I #
# I can remember #
# Look around and around #
# People still hanging on #
# And I #
# I can remember them #
# Be it night or day #
# Like lovers left holding on #
# You see it's me
I'm the one #
# Believe in me
I've just begun #
# And we'll be here
when the lights come on #
# When it all comes down #
# to me and you #
# And I #
# I can remember #
# Look around and around #
# People still hanging on #
# And I #
# I can remember them #
# Be it night or day #
# Like lovers left holding on #
# And I #
# I can remember #
# Look around and around #
# People still hanging on #
# Andonandonandonandon #
# On andonandonandon #
- # I remember #
- # On andonandon #
# You keep me holding on #
- # You keep me holding on #
- # Andonandonandonandon #
# On andonandonandon #
# On andonandon #
# Like lovers left holding on #
# Andonandonandonandon #
# On andonandonandon #
# On andonandon #
# Like lovers left holding on #
Subtitles corrected to perfection by alphanse@mail.com