Lafayette Courier.
Got 'er. Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Cam!
Have you seen Cam?
Where in the hell is he?
Cam, where you at, buddy?
Damn!
Cam!
Uptown express, okay!
- Unh!
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
Hey, you!
Come back here.
Sorry about your bike.
Come back here!
Cam.
You want
your check or not?
Sorry.
Lonnie,
I need more runs.
Cam, I'm happy
to help you out,
but you need
a bike first, man.
Got a friend
that can loan you one?
Hey, uh...
keep your head up.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
- Hey!
- What?
Where you been hiding?
Whatcha got there, Cam?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
Okay, so what?
You forget about us or what?
No, no, no, I didn't...
I didn't forget.
I just...
I didn't have it.
I just got that.
Okay. Well,
what else you got?
- Come on.
- Come on, man.
Are you serious?
I am serious.
- What is that, $9.00?
- Yeah, $9.00, probably.
- Where's all your
money going, man?
- To you guys!
You came to us
for a loan, right, Cam?
You accepted our terms.
1500.
On the first
of each month, every month.
I know. I know.
I-I-I'm sorry.
I... I'm sorry
I missed a payment.
It won't happen again.
No, it won't.
Now. Sign this please.
Jerry,
I owe somebody rent.
Don't you wanna...
And what, you think
I'm doing this for fun?
- No, I c...
- This is my job, Cam, okay?
I got a boss
just like you got a boss.
Now just sign it, okay?
This is the second time
you've been late.
And, uh,
that makes us, um...
- What's that make us?
- Nervous.
- Nervous. See?
- Yeah.
Hu is nervous.
So, you owe us $15,000.
And just don't miss
another payment.
I won't.
Don't miss another payment.
I know.
- You good, buddy?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- You all right?
- Yeah, I'm good.
Okay.
Where's your bike?
I, uh,
I hit a pothole.
It looks like you got
bigger problems.
Let's get in here.
All right.
When are we gonna go
for a ride?
Car's still broken, buddy.
I haven't had time
to work on it.
And I don't have the money
or the parts I need.
Maybe you ought
to sell it.
Yeah, maybe.
Joey?
All right,
you're good to go.
Thanks a lot, Cam.
You're welcome.
I told you to give Cam
his space.
Chill-lax, Mom.
It's all gravy.
Chill-lax?
Sorry about that.
Don't worry about it.
He's a good kid.
Hey, Ang.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
I'm gonna be a little late
on the rent this month.
I'm sorry.
I'll get it to you
as soon as I can.
I know you're good for it,
but I'm having a tough month.
Try your best,
please, Cam?
I know. I will.
Thank you.
Yeah?
You coming
in today or not?
What are you...
what are you talking about?
Do you not remember?
What do you want me
to do with your new bike, then?
What new bike?
The one
your girlfriend dropped off
for you this morning.
I don't have a girlfriend.
- Hey!
- What do you want?
To... to say thank you.
- For what?
- What do you mean for what?
For the bike you got me.
You're welcome.
Do you, uh...
How did you learn
how to do parkour?
What, did I say it wrong?
- I gotta go.
- Wait, what's your name?
Do you ride?
No. A bike's a ball
and chain.
Oh, yeah?
All right.
Well, you know,
anybody can...
hop up and climb this thing.
I'd like to see that.
All right.
You got it.
Maybe you should stick
to the bike.
Screw it.
I'm Cam.
Nikki.
You want to show me
something else?
Unh.
Ugh.
You gotta learn how to see.
I can see just fine.
If you want to vault the car,
don't look at the car,
look where the car isn't.
Okay.
Whoa, hey!
How did you get over there?
Nice to meet you, Cam.
Who are you?
What are you doing here,
Dylan?
I'm just looking out for you,
Nicks.
So what, you're just
spying on me the whole time?
- You working out alone?
- So what?
So you gotta be careful.
That's all I'm saying.
You gotta stay off my ass,
Dyl.
Who is this guy?
He's nobody.
Haven't seen you
around.
I haven't been around.
Where'd you find him?
He found me.
- You following her?
- No, no.
Just saw her in the park.
You know
this is dangerous stuff.
You get hurt
if you don't know
what you're doing.
Let's bounce.
Wonderful.
Well, some of this stuff
is kinda beat up,
but uh...
I'll give you 450.
Look, my rent's $550.
Can you go there?
One, two, three,
four, five, fifty.
Thanks.
Thanks a lot.
How much for
the muscle car, kid?
It was my Dad's.
I'm gonna have to hold onto it.
Too bad, nice car.
Hey, Cam!
You saw that, mom?
Yeah, I did, baby.
Come on...
Hey, Joey!
It's not much to look at,
but... Okay.
Better watch the potholes
this time, all right?
Hey, buddy.
Looks like
somebody's been
practicing.
You should come work out
with us.
I never see you
guys around.
We're a tight group.
We like to keep
to ourselves.
Loujaine floating
terminal in Brooklyn.
- You know it?
- No.
Pier 62. Gowanus Bay.
I'll see you at dawn.
All right.
Hey, guys.
I'm Dylan.
This is Tate, Jax.
- How's it going?
- Cam.
What's up?
This is my sister Nikki.
We already met.
This is awesome.
What are we supposed to do?
Try and keep up.
Holy shit!
He's dead, dude.
Hey, there.
You must be Cam.
Dylan tells me
you're new to parkour.
He also said
you're pretty good.
Might have to, uh,
work on this jump though.
I'm Miller.
Pick a fight with gravity
before you're ready,
you tend to get a beating.
I don't know
what I'm doing.
That's the great thing
about parkour, my friend.
There are no rules.
- You all right?
- I'm good.
Just trying to keep up.
Cam.
Is that short for Camaro?
Shut... You have
a learning disability, dude.
Excuse him.
- Where you from?
- Queens.
Play any sports
in high school?
Nah, I barely went.
I tried baseball once,
Yeah, I wasn't much of a jock
in high school either.
Look at you.
Hello.
Where'd you do your time?
You're not
the only one in here
with a record.
Abbot House.
Hillside.
Juvi.
Yeah.
Did six months in Otisville
a couple years ago.
Oh shit, what for?
B & E. Boosting cars.
Just bullshit stuff.
You ever go in hard?
Pull some hold ups?
No. I didn't want
to go that way.
Right.
So, what'd you do for money?
I'm a bike messenger.
Fifty points
for the bike messenger.
What do you guys deliver?
Documents.
Just business stuff.
At least,
that's what they tell you.
I don't know.
I mean,
they hand me a package,
I drop it off.
Sure, but it could be
anything, right?
I guess.
You never look
inside the bag?
No.
Never?
No. Why would I do that?
Just curiosity.
It's none of my business.
But you're the one
carrying the package.
Look, as long as
after I drop it off
they pay me my money,
I don't really care
what's inside the bag.
- So what do you guys do?
We do whatever we can
not to get caught.
Heh.
That looks like fun.
They are no limits, my friend.
- Only plateaus.
- Plateaus?
You've got
to constantly push past
what you think you can do
or you stay stuck.
Hmm. I like that one.
What else you got?
Well, how about this?
This whole thing,
parkour, free running, tracing...
whatever you want to call it,
is just a state of mind.
Now the real obstacles
are not out there.
They're in your head.
Okay?
I don't know.
Those obstacles look
pretty real to me.
Well, you're gonna have to start
seeing 'em differently.
Hmm. Got it.
So look where the car isn't.
Exactly.
So, uh, how's that new bike
treating you?
It's good.
Thanks again.
Where is it?
I, uh,
left it at home today.
Liar.
Somebody clipped it.
I didn't want to say anything.
It's all good.
I get it.
You're one of those kind
of people.
What kind of people
is that?
Can't hang on
to anything nice.
I guess I haven't had
enough practice.
Don't worry about it.
I should've known better.
I mean...
Next time
I'll just take my wallet
and burn it.
Hey, Niks! Let's go!
You guys all work together?
See you around, Cam.
Good to meet you, Cam.
Don't let these guys
get you in trouble.
Oh, shit!
Excuse me,
is-is Jerry here?
Jerry?
Back there?
Okay.
Excuse me, Sir.
Is Jerry here?
You just missed him.
Do you know
when he'll be back?
When he returns.
Okay.
Hey!
- Hey, what are you doing?
- Hey, Cam.
You didn't tell us
you had such a sweet ride, man.
I have your cash,
right here!
Here.
- There you go, take it.
- All right, man.
We're taking five grand
off your tab for the car,
but you got one month
to get us the rest, all right?
How am I supposed to get
10 grand in a month, Jerry?!
Not my problem, Cam.
Jerry, cut me some slack,
come on.
You still don't understand
how this works, do you?
If you don't pay,
we don't shoot you.
You got one month, Cam.
Go inside the house, Joey.
- Now.
- Joey.
Hey, Angie, I'm sorry.
Your friends
gave Joey a ride home
from school today, Cam.
Those assholes brought
my son home from school.
I don't know
what you're involved in,
and I don't want to know.
Stay away from us.
I mean it.
Oh, hey look who's here.
- Hey, what's up, buddy?
- Are you okay?
I want in.
You are in.
We don't just let
anybody train with us.
No, I'm talking about work.
Whatever you guys got going on
I want in on it.
What's your problem?
What do you guys think,
I'm a narc or something?
Come on.
Hey, Dylan.
I need to talk to Miller.
Hook me up.
No, it's a bad idea.
Why, you know
something I don't?
We're in the
transport business, Cam.
We move valuables.
People hire us
to make obstacles go away,
change hands,
land on someone else.
The difference is
I provide assurances
that other people can't.
I guarantee the work.
You want
some evidence to disappear?
We can take
of that for you.
It's a profession.
We're not thrill seekers who
pull any score that comes along.
The key is speed and silence.
In and out, fast and quiet.
We do our research.
Plan every move.
Work as a team.
Everyone knows their job.
Documents. Chemicals.
Technology. Anything.
We don't take sides.
Now I got just two rules.
The first is,
if you get in trouble,
I'm your first call.
The second,
you stay out of Chinatown.
Even if you're not on a job.
Why is that?
I'm inviting you to sit down
at the dinner table.
Show me you know how
to be a good guest.
Nice work.
Dyl!
Turn around!
Hold on!
- Don't move!
- I'm not.
- Shut up! Shut up!
- I'm not moving!
Who do you work for?
- I said, who do you work for?
- Answer his question!
No one!
What's in the bag?
- Tell me what's in the bag!
- I don't know!
- Give it to me!
- No!
Give it to me!
Give me the bag!
You tell me what's in that bag!
You tell me what's in that bag
or I'm gonna
blow your brains out
right now!
I swear to God!
- What is in the bag!
- I just carry the bag!
Good work, Cam.
What... what's going on?
You pulled some serious
moves out there, pal.
Dude, we heard about the bus.
That was sick!
And you, sir,
you were hauling ass!
Hey, it's all right, buddy.
We just had to make sure
you had our backs.
You're family now.
What do you think?
I think you're a bunch
of assholes.
Especially you.
- Hey.
Where you taking me?
All right.
Where are the others?
They're busy.
Well...
you want to grab
a coffee or something?
This isn't a date.
I didn't...
I didn't mean it
like a date.
Let's just get this done,
okay?
So how long have you been
Working for Miller?
A few years.
Did you grow up
in the city?
No.
Where'd you learn how
to do parkour?
Here.
You still live with Dylan?
Okay,
enough with the questions, okay?
I'm just trying
to make conversation.
Yeah,
but you wanted to be in.
Guess what?
You're in.
There's nothing left to discuss.
- What's your deal?
- My deal?
- Yeah, what's your deal?
- I don't have a deal.
- Then why are you
acting like this?
- Acting like what?
I-I don't know.
I just thought we could...
I didn't ask
you to come find me.
Really?
You sure about that?
You did give me that bike...
I'm gonna tell Miller you can
work on your own next time.
You don't need
a babysitter.
Okay.
This the new guy?
Yeah.
Good luck, new guy.
Dylan.
Jax.
Nikki.
Tate.
Employee of the month,
Cam.
Angie?
What are you doing here,
Cam? I'm working.
I know.
I brought your rent money.
I don't care
what you brought.
I told you to leave us
alone, right?
Angie...
Angie, please.
Hey, hey.
Please take it.
Okay?
It'll hold you over until you
find somebody else to move in.
This is too much.
What kind of trouble
are you in?
My mom got sick
after she lost her job.
So I borrowed some money
off the street
to try and help her
keep the house.
It wasn't enough.
So the bank foreclosed on her
a week before she died.
You got a good heart, Cam,
but you got to be careful.
Further you go down
the wrong road,
the harder it gets
to find your way back.
I gotta get back to work.
Wait, one sec.
One sec.
Can you give this to Joey?
You don't have
to tell him it's from me.
I'm sorry for everything.
I really am.
I won't bother
you guys again,
I promise.
Hey.
What do you think, man?
Factory paint,
marine grey.
14 inch rally wheels.
You got something for us?
Uh, that's not even
two grand here, man.
I need 10.
Give me a few more weeks
I'll get it to you.
Well, that's past
the deadline, Cam.
I was hoping
we could renegotiate.
Look, I got a new job.
You can raise the vig
if you want to...
Ugh!
You're still acting
like I'm the boss, Cam.
I'm not, all right?
Chen is the boss.
The money you owe me,
I own Chen!
You put me
in a tight spot here, Cam.
Now I don't want
to see anything happen
to your friend
and her little boy, but...
you don't make
this right, it will.
Those are the rules.
Ugh!
Two weeks, Cam.
10 grand.
- Unh.
Yeah?
- We're going out tonight.
- Want to come?
- Work?
- More like play.
Can I get a water?
Hey, what happened here?
- This?
- Yeah.
I biffed a wall trick.
- Oh, how's the wall?
Check this out.
Got it on a broken rail.
- That's nothing man.
- Check this out.
Razor wire.
Dylan, why don't you show them
what happened right here, huh?
- Is that from a curb?
- Nah.
It was a older lady.
He loves the cougar's.
Yeah.
She was a nice girl.
She was Chinese.
She was real smart.
I met her on the subway.
I see her walking down the
street one night with this guy.
I assume it must be her
cousin or something.
So I go up to her,
I give her a big hug and a kiss.
And she freaks out.
Like she's never seen me before.
Goes totally ape shit.
Turns out her cuz'
was her husband.
Yeah, husband,
mixed-martial artist.
Bad news
for the lady killer.
Is that why
we can't cut though Chinatown?
No, that's all Miller,
man.
He's got bad blood
with the gangs there.
- What, the Tongs?
- Yeah.
Yeah,
some business went south.
He had to cut a deal,
promise to stay away.
You know,
Nikki's got some cute marks.
Hey, hey.
I don't know
what he's talking about.
It's not happening.
If I show you,
I'd have to kill ya.
He said it.
There she is!
The future Mrs. Jackson Smith.
- Right there.
- Oh, yeah?
That's gonna be
my future ex-wife.
Yeah, we're gonna move
to the countryside.
Make lots
of sweet ginger babies
every night of the week.
- Oh, that's a terrible visual!
- Then rest of our lives.
- Ugh!
- I know, you're jealous.
You guys know nothing
about women.
Hey.
Hey, Hey.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
It's just stuffy
as hell in there.
That's all.
Do you wanna...
do you wanna
get out of here?
You want to go
somewhere else?
Not right now.
No, I can't.
Hey, what's wrong with you?
Nikki,
what are you afraid of?
Hey, guys.
Sorry I missed the fun.
I had some business
to take care of.
Yeah.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Hey, Cam.
If you need anything at all,
call me.
- All right?
- Yeah.
Coming back in?
No, I'm tired.
I'm...
gonna hit it.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
Wanted to talk to you.
How did you find me?
Why are you living
on the roof?
Why didn't you tell me
you were with Miller?
Dylan got into some trouble.
And Miller made it go away.
So your brother
pimped you out to the boss.
Sounds pretty simple to me.
- Miller doesn't own me.
- Is that right?
Why are you here?
What's the point?
I should have told you.
It's my fault, but...
Cam you wouldn't even
be here if I...
- So you want me to quit?
- You can still walk.
Is that what you want?
I don't want
you to owe Miller
like we do!
Do you want me to go?
No...
I heard once
tattoo's are like scars
that you wear on the outside
to show the pain
that's on the inside.
Is that true?
I don't know.
Why don't you have any?
'Cause I don't want
anyone to know.
I owe people money, Nikki.
And as soon as
I pay them off...
I'm gone.
And this moment
was brought to you by
the sounds of summer
in New York City.
Yeah, we're in a
over-crowded prison.
Uh, I don't really mind it.
- No?
- No.
I mean,
before I left Florida,
I'd never even seen a town
bigger than 500 people.
Well, you're lucky,
'cause all I've ever seen
is this jungle.
You've never been
outside the city?
No.
I mean,
I don't count my jail time.
I tried to leave.
When?
After my mom died.
When she passed away,
I found out that
she had my dad's old car.
And she never told me
while she was alive,
'cause she was afraid
if I found out
I'd sell it to
try and help her out.
So, uh...
she kept it a secret.
She wrote me a letter.
She said she wanted me
to fix it up,
get it running again.
Just hop in and drive.
Somewhere...
I don't know where,
far away.
California maybe.
That was the plan.
Well, where's the car now?
The ahh...
the bank took it.
- The bank?
- Uh-uh.
Oh.
I guess I'm just one
of those people
who can never hold
onto anything nice.
I'll agree with that.
Haha.
Where you been, baby?
I went for a walk.
Anything wrong?
Hmm?
No.
Nothing,
you know I just...
get nervous
before the big jobs.
That's all.
Sure that's all?
You seem kind of distant.
Yeah.
Like you're
somewhere else.
No.
Right here, James.
I don't know what I'd do
without you.
You know that?
I'm just tired.
I'm gonna go to bed.
Sure.
He's getting better.
Nikki and I were living
on the streets
when we found parkour.
We got hooked.
It was like being kids again.
The whole city
is our playground.
Is that where
you met Miller?
Uh-huh. Yeah.
Miller raised us.
Taught us everything we knew,
got us off the streets.
We'd be nowhere without him.
Yeah, Nikki said
that she got you out
of some sort of trouble
or something.
Nikki said that?
Yeah.
What'd she tell you,
exactly?
I mean,
nothing specifically.
Just that you got
in some sort of trouble.
And he made it go away.
But she really cares
about you.
She doesn't want
to see you get hurt.
Are you in some sort
of trouble, Cam?
'Cause if you are,
and Miller finds out,
it's not just you.
That's trouble for all of us.
And he always finds out.
No.
I'm all good.
Good.
I got the last one.
Unit 17 code...
All clear, good job.
Whoo!
That's how we do it!
Wait.
I'll catch up
with you later?
Sure. Talk later.
What do you mean?
Where's our money?
Payday is next week,
Cam, same as usual.
Okay, when's the next
gig happening?
Soon.
Hey, you did a good job.
Get some rest.
You don't understand.
I need that money.
Do we have a problem?
No. No.
No problem.
I've got a big job
coming up next week.
It's worth 15,
20 grand each at least.
Does that work for you guys?
- Sweet. Sounds good.
- Yeah.
How about you, Cam?
Work for you?
Yeah, that works.
Good.
You look just
like your dad.
Yeah, I get that a lot.
It's a nice...
constant reminder
of the amazing father he was.
Well, if it's
any consolation,
my dad wasn't exactly
a real winner either.
Sometimes it's
better not to know.
Yeah.
You're just going
to leave, aren't you?
You should come with me.
Yeah, right.
Why "yeah, right"?
I can't.
Why not?
It's complicated.
Well...
I'm not going anywhere
without wheels.
Hold on to this for me.
Thank you.
Nice spot.
I can see all the way
into the future from up here.
Yeah, what happened
to staying in the moment?
You're a good student,
Cam.
Now you're moving
beyond what you've been taught.
But outside there's
a natural order to things.
You know, there can be
only one alpha for every pack.
And that my friend,
I learned the hard way.
A long time ago.
In the back
of a Chinese restaurant,
trying to beg for my life
with a gun in my mouth.
Is there something
you need to tell me, Cam?
There's nothing.
You sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
You should get
some plants up here.
Liven this place up a bit.
Pickup tomorrow at 9:30.
Hey guys.
Where's Nikki?
Gave her the day off.
Two minutes.
You'll be needing this.
Wait, we're
going in strong?
I told you
it was big, my friend.
You're gonna
get a cut.
Twenty grand each.
Maybe more.
I didn't sign up for this.
Okay,
it's up here on the corner.
We're doing a bank?
Old bank. New money.
BTK bought it.
BTK?
Vietnamese bangers.
This is their laundromat.
They keep a big stack,
couple hundred K.
How do you know all this?
That's my job.
How we getting
in this thing?
The front door.
What?
You're risking
a lot here, man.
Tell your man
to make this look good.
Okay, game time.
Who's got my piece?
You're carrying
the package.
You'll be all right.
We've done this before.
We don't even shoot
these things.
Be safe, kids,
stay out of trouble.
Masks!
Hand off the gun!
Toss him the gun!
You deaf?
You don't like
to listen, huh?
Get on the ground!
You deaf? Get on the floor!
We got to get moving!
What... what's
the combination?!
Answer him!
Tell me how we get inside!
You think this is funny?!
Tell me what the combo is!
What, is everybody deaf
and dumb here?
Answer his question!
What's the combination?!
I don't have it.
Is there another way in?
Yo, come on!
I can get in.
What the hell
are you doing?
I can't see shit
with this thing!
We got to move, guys!
There's nothing.
It's empty!
- Check again!
- With nothing!
Where's the money?!
I don't know, dude.
I don't know.
What are you
laughing at, big guy?!
They picked it up early.
But he wouldn't
have known that.
Would you?
Dude, let's just go!
You're dead.
Back up!
A-ha!
Where you going,
little bitch?
Go! Go! Go!
You better run!
Come on! Come on! Come on!
Back! Back! Back!
Come on! Come on!
Freeze! Stay down!
Put your hands up
where I can see them, now!
Stay right there,
get down!
How about your dead buddy,
huh? Does he got a name?
I don't know, might be nice
to let his family know
where to pick up
his remains.
He doesn't have any family.
What the hell did you do
to get half the BTK
to chase your little asses
down the street?
Look, if you had anything
real to charge me with
you wouldn't
be asking.
The Feds would like
a word with you.
Ooh!
Have fun, kid.
Miller?
No sudden moves, okay?
James Hatcher.
I'm with the DEA.
You thought jumping a 20-foot
gap, five stories up was a rush?
Just breathe for me, Cam, okay?
We don't have much time.
Where's Dylan and Tate?
They're in the van
on the way home.
They should be hitting
the tunnel by now.
Do they know about this?
Cam, they all know.
How the hell do you think
I ran this circus?
Miller's a man on the ground,
shipping and receiving,
HR, transpo.
Hatcher's upstairs...
due diligence,
Neither one
of them gets much sleep,
but they work
well together.
You got to be kidding me.
I've been working
for a dirty Fed this whole time?
Yeah, or a clean criminal.
Depends on your point of view.
What about Jax, huh?
Look, I got bad intel
on this one.
Okay, and Jax is gone.
But that's the past.
All we have is the moment.
And right now,
in this moment,
New York P.D. thinks
you're one of my CI's.
That means you get
to walk out of here with me,
right now,
under my protection.
Yeah, so they
can find my body
in a dumpster tomorrow
morning?
No, thank you!
Cam, I'm not going to hurt you.
I need your help.
The cops are rousting
the whole gang.
Sooner or later someone
is going to talk themselves
out of trouble
and that will lead back to me.
It's time for me
to cash out.
Is this your
"one last score" speech?
Save it.
It's my exit plan.
But I cannot do it
without your help.
If you want me,
I need my 10 grand, today.
Right now.
Then we'll talk.
That's not going
to happen.
Fine.
Then I'm not helping you.
All right. I'm out.
The thing is, Cam, it's not
just about you anymore, is it?
Because you became
part of a family.
So you have to think
about the welfare of others.
Where is she?
I don't want
Nikki mixed up in this anymore.
So you and I are going
to finish this.
Hey!
Why didn't you tell me? Hmm?
I told you to get out.
You played me
from the start.
No.
The bike,
that was all bullshit?
- No.
- This has been
a set-up the whole time?
Cam, I swear it.
That was all me!
I felt bad
for wrecking you out.
I wanted
to get you a new one.
I didn't think all of this
was going to happen.
Well, then,
what did you think?
You wanted in, Cam.
No. I wanted you.
I'm sorry.
I wanted to tell you.
I did!
But... I couldn't.
Why not?
Because of Dylan.
What do you mean
because of Dylan?
That you couldn't tell me
this whole time?
He...
You know, Dylan is your
older brother, Nikki.
You don't need
to babysit him.
You can let him deal
with his own problems.
Somebody did
something to me, okay.
Back in Florida.
Some scumbag came
into my bedroom late at night.
He started touching me.
Dylan walked in
and he beat him into a coma.
The cops came after us.
They chased us all the way
over here.
And then I met Miller.
And Miller made it
all go away.
Dylan was there
that night to protect me.
And now it's my job
to protect him.
Cam, I was scared
to tell you anything else.
Because I didn't want
you to go.
Look...
if I can get
us a clean exit tomorrow...
will you come with me?
Miller's not going
to let us just walk away.
Do you wanna leave Miller
or not, Nikki?
I told you
what could happen to Dylan,
to us, if anything
ever went wrong.
Do you remember?
- Yeah.
- What?
Yes!
I'm getting us
out of this life.
And we're going
to start over.
Just you and me
this time.
Okay?
Where we going?
The guys and I got
a plane to catch
when we're done.
We'll drop you
on the way to the airport.
After you get your 10 grand,
of course.
Here. Put these on.
Let's go.
Nikki and Tate will lookout
while we make the pickup, okay.
Where are we?
Russians keep their VIP's here,
They stash other stuff too.
Well, what do you
need me for?
It's a two-man job.
Why can't Dylan go in...
Dylan's watching our exit.
How are we getting in?
Through the skylight?
Copy that.
What's inside there?
New plateau, my friend.
It's not loaded.
You want me to go
in unarmed?
I'm going in with you.
It's you and me together
this time.
All right?
You're really down
with this, Dylan?
How about you just do
your job, all right?
Hey, get your head
in it, Cam. Right now.
We're doing this for Nikki.
Remember?
Pull over.
Why?
'Cause I gotta
take a piss.
Tate! Come on!
- I can't.
- What?
Come on, Nikki.
Everybody knows
about you and Cam.
Stop the van, Tate.
- No.
- Pull over!
Just shut up already!
Pull the fuck over!
Once we're inside, just
do everything I say.
I've got this all
worked out.
Sure landing.
On three.
Ready?
One, two, three.
Be quiet!
Don't move! Don't move!
Sit! Sit down!
- What's going on!
- Watch them!
Don't move!
What's the exit plan?!
Huh?
This is the exit plan, Cam.
Dylan, what are you doing!
- Don't... don't move!
- Dylan...
Do it! He's got
the diamonds!
Dylan...
Dylan, put the gun down!
Don't move!
All units, 10-10.
Shots fired at 231 West 23rd.
Repeat, shots fired.
DEA, I'm taking your car!
No!
Nikki! Are you okay?!
- Huh? Yeah. I'm okay.
- Are you okay?
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on!
This way!
No, no, no!
I'm done!
Move away, Nikki,
I don't want to hurt you!
I'm not going to ask you
again, baby. Move away.
Agent Hatcher.
Chen?
James...
Okay, listen.
I can explain.
There's been a mistake.
There has.
You made it.
I believe
it was rule number two.
Stay out of Chinatown.
Watch your language!
You're in Chen's house now.
I told you long time ago
to keep your business
out of my neighborhood.
And I did, Chen, I did.
But this is personal.
So is this.
You've been making too
much trouble
for too many of my friends.
Okay.
Chen, listen to me,
please...
There is a boat leaving
for Macau in two hours.
Mr. Hu will make sure
you're on it.
Time to close you out.
You're dead,
both of you.
You're dead.
But enough about him.
You have something for me?
If I were you,
I'd seriously consider
leaving town.
Congratulations.
Your debt is clear.
That's it?
We're all done.
Wait.
What about our deal?
Where to?
Let's just drive.