Hey, Vash!
Now everything linking
you and Rem is gone.
Is that...
Is that your excuse?!
What have you learned
these past 100 years?
The scars carved into you
will never regenerate.
You are living proof
of the folly of human trash.
You're wrong.
They're all alive.
Alive!
Why grow up if you only
grow more sentimental...?
...you good-for-nothing
weepy-faced kid!
W-What's this light?
It's something
you and I can do.
Now, let's dispose
of all the trash.
Are you going
to shoot me again?
Are you really going
to shoot me again...
...Vash?!!!
Eriks?
How long are you going to
to stay in bed? Get up!
Eriks!
Let me on!
At least take me
to the next town!
I have money! Let me on!
He might try to take the town
while we stand here arguing!
But you need
a ticket to ride...
Don't you get it yet?!
Just name your price!
Wait, don't go!!
Let us on!!
There's a lot of tension
in this town.
I haven't seen you before.
Did you come in on that bus?
- That's right.
- You have my sympathy.
You will never leave this town.
This town is under
siege by bandits.
Not only that...
...they say Vash the Stampede
is running the show.
The sheriff went to negotiate, but
came back doubled his weight in lead.
Once you walk into this town,
you're here for good.
The legendary gunman,
huh? Is that true?
Don't ask me.
The man who incinerated
two of the seven cities...
...designated as mankind's
first localized Act of God.
Some even say he put
that hole in the moon...
...but you'd have to be
crazy to believe that.
Setting the thing
about the legend aside...
...this town needs help, bad.
By the way, what is that?
I'm a traveling priest.
I'm glad you're here.
We don't need anything formal,
just help with the funerals.
They took out our chaplain
a short while back.
Hey...
...what's the big idea?!
Oh, it's only Lina.
I'm not "only" Lina!!
Let go of me, Eriks!
What's the big hurry, Lina?
I'm sorry, bartender...
Will you hide me?
What did you do?
She doesn't know
when to quit!
He was just poking
a little fun...
That pedophile
had it coming to him!
I mean, just because
he fondled her butt...
Keep your mouth shut!
Does that mean...?
No, surely not...
I'm afraid so. I don't think
they saw me come in here, but...
Hey, that's not funny!
If what she says is true...
Give me back my lunch!
Where is the little girl...
...who struck my lovely face
with her heel?!
It was more like
an entire foot.
Quiet, you!
I see. That is a fine print.
The kid's got talent.
This man claims he saw
her enter this bar!
If he's wrong, I'll wring his neck
here and now for his trouble!
In any event, it will
be settled in 3 seconds!
3!
2!
One!
Eriks!
Wait a second!
Oh, hey! We're really sorry
you didn't find it funny.
She's only a little 12 year-old.
Come on, have a heart.
Yeek!
Send out the kid.
That I can't do!
After all, you look
like you wanna kill her.
I won't ask for a free favor.
If I do this...
...will you let her off?
Eriks...
That's not good enough.
Since you're on all fours,
you could at least act like a dog...
...buck-naked, of course!
Do you mean that?
Keep your word.
You don't have to do that!!
Don't do it, Eriks!
Eriks!!
Eriks...
It's not your fault, sweetie.
It's what he wanted.
But I...
That's just how it is.
Thank you for the entertainment!
I'll leave you a big, fat tip!
Let's go.
Shoot him.
ERI KS!!
What's all this?
He's been shot!
Please help him, doctor!!
Eriks again? How many
times has he been here?
I can't tell if
the bullet's out!
If you had to choose between your life
and your pride, which would you choose?
I'd never be able to strip
and bark like a dog.
It's the perfect talent
for a wimp like Eriks!
Thanks to that "wimp,"
you ingrates are still alive!!
Eriks! Eriks!
Grandma!
Eriks...
It's all right, Grandma.
The bullet was out.
He's one lucky devil.
I don't know who this
legendary gunman thinks he is...
...but does he have the right
to steal what little family is left...
...to an old woman like me?!
God dammit!
Hey, ma'am!
Stop it! You're too old!
You won't last
two seconds against him!
Let me go! All right,
who will go in my place?!
See? You're all
a bunch of cowards.
You're far too young
to order me around!!
You're going to get
yourself killed, you old bat!
Shut up!
Stop it, Grandma!
- Lina...
- It's my fault.
If I had stayed away from them,
he wouldn't have...
...he wouldn't have...
At any rate, keep the noise down.
Other patients are trying to recover.
I'm so sorry, doctor...
No, I understand how you feel.
I'll have Eriks moved to the ward.
Thank you.
Let's go fetch him
a change of clothes, Lina.
Yeah.
Let's roll him into the ward.
What? You can leave, too.
He'll be all right now.
I know that.
I want to help.
How long are
you gonna sleep?
Wake up, you!
What are you doing
to my patient?!
Doctor, doctor!!
What's this?
Are you conscious already?
Sorry, doc. Could you leave
the room for a little while?
Sure.
Don't let him strain himself.
Long time, no see...
...Vash the Stampede.
I finally found you, you idiot.
What's a legendary guy like you
doing in a place like this?
Stop it. I could have destroyed
the planet with that gun.
There's a blank in my memory.
I can't explain what I did.
Maybe, but it was you,
wasn't it?
Yes, it was me.
My fragmentary visions,
but more than anything...
...something inside tells me
I'm the one.
I'm the one who put
that hole in the 5th moon.
And you're so afraid
of what you can do...
...you're living
in easy retirement?
I only wanted
to live quietly...
...with a different name,
and a different way of life.
Why are you here?
Are you here to laugh at me?
I came to take you away.
To where?
If you're asking for
a final destination...
...I don't know. However...
...I do know that I need your help.
I turned Augusta upside-down
looking for you.
Have you ever met
a guy named Marlon?
I mentioned I knew you,
and he fixed it for free.
Why? Why are you
giving me this?
I thought you'd need it.
I want... I want
to live my life here with them.
Why was he hospitalized
the last time?
He tried to stop a violent drunk
at the bar and got punched himself.
And the time before that?
He fell off a thomas.
You be sure to thank him!
Yeah... I know.
Are you okay?
You're in horrible shape!
You poor thing...
You must have been through a lot.
It's okay...
You'll be safe here.
So you're staying, huh?
Whenever I step in,
people die.
All right.
If you want it bad enough
to give up everything else...
...then go for it.
Say...
...are you familiar with
a town called Carcases?
It's a tiny town
in Southern Cornelia.
Something strange happened
there six months ago.
Its residents suddenly
disappeared without a trace.
Everything in the town
looked completely normal...
...only, the people
had vanished.
The cavalry went in
and combed the place over...
...but didn't find a soul.
One cavalryman, however,
did discover something odd...
...a man's name painted on
the monument in the town square.
It was in red,
and they say it read...
...Knives.
Knives.
Whenever I step in, Destiny homes in
on the smell of blood and gun smoke.
It only creates
mountains of debris.
Vash...
... take care of Knives!
Rem! Rem!!
What should I do?
Your gun! Give me
your gun, hurry!!
What is it, Gramma Sheryl?
They've got Lina!
- What?!
- Give it here, quick!
Wait, Sheryl!
Don't throw your life away!
She's probably dead by now!
Don't argue,
just give me your gun!!!
Grandma! Grandma, wait!!
You know, I...
...really was fond
of my life here.
Them's the breaks.
Someone's gotta get tough
or someone else is gonna cry.
They're both gone!
" Please don't look for us.
We're going to get Lina back."
All by themselves?!
How many are there?
About 200.
100 each, huh?
That's a shame...
H-Hey, don't kill anyone!
Don't ask the impossible!!
Thou Shalt Not Kill!
What the hell kind of
a churchman are you?!
Stop saying the same thing.
You're sounding
like your old self!
Eriks!
Slaughter 'em!!
Let's do it.
I must have been
out of my mind...
...to talk to someone
so filthy-looking.
Hey, did the two of them take care
of all these thugs by themselves?
I've never seen anyone
kick so much ass in my life.
So your mind is made up?
Yeah. I think I will go...
... although I hate to
do this to you and Lina.
Isn't there anything we can do?
Tell me all about it.
Thank you...
... but I can't. If I did,
you would be put in danger.
We know you're going to wind up
alone in another alley somewhere.
That hurts us the most
about your leaving.
I'm sorry.
Who would have guessed that Eriks
was actually Vash the Stampede?
Tell me about it!
And to think, all this time
we thought pig-man here was Vash!
Hey, do you think he plans
to stay on in this town?
Don't even go there!
Yeah! We ought to
run him out right now!
I see...
...she cried, huh?
Maybe I was a little too pushy.
You hardly need apologize.
Mr. Preacher, please
take good care of our Eriks.
Unlike you, he's a bumbling
fool of a goody-goody.
Lina and I realized
somewhere in our hearts...
...we knew that Eriks would
probably leave us someday.
But that doesn't change the fact that
we're losing a member of the family.
Please don't forget that.
I'm sorry.
I'm truly sorry, Grandmother.
There.
All done.
Lina...
Thank you.
I wanted to keep you safe...
...but it turned out
the other way around.
I was too weak.
Don't be stupid.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Those are both my lines.
Lina...
... thank you.
And goodbye, for now.