John! You alright?
Yeah.
Come on.
Did you get him?
-l got him.
You sure?
-Took one in the face.
He's dead. Relax.
What're you talking about, John?
You sound like you know this guy.
Nah. Just talk to you cause
l'm a real independent contractor...
to deal with the trance.
Suppose to be the best.
Same gunner that ClA
used to encounter that time.
Yeah... same guy that turn on this
handlers and killed 3 agents.
l heard it was 5.
lt's bullshit story, John.
You know that, alright?
Those are phantom. He's a myth.
Some of the agents can't get a change.
That's if he shows,
this bullet's his signature.
Do you really think Rogue
was working for Yakuza?
That's the trouble in this business.
You never know who's working for who.
This is the San Francisco police.
Remain where you are
with your hands in the air.
Yep. He's right here.
He's right here, John.
See you soon. Okay, bye-bye.
You tell him that he cannot smoke
in front of the kids!
lf he's going to smoke
he can do it in the yard.
Okay.
Go play.
l thought he was quitting anyway.
-l thought he was too.
Yo, Tom!
-Gotcha!
You better be on the road.
Jam starts at 8:30.
l'm working on what the hell it is.
See if you got any traffic,
we'll make it behind after.
John.
Smoke fixation.
Hey, come on. Get your coat.
So, how's the case going?
Don't forget about the case.
John, you're on sick leave.
No. lnvestigations are on the way.
So far it's zip.
Somebody talked to him. Somebody inside.
Close to us.
And they know what happened to Rogue?
No, they never found the body.
They drag that pave for 3 days
and nothing.
And he's fisher by now.
Okay. Well, you scanned there, right?
Yeah. l've done this. Just tell me
how to forgot these things, okay?
Alright, so l didn't forget these things.
Christ, when are you gonna let that go?
Diane has made a check. She also
asked me to...
Hey... l heard, no smoking
in front of the kids.
Honey, we gotta stop off
and get some steaks.
Diane, hurry up.
No! Please!
No!
Diane, what's up?
Diane?
No!!
John. John. Honey.
Honey. Honey.
Oh my God.
Stay here with Daniel.
Where do you think you keep going?
l'm gonna have...
We have 3 fatal.
-What?
One male, one female and one child.
Sir. The ClA needs to finish.
We gotta let them do their thing.
Sir?
You gotta clear out of here now.
SAN FRANClSCO
THREE YEARS LATER
YAKUZA DlSTRlCT
My turn next...
Get him!
Make a hole.
Get these people out of here.
Just who the hell are you?
Asian Organized Crime Unit.
We'll be taking over from here.
Who's the authority?
-Mayor? President? Take your pick.
You don't look very Asian to me.
l know how to make sure you two
don't have this case wrap up by now.
Checked this? You Einstein?
Yes. l'm gonna cut the faces,
not the armor.
Agent Crawford?
l found this in the backroom.
We found him hiding underneath
one of the dead bodies.
He's in pretty bad shape.
Yeah. What's he been saying?
You can't right?
Who could understand all that shit?
These people come in to this country.
Think they'd at least learn
to speak American.
l think a couple of cops,
work in this district...
that close to Yakuza must learn
to speak a little Japanese.
lf they weren't
complete fucking idiots...
Give me a minute, would you?
Hi...
l'm a cop.
What happened here?
Know what l do when l'm not a cop?
l play doctor.
Hey! You can't do that!
lf l don't get this shrapnel out...
lt will get infected.
l got it.
No, it's a bone.
Sorry.
You want me to go back to my day job...
Give me something to do!
l want to die...
...before he comes back.
Well, l see it's gonna be a real picnic
working with you.
You ain't no working with me.
lt's the FBl case now.
You wanna help?
Take my shoes to the cleaners.
So what do you say?
A bunch of Japanese mumbo-jumbo.
There's no spirits.
Those stories.
Jen?
You haven't wake up?
lt's almost 9.
l was working late last night, so...
Well, l just call to remind you that...
it's Daniel's first basketball game
this Friday.
You forgot, didn't you?
No. Just a bit tired.
-See you.
Got a little thing on my mind right now.
Yeah. So what's it this time?
l found him, Jen.
Found who?
The guy who killed Tom.
He's back. l can feel it.
This time l'm taking him down.
John, it's been 3 years.
Look. You obsession with this man
has cost you our marriage.
Don't lose your son.
Tell Daniel l'll be there.
-No! You tell him.
lf you say you're gonna be there,
then be there.
Those of you who didn't get to meet
last night, this is Agent Goi.
Just graduated in Chronicle.
What's his aspects?
Oarsman.
What's so funny?
How the way you expect here?
What are you?
-D.T
Defensive Tactics.
That's right.
l dig it up close in person.
Yeah. Well, my gun's bigger than yours.
Pick a desk.
Still get to sit your arse up.
Back there.
These are all the photos
anybody has of Rogue.
The guy work up his face every 6 months.
Come on, John.
Anybody can use titanium shields
and DU bullets.
Bullets found...
Bullets that we found last night
matches the ones we found 3 years ago.
Rogue's back.
Okay, if he works for the Yakuza...
Why would he kill Yakuza?
Maybe he switch sides.
This won't be the first time.
Who're we talking about?
Shiro Yamaga.
He's all Yakuza activity from Japan.
Probably the most powerful man
in San Fancisco...
and he hasn't set foot on American soil.
Except for it wasn't this test force
was put together.
The Chang is on the left.
Like Chio Chang lives here.
Nice big mansion in Marin.
lt's the Jade rock-a-fella or something.
He's a 49. Trial at Boston.
lnto everything.
Bribery, extortion, murder, you name it.
30 years ago,
Shiro put in Chang's family.
Just let the balls
to flood in to Hong Kong.
Wiped out the whole fucking clan.
He spent the next 30 years selling
every ornament of Qing dynasty...
to collectors and museums.
Well, that slave now
is a couple of oasis.
Stash woods. Two of them.
About this big.
Word on the street is that Shiro
was looking for a buyer as we speak.
Chain lost of honor.
lt means more or less financial lost.
l don't care about the oasis.
l don't care about bloodlines
or ancient family feuds.
But the first time in 3 years,
we got a real shiny clue.
All we have to do, ladies and gentlemen.
ls pull the fucking thread out.
CHANG MANSlON
MARlN COUNTY, CA
She's a very rare breed.
And delusion.
That's my wife, Maria.
ln my father's days, such reunion
when l have been possible.
But time's changed.
Those of us who change with it...
survive.
Come.
l am really impressed, Mr. Sho.
l heard that you've spilt
the blood of my enemies.
Let's drink.
To our new partnership.
l have to admit,
l was somewhat skeptical when you first
came to me with your proposal.
By living share a service,
that was a wise move on your part.
But it makes me wonder.
How could one truly trust a man
who had betrayed his master?
l have no master.
So l have betrayed no one.
So, tell me.
My Horses, they arrive tonight?
lt's been 30 years.
All this time, my family has lived
in shame and dishonor.
All because of Shiro's treachery.
Tonight, l will take back what was stolen
from my family.
And everything will change from here on.
Shiro's men will protect his treasure
with their lives.
Are you certain... you can deliver them?
l said that l would.
These two are the Ti brothers.
They will give you everything you need.
l'll be in touch.
Watch him closely.
YAKUZA COMPOUND
TOHOKU, JAPAN
l beg your forgiveness.
The fault is not yours, but mine.
l left myself unguarded.
l trust you have news from San Francisco.
Yes, everything is proceeding
as requested.
And the Horses?
We've shipped them out.
They will arrive
in San Francisco tonight.
You must return to San Francisco...
...in advance of my arrival.
But Father...
l don't trust our people there.
They have become too lazy to be useful.
l was hoping to stay here...
...and further my role in the clan.
Nothing in the history of our clan...
...has ever been more important.
l will not fail you.
Go now. Oversee the sale of the Horses.
CHlNATOWN, SAN FRANClSCO
Hey, what's up, dude?
l'd like to see Benny.
No Benny's here.
Yeah. Again!
Hey baby.
We need to talk.
l don't talk to defense.
Someone glad. Now.
My guys lose in anyways.
Business is good l see.
Has the most for homerun security, right?
lt's the part of the family.
l bet that is fine.
lt's a gem. That's another story.
You have every right there.
How did you fuck that up?
lt wasn't hard.
Anyway. Thanks for the help.
You make me look good.
-l hope it helps.
People out there didn't expect the FBl
pay me so good to something like this.
Makes me look the gym.
Was that the end to poor Hamburg?
Come on, John.
They know signs, catch and crooks.
You know that.
They just said you have something for me.
-Yeah.
Our friend over in Russels, the guy
who make those titanium bullets.
Found him two days ago.
Now you'll have to check and see
if everyone on those association...
was wrong and having some bad luck.
Just last week.
Plastic surgeon Dr. Paramount.
He has deadly buried himself for the
kitchen knife making a turkey sandiwch.
Week before that, another one of our
scrapper friend Donald Florida was killed
Some gangs. Can't see to read the signs.
Anyway.
These guys, they're both specialize
in facial reconstruction.
Both of them.
Mass ton of blue sense.
Yeah. Well, there's another surgeon
who's accounted for.
l think he might be still alive.
Maybe trying to get out.
You let me know this set of services...
and its money.
Button up, this isn't a disco.
ls that our contact?
Yes... my contact.
Get rid of him.
He's my brother. He's with me.
What the fuck this guy thinks he is?
Go back to the car.
Wu, please. He's an outsider.
-Go!
Don't make me say it again.
After this is done...
...you and l are going to talk.
The Horses are intact.
Shiro will be pleased.
We'll contact you when we get there.
Are the Horses safe with this crew?
Of course, as far as they know...
...they're just delivering cars.
Stay calm and cooperate.
lt's just a routine check.
l need you out of the car.
Both of you.
Put your hands where l can see them.
Oh, no, sir.
You're shooting on our enterprises.
You're making a huge mistake.
We made the arrangements.
-Out of the car!
Turn around.
You're playing fire on us.
Who's your captain?
Shut up.
-Let go off us.
Fucking rent-a-cops...
-l said shut up.
Did you check the entrance?
What the fuck is going on?
l thought we made arrangement.
Just a little change of the plan.
l need my money. Now.
So, we're all good to go?
Oh yeah. You're good to go.
Just wait here for a sec.
Let me and the boys clear out.
Let's go.
Do it.
Mr. Chang send his regard.
CHANG'S WAREHOUSE 16
Compliments from Mr. Chang.
There's some serious shit here, brother
Yakuzas, all of them
All lined up
Shots at the back
The execution style
-Excuse me
Frances wants to know if you're
ready for coming in?
What?
Check this basement
This guy was escorting something big
lf it was it must've been important
There was only 1 thing that'll stop
this guy from falling down
Cops
Listen, i don't want cops
Hold on just a damn minute,
are you trying to say cops did this?
lf they didn't they were involved
-No fucking way
For all we know it could've been
1 of you guys
l'm assuming that you know
who the fuck i'm
And i wanna get this boy
free passes from the smuggling shit
And you're the one who sells
them out last nite
l don't know what you're talking about
l've never met him
Hey...
That's the federal man
Look at it
Tell me if you see the bullet
Can you see it?
-l see it
He said he'd kill me
He said he got my family
Who? who said that?
l don't know who
Who?
...he works for the Chang
He knows when my kids go to school
You stupid bastard
You think he isn't gonna kill us
if you do as he said, you fucked up
He got statements, call the Washington
Down...everyone down!
This's agent Mike
l need chase backup and an
ambulance now
Hold on, motherfucker
None
This motherfucker's out
The Triads made me look like a fool
Kill the man
Give me the word
..and i'll make them disappear
Do it
Find them
l want their head, everyone of them
Nobody told me you 2 were in charge now
Kira-san, welcome
Your presence honors me
And your stupidity insults my father
We were just discussing...
l've brought word from Sako directly
You're to do nothing until he
instructs you to
The Horses have been stolen!
lf we don't strike back...
Are you disobeying my order?
Good
l'd like a salad
l just got off a 14-hour-flight
Will somebody get me a salad?
What...what kind?
Chef
No blue cheese
Takada...
With dressing on the side, please
Bitch
Yeah
Special agent Crawford
Who's this?
-A messenger
Messenger?
Police kept in the restaurant was
he pulling your message?
l just did what you wanted to do
How the hell you know about what
i want you to fuck?
l saw it in your eyes, John
-Yeah, what did you see?
l tell you what
Why don't we meet in my shrink's
office and discuss it?
Warehouse 16
1 hour
Chang's warehouse
What? now having a sales?
We came to party, baby
Mr Chang
Still pretending to be legit?
Watch your mouth
Don't forget who you're talking to here
Open it
l said, open it
Put your hands at the back of your head!
Now! motherfucker
Put your fucking hands up
No wonder he's clean
Victor Shiro
So, that's what you call yourself
now huh?
Got it
Check the warehouse,
make sure nothing's hidden
She knew it isnt it?
Look me in the eyes
Something real familiar about it
lt's the 1 thing surgeons can't change,
can they?
Your eyes
What the hell do you know?
You don't even know he was a same man
But you're, aren't you?
l know you're
So, is the Yakuza looking for
the traits?
Only if you understand me
The one you wanna follow wasn't it?
What? don't remember?
Maybe you'd remember my partner
You do, don't you?
Remember his name?
Tom Lone
Remember his wife? Diane
And their daughter, Amy
Remember the cabin in the woods?
Cabin that you burnt to the ground?
And police still inside
Remember that?
Do you remember that?
Say it
Say it, say you remember
Say you fucking remember!
You'll only find the only pain
living in the past
Crawford, there's nothing here.
He checks out
Send to me
What if it's?
But rite now we got nothing
Come on, man, there'll be another day
Alrite?
Rite now we wait
We're police, rite?
Another day
Another day you and
l're gonna finish this
Remember that
Everyone, go back
How in the world did you know the
FBl were coming?
Experience
You've impressed me once again,
my friend
As you see
The FBl had declared war on us
Now fuck them
l turst you've secured to my Horses
They're safe
l still've a lot of work for you to do
l think you better stay in my house
for a while
Keep an eye on things
Understood
Oh Victor
This FBl guy, Crawford
He's trouble
He's chasing ghost
Give me a new one
l said pop a new 1 out!
Did i scare you?
Where's your mother?
Go find your mother
l've things to do
What's that?
Wow, do it again
Anna
He's showing a magic trick
Why don't you go down stairs
and play for mummy?
But you weren't playing
l know, but i'll be down stairs
in just a minute, ok. -Bye
l understand you've business here
But i'm warning you to stay
away from Anna
My husband's work and our family
are 2 seperate things
Do we understand each other?
-Yes, Mrs Chang
Good
Don't think...
i don't know what you're doing
You used to check my thing
You as me rite now
But i'm still the 1...
Who looks after things around here
And i remember in the world...
things change
Triad Districy
l say it again
What the fuck?
He fucking intrudes us, let's go!
..teach that fucking Jap a lesson
You fucking bastard
l knew i should never have trusted you
This guy showed a signal
So what now?
Take him for a walk
So as he, that's all i asked
We're gonna check Chang's
place in a minute
Daniel, you can get us noticed
Kira, you go to house 16
Wick and Goi, keep on the sides
of the house
We can lure that guy out
l think i know how to look thru a nite club
Keep your eyes up, everybody
We should go down somewhere and
be ready to move in in the call
The four are expecting us to retaliate
lf we strike now we risk everything
-What if it was your family?
What the fuck's wrong with you?
You forgot?
Once it was my family?
He was like a son to me
Revenge's a must
But you must be patient
l'd allow nothing to put our family
at risk
l want you to do nothing
ls that clear?
Sure all knows it's the day coming
to an end
And it's shown
More blood will be spilt before
this's over
Mr Shiro,
l want your word
My wife and daughter'll be safe
No harm'll come to them
Chang'd never give up his own
But the owner of his family
Keep that
''Sayu Tea House''
Oh man
l didn't know your mum was working
tonite
Keep going, mark boy
Yo, heads up
Looks like Takada's over for a tea
Shit, call Crawford back,
i'm stalling down now
Crawford
We get trouble
He just showed up just like you said
l'm on my way
-Copy that
This's for my brother
He's dead
-Come on!
On 3
What?
Freeze!
shit!
FBl, freeze everybody
Drop your weapons!
Hands on the counter where
i can see them
Situation secure,
units stand on cease fire
Damn it, Goi, cease fucking fire!
We gotta shoot an ass
l got him
Don't fucking move!
Fuck you!
Your pig's dead
Mr Japan
Yes?
Wu and his boys shot up in Takada's
Tea House last nite
What?
Wu Ti?
Are you sure?
l tried to stop them
Damn it, i told him not to do anything
He leaves me no choice
You've done well
My father's very pleased
He'll never ask 1 more thing from you
Chang, his operation'll be destroyed
What more do you want?
Why?
That's the order, there is no why
You know how the problem killing
woman and children before
But you dare you just bet your master
l have no master
This is my guard,
They will assist you in the test
coz you miss this side
lf l refuse?
You drop to this
What is the happening John?
There man have gun in my front yard
Just give a caution
-A caution?
For what? What did you got in to?
Oh my God, is him, isn't it
He coming after us
This is not gonna happen
l'm sorry Jenny, not just for this,
for everything
l try to do the right thing
Make the good life for you and Daniel
lf you think that she needed
lt never had anything to do what we did
ls was ajob
The job always came 1st even now,
even knowing you're putting...
... in the same danger Tom
and his family worrying
You know,
l not even mad you anymore
More this i just feel sorry at you...
for what you become
ls Benny
Say hi to Benny for me
What you got Benny?
We find the plastic surgery
Welcome home, Dr. Sherman
Hey, the profit is..
-Oh is amazing
Doc, come on, you kidding me?
Can you explain to me why i was build in...
What you fuck in nothing criminal?
Look why you look, we laughing at
the pussy on the South
Look, i could give a shit without
the mas is broke...
And i need to find this man
You know what happen to the other
2 doctor, well you could be next
We can protect you
-You know him?
Protect me, you can't protect me,
you can't stop him
You found me here, he can find me here
l can stop him. Want me to use is,
you know
This is rule
This is rule!
Yeah, we use to been committion
by the year goverment
And will do surgery work with ClA
were change the faces
He came to me 3 years ago
His faces almost turn in off
And still l create a muscle and tissue
This is what l make in Rogue
Look Doc, we will take you in this
We wanna protect you understand?
l want you go get some thing and go
Doc?
Yeah, is ok
You know l'm fright, Benny
-Fright?
Yeah
You know, no matter what you do,
you future already decided
l know about that, i was tought the
futured the choices you make
l make all the necessary arrangement
l will join you as soon as
l finish here ok?
Don't worry
l'll be back to walk you out
l love you
My brother is death
You brought onto yourself
And how did l do that?
l gave you my trust
l gave you my loyalty,
l sacrifice everything for you and
this is how l'm been treated?
You got another nerve to talk
to me about loyalty
You are fucking treated
The pieces of shit
He tell me that his loyal
and be my friend
And he right, he was loyal,
he was your friend
Here Jade Agent Clark,
we got a ranger action in chinese
What's going on?
ls the boss ok?
Don't scare ok
Chang is death
-And the woman and child?
Take me to the body and
we can take the head
No. l fill them
Where is my husband?
This Crawford. ls sound they way back
Yes sir
Look Rogue is got the change...
Why did he do that?
John, you never believe i just heard it
Father, l'm so happy to see you
And l'm happy to see you
This country was very beautiful
You english is improving
l have practicing. This is my new home
Rogue insisted on delivering
the Horses himself
You've make me very proud
l must ask one more thing of you
Anything
Return to Jepun
But l want to stay with you
the only person i can trust
is you Kira
The Special Agent Jack Crawford
Step back
Welcome to America.
i don't know will be staying long
Agent Crawford. l'm a busy man
Oh, we got a lot business to..
3 years ago, Rogue kill my partner family
You know what?
Rogue is walking to you
You think so?
Can't always trust Rogue
No time for runing...
Let me ask you something,
what did he do something like that?
l were never seen this man
before in my life
Look
l give you fuck a slow each other
to your own death and bury
Before i prove that any this
shit back to you
You will never see your friends again
Thanks for the tip, Agent Crawford
Finally
My most royal stranger
We meet to face to face
Takada Sang
l've wait the long time for this moment
ls all because of you,
that were now so protunity
Kira and you gonna walking in here
When they show me the fine leader
Yeah
l remind that all the seal
When the diamand warrior
for each other to United State
The one, who finally success was
a man by the name of...
And do you know how he did it?
He kill everyone
Thanks to you, All those for
brought me here again
l assist to deserve you
ln Asia. This could never be sold
The forture they bring here in nowest,
were more that enough to continue ...
..all American spences
And now is time for your to open it
One most review all future treat
You are treat to remand
l'm not killing the woman and child
You are desable me
l broke my most secret code
Your code, not mine
Betray no telling the forgiven
Take him downstairs
Persuade him to tell us
where the wife and child are
Falsed?
Find the woman and child
They'll lead us to the real Horses
l tought you all this years,
Why do you do this?
You were the hit
l older many hits
This one must different
You should have left the
wife and daugther alone
No, thie seek revenge
You left one
You are aset Rogue never
make him up alive
So, you're Tome Lone?
Changing your face, your voice,
also you get to me
Pain can be a weapon if you so true?
Other thing
We found out you the FBl the 1st place
You kill my family
ls Crawford, he's the one who give you up
Crawford warn for me
becoz of him, your family is death
So many talk
Crawford, she is death
Get out this place
''Make a new life''
From America?
Leave me
''Make a new life''
Crawford
Remember the deal we make
Remember my partner break your face off
You left this, only becoz what he did
Only the day, only to kill you
Meet me there
Show yourself!
l got your surgent,
you better positive lD
Come on Crowford
Like this do it!
You not him! lt can be!
Not even sound like it
Look in my eye
You are Tom, you're right here?
Yeah
Why don't you tell me
Must still only where get me responsible
l never saw you bring me
back my prices for it
For Chrst Shake l think you was death
Losten they want to teach you a lesson
For shooting Rogue,
just leave you up to bit, that's all
ls that what they told you?
Sure we do everything
Try stop very fast
ln that so many time
l thought i can win that pay for
what did you give somehow to make it
l think you forget to tell
Tell Leevie death
No!
-The End-