These are the true events
of November, 1965--
The la Drang Valley of Vietnam--
a place our country
does not remember...
in a war
it does not understand.
This story's a testament
to the young Americans...
who died in the Valley of Death...
and a tribute to the young men
of the Peoples Army of Vietnam...
who died by our hand
in that place.
To tell this story,
l must start at the beginning.
But where does it begin?
Maybe in June of 1954,
when French Group Mobile 100...
moved into the same
Central Highlands of Vietnam...
where we would go 11 years later.
Maybe the story
begins in America...
when the army first realized a new
kind of war was coming its way.
The White House anticipates
a buildup and wants a victory...
over cavemen in black pajamas.
We wouldn't be there if they hadn't
already beaten the French Army.
The French Army?
What's that?
The problem in Vietnam is terrain--
jungles, mountains, rivers.
Maneuver's a nightmare.
We have a plan to use helicopters--
leap in and out of battle.
They want you
to run the test on the idea.
It'll take a hell
of a combat leader.
I know a young light colonel
named Hal Moore.
He led a combat company in Korea.
After that, he volunteered
to test experimental parachutes.
Experimental parachutes?
Sounds like just the guy.
The other side of the mountain
was all that he could see
Was all that he could see
The other side of the mountain
was all that he could see
The bear went over the mountain
How about we go back to ''Bingo''?
What do you say? ''Bingo.''
B-l-N-G-O
And Bingo was his name-o
Tom, how much you know
about our new colonel?
He was in Korea...
has a master's in international
relations from Harvard.
Harvard? He's not one of those
academic pussies, is he?
Hal Moore?
Want me to get one of those?
Come on, Too Tall.
Gimme your best shot!
Did you see that, sports fans?
Did you see that?
Snakeshit drives that one
to the moon, baby!
Hit the cutoff man!
And he's coming around!
- Here he comes!
- No, he's not.
You're out!
Horseshit! No wonder you can't fly.
You can't see.
I believe you're out.
- You're a pilot?
- Too Tall, sir.
- Yeah, I can see that.
- You call, we haul.
- Can I speak to you, Crandall?
- Yes, sir.
- Out.
- Safe.
- Can I buy you a drink?
- Sure.
Thanks.
So, your men
call you ''Snakeshit.''
That's an affectionate appellation
of my comrades-in-arms, sir...
'cause I fly
lower than snake shit.
Well, I got a problem, Snakeshit,
and I think you're the solution.
I've been called a lot of things,
Colonel, never a solution.
You know what air cavalry
really means?
You fly into hostile territory,
outnumbered, 10,000 miles from home.
Sometimes the battleground's
no bigger than a football field.
And if the choppers stop comin',
we all get slaughtered.
Now, I figure chopper pilots
won't fly into hell for strangers...
so... I'm Hal Moore.
I know, sir.
Why us?
Well, you guys look like shit,
but your equipment is immaculate.
Yesterday was Sunday. You didn't
have to be training, but you were.
You got pilots
like that Too Tall character.
He's way outside the limits
of army regs.
They wanna fly with you
for some reason.
I guess it's 'cause
they think you're the best.
It's 'cause I only recruit
the dumb ones, sir.
I don't suppose
I have a choice in all this.
You sure don't.
Wouldn't miss it for the world.
To the Air Cav.
Good mornin', Sergeant-Major.
How do you know what kind
of goddamn day it is?
Group! Atten-hut!
At ease, gentlemen.
Welcome to the new cavalry.
We will ride into battle.
And this... will be our horse.
You don't have to catch it.
You don't have to feed it.
But I can assure you...
that neither the new technology
nor your status as officers...
will keep you above the danger.
Sergeant-Major Plumley and I
come from the paratroopers...
where the offiicer is always
the fiirst one out of the plane.
Because to follow
your instincts...
and to inspire your men
by your example...
you have to be with them
where the metal meets the meat.
Sergeant-Major Plumley
made all four combat jumps...
in the 82nd Airborne
during World War II.
Sicily, Salerno, Normandy...
and Holland,
plus one more in Korea.
He answers to me
and to me alone.
Now, I hope you gentlemen
like training...
'cause me
and the sergeant-major--
we love it.
Three strikes
and you're not out!
There is always
one more thing you can do.
Here we go, boys.
Move! Move! Go! Now!
- Two.
- Let's go!
Three.
We're outta here!
- Pretty good, huh?
- Pretty good.
There's only one thing wrong.
Be sharp! We will be the best
platoon in this battalion!
Be ready in there!
Let's go! Let's go!
All right!
Your offiicer's dead!
- What do you do? What do you do?
- First--
All right, he hesitated.
He's dead. What do you do?
- Get off the chopper!
- Get off of the chopper.
Hold off the third one.
Come on in.
Savage, you learn the job
of the man above you...
and you teach your job
to the man below you in rank.
That goes for every man
in this outfit.
- Understood?
- Yes, sir!
We'll be landing
under fiire, gentlemen.
Men will die.
Have you said your prayers?
Come on.
I'll say them with you.
- Fall in.
- Gimme that bear.
All right.
Ready. Set.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women...
and blessed is
the fruit of thy womb Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners--
Cecile, I don't hear you
praying, honey.
I don't wanna be Catholic.
I wanna be a ''Nethodist'' like Mommy.
You do?
And why is that, honey?
So I can pray whatever I want.
That's a sin.
No, that's not a sin.
God just made you hardheaded.
It's not a sin.
I'll tell you what.
You wanna--
You wanna pray and thank God
for our family?
- Yes, sir.
- That's good. Let's do it.
Hail Mary, full of grace,
the Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou among women...
and blessed is
the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
I can hear you laughing,
you know, even in here.
I'm not laughing,
I'm marveling.
Marveling? At what?
That you can fiind stubbornness
in your children...
and think it comes
from anybody but you.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
I'll give you something
to marvel at.
He's a wild man.
- When I pray--
- Mm-hmm.
whatever I want--
I thank God for you.
Beautiful morning,
Sergeant-Major.
What are you,
a fuckin' weatherman now?
Look what I found
for the new baseball player.
- Sent us another bunch of offiicers.
- Uh-huh.
Real green.
Gotta train 'em up.
Makes me think
I'm starting a new unit.
They sent new rifles too.
The M-16.
That's supposed to be
a pretty good weapon.
Lots of plastic.
Feels like a BB gun to me.
Believe I'll stick with my pistol.
You think we're gonna get close
enough to the enemy to use that?
What do you think, sir?
A leader must remain
cool and calm.
And second, he must learn
to ignore explosions...
the heat and dust,
the screams of the wounded.
This is normal on a battlefiield.
Normal!
Fortran, you need to get a company
over to reinforce the left flank.
- Where is that coming from?
- That's our advisors in Vietnam.
The new radio's picking up
atmospheric bounce.
When Crazy Horse was a baby...
he nursed from the breast
of every woman in the tribe.
The Sioux raised
their children that way.
Every warrior...
called every woman
in the tribe ''mother.''
Every older warrior,
they called him ''grandfather.''
Now, the point here is that
they fought as a family.
Take care of your men.
Teach them to take care
of each other.
'Cause when this starts...
each other
is all we're gonna have.
- Did you tune that in?
- Yes, sir.
Well, that's fiine.
You're my radio operator.
You'll be fiine.
You'll work it out.
Any of you sons of bitches
calls me Grandpa...
I'll kill ya.
Godboldt, take your boots off.
Go on.
Everybody, take your boots off.
Everybody.
Socks too.
I want you to draw
fresh socks from supply.
Keep your feet
dusted with powder.
Everybody check each other's feet
like Godboldt and me.
Now, that young man's a leader.
Yes, sir.
That other fella--
that big, strong one there--
he wants to win medals.
Why were you in the back?
Goddamn it,
why were you in the back?
He's eager.
Ladies, I'm really, really glad
you're here today.
Some of you are new to the army
and all of us are new to this post.
I thought we'd pool our resources
and cover questions we have.
So, why don't we start
with item number one-- food.
Where's the best place to shop?
Well, I tried Big Star,
and it's okay.
But I keep thinking my water's gonna
break right in the checkout aisle.
That takes care of food shopping.
So, item number two-- laundry.
The base washing machines
don't work.
They're full of sand
from the swamp missions.
I'll take care of that.
- I've already complained.
- We'll just go to the general.
In the meantime,
the Laundromat in town's okay...
but they won't let you wash your
colored things in their machines.
- At a public Laundromat?
- Didn't make sense to me either.
I'm telling you, they have
a sign right in the window...
says ''Whites Only.''
- What?
- They mean white people only.
That's awful.
Your husband is wearing the uniform
of a country that allows a place...
to say his laundry's not
good enough, when he could die for--
- I'm sorry. I just--
- That's all right, honey.
I know what my husband's fiighting
for, and that's why I can smile.
My husband will never
ask for respect...
and he'll give respect to no man
who hasn't earned it.
The rest of his family
is the same way.
Anybody who doesn't respect that
can keep his washing machine...
'cause my baby's clothes
are gonna be clean anyway.
Well, I guess that takes care
of item number two.
Are you all right?
I think-- I think
my water just broke.
We're all calm.
A car! A car!
- Colonel.
- At ease. At ease.
I heard one of my new lieutenants
just became a father.
- I came to say congratulations.
- Thank you, sir.
So, I didn't wanna disturb you.
No, it's fiine.
It's all right. Please.
Well, how's your wife?
She's okay. She's okay.
She's sleeping.
So is my daughter.
I just...
wanted to be here for a while
before I held her.
Well, tag her already?
- What's that say?
- Camille. Sorry about this, sir.
Don't take that off. Leave that
where it is. That's an order.
- Colonel, may I ask you a question?
- Sure.
What do you think about
being a soldier and a father?
I hope that being good
at the one...
makes me better at the other.
Why? What about you?
I don't know, sir.
Between college and here...
Barbara and I
spent a year in Africa.
We helped build a school
for orphans.
They were orphans because
the warlord across the border...
didn't like their tribe.
I know God has a plan for me.
I just hope it's to help
protect orphans...
not make any.
Well, why don't we ask him?
Come on.
Let's go ask him.
Our Father in Heaven,
before we go into battle...
every soldier among us will
approach you each in his own way.
Our enemies too...
according to
their own understanding...
will ask for protection
and for victory.
And so, we bow before
your infiinite wisdom.
We offer our prayers
as best we can.
I pray you watch over the young men,
like Jack Geoghegan...
that I lead into battle.
You use me as your instrument
in this awful hell of war...
to watch over them.
Especially if they're
men like this one beside me...
deserving of a future
in your blessing and good will.
- Amen.
Yes, and one more thing,
dear Lord...
about our enemies--
ignore their heathen prayers...
and help us blow those
little bastards straight to hell.
Amen again.
Amen.
Thank you.
There's one about the kid with the
apple tree, or the flying horse...
or the fairy tales
with the deer and stuff in 'em.
Daddy, what is a war?
A war is a--
Well, it's--
It's something that
shouldn't happen, but it does.
It's when...
some people--
in another country or any country--
try to take the lives
of other people.
And then soldiers
like your daddy have to--
It's my job to go over there
and stop them.
Are they gonna try to
take your life away, Daddy?
Well, yes, they're gonna try.
But I'm not gonna let 'em.
Okay?
Can't sleep?
The men are so young and--
Now they sent me a new crop
even greener.
When I look at them, I...
see our boys.
Well, then you're
just the man to lead them.
I guess.
We intend to convince
the Communists...
that we cannot be defeated
by force of arms.
l have asked the commanding general,
General Westmoreland...
what more he needs to meet
this mounting aggression.
He has told me...
and we will meet his needs.
l have today ordered to Vietnam
the airmobile division...
and certain other forces which
will raise our fighting strength...
from 75,000 to...
125,000 men almost immediately.
Additional forces
will be needed later.
Get out your best dresses,
ladies.
They're gonna want to celebrate.
Don't you ever be sad
Lean on me
when the times are bad
I didn't hear the president
mention a state of emergency.
No, he didn't.
Well, without that declaration
our enlistments won't be extended.
I'm sorry, Hal.
Forgive me, sir,
but let me get this straight.
We form a division using techniques
never attempted in battle...
against an enemy with 20 years of
combat experience on his ground...
12,000 miles away
from our ground.
And right before the army
sends us into the fiight...
they take away a third of my most
experienced men, including offiicers.
I don't like it
any better than you do, Hal.
You saw this coming, didn't you?
Yes. That's why you gave me
that new crop of platoon leaders.
Korea didn't teach 'em anything.
- Politicians?
- Politicians.
Hold me, hold me
Never let me go
Until you've told me
told me
What l want to know
and then just hold me
Hold me
Make me tell you
l'm in love with you
Thrill me, thrill me
Thank you, sir.
By the way, Hal,
since we're being deployed...
they're renumbering the units.
You're now
the commanding offiicer...
of the 1st Battalion
of the 7th Cavalry.
The 7th.
The same regiment as Custer.
Thank you, sir.
Be sensible with your new love
Don't be fooled thinking
This is the last
you'll find
But they never stood
in the dark
With you, love
When you take me
in your arms
And drive me slowly
out of my mind
Kiss me, kiss me
And when you do
l'll know
Look around you.
In the 7th Cavalry...
we got a captain
from the Ukraine.
Another from Puerto Rico.
We've got Japanese, Chinese...
Blacks, Hispanics,
Cherokee Indians.
Jews and gentiles.
All Americans.
Now, here in the States...
some men in this unit...
may experience discrimination
because of race or creed.
But for you and me now...
all that is gone.
We're moving into the Valley
of the Shadow of Death...
where you will watch
the back of the man next to you...
as he will watch yours.
And you won't care
what color he is...
or by what name he calls God.
They say we're leaving home.
We're going to what home
was always supposed to be.
So let us understand
the situation.
We are going into battle...
against a tough
and determined enemy.
I can't promise you...
that I will bring you
all home alive.
But this I swear--
before you and before
Almighty God--
that when we go into battle...
I will be the first
to set foot on the field...
and I will be
the last to step off.
And I will leave no one behind.
Dead or alive...
we will all come home together.
So help me God.
I love you.
Hal, last night the enemy
hit our camp at Plaei Me.
- How many casualties?
- None.
The enemy forces withdrew
toward this mountain...
near the Cambodian border.
How many men do you have
battle-ready?
- Sergeant Major?
- Three hundred ninety-fiive, sir.
Exactly.
What do you estimate
the enemy strength?
We appraise their numbers
as manageable, Colonel.
You have no idea.
We have no idea.
Simple orders, Hal.
Find the enemy and kill him.
They attack us, no casualties.
They run and hide in the mountains.
Naturally we chase them, of course.
Smell like an ambush to you?
They get close enough to kill us,
we'll be close enough to kill them.
Round trip by chopper, 30 minutes.
So the fiirst 60 men on the ground
will be there a half an hour alone.
Son of a bitch.
I think maybe you ought to
get yourself that M-16.
Time comes I need one, there'll be
plenty of'em lying on the ground.
Well, let's go do
what we came here to do.
Yes, sir.
Garry Owen!
lt was a Sunday.
November 14, 1965.
Before that day,
the soldiers of North Vietnam...
and those of America...
never met each other
in a major battle.
Two miles out.
Dropping to nap of the earth.
First Platoon, let's move!
This is Trojan Two. All units
maintain perimeter contact. Over.
It's a scout!
Let's take him prisoner!
Hey! Lieutenant!
There he goes! Come on!
Come on!
Captain, I want you to
keep in contact with all patrols.
Hey, I got something here.
I got a boy! here.
Boy, hell.
That ain't no boy.
- He say he a deserter.
- Bullshit, he's a lookout.
Ask him where his friends are.
He say this is base camp
of whole division.
- Four thousand men.
- Where?
That mountain.
Same army destroyed French.
And he say they want kill American
very badly.
Just not been able to fiind any yet.
Captain Metsker, tell all patrols
to hold their positions.
You, take the radio!
- Where are they?
- Sir, we gotta get that guy!
Call in all the patrols!
We have to engage the enemy
as far away from the LZ as possible!
Net Call, Net Call,
this is Trojan-Two.
Grab the wounded!
Break contact!
Fall back!
Get to high ground!
Cover fiire!
Come on!
Come on! Get up here!
Bring the wounded up to the middle!
Move it, move it!
Cover fire! Cover fire!
Everybody down! Down!
Check your ammo!
Everybody check ammo!
Come on!
I'll get us out of here!
Grab the wounded!
We'll make a run
- Sarge!
- We gotta get out of here!
Stay down! Don't anybody move!
Bungum, stay down!
You're gonna be okay.
Stay down.
Form a perimeter!
Conserve your ammo and stay down!
What's happening with those patrols?
I'm trying to reach them, sir!
This is Trojan-Two! Come in! Over!
Hey! Hey! Calm down!
Understand the situation
and communicate clearly!
Pull the chain on all the fiirepower
you can get on that mountain!
Alert Crandall!
We have a hot LZ!!
Agent Serpent-Six,
this is Trojan-Two.
You're coming into a hot LZ.
We are taking fire.
Repeat.
No shit.
This is Too Tall
goin'down and dirty.
Roger that!
Trojan-Two, out!
Herrick's platoon
is cut off and under attack.
Bravo Company's holding.
They're gonna try and flank us.
On the ground now! Move!
- Watch him!
- We gotta go.
We're outta here.
They're coming at us
from the back now! Move!
Savage.
All right, all right,
I got you.
Sir?
Don't let them
get the signal codes.
Roger that, sir.
I'm glad I could die
for my country.
Doc.
Bungum.
Sarge?
Tell my wife...
I love her.
This is Savage.
I need artillery to these
coordinates: niner-3-3-0-1
Ernie! Ernie, help!
We got more coming!
We are cut off.
Copy? We are cut off.
- Fire!
They're getting closer!
A hundred more, sir!
They're right on top of us, sir!
Bring it in close!
It's a hot LZ! We'll be jumping!
We will not touch down.
They're trying
to break right through us!
I want you to reinforce
Alpha Company there! Now! Move!
Follow me!
Charlie Company, up on the ridge!
Doc, the wounded are over
by that termite mound! Go!
Sir, if you don't fiind some cover,
you're gonna go down!
If you go down, we all go down!
Come on!
Cobain!
I want the M-60 right here!
Radio!
Sir, it's Captain Edwards
on the ridge, sir!
- Bob!
- Colonel, these guys are regulars!
Heavily armed!
AK-47s and pouches of grenades!
Heavy machine guns
and shoulder-fiired rockets!
Captain Nadal!
That creek bed is vital.
Vital!
They'll be coming right at you!
Do not let them flank!
l repeat, do not let them flank!
Secure the creek bed!
Tom, I want you to keep trying
to raise those Medevac boys.
I'm all right.
Charlie, come here.
Get me all the air support you
can get me on that mountain! Now!
Requesting immediate
close air support!
I need you to burn 'em out...
on hilltop Alpha,
shift to Alpha Bravo!
Coordinates: Golf-4-5-0-9!
- Get me something higher up!
- Shifting to hilltop Bravo!
Golf-4-5-7-2!
I say again, 4-5-7-2!
Medevac Command of the 7th Cavalry,
are you inbound?
Looks pretty hot down there.
Yeah. You can make it, though.
Watch our approach, follow us in.
Copy that, 7th Cav.
We will follow your approach.
I want you to get over there
and reinforce Charlie Company there!
Medevac, abort! Abort!
This is a hot LZ!
You see that? My Medevac guys are
buggin'out and leaving the wounded!
We're going down!
- Snake, get out of here!
- Bring me the wounded!
Wounded! Get the wounded!
Come on! Come on!
Okay, here!
They're still trying to flank us!
Stretch out along the line!
Radio!
Trojan-Six! We are in heavy contact!
In danger of being overrun!
lf they get into that LZ,
we've all had it. Can you hold?
We're spread thin, sir,
but we'll give 'em hell!
Crandall, this is Trojan-Six.
lt's too hot down here.
- l'm closing the LZ.
- You copy that, Too Tall?
Copy that, Snake.
All 7th Cav air units.:
LZ X-Ray is closed.
I don't like it. First time out,
a whole battalion massacred?
You think this is a massacre?
Losing draftees is a bad week.
Losing a colonel is a massacre.
Moore is still fiighting.
He's under strength
against more men than he can count.
- He's got a whole platoon lost.
- They're not lost.
They're only cut off
and surrounded.
Then they're lost.
- Sergeant Major!
- Sir!
We need to carve out
an emergency LZ right over there.
- Sir!
- Blow the trees down!
Fire in the hole!
Colonel, this is Snakeshit
and Too Tall.
We're comin' in
with two loads of ammo.
Crandall, we've blown a new LZ.
When you come in,
come in from the east. Out.
Colonel, it's Brigade Headquarters.
They want you out.
- Well, we can't get out, damn it!
- Not all of us.Just you.
Saigon wants to debrief you.
- That doesn't make any sense.
- Say again.
Will you repeat that order?
Too Tall, follow the colonel
to the new LZ.
I see him, Snake.
He's right here!
Let's go! Move!
Let's move! Move!
Oh, shit.
- Come on! We'll give you a hand!
- We're moving on board!
All right, get that ammo off
and get the wounded on!
Bring 'em on!
Get 'em on, boys!
No, we're overloaded!
- Leave him!
- I'll get out! It's Ray!
He's hurt worse than me!
You hang on!
I'll see you back there, Ray!
You, me and Ouellette
are all we have in reserve.
Yeah, but it's
slacking up a little.
No, they're just regrouping
for another assault.
Distribute that ammo.
Ouellette, tell Crandall he's got
time to get one more flight in here.
Yes, sir.
Doc, you give this water
to the wounded.
Running out of water.
Must be terrible for 'em.
Those guys are cut off out there.
Running low on ammo, Sarge!
Pick your target.
One shot, one kill.
- Roger that, Sarge.
- How we doin', Doc?
Ernie, we're out of water.
That's the last of it.
My face is on fire! Help!
Foster, hold still!
Hold still!
I'll cut your face!
Doc, Doc, it's Foster!
Okay.
Does anybody have
any more bandages?
Ernie, you hit too?
You hit?
No, no, I'm okay.
Our guys are gonna
come for us, aren't they?
Yeah.
When?
Plug his wound.
That's the main LZ,
but it's closed.