Back! Get back!
Spray!
Get off!
Hurry!
Run!
Okay. Pull him up!
Pull him up!
Come on
Get this to the lab. And hurry!
"28 Nov. Thanksgiving 18:00 Augrabies,
South Africa"
Move!
Let's go
509, unpack, and help him
502, the computer,
and you check with the team
Yes, sir
"3 March 06:00 Kakamas, South Africa"
Get ready
Target is approaching!
Here. Get down there!
What's this stuff?
Can't Move!
Come on, move it!
Let's go
Keep moving!
Come on
OK. You get up here
Attention!
What's your name?
Don't know, sir!
Where are you from?
Good. No names, no background
But highly disciplined
Mission is over, go have some fun
Thank you, sir
OK. Dispose your weapons,
dispose your equipment
523.
Yes
Go! Collect. Go!
To the main helicopter. Go!
Yes, sir
Go! Move it, go!
OK. Dismiss
Sorry, sir
Jackie Chan,
one of our best agents in Hong Kong
is also missing in the African action
The three men they hijacked
are the scientists responsible
for the comet research project recently
launched by the African state
Lights!
We have a serious situation on our hands
The operation was carried out
with clinical precision
using United States
Air Force helicopters
They seized the meteorite fragments
along with the three scientists
and untill now
their whereabouts are unknown
If they knew the transport schedule
someone must have leaked the information
How many C.I.A. Staff
knew about this project?
I know where you're heading with this,
Norman,
and I don't like it
How can you be so sure
it wasn't one of your own people?
Why the hell would my guys
break into a hangar
they already have access to
and steal their own aircraft?
Because it's a perfect cover
and no one would suspect them
And remember, General
The C.I.A. Pulled out of South Africa
over a year ago
Only the essential staff remain
Right now, our first concern
should be the retrieval
of the scientists and the fragments
Agreed. There could be
serious military ramifications
if the wrong people
get a hold of this formula
We've got to find out
who's behind this pulling the strings
Agent Morgan
Yes, sir
You used to head up
our South African operation
You know the terrain,
you know the locals
Take 3 agents
and hop the next flight over there
I want to see positive results. And fast
Consider it done, sir
Thank you, Terry
Bye
General Sharman
Hello, Norman
I hear you're retiring a few days
Yes, I am
Congratulations on your retirement,
General Sharman
Thank you
I bet you're going to miss being
in the middle of all the action
Norman, I'm going to take that
fat pension check of mine
and head for my favorite fishing hole
I want a Black Op assigned to this case
Are you saying
we can't trust our own people?
Better safe than sorry
Shall I select them from Washington or
from one of the outside branches?
Outside
Sir, Mr. White is here
Thank you. Send him in
And tell them to report to me directly
Yes, sir
"Your plan worked, mission completed"
What's wrong with him?
I don't know
Do you think he can still walk?
How is he?
He's just woken up
My friend! You gave us quite a scare
We're happy you've woken up.
Welcome to our land
Where am I? How did I get here?
These men found you in the mountains
Now, I want to know,
where do you come from
and how did you get here?
I don't know your language.
Does anybody speak English?
I am the chief. Me. The chief
And who are you? What is your name?
Who am I?
His name is "Who Am l"
Your name is "Who Am l"?
Who am I?
Who Am I
Who is he?
Hello
Hey! Looks like you're getting better,
my man
I knew he would
What are you doing on this search, sir?
Langley must be serious about
finding these guys
They're traitors.
They've stolen a discovery
which could keep our nation on top,
in the 21st century
Yes, sir
Baba. Sit down
Sun...
Moon...
Sun's up, down, moon's up. One day
One day
Up. Down
How many days walk
from here over the mountain?
One day, one day...
One day. Stuck here forever!
Baba, it's a lion! Baby!
Few more here!
Put it down! Run!
Lion baby!
Put it down!
Put it down?
Baba, do something! Where are you, Baba?
Baba, do something! Make them go away!
Go! Go!
Hey! Go!
Baba
Who Am I,
we have seen a miracle over the mountain
There was iron that had been burnt
We buried 8 bodies
wearing same clothes like yours
You mean come with you? Go?
Yes. Let's go!
Go!
Look at that!
Yvirorich, Russian
Jakol, Isreal
Hans, German
Thailand
Tachi, Japan
Korea
Who Am I, come quickly! Come!
I'm sorry. I don't know.
What are you saying?
See! There it is.
The fire I told you about
A light!
I can go! I can go! Yes! I can go!
The ancestors are with you!
The lion won't attack you!
The snake will never strike you!
God makes you strong!
The ancestors have heard!
They will protect you!
Now go forth as a man!
Fear nothing!
Good fortune be with you!
This bracelet will bring you luck
Remember!
The strong will become stronger
Thank you
Go in peace
Goodbye
When we found you,
you were wearing the same clothes.
Am I right?
Yes. We wear the same clothes
Eleven done one too many
Baba. Never play with
dead people's belongings
I know this is bad luck for your culture
I'll go on alone. Thank you
Go well!
Baba
Can I borrow your compass?
Can I take it?
I bring back, I promise
I promise
Please come back soon
I will miss you
Thank you
Be careful
Take care, my friend
You will succeed!
Somebody! Help us!
Hey! Look!
Don't you see us?
Help! Come back!
Somebody! Help!
We're over here!
Come back!
Are you okay?
We're over here! Help!
Look! Somebody! Help us!
Oh, my god!
Get away from him!
Stop eating my brother, you animal!
Leave us alone!
Don't move!
Don't move! You know this?
This is a gun!
You know, I can bang bang you!
You know, I can shoot you!
I can bang bang you, you know?
I know karate! Karate!
Medicine!
It's medicine!
My brother!
Your brother?
You're helping my brother!
You understand English?
Say something
Those medicine make my mouth numb
You speak French?
I understand a little, do you?
Oh, I'm sorry,
I don't understand your language
But, is my brother okay?
Is he all right?
Amazing!
You navigate, and work the G.P.S., OK?
You want to drive?
But do you know how to drive?
I think I better, you know
Nine o'clock. Turn this way!
Okay. Just go straight ahead
Aiji, how are you feeling?
Feeling better. I.V. Is helping
Good!
Please help us! We need a doctor!
Look! Here's the driver!
Back a little bit! Back!
He's very lucky
The natural herbs on his leg
neutralized the poison
and that coconut I. V... The only people
that use it are elite military units
Who applied it?
Here
That's him over there
Amazing. Very talented native!
Say again? What? Give us a story!
Where are you going?
What?
What's he on about?
Oh, it's okay. Speak to him.
He understands English
So maybe you're an alien
and they erased your memory
So you'd be safe!
Just kidding!
Is your mouth still numb?
Try to say something
I think it's better.
The medicine works well
Oh, that's good! So what can I call you?
Everybody calls me "Who Am l"
Who Am I? Who's everybody?
It's a long story
OK. So what did the doctor say?
He says I should go to the city
to see an amnes...
Amnesia?
Specialist
Amnesia specialist?
And no more herbs
No more herbs?
That's probably a good idea
But thanks anyway
Thank you
Here
Come on. Hop in!
You drive this?
Yeah. This is my baby.
This time, I'm driving
Let's go
One of them is still alive
What?
He's all over the local paper
I want to know
if any of the others survived
I want every one of them liquidated
Including this one
That's a bit difficult with these,
C.I.A. Boys scout on my tail
That's not your problem, Morgan.
We've other people to take care of that
You just find him
Who Am I?
Yes
I'm Christine Spaak
I work for the South African Tribune
I saw you on T. V... What a great story!
That was!
I want to do an in-depth article on you
Huh?
I want to do an article on you
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm very busy right now.
Maybe some other day
But you don't understand! You're a hero!
Everybody wants to know who you are!
They do?
So do I
Who Am I
Excuse me
Wait! The article. Wait!
Wait, wait!
Hi, Who Am I
Don't you want to be a hero?
Everybody wants to know
what happened in the rally
Christine. Reporter
How's your brother?
Oh, he's going to be fine.
And the doctor's ready to see you
I think she wants to interview you
Oh? So you're the journalist? Yeah?
You know my name?
My name is Yuki. It's Y-U-K-I
Our x-rays show that you experienced
a severe blow in this area
It's very sensitive
It controls your reason,
logic and memory
That's why you're feeling confused
I'm not mixed up!
But if I am, is there any cure?
That's what they all want.
There is no immediate cure
Why don't you contact the police?
Perhaps Missing Persons will have some
information that will jog your memory
So where are you going now?
I'm going to the police station
The police station?
Yes
You can use my brother's hotel room
for the next few days
Hey, don't worry. You'll get better
Sooner than you think
- Okay
- I'll see you later then
Yeah. Bye
Did it work? Do you remember anything?
- No!
- No?
- Miss
- Yes?
What do you think you're doing?
This is a hospital!
I was just helping my patient. I'm sorry
Excuse me, sir
Agent Lee, C.I.A.
C.I.A.?
Our superior would like to
speak with you, just a moment
- Me?
- Right
Nothing serious. Just a quick chat.
Would you mind coming with us?
Thank you
Feel free to use this room.
It's all yours
Are you looking for me?
Yes, I am
Who are you? Have we met before?
Not that I recall
Morgan, C.I.A.
Chief operative, Southern Africa.
Pleased to meet you
Have I done something wrong?
Do you know about my past?
Yes, I do
I know you came out of the desert.
I know you lost your memory
And I believe you can help us
with a highly classified investigation
Me?
Are you sure you saw eight graves?
Yes, I'm sure
And a skeleton hanging from a tree?
Yes. From a parachute
Good. This information
could be highly valuable to us
Of course we'll have to verify it
And remember, this is top secret
Not a word to anyone. I mean, no one
Yes, of course
Mr. Morgan,
if you find out anything else about me
Plese let me know
Sure. I'll be in touch
Thank you
Very soon
523.
Mean anything to you?
What?
Good. Keep well
Close, but no cigar
It's not him?
No. Striking resemblance though
Mr. Morgan, wait
If I remember anything,
how can I contact you?
You have a business card?
I'm sorry. I don't
Here. You can use mine
No!
Use this. It's better
The C.I.A. Will put you
through immediately
It's a phone card.
You can use it anywhere in the world
Thank you
The poor guy can't remember a thing
So put him out of his misery
I'll make sure he doesn't enjoy
the African sun. Leave it to me
Bring it in, come on
Move it along!
Okay, you take it
I want this two brought inside
Come on, let's move it!
Hurry, hurry
Get to work, and running!
We're at a very
delicate stage of testing
The process should be gradual
I can't guarantee...
And I can't guarantee
your family's safety
Now get it started!
Work!
Activate the accelerator!
All set!
How can a tiny fragment
power up a whole city?
You don't understand
the power of this fragment!
You! Keep working!
Initiating bombardment!
Watch the leve!
225.
What's the flow rate?
Forty thousand joules and climbing!
It's working! It's working!
Yeah!
Yes!
Look out!
Go! Check it out!
What's going on?
The voltage is too high!
Abort! Abort!
Don't abort! Keep going!
We told you it was too soon!
The core's expanding!
Come on!
Move it!
Quick!
Let's go
Oh, my god!
Move it!
What was that?
I don't know. Let's take a look
Officer! Officer!
Officer!
Sergeant actually!
Sergeant. What about my case?
I've been waiting two hours
I'll get to you when I can.
Everybody is waiting!
The power station has just blown up,
and it's chaos everywhere!
What are you doing
standing in front of me?
If you're a missing person,
what are you doing here?
Have you seen a doctor yet?
I've already seen the doctor, officer
Sergeant!
Look, have a seat
As soon as we have sorted out
the problem with computers,
you'll be first on my list
Okay?
Pullen
What?
Yes, sir
More coffee?
No, thank you. Five is enough
I insist
Thank you
What am I waiting for?
Computers
Thanks for popping in.
I've been dying to meet you
What's going on?
Internal Security!
I've got a couple of questions,
I want to ask you
Go!
You two stay.
The rest of you come with me
We have the suspect. Keep guard
Get me the stuff
Have a seat
28th of March, you and your group
spent the night
in this deserted exhibition hall
On the 29th, your friends disappeared
On 30 March, 3 very important scientists
from my country were kidnapped
and their whereabouts is still a mystery
Where have you taken them?
Now listen, my friend
We witnessed five guys
and the scientists at the power station
Then, mysteriously it blew up
Now if you're not a terroist,
why the hell did you blow it up?
Who are you working for?
I don't know
Now on the day
that our scientists were kidnapped
We discovered extremely high-tech,
lethal weaponry
The likes of which
we've never been seen in Africa
Now only a first world country
has got the money
and the technology
to make something like that
So, I want to know from you, my friend,
who are you working for?
The Japanese, the Chinese,
or the Americans?
Or maybe somebody else?
And tell me, Eleven done one too many.
What does it mean?
I don't know who saved my life
But I thank you
Yvirorich, Russian
Jakol, Isreal
Hans, German
And you, what's your name?
I'm Paul, France
Muhamad, I'm Malaysian
Yubicha, Thai
Tachi, Japan
Dick Sing, Korea
My name is...
Gentlemen,
what a great combination we've got here
and I'm so sorry I've to do this
Don't move!
Sorry, soldiers,
we've got only 2 parachutes
What the hell is going on?
Have a nice flight, bye
What are you up to? Say it
Let me go
Here's the control. Come on!
Come on!
Who are you?
You want to know who I am?
I want to know who I am
We found 54 different passports
That makes 6 for each of you. Why?
Where are your friends?
Who are your friends?
Well, there's no point
trying to cover for your friends
And don't you think you're in deep
trouble now, you ain't smelt nothing yet?
Talk to me. Now!
They're all dead
Quite a tough guy!
We know about your special training
But we've got special ways
to make tough guys like you crack
I'm waiting
I told you, it's no use
I lost all my memory
With this attitude, you're going to
lose more than just your memory
Get my drift? Book him.
On terrorism, espionage
and attempted murder
If any of his friends arrive,
I'd like to have a little chat with them
Let's go, smart ass!
What's happening in here?
You idiots! He was handcuffed! That way!
Go around the back!
How did he do this?
Don't just stand there.
We're losing him!
Thank you, I'll be back
He's on his way in