Is it a girl?
Yes.
Show me its arm.
She bears the mark.
No!
The omen is true.
I must tell my mother.
Help me! I can't.
They're going to kill her.
Please! Please!
Oh, thank you, Ethna. Thank you.
Stand aside for Queen Bavmorda!
You cannot stop the prophecy!
This child will have no power over me.
Start the ritual.
- No. No!
- Where's the baby?
The midwife.
Find that baby, Sorsha.
Use the dogs. Bring her back to me alive!
Your reign of terror is at an end!
She will come back,
and she will finish you!
- Silence, wench.
- My baby will finish you! - Kill her.
Dada! Dada!
Whoa! Whoa!
We found something in the river.
I can't run off and play
with you now, Ranon.
- I've got work to do.
- You gotta come. Hurry!
Come on.
Don't go near it.
We don't know where it's been.
But, Dada, it's a baby.
It's not like us.
No. It's not a Nelwyn.
- It looks like a Daikini baby.
- What's a Daikini?
Daikinis are big.
Giants who live far away.
Oh, she's so cute.
Can't we keep it, Dada?
No!
We'll push it downstream and forget
we ever saw it. Come on.
Ufgood! Willow Ufgood!
Shhh! It's the prefect. That's all I need.
Keep it quiet. Don't touch it.
Mr. Burglekutt,
my husband hasn't stolen anything!
Baaa!
Ufgood, you still haven't
paid your debts to me.
Where did you get these seeds?
Well, maybe I used magic.
You're no sorcerer, Ufgood.
You're a clown.
I sell the planting seeds around here.
Now tell me where you got them.
My family's been gathering them
in the forest since last fall.
There's no law against that.
Willow, you didn't leave them
alone by the river?
Magic? You'll need magic...
if you expect to get your planting
done before the rains start.
I will have this land, Ufgood.
And you're gonna end up
working in the mines.
Oh, you're lovely.
Yes, you are.
Kiaya!
Oh, Willow!
Good girl. Good girl.
Under no condition whatsoever...
is anyone in this family
to fall in love with that baby.
Yes, you are. Come on, Mims.
Come on. Come on.
There we are. Come on.
Hey, I will not be ignored!
Mims? Ranon?
You're gonna be all clean.
Willow, do you think we should
take her to the village council?
No. No. They'll think it's a bad omen.
There'll be a flood or a drought,
and everyone will blame me for it.
"Willow Ufgood brought around
that Daikini, didn't he?"
"That's right. And he's that
lousy farmer too. Let's get him!"
- Willow, calm down.
- Calm down?
Kiaya, tomorrow's my big day.
Love, the High Aldwin hasn't
picked a new apprentice in years.
Tomorrow's gonna be different.
I just know he's gonna pick me.
Here. Hold her.
Hey, no. I don't want her, Kiaya.
Hold her while I get some milk.
Oh, no, no. Oh.
Dada, she likes you.
Bye.
Come on, kids. Let's go.
#
I will now magically join the rings!
Whoa-ah!
Thank you, son.
If you're easily shocked,
please turn away.
#
Give me a ripe one. Good.
And now, for my final amazing feat,
I will make this entire pig disappear!
- Mims, see?
- Please, watch very closely.
Wuppity bairn, deru, deru!
Well-
What happened to your pig?
No! Hey, come here, you!
I seen enough.
#
Attention! The High Aldwin...
will now make his choice for his new apprentice!
You'll be all right.
Bring forth the hopefuls.
Good luck.
Good luck, Dada.
Willow Ufgood, a hopeful?
How did he get picked?
Is this a joke?
Willow?
Magic is the bloodstream of the universe!
Forget all you know... or think you know.
All that you require is your intuition.
Now, the power to control the world...
is in which finger?
No apprentice this year!
#
- Where's Mims?
- I don't know. She was right here!
Take Ranon in there, quick!
Mims!
- Mims!
- Dada...
I'm scared, Dada!
Come on!
Vohnkar!
Check to make sure it's not still alive.
It's dead!
Dada! Dada!
It was looking for somebody's baby!
- Mommy.
- Kiaya!
Kiaya! Kiaya!
I'm here.
Oh, Kiaya.
We can't keep the baby, Kiaya.
We have to take her
to the village council.
Silence! One beast we can kill,
but there may be more.
And you can be assured
that they won't give up...
until they find what they're looking for!
It's a sign!
Who's to blame for this?
We must find the culprit
and throw him in the pit!
In the pit! In the pit!
Willow.
Willow Ufgood.
Come forward.
My children found this baby
alone by the river, High Aldwin.
A Daikini child.
That's what the beasts want.
Let's give it back to them!
Yeah!
- They'll kill her! You can't!
- It isn't one of us.
This child is special!
This child must be taken beyond
the boundaries of our village.
All the way across the great river...
to the Daikini crossroads.
- Well, who'll do that?
- It seems only fair...
that the man to take
this baby to the crossroads...
be the very man who
plucked it out of the river.
I nominate Willow Ufgood.
No!
I will consult the bones!
The bones tell me... nothing.
Do you have any love for this child?
Yes. Yes, I do.
The bones have spoken!
Willow Ufgood, the safety
of this village depends upon you.
- Praise the bones!
But you will need help.
Who has the courage to protect
our brave fellow on his journey?
- I'll go with him.
- Ah, Meegosh.
- Excellent choice.
- I'll go!
Vohnkar! Vohnkar!
No! Not Vohnkar!
He's the best warrior in the village!
We need him here! Vohnkar, step back!
All this expedition needs is a leader.
And according to the bones,
that leader is...
you, Burglekutt!
Vohnkar!
What's your problem, son?
How do you mean?
When I held up my fingers,
what was your first impulse?
Well, it was stupid.
Just tell me.
To pick my own finger.
Aha! That was the correct answer.
You lack faith in yourself.
More than anyone in the village,
you have the potential
to be a great sorcerer.
Now, when you're out there,
listen to your own heart.
These will protect you.
Acorns?
They're magic!
Anything you throw them at
turns to stone.
You have much to learn, young Ufgood.
- Are you scared, Dada?
- No!
Even with fairies in the woods...
that'll put you to sleep
for a hundred years?
Doesn't bother me.
Brownies?
- Dragons?
- Trolls?
Trolls that'll skin you alive
and take your face off?
Ranon! You know I hate trolls.
I can be your guard and carry your spear.
Me too. Me too, Dada.
What a lucky father I am.
I wish I could take you bobbins with me.
Good-bye, Dada.
Go play! Go on.
We've never been apart.
I miss you already.
Don't worry, Kiaya. I'll be fine.
I'll be back before you know it.
Well, remember to keep her warm.
And... here.
This will bring you luck.
Good brave people!
The outer world is no place for a Nelwyn.
Give the baby
to the first Daikini you see,
then hurry home.
Tuatha... lokwathrak... tuatha!
Go in the direction the bird is flying!
It's going back to the village!
Ignore the bird. Follow the river.
Move out!
Hold on, Meegosh.
What's wrong?
- We have to stop.
- Stop? Why?
The baby's sick.
She's not sick! Let me see.
Uhaghh! Take her! Take her!
She'll be fine once she gets some rest.
Clean me up.
I didn't ask you
to bring me a dead nursemaid.
Sorsha, you're useless!
I'm backtracking the nursemaid's trail.
I'll find where she hid the baby.
Ah, General Kael, at last.
My queen, I have destroyed
the castle at Galladoorn.
Well done. But now I have
another task for you.
Help my daughter to find
that tiny, helpless baby...
that continues somehow to elude her.
The baby of the prophecy?
- The one that would destroy you?
- I need that baby alive.
I must perform the ritual that will exile
the child's spirit into oblivion.
- Find her!
- I don't need his help, Mother.
You'll do as I say, child.
I read the signs.
One day, I fear,
your daughter will betray you.
I trust her loyalty
more than I trust yours.
Move!
Into the bush. Come on. Move!
Come on!
The Nelwyns have got the baby.
We've searched the village.
But a group of them
are on the road somewhere.
They couldn't have gone far!
Widen the search and report to Sorsha!
Come. We'll keep to the woods.
That's it! It's the crossroads!
Keep this fire high.
We don't know what's out there.
What was that?
Get the spears!
Uhh. Uhh.
Give me some water, peck, or you die.
Do you understand?
Water.
Yeah.
Hurry up!
Get me some water,
you measly little pecks.
It's a Daikini. We're in luck.
We can't give her to him!
Somebody put him there for a reason.
We've got to get rid of her.
Those soldiers are after us.
Shhh.
He's looking right at us.
We've got to give that baby to somebody.
I'm somebody.
Let me out of here. I'll take care of the baby.
I trust him completely.
But he tried to strangle me.
- I want to go home!
- No, Burglekutt!
- We should wait!
- Are you challenging my authority?
As far as this baby is concerned, yes.
Don't listen to him, Burglekutt.
Fine. You stay here alone,
but we're going.
That's a bad idea. Very bad.
- Dangerous out there.
- Get the gear, men.
Vohnkar-
It's not his decision!
Burglekutt, you're troll dung.
Don't let him talk to you that way.
Listen here, runt.
While you're wasting time here,
your fields aren't getting planted.
Think about it!
Burglekutt, I'm gonna...
You're gonna what?
Someday, Burglekutt. Someday.
Vohnkar, let's go!
Meegosh, are you coming?
- I'm staying.
- Come on, men.
Burglekutt, let me out of here.
I'll take care of the baby. I swear.
Just let me out of here. Please!
Vohnkar, let me borrow that spear...
just for a minute.
Well, at least get me some water!
Burglekutt, don't leave me alone
with these two!
What'll we do now, Willow?
Well, that was really stupid, peck.
- Don't call me a peck.
- Oh, I'm sorry... peck.
- Peck, peck, peck, peck.
- You be careful!
I'm a powerful sorcerer. See this acorn?
- I'll throw it and turn you to stone.
- Whoo...
I'm really scared.
No, don't! Don't!
There's a peck here
with an acorn pointed at me!
Oh, I wouldn't want to waste it.
Ha! Peck, peck, peck, peck,
peck, peck, peck, peck, peck!
What was that?
Mornin', boys.
Rough night last night, wasn't it?
I don't think I introduced
myself yesterday.
My name is Madmartigan,
and you are, uh...
No, Meegosh. Don't go near him.
- He's dangerous.
- I am not.
Good.
Stop! Wait!
Whoa!
- What's going on?
- Smells like a battle.
I suppose you're a warrior.
I am the greatest swordsman
that ever lived.
Hmph.
Say, uh-
Could I have some of that water?
I don't know why I try.
I guess I am gonna die here.
Who cares?
Here.
Thanks, friend. Oh!
What's that?
I'd say two or three hundred horses,
five or six wagons
and about a thousand fools.
Thank you. Ohh-
Come on, Meegosh.
It's gonna be all right, little bobbin.
Everything's gonna be all right.
- Excuse me, sir.
- Out of the way, peck!
Uh, pardon me.
Uh...
Excuse me, sir. We found one
of your babies in our village.
Will you please take care of her?
We're going into battle, little ones.
Find a woman to take care of her.
They thought you were a woman, Airk.
Well...
Madmartigan! What did you do this time?
Nothing you wouldn't have done.
I always knew
you'd end up in a crow's cage.
At least I'm not down there
herding sheep.
What are you doing this far north?
The Nockmaar army
destroyed Galladoorn.
The castle?
Bavmorda's troops are
crushing everything in sight.
Come on. Let me out of here, Airk.
Give me a sword.
I'll win this war for you.
Madmartigan. I still serve Galladoorn.
You serve no one.
Remember?
Sit in your coffin and rot.
Wait, Airk. You need me!
I'll be around long after you're dead!
When I get out of here,
I'm gonna cut your head off...
and stick it on a pig pole!
I miss Kiaya and the bobbins.
We're running out of food.
Nobody's gonna take care of that baby.
You know why? Nobody cares.
Except me.
You want to go back to your families.
I want out of this cage.
Let me take care of that baby.
I'll look after her like she was my own.
I believe he would, Willow.
He doesn't know anything about babies.
Right. But I know a lot of women who do.
If I had somebody in my life,
a little daughter, perhaps,
I might have a reason to go on living.
You can't leave me in here to die.
Not when all I want to do is protect her.
I feel better!
You've done the right thing! Whoo!
Okay. All right. All right.
- You gotta promise to feed her.
- Come to Daddy, little darlin'.
And keep her clean.
Absolutely.
Hee, hee, hee!
Wheee!
She likes me.
Here are her changing rags.
- And her milk bladder.
- Any milk in there?
- It's for her!
- I wouldn't steal from a baby.
You worry too much, peck.
It's Willow.
I mean Willow.
Now listen, boys- Willow.
You've done the right thing.
Now I want you to get home
and bring your crop in.
Good-bye, little one.
Please take good care of her.
I give you my word of honor!
Meegosh, slow down!
Oh, come on!
If we hurry, we can be home by
tomorrow morning. We'll be heroes.
Do you really think so?
Sure.
"Look, there's Willow and Meegosh.
The heroes have come home."
"Welcome back, boys.
You deserve medals!"
Yeah. Medals.
Meegosh...
- Did we do the right thing?
- Absolutely.
There's nothing to worry about.
Hyah! Ha ha!
I stole a baby! I stole a baby!
- Hyah!
- That's my baby!
Stop! Wait! Come back!
Left, you stupid bird. Left! Ha ha!
Ow!
Brownies! Let's get out of here!
Come on, Meegosh!
Ow!
We'll outrun 'em!
Hey, ugly, wake up!
Huh?
Stand your ground. He's our prisoner.
Meegosh, where's the baby?
Bring the Nelwyns to me.
All right, you heard her!
- What's going on?
- Shut up, or I'll break your nose.
You are mine to toy with.
Forward!
Gimme the rope.
Where- Where...
did you get that baby?
I stole it from a stupid Daikini.
Franjean, release the Nelwyns.
And stop pestering them.
Uh-oh.
Yaah!
Welcome to my kingdom.
I'm happy to meet you, Willow Ufgood.
How do you know my name?
Elora Danan told me.
Elora? Elora, Willow is here.
- But she's just a baby.
- She's very special.
My Brownies have been searching for her
ever since we heard she was born.
Elora Danan has chosen you
to be her guardian.
- Me?
- Yes. She likes you.
And Elora Danan knows
you have the courage to help us.
Take my wand to the sorceress
Fin Raziel.
She will guide you and Elora Danan
to the kingdom of Tir Asleen...
where a good king and queen
will look after her.
You need a warrior for a job like this.
I'm a nobody.
Elora, you don't want me.
Tell her. I'm short, even for a Nelwyn.
Hello?
Elora Danan must survive!
She must fulfill her destiny and bring
about the downfall of Queen Bavmorda,
whose powers are growing
like an evil plague.
Unless she is stopped,
Bavmorda will control the lives...
of your village, your children- everyone.
All creatures of good heart
need your help, Willow.
The choice is yours.
Hey, Meegosh. Wake up.
Huh?
- It's time to go home.
- Home?
Listen, Meegosh. Tell Kiaya I love her.
- And I think of her every day.
- Willow...
And tell her I'm not going to let
anything happen to the baby.
Are you sure
you know what you're doing?
I hope so.
Listen, be careful.
I know the way, Franjean.
You always think you know the way.
I am the leader!
How long will it take to
find this Raziel? Not long.
She's been exiled to an island
just over those hills.
- She's what?
- Exiled...
by the evil Queen Bavmorda.
Rool, you fool. He does not need
to know everything.
I didn't tell him everything.
You told him enough.
You mentioned the island, the queen.
Wait a minute.
So?
What do you mean?
What are you saying, mysterious island?
Don't play with that wand.
Cherlindrea told you it holds vast powers.
Only a great sorcerer can use it,
not a stupid peck like you.
This way.
No. No. No. I don't think so.
All right, then this way.
Eh, nope.
This way.
This way?
That's what I said.
This way.
- You sure you know where you're going?
- Of course.
With us as your guides,
no harm will befall you.
Take it up!
We are not going in there!
But Elora needs fresh milk.
- And we are drenched.
- You are not in command, shorty. I am!
You hear me? Whoa!
Excuse me? Excuse me.
Could you spare some milk
for this poor hungry baby?
- Get out of here, peck!
- Get outta here or we'll cook ya!
Ooh, look at her!
I could use a love potion on her!
Franjean! Hey!
Give me that dust of broken heart.
Come on! Give it to me!
It's very dangerous.
It belongs to the fairies!
Hey, quiet! You want to get us killed?
Oh, Rool!
Always playing with those fairy love potions.
You are so beautiful!
Your eyes! Your whiskers!
I have to kiss you!
Rool!
That dust of broken heart!
Beer!
These people are crazy!
This could be bad!
Hurry! Hurry!
My husband's coming!
If he catches you here,
he'll kill us both!
- How do I look?
- Not you!
Where the hell did you come from?
I knew I shouldn't have trusted you.
Don't I know you?
I stole the baby from you, Daikini,
while you were taking a pee-pee!
Cover your face!
You are crawling with Brownies.
I hate Brownies!
Whoa!
- Where is he? Where?
- Hello, dear.
There's nobody here
but me and, uh, my, uh...
I'll kill him!
...my cousin, Hilda.
- Hilda?
- Hilda.
Oh, Hilda!
This is my husband, Llug.
- Mm. Big husband.
- Yes.
How do you do?
Hilda! Ooh.
Come on, girly. Don't be shy.
Hey! Give her back!
Pecks make terrible nursemaids.
Nursemaid?
They get too excited.
Excuse me! Are we having a party?
Huh?
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Stop, please. Ooh.
Come on. Fight like a man!
Want to breed?
Tempting, but no.
Thank you. Time to leave.
Bye, Hilda! Take them out.
Hey! Come along!
Careful, you lout!
Move along!
Gather up all these babies.
That baby over there.
Let me see its arm.
That's not the one.
You! Are you the mother of that child?
Yes.
Yes, I am. Let me see it.
No! Don't let her!
Aah!
I gave you an order, woman!
You- You're... beautiful.
And you're very strong.
Thank you.
You're no woman!
Now, honey, take it easy.
- Gentlemen.
- Not a woman?
Meet Llug.
- After them!
- Out of the way!
To the horses!
Hyah!
Madmartigan! Madmartigan! Wait!
He's not a woman!
Don't let them get away!
Madmartigan, stop!
Madmartigan, I'm warning you...
- Ow!
- Prepare to die!
Madmartigan! Stop!
No... more... beer.
Franjean, help me!
Rool!
Help!
Rool! Rool.
- Rool! What are you doing?
- Help me!
Come on. I am.
Pull me in.
Yeah, pull!
Whoa!
Rool, this isn't funny!
Help me cut the rope!
Who-oa!
Willow, stay down!
Whoa!
Have you gone crazy?
You can't chase around
with Elora like this.
- We're getting off!
- Hyah!
Hyah!
Whoa! Whoa!
Oh, Rool.
Now we stop, peck.
Stupid Daikini.
Ask him to stop the wagon.
Madmartigan! You never, ever
drive that fast with an infant!
I just saved that infant's life!
Hah! Hah!
Gather your wits. Come on.
- Don't worry about me.
- Come on!
Get down!
Uh, where am I? Oh!
Rool, you fool, get out of the road!
Ah, Franjean!
You better clear out, Willow.
Before those troops come back.
- Ah, my head!
- We don't need him, Elora.
Madmartigan, wait!
Go home, Willow! It's a dangerous world.
Yeah, and that's why
we need your help.
My help? What
do you need my help for?
You're a sorcerer!
You're a great warrior
and a swordsman.
And you're ten times
bigger than I am, stupid!
Are you trying to make my life
more difficult than it already is?
Hurry! Big dogs!
Look. I'm sorry I got angry.
We wouldn't have escaped without you.
Well, don't expect me to help you again.
Good! Then we go that way!
To the lake!
That way.
You are drunk, and when
you are drunk, you forget that...
I am in charge!
You are in charge.
Fine. Then which way do we go?
That way!
Oh, no! That's the way I'm going.
All right, all right.
You can follow me as far as the lake.
But that's it!
- You're not going south, are you?
- No, just as far as the lake.
Good. Jumbo. Jumbo. I am hungry.
Go get me some eggs or something.
- We are not afraid of you!
- Now!
Kael, have you found the child?
The search goes on, my queen.
Why, with my powers,
with the strength of my great army,
can you not find one little child?
We look even now. It won't be long.
Find the child. Find the child!
Time is running out.
- Good night.
- She is kinda cute.
When she's quiet.
She's really a princess.
Really? And you're a great sorcerer.
And I'm the king of Kashmir.
Go to sleep, Willow.
Good night, Madmartigan.
Rats! Big rats! Rats!
Uh- Uh! Oh! Rats! Ra...
Oh, Rool, you and that
stupid rat dream! Ha!
Tuatha...
Lawkathok...
Tuatha!
Huh? Willow?
Willow?
Oh. There you are.
Madmartigan!
Night, Willow.
This way! This way!
What are you doing?
I found some black root.
She loves it!
Black root?
I am the father of two children,
and you never, ever
give a baby black root.
Well, my mother raised us on black root.
It's good for ya!
It puts hair on your chest.
Doesn't it, Sticks?
Her name is not Sticks.
She's Elora Danan,
the future empress of Tir Asleen.
And the last thing she's gonna want
is a hairy chest!
Did you see what he did?
He stole our black root.
I'll get some more. Don't worry about it.
There it is! The island!
We made it.
We have led you to the
island of the sorceress Fin Raziel.
We'll get a boat in that village.
A big boat.
Well, looks like I got you here.
You! What did you do?
All you did was hang around
and eat our eggs! Huh?
I found a boat. We're all set.
Good. Take these two lizards
out and drown them.
Lizards! Who are you calling lizards?
Heh? Heh?
Your mother was a lizard!
Good-bye, Sticks.
If you really are a princess,
take care of him.
- Madmartigan!
- What?
Thanks.
Hey! Aah!
Keep walkin', hero!
Don't even turn around!
It's all right, Elora.
Go to sleep.
Nobody'll find you here.
I'll be back with Fin Raziel very soon.
We will guard her with our meager lives.
Raziel!
Fin Raziel! I have to talk to you, please!
She's not here.
Aah!
Get back! Who are you?
Who are you?
- I'm Willow Ufgood.
- What are you doing here?
I've come to find
the great sorceress, Fin Raziel.
That's me! I'm Raziel!
This can't be right!
One of Bavmorda's spells
transformed me.
Believe me, it could have been worse!
Oh. Well, this wand is for you.
It's from Cherlindrea.
Then the prophecy is true.
The princess has been born.
Take me to her.
It is Elora Danan.
Isn't she beautiful?
That's Raziel?
I don't know. I...
I expected something more grand.
Less, uh...
Fuzzy.
Fuzzy!
You must use the wand.
Turn me back into my human form.
- What do I do?
- You mean you're not a sorcerer?
Yes. Sorta.
I'm a farmer.
But I do know a few tricks.
Tricks? Cherlindrea sent you?
You must learn real magic.
Horses! Horses!
Quick! Take her! Hurry! Hurry!
I knew he was a traitor!
Sorry about this, peck.
Keep your mouth shut!
Told you we'd find him without your help.
Give me that baby.
No!
- Give her back!
- Leave me alone! Don't touch me!
This is the one we're looking for.
We must take it back to Nockmaar.
Lose your skirt?
I've still got what counts.
Not for long.
- Bring him.
- Over here!
We'll never keep up with those horses.
Then we will have to track them.
That would take forever.
Besides, even if we find them,
they'll catch us,
stick us in cages, torture us
and finally devour us.
Are you suggesting we go home?
Nah. This is more fun!
All right.
Fine, then. Come on!
I'm worried about Elora.
She doesn't sound good.
Hurry! Practice the chant I taught you!
Tanna... looatha-
Oh, I can't remember the middle part.
Locktwaar!
That's the word that pleads for change.
Locktwaar.
Elora's cold and hungry. She knows me.
Please, let me take care of her.
I don't need help from a peck.
- What are you staring at?
- Your leg.
I'd like to break it.
You may find that difficult, slave,
while I'm up here and you're down there.
I hate that woman.
Hyah!
I found it, Kael.
That should make my mother happy.
What are they gonna do to her?
Hither walha...
bairn deru bordak...
bellanockt.
That's magic?
Smells terrible.
It's the life spark. It forms after-
Well, it stinks!
- This whole thing stinks!
- Ignore him, Willow.
- He's a fool!
- If only I had a sword!
If only you'd quit talking about it.
Willow, you must transform me
to my human self.
But, Raziel, I'm not ready yet.
You'd better be. Get me down.
Ow!
Why don't you help me get out of here
instead of chattering with that muskrat?
Muskrat! When I change back...
to my former self, I will crush this army...
and take Elora Danan to Tir Asleen...
where she will be safe.
Ow!
What'd you bite me for?
You need three drops
of your blood to put in the potion.
Well, you could've warned me.
For beginners, there's some pain,
but don't let anything
break your concentration.
Hither greenan bairn claideb lunanockt.
Hello, everybody! We have arrived!
You are saved.
- Shh!
- Don't interrupt.
Hither greenan bairn claideb lunanockt.
What are you gonna look like
if this works?
- Don't interrupt.
- Sorry.
Hither greenan bairn claideb lunanockt.
I am a young, beautiful woman.
Concentrate, Willow.
Hither greenan bairn claideb lunanockt.
No! You're losing me!
Hither greenan bairn claideb...
Aah! Aah!
You all right? Nice try, Willow.
Farmers! Cherlindrea sends me farmers!
Whew!
The Nelwyn really butchered that one.
I'm sorry, Raziel.
You want out?
Easy. We can pick a lock. Come on.
No. No, no. Like this!
I know what I'm doing.
It's my spear. Leave it alone.
Let me do it. Out of the way, rodents.
Take your hand off that.
You leave that alone,
you stupid, fat Daikini!
Ow!
Dust of broken hearts.
Ha, ha! You are free!
Come on, Madmartigan.
Let's get Elora Danan out of here.
Yeah. It'll be fun.
Come on!
Are you all right?
Yeah.
I feel... good.
The dust of broken hearts.
Ah...
Hey, come on!
Let me see!
Let me see. You always see.
There's Elora, right there, on those furs.
Hey, wait! Leave this to us.
- It's too dangerous for you.
- Only one of us should go in there.
I've had experience in this sort of thing.
I know what I'm doing.
Uh-oh.
Wait. Shh. No! No!
I love you. Madmartigan!
What are you doing?
Take the baby and go! Come on!
Come on!
- Oh, Sorsha.
- Oh!
Wake from this hateful sleep.
It deprives me of your beauty.
- The beauty of your eyes-
- One move, jackass,
and you really will be a woman.
You are my sun! My moon!
My starlit sky.
Without you, I dwell in darkness.
I love you.
What are you doing here?
Your power has enchanted me.
I stand helpless against it.
Come to me, now.
Tonight, let me worship you
in my arms.
Get away from me!
I love you!
Stop saying that!
How can I stop the beating of my heart?
It pounds like never before.
Out of fear.
Out of love!
I can stop it. I'll kill you.
Death, next to love, is a trivial thing.
Your touch is worth 100,000 deaths.
What goes on here?
Deceiver!
Stop him!
Captain, get up!
You are great.
Get on that shield!
Sorsha!
After them!
Whoa! Hey!
They're getting away!
Follow me, Rool. I don't know.
Where are you?
Aah! Ooh.
Oh, no, where did everybody go?
Maybe it was something we said.
Ohh-h-h-h!
Madmartigan!
What the hell happened up there?
You started spouting poetry.
Poetry?
Yeah.
"I love you, Sorsha.
I worship you, Sorsha."
You almost got us killed!
"I love you, Sorsha"?
I don't love her.
She kicked me in the face.
I hate her! Don't I?
Kael! Kael!
Nockmaar soldiers!
Hide! Get the children! Come on!
Get the children!
They're after us!
Come on. Follow me.
Quick! Come on! Move!
I knew you'd get out of that rattrap.
You left me to die, Airk.
I probably saved your life.
We were slaughtered, and I lost a lot...
Shh! Quiet!
Tear this village apart!
Look everywhere! Find the child!
Shh!
Shh-shh-shh!
Tell Sorsha I search the north bank!
Hah! Hah!
Yes, General.
Quiet. Shh!
- Sorsha!
- Back.
Back!
Keep the baby quiet.
She needs to be changed.
Nockmaar scum!
You'll never defeat us.
Give up the baby!
Shut up!
What does Bavmorda want
with this baby, anyway?
She's a princess.
We're taking her to Tir Asleen.
Tir Asleen?
Even if you could find it, peck,
she's right- you'd never
get past the Nockmaar army.
There's an even bigger army
at Tir Asleen.
If we can just get there...
I've lost more than half my men
fighting Bavmorda.
Now you and this peck
are gonna take her on?
You always told me you served
no one, Madmartigan.
Since when are you a crusader?
He's not gonna help you, peck.
He's a worthless thief.
I'm not a thief, Airk.
He's not a thief.
Are you?
I serve the Nelwyn, Airk.
- Want to come with us?
- You'll never make it, Madmartigan.
Then once again we say good-bye.
- Over here!
- Sorsha!
Weapons down or she's dead!
Hyah! Hyah!
Hyah!
Get to your horses! After 'em!
This way! This way!
As the crow flies, you fools!
You're holding me too tight!
I don't want you to get away.
Why? Because I'm your sun,
your moon, your starlit sky?
Get your hair out of my face,
or I'll chop it off.
Did I really- Did I really
say those things last night?
In your tent?
You said you loved me.
I don't remember that.
You lied to me!
No, I...
I just wasn't myself last night.
I suppose my power enchanted you,
and you were helpless against it.
Um, sort of.
Then what?
It went away.
It went away?
"I dwell in darkness without you,"
and it went away?
Yeah.
Whoa.
Hurry! Kael's coming!
Madmartigan, come on! Now!
Madmartigan, come on!
They're coming! Away!
Go on! Hyah!
Whoa! Whoa!
This way!
Tir Asleen! At last, Tir Asleen!
Hello?
Why did I listen to you, peck?
"Everything will be all right
once we get to Tir Asleen."
The only army around here...
is the one that's about to ride
across this valley and wipe us out!
But Cherlindrea said we'd be safe here.
Safe? Look at these people.
This place is cursed, peck.
It's falling apart. Open your eyes!
And it...
Trolls.
I hate trolls.
This is the work of Bavmorda.
Willow? The wand.
Turn me back into my human form.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Good.
Hurry, Willow. Transform me.
I can't do it. I'm just not a sorcerer.
But you can be. Speak...
and be one with the words.
Avalorium, greenan...
luatha, tye...
Oh, Willow, you're losing me.
Madmartigan, Kael's coming!
Willow, you idiot.
Raziel? Willow,
arm that catapult up there.
Whoa! Whoa!
- Good work, Madmartigan.
- What the hell happened to you?
Assault! Sorsha, battering ram!
Cut it down!
Faster!
Forward! Break it down!
Again! Again!
Willow, use the wand on that troll.
Bellalockt!
Ewww!
Break it down! Forward!
Whoa! Whoa!
Get him!
The other side!
Destroy the beast! Find the baby!
Baaa! Take tha-a-a-at!
Willow!
Madmartigan, help!
Get him, Madmartigan!
Here.
The baby!
Airk's army. Get Kael!
Airk's army!
We are here!
You are rescued!
Charge!
No mercy!
Elora!
Willow!
Elora's gone.
Willow.
They've taken her.
There were too many of them.
Willow.
Can you ride?
Let's ride.
I have the child!
We need towers and a battering ram!
Break out the tents! Make camp!
Make camp!
We'll assault at first light.
Where's Sorsha?
She has turned against us,
Your Highness.
Turned against me?
Prepare for the ritual!
This is not an army.
Willow,
quick, hide.
Use the shelter chant. Protect yourself.
- Why?
- Just do it.
- We've come for Elora Danan.
- You dare to challenge me?
You're not warriors.
You're pigs!
Toa thonna mondarr!
Nocklith! Vohkbar!
You're all pigs!
Pigs!
Avaggdu luatha bairn off haefermore.
Sorsha!
Mother, no!
Kothon!
Avaggdu luatha bairn off haefermore.
Begin the ritual.
This baby will not destroy me.
Come, thunder!
Come, lightning!
Touch this altar with your powers.
Aah!
We've come all this way
and now Elora Danan's gonna die!
No, we can still defeat Bavmorda.
She's too powerful, Raziel.
Transform me and I will destroy her.
Elements of eternity, above and below.
Balance of essence, fire beget snow.
Locktwaar danalora luatha danu...
Willow,
believe in the words.
Tuatha, tuatha, chnox danu.
Concentrate.
Locktwaar danalora...
luatha danu tuatha, tuatha.
Oh, no!
Locktwaar danalora.
Locktwaar danalora luatha danu...
tuatha, tuatha, chnox danu.
Don't give up,
Willow!
Locktwaar danalora luatha danu...
Oh, Willow!
tuatha, tuatha, chnox danu.
Locktwaar danalora luatha danu tuath...
tuatha chnox... danu.
Raziel.
- Has it been so long?
- I'm sorry.
Willow, we have work to do.
Give me the wand.
We must undo Bavmorda's sorcery.
Let them in now.
Tuatha grin chnox, y foel famau.
Black fires forever kindled within,
let the second rite begin.
Quick, inside.
That won't reach the wall.
We can't get inside.
- Elora Danan will die.
- Unless we save her.
Bavmorda's too powerful.
No!
She cannot transform you again.
My spell is protecting this camp.
But can your magic
get us inside the fortress?
We can't do it.
Wait. Back home in my village,
we have a lot of gophers.
Willow, this is war, not agriculture.
I know, I know.
But I've an idea
how to get inside the castle.
Ocht veth bordak stira.
Come on, Madmartigan,
you and I are soldiers.
You and I know the peck's plan
will never work.
If the baby dies,
all hope for the future is lost.
I'm going to fight.
Me too.
All right, we've got to decide
who's gonna go and who's gonna stay.
Raziel.
Willow, all these years
I have waited to face Bavmorda.
It is you that has made this possible.
Whatever happens,
I shall always admire you.
Your children...
will come to remember this day.
We call upon you to surrender!
We are all-powerful sorcerers.
Give us the baby,
or we'll destroy you!
Kill them!
Patience, Willow.
Courage, Willow.
Whoa!
Back to the castle!
Ocht veth nockthirth bordak!
- Exile the child to the 13th night.
This way!
Nockthirth plankton
firth foreth forewar.
Ocht veth nock!
It's all right, Willow.
You don't have to go.
Light the 13th candle!
Raziel.
Mother!
I...
Traitor child. I must despise you now.
I won't let you kill that child.
Away!
Avaggdu...
strokt!
Your powers have gained
in strength, Raziel.
I have Cherlindrea's wand, Bavmorda.
Elora Danan will be queen.
Now you die!
Furrochk flarem!
Claideb cla...
Clai main! Lunano ocht!
Bachktu inno!
Wanu!
Yikes! Ohh!
Airk!
Airk.
Win this war for me.
Die!
Huh?
Beah!
Bring back that child, peck.
Who are you?
I'm Willow Ufgood.
I'm a great sorcerer.
Greater than Raziel.
Greater than you even.
I'm the greatest sorcerer!
Is that the extent
of your powers, little one?
Now you will watch me draw
upon the power of the universe...
to send that child into the netherworld.
Now place it on the altar!
No!
No?
You stupid hag!
With my magic, I'll send her into the...
Into a...
You're no sorcerer.
Into a realm where evil cannot touch her.
Impossible!
- There's no such place!
- Helgafel swath ben helgafel.
You're a fool! I shall destroy you
and the child with you.
You're a fool! Nockmaar-
Bairn off danu famoww.
Good-bye, Elora.
Bohi bakstiy.
Helgafel!
Im... possible!
You...
Willow, where's the baby?
It was just my old disappearing-pig trick.
Oh, well done!
Oh.
Willow Ufgood,
receive this book of magic.
You are on your way
to becoming a great sorcerer.
- Willow the Sorcerer!
- You make us proud!
Good-bye, Elora Danan.
Hey.
Good-bye, Willow!
Farewell!
Eh?
Willow! Willow!
Hello, Regan. Hello.
Willow's back! Willow's back!
Willow! Willow!
Willow! Willow Ufgood!
- Willow!
- Hey, Meegosh!
It's a bird! He made a bird!
Aaaaaagh!
Kiaya!
- Willow?
- Kiaya.
Willow! Willow!
Kiaya!
- Dada! Dada!
- Dada, I missed you!
Oh, I missed you.