There comes another one to snatch our rice bowl
Okay, let's practice
Come, get ready
One
Two
Young master, there is a Master Liao looking for you
This is....
I am the Master of the Liao's Fist
Just opened a dojo in Fuoshan
Congratulations
I heard that your Wing Chun fist is very good
That's why I came here today to get some pointers
Make it another day, okay?
Now is not the right time
Since I am here
and just sparring only, won't take too much time
Let's close the doors and spar. Win or lose, nobody will know
It's not a matter of winning or losing,
I am having my meals right now
Then, I'll wait for you
Master Liao, have you eaten?
Come, join us.
You smoke?
It's okay
How are the dishes tonight?
Good
That is good
Very quick
Uncle Wang, don't clean up the table.
Just close the door first
Master Liao
Please
Are you okay?
I'm okay. I'm okay.
One more time
Then, here I come
Hit!
Hit! Hit!
All hits!
Hit!
Thank you for letting me win, Master Liao
Thank you for the lesson. I've learnt a lot
Same here. Same here
Today's closed door sparring.... Master Ip
Don't worry, it'll never leak out
Thank you very much. I am taking my leave
Do be careful
I am not sending you off
Ip Man's "Heavenly King smashing the tower"
One more time and using the "Four Taels to heave a thousand katis"
that thrown Master Liao's to a thunderous grounding
Isn't that stroke used in Tai Chi Quan?
I heard that Mast Ip practice Wing Chun, right?
Whatever! Anyway, he just push him away with just one hand
Master Liao still did not concede defeat
Later, Ip Man ferociously chased after him and beat him up
But Master Liao after being beaten is still not satisfied
and uses "Hungry Dog snatch faeces" to beat Ip Man
This type of tea leaves is very nice. It's cheap
Do be careful
Thank you
Goodbye. See you again the next time
Uncle Ping, who put this here?
It's your younger brother
Initially I thought Master Liao's kung fu is good
but he didn't even have a chance to attack
Being beaten like a pig's head
He also have a share in our father's teahouse
Always loitering and fooling around
Ask that asshole to take care of the customers
Good morning
Brother Man
Is Brother Quan is here?
He's waiting for you upstairs
Ah Quan, have you been waiting long?
You are always late
Busy!
Busy with what?
It's always the same.
Eat, drink and kung fu
What's there to be busy about?
This tea is quite fragrant
I am saying you!
Let's order some food
I've something to discuss with you
Eat first, we'll talk later
Fresh from the oven. Come, try it!
I heard them say,
you had a duel with Master Liao
and quickly defeated him
Is that true?
Who told you, Crazy Lin
My younger brother
You should have told me earlier
I've even ask him to be my master
You've ask every master in town to be your master
Brother Man, did you have a closed door duel?
We've something to discuss. Please go
Then, I will not disturb your discussion
Good morning Master
Good morning
Master
Good morning Master
Good morning
Master, someone said you got beaten by Ip Man
Now, everyone in Fuoshan knows about it
Nonsense, who said it?
Sha Dan Yuan from the teahouse
The cost of things in Fuoshan have risen
So what about it?
That is to say, Fuoshan's economy is good
Everyone have expendable income
Really?
Think about it! Clothes, food, accommodation and travels. Clothes comes first
In future, the demand for cloth will be huge
That is why I want to set up a cotton factory
so that I can supply them to the cloth factory
I want you to be my partner
I am not suitable for business
It's okay, I am suitable
I am not in need money
Who is Sha Dan Yuan? Get the hell out here!
I am
You're the one talking nonsense and ruining my reputation?
Master
I want to teach you a lesson today
Master Master
He's my younger brother. Let's talk slowly
Don't get angry, master
Your brother
Your brother is talking nonsense and ruined my reputation
Said I lost to Ip Man in a fight
Tell me, how can I survive in Dojo Street?
How can I open my dojo and take in students?
Master! Apologize now!
I am not in the wrong. I just stating facts
You're talking nonsense
Sifu
Ip Man is upstairs. If you've got the balls, go find him!
What! Go!
Sifu, cool down, cool down
Sifu Sifu  Don't get angry. Sifu
Master Ip, I've been wronged!
Sifu Sifu
Please, tell everyone
that you have a duel with Master Liao
and beaten him
Master Ip, you must clear my name
Still telling lies!? And troubling Brother Man!
I did not lie
When I was retrieving my kite, I saw them fighting
What a coincidence that your kite broke loose
and landed in Brother Man's garden
and what a coincidence that you saw Master Liao and Brother Man having a duel
and coincidentally, the whole scene was seen by you?!
There is just too much coincidences!
Yes, it's all coincidences
Even if it's true, you can't go around telling everyone
There are some things which one can't admit
If it's true then one won't be afraid to admit it
If one admits one would lose face
Lose what face? How should I know?
This is called " Lose face"
Crazy Lin, no need to be like this
What are you laughing at!
Don't treat me like I am not around!
Sir, it's a small matter
What small matter?
Disperse...
Don't go!
Sir, small matter
I've seen everything. Let me tell all of you
whoever create trouble in my territory, not obeying the law
I will arrest them
I didn't come here to create trouble
It's someone who ruined my reputation
I am here for justice
What justice? I am justice
You bunch of loafers, fighting everyday
What era is it now?
Still going for duels!
Let's duel with weapons. Gun! Gun!
Do you know?!
You also know, Inspector Lee
we, practitioners of martial arts have lots of energy
and sometimes may be loud in our speech
But being loud in our speech does not mean that we have no manners
Technically, we are all cultured people
No need to draw your gun for any small matter
Give me some face
Crazy Lin, take care of Insp. Lee. All on me
Good
Insp. Lee, this way please
What are you looking at? Quick scram
Don't look! All disperse
Insp. Lee, please
Master Liao
Take care
Why are you so secretive?
I am really not suitable to do business
Take it and open the factory.
When you have profit then you can pay me
I won't be able to repay you so quickly
Take your time to pay
Do me one more favor. Accept my son as your student
There are so many Masters in Dojo Street
just ask any of them will do
Those masters are not as good as you
About the same
Crazy Lin
Brother Quan
Brother Man, I've learned a new technique
You help me to test it, alright?
You're so free!
Have you found your younger brother yet?
Don't worry about him. Once his money is depleted,
he'll come back
Let's try
Father, is Uncle Man willing?
You go and have a look first
Ah June, your drawings are so beautiful
Let's see what moves you've learn this time
It has defense when attacking and in defense there is element of attacking
when attacking there is defense and in defense there is attack
The words you say are all the same
You won't understand, kid. Go further away
This move is to attack the middle section.
Very deadly
Don't just know how to say the words
Most important is to get a hit
Mother, I've finished drawing
It's so good. Let Daddy have a look
Okay
Use attack as defense. Continued defense is attack
That's what I do
What I did earlier on is constant defense
Daddy, have a look
Daddy is not free. Later...
Don't understand
Yes
One more time
Daddy won't look
You've already lost
What?
This is called constant defense with attack
Master Ip, one more time. I didn't see clearly
See! See! See! What's there to see!?
Come here everyday and fight, fight fight!
Really frustrating!
Brother Man, what now?
Sister-in-law, I am sorry
Sister-in-law, I am leaving
I am not saying you
No, there are lots of things to do in the factory
Ah Yeow
Uncle Man, we are leaving
Okay, come again the next time
We're leaving
If you are not happy, you can tell me.
No need to throw your temper
Okay. I am asking you now to look at the son's drawings
Show more concern
and don't stay with your friends all day
Let's go in, okay?
Slowly
Brother
Where is Dojo Street?
Ah...
Dojo
Go straight ahead
One
Two
Boss, there are so many dojos,
which one shall we start first?
One
Two
One, retract
Brother! Teaching kung fu?
You guys came here to learn kung fu?
Come in, let's talk
Who is the Dojo master?
I am the dojo master
I am Jin Shan Zhao
I've long admired Fuoshan as the town of martial arts. I came south especially
and would like to exchange pointers with Masters of Fuoshan.
Exchange pointers!
Correct
Then you are here to challenge!?
Yes
Okay
All of you stand one side
See how your master teach this country bumpkin a lesson
Not that side. This side! This side!
Someone here to challenge!
What is it?
Look and learn
Boss! Boss! You're terrific!
Where is your Master?
I am here!
You really want to kill me, huh!?
Sifu is not here
Wondered what happen to the weather in Fuoshan
blowing cold and hot
Let me
What are you drawing, Ah June?
Ah June is not talking to you
If you are free, do keep him company
Okay
Crazy Lin, so early?
Sister-in-law, I am not here to fight.
Just have a few words and I'll leave
Hey, what is it?
There are a bunch of country bumpkins
going around challenging all the dojos
Their kung fu is good
Every dojos have lost
If you can, do go and have a look
Really that good?
Yes
Sister-in-law, I am leaving now
Hang on, Master Liao
We're all depending on you, Master Liao
Fucking bitch!
There is not one who can fight in Fuoshan
I thought everyone in Fuoshan is like Wong Fei Hung
but actually they are worms
All weaklings, can't even stand one blow
Brothers, we didn't come here for nothing
There is not one who can fight in Fuoshan
This time we're going to get rich
Brothers, we've got to keep working hard
Open a martial art school in Fuoshan
and let them know how good we are
We got to be number one in Fuoshan
You, country bumpkins!
Won a few masters and you think you are damn good
Win the best, then we'll say
Who is the best in Fuoshan
Of course it's Ip Man. Do you think it's me?
Let's go
Come! Come!
See how we are going to win Ip Man
Daddy, there is a lot of people outside
Young Master, they....
You are Ip Man?
I am Jin Shan Zhao.
I've heard that Fuoshan is the town of martial arts
I know, Master Jin, I know
You've brought so many people
to tell me that you want to challenge me, right?
Of course!
We are opening a dojo in Fuoshan
We have to show our ability to them
Opening a dojo, right?
If you want to open a dojo, you don't have to fight with me
You just have to find a good location and that's it.
Please leave.
Uncle Wang, bring Ah June in
Ip Man
Don't give any excuses
Are you afraid and don't want to fight
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Do you think my house is a dojo?!
Do you think you can just come in and fight and kill?
Get out!
You heard her. I won't fight with you
Please leave immediately
I heard that Wing Chun fist is developed by a woman
I think it's very suitable for you
Ip Man, you're really henpecked
There is not anyone that is afraid of their wives
but men who respect their wives
Mrs. Ip, don't worry.
I won't kill him
If you are afraid that he would lose,
I'll use one hand
If not,
I will not use both my hands
Master Ip, fight
Fuoshan have really disappointed me
There are so many martial arts
practitioner but there is none
Shut up!
Don't break anything in the house
Give way! Give way! Give way!
Give way! Give way!
You bunch of....
You came at the right time.
This is a small place
Please ask all the people to go out
and please close the door on your way out
You must win back our reputation
Let them go out!
Quick!
Faster! Faster! Out!
Out! Out!
Wing Chun, Ip Man
I really like to see
how a macho man
uses a woman's martial arts
Good kung fu does not have sex or age differentiation
Have to see who is using it
You will know immediately how it is fought
Please
I'll pay
Good
How is it? How is it?
Who is better?
I'll pay
Daddy, mummy says
if you won't attack,
all the things in the house will be broken
Okay...
Little rascal!
Be careful what you say!
Boss
Boss Boss
Master Jin, are you alright?
I am okay
How is it, Master Jin?
Do you think my kung fu is okay?
No need to say
Today, the northern fist
have lost to the southern fist
You're wrong. The problem lies not within Northern or Southern Fist
It lies within you
Who lost and who won?
No need to ask. Look at his pig face
you'll know that he had lost
Scram!
Sifu
Brother Man Okay, good show
Master Ip
You have saved the reputation of all the dojos in Fuoshan
It's luck. It's luck
I would say that you are the jewel of Kwangtung
Thank you
This has just been imported from overseas.
Please, look around
Mr. Ip, this is your wife's flowers
Thank you
Boss, how much is it?
No need money, Master Ip
You've brought glory to the people of Fuoshan
How can I take your money?
I can't don't pay?
You're doing business, right?
Really, there's no need to pay, Master Ip
You're too kind
Don't be
The next time
Okay, the next time
Master Ip, have some fruits
So kind
For the kids
How could you...
Goodbye, Master Ip
Thank you
Little friend, for you to play
Say, thanks
Thank you
No need to
Take care
Master Ip, how are you?
Mrs. Su, how are you?
This is not bad
This is the best in our shop
If this could be in your house
it would be my honor
You're kind
Why is it so crowded?
Uncle Man, Auntie
You are so sly
If you want to open a dojo
Why didn't you inform me first?
When did I say I want to open a dojo?
The whole of Fuoshan knows about it
Everyone in Fuoshan knows, except me
Uncle Man, let me help you
Sifu  Master
Fellow disciples
Looks like you're the one who spread the rumor
You've better fix this mess
Come, walk yourself
I don't care
Ah Yeow must be your first student
There you go again.
This is not the first day you know me
I'll never accept any disciples
Quiet!
We must observe rules.
Once we observe rules, it will be right!
Master Ip Master Ip
Wing Seng, I am going out for awhile.
Will be back soon
Wait
It's cold outside. Wear one more
Ip June
Ip June, be careful.
Don't hurt others
Master Ip, I gave you a bit more
Thank you very much
No need to rush
Next! You take this
Once you have taken, leave immediately
One by one. Line up
This factory might be old but it's still not bad
Fuoshan is now in a mass of confusion
You've gone. Why come back?
If I don't come back,
where would the workers have money to eat
My money is all invested here
I still can't pay you now
No need
If you don't say, I would have forgotten about it
This can't be.
I'll treat it that you have invested here
It might be little but it still have 10% of the shares
Really, there's no need
Stay and help me.
After all you have a share in it
Uncle Man
Kwong Yeow
You're here to help? That's great!
With you to lead us,
everyone would be more energetic
and I can also watch you practice Wing Chun fist
Stay and have your meals here.
The workers are about to have theirs
Yes, join us
No need
I still have things to do.
Next time
I am leaving now
Father, why don't you ask Uncle Man to stay
I understand him all too well
Daddy, didn't you always practice martial arts?
Why didn't you practice nowadays?
If daddy move too much, daddy would get hungry
That's why I move less, right?
Uh, I understand
Then I won't go out and play
You will only stop playing today. Quick, eat
Quick, eat
This porridge is a bit starchy
but somehow you have to eat something
Come
Careful, it's hot
How much rice are there in the house
Don't have to worry
Whatever valuables in the house have been pawned
Your husband have strength and energy
I can go out and get a job
Won't die
You go out and work?
Of course I have no need to before
but now times are bad
There is always a first time
We have more than enough people here
Not hiring anymore
Boss, do you require any worker?
No. We've enough
Sorry to trouble you
Boss, employ me
You! You! You! Come up
Boss! Boss!
Master Ip, you're looking for a job?
Come Come
Thank you
Brother Man
Brother Man, the way you dress is not suitable for work
How do I know that I'll be digging for coal?!
Master Ip, how are you?
How are you?
Why are there so many masters here?
Right! The boss here used to practice martial arts
That's why he like to employ
those who knows kung fu
Do you still practice kung fu?
If there is time,
I would come out and look for work, right?
Go there and eat
Okay
Brother Man, I can't eat anymore
Help me to eat some, okay?
Eat a little
How are sister-in-law and Ah June?
They're fine. Thanks
Have you found your younger brother?
I haven't seen him since the last time he left
I don't know if he is dead or alive
I don't have a chance even to apologize
You lost something?
Yes, I've lost a steel box
What kind of steel box
Japanese soldiers!
Japanese soldiers are coming!
Fellow workers, this is Colonel Chuodeng
The colonel admires Chinese kung fu
and also knows that Fuoshan is the town of martial arts
and like to find those who knows kung fu
and spar with the Japanese
Are there anyone who is willing to go?
Master
You just want us to be their sand bags
Let me tell you, no way!
Idiot! If you win there is a bag of rice
Those who wins the fight will be awarded a bag of rice
I'll go
Crazy Lin, don't look for trouble
I'll go too
No, they have stolen our rice
now is our chance to take it back. It's only fair
Hey! Hey!
Forget it!
Help me find the steel box.
Hey!
It's alright. Come
Be careful
Come, come over and line up
Quick
Are there any more orders?
No. Let's go
Yes
Master
General
Thank you, Sir
Okay, good show Okay, good show
Knock them down
Let me go there and have a go
They are not your match, General Sanpo
Just treat it as to let them know
our Japanese martial arts
Find 3 guys to fight with me
Even if they lost,
they would still get a bag of rice
Yes
Don't say I didn't help you guys
I've arranged with General Sanpo
to fight with the 3 of you
No matter win or lose,
you'll still get a bag of rice
It's okay if there is no rice.
Most important thing is, is to beat them up