The scandal that has rocked
the college football world--
12 starters from
Blue Mountain State,
as well as head coach
Marty Daniels
have been suspended by the NCAA
for various rule violations
and not allowed to participate in
the National Championship game.
Before the suspensions Blue Mountain
State was favored by three points,
but by game time
Blackwell U
was favored by 17.
Feels good
to be a champion.
That was the easiest game
we've played all year by far.
You know, we didn't want
to win it this way.
We wanted
to beat their best--
Thad Castle, Moran,
coach Daniels.
And it sucks
because now there's
always gonna be doubters.
And doubters should know
that we'd play
- the real BMS team anytime.
- Anywhere.
Reporter: At what point did you realize
that you had won the championship?
Well, when we went up
by five touchdowns,
our offense took
its foot off the gas.
There ain't no way BMS
was gonna score on our D--
no way!
We played by the rules
all season.
BMS did not.
That's why
I'm sitting here tonight
and coach Daniels is
wherever he is.
Reporter: Coach, your system
seemed to fall apart today
without Alex Moran at quarterback.
Do you stand by your system?
I think the system still works.
I can plug players in.
Just today it didn't work out
as I had hoped, that's all.
Reporter #2: Do you think you're
still employable as a D1 head coach
after such
an embarrassing debut?
( Reporters chattering )
Commentator #1: So the Blackwell Warriors
are the new national champions.
But are they the best team
in college football?
I still think
it's Blue Mountain State,
but we'll never know.
You son of a bitch.
Ty: Thad.
Thad Castle.
Stalin:
Thad! Hey, Thad!
Both:
Wake up, Thad.
Thad, wake up.
Hey, Thad.
Wake up, Thad.
Man: And the Blackwell Warriors are
the 2012 national champions!
I want to beat
Thad Castle.
- ( Exclaims )
- Ty: Anytime.
Stalin:
Anywhere.
- ( Crowd cheering )
- Man: Can you feel that?
You better hold on.
This one's about to get bumpy.
♪ Give me a hell,
give me a yeah ♪
♪ hell yeah ♪
♪ stand up right now ♪
♪ give me a hell,
give me a yeah ♪
♪ stand up right now,
right now ♪
♪ give me a hell,
give me a yeah ♪
♪ stand up right now. ♪
Sync by Alex1969
www.addic7ed.com
( hip hop music playing )
Alex, what's up, buddy?
Wow, you look terrible.
Hey, I've got an idea.
What do you say me and you go watch the
girls' tennis team practice, right?
- No.
- Come on, man, it'll be good.
You haven't been out
of the house in a week.
I no longer care about
the passage of time, Sammy.
Plus Donnie bet me I couldn't eat
an entire pizza in one sitting.
Come on, man.
It was only one game.
Hey, remember when we were little we
used to play football in your backyard?
We played that game, and then after
that game we'd start another game.
That's the great thing
about football--
there's always
next season, right?
You're right, Sammy.
It was just one game.
But really, maybe they're
all just one game.
Maybe I shouldn't care
about any of 'em.
I'm not finished.
- It wasn't just one game.
- Oh you.
It was my last shot
at a title.
And those bastards
at the NCAA
just took it away
from me.
And why?
Because I did
a little rabies,
I made a sexy tape?
They took it away
from you
because you told them
all of those things.
For the last time, I didn't
know he was recording me!
On 12 separate occasions?
- Ah.
- He was buying me drinks!
I know I screwed up, guys.
I'm gonna make it up
to you, I swear.
Harmon: Hey, guys, I've got
a better way to spend the time.
It's called the best weed
you've ever smoked.
And I'm going to use it
to roll a mega spliff so big
it will take our entire o-line
a week to finish it.
( Laughs )
I love it.
Follow me.
I have the answers
you're looking for.
- How did you do that?
- Do what?
- ( Chattering )
- ( Door opens )
- ( Chattering stops )
- ( Door closes )
Darlene, what happened
to all my pictures?
Tony took them down.
It was bumming out the customers.
Why don't you ask Tony to come
out and tell me that to my face?
- Let's not make a scene, Marty.
- Shh!
I am so sorry
I bum you all out.
I only gave you assholes
20 years of joy.
You know what?
You tell Tony
that I lied about him having
the best coffee in town.
Yeah, and I think
he's fat.
Come on, Jon Jon.
- Just a little piece of pie.
- Come on!
( Hip-hop music playing )
( Mumbling )
So how big is this
joint gonna be?
I'm thinking maybe 4' long,
about 1 1/2' around.
Let's make it 5', huh?
Excuse me just
for a moment, gentlemen.
- Hey, Thad.
- Hey.
Mind if I borrow
the keys to your truck?
What for?
Are you looking for answers?
Sure, something like that.
Yeah, sure thing.
There you go.
- Oh. Damn it!
- ( Cans spraying )
Where are we?
The promised land, Alex.
Follow me.
I just lost
a six-pack.
- Donnie: Where are we going?
- Moran: Yeah, Harmon.
You know what they say--
the man with the hash
is the man
with the stash.
- Donnie: Holy mother of Mary.
- This is yours?!
I planted this marijuana field
when I was in my freshman year.
The farmer's cool with it and he
gets all the free weed he wants.
( Grunting )
Here is your answer.
( Exclaims )
This looks
about ready to harvest.
What do you say
we sample it tonight?
I'm in.
Thank you, God!
( Laughs )
- Let's go.
- ( Engine stops )
What are we
doing here again?
You're my houseboy, Mascot.
You don't ask questions.
You follow me
and obey orders.
- Are you gonna kill me?
- ( Cows mooing )
Holy shit!
Is all this weed for us?
It's for all of us.
I'm gonna start chopping.
You start hauling.
I'll explain later.
( Hip-hop music playing )
If I could have
one wish?
I'd wish for the chance to kick the
shit out of that cheap punk Alex Moran.
I'd take him
to a dark place, baby.
I was gonna say
$50 million,
but that sounds
all right too.
God, I hate those guys.
It doesn't help
that they're so handsome!
( Grunts )
Did we make out before?
Mm-hmm.
It was much better
the last time, wasn't it?
Yeah, okay.
God, I think there's something
wrong with the beer, guys.
It's giving me bad breath.
Mine tastes fine.
Have you guys seen Sammy?
- Is he okay?
- ( Clattering )
Who cares?
I heard that, Larry.
And God heard that too
and he's on my side
right now.
So if I were you,
I'd shut up.
- Have you seen Sammy?
- ( Hisses )
( Hisses )
You know what?
I say screw BMS.
You should be coaching
pros anyway, Marty.
Call Jerry Jones.
He'll hire you.
He'll hire anybody.
Hey, coach,
I just wanted
to say goodbye
and thank you
for ruining my career.
You did that to yourself.
Oh, no, I did not bring
shame to this program
with an NCAA scandal.
That was you.
You wanted your shot
and you got it.
But you couldn't handle it and
now you want to blame me, right?
Yeah? If you could just control
your players a little bit better,
we wouldn't be
in this situation.
- Hey, don't you tell me how to--
- Coach, come on.
Hey, I don't ever want to see your
face in this locker room again.
Oh, you'll see it again
from another sideline next
year, you cheating has-been!
I'm okay,
all right? Relax.
( Rooster crows )
( Birds chirping )
- Mascot.
- Yeah?
Make me some eggs.
You've got it, boss.
Hey, what the hell are you two
doing sleeping in my barn?
Sir, my name is
Thad Castle.
I'm a Blue Mountain State
football player
who's been chosen by God to carry
out a mission on your farm.
God speaks to you, son?
He sent me here.
This is my houseboy.
His name is Mascot.
How's it going?
- Gun! Gun!
- What?
Anything I can do
to help, Mr. Castle?
( Rock music playing )
( Cow moos )
( Men yelling )
We want to beat
Thad Castle.
And after we beat him,
he can suck our schlongs.
Are you okay?
I was dreaming.
Nice.
You need a tissue?
Why would I need
a tissue?
A wet dream.
I used to get them
all the time, real bad too.
I'd like wake up
all sticky, icky.
Ugh, but it made me
feel so good though.
I'd wake up.
I was like having sex with this girl
for like 11 minutes
in my dream.
It's time to invite
Blackwell to play.
Yeah, have you seen
Alex and the guys?
They are in no shape
to play football.
They'll play.
God told me so.
I can picture
this joint already.
It's gonna be
like a huge zeppelin.
Yeah, man, we'll call it
the Hindenburg,
watch it go up
in flames.
( Laughs )
Oh, the humanity! Oh!
You know, the Hindenburg
wasn't funny, man.
36 people died.
Larry, I think
you're the one
who needs this joint
more than all of us.
All right, boys,
get ready to feast
your eyes on this.
Hey!
See? I told you
they'd come.
Hey!
What did you do
with all my weed?
- That was here?
- What did you--?
- Whoo!
- ( Guys yelling )
You tore up my pot field
so you could build
a football field?!
- Correct.
- Where's all the weed?!
I burned it
to get God high.
( Men groaning )
I wanted to thank him
for my visions.
Let's talk about
your vision, Thad.
What do you expect to do at
this stupid field of yours?
- Exactly, dude.
- We're gonna play for the national title.
( Laughs )
Bullshit.
Thad: Don't tell me
you wouldn't kill
to have a shot
at those assholes, Moran.
- ( Grunts )
- They've been spouting off for weeks now
about how they wish that
they played the real BMS.
They said,
"anytime, anywhere."
Moran: Blackwell is not
gonna want to play
your stupid game
that doesn't even matter.
It does matter.
And they are gonna show.
The wheels are already
in motion.
- ( Cheering )
- ( Rock music playing )
Girls, cheerleaders,
we've got a mission!
I'm gonna need
your scooters!
Seriously? This is what you
guys do when I'm not around?
( Scooters revving )
Let's go!
To Blackwell! Whoo!
Whoo whoo whoo whoo!
Let's go!
( Spits ) Ugh.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
I was just thinking
this could be the last time I
set foot in this locker room.
You don't mean that.
Even if they
wanted me back,
between the scandal,
the NCAA
and all the political
bullshit,
- I don't know if I'd want the job.
- ( Door opens )
( Guys chattering )
Thad:
Everybody grab your gear.
What the hell is this?
Thad has the whole
team convinced
we're gonna play Blackwell
in the morning.
Is that a joke?
It's not a joke.
We're gonna need you, coach.
What the?
( Rock music playing )
- Guys: Whoo!
- ( Snorts )
Whoo!
Who wants to start
the ruckus?
( Men chanting )
Who wants
to start the ruckus?
Who wants to start
the ruckus?
Yeah!
( Scooters revving )
( Engines stop )
- Hello.
- ( Music stops )
My name is
Sammy Cacciatore.
I come bearing
a message
from Thad Castle.
"Dear Blackwell,
you idiot douchebags have
been talking a lot of trash.
I'm offering you a chance
to back it up--
tomorrow morning,
sunup,
on a neutral field.
No media. No hype.
Just two teams battling
to decide once and for all
who the real champion is."
You can't be serious.
I'm not done yet.
"On that field we will
destroy your asses
like they've never been
destroyed before.
Stalin, Alex Moran
will make you look even
dumber than you already do
in that piece of shit,
outdated mullet.
Wilson, I will
personally sack you
more times than the Hell's
Angels have sacked your mom.
You're all a bunch of gutless pussies.
The BMS Goats."
Did you
just call me
a pussy?
I did.
I did, yeah.
Oh, Thad Castle wanted me to
tell you one more thing, so...
Oh! Damn it.
Wow, you look
really mad now.
You're a big dude.
Whoa!
( All shouting )
( Birds chirping )
Oh my God.
Holy shit.
I built it all by myself.
Can you believe it, coach?
Wow.
It really is pretty good,
isn't it, coach?
You mean Blackwell's
gonna come here?
They're not coming.
He's just setting us up
for another letdown.
Let's just go back
to the Goat House and drink.
Sammy: Yeah! Whoo!
It worked!
It's happening!
Whoo!
Sammy?
Sammy:
Yeah! Whoo!
Oh my God.
Yes! Whoo! Yeah!
What the hell happened
to your face?
Blackwell did this
to me, man.
They jumped me
and the cheerleaders
for no reason.
I didn't do anything.
That little shit mascot
wasn't kidding, was he?
Daniels.
Are we really
gonna do this?
That trophy means
nothing to me
unless we beat you
for it.
Moran: Oh, screw this.
I'm out of here.
Thad: Moran, where
are you going?
Home. I'm done
with this shit.
The beer hasn't tasted as good
these last few days, has it?
How did you know that?
You've had
the taste of winning.
Now there's
no going back.
Once you try,
beer loses taste,
sex loses
its squishiness,
pot loses
its highness
until you win again.
BMS is considered
the home team.
Blackwell calls it
in the air.
This is heads.
This is tails.
Both: Heads.
It's tails.
- Yes, we'll...
- Take the ball.
Yes, Moran.
You're gonna regret
that decision, Moran.
Okay, I don't know
how we got here,
but we're here.
Now all the anger
and aggression
that you've felt
the last few weeks
at those trash talkers,
at the NCAA,
- now is the time to let it all out.
- That's right, that's right.
Let's show 'em what
real champions looks like.
Yeah!
Let's go kick the shit
out of those guys
on this awesome field that I built
all by myself with no help.
- Bring it in. On three!
- Yes.
- One, two, three.
- Go Goats!
( Music playing )
( Pants )
- ( People chattering )
- Girls:  BMS! BMS!
- ( Grunts )
- ( Rock music playing )
- Girls: Whoo!
- ( Chattering )
( Man shouts )
- What are you doing?
- I was taking a piss over there.
- I was looking for you.
- ( Cheering )
Hammer two.
52 is the Mike.
16. Blue 16.
Hut.
- ( Whistle tweets )
- Whoo!
All day, Moran!
You're nothing!
I don't think so.
What's going on?
You ran three plays.
We lost 11 yards.
Do you have anything that works?
- I'm trying, coach.
- Jeez.
Hey, Stalin, you suck
and you punch
like a little bitch!
- I need a ride.
- What about the game?
- This is for the game.
- Girls, quickly,
take this woman
anywhere she wants to go!
Get out of here!
Go go go!
Go.
( Rock music playing )
Hey, Wilson, here I come--
your worst nightmare,
a freight train
full of balls, muscles
and tackles.
Down.
Hit.
( Whistle tweets )
( Laughs )
Shit!
Damn it.
Castle,
I'm starting to think the NCAA
did you guys a favor
by not letting you play
in that game,
saved you the embarrassment.
( Kisses )
( Mouths word)
( Snaps finger )
Waitress, waitress, hey,
can you give me a couple more beers, please?
Oh, and an espresso.
Those will be your
fifth and sixth beers.
- So?
- So it's 9:30 in the morning.
What, are you my mother?
Get a life.
- Marcus.
- ( Groans )
God, what, is this?
Bitch Central?
I'm here to make you an
offer to make things right.
There's a game going on
as we speak
in a cornfield
outside of town,
BMS vs. Blackwell.
- No way.
- Mm-hmm.
Marty needs you.
They're all over him.
( Chuckles )
I'm done here.
And you can tell Marty,
whatever he needs--
he can shove it up his ass.
- Watch your language.
- No, you watch your language.
Cut the poor-me bullshit.
This game's real.
You'll have Moran, Castle--
all your weapons.
You've played Blackwell
once before.
You have insight
Marty doesn't have.
You're serious about this.
This is your one chance
at redemption.
Do you want it or not?
- ( Whistle tweets )
- ( Yells )
Down goes the big man.
Have fun in rehab.
( Screams )
Blue 16.
I smell me
some fresh meat, boys.
Set. Hit.
Whoo! Yeah!
( Cheering )
Jesus, Moran,
your cheerleaders put up
more of a fight than you.
Souvenir?
- Whoo!
- ( Moran yells )
- ( All shouting )
- Moran: I'm gonna kill you!
Stalin: You son of a--
you're going down, Moran!
I'm taking you down!
- ( Whistle tweets )
- That's the half.
- ( Cows mooing )
- ( Chattering )
Might have to
amputate that ankle.
I would if it would
make it feel better.
I don't think
I can play.
If I still had my pot,
I'd get you so high
you wouldn't feel a thing,
but our asshole captain
burned it to get God high.
Yeah, he didn't burn it.
What?
He told me to burn it,
but I'm not an asshole.
Follow me.
What did I tell you?
Et voila!
I was so sure
you guys were gone.
Are you crying?
( Inhaling deeply )
Oh okay.
- ( Moaning )
- That's weird.
You are one
weird guy, man.
Look, there's got
to be someplace
where they're
vulnerable defensively.
They're kicking our asses.
- I didn't see any, Marty.
- ( Doors opening )
This is
a private meeting.
What the hell
are you doing here?
Oh man, I knew
this was a bad idea.
- Yeah, it was a bad idea, asshole.
- Hey.
Marty, shut up
and listen.
What, are you two both that arrogant
to think you got here alone?
Both: Yes.
Marty, your offense is
getting crushed out there.
And yes, Gilday can be
a selfish prick,
but he knows how
to run an offense.
If this team has any chance
at winning today,
it's gonna start
with you two.
You know, I grew up
watching you, coach.
I used to want to be you.
And when I got
to BMS,
I guess I just
wanted it so bad
that I lost sight
of what it was
that I loved about coaching
in the first place.
- What about Stanford?
- Screw Stanford.
I only ever coached at Stanford
because my wife wanted me to.
She left me, by the way.
She said she couldn't stand
being married to a loser.
I am sorry
about everything.
Let me make it up
to you right now.
- Yeah.
- Hmm?
Tell me I'm the greatest coach
that ever lived.
You are the greatest coach
You always come through
for me, buddy.
You want some, Alex?
No, he doesn't.
He needs to focus.
I need to focus?
How did you talk me into this
in the first place?
- This is a stupid idea!
- This isn't over yet!
Might as well be!
All right,
everybody listen up.
That was the worst half of football
I think we've ever played.
But it's behind us.
You know, what I said
before the game
about how this game
was about sticking it
to all the people
who wronged us.
Well, I was wrong.
This game should be
a celebration.
There's no media.
There's no money.
There's no NCAA.
There's no bullshit.
It's just football.
I want you all
to close your eyes
and think about the
first time in your life
when you realized
how much you love
this game.
What a beautiful day.
You know, Thad, there's no
money in rollerblading.
- So what?
- I'm just saying
you can make a billion
dollars playing football.
A billion dollars?
Thanks, dad.
I love you!
Hit this, little cousin,
and you can smoke a bowl
out of each bong.
Yeah!
Pack 'em up,
cousin Denis.
Yes.
( Snickers )
( Bong bubbles )
( Laughing )
Man, I love football
so much.
Me too.
Daniels: Now I want you to
do another thing for me.
I want you to stop
playing this game
for that
crystal trophy
and play this game
for that moment.
All right,
everybody listen up.
We've been running screens
to the left all game,
but in the championship game that was
their strongest side of the line.
Moran, I want you to fake
a screen to the right,
drawing over
the left side.
And that leaves the middle
wide open for a draw.
I've been faking screens all day.
They've been all over me.
That's 'cause you're not
selling it, Moran.
You've got to make them
believe that when you pump,
that ball is going to
leave your hand
just like you make
every single girl believe
that she's
the only one for you
right before
you take them to bed.
- Hmm?
- Sounds mean when you say it like that.
- Yeah.
- It's a pretty good metaphor though.
- Yeah!
Hey, are you all right, Donnie?
How's the leg?
I've never felt better, coach.
( Laughing )
Put me in.
Put-- put me--
put me in, coach.
Put me in please.
( Laughing )
- ( Chattering )
- Blue 16. Blue 16.
Hut hut.
- Hit. Hit.
- ( Donnie laughing )
Donnie.
( Cheering )
All right.
All right, Donnie's stoned
off his ass right now.
So nobody moves until you see
the ball move, understood?
- Ready?
- All: Break.
- ( Donnie laughing )
- Blue 16. Hut. Hike.
( Whistle tweets )
Offside. Defense.
( Donnie laughing )
Blue 16.
Set. Hut.
( Whistle tweets )
Offside. Defense.
I can't stop laughing.
Snap the damn ball, fatty!
Hit.
( Cheering )
Sammy:
Uh-oh, that's a touchdown!
That's six!
Check out, check out.
Watch the play action.
Hit.
Whoo! What time is it?
It's sack time!
What time is it?
You just got sacked!
Oh shit,
did I ring your bell?
Whoo!
Hey, Stalin, you want
to know something?
I built this field
all by myself with no help.
For real.
Yeah!
Razor two! Razor two!
Red one.
Red one. Red one.
Set. Hut.
- Go up the middle!
- Shit.
- All: Oh!
- Jesus.
- ( Chattering )
- Girl: That must've hurt.
Guy: No way.
Is he all right?
Go deep, Sammy.
Set. Set. Hit.
I'm open.
Yay! We won!
- Nice throw.
- Thanks.
( Chuckles ) Thanks.
Time out, ref!
Time out!
- ( Whistle tweets )
- Ref: Time out. Blue.
What the hell is the mascot doing
calling our last time out?
Alex, listen to me.
There's seven seconds
left in this game.
I didn't spend
three days building a field,
sleeping in a barn, drinking
milk from a cow's tit
and getting punched in the
face by a giant douchebag
for me!
I did it for you.
Thanks, bud.
Hey, coach,
last play of the game.
I think we run
a post to the corner.
Their DBs are tired.
Look.
Coach, put me in the game.
We're on offense, Thad.
I know, but this might be the last
time I ever put on this uniform.
And I want the weight of this
game on my shoulders.
Look, I can't do that.
He's right, coach.
Who knows if any of us are
gonna play again next year?
No one wants this win
more than the guys
who didn't get to play
in the Bowl game.
Now if you meant
what you said in the barn,
and you really want us
to play for that moment,
you've gotta let us.
I want to kiss you so bad
right now, Moran.
All right.
I want in too, coach.
Me too.
All right, you guys, you can play.
Get in there.
I don't know, coach.
Let them play.
All right.
All right. Yes.
All right, this is what
we're gonna do, okay?
T-formation, all right?
( Voice fades )
They're gonna come hard
from the left side
which should leave the right wide open.
Harmon, you're the quick out.
- Larry, you're the safety underneath. Got it?
- Larry: Right.
- Are we good?
- Wait, what do I do again?
Just keep Stalin
off me.
( Girls cheering )
Don't you dare try
to run it at me, Castle.
- All right, you guys remember what to do?
- Stalin: Is this a joke?
- Am I running or are you?
- The only joke is that haircut, Stalin.
Blue 16.
Hit.
Whoo!
Yeah!
We did it, Sammy!
You know my name!
Yeah!
You saved us today.
Whoo!
- Hey.
You are all right, Moran.
You too, Castle.
Awesome job building a field.
Finaly!
We did it!
Yes! Yes!
We did it, coach.
We finaly did it!
All right, give it back.
- What?
- We didn't play for that.
- What?!
- Just give it back.
Oh, man!
( Music playing )
Hey, Thad. God saved me
enough weed,
to add an extra foot
to the mega spliff.
Shit!
Let's light it up!
Say " BMS".
BMS!
Sync by Alex1969
www.addic7ed.com