Clear the way, people.
Superstar comin' through.
And her jet_set friend,
Miss Lola Lafonda.
Lola Lafonda?
lf people figure out l'm Lilly,
it's only a short jump to Miley.
Oh, very smart, Miss Lola.
Thank you, everybody.
l love you all. Thank you.
This is totally insane.
Back off, people. Back off.
Don't make me release Thor.
Yeah, you go get 'em, Thor. Two pounds
of pure piddle just looking for a target.
_ Actually, l think he just...
_ Oh, man!
Hannah! Wait!
Oh, no. lt's Oliver again.
He snuck into my dressing room last week,
nearly jumped on stage the week before
and just when you think he can't get any
more obsessed... he kicked it up a notch.
Look at those bony little elbows go.
That boy cuts through the crowd
like a Weedwacker.
Let me through!
Hannah, please. Kiss my hand
and l'll never wash it again.
Looks like he never
washes it now.
Come on, Thor,
make yourself useful.
Baby. You're an animal.
l like 'em feisty.
_ Let's rock_'n'_roll, driver.
_ He's never gonna give up.
Better hope he does,
because if he finds out your secret,
he's not only gonna be in love with
Hannah Montana, he'll be in love with you.
What? That's crazy.
The only thing that's the same
about Hannah Montana and me is...
me.
And me doesn't feel that way
about him.
Don't worry.
l know guys, and sooner or later,
he's gonna get tired of chasing after
somebody that's not chasing him back.
Do a dude a favor
and don't get on the freeway.
For you, my love.
Why did you have to be
such a good kisser?
lt's all true.
Hannah actually kissed this hand.
_ You gotta be kidding me.
_ A big, slobbery wet one.
Look. lt's still shiny.
Yeah, there's nothing like
the romantic glow of dog drool.
Chad, dude.
Close up shop when you chew.
You're getting spit
on the Hannah hand.
Miley, let's go.
You're cutting into my tan time.
Look at him.
He's never gonna quit.
What happens if he does find out?
l really do care about Oliver.
And l just don't wanna weird out
our friendship.
Unless, deep down, maybe,
just maybe, you feel the same way.
Yes, and maybe,
just maybe, that's insane.
And now that she's
left her mark on me,
it's time to take our relationship
to the next step.
Tonight at her CD signing,
l'm gonna stare into her eyes and say:
''You are my love, my life.
Someday you'll be my...''
Note to self:
''Think of words that rhyme with 'life.'''
Dude, isn't that the Hannah hand?
The CD signing. lf he stares into my eyes,
he might recognize me.
_ That's never gonna happen.
_ But what if it does?
You could learn to love him,
like with my brother's hamster.
And here's the beauty part.
lf Oliver dies,
you won't have to bury him
in the backyard.
When you talk, do you hear it,
or is it like a big roaring in your ears?
Step off, Chad.
Fine. But you're gonna
throw this away for me.
Take it off, dude! Take it off!
Dude. What's with you
and the gum_chewing?
Little Baby Ollie.
Aunt Harriet just wants to eat you up.
'Cause you're yummy,
yummy, yummy.
Let me kiss that off you.
l hate that woman.
Been sittin' here all morning,
l'm trying to write a song.
Can't remember
when it ever took me this dang long.
Maybe l should just up and fly the coop
'Cause everything l've written sounds like...
l got it, Dad, l got it.
Prepare to be blown away.
This better be good, son.
l was in the middle of a masterpiece.
Jackson Stewart, come on down.
You are the proud owner of a brand_new...
used car.
Yes, over the last 1 5 years,
this preowned beauty's been driven
by heavy smokers and sloppy eaters
and one Wilma McDermott, whose cat
popped out six kittens on the front seat.
Yes, some stains
just don't come out.
_ And you're happy about that.
_ Yes, l am.
Dad, it's mine.
lt's not perfect,
but it's my own car,
and l bought it with my own money.
l'm proud of you. Especially
the bought_it_with_your_own_money part.
_ Let's take a look at this puppy.
_ Puppies.
_ That reminds me. And in the back seat...
_ l don't wanna know.
Yep, there she is.
Clean, no dents and...
there's that stain.
_ Where is it?
_ lt's right here.
This?
l know.
l can't believe it's mine, either.
And l can't believe
you just bought a girl car.
What?
Jackson, only girls drive this thing.
lt's a chick mobile,
a babe bucket, a skirt scooter.
You might as well have bought
a bra with tires, man.
You are so wrong.
This is totally a guy's car.
When l was driving home,
there was guys honking
and waving and...
giving me kissy faces.
Oh, no, Dad.
Tell me l didn't just buy a chick car.
You didn't buy a chick car.
Now say it like you mean it.
l'd like to, son, but you know
how ladies like to have the final word.
Thank you so much.
l love you all. Thank you.
Thank you.
Let's boogie, driver.
That was great. Oliver stared
right into my eyes and never had a clue.
Kinda like the look
he has in Spanish.
l don't know what
l was so worried about anyways.
Better pull over, driver.
Don't be scared.
lt's me _ Oliver Oken.
Wow. You're even more beautiful
upside down.
Thank you. You're so sweet.
He was talking to me.
Look, you are very sweet,
but l have a boyfriend.
A boyfriend? Wait, l don't understand.
Then why did you kiss me?
l didn't. The dog did.
Ah, man!
Those are the lips l've been thinking about
for the past 24 hours?
l'm sorry.
l was trying not to hurt your feelings.
lt's just that...
l'm just not interested. OK?
OK. l get it.
Now get down off the roof, son,
before you dent it. This is a rental.
Fine. l won't bother you anymore.
lf it helps,
the dog hasn't stopped talking about you.
_ You must think l'm pathetic.
_ No. l think you're sweet.
_ And maybe if l didn't have a boyfriend...
_ l'd have a chance?
_ l never said that.
_ But you implied it.
And that's good enough.
l'll wait for you forever.
_ l never said that.
_ Forever. Do you hear me, Hannah?
Forever.
That was close.
He almost got you tonight.
Ya think?
You know what that boy needs?
A real girlfriend.
Dad, that is...
the smartest thing you've ever said.
You know what they say _ every now and
then, even a blind pig snorts up a truffle.
And that is the weirdest.
That's right _ it's me.
_ Yo, locker man.
_ l'm up.
_ l owe you.
_ l'll be back to collect.
Locker man.
You're amazing, Oliver.
l've been told that.
_ Having trouble with your locker, Chad?
_ Yeah. Could you?
Well, locker man is on the job, but...
not for you, sucker.
Oliver.
See that girl Pamela over there?
_ She thinks you're cute.
_ Can't say that l disagree.
Too bad l'm cruising
down the Hannah Highway.
What about Kyla Goodwin?
She is so desperate
she'll go out with anybody.
My type of woman.
Too bad l'm taken.
What about Lilly?
You guys would be perfect together.
_ Excuse me?
_ You're both stubborn.
_ l am not.
_ See? You always agree.
_ No, we don't.
_ l am definitely seeing a couple here.
You're not... because l'm not...
That's smart, because what if one friend
loved another but didn't get loved back?
Then things would get weird,
and they couldn't be friends anymore.
And there is nothing more important
than our friendship.
Oh, man, you love me.
No.
l mean, l do love you.
But like a brother or a pet fish.
l'd cry if l had to flush you down the toilet,
but l don't wanna kiss you.
That's a relief,
because you're my buddy.
l think Hannah and you
could wind up being close friends.
_ Closer than you think.
_ Great.
Once Hannah and l are together,
we'll have you over for some sushi.
Yeah.
Soon, my love, we'll be together.
You enjoy that.
This isn't over, pal.
Goodbye.
Hello again.
l know that look. Either you have
a great idea or you really gotta go.
Oliver is about to totally get turned off
to Hannah Montana.
And l really gotta go.
l can't believe
he wouldn't take the car back.
l thought l made
a very convincing argument.
Well, technically, son,
getting on your hands and knees
and begging for a do_over
is not really an argument.
_ Hey there, neighbor.
_ Oh, man, it's Mr. Dontzig.
And he's wearing his robe again.
Yeah, well, count your blessings.
At least this time it's the long one.
So... Stewart family.
What would another leaf from your tree
be doing in my hot tub?
l don't know.
Maybe it wanted to party.
_ Come on. Just trying to be neighborly.
_ That's nice.
But l hate neighbors.
That's why l got the big hedge.
So, something needs to be done
about this.
Yeah. And l think something needs
to be done about this.
l would recommend possibly some sit_ups
or maybe a bigger robe.
Very neighborly.
Got a new car.
You know, my wife,
she had a car just like this.
Traded it in.
She thought it was too girly.
Get your leaves out of my hot tub!
l'll have you know that we Stewart men
don't define ourselves
by the types of cars we drive.
That's it. This dolly wagon's
going back where it came from.
_ But the salesperson already said no.
_ To you, not to me.
Face it, son _ l'm a bit more intimidating.
Lord, take me now.
_ l came as fast as l could. ls she still here?
_ There.
l can't believe you saw Hannah
break up with her boyfriend on our beach
the moment l was getting home
from the orthodontist.
_ l know. Knock, knock. Who's there? Fate.
_ Fate who?
Just go.
_ This is it.
_ Good luck, Oliver. But remember:
lf things don't work out,
you're still Smokin' Oken.
_ Thanks, but it's gonna work out.
_ Absolutely.
But if it doesn't, Smokin' Oken.
'Nuff said.
lt's me. Oliver. l heard about your breakup,
and l'm here for you.
lf you need a hug, my arms are open.
_ Get away from me.
_ l can do that.
Hannah?
Hi. The kid from the moonroof.
Look at you, all upside right.
Where are my manners?
Sit down, sweetie. Join the party.
Here. You want some gum?
Load yourself up.
l didn't know you liked gum.
l've surfed all your websites, and none
of them mentioned you're a chewer.
l'm a chewer, all right.
l love to chew.
l chew all the time, like a train.
l chew in the morning,
the afternoon, the evening.
_ lf it can be chewed, it's in my mouth.
_ Good to know.
You should think about
updating your websites.
Why? Does it bother you?
lt really turns off some people.
They can't even be around me.
They love me, but l disgust them.
Well, l'm not like that.
You're not?
_ Because it's OK if you are.
_ No.
Relationships are about sacrifice,
and l accept you just the way you are.
Good to know.
Move over, boys.
New chew comin' through.
Your mouth... lt's...
Turning black?
lt's licorice. l love licorice.
Don't make me laugh _
it comes out my nose.
_ You wanna see?
_ No.
Too late. She's about to blow.
Am l grossing you out?
Because l totally understand
if you want to transfer
your obsession to Mandy Moore.
_ You know, she's blond again.
_ No, no, no.
My love is bigger than my disgust
and your black drippage.
Black drippage. Watch this.
Sacrifice, sacrifice, sacrifice.
How do you like me now?
l...
_ ...still love you
_ What does it take with you?
What more do l have to do?
You and Hannah Montana
are never gonna be together.
Why not?
Because...
l'm Hannah Montana. Me. Miley.
OK, that went well.
_ You were Hannah in the limo?
_ Yeah.
_ Backstage when l hung out the window?
_ Yep.
And when l hid in your bass drum
and rode on your tour bus to Phoenix?
_ You did what?
_ Nothing.
_ How come you didn't tell me?
_ l'm sorry.
lt's just that l knew
that you were so in love with Hannah
that l was afraid that
maybe you might...
Be in love with you?
Do you think l am?
You tell me. l mean, have you ever pictured
yourself with Miley, your friend the dork?
_ You're not a dork.
_ Oh, come on.
What about the time l tripped in the biology
lab and spilled frog juice all over you?
Right. Mom made me take off my pants
in the school parking lot.
Or when we were at Andrew's birthday
party and you accidentally knocked me
into the pool
in your one_man stampede for the cake?
That's not fair.
lt was an ice_cream log cake,
and you know l have to get an end cut.
Come on, Oliver.
Let's face it. The girl you thought you loved
is standing right here, and the truth is...
you don't love her.
Wow. l think you're right.
That's two years of my life
l'll never get back.
Sorry about that. So, what do you think?
Are we gonna be OK?
Yeah, we're OK.
_ Anything?
_ No.
ln fact, it's a little awkward.
Let's go grab a hot dog.
So... Mandy Moore. You don't happen to
have her number, do you?
Boy, you bounce back fast.
Where's my dad? lt's been hours.
He couldn't sell it _ that's what it is.
And now he can't face me.
Maybe something good happened.
Maybe he parked it
and a bunch of cheerleaders stole it.
You think so?
Here he comes.
Still driving it.
l knew it. Failure.
You're a failure as a father.
Get a grip. They wouldn't take the car back,
but l did do something to beef it up a little.
Dad, changing the horn
is not gonna make it a guy car.
l know. But this might.
Dang. This is tight.
_ Son, l primped your ride.
_ Oh, yes, he did.
Thank you!
Thank you, thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you, thank you.
OK, son, you can let go now.
lt was cute when you were five.
Now it just throws my back out.