[Man Narrating]Allmylife,
I´ve livedandworkedin thebig city,
which, nowthatI think ofit,
iskindofaproblem,
since Ialways feel
uncomfortablearoundcrowds.
Imeanit.
Ihave this fearofenclosedspaces.
I-I-I-- Everythingmakesme
feeltrappedall the time.
Youknow, Ialways tellmyselfthere´s
gottabesomethingbetterout there.
Butmaybe I--
maybe I think toomuch.
I-I-I think everything
mustgoback to the fact...
thatIhada veryanxious childhood.
You know, my mother
never had time for me.
When you´re the middle child
in a family of5 million,
you don´t get any attention.
I mean,
how is it possible ?
And-And I´ve always had these
abandonment issues which plague me.
My fatherwas-was basically a drone,
like I´ve said.
And, you know, the guy flew away
when I wasjust a larva.
And myjob, don´t get me started on,
because it really annoys me.
I-I was not cut out to be a worker,
I´ll tell you right now.
I-I-I feel
physically inadequate.
Mywhole life,
I´ve never been able to lift...
more than 1 0 times my own bodyweight.
And, when you get down to it, handling
dirt is, you know-- [ Shudders ]
is not my idea
ofa rewarding career.
It´s this whole gung ho,
superorganism thing...
that-- that, you know, I can´t get.
I try, but I don´t get it.
I mean-- What is it ? I´m supposed
to do everything for the colony.
And-And what about my needs ?
What about me ?
I´ve gotta believe there´s someplace
out there that´s better than this.
Otherwise, I wouldjust curl up
in a larval position and weep.
[ Sighs ]
The whole system makes me feel...
[ Exhales ]
insignificant.
Excellent.
- You´vemadearealbreakthrough.
- I have ?
Yes, Z.
You are insignificant.
I am ?
[Whistling]
[ Man ]
Ground floor.
[ Babies Crying Softly]
- [ Cries ]
- Uh, worker.
Soldier.
Ooh.
[ Giggles ]
- Uh-oh.
- Worker.
[ Cries ]
[Man]
Let´s tryitagain.
Firm grip. Swing hard.
Back straight. Concentrate.
Follow through.
[ Grunts ]
Okay. I´ve got to keep
a positive attitude.
A good attitude, even though
I´m utterly insignificant.
I´m-I´m insignificant, um,
but with attitude.
- [ Coughs ]
-[Woman]Oh, sorry, Z.
- [ Chuckles ] I didn´t seeya.
- Great, Azteca.
It´s working already.
I´m so meaningless, I´m invisible.
- [ Grunts ]
-[Laughs]
Now, you´re getting it.
After all, it´s not aboutyou.
It´s about us-- the team.
It´s about... this.
Uh, a giant hole
in the ground ?
- Okay, people. Are we feelinggood?
- [ All ] Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Great.
Now, R-1 734 through Z-7829,
you guys are on wrecking ball.
- You got it.
- Swell.
-[Man]Allright. Swing time.
- Let´s get physical.
- I love thisjob.
Now, remember, Azteca,
'' Be the ball.''
That´s the main thing.
Now, remember that.
You know, gotta be
one with the ball.
Would you cut it out already ?
Jeez. I love mywork.
And you, well--
You think too much.
Come on, Z. Help us build
a bigger, better colony.
And, for cryin´ out loud,
try to be happy about it.
Sure, you know.
I mean, why-why--
How could I possibly be unhappy being
a piece ofconstruction equipment ?
- Okay, workers, remember.
- Here it comes.
- Be the ball.
- Oh !
[Foreman]
Let the energy flowthroughyou.
Grin and bear it. This is--
This is for the colony. Oh.
- [ All Yelling ]
- Ow. This is--
This isjust a lawsuit
waiting to happen.
- Hang on. Here we go.
- Faster. Harder.
Did I happen to mention
that heights make me nauseous ?
No.
- This is a ball.
- Hey.
- [ Yelling, Indistinct ]
- [ Gagging ]
- [ Azteca ] Oh, Z.
- Yes. Yes. I understand.
I dropped the ball.
[Man]
Workers. They´re weak.
They lack discipline.
They lack commitment.
General, I know there´s
been a glitch or two.
But everybody is working
full tilt as it is, and--
You can´t help it,
it´s your nature.
But in spite ofyour limitations,
you are going to finish
this tunnel on schedule.
Come hell or high water.
Anyone who falls behind is going to have
to explain themselves to Colonel Cutter.
Andletmeassureyou, the colonel
isnotas understanding as Iam.
Dismissed.
Four more days, Cutter.
Four more days.
Then we can bid final farewell
to their kind ofincompetence.
Yes, sir.
A fresh start.
- Imagine it !
- A strong colony, sir.
A colonywe can be proud of.
Yes, but we´re not thereyet.
Cutter, wejust got word that
a termite army has mobilized against us.
Against us ?
We´ll have to send troops
deep into hostile territory...
to attack their colony.
Attack a termite colony, sir ?
- That´s suicide.
- Exactly.
- Doyou have the list I asked for ?
- Yes, General.
These are the units
loyal to the queen.
Hm. Then they´re
the ones we´ll be sending.
It´s a shame.
There´s some fine officers here.
Don´t we need the queen´s
approval to declare war ?
Ourvery next stop, Cutter.
General, we´vebeenatpeace
with thatcolony foryears.
- Whywould they attack us ?
- Theywant our land.
They´re desperate
for more foraging territory.
Perhaps they think
we´ve grown soft orweak.
Why don´t we dispatch an ambassador,
negotiate a new treaty ?
- We don´t need to send soldiers.
- Believe me.
Every ant in this colony
is so precious to me.
- [ Grunts ]
- That´s whywe must strike now.
We have the element ofsurprise.
Ifthe termite shock troops
enter our colony, well--
Yes, General,
I know what they can do to us.
- Verywell.
- You´ve made a wise decision.
In fact, you´ve insured
the future ofthis colony.
Hello, General.
Princess Bala.
What a nice surprise.
You look lovelier
each time I seeyou.
Thanks. I hopeyou´re not
just here on business.
Oh, ofcourse-- [ Chuckles ]
ofcourse not.
Because, um,
it might be nice...
ifwe had a conversation once
before we get married.
You´re absolutely right.
Cutter, schedule some private time
for me and Princess Bala.
Uh, in fact, sir, there is time
right now for a personal moment.
We´re a few seconds
ahead ofschedule.
Excellent.
Princess.
Well, a few seconds isn´t much,
but I guess ifit´s quality time--
So, how was your day ?
-Anything interestinghappen ?
- We declared war.
Declared war ?
Boy, talk about a rough day.
Sir, I hate to interrupt,
but time stands still for no ant.
Princess.
Mom, could you remind me,
why am I marrying this guy ?
Bala, do we have to argue
about this again ?
We don´t seem to have anything
in common. The guy´s a stiff.
Yes, darling.
I know the general may be...
a little gruff
and somewhat overbearing at times,
but I know that he cares aboutyou.
He´sjust not particularly good
at showing it.
Butyou should´ve seen how persistently
he asked foryour hand in marriage.
But why me ?
Becauseyou´re the one
who has to continue mywork.
It´s your place, dear.
- What ifI don´t like my place ?
- Everyone has their place, Bala--
you, the soldiers, the workers.
Now, it´s not all that bad
being princess, is it ?
Would you prefer to be
carting around dirt all day ?
Mother, don´t be so dramatic.
At least, they seem to have
some fun every now and then.
- [Man] Two aphidbeers.
- Why´d I have to be born a worker ?
You soldiers get all the glory,
plus you get to go out in the world.
You meet interesting insects,
you get to kill them.
Yeah. Butyou get to spend
all daywith those...
beautiful workergirls.
Weaver, they´re careergirls.
They´re obsessedwith digging.
[ Sighs ] I don´t think I´m ever
gonna meet the right girl for me.
Who said a girl foryou ?
I was talking about a girl for me.
[ Chuckles ]
Don´tyou wantyour aphid beer ?
Call me crazy, but--
[ Clears Throat ]
I have a thing about drinking from
the anus ofanother creature. Okay ?
Suityourself.
Ahhh.
Me, I´m cuttin´ loose.
We got royal inspection comin´ up.
Inspection, meaning you´re gonna
stand around like an idiot...
while a bunch ofblue bloods
smirk atyou.
I don´t know how
you put up with it, Weaver.
Z, I´ve known you
for a long time. Right ?
Definitely.
You were born two seconds after me.
Yeah. And ever since we were little,
I´ve been listenin´ toyou complain.
What areyou bitching about ?
In caseyou haven´t noticed,
we ants are running the show.
We´re the lords ofthe Earth.
Hey. Don´t talk to me
about earth, okay ?
´Cause I just spent all day
hauling it around.
[ Sighs ] There´sjust
gotta be a better place.
There is.
I´ve been there.
I´m sor-- I´m sorry.
Wereyou talking to me ?
There is a better place--
Insectopia.
Oh, really.
Lunatic at 3:00.
You can´t understand
till you go there and see ityourself.
You can beyour own ant there.
The streets are paved with food.
Nobody tellin´ you what to do.
No wars. No colony.
- I shoulda never left.
- [ Chuckles ] Oh, yeah. Fascinating.
We were on a long-range recon.
I got cut offfrom my unit.
Nothing like post-traumatic stress
disorder to makeyour day complete.
- Then I saw it-- Insectopia !
- Hey !
You head towards the monolith.
Ten clicks past the great canyons
to the land ofred and white.
Hey, gramps.
You´ve had enough for one night.
Come on.
Beforeyou get in trouble.
Head for the monolith.
Listen to me !
Themonolith !
[ Chuckles ]
That guy´s got a screw loose.
- Cross thelake!
- Insectopia. [ Scoffs ]
Wouldn´t it be great
ifit were that easy ?
- [ Chuckles ] Yeah. Dream on, Z.
- Cross thelake.
Look for the land
ofred and white.
Wow !
This is so... gritty.
Ten minutes and we´re out ofhere.
Right ? This place is offlimits.
Just blame it on me.
Say it was all my idea.
- It is all your idea.
- Besides, no one´s gonna recognize us.
Come on, girls.
What doyou say ?
Let´s take a walk
on the wild side.
[Man On LoudSpeaker]
Okay, everybody. 6.:15. Time to dance.
- Time to cut a rug, Z.
- Oh, no. That´s okay.
I´m gonna leave the rug
just the way it is, Weaver.
[Jazz, Slow]
Step back, ladies.
I´m gonna ask one ofthese
workers to dance with me.
Oh.
What a bunch oflosers.
Mindless zombies capitulating
to an oppressive system.
- Hi. Want to dance ?
- Absolutely.
Follow me.
So, how come I haven´t seen you
around here before ?
Oh, I don´t get out much.
I, uh, I work over at the palace.
Oh, the palace, huh ?
I bet those royals really live it up.
Course they´re all a little--
you know-- from inbreeding.
What ?
Yowch !
Ya-Ya-- Yowch !
Yowch.
- Yowch.
- What on earth areyou doing ?
Well, actually, to tell you the truth,
I´m sort ofmaking it up.
Really ?
Why does everybody
have to dance thesame way ?
That´s completelyboring.
It´s-- It´smonotonous.
It´s no fun.
[Orchestra.:
Latin, Up-Tempo]
Hey.
Watch your step, worker.
You watch yours, buddy,
oryou´ll be in big trouble.
Th-Th-That´s okay. I´ll--
I´m gonna let him offthis time.
What ? Areyou crazy ?
This guy´s built like a pebble.
Aren´tyou even
gonna defend yourself?
Hey, buddy.
Get back in place.
- Me ? Uh-- Uh--
- What ifhe doesn´t want to ?
[ Clears Throat ]
Yeah. What ifI don´t like my place ?
- What´s he talkin´ about ?
- We got us a troublemaker.
Buckle up, Spanky.
This one goes out
to all the lazyworkers.
[ Grunts ]
You ought to watch that
aggressive behavior, buddy.
He´sjust a worker.
[ Muffled Talking ]
- [ Ants Shouting ]
- [ Chuckles ]
Princess Bala ! Princess Bala !
The guards are coming.
- Let´s get outta here.
- Wait.
[ Shouting, Indistinct ]
Princess ?
You´re a princess ?
Uh, I gotta go.
- When can I seeyou again ?
- Let me think. Never.
- Bye.
- No. Wait.
[ Grunts ]
[Z]
Whata dayithasbeen
What a rare mood I´m in
Why, it´s almost
like being in love
- There´sasmile
- Huh ?
On my face
for the whole insect race
Why, it´salmost
likebeing in love
[ Whistle Blows ]
Yowch.
[ Talking, Indistinct ]
- Can I getyou another one, pal ?
- [ Sighs ] No, thanks.
- I think I´m gonna go.
- Yeah. I don´t blameyou.
It´s always slow in here the night
before one ofthose royal reviews.
I guess the soldiers need their shut-eye
before they meet the queen.
- I don´t blameya.
- That´s it !
You know, I was once--
Seeya.
[ Snoring ]
Psst.
Weaver.
I figured it out.
Weaver. Weaver.
What ? What ?
-[Clears Throat]
- I got a great idea.
You gotta switch places with me. Let me
go to the inspection instead ofyou.
-What time is it ?
-Weaver. The royal familywill be there.
This is the onlyway
I can see her.
- See who ?
- Princess Bala.
Areyou nuts ?
You want me
to switch places with you ?
Doyou know how much trouble
you can get into...
for even talkin´ about
impersonatin´ a soldier ?
You can get in trouble
just for listenin´...
to someone talkin´ about
impersonatin´ a soldier.
You have to help me.
IfI can´t see her again,
my life is not worth living.
Pl-Pl-Please, Weaver.
Please.
Switchjobs with me
just for a day.
Th-Think ofall the things
that I´ve done foryou.
Hm. I can´t
think ofany.
Okay. So, think ofall the things
that I´m gonna do foryou.
Would I meet
some worker girls ?
Areyou kidding ?
They always go after the new guy.
It´s like a sport for them.
And-And believe me,
theywill definitely go...
-foranadorable little insectlikeyou.
-Mmm.
Weaver, I--
I have to see her again.
Z, what kind ofchance
doyou have with a princess ?
I mean, she probably
won´t even rememberyou.
[ Sighs ] I-- I know it sounds nuts,
but I have to try.
Oh, boy.
[ Exhales ]
-[March]
- Princess, fancy meeting you here.
What doyou say
we lose this crowd ?
Oh, me ? Youknow, I--
I wearmanyhats.
I guess you´d have to call me
a Renaissance ant.
[Man]
Eyes right!
- Beautiful !Just beautiful !
- Mm.
- The precision. The order.
- Oh.
Princess Bala ! Princess Bala !
Hey. It´s me.
RememberZ from the bar ?
Princess Bala !
Princess Bala ! Princess--
Bala, you must
encourage the troops.
Wave.
Oh. She sees me.
Excuse me, guys. I-I-- Sorry.
Ijustgotabetteroffer.
Couldyouexcu--
Companyhalt!
Princess.
Princess Bala.
Quiet there !
Getback in rank.
- You new, kid ?
- Oh, y-yes, but I´m gettin´ out soon.
I got a trial membership.
Trial membership. [ Chuckles ]
That´s a good one !
- Name´s Barbatus.
- Z.
- Rightface!
- Psst.
- [ Footsteps ]
- [ Whip Cracks ]
Sacrifice.
To some, it isjust a word.
To others, it is a code.
-Jeez. I´m really bad at word games.
- [ Chuckles ]
A soldier knows that the life
ofan individual ant doesn´t matter.
What matters is the colony.
He´s willing to live for the colony,
to fight for the colony,
to die for the colony.
- This guy´s crazy.
- I hearya.
At 0800 hours, we received word
that the termite enemy has mobilized.
We have no choice
but to launch a preemptive strike.
You are the queen´s finest.
Iknowyou will
all doyouduty.
I am proud to send you into battle.
Into-- I´m sor-I´m sorry.
Into battle ?
- Dismissed.
-[Man]Leftface. Forwardmarch.
You know, I think
there´s been a terrible mistake.
You know, the truth is I just--
I just came for the speech.
Don´t worry, kid.
I´ll watch out forya.
- Sound off.
- One !
- Two !
-Soundoff.
- Three !
- Huh ?
-Soundoff.
- Five !
- Six !
- Seven !
- Eight !
- Nine !
- Ten !
- Eleven !
- Twelve !
- Thirteen !
We ants go marching one by one
Hurrah, hurrah
[ All ] We slaughter termites
just for fun, hurrah, hurrah
- So, these termites, they´re-they-re--
-  [ Continues, Indistinct ]
These guys aren´t gonna put up much ofa
fight ? We´re talkin´ pushovers, right ?
Not really, kid.
They´re five times our size.
And they shoot acid
from their foreheads.
[ Gasps ]
- [ Grunts ]
- Hey. Keep it movin´, shorty.
[ All ] We ants go marching two by two
Hurrah, hurrah
We´ll all be dead before we´re through
-[Humming]
- Say, what exactly does our platoon do?
I mean, will we be serving beverages
or processing paperwork ?
Our platoon has the best assignment--
first into battle.
Huh ?
We ants go marching three by three,
hurrah, hurrah, hurrah, hurrah
We´re offto face our destiny
Hurrah, hurrah
Hey. Wait a minute. Let´s not get--
We´re being too hasty here.
These-- These guys
sound like bruisers.
Just how wereyou figuring
on beating them ?
Superior numbers, kid. Overwhelm
their defenses and kill their queen.
Hey, fellas.
You´re being a little extreme, I feel.
W-Why don´t we try
and influence their political process...
with campaign contributions ?
I likeyou, kid.
You got a sense ofhumor.
Forward!
Come on.
Let´s kick some termite butt.
Over the top !
- [ All Shouting, Indistinct ]
- Yeeow !
[ Shouting Stops ]
- Where is everyone ?
- Something´s not right.
Don´t be scared, kid.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Growls ]
Attack !
[ Groans ]
Come on.
- [ Growls ]
- [ Yells ]
Barbatus, you saved my life.
Ah, don´t get all sappy about it.
- Hey, guys. Look out behind you !
- [ Growls ]
Hey-- Hey, guys.
Cansomebodyhelpmehere ?
Cananybody-- Hey.
Yeah.
[Grunting]
Okay, mama.
[ Grunts ] Yeah.
Oh, yeah. Big guy comin´ through.
[ Grunts ]
I love it.
Hey. Hey. Hey.
Takeiteasy, muscles.
You´re makin´
the rest ofus look bad.
What happened to Z ?
He´s takin´ a personal day,
so I´m fillin´ in.
You fill in any more,
and you´ll explode.
Eh, you got a problem ?
No, uh-- uh--
Nobody told me
digging was so much fun.
You know, you pick the dirt up.
You move it.
You pick it up again.
You move it again. Lots ofreps.
You exercise the arms
and the thorax.
Yes, I--
I see whatyou mean.
- Um. Yeah. That is fascinating.
- Sorry, sir.
I wasjust havin´ a chat
with my friend, sir.
You know, I just had a chat
with General Mandible.
Anybodywho doesn´t meet his quota
is going to be downsized.
Come on. Cut him a break.
He´s new.
Hey. What doyou saywe help
your attitude a little bit...
by taking away
your rations for the day.
Thanks foryour time.
I don´t know what came over me.
Talking back like that.
I must be losin´ it.
Sorry I gotyou in trouble.
But, listen, you can...
share my rations. Whoa.
Ifyou want.
- Areyou askin´ me out to dinner ?
- [ Chuckles ]
Oh, no. I--
Well, ifyou don´t have
anything else planned.
[ Laughs ]
I´ll check my calendar.
You know,
I´m kinda glad
Z´s takin´ a breather.
Kid !
Kid, over here.
Barbatus.
Be honest, kid.
Am I hurt bad ?
N-No. N-Not at all. You´re--
Actually, you´re lookin´ terrific.
You got, you know,
swell color in your cheeks.
No.
I can see it in your eyes.
I´m a goner.
Helpme up, Z.
[ Sniffs ]
I can´t feel my legs.
You gotta hang in there, buddy.
I knowyou´re gonna make it.
Just take-- take deep breaths.
Because I´m gonna try
and find your body.
It´s bound to be
out there somewhere.
[ Coughs, Sighs ]
Barbatus, hang on.
- B-Barbatus.
- Don´t make my mistake, kid.
Don´tfolloworders
your whole life.
Think foryourself.
[ Sighs ]
Barbatus.
[Cutter] We´re onschedule.
Work is completedon 'A ''section, sir.
We´re clearing a path
through '' D'' section now.
We need to push harder, Cutter.
I want double shifts around-the-clock.
We can´t afford to let up.
Is that clear ?
- Crystal, sir.
- Good.
- What about section--
- Excuse me, sir.
This had better be important.
Well, it´s about
the termite battle, sir.
The enemywas destroyed, but it was
a disaster for our troops, as well.
Well, that´s terrible.
Terrible.
There is good news, sir.
One soldier did make it back.
- No kidding.
- What did you say ?
Word is spreading
through the colony.
The queen requested a meeting
with the war hero.
Damn ! Good.
Damn good.
Uh, I´ll handle this.
[FootstepsApproaching]
- Congratulations, soldier.
- [ Clears Throat ]
[ Chuckles ] Well, you´re a little short
for a war hero, aren´tyou ?
A war hero ? Sir, I-I don´t
actually think that I´m a hero.
Good.
I don´t like heroes.
- But, sir. Youdon´tunderstand. I--
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
I-- I didn´t do anything.
I mean, it was all horrible.
It wasjust a massacre.
A-A massacre upon a massacre.
That´s good, soldier.
Now, wave.
There was nothing
you could do, Weaver.
You didn´t know
theywere going to war.
I just feel horrible.
PoorZ.
I should have never let him go.
Wait a minute.
That´s no soldier. That´s Z !
Z ? The little guy made it !
[ Chuckles ]
[Crowd Cheering]
Let´s go, soldier.
As I wassaying, son,
youareanantaftermyownheart.
An ant that looks death
in the face and laughs.
Well, actually, the truth is,
I-I generallyjust make
belittling comments...
and snicker behind death´s back.
[ Chuckles ]
GeneralMandible.
Keepyour comments toyourself.
Let me do the talking.
[ Yawns ]
May I present
Her Majesty the Queen.
Charmed. Charmed.
And the Royal Princess Bala.
[ Growls ]
Welcome home, soldier.
We cannot begin to express
our gratitude foryour heroic efforts.
The private has asked me
to convey his most humble appreciation.
Please. Please.
It was nothing really.
Justyour average
run-of-the-mill valor...
and extraordinary courageousness,
you know.
In the heat ofbattle,
there´s very little time to think.
One must attack ! Attack ! Attack !
[ Chuckles ]
- [ Chuckles ] Well, indeed.
- [ Muffled Talking ]
As you can see, Your Highness, the
battlefield is still fresh in his mind.
So, begging your pardon, but this is
the perfect time to debriefthe private.
Oh, please, General.
Not on our first date.
[ Chuckles ]
Haven´t I seen you
somewhere before ?
Well, maybe.
Then again, maybe not.
And then-- then again.
-Yowch.
-That´s it! You´re the guy from the bar.
- Don´t-- Shh.
- Bar ? What bar ?
I danced with this guy at the bar
the other night.
He wasjust a worker then.
- What wereyou doing at a bar ?
- Preciselywhat I want to know.
No. This isn´t about me.
I mean, look at this worker.
Lookwhat he´s done.
I thinkyou´re thinkin´ ofsomeone else.
After all, I am a soldier.
Exactly.
You were a worker.
But now, you´re a war hero.
- He´s a worker ?
- A worker danced with my fiancee ?
F-Fiancee ?
W-W-Wait a minute.
This is not how it looks.
I can explain this.
Hey. She was the one
making all the moves.
Arrest him.
H-Heywait a minute. Take it easy.
Can´t we discuss this ?
What areyou doing ?
Let go ofmy daughter.
He´s taking her hostage !
No. No. I´m not.
I mean, yes, I am.
One more step
and then the princess gets it.
[ Grunts ]
Let go ofme !
Ow !
Don´t make me hurt her.
[Z Yelling]
[ Both Screaming ]
[ Groans ]
Oh.
What areyou doing, you creep ?
Areyou out ofyour puny little mind ?
[ Man ] There they are down there !
Let´s go. Move. Move. Move.
Oh, good.
Here they come
to rescue me and kill you.
Kill ?
- Hey, you guys.
- Stop it. Stop it.
- What areyou tryin´ to do ?
- Get offme, you little twerp !
What doyou want to do ?
Throw away everything we´ve got ?
What´reyou waiting for ?
Hello. Guys.
- Huh ?
- What is it ?
It´s beautiful.
Ridgeway, get out ofthere !
[ Both Grunting ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Sighs Softly]
- Oh. Don´t worry. I´m okay.
- You ?
You´re okay ?
Hey. Who cares aboutyou ?
- Ialmostdiedhere.
- Will you please calm down ?
You´re not gonna let a little near-death
experience ruin your mood, areyou ?
Hey. This is not a mood.
You´re not listening to me.
Where am I ?
Look, what´s-your-name.Just climb up
that tree and find out where I am.
Look, t-the trick is not to panic.
You know, h-h-he w-who panics is lost.
What am I saying ?
We are lost.
- [ Yells ]
- [ Gasps ]
[ Chuckles ]
Ow !
I´ve been kidnapped
by the village idiot.
Who´s the bigger idiot,
the idiot or the idiot
who gets kidnapped by the idiot ?
What´d you do,
talk those termites to death ?
I can´t believeyou tried to
pass yourselfoffas a soldier.
Why areyou stalking me ?
Don´tyou realize
that I´m out ofyour league ?
You´re the one who was cruising the
worker bar looking for a little action.
And youjust happened to find it--
the swarthy, earthy, sensual worker.
Please.
I was slumming it.
Don´tyou get it ?
I choseyou becauseyou were the most
pathetic little bug in thejoint.
I was gonna letyou become part
ofmy most erotic fantasies.
Butnow, youcan forget that.
Write it off, you know. I guess
whatyou prefer is Old Blood and Guts.
This guy´s idea ofa romantic night out
is two seats at a public execution.
Boy. You really chose
the right husband.
Foryour information,
the general and I are deeply,
deeply in-- engaged.
You come right back
down here this instant.
We are marching straight back
to the colony so that I--
[Bala Continues, Indistinct]
The monolith !
Absolutely. Wonderful.
That´s an appealing offer.
But, considering the options,
you go back. Okay ?
´Cause I´m going to Insectopia.
Oh. Come on. Insectopia ?
You´re crazier than I thought.
Yeah. Well, I happen to have it
on a very reliable source.
[ Clears Throat ]
Or-- Or should I say,
a drunk-raving source ?
But the point is, I´m convinced
the place definitely exists.
Stop !
I orderyou to stop, worker !
Hey. I got a name.
Okay ? It´s Z.
And out here,
you can´t order me around.
All right. Fine.
No problem.
[ Seething ]
-[Crashing]
- [ Screams ]
[ Gasps ] Worker ! Worker !
Where areyou ?
Z ? Z ? Wait for me.
No more excuses, General.
I want my daughter back.
Frankly, I´m beginning to doubt
your ability to handle this.
Believe me, Your Highness, we will
spare no effort to bring her back.
Princess Bala is essential
to all our plans for the future.
So he kills himself
a hundred termites,
gets a few medals, then bada-bing,
bada-bip, bags himselfthe princess.
-[Worker]
He lookshim deadin the eye--
- And says, '' Bite me.''
He said that
to General Mandible ?
Buddy. Hey, hey, buddy.
You heard about
the war hero named Z ?
Runs offwith the princess, right ?
When they sent the guards after him,
hejust looks at ´em and boom !
- They burst into flames.
- Z ? [ Chuckles ] You talkin´ about Z ?
Hey, I know the guy. He´s a friend
ofmine. I thinkyour information--
- You know Z ?
- Yeah.
He´s a worker.
He used to dig around here.
A worker? That´s impossible.
A workercan´tdoanything, except work.
Yeah. It´s not like
we got a choice.
We do have a choice.
Uh, I mean, look at Z.
He decided he wanted something,
and he went for it.
He´s not alone. I used to be a soldier,
and I switched places with him.
Wait a second. You´re tellin´ me...
I don´t have to be here ?
We´ve got a choice ?
The authorities
don´t wantyou to know,
but we don´t have to work
on the tunnel anymore.
It´s the workers who control
the means ofproduction.
IfZ don´t dig, I don´t dig.
[Foreman]People, whatis this ?
An encountergroup ?
- Let´s get back to work.
- Why ?
...on the tunnelanymore! Thisguy, Z--
he´s leadin´therevolution!
- I´ll... get back toyou.
- [ All Chattering, Indistinct ]
Think about it, Z-- two ants.
Who ever heard oftwo ants ?
Two million ants, maybe. But two ?
Look, I´m hungry, I´m thirsty.
And this whole desert thing ?
- Itjust doesn´t work for me.
- Yada, yada, yada.
I think it´s about time
foryou to take me back.
Takeyourselfback.
[ Scoffs ]
Excuse me.
You kidnapped me, remember ?
That means you have
certain responsibilities.
You can´tjust abandon me
here in the wilderness.
Yeah, well, it´s better than
being back at the colony.
- You´re not serious, areyou ?
- Maybeyou were living the high life,
but personally,
this beats digging.
Ifyou´d ever done a day´s labor
you´d know what I was talking about.
Labor ?
What doyou know about labor ?
How would you feel
ifyou were expected to give birth...
every ten seconds
for the rest ofyour life ?
Gee.
Water !
Ahh. All you think about
is yourself.
Yeah ? Well, nobody else
ever thought about me.
Soas faras I´m concerned,
Idon´tneedanybodyelse.
- Uhh !
- [ Muffled ] Help ! Help me, Bala !
Help !
B-B-B-B-Bala !
Hold on. I´ll getyou out.
Hold on.
- Help, Ba--
- [ Grunting ]
[ Both Gasping ]
- Thanks.
- Don´t mention it.
Now, maybe we can put
this fantasy behind us...
and head back to the colon--
Oh, Z !
What areyou doing ?
- We´ve gotta cross the lake.
- Am I missing something here ?
Didn´t wejust get out ofthe water ?
Bala, look,
what haveyou got to lose ?
I mean, think about it. Doyou really
want to be Mrs. Raving Lunatic ?
There´s a better place.
Z, please.
Just... gimme one chance.
Ifwe don´t find Insectopia soon,
I promise
I´ll takeyou back to the colony.
I hopeyou know
whatyou´re doing.
Yeah, me too.
[Ants Shouting, Indistinct]
[ All Chanting ]
We want Z ! We want Z !
People, come on.
I know some ants who aren´t
gonna make their quota.
Buzz off, pawn ofthe oppressor.
[ Chanting Continues ]
We want Z ! We want Z !
Sorry, sir. I came as soon as I heard.
I was debriefing the trackers.
- And ? What´s the report ?
- Well, this Z, sir--
He´s one slippery character.
They lost Bala´s trail
at the edge ofthe lake.
The lake ?
[ All ]
All we are saying
Is give Z a chance
What´s that soldier doing there ?
It appears he´s holding hands, sir...
with a worker.
I don´t like the way
things are going, Cutter.
I´m counting on you for results.
- Now, can I depend on you or not ?
- Yes, sir.
All right, then.
Let´s wrap this up.
[ Chanting Continues ]
We want Z ! We want Z ! We want Z !
I´ve heard a lot about this Z.
I even had the pleasure
ofmeeting him once.
But where is he now ?
Cananyonepointhim out ?
I mean, ifthis Z
cares so much about us,
then why isn´t he here ?
I´lltellyou why.
BecauseZdoesn´tgivea damnaboutus.
[Ants Murmuring]
That´s why he kidnapped our princess.
That´s why he ran away.
Zisnohero.
Weare theheroes.
We are the ones ensuring
the future ofour great colony.
And when we´ve completed
this magnificent structure,
we will reap the benefits:
more food and less work for everyone.
[Murmurs OfApproval]
And as further reward
foryour heroic efforts,
each and every one ofyou
will get the day off,
[ExcitedMurmurings]
soyou can be the guests ofhonor at
the MegaTunnel dedication ceremonies !
[ All Cheering ]
Mandible ! Mandible !
[Ants Chanting]Mandible !
Mandible!Mandible!Mandible !
[ Chanting Continues ]
Now bring me that soldier.
[ Yawns ]
[ Gasps ] Oh, my God !
Z ! Come here !
It´s Insectopia !
You were right.
It really is here.
- Huh ?
- All right. All right !
- You´re a genius.
- Let´s eat. Mmph !
Huh.
[ Nervous Chuckle ]
[ Muttering ]
Well ?
What´s the problem ?
- There´s some kind offorce field.
-[Buzzing]
Uh, excuse me. Excuse me.
How doyou get in ?
Yes, well, I´m afraid
this is a private function.
- Who areyour friends, dear ?
- Crawling insects, poopsie.
Oh.
The poor dears.
[ Slowly]
Uh, good morning.
- Huh ?
- Darling, really.
Greeting every insect
that emerges out ofthe grass ?
Pardonme.
Iguessyoudon´trecognizeme.
I´ve been traveling
and I´m all... schlumpy.
I´m Princess Bala.
Oh ! It´s even worse.
They´re Eurotrash.
Darling, they´re poor.
They´re dirty. They´re smelly.
We have to help them.
Ifyou´ll just wait right here,
we´ll fetch you a little something.
Oh, please, Muffy.
Not another crusade.
Chippie, we have a social obligation
to the less fortunate.
I knowyou laugh at my hobbies,
but this is important to me !
Mm. You have such a big heart.
That´s whyyou´re
my little cuddly-widdles.
Oh, my big, strong pheromone factory.
- Mmm !
- Oh !
Oh, brother.
Suddenly I´ve lost my appetite.
- You know...
- [ Muffy] Oh !
I guess I had
imagined Insectopia--
I don´t know--
a little differently.
- Oh, Muffy!
- [ Gasps ]
- No ! Oh, no ! [ Crying ]
- Oh, no.
-[Rumbling]
- Look out !
Z, help me ! Z !
Don´t let me--
Don´t let me go, Z.
Get me out ofhere !
Bala !
Whoa, this is not good.
Whoa !
Whoa-oa-oa !
[ Bala Screaming ]
Hi.
[BothScreaming]
[Thudding]
- Z ?
- Yes ?
It looks like this is it,just when...
I was starting to likeyou.
[ Both Screaming ]
Who the hell is that ?
Uhh !
That´s enough.
I ain´t tellin´ you nothin´.
Soldier, the princess is vital
to the future ofthis colony.
She must be returned
to take her proper place as queen.
We already have a queen.
As foryour friend Z,
why should I hurt him ?
[ Chuckles ]
He´s not important.
Now, soldier,
we all know that one individual ant
doesn´t matter.
Notyou...
- not Cutter...
-[DoorOpens]
- [ Azteca Grunts ]
- Not even her.
Azteca !
[ Groaning ]
Don´t tell that tight-ass
anything, Weaver ! Aagh !
- [ Grunting ]
- Where is Z ?
- I don´t know where he is !
- Hmm.
That´s too bad.
[Azteca Groaning]
Wait ! Insectopia.
Uhh ! I know it sounds crazy,
but that´s where he´d be going.
Soldier, you think this is a game ?
Insectopia does not exist.
As a matter offact... it does.
- Sir ?
- I´ll briefyou on the coordinates.
You´regonnabring
theprincessback.
And as forZ... kill him.
Butyou said he didn´t matter.
It´s for the good ofthe colony.
You made the right decision.
Gentlemen, nowyou can see...
how dangerous individualism can be.
It makes us... vulnerable.
Let´s go.
[DoorSlams]
Take him back to the MegaTunnel.
Put him on the front line.
Dismissed.
[ Sighs ]Jeez, what was I thinking ?
I almost gotyou killed.
Z, you know, you really
shouldn´t be so hard on--
[ Straining ] That´s it.
I´m taking you back to the colony.
- Uhh ! Ow ! Oh.
- Uhh !
Insectopia.
You know, I must´ve been crazy.
- Z ?
- Butyou know what ?
- I can admit it when I´m wrong.
- Z.
And this time, I gotta tell ya,
I was absolutely, 1 00%...
correct.
Have-- Haveyou ever seen
anything more beautiful in your life ?
- It´s... Insect--
- Shh ! Don´tjinx it. Come on !
Icansee clearlynow
Therain isgone
[ Burps ]
Icanseeallobstacles
in my way
Goneare the dark clouds
thathadmeblind
- [ Ladybug ] Pardon us.
- It´sgonnabeabright
-Bright, bright
-Brightsunshiny day
- [ Insects Squealing ]
-It´sgonnabeabright
- Bright, bright
- Brightsunshiny day
Lookallaround
Nothingbutblueskies
Lookstraightahead
Nothingbut
Blueskies
Whoa
Icansee clearlynow
Therain isgone
[Buzzing]
Icanseeallobstacles
in my way
Allright, everybody.
I wantallteamsinplace,
fully prepared,
ready to seal the doors here and here.
Make certain the digging crew
stays onschedule...
forbreakthroughmidway
in the dedication ceremony.
Nowall weneedis theprincess.
[ Sniffing ]
Mm.
- This stufftastes like crap.
- Really ? Let me try some.
Hey, it is crap.
Not bad.
- Somebody needs to feed that fire.
- Dude, I did it last time.
I´m not gonna get it.
It´s not myjob.
What about the new guy ?
He hasn´t contributed yet.
And... [ Sighs ] you know,
hejust died in my arms like that.
I-- You know, I don´t think
he ever once in his life...
made his own choice.
I never knew it was like that.
I mean, up in the palace--
Well, I guess wejust let the general
make all the decisions.
Let me askyou something. What
madeyou come to the bar that night ?
I guess I was looking
for a little trouble.
Well, [ Chuckles ]
trouble´s my middle name.
Actually, my middle name
is Marion, but, uh,
-I don´t wantyou to spread that around.
-You´re pretty strange.
- You do know that, don´tyou ?
- Well, [ Clears Throat ]
strange´s not exactly
the word I would use.
I like it.
You´re not like anyone else.
Actually, now thatyou mention it,
there is a certain strangeness to me.
I mean, it´s a, you know, kind ofa
bizarre quality. Some have said ''freak.''
But it´s, uh,
you know, complimentary.
Hey, newguy.
Weneedmore wood.
I´ll be right back.
Just hold that thought--
whatever it is
you were thinking.
Hey, you everwonderwhy
they call you guys ''pests'' ?
[Mosquito] Whatif, like,
we´rejust these tinylittle things...
and we´rejust, like, part of
this whole other huge universe...
that´s, like, so big
we don´t even know it exists ?
[ Ladybug Chuckles ]
Man, that is so deep.
Perfect. Nothing like
a little manual labor...
on the most romantic night
ofmy life.
[ Buzzing ]
Hi. I was in the neighborhood
and I thought I´d drop in.
This is, uh, very bohemian.
Aloha, dude. Welcome to Insec--
[ Groans ]
[Insects Gasp]
Sorry for interrupting.
You see, our princess has,
uh, gone missing,
and we´rejust sick about it.
She´s aboutyea tall,
fairly easy on the eyes.
- Anybody seen her ?
- That´s her.
Don´t worry, Princess,
you´llbebackhomesoon.
Listen, Cutter, I´m--
I´m not going back.
[ Sighs ] The thing is, Princess,
I got orders.
Orders ? Can´tyoujust once
think foryourself?
Well, that was very impressive.
Where´s Z ?
- Z ? He´s, uh--
- Dead.
Z´s dead.
You don´t need to worry about him.
Well, he was an ant with ideas.
Too bad for him.
Princess, your colony needs you.
- [ Grunting ]
-[Bala]Cutter!
- Stop right now ! Let go ofme !
- Bala !
Stop, you--
Oh, no.
[ Muttering ]
What am I gonna do ?
All right, look.
Let´s be rational about this.
You know, Bala and I,
you know, she´s a princess...
andI´m a--
I´m asoil-relocation engineer.
So wha-- You´re no--
Whew !
On the other hand, uh...
I´ve gotta go back for her.
[Chippie]
I´ll-I´llgiveyoualift.
S-S-S-- Whoa !
Ohh !
It´s the least I can do.
Besides, it´s what mywaddly-kiddles
would want.
[ Sniffling, Sobbing ]
Uh, look, [ Clears Throat ]
how about a cup ofjoe first ?
- Well, old boy... saddle up.
- I think Isaw
apuddle ofcoffee overthere.
It-- Whoa !
[ Both Groaning ]
[Z]
Look out!
[ Bala Grunting ]
Ah, Princess.
- You´rejustin time.
- Takeyour hands offme.
General, what exactly
is going on here ?
- I demand an explanation.
- I´ll explain everything afterwards.
- Is the southeast entrance secure ?
- Yes, sir.
Not afterwards. Now.
I don´t like the wayyou think and I
don´t like the wayyou run this colony.
And I don´t likeyou.
The wedding is off.
-Things are going to change around here.
-You´re right, Princess.
Things are going to change.
Why don´t we make her more comfortable ?
- [ Gasps ]
- She´llbehere fora while.
What doyou thinkyou´re doing ?
My motherwill haveyour head.
I doubt that. [ Chuckles ]
Ah, you´ve got a fighter spirit, Bala.
And that´sjust what we need
to start our new colony.
We will rinse away
all the filth from our gutters.
We´ll start anew,
with you by my side as my queen.
You´re crazy.
I believe history
will see things differently.
All right, gentlemen.
Time to takeyour positions.
Someday--
Somedayyou´ll thank me.
[ Both Moaning ]
[ Z ] Pull up ! Pull up !
Aah ! There it is !
[ Muttering, Hiccupping ]
Oof! [ Coughs ]
Oh !
Well, then, go get
the woman you love, Z.
So long, Chip. And thanks.
You there.
Where doyou thinkyou´re goin´ ?
Me ? Oh, no, I wasjust--
You know, I--
You´re not supposed
to be out here.
All workers are to report to
the tunnel-opening ceremonies.
Yes, yes, ofcourse.
The-The tunnel-opening ceremonies.
I-- Well, I should get going, then.
I-- [ Clears Throat ]
- You know, the-the--
- [Soldier] Hey!
I´m going to the-- [ Clears Throat ]
the tunnel-opening ceremonies.
- I´d... better get goin´.
- Getmoving.
I´m going to the--
the tunnel-opening ceremonies. I--
Excuse me, please. [ Chuckles ]
Tunnel-opening ceremonies.
- Hey, worker !
- Opening the tunnel. They need me.
- I´m the key man.
- Where doyou thinkyou´re going ?
Tunnel-opening ceremonies.
-[CrashingSound]
-[Bala]Hey!Letme outtahere !
Hey!
- [Bala Continues, Indistinct]
- Gosh, this-this dayjust keeps
getting better and better.
- Imeanbig trouble !
-[Crashing]
Areyoulistening tome out there ?
I´m theprincess !
Damnit!
Wow, your manners
haven´t improved much.
Z !
[ Gasps ]
Whoa ! Whoa !
- [ Gasps ] Ooh !
- It´s you. You came back for me.
Well, yeah, I came back foryou.
I have strong feelings foryou.
Let´s face it, you´re--you´re--
[ Clears Throat ] you´re beautiful. I--
A little combative at times,
but I thinkwe can work on that.
You talk too much.
Gee, I think I´m about to become
the strong, silent type.
Come on. The city´s deserted.
We´d better get outta here.
Z... [ Sighs ]
we can´t go.
Mandible´s insane.
He-- He keeps talking about...
washing away the filth
and-and changing history and--
and I think he´s going to try
to kill my mother.
Notjustyour mother-- everyone.
- What´s going on ?
- Look.
Here we are, safe in the city.
But they´re gonna seal
everybody offin the MegaTunnel.
And... here´s the lake.
You´re right.
We can´t leave now.
Come on.
We gotta get down there.
Today is the realization ofa dream.
A dream ofa proud colony.
A pure colony.
A colony reborn.
[ Ants Cheering ]
Moments from now
this tunnel will open.
The past will be washed away
and a new daywill dawn.
[Cheering Continues]
A stirring speech, General.
I onlywish my daughter
were here to appreciate it.
Your Majesty, I know
how concerned you are about Bala.
But my scouts are on her trail
and it´s only a matter oftime--
General, I don´t want to discuss it.
Just find her.
I will, Your Highness.
Good-bye.
[Soldiers Chattering, Indistinct]
[ Ants Chattering, Indistinct ]
Sealup the doors.
- Cutter, did you hear me ?
- Sir, I´ve been thinking.
Do we need to go through with this ?
Look at what these workers have done.
They got the right stuff.
Isn´t there any otherway ?
Cutter, you´re a fine officer.
You have discipline, courage, ability.
Butyou seem to have a weakness for
the lower orders that I find disturbing.
- Now, areyou with me ?
- Sir, uh... I apologize.
- All right, then. Seal it up.
- Yes, sir.
[ All Grunting ]
[Queen]As Ilook out
on thismagnificent tunnel,
I am filled with pride.
- [ Z ] Jump !
- In these difficult times,
it is a great solace to know
thatyou, ourworkers--
-[Queen Continues, Indistinct]
- Mom ! Wait !
Everyworker in the colony is here.
Wait a minute. That guy owes me money.
This tremendous accomplishment
is a testimony to the strength--
-[Foreman]Putyourbacks intoit!
- Go warn your mother.
- I gotta get to those diggers
before they break through.
- There´s not enough time.
Hey, leave the pessimism to me, okay ?
-[Queen Continues, Indistinct]
- Ow ! Ooh ! Yeeow !
Excuse me ! Sorry about that.
Excuse me.
In a few moments when our expert diggers
break through to the surface,
- Mom ! Mom, stop.
- the sun will pour into this--
Bala ! Where´veyou been ?
Areyou all right ?
- I´m fine.
- [ Sighs ] What happened ?
Mother,
we´re in terrible danger.
[ Panting ]
[ Sighs ]
Putyour backs into it, people.
Wait ! Hold--
Hey, stop digging !
- Z ? Is thatyou ?
- Wemuststop !
- Z ! You´re back !
- [ Crunching ]
- Oh, Z ! Oh.
- [ Gasping ] Weaver !
Z ! What´s the matter ?
Ho-Hold up, everyone.
Stop. Stop digging.
- On whose authority ?
- On your own authority.
Ifyou break through that wall,
we´re all gonna--
Drown.
This tunnel is going to flood.
So we´ve got to get
everyone out ofhere.
[ All Murmuring ]
Look, I got orders,
and those orders say ''dig.''
What ifsomeone ordered you
tojump offa bridge ?
Oh, brother, I´m asking the wrong guy.
Look, think foryourselves !
Gimme that !
I´ve had enough out ofyou.
Get back to work.
What´s that noise ?
Uh-oh.
- [ Weaver] Let´s get outta here !
- Run!
[ All Screaming ]
[ Weaver]
Run ! Keep going !
Everyone, listen to me.
We´ve all been deceived.
We need to calmly
head toward the exits.
- Run foryour lives! It´s gonna flood!
- No. Don´t panic.
- Don´t panic !
- Every ant for himself!
[ Gasps ]
[ All Screaming ]
- All the exits are blocked !
- We´re trapped !
- What are we going to do ?
- There´s nothing we can do !
Yes, there is.
Weaver, give me a leg up.
Everyone, listen to me !
- Who the heck areyou ?
- He´s Z !
[ All Murmuring ]
Listen, we gotta help each other
get outta here before we all drown.
-[Man]How?
- By making a ladder.
A ladder !
Hey, ifwe built this,
we can do anything.
- Okay, let´s move it !
- I´m on it. All ofyou, gather round.
You, start climbing.
- Grab my arm.
- All right. Here I go.
- Come on.
- Go, go, go !
- Right !
- Excuse me, Your Majesty.
- [ Grunting ]
Z, I´ve gotta help my Mom.
Don´t worry. I know almost
exactlywhat I´m doing.
I´ll seeyou at the top.
Gentlemen, there comes a time...
in the evolution
ofa perfect colony...
when the strong are meant
to rise above the weak.
Nowis that time.
Belowus rightnow,
the weak elements
ofthe colony...
arebeing washedaway.
- [ Straining ]
- Oh, my God, we´re not gonna make it !
- We need more ants.
- You two better get up there.
Weaver, you can´t hold it alone.
Get going.
Hang in there, buddy.
[ Kissing Sound ]
- Got it !
- Hurry up ! Go, go, go, go !
[ Gasps ]
Our princess is secured,
and our glorious future is at hand.
We canallstandproud.
Itis time foranewbeginning.
- [ Soldiers Gasp ]
- What the hell is that ?
I think that´s
the weak element, sir.
- Gimme-- Gimme a hand !
- Z ! You ?
Let go ! Don´tyou understand ?
It´s for the good ofthe colony.
Wha-What areyou saying ?
We are the colony !
[ Soldiers Gasping ]
Cutter... what areyou doing ?
Something I should´ve done
a long time ago.
This is for the good
ofthe colony, sir.
You useless, ungrateful maggot !
- I am the colony !
- [ Gasps ] Look out !
Oof! Aa-aah !
Aa-aa-aah !
Z !
Men, let´s move it !
Get these ants up here.
- [ Azteca ] Keep it moving.
- Thank goodness we made it.
Wait here.
- Uhh ! Okay.
- Thankyou.
Weaver.
Where´s Z ?
-Oh, no.
-[ Weaver] Back up, everybody, back up!
- Give him some air. Back up.
- Z, oh, Z.
Please wake up.
Oh, no !
[ Sobs ]
Huh !
[ Coughing ]
[ All Cheering ]
Yowch !
You know, Weaver,
you still owe me that dinner.
- [ Kissing Sound ]
- Babylove.
- We made it, Z !
- You da ant !
- Eh !
- You did it.
We did it.
- Oh !
- Fellas ! Fellas, please !
- This is very embarrassing for me, I--
- [ Laughing ]
On the other hand,
I probably could get used to this.
[ZNarrating] Thereyouhaveit.
Youraverage ''boymeets girl,
boylikes girl, boy changes
underlyingsocialorder´´story.
So, whatelse can I tellyou ?
We rebuilt the colony.
It´s evenbetterthanbefore.
Youknow, ´causenowithas
a verylargeindoorswimmingpool.
BalaandI, incidentally,
are thinkingofstartinga family,
youknow,justa fewkids--
maybeamillion ortwo tobegin with.
AndI´m workin´ withanewtherapist,
youknow, terrific, absolutelyterrific.
He´sbeenputtingme
in touch with myinnermaggot,
which ishelpingmeagreatdeal.
And, youknow, Ifinally
feellike I´ve foundmyplace.
Andyouknow what ?
It´s rightback where Istarted.
But the differenceis,
this time Ichoseit.
Just whatmakes
thatlittle oldant
Thinkhe´llmove
thatrubber-treeplant
Anyoneknowsanantcan´t
movearubber-treeplant
Buthe´sgothighhopes
He´sgothighhopes
He´sgothigh applepie
in theskyhopes
Soanytimeyou´regettin´low
´Steadoflettin´go
justrememberthatant
Oops, theregoesanother
rubber-treeplant
Once there wasasillyoldram
Thoughthe´dpunchahole ina dam
No one couldmake thatramscram
Hekeptbuttin´thatdam
´Causehehadhighhopes
Hehadhighhopes
Hehadhigh applepie
in theskyhopes
Soanytimeyou´re feelin´bad
´steadoffeelin´sad
Justrememberthatram
Oops, theregoes
abillion-kilowattdam
Sokeepyourhighhopes
Keepyourhighhopes
Keep thosehigh applepie
in theskyhopes
Aproblem´sjusta toyballoon
They´llbeburstingsoon
They´rejustboundtogopop
Oops, theregoesanotherproblem
Ker-plop