AMY: I'm Amy Mitchell,
and I'm a mom.
I had my first kid
when I was 20 years old,
and I've been running late ever since.
My days are filled with
dropping the kids at school...
Love you.
...then racing to work
where I have meeting,
after meeting, after meeting.
I usually end up eating
a shitty lunch at my desk,
and I try to work out once a week.
(SIGHS)
Why do I suck at Zumba?
Most days,
I race back to school
for the kids' plays,
and poetry readings and class projects...
Mom!
...which I'm always late for.
(MOUTHING) Sorry.
And then there's PTA meetings,
and volunteering
and parent-teacher
conferences.
Jesus, Miss Wiggins fuckin' hates me.
At least once a day,
I feel like the worst mom
in the world,
and I cry in my car.
(WAILING)
Then I shuttle the kids
to piano lessons
and soccer games
and dance classes
and doctors' appointments,
before my daily trip
to the grocery store.
Ugh.
This chick seems like
she's got it all figured out.
But I feel like
I'm screwing up
all the time.
Still, I love being a mom.
Here, baby.
There's your organic
turkey club sandwich,
and Dylan,
here's your peanut-free
peanut butter for lunch.
What's peanut-free
peanut butter?
I have no idea.
Baby, here's your
American history project
I made you.
I hope you like it.
I love you.
I love you!
Oh, my God, Mom!
Not so loud! My God.
I love my babies so much!
God, they hate me.
Hey, Amy!
Hey, guys.
God, I just don't know how you do it.
You just leave your kids all day
and go to work?
You're so strong.
Yeah, thank you.
Don't you miss them?
I do. But I also
need, like, money.
Right.
STACY: Hmm.
Oh, gosh, you guys,
I'm so sorry.
I gotta go.
I'm really late to work.
Well, you're always late.
I know. It's basically
the only thing
I'm good at these days.
See you guys later.
God, I just love how hard she works.
Oh, my God, I love how hard she works.
I just fuckin' said that, Vicky.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
AMY: I work at
a super-hip coffee company.
I love my job,
but I'm 32 years old and
I'm the oldest person here
by far.
Most of these dudes
just play ping-pong all day.
TESSA: Morning, Momma.
AMY: Morning, Tessa.
Oh, my God,
I am so fucking hungover,
I might actually die.
(CHUCKLES)
That's probably something
you shouldn't tell your boss.
Oh.
Right. Except that I took
like a shitload of
pills this morning,
so I don't totally know where I am yet.
You're at work, Tess.
Oh, perfect.
Yeah.
May I have a vacation?
I'd like to go to Cuba.
Is that allowed?
No.
Good morning.
TESSA: Hey, boss!
Good morning, Dale.
I had a dream last night.
Ooh.
I was naked in a hotel.
I'm talking fully naked, dick, balls...
Yep, got it.
No glasses. Everything,
fully fucking naked.
We got it.
I walk over to the coffee maker
and there is
a bag of our coffee
in the hotel room.
Cool dream, Dale.
Thank you, Tessa.
(CHUCKLES)
Um...
Is this your way of saying that
you wanna start selling
your coffee to
hotels, now?
No. This is my way
of saying that
I want you
to start selling
our coffee to
hotels now.
But Dale, I'm already
running sales
for supermarkets,
airlines and restaurants.
I mean,
I'm just part-time.
You are?
Since when?
Six years ago!
(LAUGHS) What?
No way.
She's here like
every day.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, I know, but I have
a family and stuff, so...
Hey! You know
how important
family is to me.
I got it wrote on my arm right there.
AMY: Oh, wow.
It's dope, right?
So tight.
Oh, shit!
I gotta go roller skating.
Do you wanna come?
Yes!
No, Dale!
I have lots of work to do.
The History Channel was right.
You guys are the greatest generation.
AMY: I live just outside
of Chicago with my two kids,
my dog and my husband, Mike.
He's a successful mortgage broker,
but sometimes he
feels like my third child.
Hey, babe.
Hey... Oh! (CHUCKLES)
Look at all
the bags you're carrying.
That's hilarious.
You look like a Sherpa.
AMY: Oh!
You guys. Thank you
for being super patient.
I appreciate it.
(GROANS)
Here we go, guys.
Thanks, honey.
All right, love.
How was work?
Oh, I had two
conference calls and then
I took a nap.
It was exhausting.
I bet. I bet.
Uh...
Dylan, baby, how was your science quiz?
Oh, I got a D.
A D? But we
worked so hard.
Baby, what happened?
Do you need extra help?
Should we get
you another tutor?
Mmm, nah, I'm good.
Mike?
Did you hear?
Dylan got a D
on his science quiz.
Way to go, bud.
What? Okay.
Um...
Jane! Oh, my gosh! Wait!
How was your
soccer tryouts?
(SIGHS) Coach is posting
a list of who made
the team tonight at 9:00,
and I'm so nervous.
Baby, it's okay, relax.
You will make
the soccer team, I promise.
Just don't freak out.
(GASPS)
I'm freakin' out.
I am, too.
What time is it now?
8:59.
(SIGHS) Come on!
(COMPUTER DINGS)
Oh, it's 9:00! It's 9:00.
Go, go, go! Hit refresh.
Oh, my God. I made the team.
(SQUEALS) I made the team!
Oh, my God.
I am so relieved.
(WHISPERS)
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
(GASPS) Baby, I'm so proud of you!
Oh, I'm so excited.
Oh, my God.
This is gonna look
so awesome on
my college applications.
Baby, it's great, it's great,
but just remember
you're only 12,
so it's...
Wait.
What if I don't play?
What if I'm a loser benchwarmer scrub?
You're great,
you're gonna be fine,
you're...
No! It's not fine, Mom.
Do you understand how hard it is
to get into an Ivy League school now?
I mean, they turn away Asians.
That's a little racist, but...
Oh, my God! I need to
practice my footwork.
Why'd you let me eat dessert?
Oh, I know, because you hate me!
Holy shit.
Hey, babe. It's late.
I'm going to bed.
No.
(GASPS) Oh, my God, are you...
No, no, no, I was just
checking my prostate.
(KEYS CLACKING)
You know,
I've always wondered
what kind of porn you like.
Why won't this fucking window close?
(GASPS)
Oh, my God, that's a giant bush!
Uh, who the hell are you?
I'm his wife.
Oh, shit.
Are you masturbating
online with
some chick?
No, no!
Well, then, what are you doing?
(STAMMERING) Uh, um...
I was clicking
and then I...
So then I was...
Yes, okay,
I was masturbating
online with some chick.
What the fuck!
Why are you doing that?
Hold on a second.
I don't think I've
done anything wrong.
This is totally mainstream now.
Hi, I'm Sharon.
I don't know, I don't know, Mike.
This really feels like cheating.
No, no, no, no, no,
this is definitely
not cheating, honey.
I've never even touched her.
Her giant bush is 2,000 miles away.
But how long have you been doing this?
Oh, I don't know.
Not long.
Ten months next Friday.
(MOUTHING)
What the fuck?
Ten months?
Do you have feelings for her?
(EXHALES)
You don't masturbate
online with someone
for 10 months
without developing some feelings.
I mean, I'm not a monster.
Do you have feelings for her, Mike?
Yes! Okay?
I have feelings
for her! God!
(MIKE SIGHS)
She's actually a pretty amazing woman.
You know, she runs her own dairy farm,
she's developing an app.
Get out!
What?
Get the fuck out of my house.
So uncool.
(DOOR CLOSES)
SHARON: You know, Amy,
I just feel like
Mike is feeling
really trapped right now...
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
Okay, so your dad
had to go outta town
on a business trip,
so I'm gonna try to do
everything myself today,
which should be fine,
as long as everybody does
what they are
supposed to do.
Right?
(WHINING)
Oh, no.
Why is Roscoe walking like that?
He's fine.
He's totally fine.
(GASPS) Oh, no, buddy!
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(CAR DOOR SHUTS)
Lookin' good, Jeff.
Oh.
Thanks.
Yeah, you been
workin' out?
No, not for like 10 years.
Your beige windbreaker
is really lightin'
up my board.
Oh, uh, thanks.
Do you know what I mean?
My vagina.
(SIGHS)
Bye, Jeff!
Emergency PTA
meeting tonight.
Tell all your friends.
STACY: (GASPS)
Oh, God.
There goes that little weird
stay-at-home mom.
Emergency PTA
meeting tonight.
Tell all your friends.
Oh, I don't have any friends.
Oh.
I'm pretty isolated
at home.
I have four kids.
Okay, good.
Please move along.
Thank you.
Emergency PTA meeting tonight.
Thank you for inviting me.
Oh, my God.
She just got all her
sadness all over me.
Oh, shit!
Here comes the hot widower.
Hey, Jessie.
Hey, guys.
VICKY: Hi.
GWENDOLYN: Hi.
Cute backpack you got there.
Oh, yeah.
Uh, I'm such an Elsa.
(ALL LAUGHING)
You're hilarious!
You really are!
God, he's so fucking hot.
Here you go.
VICKY: I know.
I'm so glad his wife died.
You know what? I saw
him install a car seat
yesterday in two seconds.
I'm tellin' you, it was
like boom, boom, click.
(MOANING)
It was so hot.
Oh, gosh.
You know what?
I think I'd let him
put it in my butt.
I mean, in theory,
I'm not really
into the butt thing,
but I would let him
go to town back there.
I'm with you.
Emergency PTA meeting.
AMY: Okay, I got
four minutes to get
Roscoe to the vet,
so I love you kids, get out,
get out, get out, get out.
I love you so much.
I'm so sorry.
Bye, Mom.
(GASPS)
Oh!
Oh, my God! Oh!
Fuck, it's so hot!
Can you roll down...
Can you roll down
the window?
Okay. Okay, okay.
Hey. Hey,
babe, listen.
Hi.
There is a emergency
PTA meeting today
at 5:00.
It should be about two to three hours.
Awesome. Awesome.
Okay?
Your dog's
wearing a helmet.
Okay, I know.
Yes, it's... Thank you.
Okay.
Fuck!
Your dog has vertigo.
That can't be a thing.
And you are gonna
have to carry him
until he gets home.
Are you shitting me right now?
I don't shit.
But he will, uncontrollably,
for the next 36 hours.
(WHINING)
I'm here.
I'm here. Amy's here.
You missed the meeting, bro.
Oh, no.
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck.
(INDISTINCT)
(PANTING)
(GASPS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
I know, I know.
I'm sorry, I'm late.
Get in, get in, get in.
I can't believe
I'm gonna be late
to my first soccer practice.
Baby, I'm doing the best that I can.
Yeah, that's what makes it even sadder.
Oh, God.
Hey, Dylan.
Hey, honey.
How was your day?
I swallowed a pen cap again.
Oh, God.
DYLAN: Ooh!
Crap.
Was that a hit-and-run?
Nope.
That was nothing.
Jane, go!
Go, go, go, go!
Excuse me, Coach?
I'm so sorry that
Jane is late.
It is all my fault.
You look wrecked.
You having a bad day?
Oh, God, it literally
could not get any...
Ah! (GRUNTS)
Shit.
(GROANS)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Hey...
Hi, guys! Guys, um...
For those of you who have
been living under a rock...
(CHUCKLES)
I am Gwendolyn James.
I am the president of the PTA,
but most importantly,
I am the proud mommy
to two beautiful daughters,
Blaire and Gandhi.
Now, I called this emergency PTA meeting
to address an issue
that radically affects
the safety of our children.
The bake sale.
Is this a joke?
Now, this is a list
of the toxic ingredients
that are absolutely banned
from the bake sale.
No BPA, no MSG, no BHA, no BHT.
Plus no soy, no sesame,
and, of course, no nuts
or eggs or milk or butter
or salt or sugar or wheat.
Okay?
Sorry, what ingredients can we use?
Anyway,
I will be putting together...
Thank you.
...a special bake
sale police force
that will monitor the food.
That will destroy
any offensive treats
and prosecute the wrongdoers.
Yes.
So who will be my first volunteer
for the bake sale police force?
I think we're gonna have Amy Mitchell!
What?
That's what you get
for being late, sweetie.
No.
(ALL GASP)
(CHUCKLES)
What's that now?
I've had a really long day.
I have been bruised and burned,
knocked unconscious.
I screwed up my daughter's
first day at soccer
and I hand-searched
my son's poo for a pen cap
and my poor dog has vertigo.
I mean, who knew that
that was even
a real thing, you guys?
God, I'm drowning at work
and my boss is a fucking moron
and... (CHUCKLES)
Three hours ago I may or may not
have committed
a felony hit-and-run.
(GASPING)
I can't do this anymore.
I'm sorry.
I'm done.
I quit.
(INDISTINCT MURMURS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, what can
I get ya?
Oh, Scotch.
Oh, hey, I know you.
You're that chick
that always picks up
my kid from school
when I forget/don't want to.
Amy Mitchell.
Yeah, Carla.
Carla Dunkler.
Jesus, you look like a bag of dicks.
(CHUCKLES) Thanks.
Hi.
I'm really sorry
to interrupt, but, um,
I just have to tell you,
what you did back there was amazing.
(CHUCKLES) Thank you.
It's Kiki, right?
Yes.
She knows my name.
(STUTTERS)
I feel like Beyoncé Knowles.
Why don't you sit down
and have a drink with us?
What do you mean "us"?
Honey, I was just
sitting here by myself.
I would love to, but I can't.
I have to go to the grocery store
and then I have to go home
and clean out my
son's hamster cage,
'cause he gets so mad when I forget.
Have a drink, Kiki.
Okay, yeah.
Okay.
Yes, I'd like
an apple juice.
Why don't you have this instead?
Excuse me?
(LAUGHING)
Oh, do you know
what my favorite
mom fantasy is?
What?
Uh-oh.
Having a quiet breakfast by myself.
Oh! That is so hot!
Oh!
Sounds glorious.
Oh.
(SIGHS) Sometimes
when I'm driving
all by myself,
I have this fantasy
that I get into
a car crash.
Not a big one with
fire and explosions,
but just like a little one.
But I do get injured
and I get to go
to the hospital
for two weeks
and I sleep all day
and I eat Jell-O
and I watch so much TV
and it's all covered by my insurance.
My kids bring me balloons,
and the nurses rub
cream on my feet,
and oh, my God, it's so amazing.
(SIGHS)
Is that like
something you guys
fantasize about, too?
No.
You're bat-shit
crazy.
Yeah.
And I'm never
gonna get into
a car with you.
Is it fun being a single mom?
Yes!
I go to the casino.
Yeah.
You know, I'm learning karate now.
Plus, I have, like,
a stable of hot
dudes to call right up
whenever I want some D in my V.
I wanna be a single mom.
No, it's fuckin'
awesome.
Bottom line is,
I have to live
my life one quarter
mile at a time.
Is that from... Yeah.
The Fast and Furious.
I fucked Vin Diesel
when he was in
town doing Furious 6.
You fucked Vin Diesel?
Yeah.
Vincent Diesel?
It might not have
been actually
Vin Diesel,
but I definitely fucked a bald guy.
Salud.
Yep.
To Vincent Diesel.
Oh, my God.
Jesus.
Kiki, get your
shit together.
Oh, my God.
Do you know what I hate?
Mmm?
There are so many fuckin' rules now.
Yes, God.
"Don't punish your kids."
"Don't say no to your kids."
Yeah. "Go to your
kid's baseball games."
"Tell your kids
you love 'em."
"Don't fuck the janitor
at your kid's school."
I mean, what the
fuck is this? Russia?
We're killing ourselves,
trying to be perfect,
and it's making us insane.
In this day and age,
it's impossible
to be a good mom.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
Screw it.
Yeah.
Let's be bad moms.
Oh, I'm in.
Right?
Oh, my gosh, okay.
This is exciting.
I'm in!
Yes! To bad moms.
Whoo!
To bad moms!
Aw.
I love you guys.
Mmm.
Oh, dude.
We love you, Kiki.
We just met, Kiki.
Forever.
I love you forever.
I'm not into
this kind of...
Oh, gosh, honey,
we gotta go get
you home.
We gotta go.
Yeah, let's go.
No, I can't. I have to
go to the supermarket.
(KIKI SIGHS)
Let's go to the supermarket!
(INAUDIBLE)
(ALL GASPING)
Oh, my God.
You're so cute.
KIKI: Adorable.
Oh, I wanna eat her face.
Hi, bunny.
All right, let's go!
Where is she?
(GROANING)
Oh, it's so bright, you guys.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm awesome.
What did you do last night?
Nothin'.
But we may need to
find a new supermarket.
(AMY GASPS)
Oh, my God.
I made nachos
last night!
Oh.
Amazing.
Mmm.
The cheese is so hard.
(GRUNTING)
Um...
Aren't you gonna make us breakfast?
Oh.
No.
But what are we gonna eat?
You guys are really smart.
You can make your own breakfast.
I'm just gonna take these to go.
Peace!
All right, get in the car.
You know what?
On second thought,
let's take your
daddy's special car today.
Won't Dad be mad?
Yeah.
Probably.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(INAUDIBLE)
Whoo!
That was so awesome!
All right.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
What is she driving?
Have a great day at school!
Oh, wait, wait, wait!
Your lunch!
(GASPS) Thanks, Mom.
You're the best mom ever!
Aw, I love you, guys!
Is that Arby's?
I love their hot fish sandwich.
Hey, Amy. Hi.
Hey, we're having a PTA meeting today
to discuss the
upcoming election
at 2:00.
Will we see you there?
No.
Oh.
That bitch is playing a dangerous game.
Amy plays football?
Oh, my God.
Oh, thank you.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Amazing!
Oh, this is Amy.
Amy, where are you?
The morning huddle
started an hour ago.
Oh, yeah,
Dale, I'm not going to that.
It's a total waste of time.
(SNICKERING)
Are you feeling okay, Amy?
Are you having a senior moment?
I've actually never felt better.
I'm having a quiet breakfast
and reading the newspaper
for the first time in 12 years.
You need to come into
the office right now!
No, I don't. I don't, Dale.
I only work for you
three days a week.
If you want me to work more,
then you should
pay me to do that.
Okay, Amy, you're
kind of making
me look like a dick
in front of everybody
in the office right now.
Have a great meeting!
Goodbye, Dale.
(SIGHS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Hey, Kiki. It's Amy.
Hi!
Um, I was actually calling to see,
uh, if you'd like to join
me at the movies today.
Are we allowed to do that?
Well, I don't see why not.
I can't.
I mean, I have to
iron Kent's underwear.
What? Why?
I don't know. He likes
really stiff underwear.
Come on, Kiki, live a little.
(CRYING)
Uh... Okay. Okay, okay.
I'll do it.
(CHUCKLES) Awesome.
Okay, I'll call Carla.
Oh, fun! I like her.
I'm also very scared of her.
(CHUCKLES) Okay.
Ow! Ow!
CARLA: Yo!
Hey, it's Amy.
Um, I'm calling to see
if you'd like to join
Kiki and I at the movies this afternoon.
I'm already here.
Hey, lady.
Get off your phone.
Guess what?
She dies in the end.
Yeah, cancer gets her.
What?
Yeah, what do you bitches wanna see?
(SLURPING)
Love is stronger
than space.
You guys, lady boners over here.
(LAUGHS)
(GASPING AND CHEERING)
Cheers, ladies.
Mmm.
This has been so much fun.
Thank you, girls, for coming out with me.
Are you kidding me?
This has literally been
the best day of
my entire life.
Oh, honey.
My ex is picking
up the kid, so I can
go all night if...
Oh, hey, did you hear that?
My ex has my kid.
AMY: Hey, hon, I've got
a question for you.
Is it hard to share
your son with
your ex-husband?
(LAUGHS) Fuck no.
No?
Have you seen my kid?
He's like nine feet tall
and all he cares about is baseball.
Do you go to all of his games?
No. No, I don't.
(AMY LAUGHS)
The last game
I went to was
six hours long
and the final score was one to two.
So, I'd rather go to
Afghanistan than another
kids' baseball game.
Cheers.
How do you think
that your divorce
affected your kid?
How are things in your home, Amy?
Oh, it's fine.
(SCOFFS) Everything's fine.
Ugh.
I caught Mike
having an affair online
with a woman,
and I guess
it's been going on
for like 10 months.
Oh! Did you drive
a spike through his nuts?
(LAUGHING)
No. Here's the truth.
Our marriage has been over for years.
I don't even remember
the last time we had sex.
Kent and I have sex
every Friday night
after Blue Bloods.
(LAUGHS)
I find Tom Selleck's work
to be extremely erotic.
I feel like everything that
comes out of your
mouth is a cry for help.
(CHUCKLES)
Kiki, you're so weird.
CARLA: No, wait,
why did you
marry this shithead
in the first place?
He sounds like an asshole.
Because we were young and in love.
I mean, he wasn't
always an asshole.
I promise you.
It's true.
Listen, I got pregnant,
we got married.
I was only 20.
You know what?
Mike and I never
got our twenties.
Like, you know, the fun twenties, and...
I feel like maybe he missed that.
Oh, my God.
Maybe I did, too.
When I was in my
twenties, I would just
walk down the street
and it would just
be raining dicks
wherever I went.
It was just dick, dick, dick, dick,
dick, dick, dick, dick, dick, dick.
It was, like, forecast, lot of cock!
(INDISTINCT)
Kiki?
Hi. Kent, hi.
What are you doing here?
I'm just having lunch
with my new friends.
Who's watching the kids?
Rosie.
Isn't that your job?
Whoa! Who the fuck
are you?
Yes. Yes, Kent.
It absolutely is my job,
and I was just
about to leave, so,
um, thank you guys so much.
I can't, uh, do the math right now.
Just take that
and have a wonderful
day, you guys.
I really enjoyed it.
Thank you.
Oh, my...
Nice to meet you, Ike Turner!
That's really disturbing.
Yes!
But on the plus side,
she left way too much cash,
so I think I'm gonna get fucked up!
(GROANS)
Yeah, donut holes!
I love these things.
How much are they?
Um...
Five cents.
How about a dollar?
(GASPS) What?
Hey now, big spender.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Thank you.
Mmm.
Why are these so good?
Caramel number six.
Is that what it is?
Mmm-hmm.
They're tasty.
She's adorable.
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Good to see you.
Bye. Bye.
Oh, my, oh, my, oh, my.
What do we have here?
Are these store-bought
donut holes, Amy?
What? No.
Gosh, no, I made them by hand
and then I put them
in the weird
plastic container.
Oh, thank God.
'Cause we do not
allow store-bought
holes.
Seriously, Vicky?
AMY: Oh,
come on, Gwendolyn.
Who cares what food people bring
as long as it raises money, right?
Oh, did she just...
Oh.
She did.
Hit her with it, G.
Well, you see, I care, sweetie.
I don't... I don't know
what's been going on
with you,
I mean, with your weird outbursts
and your terrible style,
but it ends now.
Okay? I run this school,
and no one takes a class or kicks a ball
or plays a fuckin'
clarinet without
my say-so.
And I can make life a living hell for you
and your dirty little children.
Do you understand me?
Wow, Gwendolyn,
I genuinely think you should
just relax a little bit,
I mean, have a donut hole.
They're delicious.
They're from a gas station.
They're... Mmm.
You have crossed the line, little girl.
And I am going to destroy you.
Winter is coming.
(CHUCKLES)
Gwendolyn.
Oh, my God.
You are so fucked.
What...
Bye.
Out of my way!
I'm sorry, Gwendolyn.
You psyched for Mandarin class?
No!
No.
Mandarin class is so stressful.
Everyone just barfs the whole time.
Did you say "barfs"?
Yeah.
Oh, my God.
Wha...
Why are we doing this?
What are you doing?
Mandarin class
is back that way!
I know.
But we're gonna play hooky today.
JANE: We cannot
afford this place.
AMY: Don't worry.
I've got a plan.
Shh. Get in here,
you idiots.
We totally snuck in.
I know! Shh.
I can't believe
you have a real job.
You're a lucky girl, Becky.
I would never do
this for my kid.
Yeah. My mom's
pretty cool.
Also, my name's Jane.
Okay.
All right. Showers on
the left. Have fun, guys.
Bye, Becky! Shh.
Okay, thanks, Carla.
This place is fancy.
Gosh.
Oh, look.
Free soap.
No, honey, don't take that.
(GASPS) Oh, no,
that's some good soap.
Take it, take it.
This is what the tub
looks like after your
brother takes a bath.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
You look like
Kung Fu Panda.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
This is amazing.
Mmm-hmm.
We should get
matching tattoos
after this.
(LAUGHS)
I'm really glad we did this, Mom.
I haven't felt this
relaxed in, like, ever.
God, you needed
a break from school
and soccer and...
(GRUNTS)
This whole Dad thing.
What whole Dad thing?
Nothing. Nothing!
(GASPS) Does Dad have a brain tumor?
What? No!
No, no, no, no.
God, no. Um...
Your dad and I
are going through
a rough patch right now.
Are you guys gonna get divorced?
What? No, no, no.
No. We're not getting
divorced right away.
I just want you to know
that no matter
what happens,
it's not your fault.
Why would it be my fault?
Why would you even say that?
I don't know!
Oh, my God, baby,
I'm so sorry!
I suck at this!
I just don't wanna be weird, okay?
Baby, please don't cry.
Please...
No, no, no, no, no.
Honey, I need you
to look at me,
just look at me, okay?
Baby, baby...
I need you to know
that your dad loves you.
That I love you.
And I promise you, you will be fine.
(SOBS)
How do you know?
Because I'm your mom,
and I know you better than anyone,
and I know what you're made of.
Oh, honey.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Hey, Coach?
Coach!
Fuck!
Hi, Gwendolyn.
Hi, how are you?
Listen, um, I wanna talk to you about
the starting lineup
of next week's game.
Mmm-hmm.
In particular,
Amy Mitchell's
daughter, Jane.
You know I can't discuss
specific players with you.
And you know that I chair the hiring
and firing committee, right?
So let's stop dicking
around and let's
get to the fucking point.
Please don't get me fired, Gwendolyn.
My cat just died.
Oh.
And I'm really very fragile right now.
Bench the little dork.
Yeah, she's fuckin' gone.
I need this. This is my time.
Do you know what I mean?
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
(SNAPS FINGERS)
(EXHALES)
Go for Carla.
Hey, it's Amy,
I just found out
Mike is staying with
his Internet girlfriend.
Oh, fuck him!
We need to get you laid.
I wanna get laid.
I'm on my way.
I'm so excited.
CARLA: Honey,
I don't know,
what are you gonna wear?
It's like a nun's closet.
(GASPS) No, no, wait.
I got it, I got it.
Let's see this!
It's my favorite.
I love it.
No! No! Are you
trying to get laid
or adopted?
Oh.
Fair point.
Ooh.
Okay.
That's what a lonely
person gets buried in.
Fuck, you guys,
I literally have
nothing, then.
I have mom clothes, I have work clothes.
Okay, you know,
let me get in there
one more time.
I'm gonna find it.
Move. Move. Move, move,
get me in here.
I have jackets,
I have lots of 'em.
We'll find it.
We'll find
something, honey.
Don't get discouraged.
AMY: Okay. Okay.
You can do this.
I mean, Jesus Christ!
This is something that
Mrs. Doubtfire would wear.
I love that movie.
(GASPS)
Me too.
Okay.
KIKI:
It's such a good film.
Wait a minute, I see a spaghetti strap.
No, hold on. This was,
like, my slutty Halloween
costume from college.
I like the word "slutty."
Put it on.
Just try it.
Try it.
You guys are ridiculous.
I'm telling you...
Holy fuck!
Look at your mom bra!
Ooh.
There's so much surface area.
You can make
three regular bras
out of this one mom bra.
This isn't my mom bra.
This is my sexy bra.
(LAUGHS) Shut up!
Don't laugh.
Wait, are you serious?
Yes!
Oh, honey.
Amy.
Oh!
That looks like you
just got out of surgery.
Is it that bad?
Yeah, there's just
one boob-log.
Yeah.
You don't even have two tits.
I have this in black.
Do you guys wanna
see it in black?
No!
Oh, wow.
This bra will be
the death of your vagina.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh!
AMY: Oh, my gosh.
You guys, I've only handled
one penis my entire life.
Oh, honey!
What do I do if I get
a guy with a weird dick?
Kent is a never-hard.
Ooh.
What's a never-hard?
Oh, he never gets fully hard.
So I just have to
kind of fold his penis up
like a balloon animal
and shove it up in my vagina.
That sounds horrible!
AMY: Yeah.
Sometimes I take the
balls and shove 'em
up there, too,
because at least, you know, they're firm.
Honey, that is
a lot of shit to
shove up your cooter.
I mean, I'm just happy he's circumcised.
(GASPS) What if I get
somebody who's
not circumcised?
Run out of the room screaming.
It's like finding a gun in the street.
Just scream and get outta there!
No way, you guys.
Uncut guys are great.
Really?
Oh, they're always so nice to you,
because they know their dicks are gross.
How do I handle it?
What, do I
just touch it?
Oh, I'll show you. Here.
Let me just,
Kiki, do you mind for a sec?
Uh-uh. What?
Just imagine for a second
that this is the hood
of the uncut cock
and then this is
the penis face. Okay?
Mmm-hmm.
So, what you would do is very gently,
you would just kind
of try to peel it back
over like that to
expose the head
of the cock.
Okay.
And then you
would just gently,
you wanna, I'm sorry,
honey, you just
wanna kind of,
like it gets a little tight,
and you gotta kind of work it,
you know, you gotta work it off.
And then you just
go to town like
it's a, you know...
(GRUNTS) You know, you jerk it off
till you wanna sit on it.
Okay?
What do I
do with this?
What?
Like, do I put it in
a hair clip or do I just...
No, no, no, no, no, no.
No, no, no, this,
this you can flick it, suck it,
you know, rub your face on it.
I don't wanna do that.
I don't wanna
rub my face on it.
Okay, well, take care
of this, though.
Okay.
'Cause this is
like a big,
giant man clit.
This, right here.
If you work this, it's gonna be like...
(GRUNTS)
(MIMICS EXPLOSION)
Does that
make sense, honey?
Yeah, it's great.
Okay. Sure, sure, sure.
Thank you, honey.
I'm not gonna
wear this sweatshirt
ever again.
CARLA: Okay, okay,
all right. Let's get
right down to it.
What kind of guy are you into, honey?
(GASPS) You know what?
I've never been
with a Latin man.
If I were you, I would start with maybe
like just kind of fat and Jewish,
and then work
yourself into
the Latin guy.
Excuse me.
Okay.
Hi, there.
Hi!
Is this seat taken?
Um, yes.
I mean, yes, no,
like yes, sit, please. Yeah.
What do I do?
Ask him about his hobbies.
Hi.
Um, I'm Amy.
Braden.
Braden, nice to meet you, Braden.
Nice to meet you.
I like your
wedding ring.
Shit!
Um... (CLEARS THROAT)
(STUTTERING) Okay, you see,
this is a funny story.
I was, um...
I was grocery shopping
and I found it on
the floor, and I
picked it up and...
And then I put it on.
I'm gonna
sit somewhere else.
Okay.
Ooh, maybe next time,
try it without
your wedding ring.
Oh, that's
a great idea!
Yeah?
Yes.
Hey, ladies.
Hi!
Where are you
comin' in from?
Uh, we live in Westbury with our kids.
Great. Oh.
Oh, forget it.
I'm really nervous,
you guys.
You're doing great.
I know, I know. There is...
Look it, there is so much cock in here...
Yeah.
...that if you
literally...
Just try to act
half-normal and
you are gonna get laid.
Just don't be
such a mom.
Okay.
You should eat more soup.
Oh, I loved breastfeeding
until my nipples
started cracking.
This should prevent
the stain from setting,
okay?
Tupperware! Pinterest!
Explosive diarrhea!
Does your mom know you're here?
See, it wasn't just
about a dolphin
getting a new tail.
It was about a family coming together.
What did I say?
(LAUGHS)
Hey! Where are you going?
Oh, my God, you guys.
How'd it go?
Oh, horrible.
What's the matter, hon?
What happened?
I suck at this.
I just wanna go home.
Oh!
I really do.
Amy!
Mmm.
Jessie!
What are you guys
doing here?
We're just, you know,
having a little
girls' night.
Cool, so the husband's
at home with the kids?
That's nice.
Oh, mmm...
My husband's not really
in the picture anymore.
Yeah, yeah,
she caught him jerking off
with a dairy farmer.
He's a sex criminal.
(CHUCKLES) I don't know
where to start.
Are you okay?
I'm actually really,
really good. Yeah.
I'm glad I ran into you.
This is really nice.
Yeah, me too.
Me too.
Okay, creepy.
Let's go.
Let's go, creepy.
Yeah.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Okay.
Have fun.
You are so hard.
Really, he's got a hard body.
Thank you. I think.
I cannot believe
Amy is talking to
Jessie Harkness.
I have dreams about him braiding my hair.
Okay, can you not stand so close to me?
Because I'm still trying to get laid.
Yeah, sure.
No problem.
Okay.
And don't dance walk.
You work at the, uh,
coffee company, right?
What? Yeah. Wait,
how did you know?
I might have asked around
about you a little bit.
Wait. You asked
about me?
Yeah.
Yeah, I...
Okay, I've kind of
always had a thing
for you and...
What?
I thought you knew that.
No! I had no idea.
No? You had no idea?
Oh, come on.
You're like my favorite
mom at the school.
I mean, I honestly
don't know
how you do it.
You take your kids
to all those activities,
and you do all those insane projects.
I saw your Richard
Nixon, by the way.
That was incredible.
Well, you know what?
I do have a little
thing for papier-mâché.
It was really good.
Thank you.
Oh, and are you kidding me
with those lunches?
You know, my daughter's always saying,
"Why can't you make lunch
like Dylan's mom?"
Oh, my God, I love your daughter.
You're making me
look bad.
Oh, my God.
Oh, this makes me
so happy. (CHUCKLES)
You know what's just
really amazing, though,
is the fact that your kids
are actually nice people.
Meh, eh...
No, no, I'm serious!
Anyone could force
their kids to play cello
or speak Chinese
or, you know,
go to a fancy college,
or something like that,
but what's really hard is raising kids
who are actually decent and kind
and somehow you've done that.
And you should be really proud.
You're a fuckin' great mom.
(GROANS) Oh, oh...
(CHUCKLING) Oh, my.
I'm so sorry.
It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
And I'm so embarrassed.
You kind of nailed my
face, but we should
probably do it again.
Are you sure?
Just no sudden
movements.
Just nice and slow.
Carla. Carla!
What, hon?
Carla, look, look, look, look!
CARLA: No, Kiki.
No, Kiki!
Kiki, no, no.
(CELL PHONE VIBRATES)
(CHUCKLES)
Mike!
Hey, babe!
What are you doing?
I wanna get back together.
I never should've left you.
That was a total dick move.
And I feel like
we should just
put that in the past
and not talk about it.
Wait, what are you talking about?
Look, I...
I just needed a break.
Haven't you ever needed a break?
Of course I have, Mike.
But I didn't break up
our family to do it.
(SIGHS)
I miss the kids.
So much.
Mostly Dylan, but even
Jane a little bit, too.
And the dog, God, I miss Roscoe so much.
How is he doing?
He's fine.
Thank God.
The bottom line is,
I will do whatever
it takes to keep
this family together.
Really?
You'll finally go to therapy with me?
I knew you were
gonna say that!
Therapy is so dumb!
Great. Get out!
Have fun. Bye-bye.
Hey! I'm trying to
do the right thing!
Bye-bye, Mike.
Honestly!
All right, you know what?
Even though it's a total
waste of time and money,
I will go to therapy.
But when I say go,
I mean, like actually go,
like participate, cry.
I haven't cried
since the Cubbies
lost it all in '03.
How do you expect me...
Mike, you know what?
Have fun with your little
weirdo girlfriend
on the Internet.
But wait, are we gonna
go to therapy or what?
I'll think about it.
Hey.
(CRYING)
Honey? Honey,
are you okay?
Coach says
I'm not starting.
I'm a benchwarmer.
Wait, what?
No, that's impossible.
You're the best forward on that team.
Oh, my God, my life
is ruined. I'm never
going to college.
I might as well just become a teacher.
Baby, baby, look at me for one second.
You'll be okay.
I promise you
I'm gonna handle this.
Okay?
Okay.
Just please don't make a scene.
Honey, I would never embarrass you.
(GRUNTS)
Gwendolyn made me do it!
Oh, my God.
Are you kidding me?
What is it with you moms?
I am a middle school soccer coach.
All I wanna do
is make enough
money to feed my cats
and fill my fuckin' Prius.
Grow some balls! Jesus!
Hey!
How dare you bench my daughter?
Oh, hi, Amy.
You have no right to do that.
Oh, actually, I do,
uh, because soccer
is a PTA-sponsored activity
and I am the president
of the PTA. So...
Oh... Okay.
Uh...
Well, um...
Not for long.
Oh, dear.
What does that mean?
That means
I'm gonna run against you
for PTA president.
Oh. (LAUGHS)
(WHISPERING) Amy's husband
just recently left her,
so she's kind of having
a mental breakdown right now.
Oh, that's so sad.
Ooh.
You're goin' down.
GWENDOLYN: No, honey,
the only thing going down
is your husband
on another woman.
Well, damn.
KIKI: This is
a terrible idea, Amy.
There's no way you can beat her.
Gwendolyn has been
president of the PTA
for the last six years.
Kiki, she messed
with my kid. I can't
let that stand. Come on!
KIKI: Right, but all
the different mom groups
are gonna vote for Gwendolyn.
She's got
the attachment moms,
she's got the tiger moms,
the sad moms.
She has the blogging moms.
She's got the CrossFit moms.
Camel toe moms.
She's got the drunk moms.
The moms that you wanna fuck.
The moms that used to be dads.
She has the moms that
always have a limb broken.
The hairy moms.
The wearable art moms.
The juicing moms.
Mmm-hmm.
She has the moms with the huge areolas.
The black moms,
the lesbian moms,
the divorced moms.
She even has the divorced
black lesbian moms.
That is a really hard group to get.
I love those girls.
Plus, Amy, if you lose,
she'll destroy you.
She'll put your kids
in all the dumb classes
with all the dum-dums.
She'll give 'em the crappy teachers.
You can forget about soccer,
she won't even
give your kids milk.
But that's all the more
reason we have to
bring her down.
I mean, you guys, she's a bully!
Okay, she wants us all
to be these perfect little
Nazi-moms
and our kids
to be hyper-stressed
and over-scheduled.
My daughter gets
a new rash every week,
and she's 12.
You had me at Nazi.
I say we go punch
that chick
right in the tits.
Yes!
Would you like a new
PTA president? Me too!
Hi. Meet the Candidate Night
tomorrow night, 7:30.
Here, honey. Take one.
Vote for Amy. Really?
Amy Mitchell.
PTA president.
Come tomorrow, 7:30,
Meet the Candidate Night.
PTA president.
No! No, thank you!
Take it!
Okay!
Great!
(LAUGHING)
I'll fuck your
husband if you don't go.
I'll fuck him!
Vote for Amy!
Carla, get her!
Hey! Hey!
Don't you fuckin'
run from me!
Don't you fuckin'...
Ah!
(CHUCKLES)
It's so cute.
So, how many people
do you think are coming
to the Meet the Candidate Night?
Well, I told all the moms that I would
bang their husbands
if they didn't
show up, so...
AMY: (CHUCKLES) Carla.
A lot. My answer is a lot.
Thank you, Kiki.
Oh, Jesus, you guys, look at the kids.
My daughter won't stop studying.
CARLA: Oh, feel lucky.
All my kid wants
to do with books
is rip 'em in half.
I just wish I knew
how I was doing, you know?
Yeah, that's the worst part
about being a mom, though,
is you don't know
whether or not
you're doing a good job
until they're fully grown.
And by that point, it's too late.
(AMY SIGHS)
Your kid
is either a nice guy
or he's giving hand
jobs in an alley for rent.
I don't think those
are the only two options.
(BLOWS RASPBERRY)
(CHUCKLES)
Yesterday, I gave
Bernard the wrong juice box
and he called me a dumb bitch.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
My kid still
watches Sesame Street
and he doesn't get it.
(CHUCKLES)
My daughter's scared of balloons.
My kid eats butter like an entrée.
You gonna eat your butter?
My daughter stole money
from a homeless woman.
(KIKI SIGHS)
My son failed study hall.
Claire killed our neighbor's ferret.
I mean, we all pretended
like it was an accident,
but it wasn't.
She's a killer.
(LAUGHING)
Ugh.
I know we make
fun of them, but fuck,
I love them so much.
KIKI: Me too.
I would literally die for them right now.
Oh, you're making me cry.
(SNIFFLES)
I'm already there.
I mean, oh, my God,
you guys, children are such a gift.
Every time I think about that big,
dumb motherfucker going off to college,
I wanna cry like a baby.
(BLOWS NOSE)
This sucks.
I can't believe you're making me cook
my own breakfast every single day.
You're doing
awesome, buddy.
You really are.
Hey, so where's my science project?
Oh, I didn't do it.
What? But it's due today.
Yeah. Yeah.
That's so unfair!
I know. I know.
I'm so sorry.
But you're gonna actually have to start
doing your own homework from now on.
I am a slow learner, remember?
You're not a slow learner.
You're just entitled.
Honey, do you know what "entitled" means?
No. Because
I'm a slow learner.
It means that
Mommy and Daddy
have been spoiling you,
and now you think
the world owes
you something,
but it doesn't.
And if you don't learn
how to work hard now,
then you're just gonna
grow up to be like
another entitled white dude
who thinks he's awesome for no reason.
And then you'll start a ska band,
and it'll be awful,
and you'll be mean
to girls,
and you'll grow
this ironic mustache
to look interesting,
but you won't
actually be interesting,
and I'm not okay with that.
So will you please,
please, just do
your own homework?
Fine. Jesus!
Great.
I love you.
So where are your kids tonight?
Oh, they're staying at a friend's house.
I gave my kid $10 and a cell phone
and I dropped him off at Arby's.
He'll be fine for hours.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
CARLA: (GASPS)
Somebody's here.
Amy for president!
AMY: Yes!
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Thank you so much for coming.
I didn't want her to bang my husband.
No, she was just kidding.
Oh.
(MOUTHING)
I wasn't kidding.
Ugh.
Come in, come in.
I'm sorry, nobody's
here yet.
Yeah, well, I figured, what
with Gwendolyn's party
and everything. (CHUCKLES)
I'm sorry, what did you say?
Oh, nuts.
You didn't know.
Gwendolyn decided
to throw a competing
party at her house.
And she has Martha Stewart.
How would you like to try
these special meatballs?
Now, I don't have anything
nice to say to anyone,
but I have to tell you, I just love you.
I've always wanted to be you, actually.
Yes.
Oh.
Martha, sweetheart.
Hi, hi.
Everything looks so beautiful.
Well, thank you so much,
and how's Blaire and Gandhi?
It's been nice
talking to you, Martha,
but I have things to do.
Stop talking to her.
Okay.
Um, ladies? Hi, can I get
your attention, please?
Eyes here so I know
you're hearing me.
PARTY GUESTS: Shh.
Listen, the program
is gonna begin
in about five minutes,
so take your assigned seats, okay?
Right now. Do it right now.
I can't believe Gwendolyn would do this.
I'm so sorry, sweetie.
You guys, what are we
gonna do with
all this shitty wine?
For the next two hours,
I'm gonna talk to you guys
about the advantages
of year-round school.
We need to change our children's future
by making them
go to school
365 days a year.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Three, two, one, go!
(GASPS) Catfish!
Did she say it?
Drink again!
Drink again,
drink again!
Why am I the one that's always drinking?
Because you said the clue word.
KIKI: That's when
you say it.
I don't understand this game.
It's not a reading game!
(CARLA LAUGHING)
Okay, go.
Amy.
AMY: What?
Emu!
No, Amy!
(INDISTINCT)
It said fuckin' "emu"!
You're not good at this.
(LAUGHING)
CARLA: Drink!
Drink again!
I'm gonna take you back a little bit.
Genghis Khan.
Do you think he had
year-round schooling?
I think not.
Skip forward a little bit.
Osama bin Laden.
(CELL PHONES RINGING)
He didn't have
year-round school.
(INDISTINCT MURMURS)
There's nothing
more dangerous
than summer vacation.
GWENDOLYN:
Okay, ladies?
WOMAN: Yeah, let's go.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hi, I'm Amy, nice to see you.
Come in, come in, come in.
Wow, there's a lot of you.
Ooh.
Are you sure you
can't stay a little
bit longer?
I've only got my sitter
until 9:00.
Oh.
So I have to skedaddle right now.
Okay. No, I understand.
I'm a mom.
I had such a great night.
Bye!
WOMAN: We'll see you
over there.
Well, that ended
a lot earlier
than I anticipated.
Yeah.
You don't think they're all going over
to Amy's party, do you?
(LAUGHS)
Vicky, we had
Martha fuckin' Stewart
here tonight.
Who does Amy have, hmm?
I'll drive.
She could
have a point, yeah.
(ALL CHEERING)
This party is raging.
What a turnout.
(GASPS)
Hi, would you ladies
like a Jell-O shot?
Is that...
Martha Stewart?
KIKI: Thank you.
AMY: Martha.
Oh, my God.
MARTHA: Good, right?
I'm cumming.
AMY: Oh, my God.
What's in this?
Well, it's bespoke lingonberry gelatin...
Mmm.
...and a shitload of vodka.
(CHUCKLES)
They're delicious.
I start my day with six of these.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Drink! Drink!
Drink! Drink! Drink!
(LAUGHING)
Whoo!
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(CHEERING)
Holy shit.
Is that Jennifer
Noonan peeing
behind that car?
STACY: Oh, my goodness.
VICKY: This party
looks awesome!
I need to go to this party.
What? Vicky!
Whoo!
Please, shut up!
Just shut up for one second.
I know it's a school night,
so we're just gonna
get right down to it.
I wanna introduce you
to your next PTA president...
(ALL CHEERING)
Amy Mitchell!
Yes!
First of all, I just wanna say this,
that I think that we,
as moms,
do way too much stuff.
And if I'm elected,
I promise you
we are gonna do way less.
Whoo!
Right? Less PTA meetings,
less luncheons,
less fuckin' bake sales,
just less bullshit!
(ALL CHEERING)
AMY:
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
And I think that our kids
need a break, too, you guys.
Come on, now, school
starts way too fucking
early, okay?
God, and they have way too much homework.
I mean, our kids don't even have time
to be kids anymore, am I right?
(ALL AGREEING)
And what is up with these
five standardized tests
a week?
We should not be
teaching our kids
how to be good test-takers.
We should be teaching them
how to be good people!
What is a standardized test?
So, if you're a mom
who's overworked,
overstressed,
or if you're just a mom
who wants to do less...
ALL: Yes!
Then just vote for me.
(ALL CHEERING)
ALL: (CHANTING)
Amy! Amy! Amy! Amy! Amy!
This basic bitch right here,
she's gonna win the election.
No, she's not.
Because I'm going to
hit her where it counts.
You're gonna punch her in the vagina?
I literally don't know
why we hang out
with you anymore.
Do you know the best thing
about mom parties?
They end at exactly
11:00.
(CHUCKLES)
I made out with so many women tonight.
I know.
KIKI: Guys...
I really like whippets.
(LAUGHING)
Hello?
Wow. Hey.
What are you doing here?
Well, you kind of booty texted me.
Uh...
What?
It was a great party,
Am. So, uh...
Okay.
You got
all this, right?
Hi, Jessie.
I really like
your clothes.
That was odd.
(INAUDIBLE)
(CHUCKLES)
I'm so sorry.
Um...
I actually think Carla
may have booty texted you
off my phone.
Oh, okay. (LAUGHS)
Okay, that makes sense
because what she wrote
was fuckin' disturbing.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Um, I don't know.
Should I leave?
No.
Uh...
I was really hoping you'd say that.
So what exactly did Carla text you?
Why don't I show you?
(GASPS) Oh.
Okay.
(GASPS)
Oh, yes!
(BOTH MOAN)
AMY: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
(JESSIE PANTING)
Oh, that was...
Unbelievable.
I can't...
(BOTH BREATHING HEAVILY)
What was that...
Wow.
That thing you did at the end?
(LAUGHS)
I don't know.
I kind of came up with it in the moment.
Was it okay?
Oh, my God,
it was amazing!
Yeah?
That was by far
the best I've ever had.
Oh, God.
Oh, I was so worried.
You know, it's been
awhile since
I've done this.
I think I got pregnant.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, my God.
Really. Hey.
Hi, yeah.
Can I go down
on you again?
Oh, yeah, that'd be great.
Cool.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Oh, my God.
Okay.
All right.
Oh.
Mmm.
(GASPS) Oh.
Oh, look at you go.
VICKY: God,
it's dark in here.
(WHISPERING) God.
I still don't understand
what we're doing.
Stop it.
You guys never
tell me what we're...
GWENDOLYN:
Vicky, why are you
so fuckin' stupid?
I like to start by saying
that every marriage
is savable.
You just need two people
who are willing
to work at it.
Okay?
Mike, Amy, I want you
to look at each other
and say three things
that you like
about each other.
Mike?
Can I go second?
Okay. Yeah, sure.
Uh, Amy?
Okay, uh, Mike,
I like that you
gave me my children.
Uh, I like that you
pick them up
from school sometimes.
It's actually really helpful.
And, uh, I like that you
came to therapy today.
Okay, Mike. Your turn.
MIKE: Okay.
I like your spaghetti.
And you make pretty good calzone.
Was that three?
That was like one and then 1A.
You know what? Um...
Let's try some role playing.
All right, Amy,
I want you to
pretend to be Mike,
and Mike, I want you
to pretend to be Amy.
Okay? And now
I just want you to
just tell me about your day.
(IN FALSETTO)
Hi, I'm Amy.
All I did today was, like,
rub lotion on my face
and talk, talk, talk, talk.
Okay. Uh...
Amy, would you like to...
Yes, I would!
Hey, I'm Mike.
Um...
My life is awesome
because my wife takes care
of everything
in the world for me.
This is the problem!
Here's the bottom line!
She's a perfectionist.
So what's the point of even trying, okay?
How is that a problem?
And she hasn't given me a blowie
since my birthday five years ago!
Are you fucking
kidding me?
Which is so not cool!
Hold on one second!
You want a blowie?
Maybe if you
cleaned the kitchen,
made the kids dinner,
cared for someone other than yourself,
I would give you so many blowies
your fuckin' dick would explode.
My dick would never explode
'cause it's indestructible.
Oh, my God,
I can't deal with you!
I can't fucking look at you.
I'm...
Mike, I...
I don't love you anymore.
I'm so sorry, but I just don't.
I'm so sick and tired
of pretending like I do.
That is exactly how I feel.
Okay...
Remember when I said that
all marriages are savable?
Well, it ain't gonna happen for you guys.
So what do you think we should do?
Well, as a therapist,
I'm not allowed
to tell you what to do,
but as a human being
with two fuckin' eyes
in my head,
yeah, I think you
should get divorced
as soon as possible.
This is some catastrophic shit.
I think it's for the best.
Yeah. Me too.
Can I give you a hug?
Mike. I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
Mmm.
You gotta watch out for you first.
Dale, why is there
a security guard
in my office?
Hey, Amy, uh, I'm so sorry,
but we're gonna have to
positively transition you.
Are you firing me?
Yuck. Okay,
that's not my word.
I don't like that word.
But, yes, I'm firing you.
Why?
Well, you quit coming to the office.
Okay, maybe I've been
slacking off
a little bit, but...
Tessa took two weeks off
when Jon Snow died
on Game of Thrones,
and he's not even a real person.
To be fair,
we all took two weeks off
when Jon Snow died.
You're the only person
that didn't
take two weeks off.
But as a token of appreciation
for your six years with the company,
I got you a very special gift.
You got me
the four-ounce bag?
Couldn't even splurge for the eight?
(SHRIEKS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
What?
PRINCIPAL BURR: Ms. Mitchell,
this is Principal Burr.
We need you to come in.
Okay, okay.
I'll be right there,
and I'm very sorry,
Principal, for how
I answered the phone.
I'm sorry.
You found what?
I found marijuana cigarettes
in your daughter's locker.
Now, it looks like
Sour Diesel or
a little Afghan Kush.
That's impossible.
She's only 12.
It happens.
Snoop been smokin'
since he was five.
Those aren't mine.
I mean, Mom, I swear to God,
they're not mine.
Baby, I believe you.
And why were you looking
in my locker anyway?
We were tipped off by a concerned parent.
Wait a minute.
Was this
concerned parent's name
Gwendolyn James?
Hey, listen, I don't
know nothin' about
Gwendolyn James, all right?
That woman scares me.
What I do know
is this school is
a zero-tolerance school,
so that means that your daughter's banned
from all extra-curricular
activities.
What does that mean?
That means you're off the soccer team.
What?
Oh, my God.
Hey, my hands were tied.
Honey, baby, hold on.
That little girl rolls a real tight jay.
This is all your fault.
Why did you mess with Gwendolyn James?
AMY: Sweetie,
I am so sorry.
Honey, please, I didn't mean for this.
Yes, you did mean to, Mom!
You were sick of being a mom, so you quit
and you started partying
with your weird, new friends,
and blowing off work, and, oh, yeah,
having sex with Lori Harkness' dad.
So gross!
Honey, I know that you're mad.
I get it.
You are so selfish, Mom.
You are so selfish
and it frigging
sucks, okay?
Baby, I'm so sorry.
Tell me, how can I
make this better?
No. I wanna stay
with Dad tonight.
Even he's a better parent than you.
(SIGHS)
Oh, my God.
Guys! Guys, guys.
Did you hear?
Amy Mitchell's daughter
got busted for drugs.
What? No way!
Yeah.
Look, I am not blaming
Amy Mitchell. I mean,
my God, I would never...
Of course.
...ever judge
another mother,
but I think we really
have to ask ourselves,
do we want someone
who is that reckless
and irresponsible
and mentally unhinged
alcoholic to be president
of the PTA?
I don't know.
You know what?
I never even liked her.
She looks foreign.
Oh, God.
Foreigners.
Listen. I think now
we just need to pray
that Amy's little
crackhead daughter
gets the help she needs.
(INAUDIBLE)
Mike, if Janey needs anything,
and I mean anything, just please call me.
Babe, it's gonna be fine.
I'm staying at the Waldorf.
They got
an indoor-outdoor pool,
room service,
18-hole golf course.
It's killer.
You're staying at the Waldorf?
God, this is a divorce,
not a luxury vacation, Mike.
It's a safe hotel.
Wait, bye, angel!
Have so much
fun with Daddy!
Can I get a hug?
No? Okay. Okay.
Oh, no, buddy, wait.
You're also going?
Dylan, you know the hotel has TVs.
You don't have to bring your own.
(ROSCOE WHINES)
Oh, Roscoe, not you, too.
Oh, the Waldorf's
dog-friendly,
so don't worry.
Yeah. So.
Mike, please go.
Yeah.
Bye, kids.
(SIGHS)
PRINCIPAL BURR: Welcome to
the annual PTA election.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
We will start with
the candidates' statements,
and since only one bothered to show up,
she will go first.
Gwendolyn, you have five minutes.
Thank you.
I'll talk as long as I want.
(MAN SCREAMING
ON TV)
God, this movie's depressing.
(KNOCKING)
CARLA: Amy! Amy,
I'm sorry we're late.
Oh, my God!
It's Kiki's fault.
Sorry we're late, honey.
So sorry.
I had to pee.
What's happening?
Why aren't you ready?
What's going on?
What are you talking about?
What are you...
It's the PTA election.
Oh, my God, no.
Sorry, I'm not
going to that.
What? Why not?
Oh, I don't know.
Maybe because my
husband left me,
my kids left me.
My fucking dog left me.
All the moms in school hate me,
and I am a complete
and utter failure
as a mother.
First of all, you are
so not a failure
as a mother.
In fact,
you're the best mother
that we've ever seen.
True that.
You give your kids salad.
You remember your kids' birthdays.
I mean, I sat here and watched you wait
until your kid fell
asleep before you got high.
Most moms do that, Carla.
(WHISPERS)
That's most moms, yeah.
Well, whatever.
This is the worst thing
I've ever seen you do.
You've quit trying.
We don't quit!
Moms don't quit!
No! Quitting
is for dads!
Uh...
Listen, no matter what
shit is thrown at us,
us moms, we have to just...
We have to just
keep going.
Mmm-hmm.
And do you know why?
Because we have
low self-esteem.
No. No, no.
It's because we love our kids.
It's because we love our stupid,
selfish, ungrateful,
little shit-faces!
That's why.
We love 'em so much that we would do...
Literally anything for them.
You guys, I can't win the election.
Oh, my God!
Amy!
This is not
about the election.
Amy, sit up.
This is about standing up to the bitch
that hurt your little girl!
Now, are you gonna sit here
and let Gwendolyn get
away with this shit?
Don't do it, Amy.
Fuck that!
Fuck it!
You are gonna rise up
like a small, little
white Apollo Creed
and you are gonna
look at Gwendolyn
and you are gonna say,
"You can do what
you want to me,
I don't care,
"throw it at me,
"but you fucked with my daughter,
"and now I have to fight you.
"I will fight you in the playground.
"I will fight you in the cafeteria.
"I will even fight you
in the parking
lot of Trader Joe's.
"But I will have
justice for
my little girl,
"because I am a fucking mom.
"And we protect
our young."
So get up off this couch,
turn off 12 Years a Slave
and let's body slam this bitch.
KIKI:
Come on, Amy.
Come on,
get those tits up.
Get 'em up.
Get your boobs up.
Get those tits right up.
I'm gonna get
my tits up.
Get your tits up!
They're getting up,
you guys.
They're getting up.
I can see it.
Guys, my tits
are gettin' up.
They're getting up.
That's it.
They are up!
(CARLA WHOOPING)
Go, go, go, go!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Oh, my God.
I can't seem to locate
my safety belt back here.
This is a one-way street!
Move out of the way!
We're on our way
to a PTA meeting,
motherfuckers!
Oh, my God, there's a truck!
Truck! Truck! Truck!
Oh, my God!
(HONKING)
Oh, my God.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh, shit.
Oh, fun.
Kent is calling.
Hi, honey.
KENT: Kiki.
(CRYING)
The kids are going insane.
I can't do this.
You gotta come home right now.
But I can't come home.
I'm going to the PTA
meeting with my friends.
No, no, no, no.
I said come home now,
damn it!
And I said,
"I'm going to
the fucking PTA meeting
with my fucking friends,"
so stop being
such a goddamn pussy
and make it work!
Kiki. Kiki...
(SCREAMS)
That was very exciting.
How good did that feel?
That felt good, didn't it?
It's very exciting!
Yes!
(CARLA AND AMY WHOOPING)
And it is for that reason
and the 47 others
that I laid out for you today
that I humbly ask for your vote.
All right, thank you, Gwendolyn.
Uh, well...
Sorry I'm late!
Actually, you're
just in time to give
your candidate statement.
What's a candidate statement?
KIKI: Oh, I think
that's like a speech.
You got one of those,
right, honey?
What are you talking about?
You don't have a speech?
(SOFTLY) Of course not!
It's all good.
She's got a great speech.
AMY: I'm not good at
this public speaking.
Hey, we're sitting here.
Move, move, sorry, move.
(EXHALES)
Okay.
Wow, there's a lot of you.
Introduce yourself.
Hi, I'm Amy Mitchell.
Good.
And I'm running for PTA president.
(WOMAN COUGHING)
You're doing great.
Just 'cause they're not responding
doesn't mean they think you're terrible.
You know...
I know there's a lot of
rumors going around
about my daughter.
(WOMEN MURMURING)
That's a bad place to start.
And I'm guessing
a lot of you think
that I'm a bad mom.
Yes.
No, no. No,
you know what?
You're right.
Sometimes, I'm too lenient with my kids.
Sometimes, I'm too strict.
Well, we overestimated her, obviously.
Sometimes, I'm so crazy
that I don't even understand the words
that are coming out of my mouth.
You see, what works
for my daughter almost
never works for my son.
And whenever I think
I'm actually starting
to figure my kids out,
they grow up and I'm back to square one.
So, the truth is,
when it comes to being a mom,
(CHUCKLES)
I have no fucking clue what I'm doing.
(ALL LAUGH)
And you know what?
I don't think anyone does.
I think we're all
bad moms,
and you know why?
Because being a mom today is impossible!
I never doubted her.
She's doing great.
She's a natural.
So can we all just
please stop pretending
like we have it figured out
and stop judging each other for once?
Look, I'm running
for PTA president because...
Because I want our school to be a place
where you can make mistakes,
where you can be yourself,
where you're being judged
on how hard you work
and not on what you bring
to the fucking bake sale.
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDING)
Yeah!
I want our school
to be a place where it's okay
to be a bad mom.
Do you know what I mean?
My kids haven't had
a bath in three weeks.
That's okay! Listen,
we've all been there.
(ALL CLAPPING)
I confiscated my son's weed
and then I smoked
the shit out of it!
(YELLS)
What's your number?
I give my kids a Benadryl
every Tuesday night
so I can watch The Voice.
(LAUGHS)
I can't tell my twins apart!
I let my 7-year-old
watch Mad Max.
I drink margaritas for breakfast.
I threw my son's violin in the garbage.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Oh, honey, we don't speak Spanish.
I like my nanny better
than I like my husband.
Wait, really?
(WOMEN GASP AND CHEER)
(WHOOPING)
Yeah, you do!
I don't even have kids!
I just come to
PTA meetings
because I'm lonely.
CROWD: Aw.
(APPLAUSE)
AMY: Here's the thing.
If you're a perfect mom
who's got this whole
parenting thing figured out,
well, then, you should
probably vote
for Gwendolyn,
'cause she's amazing.
Yes.
But if you're a bad mom like me
and you have no fucking clue
what you're doing,
or you're just
sick of being judged
all the time...
Then please vote for me.
Thank you.
(LOUD CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Oh, my God!
Are you kidding me?
Yes!
ALL: (CHANTING)
Amy! Amy! Amy!
Look at that!
This is your PTA president!
ALL: (CHANTING)
Amy! Amy! Amy!
Oh, mama.
I feel invigorated.
This is so great!
I still can't believe
you won.
I know!
Oh, I'm so happy
you guys dragged me
out of the house.
Oh, sweetheart,
I didn't doubt you
for a second.
Oh, God, you know, I forgot what it was
like to have real friends,
like, true friends.
I know.
Before you guys,
my only friend
was that lady on Google Maps.
(LAUGHS)
You're pretty much the first bitches
to ever talk to me at this school, so...
I'm so happy we found
each other, you guys.
Me too.
Me three.
Let's hug for a really long time.
Come on, bring it in.
Bring it in.
(KIKI LAUGHS)
(SAD MUSIC PLAYING
OVER CAR STEREO)
(GWENDOLYN SOBBING)
Hey, will you guys
give me, like, a second?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, honey. Sure.
Okay.
Sure, take a minute.
Digest it.
Thanks.
What, did you come
to gloat? (SNIFFLES)
No. No, no, I'm just
seeing if you're okay.
I'm fine.
Everything's fine.
Okay. I don't wanna
bother you.
No, I'm good.
It's just that the PTA
was the only good
thing in my life and
now I've lost that, too.
Come on, Gwendolyn, your life is awesome.
You have, like, three boats.
I have four boats.
(LAUGHS) Okay.
But, no... (SCOFFS)
My life is so not awesome.
Gwendolyn, what could possibly be wrong?
Oh, God.
Okay, well,
for starters...
(SNIFFLES)
My husband was just arrested
for embezzling
$100 million from a children's charity.
(VOICE BREAKING)
And I have night terrors.
And I have to take
Vicodin every 20 minutes,
and I'm not even in any pain.
I'm just addicted to them now.
I'm pretty sure
my brother-in-law
just joined ISIS, and he's a Jew!
Oh, and also, my DVR
just stopped recording
Castle.
Just out of nowhere.
Like, how the fuck does that even happen?
And I am the only thing
holding my family together,
so, yeah, it's awesome.
It's just awesome.
Wow.
I had no idea.
Yeah.
You just always acted like
everything was so perfect.
Hey,
I'm really sorry about
what I did to your daughter.
I promise you I will
get her back on
the soccer team, all right?
I know that was
a really shitty thing to do.
Yeah.
Even for me.
Listen, we're all bad moms, right?
Yeah.
That was
literally the only thing
you said tonight
that made any fuckin' sense.
(LAUGHS)
Bye.
Hey, guys. Can I talk
to you for a second?
Yeah.
Look, I just wanna say
I'm really sorry
for how I've been
acting lately.
Oh, it's fine.
Yeah, it's just
menopause, right?
(CHUCKLES) No.
It's not menopause.
And I'm sorry for acting so crazy
about the whole soccer thing.
I'm really trying to chill out more.
I mean, it's just
soccer. Right?
I got you back on the soccer team.
Shut up!
Shut up.
Shut your face!
Oh, my God.
Thank you so much, Mom.
(CHUCKLES)
Oh, I love you.
Get in here.
There. Oh, I love you guys
so much.
You're amazing kids.
I promise, I promise
to always be here for you.
Oh.
My babies.
(OVEN DINGS)
Oh...
I almost forgot!
Where is he going?
Why is he touching the oven?
DYLAN: I made a frittata.
Did you just say "frittata"?
You said you weren't
gonna cook for us
anymore,
so I taught myself how to cook.
Oh, honey, I'm so
proud of you!
Get in here. I love you.
I love you.
Okay, okay,
all right, all right.
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
All right, okay, let go.
Okay.
I gotta go
do my homework.
Who are you?
(SONG PLAYING)
I said, "You're holding back"
She said,
"Shut up and dance with me!"
This woman is my destiny
She said, "Ooh-ooh-hoo,
Shut up and dance with me!"
(LAUGHS)
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Oh, hold on.
Sorry, guys.
One sec, one sec.
Hello, this is Amy.
Hey, Amy, it's Dale.
The company is
falling apart without you.
Could you please come back?
I will give you whatever you want.
Whatever?
Whatever I want?
Yes! Yes! Anything.
Okay, um, well, I wanna double my pay.
I wanna work from home two days a week.
Oh, and I wanna hire
three women over
the age of 12
to fill out my team.
Okay, okay, fine.
Anything you want.
Can you start today?
Oh, no, no. No, sorry,
today's not good for me.
I'll start sometime
next week.
Thanks. Bye-bye.
(SCREAMS)
Come here.
Love you.
Great day at school.
Love you, Mom.
I love you kiddos.
Be great, okay?
Okay.
Be amazing. Be awesome.
Love you!
(SIGHS)
When did they get so big?
I don't know.
Hey, what would happen
if I came over
Friday night,
brought a great bottle of wine,
you know, made you a nice dinner,
maybe ran you a hot bath
and someone just
took care of you...
I love you.
...for a change?
What did you just say?
What?
What was that?
I said nothing.
You said nothing.
I meant to say that I...
God, I would love that.
I would love that.
Great.
Yeah.
I'll see you Friday.
Okay.
I'll see you after school.
Be good, okay?
VICKY: Hey, how's it going?
I'm doing amazing.
I slept in late,
skipped my workout,
had, like, four donuts.
I told these kids,
"Look, you get yourself
ready for school today."
And my husband totally
Fifty-Shaded me
this morning.
Oh.
I've never felt better.
Wow.
Yeah.
Hi!
Did you remember Maddie's backpack?
(SIGHS)
Shoot. No, I left it
in the car.
Okay, well,
let's go get it, dude.
Right?
Chop-chop.
I'm so sorry.
Be right back.
It's not gonna grab itself.
Hey, Jackson.
I, uh...
I made you lunch today.
It's a hummus wrap with some kale.
Gross!
Yeah, I know,
it sounds totally disgusting,
but it's supposed to
be good for you, so...
And I'm gonna come to your
baseball game tomorrow night.
For real?
I'm gonna stay
the whole stupid game.
Mmm-hmm.
Because...
I love you.
And stuff.
CARLA: Oh.
(SIGHS)
Still cannot believe I pushed
that thing outta my chotch.
Hey. What's up,
pretty ladies?
What should we do today?
How about we go to brunch?
Mmm.
Oh, how about we go to Color Me Mine
and make each other salad bowls?
I love it.
Oh, I got an idea.
Why don't we try something
that doesn't suck?
Hey, bitches! Get in.
Wait.
Holy shit.
Wait. Wait.
Wait. Is that...
Well, I have my husband's
plane for the whole day,
so where do you guys wanna go, huh?
You know what?
Gwendolyn's starting
to grow on me, guys.
I'm not gonna lie to you.
I think she's
a really good person.
Come on, come on!
Very generous.
(CHATTERING EXCITEDLY)
My role as a mother
was so hit-and-miss.
(LAUGHS)
I was a little looser,
but too loose
in many ways.
I would give her whiskey.
(LAUGHS)
We left the country
when she was
seven years old.
My mom kept telling me
that we were
moving up the street.
And then we flew to L.A.
My mother's a filthy liar.
When I went into labor and stuff,
I didn't even ask if
it was a boy or a girl.
I just asked for Demerol.
(LAUGHING)
I heard someone calling my name.
"Please come to
the service desk."
I thought,
"What's that?"
And I looked around,
there was no Kathryn.
(GASPS)
She was three years old.
(LAUGHING)
I was three years old.
I'm thinking, oh, my God, that was bad!
When I was nine years old,
um, my mom
took me to see Cruising
in the theaters
because she loved Al Pacino.
I loved Al Pacino.
Cruising is a movie about a man
investigating the
underworld of
S&M gay clubs
because there was
a man murdering men
after raping them.
Al Pacino.
You do stupid things as a parent
and you're like,
"Oh, they're fine,
they're fine,"
and then you're in the hospital.
Yeah, of course
you lie to your kids,
of course you do,
and you go
through their things.
You have to.
You go through my things?
Sometimes you have to make people happy,
to lie a little bit.
You know?
Easter Bunny.
Tooth Fairy.
(CHUCKLES)
Food out for Santa Claus.
You had me clean the fireplace that year.
Yeah, well, that was a good idea anyway.
Like a chimney sweep.
I would just be all, you know, upset
because of the way
I thought that it had to be.
You know,
I was so angry one day,
and I said to her,
"Dominic doesn't like you,
Eric doesn't like you."
You told me to fuck off.
(SNORTS)
"Laura doesn't like you.
Your dad doesn't like you."
You said, "Fuck you, Mom."
Or something like that.
"I don't like you,
and the dog
doesn't like you."
(LAUGHING)
Yeah, I don't know what I was thinking.
I just really didn't have a clue about...
You were perfect.
(LAUGHS)
Yeah, it kind of worked out for her.
It worked out perfectly.
I had the best childhood.
I loved my childhood.
I had a very happy childhood.
And we would have the best days.
Yeah, it was absolutely like
some of the best
times of my life.
You were an amazing mom.
(LAUGHING)
Which is fine.
I feel good.
It's nuts
being a mom, guys.
(BLOWS NOSE)
Raising kids is an amazing experience.
I did some mistakes,
but the end,
I can see it's not as bad.
They survived.
In spite of us.
Now, thank goodness...
(LAUGHS)
You know, she turned out
to be the wonderful
woman that she is.
I think she's perfect.
The love that you had
when that kid was born,
that you didn't have...
(SNIFFLES)
It is a miracle.
It's the wife that she is
and the mother that she is,
and I'm really proud of just her.
Mom.
Yeah.
She's so good, like a mom.
She's so good.
Yeah.
Thanks, Mommy.
So I think
she's the best mom
in the world,
and I go, "I wish,
you know, I'd been
more like that."
Oh.
I love you.
I love you, hon.
I love you, Mommy.
(LAUGHING)
Aw.
You said it would be fun, Kathryn.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
Don't touch my makeup.
See this shit?
(LAUGHING)